Go! Go!
Jessica, are you
dating anybody?
Jessica, is it true?
The magazine says that you're
still in love with Nick.
Jessica, who are you dating?
I love you, Jessica!
Jessica?
Jessica, is it true that
you're still in love with Nick?
Jessica...
It's a really, weird, scary
feeling.
- Jessica, is it true...
- You're disoriented.
You can't see in front of you.
It's false imprisonment.
I can't get away.
I can't get out.
I can't get out of a store because
these guys are blocking the door.
Can't get to my car.
When I'm in my car,
they're surrounding me.
I can't see.
They flash light bulbs.
It's nighttime.
My vision is impaired.
Back off.
Back off!
Jessica?
Jessica...
It's high stress.
♪ Bright lights, big
city going to my head ♪
♪ bright lights, big
♪ I don't care, no, 'cause
you don't care, no ♪
♪ as long as you know my name ♪
♪ oh, yeah ♪
♪ you're gonna know my name ♪
♪ yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
I've been shooting since the
'80s, and celebrity photography
has changed a lot.
With big award shows, there are
about 50, 60 guys in the pen,
and they're all fighting
for the same image.
They're trying to get a head shot
or a full-length fashion shot.
They're screaming at the
celebrities, trying to get eye
contact into their camera.
Rihanna, you didn't look... - I, on
the other hand, I'm outside the pen.
I'm on the red carpet, where
I go right up to them.
I can make them pose for me, give
me eye contact, or set up a shot.
You'll talk to the p.R. People.
They'll even tell you, flat-out, "we
don't need all these photographers.
It's just for camera and show.
Basically, all we need is,
like, five or six guys.
But no, we want all these
photographers here because it
looks great on camera, and it
makes it look more glamorous."
It's Hollywood.
If you look in the magazines
and on all these websites and
TV shows and seen all these celebrities,
where does it really come from?
The red carpet is just one
piece of what's become a
billion-dollar-a-year industry.
This is the second time
I've seen this picture.
I adore it.
I think you will, too.
In the days of hedda hopper,
at the premiere of something,
the studios would hire photographers,
but it was gracefully waiting.
"May I take a picture?"
It was all agreed upon.
Client would walk in a room
and say, "hey, how'd you get all
these photographers here?!"
- You know?
- Nobody bothered anybody.
I didn't cross your fence.
You didn't cross my fence.
Now it's become something
totally different.
I'm getting a shot!
Someone jumping
over your wall, okay?
Your wall.
You know, how is that
not a clear line?
You can't do that, right?
This is a perfect example
...Marc and I getting married.
We took every precaution and every measure
so we could have a private moment.
Decided to do it in the
backyard, invite 20 people.
They thought they were
coming to a barbecue.
So, some of them are not
even that dressed up.
Wearing shorts.
Marc built the runway.
Literally... hammer and
nails, 'cause to get a
contractor to do that,
it would have been...
We couldn't trust anybody.
We had to do it all
ourselves, which is fine.
It was actually a beautiful
experience in its own way.
But even with that,
they found a way.
Helicopter comes over, right
as I'm walking down the aisle.
We couldn't hear each
other making the vows.
The people who were there
couldn't hear our vows.
Till this day, I'm not sure
if she said yes, because...
Did you?
You did, right?
You know, technically, you can get out
of this, because I never heard it.
But that place
wasn't even sacred.
Shouldn't our home,
at least, be sacred?
Yeah, at getty images, we're
selling an image every single second.
And within the news or editorial
area, about 40% of all those
images are entertainment images.
I get the same names
thrown at me.
"Oh, do you work with
Annie leibovitz?
Do you work with
Patrick demarchelier?"
But the most published
photographers in the world are
the entertainment photographers.
A lot of people may not have
heard of them, but these folks
are being published in the thousands
and thousands every week.
Photographers... the
difference in photographers.
Well, I guess there's
three kinds.
You got the guys that you
regularly see on the scene, like
Kevin and guys from wire image, where
you see them at all the shows.
You kind of become
friends with them.
They're not looking
for a bad shot.
They're looking for
something interesting.
Cool... no problem.
Then, you got the "stalkerazzis,"
you know, who go
through anything to get a shot
and who sit there like you're
eating lunch with a bag with a
big camera in it and whip it out
on you, like, a moment's notice.
And then some of the worst offenders are
just the creepos with the cellphones.
They're acting like they're
looking for a number when I'm
buying a Boca burger, which I
don't want anybody to know about.
You know what I mean?
I eat steaks and meat.
I'm a badass.
I'm in the Boca burger
section, like... "Fuck!"
You know?
So, I'm like that.
Those people suck.
People with mobile phones.
You can't go anywhere without being
photographed, basically, now.
You have to be very careful.
You have to accept it, you have
to be aware of it, and you have
to behave accordingly.
Now, the regular citizens
have become paparazzis.
You're not safe anywhere.
Anyone can sell you.
Anyone can sell a piece of you.
The kind of fascination that we have
with celebrities changed over time.
We used to go and see movies in
these amazing movie houses, many
of which were not only built to look
like palaces but were called palaces.
And we would sit in the dark,
and we would watch these huge,
larger-than-life people... idols
that were literally like deities.
The first people who appeared in
movies, their names weren't used.
The audience had to make up their
own names for these people.
Mary pickford, for instance,
became known as "the girl with
the curls," because the
studios didn't promote them.
They knew if they promoted them that
they would have to pay them more.
Pickford really changed
that, personally.
She and her mother invented
stardom and the percentage deal.
"The movie makes so much
money, I make so much money."
Unheard of, unthinkable.
And she married Douglas Fairbanks, who,
on the male side, did the same thing.
Back when Hollywood was in its
golden age, it was glamorous
and beautiful and mysterious, and
you wondered how they lived.
And if they did a spread in somebody's
house, it was just so special.
And now we're so exposed.
There's no mystery.
Today, celebrity is an
industry, and in every industry,
you have raw material.
And the raw material in the
celebrity industry is an actual
body, an actual flesh-and-blood
person, who has feelings, has
emotions, has a family.
That raw material is shaped.
You have to look a certain way.
So, they have a stylist and ay.
Publicist and a manager and an
agent that help form the raw
material into the
finished product.
Second of all, you have
authorized publicity, things
that the celebrity and his or
her publicist have decided will
become part of this person's
image... interviews, magazine
covers, the actual films, the
products in which the star appears.
And then you have the
unauthorized publicity, which is
paparazzi photography and
gossip, unsanctioned.
But, at the same time, it still contributes
to the formation of the image.
Next, media takes this image
and gives it to the consumer.
As far as outlets, there's print,
there's television, and there's online.
So, some of the authorized
outlets would be people,
"entertainment tonight,"
"extra," "access Hollywood," and then a
star's website or a star's fan club.
Unauthorized?
In print, we have in
touch and life & style.
There's gossip blogs, like tmz,
Perez Hilton, dlisted, gawker.
So, bottom line, all these
different players... they're all
interconnected and
symbiotic on one another.
Watch the cars behind you guys.
Have a great day.
I don't know who that was.
Do you know?
No. Pretty hot.
There she is. Look.
And she sells?
Oh, fuck, yeah, she sells!
Yeah, yeah, she
sells, for sure.
Usually, they run,
what, $250, $500.
Truthfully.
Usually, they're $50, $250,
to as much as $250,000.
Oh, there's keyshawn Johnson.
Because here's the deal.
You may get nothing today, but
you may come today or tomorrow
and make more in one day
than most make in a year.
For the love of the game.
The problem is, it has to be
the most audacious, the most
outrageous, the most intrusive behavior
may get the most saleable shot.
The agencies are trying to get
that to sell them to magazines
or video outlets that
will pay money for it.
And the public buys the magazines
and watches the shows.
So, it's that whole cycle.
Hey, guys!
Get back!
Guys, guys!
Mike, right here.
Part of the game is
to provoke a reaction.
Get back, guys.
Best thing that will happen
is somebody will take a swing at
them, you know, or start
pushing or screaming.
That's a better shot.
It's more money.
Who are you dating?!
They usually bring up
ex-girlfriends, ex-wives.
They say stuff about Pam.
There's not too much they can
really say to get my goat.
It's more invading your
space, getting in your face.
You're like, "wait a minute.
I don't know you, dude.
You're gonna come at me and
try to get a reaction?"
There's my reaction.
We're all good.
I've given them one or
two of those in my time.
But now you just have to know
that that's the photograph that
they want, and you just have
to not give it to them.
What they're trying
to do is provoke you.
Like, "oh, you were voted
worst 'this' or 'that.'"
and if they do provoke you, they
have won, and you have lost.
- Me, on the other hand...
- Yeah.
Marc doesn't have as much
of a tolerance for that stuff.
So, we try not to put him in
those situations too often.
Lindsay, big smile!
They kind of want Lindsay Lohan to
melt down in public so they've got their
photograph.
This week in the celebrity spotlight,
Lindsay Lohan is jail-bound...
And, you know, half the time
she gives them the thing they
want, and it's very sad, because it's
like, this girl was a good actress.
She had talent.
She made records, you know?
And now it's kind of
she's become their toy.
It's frightening.
There is a uniquely American
sport called "grandicide."
We build someone up to spectacular
heights in order to tear them down.
It's a vicious cycle.
You build up.
You break her down.
The next famous person
comes back again.
Next thing, you have to
break them down again.
So, you just sit back and watch.
I know it's only a couple days in,
but they say it's gonna go number one.
...superstar whose shocking private
life became an international soap opera.
...questioning whether
she can be a good mother.
...self-destructive cocktail of
courtrooms, psych wards, and paparazzi.
That moment of her just
looking in the camera shaving
her head was such a
powerful moment.
It was like, "fuck you, guys."
I mean, there was something about
it that was just "fuck you."
You know? She had enough.
She broke in front of all of our
eyes, and then people captured that.
But it was really sad to me.
People used to be able to
develop kind of quietly, and if
they made mistakes, the whole
world didn't know about them.
Gee, Mickey, we don't
know how lucky we are.
But that's not the
way it is anymore.
Now, really horrible behavior and
people who are definitely in
trouble and need help are often
just seen as people who are
supposed to entertain you.
This is a mess.
Our celebrity images are
supposed to be seamless.
But when those cracks open, it's kind
of dirty, but it's also fascinating.
I am on a drug.
It's called "Charlie sheen."
But then, you know, if it cracks
open too wide, there's nothing left.
You borrow my brain for
five seconds and just be like,
"dude, can't handle it!"
He's a train wreck.
He's an absolute train
wreck, which is fabulous.
It's great.
You know you shouldn't look,
but you're just curious.
Come on, Mr. "p."
I'm darryn lyons, "Mr. paparazzi,"
and this is my mini-me, Mr. "p."
I started as a news
photographer on a local paper,
but my passion was
certainly photography.
A lot of the world, looking from
the outside in, live really
disinteresting lives, and I
think that is what's captured
the culture of celebrity today.
I'm a true believer
in the image.
I've been to Bosnia on the frontline
getting shot at in full metal jacket.
I've won press photographer for
the year in the United Kingdom
two years in a row.
I've won all the awards you can
imagine being a photographer.
The fact of the matter is,
awards don't pay the mortgage.
I saw celebrity as being the
huge moment of the future.
With mrpaparazzi.Com, I embraced
it, and I'm still embracing it.
Celebrity isn't gonna go away.
It's been around
since time began.
You know, Julius
Caesar was famous.
Napoleon was famous.
They were famous
in different ways.
Your key is mass media.
It had taken Napoleon a
lifetime to become famous.
It took Charlie chaplin a month.
One day he was nobody, and a
month later he was known in the
deepest jungles of Africa.
He couldn't appear in public
without a mob coming around him.
And he had to invent
strategies to deal with that.
♪ Fame, fame ♪
♪ fame, fame ♪
♪ is it any wonder you're
too cool to fool? ♪
♪ fame, fame ♪
♪ fame ♪
♪ bully for you, chilly for me ♪
♪ got to get a rain
check on fame ♪
Celebrity today means
anyone who's famous.
Now, you can be famous... you
know, guy who was in a balloon
who floated across the country.
Is that a star?
You know... Is Jeffrey
dahmer a star?
The real name of
the game is fame.
♪ Oh, fame ♪
♪ oh, fame ♪
♪ fame, fame, fame, fame, fame, fame,
fame, fame, fame, fame, fame, fame ♪
♪ fame ♪
♪ what's your name? ♪
Historically, the American dream meant
that anyone could come to America and
through hard work could own a home
and provide for their family.
Now, the American dream has
really transformed into anyone
can become a celebrity.
Say something with
that great radio voice.
When you're listening to
nothing but the best of oldies...
♪ So hold your head
up, and you'll go far ♪
The way that people talk about
YouTube is that anyone who
puts a video on YouTube
can become famous.
Everyone can deny Justin bieber
a contract, but then because
enough people are interested
him, he can still become famous.
It's this idea that if you have
talent, and if you make that
talent visible, then you can be voted,
in our Democratic society, to be a star.
I think a recent survey of
British children under 15 said
they wanted to be a doctor or a nurse
or an architect or a photographer.
No, they just wanted to
be either rich or famous.
I want to be famous, but,
like, the "Jersey shore" people,
like on a reality
show or something.
I had sex with Vinny.
You had sex with Vinny.
Bring it on!
You know, "Jersey shore's"
a huge success because we're
nutjobs, and we don't care
what people think about us.
So, I think that's why
everybody loves us.
In general, a reality celebrity
is like a one-use celebrity.
You pay a little for them, but
then you can exploit them until
they disintegrate.
There are people out there
now that are completely
celebrities and absolutely
famous who don't work...
Who don't even work.
They have nothing to sell.
They have no product.
- There's...
- It's so scary.
I hate reality television.
I think it's the lowest
common denominator.
It's mind rot to me.
It numbs my brain.
And the people being called
celebrities and have their own
reality shows, I
want to kill them.
Told you you
wouldn't regret it.
I think what people
misunderstand is that we're in
the entertainment industry.
We're not these serious people,
and everyone's just gotten so
used to all these actors taking
themselves so seriously, when
it's really just
a joke industry.
It's supposed to be fun.
You need a keg.
There's nothing wrong with the
Kim kard... all of those people.
If that's how they choose to make
a living, more power to them.
It's not my... my line
of work is different.
I want to entertain people.
Reality TV is, in a
way, the new vaudeville.
There's nothing real
about reality TV.
People are led to believe that
it's real, and it's the big lie.
There's nothing real about it.
I'll tell you the first
time it bothered me.
I walked out of my house.
I wanted to go and get my
mother-in-law a birthday present.
And I walked out, and, for the
first time ever, there were all
these photographers outside.
And my first instinct, curiously
enough, because we're
kind of all animals,
basically, was to run.
But then I got scared to run,
because I was pregnant, and I
didn't trust the streets
of New York to be my ally.
And I started crying, and I said to the
photographers, "please don't chase me.
I'm pregnant.
Please don't chase me."
And they kept following me.
And I went into a building.
I saw a doorman in a building,
and I said to him, "is it okay?
Can I come in your building?"
And he took me down
to the garage.
And there was a couple, and
they were on a motorcycle.
And they saw me crying.
And she and I traded clothing,
everything... from head to
toe... and I got on the back
of her boyfriend's motorcycle.
And she walked out in my clothes, and he
took me elsewhere and dropped me off.
But it's just gotten exponentially
worse ever since then.
Sarah!
Get out of my way, asshole.
♪ Ooh-whee ♪
♪ talkin' 'bout a party ♪
♪ waiting for celebrities ♪
The paparazzi life
is like the lottery.
You might want to take a day
off, but that might be the day
when something major happens.
Oh, he just gave up.
He gave up... quitter.
You're hours away.
I start off very early in the
morning, and I go late at night.
And I try to do it six days a
week, if not seven days a week.
Got to do that
celebrity rain dance.
Come on!
Bring them in. Bring them in.
Bring them in.
I love what I do because I get
to drive up and down the streets
of my favorite city in the world, Los
Angeles, California... - How are you?
- ...interact with celebrities...
- It was awesome!
...meet the tourists.
I can take a day
off when I want.
I'm my own boss.
I have no one to answer to.
Loving life, man.
Loving life.
They would work
together in teams of two.
One of the photographers would
aggravate the celebrity they
were shooting, start some kind
of confrontation, so that the
other one could take
the photograph.
The advent of the paparazzi took
on a whole different nastiness.
Paparazzi were "I'll
get you at any cost.
And I'll get it if it
means killing you."
And the competition among
them was so fierce.
♪ I can't stop this
feeling deep inside of me ♪
Ron galella was probably the
first well-known paparazzi, who
every day woke up and decided
to focus his lens on
Jackie Kennedy no matter what
she was doing or where she was.
♪ I... I'm hooked
on a feeling ♪
♪ high on believing that
you're in love... ♪
Age has been good to Ron, because
he got a lot of very bad press.
He was seen to be a parasite.
His photography's now being collected
by serious photography collectors.
But, you know, when Ron was
working, it was completely
different from the
way it is now.
Getting your picture taken
went from something where you
felt that somebody was honoring
you, a part of you... your work,
your beauty, your youth,
something... to a hunt.
And most of the time, instead of
celebrating something about you,
a lot of the time is trying to
find something wrong with you.
I'm not out to get a bad
shot of Lindsay Lohan.
I'm out to get a shot.
Now, if she's doing good,
well, I'm taking a good shot.
If she's doing bad, well, in her
eyes, I'm taking a bad shot.
To me, it's still the shot.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
You're about the rudest
people I've ever run into.
Thank you.
No wonder people come up and slap you.
He threw the finger at me.
I don't blame him!
You're an asshole!
They use us as a scapegoat.
"Oh, paparazzi... bad.
Well, you took the picture, and
they wrote about it, but you
shouldn't have
took the picture."
Well, okay, but they still sold
magazines, and you still read it.
Hey, I got a question.
Who do you think people hate more, the
parking enforcement or the paparazzi?
You guys.
Really?
Yeah.
I think it's really easy to
blame the paparazzi because
they're actual bodies right there
that we can pinpoint as the cause.
There are photos of the paparazzi getting
in celebrities' faces, whereas the
writers and editors,
completely unseen.
And we certainly don't
want to blame ourselves.
I think the
paparazzi has a place.
40% of many of the magazines
have paparazzi photos.
They're an important
part of the industry.
♪ Whoo-ooh ♪
♪ I want to get
away, get away ♪
♪ whoo-ooh ♪
♪ to our sweet
escape, sweet escape ♪
♪ whoo-ooh ♪
♪ I want to get
away, get away ♪
If I'm in a doctor's office,
and they're all there, and
there's no men around me, that's
the one I'll go for first.
Either ok or us.
I'll pick that up before
a sports illustrated.
Perez Hilton and tmz andok
magazine... yes, I do read them all.
If someone I know is on
the cover and it has the big
headline, I want to
know what's happening.
If there's a controversy,
like, an argument between
people, and I know it's gonna be,
like, ongoing, that's when I buy.
Good gossip, basically.
Confidentialgoes behind the
headlines for its stories...
stories that we feel, that I
feel, the public should know.
Robert Harrison published
kind of pulpy skin magazines out
of his apartment in the 1940s,
and then he started confidential
in the 1950s.
Confidential basically made
what had to that point been
unspeakable speakable.
So, women's sexuality, having relationships
between races, even homosexuality.
Confidential was operating
entirely outside of the system
and had no qualms about reporting
on these sorts of things.
Some of the stories were
outrageous, like, "I boiled my
baby in the oven this morning"
and things like that,
terrible things.
And there were people
who believed it.
And our damage control was just
ignore it, 'cause it will go away.
And most of the time, it did.
The outlaw magazines took
advantage of the fact that there
were secrets that they could
basically use as blackmail.
The classic story, of course, was the
story about rock Hudson's homosexuality,
which confidential had absolute
evidence of, and they said,
"give us an exclusive story,
and we won't print it."
So, the studio took a much
lesser actor, who was also gay,
and they sacrificed him
Pretty sleazy stuff.
But it was business.
Confidentialbecame extremely popular
in a very short amount of time.
I mean, upwards of 5 million
copies of month at its height.
But all of these stars,
including Maureen O'Hara,
liberace, and Dorothy dandridge,
filed suit against confidential
for the various things
that were said about them.
- If they don't feel it, evidently...
- Robert Harrison agreed to
basically stop covering the
stars, and then the stars and
the studios would
stop suing him.
So, he sold it off.
I think it's a
part of americana.
I think it's gonna live
long after I'm gone.
You're so funny.
I mean, you're never gonna get the ball...
Yeah, yeah.
Looking for all those sort of
fun, little, behind-the-scenes
kind of images that are gonna
make a reader feel like that
they were really there...
someone stepping on someone's
train, someone greeting someone,
saying, "hi," Nicole Kidman,
Keith urban going out on their
date night, things like that.
- We can do a wide shot of the cast...
- From this we pick a few
hundred pictures, and I would
say, in terms of our space in
the magazine, we have room for six
consecutive pages of award-show coverage.
Now, something really juicy happens
at the show, you never know.
You could get a cover story out
of it, or it could go in the
"hot stuff" section
and be a gossip item.
Mila kunis looked amazing.
So, we might run a full-length
dress shot of her, in which case
we can't necessarily run another
picture of her inside with
Natalie Portman, even
though it's really cute.
So, it's really just
a giant puzzle.
...whether or not that runs in a
different section of the magazine.
Right.
Us weeklywas launched in the
1970s to compete with people.
People magazine was
first published in 1974.
One of the first issues had
Gerald Ford not, like, in a
suit, in the white house.
He's in a pool, and
his shirt is off.
So, it's really trying to give
this intimate look into these
different personalities' lives.
And it was a tremendous
success immediately.
Us weekly was actually published
by the New York times company
originally and eventually sold
it to jann wenner, the founder
of rolling stone.
It has been a monthly, a
biweekly, and a weekly.
They have changed its format,
its tone, who they're covering.
He tried everything,
and none of it worked.
It seemed like people
was invincible.
Around 2002, Bonnie Fuller
took overus weekly, and she
changed the face of
celebrity reporting.
A lot of the magazines would
feature these glamorous shots of
celebrities, and at the time us
weekly wasn't doing that well.
And so the only photos that
us weekly could afford were
those shots that magazines
wouldn't print.
I was interested in
celebrities being glamorous, but
then I also wanted to see the
human side of them, too.
And so, we created a section
called "stars are just like us."
♪ Whoo-ooh ♪
♪ if I could escape ♪
♪ whoo-ooh ♪
Bonnie snapped up those shots
of celebrities taking out their
garbage, picking up their kids.
It was a home run for us.
I guess I was a pioneer,
because that was the first time
that paparazzi photos had
been presented that way.
She definitely has the good
hair and then the pretty... hello.
Yeah.
She's so gorgeous.
Everybody wants to know who
it is and kind of become the
expert and the insider.
So, we want to always give that.
That's one of the reasons why
they come here, to us weekly.
The way that we lay it out, it
always does feel like you were
like a member of
the party there.
And they love it.
- Do you know if this thing...
- 'Cause if not, I'll take it.
It's not.
It's Keith and Nicole.
Is that nowhere?
Well, then I'm using it.
All right.
Let me just check...
Can't not use Halle Berry.
It's a crime against humanity not to run...
All right.
Everybody wins.
When Bonnie and I worked
together as editors at
us weekly, I broke the story
that Britney Spears and
Justin Timberlake had broken up.
And then the next week, we had a
follow-up to that story, and we
created these soap operas.
There was a time when I was
on the tabloids every week for
maybe two year straight...
Try every day.
...and a soap opera.
[ "The young and the restless"
If you're in a relationship, and
you're in the tabloids all the
time, it's like, "well,
maybe that part was true.
Maybe it wasn't."
Then, all the sudden, you're a
victim to believing what they're
saying and what they're writing.
Gossip is itself just as much
of a product as a movie is.
Actual people's lives are turned
into a story for us to consume.
For example, with the love triangle
of Brad pitt and Angelina jolie and
Jennifer Aniston and also with
Liz Taylor and Eddie fisher and
Debbie Reynolds in the 1950s,
each of the people in both of
these situations was given a
role to play... the temptress,
the innocent man in the
middle, and then the victim.
And once Jennifer Aniston was
made the victim, it's very
difficult for her to become
something else, which is the
reason why there are still
magazine covers now, years
later, saying Jennifer Aniston can't find
love, Jennifer Aniston can't get over
him, because that is still her
role is victim, when, really,
she's of course found happiness, and
she's dated other people and whatever.
But that has been the role in
which she has been slotted.
In the early days ofus
weeklybecoming successful,
people magazine began to
feature more of these breakups
and who's dating whom.
Whenuswanted to scoop
people, at whatever cost, so
that they could claim the exclusive and
thus attract bigger newsstand sales.
There was this great photo
of Jennifer Lopez reading
us weekly, and we
wanted that shot.
But people magazine
outbid us all day.
It kept going up and
up and up and up.
And people never published those
photos, but they paid tens of
thousands of dollars just so
that we couldn't publish them.
What happened is a series of
bidding wars for photos under
Bonnie Fuller and Janice min
after her that really escalated
the photo price for all photos.
Even small photos inside the
magazine, they still wanted to
be the only ones who had them.
Bonnie Fuller
flipped the demand.
So, instead of just tracking the moments
when a star was either doing something
scandalous or doing something
that was absolutely glamorous,
really on, the paparazzi now
needed photos of the stars doing
everything in between, which
meant near 24-hour surveillance.
Once you spot a car, you look
at the last three numbers of the
license plate that you
match with the car.
Nicky Hilton... black
range rover, 069.
Paparazzi know all the
license-plate numbers.
They know all the tail-plane
numbers of their planes.
Find out and then
call me or text me back.
They pay people off... valet
Parkers, the doormen at hot
restaurants and clubs.
Whoo! We got Paris Hilton.
They have a network
of informants.
Check out what's happening.
Want to see if our crowd's moving
across the street right now.
There's a lot of
paparazzis and their cars.
You see the guy's
got the trunk open.
There's a path.
Get down in position ourselves.
So, nobody's talking about...
When you know you see one,
you just got to deal with one
guy, and you hope and pray that
he doesn't start calling all his
friends, you know?
Go, go!
Within 15 minutes, there are
5 other people that are there.
Let the two guys get the
shot and be done with it.
But why there has to be 50
people getting the same shot...
If I saw someone I want to
photograph walk out of the
house, I sure as hell
wouldn't call my buddies.
Why not enjoy the
entire piece of steak?
I don't get the whole call
friends and relatives and...
It's literally being pursued
like prey, like an animal.
What's "the price of beauty"
really worth?
There's no kind of structure.
There's no type of regulations.
There's just "get that picture.
Get that shot.
I don't care what it takes."
They don't care about
breaking the law.
They'll climb a wall and
take pictures over the gate.
They've done it at my
office, in my backyard.
They do it, the helicopter.
You're in your backyard, and the
helicopter's coming that low,
and you keep running in.
And it's like a stupid game of,
you know...
Have you ever tried to reason
with... I know that... -
I've always tried to reason.
Oh, my God, have I
tried to reason.
I have tried to
reason with them.
I have had talks about "come on.
There's better things
that you can do.
You can achieve your dreams."
I mean, it's stupid.
It's just gotten out of control.
There are certain instances
where the paparazzi are gonna
just overexcite themselves.
Move!
You got to move!
Cameras get broken.
People get hurt... the aggression,
the hits, the elbows.
You won't get no video, man.
I try to avoid it, but
this is what it's all about.
Get that shot, no matter what.
I had a very public
relationship that fell apart,
and I was diagnosed with breast
cancer, and I had never been an
a-list celebrity before.
I pretty much was just
photographed on red carpets and
maybe the occasional lunch
at the Ivy or whatever.
But once that happened... once I
was diagnosed, and I was going
through such unhappiness and
such real dark chaos in my
life... I couldn't
leave my house.
And it really made me, I guess,
start to dissect what it is that
would make that such an
interesting thing to photograph
and is that what sells magazines is
seeing somebody at their lowest?
A word that has become absolutely
meaningless today is "unspeakable."
There's nothing that's
unspeakable anymore.
You know, stars' cellulite.
They pump gas, too.
There are still love triangles.
It's degrading to women, especially
the way they show women celebrities.
It's just, like... - I
was in Hawaii, and I have
this horrible bikini shot that a
paparazzi got and crap light and
a weird angle, and
it's terrible.
And it was everywhere.
And they did everything to just
make me look like I was just
this beached whale
with cellulite thighs.
It was just so bad, and I was like,
"oh, my God, do I look like this?"
I have a little girl.
I don't read this
in front of her.
I don't really read any of
my magazines in front of my
daughter because I don't want
her to get that bad body image
at such a young age, and
it happens really young.
I've had little girls as a teacher
tell me they're fat at four years old.
Where are you getting this from?
I think the magazines and
the media are the catapult.
That's the breeding
ground for them.
Whether it be people, us,
instyle, glamour, vogue... they
all portray women as
this untouchable goal.
You can create the illusion that
someone is a normal, ordinary person.
In other words, Joan Crawford
vacuums her own house, or she
has the perfect family.
Or you can create the illusion that
they're aloof and aristocratic goddesses.
But control was the
name of the game.
And the whole apparatus
grew up around that need.
The studio system determined which
movies the stars would appear in.
It also determined where they
would live, what cars they would
drive, and, in certain
cases, who they would marry.
It also provided them
with protection.
All of the images came through the
studio's publicity department.
So, if you were running a fan magazine,
and you ran a photograph which was
unflattering, that was it.
You didn't get another
photograph not only of that star
but of all the other stars that were
working for that particular studio.
If one of their stars was
involved in a scandal, the
studio would rush right
in and do damage control.
It could be hushed up.
So, the control at that
time was fairly easy.
It's just not the case anymore.
The mainstream media can say,
"we won't report about 'x, '
'y, ' or 'z, '" and it's still
gonna be widely known because so
many are reporting
it on the Internet.
So, the kind of control that
celebrities and their managers
and their studios used to have over their
images simply does not exist anymore.
Tmz is not about getting the
next tom cruise interview.
It's just not.
And so, I don't think
there's as much leverage.
Harvey levin got his start
as a lawyer and correspondent
covering the o.J. Simpson
trial in the 1990s.
Police are banking on
blood in the Ford bronco...
He started tmz in 2004, and
what tmz is doing is taking the
tactics, the form, the
colors, the general ethos of
confidential, and just
transferring it to new medium.
A little over half
past the hour now.
Here's a look at the stories
that you may have missed.
Lindsay Lohan... - Cable news pushed
the network news to be faster and more
immediate.
And now the network news and
cable news are in many ways
responding to what
happens on the Internet.
Media habits have totally changed
ways of getting information.
People go online.
They don't wait for a weekly.
They don't wait for a
monthly magazine anymore.
When some news breaks, they want
to know now what's going on.
Whenever something happens
to Justin bieber... like, his
birthday was yesterday...
Google, sent to my phone.
Robert pattinson
got a new haircut.
Sent to my phone.
Tmz just fascinat... I'm
obsessed with tmz.Com.
In 2006, tmz broke the story
of Mel Gibson's arrest, which
drove a tremendous amount
of traffic to the site.
Since then, tmz has grown into
an incredibly well-read site.
They then went on to use the
base product, this raw footage
from the website, and then came
up with a way that he could
repackage it on television.
Today, on "tmz"... -
Finally, snooki is good.
Nicole, you were amazing
on "wrestlemania."
You did a great job.
If you ask around, and you
say, "why do you come to tmz?"
Increasingly, what you're gonna
hear people say is, "they seem
to get the stories first."
When I was running msnbc, we
would do our best to make sure
the source was credible.
But these news operations simply
don't have the time or the
ability to fact-check some
of what they're reporting.
You know, that was a terrible
misquote, and it's very good
that you brought that up.
I never said that
in that context.
He never talked to those people, and
I never talked to those people, either.
They make up things!
Yeah, they do!
It's very tough, unfortunately, for
a celebrity to sue a publication.
You have to prove malice.
You have to prove negligence.
Also, a lot of celebrities don't
want to draw attention to a
story that is completely wrong
or defamatory or give publicity
to some blogger who's
working out of his garage.
If you sue that person, suddenly
you make their site relevant.
I had a big, famous lawsuit
againstthe sunnewspaper in
britain a long time ago, in the
'80s, which drove me crazy... it
went on for a year and a half
That said that I slept with
underage rent boys, gave them
drugs, urinated on them.
I mean, it made my life hell.
But I got a front-page apology, which
was the most important thing for me.
"We were wrong. We're sorry."
Now, people can just make up
what they want on the Internet,
and as soon as they put it on the
Internet, it goes worldwide.
So you're forever
denying things.
They discourage you from
going after the tabloids.
Like, a lawyer will be like,
"it's gonna cost you so much
money, and it's gonna take so
much time, and it's not gonna
make a difference, and nobody's gonna
care about the story tomorrow."
And they convince you
to just deal with it.
When all the sudden you're
hearing rumors that are not true
on a CNN crawl, that... you
sort of go, "this is CNN."
I don't take it personally
at this point, but there was
something about the outlet of CNN that
felt like that's a prestigious channel.
If you respond to certain things,
you're right in the sandbox with them.
If you don't respond, the story
now grows because of the viral
world and because of
24-hour news cycle.
So, we're constantly trying to
figure out how to put out a fire.
Perfect example is Tiger Woods.
He didn't say anything.
He issued a statement that he
had "transgressions," and then
he disappeared for months.
Women came out of the woodwork,
and it ended up being a giant
scandal because he
let it blow up.
Think of this as a system.
Anything that happens here also
has a chain reaction throughout
the rest of the industry, like
Tiger Woods, who, we were being
served a very tightly
controlled image.
As soon as the scandal broke, a
watch company or nike doesn't
want their name affiliated
with this sort of behavior.
- This morning, tmz reports...
- Tmz is saying... - Tmz has learned...
Until very recently, major
news organizations wouldn't have
cited a tmz as a source.
And now they do.
There's something beyond just
reporting who's making out with whom.
Therein lies the love/hate relationship
that we have with someone like levin.
He's illuminating things that we
maybe don't want to know about
that we also feel we
should know about.
But then, on the flip side,
there's a lot of sagging flesh
and giving the
camera the finger.
So, a blog will have unauthorized
content that may or may not be false.
Maybe in a post right above or
below, journalistic content.
It's dictating that we learn
how to do our homework, not
believe everything we're reading in
blogs because everybody has an angle.
We're at a really dangerous
spot as far as our inability to
discern what is fact
and what is fiction.
You have no choice but
to believe what you read.
You have no choice but to
believe what you read.
- This one...
- Yeah.
...kind of shocks me.
Yeah, yeah.
But it's probably not even true.
And we'll read it.
We'll still read it.
Yeah.
You can't beat the truth of
a camera, and this is what the
celebrities are paranoid about.
The camera doesn't lie.
It doesn't stop the Botox, it
doesn't stop the surgery, and it
doesn't stop you having
sex with a costar.
This is real.
No one can lie about
this picture.
It's there.
And that's one of the great,
historical significances that
photography and the
media bring today.
The problem is with
the celebrities.
It's instantaneous.
They have no control.
Even when we're talking about
authorized photos, there's still
a lot the celebrities
can't control.
♪ Take it out, baby, and
show me what you really want ♪
♪ they'll not ever see
the beauty inside ♪
This is pretty much how
we receive things back here.
Pretty much their entire
body gets retouched.
Well, you can kind of see.
Here, where it asks
to cut in, we cut in.
We have to make sure that all the
red carpets match, and it doesn't.
So, we're gonna
have to fix that.
Some of the time, the people in
the background that you see are
not really there
or are duplicated.
We get rid of stains on her dress...
And we try to get rid of ht wrinkles.
Paparazzi shots need a lot more
tlc than a photo that we get
from a great photographer.
That's definitely
a lot less work.
And let's help her a little bit,
'cause she looks a little tired.
Sometimes we get photos
that are, you know, green.
Yeah, but we can fix that.
The idea that a picture
never lies is simply not true.
A picture captures somebody at
a particular moment in time.
A celebrity can tell a joke
and pull a face or something.
And then, when that person is in
trouble, that image will appear,
and it will look like it was
shot at the same time in
reaction to something
that they've done.
So, images don't
always tell the truth.
It's the context.
The context is very important.
So, I think people need to be more
discerning when they're looking at images.
Renee zellweger's probably one
of the toughest shots to get
because she doesn't really come
out and be seen as often as we'd
like her to be seen.
Haven't seen you in a while.
You're looking great.
That was exhilarating.
I enjoy making her smile and laugh
and making her feel good, you know?
The ride is about staying in the
public eye, because if you're
forgotten, then my camera goes
down, and then the world doesn't
know or even want to care
about who they are anymore.
You'll be gone in a flash.
It's called Hollywood.
Who makes them famous?
Well, actually, I do.
They're reliant on the paparazzi to
photograph them to make them money.
That's delusional.
That is absolutely delusional.
Paparazzi do not keep
your career alive.
You know, we're not saying,
"don't take our pictures."
We understand there's
a market here.
But a photograph of you in your
backyard sunbathing topless,
'cause you can and you should
be able to, that's a violation.
And a photograph that's in a
magazine... there's an agreement
that this is my job, and
I'm to be photographed.
One is like having someone rob
your house and go into your
panty drawer, and the other
is something artistic and
beautiful, and both are in agreement
that this is going to take place.
There's a difference.
Vitamin water zero hotline.
This is Ellen.
How can I help you?
As long as you're famous, you become
an enormous commodity in this country.
My guest tonight is somebody
who's been in the center of a
huge scandal rocking
America this week.
And news is a business.
Newspaper entities
need to sell papers.
Websites want traffic.
Television networks
want ratings.
Developing news out of
California... Lindsay Lohan...
Increasingly, the way to get that
is to have an entertainment component.
...record-setting weekend,
to the tune of $30 million.
...and more than $155
million this opening weekend.
Every Sunday night, what's the
first item we see on the news?
How much money a movie
made over the weekend.
- "Avatar" is at the number-one spot...
- I mean, "avatar" hit a
billion, and it's bigger than the
security breach at the airport.
It's bigger news.
Why?
Nick paton Walsh joining us
live from kabul, Afghanistan.
Many thanks.
She made sure he
got the message.
Wait until you hear about Charlie sheen's...
The concept of hard news has
really changed.
- Charlie sheen insists...
- A lot of what used to be
considered tabloid
is now mainstream.
Frankly, they stopped telling
important news about the world,
and they just tell gossip.
Maybe you need a... like,
sometimes, you, you know, watch
so many things or somebody's
gotten stabbed, like, all day
long, and there
was a flood here.
There's an earthquake there.
Like, maybe you kind of want to know the
new shirt that Brad pitt's wearing.
Who doesn't like a good Hollywood
escape from time to time?
There's an argument that
celebrities act as "info-tainment"...
...parkinson's
awareness month.
Michael j. Fox... - ...actually often
helping issues of real concern getting
into the public domain.
So, for instance, if
tragically, a celebrity is ill
with breast cancer or something
like that, it does raise awareness.
Does speak to the
importance of screening...
But there's concern on the
other hand that focusing so much
on the minutiae of how famous
people live their lives is just
diverting attention from issues
which the press should be
filling their pages with.
Sarah Palin, entertainment
or journalism?
Sarah Palin is a very good
example of the way in which
celebrity culture has
influenced politics.
I'm ready, and cross my fingers,
hoping it wasn't a mistake.
I mean, say what you
will about Sarah Palin.
She has been brilliant in
manipulating her image.
What an adrenaline rush.
I think there's real
indecision over whether or not
Sarah Palin really wants to be
president, or if she just wants
to be a celebrity.
I think it's unclear.
It certainly is the question that's
united Hollywood and Washington.
Democracy becomes
another reality show.
Is trump actually serious
about running for president?
That's not good for anyone.
If the mainstream media were
to fold, and celebrity tabloids
were the only people out there
publishing, it would mean that
our entire system of
democracy has collapsed.
Democracy relies on an informed
electorate to make educated
decisions at the ballot box.
You can only do that if you have access
to truthful, timely information.
The public has a lot of
responsibility here.
The paparazzi doesn't get
away with this in a vacuum.
So, I think citizens need to
step up and start valuing that
information they're getting from
their local news gatherers.
...the Paris Hilton story.
Wait a second here.
Hold on a second.
I'm gonna make a point.
We're not covering
this, all right?
Yeah, exactly.
Easy, easy.
I'm done with the
Paris Hilton stories.
What do you have
against Paris Hilton?
I have nothing
against Paris Hilton.
That was not the issue.
The issue was the story and whether
or not it was worthy as the lead.
Paris, I love your lips.
I think at this point it's
getting to be supply leading
demand, because look at how
many magazines there are now.
It's like, "do we
really need that?"
But people keep picking them up.
I'll walk through an airport,
and there will be three out of
four people buried in this
magazine, and I'll walk through,
and no one will notice
me, which is great.
But there is some irony there.
And I understand it, 'cause
I can get sucked into it.
I can spend 20 minutes on an
airplane and flip through that
stuff, and I can be in that world, reading
about who's dating who or looking at
somebody's cellulite on
a beach or whatever.
And it makes me feel awful.
You know, the celebrities
are famous people.
They know that.
They work hard, I think, to
become a celebrity in the first
place, and then you got their
picture all over the magazines.
I don't feel guilty at all.
Plus, I'm buying the magazines.
It costs me a little bit of money
to even buy the magazines.
So... I don't feel guilty.
It comes with your job.
You asked for this life.
You wanted to be in the limelight,
in the spotlight, so deal with it.
Yeah, I kind of asked for
this life and kind of knew that
this was part of it
that comes with it.
But the same way the magazines make
money, they make money for me.
They get the word out that I
have a record out there and put
me in some light that hopefully
shines that people connect to
and make them want
to hear my record.
There's a price to fame.
Are you willing to pay it?
Yes, that's part of your
job is promoting your work.
But not... I don't think it's your job
when you're going to a yoga class.
That's not your job.
That's an invasion of privacy,
and they need to stop.
Look.
I have a great life.
I wouldn't trade myself, even
with the paparazzi following me.
But not because I have a great life
they should feel like they own it.
We represented Barbra
Streisand for many, many
years, and I got into the habit
of carrying a large, black
umbrella, whether the weather
called for it or not.
And if I saw photographers
coming towards us, I would open
the umbrella, and like two
fools, we would walk down the
street with the umbrella in front
of me so the photographers
would not take her picture.
She did not want
her picture taken.
On the other hand, Frank Sinatra,
who we represented, controlled that
part of his celebrity by
never appearing in public.
Sinatra wouldn't walk
down the street.
If he had to go from here
to there, it was in a car.
Do you remember when we were
in the trunk of somebody's car,
trying to get away?
- In Gina's car?
- Mmhmm.
We were just
laying in the trunk.
I'm like, "when
did this happen?"
I wanted to go shopping.
I'm like, "I'm in a trunk
with my girlfriend," and I'm
like, "this is your life?"
Well, there's nothing
you can do about it.
I was like, "I beg to differ.
I beg to differ."
You feel out of control, like
you have no control over this,
and then you realize, "I have
to actually change my life."
We've moved out of Miami.
We've taken measures to just sort of
concentrate on the quality of life.
There's a lot of places where you can
live, where there are not paparazzi.
You don't have to be
in the public eye.
There's ways to
avoid the cameras.
And then they'll say,
"well, she's isolated.
She lives a rarefied life.
She doesn't have
the human touch.
She's not..."
Well, I'm desperate to be
like you and you and you.
They told me
they're coming over.
The big black guy?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
Here comes Spencer.
Here she comes.
Hey!
Hey, Happy Birthday, Spencer!
My birthday present.
Let's see it. Let's see it.
The problem always is that certain
celebrities invite in the attention.
And so, the response of the media
is, "well, we're getting called."
They should have an agreement.
Whether it's the Paris hiltons
or the girls that don't have an
issue with it, the "Jersey shores," all
those television shows... there should
be an agreement.
But it doesn't mean that everybody
else is a free-for-all.
What could any guy want more
than this on his birthday?
Wow! Look at that.
A lot of the time, they're
told where to be and when.
Yeah, it becomes kind of a game.
I've got Darren coming out.
I'm gonna walk him down.
Well, when he comes, we'll
definitely... - Okay.
Publicists either tip you,
or they'll give information out
indirectly, what the client won't
even know, just to build more hype.
They're supposed to.
That's their job.
Yeah, she was twittering us.
She tweets. She told us.
Twitter has become
another source.
She was actually
telling us to come here.
That's fine, but the owners
of the establishment don't want
you on their property.
It's not her. It's them.
One time we had a source
that was giving us specific,
incredible information.
It was almost as if it was coming
from Angelina jolie's mouth herself.
On when pitt flew into Africa...
private, little resort... we had
three or four minutes to get the
picture that was bought in an
auction overnight
by us magazine.
Unauthorized publicity
definitely has a role in
maintaining a star's visibility,
and I think that today
celebrities have learned to
allow just enough coverage, so
as to make it seem like you are
giving some of yourself but at
the same time maintaining
a semblance of privacy.
I mean, someone like Brad
and Angelina have a really
meticulously
maintained star image.
But they also allow slight moments of
authenticity that make them interesting.
Angelina jolie knows exactly
the moment that you need to have
this particular part of her
persona exposed to the world,
this particular part of her life
exposed to the world, and she's
brilliant at it.
You have to constantly be
able to reinvent yourself, and
the ones who stay before us
really are the ones who, one way
or another, manage to do something that
keeps us interested and fascinated.
That, to me, smells
celebrity double standards.
I don't agree with it.
I think it's completely
and utterly wrong.
Like, Angelina and Brad pitt
say, "under my terms, I'll put
my children on the front of a
magazine for 15 million bucks.
But when you're photographing me
in a public place, unh-unh-unh,
that's not on."
I don't understand that.
That was a very
interesting case.
We worked with them for free.
They wanted all the
money to go to charity.
So, it worked perfectly.
The value of an exclusive image
is very high, because that baby
or that wedding hasn't
been photographed before.
So, if we can work with the
celebrities and get those
pictures out first, it is a
massive disincentive to the
paparazzi to chase after them,
because they're not gonna get a
lot of money for the third
picture of the baby, when the
first pictures have been
published everywhere.
Publicity... You know, it's a game
played for the benefit of everyone
involved up to a certain point.
And that certain point is
where it gets dangerous.
Drive out the garage.
Couple yards down the street,
one, two, three, four cars.
They'd all be smoking cigarettes,
waiting for you to come out.
Jump in their cars,
and then you're off.
The main car runs
a yellow light.
Everybody behind that person,
the ten cars, are running
lights until it
turns green again.
Then you find yourself
driving kind of like crazy just
to get away from them.
One in the front, one in the
back, one on the side... you
feel like a trapped rat.
It's a matter of
playing chicken.
Either you're gonna stop, or
you're gonna crash into the car.
Nicole Richie was chased by a
paparazzi and got in a car accident.
Thank God her children
weren't in the car.
It can get really dangerous.
Look what happened to Diana.
Reports say a vehicle
carrying the princess and her
entourage was being
chased by photographers.
Several hours after the accident, French
emergency services were still at the
scene, cutting people
from the wreckage.
This isn't the time for
recriminations but for sadness.
However, I would say that I
always believed the press would
kill her in the end.
But not even I could imagine
that they would take such a
direct hand in her death,
as seems to be the case.
It would appear that every
proprietor and editor of every
publication that has paid for
intrusive and exploitative
photographs of her, encouraging
greedy and ruthless individuals
to risk everything in pursuit of Diana's
image, has blood on his hands today.
Well, if the publishers have
blood on their hands today, so
do the readers of
those magazines.
After the whole shock of her death,
people started putting flowers outside
Buckingham Palace.
And several legitimate news
photographers were assaulted
because they were taking photographs
of people putting the flowers there.
The people who assaulted them
were the same people who had
bought the magazines that made
her image a valuable commodity.
Photographers would not have
chased her if they couldn't have
got good money for
those photographs.
And it was the people who were
buying the magazines that were
ultimately supplying that money.
When princess Diana died,
there was that sense of
"wow, this is gonna change everything."
What was sort of the immediate
impact, do you think?
I think media interest in
princess Diana and particularly
her death led to a
change of culture.
The commercial demand for
those kind of photos fell.
But, unfortunately, in the last
few years, as the younger royals
starting to join the family, the
media interest in them and the
intrusion is escalating again.
...is just 16 days away... -
And on the big day, a viewing
party in London's iconic
trafalgar square...
...the world is waiting for,
the first real... - ...more
than a billion pairs of eyes.
...on a fairy tale we've all
been living and breathing.
...echoes of Diana's "I dos."
Reminds me so much
of Diana's wedding...
What I love about teaching
history is to say, "well, this
isn't the first time
this has happened."
You can go back and show how
it all happened before.
It's a madhouse around here.
George, welcome to the party!
We should rush this,
Britney-style, man.
I'm going in.
This is a gang-bang.
It's a gang-bang.
Kim!
Very nice.
I am a photojournalist.
It's an art.
No, they're not journalists.
Paparazzi are people
with a camera.
Anyone can get a camera.
You can go to the drugstore
and buy a disposable camera.
Now you're taking pictures.
You're all the sudden
this journalist?
No way are they a journalist.
If they're allowed to do
it... if they're allowed to
chase you, if they're allowed to
invade your privacy, and they
know they're gonna make money off
of it, they're not gonna stop.
If you're a photographer,
take a decent photograph.
Go and learn your trade.
Make some beautiful photographs, like
Irving penn or someone like that.
What you do is just crap.
It's crap.
It must be frustrating.
What I think might be even more
frustrating is to never see a
photographer again.
Paparazzi are doing journalism.
They are gathering information.
They're telling a story of some sort
and disseminating it to an audience.
The first amendment protects
artists in their ability to be
creative and sometimes risqué.
And it also protects
the paparazzi.
But it doesn't necessarily mean that it
protects against each and every action.
There definitely are
limits to free speech.
You don't get to publish
false things about somebody.
obscenity, child pornography.
You do not get to invade
someone's privacy by shooting
with a long telephoto lens
into somebody's bedroom.
The supreme court has said you
don't get to do those things.
You tell me this kind of
behavior is covered by what
journalism should be covered by?
That's just bull.
Back off.
Wow, dude.
No way. Are you kidding?
These people are
behaving terribly.
It's beyond rude and
crude and unacceptable.
But it's very hard to
legislate good behavior.
I'm not somebody for more
laws, more laws, and more laws,
to say who can shoot a picture
and who can't and where they can
put it and what they can do.
I mean, that's part of the beauty
of our society is the freedoms.
But there's got to be something
that we can stand up morally, as
a culture, and say, "hey, that's
not cool taking a picture of
that kid over there.
Cut it out."
How?
He's the manager of this big, big, big...
I love to walk my son to school
because it's the time of
day that he's very open.
The whole world is
interesting to him.
And to have long lenses aimed
at you, purposefully getting in
your... never mind your physical
path but your emotional path...
it's actually a scary feeling... like
having sharpshooters aimed at you.
All righty, here it is.
The more intimate shots are
the ones that people criticize.
"Well, why don't you
leave them alone?"
But there is a demand for it.
We just shoot and submit
them into the library.
It's up to the agencies, the
publication, the TV networks,
the websites and blogs.
I want to be like my dad when
I grow up so I don't have...
Wherever you read it or saw it,
ask them why do they publish it?
Cute kids are popular, and
celebrities have a lot of cute kids.
A lot of women love to
look at cute babies.
Now they're having
covers of these magazines.
It's like, "who's the
cutest Hollywood baby?"
They haven't decided to
become a famous person.
So, you can't do that to them.
There are so many outlets now
to sell pictures of celebrity
kids, and there's so much
money to be made in it.
You can't even argue with
somebody about the ethics of it.
I can't explain to somebody, "I'm a
high-profile person, but my son isn't.
And just because he's with me
It's not like a handbag.
He's a person."
And it's worrisome.
It's really worrisome.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
How's everything
going, Britney?
Stop.
Whoever flashes these lights
at my kid again, I'll push your
face through the
back of your head.
You got it?
Get back, back, back, back.
That includes you.
I know. I know.
Jack!
Stop it!
Stop taking pictures!
I'm not kidding!
Stop it!
The thought is
devastating to me.
It's frightening, terribly
frightening to me.
Wow, it really just made me really
upset to think about that, right?
I mean, to have someone
following your children is...
It's entering a place that
just no one should be.
Leave children out of it.
They didn't ask to be famous, and
they have their rights, too.
The kids ought to
be doing the suing.
And that might be a way legally
to get some traction on this.
There are very different
laws of privacy via the English
courts than the American courts.
J.K. Rowling brought proceedings
on behalf of her very young son,
and it was held that her son had
a reasonable expectation of
privacy, that he wouldn't be
followed around by photographers
on the street, in the same way
that any ordinary child wouldn't
be photographed
by the paparazzi.
And it was a landmark case,
because it established that the
children of famous people should
be treated in the same way as
the children of
ordinary parents.
A 3year-old suing me in
court, I think, is wrong.
I think it's
absolutely ridiculous.
The fact of the matter is, the j.K.
Rowling case... I didn't lose the case.
She was just given the
right to go to a trial.
But it was... you take on the
world's richest woman, and it
was David and goliath.
In France, they can't
take a picture of my child.
It's illegal.
It's night and day, if you compare
Paris to Los Angeles or New York.
Here, in the United States,
probably any judge under the law
is going to say, "hey, no, you don't
get to follow them wherever."
You know, the very first case
out there... jacqueline Kennedy
had a lawsuit against Ron galella because
she was concerned for the safety of
Caroline and young John.
And she was able to get it
declared in New York that he had
to stay a certain distance
away from those children.
Since then, there's pretty much been a
truce around presidential children.
But I think it's a little bit
different from what children of
celebrities experience.
I remember it was night,
and it was really cold.
So, imagine the flashes on a baby that's,
like, two months, three months old.
So, I told, "take her."
And when they were taking my picture,
they were all over, and they didn't care.
They pushed the baby.
It nearly went to the floor.
And then, of course, I charge
after the photographer.
I made sure the baby was okay.
And I was just so angry.
My child could have had a
really serious accident.
When you're two, three, on the street
He could have stepped on her!
That just ought to be illegal.
It's a little criminal.
There should be certain
rules, I think.
I just feel like it's an
invasion of privacy and that
these kids really don't need
that kind of attention at this
point in their lives.
Even if their mom or their
dad is the famous one, it
doesn't give the
paparazzi no right.
The children aren't
nothing to do with it.
Yeah, but that's what
everyone wants to see.
Everyone wants to
see their kids.
Don't they? That's
why they do it.
I suppose.
- It's true.
- Yeah.
It's kind of sad, but it makes
me more interested in what
the kids are doing because,
like, that's the new generation
of celebrities coming up.
The public has to take some
degree of some responsibility
and demand that these sort of
photographs not be published,
that they put pressure...
economic, political, social
pressure... on media entities
to say, "we don't want this.
We won't have it."
Could you just let
them be normal people?
You should be normal.
You should be going home
and enjoy yourself.
Disgusting what you're doing.
We are working.
Disgusting!
Wow.
I took a total of
289 pictures today.
Here, atus weekly, we get about
750,000 to a million images a month.
Images are coming at us
from all different angles.
And anybody whose eyes are working will
see about a thousand images a day.
We should be asking ourselves,
"what's happening in this photo?"
Where it was taken, when it was
taken... context is everything.
We are drenched and piled
over with media coverage.
I'm not gonna say it's
good for us or bad for us.
It is what it is.
And we're gonna have to
make the best of it.
We watch tabloid-magazine
television shows, and we buy the
magazines, and we're
invested in reality TV.
But we don't have an
interconnectedness that is
personal, where we're sitting
in front of each other.
It's become the disease
of our culture... celebrity.
♪ One cuts you down,
one makes you fly ♪
♪ so I'll take
both sides, yeah ♪
We are complicit in the
driving of this industry.
It's something that we
should think about.
We should analyze.
And what we need to actually
enact change is action.
♪...believing you... ♪
Be aware.
Don't be naive about where these
pictures are coming from.
They sell it because
there's a market for it.
Consider where you're
going to place value.
We don't have to watch it.
We don't have to read it.
I've been guilty of it myself.
I try to be a little
more conscious of it.
Like, if you're gonna have fun
and see what's going on in the
celebrity world, you should at
least be a little more conscious
about what's going on
in the real world.
Somebody in the army or marines
That's a celebrity.
Doctors that save lives,
teachers, cops, firefighters.
You know?
That's a celebrity, you want
to really get down to it.
All I wanted when I got into
this industry was make some
money... make a lot of
money... make history.
Tomorrow... wake up, get
out there, do it again.
[ Introduction to U2's
"desire"
♪ Yeah ♪
- What are you doing to me?
- Let me at them.
- They want out of there?
- No.
♪ Lover, I'm on the street ♪
♪ gonna go where the bright
lights and the big city meet ♪
♪ with a red guitaret ♪
On fire ♪
♪ desire ♪
♪ she's a candle
burnin' in my room ♪
What's your opinion
on the paparazzi?
Depends on the day.
♪ Over the counter
with a shotgun ♪
Tourists will soon be able
to take a tour of Los Angeles
courtesy of a member
of the paparazzi.
For $150, two people can hang out
with paparazzo Rick mendoza.
He's probably best known for
suing pop star Britney Spears
after she allegedly
ran over his foot.
You can stand behind
me but not hit me.
Like, Jesus Christ could come
back after 2,000 years, forgive
us of all our sins.
Somebody get a picture,
put it on tmz.
The first comment would be,
"Jesus is a fucking douchebag."
You know what I mean?
♪ desi-i-i-re ♪
I'm just glad they
ain't fucking with me.
That's all.
Can I run one over now?
Is that against the law?
Do I get... is there
points for that?
Like, if I took three or four
of them out, especially the big
guy... got to get at least
5 points for him, right?
♪ She's the dollars ♪
My wife got "papped"
at JFK last night.
Well, they see a blonde
with Louis vuitton bags.
They were right in her face.
She goes, "he was
right in my face."
Just bap-bap-bap-bap.
And then just walked away,
like nothing happened.
♪...stealing hearts
at a traveling show ♪
♪ for love of money, money,
money, money, money, money ♪
♪ money, money,
money, money, money ♪
♪ and the fever getting
higher, desi-I-I-re ♪
♪ desi-i-i-re ♪
All right.
♪ Desi-i-i-re ♪
♪ desi-i-i-re ♪