I'M WISHING ON A STAR
TO FOLLOW WHERE YOU ARE
I'M WISHING ON A DREAM
TO FOLLOW WHAT IT MEANS
AND I WISH
ON ALL THE RAINBOWS
THAT I'VE SEEN
I WISH ON ALL THE PEOPLE
WHO REALLY DREAM
I'M WISHING ON A STAR
TO FOLLOW WHERE YOU ARE.
Girl:
MY NAME IS VIRGINIA AND I LIVE
ON THE EDGE OF THE FOREST.
( chuckling ):
WELL, KIND OF.
MY DAD'S A JANITOR.
THAT'S HOW WE GOT
TO HAVE AN APARTMENT
ON THE EDGE OF CENTRAL PARK.
AND YOU MIGHT THINK
THAT THE FACT
THAT I STILL LIVE WITH MY DAD
IS A BIT SAD AND...
WELL, YOU MIGHT BE RIGHT...
OH!
BUT, I DON'T KNOW,
I'M ALL HE'S GOT, REALLY
AND I'M SORT OF PERMANENTLY
BETWEEN BOYFRIENDS
AT THE MOMENT.
SO, YOU KNOW...
I'M JUST A WAITRESS
AT THE GRILL ON THE PARK
BUT ONE DAY, I'M GOING
TO FIND A PARTNER
AND OPEN A RESTAURANT
OF MY OWN.
ALL I NEED'S A GOOD MAN
WHO'S INTERESTED IN FOOD.
DID YOU SEE THIS?
THIS HAS
BEEN CHEWED.
IT'S NOT MY JOB.
THIS IS AN ELECTRICIAN'S JOB,
BUT WHO GETS TO DO IT?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO WORK, DAD, LIKE
I DO EVERY DAY.
OH. UH, ON THE WAY BACK...
USE THE STAIRS.
JUST IN CASE.
( cawing loudly )
WHO'S THERE?
SO, WHERE EXACTLY ARE WE GOING?
TO BEANTOWN, IN THE SOUTHWEST
CORNER OF YOUR KINGDOM, SIR.
YOU'RE ACCEPTING
THE THRONE THAT
THE CRAFTSMAN THERE
HAVE MADE FOR
YOUR CORONATION.
WELL, IS IT MUCH FURTHER?
CAN'T WE STOP
AND GO HUNTING OR SOMETHING?
VERY SHORTLY,
SIR.
WE MUST MAKE A BRIEF STOP
AT THE SNOW WHITE
MEMORIAL PRISON.
( sighs )
I HATE THESE OUTER PROVINCES.
THE PEOPLE ARE SO COMMON.
YOUR STEPMOTHER
HAS APPLIED FOR PAROLE AGAIN
WHICH WE WILL, OF COURSE,
TURN DOWN.
OH...
IT'S SIMPLY A ROUTINE
COURTESY VISIT.
STOP IT!
YOU'RE PATHETIC.
CALL YOURSELVES TROLLS?
YOU MAKE ME ASHAMED.
SORRY, DAD.
IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
THIS IS THE LAST TIME
I COME AND RESCUE YOU.
DAD, TAKE OFF
THE MAGIC SHOES.
I CAN HANDLE THEM.
( groaning )
Father:
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M
STARTING TO THINK?
THAT THE ONLY KIND
OF PEOPLE
THEY WANT
IN THIS COUNTRY
ARE GUYS LIKE ME.
YOU KNOW, GUYS WHO WILL WORK
FOR SCRAPS, DO SIX JOBS...
BASICALLY,
BEND OVER AND TAKE IT.
WANT TO KNOW
SOMETHING, DARLING?
TEN, 15 YEARS TOPS
THIS COUNTRY IS FINISHED
AS A DEMOCRACY.
AS A CARING SOCIETY, WHERE
PEOPLE DO THINGS FOR EACH OTHER
WE'RE DONE, WE'RE FINISHED
WE ARE OUT
OF HERE.
YOUR BARBECUE RIBS
ARE ON TOP OF THE MICROWAVE.
( bell dings )
TONY
I HAVE BEEN CALLING
THIS ELEVATOR FOR
THE LAST HALF HOUR.
I THOUGHT YOU
FIXED IT.
I DID, SIR,
BUT IT'S BROKEN AGAIN.
DON'T TAKE
ALL NIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT TO LOOK
AT THAT BOILER.
IT'S DRIVING
EVERYBODY CRAZY.
THERE'S AIR
IN THE PIPES.
THE WHOLE SYSTEM'S GOT
TO BE DRAINED AND BLED.
Tony:
YES, SIR.
I JUST HAVE TO FIX
THE LEAK IN NUMBER NINE
AND THEN I'M ON IT.
TONY, I AM ONLY GOING
TO TELL YOU THIS ONCE.
THERE ARE AN AWFUL LOT
OF PEOPLE OUT THERE
WHO WOULD
LOVE YOUR JOB--
AN AWFUL LOT
OF PEOPLE.
YES, SIR.
DRAIN THE SYSTEM...
I'D LIKE TO DRAIN HIS SYSTEM.
BYE, DADDY.
Tony:
OH, OH, OH, LISTEN.
DON'T GO THROUGH
THE PARK. PROMISE?
YUP.
YOU GOT A COAT?
YOU'RE GOING TO GET COLD.
OH, WHAT DID YOU
FIX ME FOR DINNER?!
Woman:
WAIT!
COME TO ME.
( snorting )
WELL, THIS IS MARVELOUS,
ISN'T IT?
NOT EXACTLY THE RED
CARPET TREATMENT.
I'M SURE THEY WON'T
HAVE FORGOTTEN
ABOUT OUR VISIT,
YOUR MAJESTY.
CHECK IT OUT!
OH, YOU WERE RIGHT.
"MAXIMUM SECURITY."
WE'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE IN HERE!
DAD, NO ONE'S
EVER ALLOWED IN THERE.
THIS IS WHERE
THEY KEEP THE QUEEN.
THIS IS REALLY BAD.
NO, DAD, DAD, PLEASE.
THIS COULD BE A TRAP.
DAD, DON'T.
NO, DAD!
Woman:
OPEN THE DOOR.
OPEN THE DOOR
TO EVERYTHING YOU DESIRE.
GILES?
HELLO?
GILES!
HELLO, PRINCEY!
( laughing )
DID THAT HURT?
I'D LIKE
YOU TO MEET
MY SISTER.
NOW, HE'S MINE.
I GET THE FIRST SHOT.
YOU WERE FIRST
LAST TIME.
I ALWAYS GET THE FIRST...
Woman:
ENOUGH!
YOU'RE A LONG WAY
FROM YOUR CASTLE, WENDELL.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
HAVE STAYED THERE.
MY SILLY
LITTLE STEPSON.
YOU... YOU...
YOU WILL PAY FOR THIS.
ON THE CONTRARY.
I THINK THAT YOU WILL
BEG AT MY FEET FOR FOOD.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THIS IS?
THIS IS A VERY
SPECIAL KIND OF DOG.
THIS IS A MAGICAL DOG.
I HOPE YOU LIKE
DOGS, WENDELL.
YOU'RE GOING TO SPEND
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE AS ONE.
( laughing )
( barking )
COME, COME, PRINCE WENDELL
YOU DON'T GREET PEOPLE
ON ALL FOURS
DO YOU?
( troll laughing )
Troll:
GET HIM!
BRING HIM BACK TO ME
ALIVE!
WE'LL GET HIM.
HE'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
HE CAN'T ESCAPE.
WE'RE IN A PRISON.
Queen:
WELL, YOUR HIGHNESS...
JUST WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO SAY FOR YOURSELF?
WH-WH-WH-WH...
WHERE'S MY TAIL GONE?
Virginia:
I GUESS YOU GET
TO A CERTAIN AGE
AND YOU REALIZE
THAT NOTHING EXCITING
IS EVER GOING TO HAPPEN TO YOU.
MAYBE THAT'S
JUST THE WAY IT IS.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE SOME PEOPLE
JUST HAVE QUIET LIVES.
( prisoners shouting )
Man:
GIVE US SOME
FOOD, SAY.
I HAVEN'T HAD ANY FOOD
SINCE YESTERDAY.
LET US OUT.
COME ON--
JUST GIVE US THE KEY.
LET US OUT.
YOU.
HELLO.
WHAT ARE YOU?
ME?
A VERY, VERY FINE CHAP...
DO NOT MAKE ME ASK AGAIN.
I'M A...
SHH...
HALF-WOLF.
IF I GIVE YOU YOUR FREEDOM
YOU MUST AGREE TO SERVE ME
WITHOUT QUESTION.
OH, BREAKFAST, LUNCH, DINNER.
I AM YOUR WOLF.
"LOYALTY" IS MY MIDDLE NAME.
I'VE TURNED PRINCE WENDELL
INTO A DOG.
GOOD IDEA.
FIND HIM BEFORE THE TROLLS.
OH... TROLLS!
WAIT!
GIVE YOUR WILL TO ME.
BE MINE
TO SUMMON
AND CONTROL.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH.
( grunting )
( barks )
Wolf:
HUFF... PUFF.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
OH...! OH!
WOW!
Troll 1:
SUCK AN ELF!
WHERE ARE WE?
WOW.
WOW, GET A LOOK
AT THAT.
THIS ISN'T PART
OF THE NINE KINGDOMS.
THIS IS A MAGICAL PLACE.
LOOK AT ALL THOSE LIGHTS!
Troll 2:
THEY MUST GO THROUGH
A TON OF CANDLES!
Troll 3:
MAYBE WE SHOULD
CLAIM THIS KINGDOM!
THAT'S A SENSATIONAL IDEA.
LET'S GRAB IT
BEFORE SOMEONE ELSE DOES.
I HEREBY
CLAIM THIS LAND
AND ALL ITS
INHABITANTS
IN THE NAME
OF THE TROLL NATION.
HENCEFORTH,
IT SHALL BE KNOWN AS...
WHAT SHALL WE CALL IT?
( gasping )
THE TENTH KINGDOM!
AH.
All:
THE TENTH KINGDOM!
IN A MONTH, I WILL
HAVE CRUSHED THE
HOUSE OF WHITE.
I WILL HAVE WENDELL'S CASTLE
AND HIS KINGDOM
AND FOR HELPING ME TO ESCAPE
YOU MAY HAVE HALF HIS KINGDOM
TO RULE.
HALF THE FOURTH KINGDOM--
BUT IT'S HUGE.
WHAT'S YOUR PLAN?
WHAT DO I HAVE TO DO?
SIMPLY ALLOW ME THE USE
OF YOUR CHILDREN
UNTIL THEY'VE CAPTURED
THE PRINCE FOR ME.
THAT'S ALL?
TELL NO ONE WHAT
YOU'VE SEEN, OF COURSE.
DO I GET TO CHOOSE...
WHICH HALF OF THE KINGDOM
I WANT?
( moaning softly )
( moaning )
OH, MY GOD,
I'VE KILLED IT.
ARE YOU OKAY?
OH, I'M SORRY.
( whimpers )
WHERE'S YOUR MASTER?
HOW COME YOU
DON'T HAVE A COLLAR?
( trolls grumbling in distance )
COME ON, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
( grunts )
Troll 2:
AH...
( gasping )
HELLO.
( grunting )
( laughing )
( footsteps approaching )
OH, MY WALLET.
( sighs )
Troll 2:
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S NOT EVEN LEATHER.
ARE THERE ANY OTHER
SHOES IN HERE?
WHAT'S THIS?
( groaning )
( grunts )
...Night fever, night fever
We know how to do it...
MORE MAGIC.
( faintly ):
Night fever, night fever...
( distant howling )
( distant siren wailing )
( howling continuing )
NO.
VIRGINIA, JUST LEAVE.
GO.
( barks )
( grunting )
THERE.
THERE'S BEEN AN INCIDENT.
AHA!
LOOKEE LOOK.
DOG HAIRS.
AH, CALFSKIN--
NICEY NICE...
SQUEAKY CLEAN.
( growling savagely )
"IF FOUND, PLEASE RETURN
TO VIRGINIA LEWIS
APARTMENT 2006, NUMBER TWO
EAST EIGHTY-ONEST STREET."
"EIGHTY-ONEST
STREET"?
"EIGHTY-ONEST STREET"?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT IT SAYS,
"EIGHTY-ONEST."
HOW ABOUT THIS WAY?
COME ON,
LET'S GO!
LET'S GO.
( panting )
( sniffing deeply )
( exhales ecstatically )
( gasps )
MEAT!
( growling softly )
( music playing softly )
( people chatting )
HI.
Woman:
OH, AND WHERE
HAVE YOU BEEN, HUH?
I'VE BEEN
COVERING FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
YOUR HEAD...
YOU'RE BLEEDING.
I SMASHED MY BIKE
AND I LOST MY WALLET
AND I'VE PICKED UP
A NEW BOYFRIEND.
OH...
( laughing )
WELL, HELLO.
I HIT HIM WITH MY BIKE
BUT I DON'T THINK HE'S HURT.
HE'S NOT BLEEDING
OR ANYTHING.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
I DON'T KNOW. HE
DOESN'T HAVE A COLLAR.
UH-HUH...
COME ON, LET'S SEE, HUH?
YOU LOOK LIKE A PRINCE
TO ME, HUH? YES.
HELLO, PRINCE.
HELLO.
( music playing softly )
( footsteps approaching )
OH...
( snarling )
( growling softly )
TASTY.
REMEMBER WHAT YOU CAME HERE FOR.
FIND THE PRINCE.
BUT HUFF PUFF...
A WOLF'S GOT TO EAT,
HASN'T HE?
CAN'T WORK ON
AN EMPTY STOMACH.
HELLO.
( sniffing )
( gasping ):
I SMELL DOG!
WOULD YOU
BELIEVE IT?
WORK AND PLEASURE COMBINED.
ALL RIGHT, YOU CAN STAY IN HERE
AND I'LL CHECK
ON YOU WHEN I CAN.
DON'T MAKE A NOISE
OR YOU'LL GET ME THE SACK.
( barks )
SHH!
( whispering ):
QUIET OR I'LL PUT YOU OUTSIDE.
Woman:
SO, THE SPECIALS ARE
Wolf:
LAMB?!
LAMB...
NEW SEASON'S LAMB, I
HOPE-- YOUNG AND JUICY
AND FROLICKING
PROVOCATIVELY
IN THE FIELDS,
BOUNCING
UP AND DOWN
WITH SOFT, FLUFFY WOOL.
( gasps )
STOP IT.
PULL YOURSELF
TOGETHER.
SOME SHEPHERDESS
NOT REALLY PAYING ATTENTION
TO THE FLOCK
PROBABLY ASLEEP,
IF I KNOW LITTLE GIRLS...
WELL, I'M NOT GOING TO EAT HER.
( chuckles )
NOT IF THERE'S
A LAMB FILET
OR A NICE FAT
RACK OF CHOPS!
I'M NOT GREEDY!
WELL, I AM GREEDY.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I JUST SAID THAT.
I HAVE A SUBSTANTIAL APPETITE.
BORN TO GORGE...
THAT'S ME.
( horn honking )
( yells )
SUCK AN ELF!
( horns honking )
( grunting )
Troll 1:
ALL RIGHT.
( brakes squealing )
( glass breaking )
( radiator hissing )
( yelling )
( hissing louder )
OUR CARRIAGE
IS HERE.
( laughing )
( music playing softly )
OKAY.
Wolf:
NO, NO!
SORRY, WHAT
CAN I GET YOU?
RARE IMPLIES
DANGEROUSLY COOKED!
WHEN I SAY, "RARE"
I MEAN, JUST
LET IT LOOK AT THE OVEN
IN TERROR
THEN, BRING IT OUT TO ME!
NO FRIES, NO
VEGETABLES--
JUST MEAT!
RED...
AS A YOUNG GIRL'S FIRST BLUSH.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I MISSED THAT.
I'LL HAVE A JUG OF MARGARITA,
A DIET COLA AND TWO BEERS, OKAY?
( Prince Wendell barking )
AND MY WIFE WILL HAVE...
I'M SORRY,
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
SHE'LL HAVE
A DOUBLE, BIG...
( dishes clattering )
Man:
...COLD PLATES!
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT
I'M TAKING YOU OUTSIDE.
( sighs )
( chuckles )
OKAY, CANDY, VERY FUNNY.
YOU CAN COME OUT.
I SUPPOSE
YOU WROTE THAT, EH?
( barks )
BARK ONCE.
( chuckling ):
OKAY...
BARK TWICE.
( barks twice )
( shrieks )
OKAY, SO,
YOU GOT THE LAMB SPECIAL
AND SIX GLASSES OF WARM MILK?
YEAH.
OKAY.
OH, OH, OH, OH!
UH-HUH?
I ALMOST FORGOT.
UH... I'M LOOKING
FOR THIS LOVELY LADY
WHO, UH, FOUND MY DOGGIE.
OH, SO, IT'S YOURS.
OH...
I'LL TELL VIRGINIA.
SHE'S OUT BACK.
CAN YOU...
UNDERSTAND
EVERYTHING I'M SAYING?
( barks )
S-STOP IT!
WELL, WHO'S IN DANGER?
BOTH OF US?
( barks )
WHOA.
JUST WAIT A MINUTE.
OH, YOU CAN'T
COME IN HERE.
UH...
UM...
SHE MUST'VE GONE HOME,
YOU KNOW?
MAYBE SHE HURT HERSELF
WHEN SHE FELL.
OH... POOR LITTLE SAUSAGE.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
WHERE SHE LIVES?
THAT WAY,
I CAN THANK HER.
UH... WELL, I...
I CAN'T TELL YOU
WHERE SHE LIVES.
YOU KNOW, UM, I DON'T
KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
OH...
YOU CAN TELL ME.
( snarls )
( distant siren wailing )
THIS IS MY STOP.
YOU GOT TO GO NOW.
( sighs )
OKAY, YOU CAN
JUST STAY ONE NIGHT
AND, THEN,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
( barks )
I'VE GONE CRAZY.
HOW CAN I BE TALKING
TO A DOG?
( barking )
YES, I HAVE.
DON'T TRY AND REASSURE ME.
( snoring softly )
THAT'S MRS. GRAVES
FROM NEXT DOOR...
AND HER HUSBAND...
AND THEIR SON ERIC.
( barking )
( sighing incredulously )
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO THEM?
( elevator bell dings )
( elevator doors creaking )
WAIT HERE.
( barks )
SHH!
WAIT.
I'M GOING TO GO SEE
IF DAD'S ALL RIGHT.
( elevator bell dings )
( door creaking continuing )
( whispering ):
DAD.
WAKE UP.
( door closes )
Troll 1:
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOOK.
HERE THEY ARE.
( sighing admiringly )
SOFT COW.
NICEY NICE.
( troll growling )
Troll 2:
WALK THE CAT WALK.
( chuckling )
HELLO THERE,
GIRLIE.
THESE SHOES...
THEY'VE BEEN
VERY BADLY CARED FOR.
THEY'RE-THEY'RE SCUFFED,
AN-AND CRACKED
AND NEGLECTED.
( crashing )
YOU HAVE NICE SHOES
AND SO TINY.
WE HAVE HUNDREDS
OF PAIRS
AT HOME.
SO, WE KNOW
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Virginia:
WHO ARE YOU
AND WHAT HAVE DONE
TO MY DAD?
AW, HE'S JUST SLEEPING.
HIT HIM WITH A BIT OF
TROLL DUST, THAT'S ALL.
"TROLL DUST"?
I AM BURLY THE TROLL
FEARED THROUGHOUT
THE NINE KINGDOMS.
Troll 3:
I AM
BLABBERWORT THE TROLL,
DREADED THROUGHOUT
THE NINE KINGDOMS.
Troll 2:
AND I AM
BLUEBELL THE TROLL
TERRIFIED
THROUGHOUT THE NINE KINGDOMS.
( yelling )
( gasps )
( crackling )
Burly:
SO...
WHERE IS HE?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Blabberwort:
PRINCE WENDELL.
WHO?
THE DOG.
( yelling and gasping )
WE ARE GOING
TO COUNT TO THREE
AND, THEN,
WE ARE GOING TO MAKE YOU
INTO A PAIR OF SHOES.
ONE...
I'LL CUT THE SHOES.
TWO...
I WILL SHAPE THE SHOES.
THREE...
I WILL STICK...
ALL RIGHT!
I'LL TELL YOU
WHERE HE IS.
HE'S...
HERE.
HE-HE'S JUST,
UH... OUTSIDE.
Burly:
SHOW US!
TAKE US TO HIM.
( groaning )
GO THROUGH THE DOOR!
BE CAREFUL!
SHUT UP, BLUEBELL!
( elevator bell dings )
WHERE IS HE?
( bell dinging continuing )
HE'S HIDING...
UH... BEHIND THOSE DOORS.
( grunting )
( yelling )
( gasping )
Burly:
THAT ROOM WAS NOT THERE
A MOMENT AGO.
YOU ARE CRAFTY.
THERE'S NO ONE
IN HERE!
OH, YES,
HE'S HERE.
I'M... I-I'M JUST GOING
TO OPERATE THE SECRET DOOR
AND SHOW YOU
WHERE HE'S HIDING.
NO!
( yelling )
IT'S A TRICK!
( screaming )
SUCK AN ELF!
( yelling )
OPEN UP!
ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
DAD'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I THINK IT'S YOU THEY'RE AFTER.
( knocking )
( snoring )
( knocking continues )
OH, WHATEVER IT IS, GO AWAY.
GOOD EVENING!
TROLLS HAVE BEEN
TO VISIT YOU FIRST,
I SEE.
NO MATTER!
TONIGHT AND TONIGHT ONLY
I AM AUTHORIZED TO MAKE YOU
A UNIQUE OFFER.
NAMELY, THE END
TO ALL YOUR PERSONAL
AND FINANCIAL PROBLEMS.
HEY, HOLD IT A SECOND.
TAKE ANOTHER STEP,
I'M CALLING THE COPS.
IT'S PRIVATE PROPERTY.
UNDER THE TERMS OF THIS POLICY
I AM, IN EXCHANGE
FOR INFORMATION
AS TO THE WHEREABOUTS
OF YOUR DAUGHTER
ABLE TO OFFER YOU
THIS MAGIC BEAN
WHICH, ONCE EATEN,
WILL GIVE YOU SIX
GLORIOUS WISHES.
( whooshing )
IS THIS HER?
THIS CAN'T BE HER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
OH, SHE'S SUCCULENT!
WHAT A DREAMY, CREAMY GIRL!
( whimpering )
( howling )
( fiercely ):
TASTY, OR WHAT?
( all grunting rhythmically )
( all yelling )
( fierce yelling )
( exhausted sigh )
I'VE BEEN THINKING
BACK OVER THE YEARS
AND I FEEL THIS IS QUITE
THE WORST SPELL WE HAVE
EVER BEEN PUT UNDER!
WE'VE HAD SOME STINKERS
BUT NOTHING LIKE THIS.
SHE'S A POWERFUL LITTLE WITCH,
THAT ONE.
I THINK...
WE MIGHT BE IN HER POCKET.
HMM?
WHAT?
I THINK
SHE MIGHT HAVE SHRUNK US
AND PUT US IN A MATCHBOX
IN HER POCKET.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
YOU'RE FALLING
TO PIECES.
GET A GRIP ON YOURSELF.
HOW CAN WE BE IN A MATCHBOX,
YOU IDIOT?
WHERE ARE ALL THE MATCHES?
( soft boinging )
WHAT THE HELL'S IT DOING?
SIX... BIG WISHES.
IMAGINE HAVING ANYTHING
YOU DESIRE.
AND FROM THE LOOK OF
YOUR MODEST SURROUNDINGS
I'M SURE THERE
ARE MANY THINGS THAT
YOU'D LOVE TO CHANGE.
I... OH...
WELL, YOU KNOW, I WOULD...
UH... JUST GET THE HELL
OUT OF MY APARTMENT
ALL RIGHT?
( growls )
WELL...
THIS IS A JOKE, RIGHT?
NO! NO...
IT'S A STANDARD
MULTIPLE-WISHES DEAL--
SIX WISHES; NO GOING BACK
ON WISHES ONCE MADE;
NO MAKING FIVE WISHES AND
WISHING FOR ANOTHER THOUSAND.
NOW, COME ON,
IS THAT A FAIR DEAL
OR WHAT?
NOW...
WHERE... IS YOUR...
LOVELY DAUGHTER?
WHAT DO YOU WANT HER FOR?
SIMPLY TO RECLAIM
MY LITTLE DOGGY
WHICH SHE FOUND EARLIER.
DOG?
THERE'S EVEN A REWARD INVOLVED
WHICH I INTEND
TO GIVE HER PERSONALLY.
( sighs )
IF SHE'S NOT AT WORK
SHE'LL BE
AT MY MOTHER-IN-LAW'S.
OOH.
SHE'S ALWAYS TRYING
TO TURN VIRGINIA AGAINST ME.
DOES THIS MOTHER-IN-LAW
LIKE, UH, FLOWERS?
SHE LIKES MONEY.
THAT'S THE ONLY THING
THAT IMPRESSES HER.
ADDRESS, PLEASE.
IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE.
WAIT. HOLD
ON A SECOND.
HOW LONG DOES THIS
TAKE TO WORK?
OH, DON'T WORRY--
THE FIRST THREE HOURS...
ARE THE WORST.
( sighs )
ANYTHING I WANT, HUH?
( snorts )
OOH...
'KAY.
ALL RIGHT...
FOR MY FIRST WISH...
( stomach grumbling deeply )
FOR MY F...
( grumbling continues )
( groaning in pain )
Virginia:
HELLO?
Grandma:
WHO IS IT?
IT'S ONLY ME, GRANDMA.
HI.
( laughing ):
FOR A MOMENT THERE
I THOUGHT IT WAS YOUR MOTHER.
( laughs )
WELL, I'M SORRY
TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
WOULD YOU MIND
IF I STAYED THE NIGHT TONIGHT?
YOU KNOW,
SHE'LL COME BACK ONE DAY.
SHE'LL JUST...
SWAN IN WITHOUT A WORD.
YOU DON'T THINK
SHE COULD BE IN ASPEN, DO YOU?
SHE ALWAYS
LOVED THE SNOW.
( laughing ):
WELL...
I THINK SHE WOULD HAVE
COME BACK BY NOW.
I DON'T KNOW, 14 YEARS
IS A LONG TIME FOR APRES-SKI.
DON'T BE CHEAP, DEAR.
( Prince barking )
( little dog barking )
GOD... WHAT'S THAT?
THIS IS A STRAY
I PICKED UP TODAY.
WELL, JUST KEEP HIM
AWAY FROM ROLAND.
HE'S PROBABLY GOT FLEAS.
AW, YOU DON'T
HAVE FLEAS.
DO YOU HAVE
FLEAS? NO. SHH.
SHH.
( Roland barking )
THANKS.
YOU KNOW
YOU COULD STILL BE SOMETHING
IN SOCIETY, VIRGINIA.
I HAVE CONNECTIONS, YOU KNOW.
YOUR MOTHER'S DEBUT
AT THE RITZ CARLTON
WAS... AH...
A CORONATION.
AT NINETEEN
SHE COULD HAVE HAD ANY BACHELOR
IN THE WHOLE OF NEW YORK...
AND WHAT DOES SHE END UP WITH?
DAD.
DON'T THROW AWAY YOUR LIFE
THE WAY SHE DID, VIRGINIA.
I CAN SEE THE WHOLE THING
HAPPENING ALL OVER AGAIN.
YOU'RE A WAITRESS,
FOR GOD'S SAKES.
WHO ARE YOU GOING
TO MEET?
SOME... ELIGIBLE
SHORT-ORDER COOK?
( Virginia laughing )
NO.
( knocking on door )
( knocking louder )
UH... SO, OF COURSE
YOU NEVER FIXED THE PIPES
LIKE YOU PROMISED--
THAT I'VE COME TO EXPECT--
BUT THIS!
I CAN, UM... THIS...
I CAN EXPLAIN ALL OF THIS,
AND I'M GOING TO...
I'LL GET ON IT RIGHT AWAY,
MR. MURRAY.
NO.
"I'M GOING TO GET ON IT"
IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
I WANT YOU AND YOUR DAUGHTER
OUT OF THIS APARTMENT TODAY!
YOU'RE FIRED!
FIRE... FIRED?
NO, PLEASE, MR. MURRAY...
WHAT, YOU BIG JERK?
I WISH
YOU AND YOUR ENTIRE FAMILY
WOULD KISS MY ASS
AND BE MY SLAVES
FOREVER.
WHAT DID YOU JUST SAY?
OH, MASTER.
( short laugh )
Burly:
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK
THIS SPELL WILL LAST?
IT CAN'T LAST LONG.
100 YEARS?
AT MOST.
MAYBE ONLY 50.
WELL, WE'LL JUST
HAVE TO MAKE
THE MOST OF OUR IMPRISONMENT.
AND AGREE NOT TO EAT
EACH OTHER.
ABSOLUTELY.
WE'LL DO
THE HUNDRED YEARS
AND MAYBE IF WE'RE LUCKY
WE'LL ONLY HAVE TO DO
TWO-THIRDS OF THE SPELL
AND GET OUT EARLY.
( doorbell rings )
( gasps )
OH.
I... THERE MUST BE
SOME MISTAKE.
I DO APOLOGIZE.
I WAS LOOKING FOR
VIRGINIA'S GRANDMOTHER.
I AM SHE.
THAT CANNOT BE.
HER YOUNG SISTER, PERHAPS.
HER MOTHER
PERHAPS.
BUT HER GRANDMOTHER?
PAH!
YOU ARE A...
DAZZLING BEAUTY.
OH.
WELL, I, I DON'T
HAVE MY MAKEUP ON
OR ANYTHING YET.
MAY I COME IN?
I HAVE FLOWERS.
YEAH, BUT WHO ARE YOU?
I AM VIRGINIA'S SUITOR.
HER BETROTHED.
BETROTHED?
SHE DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT A FIANCE.
HOW LIKE HER.
HOW MODEST.
MOST GIRLS WOULD
BRAG AND BOAST
ABOUT DATING THE HEIR
TO AN ENORMOUS FORTUNE
BUT NOT VIRGINIA.
OH, WELL, DO COME IN.
I'LL, I'LL JUST GO
AND GET DRESSED.
OF COURSE.
GET DRESSED.
( humming )
OKAY, WISH MASTER, GIVE ME
A NEVER-ENDING SUPPLY OF BEER.
TWO?
YOU CALL THAT A WILD NIGHT
WHERE YOU COME FROM?
OH!
HEY, OH, MURRAY! MURRAY!
MURRAY! YOU GOT
TO SEE THIS.
THE REFRIGERATOR,
IT JUST KEEPS GO...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M WORRIED THAT THEY'RE
NOT CLEAN ENOUGH, MASTER.
SHALL I LICK YOUR SHOES AGAIN?
LET ME SEE YOUR TONGUE.
ALL RIGHT,
FIVE MORE MINUTES.
HOW IS YOUR MOTHER COMING
WITH THAT DOOR?
OH, UH... AL-ALMOST
DONE NOW, MASTER.
JUST HURRY...
STOP. NO, NO.
ONCE WAS ENOUGH.
HERE. OPEN THIS.
WHAT SHALL I WISH FOR
NEXT?
I WISH...
I WISH I HAD SOMETHING
THAT WOULD CLEAN THIS APARTMENT
ALL BY ITSELF, AND I WOULD NEVER
HAVE TO LIFT A FINGER.
( whirring )
OH, HERE WE GO.
( gasping )
( laughing )
HERE WE GO.
CLEAN, CLEAN
CLEAN, CLEAN,
CLEAN, CLEAN.
CLEAN.
AW, I GOT TO GET THIS CLEAN.
OH, OH, LOOK HERE.
OH, THERE'S DUST
ALL OVER THE FLOOR.
PICK IT UP.
OH, HERE'S SOME OVER HERE.
HERE'S SOME MORE. OH...!
( muffled shrieking )
I AM SO BAD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M DOING THIS.
OH, STILL...
I SUPPOSE YOU
WOULD LOOK BETTER
SURROUNDED BY POTATOES.
WHERE'S THE GARLIC?
THE ROSEMARY?
OH! WHAT DO I HAVE
TO WORK WITH HERE?!
THREE-YEAR-OLD DRIED HERBS?
( groaning )
AH! YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO FIT IN THE
OVEN, ARE YOU?
NOT IN ONE PIECE, ANYWAY.
SHEPHERDESS
MAKES GREATNESS
THE LITTLE LAMBS ARE LONELY
SHEPHERDESS...
( gasping )
OH, WHAT AM I DOING?
I SHOULD UNTIE YOU.
HMM.
OH, A POOR OLD LADY
FRIGHTENED OUT
OF HER WITS.
I SHOULD UNTIE YOU...
BUT FIRST I'LL PUT
A DOLLOP OF FAT
IN THE OVEN TRAY.
Virginia:
GRANDMOTHER?
OH! OH... GUESTS ARE UP.
BREAKFAST ISN'T READY.
GRANDMOTHER?
Falsetto voice:
IN HERE, DARLING.
( knocking )
GRANDMOTHER?
Falsetto voice:
IN HERE, DARLING.
GOOD MORNING.
DO YOU WANT SOME
COFFEE OR TOAST
OR SOMETHING?
HMM?
( whimpering )
WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU GOT A COLD?
( whimpering )
GRANDMA?
SURPRISE!
OH, BOY!
YOU'RE FANTASTIC.
YOUR PICTURE DOESN'T
DO YOU JUSTICE.
WOW!
OH, NO.
HOW DID THIS GET HERE?
NO. NO...
OH, NO.
BY THE WAY,
WHERE IS THE DOG?
SLEEPING IN
IF I KNOW ROYALTY.
OH, YOU SMELL GREAT.
I'VE HAD LITTLE TEASERS
OF YOUR SCENT BEFORE, VIRGINIA
BUT IN THE FLESH.... AH!
PERFUMES ARE NOT FOR ME, NO.
I RESPOND FAVORABLY
TO THE AUDACITY
OF A WOMAN
WHO FLAUNTS HER OWN AROMA,
AND YOU, VIRGINIA--
YOU SMELL LIKE SUNDAY LUNCH.
YOU KEEP AWAY FROM ME.
OH, BEAUTIFUL EYES,
BEAUTIFUL TEETH.
ALL THE RIGHT STUFF
IN ALL THE RIGHT PLACES.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT,
I AM IN LOVE.
MMM...
LET ME PUT YOUR
MIND AT REST.
NOW THAT I'VE SEEN YOU
EATING YOU
IS OUT OF THE QUESTION.
NOT EVEN ON THE MENU.
OH, NOW, I KNOW THIS
IS GOING TO COME OUT OF THE BLUE
BUT HOW ABOUT A DATE?
WE'VE STARTED BADLY
BUT I TAKE
ALL THE BLAME FOR THAT.
COME ON,
GIVE US A CHANCE. PLEASE.
OOH!
OH, YOU ARE ONE DYNAMIC LADY.
THERE'S NO QUESTION THAT...
( howling )
( sighing )
( faint shrieking )
( shrieking )
OH, MY GOD.
GRANDMOTHER!
OUT OF MY WAY.
WORK, WORK, WORK.
Tony:
NO, NO, NO, NO.
OKAY, OKAY, FINE.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S ENOUGH. GO.
GO DO SOMETHING ELSE.
MM-MM-MM-MM...
NO. HEY, GET UP.
GET UP. GET UP.
LISTEN, YOU'VE ALREADY
KISSED ME THREE TIMES TODAY.
LET ME KISS YOU
AGAIN, MASTER.
NO! GO CLEAN SOMETHING.
YOU'RE RIDICULOUS.
MASTER, OH,
WONDERFUL MASTER
MY WIFE HAS
A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
OH, REALLY?
WELL, I'LL
TAKE CARE OF HER.
YOU GO GET ME A BEER.
YES, MASTER.
IT'S MY HUSBAND'S
ROLEX OYSTER.
SOLID GOLD.
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S NOT ONE
OF THOSE CHEAP IMITATIONS?
OH, NO, MASTER.
WHOA! OH!
( gasping )
I BOUGHT IT FOR MY
HUSBAND'S 40th BIRTHDAY
BUT YOU MUST HAVE IT.
ALL OUR POSSESSIONS
ARE YOURS NOW.
MURRAY, I'M GOING
TO TAKE YOUR WIFE OUT
AND BUY HER SOME UNDERWEAR.
OF COURSE, MASTER!
HELP YOURSELF!
Woman:
MASTER?
I, UM, I THINK THERE MIGHT BE
SOMEONE TRAPPED IN THE ELEVATOR.
I CAN HEAR VOICES
AND BANGING.
YES, WELL, I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU'VE NOTICED
BUT I'M NO LONGER
MR. FIX-IT
SO WHY DON'T YOU GET
YOUR RICH BEHIND OUT THERE
AND FIX IT YOURSELF?
AT ONCE, MASTER!
I THINK WE NEED
SOME SPENDING MONEY.
UM, WISH MASTER,
HOW ABOUT A MILLION DOLLARS?
( doorbell rings )
( gasping excitedly )
( chuckles )
( laughing )
OH, YES, I'M RICH!
I'M RICH! I'M RICH!
SAY HELLO TO BENNY!
CAN I HELP YOU?
OH, I HOPE SO.
I'M VERY CONFUSED.
YOU MUST BE
PAUL'S REFERRAL.
HE SAID YOU'D DROP BY
TO MAKE AN APPOINTMENT.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT I'M DOING HERE?
LET'S GET TO KNOW
EACH OTHER A BIT
BEFORE WE TACKLE
THE BIG QUESTIONS, OKAY?
YEAH. BIG QUESTIONS.
NOW I'M GOING
TO GIVE YOU A WORD
AND I WANT YOU
TO SAY THE FIRST WORD
THAT COMES
INTO YOUR MIND, OKAY?
GAME, YEAH.
HERE WE GO. "HOME."
COOKING.
"COWARD."
CHICKEN!
"WEDDING."
CAKE.
"DEAD."
MEAT!
"SEXUAL."
APPETITE.
"LOVE."
( gasps )
TO EAT ANYTHING FLUFFY!
( grunts )
SORRY. SORRY.
MORE THAN ONE WORD.
START AGAIN.
Tony:
YOU KNOW, MURRAY,
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
LISTEN, I WANT EVERYBODY
OUT OF HERE
EXCEPT YOUR WIFE.
I HAD NO IDEA YOU HAD
SO MANY RELATIVES.
OF COURSE, MASTER.
( vacuum cleaner munching )
YOU CAN GO.
BE WITH YOU IN
A MOMENT, MURRAY.
JUST GOT TO PUCK UP
TO THE MASTER.
UH, UH, DON'T PUCKER.
HEY, HEY, CUT THAT OUT.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
STOP!
CLEAN IT UP. CLEAN IT UP.
CLEAN IT UP.
CLEAN IT UP! CLEAN IT UP!
CLEAN IT UP!
OH, JEEZ!
I SAID...
STOP!
STOP! STOP!
( sirens wailing )
( officers yelling )
Officer:
UPSTAIRS!
MOVE IT! MOVE IT!
I CAN'T STOP IT, MASTER!
THANK YOU!
THANK YOU, MASTER!
I'M TRYING!
IT'S NOT GOING TO STOP, MASTER!
MASTER, WAIT!
COME ON!
PLEASE, LET'S GO!
( all yelling )
WHOA! WHOA!
MOVE! MOVE!
WAIT A MINUTE! WHOA!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?!
SPREAD 'EM!
ALL RIGHT!
WHAT HAVE I DONE?!
BINGO. LOOKIT HERE.
THE MONEY FROM THE ROBBERY.
NO! HOLD ON
A SECOND. NO, NO.
THAT JUST APPEARED
IN FRONT OF MY DOOR.
I'VE BEEN IN MY APARTMENT
ALL DAY.
ALL THESE PEOPLE
CAN VOUCH FOR ME, RIGHT?
All:
YES, O MASTER.
I'VE BEEN HERE
ALL DAY JUST
HAVING A BEER WITH FRIENDS.
YOU KNOW, I THINK
YOU'RE STILL HOLDING BACK.
WHAT IS
REALLY TROUBLING YOU?
OKAY, ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
DOC, I MET THIS
TERRIFIC GIRL
AND I REALLY, REALLY,
REALLY LIKE HER
BUT THE THING IS THAT...
GO ON, SAY IT.
SAY IT!
I'M NOT SURE WHETHER
I-I WANT TO LOVE HER
OR EAT HER.
( growls )
OH, OH.
OF COURSE,
I BLAME MY PARENTS.
THEY WERE BOTH ENORMOUS.
THEY COULDN'T STOP EATING.
EVERY DAY I CAME HOME
FROM SCHOOL
IT WAS, "EAT THIS. EAT THAT.
EAT HER!"
YOU SHOULDN'T PUNISH YOURSELF.
OH, I SHOULD. I SHOULD.
I'M BAD. I'M SO BAD.
I'VE DONE SO MANY BAD THINGS!
BUT THAT WASN'T ME, YOU SEE?
THAT WAS WHEN I WAS A WOLF.
DOC, I WANT TO CHANGE!
I WANT TO BE
A GOOD PERSON.
OH, CAN'T THE LION
CUDDLE UP WITH THE LAMB?
CAN'T THE LEOPARD
RUB OUT ALL ITS SPOTS?
THIS IS THE EXACT SPOT
WHERE I FOUND YOU
SO THIS IS REALLY
WHERE WE HAVE TO GO
OUR SEPARATE WAYS, OKAY?
( sighs )
LOOK, I'M NOT THE ADVENTURE
TYPE, YOU KNOW?
I MEAN, I'M A WAITRESS.
THIS JUST REALLY...
THIS ISN'T MY THING.
WHOEVER THESE PEOPLE ARE
WHO WANT YOU
THEY CAN HAVE YOU.
NO, I GOT TO GO.
GOOD-BYE. I GOT TO GO.
( whines )
HERE IS THE READING
LIST I STRONGLY
RECOMMEND NOW.
OKAY.
WHY DON'T YOU COME BACK
AND SEE ME NEXT WEEK?
OH, BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I WON'T BE HERE NEXT WEEK.
UH, UH, UH, UH.
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO INTIMIDATE ME
WITH SUICIDE.
THAT'S BETTER.
OKAY.
Policeman:
IF YOU COOPERATE
AND GIVE US
THE DEALER'S NAME
MAYBE I'LL PUT IN
A GOOD WORD FOR YOU.
"DEALER"? WHAT DEALER?
I'M NOT TAKING DRUGS.
YEAH, RIGHT.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER
STEALING THE MONEY
BECAUSE YOU WERE
UNDER THE INFLUENCE
OF THESE MAGIC
MUSHROOMS, RIGHT?
"MAGIC MUSHROOMS"?
NO, I DIDN'T TAKE...
WELL, I SWALLOWED
THE BEAN, BUT...
I ALMOST FIXED
THE ELEVATOR NOW, MASTER.
WE WILL BREAK THE SPELL.
TRUST ME.
I TRUST YOU.
I TRUST YOU MORE.
NO, I TRUST YOU MORE.
YEAH!
I TRUST HER MORE.
I TRUST HER!
I ALWAYS TRUSTED HER!
SUCK AN ELF!
( all yelling )
Burly:
WE'RE MOVING.
WE'RE GOING DOWN.
IS THAT GOOD OR BAD?
WE ARE ABOUT TO ENTER
THE UNDERWORLD.
PREPARE YOURSELVES.
( bell dings )
( all yelling )
THIS ISN'T THE UNDERWORLD,
YOU IDIOT!
THIS IS WHERE WE CAME IN.
MAGIC, INDEED!
HOW DID SHE DO THAT?!
AH, SUCK AN ELF!
( Wolf gasps )
SHEEP! SOMETIMES I LIKE SHEEP.
OOH!
EXCUSE ME. I NEED
EVERYTHING ON THIS LIST
AND ANYTHING ELSE
YOU MIGHT THINK IS
USEFUL, PLEASE, MISS?
( gasps )
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND IF MY PLAN IS SUCCESSFUL
I WILL CERTAINLY INVITE YOU
TO THE WEDDING.
THAT'S MINE.
THAT'S MINE, TOO.
Tony:
HEY, HEY, COULDN'T WE COME
TO SOME KIND OF DEAL?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I CAN GIVE YOU ANYTHING
YOU WANTED.
ANYTHING WHATEVER.
I'M SERIOUS.
A HOUSE IN THE HAMPTONS,
BOATS, CARS, WOMEN.
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
IT WON'T MAKE IT ANY BETTER
TRYING TO BRIBE US.
WHAT HAVE I GOT TO LOSE?
I WISH I COULD ESCAPE
FROM THIS POLICE CAR RIGHT NOW.
( chuckling )
WES, THE BRAKES
ARE FAILING.
( horn beeping )
NO!
"HOW TO MARRY THE GIRL
OF YOUR DREAMS."
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I'M LOOKING FOR.
OH, MY GOD!
Officer:
STUPID IDIOT!
STOP THAT MAN RIGHT NOW!
HE'S GETTING AWAY!
HEY, PAL!
THANK YOU. THANK YOU!
NO, WAIT!
YOU HAVEN'T PAID FOR THOSE!
LOOK, I CANNOT TAKE YOU BACK
TO WHERE YOU CAME FROM
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU CAME FROM.
NO, LOOK, THIS
REALLY IS IT, OKAY?
GOOD LUCK.
I DIDN'T DO IT!
DAD?
DAD!
YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO ME.
DON'T BET ON IT.
COME ON!
FAN OUT, YOU GUYS, FAN OUT!
IS THAT THE DOG
THAT GUY WANTS?
WHY DON'T YOU
JUST GIVE IT TO HIM?
DAD, I DON'T THINK
HE IS A DOG.
HE'S TRYING
TO SAY SOMETHING
TALK TO ME OR SOMETHING
BUT I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT HE'S SAYING.
TRYING TO TALK?
YEAH, I DON'T KNOW.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU WATCH THIS.
I WISH THAT I COULD UNDERSTAND
EVERYTHING THIS DOG IS SAYING.
WHAT?
YOU'RE IN TERRIBLE DANGER.
BOTH OF YOU.
IT WORKED.
IT WORKED!
IF YOU VALUE
YOUR LIFE
YOU HAVE TO DO EXACTLY AS I SAY.
LISTEN! SHH. WHAT?
WE HAVE TO FIND THE WAY BACK.
HE'S TALKING.
CAN'T YOU HEAR HIM?
NO.
( police voices coming closer )
COME HERE.
WHAT?!
( all yelling )
WHY ARE ALL THESE
COPS AFTER YOU?
AND WHY ARE YOU
WEARING HANDCUFFS?
THEY THINK I DID
A BANK JOB.
WHAT?
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
STOP RABBITING
AND HELP ME FIND THE MIRROR.
NOW, IT'S A MIRROR
BUT IT MAY NOT
LOOK LIKE A MIRROR
FROM THE OTHER SIDE.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK
VERY, VERY CAREFULLY.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A MAGIC MIRROR.
YEAH, OF COURSE WE ARE.
( Prince Wendell barking )
JUST LOOK FOR A PIECE OF FOREST
THAT DOESN'T FIT.
I'M SURE THIS IS WHERE...
LOOK.
THERE IT IS.
Tony:
THAT'S WEIRD.
Blabberwort:
THERE THEY ARE!
IF YOU VALUE YOUR LIVES,
FOLLOW ME.
UH, UH... COME ON.
( gasps )
WHERE THE HELL ARE WE?
I DON'T KNOW
BUT I'M PRETTY SURE
IT'S NOT CENTRAL PARK.
FOLLOW ME.
THE DOG SAID FOLLOW HIM.
HURRY UP!
WHAT HAPPENED TO EVERYBODY?
WELL, THE
SAME THING
THAT HAPPENED
TO YOU, OLD CHAP--
TROLL DUST!
IT LOOKS LIKE
IT'S STARTING
TO WEAR OFF.
IS THAT DOG
TALKING AGAIN?
COME ON.
SO, WHAT SHALL WE DO
WHEN WE HAVE
OUR OWN KINGDOM?
AH, I KNOW, I KNOW.
WE'LL HAVE SERVANTS--
THOUSANDS AND THOUSANDS
OF SERVANTS
TO POLISH OUR SHOES.
DAD, LET'S GO HOME.
NO, I CAN'T
GO BACK YET.
POLICE ARE ALL
OVER CENTRAL PARK
LOOKING FOR ME.
WELL, WE CAN'T STAY HERE.
SHH! I CAN SMELL THE TROLLS.
HE SAYS HE CAN
SMELL TROLLS.
WE'LL HAVE
FOOTWEAR PARTIES
WHERE YOU HAVE
TO CHANGE SHOES
SIX TIMES AN HOUR!
AND ANYONE FOUND
HAVING DIRTY SHOES
WILL HAVE THEIR FACE SEWN UP!
( laughing )
COME ALONG, THEN.
FOLLOW ME.
WHOA. HOLD ON.
I'M NOT GOING TO FOLLOW YOU.
WHERE ARE WE?
WE'RE IN THE SOUTHERNMOST PART
OF MY KINGDOM--
WHERE I WAS ATTACKED
BY MY STEPMOTHER
AND TURNED INTO A DOG.
THIS IS THE SNOW WHITE
MEMORIAL PRISON, HOUSING
THE MOST DANGEROUS CRIMINALS
IN ALL THE NINE KINGDOMS.
ALL RIGHT, BACK UP.
THE NINE WHAT?
KINGDOMS.
I AM PRINCE WENDELL
GRANDSON OF THE LATE SNOW WHITE
AND SOON-TO-BE-CROWNED
KING
OF THE FOURTH KINGDOM.
AND WHO
MIGHT YOU BE?
I'M TONY LEWIS, JANITOR.
I THINK YOU ALREADY KNOW
MY DAUGHTER
VIRGINIA.
THE "TROLL KINGDOM."
"RED RIDING HOOD FOREST." WOW!
WAIT. HOLD ON A SECOND.
SO WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S CINDERELLA-SLEEPING BEAUTY
FAIRY TALE STUFF?
WELL...
THE GOLDEN AGE WAS
ALMOST 200 YEARS AGO
WHEN THE LADIES
YOU REFER TO
HAD THEIR GREAT MOMENTS
IN HISTORY.
THINGS HAVE GONE DOWNHILL
A BIT SINCE THEN.
"HAPPY EVER AFTER" DIDN'T LAST
AS LONG AS WE'D HOPED.
ALL THE RULERS
OF THE OTHER KINGDOMS ARE
DUE TO ATTEND MY CORONATION.
SOME WILL HAVE
TO TRAVEL GREAT DISTANCES.
THE KINGDOMS ARE VAST.
NO ONE CROSSES THE BORDERS
EXCEPT ON SPECIAL OCCASIONS.
WHO WAS THE STEPMOTHER
WHO TURNED YOU INTO A DOG?
SHE IS THE MOST DANGEROUS
AND EVIL WOMAN ALIVE.
SOUNDS LIKE MY MOTHER-IN-LAW.
LOOK, WE CAN'T
SIT AROUND TALKING ALL DAY.
WE MUST FIND
MY STEPMOTHER'S CELL.
THIS WAY.
VIRGINIA,
HE SAID FOLLOW HIM.
COME ON. COME ON.
LOOK!
THERE'S A DOG BOWL DOWN HERE.
THAT'S THE DOG
THAT'S GOT MY BODY!
OH, IT'S OUTRAGEOUS!
WHAT DID SHE DO, THIS WOMAN?
SHE POISONED
MY MOTHER AND FATHER.
TRIED TO KILL ME, AS WELL.
BASICALLY, POISONED
HIS MOM AND DAD
AND TRIED TO
KILL HIM, TOO.
VIRGINIA, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I... I FEEL WEIRD BEING IN HERE.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH. I'M JUST GOING
TO WAIT OUTSIDE FOR A MINUTE.
THE TROLLS HAVE BEEN HERE.
OKAY, JUST DON'T
GO TOO FAR, OKAY?
STAY OUTSIDE
THE DOOR.
VIRGINIA!
PRINCE! PRINCE! PRINCE!
I WASN'T SCARED.
IT'S JUST THAT PEOPLE MUSTN'T
SEE ME AS A DOG, ANTONY.
IT'S DEEPLY, DEEPLY
EMBARRASSING.
I COULD CARE LESS
ABOUT YOU
BEING A DOG!
VIRGINIA! VIRGINIA!
WHERE ARE THEY?
I NEVER SHOULD HAVE
TRUSTED TROLLS TO DO ANYTHING.
BE CAREFUL
WHAT YOU SAY.
I'M THE ONLY REASON
YOU GOT OUT OF PRISON
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
OF COURSE,
YOUR MAJESTY
AND FOR THAT I'M
ETERNALLY GRATEFUL
BUT I CAN'T STAY
HERE ANY LONGER.
NO ONE MUST SEE
THE PRINCE LIKE THIS.
( barking )
HAVE YOUR CHILDREN
BRING THE DOG TO ME
WHEN THEY RETURN.
I AM NOT
YOUR LACKEY!
I AM RELISH
THE TROLL KING!
YOU WILL DO WELL
TO REMEMBER IT.
OF COURSE, YOUR MAJESTY.
AND I WILL
REWARD YOU HANDSOMELY
WITH HALF
OF WENDELL'S KINGDOM
AS I PROMISED.
JUST EXACTLY WHEN
DO I GET IT?
SOON.
BUT NOW I MUST GO.
I HAVE STAYED
TOO LONG ALREADY.
( panting )
OH, GET IN
THE CARRIAGE!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
THERE'S NOWHERE YOU CAN HIDE.
WHEN THEY FIND OUT
YOU'VE ESCAPED
THERE WILL BE
ROADBLOCKS EVERYWHERE.
THEY'LL SEARCH EVERY HOUSE
AND CARRIAGE IN THE KINGDOM.
NOT EVERY CARRIAGE.
SHOULDN'T WE GO
BACK FOR THE DOG?
NO, WE CAN'T.
THE TROLL DUST
WILL BE WEARING OFF.
( ringing )
WAIT A MINUTE!
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
THEY'RE ALL WAKING UP.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
OH, THE QUEEN
WILL BE VERY ANGRY.
AW, THE QUEEN CAN SUCK AN ELF
FOR ALL I CARE!
WE'VE CAPTURED
THE WITCH FROM
THE TENTH KINGDOM!
LET'S GO TELL DAD.
WHAT ABOUT THE WITCH'S FATHER?
PERHAPS HE'S A GREAT WARLOCK.
OH, HE'S HANDCUFFED.
A GREAT IDIOT,
MORE LIKELY.
I WISH I COULD BE THERE
WHEN THE GOVERNOR FINDS HIM
IN THE QUEEN'S CELL.
( laughing )
Tony:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I CAN'T FIGHT.
IT WAS SOME
KIND OF SPELL.
ME AND THE LADS
BEEN LAID UP
FOR OVER A DAY.
I'VE SEARCHED
EVERY INCH OF THE PRISON
BUT THE QUEEN'S
GONE, SIR.
I HAVE BEEN
THE GOVERNOR
OF THIS PRISON
FOR 12 YEARS.
NO PRISONER
HAS EVER ESCAPED BEFORE.
THAT'S A VERY IMPRESSIVE RECORD.
WHATEVER
YOU DO, ANTONY
DON'T TELL HIM I'M A DOG.
WHY NOT?
SPEAK WHEN YOU'RE SPOKEN TO!
BECAUSE
THE QUEEN HAS GOT
SOME TERRIBLE PLAN.
MY WHOLE KINGDOM
MAY BE IN JEOPARDY.
NO ONE MUST KNOW
I'M HELPLESS.
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE IS THE QUEEN?
I WISH I WAS HOME.
I WISH VIRGINIA AND I
WERE BACK IN
OUR APARTMENT
IN NEW YORK NOW.
WELL...
IT SEEMS YOU'RE NOT.
( coughing )
( gagging )
OH, NO, ANTONY!
YOU DIDN'T SWALLOW A DRAGON
DUNG BEAN,
YOU MORON!
I GUESS THAT MEANS I'VE HAD ALL
MY WISHES, HUH?
HOW DID THE QUEEN ESCAPE?
I'M TELLING YOU, I HAVE NO IDEA!
THEN WHY WERE YOU FOUND
LOCKED IN HER EMPTY CELL?
I AM AN INNOCENT VICTIM.
I HAVE NEVER BEEN IN TROUBLE
WITH THE POLICE MY ENTIRE LIFE.
THEN WHY ARE YOU
WEARING HANDCUFFS?
WELL, BECAUSE I'M WANTED
FOR ARMED ROBBERY
WHICH I DIDN'T
HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH EITHER.
OH, CARRY ON, ANTONY.
YOU'RE DOING
SPECTACULARLY WELL
SO FAR.
I'M FROM
A DIFFERENT DIMENSION.
I CAME HERE
FROM A DIFFERENT DIMENSION
LED BY THAT DOG,
WHO IS ACTUALLY PRINCE WENDELL.
OH, I TOLD YOU NOT TO SAY THAT.
PRINCE WENDELL?
LOOK, I CAN MAKE YOU
BREAK ROCKS
WITH YOUR TEETH
FOR 100 YEARS.
( clinking )
I'M TELLING YOU,
IT'S THE TRUTH.
THAT IS
THE QUEEN'S DOG.
SHE HAS
BEEN PERMITTED
TO KEEP HIM IN HER CELL
FOR THREE YEARS.
DON'T INSULT
MY INTELLIGENCE.
I'M NOT. IT'S THE TRU...
ALL RIGHT, I'LL PROVE IT.
BARK ONCE
IF I'M TELLING THE TRUTH.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF BARKING, ANTONY.
HE IS BEING JUST STUBBORN.
YOU HAVE TO
LET ME GO
IMMEDIATELY.
I THINK MY
DAUGHTER WAS
ABDUCTED BY TROLLS.
THAT'S ENOUGH!
I'LL GET THE TRUTH
OUT OF YOU
SOON ENOUGH.
WARDER, REMOVE HIS HANDCUFFS.
ISSUE HIM
WITH PRISON UNIFORM
AND PUT HIM IN
UH... YES!
PUT HIM IN 103
WITH ACORN THE DWARF
AND CLAY FACE
THE GOBLIN.
CLAY FACE THE GOBLIN?
I DON'T WANT TO BE PUT
IN ANY ROOM WITH CLAY FACE...
NO!
WHERE'S
MY DAUGHTER?
WHAT ABOUT
THE QUEEN'S DOG, SIR?
GET THE FURNACE
GOING.
I'LL SLIP
SOME RAT POISON
IN HIS DINNER TONIGHT,
AND WE'LL CHUCK HIM
IN THE INCINERATOR TOMORROW.
Prince Wendell:
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
ANTONY, DID YOU HEAR THAT?
YOU HAVE TO GET ME OUT.
IT'S YOUR DUTY.
GET HER IN THE BOAT.
GET HER IN THERE.
HEY, THAT'S MY BOAT.
IT'S OURS NOW.
NOW, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
( trolls yelling )
Blabberwort:
SIT DOWN AND STEER!
( all yelling )
MIDDLE BUNK.
SO, WHAT ARE
YOU IN FOR?
UM... ACTUALLY,
A PRETTY SERIOUS BANK ROBBERY.
COUPLE OF PEOPLE GOT HURT
BUT THAT'S THE WAY IT GOES.
AND YOU?
AGGRAVATED ASSAULT.
I'VE VERY EASILY
AGGRAVATED.
I'M ACORN.
GOT ANY METAL
ON YOU?
KNIVES? FORKS?
COAT-HANGERS?
SORRY.
IF YOU GET
STABBED...
SAVE THE KNIFE
FOR ME, WON'T YOU?
OF COURSE.
DO YOU LIKE
CARVING?
WELL, NOT FLESH
OR ANYTHING.
LOOK WHAT I'M DOING.
AH.
YOU'VE GOT REAL TALENT.
MY NAME'S CLAY FACE,
THE GOBLIN.
TONY.
WHAT ARE YOU IN FOR?
CARVING.
WILL YOU BE MY FRIEND?
WHAT EXACTLY DOES THAT ENTAIL?
Bluebell:
ROW!
Blabberwort:
WHEN WE'RE HOME, I'M GOING
TO LET YOU HAVE IT!
KEEP ROWING.
I'M ROWING.
ANY MINUTE NOW...
I'M SURE PRINCE WENDELL
WILL ARRIVE
TO RECEIVE THE CORONATION THRONE
WHICH OUR CRAFTSMEN
HAVE TIRELESSLY SPENT
THE LAST TWO YEARS MAKING.
HE'S NOT COMING,
IS HE?
OF COURSE HE IS.
HAVE NO WORRY.
I'M SURE HE'S BEEN DELAYED
FOR A VERY GOOD REASON.
HORRIBLE NEWS.
THERE'S BEEN A BREAKOUT
FROM THE PRISON.
THE QUEEN
HAS ESCAPED.
THE QUEEN?
THE QUEEN.
PUT UP THE ROADBLOCKS.
SHE MUST BE CAUGHT
OR WE'RE DOOMED.
OH, WONDERFUL NEWS!
WONDERFUL NEWS.
PRINCE WENDELL
IS COMING.
THANK GOODNESS.
HE'LL KNOW WHAT TO DO.
( townspeople cheering )
WELCOME TO BEANTOWN
YOUR MAJESTY...
PSST. ANTONY.
OVER HERE.
BEHIND THE
GOVERNOR'S DOOR.
HOW DID YOU
KNOW IT WAS ME?
YOU HAVE
A DISTINCTIVE UNWASHED SMELL.
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
I'M SCRUBBING THE FLOOR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK I'M DOING?
HAVE YOU GOT A SOAP BAR?
WELL, YES.
WHAT, DO YOU WANT ME
TO WASH YOU?
NO, JUST STAY THERE.
DON'T GO AWAY.
PRINCE...
THIS IS THE
GOVERNOR'S
MASTER KEY.
MAKE AN
IMPRESSION
IN THE SOAP.
HE'LL BE BACK
ANY MOMENT.
HERE.
VERY STUBBORN STAIN, SIR.
Bluebell:
I THINK
SHE'S WAKING UP.
GOOD MORNING.
( all laughing )
GET SOMEONE OVER HERE.
Prisoners:
WE PROMISE TO SERVE
PRINCE WENDELL
KIND AND BRAVE MONARCH
OF THE FOURTH KINGDOM
AND PLEDGE TO MEND
OUR NAUGHTY WAYS
SO THAT WE MAY ALL LIVE
HAPPILY EVER AFTER.
( all grumbling and muttering )
WHAT IS THIS STUFF?
BAKED BEANSTALK.
BAKED BEANS?
BEANSTALK.
( gags )
MY GOD!
I CAN'T EAT THAT.
IT TASTES LIKE
AN OLD MATTRESS!
NO, IT DOESN'T.
OLD MATTRESS HAS
A SWEATY, MEATY TASTE.
AND HOW OFTEN IS
THIS ON THE MENU?
THREE TIMES A DAY.
THAT'S BEANSTALK JUICE.
TAKES A BIT
OF GETTING USED TO.
( gags )
LISTEN, UM...
LET'S SAY I WANTED
TO TALK TO SOMEBODY
AND I WANTED TO GET
SOMETHING... MADE.
FOR INSTANCE--
FOR THE SAKE OF ARGUMENT--
A SMALL PIECE OF METAL.
WHO WOULD I HAVE TO TALK TO?
I MEAN, WHO'S MR. BIG
AROUND HERE?
IF YOU WANT ANYTHING
BOUGHT, SOLD, BORROWED
OR MADE IN HERE
YOU HAVE TO SEE
THE TOOTH FAIRY.
UH... THE WHO?
THE PRISON DENTIST.
AH.
UH... AND HOW WOULD I GET
TO SEE HIM?
OH, UM...
THAT'S EASY.
OH, YEAH?
( yells )
( knocking )
OH, OH...
THAT'S NO GOOD.
THEY'LL ALL HAVE
TO COME OUT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "COME OUT"?
YOU HAVEN'T EVEN
LOOKED IN MY
MOUTH YET.
SIT DOWN.
I-I...
COME ON.
THERE. THAT'S IT.
( chuckles )
THERE.
W-WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME CANDY?
WHAT? YOU'RE A DENTIST.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE
GIVING PEOPLE CANDY.
WHY NOT?
WELL, BECAUSE
IT ROTS TEETH.