Are you sure you want to
be on that side of the wall?
They begin to tear down the
walls on Monday.
At the end of the month open season
police and schools.
Dont make that face, it seems
you are not happy.
I only hope they meet
what they promised.
Listen, it's the law and the law always
Looking for a fool like me...
...to make sure
these things are fulfilled.
Three years later,
the government has changed.
...the rest...
Sector 13 Ultimatum
Stop!
Keep it! Keep it!
There he is! There he is!
What?
Over here.
Hey, man.
Now we bring cops?
Sorry.
I am not enough.
Do you think a musketeer?
- Yes, I am Dartagnan.
- Are you teasing?
Dudu, leave.
Dudu, I never understand.
Why dont you study anything?
- Say, you look like a child.
- I am a child.
You Take care of others.
See you.
Sit back,
What did you do now?
- This city is not a hotel.
- Sorry.
- I got tired.
- Not in the same situation.
You're free, you
the whole city for you.
They treat us like animals.
And so since we were born.
Three years ago that
we say the same thing.
A government that fails to meet
their promises? That's weird.
If we do something,
will ignore.
We take the latter.
Not your culture, dude.
To us this wall protects us...
...as a fortress.
And those who come to disturb us
of society, not to us.
We have our own.
And that is fine
in this way.
And frankly, I prefer to be
the king of this small kingdom...
...than a pawn out there.
So it is nice and lets you bring
police our wall...
...if not, we will
measures with you.
Do you understand?
This is good.
Take this.
A gift.
Yeah, boss?
Yes, boss.
Come on.
¡Leave!
Come on!
Your merchandise arrived.
Do I enter the first client?
Rude, let me enjoy
a while.
Get him out, at least that.
Everybody out!
Not you.
Go see the boss.
Come on, dance a little.
Mr. Ou will receive
at a time.
Tell me that hurts the ass
of sitting here.
Tell yourself, sir.
Come on, get on his knees.
If you want to win more
you should be more inclined.
Put on your knees, my man.
And with his hands on his head.
- Thief?
- Worse.
Police.
Being arrested,
can be silent...
...until the present
the judge...
If you think that I a...
In French it means
shut up, okay?
No, it's a Ming vase
the twelfth century.
Do not worry, it is false,
long time ago that the monitors.
And the rest?
Are all fake?
Almost. Except for the Van Gogh.
Central, and I have the soap.
Again, I have soap.
Understood,
precise location.
- I am the soap?
- I feel more of a shampoo.
- In the fishing would be more appropriate.
- How, fishing?
Do not worry.
You do not have to understand.
Mr Calma.
Health monitoring.
We would like to see the boss.
Lord, there is a control
at the door.
Two police officers and insurance
there are more hidden.
Here is why. Dale.
Dale.
- You bastard!
- You see, already beginning to fall.
Never leave here, this building
is monitored by all parties.
If it were easy,
I have sent.
What is that?
It's simple, if you talk
your cheeks explode.
Want to try?
Okay.
I'll report
you are cooperative.
Central, I'm going fishing.
Mr Ou awaits.
They stay.
Stay here
okay.
Mr Ou,
gives me pleasure to see you.
Do not move.
There.
Walk.
Gentlemen, after you.
I left the last or what?
Them first.
- Hugo.
- Do you know?
Yes, I have photos of yourself
all over my room.
Shit!
Come on.
Raise the head.
- What is that?
- You know, it was you who invented it.
Gentlemen, follow me.
Is thumbing its nose at me.
And let it gives the same.
A week ago!
that fat...!
Come on, calm down.
Drink a margarita, you relax.
When you fuck with your margarita!
I'm sick of these guys!
Outside, start
to despair.
Mr. Sam, just went looking for him.
Now I try this?
Do your best customer?
Since when
I leave for the final?
Always let the shit
for the final.
Open arms.
What are you doing?
And that picture?
And this shit?
Do not you do anything?
I fell on it
when I was kid.
Well, fix it.
It's nothing,
I fell Bucar.
Central Fisheries ended.
Sent to males.
I already did.
- Nobody move!
- ¡Todos al piso!
Hands on your head!
- Come on, come on!
- Leaving!
Come on!
Never leave live here
Police disgusting.
You do not have any
Chance!
Are you sure?
Let go! Let go!
- I guess I did not give the code.
- Fuck you.
No matter, I have the key.
¡Move!
- I head to the south.
- South?
Send the rest.
Watch your feet!
Push!
Drop it!
Get out! Shit, get out!
The found it!
I told them I was cheating
everywhere.
What happened?
I will kill you.
Open up!
Crap.
- You okay?
- Yes, but try to open.
T move.
This picture is worth
200 million euros.
It's a Van Gogh.
A stray bullet, a scratch
and no longer worth anything.
Die motherfucker!
There he is! There he is!
Okay, I see the keyboard.
Do I have?
Nice to meet you.
Central, there is a bomb.
- A bomb?
- Any idea?
- Where is it?
- In the kitchen in the basement.
It's good,
we will send you the necessary.
Beware!
Well, since you sent it.
Fantastic!
Nice to see them.
Welcome.
- Do you have scratches?
- No, I do not think so.
- I was referring to you, Damian.
- I'm fine, Commander, thank you.
Anyway,
not just these.
Go to rest,
make the report tomorrow.
I prefer to continue working
in what I have in my head.
Tomorrow I'll go early,
If you do not mind.
No, I will see you in my office
at noon. Is an order.
Thank you.
- Good work.
- Thanks.
Everything is fine.
Is clear.
Do come.
Gentlemen.
- How does the work?
- Superb.
How long does it take to
a tower like this?
That depends on the start
of work.
But more or less
eight years.
Good.
Yes
Get him out.
As in the neighborhood
Chantier of...
...twice now, if we give the
guarantee that the constructed.
The operation will begin
tonight.
Perfect.
- Well, thank you tomorrow.
- Goodbye, Damien.
Crap.
Damian ¿?
Have you forgotten me?
No.
This only gave a time
to rest.
For eight hours I'm
resting, and I'm fantastic!
Wait.
Soft, soft.
It hurts the whole body.
Does it hurt the whole body?
Almost.
Is that makeup?
Yes, it's for work.
It is the work.
You told me you spend
the day looking for pictures.
I say it's my job.
Well, you better show me
that the wait was worth it.
Speaking.
The suspect is
in the next seven.
What good music.
Excuse me.
Again, auto blue...
54, we are close.
Well, received 54.
So, Salim
Is not it?
- Yes, yes!
- Listen!
Yes, hi.
Are you at home?
No, I'm in a palace
overlooking the Eiffel Tower.
- And where is your palace?
- On the Champs Elysees.
Beautiful direction.
Well, you listen,
Do you want to do?
Yes, it is Sofia.
Well, "Push the Air"
is for her.
Well, you know,
Coordinator...
- No!
- Shit!
What?
Everything will be fine.
- Sami.
- What?
The police.
- Download music.
- It's our music.
- It's nothing bad.
- I decided I did.
Come on, roles,
the two.
- Come on, here.
- Grab.
- Who owns the car?
- Of my father.
¿Driving license?
I have not, take it away.
What about your license?
I'm 17 years,
I have no license!
Not doing anything,
we hear music!
¡Since when is prohibited
listen to music?
We're not bothering
anyone.
- Come out of that car.
- No.
Hurry.
Shit! Again.
Go see what happened.
Okay.
- And what is this?
- I do not know, I do not know.
Shoot, shoot.
- What is it, officer?
- A routine check.
Some girls who listen
music is not so dangerous.
Why not search? Are
the girls carrying...
...drugs in this neighborhood.
We'll give you a vote
confidence tonight.
- Can you drive?
- Yes
- Get out.
- But I have no license.
Get out!
Shit, they left.
But she has no license.
What do we do?
Do we continue?
- Come on.
- No, stay.
- You keep shooting.
- I am.
What service
are you exactly?
Secret Service.
Talk in your car.
Shit!
Do not move,
still filming!
- And what is this?
- You keep shooting.
And what is this?
The registration, make him zoom
to enrollment.
Now I do.
Shit, never
I had seen that.
Give me here, and I do.
- Samir.
- What?
Policemen killed
police, is a bomb.
Precisely, rather than see it explode
hear the official version.
That will do.
What?
- A police here?
- What are you talking about?
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Something wrong, I assure you.
Hey, you,
Are you lost the way?
- This is not a parking lot.
- Yes, you can be sure.
- Do you have framed?
- Yes
Perfect.
They're shooting!
Fire!
Come on, abnormal
excédanse.
- The clock is well placed?
- Yes
Dale, collects and
we go home.
Diss.
Where are you going?
Still asleep, I'm going to see a
film. Do not worry.
Get down, hands behind!
- I'm police!
- Get down!
¡Damien!
What?
Who is responsible for
the unit? I want to talk.
I am.
I think they are wrong
person.
Damien Tomaso, captain
the armed forces 31 years.
What is the reason
of this record?
Captain, we find
this in the kitchen.
Well here is why.
Come, collect a few things...
...we go.
It is unbearable.
Georges, explain.
Six months ago we
gives good results.
Mr. President, we do not have the means to
reviewed every quarter, every season.
Ahórreme story
the means, please.
There was a plan to
the periphery.
So something had to
have improved.
How Explíqueme
Could we do this.
I assure you that it is not
a generalized case.
- What is it then?
- Well this is...
...an isolated case.
No more.
I hope so.
Meanwhile someone in póngame this
case. Someone seriously and effectively.
That Tomaso, for example.
It is your type of mission, huh?
I thought of him but was arrested this
morning for drug trafficking.
Do you? Are you sure?
Unfortunately.
I would climb
next week.
I thought Gazmán, the head of Diss.
They are well informed about the industry.
Yes, very well. Okay.
Sir.
What? Already?
I guess they are
abreast of the situation.
I had the time
to inform you, Chairman.
Well.
If this film is broadcast, we can
lose our credibility.
Put a civil car
in place.
We have 48 hours.
It is exactly the time they have
to resolve this matter.
- Under the utmost discretion.
- Yes, sir.
We will, Mr. President.
This does not know that war is never
has been at odds with democracy.
Special Feature:
Last night in the 13...
...an altercation between a banda
and law enforcement...
- Wow!
- Look, it's an inner chamber.
That's bullshit!
That was not by chance!
Yes?
Why are you here?
I was wrong place,
as the whole world.
Is no reason to
we have here.
You did well,
so get out!
I have rights!
Come on, go get your
colleagues and tell them to take care.
Come on!
- What industry?
- 13.
Perfect.
Boss, can I show you something?
Sent us this.
Is the chamber that
passed yesterday.
But look at this.
Probably some boys who
attempting to get some girls.
When I saw
I did a zoom...
...and saw this.
Shit, it filmed.
Yes
Encuéntrenme that number
Registration away.
- I'm on it.
- Perfect.
Letto, I seek.
- I filmed everything and now I seek.
- What are you talking about?
Car of television.
Shit!
There!
Stop!
- This is Samir.
- Stop!
¡Suéltenlo! ¡Suéltenlo!
Let go of my partner!
Estate calm
or you take yourself too.
Let go of my partner!
Open the door 14.
Come on.
- Can I borrow my cell phone?
- What else you want?
My cell phone.
Thank you.
Come on up.
Letto, I'm Damien, I'm fucked up,
partner, I need a hand...
I am not at home.
...or maybe do not have the courage
to tell me in the face...
...left the message.
You gotta help me.
I'm Damien.
I'm in the basement of the
Central Police Station.
I lay a trap.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count on you.
Drop the phone!
Hey, guys!
The police are
everywhere, are you crazy?
Yes, I know.
Are everywhere.
Okay.
Leaving a minute.
Yes?
Called someone and told him.
- Who called?
- A one bed.
Locate in sector 13.
- Is aware of before?
- Yes, they were comrades.
Tráiganme in that bed,
we do not risk it.
Has a new message.
Letto, I am calling
but never are. Okay, bye.
Do not move!
- Do not pass.
- We ask you to think.
Think well.
Let's talk seriously.
Some must die.
And you will be.
Up! Up!
Shit, they left.
But she has no license.
And what do?
Do we continue?
- Come on.
- No, stay.
- You keep shooting.
- I am.
- What are they filming?
- Shoot, shoot.
Shit!
Do not move,
still filming!
- And what is this?
- You keep shooting.
And what is this?
The registration, make him zoom
to enrollment.
Now I do.
Crap,
never seen that.
Come on.
You gotta help me.
Is Damian.
I'm in the basement
Central Police Station.
I lay a trap.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can
count on you.
You gotta help me.
I'm Damien.
I'm in the basement
Central Police Station.
I lay a trap.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count
you.
What are you doing there?
Hurry!
Just disappear.
I look.
Hurry! Hurry!
Over here!
There it goes!
We have to go to the other side!
Wait! Wait!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, shit! There he is!
Hurry!
Shit!
Were you shopping?
- No, sir.
- Are you unable to catch...
...a guy with three
drives you?
The individual is very clever, sir
I had never seen anything like this.
Next time, ask
getting lessons.
Back to base, I will go
to see Mr. President.
Yes, sir.
And how are
things over there?
I do not think it takes
to react.
Do not kill the boy on purpose
I guarantee it.
Tried to leave alone.
What is going to do?
Explain to his mother.
¡Move!
Right in the middle!
Go, go!
Can I help you?
Can I see the head,
please?
Head, a young man who wants
talk to the manager.
- Do come.
- Come on, come on.
- What is it?
- It is a room, please.
Are you teasing?
This is not a hotel.
Outside says
"hotel of the police. "
Get out before they
bother me.
Go, go!
Listen, you better be
locked up because I am a criminal...
in power... and if I stay outside,
I do some nonsense.
Have you committed any crime?
No.
¿Well, you know what? Return to us
when you've committed any.
I'll give you a good cell
Okay?
Okay.
Get down! Get down!
Do not move!
Open the door 14.
You're lucky, only
a room.
- But there is no cover or food.
- What?
What do you expect?
Drop it!
You say you drop!
Security.
Security doors
are blocked.
You take your time.
Want to return later
when you're in a good mood?
No, okay.
- Good to see you.
- Me too.
Out there is shit,
Are you sure you want to leave?
Yes, I have accounts
to fix.
Come on, do you have a plan?
Why not have a plan?
I thought we had come as
so easy, you'll have one.
Sign was not so hard.
Exit will be a little more
complicated.
You are well trained.
Yes, more or less.
Come on, I know a shortcut.
Is this your shortcut?
Run! Run!
Tomaso escaped
of his cell.
Have you been?
No, it is still
on the inside.
- Find it.
- Yes
And fast.
...in the 13...
Gentlemen.
Already started?
...of law enforcement...
and incidents...
multiply.
Among the wounded are
many officers.
Well, commander,
How can we?
Sector 13
is out of control.
And the risk in the next few hours is that
Nearby areas join him.
The entire country may be
alarm in 24 hours.
Overall, how a military intervention is
still advisable as a preventive measure?
Yet. But the army...
...is not ready to
an internal invasion yet.
Unfortunately, time
which is a luxury not available.
Mr. Gazmán,
its recommendation.
When the gangrene spreads,
need to be cut.
Well, I was not elected because
my tolerance for metaphors.
When I request a recommendation
I want a recommendation.
Well, Mr. President,
I will be more direct.
Evacuate area 13
in twelve hours.
Tomorrow morning we fly across
the place and nobody can go back there.
And there are more advantages.
This will create new jobs.
Building a new
neighborhood full of middle class...
...which will probably vote
for you in the upcoming elections.
Could not be clearer.
Gentlemen.
That inspires them something?
Politically, such a solution
would be extremely serious.
What is your solution?
Well.
I note that none of you
have any specific proposal...
do to defend that...
our democracy.
Very interesting.
I remember that our function
first is to protect the French...
...and look after their interests.
And so do the values of
freedom, equality, and fraternity...
...is still respected
in this country.
Is somewhat, how do I say?
The foundation of our republic.
And the only proposal that I made
is to exploit the site, a nasty.
Thank you.
Mr. President,
the idea is appalling...
...but we have priorities.
Perhaps in two hours
the situation becomes uncontrollable.
Perhaps not the best idea,
but believe me...
...is the least worst.
General...
...Is that we can evacuate one million
of civilians in less than twelve hours?
If you give the order now,
may be possible.
I suppose that some heads of clans
not so easily be evacuated.
Who will mourn?
General.
Proceed to the evacuation.
We will plan
tomorrow morning.
Mr. Gazmán, I demand that all
the inhabitants of that neighborhood...
...are treated with respect
and dignity, and that means...
...all.
I will give the order personally,
Sir.
Can go.
Go there!
Keep looking!
Here we are.
- Do not you were a cop?
- They found drugs in my kitchen.
Do not you know to save your stuff?
It was not mine.
I planted.
A classic.
Police want to fuck
other policemen.
It is not common.
Above all,
I wonder why.
Sure to impedirte
you went somewhere.
You are very sociable.
I do not know.
Surely something is
they do not want you goals.
Super police
are not good for everything.
I had been given a holiday
or I would have graduated.
You would go on vacation?
No, of course not.
You know what happens
out there?
What's out there?
There is a recording that offers a
banda sector shot 13...
...a patrol.
But there is one in which
Moreover banda police...
...is what you shoot
the patrol.
And what was in the 13?
May have carried.
And then?
After I gave the second
operates a portion of the building.
It was the police.
But I managed to escape before.
They are not policemen.
They must be criminals
posing as policemen.
Why?
For pleasure?
It is a strategy for
end the sector 13.
And then build on it.
Remember tuition?
All have the same
Registration No: DISS.
DISS not think so.
What is it?
Internal Division Secret
Security.
Well, that is.
Receive direct orders
President of the Republic.
The head of the DISS
Gazmán is fine.
- Did you know?
- No, not really.
No, I wanted to move there
six months ago and I refused.
Well, there it is. Have mobile
crime and the offender.
Before we need
evidence.
How about this?
The images are not
sufficient.
Something is necessary
the mind.
- What are you doing?
- Reflection.
I do not like when
thinking.
- We must go to the office of Walter.
- That I feared.
- Where is it?
- First floor, room 17.
Do we do the former?
Okay, the old one.
Can not be discreet
like me?
You do not mind being discreet.
And now what are you doing?
I'm thinking.
There they are!
I say that I do not like.
Do you have any idea?
I will entertain you and
go to the office of Walter.
Remember, first floor
in room 17.
Bring anything
that can serve as evidence.
Are we seeing again?
I do not think I move
far from here, quick, go!
Now you'll see!
If you stay well, without saying anything,
no nothing will happen.
You have my word, okay?
What is the computer
Mr. Garzo?
Do not know
password?
Good morning, some of you
have a computer...
...that one moved?
Yes, me.
Service, it is I who
you install the new server.
I regret causing inconvenience.
I found it.
Thanks, gentlemen.
Damiano.
It is more reasonable and let
justice address your problem.
I did nothing,
and you know it well.
Yes, I know. Prisons are
full of innocent people.
However, the farms.
Well, do we?
What I do for you.
I already pay.
Do not go!
Shit!
We can still walk, no?
Put the belt.
- What are you doing?
- Well, go ahead.
Sorry.
I listen.
- Damian escaped.
- How to be escaped?
Letto what came to seek.
He came to look for
and escaped.
Can you explain
how they escaped?
Go to your office.
What do we do?
Do we pursue?
No, too, the military
are everywhere.
More attentive
anyway.
Understood.
Follow the instructions
that he was given.
And where you lead us well?
There is always a watchful
about the law.
Yes, that I was you
promised to change.
There will always be a fool
like you to apply.
They are laws which are bad,
are the people that deliver them.
Yeah, like religion.
Incidentally, what's yours?
I was baptized when he was a boy,
but my only goal...
now...
is the civil code.
What?
My only goal now
is the civil code.
You're worse than a Mormon.
Well, do we or do we
were to give us?
We're going.
- What do you want?
- Talking with Tao.
About what?
About the sector
and its inhabitants.
Are you kidding.
Business.
Let them pass.
What are you doing here?
They stole a team
national protection.
Are good.
Well?
They will, provided we
get some things that interest us.
And what is this?
A little catechism.
You've always lived here
in sector 13.
Where do you think will live
when you destroy?
We must avoid that.
ANIEL, get that.
That's it.
Is open.
- They are everywhere.
- Everywhere.
Where did you learn that?
Well, in books.
Come on, do it.
That interests me.
- We are now on Iran.
- I too am interested.
Here it is, sector 13.
These are the goals,
five towers.
There must be something else.
Walter manages to
is angry with you.
The President ordered their destruction
and build everything new.
- As in Iraq.
- Yes
But now
the French.
And how will destroy
towers?
In position.
Three helicopters.
They are up there.
Shoot them with lasers.
That sent the missiles.
How?
Probably do
from a command post.
Only the President can
have given an order like that.
And what do
to prevent it?
Go read the manual.
Because your head voice...
...starts to sweat
a little.
Bothers you because I do some
Ambivilent, is it?
I apologize.
If you call "lechuguita"
Does this do you prefer?
- What if you call me by my name?
- Okay.
What is your name?
Damien Tomaso, commander
French army.
A police
if preferred.
Now I believe I should
forget prejudices...
...and let us hand.
Tao delighted.
Alike.
Now, what is your plan,
lechuguita?
- Thanks for coming.
- What is it?
You explain.
Hello.
Is there.
Alika, guns.
March specialist
in machetes.
Carlos Skin,
specialist cars.
Montana pumps.
Sorry.
Think you can
take place?
Yes, not lose the opportunity
to show their skills.
Gentlemen.
Thanks to all
to come.
For 19 hours,
Sector 13 was evacuated.
Their intention is to fly around.
If you are in need,
I have everything they need.
The idea is to avoid it.
Who is in favor?
Well, you pass the word a...
Damien who...
will explain his plan.
We all have to agree
in the five hours we have left.
Then I need
of about thirty men.
Trained in combat,
and care nothing about weapons.
We will not hunt.
We broke in silence
the neutralized...
...and let live
center operations.
Questions?
Where is
the command post?
Here, in the Paris.
Over here, Mr. President.
Strengthen security
around the building.
Go to the signal.
Remain in the air,
Over and out.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Sit down.
So, General,
Where are we?
The order is Jaguards
flying over the targets.
Talked about the evacuation,
rather than destruction.
It is a priority, right?
Yes, sir.
Sir.
We evacuated 1087310
people in less than two hours...
...but there are persons who
We have not approached.
It all
located here.
We have tried
and there is already injured.
This could be delayed.
How many people do not
have been evacuated yet?
Long time no
a census is done in that neighborhood...
...but I think
a few thousand.
Those few, are many.
Continue the evacuation.
- We are sent here.
- To us too!
Okay.
Turn both keys
at once.
Five missiles, all will
at the same time.
To tell you the truth,
Gentlemen...
...I do not feel very well
with all this.
- Can I give you some advice?
- Please.
I know that guy
men.
They do not respect anything, not to
people and to the laws.
Just kill and steal
for their benefit.
And you are not
responsible.
They were there before
their arrival.
And what can be
do with them?
Are you?
No.
Believe me, to get rid of them,
must be exterminated.
¡Warning!
Mr. Gazmán, find your
cynicism, in terror.
No, Mr. President, just
I am being pragmatic.
One of the causes of our
recession is the parallel economy...
...with these guys that make you lose
million at the box state.
With destruction
like that...
...we can build a site
we make money again.
So we are rid of this scourge
and we can build something more.
Destroy to build,
Is that your solution?
In any case,
what comes to mind.
Here.
General.
Do the helicopter assault
already in the air?
Yeah.
Landing.
Do not get this key
in the lock...
...until it is satisfied that there is no
civil strife in that neighborhood.
- Understand?
- Well, sir.
My General, a banda
entered the building.
Well, neutralícela.
They are unarmed,
but many.
To continue, I occupy.
Go see what happens.
Come, dear.
Montana, said that
no injuries.
It is only
my personal safety.
What?
Do not worry, the building
is heavily equipped.
Calm down.
This is mine.
So?
How prefer?
Listen, you...
The rules are
adhered to.
But not with guys like you.
We love to know
to guys like you.
And these orejitas?
You okay?
No answer.
Te llamo.
Mr. President, I inform you that any
the sector is completely evacuated.
I do not understand, one hour ago
risked...
...you can not evacuate
those thousands.
I do not know, maybe the message
had not come either.
Anyway, everything is
vacuum, we guarantee it.
In that case.
Get in position.
Received signal,
attack in a minute.
Are in position,
Sir.
Do not move!
Come on!
We say that...!
This is the hand you get
in the throat if you do not shut up, okay?
Gentlemen, I am the President
of the Republic.
- On the television.
- I've seen on the Internet.
Captain Tomaso,
Can you explain?
The images speak higher
that the words, Mr. President.
- Shoot, shoot.
- And what is that?
I do not know,
but still rolling.
Shit!
What is that?
The DISS in action.
The police wanted
discredit the sector...
...to destroy everything
and then build.
It sure will
a commission for that.
If the images
do not meet...
...behold the disk of
special operations of DISS.
Is it not true, Walter?
We have sent
vacation.
Nobody move!
What are you doing?
Remove the key.
Fast.
Come on!
Remove the key.
Get the key,
do what I say!
What?
I think there will be
new elections.
Come on, let the
artifices, ¡the key!
¡Tomaso not move!
If you move, kill it.
Come on, turn it
I tell you the key!
¡Signal received!
Done!
Come on.
Pare, Gazmán,
not going anywhere.
A soldier goes to
the end of their mission.
Even if that
it costs life.
That is called honor.
It is a notion that it is
strange in their neighborhoods, right?
Yes, it is true, we prefer
another concept: the family.
Which unites us
between us.
Which protects us.
Which we believe.
Yes, will be joining.
I am going to mourn.
And die together.
Come on, just fuck!
And you, where are you?
Calm down, I just a... go, was
surely there would be a snuff.
Leave it.
Tomaso ¡!
For my collection.
This is a good wallpaper,
Sir.
A gift.
Gentlemen.
Miss, excuse me.
I do not know what to say.
Thank you, thank you very much.
I owe much.
I think the whole france
owes much.
Well, I guess you do not believe
much to the politicians but...
I assure you that...
the next 48 hours...
...I will do whatever it can to
unlock the previous laws...
...for your sector
back to...
...all his dignity and a place
prominent in our society.
Thank you.
- I have a question, Mr. President.
- Tell me.
Instead of spending a fortune
hiding the rotten...
...Why not
start again?
What do you mean?
A real neighborhood.
A real city.
With green
and places to work.
I agree.
Damian, appointed him responsible
this project through to implementation.
Well, Mr. President.
You have my word, and
as the word of my government.
And the word of man?
And my word of man.
Sir?
- It's OK for me.
- Me too.
Too.
Clear.
Yes
Well.
Well, that's better
que las mías.
Everything is for the better.
BluRay ripped by TSTeam
Visit us @ www. tugashare. net