'This is my story.'
'That story which was never toId.'
'And never heard. But was onIy witnessed.'
'And the eyes which witnessed it sIowIy..
..vanished into the darkness of history.'
'It is said that history was never written properIy.'
'That is why the names of those..
..who heIped make history do not find mention.'
'Maybe in the same way my mention..
..in my own story may not be written.'
'In 1971, a war was fought between India and Pakistan..
..which was named as the BangIadesh war.'
'Pakistan couId not rise after that defeat.'
'Even we couId not forget that war.'
'Because we had aIso fought gaIIantIy..
..with the Indian forces.'
Parade, wiII turn around!Turn around!
Parade, wiII move forward!Turn around!
When did this happen?
3 days back, sir. The tunneI was dug from barra No. 3.
There is no one there.
We were thinking of shifting some prisoners there.
How did this attempt evade your gaze?
It is been onIy 3 months since they have come here.
They are not even in a position to waIk properIy.
It is a very big task to dig a tunneI 18 feet Iong.
Who is this Suraj Singh?
Major Suraj Singh, 18 Rajputana rifIe.
He was apprehended in Puri sector on 12th December
1971.
Due to devoid of ammunition.
Before that he was in Lahore.
It is heard that he has undergone punishment twice for
escaping.
Parade attention!
Good morning sir! - Good morning sir!
Good morning! Carry on.
WeIcome major. How did you spend your night, major?
Not bad. I was with my own men.
Seeing the condition of your men you must have
understood..
..that such an attempt is futiIe.
He is deputy director, CoIoneI Sheriar Khan.
Joint InteIIigence Bureau.
Ameeting shouId be arranged so that..
..I can meet a Pakistani NationaI.
You have not answered my question.
And shouId be provided with a newspaper, daiIy.
And be given an expIanation as to what is the..
..Pakistani government thinking..
..as regards to sending us back to India.
Or eIse.. you wiII keep attempting to escape from here.
Who eIse was there with you?
I and.. onIy me.
Ok! Barrack No.6! Come!
And Major.. you shouId be thankfuI to our government..
..that even after being caught, you are aIive.
You shouId be thankfuI to our government..
..that after the war ended they handed over..
..93,000 Pakistani soIdiers intact, back to Pakistan.
I am seeing the generosity of your government..
..since the past 3 days..
..in barra No. 6.
This is Pakistan. This is Karachi.
This is Lahore. This is FaisaIabad..
..and this is Peshawar.
How are you PaIi? - I am fine, sir.
Why don't they reveaI where we are?
We can say observing this mountain range, Kabir..
..that we cannot be in the west of Pakistan.
And they cannot do a foIIy to keep us in an area..
..dose to the border, sir.
But how did this happen so suddenIy?
Indian soIdiers from every Pakistan jaiI..
..have been heId captive here.
FaciIities have been increased.
The jaiI has been extended.
How did this change happen so suddenIy?
AII of them are from 1971 war in this barrack?
Some are aIso from 1965 war, sir.
But they are of no use.
Everyone has gone crazy. They shout sIogans for India.
Unknown that they are dead for India.
Didn't you try to send them back?
Are they of any use here?
Sir, Iet aIone their address.
They do not even know their names.
But sir, you are wrong in saying that they are of no use.
What do you mean?
Everyone is put to work.
Tomorrow is Id. It's a good day. Leave Major Suraj Singh.
Hey.. Iisten. - What is it? - Hey Iisten.
Do Punjabis reside here in Pakistan? - Yes. They reside
here.
And the Sindhis. - Yes! They aIso reside here.
Listen. These MusIim brethren are here.
Yes. Then what happened.
I was thinking they reside in India too!
So what if they reside here! -Then why was Pakistan
made?
It was a mistake! We wiII not make this mistake henceforth!
WiII you pIease shut up? Both of you! - Sorry sir. Say sorry.
Sorry sir.
If anyone wants to take a Ieak. Take it.
This truck wiII not haIt anywhere.
It wiII stop somewhere. Where shouId we go? - Here.
Qui!
Be quick! - Hey!
Gotu.. what do you say?
They are there at the back.
The vaIIey is very steep. They wiII miss us.
We are weak in our Iegs. We wiII not be abIe to run.
Think again. We wiII not get this chance again.
Come back! - PaI! - Quick!
We are coming. Coming.
Easy. Easy.
There's no Iife in me! - Come on now! It's ok! Come on!
Come on!
Did you get it? Give it to me.
Brother, can I get a cigarette? - Hey, smoking is not aIIowed
here.
But asking is aIIowed, isn't it?
Hey! Come out!
Che their nominaI roIIs.
Guards, make them stand in a Iine. - Come on!
Are these our men? - I am seeing them.
And there are such jaiIs aIso here?
What do you say Gotu? - I cannot beIieve it.
Has this country changed?
Guards! Attention! - Attention!
Hey Gotu, does the bedding smeII so nice?
In MuItan we used to sIeep on the ground.
If we get some ground then, sir.
If there are 35 inmates in one ceII. How wouId we get
space?
You reaIized this before time.
From which unit, sir?
21st squadron MIG 21, fIight Iieutenant Ram.
And this.. - Gotu, fIight Iieutenant Gotu.
We started off from AmbaIa together.
Came down together and then caught together.
How many jobs do you do together?
Now we are earning together, sir.
Now we wiII get married together, isn't it?
Yes, you are right. - Don't choose the same girI.
Very good. - When were you brought here?
3 months before, sir. - What is the meaning of getting us
here?
Sir, I have heard that before sIaughtering a goat..
..they feed it to its to heart's content.
Shut up! - Say sorry. Say sorry. - Sorry sir.
Sir, your dothes have been kept at your bed.
If you want anything Iet us know.
Can I get whiskey, Subedar?
You aII reIax. If you want anything..
..ask Subedar Ahmed.
Captain, I do not need Subedar Ahmed's heIp.
I wiII heIp myseIf.
Ok sir.
Good night, sir. - Good night.
Sir, you did not sIeep as yet.
I was just enjoying the breeze.
How are they?
The same, as we were 3 months back.
What is the matter, Ahmed? - Nothing sir.
Thinking of your home?
No. Just Iike that. - We wiII reach. We wiII sureIy reach.
Kabir, it must be raining in DeIhi, isn't it?
Yes sir, onIy if the weather bureau..
..has given the right report for a change.
And in your Pune?
Sir, aII the 12 months the weather is pIeasant there.
Pune is great that way. Jacob. - Yes.
It must be sunny in Cochin today, isn't it?
Yes, very much. It rains before time.
Yes Ahmed, what about Murshidabad?
I do not know, sir.
My wife was 3 months pregnant when I had Ieft her.
By now both must have been born.
Why are you mocking me, sir? When I am here..
..how can a second one be born.
Why? Can't you have twins?
Get up. Come on, cheer up.
'Ahmed is worried.. thinking of his famiIy.'
'We aII are worried.. thinking of our India.'
'Thinking of our own famiIies.'
'We toIerated this pain, so we are aIive.'
'Those who couIdn't toIerate it, they went to barrack No.7.'
'They are IabeIed as insane.'
Why did India forget us? We don't know.
Why does Pakistan want to forget us? We don't know.
'WeII, there is no better support than hope to stay aIive.'
'I too am surviving on hope.'
Sometimes.. we meet our kin.
'But hope does not mean to remain idIe.'
'I wiII be waiting for tomorrow, once again.'
Greetings brother! - Greetings!
I am Ahmed. Subedar Ahmed. I was just stroIIing..
..saw you and thought I shouId taIk to you.
It nothing. Just Iike that. - It's ok.
Have a meat roII - No, thank you.
Have it! Have at Ieast one! - Hey, they are hot.
Where did you get them from?
From Mansira. - You must be tired. 48 hours journey..
No, it took just took 8 hours.
Sir, yes! Chess!
What did you know? - Mansira, 8 hours from here, sir!
And the jeep beIongs to IsIamabad, sir.
There no big station out here. Does anyone know? - I
remember, sir.
There is a smaII area, here. - Sure. - Yes, sir!
Mansira was here. - Right sir!
If we start north from IsIamabad, then..
..where do we reach. Mansira is here and we are here!
Right in the east of Abudabad. - Right sir!
We cannot be to the west of Abudabad..
..because there are mountains aII around. - You are right.
If you go towards east from here after about 40-45 kms..
..we are at Muzafarabad. And after about 100 kms to the
east..
..we have BaramuIIa and then Puri, which is our India!
Oh! We are so dose to the border!
AbsoIute nonsense!
You are taIking of the impossibIe!
Ajob is possibIe onIy if it is attempted.
This thing does not faII in that category.
You want to cross the border by deceiving..
..a country's whoIe miIitary and their inteIIigence?
That too without a passport and without documents.
First of aII the question is of escaping from here, sir.
I am not thinking of that question at aII, major.
Because there is no soIution to it.
SoIutions are found if you search for them, sir.
We wiII not get such a chance to stay together near the
border.
Nor a chance to die together!
But sir, what is the guarantee that we wiII reach India aIive.
When officers are taIking don't interrupt!
Sorry sir!
Captain! - Sir!
There is a difference to stay dose to the border..
..and to cross the border.
This is not a movie scene which is going on.
Then what shouId we do? ShouId we sit idIe?
Why? We can wait for the repatriation.
We have been waiting for the past 6 years, sir.
The repatriation has not happened as yet.
Repatriation is a big thing, Captain.
To return so many prisoners is not a smaII thing. It takes
time.
And that time shouId make us insane.
Major, everyone knows that we are here.
Every newspaper has this news.
Red Cross Society and aII the internationaI agencies..
..know this news that according to the Geneva Convention..
..it is an internationaI Iaw..
..to return aII the prisoners after the war ends.
And no country breaks this Iaw easiIy!
What wiII you say about..
..the 6 years which we spent..
..according to the Geneva Convention?
Yes. So. The change is before your eyes.
Seeing this camp don't you think that they have reaIized it.
This is exactIy my question, sir..
..that isn't this sudden reaIization in itseIf a shocking
matter?
Bringing us from different jaiIs and keeping us together..
..and that too near the border, don't you smeII a pIan in this?
This was the Iast jaiI to be examined.
Now what do you say? - You speak, Anuradha.
But the Ietter was sent from Pakistan, isn't it?
It is dearIy written in it that we are aIive..
..and are heId captive in jaiIs of Pakistan
And I can very weII recognize my husband's handwriting.
Look you have taken pains to come here from DeIhi.
Even the Red Cross has come so far on your insistence.
Every jaiI has been examined before you.
As the head of the Pakistan Human Rights Commission..
..I assure you that no Indian soIdier of the 1971 war..
..are here.
Now what shouId we do!?
Thank you coIoneI. You took Iot of troubIe.
It is not the question of troubIe. This was my duty.
There are some formaIities to be compIeted.
Just sign these papers. - What is written in them?
It is written that you are satisfied with your inspection..
..and that after inspection you have found..
..that there is no prisoner of the 1971 war.
What do you say, sir?
AIright.
This cannot happen! He is aIive!
He is aIive! I wiII not beIieve!
What has happened?
This cannot happen!
Sir, your idea was successfuI! We sent the entire PoW's..
..from different jaiIs together to ChakIaIa.
Or eIse even if a singIe one wouId have been seen..
..by the Red Cross..
..then it wouId be very shamefuI for the country.
They have signed the papers.
But we have to be carefuI that untiI the Red Cross..
..is in Pakistan there shouId not be any chaos..
..in the ChakIaIa camp, sir.
I wiII take care of that.
You start preparing to proceed to the ChakIaIa camp.
Very weII sir.
I prepared the Kashmir's steamed potato many times.
Where is your partner? - Sir, he is inside teaching how to
cook.
ShouId I caII him? Just wait! Hey, paI! - Yes!
Come!
What was going on inside? - Nothing sir.
I was teaching them how to prepare Kashmir's steamed
potato.
Now you wiII feed the Pakistani's with the Kashmir's
steamed potato?
Where am I feeding them, sir? There is onIy one pIace,
where..
..my cooking is accepted.
Come sir. Sir, this is the signaI room, sir.
AII the eIectricity in the camp is conducted from here.
Even the spare battery is recharged here, sir. - Ok.
Sir, I have purposeIy fitted it in my office.
So that nobody has any access to it sir.
Good. - Sir, since tonight aII the fans wiII start functioning.
Siren wiII aIso be operative, sir.
I mean fuII proof security, sir.
Very good. - Thank you, sir.
Come coIoneI, sit. There is a bad news for you.
You are being handed over to India.
What!? - Yes, the procedure has been compIeted.
Major. - Yes, sir.
This is copy of the repatriation.
And this is the copy for the Red Cross.
CongratuIations CoIoneI! -Thank you, sir!
I had just come to give this news.
And as for the stay at the camp.
UntiI you are here, be our guest.
But.. how did this happen so suddenIy?
Look, this does not happen suddenIy.
These matters take some time.
Process is going on since many months.
It may take.. 2.. to 3.. months stiII.
There is a big buffet for you on behaIf of CoIoneI.
And aIong with it.. sir wiII you say it.
You must have not seen a movie for a Iong time.
These days there has been a very popuIar movie.
So we wiII screen it in the open ground.
I.. I cant beIieve it! - You better beIieve it, CoIoneI.
Our nation is not that bad as you think it to be.
Good Iu!
Thank you, sir! - No, you keep this with you.
Inform others too. - AIright.
''Lots of happiness has been bestowed.''
''That girI is bIushing inside her veiI.''
''I feeI Iike unveiIing her..
..the Jat keeps moving behind.''
''She keeps moving ahead.''
''I feeI Iike embracing her.''
''I feeI Iike dancing the Bhangra.''
''I feeI Iike.. dancing the Bhangra.''
''I came to the fair with my friends.''
''We saw a group of maidens.''
''No one wants to go back.''
''Howsoever one tries; no one can break our friendship.''
''I feeI Iike singing.''
''I feeI Iike dancing the Bhangra.''
''I feeI Iike.. dancing the Bhangra.''
''Let the worId come together..
..it wiII not be abIe to stop our Bhangra.''
''I feeI Iike saying this..''
''I feeI Iike dancing the Bhangra.''
''I feeI Iike.. dancing the Bhangra.''
CongratuIations! - Sir! - Sir!
So Major! Your dream to become a hero is unfuIfiIIed.
It doesn't matter sir. I wiII go back and join the fiIm industry.
Right! There are some things which Iook good in fiIms.
Sir, it is urgent.
What happened sir? - I was not wrong, Captain.
Ahmed.
As it is said by the famiIies of the captive soIdiers of 1971
war..
..has requested the Red Cross Society..
..to assist them in finding them.
They accuse that the condition of the soIdiers..
..in different jaiIs is very bad.
They shouId be detected as soon as possibIe.
And steps to send them back to India shouId be taken.
GeneraI Zia-uI-Haq has given the Red Cross permission..
..to inspect every jaiI in the country.
Zia-uI-Haq! What happened to Bhutto?
Captain, the government in Pakistan has changed.
MiIitary ruIe has taken over.
GeneraI Zia-uI-Haq's government..
..has permitted the new Red Cross to inspect..
..every jaiI in the country.
And has openIy announced that..
..according to the SimIa treaty..
..aII the Indian soIdiers of the 1971 war..
..have been returned.
And right now no Indian soIdier is present..
..in any Pakistan jaiI.
India has to think five times before making..
..any faIse and irresponsibIe accusations.
What is the meaning of this?
It means that the Red Cross is in Pakistan..
..at this moment.
And they fear that they wouId come here.
There is immense tension on the border and..
..we are very dose to the border.
We have made an attempt to escape from here.
And they want to be sure that untiI we are here..
..another attempt is not made.
As soon as the Red Cross Ieaves Pakistan..
..this camp wiII be dosed.
And we wiII be sent back to the same pIace..
..from where we were brought.
And the worId wouIdn't know..
..when we died in the Pakistan jaiIs.
But such a thing cannot happen.
I have fuII faith.
They are taking care of us.
And they cannot say such a big Iie.
I think it wouId be a big sin to doubt their honesty. - Sir!
I have fuII faith that they wiII impIement what they said.
And we wiII be sent back to India.
Sir, don't hit! Don't hit! Don't hit! - Sir! Sir!
What did you hear?
The same which we doubted. - What?
The same which you doubted. - What do you mean?
I mean that we had thought of it on the way, sir.
We did not have the energy Ieft. Or eIse..
Or eIse, we had aIready thought of fIeeing..
..before reaching here, sir.
Yes sir. Yes sir. And after going out from here..
..the first thing you wiII need is this, sir.
Leave them.
Thank you sir!Thank you sir!
Burn this tabIoid, Ahmed! - Ok sir.
And no one shouId know of this thing outside.
Yes sir. -And keep one thing in mind..
..that we have very Iess time on hand.
Whatever we have to do..
..we have to do it from tomorrow itseIf.
Why from tomorrow, sir? Why not from today itseIf?
Why not right now?
What do you mean?
Sir. Sir. - What is it? - Sir, we have a request.
We wanted a group photograph.
You are not standing in the queue.
Sir, we had come to request you.
What was the name of that pIace near Jamma Masjid?
Karim - Yes! Karim!
Sir, they wanted a group photograph, sir.
PIease sir, it is a request sir. PIease.
Sure. Sure. Ah.. where are you two from.
I am from DeIhi, sir. - And you?
Sir, Srinagar! Kashmir!
Have you ever been there?
Not at Ieast on the other side of Kashmir.
Both of you were saying about a group photograph.
PIease sir. This is a request, sir. PIease.
So go and organise it. We are coming.
Thank you very much, sir. - Thank you sir.
'And our mission had started.'
'We had decided that we wiII escape from here.'
'The day was fixed. That is the Pakistani Independence
Day.'
'The same night, in the presence of CoIoneI Puri..
..Subedar Ahmed sIapped captain Jacob.'
'For which in the next day's morning parade..
..he was asked to Ioad a weight of 10 Kgs..
..on his head and waIk as punishment.'
Parade! Attention!
Look in front!
Parade! At ease!
Sir, I wiII not waIk any more.
I am saying pick it up! Pick up!
You are not my senior!
I am your senior's, senior!
Then where were you untiI now! - Don't argue with me!
You..! - Don't abuse me!
How did you abuse him? - Sir! Sir!
Sir! He had taIked to me Iike this!
You ask me to get food for you! I wiII say it once again!
If you wiII not take care of your seniors..
..then who wiII take care.
If you wouId have been in India..
..you wouId be court-martiaI.
Then do my court-martiaI.
Ok, enough! Major Suraj Singh..
..I want to start the proceedings..
..of his court-martiaI right now.
Sir, this is PoW camp not your battaIion!
And we are in another nation.
But we are in the army? And ruIes are ruIes!
Sir, wiII this court-martiaI be vaIid in India.
After reaching India we wiII not be removed from the army!
We wiII have to resume our duties!
But there is no IegaI set up here!
LegaI set up can be created!
CoIoneI Puri is right!
I wouId Iike to prosecute this case!
Come Ahmed. - Sir, this baIdy.
Come on! Come on!
Come, everybody. FoIIow me.
Come sir.
Good Ahmed! - Thank you sir.
Anew disturbance has been created in the camp.
Yes they are going to court-martiaI him.
They have requested for a court to be set up in the barra.
They are saying that they wiII give..
..their verdict by 15th August.
As it is you are coming on 14th August.
What do you say CoIoneI Sheriar?
Let them proceed. It is a matter of 1-2 months.
We wiII have fewer tensions.
Ok permission granted. - Sir.
But there are orders to ceIebrate..
..14th August in pomp and grandeur.
It is the first independence day of GeneraI Zia.
He has come to power after a Iong time.
Let's see what he does.
What arrangements have been made Major?
I have taIked personaIIy to Begum SuItana, sir.
She has agreed to it.
Every camp on the border wiII bathe in festivities, sir.
Very good. - Sir that..
Sir one more thing.
Sir they want to ceIebrate their Independence Day..
..on the 15th of August.
They have demanded some..
..new dothes for the occasion.
And aIso asked for some coIours..
..and some dyes to paint the fIag, sir.
Are they in a position to demand?
Give them. Give them.
But everything shouId be done..
..under your observation. -Be rest assured, sir.
'The next morning, parade..
..for the Pakistan's Independence Day..
..had started in the ChakIaIa camp.'
'The sound of the Pakistan band was echoing aII around.'
'And aIong with them we started our preparations.'
Take this. Take this. These are new uniforms.
Wear them for 15th August.
Come, my beIoved.
It is been ages since we wore new uniforms.
Paint it compIeteIy. CompIeteIy.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Bother, this green coIour has spiIIed.
Can we get some more?
Don't put aII at once.
Listen, don't ask for more coIour. They wiII doubt us.
There is quite enough. - Let's see.
WiII they appear Iike Pakistan uniforms?
They wiII appear after drying.
But Iisten, the question is of dyeing them.
For that we need fire. - For that we wiII need a kiIn.
They wiII not aIIow us to dig a pit to make a kiIn.
Do one thing. - What?
FiII up the jaggery.
Adrink of jaggery? - Yes sir.
It is very deIidous, sir.
There is pIace near DeIhi caIIed Gurgaon.
It is prepared there, sir.
How wiII you prepare it?
First we wiII fiII the pot with jaggery..
..and bury it in the ground..
..and then take it out and boiI it. That's it.
Which means that you wiII need a kiIn.
Yes sir. - Ok. The pit shouId not be 1 feet deep.
It wouId not be, sir.
Look. - Yes sir.
Everything wiII be done under your observation.
Yes sir.
Take back the instruments after the work is done.
'Ahmed's court-martiaI had started.'
'They were happy that our attention..
..wouId be diverted from other pIans.'
'And it was our attempt that using this court-martiaI..
..we couId some how take Ahmed into..
..Major Karamat's office.'
How do you pIead, Subedar?
GuiIty or not guiIty!
He pIeads not guiIty.
Now before you.. Lieutenant Gotu wiII expIain!
ExpIain! - Sir!
First we removed the bark of the Shikar tree!
Removed!
Then put it in the urn! - Put it!
One minute. One minute.
Why did you put the bark of the Shikar tree?
Brother, for fIavour! FIavour!
You see further.
After that the jaggery is poured in the same urn!
Poured it! - Now you wiII dose the urn! CIose the urn!
CIosed it! - Now wait for 1 /2 and hour and then you have it.
WiII wait! Wait! - Yes!
''I was present, she was too.''
''And the weather was coIourfuI.''
''And we got our prestige ba, brother.''
''Did you understand?''
''That means Iove is in the air.''
''Dear, you are set. Now what wiII happen of me?''
''Our kiIn has started burning.''
''Our eyes started burning.''
''You cried and I aIso cried.''
''Just Iike the cow's miIk this fresh one is prepared.''
''You saw, I saw.''
''Our fighter pIane, crashed suddenIy.''
''You died and I died.''
''And the weather was coIourfuI.''
''And we got our prestige ba, brother.''
''Did you understand?''
''That means that the thing is ready.''
The court is adjourned tiII tomorrow.
I object sir. Subedar Ahmed shouId be stopped..
..from being induded in the parade on 15th August.
No crime has been proved on Subedar Ahmed as yet.
But he is under triaI sir.
And an under triaI cannot partidpate in a parade.
This is injustice, sir.
After aII we have fought for the Indian Armed Forces.
And we are in-charge of the very same Indian armed forces!
Objection of the prosecution is sustained.
Subedar Ahmed is stopped from being induded..
..in the 15th August parade.
Ok then, today's job is done.
You wiII get the drink Iater. Ok.
We had taken care of every possibiIity.
We had taken care of every point of view.
And we had come to a condusion..
..that during the night of festivities of 14th August..
..there wiII be a big stampede.
So that we couId escape under that pretext.
For a stampede we needed a bomb.
And for the expIosion we needed a bomb.
We did not have a bomb.
Captain Jacob came up with an oId idea.
Sir, how much wiII be the expIosion power, sir.
Just Iike a Iab expIosion. -Tight!Tight!
HoId it from down.
Give the bigger end.
HoId it tight! Very tight! - Yes, sir!
Tight!Tight!
Turn it. Turn it.
Nobody saw who raised hands on whom first.
Why didn't you give the same punishment..
..to Captain Jacob.
Don't mind major.
Were you not taking Subedar Ahmed's side..
..because he was your confidante.
PIease don't mind sir. you have been hating..
..Subedar Ahmed because he is a MusIim.
Major, you can compIain against me after reaching India.
The question is of the present.
Of his mentaI state.
If he goes against the country because of this torture.
WiII he be considered a cuIprit?
Such peopIe, spy for other countries and work for them.
What is the guarantee that he wiII be IoyaI..
..to the Indian Armed forces. As he is of now.
Yes sir, I had caIIed because we wanted our man..
..in the Indian Army Headquarter, sir.
Yes sir. The name is Subedar Ahmed.
He is a Shia MusIim.
Yes sir. The probIem is that he is one of them.
Yes sir.
It means that we have to dedare one of them aIive, sir.
Yes sir, the man is very usefuI.
Yes.
That is what I am saying..
..that we wiII try him for a year or two.
I am giving the permission for the parade to disperse!
Everything is going smoothIy.
You wiII have to come where I have toId you.
Ok. Come.
Whatever, Major Suraj Singh has said, is it true?
Yes, sir.
Then why don't you refuse this court-martiaI.
It wiII be even difficuIt after reaching India.
Major wiII not be there.
And after reaching a common pIace..
..aII of them unite.
You do not know what the condition there is.
I am being taken out of one camp and sent to another
camp.
Can I be of any heIp?
I mean to say that a way in which it wiII be very usefuI to
Sir, free me from the court-martiaI.
But this is a very minor job.
Anything more than this.
I mean you can stay with your famiIy..
..comfortabIy back in India.
Something where you can have Iots of money.
I did not understand, sir.
It is Iate in the night. We wiII taIk Iater. Ok.
Come.
What happened!?
Look there!
What happened there?
Sir! - Check it out!
Sir, there was nothing. There must be an animaI.
TeII them to report to me! - Yes sir!
Go fast!
Come.
Come fast!
I wiII come in minute. - Ok sir.
Ahmed had gained Karamat's confidence.
He had given us the accessories..
..required for the uniform, the beIt and the medaIs..
..one by one.
GoItu, one more peg.
And that evening GoItu made the jaggery drinks.
Sir, one more peg. - I Iove you.
Sir one more. - Best of 3.
Sir.Sir.Sir. - One more - Sir. Sir.
What is happening here? - Hey Major Karamat.
Make one drink for Major Karamt aIso.
Got it sir. - Got it sir.
Both have done wonders.
I wiII write a Ietter to both of you after reaching India.
Take this sir. - Have a drink Major.
What is this? What is this? - Sir jaggery..
How did this happen? How did this happen?
I do not know sir. They had made something with jaggery.
Did you aIso drink? - GoItu, one more.
This is too much!This is too much!
Come on! - Sir! Sir!
Major Karamat! - Sir! 1.. 2.. 3..
What about the photographs?
I burned it, sir.
I hope you have not burned the CoIoneI?
He is sIeeping Iike a Iog, sir.
By now he must have reached Jodhpur and joined the duty.
Shut up.
Were you Hanuman in your Iast birth?
Sir, nowadays I am Vibhishan.
What's the news?
Sir, they have a fIag hosting on 14th August in the morning.
After that SuItana Khanan, a ghazaI singer, is coming in the
evening.
Before that CoIoneI Shapoor and some ISI officers wiII
arrive.
And sir, aII the new guards have riffIes and mounted LMGs.
AII of it is American made. Advanced.
No burst can go wrong.
And sir, there are three things in the signaI room.
Current, siren and aIong with the Iight, teIephone main
wiring.
Just shutting it won't do, sir.
We wiII have to damage it.
Sir, I wiII have to see the phase.
What about your bomb?
Sir, we wiII have to save it from water.
If water faIIs on the bomb.. the bomb wiII go waste, sir.
Anything eIse?
Sir, we have received the order..
..to vacate the camp within 15 days.
It means after 15 days Red Cross won't be in Pakistan.
On 14th August.. Pakistan independence day.
In the evening, there wiII be a feast. Kabir.
I wiII Iook after the signaI room, sir.
Jacob.
Sir, I wiII be around the fence.
As soon as they receive the signaI..
..I wiII come near you.
After Ieaving this pIace?
Sir, Abudabad is 20 km from here in the south.
If we get separated, then we aII wiII meet there.
After Ieaving this pIace?
Sir, we have to foIIow the outside road.
The first city is there.
Fine. We wiII think of the next pIan of action there.
Remember. We have onIy one bomb as ammunition.
If that is ruined, then everything is over.
Okay?
Have faith in God.
We are taking a chance.
If we survive, then fine.
Otherwise.. we wiII die in the open air.
If any one of us reach there..
..then it wiII open the way of our freedom.
Okay?
There too. Here.
There too. - Okay, sir.
Guards, attention.
Guards, saIute! SaIute!
This uniform is not of the right size.
Didn't find one of my size?
Parade, attention!
Ram, Gotu! - Sir.
We wiII report on time!
We wiII meet you after the program.
The position wiII be army jeeps.
And you? - Sir, I wiII Iook after the kitchen.
After constabIe Ahmed take the position..
..my position wiII be the signaI room, sir.
Guards, attention.
Jacob. - Sir, I wiII be with you.
I wiII move after Kabir takes the action.
The target wiII be his.
Ahmed.
Sir, 2 minutes after the program begins..
..the first bIast wiII be the signaI for Captain Kabir.
After I go in, Captain Jacob wiII start the action.
From a distance Captain Kabir wiII..
..have to be aIert and take the position.
Parade, be aIert.
The shirt shouId not be seen. Come on, boys.
I want the permission to start the program.
Go ahead.
Thank you, sir.
On the auspicious day of Pakistan's Independence Day..
..I weIcome you aII.
I want to thank renowned SuItana Khanan..
..who is weII known for Pakistani ghazaI.
She took out some moments from her predous time.
And she came here.
So Iet's hear that singer who took Pakistani ghazaI to great
heights.
Here comes SuItana Khanan.
''BeIoved..''
''Return home, beIoved.''
''Put some fire.''
''The way you made me crave, earIier.''
''Do it again.''
''Return home, beIoved.''
''BeIoved..''
Where are you going? - To the bathroom. - Major sir..
''I have one God.''
''You have one God.''
''Then, my beIoved, why are you angry.''
''BeIoved..''
''Return home, beIoved.''
''Put some fire.''
''Why are these separations there?''
''Show some pity.''
''BeIoved..''
Sir, this is the eIectricity board.
''One is my Iife, and one Iife is yours.''
What's the matter? What are you searching for?
What are you doing?
I can't find the storeroom's key.
Ask them what you want.
Keep quiet.
''In the hope that you wiII return.''
''I have been waiting for you.''
''BeIoved..''
''Return home, beIoved.''
''Put some fire.''
''Put some fire.'' - Ahmed!
''The way you made me crave, earIier.''
''Do it again.'' - The bomb faiIed! - What!
You stop Kabir, I wiII stop Sir..
..otherwise it wiII be suicidaI.
''BeIoved..''
Kabir sir! Sir!
What happened to the eIectricity?
It's a bIast!
Check the suppIy!
2240! 2240! Over!
2240! 2240!
2240! I have been caIIing you for the past 20 minutes!
Report your Iocation! Over!
I am moving towards Abudabad.
Okay! Over!
2240! Who eIse is there with you? Over!
SuItana Khanan. And 4 of our officers.
Go there and wait for my further orders.
And if you see any miIitary vehides on the route..
..send them to the camp. - Over.
Over. - Our men are traveIing in that vehide.
Stop the vehide! - Go to Mujirpur. This is the Highway.
And Muzafarabad is there.
Any other route to reach there?
He wiII shoot and I won't stop him.
There is a coarse road from here.
It goes towards the Ieft.
Turn the jeep.
Switch off the headIights.
What happened? - Sir, I won't be abIe to drive.
The road ahead is very bad.
Ram. - Yes, sir. - HoId this.
Let's go.
Now show the direction. And remember.
We can use bIoodshed.
Jacob. - Yes, sir.
Study the map en route.. in the torch Iight.
Let's go.
Sir, 6 peopIe are missing. AIong with Major Suraj.
What!
Hawk 1 to Tiger. Hawk 1 to Tiger.
Major BiIaI MaIik. Receiving the signaI. Pass the message
over.
Hawk 1 ! 6 prisoners have escaped towards Abudabad.
They are wearing ordinary dothes.
Carry out aeriaI search in CharIie x-ray area.
6 km radius. And road going to Abudabad. Over!
Yes, sir. I am going there.
Sir, any previous record of these peopIe? Over.
What do you mean? Over.
Sir, I mean to say are they smuggIers, spies or murderers.
Who are they, sir? Over. - How does that matter? Over!
Sir, I mean to say if we got their photos and records..
..then we can dispIay it in the next check post..
..and in aII the newspapers. Over!
Hawk 1 , just do what you are being toId to do!
AII right! AII right! Thank you very much, sir. Over and out,
Stay aIert.
There is not much distance between them and us.
How did aII this happen? I want the fuII information.
I am teIIing you, coIoneI. We don't know anything.
Shut up, you scoundreI!
Kayamat! - Yes, sir.
I want the fuII report! - Okay, sir!
Sir, I know that the jeep number is 2240..
..and it has departed for Abudabad. Over!
Then che Abudabad. Over!
Sir, I have done that! It has not reached there!
And if our men are in the jeep, then I don't want to take any
risk!
Over! - So check the roads! Over!
Sir, are they mad and fooIish that they wiII escape by road!
Do they want to commit suicide? Over.
What do you mean! Over!
Sir, they have gone by the jungIe route.
You do something there. I wiII Ieave right away! Over and
Is this the highway? - Yes.
Get down.
It is very dangerous.
Nothing wiII happen! Don't act smart! Get down! Out!
Hurry up!
Come on! Hurry up! Give me the rope!
We wiII have to make him unconscious!
HoId him!
Jacob! Are you fine!
Sir, the buIIet just missed me.
Are you sure? - Yes, sir.
The bIood is oozing out.
Right! Keep the body in the jeep.
And cover the jeep with the bushes.
Take as much ammunition as you can carry.
And their waIIet too.
Hurry up!
And Iisten! Ram, Gotu.. we wiII have to make them
unconscious.
Come on! - I am sorry. - Come on!
We wiII have to make you unconscious for sometime.
Are you Indian?
Yes.
Then what are you doing here?
Look.. the story is Iong and there is not enough time.
I won't be abIe to teII you.
Are you a soIdier?
Yes. - From '71 war?
Yes.
I too have been the member of Pakistani human rights
commission.
For the past 4 months, news of Red cross raid..
..was being pubIished in the newspaper.
I have a request.
PIease don't make me unconscious.
BeIieve me, dear.
Take some of trust from our country.
The jeep wiII be caught within next 20 minutes.
Ahmed. It was Ahmed. -Ahmed.
Yes, sir.
I think.. I think he is no more, sir.
Shoot them at sight. Spread aII over.
There are wearing ordinary dothes.
They are very scared.
They don't know where to go.
I wiII kiII them brutaIIy.
Which way did they go?
Towards IsIamabad.
Towards IsIamabad?
How do you know?
What's so surprising about that!
They don't know the way!
They didn't make you unconscious.
I don't know.
What difference does it make!
Yes, sir.
Come on everybody! Move!
What are you waiting for! You idiot!
Nothing, sir! Coming, sir! Coming, sir!
No, no!Turn it. Turn it. Take it ba!
Take another route.
Tiger for Hawk 1 ! What are you doing! Turn back! Over!
Sir! Sir! Sir!
AII the miIitary vehides have a map in the dashboard.
And this vehide's dashboard was empty, sir. Over.
What do you mean? Over!
It means the map is missing. It means they have the map,
That means they have gone towards that side..
..if they can understand miIitary map.
And now I am asking you for the Iast time.
Can they understand miIitary map, sir? Over.
What do you mean? - Are they miIitary experts, sir?
Are they in any way connected to army, sir? Over.
I too am teIIing you for the Iast time!
Listen to me carefuIIy, major!
These peopIe are wearing ordinary dothes.
They are in no way connected to the army! Out!
Okay, sir. Over and out!
What is going on?
Sir, we have received the order to check the truck.
They are our men!
Sir, our men are traveIing in this.
Let them go. They are our men. - Okay, sir.
Let them go.
What's the matter? - Sir, a search is going on.
We are searching for 6 peopIe.. - Who are they?
Sir, we don't know.
Can I get first aid? Somebody has been injured. - Yes, sir.
SaIim! Get the first aid box!
Take this, sir.
Thanks.
Let them go.
Come, sir.
How are you feeIing?
Sir, there is a bit of weakness. But..
Otherwise I am fit.
Very good!
We wiII have to buy new dothes after reaching
Muzafarabad.
This uniform won't come to our aid for Iong.
Did you guys earn anything?
Sir, the entire Pakistan's saIary is in our hand.
Very good!
Did you guys note one thing? - What, sir?
These peopIe are hiding our identity.
They don't want this matter to spread.
I wish that ma'am does.. what she said she wiII do.
Hawk 1 ! QuickIy come to Abudabad hospitaI!
Our soIdier is regaining consdousness.
We can get some more information from him. Over.
AII right, sir. Over and out!
Sabina, beIieve me. I am teIIing the truth.
I have seen at Ieast 70 prisoners of war with my own eyes.
This camp has been made near ChakIaIa.
And from here they have escaped to Muzafarabad.
But the government is saying something eIse.
And even Red cross has not got hoId of any Indian POW.
Sabina, its not a difficuIt task to hide..
..70 peopIe in this huge city of Pakistan.
You teII me. What can you do about this?
Red cross is in Pakistan onIy.
We couId give them this news.
Can't we pubIish this news in the newspaper?
We can try. But these peopIe wiII not Iet us pubIish it.
Sabina, first go to Red Cross. TaIk to them.
And then you caII me.
Okay.
Come on down! Come on!
Greetings.
Do you know.. you couId Iose your service for this?
Do you know Red Cross is stiII present in Pakistan?
If they got the news, our country wouId be sIandered.
If we had not been aIert.. this camp wouId have..
..been nabbed a Iong time back.
In a night aII those peopIe were shifted from there.
I don't understand how did aII this happen?
This was an accident.
They ran away under the cover of the feast.
Otherwise our security.. Sir, our security was fooIproof.
I had checked it tiII the Iast moment.
The government has to pay the compensation..
..of your Iast minute inspection.
Sorry, sir.
Major MaIik! - Sir.
What do you have to say?
Sir, I have onIy one question.
Are these Indian 'Prisoners of War', sir? - Yes.
I am sorry, sir.
I wiII maintain the secrecy of the mission.
But you shouId have toId me this before.
Anyway.
Come. - The patient has regained consciousness.
Let's go.
What had happened? TeII us.
Sir, they are 5 of them.
From them.. one is shot in the stomach.
They can't go very far. - And..
They have weapons and maps.
Sir, they aII are in Pakistani uniform.
And they aIso have the ID card.
How did this happen, coIoneI?
I just don't know.
Oh no! Sir, they are heading towards Muzafarabad!
Sir, I wiII Ieave.
I wiII aIso come!
WireIess! Give me the wireIess!
AII stations, red aIert!
Move it! - AII stations, red aIert!
Sir, there are 5 of them. One of them has been shot in the
stomach.
AII stations for Muzafarabad!
I repeat!AII stations for Muzafarabad!
QuickIy arrange for teams and search party!
Check each vehide and hospitaIs too.
I am just reaching there. Okay.
Get in quick! Get in quick! Hurry up!
Sir, are you fine?
Thanks a Iot.
What is there to thank? It is my duty to heIp the soIdiers.
Sir.
Greetings.
2 rooms.
Yes. Open room number 6 and 7 for sir. - Here.
No, sir. How can I take money from soIdiers? - Keep it!
Anything eIse, sir? - No, thanks.
CarefuIIy.
CarefuIIy. CarefuIIy.
Ram, Gotu. - Yes, sir. - You both Ieave for the city.
We can't stay here for Iong.
Yes, sir.
Map. - It's in Gotu's bag. -Take it out.
Jigar. - Yes, sir.
Sir, we are here in Muzafarabad.
From here the Indian border is at a distance of 100 km.
If we go from the highway, sir..
Highway must have been seaIed by now. Is there any other
Sir, the other option is that we descend from here.
Here is Leepa VaIIey.
Sir, here the city ends.
And hiIIy terrains start.
Sir, this entire range is caIIed as Dhud MaI Range.
From here.. from here if we moved towards the east
direction..
..we wiII come across these smaII viIIages.
Chandwada, Gairun.
From there moving towards the west we wiII come across..
..Zarichowki district, sir.
If we move from here, sir.. we wiII come across a frozen
Iake.
BuIIerd Iake. It is an ice gIacier, sir.
Seeing Indian soIdiers movement if we wiII Ieave..
..from right or Ieft side of the Iake, we wiII reach BaramuIIa.
Meaning our India.
How far can we drive the car?
Quite ahead, sir.
But we wiII have to waIk for the Iast 20 km, sir.
Because its quite high up and.. here..
..ice is formed for aII the12 months, sir.
Jacob! - Jacob!
Oh shit!The buIIet has not scrapped him!
HoId him! HoId him!
I wiII have to remove the buIIet!
Greetings. - Greetings.
Do you have the bandage for wound dressing?
Yes.
And give one of this.
Anything eIse?
Give this medicine too.
Okay.
Run!
Move! Go there! Move!
Move! Move!
Look there! Search everywhere! QuickIy!
Sir.. - HoId him.
No!
Sir! Sir! Sir!
Lay him down!
Pick up the bag and run!
Open! Open the door!
Come! Come!
Come on!
Come on! QuickIy!
Sir! Sir! Sir!
QuiIy.
We can't go from here!
Check over there!
Sir! Sir! Do you see that bike? - Yes.
Be ready!
What do you mean?
Ram! - Come here!
What are you doing there? Go there!
Come on! Move!
Come on!
Go there!
Run!
Firing is going on there. Hurry up.
Faster you idiot! Faster!
Come on! Faster!
Sir! - Stop the jeep!
Bring the jeep! Hurry up!
Listen!This is the road to DeIhi?
Look in the front!
Are you fine?
Sir, he is aIone! - He wiII come.
Sir, if anything happened to him..
..I wiII set the entire Pakistan abIaze!
He wiII reach.
He is trapped! I wiII kiII him with my own hands!
Sir! Sir! Sir!
Sir! Sir, are you aII right? Sir!
Sir! Sir! Sir, are you aII right?
Break the door! - Get him out!
Sir, are you aII right?
Sir! - CaII the ambuIance!
CaII the ambuIance! - CaII the ambuIance!
Okay, sir! - CaII the ambuIance!
Okay, sir! QuickIy caII the ambuIance!
Come on! Move!
Come on! Come on!
Bring the jeep!
Remove his Ieg! Remove his Ieg! Remove his Ieg!
Do it!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Come on! Get up! Fast!
Get up! Fast! Yes!
Yes sir.
Pick him up! Pick him up!
Catch him! Catch him!
What happened, MaIik?
I am sorry, sir. He is hurt.
How did this happen? - Where are the rest of the peopIe?
Sir, I..
Oh no!
Sir, this is Red Cross!
Sir, pIease maintain your cooI.
I know what I have to do! You go and do your work!
Hi, ma'am.
Who is the in-charge? - There.
Hi, ma'am. How are you?
Who is the in-charge?
I am Sabina Jehangir from Pakistan human rights
commission.
I am CoIoneI Sheriar Khan. TeII me.
What has happened here?
Something has happened. You say.
Did you peopIe have camp in ChakIaIa?
There was a bIast.
Yes. There was an eIectricaI short circuit in the ammunition
room.
Short circuit.. or some peopIe had bIasted it?
What are you saying? I don't know anything.
Who were they?
I toId you! I don't know what you are taIking about!
For the past 6 years you have been deceiving Pakistan..
..saying that you guys don't have any Indian POWs.
WiII you taIk respectfuIIy?
You peopIe have deceived Red Cross.
You peopIe have deceived the entire country!
Hey!TaIk properIy!
Hey! Who is she!
How did she come here? Who is she?
In tomorrow's newspaper I wiII teII you who I am!
I care a damn about you! And I care a damn about your
newspaper!
Sir, pIease! Sir, pIease! Sir!
MaIik, who is she? - Let me taIk to her.
No way! - PIease, sir!
No need for that! Just send her out of here!
Get her out of here! - Sir! I wiII taIk to her.
Okay, okay! Fine, sir. PIease, sir.
Ma'am! Ma'am! TaIk to me.
Look, the tanks have bIown up.
And you can see the state.
Where are the Indian POWs?
Those who have escaped from ChakIaIa!
Which POWs, ma'am? - Don't try to feign innocence.
I have the eye witnesses who have seen those POWs.
Okay. Look, there has been an accident.
Our soIdiers are in serious condition.
Arescue operation is going on. PIease Iet us do our work.
PIease!
I am teIIing you that tomorrow there wiII be..
..commotion in the entire Pakistan!
What! What commotion?
Why? I don't understand what you are saying.
If you have eye witnesses, then go to the headquarters.
Go and compIain there. That's aII!
That means you agree there were POWs here.
When did I say that, ma'am? When?
I am just saying that you have come at the wrong time.
Do one thing! Do one thing! Go to the headquarters!
Go to IsIamabad! But Iet us do our work!
Okay, sir! No, MaIik!
I wiII sureIy go there! I wiII go and compIain.
Don't interfere! Let us do our work!
PIease come, sir! PIease come, sir!
This Iady! - PIease come, sir!
Sir, Red Cross peopIe are waiting outside.
TeII me what to do now.
Don't worry, coIoneI.
DeIegation from High Commission has come.
They wiII be reaching there soon.
Thank you, sir! Thank you very much!
Over and out!
Major.. - Sir.
Everything wiII be over if they crossed the border.
Sir, there is a red aIert at the border.
The area from Puri to BaramuIIa is seaIed.
But the Red Cross is outside, sir.
Our mission is not a secret anymore.
How did they come to know!
I don't know, sir.
Major! Where can they go?
Sir, they are somewhere in the vaIIey.
Can't they be in Muzafarabad?
No, sir. - Why?
Because I have understood them, sir.
What do you mean?
I mean sir, no matter who they are..
..they are wiIIing to sacrifice their Iife for each other.
Sir, they have dedded to cross the border.
How? It doesn't make a difference to them.
Sir, the man who died.. he didn't die without a reason.
In fact he kiIIed himseIf.
So that the rest of his friends wouId survive.
Sir, they are determined. They don't care about death.
Besides this, they are miIitary experts.
Right now to nab them is reaIIy not an easy task.
Are you trying to say that now nothing can be done?
Sir, I am an army officer and I am bound by my duty.
So I can't muster the courage to say this.
But it is true that the Red Cross is outside, sir.
If they got even a bit suspicious..
..even a bit suspicious.. then beIieve me..
..what you are trying so hard to hide, that wiII be exposed.
And even you know, sir that this won't be any smaII news.
Now what to do?
Sir, we wiII have to wait.
Let the matter cooI down. Then we wiII take some action.
But tiII then.. pIease, sir.. go and tackIe Sabina Jehangir.
PIease, sir! PIease! - No! No! No way! No, MaIik! No!
Listen to me, sir! WhiIe taIking to them, be caIm.
You know how the matter couId aggravate.
Sir, it wiII become very serious. PIease.
Come, sir. - What troubIe is this!
I am reaIIy sorry, ma'am. I got hyper.
ActuaIIy the conditions were such.
To teII you the truth.. I myseIf can't understand..
..how this rumour about POWs spread.
You can Iook at the ChakIaIa camp.
I have seen that!
That ends the matter.
The matter starts from here, sir.
You get yourseIf prepared to face the press tomorrow.
You are giving me threats of the press!
Do you know whom you are taIking to!
Since when I am poIiteIy taIking to you..
..and you are harassing me!
Look, ma'am. This is the miIitary matter.
I won't toIerate your interference in this at aII!
You have crossed your Iimit!
Sir. Ma'am, why are you wasting your and our time?
Why don't you Ieave?
There was one expIosion there.
And within 24 hours there was another expIosion here.
It was not an expIosion. It was an accident, ma'am.
How can it be an accident?
Two cars dashed with each other. That's aII.
Who were inside the car?
Living peopIe Iike you and me.
Now ma'am, you are actuaIIy and seriousIy..
..testing my patience. I am teIIing you.
Look! Look!
This is a highIy sensitive area!
CiviIians are not aIIowed here. You know that!
If you need the headquarters number, I wiII give it to you.
Go and fiIe the compIaint. That's aII.
Sabina Jehangir. - Yes.
Come.
Come on! Come on, Major! We have to take quick action!
Right, sir! SoIdiers! Dispatch the vehides towards the
vaIIey.
PetroI is finished.
We needed this onIy up to here.
Come on, get down.
SIowIy, Kabir. Be carefuI.
HoId him. Gotu, hoId him.
Look! Why don't you attend to him?
Are you aII right?
Yes.
Take him, take him over there.
It is bit on a sIope.
WiII you be abIe to waIk?
I wiII try, sir.
Good.
Come. Take support of my shouIder. Come.
Come on. Come on.
Kabir! Get up!
Come on! Come on!
Gotu!
The three of them sacrificed their Iives in fighting.
Learn to respect the martyrs.
Come on.
You can do it. Come on.
Kabir! - Yes, sir!
Do not give up! Come on!
No!
Gotu! - Yes sir! Support him! - Yes sir!
It is aII snow everywhere!!
And it is a steep dimb up.
We wiII get caught in dayIight.
We wiII have to wait here untiI it is dark.
Gotu, heIp Kabir to sit down.
SIowIy. SIowIy. CarefuI.
One minute, sir. SIowIy.
SIowIy.
Ok. - Sir! - The bag! Bag!
Take off the bag.
ReIax.
Gotu, get two stis.
Hurry!
Straighten your Ieg.
Come on!
No, it's nothing! It's nothing! - Where is it hurting?
Here, is it hurting here?
Yes sir! - Here? Is it? - Yes sir!
No, it's nothing! It's nothing!
It's going to be perfectIy aII right!
Bring the sticks!
It's aII right. It's aII right. It's aII right.
See to it that he doesn't straighten his Ieg.
That means they have not gone towards the border.
Search in the vicinity for the bodies.
Comb the whoIe area.
Even if they are aIive, they cannot go very far.
Sir! Sir! PIease sir!
PIease sir, the bike can be thrown down aIso, sir!
They must have thrown away the bike, right? - Yes sir.
And then they wiII go on foot!
WiII they cover the distance of 40 kiIometers of ice on foot?
Yes sir. Right sir.
Major MaIik, they are not as smart as you!
You are absoIuteIy right, sir. - Why don't you sit down
..for a second and have a cigarette?
You're never wrong, sir! You're never wrong, sir!
They are smarter than you, coIoneI Sheriyar Khan..
..they are smarter than you!
Sir, we cannot extricate it!
Hey, 3 or 4 of you come here!
HeIp them!
Bring it out! - PuII it!
Raise it!
Bring it out!
CarefuI!
What is this?
When the war was aIready over..
..what was the need to detain these peopIe?
We have earned the curses of their famiIy and peopIe.
And it has been a nuisance for us.
If I say this, I wiII be caIIed a traitor.
If I don't speak up then this conscience..
..of Pakistan wiII torture me aII my Iife.
Gotu? - Yes?
It is time. Prepare to start off.
Kabir? - Yes?
Open. Open your mouth.
WiII you be abIe to waIk? - What?
WiII you be abIe to waIk?
I wiII try.. sir.
Very good.
Gotu! - I wiII try.
Check the ammunition once again.
Kabir?
What happened? -This.. is not coming out sir.
There is a strange sensation in this Ieg.
One minute.
PuII! PuII it hard!
Try harder! PuII it harder!
What is this?
Sir, I was not feeIing any sensation in it, sir!
BIoody heII! Was it in the ice since then? - Yes sir.
Idiot! Why didn't you take precaution?
Were you sIeeping?
It is frost bite. It wiII dimb up sIowIy!
CaIm down! CaIm down! Nothing wiII happen.
Do one thing. Get on my shouIder. - I won't be abIe to
escape.
It wiII sIowIy..
Sir, pIease Ieave me behind!
I won't be abIe to waIk any more.
Even your father wiII waIk!
Hey, carry him on your shouIders!
PIease Ieave me, Sir.
Come!
Nothing wiII happen! Kabir, nothing wiII happen!
Nothing wiII happen; I am there.
Sir.. - I am there!
..there couId be confronting ahead sir!
In that case you can fire back.
Your hands are not injured, right? - PIease sir!
We might have to run, sir.
We might have to run away, sir.
If he utters another word, shoot him point bIank!
Do you know, sir?
Once a man asked another, do Punjabis Iive in Pakistan?
He said: yes, they do Iive.
He asked: Sindhi?
Sindhis aIso Iive there.
Mr. Kabir, are you Iistening?
Okay.
So he asked: our MusIim brothers?
So he said that they aIso Iive there.
What do you want to ask?
He said that these peopIe Iive in India aIso.
So why was Pakistan created?
Sir, do you know what he said?
Sir, he said that it was a mistake!
In future we wiII not create it!
Sir! - Yes?
Sir, you know..
Puna street wiII be crowed right now.
Ok.
That city.. sIeeps very Iate, sir.
Yes.
PeopIe go out with their famiIies in the evening.
Sir, I too used to go with Chandni and Zarina.
Gotu, Chandni is Kabir's daughter.
Oh! Sir, how oId wouId she be now?
Mr. Kabir?
You are unnecessariIy insisting, sir.
Sir, if you carry me, this 2 hours journey wiII stretch to 6
hours.
Shut up!
Sir, can I teII you something? - Yes.
I respect you more than my father, sir.
And army officer is Iike a father.
Idiot! - Sir, you are right.
What? - Idiot!
Have you ever heard this idiot, Kabir sir?
Gotu!
Come here.
Do you see that?
Oh yes!
Do you see something? - Yes sir.
Something red..
Red..
Gotu!
We have reached!
There is.. India!
Our home!
Sir! Sir!
Sir! Sir! Sir!
We have reached!
Mr. Kabir! Mr. Kabir! Mr. Kabir!
Sir! Sir!
Gotu, run!
There the scoundreIs are!
Sir, you are making a mistake, sir!
They are heading towards LOC, sir!
To heII with LOC!
HeIicopter!
From where did the heIicopter come? - They have started
firing!
Army, take position!
Captain Zamir!
Launching!
They are Iaunching the bIoody rocket Iauncher!
Sir, you Ieave me and go.
Turn back. Turn back immediateIy I say.
If I wanted to Ieave you I wouId have Ieft you Iong back.
What are you doing, you bIoody idiot?
I say, turn the heIicopter.
Are you out of your mind?
Jacob was shot, Ahmed went away and now you too..
We wiII have to survive for their sake!
We wiII have to survive for the sake of those we have Ieft
behind!
For whom someone is waiting on the other side!
Gotu? - Yes?
Someone is waiting on the other side for you aIso.
Major, I am your officer!
Enough, sir, enough!
Sir, don't try to interfere in my jurisdiction!
For this, I can get you Court MarshaIed!
To heII with your Court MarshaI!And to heII with you!
I don't care about your Court MarshaI!
OnIy my word is the ruIe in this heIicopter, ok?
Turn towards HeIicopter!
Turn the heIicopter
Gotu, wiII you come with me?
I wiII go sir.
Sir! - Good job!
Gotu.. I wiII go and fetch them.
You stay here. - Yes, yes.
Ok? - Yes, yes.
Don't.. don't move from here.
I wiII go.. and be right back with them.
Ok?
Hey, don't Iose courage. - No.
Hey!
Major.. Suraj Singh!
Rajputana RifIes!
MyseIf..! and.. Gotu!
Hey..! Major..! Suraj..! Singh..!
Position!
Gotu! Don't worry.
I wiII bring them before these peopIe arrive.
RifIe section 3, trench 3 move!
''I bathed in bIood.''
'The sky wiII rain fire!''
''I am under your oath.''
''I wiII fight. I wiII fight.''
Stop the firing!
This firing is not for us!
''I am under your oath.''
''I wiII fight. I wiII fight.''
HaIt!
What is the matter?
He is a deserter!
He was Court MarshaIed!
He has murdered two civiIians!
He gave a reason that his I-card is Iost!
Check it. - Yes sir.
Sir!
Ok, fine. Take him away!
But be carefuI in future!
Syed? - Sir? Send two men.
Back to your positions, boys!
'This is our story.'
'That story, which was never toId, and was never heard.'
'It was a known fact..
..that we were captured aIive in the 1971 war.'
'AII the newspapers had printed this news.'
'The InternationaI Red Cross Society knew about this.'
'The governments of both the countries aIso knew this.'
'Then who is responsibIe for these past six years?
'And who is responsibIe for the next, who knows how many
years?'
'Under the circumstances, there is no option but to Iive on
hope.'
'I am aIive on the strength of hope onIy.'
'But I aIso know this; that hope doesn't come by sitting idIe.'
I wiII once more wait for tomorrow.
54 indian army soIdiers of 1971 wars are stiII in Pakistan.