1
00:00:04,195 --> 00:00:07,528
♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum
Bum-bum-bum-bum Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

2
00:00:07,598 --> 00:00:11,326
♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum
Bum-bum-bum-bum Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

3
00:00:11,460 --> 00:00:16,523
- Mister Sandman, bring me a dream ♪
- Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

4
00:00:16,598 --> 00:00:20,898
- ♪ Make him the cutest
That I've ever seen ♪
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

5
00:00:20,969 --> 00:00:25,167
- ♪ Give him two lips
Like roses and clover ♪
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

6
00:00:25,240 --> 00:00:29,176
♪ Then tell him that
his Lonesome nights are over ♪

7
00:00:29,244 --> 00:00:33,772
- ♪ Sandman, I'm so alone ♪
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

8
00:00:33,849 --> 00:00:38,013
- ♪ Don't have nobody to call my own ♪
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪

9
00:00:38,086 --> 00:00:41,419
♪ Please turn on
your magic beam ♪

10
00:00:41,490 --> 00:00:45,085
♪ Mister Sandman
bring me a dream ♪

11
00:00:45,160 --> 00:00:48,095
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪
- ♪ Ba-bum-ba-bum
Ba-bum-ba-bum-ba-bum ♪

12
00:00:48,163 --> 00:00:50,097
♪ Ba-bum-ba-bum-ba-bum ♪

13
00:00:50,165 --> 00:00:52,565
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum ♪♪
- [Glass Crunches]

14
00:01:02,377 --> 00:01:03,704
[Latch Opening]

15
00:01:03,704 --> 00:01:04,636
[Latch Opening]

16
00:01:04,705 --> 00:01:06,639
[Clock Ticking]

17
00:01:11,412 --> 00:01:13,346
[Creaking]

18
00:01:20,888 --> 00:01:23,152
Shit!

19
00:01:32,633 --> 00:01:34,567
[Doorbell Ringing]

20
00:01:37,171 --> 00:01:39,105
[Clattering,
Clinking]

21
00:01:52,353 --> 00:01:56,153
- Oh!
- Hey. Hey, Miss Wittington.
What's goin' on?

22
00:01:56,224 --> 00:01:58,590
- My house was broken into.
- No shit?

23
00:01:58,659 --> 00:02:00,490
No shit.

24
00:02:00,561 --> 00:02:04,190
Hasn't anyone told ya?
Secondhand smoke kills.

25
00:02:04,265 --> 00:02:06,927
Yeah, but they're all dead.

26
00:02:07,001 --> 00:02:08,935
Yeah. Yeah, it's um...

27
00:02:09,003 --> 00:02:12,837
4946 Cypress Pond.

28
00:02:12,907 --> 00:02:15,034
Okay.
Right, thanks.

29
00:02:15,109 --> 00:02:17,771
They said to give 'em
15 minutes and they'll be by.

30
00:02:17,845 --> 00:02:21,144
- Jimmy, where are you going?
- Check out your house.

31
00:02:21,215 --> 00:02:25,447
- No, wait for the police.
- [Scoffs]
Where's the fun in that, huh?

32
00:02:27,555 --> 00:02:29,853
- [Children Chattering]
- Are you coming?

33
00:02:29,924 --> 00:02:33,291
Nah, l-I better stay
here and protect her.

34
00:02:33,361 --> 00:02:35,955
Oh-ho!
Right, dude.

35
00:02:36,030 --> 00:02:37,964
Good.

36
00:02:45,139 --> 00:02:47,073
[Crunching]

37
00:02:57,251 --> 00:02:59,185
[Creaking]

38
00:03:10,698 --> 00:03:12,893
[Creaking]

39
00:03:17,138 --> 00:03:20,266
All right, let's not anyone
mess with me here!

40
00:03:20,341 --> 00:03:22,434
Jimmy been suspended
five times this year already...

41
00:03:22,510 --> 00:03:26,571
for gettin' a little crazy
with the stick, all right?

42
00:03:26,647 --> 00:03:28,581
Okay!

43
00:03:31,652 --> 00:03:34,951
- [Creaking]
- [Gasping]

44
00:03:55,476 --> 00:03:58,707
[Exhales]
Hoo. Shit.

45
00:04:26,307 --> 00:04:28,639
[Creaking,
Banging]

46
00:04:28,709 --> 00:04:31,837
Shit!

47
00:04:33,414 --> 00:04:35,575
God.
[Gasping]

48
00:04:41,489 --> 00:04:43,753
All right.
[Clears Throat]

49
00:04:43,824 --> 00:04:46,793
Nothin' to fear.
The coast is clear.

50
00:04:46,861 --> 00:04:48,488
- You sure?
- Yeah.

51
00:04:48,562 --> 00:04:51,588
- I checked all the rooms
and all the closets.
- Nothing's missing.

52
00:04:51,665 --> 00:04:55,761
I don't think so, but they,
uh, they did a real number
on your office.

53
00:04:55,836 --> 00:04:59,169
- My office?
- Yeah, there's crap everywhere.

54
00:04:59,240 --> 00:05:04,075
Oh, and, uh, also they messed up
your kitchen really bad, too. Ick.

55
00:05:04,145 --> 00:05:06,170
Good night.

56
00:05:10,351 --> 00:05:12,911
So much for the cops.

57
00:05:26,300 --> 00:05:29,030
[Sighs]
Perfect.

58
00:05:34,241 --> 00:05:38,575
- [Bottles Rattling]
- We got beer! Yes!

59
00:05:38,646 --> 00:05:41,046
- We'll get messed up, man.
- [Jimmy Laughing]

60
00:05:41,115 --> 00:05:43,049
I say we egg the house
across the street.

61
00:05:43,117 --> 00:05:45,051
- Shut up, dude.
- Why not?

62
00:05:48,122 --> 00:05:50,056
Shit.

63
00:06:24,692 --> 00:06:27,160
[Banging Sound]

64
00:06:27,228 --> 00:06:29,162
[Door Latch Clicking]

65
00:06:31,432 --> 00:06:33,730
[Creaking]

66
00:06:33,801 --> 00:06:35,735
[Rustling]

67
00:06:36,804 --> 00:06:38,738
[Children Chattering]

68
00:07:25,152 --> 00:07:28,610
[Man On TV]
Even a stronger nation than now.

69
00:07:28,689 --> 00:07:31,317
[Man #2] You see? You see?
Your stupid minds...

70
00:07:31,392 --> 00:07:33,622
Jimmy!

71
00:07:33,694 --> 00:07:35,628
[Shrieking, Crying]

72
00:07:43,904 --> 00:07:46,805
Oh, my God! Oh.

73
00:07:50,377 --> 00:07:53,369
Oh! Oh, my God! Oh!

74
00:08:04,124 --> 00:08:06,115
[Sirens Blaring]

75
00:08:13,033 --> 00:08:15,524
Hey! Oh!

76
00:08:17,972 --> 00:08:20,133
[Chatter On Police Radio]

77
00:08:24,545 --> 00:08:27,241
Help! Andy...

78
00:08:27,314 --> 00:08:30,477
- Looks like a prank.
- Andy! Oh!

79
00:08:33,520 --> 00:08:35,750
Police! Anybody home?

80
00:08:39,827 --> 00:08:43,024
Andy! He's not dead!
[Screaming]

81
00:08:50,638 --> 00:08:54,233
- [Chatter On Police Radio]
- [Officer] Team 9-10 requests
burglary detectives at, uh,

82
00:08:54,308 --> 00:08:58,574
4946 Cypress Pond Road.

83
00:08:58,646 --> 00:09:00,841
Hey, Bobby!

84
00:09:00,914 --> 00:09:02,905
What do ya got?

85
00:09:02,983 --> 00:09:05,247
Looks like we hit
the Daily Double here.

86
00:09:05,319 --> 00:09:07,617
- What, another B and E?
- Yeah.

87
00:09:22,936 --> 00:09:25,302
[Siren Wails]

88
00:09:25,372 --> 00:09:27,306
[Man]
So, whose house is this, anyway?

89
00:09:27,374 --> 00:09:30,468
[Man #2] Marion Wittington.
Dr. Sam Loomis's nurse?

90
00:09:30,544 --> 00:09:32,637
He was that shrink
that died a few years ago.

91
00:09:32,713 --> 00:09:34,647
He lived here.
She took care of him.

92
00:09:34,715 --> 00:09:37,115
Oh, I remember him.
I saw a thing on 60 Minutes on him.

93
00:09:37,184 --> 00:09:39,152
Spent his life tracking down
that Halloween guy...

94
00:09:39,219 --> 00:09:41,153
who butchered all those kids
up in Haddonfield, right?

95
00:09:41,221 --> 00:09:43,781
- Michael Myers.
- Right.

96
00:09:43,857 --> 00:09:48,021
- Hey, you don't think Michael Myers...
- They never found his body.

97
00:09:48,095 --> 00:09:50,029
Yeah, but that was,
like, 20 years ago.

98
00:09:56,570 --> 00:09:59,664
[Whistling]
Fuck me.

99
00:09:59,740 --> 00:10:01,674
Loomis was obsessed
with Michael Myers.

100
00:10:01,742 --> 00:10:04,836
This is quite
a love fest.

101
00:10:04,912 --> 00:10:07,972
- I'll call up to Haddonfield
and warn 'em.
- There's no way, Fitz.

102
00:10:08,048 --> 00:10:10,016
Just a precaution.
Tomorrow's Halloween.

103
00:10:10,084 --> 00:10:12,712
All right, you tell 'em to look for
a guy with a cane and Alzheimer's.

104
00:10:12,786 --> 00:10:15,119
The guy would be
younger than I am, okay?

105
00:10:15,253 --> 00:10:18,381
I was 15 when he killed
his sister back in '63.

106
00:10:18,456 --> 00:10:21,482
Yes, Fitzsimmons. Patch me through
to Haddonfield, please.

107
00:10:21,559 --> 00:10:25,120
- Yeah.
- Michael Myers.

108
00:10:25,196 --> 00:10:27,460
Yeah, right.

109
00:10:28,800 --> 00:10:30,734
[Thunderclap]

110
00:11:06,037 --> 00:11:08,505
[Man's Voice]
I met him 15 years ago.

111
00:11:08,573 --> 00:11:10,541
I was told
there was nothing left.

112
00:11:10,608 --> 00:11:13,133
No reason, no conscience.

113
00:11:13,211 --> 00:11:16,840
No understanding. Even the most
rudimentary sense of life...

114
00:11:16,914 --> 00:11:20,315
and death, of good or evil...

115
00:11:20,385 --> 00:11:22,319
right or wrong.

116
00:11:22,387 --> 00:11:25,413
I met this
six-year-old child...

117
00:11:25,490 --> 00:11:30,359
with this blank, pale,
emotionless face, and...

118
00:11:31,963 --> 00:11:34,090
the blackest eyes.

119
00:11:34,165 --> 00:11:36,429
The devil's eyes.

120
00:12:02,160 --> 00:12:04,560
[Man, Continuing] I spent
eight years trying to reach him...

121
00:12:04,629 --> 00:12:06,893
and then another seven
trying to keep him locked up...

122
00:12:06,964 --> 00:12:10,866
because I realized that what was living
behind that boy's eyes...

123
00:12:10,935 --> 00:12:14,530
was purely, and simply...

124
00:12:14,605 --> 00:12:16,539
evil.

125
00:13:09,649 --> 00:13:12,345
- [Bell Tolling]
- [Creaking]

126
00:13:46,185 --> 00:13:48,119
[Ticking]

127
00:14:12,678 --> 00:14:15,340
[Screaming]

128
00:14:18,084 --> 00:14:20,484
Mom! Mom! Mom. Mom.

129
00:14:20,553 --> 00:14:23,784
- [Screaming Continues]
- Mom! Mom! Mom. Mom!

130
00:14:25,391 --> 00:14:27,518
You okay? You all right?

131
00:14:27,593 --> 00:14:32,223
[Moaning]
Oh. Oh!

132
00:14:32,298 --> 00:14:36,462
- Everything's okay. It's okay.
- [Gasping]

133
00:14:36,536 --> 00:14:40,996
- Do you need somethin'?
- Oh! Uh, yeah.

134
00:14:41,074 --> 00:14:43,008
Yeah, please. Thanks.

135
00:14:43,076 --> 00:14:45,510
- Sure.
- It's okay.

136
00:14:48,548 --> 00:14:51,346
[Moaning]

137
00:14:54,120 --> 00:14:57,988
[Sighs]
Nightmares.

138
00:14:58,057 --> 00:15:00,582
Nightmares.

139
00:15:02,595 --> 00:15:04,529
[Whispering]
Nightmares.

140
00:15:18,401 --> 00:15:20,198
[Crow Cawing]

141
00:15:24,874 --> 00:15:26,808
[Birds Twittering]

142
00:15:39,302 --> 00:15:41,236
- [Boy] Making toast.
- [Laurie] Mm...

143
00:15:41,304 --> 00:15:44,967
No.
None for me, thanks.

144
00:15:45,041 --> 00:15:48,704
- Caffeine is not a food group.
- We're out of Percodan.

145
00:15:50,947 --> 00:15:53,677
Got mail.
It's from your dad.

146
00:15:59,555 --> 00:16:02,649
- Birthday card.
- It's only two months late.
I'm impressed.

147
00:16:02,725 --> 00:16:05,091
Cash is good. I'm gonna need it
when I go to Yosemite.

148
00:16:06,228 --> 00:16:08,162
- You're not going.
- Yes, I am.

149
00:16:08,230 --> 00:16:11,199
[Scoffs]
No, you're not.

150
00:16:11,267 --> 00:16:14,327
Yes, I am, and with your full blessing.
Do you want to know why?

151
00:16:14,403 --> 00:16:17,395
- Why?
- Because today is the day.

152
00:16:17,473 --> 00:16:19,941
I can feel it.
Today is the day...

153
00:16:20,009 --> 00:16:22,671
that you're going to realize
that I'm 17 years old...

154
00:16:22,745 --> 00:16:26,237
and your over protection and paranoia
is inhibiting my growth process.

155
00:16:27,683 --> 00:16:29,742
Want to go camping?
I'll take you camping.

156
00:16:30,820 --> 00:16:33,118
I don't want
to go with you.

157
00:16:33,189 --> 00:16:36,124
Sorry.

158
00:16:36,192 --> 00:16:39,355
- Dad would let me go.
- Well, Dad...

159
00:16:39,428 --> 00:16:41,919
is an abusive, chain-smoking
methadone addict.

160
00:16:41,998 --> 00:16:43,932
Who would attract
someone like that?

161
00:16:45,201 --> 00:16:47,897
- Ouch.
- And just think, he left you.

162
00:16:47,970 --> 00:16:50,962
Look, John.

163
00:16:51,040 --> 00:16:55,067
I know you get your smart mouth
from my side of the family,
so I'll give you a break.

164
00:16:55,144 --> 00:16:58,204
- But point check, you're going too far.
- No, I'm goin' to Yosemite.

165
00:16:58,280 --> 00:17:01,579
- No, you're not.
- Look, Mom, help me out here.

166
00:17:01,650 --> 00:17:04,380
I need a little more open air.
I've earned it.

167
00:17:06,355 --> 00:17:08,380
Look, I know today is the day,
but I think that...

168
00:17:08,457 --> 00:17:11,551
- Oh, really? What day is that, John?
- Halloween.

169
00:17:12,762 --> 00:17:15,060
Oh, I hadn't noticed.

170
00:17:16,332 --> 00:17:18,266
Look, Mom,
we're through with all that.

171
00:17:20,236 --> 00:17:22,101
We really are.

172
00:17:30,079 --> 00:17:33,708
You know what you're becoming?
You're becoming an Oedipal
enabler, you know that?

173
00:17:33,783 --> 00:17:36,581
- Thank you.
- I'm serious!

174
00:17:36,652 --> 00:17:38,847
Twenty years from now, you're still
going to be living with her.

175
00:17:38,921 --> 00:17:40,855
Probably running some weird motel
out in the middle of nowhere.

176
00:17:40,923 --> 00:17:42,914
- So this means no Yosemite?
- Correct.

177
00:17:42,992 --> 00:17:44,983
- Now, how do I get out of it?
- Why don't you want to go?

178
00:17:45,061 --> 00:17:47,825
Oh, it's so lame.
No, no, no. It's worse.

179
00:17:47,897 --> 00:17:50,195
L-I went there
two summers ago with my family.

180
00:17:50,266 --> 00:17:53,997
Loathsome. No, it's worse.
It'll come to me.

181
00:17:54,070 --> 00:17:57,130
Wretched. You know?
Okay, think-think...

182
00:17:57,206 --> 00:17:59,140
campfires, s'mores...

183
00:18:21,597 --> 00:18:24,088
Repugnant!
That's it, repugnant.

184
00:18:24,166 --> 00:18:26,134
I would rather have
my eyes pierced.

185
00:18:28,270 --> 00:18:30,363
I'm very sorry.
I wish I could help. I'm sorry.

186
00:18:30,439 --> 00:18:32,464
- But he promised that...
- [Girl] No. I'm not going.

187
00:18:32,541 --> 00:18:35,305
You couldn't pay me to go.

188
00:18:37,580 --> 00:18:41,448
- Hey, what's wrong?
- Oh... Uh, my dad.

189
00:18:41,517 --> 00:18:44,452
He flaked on
my financial aid again.

190
00:18:44,520 --> 00:18:47,387
- The bursar's being such a dick.
Now I can't go to Yosemite.
- You're not going either?

191
00:18:47,456 --> 00:18:49,390
- No.
- I'm not going.

192
00:18:49,458 --> 00:18:51,392
- How are you going to get out of it?
- Please.

193
00:18:51,460 --> 00:18:54,554
- [Bell Ringing]
- Hey. Hold on. We ditch Yosemite.

194
00:18:54,630 --> 00:18:57,098
It means we could have
a Halloween party, just the four of us.

195
00:18:57,166 --> 00:18:59,498
Whole place would be empty.
We'd have the run of it.

196
00:18:59,568 --> 00:19:02,969
- We could have a roaming orgy.
- I love the way this man thinks!

197
00:19:03,038 --> 00:19:06,166
[Laughing] Hope that's not
the only thing you love about me.

198
00:19:10,579 --> 00:19:12,740
- Hey, come on.
- All right, let's go.

199
00:19:18,727 --> 00:19:21,195
[Crow Cawing]

200
00:19:39,384 --> 00:19:42,410
Okay. You see,
I told you we'd make it.

201
00:19:42,487 --> 00:19:44,921
When I was a little girl,
we used to pee in the woods.

202
00:19:57,702 --> 00:20:01,263
- Ohh! Uh...
- Don't worry!

203
00:20:05,410 --> 00:20:08,208
Come on.

204
00:20:08,279 --> 00:20:10,440
Mom, that's the boys' room.

205
00:20:10,515 --> 00:20:12,608
Then the boys are just
gonna have to deal with it.

206
00:20:14,085 --> 00:20:16,019
Hello?

207
00:20:19,624 --> 00:20:22,286
Okay. Coast is clear.

208
00:20:22,360 --> 00:20:24,954
[Clicking]

209
00:20:33,871 --> 00:20:36,271
[Whispering]
Okay. Come on.

210
00:20:40,344 --> 00:20:45,577
I'll be just next door.
Mom's gotta go too.

211
00:20:45,650 --> 00:20:48,915
♪♪ [Child Humming
"Mary Had A Little Lamb"]

212
00:20:49,821 --> 00:20:51,755
- Oh!
- Mom?

213
00:20:51,823 --> 00:20:53,757
I know.

214
00:20:54,959 --> 00:20:57,154
[Heavy Door Slamming]

215
00:20:57,228 --> 00:21:02,427
- Mom?
- It's just the door, Casey.

216
00:21:02,500 --> 00:21:04,434
[Sighs]

217
00:21:06,304 --> 00:21:10,434
Here's some tissues...
Casey?

218
00:21:12,577 --> 00:21:14,545
♪♪ [Casey Humming]

219
00:21:14,612 --> 00:21:16,603
[Sighs]

220
00:21:16,681 --> 00:21:18,876
♪♪ [Humming Continues]

221
00:21:50,481 --> 00:21:52,415
♪♪ [Humming Continues]

222
00:22:03,227 --> 00:22:05,320
[Casey Screaming]

223
00:22:05,396 --> 00:22:07,796
Spiders!

224
00:22:07,865 --> 00:22:10,561
- [Sighs]
- [Car Starting]

225
00:22:16,607 --> 00:22:20,668
[Laurie] All right.
Ready? You know why you're here.

226
00:22:20,745 --> 00:22:24,203
The buses leave for Yosemite
at 4:15, sharp.

227
00:22:32,623 --> 00:22:35,922
And now it's time for me
to do my obligatory plea...

228
00:22:35,993 --> 00:22:38,791
that you uphold
the standards of Hillcrest.

229
00:22:38,863 --> 00:22:42,355
And that means
no musical sleeping bags.

230
00:22:42,433 --> 00:22:44,367
- [Students Groaning]
- No booze.

231
00:22:44,435 --> 00:22:47,461
- [Louder Groaning]
- No drugs, no kidding.

232
00:22:47,538 --> 00:22:50,371
Undoubtedly, someone will ruin it
for the rest of them...

233
00:22:50,441 --> 00:22:53,569
so I just want to remind you that
the entire teaching faculty has...

234
00:22:53,644 --> 00:22:56,112
- Hey! Guess what this is.
- What?

235
00:22:56,180 --> 00:23:00,310
It's my history report.
Forgot to hand it in.

236
00:23:00,384 --> 00:23:02,716
Guess who's not going to Yosemite.
I'm so bummed.

237
00:23:02,787 --> 00:23:04,721
[Gasps]
Guess who has a fever of 102...

238
00:23:04,789 --> 00:23:06,723
and has to stay in bed
all weekend long.

239
00:23:06,791 --> 00:23:10,386
- You two company?
- So, what's the plan?

240
00:23:10,461 --> 00:23:13,157
Romantic dinner,
candlelight, soft music.

241
00:23:13,231 --> 00:23:16,462
- Animal sex.
- You need a hormone suppressant.

242
00:23:16,534 --> 00:23:19,298
You're embarrassing
the newlyweds, Charles.

243
00:23:19,370 --> 00:23:21,964
That's it.
Have a good time.

244
00:23:26,477 --> 00:23:28,843
And why aren't
you going camping, Miss Tate?

245
00:23:28,913 --> 00:23:31,711
Because it sounds like fun.
And you, Mr. Brennan?

246
00:23:31,782 --> 00:23:34,615
Guidance counselors aren't usually
a big hit in the wilderness.

247
00:23:34,685 --> 00:23:37,745
Besides, somebody has to stay behind and
watch over the three or four outcasts.

248
00:23:37,822 --> 00:23:39,756
[Bell Rings]
[Woman] Oh, good morning, Miss Tate.

249
00:23:39,824 --> 00:23:41,849
- Morning, Norma.
- Your mail and messages are
on your desk,

250
00:23:41,926 --> 00:23:44,258
along with the
new quarter budget, and oh,

251
00:23:44,328 --> 00:23:47,923
surprise, surprise, the drains in the
girls' shower room are clogged again.

252
00:23:47,999 --> 00:23:50,467
- Can I talk to you alone
for one second?
- But, l-I called the plumber,

253
00:23:50,534 --> 00:23:52,468
and he assured me that
he will be here as soon as he can...

254
00:23:52,536 --> 00:23:55,300
Thank you, Norma.
Thank you very much.

255
00:23:57,675 --> 00:23:59,905
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Place of employment.

256
00:23:59,977 --> 00:24:03,208
I'm sorry, l-I just...
I needed a fix.

257
00:24:05,583 --> 00:24:08,882
- We still on for lunch?
- Uh-huh. 1:00.

258
00:24:08,953 --> 00:24:13,322
You are, without a doubt,
the most amazing,

259
00:24:13,391 --> 00:24:16,121
challenging woman
I have ever met.

260
00:24:16,193 --> 00:24:18,127
And what's wrong now?

261
00:24:18,195 --> 00:24:21,858
Can you just stop with the
Keri analysis just once, please?

262
00:24:21,932 --> 00:24:24,093
You can do it tomorrow,
all you want.

263
00:24:24,168 --> 00:24:26,898
But please, can I just
have today off?

264
00:24:26,971 --> 00:24:30,270
- [Sighs] Whatever you want.
- Thank you.

265
00:24:30,341 --> 00:24:33,105
- Lunch. Don't forget.
- 1:00.

266
00:24:33,177 --> 00:24:35,111
Uh...

267
00:24:38,883 --> 00:24:40,817
[Phone Ringing, Chattering]

268
00:24:55,800 --> 00:24:58,428
[Man Speaking, Indistinct]

269
00:24:58,502 --> 00:25:02,131
"He turned, just in time
to see her enter the room,

270
00:25:02,206 --> 00:25:07,166
with her long, slender legs
that climbed high up her skirt,

271
00:25:07,244 --> 00:25:09,940
leading to two tumultuous,

272
00:25:10,014 --> 00:25:13,142
round, melon breasts."

273
00:25:13,217 --> 00:25:15,151
[Woman On Phone]
Round melon what?

274
00:25:15,219 --> 00:25:17,153
Now why do you want
to label it like food?

275
00:25:17,221 --> 00:25:20,713
A-And what kind of melon
you talkin' about?
Cantaloupe? Watermelon? What?

276
00:25:20,791 --> 00:25:23,954
Baby, it's fiction! People like
to read descriptive adjectives.

277
00:25:24,028 --> 00:25:26,360
- It sets the scene.
- It's stupid is what it is.

278
00:25:26,430 --> 00:25:28,364
It's sensual
and romantic.

279
00:25:28,432 --> 00:25:30,210
Ronny, it's unrealistic. This whole
writing career is unrealistic.

280
00:25:30,210 --> 00:25:33,270
Ronny, it's unrealistic. This whole
writing career is unrealistic.

281
00:25:33,347 --> 00:25:36,043
Hey, we're married now,
baby, we gotta get serious.

282
00:25:36,116 --> 00:25:39,313
- This is serious.
- Honey, I been patient,
but this writing thing...

283
00:25:39,386 --> 00:25:42,685
just ain't takin' off, and I want
a baby before I get so old...

284
00:25:42,756 --> 00:25:44,951
- I can't get my butt back.
- You gotta give me a chance, honey.

285
00:25:45,025 --> 00:25:48,893
I have to express myself creatively.
We payin' the bills, aren't we?

286
00:25:48,962 --> 00:25:51,328
- Uh! Fuck me! Shit!
- What?

287
00:25:51,398 --> 00:25:53,866
Not you, honey. Hold on for a sec.
You scared the shit out of me!

288
00:25:53,934 --> 00:25:56,425
Sorry, Ronny.
I gotta ask a favor, man.

289
00:25:56,503 --> 00:25:58,368
- I'm not lettin' you out of here.
- Aw, come on, man.

290
00:25:58,439 --> 00:26:00,373
- Jus-Just for lunch. Please.
- Look, your mom told me...

291
00:26:00,441 --> 00:26:02,705
the next time I let you loose,
I was gonna be fired.

292
00:26:02,776 --> 00:26:06,177
- Look, man.
I got a date with Molly tonight.
- Mm-hmm.

293
00:26:06,246 --> 00:26:09,147
And I want to make it special.
What do you say?

294
00:26:11,085 --> 00:26:13,986
Look, I promise I'll be back
for afternoon classes.

295
00:26:14,054 --> 00:26:16,454
Huh? I just want
to get a gift.

296
00:26:16,523 --> 00:26:18,548
Come on, man, have a heart.

297
00:26:21,361 --> 00:26:25,092
No. No. Can't do it.

298
00:26:25,165 --> 00:26:28,464
Aw, come on, man.
Okay, how about this?

299
00:26:28,535 --> 00:26:31,971
- You accidentally press the gate.
- Mm-hmm.

300
00:26:32,039 --> 00:26:34,234
And when you have
your back turned, we sneak out.

301
00:26:34,308 --> 00:26:36,538
[Woman On Phone]
Ronny, don't you get your ass fired...

302
00:26:36,610 --> 00:26:38,737
[Sighs]

303
00:26:42,816 --> 00:26:45,580
- Don't you do me wrong, okay?
- [Laughing] Not a chance, man! Cool.

304
00:26:45,652 --> 00:26:48,086
- All right.
- Get outta here, get outta here.
Comb your hair.

305
00:26:48,155 --> 00:26:50,988
- [Beeping]
- Just one more book.

306
00:26:51,058 --> 00:26:54,084
Just one more, and I promise
I'll work with your daddy, all right?

307
00:27:18,085 --> 00:27:20,019
[Alarm Chirps]

308
00:27:25,759 --> 00:27:27,693
[Children Laughing]

309
00:27:27,761 --> 00:27:30,525
[Chattering]

310
00:27:30,597 --> 00:27:32,531
[Boy Screaming]

311
00:27:50,317 --> 00:27:52,251
- Oh. Oh.
- Oh, Jesus, Will.

312
00:27:52,319 --> 00:27:55,755
- I'm sorry. I thought you saw me.
- No.

313
00:27:55,823 --> 00:27:58,656
You see me now?

314
00:27:58,725 --> 00:28:01,489
How are you doin'?

315
00:28:01,562 --> 00:28:03,928
- [Diners Chattering]
- [Bell Dinging]

316
00:28:07,234 --> 00:28:09,168
[Sighs]

317
00:28:12,439 --> 00:28:14,464
You wanna talk about it?

318
00:28:17,811 --> 00:28:19,745
I think I'm losing John.

319
00:28:22,416 --> 00:28:24,748
I think he's finally
tired of my bullshit.

320
00:28:26,520 --> 00:28:29,455
[Sighs]
How about you?

321
00:28:29,523 --> 00:28:31,457
You tired of my bullshit?

322
00:28:31,525 --> 00:28:34,085
I'm a counselor.
I'm attracted to it.

323
00:28:36,396 --> 00:28:40,924
- So counsel me.
- Oh, no. I know better.

324
00:28:41,001 --> 00:28:43,196
I love you just
the way you are.

325
00:28:46,874 --> 00:28:49,138
Do you think
it's possible...

326
00:28:49,209 --> 00:28:51,143
that something so tragic
can happen to somebody...

327
00:28:51,211 --> 00:28:53,145
that they never
recover from it?

328
00:28:53,213 --> 00:28:57,377
I like to believe that
recovery is always possible.

329
00:29:03,090 --> 00:29:06,582
There's a little back story
that I haven't been, um...

330
00:29:09,796 --> 00:29:13,027
- completely successful with.
- I know.

331
00:29:13,100 --> 00:29:17,298
I've tried everything. I really have.
I've tried everything.

332
00:29:17,371 --> 00:29:22,741
Twelve steps, uh,
self-help, group therapy,

333
00:29:23,810 --> 00:29:27,644
shrinks, meditation...

334
00:29:30,984 --> 00:29:33,509
- Everything.
- That's not everything.

335
00:29:33,587 --> 00:29:37,546
Oh, yeah?
What else is there?

336
00:29:37,624 --> 00:29:40,092
I'm a really
good listener.

337
00:29:48,201 --> 00:29:52,001
Maybe.
Some night, by a...

338
00:29:52,072 --> 00:29:54,006
warm fire.

339
00:30:00,113 --> 00:30:02,172
I'll be right back.

340
00:30:08,689 --> 00:30:11,283
Can I get another glass
of Chardonnay, please?

341
00:30:13,427 --> 00:30:16,294
- Today.
- Yes, ma'am.

342
00:30:16,363 --> 00:30:18,297
Thank you.

343
00:30:21,835 --> 00:30:23,769
[Banging,
Girl Screaming]

344
00:30:28,976 --> 00:30:31,206
Thanks.

345
00:30:34,448 --> 00:30:36,382
Thank you very much.

346
00:30:44,758 --> 00:30:46,692
♪♪ [Whistling]

347
00:30:50,664 --> 00:30:52,791
God. I can't believe
we're doin' this.

348
00:30:52,866 --> 00:30:54,857
- Desperate measures.
- It's illegal.

349
00:30:54,935 --> 00:30:56,903
It's harmless,
and expected.

350
00:30:56,970 --> 00:30:58,961
Studies have proven that
all teenagers, at some point...

351
00:30:59,039 --> 00:31:01,769
- in their adolescent lives,
have shoplifted.
- What studies?

352
00:31:01,842 --> 00:31:03,707
Hey. We could have avoided
this whole thing...

353
00:31:03,777 --> 00:31:05,711
if you woulda simply scored
some of your mom's booze.

354
00:31:05,779 --> 00:31:08,213
- Look, my mom's a functioning
- alcoholic. She accounts for...
- John!

355
00:31:09,950 --> 00:31:13,078
- John, what are you doing here?
- Just gettin' some off-campus lunch.

356
00:31:13,153 --> 00:31:16,714
You're not allowed to have
little off-campus lunches, John.

357
00:31:16,790 --> 00:31:20,692
- You know that. You too, Charlie.
- Sorry, Miss Tate.

358
00:31:20,761 --> 00:31:25,095
[Scoffs] Come on,
I'll drive you back.

359
00:31:25,165 --> 00:31:27,429
You know what?
Charlie, here.

360
00:31:27,501 --> 00:31:29,935
Go get in the car.
I'll be right there.

361
00:31:30,003 --> 00:31:31,766
What the fuck
do you think you're doing?

362
00:31:31,838 --> 00:31:33,772
Mom, I'm really uncomfortable
with you saying that word.

363
00:31:33,840 --> 00:31:37,003
Well, then don't put me
in the position, John.

364
00:31:37,077 --> 00:31:39,637
Do you know
what day it is?

365
00:31:39,713 --> 00:31:41,806
Of all the days
for you to pull this shit...

366
00:31:41,882 --> 00:31:47,514
What do you think you can do?
Just wander around town?

367
00:31:47,587 --> 00:31:49,521
I don't ask you
for very much.

368
00:31:49,589 --> 00:31:52,990
- Just give me one day!
- Mom, I've given you 17 years!

369
00:31:53,060 --> 00:31:55,358
And I need you
to be responsible.

370
00:31:55,429 --> 00:31:58,694
- Do you know what that means?
- Responsible. Don't talk to me
about responsible, Mom!

371
00:31:58,765 --> 00:32:03,245
- I just need this one thing!
- Mom, I am not responsible for you!

372
00:32:04,780 --> 00:32:07,442
That's it. That's enough.
I can't take it, Mom.

373
00:32:07,516 --> 00:32:09,450
He's dead.

374
00:32:09,518 --> 00:32:12,578
Michael Myers is dead.

375
00:32:14,957 --> 00:32:17,357
- What do you want me to say?
- That it's over?

376
00:32:17,426 --> 00:32:22,261
That we should try to get on with
some attempt at a happy existence, Mom.

377
00:32:22,331 --> 00:32:25,198
Because all the shit that's going on
in your head is leakin' out on me.

378
00:32:25,267 --> 00:32:27,360
And I can't take it anymore.

379
00:32:29,505 --> 00:32:32,668
You told me yourself
you watched him burn.

380
00:32:34,510 --> 00:32:37,707
- I didn't e-exactly stay
to see his ashes, John.
- Mom, 20 years.

381
00:32:37,780 --> 00:32:40,806
Twenty years.

382
00:32:40,883 --> 00:32:43,750
Don't you think he would
have shown up by now?

383
00:32:43,819 --> 00:32:46,287
What's he waitin' for, huh?

384
00:32:49,058 --> 00:32:51,185
Okay, Mom. I can't live
like this. I'm sorry.

385
00:32:51,260 --> 00:32:54,627
Wha...
What does that mean, John?

386
00:32:54,697 --> 00:32:56,995
If you want to stay handcuffed
to your dead brother, that's fine.

387
00:32:57,066 --> 00:33:00,524
But you're not draggin' me along.
Not anymore.

388
00:33:04,974 --> 00:33:07,670
[Engine Starting]

389
00:33:07,743 --> 00:33:10,678
- ♪ Mister Sandman ♪
- [Man] Yes?

390
00:33:10,746 --> 00:33:15,547
♪ Bring us a dream
Give him a pair of eyes with a... ♪♪

391
00:33:27,997 --> 00:33:30,989
[Horn Honking]

392
00:33:31,066 --> 00:33:33,000
Ronny?

393
00:33:33,068 --> 00:33:37,061
- Mom, let me.
- Where the hell is he?

394
00:33:37,139 --> 00:33:39,073
[Honking Continues]

395
00:33:41,243 --> 00:33:43,905
- Ronny!
- [Engine Chugging]

396
00:33:45,047 --> 00:33:47,106
Hey, Ronny!

397
00:33:50,186 --> 00:33:52,654
[Chugging Continues]

398
00:34:02,097 --> 00:34:04,793
- Where the hell were you?
- Norma told me to walk the perimeter.

399
00:34:06,569 --> 00:34:08,560
And where were you
when these two got out?

400
00:34:09,605 --> 00:34:12,369
Eyes up, Ronny.

401
00:34:14,476 --> 00:34:16,410
[Laurie Sighs]

402
00:34:19,048 --> 00:34:20,982
Psycho.

403
00:34:24,186 --> 00:34:26,120
[Beeping,
Clanking]

404
00:34:34,196 --> 00:34:37,165
- [Laughing, Chattering]
- [Girl] Okay, bye!

405
00:34:49,545 --> 00:34:51,479
[Bell Ringing]

406
00:34:53,916 --> 00:34:56,248
- [Ringing Continues]
- Dennis!

407
00:34:56,318 --> 00:35:00,652
- [Knocking]
- Don't send down any more, all right?
I gotta go to class.

408
00:35:01,891 --> 00:35:04,121
[Thumping, Clattering]

409
00:35:15,437 --> 00:35:17,371
[Rumbling]

410
00:35:17,439 --> 00:35:19,634
[Banging]

411
00:35:19,708 --> 00:35:21,642
Dennis?

412
00:35:56,412 --> 00:35:58,346
[Water Dripping]

413
00:36:26,108 --> 00:36:29,236
- [Molly] Oh! Uh!
- [John] Shh! The best part.

414
00:36:31,347 --> 00:36:34,839
[Molly] Oh!
[Laughs]

415
00:36:34,917 --> 00:36:37,351
Do I get points or what?

416
00:36:37,419 --> 00:36:39,387
Huh?

417
00:36:39,455 --> 00:36:43,186
You score. Yeah. Yeah.

418
00:36:43,258 --> 00:36:45,590
Hmm. Well, it just
occurred to me today...

419
00:36:45,661 --> 00:36:49,256
that I've never
celebrated Halloween before.

420
00:36:49,331 --> 00:36:51,265
And why is that?

421
00:36:51,333 --> 00:36:54,097
Oh, we've got a psychotic
serial killer in the family,

422
00:36:54,169 --> 00:36:56,660
loves to butcher people
on Halloween, and...

423
00:36:56,739 --> 00:36:59,833
I just thought it
in bad taste to...

424
00:36:59,908 --> 00:37:01,842
celebrate.

425
00:37:01,910 --> 00:37:04,071
So why now?

426
00:37:04,146 --> 00:37:07,309
Mm, because there comes a point in your
life where you have to concentrate...

427
00:37:07,383 --> 00:37:09,317
on what's right about it.

428
00:37:11,320 --> 00:37:13,254
Really?

429
00:37:16,492 --> 00:37:19,290
And you...

430
00:37:19,361 --> 00:37:21,659
are a sterling example...

431
00:37:21,730 --> 00:37:23,664
of what's right.

432
00:37:25,601 --> 00:37:28,502
And tonight you get
my full concentration.

433
00:37:30,572 --> 00:37:33,473
I'm honored.

434
00:37:33,542 --> 00:37:35,476
[Laughs]

435
00:37:42,317 --> 00:37:44,751
Very good point, A.J.
So, what could Victor have done...

436
00:37:44,820 --> 00:37:46,845
to save Elizabeth?

437
00:37:50,559 --> 00:37:53,050
[Laurie Sighs]

438
00:37:53,128 --> 00:37:55,619
Anybody at all?

439
00:37:57,666 --> 00:38:01,363
Come on, people.
Did anybody read the book?

440
00:38:02,852 --> 00:38:06,754
Guys.
It's "Frahnk-en-steen."

441
00:38:06,822 --> 00:38:10,986
- [Students Laughing]
- You could have watched the movie!

442
00:38:12,528 --> 00:38:14,860
Molly. Please.

443
00:38:14,931 --> 00:38:16,990
Do you have any thoughts
on Victor and Elizabeth?

444
00:38:17,066 --> 00:38:19,694
Well, uh...
[Coughs] Um...

445
00:38:19,769 --> 00:38:23,170
Well, I think that Victor should have
confronted the monster sooner.

446
00:38:23,239 --> 00:38:25,207
I mea... He's completely responsible
for Elizabeth's death.

447
00:38:25,274 --> 00:38:29,005
He was, he was so paralyzed by fear
that he never did anything.

448
00:38:29,078 --> 00:38:31,842
It-It took death
for the guy to get a clue.

449
00:38:31,914 --> 00:38:36,442
And why do you think he was
finally able to confront his monster?

450
00:38:36,519 --> 00:38:39,955
I think that Victor had reached
a point in his life where he
had nothing left to lose.

451
00:38:40,022 --> 00:38:42,786
I mean, the monster saw to that
by killing off everybody that he loved.

452
00:38:42,858 --> 00:38:44,849
Victor finally
had to face it.

453
00:38:44,927 --> 00:38:47,657
It was about redemption.
It was his fate.

454
00:38:50,233 --> 00:38:52,667
[School Bell Rings]

455
00:38:52,735 --> 00:38:54,794
Okay, everybody, um,
have a good time!

456
00:39:06,649 --> 00:39:09,015
John!

457
00:39:17,593 --> 00:39:19,584
What?

458
00:39:26,302 --> 00:39:29,328
It's a permission slip.

459
00:39:29,405 --> 00:39:31,839
Bus leaves in 45 minutes.

460
00:39:31,907 --> 00:39:35,399
- Go pack quick.
- Ma, I don't have to go.

461
00:39:35,478 --> 00:39:37,412
Go, just go! Have fun.

462
00:39:37,480 --> 00:39:40,313
- You sure?
- Yes. Look, it's good for you.

463
00:39:40,383 --> 00:39:42,578
It's good for me.

464
00:39:42,652 --> 00:39:45,951
So, just call me.
You know, call. And call.

465
00:39:46,022 --> 00:39:48,513
If you feel like
you've called too many times,

466
00:39:48,591 --> 00:39:50,923
call once more.
[Laughs]

467
00:39:50,993 --> 00:39:54,019
Have a great time.

468
00:39:54,096 --> 00:39:56,189
Thanks, Mom.

469
00:39:58,401 --> 00:40:00,335
[Sighs]

470
00:40:02,104 --> 00:40:05,335
- Hi. So what was that all about?
- Hey.

471
00:40:05,408 --> 00:40:07,342
She changed her mind
about Yosemite.

472
00:40:07,410 --> 00:40:09,435
- [Bell Rings]
- So now you're goin'?

473
00:40:09,512 --> 00:40:11,446
Ah, I wouldn't say that.

474
00:40:11,514 --> 00:40:13,448
[Excited Chattering]

475
00:40:30,366 --> 00:40:33,130
I don't know.
If we were at the midterm...

476
00:40:34,236 --> 00:40:36,170
No, she's doing fine.

477
00:40:36,238 --> 00:40:39,366
No...

478
00:40:43,312 --> 00:40:46,770
Mrs. Cheney,
can I call you right back?

479
00:40:58,527 --> 00:41:01,291
[Students Yelling, Laughing]

480
00:41:07,002 --> 00:41:10,335
- Uh, oh! Oh!
- Damn it!

481
00:41:10,406 --> 00:41:14,604
Oh, Miss Tate, I'm-I'm so sorry.
L-I didn't mean to make you jump.

482
00:41:14,677 --> 00:41:18,135
- It's okay.
- Well, it's Halloween.
I guess everyone...

483
00:41:18,214 --> 00:41:20,580
- is entitled to one good scare.
- [Sighs]

484
00:41:20,649 --> 00:41:25,348
- I've had my share.
- U-Uh, Miss Tate,

485
00:41:25,421 --> 00:41:28,015
I know it's not my place.

486
00:41:28,090 --> 00:41:32,026
If I could be maternal
for a moment,

487
00:41:32,094 --> 00:41:34,858
I don't like
to see you like this.

488
00:41:34,930 --> 00:41:38,331
I've seen you
like this before, and...

489
00:41:38,401 --> 00:41:41,893
we've all had bad
things happen to us.

490
00:41:41,971 --> 00:41:45,668
The trick is
to concentrate on today!

491
00:41:47,810 --> 00:41:49,744
What do I know?

492
00:41:49,812 --> 00:41:53,942
You just take care
of yourself, okay?

493
00:41:54,016 --> 00:41:56,314
Thank you very much.
I'll see you Monday.

494
00:42:02,625 --> 00:42:05,992
Oh! Mi-Miss Tate,
uh, Happy Halloween.

495
00:42:17,673 --> 00:42:20,540
[Car Door Slams]

496
00:42:20,609 --> 00:42:23,237
[Motor Starts]

497
00:42:56,245 --> 00:42:58,213
[Motor Starts, Revs]

498
00:43:05,821 --> 00:43:08,813
"She took off her clothes,
revealing her satiny-soft femininity.

499
00:43:08,891 --> 00:43:10,984
And Lawrence looked at her
with lust in his eyes...

500
00:43:11,060 --> 00:43:14,427
and said, 'I want to invade
every part of your being.

501
00:43:14,497 --> 00:43:17,591
I want to tantalize myself
with your sweet nectar.'"

502
00:43:17,666 --> 00:43:19,600
Old Tanya better not
fall for that shit.

503
00:43:19,668 --> 00:43:23,035
- I smell that a mile away.
- " And Tanya laughed at him.

504
00:43:23,105 --> 00:43:25,096
'You don't expect me to fall
for that shit,' she said."

505
00:43:25,174 --> 00:43:28,007
[Laughing] That's right,
make her smart. That's it.

506
00:43:28,077 --> 00:43:30,102
- [Car Driving Up]
- Oh, shit, honey, someone's here.
Can I call you back?

507
00:43:30,179 --> 00:43:32,340
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. I'll hold on.
I wanna know what stupid line...

508
00:43:32,414 --> 00:43:35,144
- Tanya falls for.
- The same one you did. Hold on a second.

509
00:43:46,495 --> 00:43:49,862
- Hello!
- [Engine Chugging]

510
00:43:49,932 --> 00:43:51,866
Hello!

511
00:43:56,639 --> 00:43:59,267
[Beeping, Mechanical Whirring]

512
00:44:24,199 --> 00:44:26,292
[Engine Shuts Off]

513
00:44:42,251 --> 00:44:44,446
[Beeping, Mechanical Whirring]

514
00:44:54,857 --> 00:44:56,791
- Hey, honey.
- What's up? Where did you go?

515
00:44:56,859 --> 00:44:59,953
I don't know. Some car at the gate.
I'm gonna have to call you.

516
00:45:18,347 --> 00:45:20,611
- Hey.
- Wait, wait. What's goin' on, baby?

517
00:45:20,683 --> 00:45:23,413
- I don't know.
- [Tapping At Window]

518
00:45:23,486 --> 00:45:25,716
Honey... Where'd you...
[Clicks Tongue] Ronny!

519
00:45:25,788 --> 00:45:29,019
You always fuckin' doin' this. You get
me goin', and then you gotta go. Ro...

520
00:45:29,091 --> 00:45:31,025
[Line Clicks]

521
00:45:31,093 --> 00:45:33,584
Hello?

522
00:45:33,663 --> 00:45:35,790
[Clicking Phone Hook]

523
00:46:00,423 --> 00:46:02,357
[Clattering]

524
00:47:06,422 --> 00:47:08,287
- Aah!
- Oh! [Chuckles]

525
00:47:08,357 --> 00:47:10,791
I keep scaring you today.

526
00:47:10,860 --> 00:47:13,693
Wh-What are you doing?

527
00:47:13,763 --> 00:47:16,698
[Panting] Uh, n...

528
00:47:18,601 --> 00:47:21,627
Nothing. I, um...

529
00:47:21,704 --> 00:47:23,638
What are you doing?

530
00:47:23,706 --> 00:47:26,800
I'm making the rounds. I still
have to check on the kids, but...

531
00:47:26,876 --> 00:47:30,744
I was hoping I would have the honor of
spending the evening with you tonight.

532
00:47:33,249 --> 00:47:35,183
I'd like the company.

533
00:47:35,251 --> 00:47:38,550
- Give me 20.
- Okay.

534
00:47:38,621 --> 00:47:40,555
I'm okay.

535
00:47:56,739 --> 00:47:58,934
Hello?

536
00:47:59,008 --> 00:48:03,342
[Man On Phone]
Do you want to die tonight, Cici?

537
00:48:03,412 --> 00:48:07,712
- [Knocking On Door]
- Oh, uh, come on... in.

538
00:48:09,618 --> 00:48:11,779
Sarah, Molly.

539
00:48:11,854 --> 00:48:16,052
Just checking on the Hillcrest remains.
You girls okay?

540
00:48:16,125 --> 00:48:19,424
- Good. Thanks, Mr. Brennan.
- And how are you, Mr. Brennan?
Looking cute as ever.

541
00:48:19,495 --> 00:48:21,963
Thank you, Sarah.
What are you two up to tonight?

542
00:48:22,031 --> 00:48:24,556
Well, we thought we'd hit the town,
pick up some guys.

543
00:48:24,633 --> 00:48:27,466
You know, drop some Roofies in their
drinks. Have a whole date-rape evening.

544
00:48:27,536 --> 00:48:29,868
- Oh. Sounds good.
- Care to join us?

545
00:48:29,939 --> 00:48:32,737
I can't. I'm, uh, I'm having
my nipples pierced.

546
00:48:32,808 --> 00:48:35,038
- Oh.
- But you two have a good time.

547
00:48:35,111 --> 00:48:38,137
- Will do.
- If you need anything,
contact me or Miss Tate.

548
00:48:38,214 --> 00:48:40,307
- Okay?
- Thanks, Mr. Brennan.

549
00:48:40,383 --> 00:48:42,044
Behave.

550
00:48:42,118 --> 00:48:45,554
- [Door Closes]
- My stash. Come on.

551
00:48:48,591 --> 00:48:53,051
- Come on.
- All right. Send it through here.

552
00:48:53,129 --> 00:48:55,154
[Rustling Sound]

553
00:48:55,231 --> 00:48:57,131
Come on, man. Let's go.

554
00:48:58,501 --> 00:49:00,469
Yeah.

555
00:49:00,536 --> 00:49:02,470
Come on.

556
00:49:03,539 --> 00:49:06,440
John.
[Laughs]

557
00:49:06,509 --> 00:49:08,636
Come on!

558
00:49:08,711 --> 00:49:13,171
I got you.
[Laughing]

559
00:49:27,630 --> 00:49:29,564
[Sighs]

560
00:49:43,212 --> 00:49:45,146
[Sighs]

561
00:49:46,315 --> 00:49:48,249
[Sighs Deeply]

562
00:49:53,255 --> 00:49:55,086
- [Spits]
- [Car Door Closes]

563
00:49:55,157 --> 00:49:57,591
[Exhales, Chuckles]

564
00:49:57,660 --> 00:49:59,594
Fuck it.

565
00:50:01,163 --> 00:50:03,393
[Knocking On Door]

566
00:50:09,772 --> 00:50:11,637
I thought we'd do this right.

567
00:50:11,707 --> 00:50:13,641
Come on in.

568
00:50:17,313 --> 00:50:20,339
Oh, I love food.
I really do.

569
00:50:20,416 --> 00:50:23,249
I hope you don't mind
if I get really big and dumpy.

570
00:50:23,319 --> 00:50:25,287
- It's my goal in life.
- Oh, no.

571
00:50:25,354 --> 00:50:28,755
I, uh, I always found obesity
to be very sexy.

572
00:50:28,824 --> 00:50:31,190
God, you are so Renaissance.

573
00:50:31,260 --> 00:50:34,195
♪♪ [Woman Singing, Faint]

574
00:50:42,705 --> 00:50:45,435
Oh, the buffet has arrived!

575
00:50:45,508 --> 00:50:47,976
Ah, for your pleasure tonight,

576
00:50:48,043 --> 00:50:52,639
we have prepared Wednesday, Thursday and
Friday's Hillcrest dinner selections,

577
00:50:52,715 --> 00:50:55,275
ignoring Meat Loaf Monday
and Turkey Tuesday.

578
00:50:55,351 --> 00:50:58,684
- Thank you very much.
I hate that meat loaf.
- Where's the booze?

579
00:50:58,754 --> 00:51:01,746
- [John] We need a corkscrew for that.
- Oh, I'll go get it.

580
00:51:01,824 --> 00:51:05,487
- Just don't start anything without me.
- [Sarah] Don't worry.

581
00:51:06,595 --> 00:51:09,530
♪♪ [Singing Continues]

582
00:51:30,391 --> 00:51:33,326
I'm not who you think I am.

583
00:51:34,895 --> 00:51:36,829
Okay.

584
00:51:36,897 --> 00:51:38,831
Who are you?

585
00:51:41,635 --> 00:51:44,160
My name's not Keri Tate.

586
00:51:44,238 --> 00:51:47,332
Mmm. [Chuckles]

587
00:51:47,408 --> 00:51:49,342
What is it?

588
00:51:51,311 --> 00:51:53,677
Laurie Strode.

589
00:51:53,747 --> 00:51:56,511
[Wheezing Laugh]

590
00:51:57,651 --> 00:51:59,676
- Strode?
- Strode.

591
00:51:59,753 --> 00:52:02,119
Okay.

592
00:52:02,189 --> 00:52:04,953
I changed my name
when I went into hiding.

593
00:52:05,025 --> 00:52:08,927
Oh, I like that.
That's like... like the...
like the witness protection program.

594
00:52:08,996 --> 00:52:12,295
What, did you like rat out
the mob or something?

595
00:52:12,366 --> 00:52:15,130
[Kissing]

596
00:52:15,202 --> 00:52:18,638
My brother killed my sister...

597
00:52:18,705 --> 00:52:21,037
- when she was 17.
- Wow.

598
00:52:21,108 --> 00:52:24,077
Well, that's..."sucky."

599
00:52:24,144 --> 00:52:26,112
[Both Laughing]

600
00:52:26,180 --> 00:52:28,080
How'd he do that?

601
00:52:28,148 --> 00:52:31,311
With a really big,
sharp kitchen knife.

602
00:52:31,385 --> 00:52:33,751
That's terrible.

603
00:52:33,821 --> 00:52:35,755
Take off your clothes.

604
00:52:35,823 --> 00:52:37,848
You said you'd listen.

605
00:52:37,925 --> 00:52:40,723
[Sighs]
Okay.

606
00:52:45,299 --> 00:52:48,393
They locked him up
for a long time,

607
00:52:48,469 --> 00:52:51,905
but he got out and...

608
00:52:51,972 --> 00:52:54,566
he came after me,

609
00:52:54,641 --> 00:52:57,405
but I got away.

610
00:52:57,478 --> 00:53:01,039
But he killed
a lot of my friends.

611
00:53:02,749 --> 00:53:07,186
- It happened...
- [Together] On Halloween.

612
00:53:07,254 --> 00:53:10,348
- You've heard the story.
- Who hasn't?

613
00:53:11,758 --> 00:53:14,591
Michael Myers.

614
00:53:14,661 --> 00:53:17,255
It's like 20 years ago, right?

615
00:53:17,331 --> 00:53:20,027
1978.

616
00:53:20,100 --> 00:53:23,092
And the girl that... What happened
to the sister? She died, right?

617
00:53:25,606 --> 00:53:28,370
No, she faked her death.

618
00:53:30,611 --> 00:53:32,738
And now she's the headmistress...

619
00:53:32,813 --> 00:53:36,408
of a very posh, secluded
private school in northern California.

620
00:53:36,483 --> 00:53:38,713
What?

621
00:53:38,785 --> 00:53:41,219
Hoping and praying every year...

622
00:53:43,290 --> 00:53:45,656
that her brother won't find her.

623
00:53:45,726 --> 00:53:48,160
You're tellin' me the truth?

624
00:53:51,098 --> 00:53:54,465
- Now do you want a drink?
- Yeah.

625
00:53:54,535 --> 00:53:56,503
I'll be right back.

626
00:54:07,748 --> 00:54:10,512
Explains a lot, doesn't it?

627
00:54:10,584 --> 00:54:14,247
So you... you have been living
with this for 20 years?

628
00:54:14,321 --> 00:54:17,518
[Clears Throat]
Something like that.

629
00:54:17,591 --> 00:54:20,424
But honey, you-you don't...

630
00:54:20,494 --> 00:54:22,928
You don't think that
after all this time h-he'd...

631
00:54:22,996 --> 00:54:26,159
he'd still be comin'
after you, do you?

632
00:54:27,834 --> 00:54:31,531
He sat in a sanitarium
for 15 years, waiting for me.

633
00:54:33,206 --> 00:54:35,140
And then...

634
00:54:37,277 --> 00:54:41,475
one rainy night, he decides
to go trick-or-treating.

635
00:54:47,754 --> 00:54:49,688
How old were you?

636
00:54:56,196 --> 00:54:58,130
Seventeen.

637
00:55:00,934 --> 00:55:02,868
What?

638
00:55:04,504 --> 00:55:08,099
Do you think they made it to Yosemite?
Do you think they're there?

639
00:55:08,175 --> 00:55:12,509
- I don't know.
- I just... I just want
to call Johnny. Just...

640
00:55:15,749 --> 00:55:18,309
What is it?
Keri, what are you doing?

641
00:55:18,385 --> 00:55:20,319
My phone's dead.

642
00:55:24,191 --> 00:55:26,125
Shit.

643
00:55:36,837 --> 00:55:40,034
- What's goin' on?
- Somebody didn't go to Yosemite.

644
00:55:40,107 --> 00:55:42,268
Keri. Uh, what are you doing?

645
00:55:42,342 --> 00:55:45,539
- I'm just gonna go find John.
- Th... This is nuts.

646
00:55:45,612 --> 00:55:48,046
I hope so.

647
00:55:48,915 --> 00:55:51,850
- Jesus!
- Christ!

648
00:55:51,918 --> 00:55:54,011
[Panting]
Ronny, the phones are out.

649
00:55:54,087 --> 00:55:57,113
I know, and there's a strange car
parked down at the gate,

650
00:55:57,190 --> 00:55:59,886
but I can't seem to find
any signs of trespassing.

651
00:55:59,960 --> 00:56:02,827
- Fuck.
- Okay, th-there's no reason
to get upset yet.

652
00:56:02,896 --> 00:56:05,160
Let's just calm down.

653
00:56:05,232 --> 00:56:07,632
Look, I'm gonna go look
for John and the kids.

654
00:56:07,701 --> 00:56:11,467
See if you can get the phones
working, and we'll meet back
at the gate, okay? Come on.

655
00:56:13,874 --> 00:56:15,933
Charlie!

656
00:56:16,009 --> 00:56:18,307
Charlie?

657
00:56:18,378 --> 00:56:21,347
Where are you, Charlie?
We're waiting on you.

658
00:56:23,250 --> 00:56:26,014
Charlie.

659
00:56:26,086 --> 00:56:28,520
Inconsiderate,
party of one,

660
00:56:28,588 --> 00:56:30,852
your table's ready.

661
00:56:35,062 --> 00:56:36,996
Charlie?

662
00:56:43,537 --> 00:56:45,664
Hi! Gotcha.

663
00:56:45,739 --> 00:56:47,673
You shit.

664
00:56:47,741 --> 00:56:50,369
I found these,
but no corkscrew.

665
00:56:50,444 --> 00:56:53,811
Come on. I'm hungry!
Where are you going now?

666
00:56:53,880 --> 00:56:56,348
To see if there's
a corkscrew upstairs.

667
00:56:56,416 --> 00:56:58,646
- I'll be right back.
- [Ringing]

668
00:56:58,719 --> 00:57:01,882
- Charlie.
- [Door Shuts]

669
00:57:04,998 --> 00:57:07,432
[Creaking]

670
00:57:26,052 --> 00:57:28,020
[Sighs]

671
00:57:32,492 --> 00:57:34,426
Shit.

672
00:57:37,163 --> 00:57:39,688
[Motor Roaring, Metal Clattering]

673
00:58:18,271 --> 00:58:20,705
Hi.

674
00:58:34,721 --> 00:58:37,747
[Electricity Crackling]

675
00:58:46,299 --> 00:58:48,893
- [Latch Rattling]
- Shit.

676
00:58:49,969 --> 00:58:52,335
Lights up, Charlie.

677
00:58:52,405 --> 00:58:55,340
No sex games
till I've eaten.

678
00:58:59,846 --> 00:59:01,780
Fuck.

679
00:59:02,515 --> 00:59:04,949
[Rattling Sound]

680
00:59:06,586 --> 00:59:08,520
[Thudding]

681
00:59:12,492 --> 00:59:15,222
[Chuckles]
Charlie.

682
00:59:15,295 --> 00:59:18,196
Charlie, what are you...
[Screams]

683
00:59:19,499 --> 00:59:21,467
Oh, shit!
Oh, my God!

684
00:59:23,870 --> 00:59:25,599
No!

685
00:59:27,440 --> 00:59:29,738
Oh, my...
[Gasping]

686
00:59:32,011 --> 00:59:33,740
[Rings]

687
00:59:34,847 --> 00:59:37,077
Aaah!

688
00:59:42,822 --> 00:59:45,757
[Crying]

689
00:59:46,960 --> 00:59:48,894
Oh!

690
00:59:55,401 --> 00:59:57,995
- Oh! [Moaning]
- [Material Rips]

691
00:59:58,071 --> 01:00:01,438
[Grunting]

692
01:00:07,747 --> 01:00:10,580
[Screams, Grunts]

693
01:00:18,825 --> 01:00:22,454
[Stereo: Man Singing]
♪ They're laid to rest before ♪♪

694
01:00:22,528 --> 01:00:25,429
- Did you hear that?
- No. What was that?

695
01:00:25,498 --> 01:00:27,432
♪♪ [Off]

696
01:00:28,935 --> 01:00:31,096
I'm gonna go check
on those guys.

697
01:00:31,170 --> 01:00:33,365
They've been gone
for a while.

698
01:00:33,439 --> 01:00:35,532
- What do you think they're doin'?
- Hmm.

699
01:00:35,608 --> 01:00:38,042
- Mm-hmm.
- Kind of rates a cheap scare,
doesn't it?

700
01:00:38,111 --> 01:00:40,045
- Let's go.
- All right.

701
01:00:42,115 --> 01:00:45,050
[Moaning]

702
01:00:52,058 --> 01:00:55,550
Oh, fuck!

703
01:00:55,628 --> 01:00:57,653
Please.

704
01:01:06,472 --> 01:01:09,236
Oh, please!
[Groans]

705
01:01:32,432 --> 01:01:35,924
- Hello!
- Maybe they just skipped to dessert.

706
01:01:36,002 --> 01:01:38,368
- [Chuckles]
- [Squishing]

707
01:01:38,438 --> 01:01:40,565
- What the hell's that?
- Oh, man.

708
01:01:43,409 --> 01:01:45,343
What the fuck?

709
01:01:56,155 --> 01:01:58,715
This is a sick joke.

710
01:02:13,940 --> 01:02:16,374
[Hinges Squeaking]

711
01:02:17,977 --> 01:02:21,071
[Liquid Dripping]

712
01:02:21,147 --> 01:02:23,047
[Electricity Crackling]

713
01:02:23,116 --> 01:02:26,779
- [Screams]
- Oh, shit!

714
01:02:26,853 --> 01:02:30,482
[Whimpering]
Who's that?

715
01:02:30,556 --> 01:02:33,116
- Let's get out of here.
- [Molly Screams]

716
01:02:33,192 --> 01:02:36,025
Keep moving. Keep moving!

717
01:02:37,430 --> 01:02:40,160
Go. Go.

718
01:02:40,233 --> 01:02:42,360
- Go.
- Come on!

719
01:02:50,343 --> 01:02:52,937
- Come on!
- John, please!

720
01:02:53,012 --> 01:02:55,606
Oh, God. Oh, God.
What the fuck are we gonna do?

721
01:02:55,681 --> 01:02:58,946
We go to the dorms, and we're gonna
call the cops. Okay?

722
01:02:59,018 --> 01:03:01,680
- Come on.
- [Screams]

723
01:03:01,754 --> 01:03:04,154
Oh, my God!
Oh, no, please!

724
01:03:04,223 --> 01:03:06,783
[Screaming]

725
01:03:10,763 --> 01:03:12,822
Aaah!

726
01:03:15,768 --> 01:03:17,668
[Grunts]
Come on!

727
01:03:17,737 --> 01:03:20,297
Come on. Come on.

728
01:03:30,283 --> 01:03:33,030
Get up.

729
01:03:39,837 --> 01:03:41,964
[Grunting]

730
01:03:42,039 --> 01:03:43,973
Oh! My keys.

731
01:03:44,041 --> 01:03:46,669
- Fuck! Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, my God.
- Come on. Come on.

732
01:03:46,744 --> 01:03:49,941
I can't find it! Oh, God.

733
01:03:50,014 --> 01:03:52,346
- Find the fucking keys!
- I know!

734
01:03:54,519 --> 01:03:57,488
Fuck!

735
01:03:57,555 --> 01:04:00,683
Oh... shit!

736
01:04:01,959 --> 01:04:03,984
- [Grunts]
- Molly!

737
01:04:04,061 --> 01:04:05,892
- [Screams]
- Molly!

738
01:04:05,963 --> 01:04:08,227
- No!
- Molly!

739
01:04:10,701 --> 01:04:13,864
[Whimpering]

740
01:04:18,976 --> 01:04:21,638
Somebody open
the fucking door!

741
01:04:21,712 --> 01:04:24,374
[Molly Screaming]

742
01:04:25,616 --> 01:04:28,141
[Panting]
Oh, my God!

743
01:04:28,219 --> 01:04:31,916
- [Both Screaming]
- Somebody open the door!

744
01:04:57,281 --> 01:04:59,340
- [Molly Panting]
- What happened?

745
01:04:59,417 --> 01:05:01,681
- Oh, God, he's stabbed.
- Can you walk?
- Yeah.

746
01:05:01,752 --> 01:05:04,380
- Oh, God.
- [Molly Crying]

747
01:05:08,793 --> 01:05:10,954
- Wait.
- Who was that?

748
01:05:13,030 --> 01:05:14,964
My brother.

749
01:05:20,838 --> 01:05:23,932
Get in there.
Barricade the door. Lock it.

750
01:05:24,008 --> 01:05:26,442
- Do as I say, now!
- [Will] Go.

751
01:05:26,510 --> 01:05:28,978
Go!

752
01:05:29,046 --> 01:05:31,276
All right, what do we do?
What do we do?

753
01:05:31,349 --> 01:05:33,283
Try to live.

754
01:05:44,395 --> 01:05:46,226
- [Panting] Go.
- What?

755
01:05:46,297 --> 01:05:48,231
- Jump. Go!
- Keri.

756
01:05:48,299 --> 01:05:51,097
- I'm not leaving you.
- I'm not leaving John.

757
01:05:53,638 --> 01:05:55,765
Keri!

758
01:06:02,480 --> 01:06:04,448
[Laurie Panting]

759
01:06:10,421 --> 01:06:12,912
Oh.

760
01:06:16,827 --> 01:06:19,921
[Crying]
Oh, no!

761
01:06:19,997 --> 01:06:21,487
Oh! Oh, God!

762
01:06:23,234 --> 01:06:25,600
Oh, God. Oh, no.

763
01:06:25,670 --> 01:06:29,197
- Oh.
- [Crying]

764
01:06:31,242 --> 01:06:34,268
Oh, God. Oh.
I thought...

765
01:06:34,345 --> 01:06:37,678
- Will!
- [Grunts]

766
01:06:37,748 --> 01:06:42,208
- [Flesh Ripping]
- [Groaning]

767
01:06:55,800 --> 01:06:58,166
Oh, fuck!

768
01:07:19,790 --> 01:07:22,122
Open up! It's me!

769
01:07:22,193 --> 01:07:24,286
- Open up!
- Oh, my God!

770
01:07:24,361 --> 01:07:26,955
Go. Go!

771
01:07:36,941 --> 01:07:39,739
[Laurie]
Run! Run!

772
01:07:40,878 --> 01:07:42,812
Run!

773
01:07:46,784 --> 01:07:49,719
Oh, my God!
[Crying]

774
01:07:54,325 --> 01:07:56,589
Shit!

775
01:07:56,660 --> 01:07:59,026
[Molly Whimpering]
Come on.

776
01:07:59,096 --> 01:08:00,859
[Laurie]
Go! Now!

777
01:08:08,606 --> 01:08:11,097
Mom!

778
01:08:12,343 --> 01:08:15,073
[Engine Stalling]

779
01:08:15,146 --> 01:08:17,307
- Mom!
- [Engine Starts]

780
01:08:17,381 --> 01:08:20,407
[Molly Screams]
Oh, my God!

781
01:08:20,484 --> 01:08:23,078
[Tires Screech]

782
01:08:29,093 --> 01:08:31,027
[Tires Screech]

783
01:08:33,330 --> 01:08:35,264
[Beeping]

784
01:08:37,535 --> 01:08:39,400
Miss Tate, come on!

785
01:08:39,470 --> 01:08:42,098
- [Crying]
- Go.

786
01:08:43,207 --> 01:08:45,937
- What?
- Go!

787
01:08:46,010 --> 01:08:48,911
I want you to drive down
the street to the Becker's.

788
01:08:48,979 --> 01:08:51,812
It's a mile down the road. Tell them
to call an ambulance and get the police.

789
01:08:51,882 --> 01:08:55,045
- No, we're not leaving you.
- Do as I say, now!

790
01:08:55,119 --> 01:08:57,246
- Mom?
- I'll be right behind you.

791
01:08:57,321 --> 01:09:00,552
- Mom!
- I'll be right behind you. Go!

792
01:09:05,729 --> 01:09:09,300
- [Beeping]
- [Gate Closing]

793
01:09:49,440 --> 01:09:51,601
[Screaming]
Michael!

794
01:09:55,013 --> 01:09:56,947
Michael!

795
01:10:01,186 --> 01:10:03,279
[Door Closes]

796
01:10:06,024 --> 01:10:07,958
Michael?

797
01:11:08,686 --> 01:11:10,984
[Panting]

798
01:11:11,055 --> 01:11:13,080
[Metallic Sound]

799
01:11:16,494 --> 01:11:18,428
[Creaking Noise]

800
01:11:35,313 --> 01:11:37,747
Ohh!

801
01:13:11,009 --> 01:13:13,409
[Yelling]

802
01:14:27,652 --> 01:14:30,348
[Grunting]

803
01:14:39,797 --> 01:14:42,459
- He's dead. He's dead. H-He's dead.
- No. No.

804
01:14:42,533 --> 01:14:46,060
- Shh, shh, shh, shh. He's dead.
- [Grunting]

805
01:14:46,137 --> 01:14:49,800
He's dead, gone.
Shh, shh. Shh.

806
01:15:04,655 --> 01:15:07,920
[People Chattering]

807
01:15:07,992 --> 01:15:11,928
I got it! Hey, baby,
I'm gonna write a romantic thriller!

808
01:15:11,996 --> 01:15:14,021
- What?
- Yeah, a thriller.

809
01:15:14,098 --> 01:15:17,590
- I love you.
- I love you too, baby.

810
01:15:17,668 --> 01:15:21,104
Yeah! I'm fine.
The bullet just grazed me.

811
01:15:37,321 --> 01:15:39,289
Don't move.

812
01:15:39,357 --> 01:15:41,791
Load him in!
Shut the door!

813
01:15:41,859 --> 01:15:44,794
- Hey, hey! Wait a minute.
- You, move!

814
01:15:49,534 --> 01:15:53,334
[Man]
Watch out!

815
01:16:34,526 --> 01:16:37,393
[Engine Revving]

816
01:17:23,175 --> 01:17:25,609
Come on.

817
01:17:27,846 --> 01:17:29,677
Come on. Get up.

818
01:17:39,825 --> 01:17:42,259
[Tires Screeching]

819
01:18:16,862 --> 01:18:18,796
[Groaning]

820
01:19:21,693 --> 01:19:25,322
Michael?

821
01:19:25,397 --> 01:19:27,331
Michael?

822
01:19:32,738 --> 01:19:34,672
Michael!

823
01:20:23,021 --> 01:20:24,852
[Grunts]

824
01:20:32,631 --> 01:20:35,566
[Sirens Approaching]

825
01:20:36,868 --> 01:20:39,302
[Panting]

826
01:21:52,093 --> 01:21:56,257
♪ Hurray for a child ♪

827
01:21:56,330 --> 01:21:58,389
♪ That makes it through ♪

828
01:21:58,466 --> 01:22:02,368
♪ If there's any way because ♪

829
01:22:02,436 --> 01:22:05,303
♪ The answer lies in you ♪

830
01:22:05,373 --> 01:22:09,207
♪ They're laid to rest before ♪

831
01:22:09,276 --> 01:22:12,177
♪ They've known just what to do ♪

832
01:22:12,246 --> 01:22:15,545
♪ Their souls are lost because ♪

833
01:22:15,616 --> 01:22:19,108
♪ They could never find ♪

834
01:22:19,186 --> 01:22:25,819
♪ What's this life for ♪

835
01:22:25,893 --> 01:22:32,662
♪ What's this life for ♪

836
01:22:32,733 --> 01:22:39,366
♪ What's this life for ♪

837
01:22:39,440 --> 01:22:45,538
♪ What's this life for ♪

838
01:22:54,755 --> 01:22:58,156
♪ I see your soul
It's kind of gray ♪

839
01:22:58,225 --> 01:23:01,592
♪ You see my heart, you look away ♪

840
01:23:01,662 --> 01:23:04,961
♪ You see my wrist, I know your pain ♪

841
01:23:05,032 --> 01:23:08,263
♪ I know your purpose on your plane ♪

842
01:23:08,335 --> 01:23:11,668
♪ Don't say a last prayer because ♪

843
01:23:11,739 --> 01:23:15,038
♪ You could never find ♪

844
01:23:15,109 --> 01:23:21,708
♪ What's this life for ♪

845
01:23:21,782 --> 01:23:28,381
♪ What's this life for ♪

846
01:23:28,456 --> 01:23:35,225
♪ What's this life for ♪

847
01:23:35,296 --> 01:23:41,064
♪ What's this life for ♪

848
01:23:43,471 --> 01:23:46,963
♪ But they ain't here anymore ♪

849
01:23:50,411 --> 01:23:53,744
♪ Don't have to settle the score ♪

850
01:23:58,285 --> 01:24:00,753
♪ 'Cause we all live ♪

851
01:24:00,821 --> 01:24:03,756
♪ Under the reign ♪

852
01:24:03,824 --> 01:24:06,520
♪ I say, you know of the one king ♪

853
01:24:06,594 --> 01:24:10,291
♪ One king, one king ♪

854
01:24:10,364 --> 01:24:12,855
♪ But they ain't here anymore ♪

855
01:24:17,004 --> 01:24:20,371
♪ Don't have to settle
no goddamn score ♪

856
01:24:24,612 --> 01:24:27,206
♪ 'Cause we all live ♪

857
01:24:27,281 --> 01:24:30,045
♪ Under the reign ♪

858
01:24:30,117 --> 01:24:32,779
♪ I said, you know, of the one king ♪

859
01:24:32,853 --> 01:24:36,653
♪ One king, one king ♪

860
01:24:36,724 --> 01:24:39,056
♪ But they ain't here anymore ♪

861
01:24:43,130 --> 01:24:46,395
♪ Don't have to settle
no goddamn score ♪

862
01:24:50,805 --> 01:24:55,640
♪ 'Cause we all live under the reign ♪

863
01:24:57,077 --> 01:25:01,844
♪ Of one king ♪♪


