(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
(Episode 1711)
This is Entertainment Weekly, and I am Shin Hyun Joon.
Hello, I am Jung Ji Won.
It's Friday night of the first week in April.
This week, many things happened...
in the entertainment world.
Among them was the performances held by South Korean artists...
on the 1st and 3rd in Pyongyang to promote peaceful cooperation...
between North and South Korea.
Right. I was really touched watching their performance yesterday.
We'll talk about it today, right?
Yes. We'll see them united by music in a bit.
All right. Here's the first news.
Anchor Kim Sun Keun prepared it.
This Week's Hot Click.
The late Jang Ja Yeon case...
and the suicide of the sisters who were extras,
are being reinvestigated.
Entertainment Weekly will report on these cases.
We'll report on Kim Saeng Min's sexual harassment case...
and Kim Heung Kook's police investigation...
for his sexual harassment allegations as well.
The disclosure that Kim Saeng Min committed sexual harassment...
in the past has shocked the nation.
The controversy started with a media report on Monday.
(Ms. A claims to have been sexually harassed 10 years ago.)
The media exclusively reported an interview with Ms. A,
who claims that Saeng Min sexually harassed her 10 years ago.
(He put his arms around me. I pushed him, but it was useless.)
(No matter how much I resisted I couldn't beat his strength.)
The report says that on a day of a get-together for a program,
two victims were sexually harassed,
and Ms. A, the informant, didn't get an apology from him.
Right after the report, Kim's agency officially announced...
that he admits what happened and apologizes.
However, as he had an honest and hard working image more than anyone,
the disclosure this time was a big shock to the public.
After that, the criticism towards Kim did not stop.
The public opinion wanted him to drop out of all the shows he's in,
and on last Tuesday, the next day after the report,
he clarified his official position that he would resign...
from every program he's in now.
The programs that he is currently on also announced that...
on top of his resignation, the programs will be stopped,
edited, or pre-empted.
Kim has long been working as a reporter in Entertainment Weekly.
After the controversy, he stated that he would resign.
Entertainment Weekly accepted his opinion,
and decided to have him step down from the program.
(Saeng Min also resigned from Entertainment Weekly.)
He had his first glory day since his debut, 25 years ago.
His flower road lasted only for six months.
His wrongdoing 10 years ago caught up with him.
It seemed that he would drive on without a stop,
but he resigned from every show his heyday was over so suddenly.
In addition, as he decided to stop working due to a scandal,
his responsibility on dozens of commercials he had appeared in...
before the controversy remains.
Saeng Min admitted that he committed sexual harassment...
and apologized to the victim and the public.
All eyes are on his position now.
Last Monday, the Committee on Past Affairs of prosecution...
selected the late Jang Ja Yeon case...
and the suicide of the sisters who were extras...
to be reinvestigated.
Nine years ago, the late Jang Ja Yeon committed suicide...
after leaving a note saying she gave sexual favors to figures...
in the financial and the media world.
In regard to all suspicions concerning the late Jang Ja Yeon,
we'll make a thorough investigation and get to the bottom of the matter.
During the initial investigation, the police said they would...
do a thorough investigation regardless of one's rank.
However,
It was hard to investigate him as his wife was a prosecutor.
He wouldn't make an appearance.
The investigation on influential people beat around the bush.
Including a journalist who said he mistook Ja Yeon as a hostess,
many of those under suspicion...
were not reinvestigated or cross-examined at all.
There are people whom we didn't investigate.
From A's testimony, we found nothing to investigate those people.
That's why we didn't investigate them.
The investigator kept changing his words.
Thus resulting in suspicion that he was pressured to close the case.
I admit it was my fault.
Many of you are suspicious that I received pressure...
for changing my statement from what I had said earlier,
but it's not true at all.
So, there was a controversy on the poor investigation on the case.
The public was resentful.
Finally, all of those charged for receiving sexual favor...
were cleared of the charges, and the case was closed.
The case was exempted from the prior investigation last February.
But as the public gained interest due to the MeToo Campaign,
it was selected as a subject of the secondary investigation.
(228,798 people participated in the petition.)
The Committee on Past Affairs stated that they will find out...
if there was a problem with the conclusion that...
the former CEO was not guilty of coercion,
and whether or not there was pressure on the investigation.
Then can the Committee on Past Affairs exercise legal punishment?
A lot amount of time has passed,
so statute of limitations is an issue.
Also, it will be hard to get evidence to support the case.
However, depending which crime the investigation identifies,
the statute of limitations can be different.
Regarding the law on punishment of assisting prostitution,
if the prostitution was utilized by relationships of employment...
or forced by assault or threat,
one can be sentenced to 10 years of imprisonment.
Thus, the statute of limitations is 10 years.
As the statute of limitations is not over in this case,
the possibility of a criminal charge still exists.
The public is keeping their eye on whether the truth behind...
her decision to end her life in 2009 will be revealed.
(What is the truth?)
Please sign the petition.
There's another case that came to the fore with MeToo campaign,
It's the suicide case of the sisters who were extras.
Ms. A was recommended to work as a movie extra by her sister,
and began working 14 years ago.
According to Ms. A's record at that time,
from July 2004, when the shooting started, to November 2004,
the casting manager and assistant team leader who managed extras...
raped and sexually harassed her frequently.
(They sexually assaulted me.)
She would hit and break things, so the police came...
and committed her to a mental hospital.
After she was hospitalized, she said she was raped...
and sexually assaulted.
After Ms. A's mother found out the truth,
she filed a lawsuit against 12 people...
for rape and indecent act by compulsion.
However, the inflictors insisted Ms. A consented to it,
and it was not a crime by compulsion.
(I cannot live anymore.)
And after that, Ms. A could not endure her situation...
and made an irreversible choice.
(Ms. A's sister committed suicide six days after her death.)
After Ms. A's death, her sister who recommended the extra work to her...
committed suicide six days after she died.
(The dispute on police's poor investigation was brought up.)
When it was revealed that there was a cross-examination...
between the victim and the assailant,
there was controversy that it was poorly investigated.
This was the court ruling at the time.
They stated that when reviewing the many witness testimonies...
and the investigations of the assailants...
there was a possibility for rape and indecent act by compulsion.
(It is possible she was sexually assaulted by compulsion at work.)
However, the court ruled against Ms. A's mother, and she lost.
Last Monday, the committee announced the reinvestigation.
The police recently organized an investigation team...
to find out the truth behind the sisters' suicide.
(Dismiss the statute of limitations. Please find the truth.)
With a reliable investigation,
there shouldn't be any more unfair deaths in the entertainment world.
I haven't committed sexual harassment or assault.
I have nothing on my conscience. I will answer everything.
Kim Heung Kook was investigated by the police...
after charges were made against him for sexual assault charges.
(Kim Heung Kook was summoned and investigated by the police.)
Suspicions of his sexual assault...
has turned into a war of disclosing truths.
He was summoned for the first investigation...
two weeks after the complaint was filed.
He walked into the police station with a grim face.
We got to hear how he felt at the moment.
I apologize to all of my fans.
I am also very sorry for my beloved family.
My family...
suffered so much,
and I had to leave the industry overnight. It just feels...
I hope the truth gets disclosed today,
and I would like to recover my honor as soon as possible.
I truly apologize.
He also strongly denied his charges of sexual assault.
I have a lot evidence...
and witnesses.
I really did not live to deserve something like this.
I have no idea why this is happening to me.
It's really heartbreaking.
After Heung Kook left for his questioning,
Ms. A's attorney also came forward...
in front of the reporters.
(The victim's attorney came forward.)
Mr. Kim has not once...
apologized to the victim...
and insists that he did nothing wrong.
The victim wants him to look back on himself...
and to sincerely make an apology to her.
The victim, Ms. A claimed through a news media...
that she was sexually assaulted twice by Mr. Kim at the end of 2016.
She accused him of rape, quasi-rape,
and defamation through printed media.
Then Heung Kook denied the charges and filed a suit against her...
for defamation and calumny,
and prepared himself for a legal battle.
Last Tuesday, Mr. B, someone who claimed to be Mr. Kim's old friend,
disclosed his sexual harassment once again in an interview...
and shocked everyone once again.
He disclosed many sexual harassments...
that Heung Kook has committed over the years.
The first incidents were back in 2002 and 2006 World Cup.
He said he used the festive mood to molest women...
while everyone was cheering for the Korean team.
The next incident happened in 2012,
when he molested a part-timer at his cafe,
and the victim's parents ended up...
coming to the cafe to complain.
Heung Kook claimed the disclosure was absurd,
and he has completely denied the allegations.
He claimed to know who the informant is...
and said he made up this story out of personal spite.
He argued that none of this is true.
("Claim Done Out of Personal Spite", "Heung Kook Denies Molesting Women")
We had a chance to hear more from him...
as he walked out from his questioning.
I told everything...
to the investigator.
I had nothing on my conscience,
and I told them everything.
I want to regain my honor as soon as possible,
and I want to sing and be on TV again.
What do you think about additional disclosure from your friend?
That's not even worth refuting.
I think that guy...
turned off his phone and ran away.
It's a scheme that...
he plotted with someone...
to hurt me.
Is there anything else you'd like to say?
I really feel sorry for my family...
and my fans.
I hope something like this would never happen again.
Thank you.
The charges against him of rape...
along with additional disclosure of sexual molestation...
are now in the hands of the legal system.
There is much attention given to the result of this case.
You can't do this. You'll make me look really weird.
Actor Lee Jong Soo is charged with fraud.
On March 28th, one internet news outlet...
reported that Lee is facing a lawsuit for fraud.
His charges were as follows.
Mr. A asked Lee to preside over his wedding...
and sent him 850 dollars for the presiding cost.
However, Jong Soo did not appear on the day of the wedding,
and Mr. A filed a suit against him for fraud.
This case was resolved when someone from his agency...
came out and paid for the damage on his behalf on the 2nd.
However, Lee was nowhere to be seen even after he was charged.
("Lee Will Not Get Any Support", "Lee Has Been Gone for a Week")
Last Tuesday,
another man came forward and claimed Jong Soo swindled him.
(Mr. B claims Lee borrowed 30,000 dollars for business.)
According to Mr. B, Jong Soo borrowed...
30,000 dollars from him for his business.
He said he'd pay back 10,000 dollars a month but did not.
Also, an eyewitness said they saw Jong Soo...
on a flight to Los Angeles.
(A witness saw Lee on a flight to Los Angeles.)
On the 21st, a news outlet said he was reportedly seen...
at a Korean restaurant in Los Angeles.
He has been off the grid for over a week.
("Lee's Agency Will No Longer Support Him")
("Lee Apologizes and Claims He Is Not a Con Man")
Last Tuesday, a news outlet reported...
on what Lee said to his agency when he contacted them.
Lee apologized to the agency...
and showed frustration for all the rumors about him.
His agent said it's true...
that Mr. Lee borrowed 30,000 dollars from Mr. B back in 2017.
She also said he has been paying the interest and principal back,
and showed his bank account statement.
(His agency showed his bank account statement.)
Jong Soo's anxiety could be seen...
in the second email that he sent.
They decided to take legal actions for any rumors.
We will keep our eyes on this to see how the case will be resolved.
Actor Oh Soon Tek﻿, one of the first Korean actors to work in Hollywood,
has passed away at the age of 84.
We heard of this news yesterday.
He passed away at his home in Los Angeles due to chronic disease.
I came to the US because I thought...
it would be great if I can...
study film here.
In 1959, he moved to the US at the age of 25...
and made his career in Hollywood and Broadway for a long time.
He is also remembered as the first Korean actor...
to have made his career in Hollywood.
He starred on the movie, "The Man with the Golden Gun"...
and many other movies, dramas, and plays,
starring in over 200 pieces of work, regardless of the genre.
He was the go-to Asian actor...
in Hollywood during the 70s and the 80s.
He returned to Korea in the early 2000s...
to teach his juniors at a university...
and shared his experience with them.
Although he has left us, the great actor Oh Soon Tek...
will be remembered through his works.
Rest in peace.
(Rest in peace.)
Rest in peace, Actor Oh Soon Tek.
Let's continue with other news.
Ji Yeon and Tae Jin have prepared our next segments.
It's our special segment time,
titled Korea's Favorite 100 Dance Artists.
We're going to begin with the 30th singer today.
It'll be fun and interesting. Please stay tuned.
Before we go into that, on April 1st, April Fool's Day,
something unreal happened.
Some Korean stars have performed in Pyongyang.
It's been 16 years since South Koreans performed there.
It was a meaningful moment,
so we went out and asked them for behind-the-scene stories...
and captured their arrival as well.
Let's watch.
(The 31st of last month, Gimpo International Airport)
This was March 31st.
Amazing celebrities have gathered together...
to go perform at Pyongyang.
There are many legendary seniors...
who will be going with us.
(April 1st, the first performance in 16 years,)
(Entertainment Weekly made a review for you.)
(Are you ready? Do not even blink.)
(Legendary artists have gathered together for this.)
The king of singers, Cho Yong Pil.
The queen of ballads, Baek Z Young.
The hottest girl group, Red Velvet.
What happened in Pyongyang with these amazing artists?
Let's find out.
(An in-depth report on what happened in Pyongyang)
We rushed over to the airport when we heard...
the performance team was coming home on the fourth.
The South Korean performance team is coming back to South Korea.
They were scheduled to arrive at 1:21am,
but it's been delayed for over an hour.
And it got delayed even longer.
Please come quickly.
It's been delayed once again to 3am.
They'll arrive at 3:51am.
It must be my name. Ji Yeon means "delayed".
(Ji Yeon looks worn out from the delay.)
All of the reporters, as well as the fans,
began to grow weary.
That's when the performance team finally arrived.
Unlike when they left,
- they looked very close. - It was really fun.
It's an unforgettable experience.
I was very thankful.
How was it during the performance?
Yes, it was really touching.
It was almost unbelievable...
how everything ended in a very friendly way.
Any thoughts?
It was a great journey.
Thank you.
The hottest star of the day was definitely Cho Yong Pil.
Everyone did well. It was good.
I was the worst performer.
Even Yong Pil praised the performance at Pyongyang.
What kind of performance were given there?
That's why we prepared this. Pyongyang performance at a glance.
(A North Korean performance team visited South Korea last February.)
Last February, to celebrate the Winter Olympics,
a North Korean performance team visited South Korea.
In return, an event that sounds too good to be true...
took place on April Fools' Day.
The host of this peace-offering event...
was Seo Hyun of Girls' Generation.
I am the host...
of this meaningful event.
Hello, everyone.
Performing next were two singers with captivating voices.
It was Jung In and ALi.
(Jung In and ALi show off their captivating voices.)
Baek Z Young delivered an emotional performance...
of "Like Being Hit By A Bullet", which is the most favored song...
of university students in Pyongyang.
(The most favored song of Pyongyang students.)
Due to its shocking title and lyrics,
the song and its singer received a lot of attention.
(Kim Jong Un showed special interest in the song.)
My parents...
have passed away.
However, they're buried in South Hamgyeong Province.
Kang San Eh...
moved everyone by singing "Raguyo,
the song that portrays the yearning he has for his father.
(Oh, how I wish to be able to go there at least just once)
I kept picturing my mother.
On stage,
there were a few moments when I had to focus very hard...
to not think about her.
Rock and roll also resonated in Pyongyang.
YB took the stage next.
(YB, South Korea's best rock band)
Cho Yong Pil,
the legendary artist who held a concert in Pyongyang 13 years ago,
and Choi Jin Hee,
who is loved equally in the North and South took the stage.
The crowd went wild for them.
This marks Ms. Choi's fourth performance in North Korea.
She was asked to perform "A Belated Regret" by the North,
and the song became a hit too in the South afterwards.
We met with her personally right after she got back.
("A Belated Regret" was re-released after 33 years.)
"A Belated Regret"...
topped the search engine ranking for quite some time.
So I heard.
While I was in North Korea,
I was too busy getting ready for the show...
to know what was happening.
I'm curious as to how it was like meeting Kim Jung Un.
What is he like and are there any anecdotes?
He mentioned my song, "A Belated Regret".
He said he enjoyed it.
(She made quite an impression with her captivating voice.)
He was impressed, and he thanked me.
I'm sure it felt different to perform there.
The audience clapped and cheered...
which I found astonishing.
They've never been like that before.
So what was it like back in the day?
Here are some of the past performances.
There was a group who showcased a shocking song and style.
It was the charismatic Baby V.O.X.
Shinhwa who attended the concert in 2003...
were victims of the non-responsive crowd.
Back then,
we showcased a dance song and a powerful choreography.
Let's take a look.
My gosh. Could the air be any colder?
(Shinhwa's performance in North Korea)
The audience seem to be very shy.
Here's the anecdote that even caught CNN's attention.
In 2002, YB heard this...
when they first arrived at the airport in Pyongyang.
(YB visited North Korea in 2002.)
The band was close to being banned from the stage,
but Heo Jun became the first Asian to be on a North Korean TV show...
with colored hair.
The most anticipated group of the whole delegation...
was the youngest participants, girl group Red Velvet.
There was no intention behind it,
but the song they performed was "Red Flavor".
As the only idol singer of the delegation,
everything including their song choice made news.
Even Kim Jong Un...
watched their performance and talked to them afterwards.
Would you have ever expected them in one photo?
The audience responded quite well to our performance.
They clapped a lot.
The group's name must have been foreign to them.
So what would the lyrics be like if translated in North Korean?
(Clapping)
"Take a bite, and it'll keep on melting."
I'm sorry, but I don't even understand this myself.
"I'm curious of the red flavor, honey."
North Koreans would say, "What was that?"
What about this part?
(Find the corner candy shop, baby)
"Find the corner candy shop, baby."
That's what it would be.
So what was it like after the concert?
The first day of the concert...
ended with a North-South joint performance.
(The event was a success.)
You can't do anything on an empty stomach.
The entire delegation headed to...
a naengmyeon restaurant the next day.
I'm not camera-ready!
It wasn't just any restaurant though.
It was Ok Ryu Gwan,
a popular restaurant that gets over 10,000 people a day.
So how is the taste of Pyongyang naengmyeon from Pyongyang?
Z Young, please let us know.
The concert is important,
but the naengmyeon was just as important to me.
- Of course. - It exceeds my expectation.
With another joint performance on the third,
the delegation wrapped up its successful concert.
Before they headed back, they enjoyed a feast.
Which dish was most memorable?
Every dish was delicious.
If I had to pick one, it'd be the sturgeon.
Really?
Dishes made with sturgeon.
They were delicious.
We were treated as honorable guests there.
Just so you know,
the entire dinner banquet was nothing but harmonious.
It was great.
I can tell that it was just by...
- hearing you say it. - I'll never forget it.
I've never been known to enjoy alcoholic beverages...
or to enjoy feasts and parties.
But I was singing and dancing with everyone else.
It was so much fun.
Spring hasn't found us just yet.
(We took a step closer to each other.)
However, we hope that music and culture...
can shed a layer off the cold winter.
(Don't forget how we met on April 1.)
We should always remember...
how we gathered here on this day.
(Don't forget how we met on April 1.)
Spring is coming. We won't forget that.
Thank you all so much.
(Entertainment Weekly)
(Entertainment Weekly News)
This is Entertainment Weekly News. I'm Kim Sun Keun.
And I'm Kim Seung Hye.
Korea's Favorite 100 Dance Artists that aired last week...
received a viewer rating of 70 percent.
The people of Korea just can't get enough of dancing.
Here is Kim Seung Hye with the details.
Korea's Favorite 100 Dance Artists that aired last week...
brought about a dance frenzy in Korea.
Many viewers danced as they watched the segment.
While dancing, one viewer lost his mind...
and caused a scene.
His moves seem quite silly, don't they?
I wish he'd...
restrain himself a bit.
Yes, I agree.
I don't care how much you love to dance,
there's a line you shouldn't cross.
He's a piece of work, isn't he?
- I'm sorry. - You're right.
We hope that this never happens again.
Korea's Favorite 100 Dance Artists, 30th to 16th place.
- Here they are! - Here they are!
Okay, let's go.
Dance is in the air, everyone.
It's the special segment that will fire up your Friday night.
Korea's Favorite 100 Dance Artists.
Here is the artist in 30th place.
It's the artist that took Korea by storm.
She is both elegant and sexy.
It's the devastatingly captivating Sun Mi.
Every single she releases became an instant hit.
She released four hit singles in a row.
So what's the secret to her success?
It's none other than her dance moves such as the clock dance...
and the hip dance.
Sun Mi is known for having memorable choreography.
Even the nation's MC Yu Jae Seok covered the dance.
So how can the dance not be popular nationwide?
Stop it!
("Gashina" swept the nation in 2017.)
In 2017, Sun Mi brought back...
the dance frenzy with her gunpoint dance move.
What's popular is always parodied.
Her gunpoint dance move swept the entertainment industry.
So we asked the singer for her thoughts on it.
(Parodies of it were a craze in 2017.)
Which celebrity do you think did the best job on it?
- It has to be Psy. - Psy?
I can't bring myself to watch the video though.
Psy's cover of Sun Mi's song left her shock...
and in lost for words.
Isn't it scary?
(Ta-da!)
He's a maverick when it comes to parodies.
(We look forward to her in 2018.)
Also in 2018, we await another great dance number by Sun Mi.
Now let's move on.
In 29th place on the list...
is the artist that went around and around.
She's the dancing queen of the 80s, Nami!
(The song made us go around and around in circles.)
There was a time when girls would...
dance to this song whenever two or more got together.
Also, here's her signature move that has been loved...
for over 30 years.
How can I not mention her rabbit dance?
The shuffle was the craze back then,
and she introduced it in Korea.
Her group Nami and Boom Boom spread the dance across the country.
Being the trendsetter she was, she had a great sense of fashion.
Her style was ahead of time,
and she was always in the spotlight for it.
Nami is a dancing queen,
who dominated an era.
Let me introduce you to Korea's 28th Favorite Dance Artist.
(Legendary dance duo Deux)
This hiphop duo was one of the biggest stars of the 90s.
Their hairstyles don't look tacky even today.
Their dance skills would give everyone goosebumps.
This legendary duo sure was ahead of its time.
It's Deux!
Although they were always at the center of attention,
they broke up after only two years, leaving many fans heartbroken.
In November of 1995, Kim Seong Jae's sudden death...
shocked their fans again.
It's been 23 years since his death,
but we still miss him.
In 27th place is Lee Jung Hyun.
There is a word that is always associated with her.
Were you the nation's little sister?
I was...
a female techno warrior.
That's right.
Her meteoric debut at the end of last century...
started a techno fad in the country.
We call her the female techno warrior.
Who hasn't danced to this song?
The techno fad in 2000...
is still valid.
The female techno warrior can make everyone...
get up from their seats and dance.
Her passionate facial expressions and movements...
could never be copied...
by anyone.
There are items associated with her too.
The fan with an eye on it and the finger microphone...
were both her own ideas.
With each song, she had a unique concept...
and showed off different charms.
She's been praised as Korea's Lady Gaga.
But she was even 10 years earlier...
than Lady Gaga.
(Performance queen)
In 26th place is...
Momo of Twice. Who is in 25th place?
The original idol group...
and dance group, Sobangcha.
("Last Night Story" by Sobangcha)
When they debuted in 1987, many girls fell in love with them.
The team consists of Kim Tae Hyung, Jung Won Gwan, and Lee Sang Won.
(I dare say...)
(we were as popular as EXO.)
And he is not wrong. They were EXO of the 80s.
Their trademarks include...
acrobatic performance, denim outfits,
sunglasses, and horse-riding pants.
Everything they put on would become popular.
Sobangcha will always be our idols.
In 24th place is...
the tall, beautiful singer of the 90s,
Kim Hyun Jung.
This song was loved by everyone in the country...
and was played in every single club in the 90s.
(You have to sing it whenever you're in a karaoke room.)
This song always heats up the mood.
Because of the famous line,
many people think this song is called, "Turn Back".
However, it is actually called, "Bruise".
Everyone knows this dance move.
It's still popular after 20 years.
All the cars are turning right now.
Everyone is turning.
The twister dance makes everyone one.
It feels like we're back in the 90s.
In 23rd place is Hyo Yeon of Girls' Generation.
(Korea's 22nd Favorite Dance Artist)
Are you ready?
In 22nd place is Beyonce, the queen of pop.
Also known as Black Pearl, this sexy diva...
has amazing stage presence.
(Her charisma is unrivaled.)
Her charisma and passion conquer the stage.
This winner of six Grammy Awards in one night...
is the most loved diva of the 21st century.
("Crazy in Love" by Beyonce)
Even while dancing vigorously, she shows off amazing singing skills.
From the looks to singing and dancing skills,
everything about her is praised throughout the world.
Many female singers...
have tried dancing to her song, "Single Ladies".
They've stolen many people's hearts...
by showing off their legs while dancing to this song.
If Beyonce is the hottest star of the 21st century,
the diva of the 20th century is this lady.
In 17th place is...
Madonna, the living legend and greatest diva in history.
With her progressive style and performance,
she became a pop icon.
The word, "seductive", exists just for this lady.
(Madonna's best song, "Vogue")
She is also a trend-setter.
The "Vogue" dance moves were...
inspired by models' poses.
She even pulls off disco dance,
proving herself to be a legend.
She sure is a textbook example of a pop diva.
Even though she is over 60,
she proves to us that age is just a number.
In 21st place is U-Know Yun Ho of TVXQ.
Having debuted in 2004, this is their 15th year.
U-Know Yun Ho is the leader and dancer of the team.
He is known to have a peculiar habit.
He always starts his day with some vigorous dance.
This hard-working dancer is Korea's 21st favorite dancer.
The greatest dancer would be Michael Jackson.
It's such an honor to be in 21st place.
I'll work even harder from now on.
Please give me a lot of support.
Can you dance for us?
It was unexpected. He was asked to dance.
- Just like this? - It should be no problem for him.
(Dancing)
I'm one of Korea's favorite dancers, U-Know Yun Ho of TVXQ.
Thank you for the great performance.
He's always great, but he shines brightest on stage.
We'll look forward to even more amazing dances from you.
In 19th place is Kim Choo Ja.
(The 70's icon)
She turned the music scene upside down in the 70s.
She is Korea's original sexy diva with oriental charms.
She was the first Korean female singer to try the butt dance.
Her dance always has a unique feel to it.
Even her name means, "Let's dance."
This passionate diva...
made a comeback in 2014, after a 33-year hiatus.
We hope to see more of you in the near future.
In 18th place is...
the late 90's teenagers' idol.
The legendary idol group, H.O.T,
had an amazing dancer named Jang Woo Hyuk.
Even after the breakup of H.O.T, he is still a great dancer.
When he dances, every joint seems to be...
moving separately.
He can even pull off this powerful and manly dance.
It seems like he's mastered every kind of dance.
His skills are getting better and better.
Recently, he came back to stage as a member of H.O.T.
H.O.T is amazing both 20 years ago and now.
Long live the nation's idol!
(H.O.T will forever be the nation's idol.)
Who is in 16th place?
Are you surprised to see him?
In 16th place is the clumsy and friendly Kim Jong Min,
who is known for his comic dance.
Actually, he is an amazing dancer from the dance team, Friends.
The dancer of Koyote...
can even pull off Michael Jackson's dance.
(He is as good as Michael Jackson.)
Watch.
Forget the Kim Jong Min you know.
I'm the king of dance!
Back in time,
he debuted as a backup dancer for Uhm Jung Hwa.
His handsome face and cute gesture stole many girls' hearts.
Let's find out the truth.
- That song got him where he is now. - That's right.
Some of his fans would even push me away...
to see him.
Kim Jong Min, who was loved by many girls in the 90s,
is Korea's 16th favorite dance artist.
We've looked at 30th through 16th places.
Next week, you'll finally find out who is in first place.
To wrap up, let me quote Dutch philosopher Spinoza.
"Even if I knew that tomorrow the world would go to pieces,"
"I would still dance today."
We'll keep doing our best.
Bye.
- Bye. - We'll come back next week.
(Find out who is in first place next week.)
We were looking at Korea's favorite dance artists.
I didn't expect to find myself in the video.
I enjoyed it.
Entertainment Weekly has all kinds of videos.
Please look forward to who is in first place.
Before hearing from Kim Tae Jin,
let's hear from Kim Seung Hye, who showed off amazing dance skills.
They weren't exactly amazing.
I've even prepared some singing.
The star of the night is me, it's me
The most popular idol group right now,
- What's that? - Wanna One,
is the star of School Attack tonight.
Wasn't it okay? It's me... I'm sorry.
They made a sudden visit to a classroom in first period.
Are you curious? Stay tuned.
I met some actors who deserve our trust,
Ma Dong Seok, Kwon Yul, and Han Ye Ri.
They had such great chemistry.
Find out more about their fun movie and interview now.
(15 years as a reporter)
No one intimidates me...
except...
this man.
Why would he look at my script?
He startled me.
(Will it be my last day?)
Ladies and gentlemen, let me introduce you to today's champion.
Ma Dong Seok, the arm champion.
His expressionless face looks scary.
Ma Dong Seok!
He's so adorable when he smiles.
The interview with the cheerful actors starts right now.
We're looking forward to seeing the movie.
Is it like a uniform?
- Who'll introduce the film to us? - I'm not good, but I will.
Usually, younger actors do this, but are you doing it because...
you're the producer?
No. It's only because I've memorized the lines.
"Champion" is...
the first Korean film about arm wrestling.
It's about a touching yet entertaining story.
- It's a family drama about sports. - I think It'll be really good.
(It's about a guy and his journey to become arm wrestling champion.)
It's hilarious.
It's the second time.
And it's thrilling.
- What are you doing alone? - I was thirsty.
It's the first Korean film ever about arm wrestling.
What does it feel like to work with Ma Dong Seok?
He's so caring...
and enthusiastic in action scenes,
so I just hoped he wouldn't get injured during the shoot.
What do you call each other?
- Executive Ma? - Executive Ma?
Executive Ma.
He's the executive of the Arm Wrestling Association.
- Is that why you call him that? - Yes.
Are you really the executive of the Arm Wrestling Association?
- Let's clap for him. - A round of applause.
Look at his huge arms. They're has big as one's legs.
Your arm is as thick as a skinny woman's waist.
You kept saying he looks like he lost weight.
Really? I think he looks skinnier now.
Yes. I only have skin and bones.
Yul, have you ever felt his strength first-hand?
If I ever did, I wouldn't be here right now.
I don't ever want to feel it.
- Have you two ever arm wrestled? - No, because...
I could die.
- That's possible. - They resemble each other.
- I have another question for you. - Okay.
It's a pretty well-known story,
but the way you became an actor is interesting.
- I majored in dance in university. - Okay.
I became close friends with people in the film industry,
and I was their dance instructor on set at first.
That's how I set my foot in the industry.
And from then on, I sometimes played small parts in their movies,
and that's how I started my career as an actor.
Do you play the role of Dong Seok's little sister?
- Yes. - Yes.
But you don't look like each other at all.
That's possible.
That's possible. I feel sorry for her.
I'm sorry.
He took everything, and that's why I look like this.
If this movie is a success, it'll be the third successful movie in a row.
Your income last year must have been huge.
(I earn money by the thickness of my arm.)
You've shown my so much love and support.
I just hope that this movie can entertain you.
I think that's all I can do for the fans.
I hope you'll support us.
We've prepared another section with cutout boards.
"I'm the champion of blank."
What did they write about themselves?
Show us your belts.
"I'm the champion of public relations."
For PR, can you make hearts with your hands,
wink, or put your hand under your chin?
I can do anything but putting my hand under my chin.
Let's say that...
you were asked to come to...
Entertainment Weekly's live studio for PR.
Would you do it?
His pupils are shaking.
You're the champion of PR.
- Why did you write that? - I don't think he meant it.
You can't write something like that.
- I'd do my best. - I see.
And Yul wrote that he's the champion of happiness.
It's embarrassing to write something like this...
- myself. - I wrote this myself.
(Will he get his belt taken away from him?)
When we greet our fans on stage and such,
I try my best to entertain them and...
- keep them happy. - I think he's blushing.
I'm the champion of embarrassment.
I'm the champion of happiness and embarrassment.
Out of the three of you,
- we'll see who's the strongest. - Okay.
Anyone can tell who it is, though. So...
here it is.
We prepared a toy that requires you to flick instead of punch.
Whose finger is the strongest?
(What's Ye Ri's score?)
I didn't know that existed.
You got 550 points.
Maybe you'll get 5.5 million viewers for your film.
That's my prediction.
(She's happy.)
Go, Dong Seok!
The actors seem cheered up.
I'll go.
(Inhaling)
It's actually nerve-wracking.
They might get 7.36 million viewers.
Finally,
- It's the viewer count. - it's Dong Seok's turn.
- Maybe he'll break the toy. - Let's go.
How do I do this?
(He's cute.)
(Executive Ma has flicked it.)
- 799 points. - He's weaker than I thought.
- I'll go again. - He's ambitious.
(The champion arm wrestler is ambitious.)
825.
Since he said it could be the viewer count, I lost control.
- I became competitive. - The champion is...
Dong Seok.
Can you make an acrostic poem with "Champion"?
Since this is the first interview for us,
we just wanted to get it over with quickly.
Upon the sudden request, they froze.
- Has the screen paused? - No. Sorry.
- I thought it was paused. - Me too.
- Cham. - "Champion" is...
Pi.
(Pi)
A movie you can't avoid.
On.
You have to watch this at least once.
- That's good. - It's impressive.
- I hope that's true. - Sesame seed oil...
does not go well with pizza.
- That's lame. - Can I go again?
I can't think right now.
Our movie, "Champion", will be out on the 3rd of May.
I hope you'll show your love and support for this movie.
Anyone who watches... I'll go again.
Anyone who watches...
(He's the champion of making mistakes.)
- Anyone who watches... - Is a champion.
We'll look forward to it.
Thank you.
(Entertainment Weekly)
Anywhere these guys go, the road gets covered in flowers.
Don't tell anyone about this.
The celebrities on this week's School Attack are...
I can't believe this. It's Wanna One.
Really? No way.
(Wanna One)
We'll go over there.
- Everyone, - Let's go.
For this event, the members of Wanna One are here early morning.
Will the surprise event be successful? Let's find out.
The students have gathered for their first period.
They still look sleepy.
What will happen if the members of Wanna One...
- enter the classroom? - They'll go crazy.
We'll welcome the special lecturer for the day.
The class you won't see anywhere else will begin now.
Hello, everyone!
This is Entertainment Weekly's School Attack.
Hello.
Is this real? The students are speechless.
Because you're so happy to see them, you all froze.
- They're so excited. - That's right.
It's Wanna One!
In 1, 2, 3.
- All I want to do Wanna One. - Hello, we're Wanna One.
Now that you saw them in real life, who do you think is the handsomest?
- Ha Sung Woon. - Ha Sung Woon?
Can you scream and show him your love?
(Screaming)
- She's too shy. - Your throat isn't...
- Right. - warmed up yet.
Let's make some acrostic poems with their names.
One student raised his hand with confidence.
I didn't know...
- a male student would come up. - Hello.
Everyone's greeting him politely.
Who is your favorite member?
My favorite is Yoon Ji Sung.
(The male student picks Ji Sung.)
Stand next to him...
Really?
Stand next to him and...
This is very nice. Let's give them three seconds for eye contact.
Since they like each other. In 1, 2, 3.
Look at him.
(Just looking at each other's face makes them happy.)
They're so happy.
(Ji Sung is his first pick.)
Can you shake his hand?
- Okay. - Yes.
Great. Please say the syllables.
Yoon.
Mr. Yoon Ji Sung.
(His heart stops.)
What's with him?
(What is this feeling?)
Is this how this feels?
- Ji. - Ji Sung.
- Sung. - My life as a fan is complete.
(My life as a fan is complete.)
Thank you.
- Thank you. - Everyone,
He's very cool. He didn't shake my hand at the end.
- Did he just leave? - Yes.
- There's another. - Wanna One has lots of male fans.
They're so popular.
Who is your favorite?
Park Ji Hoon.
(He picks Ji Hoon.)
Okay. Please come up.
Why do all Wanna One members...
have red ears?
- Just take it easy. - He's so red.
They're so red.
Take it easy.
He's too shy.
I'm shy right now.
Do you want to do the five-syllable talk?
Sure.
Okay. Make it short. Go.
Have you eaten?
No, I haven't.
Do you want to eat with me?
The atmosphere is becoming flirty.
Whenever you want.
This is such a natural conversation.
People might think these two are just talking normally.
His ears are even redder.
Let's see if there's a peculiar person in this room.
I think he's a professor. The gentleman in the back.
(Professor Lee Moon Ki)
The professor was watching us...
with a big smile on his face.
Who is your favorite Wanna One member?
The one in the middle in blue.
That's Ong Seong Wu. Yes.
- He says you look cool. - Yes.
Can you make a poem out of Ong Seong Wu's name?
All of a sudden?
Yes. You're a professor.
He looks so kind.
Just look at their eyes.
- Ong. - Ong my gosh.
He has a humorous side to him.
- Seong. - I hope you succeed.
That's great.
- Wu. - Wanna One is the universe's best!
- Were you preparing for this? - No, no.
Lastly, do you have anything...
to say to the students here?
I became a university student in 2011.
I might seem really old to you.
When I was in school, my professor told me...
I should just tell him if I needed a break and to take a year off.
- Really? - Yes.
- I don't think he agrees. - What?
I don't think he agrees with you.
I think he's just watching...
to see what you'll say.
Your early 20s will never come back.
It's an age where you can be forgiven for whatever you do.
I hope you'll always do your best.
Did you like his speech, professor?
Yes, yes.
- Yes, yes. - Yes, yes.
I dare you to try and skip my class.
Try to skip my class.
The reaction was wilder than ever with Wanna One's School Attack.
We could feel the popularity of Wanna One skin deep.
After meeting with the passionate students,
we had the opportunity to have...
a deeper conversation with Wanna One.
(They had an enjoyable time with the students.)
It's time to get to know more about Wanna One.
You got to meet some students. How was it?
Since they're studying hard,
I wanted to cheer them up.
How would you cheer up...
the university students?
Everyone, cheer up.
I have to continue interviewing,
but I almost fainted too.
We have a few members who just turned 20.
I wanted to go back to school after seeing them in their desks.
It reminds me of the past.
He was reminded of the past.
Are you...
- Are you old? - You must be very old.
You were reminded of the past.
Everyone dreams about their ideal university life.
Universities have campuses.
I heard getting Chinese delivery is a delicacy.
Yoon Ji Sung, you actually graduated university.
I think all I did was drink.
(I was drinking every day.)
He's ruining every child's imagination.
- I'm being honest. - Yes.
- That's true. - Don't you agree?
That's why you should never tell them you're living alone.
Once they know, the senior students...
force you to come out to drink.
That's a good tip.
How do you feel after hearing these stories?
Will your dream come true?
I'm in trouble.
If you can name one thing that defines you, what is it?
- Ji Hoon has one. - Ji Hoon has a charm.
- It's his cuteness. - It's your trademark.
Everyone in Korea has tried this pose before.
However, no one can be as cute as the original.
We were all busy saving things in our hearts.
We must watch the original version.
I'll save Entertainment Weekly in my heart.
Show them the new one.
Entertainment Weekly, you're mine.
- Gosh. - Thank you.
- Ji Sung, you have your tears. - Yes...
We thought you'd cry like this, but...
(Wailing)
That's him. That's this guy here.
Lee Dae Hwi is good at copying Ha Sung Woon.
Sung Woon tries to hold it in.
It boils inside of him.
His nostrils move.
(Sung Woon cries with his nostrils.)
The nostrils.
I saw him cry like this.
Kim Jae Hwan cried too.
(They're copying Jae Hwan.)
That looks the same.
Hwang Min Hyun. Look at him.
Everyone cried except for Lai Kuan Lin.
We thought you would cry a lot since you're the youngest.
- I don't cry much. - He's mature.
You're such a man.
What is it, Jae Hwan?
I know how Kuan Lin cries.
Have you seen him cry?
Let's reveal how everyone cries today.
Most people have weird expressions.
But Kuan Lin makes sounds.
(Humming)
- That's because... - Do you agree?
he wasn't crying in front of me.
- Was he crying by himself? - I overheard him crying alone.
- In his room? - Yes. I felt so sorry for him.
Yes, that happened.
Unfortunately, Wanna One has a limited time together.
What do you think you'll be doing one year from now?
If I may be honest,
- we haven't talked about our end. - No.
Really. We haven't talked about it.
We're too busy thinking about our performances day by day.
Just like how we're performing hard as Wanna One,
no matter what position we're in,
I assume we'll be giving our best while thinking of each other.
You look teary.
When your eyes are dry...
(Their present is too precious to talk about their end.)
Thank you so much for all your love.
Entertainment Weekly is the best. We had a lot of fun today.
I hope you'll listen to our new album...
and cheer for us.
See you later, Entertainment Weekly! We promise!
Wanna One had a great time with their fans.
We'll continue to cheer you on!
(We'll visit you again, Entertainment Weekly!)
We wish Wanna One the best.
They're so charming and handsome.
Also, Ma Dong Seok's movie trailer looks like a lot of fun.
I hope your film becomes a hit and reaches three million in sales...
so that you would visit us at the studio.
We'll prepare a strong chair for you.
- Good luck. - We'll look forward to it.
That's all we prepared for today.
We'll see you next week on Entertainment Weekly.
- Everyone, be happy! - Be happy!
("LADY" by EXID)
("Giddy Up" by The Boyz)