- Baba-chan, morning!
- Morning.
- We're first ones here today.
- Yeah, really early.
- Did you sleep well?
- Yep!
- Our phones...
- Why?
I thought they were stolen at camp.
It's mine.
Who did this?
What is this report?
Survival Camp Report
- Is there a problem with it?
- There's nothing but problems.
Survival on their own without cell phones!
Banishing people from the group by majority vote!
An unbelievable camp after all.
I followed the instructions in your manual!
I don't remember writing anything like this!
Huh?
Everyone! Big problem!
Excuse me.
Student Rankings
There's been a change in the student rankings?
Yeah. This site used to divide
students into
teams 1, 2, and 3.
Look at this!
Look look.
Everyone's the same.
Why?
It has to be because of the survival camp.
A lot happened there.
Team 2 attacking team 1.
And team 1 fighting among themselves too.
So it seems that taking
them outside of the classroom
makes school caste meaningless.
So, the school caste is gone then?
I think so.
Hey, how about we eat lunch together?
Yeah.
What should we call you guys?
Just Ren and Ozamu is fine.
- Right.
- Sure.
Yay!
Okura, Kashiwagi, Jinbo!
My phone?
The History of Baba Ayako
- It's thanks to Baba-chan.
- Yeah.
The History of Baba Ayako
- It's thanks to Baba-chan.
- Yeah.
The classroom changed ever since you got here.
It was tough for awhile but it
looks like the school caste is gone now!
That wasn't my plan.
Perhaps
you came from the stars, the amazing Baba-chan-man!
- Baba change!
- Not funny!
Come on! Let's all do the Baba Ranger pose!
You just want the girls to play with you!
No no!
What?
What's this message?
The truth is in locker 28.
28?
I don't think anyone's using that locker.
But who knows the emails for everyone in the class?
I bet whoever stole the
phones took our addresses too.
Really!?
Let's look at the locker.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Open it up.
It's an indictment.
Baba Ayako of Kunikida High School Class 3-A
Baba-chan?
was placed in there by orders of Superintendent Asada.
Her objective was to use current high school students for live experiments
and observe the results.
Indictment
...live experiments...
This...
That's her.
- Who's next to her?
- What is this?
High schools nowadays are like endless wastelands.
Bullying, truancy, depression.
Everything is controlled by monsters in the school caste.
No matter your role, you get tired of the part you play.
Kaiser...
And not just for students.
Teachers and parents
find themselves having to apologize for their mistakes.
There are very few rays of hope now.
But, within this
never ending darkness.
Can the 35 year old
high school student find something?
Translation: Rollins   Timing: furransu
35-Year-Old High School Student
Support fansubbing by not watching on streaming sites! Find all your favorite dramas at d-addicts.com!
Baba Ayako?
Live experiments?
So she was a spy for the Kaiser then?
Well, I don't know the details...
But the students are all worked up.
But if it's true
it does give a good reason for placing a 35 year old woman in high school.
So then our school
is just some testing lab?
Everyone, calm down.
Let's just double check when
the principal gets back in.
Asada Yukinobu
Unknown Number
Hello.
Just as I thought.
Superintendent Asada was using
our class for some experiment.
That's why you came here.
What are you saying? Of course not...
There's no point in lying.
I know everything about you.
I know where you live. I know everything about your past.
You don't need to sneak around anymore.
Just tell us everything and become our savior.
For me. And you too.
Baba-chan, this...
Sorry.
Baba-chan.
It's not here...
I can't believe it, Baba-chan was a spy.
We don't know that yet.
Again...
Turn on the TV
The TV...
We have Superintendent Asada from the
Kawahama City Board of Education.
Is that the guy from the photo?
Let's get right to it Asada-san...
The Kaiser is on TV!
You're right!
Record it!
One of the reasons that
bullying has not left our schools is
to due a problem known as school caste.
The problem of bullying is a difficult one to solve
but I hear you have a new educational reform in place?
To eliminate bullying we will stop the class system.
Stop the Class System
What!?
- Stop?
- In doing so,
students are not confined but rather
are free to take classes they like
similar to a university system.
You believe this will eliminate bullying?
Actually, we did an investigation with a high school
in this city and found that when they left the
classroom, the instances of bullying went away.
So you have actual evidence.
That's us, isn't it?
They used us for an experiment!
You tricked us.
Baba-chan, why didn't you tell us?
If it's not true, just say so!
Ah, you guys are hilarious.
You let that lady trick you all.
You let her use you as guinea pigs for some experiment!
You're wrong.
You think I'm making it up?
Well, let's see if this is fake too.
Nope, looks real to me.
Hey, Ren.
Isn't this in the way?
Yeah...
- Move.
- Ren.
Go go! Ren!
Asada Yukinobu
Who are you calling?
You called me yesterday, right?
You left that packet in the locker.
And sent messages to everyone, right?
You're right.
Why did you...
You've done some amazing work.
I thought they'd be happier about it.
You're mistaken.
- I didn't...
- I didn't do this
to be mean to you.
What?
Remember. Everything that's happened in 3-A up to now.
The paper put in the toilet that Hasegawa-san ate in.
How about you disappear? If you did everyone would be happy.
I put that up.
Why?
And I was the one who pushed Yamashita-san down the stairs.
Not just that. I used those high school girls
to set up the pervert accusation,
I told the board of education about the abuse on the track team,
I placed the hidden camera,
and I changed the camp manuals to make a survival game.
I did it all.
Why did you do it?
You of all people should know.
You're actually my ally, right?
School caste, this pointless ranking,
you want to destroy it, right?
- To get rid of the school caste?
- Yes.
And now the school caste is gone.
Why did you have to trick everyone?
Use poison to get rid of poison.
In order to show everyone how stupid
and terrible the school caste was
I needed to make some easy to understand situations.
And I managed the rankings
of everyone in the school caste
so they knew where they stood.
Just to make sure everyone was aware.
What's that?
The letter to myself ten years from now.
You didn't write anything.
There's no point.
I achieved my objectives.
All that I need to do now is disappear.
Akutsu-kun?
Tell everyone what I did.
- Let go!
- Are you running away from what you did?
What you've done is unforgivable.
But, you can make it right.
So...
"Disappear"?
Don't say it so easily.
Okay okay okay!
Let's use our heads and think!
We were all just manipulated by Baba Ayako.
That's Baba-chan's bag.
She put them on every time she got a new friend.
But really!
They're just proof of her tricking us.
Are your eyes open now?
It's just like Masamitsu says.
What are we going to do?
I believe Baba-chan.
There's no way that she would
trick us like that!
Yeah.
Thanks to her we got rid of the school caste!
I think so too.
You're still with her?
The school caste is never going away.
And she's back!
It seems like they want to believe you.
I guess it can't be helped. Let me give you a
time to tell us everything.
Let's find out if you're innocent or not
with a Kunikida Witch Trial!
I wonder if she can tell the truth though.
It'll be fine. They trust her so
I know that she can't lie.
Anyway it's up to her
if she wants to do it.
I wonder what the truth is.
You don't trust her?
Of course I believe her but...
But there are those photos of her
with Superintendent Asada.
It doesn't matter why she came to
this school.
We've got this far together because of her.
Yeah.
Baba Ayako is a spy for the Kaiser?
Have you heard anything from Superintendent Asada?
No, I haven't heard anything.
They chose our school to
try and implement some new educational reform?
I don't know that.
Although, the Kaiser did say before...
Who is she?
She's my student.
Student...
Let's have an emergency meeting.
- The data on Baba Ayako.
- Okay!
Let's check Kaiser's video from this morning one more time.
Okay.
Koizumi-sensei, a moment...
- Hey hey...
- What is it?
This.
What are they doing!?
Stop! Calm down! Just watch.
Watch them?
Baba-chan!
The Kunikida Witch Trial? Masamitsu's just being stupid, don't worry.
We don't care who you are.
You're Baba-chan to us, no matter what.
Here.
Go ahead.
Everyone...
Baba Ayako
Asada-san!?
Are you okay? Asada-san!
Asada-san! Are you okay? Asada-san!
Guess she's not coming.
She's afraid of the truth, so she ran.
Baba-chan, why...
Oh, so you're ready?
Come on.
So then,
the Kunikida Witch Trial will begin.
Make sure you answer all of the questions honestly.
- Huh, questions?
- Question!
18 years ago Baba-chan dropped out of high school.
Why?
A, bullying.
B, her mother's hospitalization. C, distrust of others.
- D, everything! Answer!
- What is this question?
What does this have to do with the experiment?
Hurry up! Everyone is waiting for you.
What is he planning?
He wants to expose all of her secrets.
D.
D. So then...
Everything.
D, everything. Right!
So...bullying, your mom in the hospital, and distrusting people.
What does that have to do with you dropping out of school?
Explain it so
everyone can understand!
It all started
with something my mom said.
Your friend is being bullied?
Yes.
And you pretended not to see anything?
What will happen if you don't stick up for your friends?
Okay.
Stop it.
Baba-chan.
But then, the next day,
they just started bullying me.
Haha, so funny.
Die
Disappear\Why are you still alive?
Haha, so funny.
Hey,
let's go home together.
The bullying got worse.
Then I was caught shoplifting.
Show me what's in your bag!
- Let go!
- Stop struggling.
Let go of me!
You're fired.
Aya-chan.
Why?
You told me
to protect my friend and look
what happened.
Aya-chan...are you being bullied?
I blamed my mother for why I was bullied.
I don't
need any friends!
I couldn't trust any of my classmates.
I'm home.
Aya-chan.
What are you doing? Stop it!
It's my fault, right?
I'm sorry. It's all my fault!
Yeah.
It's all your fault.
You and your stupid words
ruined my life!
Only if you weren't around...
Please. Just disappear from my sight.
Aya-chan.
Aya-chan!
Disappear from my sight!
Disappear.
So then you stopped going to school
and turned into a shut-in, right?
And then, soon after,
my mother checked into the hospital.
You had no other relatives
so you had to quit school just to get enough money to get by.
But there's one mysterious thing here.
You didn't trust people back then
so how did you turn into some
strong and trustworthy character here?
That's true.
Maybe the way you act now
is just an act to trick all of us!
- No!
- So let's bring up
question 2!
How are Baba-chan and Superintendent Asada connected?
A, the homeroom teacher who checked up on her when she dropped out.
B, the homeroom teacher who visited Baba-chan's home so many times.
C, the homeroom teacher who kept helping her all these years.
D, everything! Answer!
Huh? I guess everyone can guess
where the answer is but still!
What is it?
D.
D, everything. Correct!
So he's been taking care of you all this time?
I had no job prospects so he helped me find work.
Employment Request
They'll take even just junior high graduates.
Why don't you at least interview?
Why?
You're the only one who can
support your mother.
But,
I was never good enough at anything.
Being a guard or a cook,
I just kept moving around.
That makes sense.
You couldn't trust people.
When my mother died half a year ago...
Are you okay?
Asada-sensei was
always by my side.
So then that special teacher
made a special request of you?
- An important request you couldn't refuse.
- That's...
Everyone! This is important so make sure you remember!
Baba was working with Kaiser then?
Huh?
Nagamine-sensei?
Next one should be easy!
Question!
Baba-chan said her mother was in the hospital,
so why was she there?
A, illness. B, accident. C, violence.
D, she jumped from a tall building!
Okay, we have four choices here.
What is she going to say now?
- D.
- D, jumping from a tall building, correct!
Baba-chan's mother...
Why?
What an amazing life.
We're getting to the heart now.
Make sure you listen to everything now!
I was a shut-in for a very long time.
And I stopped talking to my mother.
Aya-chan.
It's my fault.
I'm sorry.
I know it's tough for you.
So I'll disappear.
I hate this damn school.
Mom!
I couldn't forgive her then.
My mom was running away to leave me alone.
She regained consciousness but...
It's your daughter, Ayako.
Who?
My mother had serious head trauma
and suffered memory loss.
Over the next 18 years...
My mother never recovered.
My mother never remembered who I was.
I killed my mother.
I killed her.
- Baba-chan, that's enough!
- Stop this!
That's not it.
Something come to mind?
The people at fault were the
classmates who bullied you.
They're the ones who
messed up your life
and made you have this grudge against school.
Did you come to this school
to exact some measure of revenge?
- I didn't want revenge...
- Okay everyone!
After listening to all the stories
we know she hide her real self with an act
and was loyal to her old teacher Superintendent Asada.
And she hated school, which had ruined her life.
So, here's the last question.
- Are you still going on?
- How can you keep asking her questions!?
What? We haven't heard the full
truth yet.
That's enough! Baba-chan is who she is!
Say something!
- Sorry...
- I'm confused too now.
It's okay.
I always thought about it.
When I'd have to tell you everything.
Huh?
Go on.
Question!
Why did you come to our school?
A, revenge against school.
B, a mission for Superintendent Asada.
C, an experiment.
D, everything.
The answer?
It's not there.
No answer!?
How strange. You answered everything up to now
but why won't you answer this one?
- It's not there.
- Tell the truth!
You can't tell the truth, can you?
I'm not lying.
Stop pushing her!
Besides, how would you know the answer?
How? Well...
This.
A notebook found in her apartment.
Everything is written inside.
Give it back.
Looking at this notebook,
how old do you think it is?
One month? Three months?
No, it must be older than t hat.
Otake, what do you think?
It looks two, three years old.
We have two to three years old!
So then, this notebook
it existed for years before
she ever came to our school, right?
So what?
How strange.
So then why does the notebook
have entries about everything that's happened over the last three months?
For example, the first page!
It says "made a 100 friends".
Oh? A little excited now, right?
Remember.
The first day she came to our school.
I'd like to make a hundred friends.
Nice to meet you.
So all her actions are written in this notebook.
Moving on.
Had a lunch together!
That's just a coincidence.
Next.
Became the class representative.
Solve the problems of the other students.
We're going to decide the class representative. Any volunteers?
I'll do it.
The lady did volunteer to do it...
Next.
A fight between best friends!
You guys...
are best friends.
Let's keep going.
A popular teacher in trouble!
Let teachers teach their students.
The culture festival.
The class all together except for one!
The festival...
You think this is easy!?
Become the savior for
a club in trouble!
The track team?
I don't think it's disgusting at all.
The class meeting between former friends.
The teen court, right?
You can show a little more weakness.
A problem with suicide and the homeroom teacher.
Maybe it's okay to be tricked every now and then.
Went on a school trip.
Talking with friends, but can't see our futures.
The camp we just went on.
You'd call that a coward perhaps?
What is this?
Baba-chan.
Baba-chan?
- That's...
- When I read this,
I had a thought.
It's everything that's happened here in 3-A.
Hasegawa, you.
When you ate alone in the toilet, there was a paper there, right?
And the person who found her in the toilet
was the old lady.
No way...
That paper...
Maybe something comes to mind for you too?
When I was pushed down the stairs,
Baba-chan just happened
to be there too.
That's not all!
Everything that's happened here
has had some strange connection!
It's like she knew about everything...
And even when Saruwatari-sensei was arrested...
Or the hidden camera for the teen court...
Those cards that told me what to do with Koizumi-sensei...
Was that you?
So then,
she set up all these events just to
fulfill her mission for Superintendent Asada.
Then she pretended to solve them
- and make herself to be our savior!
- No!
What? Then who was it?
That's...
You can't answer and you have no proof.
This notebook.
It's the script for the
35 year old high school student, Baba Ayako!
Good work.
Our fake savior.