Subtitles by Renatinha Tankinha.
Every five seconds, someone lives.
And every eight
seconds, someone dies.
And every second in between,
we're here
or here
time...
they say that time
is lost in memory.
We cannot touch, see
or control time.
We are essentially prisoners
in this fourth dimension.
And one day,
all of this will be gone.
Yet, for some reason,
we don't seem to care too much
and would rather
fight each other.
The truth is...
we are not really
here for that long.
And for the majority of us,
we only get one chance
at all of this.
- Why?
The question that has plagued the human
mind since the birth of the world.
What is all this about?
Who am I
and how did we all get here?
I find it interesting that
everything seems so strange to us.
If we look at a word too long,
if we really think too much,
It already doesn't make sense.
How strange is everything?
We float on a giant water-covered
ball in the middle of nothing.
Why is it so strange?
Why does it seem so weird?
What are we comparing this to?
I want honest answers here, people.
Right now.
The question is of course the ultimate one:
"Why are we here?"
I know what I think.
I wanna hear what you all think.
Jennifer?
- The bible has all the
answers for me, Mr. Wertz.
- Thank you.
Finally some truth in this room.
I wanna hear something new for once.
Something
totally different.
Raise your hands, people.
Dennis?
- Mathematically speaking,
we're most likely a microscopic
molecule in an atom that... that
makes up something a lot
larger than we can comprehend.
If we add time to the equation.
We could... we could be making up the
dirt on the bottom of the universal sizes
elephant that... that has taken
one step in our galaxy's lifetime.
- That's very interesting,
Dennis. And is this your truth?
- It just seems to
make sense to me.
You know? We used to think
that inside an atom was a
couple of nuclei. Now we've
discovered an entire cosmos.
The... the solar system itself resembles
the interior rotation of an atom anyway.
Science has to play a part in all of this.
- Take your pants off and prove it!
- Please, please... ladies
and gentlemen, please.
Anyone else?
What do you think?
Aidan,
what do you think?
- I... I believe in the unknown.
I don't know. I don't think we'll ever
know the answer to that question.
- So you believe in nothing?
- Oh, belief and reality
are two different things.
- Well, what about when you die?
- When I die?
- All of us.
Well, let me ask you, Jennifer.
What happens when you die?
- Heaven...
or hell.
- Dennis?
- That universal sized elephant
just keeps on walking.
- OK... OK.
Now, please, Aidan.
- We've all been dead a lot
longer than we've been alive.
- OK now down to business.
Ladies and
gentlemen, please
take out your papers.
Officially,
exclusively and mathematically
this is your final Philosophy exam for
the term this semester and the year.
Unfortunately, the remainder of your
possible careers finals to this point.
So, if you feel you're not ready,
bad luck. You have four and
a half hours, starting now.
Good luck. See you in the future.
- Hello.
- What?
- You're gonna listen
to me very carefully.
Don't go to the Ritz East Gate motel.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Don't go to the East Gate motel.
Stay away.
- Wait!
Wait... wait a minute!
- So... Sarah...
- Haven't heard of her.
It's open!
- Uh... She's pretty cute.
- Really?
- She's got it going on.
- How?
- I don't know.
- Hey, how was your exam?
- Alright, she's cute. You just... are
you gonna talk to to me about her?
- Oh, what's cute about her?
- Uh...
She's chubby, she's funny...
- Are you OK?
- I'm having...
running round and round
just doing finals stuff and...
- Did you just say that she's chubby
and that's what you love about her?
- Yeah.
- That's odd? That's...
- She lost so much weight, so.
- She was sweet, wasn't she?
- I'm taking my bike after
the exam and someone
came up to me and it
was... me, like...
- You?
- My clothes, my face,
my voice, everything.
- Were you standing in front of a girl?
- Was it like a cousin or relative
or something that you didn't...
- At first I thought it
was a joke, but then...
when I actually looked it freaked me out.
- Are you on drugs?-Are you
sure you want me to...
- He said "Don't go to
the Ritz East Gate Motel."
- How? Are you gonna do it for me?
- I hate to...
- I just don't see why...
- What?
- Why would he say that?
- Don't go in the Ritz East Gate Motel?
- Yeah.
- What's going on down there?
- Hello Gran.
- I've seen you before.
- Yeah. Something like that.
Hello?
Yeah, who else?
Yes. Middle name?
Uh, it's Sal.
Listen man, I gotta go.
- How was your exam?
- Yeah, it was fine, just fine.
Fingers crossed.
- What's the matter?
- Something... happened this morning.
- Are you in trouble?
- No, nothing like that, just...
something weird happened.
I saw something I can't explain and...
does our family have a
history of mental illness,
depression, paranoia,
hallucinations?
- A golf ball
drowned your grandfather, you know?
- Yes, I know, Gran.
- Wish I could see him again.
Your great-grandmother had diabetes,
there is a history of cancer, and
both was too, in the men.
What does Lauren think?
- Oh, nothing.
- When are you two
gonna get married?
- I don't know, grandma. Soon, maybe.
- But first
I want great-grandchildren and I want to
be at the wedding, but not in that order.
- OK.
- So, nothing brain related?
I just wanna make sure it's
not all just... in my head.
- Isn't everything just
in your head?
Will you read to me?
- Yeah, sure.
What shall we read?
The four swans
where did we stop?
- I'm at the beginning.
- It's a good place.
- Can I help you? Aidan.
- Hey, Lauren.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm sorry. I didn't know you worked here.
How's things?
- Things are good.
- How's your shift going?
- It's fine. Good.
Are you here for something?
- This is gonna sound strange.
Have I been here before?
- I don't know. Shouldn't
you know that?
- I know it sounds weird,
but have you seen me here
before? Like someone who
looks a lot like me?
- Uh, I don't think so. I...
- E... Everything alright here?
- Yeah, it's fine.
- He said "Don't go to
the Ritz East Gate Motel."
Well, here I am.
- Yeah...
That's an interesting story.
And I don't know whether I
should believe a word of it.
- That makes two of us.
- Don't you mean two of you?
- So what are you doing now?
- Nothing. Nothing much. Just working.
- Just working?
So you work, you go home
and you do absolutely nothing?
- No. I do things.
- And?
- And I'm doing a painting course.
- Painting? Really?
Finally.
- Yeah.
- And how's your grandma?
- She's OK.
Uh... we had to put her
in a home, pretty much.
Just after we broke up.
- Oh...
OK...
- It's been good to see
you again, Lauren.
- Good to see you, too, Aidan.
- You still live around here?
- No, I've moved, actually.
- Do you want a lift?
- Aidan?
- Yeah?
- I think I should tell you something.
- Something I should have
told you a while ago.
Well, I'm just gonna say it.
Look out!
- OK...
There's no signs of
concussion or anything.
And he's gonna be sore for
a couple of days, but
other than that, he's
gonna be absolutely fine.
- OK.
- Thanks.
- Hey man.
- Hi... hi.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How are you feeling?
- Fine.
- Are you okay?
- You look pretty...
- What happened?
- You were in a car accident.
- Yeah, it was pretty bad.
And... and the... the... the doctor called
your grandmother and they called me and...
And then I called Nick and... and
we've been here for a while now...
- Where's Lauren?
- Oh, and... and he said that you may have
hit your head. They think that maybe
you've hit your head, so... um to ask
you if... if... if your head hurts.
Where's Lauren?
We could get you some
water, we could...
Get him some water.
- Sit back.
- Sit back... look, look, relax. It's okay.
The doctor will be here any minute.
- Don't sit up. Just relax, it's fine.
- The doctor will be here...
- I'm fine.
- Sit back.
- Where's Lauren?
- You cannot leave the hospital.
You are allowed to use the phone
to call family and friends.
A lawyer has been assigned and
will be meeting with you tomorrow.
- So I'm being charged for something?
- Well, the family has stated that
they'd like to press charges.
Given the circumstances of your past
relationship with the deceased,
they're having a hard time understanding
what she was doing in the car with you.
- Man, I was just going
to drive her home.
- You don't have to explain to us.
- Yet.
- Well, I don't see
your lawyers present.
- Just some of the things that have to
be done these days, unfortunately.
Now, we have to be
very clear on this.
You cannot leave the hospital.
Even though you're not
in custody, if you do
leave here, it can make
things a lot worse.
Do you understand?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Peanut butter and Russian currency,
the Atlantic Ocean and
a melted Rollerblade.
It's a great game. Really simple.
You think of two things,
any things,
the only rule is
they have to be as non-related as
possible, just like you and me.
A lava lamp and a dead horse kidney.
The Atlantic Ocean
and a melted Rollerblade.
Helps take your mind off things.
Give it a go.
- No, thanks.
- Well,
maybe one day I'll
find someone to actually play with.
You're in some trouble, I see.
I know something you don't know.
Something weird happened to you.
Didn't it?
Something really strange.
Something you don't seem able
to explain and most likely...
- What?
- Git you into this mess.
- How do you know about that?
- I could tell you,
but you're gonna figure it out for
yourself no matter what I say.
But I can give you a hint.
Go to the East Gate motel.
- I knew it! I knew
something was going on.
- Room 41.
There's a hole in the bathroom.
In the ground. You have
to go into the floor!
- The floor?
- Exactly.
- Hi, Aidan.
This is going to help you relax and sleep
and make sure you stay here tonight.
- Room 41, you said?
- And you're late!
- John turns up, and then,
his best friend.
And she brings up her brother,
You know who her brother is?
Sam! Jess!
- Yeah, looks funeral gonna be one night
next week I'm not sure when, but.
Um... I'll let you know when we've
got some more detail.
Uh, can you hang on for a moment?
I've got someone out here.
Uh, excuse me, can I help you? Come in.
Come in. I'll... I'll...
I'll have to... uh... call you back.
I've got to help somebody, OK?
Yes, sir, how can I help you?
- I just wanna get a room.
- Uh, fine, yes. We've got... uh...
got room. We've got room 11... eh... just
for yourself? One night?
- That's fine.
- How are you gonna pay for that?
Card? OK. Thank you.
OK...
Here you go.
OK, thanks very much. Good.
- It was late this afternoon
when a car swerved off.
Berkey Road and hit this
power pole behind me.
The passenger died on
site while the driver was
taken to the hospital
with minimal injuries.
It is not yet known what caused
the car to lose control,
but police are pushing forward
for full investigation.
- Hey!
Get out of me
- Hey, man. It's me.
- Get out!
I'll stab you out!
- Aidan!
I read your paper.
You really outdid yourself this time.
- You could have
told me, Mr. Wertz.
- You know, it's minds like yours
that... well... you really
think outside the box.
Me and a couple of colleagues of mine,
we meet every Wednesday to talk
about... science
related issues and...
- She's fine. You talk to her for
longer than sixty seconds and
she still informs you that a golf ball
thrown to my grandfather
- Grandfather. Yeah, I do remember that.
- I never actually told
her that we broke up.
- What?
After all this time?
- Yeah, after all this time.
- That's a bit strange, isn't it?
- It would have killed her.
She's still got that photo that you gave
her for her eightieth birthday of us.
She loves you.
Still loves you.
- I miss your grandma.
- She called me out the other week and
she told me she wanted to go bowling.
I said "Are you serious?"
We went bowling and
Amy was in the stand bow. She
was in her slippers and gown.
Bowled a few balls within
the slab magazine thing.
She had fun.
- Yeah, that's cute.
- Mmm.
- I love bowling.
You remember that time that...
- ... we went bowling.
- Watch out!
- Can I get an ambulance please? To room 41.
East Gate motel.
- I don't know, like... he was
really weird. He was talking
about this room 41 of a
motel room that has a black
hole that... that leads to
yesterday and something about
like... he was in a car accident
with Lauren and she died.
And that he was the reason that she died?
And he's gonna be back
in time or something?
- Hey kid.
- Hi.
- How was your nap?
- You don't believe, right?
- Come on, man, you're
actually joking, right?
- Come with me.
- Why? Did you lose it?
- What for?
- No, I'm trying to prove a point.
Call him.
- Hello?
Who? Aidan.
This is you, Aidan.
- It's the other Aidan. He hasn't
been through this yet, right?
- If this is Aidan, what's
my brother's middle name?
- Uh, it's Sal.
Listen man, I gotta go.
- Hello?
Who tal...
He hung up.
- What? Are you sure?
- You hung up.
Come on, this is
actually a joke, right?
- Listen, you guys were
both there, after the
accident, in the hospital.
It's all gonna happen.
- Look, it's just weird, alright?
This is just getting really weird,
Aidan. Look, I... I know that you had
problems getting over Lauren and I
understand that, really, we do, we
care about you a lot, but Nick and I,
we checked her Facebook page before
and she was online. She's not dead.
- Not yet!
- Not yet?!
Can you go forward in time?
Like in the future?
- I don't know.
- What if Nick said that to you?
You know, "Ah, hey, I've found a
motel room 41 with a black hole.
- Crazy.
- But at least check it out.
- It's crazy.
- No.
Because you remember this time
last year I told both of you
to come with me to the petrol station.
And I've been drinking
but I saw Elvis.
- Oh, hell no.
- He's alive.
I saw him and you wouldn't believe me.
- Shut up.
- And you wouldn't believe me.
- Guys, you're not listening to me!
Just come to the motel with me
and I can prove it all to you!
- I'm sorry, OK? We're not gonna come, OK?
- Oh, oh... here, look what we've done.
- When all this happens...
- Look what we've done.
- Where are you going?
- When all this happens, just act surprised.
- Where you going, Sully????
- Aidan...
- I'm leaving.
- Look...
- He's probably going for a sniff.
- He's not going for a sniff.
- Aidan... Hello, what brings you here?
- Hey, Mr. Wertz. Sorry to bother you.
I got your listing from the... university.
You said you had a meeting here?
- Yes!
Y... yes, of course. Please, come in.
- Thanks...
- It's screwed, but I disagree.
The fundamental world
of mathematics exists
only to comprehend the impossible.
One plus one does not always equal two.
- Everyone, this is Aidan.
Professor Jacobs has a fascination with
the alternative perspective of knowledge.
- To think, to know is to...
- ... know what to think.
Aidan, this is my very
old friend,
Mr. Wertz.
- Aidan takes my philosophy class.
Top grades.
- So, what brings you here, Aidan?
- I've got a few questions.
- "Why" questions?
- Not why, how.
- It's about time travel.
- Ah, excellent.
- Interest or research?
- Both.
- Would you go forward or back?
- You can't go back.
It's already happened.
Forward is the most probable outcome.
It's being proven
that it's possible.
- I'm writing a book.
A novel, actually. So some of the questions
I ask may seem a little out there.
- We need more time-travel
books in this world.
- We don't need more books,
Mr. Wertz. We do need more
scientists that make the ideas
in those books a reality.
- Professor Jacobs...
- I'm sorry, Aidan. Go on.
- Uh... It's about a guy who finds a hole
in a room that leads to yesterday.
He goes through it and then
comes back out twelve hours earlier.
- Intriguing.
- Impossible.
- Let him finish.
- If you were to travel backwards,
in time, say, to yesterday,
would you be... able to change your future?
- That all depends on the rules
of the time travel setting.
Can the traveler see
alternate versions of himself?
- Yes. Definitely.
- So that's complicated.
because time doesn't exist
in nature, of course.
It's a measurement of
movement in space.
- I tend to disagree with that.
Nature is based in time.
But we can go on and
on all night arguing
about what does and
doesn't exist.
- I guess.
So, what are the rules?
How does it all work?
- Well, in fiction there are
four elements of time.
- What about non-fiction?
- I guess it would be the same.
If you could travel through time,
there would have to be
a hole in space-time,
a rip, if you like.
If you could survive the
journey through the hole,
well, you'd arrive at the same
space at a different time,
or a different space, different time.
- Correct me if I'm wrong.
- Yeah, like a wormhole or a Stargate.
Go on. You're doing fine.
- So, if you could travel
back through... uh...
I'll tell you what.
A visual might be useful here.
- What are you doing?
- So, this is your life from birth to death.
And this is you today.
So, if we would go back in time to...
- Yesterday.
- ... yesterday,
OK, now, if time is circular,
you would bring space back to yourself
and travel through.
You could in theory visit
past versions of yourself.
In a two parallel universe theory
one that is all in slices,
an infinite amount really,
it wouldn't actually be time but
another dimension in reality.
- Because time...
- Doesn't exist in nature.
Well, I need to add that.
- So, what does this man do
when he goes through the hole?
- Uh... well, he's trying to save somebody.
A girl.
- Classic.
- Predictable.
- So, he's already in a parallel universe,
because past versions of himself have
already visited him before he traveled.
You seem confused by
your own writing.
It's very confusing.
There's no pattern to it. He
tried to stop the accident
as many times as he could,
but nothing ever worked.
- If he can't change his
own future surely he can
change the future of a
different version of himself.
Exactly. He cannot
change his own line of
existence and yet
influence another line.
- Then that sucks.
- So he needs to change a
different version of himself
to get the desired result.
- This story needs more emotion.
How does he know this girl?
- Uh, it's his ex-girlfriend.
- Weak, overused plot element. He
needs to save a part of himself.
- But wouldn't the girl be a part
of himself? A part of his history?
- Only if he set up a relationship in
the beginning. Set up to destroy.
It... lacks surprise, but it works.
What you'd really need is a twist.
- There are a lot of twists.
- But..
That's what keeps it into these days.
Special effects and twists.
- None. He just goes through the hole.
Turns up at the same hole.
- Sounds like the last 25
years of my marriage.
- Well, thanks for letting me
speak to your friends tonight, Mr. Wertz.
- You're more than welcome, mate.
Are you sure you're OK?
- Yeah.
I'm all good.
- So where would you go?
If you could?
- I don't know.
How about you?
Forward first
and then back to fix it.
When I was twelve years
old, I had this idea.
Most of my friends had
dreams of flying.
Mine were of traveling through
time, as a matter of fact.
I'd sit down at my grandfather's
typewriter and write to the universe.
The idea was to become famous.
I'd put the call out that I
wanted to travel through time.
Go on T.V.,...
... newspapers, concerts, t-shirts, books,
really put the word out there that
I wanted to travel through time.
But I realized that time travel
in my lifetime would be impossible.
So I hoped that
someone in the future would
remember the time travel kid.
When time travel was actually possible,
you know? They'd go back
and come and get me.
- Maybe one day.
- So, your character... can it go forward?
- Only back.
- Make sure he goes back
for the right reasons.
Make sure he influences
the most important situations.
- I will.
- Aidan, 27. Graduated two years ago,
extremely high marks in
philosophy and psychology.
You were a state champion scout member.
Mom left you as a baby,
then Gran took the rights.
You broke up with
Lauren a few years ago,
decided to take her on a joy ride.
You crashed the car, killed her,
then ran away and then
you find yourself here.
- Dum, dum, dum...
Can I ask you why you
left the hospital?
- I don't know.
- Do you remember us telling
you that you shouldn't?
- Yeah.
- You're deep in a lot
of trouble, Aidan.
We know what you did and why you did it.
Were you supposed to
die in that crash?
Is that why you're upset?
Your plan didn't work out properly?
- I had nothing to do with it.
The accident.
- Ah...
the boy's triggered a memory.
Things don't add up, Aidan.
You seemed genuinely
concerned the last time we
spoke to you, then you
decided to just run off.
Not to get away,
but to go back to... where
you... picked her up from.
So, the question is...
what happens next?
- What happens, Aidan?
- You confess to us,
right now.
You're heading to court,
the judge will be lenient,
say nothing, confess silence,
your penalty will be
something to regret.
- So what's it gonna be?
- You wanna know the truth?
- Please.
- I found a time portal.
A hole that leads back to yesterday.
- Wow...
- This is classified as insanity.
- I tried to go back and stop the accident.
- I couldn't save her.
- They never can.
- So you killed her and then went back in
time to stop yourself from killing her?
- I'm telling you the truth.
- So, you can really travel back in time?
So, why waste that privilege
on trying to save Lauren?
You still love her.
- I went back to stop the
accident from happening.
To save her.
I couldn't.
So I have to go back and try again.
- Why not go back in time and
break yourself out of custody?
- I'm not the only one of me out there.
Thanks for the idea.
- Woohoo!
Hoohoohoo.
- Come on! Come dance with me! Come dance.
Come dance with me!
- You'll be waiting.
You're not even funny.
- Ha-ha! You got Meth?
Got heroin? Got any of the good kind?
Huh? You got to answer.
You got to answer to me.
Never. We're in this together. Dancin',
dancin', you gonna dance with me?
Try this step. This works well.
This works well.
Try this step.
Try it. Try these. Try dancing with me.
- Hey, hey, hey... you have to swap with me.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Alright!
Oh, good step!
Oh! Oh!
- OK... go.
- Oh, wow! Look!
- Shh!
- Gotta keep dancing, man.
We're ahead of you, beginner.
it can't hurt.
We'd go home. Really good, man.
Don't leave me. Don't go.
Don't go! Don't leave me!
Come back! Come back!
Me and you!
Oh!
Hey!
It's me, Aidan.
- Sorry? Can... can I help you?
- You don't remember, do you?
- I'm sorry?
- Can I ask you a question?
- I think you just did.
- What do you do for a living?
- I'm a lawyer.
- Was there ever a chance any lot of
this could have gone another way?
- I don't know what you mean.
- Like your lot could have changed?
Like you weren't gonna be a lawyer?
- Well,
yes, as a matter of fact,
I almost went off to war.
- And then what happened?
- I... I registered and I
was preparing to leave
and then the strangest thing happened.
I'm sorry. I don't know you.
- That's alright. You've said enough.
You've changed, moved on,
it's... it's possible.
- OK.
- Tomato sauce
and the musical Archie.
- A blue guitar and a
frozen gorilla lamp.
- Hello?
- I've seen you before.
- Grandma.
- I wish...
I could see your grandfather again.
- Can I take you somewhere?
No...
- I'm so sorry.
- No, nothing.
- Will you read to me?
- Yeah, sure.
- In my bag
at the top.
- Where shall we begin?
- The end.
- Oh, well, you again!
Is this the first time?
Or the second time?
Yesterday or... or tomorrow?
Who knows? Who cares?
- You might wanna put that knife down.
- Oh no,
you can't stop me from cutting myself.
Don't you get it yet?
If I don't cut myself, I
don't get take to hospital,
I don't meet you for the first time,
and tell you to come here!
- I can't change it?
- You can only influence it
to change it, not intervene.
You can't physically stop
me from cutting myself!
- So how do you... know that you're
gonna tell me to come here
if I'm already standing in front of you and
you haven't been to the hospital yet?
- Exactly!
So how do I influence time?
- Open the door please, it's the management.
- I saw you.
A better version...
a different version of you.
You saw her, did you?
- Thought I'd try it out.
- Worse. It will change your life.
- Not exactly, but close enough, right?
What the hell?
- You think that's how we go there?
- You're a smart one!
- How did you do it?
How did you influence the
alternate version of you to do...
- The trick is to stop the person from being
in the situation in the first place.
if you can figure that out.
Open please.
Open up.
Remember...
time travels with you.
- Hello.
- I'm looking for Bloodfield.
- Oh, you're a field away from there.
- Oh, really?
- Say... you look familiar.
Do we know each other?
- Not yet.
Aidan.
- Dwight.
This is Aidan, dear.
- Oh.
- Aidan, this is my wife.
- Hello. Nice to meet you, Aidan. Stop it...
- I'm going to give Aidan a lift in
the town. Would you like anything?
- Yeah, actually, if you could return the
library books for me that would be great.
Say, you look awfully familiar to me.
- I get that a lot.
- I said the same thing.
- Must just be all in my head.
- Isn't everything all just in your head?
- Well, we should be off.
- OK.
Bye.
Lovely to meet you, Aidan.
- You too.
- Goodbye.
- A golf ball
drowned your grandfather. You know?
Wish I could see him again.
- I've got something.
- What is it?
- You have to open it tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- Don't open it until then.
It's very important.
See you soon.
- So,
your character,
can it go forward?
- Only back.
- Make sure he goes back
for the right reasons.
Make sure he influences the
most important situations.
- I will.
- You have to go to the East Gate motel.
- Can I walk you home?
- The truth is
we're not really here for that long.
And for the majority of us,
we only get one chance.
At all of this.