In 1964, Granada Television brought together
a group of 7-year-olds
from all over the country
and from all walks of life.
I'm going to work
in Woolworth's.
I read
the Financial Times.
They talked about their dreams, their
ambitions, and their fears for the future.
Everything flew up in the air
and that all landed on my head.
For nearly half a century,
in a unique groundbreaking series of films,
we have followed their lives
every seven years.
They are now 56.
Lynn, Sue and Jackie grew up
in London's East End
and were friends
at school.
In this school,
we do metalwork
and woodwork
and the boys
do cookery.
All you girls want to do
is walk out, get married,
have babies and push
a pram down the street
with a fag hanging out
the side of your mouth.
I think that we all
could have gone
any way that we wanted to
at the time
within our
capabilities.
But we only had
a limited choice anyway.
Truth be told...
we didn't have the choice
or private education
because they couldn't have
afforded it anyway.
Our lives are changing
far too much.
All of us.
To be honest, when you look
at the 7-year-old us,
it's difficult to believe
it is us.
I've got to say, girls,
I wanted to work
in Woolworth's.
I'm glad you said that, 'cause
everyone thinks it was me.
Sometimes we go out and play
nasty with the boys
and sometimes we go out
and argue with the boys.
I don't think I'll get married
too early.
I'd like to have
a full life first.
Marriage means a different thing
to me.
I've still got my ideals
about marriage.
I don't know
what it's all about.
Sue was 24
when she married Billy
and they had two children,
William and Katherine.
I think that
to get married young,
there must be things
that you miss.
You must miss that crucial stage
of being yourself,
because the minute you
get married,
you're no longer a single being,
you're a partnership,
and that should be
the idea behind it.
By the time Sue was 35,
she was divorced.
I've never sat down
and thought,
"What was it?
Was it this, was it that?"
I just knew
it wasn't working.
There have been relationships
when I could have settled,
but they didn't feel
quite right.
So I've always come away
and pulled away
and just waited until
the right one come along.
If they ever do.
♪ Said you'd be comin' back... ♪
At 42, when we filmed Sue
in the karaoke bar,
she brought Glen along
to watch her sing.
♪ Oh, baby ♪
We just met and things are going well,
but now, obviously,
things are going very well.
Well, we've been engaged now
for about...
14 years.
I'm not beating any records,
but it's quite a long time, isn't it, yeah.
Come on!
Jessie, come on!
We're completely different
people.
He's very energetic
and tidy-minded,
and I'm lazy
and completely un...
You're lazy?
I am completely,
absolutely lazy.
Anything you want me
to do?
What about the romance
of getting married?
Yeah, I mean,
I do admit it would be a nice party
and I quite relish the idea
of having everyone round
and having a good old drink
and a celebration.
But I can have
a party anytime.
Who are you on the phone to?
Never you mind.
When I got married,
the primary reason was because
I wanted to have a child.
The two to me went together.
Have you and Glen thought
of having your own child?
Glen would have
made a great dad.
When we first got together,
he sort of asked me
if we could have a family
and all that,
but I felt that I was past it,
to be honest.
I mean, I had two teenagers and didn't want
to do that again.
But he's loved
bringing them up.
Last time we talked about
a bit of tension in that area.
No, I think that was
probably just the age they were
and every family goes
through that.
There was nothing in particular,
I don't think.
It's just the whole part
of growing up, really.
Wasn't easy being
a single mother, was it?
No, it wasn't.
I look back on it now
and I'm just amazed
at how I got through it,
you know.
What was
the toughest part of it?
Probably a combination of not having
enough money to do what you want
and being alone and scared
when things happen
and things go wrong, which they
always do when you've got kids.
You've got no one there
to turn to, you know,
to talk about things
like that.
And you had to work.
Yeah, but I was always
only part-time,
so that I could fit it
around school.
So who was
the biggest help to you
during this whole
single-parent...?
There's no doubt at all,
without my mum and dad,
I would never have survived it.
They were brilliant.
They were really good.
They mean the world to the kids
and they used to look
after them.
Always be there if something happened
and I had to go somewhere.
Yeah, nice, ain't they?
And how
are they doing now?
Yeah, they're fine.
Dad's 80 now.
And mum's 78.
I think I'm so lucky that
they're still reasonably active.
There you go.
That's lovely, that one,
isn't it?
I've still got Katherine
with me
because she hasn't found
anywhere else to go.
I mean, I'm sure she would
love to leave me,
but I love it,
the fact that she's here.
We go shopping
and do girlie things.
Do each other's hair
and things like that,
so I would miss her,
but I know
that she needs to get out
and move on.
Only had to have one filling.
That's about the only thing
that I had done.
What about William?
Well, he went
to Australia for a year.
And he never settled back in,
being independent.
I think it was too much.
Plus his room here
was far too small.
And his computer was bigger
than the room, you know.
So, um...
Yes, he's renting.
It's just so hard for him to
be able to afford something,
so in the future, your kids
are going to be with you
for a long, long time.
But a lot of my work is involved
in making bookings
and dealing with
hotels abroad.
At 21, Sue worked
for a travel agent.
At 35, part-time
for a building society.
Everything's changed for me
because I'm now
supporting myself a lot more
than I was, say, a year ago.
At 42, she went back to work
full-time,
helping to run the courses
in the legal faculty
of Queen Mary College,
University of London.
At 49, she was
the main administrator
for their
post-graduate program.
Do you like
the responsibility?
Yeah, I love
the responsibility.
I think I was born
for the responsibility.
I'm now sort of
the coordinator
of the entire program.
So, sort of "Marge in charge,"
really, of the LLM.
It's like my baby, really.
You know, I've nurtured it from its
small beginnings into what it is now.
Thank you very much.
See you at graduation, yeah?
I really do enjoy it.
I get up of a morning
and I don't ever think, "oh,
I can't face going to work."
But that happens to a lot of
people, so I'm lucky, really.
Someone's having trouble
downloading this attachment
so I'll take this down
for them.
Sue, you've got
a lot of responsibility.
Is there stress
attached to it?
Sometimes. I mean,
some parts of the year
are busier than others,
and you've got deadlines
to meet.
But then, in a way,
that's good,
because it keeps you
on your toes, you know.
Never get bored.
Where does the life of my
respectable, middle-class mother
overlap with
a working-class slapper
who leaves her illegitimate
child on a church doorstep?
- She was not!
- You don't know!
She was young and frail...
It started not long after
the last program with Tony,
my neighbor, and he belonged
to the group.
And I said,
"Oh, I've been wishing
I could do dramas for years,"
you know,
since I was at school,
and he said, "Come along."
♪ That's the time you must
keep on trying ♪
♪ Smile ♪
♪ What's the use of crying... ♪
To stand on the stage
and sing
and have people, hopefully,
appreciate it, hopefully,
you know, but there's still
that little nervous thing,
the butterflies in your stomach
when you're waiting
for the curtains to open
and, you know,
it's a buzz, really.
Realistically, this is the point
you really do have to consider.
You can't do two modules
that are taught
at the same time, obviously.
When I get on the stage to speak
to 500 students,
some people would find that
very daunting.
But I actually don't
because I think if you know they
can never ask you something
you don't know the answer to,
then I think that helps build
your confidence.
And I'm not exactly shy,
am I?
It always takes one, you see.
Once you get one,
other people tend to ask.
You never went
to university and now
you're right in the middle of
a huge university machine.
I suppose I should count
my blessings
that I'm actually in
a university,
having not done it myself,
yeah.
Looking at it,
do you wish you had had that opportunity?
Not really.
It's the same as anything.
Why look back and say, "I wish
I did this or had done that"?
I've had a good career.
At least I'll have my own home.
Which is a new thing
for my family.
My mom and dad are obviously
still in Council Place.
I'll never be a rich pensioner;
I'll never be able
to travel the world once
I retire, I'm afraid,
but as long as I can keep
the house warm
and we can feed ourselves,
that will be fine.
I don't like the big boys
hitting us
and the prefects
sending us out for nothing.
When he was 7,
Paul was in care
in a children's home
in London.
Were you happy at
the children's home in England?
We didn't mind that, really,
because we didn't know
what was going on
'cause we were a bit young.
Well, as far as I know,
my mother and father...
Well, they separated
originally, I think.
And they eventually
got divorced.
I went to the boarding school
for one year
and then we emigrated
to Australia.
Paul settled with his father
and stepmother
in a suburb of Melbourne.
Would you like to get
married, Paul?
Tell me why not.
I don't like like, um...
Say you had a wife.
Like, say you had to eat
what they cooked you.
And say I don't like greens.
Well, I don't.
I know I'd prefer
to be alone, really.
I can't say I don't want
to get married,
'cause I think I do, but I want
to be happily married,
and not before
when I'm not sure.
What was it that you
fell in love with?
What is it about him?
His helplessness,
I suppose.
Just the motherly instinct
in me,
to pick him up
and cuddle him.
He's also very good-looking,
I think,
but he doesn't agree with me.
In the summer, he's got this
cute little bum in shorts.
I mean, I can tell
quite a few stories,
but the one that really
irritates me the most is,
when we have an argument,
he says, "That's it, leave me."
I say, "Fine, all right,
I will one day."
We had our 20th wedding
anniversary
just before Christmas.
Which is
the life sentence.
And one reckons that we
should be out of jail by now.
To a certain extent,
we started thinking,
well, do we really know
each other now?
Because you just get in
the humdrum
of going to work,
coming back home.
Running kids here...
Kids here and there.
I don't think you mean to be,
probably stop thinking
about each other a lot.
It's still the last
person you want to see at night
before you go to sleep
and the first person
you want to see
when you wake up.
Do you still like to
cuddle and love and all that?
Yeah, but not in public.
No. Yes.
But is
the chemistry still there?
Yes.
You don't sound sure.
Well, we like
to keep it private.
I had to wait
for the answer.
I find it hard to express
emotion most of the time.
Although I'm getting on top of
that more now, you know.
Just the simple things
to say to Susan.
"I love you,"
something like that.
I mean, I can tell you
about it,
but I really haven't been able
to say it
to Sue, you know.
I did end up having to get
a bit of help.
It wasn't directly due
to our relationship.
It started at work,
unfortunately.
Which brought
my self-esteem down,
which tended to affect
everything else.
I know the lack of confidence
is there.
It still applies to me.
But I don't dwell on it.
It's there, and I have
to put up with it.
I just think you take on
a little bit more of
each other's personality.
'Cause whenever I was decisive
and made a decision and said,
"Let's do this," because Paul,
not that he couldn't make
the decision
but he had all these questions
to ask, and I used to think,
"Oh, stop asking questions,"
and I suppose now I start to question myself,
"maybe he should
ask the questions."
So it is that bit of living
with the other personality.
I was going to be
a policeman
but I thought how hard it would
be to join in.
I was going to be
a phys-ed teacher,
but one of the teachers
told me that
you had to get up
into university.
As a young man,
Paul spent many years
in the building trade
and then moved on
into factory work.
Okay, the question was,
Gracie Fields' sang...
"In the what
in the Moonlight?"
It's a retirement village
with independent living.
And then it's got
assisted living in the hostel,
which is mainly
where I work.
It's got six letters.
Gracie Fields sang...
They have their own laundry.
It's a complete unit.
They have their own
lockup garage.
So there's a couple
of parcels there...
And that's why Paul's there.
I call him "the man about
the house" at work,
because he changes
light globes.
Problems with your taps,
they go check it out.
Cleans the gutterings,
fixes squeaky doors,
'cause the village is now
25 years old.
So the maintenance is starting
to gather.
How are you doing
up there, Paul?
When the job came up,
I said to Susan
that if there was
any problem at all
with us working together,
then I'd leave.
But so far we've found it
really quite good.
- Hi, Lola, how are you?
- I'm good, Paul.
I've probably always been
a little bit more relaxed
around older people, probably.
Always liked older people as I
was growing up, funny enough.
By the time they were 28,
Paul and Sue had two children,
Katie and Robert.
Katie did well at school
and went on to university,
the first person
in her entire family
ever to do so.
Robert trained
as a car mechanic.
He met his wife Stacey
when they were teenagers
and now they have
five children.
So there's Lucas,
who is 9.
Then there's Ryan,
who is about to turn 7
at the end of this month.
Then there's Haley, who's just
turned 5.
And she'll start school
in the new year.
Then there's Shane,
known as Shane-o,
and he is 3 this week.
He's the joker out of
the lot of them.
If he does something
and you laugh,
he'll laugh with you,
and he loves a joke.
And then there's little Troy
that's 12 weeks old.
I look back at my grandmother
and I've taken some wonderful
lessons from her.
Grandma made us all feel that we
were her special number one,
but I think that's the secret
to being a grandparent is to
make every child feel that they
have someone that they
can relax with,
be themselves with.
Grandparents now have a really
huge part to play
in their parents' lives because
the pressure's on them
to work so much,
and grandparents fill that hole
of mum not being home every day.
I've already made them, so there
they are for the kiddies.
And your Rich likes
fairy bread.
Get some spoilers
and snakes in there.
♪ Happy birthday,
dear Shannon ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Not you!
It's a real struggle
for them, financially.
But at the same time, like all
young kids, there's areas
we look at and go,
"We didn't have that."
I've got 23 threepenny pieces,
and I don't know how many
ha'penny pieces I've got now.
Look, there's a whole
stack of duckies over there.
None of our kids have got
credit cards.
They don't live
a credit life, yet.
They try and pay as they go,
which is what we've
always thought,
and that's kept our head
above water, just.
We always thought if we were
unemployed or out of work,
if you own your house,
you've got a huge buffer.
And Robert's
of the same belief.
In their 20s,
Paul and Sue sold up,
bought an old van, and traveled
across Australia.
We were close together,
because we really got
to know each other and relied
on each other so much.
One of the most important
things we ever did
with our children,
we spent time with them,
and particularly when
you've got holidays.
You know, go camping with them.
Well, we went over
to visit Katie,
because she was working up in the top
end of Yorkshire on a community farm.
We were missing her.
We just didn't want
to tell her that.
Well, they miss you
when you're away.
Do you miss them?
I didn't miss them, like,
God, I wanna be around them,
but I thought about them a lot
and appreciated them a lot,
which is probably good.
So are the three of you
getting on well?
Yeah, most of the time.
As long as we're not
in the car.
Getting lost.
We're atrocious
in the car.
But other than that,
we're good.
It is good.
When we were in London,
we went to Greenwich.
It was built as a maritime
retirement village, almost,
for the sailors from
the Napoleonic Wars,
so that was all
really interesting
because we work in
retirement villages.
These buildings here were built
before Australia was even
discovered.
So that's pretty amazing.
Katie was in awe of it
because
in her degree,
she did art history,
so she just loved it.
What does "university" mean?
Are you going to try and point
your grandchildren into education?
You want them to have
a good education
no matter what they do.
Better
than you had, maybe?
But that's my fault,
really.
I mean, I just didn't
work hard enough, I guess.
You hope the school systems
have changed
to encourage kids to go on,
because one thing
you can't take away from people
is an education.
I mean, the one thing
my daughter's taught me
is that it doesn't
matter what you do,
there's room for all of us,
even to the point
if you don't work, you're still
teaching us something.
You're teaching
other people to care.
How are you dealing
with getting old?
I don't think
you really notice it.
You still think
you're the same.
Maybe when you try
to do something
physically too quickly
and pull a muscle,
that just reminds you
that you're getting older.
Are you fearful of
the future of disability
or unable to do things?
You hope that you're
going to be
one of the fortunate ones
and not get ill in any way.
- Hello, Ken.
- Hello, Paul.
Maybe where I work
may have helped that recently
because people just tend to
get on with their lives
no matter what.
And then that's the one
with the palace.
You got a nice shot
of the bin, there.
That one's good.
You're getting better.
Shut up.
Do you measure your life
in terms of success
and failure in any sense?
I don't really.
I suppose the success is that
we're sitting here together
and that we haven't had
tragedy happen to us.
It's just about getting on
with life
and then enjoy
our grandchildren,
our children, and our friends,
you know.
Yeah. Our goals
of life have never...
And then work
just gets in the way.
Well, we pretend we've
got swords
and we make the noise
of the swords fighting,
and then once we get stabbed,
we go, "aaaah!"
Neil grew up in
a Liverpool suburb
and had dreams
of going to Oxford
but didn't get in.
Instead, he went
to Aberdeen University,
but dropped out
after the first term.
At 21, Neil was working
on a building site
and living in a squat.
I would like to be somebody in
a position of importance,
and I've always thought it,
but I don't think I'm
the right sort of person
to carry the responsibility
for whatever it is...
I always thought,
well, I'd love to be possibly
in politics
or something like this.
At 28,
we found Neil homeless,
wandering around
the west coast of Scotland.
If the money runs out,
then for a few days,
there's nowhere to go to
and that's all you can do.
I simply have to find
the warmest shed I can find.
At 35, he was living
in a Council estate
on the most northerly part
of Britain,
the Shetland Islands.
And what would you like
to be doing, say in seven years?
I can think of all kinds
of things I'd like to be doing.
The real question is, what am I
likely to be doing?
What are you likely
to be doing?
That's a horrible question.
Um...
I tend to think the most likely
answer is that
I'll be wandering homeless
around the streets of London.
Can I just point out some of
the considerable disadvantages?
First of all...
At 42, Neil had moved
to London
and was a Liberal Democrat
on Hackney Council.
While I was in Shetland,
I felt very strongly
that I should become
involved in politics.
Simply because I felt
I was not achieving anything
in the ways I really wanted to.
By 49, Neil had left London.
Moved to Cumbria
in the northwest of England,
and was a Liberal Democrat
member
of his local district council.
It was a committee decision,
a majority decision.
His own group on
the Establishment Committee
agreed with the decision.
Councilor Hughes?
The Councilor Cook has
reconsidered his opinion
he ventured at that meeting.
Here we are in the center
of the ward I represent
on the council.
These are
our public toilets.
I can assure you that no more
fierce battle has been fought,
either on the playing fields
or indeed
on the battlefields
of England, to save
what might appear to be
a comparatively
insignificant
local amenity.
It sounds vaguely comic,
but presumably it's not to you.
But when you live
in a small community,
you become very proud,
rightly, of the facilities here.
And people are willing to play
a part
in helping to keep them going,
but they don't want
to be ignored, they don't want
to be marginalized.
My strength is being able
to keep going, really.
My weakness is not being able
to take any positive course
of action.
No formal education can prepare
anybody for life.
Only life can prepare you
for what comes.
And sooner or later,
you're going
to have to cross
certain barriers.
There are a few things
I would like to say.
And the first thing to say is,
there's been
tremendous good will
toward the series.
But I'm also aware that I'm
not the only participant
who wants to set the record
straight in a number of ways.
For so many millions of people,
I'm here wearing my heart
on my sleeve.
And they think they know
absolutely everything about me.
There were countless people
writing me, saying,
"I know exactly how
you feel."
And actually,
from those letters,
I would say none of them,
not a single one of them,
knew exactly how
I was feeling.
I've got a great deal of respect
for the Liberal Democrats,
but I think that I won't
vote for them this time...
Here in Cumbria,
I'm really glad to be doing
what I do to be representing
people
at local political level.
But in one sense I'm doing that
because it's the only way I've
been able to make any money.
I get a derisory amount of money
for being a councilor.
I do enjoy the work, but I've
been completely unsuccessful
in trying to find a paid career
of any kind.
I have always wanted to write
as a career
and indeed have written
huge amounts.
And ironically, despite
appearing in this program
so frequently, nobody
has ever shown
any serious interest in any
of the work I do.
And believe me, it's a great
deal more important to me
than anything I can say
on the television screen.
Even if somebody sent it back
to me and said,
"Well, I read it,
and it's rubbish, actually,"
that would be very demoralizing,
but at least some interaction
would have taken place.
There's hardly a day goes by
when I don't write.
That's a great gift,
isn't it?
It is, but it shouldn't be
a sort of masturbation
about which nobody else
knows anything.
Neil Hughes is
the Liberal Democrat candidate.
I and the Liberal Democrats want
to see a just and fair society.
In 2006, I was invited to go to
Australia to give a talk,
and the chap
who introduced me said,
"Neil is clearly such a
profoundly motivated politician
that we can all expect to see
him as Prime Minister
of the United Kingdom."
This wasn't a joke, I assure you
he said this
with absolute seriousness.
Now, it was ludicrous,
but this is how wildly skewed
the perceptions have become.
Do you think I would
really have been
invited to Australia if they
were aware that I was someone
who lives on a few quid a week
benefit and has
as much chance of changing the
future of the United Kingdom
as...
I don't know,
someone who's serving
a lifetime jail sentence?
Yes, I'd say
I believed in God.
Are you religious?
Well, I go to church with
my parents on Sundays.
I don't know even now whether I
do believe in God or not.
I've thought an awful lot
about it, actually.
And I still don't know.
And how has he been
treating you?
Well, I said to somebody last
week that I preferred
the Old Testament
to the New Testament.
Because in the Old Testament,
God is very unpredictable.
And that's, I think,
how I've seen Him in my life.
And Doreen as well...
I was first a lay reader
in London.
After completing
a little more training,
I was relicensed by
the bishop of Carlisle.
Well, good morning.
Welcome to our service today.
Just a couple of notices first.
If you haven't already
been told,
the proposed pet show
is, unfortunately, cancelled.
I'm the lay minister.
I'm licensed to carry out
quite a number of functions.
That includes leading services, preaching,
taking part in the readings,
helping to distribute
the communion, and so on.
In fact, I can do more or less
everything a priest can do.
To what extent
am I a good model for others?
I don't know.
On the other hand,
I am angry that so many doors
have been closed,
not just for me,
but for so many people.
I do feel nobody's
listening out there.
There seem to be
few currents
that are encouraging people to
stand up for their rights,
not just their strict
legal rights,
but their rights
to be human.
In the name of the Father and of
the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
I'm not unappreciative of
the honor it's been
to be able to serve
the church,
to be able
to serve my community,
and I want to make that
absolutely clear.
And it's true, I think it was Albert
Camus who said that life is what happens
while you're waiting for
something else.
But it's not the sort of place
where someone
who wants to change society
is best employed.
I would have thought
that was pretty obvious.
In the winter, if you live in the country,
it was just all wet
and there wouldn't be anything
for miles around.
We're a very quiet village.
There's always room for more
activity and for more people
being involved, but I think
we do fairly well
as a diversity of groups.
They're still trying to
persuade me to go in.
Apparently Alan has cried off
at the last minute,
so there's just
the two of them.
I think it was Pascal, the great
philosopher and mathematician,
who said that if a man can live
happily in his own living room
most of his life, then he's achieved
the utmost philosophical breakthrough,
and philosophically speaking,
that's true, but I can't.
You stick me in my living room
for one hour on my own
and I want to be out
doing something.
I want to be out
changing things.
I have always had
a nervous complaint.
I've had it since I was 16.
It was responsible for my
leaving university
and for some of my difficulties
with work.
Do you worry about
your sanity?
Um...
Other people sometimes
worry about it.
Like who?
As I said, I sometimes can
be found behaving in...
in an erratic fashion.
Sometimes I get very frustrated.
Very angry.
For no apparent reason.
For a reason which won't be apparent
to other people around me.
I don't see any way out.
I've thought of everything
I possibly could.
It seemed to me for a long time
that getting a reliable job
and a nice place to live
would be the solution.
Well, I haven't succeeded.
I can't see any immediate future
at all.
Although there have been times
in my life
when I've been suicidal,
that wasn't one of them.
So there have been
worse than...
Yes, but it's not for
this program
to expose my private feelings,
and yet many people feel
it has.
Ultimately.
Although this time round,
I've been far more candid
than I perhaps ever have
in the past.
My formal contact with
the psychiatric establishment
belongs mostly to my mid
and later teens
and a short period
of my early 20s.
But I soon came
to the opinion
that I could help myself
far better
than those who were
purporting to help me.
But I was aware even then that a
lot of the therapeutic technique
is about leading people
to exactly this conclusion,
if it's done well.
So I'm not going down the line
of criticizing
the medical establishment.
But did you refuse to go
into any sort of treatment?
No, I did have contact.
But then you
discontinued it.
Yes.
Do you still think
that was wise?
Yes.
Are you scared
of getting old?
Yeah, I don't want to live
to be that old.
I think if I can reach
something like 70
or 75 in reasonable health,
that will be quite enough
for me.
When I get married,
I don't want to have
any children,
because they're always doing
naughty things
and making
the whole house untidy.
I always told myself that I
would never have children.
Why?
Because...
Well, because children inherit
something from their parents.
And even if my wife were
the most high-spirited
and ordinary and normal
of people,
the child would still stand
a very fair chance
of being not totally full
of happiness
because of what he or she will
have inherited from me.
Have you ever really had
a romantic emotional
relationship?
Oh, I've had several,
but the fact that I'm living
alone still
obviously betrays the fact that
none of them has endured.
Is there a reason
for that?
Relationships always involve
two people.
But the string of
failures,
does that tell us something?
Well, I'm sure it does.
Any fool can see that.
I'm not saying you're a fool.
What does it tell us?
It tells you what you like.
It tells you that I haven't been
successful in relationships.
It may tell you that I'm
intolerant.
But it more likely tells you
that I don't have
the capacity for making
a relationship work.
But I must stress again
that it does take two.
I have never walked out of any
relationship with anyone.
It sounds like ghostly
colored people.
'Cause you think of
a purple person
with red eyes
and yellow feet.
You can't really think of what
they really look like.
I find it hard to believe
that I was ever like that,
but there's the evidence.
Probably when I was 7, I just
lived in a wonderful world
where everything
was a sensation.
I could be happy and I could be
miserable the next minute.
What makes you happy?
"Happy"
is a difficult word.
How many people are happy?
Perhaps we're most happy
when we're not aware of it
and enjoying a relaxed meal
with some friends.
Just being with friends.
I think the few weekends
in the year
when I'm lucky to be able to
go and stay
with some of my long-term friends,
I'm really happy.
I can think of hardly
anything better
than walking across
the fields
when we just chat about the
things we're both interested in
and our aspirations, and I think
that's the noblest
and in many ways most satisfying
of relationships
you can possibly have.
How it would be if we lived
next-door to each other
I don't know,
it might be very different.
Maybe the joy in some
relationships is that
you see some people only
infrequently.
I don't think you ought to go
to university
if you want to be
an astronaut.
Watch this.
Peter and Neil
were childhood friends
growing up in Liverpool.
Peter went
to a comprehensive school
and went on to get a history
degree from London University.
I would like to think that
democracy is here to stay.
Perhaps we haven't got
full democracy.
In fact, we probably haven't,
but...
It's a pretty good system.
Are you surprised by the
way England's being governed?
I'm not surprised with
the people who govern it
at the moment right now.
I've even stopped being amazed.
Why?
Well, I don't want to get
dragged into party politics,
but basically this is the most
incompetent,
uncaring bloody shower
we've ever had.
After "28 Up,"
Peter decided not to continue
in the film.
Why did you pull out?
I pulled out because of...
the responses
and the reactions
that my participation drew
in the weeks afterwards.
Particularly in
the tabloid press.
They decided they were
going to portray me
as the angry young rad
in Thatcher's England.
Well, it's just the principle,
that's all there is to it.
I think I was articulating
at the time
what a lot of people of my age
and my background were thinking.
And I was an easy target.
They're part of it.
They perpetuate it.
But I was absolutely taken back,
completely, genuinely shocked,
at what I saw as
the level of malice
and ill-will
directed towards me.
Until you've experienced it
yourself,
you can't begin to appreciate
how it feels.
So now you're back.
So why did you come back?
I feel a lot happier
with myself.
Happier in my own skin.
And then secondly,
more specifically,
because I want to promote
the music and the band I'm in.
♪ It was a ghost town ♪
And what are you called?
We're called
the Good Intentions.
♪ But when he hit that bank... ♪
I'd always played
in rock bands.
Some of them
spectacularly bad bands.
What really got me into
this music
was being exposed to
the music of Graham Parsons,
'cause way back in the day,
I was a big Elvis Costello fan.
And I read an interview with him
in which he said, "if you think
I'm a good songwriter,
listen to Graham Parsons."
It was almost like an epiphany.
It was like I was hearing
the music I'd been waiting to
hear all my life.
Once, Caroline Sheffield said
she loved me.
And I'm going to marry...
many...
marry her when I grow up.
Doesn't appeal to me at all
at the moment,
but I mean, what,
I'm just gone 20.
Haven't even been abroad yet
in my life.
There's no way I'm going to
get settled down.
So, Paul, what do you want
to do?
Do you just want me and Peter to record
what we're doing and you'll work round it?
We were working in an office
together
when we joined
the office band
and that's how we got
to know each other.
So, Gabby, was it
love at first sight?
Well, I had a sneaking suspicion
that Pete liked me
because he was really rude and
sarcastic to me all the time,
so I thought, "I think he's
probably quite keen."
You know that's not true.
And you've always played
together since then?
Yeah, more or less.
We probably stopped for a while
when the kids were little.
Our boy is 19,
our daughter's 16.
And how
are they doing?
Great. Doing really good.
They're doing remarkably well.
Our son is in his first year
at university.
And our daughter is coming up
to her GCSEs.
Once you have your own kids,
you have this huge realization
of how your own parents
felt about you
and what they did for you.
What's the greatest gift
a parent can give a child?
It's their unstinting love
and support and their time.
Their time because I think
children value that
more than anything.
Unconditionally,
you giving them your time.
Well, if I can't be
an astronaut,
I'd like to be a Bridewell
sergeant in the police force,
like my dad is.
So are you under pressure
to get a job?
Yeah, I suspect I am
from my parents.
Keep dropping hints.
Teachers are undervalued
and underrated.
And the system's
beginning to crumble.
You know, people outside of it
don't realize that, but it is.
And it's...
it's very disillusioning.
I left teaching not long after
that program.
And it was actually nothing
to do with the program.
That was a misunderstanding
at the time,
I think, which took hold
in the press.
I'd been planning to leave
teaching anyway.
And I just didn't see
a long-term future in it
for myself.
And I thought I had been honest
with myself about that
and honest to the kids I was
teaching at the time
and move on
to something else.
After teaching,
Peter studied law
and joined
the civil service.
Gabby also works there.
Civil service, despite changes
currently taking place,
is still comparatively
a pretty decent employer.
What area of
the civil service are you in?
Department of Work
and Pensions.
I've changed the key...
an F sharp, sorry about that.
When Pete writes,
he often wants to share that
and at a fairly early stage talk
about what he's writing.
And if it's no good,
I have to tell him.
And that's quite difficult,
isn't it?
I'm sure it is, yeah.
♪ She was running down roads
I didn't know ♪
So when we started work
on the album we're doing now,
Pete said to me, "I've got 120
song ideas to go through,"
and I said, "But of those 120,
we need to get it down
to about 10 so I'm going to have
to tell you
that 110 are no good."
How do you take
criticism?
Well, I think I take it
better than I used to.
That's not setting the bar
very high, though.
No.
What have been for you
the best times?
Tommy Smith scoring
the second goal in Rome.
Definitely.
One of the all-times.
Which game was that?
That was the European Cup final,
1977.
That's still up there,
by the way.
But along with what?
But, well...
Um...
Getting married
for the second time
and having
two children
have been hugely significant
moments in my life.
What do you want
out of life?
The satisfaction of knowing
that I've left
some sort of imprint
rather than just lived out
my life.
♪ You've been gone
for so long, Evangeline ♪
♪ No one's looking for you
anymore ♪
I hesitate to say I think I have
made my mark now,
because that sounds
horrendously vain.
But I've created a body of work
of which I feel very proud.
I feel I've achieved something
of lasting value.
And in the last two
or three years,
we have begun to become
reasonably successful
in terms of
critical responses.
We were voted the U.K.'s
Americana Act of the Year
at the British
Country Music Awards.
From time to time,
like anybody else,
I look back and think,
"I wish I hadn't done that,
I wish I'd done that
differently," but I don't think
really life is there
to be regretted.
Life is there to be lived, and I
feel the most important thing
is to feel that by and large
you haven't
compromised too much
and that you've
moved your life on
where you want
your life to go.
I would like to get married
when I grow up.
Well, I don't know
what sort of boy,
but I think one that...
That's not got a lot of money,
but has got some money,
not a lot.
Jackie grew up
in London's East End.
Have you got
any boyfriends?
That's personal, isn't it?
By the time she was 21,
Jackie had married Mick
and moved to the outskirts
of London.
She and Mick had decided
early on
that they didn't want
to have children.
Basically, I would say that
would be far too selfish.
By 35, she was divorced.
We decided ourselves, I mean,
just between the two of us.
We knew it wasn't going
any further.
We both knew, I think,
at the end of the day,
we would be happier
leading our own lives.
Oh...
And this one on, oh, yeah.
Here we go.
Had a brief but very sweet
relationship,
the result of which
was Charlie.
I don't really want
Charlie to be an only.
I'd love him to
have brothers and sisters.
But not necessarily
loads of them.
One would do, actually.
Right, Charlie, there's yours.
Ooh!
Please eat it all up.
Oh!
And, James.
Thanks, Mum.
Good boy.
And last but not least...
You going to eat
that one for me?
After her relationship with
Charlie's father ended,
she met Ian, and they moved
to Scotland and had two sons.
James.
By 42, they had split up.
Lee.
Go and get 'em!
At 49, despite the split,
the family were living
in the same area
of Scotland.
Seven years later,
they're still there.
So tell me
who lives where.
Um, Lee will be here
until October.
James is here
until he moves in with
his girlfriend,
which I'm hoping
won't be too long.
Charlie's actually
already moved out
because of his dad.
Or their dad,
I should say.
Um, because Ian's been
diagnosed with cancer.
And it's stage four,
so it's quite advanced.
The strange part about this is,
his mother has also got
cancer as well.
Your grandmother?
Their grandmother.
Come on, swans!
She's brilliant.
If I could have chosen
a mother-in-law,
she was the one
I would have chosen.
She's great for me,
she's absolutely brilliant with the children.
And she's just always there when
I need her to be.
She's terminal.
How long has she got?
Don't know.
They don't know how long.
I think they're talking months
rather than years.
And to have mother and son
suffering the same sort of thing
is very difficult.
She doesn't want us
to be sorry
and be sad, she wants us
to go on and live our lives
and it's not stopped her
from trying to live her life.
It seems to have been
one thing after another.
My stepmom died,
my brother-in-law died,
my sister's died.
She wasn't 50.
She'd actually gone downstairs
and made herself a cup of tea
and collapsed on her way back up
to her bedroom
with a major brain hemorrhage.
So, boys, how is your
mother handling all this?
Uh, in her stride.
Nothing seems to be getting
to her.
She's always been
a strong woman.
She will be upset, but she won't
let us see it.
She's always a brave face
in front of us,
and then when she's alone
or with her friends,
that's when she
gets the sadness out.
This is a period when
the four of you feel close?
All: Mm-hmm.
Got to be there for each other
in things like this.
Actually, I would say
in the last six months,
they've all suddenly seemed to
have gotten maturity.
My mum, 'cause she got
five girls,
she has seven years bad luck.
That's why she's got five girls.
Two club sandwiches
on brown bread,
one Hilton burger with cheese.
Yes, chef.
Charlie is a sous chef
in a nearby hotel.
And James works part-time
as a security guard
in a local supermarket.
Check two aisles up
from your current location.
I expect my baby in December.
We're still young, obviously,
so it's a bit
of a shock, but I am excited
about it.
How old are you now?
19, coming on 20.
Are you excited
to be a gran?
Couldn't bear that.
She doesn't like
being called "granny."
No, I will be "gran,"
not "granny," thank you.
Not nappy full now,
please, madam.
Oh, look at the face.
Well, since you were here
recently,
we've had a new addition
to the family.
Her name is Mia.
Mia was born
on the 21st of November.
And unfortunately, on the 18th
of November, her granddad,
Ian, the boys' dad,
was severely injured
in a road traffic accident.
He subsequently died
of those injuries.
Unfortunately, he never regained
consciousness
so he never even met her.
But he took a photo of her
in his coffin, and I dare say
he's looking down and saying,
"Ha, I got away with it.
I've not got all those nights."
I'm due to go into the Army
on the 17th of October,
where I'll learn to become
a medic.
I can't stop him now.
He's 18, he can do what
he likes.
He can sign on
without my approval.
But it's a chance he takes,
and he knows that there's
a possibility
that he won't come home.
At the end of the day,
you're a soldier
and going to war is part
of being a soldier
and that's what
you got to do.
I want you to do it, but it's
not going to stop me worrying.
You know that.
I took a year off when
I had Charlie
and the state kept me
for that year.
But I went back to work,
and although,
to be honest, by the time
I pay everything out,
I'm not actually that much
better off, but I feel better.
James, you watch,
you're catching up to him.
Go on, Lee.
I was working up here
until very recently.
But then discovered that I've
got rheumatoid arthritis.
So at the moment,
that's put work on hold.
Misty, come on then.
For every one good day I have,
I can have two bad.
Which means I can't get out
of bed very well.
It takes me two, three hours
to get ready.
The poor,
if you don't help them, they'll
sort of die, wouldn't they?
Jackie has been living
on disability benefits
for over 14 years.
I don't cope financially.
Without my mother-in-law
stepping in to fill the gap,
I wouldn't be coping.
It's really hard to explain
to anyone
who's not had to do it.
You get to a point where,
either that bill doesn't get
paid or your children don't eat;
so, obviously,
your children eat.
So, looking
at the world of cutbacks,
how is this affecting you?
I, along with probably millions
of other people in this country,
have had my benefits reviewed.
And they sent me for a medical
and have come back and told me
I'm fit to work.
Which is a bit of a shock.
What job can I do?
I can't use my hands.
I can't sit for long.
I can't stand for long.
I can't walk very far.
I don't know how they expect
anybody to employ me.
Because I couldn't guarantee
being there five days a week.
I mean, I'm lucky inasmuch
as I've got three sons
all working,
whilst James here has got
Mia and a family of his own.
Charlie and Lee don't,
so they help me out.
They have to.
By all means,
cut the benefits.
But you've got people out there
that are healthy
and are milking the system.
And they're not touching them.
They're getting away with it.
If David Cameron can find me
a job, then I'll go to work.
You tell him to come get me
a job and I'll do it.
I know he loves her
and he loves her.
I don't, I love him.
I'd like to be able
to have a happy family.
I mean, I know it's not possible
to be happy all the time,
but as much of the time
as possible.
What about your own life?
What about relationships
for you?
I would like
a relationship.
I've been trying
for the last five years
to build up a social life
of my own.
Because I knew
that this time would come.
I've been using the Internet,
which is interesting,
to say the least.
Is it scary?
I mean, some people
have obviously
had bad experiences with it.
There was a chap
that we filmed when we were
looking at you and Liz...
what happened to him?
He decided
he needed space.
So I gave him that space.
So that was a bit of
a disaster.
But that's the way
of relationships... sometimes
they work, sometimes they don't.
What are you
looking for in a fella?
Pulse would be nice.
♪ If I said that I love you
and you know it's true ♪
You look great,
you seem optimistic.
Yeah, no, I am.
My glass is always half full,
never half empty.
And that's the way it will
continue to be, I hope.
Life's too short
and you just have to try and go
on the best you can.
And I think my life
is going to be good.
What sort of things
do you do?
Ride, swim,
play tennis.
Ping-pong.
And I might play croquet.
Things like that.
I don't think my father wants me
to be a farmer.
My youngest brother's
the deaf one,
if he can't do anything else,
he can probably run a farm.
I thought that you and I were
both in the film as being
rural, in the sense that
your family
had some big connections
to sort of rural Scotland.
I think also,
when we were 21,
I remember having to go
to some reunion somewhere,
and I remember you just
stuck out as being
the one person that I had more
in common with
and spoke to the most.
We'd been e-mailing
each other
since forty-something...
It was one night,
I think it was quite late,
and I just threw a line at Nick,
I said,
"I'm going to bed now.
Perhaps you and I ought to do
a double act on the sofa."
I mean...
And he wrote back some
funny message.
No wonder!
I would, wouldn't I?
When I leave the school,
I'm down for Heathfield
and Southover Manor.
And then maybe I may want
to go to an university,
but I don't know
which one yet.
My home life
wasn't very easy then.
I'd been sent off to boarding
school when I was quite young.
My parents' marriage
was breaking up.
And like
a lot of children,
I think you feel that you take
the blame
for why they've broken up.
That's just the way it was,
and I hated the two years
I was away at this first
boarding school, and I think
that was probably
what changed me.
Well, I hated boarding school,
too, with a passion.
I was forced to grow,
I didn't choose it.
I definitely got some messages
that said,
"You're going to be
in trouble
if you don't do well,"
and so on.
But you don't regret it.
And you wouldn't have
the life you have now.
Hey, I'm grateful for it,
but it was very uncomfortable.
I was never one
to push myself forward.
And nobody else
was pushing.
And no one else
pushed me.
I left school when I was 16.
I went to Paris.
I went to secretarial college
and got a job.
What made you decide to
leave school and go to Paris?
Well, I just wasn't interested
in school
and just wanted to get away.
If you had had no choice
but to get out there and support
yourself,
the chances would
have been greater
that you would have forced
yourself to do it.
Yeah, that's possibly true,
but at the age of...
11, 12, 13, are you really
aware of that?
Now, that's
a very telling question.
In my world, you betcha.
When I grow up,
I'd like to find out
all about the moon and all that.
And I said I was interested
in physics and chemistry,
I'm not going
to do that here.
At 14, Nick was away
at boarding school.
At 21, reading physics
at Oxford.
His road to Oxford started
in a one-room village school.
My father was here.
A long time ago, he must be
somewhere in these pictures.
I remember distinctly
coming here one day
and I'd missed a day
for some reason
and they'd been talking about
something to do with aeroplanes.
And the teacher said,
"We missed you
because you would have known
about aeroplanes."
I knew nothing about aeroplanes,
but I thought,
"Oh, I know about aeroplanes,
do I?"
So then I went off
and read about aeroplanes.
That could easily have been
the start of,
"I want to go
to the moon."
I think she planted
that idea in me.
Do you have
a girlfriend?
I don't want to answer that.
I don't want to answer
those kind of questions.
I thought that one would
come up,
because when I was doing
the other one, somebody said,
"What do you think about girls?"
And I said, "I don't answer
questions like that."
Is that the reason
you're asking it?
The best answer would be to say
that I don't answer questions
like that.
You know, it was what I said
when I was 7,
and it's still
the most sensible,
but what about them?
If you'd been somebody who
had had fixed ideas
of a woman's role in marriage
that meant
dinner on the table
at 6:00 every evening...
Didn't I tell you
about that?
By 28, Nick had married Jackie,
a fellow student from Oxford.
They had a son, Adam.
By 42, they were divorced.
What I've concluded, and
I've talked to other people
about this
who've gone through it...
I'm not sure if they feel it as strongly
as I did, but it was like a death.
Anything could happen.
We could easily drift apart.
There are so many pressures...
If your spouse died,
you could look back and think,
"well, it was wonderful
while it lasted."
But in a divorce,
you can't look back and say,
"these are all happy memories."
Hey!
Cryss is my new wife.
I don't mean to be superficial,
but I think
she's the most beautiful woman
I've ever seen.
Is he sexy?
Oh, man.
Absolutely.
Didn't you have fun
with that one?
I always need to learn
patience and...
What do I need to learn?
Shall I get out my list?
Yeah, we need the list.
Go on.
Um...
Tell me, do you have
any boyfriends, Suzy?
Um...
Yes.
Tell me about him.
But he lives off in Scotland
and I think he's 13.
Have you got
any boyfriends, Suzy?
What is your attitude
towards marriage for yourself?
I haven't given it
a lot of thought,
because I'm very, very
cynical about it.
When I last saw you
at 21, you were nervous,
you were chain-smoking,
you were uptight,
and now you seem happy?
What's happened to you over
these last seven years?
I suppose Rupert.
I'll give you some credit.
I'm now chain-smoking.
I think you can't just walk
through a marriage
and think once you get married,
it's all going to be
roses and everything forever.
It's very hard to actually say
what it is
that goes on
between a couple.
It's either there
or it's not.
Any marriage
has its ups and downs.
But somehow,
whether it's through luck
or determination, we've
worked through
the difficult times.
One of my favorite
places in Oxford,
Merton Chapel.
Here's this lovely top part
of the cross.
And there was going to be
the main part of the cross.
This is one of the places
in England
that just is tremendously
important to me.
After I left the Dales,
this was where I spent
the next six years,
and then I went to America.
Look, isn't this beautiful?
This is Mob Quad.
I believe that it's
a historical fact
that quite a lot students were
massacred in the middle ages.
When I came here, I thought I'd
died and gone to heaven.
But I was under an awful lot
of stress
all the time I was here
trying to succeed in this place
as well.
So this was my staircase
in my first year
and also in my third year.
There was this fellow
who lived in the room nextdoor to me
and he came in one day
to tell me some story.
And on his way out, he said, "Do you know,
I don't associate intelligence
with your accent."
It would seem really ridiculous
to any of my friends
who watch this if I said,
"Christ, aren't I
a great success?
Look at me!"
You know, what success?
By the time he was 28,
Nick had emigrated to America.
He was doing research
into nuclear fusion
at the University
of Wisconsin.
If you'd been offered
a similar type of job
over here...
In a heartbeat.
You would have stayed.
I mean, I dreamed of getting
a university job over here.
Maggie Thatcher was squeezing
the universities
like crazy at that very moment
in time.
And it was the worst time to be
working in a university
in generations.
England doesn't seem
to concern itself
with training people like me
and wanting them around.
There doesn't seem to be
a sense of urgency
or a strong will to have people
developing technology
to help keep the country going.
The fusion reaction
gives off energy and produces
the power that would
be turned into electrical...
I was on a mission, you know,
to get extremely cheap, clean,
plentiful electricity.
So nuclear fusion looked like
it was going to do that.
But even then, they were saying
"it's 20 years away."
I would say absolutely not
in my lifetime.
It was kind of heartbreaking.
So I had to find
something else to do.
So the area that I'm looking at
is this times this.
When I go into a classroom
full of undergraduates,
I try and explain to them
why they might want
to try and do it.
That's my attempt to open
a little door for them.
Nick is a professor
of electrical engineering.
My ambition as a scientist
is to be
more famous for doing science
than for being in this film.
Unfortunately, Michael,
it's not going to happen.
When I get married,
I'd like to have two children.
I'm not very
children-minded at the moment.
I don't know
if I ever will be.
What do you think
about them?
Well, I don't like babies.
At 28, Suzy had two sons...
Thomas and Oliver.
Come catch it.
By the time she was 35, she
also had a daughter, Laura.
Mummy? Laura wants you.
We were lucky.
We had a very good family unit
with them growing up.
And that meant an awful lot
to me,
that I was able to do that
for them,
'cause I never had it
for myself.
And you've done it, you've been
tremendously successful at it.
Well, see, that's my problem.
I don't think of myself
as being...
I just do my best and do
what I can for them.
Did all your children
go to university
or your daughter did?
Yes, and my son did,
the eldest one.
Hello.
I haven't had a successful
career, but I do feel fulfilled.