Teddy bears, they're not real.
He is a Polar, look at his claws.
This was no ordinary outing to the zoo.
It was a very special occasion.
This was part of the
program filmed in 1964...
when we brought together a group
of seven year old children...
from vastly different backgrounds.
We went to prep schools,
primary schools,
state schools and private schools...
and picked out fourteen children.
We brought them together because...
we wanted a glimpse of the shop stewards
and the executives of the year 2000.
Give me a child until he is seven...
and I will give you the man.
These children are now fourteen,
half way between childhood and manhood.
This is our interim report.
If we did all love Jeffrey
we all want to marry.
-Yeah.
I think I know the one that
he'd like best and that's her.
Jackie, Lindsay, Suzan.
Plenty of boy friends, but not one.
-Several ones.
Not one particularly. We're friends
with plenty of boys you know.
My heart's desire is to see my daddy
who is six thousand miles away.
Bruce.
No, I'm having...
I'm getting along well.
With my step father.
And I like to see my
father occasionally.
And he does come over from Rhodesia
Do you have any girl friend?
Nicolas from Yorkshire Dale.
I don't want to answer that.
I don't want to answer
those kinds of questions.
No I'm not answering that one
Suzie.
I gave that up as a failure.
I was gonna be a policeman but I
thought how hard it would be to join in.
Paul.
Baseball appeals to me
most but in the school...
I'm one of the best players in form two
But when I got into the team...
they make me look like I can't play.
I feel like joining in when
there's already a fight.
I was going to be a film star.
Simon.
Now I'm going to be
an electrical engineer.
It's more to reality.
Singing Waltzing Matilda in Latin in an
exclusive pre-prep school in Kensington,
we chose three boys.
Charles,
Andrew.
I read the Financial Times.
and John.
I read Observer and The Times.
What do you like about it?
Well, I like...
I usually look at the
headlines then read...
about them...
about it.
I like my newspaper because I
got shares in it written and...
I know everyday what shares are
-The stuff misers like you like
No. But...
on Mondays they don't move
up so I don't look at it.
I made several blunders on Seven Up.
For instance, I said I was going to
Trinity Hall instead of Trinity College.
They didn't like that too
much, nor did my father.
Also I rather exaggerated when I said
that how much I like stocks and shares
because I don't any more.
How do you think you've changed since you were seven?
What I mean...
one grows so slowly
that one never notices
I feel the same the way I felt
at seven I may not be the same.
When I leave the school, I'm
going to College Court...
and then I would be going to Westminster
Boarding School if I pass the exam.
John passed the entrance exam and is
a weekly boarder at Westminster School.
When I leave school, I'm going
to the Dragon School, I might.
and mummy is... then I go to...after I
might go to Charterhouse, Marlborough
Charles is at Marlborough
When I leave the school, I go
to Broadstairs, St. Peter's Court.
And after that I'm
going to Charterhouse.
Andrews is at Charterhouse.
When I leave the school, I'm down
for Heathfield in Southover Manor
Suzie is at Southover Manor
Would everybody please sit round now?
One third of our children...
their education was
pre-planned and paid for.
The remaining went to State schools
and their future seemed less certain.
I want to be a jockey when I grow up.
Ya, I want to be a jockey when I grow up.
Tony is on the way
to achieving his ambition.
He spends all his free time at Tommy
Gosling Racing Stable at Epsom.
My dad put me onto Mr. Gosling
Mr. Gosling tells me that I've to
come here on every school holidays.
and learn a bit more.
Next year I'll be leaving
school and work here for good.
Did your parents
encourage you to do this?
Ya they're pleased... knowing what I'm gonna do.
They always have wanted
me to be a Jockey.
Why?
Enjoyment. To say, `my son is
a Jockey', you know what I mean!
Tony's change from Elementary school to
Secondary  didn't alter his ambition.
But how about the other children?
Has the change of school, changed them?
Bruce was at the pre-preparatory
boarding school in Surrey.
And that's Farmer.
He gives me nightmares.
I was about five when
I went there and then...
I suppose, I was too young
really to understand it and...
I thought it was a bit severe at
that time then I just got used to it.
And didn't have sort of any impulses
to do things wrong or
Then I think that I just
got into the track of...
you know... what they said you
must do and you mustn't.
at St Pauls I like the
companionship you know...
with other boys...
really.
and you get that much
more in a boarding school.
Well I think boarding makes
you feel self-sufficient.
And also teaches you to
be away from your parents...
and to live with
people for a long time...
which you've to do
in later life any way.
I don't agree with that
...a certain amount
when you board on the weekly bases,
you've the best of best worlds
One sees one's parents at the weekend...
and one gets all the benefits from a
English Boarding School.
I think prep school boarding
is a bad idea. -Yes.
Because  I'm...
up till about twelve,
may be its different
with other people...
I found that...
you are much more
attached to your parents.
Once you come to
about thirteen-fourteen,
you're not quite so attached to them.
Two of our boys who didn't have the
chance to be attached to their parents
were those brought up
in the children's home...
supported by charity.
Simon.
I had one dream when...
everything flew up in the air...
and that all landed on my head.
Simon stayed there till last Christmas,
when he returned to live with his mother.
they say where's
your father then...
you know... when your
mom's out at work...
where's your father,
I just tell them I haven't got one
What effect does that have on you?
Well... I don't think it's had
any effect on me because...
what you don't have you
don't miss as far as I can see
Also at the children's home
with Simon was Paul.
He and his family immigrated
when he was eight.
I don't like big boys hitting us
the staff up in the washroom sends
the nurse out, well there's no talking
I wasn't talking today and...
Brown sent me out for nothing.
What do you remember of England?
It seemed to be raining all the time.
I wouldn't stake my life on it
I can't remember very much!
He went to Australia
to start a new life.
Well, I was going to become a bank
accountant but its more book taking...
than maths and that's the main reason...
I was thinking about
becoming a panel beater
And...
I don't know why.. I
stopped thinking about that.
I just hadn't made up my mind yet
I was gonna be a gym teacher but...
one of the teachers told me that...
I had to get up on to the University.
Were you happy at the
Children's Home in England?
I didn't mind that really because
I didn't know what was going on.
I was a bit young
You were happier
than you are now?
In a way... yes, I was.
But then I'm happy for being home.
At the school everything
you wanted you just had.
You know, everybody was your friend.
And you never knew any enemies, really.
But here...
people are undecided about you.
They can be friend one
day and not the next.
Then I moved to Comprehensive School.
I found it much bigger, of course and...
I found it hard to
settle in to it first.
From the Liverpool suburb returning home
from the School, Neil and Peter.
I'm much more happy
now than when I first came...
we have different types of people.
People have different sorts of brains
from ways of very
clever people, you know...
to people haven't
much sense at all really.
Well... we pretend we've got swords...
and then we make the
noises of the sword-fighting...
and then once we
get stabbed we'll go...
'aaaaaahh'!
I've been playing since I started at the
Comprehensive School in the first year.
We play international wrestling.
Ya, that's right. That's
summer time though.
Yes, and we can go on the grass.
there used to be a senior
team...but they lost interest.
Watch this.
Check, mate.
- O...k.
Gosh it is, how did
you do that?
This is a very good idea
to have competition...
other wise we start to relax really
and not so try hard enough.
What do you think?
I could say, yes.
It's a good thing.
For if no one competes with you,
you won't be trying it this hard.
The three little girls from East End...
had a choice of going to a Comprehensive
or a Grammar School.
I am going to work in woolworths
Lindsay chose the Grammar School.
Why am I using a wooden spoon please?
to stir this saucepan?
The noise.
The noise, yes. we got
16 people. 16 sauce pans.
We don't want noise from 16 people
stirring with metal spoons.
This is my first choice
and this is where I turned up...
even though...
my friends were
going to the other school.
I just didn't feel like going to
the Grammar School, I just...
Comprehensive School,
it just seemed more friendly, you know
yes.. and at that time but now...
It's different.
-Grammar School is fantastic.
If you say so.
- we've all got our opinions.
What advantages has a
Comprehensive School got?
Especially this school, it’s new they've
got everything you could want
equipment and...
What I enjoy in this school is...
in this school we do metal
work and wood work
The boys do cookery. we get a
share of everything, sort of thing...
It's though, metal
work and that
In the Grammar School, I don't think you
find many girls want to do wood work
That's the difference.
-That's a different school.
that shows the difference in the people.
One of the keys to the character of the 7
year old was how they spent their free time
Bruce had a school band.
When I go home, I come...
I come in and mummy
gives me a cup of tea...
and then I go out and play.
And when it starts to get dark...
I come in again and put on T.V.
last night i didn't go
to bed until seven.
I usually go to bed at ten o'clock
or eleven o'clock.
sometimes i go to the dog racing.
i like...
going there for
something to do at night
So I don't really do anything at night.
Only go to the dogs or other things
other things... watch Telly.
I don't watch very much television.
I used to watch a lot but
I'm not watching it so much.
And I think its good because lot
of it is corrupting me a bit.
I like soap operas, i always
watch them with my parents
For one thing, the
advertisements you know...
I can recite about six
tunes off and it just seems
a worthless
thing to know
There’re too many things
going on at school...
though we do have a television and...
at the weekend I can be
more selective and there's
not much that I like
Well, I am quite
interested in Archeology.
And we are doing a local
dig in Binscombe near our school.
being in set one is very very
hard to keep up with the leaders
And I've no time to relax at all.
What do you do then in the evening?
I go out with friends normally.
-Yes.
Or to clubs sometimes.
There aint many clubs
round here. It's disgusting.
It really is.
You hear people're talking
about it on television...
but it's really bad here in the Eastend
There's hardly anything.
There's always something to do here
I'm never ever bored.
Suzie now lives in Scotland on
her father's 4000 acres estate.
its very very small really
we've only got one phone
There is my zone.
it's so small there's a
kitchen and dining room...
a drawing room...
and a room we mostly
sit and let people in.
that's really it!
What sort of things do you do?
Write, swim, play tennis.
ping-pong,
might play croquet,
things like that.
What about social life? What's that?
In Perthshire?
-Yes.
It's quite fun
There's lots of
things going on.
Your dog's got a rabbit.
What are you gonna do?
do you want to save it.
Max, bring it here.
It's disgusting dog!
This is a second one you have
given me in a second week.
For God's sake leave it alone.
Does that worry you?
Nope. Not at all.
I see this birds been
wounded. I don't like that.
They run off and you
never get a chance to kill them.
Why does it worry you if
things should have to be killed?
Because I've been
brought up with it
That mustn't be delayed there.
Quiet quietly! Its a very
nonchalant little theme.
butter wouldn't
melt in its mouth
Take it very quietly and
let it just present itself
We have...
about ten pianos with practise rooms and
Orchestras Choral Societies and 2 choirs
It's a marvelous music system.
there is too much competition now a days
And there are so
many good pianists...
and only a very few
make the grade one...
and I think its very disparaging
if you can get it only half way.
Are you ambitious?
Yes.
What for?
Well...
for fame...
and power.
What sort of power?
Political power.
Are you ruthless?
Not really.
You think you can have political
power without being ruthless?
Yes.
Then what qualities do you need to have
political power if not ruthlessness?
Great strength of mind.
They'd like to come out for a holiday...
in the country when we like...
when I like the holiday in the town.
No, I 've been to Leeds
a couple of times and...
I haven't been to Manchester.
And...
I went to London with the others when
you did the first program with us.
That's the only time I've been.
Nicholas won a scholarship
to Yorkshire Boarding School.
In this village there's me and then the
next oldest is Andrew there.
i'm not unhappy...
living on the farm and going to the
school and boarding there.
All right, it would be better than
living on the farm all the time.
I won't like to live in the
school all the time either.
You want to take up farming?
-No.
I'm not interested in it.
I was interested in Physics and
Chemistry but I'm not going to do that here.
When I grow up I like to find out
all about the moon and all that.
Did your father want to be a farmer?
I don't think he really wanted to be...
but he got stuck with it.
because my grand father, he certainly
probably wanted him to be a farmer.
But I don't think my father
wants me to be a farmer.
And...
my youngest brother is deaf. if he can't
do anything else he can run a farm
but as a last last resort.
Not till these holidays
have I been out of Europe.
These holidays I went to America,
stayed with somebody from the school.
Have you been abroad?
Austria.
What was it like?
Not bad!
Would you like to travel?
No.
Well, I ski in Switzerland and
I enjoy that immensely and then...
we went to France this time and...
I lived in Rhodesia.
I enjoyed Switzerland most I think
I think it's a beautiful country.
I went to very interesting places.
I also enjoyed Austria but not to such a great extent.
Well, I've never been abroad.
-Nah... neither did I.
I've, you know.
-Oh yeah, because you went on that cruise.
I've been to Spain and...
Gibralter and... Casablanca. yeah
- Oh you loved it
That was interesting though!
Traveling doesn’t really
interest me a lot.
Happy where I'm.
I've been to so many places.
Sicily, Italy, France and Spain
and Switzerland... many times.
Have you traveled much?
When I was at the School,
we used to go... to...
have outings.
We used to go to Boxhill and places....
And we used to go to mystery tours.
and...
travel in country.
We went to History Museums
for outings and...
Geographical Museum and...
Science Museum.
I've been to Madame
Tussauds with my mom.
And the...
Planetarium Museum.
Do you want to go abroad?
Ya...
Ya, I would like to go to Majorca
take a couple of weeks out
there from everything
sort of relax myself
No but I said that when
boys go around with girls...
they don't pay attention
to what they're doing.
My Grand mother had an accident
because a boy friend was kissing...
his girl friend in the street.
The girls never do what the boys want
They always start playing with dolls...
when the boys want to
play rough and tumble.
It's quite true!
Beginning to become more important.
-Ya!
In what way?
Well, they're no longer just bores.
"We won't play this" or some thing.
well, its half of the
community and they're there.
And you can begin to talk to them.
I think they're still
bores for the most part
When I get married I will
like to have two children.
You want a Nanny to
look after them or you ?
No, I want Nanny to look after them.
Do you have any boy friend Suzie?
Well, my girl friend...
is in Africa and I don't think I have
another chance of seeing her again
And there're two in Switzerland which
I liked too in a hotel.
Do you have any girl friend?
No... not yet!
I'm sure it will come but not yet!
Say... you had a wife...
Say... say you have to
eat what they cook you...
and say I don't like
greens well I don't...
and say... she says you have to eat...
what you're given... so...
I don't like greens so if she gives
me greens then that's it
I prefer to be alone really
I wouldn't mind living with
my brother you know...
but otherwise I prefer to live alone.
Sometime on Saturday mornings
I go to the cinema
Sometime with my friends
and sometimes with him.
You don't!
-I do!
She don't. I don't
always see you
you go to different cinema
Have you got a girl friend?
-No.
Would you like to have a girl friend?
No.
I thought that one would
come up because when I was...
when I was doing the other film
said `what do you think about girls?'
and I had said that I don't answer
questions like that
is that the reason you're
asking it? yeah i thought so
What do you want me to say?
I don't know what to say.
Once... Caroline Tetford said
she was good, she loved me.
What happened after that?
And I am going to marry
her when I grow up.
I hate her. She's always cursing
bad temper and cross with me.
Is she?
Yes! Neil Hughes! Move
your desk forward.
perhaps I'm not mature enough
yet to be interested.
See, he loves Suzan
because Suzan loves him.
He loves Lindsay and Lindsay loves him.
-I doubt it!
Have you got any boy friends?
oh...
that's personal isn't it!
i don't like the way you
came out with that
We shouldn't
tell him... shall we?
What do you think
about making this program?
I think this is ridiculous.
There's no point in doing it.
Why not?
What's the point people going
into peoples lives and saying.
why do you like this, why don't
you like this. i see no point in it.
What's the point of the program?
if the point is to reach a comparison.
I don't think it is!
Because we're not necessarily
typical examples.
And I think that's what people seeing
the program might think.
Yes
-Falsely.
And they would intend to type-cast us.
So everything we say,
they will think, Oh!
that's a typical result...
of the public school system.
-Ya!
Well, in what way aren't you typical?
Well, I'm bit more
reactionary than most.
I don't know. None of the parties
really seems to agree with me.
I think if I had voted, I had voted Labour.
I would've voted Conservatives.
I don't think I would vote for any of them.
Conservatives.
The Conservatives would do the
best for the country.
I think they're all as
bad as each other really
Labour.
I don't really know.
I know what i wouldn't vote though
what way?
Labour.
Conservatives.
Why?
-Why?
I don't know i don't know
I really don't know much about
politics and it doesn't interest me, so
I don't really bother.
I didn't agree with the conservatives,
what they're doing with the Black people
You know...the racial policy
Jacqueline, what do you
think about colour people?
You said to me once you like them
but what do you really think about them?
Well, they're nice and its
as same as us really.
But one thing...
it's only because their skin is brown
and we're white, sort of pinkish we're...
Do you think of a purple person...
with red eyes,
yellow feet and...
I can't really think of
what they really look like.
They are just the same
as me, isn't it?
I don't... anybody who is coloured.
I don't want to know anybody who
is coloured. Thank you very much!
I'm not against coloured people...
but I wouldn't worry if I didn't know
one until the day I died.
People have got to get used to
knowing coloured people.
And coloured people in turn
have got to get used to
being with white people...
because... if either side
doesn't work proparly,
then no side work properly.
People just got to mix in with
every body else.
I do think it's wrong but
in a country...
like England...
there should be places where the...
there are more coloured people
than the white people.
Good old Enoch Powell
personally I've nothing
against coloured people.
I think they're same as every body else.
But it seems that they...there's lot
of argument about them because...
as any foreigner really...
they're taking up
people's jobs in England.
I don't care what colour sombody is.
unless they're blue
that would be pretty peculiar.
But...
might find somebody yet
You know, I don't care about colour.
Well, I think both Black
and Whites are equal.
As long as they are there,
they as well educated each other
What do you feel about
racial discrimination?
strong avow
Why?
Because so is any kind of discrimination
Of a basic nature that you can't change,
I mean I couldn't care less
if people discriminated
against because they are...
nasty or selfish or any thing but...
I mean one can't help one's colour.
So
Now that you are interested in politics
would like to be a politician
what kind of things would you change?
I won't allow any strikes!
How would you do that?
I would set about a Tribunal...
where people...
workers could apply for...
better wages and...
this Tribunal would
have the final word and...
if it says `no wage rise', no wage rise.
It’s a big problem because
of the discussion i think
The workers do tend to take
fewer liberties as regards strikes.
Who do you think to blame for strikes?
The workers or the management?
The manager probably…
say the workers and we will probably get
a load of letters or something like that
It seems to me iniquitous
that people should be paid...
when they don't do any work.
Which is what unions do do
I'm not commenting because mom
has been out on strike.
Ya… so is mine!
Very irresponsible because we all want
more money as much money as we can get.
And what will happen if we all stopped
working just because we want more money?
I want money. Why shouldn’t
I strike for it? I am sure anyone.
If you want more money, you will strike for it.
That’s right! Ya! That’s right!
They're going to strike for it,
they're going to get more money.
the school meals are going up so they're
going to strike, they want more money
It's going to keep on going
going going you know...
Truly by crushing...
strikes.
Then in a way that’s defeating…
a small part democracy.
It's not because they'd still have their...
They'll still be able to
ask for more money.
But they wouldn't be able to
strike for it which I mean...
it's so damaging
It's still depriving them
their freedom to strike.
so is putting people in prison
depriving them their freedom to go on
killing people and stealing from people
Who is going to do this, they're not
going to be voted in the parliament.
So its not worth it.
You can always decide a new
policy once you are in.
What do they think about each other?
And how'll they act together?
To find out, we invited
them all to one big party...
and joined in.
Yes, they were bit too
tough for my liking.
Somebody hit me right in the back
and I 've still got some pain there.
The posh ones O! Yes. O! yes. O! Yes.
They're nuts!
you just have
to touch them
And some of them were rather dirty.
what did you think about them?
-I played with them quiet naturally.
I think they were rather nice, really.
What do you think about rich people?
Well... not much.
-Tell me about it.
They think they can do everything
without you doing it as well...
they think just because they're rich...
they have to have people
that have to do all
their work and stuff.
What would you do if you have lots
of money, about say... two pounds?
I would help the poor.
Ya because the poor if you
don't, they all would die.
Wouldn't they?
And everytime we've a harvest
festival, we send them food.
Once these two went round
giving food out with Mr. Floyd.
I don't think much of the accents.
Neither do I.
-Neither do I.
That doesn't prevent me liking them.
Rich children always
make fun of poor children.
Yes. -Yes they say, O! look at that
lovely little sissy over there
Yes, and they throw things at them.
Yes.
And poor child gets scared to death.
Do you meet here many boys from
very different social backgrounds?
Not really.
Do you find that a lack in your life?
No.
Why?
I don't feel any lack any where.
Do you feel you should be meeting broader
persons from the different back grounds?
Not really.
You don’t think you are missing?
No.
I don't see what
background's got to do with it
They are people
from so many...
I think it's the interest
that makes it worth
there's people with so many...
varied interests in the school,
I can't imagine of any more.
I don't really see why
background enters it
If everybody is the
same as every body else...
no body would be missing any thing.
And people...
rich people... they've
all different things.
Have everything they want.
Where as poor people...
they don't have nothing
and they know that.
And they know that
they have got nothing.
So they know they are missing something.
What are you missing?
Well... possibly
a bike and a fishing rod and...
Ya, they like...they can get
what they want, can't they?
We've got to work for it.
they just ask for money.
and get it.
and buy what they want.
What effect does
that have on them?
Spoilt
it spoils them doesn't it
if you want to accuse us
The public schools
are producing snobs...
by mixing only a
couple of classes, the upper and middle
And Comprehensive Schools can be
accused of producing proles
because they only mix with lower and the middle.
So its like saying that public schools
like Tom Brown school days...
We do mix with people from the town.
They can be all right.
Yeah, but I don't like
people who are too posh
they look down on every body else.
They think they are better.
-Yeah.
I think the people are much more
conscious of wanting to become snobs...
because the difference that...
the differences that use to
separate the classes...
have diminished greatly.
I mean everyone was a Duke when
he used to be set above...
everybody else...
but now...
look at the Duke of....!
I think people climb
less class cultures...
beacuse I mean...
with hippies you don't
get the impression...
that one hippie says...
I'm so big guy because I'm
upper class and you're...
some petty person because
you're lower class.
Yes.
And any body can become a hippie.
I think this is happening through
out the country.
........they don't enforce...
being upper class and...
things like that...
as st pauls..they suggest that you don’t
have long hair and do get it cut.
they teach you to be well mannered
but not to sniff on the poor people.
some are good with their
money and money and give it...
for charitable purpose.
Some of them just do not know
what to do with their money.
They just spend it...waste it.
People need it.
I don’t like poverty for any body.
It kinda depresses me.
When I went to Glasgow...
and I saw the Gorbals
That rather upset me.
Why?
Well, to think that people
are living in that state.
When we waste things... every day.
Some people are just born into
rich families and they're lucky.
I don’t see why they should have the luck
when people worked all their lives
and they've got half
of as much as they have
doesn't seem fair.
I usually get about a
five or six pounds a week
What do you do with it?
I save some, spend some.
Well, I get a pound a week.
And...
what I usually do
in the middle of the week...
my mom takes half back
and I save the other half
as much as possible.
Well, out of my permanent job
I get four dollars fifty.
40 pence a week
What do you spend it on?
Well, I need to spend
very little on schools.
I collect stamps so...
I spend quite a lot on them.
My dad gives me about
three pounds a week...
And mum gives me one pound fifty pence
And my brother give me some.
Mr.Gosling gives me four pounds,
pocket money every week.
I don't want to be rich but I
like to have enough money.
What do you mean by enough?
Enough to have a nice house and...
be able to send the children to
a private school if I want to.
I mean almost everybody likes money.
Not for the fact that it....
I don't like looking at money
It doesn't give me any pleasure like that.
But I certainly don't want to be
poor or live in a slum but...
I had...I don't...
I mean a person with one million pounds
is not going to be much...
is not going to be more or less happy
than a person with two million pounds.
Money is not every thing.
It means a lot
to us now
the clothes and new fashions
and skirts and that
You need money because...
-Yeah what's skirts
they're clothes... yeah,
you need clothes
money can’t buy happiness. -Oh no! you
got to work for that yourself havent you
Do you want to be rich?
I don't mind i like
staying where i am
I don't want to be very rich but
I don’t want to be poor either.
What about you Jackie?
Just live comfortable. -Ya just have
what you want, nothing stressfull
as long as you've got all you need.
Do you want to be rich?
I won't mind.
Yes, because I don't want
to be tied down to the...
the dullness of an every day job.
I want to be able to have enough
money so I can indulge in...
things that interests me...
like collecting paintings.
No! No because if you're rich
you get bored of being rich.
Same... if you're poor, you
get bored of being poor.
You can't have too much of a good thing.
And if you're healthy and have good
friends, you can get on perfectly well.
but everybody
would like to be rich.
Mainly to be self-sufficient.
To feel that you don't have to
owe anything to any body.
I would help people...
if I had a chance.
By say, giving...
little bit of money to charity or
sponsoring things or things like that.
I mean it is wrong,
one should drive oneself...
to make a lot of money
because in the end...
you might have caused
so many people....
ruined so many people
that you will be unhappy
and what's the use of lot
of money if you're unhappy?
You've to have it to live and...
though, sort of problems you have to
face and every thing is concrete and
doesn’t seem to be possible for
anything to be invisible or...
you can’t see it.
I mean people...
all the sciences said
we've looked up into the space and we
haven't seen God so there isn’t a God.
And it just seems fatuous
Do you believe in God?
I'm not sure whether I believe in God
I think to myself I don't know.
So...I don't know.
Yes, I'd say I believed in God.
Are you religious?
Well I go to Church with
my parents on Sundays.
You got to believe in something.
So God seems to be
the most logically really.
I am not deeply religious. No,
I don't believe in God.
Why?
That's a difficult question
to answer `why?'
I just do
It's either a `Yes' or `No' question.
You're brought up to
believe in Him and i do.
You must've your own
opinion on that as well.
Ya...
-I don't really know
I mean if I do or not.
Don't really think about it very much.
No, you don't have much time to
think about it
No when there's so much activity in
in school and after school.
I would like to certainly think
about or talk to some one about.
When I sit down and think...
I think I believe in God.
But if somebody just
asks me I will say `no'!
Supposed just to be big
Why do you believe in God?
I believe in God because...
somebody had to
make the world
this world
they call Him what everybody
else calls Him Which is God.
You can't really say if there
is God or not. Can you?
You haven't seen him.
You can't say!
When you were seven, you wanted to
be a Missionary. any thoughts on that?
No I don't want to be a Missionary
because I can't talk about it to people.
You know...
I'm interested in it myself but..
I wouldn't be very good at it at all...
and I wouldn't enjoy it.
Why won't you be good at it?
Well...
I'm just not very good at...
at standing up in front of people and
making a speech or any thing like that
I like to keep it private, you know
Well, going to Africa...
and try and teach people
who are not civilized...
to be more or less good.
And after that Trinity Hall, Cambridge.
I am going to work in woolworths
I might go to Oxford.
I'll just walk around...
and see what I can find.
Then we think, I am going...
to Cambridge and Trinity Hall.
I don't think I need to go to university
because I'm not gonna be a teacher.
I don't think you want to go to university
if you want to be an astronaut
What does university mean?
Well...
When I grow up I like to find out
all about the moon and all that.
If I can't be an astonaut I think
I'll be a coach driver.
It is probably linked up with the
fact that now I like traveling.
My thought hasn't really changed
I would like to be a Coach driver now.
You wanted to be an astronaut
when you were seven.
Ya!
What feelings have
you got on that subject?
Well, changed now completely of course.
I mean it was just the imagination
of a seven year old.
I'll buy myself a nice
new made house
that's all nice and comfy.
I would like to be a...
have a happy family.
I mean I know it's not possible
to be happy all the time...
but as much as the time it was possible.
Just... be content with what
I'm doing and be happy with it.
And to know where I'm going...
and to remember fondly what I've done.
I think I'm following a legal career...
with a view to ending in parliament.
I would like to do may be shorthand
typing or some thing like that.
Nothing too much, just wonder.
Be like every body else.
Nothing too... marvelous!
What would you do if you don't
make it as a Jockey?
I don't know. If I knew
I couldn't be one...
I would get
out of it
wouldn't bother.
What do you think you would do then?
i'll learn taxi's
A Taxi driver.
There is a danger that
you would get married...
at the early twenties and have
children quickly and then be...
stuck at home.
Have you any thoughts on that?
I don't really think very much.
-I know.
I don't think...
I'll get married too early. I like to
have a full life first and...
Get some job before.
-Ya.
before you commit
yourself to a family
How do you think England would
change over the next few years?
England?
-Yes.
Not very much!
England is too English,
you know what I mean.
Are you a traditionalist?
Yes!
In what way?
I like tradition.
Do you expect to live
your life in England?
I think it's just about the best place
you can live your life in England
Why?
I think the
Parliamentary System is agreeable.
I mean...
to me at least and...
and that's about it.
One's free in England.
one has good opportunities
for everything.
Well, we've got much
more equal opportunities.
In those days the people at the
bottom really had to work.
Like Blacks...so that they
could achieve something.
Now a days...
to get kicks out of life...
you've to use synthetic
means where originally...
earlier on...
forty years ago...
these things came in life.
With the coming...
with all the modern world...
we are in the modern world today.
All... lots of these things've been stopped.
Lot of enjoyment of life
has been taken out of it.
Yes! The natural enjoyment.
Nothing is being taken out.
It’s just people.
It’s still there if you look for it.
How many people can look for it?
- how many people can look for it.
- Every body can pursue happiness.
At the end of their very special day in London...
after their trip to the zoo and the party...
we took our children to an adventure play ground...
where they could do just what they like.
There's from a children's
home set about building a house.
That's Nicholas.
And Tony.
Andrew.
And Bruce.
John.
Suzie.
Jackie and her friends.
Give me a child until he is seven
and I will give you the man.
This has been a glimpse
of Britain's future.