Fucking...
Fucking bastards.
Come on, you fuck...
Mikey, get down I
Mikey!
I'm hit, Charlie.
I'm hit.
You'll be all right,
Mikey. Hold strong.
You'll never
take me alive,
you bastardsl
Do I need to introduce myself?
I know Who you are.
Good.
I know who you are.
My brother's taken
a bullet, Stanley, and is in need
of medical attention.
well, allow me to address
the subject of your brother,
Mr. Burns.
Christmas, as you're probably
aWare, is fast approaching.
And Christmas this year
will hold a unique significance
for young M icky here.
Mikey.
Because on Christmas day
I have made plans
that he be taken
from the jail in Banyon
and hanged by the neck
until he's dead.
Charlie...
You're a copper, Stanley,
not a judge and jury.
well... clearly, Mr. Burns,
I am what I wish to be.
So what is it that you want?
I want Arthur Burns.
I no longer ride with my brother.
Aah!
Now, I will allow you
a moment to think
about it.
what's happening, Charlie?
It's all right, Mikey.
It's all right.
Australia.
what fresh hell is this?
I've kept company
with bad men all my life.
I was 22 years in
Her Majesty's Land Forces.
I dealt with your type
many times.
Touch me brother again
and I'll kill you.
Make no mistakes, Mr. Burns.
It will be done.
I will civilise this place.
what the fuck are you
talking about, Stanley?
Listen to me Now, Charlie.
Don't speak.
Hush, Mikey, you'll be fine.
Hush.
I wish to present you
with a proposition.
I know where
Arthur Burns is.
It is a godforsaken
place.
The blacks won't go there,
nor the trackers.
Not even my own men.
I suppose in time
the bounty hunters
will get him.
But I have other plans.
I aim to bring him down.
I aim to Show that
he is a man like any other.
I aim to hurt him.
when you're ready, sir.
And what will most
hurt him?
well, I've thought
long and hard about that.
And I have realised,
Mr. Burns...
that I must become
a little more inventive
in my methods.
Don't speak, Mr. Burns.
Listen to me now.
Don't say a word.
Suppose I told you there was
a way to save your little
brother Mikey from the noose.
Suppose I gave you
a horse and a gun.
Suppose, Mr. Burns,
I were to give both you...
and your young brother
Mikey here a pardon.
Suppose I said that I could...
give you the chance
to expunge the guilt
beneath Which
you so clearly labour.
Suppose I gave you
till Christmas.
Now suppose you tell me
what it is I want from you.
You want me to kill me brother.
I want you to kill your brother.
Arthur Burns is a monster,
an abomination.
You were right to part
company with him,
to take Mikey with you.
what happened at the Hopkins
place was unforgivable.
I have never seen
such a sickening sight.
Did you know that, that poor
woman Eliza Hopkins
had a child in her belly?
Your business with your
brother is unfinished.
You have nine days,
Mr. Burns.
Come on, let's hit them!
You got him I
Pigsl
Who have you got?
Troopers...
dismount!
The man I have brought in
is Mike Burns,
of the Burns gang.
So that's one down
and two to go,
gentlemen.
You've got to get
the other ones Now.
I will
civilise this land.
Make yourself
at home, Mikey.
Good evening to you,
Mrs. Stanley.
Good evening,
Mr. Broussard.
Not so fucking
dangerous Now, is he?
Martha?
Good evening, gentlemen.
Good evening, Mrs. Stanley.
You should really not come here.
Can't a lady
visit her husband
in his place of work?
You men...
wait outside.
we spoke about why you
shouldn't come here, dear.
This is not appropriate...
Morris, you've been gone
for three days.
It's Ionely out there
at the house.
It's so quiet without you.
Are you coming home Now?
well, I have things to attend to.
I'll have Officer Dunn
escort you home.
I'll be back soon.
You look terrible, Morris.
Yes.
Yes, I do.
Dunn!
Who is that?
But he's no more than a boy!
Oh, he's man enough, Ma'am.
He's man enough indeed.
Enough.
Escort Mrs. Stanley home
and wait there
till I return.
how long will you be, dear?
Later.
Never speak to my wife
about such things again,
do you understand?
My apologies, Captain.
what happened today
on the Flats, that's
between you and me.
Of course, sir.
Because, there would be
consequences, were it
to become common knowledge.
Yes.
Eliza Hopkins was
a good Christian woman.
And she was my friend.
I pray to God
that her death
was mercifully swift.
It was, wasn't it?
Martha... could we
speak of other things?
Come here, Captain Stanley.
My poor husband.
Oh...
The world you live in, in there.
Don't be gloomy, dear.
This burden you carry,
you might let me carry it, too.
I believe in you.
Martha...
Stay down.
Stay in bed.
what in God's name...?
Christ, Sir...
I've shot me bloody toes off.
There's nothing
to see here, Martha.
Go back to bed.
Officer Dunn has shot his toe.
Martha,
go back inside.
Bloody fliesl
Kill one and a dozen more
turn up to his funeral.
# Oh, Danny boy, the flies,
the flies are craWling... #
Oh, a thousand pardons,
my dear man.
It appears that I am
a little scuppered.
No, no need for that, sir.
No need for that.
we are white men, you and I.
Permit me to introduce myself.
My name is Jellon Lamb.
Citizen of the world,
you might say,
an adventurer,
and if I may be so bold,
a man of no little education.
And you, sir?
By what name am I
honoured to address thee?
Of course...
a mere detail.
Mere detail.
Forgive me, sir,
but I've been
stuck here with no one
but this sorry sack
of Hibernian pig shit
for conversation.
Poor, poor
Dan O'Reilly.
Sit, sir.
Drink with me.
One more crack about
the Irish, Mr. Lamb,
and I'll shoot you.
Am I clear?
Oh, as the Waters of Ennis, sir.
Let us drink, then,
to the Irish.
No finer race of men have ever...
peeled a potato.
Do yoUpray,
Mr. Lamb?
Good Lord, son.
No, I do not.
I was, in days gone-by,
a believer.
But, alas, I came to
this beleaguered land
and the God in me just...
evaporated.
Let us change our
toast, sir. To the God
who has forgotten us.
But first, cardinal rule.
Never raise a glass
with a man whose name
you do not know.
My name's Charles Murphy.
Charles, eh?
Perhaps you've read
On the Origin of
the Species by Means
of Natural Selection
by Charles Darwin.
Oh, don't be thrown
by the title.
He had some most
fascinating things
to say.
Chilling things!
Mr. Darwin spent time
studying Aboriginals.
He claims we are at bottom...
one and the same.
He infers,
Mr. Murphy,
that we share a common
ancestry with monkeys.
Monkeys!
Mr. Murphy, Russia,
China, the Congo...
Oh, I have travelled among
unknown people in lands
beyond the seas,
but nothing...
nothing could have
prepared me for this
godforsaken hole.
You see,
Mr. Murphy,
I am something
of a fortune hunter.
And what fortune do you
hunt out here, Mr. Lamb?
No, that would be
my question to you,
Mr. Murphy.
Unhand me Murphy,
or I'll slit your
fucking throat.
we are white men, sir.
Not beasts.
Ahhh...
He sits
up there in those
melancholy hills.
Some say he sleeps
in caves like a beast,
slumbers deep
like the Kraken.
The blacks say
that he's a spirit.
The troopers
will never catch him.
Common force is meaningless,
Mr. Murphy,
as he squats up there
on his impregnable perch.
So I wait, Mr. Murphy.
I wait.
Aye, you wait.
You wait here, bounty hunter.
Hang him, sir.
Hang him high, sir.
Hail the
conquering hero.
what a vile specimen of humanity.
what a little
piece of filth.
Not really the one that
we're looking for, though,
is it, Captain?
I n the end,
justice will be done.
Mmm... justice.
Save your little wisdoms
for the mob, Stanley.
Has he told you
Where his brothers are?
with due respects,
Mr. Fletcher...
perhaps it would be wise
to allow police work
to be done by police men.
Hmm...
what a little piece of filth.
Still, better than
nothing, I suppose.
Good evening, Captain.
Good evening.
Your roses are looking lovely.
I've got green thumbs, I have.
I was just thinking
about England.
Do you not miss it, Martha?
There's much to miss.
There and here.
Let's get rid of that headache.
Now...
Captain Stanley...
eat your breakfast
before the flies do.
Made by me own
fair hands, them eggs.
Me eggs have never
tasted so fine, M um.
You're a good man, Morris.
And you're a good woman, Martha.
Do we have company?
Yes, I'm afraid we do.
Captain I
Excuse me, Ma'am.
Excuse me, Sir.
Martha, would you excuse us?
It's fine, Morris.
No, Martha, please.
This is police business.
how dare you come
to my house in that state?
Sir...
what exactly do you want?
we just got back from
the Arooka Ranges, Sir.
we rounded up
six rebel blacks, Sir.
Sean killed one.
Thought you'd want to know
about it straight away.
Captain...
Captain?
No, leave the door open.
It's rank in here.
Yes, sir.
Are you sure yoUput enough
iron on these men, Sergeant?
They have been
adequately secured, sir.
Jacko, get over here.
Yes, Captain sir.
Ask them how long
they've been hiding
up in the ranges.
He says
they very tired.
well, you'll have
a nice long rest
if you don't open your fucking
mouth and start yapping,
you black bastards!
Sergeant.
wait outside.
wait outside the door.
I'll call you if
and when I need you.
Ask them, again,
how long they've been
hiding up in the ranges.
Captain, Sir, he said they
don't hide in the ranges.
They live in the ranges.
Then ask him how long they
have lived in the ranges.
Them always been living
in the ranges, Captain, Sir.
Ask him if they've seen
a white man up there.
Yes, Captain, Sir, I'll ask them.
They've seen white men.
White men catches them.
Jesus Christ!
I don't mean the police.
This... this man.
This man.
A man with this man.
A white man.
This man. This man.
Ask him.
fellow
in the picture,
he live in a cave.
Dog man.
Big fella.
He said Dog Man
never sleep.
He sit there all day.
Sit down, in the cave.
Way up. He live
with small fella...
and black fella.
Cannot catch him.
Cannot kill him.
He is dog.
what? He "eats" dog?
No, Captain, Sir.
He is dog.
He changed to dog.
He grows ears.
He grow teeth, sharp.
And he grows a tail,
this Way.
Long. And he stand
with two leg,
like this.
And he goes...
Sergeant? Sergeant I
Captain is weak.
A weak man.
Oh, so, so you reckon
he's weak, eh,Lawrence?
Came out here
to sort out niggers,
fuck me, he's done nothing.
Those black bastards,
they're running all over us.
They chose
the wrong man for the job.
This isn't London.
It's not England.
This is fucking Australia.
Right.
Did I say
I wanted to fuck
the Captain's wife?
will you go back
to sleep, Paul,
for God's sake?
I would like
to fuck his wife.
If I was married to that
bucket of pig's tripe
you call a fucking wife,
I'd want to fuck her, too.
I want
to fuck his wife.
I want to fuck
his wife.
Yeah, all right. we all
Wanna fuck Missus Stanley.
She certainly isn't
getting anything from
the good Captain, is she?
And you know why?
Oh, because he's weak.
He's got other things
on his mind.
Because he really
fucked up this time.
He got the boy, yeah.
He let the other one go.
Eh?
Got good medicine.
Fix him no time at all.
Gonna need sleep,
gonna need rest.
No cry, daddy. That'll
go on good and clean him.
Gonna need sleep,
gonna need rest.
Good afternoon,
Mr. Broussard.
Remember to save
a turkey for me.
Of course,
Mrs. Stanley.
Is everything all right?
Go home, you stupid cow.
I'm sorry, what did you say?
Mrs. Stanley...
perhaps you'd better
ask your husband.
Shut up, dog.
Holy Mother of Mercy!
Look Who's raised
himself from the dead.
Him much better Now.
Him much better
because I fixed him.
Don't look better
to me.
You know, Samuel,
the thing I relished
the most while I was away?
was not having to see your
fucking face all the time.
If it weren't for me
and my crack shooting
you'd be fucking dingo dinner.
Thirty yards away I was.
Blew that black bastard's
head right off.
It was beautiful.
Show a bit of respect.
I might just have to shoot you...
with my new Winchester.
Fuck! That hurt!
Oh, Charlie...
Go easy there.
It's all right, Charlie.
You want to know
why I've come back?
I know why you've
come back, Charlie.
Look at that.
Be humble of heart, Charlie.
This is the end of things.
You're my brother, Charlie.
You belong with me.
we are a family.
All of us.
I was just getting reacquainted.
Samuel? Oh, be kind.
A little tolerance, Charlie.
Samuel's a boy.
He's a vicious little cretin.
Where's Mikey, Charlie?
Mikey stayed behind in Clarence.
You left Mikey alone?
He met a girl.
Mikey met a girl.
Aye, Mikey met a girl.
what's her name, Charlie?
Molly.
Molly O' Boyle.
A redheaded colleen, no doubt.
Aye, red.
Like the sunset.
what does she do,
this... Molly O' Boyle?
I'm feeling a bit tired
right Now, Arthur.
Is she a farmer's daughter?
Can she cook a good
lamb steW?
would you stop it?
Mikey's not the same stuff as us.
we will be flung
to the depths,
you and I.
He worshipss you, you know?
There was a time we both did.
Mikey deserves better.
You were right to leave.
Take him with you.
I need to rest.
Mary O' Boyle.
Molly, Arthur, Molly.
Molly. Molly,
right, Molly.
Mikey...
Martha...
when SergeantLawrence said
that the boy that you
are holding at the lockup
was man enough,
what did he mean by that?
SergeantLawrence
is an ignorant thug
with the moral
fortitude of a snake,
just disregard...
what did he mean?
what did the boy do?
He's a member of the Burns Gang.
There are some things
that a woman...
I know that, and I
asked you a question.
And I asked you not
to visit me...
Just tell me
what he did to Eliza.
She was my friend!
Enough!
That's enough.
Headache, Captain Stanley?
So what can I do
for you, Mr. Fletcher?
Word has it that your men
captured half a dozen
rebel blacks two days ago.
And that one was shot
in the process.
Do you have a problem with that?
Yes, Captain, I do.
Word came this morning
from Eight M ile Creek
that Dan O' Reilly's
place was attacked.
Are you sure it was blacks?
Dan O' Reilly had so many
spears in him that he
resembled your good old
garden variety, English hedgehog.
It's simple, Captain.
It's called the law
of reciprocity.
Kill one of them,
and they're going
to kill one of ours.
Do the job
I brought you here to do.
If you have to kill one,
make sure you bloody
well kill them all.
well, I'll send some
troopers out today.
Is our business here finished?
I'm going to have
Mike Burns flogged.
what?
One hundred lashes.
Martha.
Thank you.
I thought you gentlemen
might like a little tea.
Please, sit down.
Thank you, Martha,
that would be lovely.
Thank you, Martha.
Is there anything else
I can get you?
No, thank you, Martha,
this is lovely.
well, then, I'll leave
you two gentlemen alone.
Clever and well-bred
woman, your wife.
You did well
for yourself, Captain.
Word has it
that you had Charlie Burns
and you let him go.
Word has it
that you offered him
some kind of deal.
Tell me this
isn't so, Captain.
Word has it that you
promised those animals
who raped Eliza Hopkins
a pardon if Charlie Burns
brought back his brother.
A pardon for
the annihilation
of the Hopkins family.
Are you completely
out of your mind?
Listen to me. Mike Burns
is a simpleton.
He spends all day in his cell
crying like a child.
It is my belief that he's
unresponsible for his actions.
I'm not interested
in your beliefs,
Captain Stanley.
Who do you think you are?
The judge and the jury?
Arthur Burns must be stopped.
It is he Who's responsible
for this outrage.
And I know that Charlie Burns
will stop at nothing
to protect his younger
brother, Mike.
So all we need do Now is wait.
wait?
My God, man,
they raped a woman.
Tomorrow morning,
I want Mike Burns
flogged.
As I said,
one hundred lashes.
This would kill him.
So be it.
what if I'm right?
what if Charlie Burns
does as I ask?
what if he comes back?
Then we will hang
the lot of them.
Good day.
Martha.
Martha, stay here.
Do not let anyone in.
I shall return tomorrow.
Martha! Do you hear me?
Please, stay here.
what's going on in here?
I believe
Officer Davenport
and Officer MattheWs
have been entertaining
the prisoner, Sir.
Is that right, Sergeant?
Yes, Sir.
I've got a job for you.
we have unfinished business
in the Arooka Ranges.
Sir?
Rebel blacks, Sergeant.
within two hours
you must find Jacko,
and recruit some more
troopers, and depart.
Fucking snake.
why are you still standing there?
You've been dismissed.
Where's Charlie,
Mr. Stanley?
I don't know, son.
I don't know.
Captain?
Captain.
Let's see him, Stanley!
Give him to us,
Stanley!
Bring him out, Stanley.
Stand aside,
Stanley.
we want justice.
I'll shoot
the first person
Who lays hands
on Mike Burns.
Give him to us.
You heard me.
You move, I'll shoot you dead.
Are you going to shoot
your wife as well, Captain?
Martha?
She was with child,
for God's sake.
Martha, if this...
flogging goes ahead,
it will be our death sentence.
what if it had been me?
Captain Stanley?
Help me!
Get on, Mikey!
Get off of me!
Go on!
Come on!
My good people,
before you stands
one of the vilest
Most bloodthirsty villains
this country has ever seen.
Rapist,
looter,
murderer.
His crimes are
of the most heinous kind.
Before the year is out,
this man will hang.
Today he will be flogged.
A message to all
who dare transgress
the laws of this land.
One hundred lashes.
Proceed.
One!
two!
Three!
Please!
He could shame a nightingale.
Thirty-eight!
Thirthy-ninel
Go on.
Your days are over,
Captain Stanley.
Martha...
come on.
Martha, you must eat.
Tobey's made you some soup.
This is good.
You must eat something,
Martha, please.
No.
I'm so sorry.
Forgive me, please.
I just wanted to protect you.
I had an idea about justice
for the town, for the country,
for you.
For you.
But Now...
I don't know.
Hey, quit pissing down me leg.
what do you need
a fucking tree for?
Strange mob, you Whities.
Good news!
Sergeant Laurie,
over there.
what?
Where?
See?
Hard to see it.
At foot of the Ranges.
what? I can't see
a bloody thing.
There!
what?
Smoke.
Love.
Love is the key.
Love and family.
For what are night and day,
the sun, the moon, the stars,
without love
and those you love around you?
what could be
more hollow
than to die alone
unloved?
what the fuck was that?
Fucking trooper's
rifle. Four-fifties.
Shooting blacks.
Be calm, Samuel.
Shots are miles away.
Burn it!
Burn the fucking lot!
Don't stand there moping.
what are you doing?
Burn everything!
Molly O' Boyle, my arse.
Hey, Jacko, you lazy bugger.
I told you to bury
that bastard last night.
He stinks worse than you.
Jacko!
You got the Wrong
fucking black man.
slowly Now, Sergeant.
Put your privates
back in your pants
and turn around.
Come to steal my brother a horse
and we find ourselves a copper.
You fire that gun,
you'll have eight more
all over you.
Fair enough.
Step into the shade,
Sergeant.
To the back.
Has Charlie found you then?
Stanley's
little mate.
Over there.
By the straW.
That's right, stay.
Lay down, Sergeant.
Hey! Whoa!
Come here!
I know something you don't know.
Shhh, Whoa.
Sergeant.
what?
Your brother's come to kill you.
I can help.
You can help me?
Help your fucking self!
Steady, come here.
Hey, hey.
Help your fucking self,
copper.
Here's your knife
back, you dog.
There's something
I want to tell you.
I've been having a dream,
most nights.
I've kept it from you.
But I don't suppose
it matters Now.
I'm in a room.
It's our bedroom, I think, and...
I'm searching for something.
And then suddenly,
I feel a presence
in the room,
and I stand up,
and I turn around
and there in the doorway
is Eliza Hopkins.
And she looks frightful.
Her dress is all...
creased and torn
and covered in blood,
and her face, too.
All battered and bruised
and splashed with blood.
Martha...
But listen to this.
I n her arms she's
holding something. L...
I can't see what it is
because it's covered by her hair.
And then she Walks toWards me
very slowly.
Then...
she hands me a tiny bundle,
and I look down,
and I see that it's a baby.
A newborn.
And this baby...
oh, it's a beautiful baby,
Morris.
And it opens it's eyes,
and then
I feel a pressure on my hand,
and I look down, and I see
that the baby has
taken hold of my finger,
and its squeezing it tight
in its tiny fist.
Then I wake up.
But after I wake it's...
It's the strangest thing.
I can still feel...
I still feel the pressure
of that dream-baby's hand.
On my finger.
what do you think of that?
Good boy!
Nice and tight!
Right...
Up we get.
Oh, no I wouldn't
try that if I were you.
Ligatures and knots are one
of my many talents.
Right.
And it appears
that you are singularly
bereft in any talents
whatsoever, Mr. Burns.
To be speared by a savage.
how extraordinarily quaint.
Easy, Mr. Burns.
I was drunk.
You only got me
because I was drunk.
well,
I'm not drunk Now.
I'm on the job Now.
Not a bad day's work either.
For what is
an Irishman, but a nigger
turned inside out?
Now...
we're going to sit down
on this log
nice and easy,
Mr. Burns.
There.
I really should
stop saving your life,
brother Charlie...
...all things
considered.
"There's night
and day, brother.
"Both sweet things.
"Sun and moon and stars,
all sweet things.
"Very quiet.
"There's a Wind on the heath.
"Life is very
sweet, brother."
"Life is very sweet, brother.
Who would wish
to die?"
George Borrow, I believe.
A Worthy writer
and a beautiful sentiment, sir.
But you're not my brother.
Finish him.
Oh, dear.
This may hurt.
why can't you
ever just... stop me?
They are hanging Mikey
come Christmas Day.
when's Christmas, Charlie?
I have some riding to do.
Brother!
Where did you get it?
I am a very resourceful woman.
I never doubted it for a moment.
Look real good, Missus.
Thank you, Tobey.
And...
And look.
snow.
Ho-ho-ho.
Who is it?
Doctor Bantry.
Are you alone?
Yes.
Then you may come in.
It doesn't look good,
Morris. The boy is dying.
Nothing I can... do.
It sure is pretty.
You can never get
your fill of nature, Samuel.
To be surrounded
by it is to be stilled.
It salves the heart.
The mountains, the trees,
the endless plains.
The moon, the myriad of stars.
Every man can be made
quiet and complete.
Even the lowliest
misanthrope or the most
Wretched of sinners.
what's a misanthrope, Arthur?
Some bugger Who fucking
hates every other bugger.
Hey! I didn't ask you,
you black bastard.
He's right, Samuel.
A misanthrope is one
Who hates humanity.
Is that what we are?
M isanthropes?
Good, Lord, no.
we're a family.
Best you go Now, Tobey.
Tobey...
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Captain.
Prisoner coming through I
Prisoner coming through!
Stand back,
ladies and gentlemen.
This black fellow bites.
Keep moving you murdering,
bloody, bastard.
It is the jail-house
for you.
You led us a merry,
bloody dance
for many days...
but, alas for you,
you dirty mongrel,
we've got you.
how am I doing?
You are doing just fine,
Sergeant Stoat.
Keep moving,
you dirty devil,
don't lag.
And keep your lustful
eyes to the ground,
you lecherous dog,
or I'll whip the filthy
black hide right off you.
Good morning, M iss.
what's happening?
I don't know.
It must be some
ofLawrence's lot.
Oh, shit!
Mikey! Mikey!
This one's pissed himself!
Where are the keys,
you bastards?
Fucking keys?
Please...
Oh, God, please.
Mikey?
Mikey! Mikey!
It's alright!
will you shut him up, Charlie!
Mikey! Mikey!
It's Charlie.
two Bob.
I think the job is fucking done.
two Bob, you fucking,
yellow dog.
Come on, you sons
of bitches, get down I
Arthur!
I'll see you
at the good Captain's.
we'll save the best till last.
Stand back!
Get!
You're grand, Samuel.
well...
we're going visiting?
That's right.
Mikey...
It's all your fault, Charlie.
You should never have left us.
would you like me to carve?
No, no, no.
I'll carve.
Finest bird I've ever had, Ma'am.
Made with me own fair hands.
Thank you.
For what we are about to receive,
may the Lord make us
truly thankful.
Amen.
Merry Christmas.
Mmm!
Guard the woman, Samuel.
Shit!
Move out of your seat
again, Ma'am,
and I'll stick this fork
through your fucking eye.
Shut up.
I said, shut up.
It's Christmas.
what does that say?
"To my darling wife,
"Whom I love so much.
I'm sorry."
Sorry for what?
Oh, Ma'am, they're beautiful!
Never seen
anything so beautiful.
Samuel!
That's us.
You Won't want
to miss this, Captain.
Samuel, sing us
Peggy Gordon.
Charlie!
Just in time.
Mikey's dead.
Listen to that.
He sings like a bird.
Ohhh...
Not the guts, Charlie.
Shit.
No more.
I'm going to be with me brother.
You got me, Charlie.
what are you going to do now?