[One Percent of Something]
Subtitles by DramaFever
[Episode 7 - The Meaning of a Gift
From a Mere Memory to a Treasured One]
How long was I asleep?
Not too long.
About an hour or so.
I finally feel alive again.
What?
You look like you've only
managed to have a meal a day.
How many hours of sleep
have you been getting?
About four hours in total
the past three days?
Including the sleep you got just now?
Boing.
Go inside.
And be sure to lock
your door properly.
What is it?
Give me your phone for a second.
You have to unlock it for me first.
Don't even look at your phone from
now until tomorrow morning.
Just sleep.
If you don't, you'll die.
You got that?
No way.
You know what a busy person I--
I waited two hours for you last time.
Don't you even feel bad about that?
Are you still mad about that?
Well, it's not like you did anything
to try and make me feel better.
All you did was sleep.
Don't do anything once you get home,
and sleep until tomorrow morning.
If you do that,
I'll forgive you for today.
All right.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Sorry for making you wait.
All right, "Internet Safety
Protocol for Employees."
There are tons of people who
aren't adhering to this lately.
One: personal work computers,
and user information...
Deputy Han! I know all about the
shopping app you have on your computer.
Erase it.
Got that?
Yes, sir.
You will not store work-related info
externally or internally via your phones.
- You will not store work-related info...
All together, damn it!
One, two, three.
You will not store work-related info
externally or internally via your phones.
I need to crack our CEO's back open,
or something.
Why?
In case he has a battery there.
Or maybe he has a USB
port there, instead?
How can someone become
so energetic overnight?
I guess he never gets tired.
Good job.
Bye!
All right, great job!
Good job.
Oh, it's a good thing you're here.
I had something to give you.
To me?
I think your uncle is up to something.
That's what your grandpa told me.
So I'm sure that
Grandpa noticed too, then?
Of course. He's got a
sharp eye, after all.
I heard that you aren't even
getting any sleep lately.
Let's go.
Oh, there's something that
I wanted to give you.
It's a gift for you.
A gift?
You give people gifts now?
I'm not sure if you'll like it,
since it's my first time giving you one.
I'll love it no matter what it is
if you're the one giving it to me.
CEO, about lunch...
Oh, it's fine.
I'll be leaving work soon, anyway.
What?
Go home early.
It's the weekend, after all.
What's the matter?
Did something happen?
He says he's leaving soon.
And he told all of us to go home early,
since it's the weekend.
That workaholic just said that to me.
Does that make any sense?
Should you and I keep working
together, then, if you don't want to?
No, I'd hate that even more!
Heading home early!
Yes! Yes!
- All right.
- Secretary Kang.
Fancy seeing you here.
Oh... oh, yes, ma'am!
I have something to say.
Don't be too mean to me.
We weren't that bad together
three years ago.
What is it that you want to say?
You want to talk here?
Let's start over.
You don't have any feelings
toward me, though.
What kind of nonsense--
You don't care about things
like love either, anyway.
And someone like me will
definitely be of help to you.
SH Group and Hanjoo Chemicals--
You're right. I don't care
about things like love.
So I don't necessarily need to choose
Hanjoo Chemicals and you.
Because I can find tons of
better alternatives.
I'm sure that the chairman
would love to have me, though.
Because he's fully aware of
what's best for the company.
Then why don't you propose
to my grandpa instead?
Sorry. I'm a bit late, aren't I?
Yes, you are.
You're 15 minutes late.
It's fine.
Do you have a bit more free time now?
No.
I'm just making time,
even though I don't have any.
A man will make time for a woman
no matter how busy he is
if he really likes her!
Why are you smiling?
I was just thinking about what we should
do in this precious time you've spared.
What do you want to do?
Whose turn is it to choose this time?
Is it me?
Me?
Hyun Jin!
Oh, Brother!
What brings you here?
To see you, of course.
Why else would I come?
Oh.
How's business?
Can you buy some of these?
Hyun Jin.
About the guy Da Hyun is seeing...
you know who he is, right?
He's Lee Jae In, right?
From SH Group?
I knew his face looked familiar.
Does Da Hyun's family
know about this, too?
Of course not! So you better
keep your mouth shut too, okay?
Why does she have to date him,
of all people?
That's not really any of
our business, now is it?
At any rate, don't go blabbing
about this anywhere.
- Her parents will worry.
- Hey.
I don't even have
anyone to tell, all right?
I think it's my turn.
What? Why?
You came last time, and all
you did was sleep, remember?
That's what I'm saying!
That date didn't count!
We didn't even do anything!
So who told you to fall asleep, then?
Let's go to the hotel if there isn't
anything specific you want to do.
What are we going do to there this time?
There's an event marking
the first day of summer
so I'm curious to see the
guests' reactions to it.
Come on, let's go!
There's even a fruit buffet
at the Tower Lounge.
What?
Nothing.
Are you worried about something?
Mr. Jae In.
What do you consider to be
the most important thing in the world?
What?
Do you have anything that
you consider really important?
Of course I do.
Money.
Money is the most
important thing to me.
Money?
Really?
That's the most important thing to you?
Why are you so obsessed with money
when you're a third-generation heir?
That's not my money.
It's all Grandpa's.
I don't want to be a
third-generation heir.
I want to be wealthy all on my own.
Whatever.
I shouldn't have asked.
Oh, Mr. Jae In!
Are you all right?
I'm sorry!
Are you okay?
Watch where you're going, punk!
Are you hurt?
Up you go.
Be careful from now on, okay?
What?
What do you mean?
You keep following me
and staring at me!
[Good job!]
What are you doing?
It's a stamp, to reward you.
Good job!
Oh.
Let's ride on that!
I think your younger brother Jae In
still thinks of you as his older brother.
He made something that you loved most,
and gave it to me.
It was bad enough that you
made me make plastic models
now you're making me go rollerskating?
Doesn't it look really fun?
Is this something that
your students like to do, too?
Hmm, probably.
Have you done this before?
- No.
- Me neither!
There wasn't a place to do this
in my neighborhood.
I couldn't do this because they told me
it was too dangerous.
Try it now, then.
Let's try it together!
I'll be fine, but you'll probably break
a bone since you're so old!
Whoa!
Hey, what are you doing?
All right.
Be careful, now.
- Careful.
- Should I go this way?
Turn. Turn.
Whoa, whoa!
One, two, three!
I'm good, right?
Slowly!
- More!
- Whoosh!
Whoa... whoa, whoa!
Oh no!
Ow, that hurts!
Are you okay?
You lied when you said that you've
never done this before, right?
Why would I?
No, this is my first time.
You said you've never
done this before, either.
Yes, I really haven't.
This is my first time.
Who was the person you last skated with?
Geez. I told you,
I've never done this before!
Let's get up.
Whoa!
Oh no!
Oh, just a second.
Your grandpa is quite a stubborn person.
After he saw your uncle leave the company
and his family behind because of a woman
he didn't even spare a glance his way.
As such, he'd have no problem throwing
either you or Jae In out in a heartbeat.
But if Jae In hadn't been
adopted by my older uncle
do you think that things would've
been any different now?
Well, Jae In probably would've followed
his mom to Canada and lived there.
Well, it's not like I have
any brothers now, so...
my father may have brought
Jae In back here anyway.
You don't fall short of Jae In
in any way.
It's just that your last names
are different, is all.
You know that, right?
All you have to do is your best.
A chance like this
won't ever come again.
Wow, I don't think I'm cut out for this.
I can't do this anymore.
What are you cut out for, then?
I don't think you're all that skilled at
assembling plastic models, either.
I knew that it'd been quiet
for way too long.
There's no such thing as a
weekend for you, is there?
Yeah, Mom?
It's only been three months
since I started dating him, okay?
I'll see later,
after I've dated him a bit longer!
When the right time comes.
Who cares if you like him or not?
I have to like him!
I told you, we're not living together!
Bye!
Does she want us to come and see her?
Don't even think about it.
I thought she'd stop her nagging
after I got myself a man.
Why is she so intent
on getting me married off?
I'd be okay with meeting her.
Then...
do you want to...
marry me?
You freaked out a little just now,
didn't you?
Don't go around saying
weird things anymore, okay?
Because you and I can never get married.
subtitles ripped and synced by riri13
Upsy-daisy!
You freaked out a little just now,
didn't you?
Don't go around saying
weird things anymore, okay?
Because you and I
can never get married.
What are you doing?
It's a stamp, to reward you.
Good job!
What's up?
Something bothering you?
Huh? No.
It's nothing.
[New singer Ji Su Has Signed Contract
With New Entertainment Agency]
Hey, what are you smiling about?
- Oh, Ji Su got signed!
- Yeah.
Wow.
What time does your shop close today?
Why? Did you want me to close early
so we can eat and get some drinks?
No, no.
Rather than that...
can you tell me what most guys are into?
Guys?
Guys like who?
Guys, as in Ji Su?
No, not Ji Su.
Just, you know...
Your average adult male.
So you mean Mr. Lee Jae In, then.
Well, I should do something for him.
He helped Ji Su so much, after all.
A car worth 1 billion won
that a Saudi prince would drive.
A 100 million won watch.
- Do you have a death wish?
- No.
Come on, just give me one hint!
Well, there isn't much to it, really.
- A woman?
What do you want?
Are you happy living this way?
Living someone else's life, I mean.
I don't think you have the right
to say something like that to me.
I've been Lee Jae In of SH Group
ever since I was born.
I've never once lost my name,
my position, or my status.
I've never once thought that I was
living someone else's life.
And I've never given up on something
I wanted to do because of someone else.
But I can't say the same for you.
If you want to win against me,
break free from your father first.
And don't be influenced by
what your mother says, either.
And when you've done that,
come and find me again.
I'll consider you as my opponent then.
Yeah.
Here?
At SH Mall?
Can I see this for a moment?
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Mommy!
Oh, I'm not your mom, sweetheart.
- Oh no.
- Mommy!
Oh no, don't cry!
Oh no, don't cry.
I'll find your mom for you. Okay?
Oh, it's okay!
It's okay!
Your mom will be here soon, okay?
But where is your mom?
What should we do?
Oh no!
We should take her to the
Lost Children Center.
Thank goodness we found her mother.
Yes.
Well, goodbye.
Um, wait.
I'm sorry.
- But, um...
- Yes?
I'd like to buy you a meal,
if that's okay with you.
Just as a thank you.
I'm SH Mall's...
employee, you see.
Oh... oh!
It was nothing, though.
Thank you for your kind
sentiments, though.
Could I have your phone number then?
I'd like to contact you later.
Um, I have a boyfriend.
Pardon?
Well, um, I felt like I had
to tell you, just in case.
Goodbye.
What was that all about?
Was he trying to get my number?
Oh, stop overreacting, Kim Da Hyun.
I left something here.
I don't think Ms. Hyun Jin is here.
It's a bit early for her to have
closed up her shop, though.
I borrowed her entire store,
just for you!
I'm amazing, aren't I?
Come here.
I thought I saw on that contract we
signed that today was your birthday.
Was I right?
I think that's right.
What do you mean, "I think?"
It's a yes-or-no question.
You didn't have any seaweed soup
(eaten on birthdays) this morning?
This is why you need to make sure
to get three square meals per day.
Did you call your family?
And say what? "Give me a present
because it's my birthday?"
That's kind of silly.
Who'd call their family to ask
for presents at your age?
You're not a child.
You should call and say, "thank you
for giving birth to me, and raising me."
"Thank you for giving birth to me,
and raising me?"
Happy birthday to you,
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, dear--
I mean, Mr. Jae In!
Happy birthday to you!
Here.
Happy birthday.
What are you doing?
Hurry up and make a wish
and blow out the candles.
Have you never blown out
candles on a cake before?
It's just been so long, is all.
How long, exactly?
About twenty...three years.
Then, I'm sure you haven't
done this, either!
I thought you taught your students
not to play with their food.
Kids don't really listen, though.
But I do see the appeal now.
Hey, come on. Smile a little!
These will all be cherished memories!
Here.
Smile!
One, two, three!
There we go.
Let's cut the cake now.
Just a moment.
Not yet.
We have to do this together.
Don't do it!
No! No!
I thought you said that we
shouldn't play with our food!
I'm as disobedient as your kids.
All right.
Smile a little!
One, two, three!
Geez. You just refuse to be
the only one who suffers, huh?
Have you been like this
since you were a child?
I told you. I've never done
anything like this before.
Really?
Wow.
Do rich people usually not celebrate
their birthdays, or something?
I thought they'd throw
extravagant parties, and such.
Today's the anniversary
of my older brother's death.
Was he directly related to you?
Legally, yes.
But he was actually my older cousin.
I was adopted into his
family after he died.
Then, what about the person
who's your mother now?
She's my mother.
She's a good person.
You don't have to look
at me with such pity.
Oh... I don't feel any pity
toward you at all!
You have two great mothers, after all!
Is that right?
Someone said to me today
that I'm living someone else's life.
What kind of complete nonsense...
as if you'd allow yourself to do that,
with that personality of yours!
And you're not the type to
take orders from anyone, either.
You're so stubborn.
There's nobody as stupidly
stubborn as you are.
Today's my birthday, you know.
And yet you're insulting me?
Yes, but the truth is still the truth.
Where's the knife?
In here, probably.
It's a gift for you.
You're not going to open it?
I'm sorry it's not a billion-won car
or a 100 million-won watch.
But in exchange, you don't have
to buy me such things, either.
I already have cars and watches.
Why? Did someone tell you
that I'd need something like that?
Yes, Hyun Jin did.
Sun W--
I mean, um, Old Mister Sun Woo
apparently likes those things.
I like that!
"Old Mister!"
Make sure you call him that
from now on, okay?
Hurry up and open this first!
This is something
that you definitely need.
It'll help you get along
better with others.
"For ages 8 and up?"
I thought you said
that I was an old man, though.
And you got a year older today!
That's why I also prepared
an adult-friendly gift, too.
Here.
Ta-da!
Want me to open it?
I wanted to get you
a tie with that
but I didn't want you to say
that I had lascivious thoughts.
Lascivious thoughts?
You don't know what
I'm talking about?
No, what are you talking about?
Well, um... never mind, then.
Hey, you should explain things
to me if I don't know!
What is it?
- Oh...
- What is it?
"You're mine."
That's what gifting a tie means.
That's what Hyun Jin told me.
Buy me a tie, then.
You get what you get,
and you don't get upset.
You're supposed to buy people what
they want for it to be a great gift!
This is the first birthday present I've
gotten in twenty-something years.
Complaining about a
gift isn't polite, you know.
There's one present that
I really want, though.
[Happy Birthday, Mr. Jae In]
Get home safe.
Oh yeah.
Let's meet up near my
school next time, okay?
No thanks.
I'm busy.
I thought you said that the issue
at the hotel got resolved already.
And I'm busy too, you know.
You have more free time
than I do, though!
That's just your opinion.
Let's do this fair and square, okay?
- Fair and square?
- Yeah. Fair and square.
You have to come see me once
if I come to see you once
and I get to solve one of my issues
once you've solved one of yours.
We have to do things like this
for all of this to be fair!
There was nothing like that
in the contract.
Of course there is!
"We will respect each others' opinions."
That was in there as the third clause.
Today's my birthday, though.
That's why I'm saying
we'll do this after today.
Happy birthday.
Even though you only have an hour and
a half left until your birthday ends.
Thanks.
Bye.
Go in.
Yes, Mother?
Today's my birthday, apparently.
J... Jae In.
I'm sorry.
I'm so... so sorry--
Thank you for raising me well.
I don't think I've ever
thanked you for that.
Okay.
Thanks.
Thanks, Jae In.
Goodnight, Mother.
I'll be hanging up now.
Here's the result of the survey
that 1,000 Chinese tourists took.
The mean number they spend on
accommodations is 80,000 won per day.
They stay at cheap short-term
rentals, hostels, motels
or rent an apartment that is illegally
being used as a bed-and-breakfast...
- Bye, everyone!
- Goodbye!
Make sure you write up and send me
the minutes for the meeting.
Yes, sir.
And as for the plan to attract
Youker to us... we'll be doing it.
Um, yes, sir.
I'm sorry, but I have to cancel today.
[What?]
Something urgent came up.
Think of us as being even now
for you not showing up to our date.
[So what's this "urgent matter"
that came up, then?]
What the hell is with this woman?
So she's just ignoring my
texts completely now, huh?
Subtitles by DramaFever
Is our CEO even really dating someone?
I heard it through the grapevine
that he is.
I meant it when I said
let's start over.
Sun Woo told me something strange.
So the man you're dating is a rich guy?
- You can't trust me?
- You wench!
Break up with him!
Why does she not like
the fact that I'm rich?
I thought about it, and no
other man compares to you.
It's just a business transaction!
- Just a business transaction?
- I made it clear to my mom
that we're not getting married.
I think we'll have to take
some measures.
Are you our teacher's boyfriend, Mister?
There are going to be tons of rumors
circulating around the school now!
What are you going to do about it?
[One Percent of Something]