(Aning)
yeah, we should go down there. they got him.
No, we should go down there. They got him.
They've got him. Third time's the charm.
please, stay in the boat!
A new shipment's arriving today.
Ah, just what we need..
more cocky imperialist doctors.
No, what we need is new blood.
I'm sick of looking at the two of you.
Baby docs are all the same.
They don't give a crap about the work.
They're just padding their resume with a little third-world do-gooding
let 'em. I just need one good one.
help me! get in the boat!
They're gonna drown his ass.
Okay, so maybe they don't got him.
I'll open up the clinic.
Why's he gotta be such a show-off?
There are worse places to
practice medicine, papito.
Don't I know it.
*
This is it.
Señorita, when you're ready
to go back to the airport,
You call me, okay?
Oh, thank you, but that won't be necessary.
This is a one-way trip.
You're here to work at the clinic?
Yeah, I'm a doctor.
Take the card.
He's right. You should
definitely take the card.
Al aeropuerto, por favor.
okay, hijo, now this might
hurt just a little.
Hi. Um, I'm supposed to
check in with a doctor...
Zee-tah-le-har...
Ah, goody, another american.
Saved by the great white hope.
I'm sorry?
Dr. Zitajalehrena alvarez.
Zee. Oh!
Why don't you drop those bags and
go see if you can help? Okay.
please, stop!
Aah! Aah!
Whoa! Is that a-- one ugly-ass fish.
That is not just a fish.
That's a stingray. No! No! No!
Their venom is particularly potent.
What, are you a vet or something?
Infectious disease.
I- I'm mina minard.
Lily brenner, emergency med.
Tommy fuller, plastics.
I need you to stay still, buddy.
Try staying still with a
fish inside your body!
I need drugs, man! Sorry.
I don't have drugs for you.
What kind of crazy-ass witch doctor
Doesn't have drugs?!
The kind that survives on donations.
Now there's a box on your way out.
Hi. We're the new doctors. What can we do?
Hold his shoulders. Brace his legs. no,
no, get-- get the hell away from me! Uhh!
Sit down. Grab his foot.
Okay, on the count of three. One, two--
Uhh! No! No! No!
No. No.
All right, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Look at that.
Aah! Aah!
Uhh!
Welcome, doctors.
Off the Map s01e01 : Saved by the Great White Hope
Okay, we're the only medical
center with 200 miles.
We're slammed all the time.
do you have a surgical suite? On the patio.
how do you keep it sterile? When you got
a guy bitten by a 10-foot crocodile,
You get the teeth out.
You worry about infection later.
Forget what you saw in residency.
Practicing tropical medicine
in a third-world country
Is a different game.
Here, it's 1952.
You don't have high tech.
You don't have big pharma.
You have your brain.
You have your instincts.
You use them well,
you'll learn more here in a week
Than doctors learn in a year of residency.
And you're standing in the middle
Of the greatest medical resource on earth.
This is the tropical rain forest.
Here, we have plants to cure viruses,
Tree sap to heal wounds,
insects that stop gangrene.
And this is where medicine was born.
You up for it?
Great,
'cause out of hundreds of doctors,
I picked you three.
So don't screw it up,
is what he's trying to say.
Dr. Otis cole.
His bark's worse than is bite.
Okay, um, they're both pretty bad.
When in doubt, hand out ibuprofen.
Dr. C-cole?
I-- we've been traveling for days.
Before we get started,
is it cool if we hit the beach?
You know, get our swim on.
Hey, ladies, dr. Otis cole
just personally asked me
To look after one of his patients.
You realize we're objectifying
One of the greatest
humanitarians of our time?
Just admiring his credentials.
This place is awesome.
Not only are there no malpractice suits,
But there's surfing.
And you know how many days
a year it's sunny here?
All of them. Oh, oh, oh. Sunblock.
I got you guys some samples from the office.
Aw, that's really nice.
thank you. Yeah, I think there's,
like, three topless beaches
Right around here, and you do
not want those to shrivel up
Before their time. I've seen it happen.
It's... It's tragic.
Ugh. All right. I'll see you guys later.
Going on a house call.
This is gonna be so cool.
You brought your own trauma kit?
Well, I figured for the jungle,
you need flares, tourniquets,
Field splints. Girl scout.
So guilty.
Hey, you lost?
Ah, english. Hey.
Uh, do you have any idea
where this village is?
They said it's near a river,
But there's, like, 80 rivers on this thing.
Really, you getting stuck on a
house call on your first day?
You must have pissed off cole.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's not like that.
He's trusting me with one-- mm-hmm.
Who are you? I'm charlie.
I'm the translator for the clinic.
How old are you? Trece.
I... If you don't know what that means,
I think you might need my help.
Dr. Cole said the patient has t.B.
I'm not gonna expose a kid to that.
You're right. I'm sure you'll find your way
Over a treacherous mountain range
To a very remote village just fine.
Uh, hey, wait, wait.
You might wanna bring
some water. It's a walk.
I can handle a walk.
Wrong way.
Come on, gringo.
"gringo"? What's gringo?
It means "white person."
Ladies, I have 40 patients
waiting to be seen.
Not to mention, I'm down another doctor.
Oh, is that the woman I saw leaving today?
She seemed really upset.
Radio distress call just came in.
We got an injury in the jungle.
I could use another hand out there
If you don't mind being
short a doctor. I could go.
I'm ready. Why not?
They seem to be dropping like flies today
anyway. I'm trained in triage protocol.
Oh. Me, too, and I've got a trauma
kit already packed. Okay, well,
You just got yourself your
first field trip. Come on.
So this is how you, uh, get around?
It's better for jungle roads...
If you can call 'em that.
Okay, let's do this.
Doctor, you hang on like that,
you're roadkill.
aah!
Dr. Minard, what, um,
what-- what are you doing?
Patient presented with limb
stiffness and numbness.
I did a full body check for lesions.
And I don't wanna alarm you,
but I haven't been able
To rule out hemorrhagic fever.
Â¿es el brazo izquierdo otra vez?
Igual que antes.
Mm.
Tenga.
Gracias, doctor.
It's, uh... Very thorough, doctor,
But, uh, sometimes it's
not hemorrhagic fever.
It's just good old-fashioned tennis elbow.
We're in one of the biggest hot zones
For infectious disease.
How does someone get... Tennis elbow?
Oh, from using a machete?
Or from playing tennis.
oh, please, stop! I told you it's a walk.
No, this isn't a walk. It's an ironman.
I'm-- I'm being punished, aren't I?
This is the reason why
americans are fat and lazy.
They only drive.
You know why? 'cause we
invented streets for ourselves.
It's called civilization.
You should really try it.
Wait. Did you just call me fat?
The patient dr. Cole was
treating lives over there.
Great. The doctor is in.
Buenos días.
buenos días.
Es el dr. Fuller de la clínica.
They're all sick.
Which one was dr. Cole treating?
¿a quién estaba atentiendo el dr. Cole?
Allá... A mi esposa.
His wife.
She's dead.
Keeton, thank god! This guy
just slammed right into a tree.
There's blood everywhere.
There's gonna be internal injuries then.
Where's the patient?
Alláarriba!
por favor, escucha al doctor.
No! No! No! No quiero más medicinas!
Tell him that his family
has advanced tuberculosis.
It's a bacterial infection.
It needs to be treated.
El dr. Fuller que dice que es
una infección bacterial
Y puede curar, se necisitan esas medicinas.
Sí, los doctores nos trajeron esa--
Esto es lo que las medicinas le
han hecho a mi familia.
he says he doesn't want medicine,
Not for him or the children.
These children are dying of a
totally curable disease.
I- I can save their lives
if he'll just let me.
El dr. Fuller dice que sus
niños están muy enfermos
Y para salvarlos necesitan esa medicina.
Mi esposa tomó esa medicina,
Y entonces no podía respirar.
He said the medicine from dr. Cole
Is what killed his wife.
That doesn't make any sense!
The antibiotics--
they take time to start working.
he says they made his wife worse,
So he made her stop taking the
medicine. Well, then it's his
damn fault that his wife is dead!
I'm not gonna say that.
well, then I've done
everything I can do here.
Okay, we'll go out on the same line.
That way, we can both reach him. Uh, no.
One line won't hold three people.
Maybe not even two.
Hold that there. Can you lift your shirt?
What are you doing?
Okay, you're lighter than me.
You're gonna have to go out on your own.
I'll get as close as I can and
talk you through it, okay?
Okay?
hold with the right, brake with the left.
These things are safe, right?
Hold with the right, brake with the left.
Whoa.
okay, brake.
brake! Use the brake!
I'm trying! It's stuck!
Aah!
Sir?
Sir, can you hear me?
His arm's caught in the roller.
I think he's in...
I think he's in shock. Well, then we
need to move fast. You're gonna have to
Tourniquet the extremity
and cut the flesh free.
Cut his arm out? We need to get him
down before he bleeds to death.
You got a better idea?
Oh! Aah!
You have un frio.
A cold.
Very common.
Uh, make certain to...
Reloj... "to watch"
If make fiebre...
Return aquí for visita.
Look alive, doctora.
Our ebola rush starts around noon.
That's hilarious. Go to hell.
Calm him down, brenner! I'm trying! Sir--
The more he moves, the more he bleeds!
You gotta try harder!
I gotta get down! I gotta--
I can't die up here! Hey! Hey!
You stop that right now!
What's your name?
Ed. Ed greenman.
Okay, ed greenman, you listen to me.
Yeah?
You are not going to die. You're gonna live.
Okay?
Now...
I'm gonna have to cut your arm.
I'm gonna try not to cut too deep,
but it's gonna hurt.
And then I'm gonna tie you to my harness,
And we're gonna get the hell off this thing.
Stay superficial so you don't
sever the radial artery.
right.
Don't watch it.
Ed. Look at me. Look at me. Aah!
Look at me.
Talk to me. Ed, talk to me.
So, ed, what--
what brings you to the jungle?
I came here when I was 25 on my honeymoon.
that was the best trip we ever had.
we even did the zip line,
But somehow
It didn't seem quite so high 40 years ago.
I probably shouldn't even be up here.
You and me both, ed.
Aah! You and me both.
The bleeding's under control,
but we're gonna take you back
To the clinic and check for
internal injuries, okay?
Not bad,
For your first day back.
What?
I spoke to your chief
resident back in the states.
You took a pretty long leave of absence.
Well, I lost somebody,
So I took some time,
But I-I'm good now.
I'm a doctor, right? So...
That doesn't make it any easier.
Well, we should go. It's a long ride back.
Mm. Yeah.
Uh-oh. I hear bad words in spanish.
Wh-what's wrong, loca?
What's wrong?
I am slammed,
And I haven't figured
out how to clone myself.
And...
She left. Again. They all leave,
so I don't know why
I waste my time training these
useless americanos
Who don't even bother to learn spanish.
Because you're a great teacher,
and, uh, you know, you have
The patience of a saint. 100 pesos says
they're all gone by the end of the week!
Maybe not so much the patience,
But deep down is a heart
of gold in there, woman.
Heart of gold.
Only for you, cariño. Muévete.
Ed, your arm's gonna be fine,
but it looks like
You're starting to bleed internally.
And how do you fix that?
Well, with a small rupture,
the spleen can heal itself,
But if it doesn't, we operate.
Surgery in the jungle.
I thought zip-lining was scary.
There any family we should contact?
Your wife, maybe?
She passed away a few months ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Been promising her for 30 years
We'd come back here.
But you get busy.
Had a mortgage to pay.
I finally retired
And booked this trip.
And I guess I waited a little too long.
Can't we airlift him out and
get him to a city hospital?
They have a c.T.
The airlift can't land till tomorrow.
Just get him on packed cells.
He's weak from blood loss.
You're still here?
I- I told you, it's--
It's just chest congestion.
You can go home.
Home.
Or not.
How was your field trip, plastics?
Your patient's dead.
No, I-I had her on a triple drug regimen
For over two weeks. She was improving.
Yeah, and then her husband stopped the meds.
The whole family's got t.B. Now,
And he doesn't want anyone treated.
I- I don't know the exact procedure here
In terms of a.M.A.S and stuff,
so I had the guy sign that.
"I am refusing treatment
Against medical advice."
This-- this is a joke, right?
It's a little makeshift,
but I think it'll work. I mean you.
You're a joke. You don't
know anything about me.
Oh, I did my homework on you, plastics.
You drank your way through medical school,
Barely made it through residency, but, hey,
It's no big deal. I mean,
you were never really trying
To be the best doctor, right?
Just good enough so you could
do surgery in a strip mall.
I mean, that's the real tragedy here,
man. You're not stupid.
You're lazy. What was I
supposed to do, force--
You are supposed to be a doctor!
First light, you will haul
your ass back up there,
And you will treat those people,
every last one of 'em,
Or don't bother coming back.
It's 3:00 a.M.
how is it this hot out,
And it's 3:00 a.M.?
Hi.
Oh.
Oh, god.
Right?
They've got a cage match going out there--
Scorpion versus tarantula.
I just lost 50 pesos.
What are you doing?
Oh, my god. I just had an orgasm.
See? It's not that bad.
Ohh. We have a fan.
I got to save a guy's
life on a zip line today.
You-- you got to save a guy's life...
you...
You win.
You know, on the web site for this place,
They promised us a perfect beach.
Oh, there's a beach.
You just have to kill yourself to get to it.
I wanna live, but I want the beach.
I can't go anyway. I gotta go check
on my patient. Yeah, at least
you have a patient to check on.
I handed out band-aids today,
like a school nurse.
I traveled 5,000 miles, and for what?
They know everything about us.
What's he talking about?
They did their homework on us.
Whatever.
So much for a clean slate.
Just follow the fan.
♪
You must think I'm a real nut job.
I lose someone I love
And hop on a plane to the jungle.
Not at all.
I didn't come for a vacation.
My wife cora--
I brought her with me.
I'm sorry?
She's in my duffel.
Her ashes.
Got it.
Figured I'd take her to the
place she loved the most.
You heard of lago de luz?
No.
Cora called it the firefly lake.
At night, the algae lights up.
It looks like millions of fireflies
Trapped just underneath the water,
Flapping their wings,
Trying to break free.
It's like nothing you've ever seen.
It's beautiful.
And that's where you're gonna say good-bye?
That was the plan.
Life sure has a way
Of changing your plans, though.
Yeah.
It does.
Ed?
So what's your plan?
My plan is to express the dangers
Of refusing treatment.
Hmm.
And how is that any different
from what you did yesterday?
Well, this time I'm gonna turn on the charm.
So what's your plan for tomorrow?
You're a little bully, you know that?
I'm cutting through the peritoneum.
Man, it is ugly in there.
Yeah, it looks like more
than just the spleen.
Oh, we've got multiple trauma sites--
Liver, mesenteric artery, hepatic vein.
It's way worse than I thought.
he's bleeding out. Get a vascular clamp
On the spleen. Oh, we don't have enough
ab-neg to handle this much blood loss.
Okay, switch to o-neg. Only one unit left.
what? We never have
enough of the rare types.
we don't have enough blood?
Okay, pour in the fluids.
Mobilize the spleen.
Tie off the liver. You, come with me.
Oh, for the love of god.
You're back? I told you, it's a virus.
I can't do anything.
Oh.
Crap. She's not breathing.
Get me epinephrine.
You're gonna put coconut in his veins?!
The water from green coconuts
has the same electrolyte balance
As blood plasma.
They used in world war ii
when they ran out of fluids.
But there's gotta be another
way to get him stable.
I mean, this is-- yeah, we could go
door-to-door asking for blood donations,
But that could take a while. Don't worry.
I've done this more times than any other guy
down here. Oh, you have? How many times?
Once. Great.
okay.
Now when I cut, you catch.
I hope you played little league.
What? No. I- I never played anything.
I was on the debate team. Okay.
Are you ready? You can't miss.
I know. If it breaks, it's unsterile.
No, if it hits you
On the head from up here,
you're pretty much dead. Right.
On one...
Two...
Three!
oh, my god! I did it.
All right. Let's go for another.
Come on. Breathe!
Es lo único que tenemos.
Es una dosis bien--
I have no idea what you're saying.
Just give it to me.
come on, lady! Breathe!
Breathe already!
Breathe. Ohh. Oh.
scalpel.
He's bleeding out.
Okay. Open the net.
Okay. Needle.
Okay. Tubing.
Hang it.
no quiero más medicinas y más inventos
Que no funcionan.
Fever's spiking. Okay,
tell him she doesn't have much time.
A couple days at most. A su hija
no le queda mucho tiempo.
No quiero más medicinas, dije. He says no.
And him? Tell him I can barely feel his
son's pulse anymore. Dije que no más!
Stop saying no, damn it!
I get it, okay?
I don't speak the language.
I'm just a dumb american.
I- if you came to chicago
and barged into my place,
I would call the cops on you.
I don't get to come in here
and tell you how to take care
Of your family,
all right? You're a proud man.
I- I respect that. I'm a proud man, too.
I don't listen to anyone.
My parents told me to go
To college and study hard,
and I just partied. They told me,
"go to med school.
Learn how to take care of people."
And I learned how to put
boobs in-into strippers.
They told me, you know,
"stop screwing around. Be a man.
Be someone-- a son that we can be proud of."
And I tell them to get out of my life.
I-I can't go home now.
It's been a year, and I can't go home.
I lost my family,
Because I was proud.
I don't want you to do the same thing.
Come on, man. Let me help you.
Es un buen doctor.
Puede ayudar a su familia.
I'm just talking to myself now.
Estábien.
Por favor.
Ayúdelos.
He says okay.
He wants to shake your hand.
Ayúdela mi familia,
Por favor.
Spleen's out.
Sponge stick.
Lily, give me a hand.
I want you to hold this
bleeder while I tie it off.
I'm not a surgeon.
Here, you are a surgeon.
Here, you're a surgeon. You're a paramedic.
You're search and rescue.
If I need you to run labs to the city,
you're the mailman.
You're anything I need you to be.
Now don't pinch off the vessel.
Just keep steady. Squeeze.
I got it. B.P.'s coming up.
Nice work, dr. Brenner.
You'll never believe
What we just did.
A coconut transfusion!
And-- and actually,
It saved the guy's life.
that's great. Very happy for you.
Are you okay?
If I could find a damn steroid.
All they have is, uh,
ecuadorean tree sap, so...
Oh!
I was looking for rare,
complicated diseases,
And I almost lost a woman to asthma.
They say when you hear hoofbeats,
You gotta think horses,
Not zebras.
Really? it's that simple?
God, you really are a girl scout.
Look, I'm trying to be your friend here,
But you're making it really hard.
At my hospital...
They liked to, uh, weed out the weak.
You had to fight to get on cases.
Made it pretty much
impossible to learn anything,
So I started moonlighting at county,
picking up shifts.
I was doing 8 hours at county
and 12 hours in my residency,
And 1 day after 72 hours without sleep,
This kid came into the-- into the e.R.
With a fever,
And I thought it was the flu.
I mean, 20 kids a day came into that e.R.
It was always the flu.
So I sent him home...
And he died...
Three hours later.
I got kicked right out of residency.
The...
It was bacterial meningitis.
All it would've taken was, uh, a spinal tap,
But...
I was too exhausted to do it.
So sometimes it is zebras.
You have untreated asthma.
You had a severe attack.
I didn't-- I didn't see it before,
because I...
I didn't see it.
This is an inhaler.
It'll help you breathe.
I only have a few,
Because I brought them from home.
See?
Uh...
It's no big deal.
It's...
status-- post-splenectomy
and liver laceration repair.
Bled down to a crit of 22.
he needs 5 liters of o2
And two more units of blood when you land.
Dr. Brenner. They're taking
you to a city hospital now.
You're gonna be fine. The fireflies.
He's been talking about the damn fireflies
Since he came out of surgery. Can't leave.
I-- the fireflies. I promised her.
Okay. Rápido, vámonos. No, no. Wait! Wait.
They can't take him away yet.
There's something he's
gotta do before he leave.
What are you talking about? The-- the lake.
The one with, um, the algae that lights up.
Lago de luz. We have to take
him there. He needs to go.
It's a half-hour by boat.
Medevac's gotta get back to the hospital.
Well, they'll wait for us, right? Por favor.
There's no time for sightseeing right now.
Come on, fellas. It's not about that!
It's-- he has his wife's ashes.
He came all the way--
Listen, brenner,
we can't-- you listen to me!
He came down here to do one thing,
To say good-bye, and he got so close.
We can help him finish
what he came here to do.
we can help him say good-bye.
He needs to say good-bye.
we saved his life today,
And now we can give him a
chance to move on with it.
What if we had been lost in the
jungle for, like, 20 years?
No. But it's just you and me, naked,
Braiding each other's hair,
'cause it'd be long.
No.
Okay, but I'm super buff now
from hunting and gathering,
And there's no other dudes on earth,
And it's up to you and me to
carry on the human race. No.
Well...
You're not a humanitarian.
Are you the one that treated my grandmother?
I'm sorry that she had to almost die
To get my attention.
My grandmother is 80 years old,
And today she took her first real breath.
She said that because of you,
She finally knows what
it feels like to breathe.
ohh.
no, no, no, no.
No, no. Don't. No. So kind. So kind.
so un-- not necessary.
Gracias, doctora.
okay.
Mm.
Mm. Mm. Mm.
Well, thank you.
well, this is it--
Lago de luz.
It's just a pond.
A microscopic organism.
When it's disturbed,
The chemical reaction causes the phosph--
Fireflies.
Ed.
Are you ready?
we made it, cora.
You're with the fireflies now.
We made it, sweetheart.
Thank you.
My fiancee.
That's who I lost.
And that's why I left residency.
You ever seen the southern cross?
Right there.
Those five stars.
Yeah, they say magellan used it
To find true south whenever he got lost.
It gave him the strength to keep going.
Keep going.
♪
What the hell are those tontos doing?
Getting themselves killed.
100 pesos says the bitchy
one is anaconda lunch.
yeah, I'll get on that.
♪
I hope you're planning on sharing that.
How far did you get this time?
Airport.
Sat there for two days,
ate bad airport food,
And prayed on it.
Oh, by the way, god says you're an ass.
Well, he never did like me all that much.
I'm glad you're back.
Well, you need me here,
And I'm not gonna throw away
All the good I can do in this place
Just because you're not able to...
Whatever.
I'm back.
You coming to bed?
No.
I know you miss her,
But she's gone.
She's not coming back.
I won't wait up.
♪ we'll do it for our sisters ♪
♪ we'll do it for our brothers ♪
Over here.
So this is our beach.
Looks like a postcard.
you can look, but you can't touch.
If there was ever somewhere to start over,
It's right here.
♪
Come on.
Whoa!
Whoa! Ohh.
Whoa.
Nuh-unh.
Aah!
Oh!
Okay, you are both crazy! Come on, fuller!
jump!