I'm the man.
Are you okay?
I'm totally okay.
By the way, what happened to your arm?
Is it because of the earthquake?
It's not broken, is it?
It's nice.
What's so nice when you're injured?
Are you really okay?
It feels so nice when you worry about me.
Since I'm already hurt,
I should've broken it.
What nonsense is that?
You can't fool me twice.
- Does it really hurt?
- Yeah.
Let me see.
Whatever.
Thanks...
...for accepting my love.
I'm sorry...
...for making you wait.
We are here.
My place is over there.
Oh, this is where you live.
I don't want to say bye.
Go. You said you needed to go right away.
Alright.
You can go in first, Secretary Jung.
You can go first, Director.
You first.
You go first, Director.
You go ahead. I'll go
after I see you go in.
Then...
Shall we count one, two, three
and leave at the same time?
Sure. Okay.
But then...
let's not do this, okay?
Okay.
- So embarrassing...
- Right.
- Play it cool.
- Sure, let's play it cool.
One.
Two.
Three.
What is this?
Jeez.
What is it?
Oh, really. Why aren't you going?
I really thought you were leaving.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Go ahead.
I was really scared.
She is really leaving.
She will turn.
She will turn...
Coach
Oh, shit.
King of High School. Episode 9.
One.
Unless...
Two.
I'm...
crazy...
One.
How dare...
Two.
...would I sneak out?
One.
Unless...
That crazy dork.
He's doing this for an hour
already. He might die doing that.
Thank God we made up an excuse for him.
But why did that dork sneak out anyway?
How would I dare sneak out?
You, punk.
You can have an emergency.
But you left without telling me?
I'm sorry.
You finally struck out three times.
Huh?
I won't let this go this time.
We'll talk again after the league is over.
Got that?
Okay, sir.
Manage properly, okay?
Follow me.
I'm sorry.
You went crazy. You are completely crazy.
What's up with you? Why did you
sneak out? Where have you been?
I have my reasons.
Oh, hey.
Hey, hey.
I think he completely went
mad with too much punishment.
I think he got his head
injured along with his arm.
Stop it already.
Let's just go.
Hey, friends.
This hyungnim really loves you.
Jeez, crazy bastard.
Let me get up.
Hey, hey. Up.
My legs.
They don't belong to me any more.
Stop it.
They are not mine.
They are not his.
I really want to go.
Please let's go.
Yes, I'm home safely.
Are you home as well, Director?
How can I wait until Monday?
I miss you so much already.
Oh my, Director.
What...
We were together just a minute ago.
Oh, but your arm is hurt, and...
you can't rest because of work.
I'm worried.
Huh?
Oh, that...
You know, after a business trip...
you need to take care of a lot of things.
Hubby Lee, did you enjoy
my fried tofu sushi?
You know...
We should...
When we finish work on Monday...
Wait for a second.
Hubby Lee.
Did you enjoy my fried tofu sushi?
You must be tired because
of the hard training.
Fighting.
If you are busy, we can hang up now.
Oh, no, no.
It was a text message from a friend.
So...
When we finish work on Monday...
let's have our first date.
Date?
I like that.
Is there anything you want to do?
What I want to do...
I'll think about it.
Director.
Take a rest now.
Okay.
What?
Gosh...
Unni, are you seeing someone?
Huh?
How did you know?
Am I an idiot?
You're making it so obvious.
What is it?
So, you finally decided
to see the director?
Then you should have
told your sister first.
You were saying you shouldn't see him.
When did you decide to see him?
Today is our first day together.
Oh, my. You're almost tickled pink. Are
you an elementary student or something?
Have him come over someday.
I'd like to meet him.
Sure.
Oh, god.
You...
You didn't... did you?
You wicked dork.
Is this for real?
Are you saying you decided
to date that popcorn sister?
Popcorn sister, popcorn sister...
should I just pop those corns?
So, with that popcorn sister...
you went like this?
Oh, my. Oh, my.
By the way...
what are you really gonna do?
That pop...
I mean... that popcorn sister...
You said she is in her late twenties.
Her late twenties...
Age is not a problem here.
She doesn't know a thing about you.
You are Lee Hyung Suk, a 28-year-old super
ultra elite director of Comfo from Germany.
Out of breath...
Anyway, she knows you as Lee Hyung Suk.
She can't even imagine you as Lee Min Suk,
an eighteen year old high schooler.
This is a problem. A big problem.
What are you gonna do?
Do you think it makes sense?
Of course.
Sure.
I won't think of anything from now on.
What?
I mean...
The fact that I like that woman...
That noona...
Noona means older sister or older
female from a male perspective.
Noona.
Noona, right.
My feeling that I care
about the popcorn sister.
I'll only think about that. Nothing else.
I only believe in that and keep going.
Come on here.
You were so romantic there.
I really envy you. You
have everything, punk.
Congrats, huh?
You... you did...
- Did you do chup chup with lips?
- Chupa chupa.
Chupa chupa?
Oh, man.
How old do you think we are?
Chupa?
Chu?
What's up with chu chu? What was that?
Chu, chu...
Hey, what's next then?
I don't know. I don't know.
King of High School
Father, your food tastes extra
good today. Really, so good.
I haven't been to the market lately.
We are having the same food.
Overreacting...
You like it?
I like it.
Completely, no joking.
Gramps.
Wow!
Why are you looking...
extra handsome today?
Handsome guy!
I'm going.
Need to go.
Are you in a hurry?
Yes, I am.
Oh, Gramps.
Father.
I'm leaving.
Good-bye, Director.
Did he have a sweet dream or something?
Oh, my.
Is it your first love or something?
Yoo Ah.
How is it?
What do you think?
Really... You got me all curious.
What kind of ahjussi is it?
The scarf is...
I'm dying to see him.
Bring him over soon, okay?
Okay.
Director.
Hello.
Oh, my.
You have something there.
Director.
Always dress up nicely, please.
What is that?
We all know you're his secretary.
Enough with all that nagging.
By the way, Soo Young...
why are you all dressed up today?
Do you have a date?
Oh, no...
Your hair...
You're wearing mascara, too.
You're right.
You're wearing perfume, too.
It's just cologne.
Can't I even wear mascara and perfume?
Soo Young.
All she has to say is no.
Why get mad at us?
Hello.
Oh, hello.
Good morning.
Assistant Manager Yoon. Good morning.
Hello.
Soo Young, you must have
something nice going on.
Oh, no.
You're not telling the truth.
Something must be going on.
Nothing's going on...
Did you happen to hear about that person?
You know, long time ago...
who used to work as a
chauffeur for Lee Jung Soo.
Lee Jung Soo's chauffeur?
Oh...
the one with unique way of speech...
His name was...
Choi something...
Right. Chauffeur Choi.
Well...
After what happened to Lee Jung Soo,
I haven't heard anything.
Why bring up Chauffeur
Choi all of a sudden?
I think...
a few days ago...
I saw a man who looked like him.
Alright then. You can leave.
Alright then.
Jung Soo Young. Really...
I really didn't think of you
that way. I feel betrayed.
Excuse me?
You should get a conscience at least.
This is so good. You must have
enjoyed this everyday by yourself.
Oh, boy.
Director.
God.
Not that much. You slapped me too hard.
I didn't slap that hard.
Does it hurt a lot?
Touch it. Touch it.
You thought I would say that.
I won't be fooled anymore.
Speechless.
Speechless. You already figure me out?
We only dated for a few days.
Jeez, my life is ruined.
Try this, too.
Oh, it's so nice...
to eat while looking at the sky.
I feel like going out somewhere.
Let's go.
Excuse me?
Let's go out.
Weekend starts tomorrow,
so we can go tomorrow.
Seriously?
Where to?
Well...
Hm... where should I take
you to make you happy?
Right.
I'll get it all planned out today.
You, Jung Soo Young...
can just come along...
You can bring things like
this, and just come.
Yeah!
Oh, yeah!
I have to work.
It's alright.
- Only ordinary workers...
- Director.
Huh?
This is your entire schedule for today.
I don't care how busy it is.
Come up all the way and
bother me when I'm eating?
I really don't understand you.
Just leave.
Go back to your work.
I can't...
...even enjoy my food.
I don't have anywhere to relax.
Isn't it too much?
Well...
Ji Dae Han wanted to buy me a coffee...
You said only ordinary workers come here.
I know. Why is he here?
It's my birthday today, and
what rotten luck I have!
Let's go together.
Oh, my.
- Director.
- You scared me.
What if someone sees us?
No one will. It's okay.
Gosh!
Director.
I'm a modern woman who can draw a line
between public and private matters.
Even before I establish
myself as a secretary,
I can never let people talk about
my private life behind my back.
There, there. There you go again.
Hey, Secretary.
Take this please.
Go first. Lead the way.
Let's go. Go.
You looked good together.
You and Director Lee.
Cheap women don't attract me much.
I mean...
You seem to change your mind
rather quickly, Jung Soo Young.
It's just advice.
I apologize if I was presumptuous.
Yes.
You were a little presumptuous.
Director Lee...
Do you really like him?
Yes, I do.
At least he is not like someone...
who is different inside out.
Oh, today...
...is Assistant Manager Park's birthday.
Shouldn't we have a party for him?
Oh, really?
Oh...
I'm too old to have a party.
It's alright.
If we didn't know, it would've been okay. But we
can't let it pass like that now that we know.
Assistant Manager Park.
We are going to sing a
song for you as a gift.
You treat us to lunch, okay?
Oh, that sounds like a good idea.
Song?
Happy birthday to you.
We sang a song. We sang a song for you.
Alright then...
Lunch is on me.
Wow, yeah!
- Director.
- Yes.
Today is Assistant Manager Park's birthday and
he's buying us lunch. Why don't you join us?
Oh... birthday...
You know on summer days,
cold ramen is the best.
Enjoy, enjoy.
Can I order chicken teriyaki or something?
If you don't have enough kkakdugi or pickled
radish, I'll bring it for you. Refills are free.
It looks yummy. Let's eat up
quickly and go back to work.
Sure.
No meat...
We haven't been weekend
mountain-climbing that much this spring.
We did a lot last year though.
That's right. It was so windy back then.
We are so fickle, aren't we?
Now it's brought up...
shall we go mountain-climbing?
- Tomorrow is a holiday.
- Huh?
Mountain-climbing sounds good.
I was worrying about my fat belly
anyway. What about you guys?
Of course, I will. Doing nothing
on the weekend is so boring.
I am going, too. I have
nothing to do this weekend.
So am I. Nothing to do.
I...
don't think I can go. I need to visit my
mother. She wants to make seaweed soup for me.
Oh, that's a pity.
So, everyone will attend except
Assistant Manager Park, right?
Oh, oh... I...
have something with my family.
So I don't think I can go.
Oh...
Me, too. My friend is
getting married that day.
Oh, oh... What's going on?
Our important member...
Director Lee can't miss
it. It's so disappointing.
Oh, it's okay.
This time, only people who can make it can
go. We can go all together next time, okay?
Sure, sure.
Of course.
- The food here is good, isn't it?
- Sure.
By the way, our director...
Isn't he a little fishy these days?
What about him?
I mean, he whistles all day long.
He said he'd miss out
on the weekend outing.
His face looks so good.
It's fishy.
I think he's seeing someone.
You felt it, too, unni. I totally felt it.
With his career, personality,
and good-looks...
And he is so young...
What kind of woman would a
man like our director date?
I'm curious.
It's me. It's me.
I said it's me. Me!
Oh, gosh. I was once...
...really busy dating on weekends.
I miss those good old days.
When I went on a trip with my
boyfriend and missed the last bus...
That night...
our history began...
Really...
He knew what time the last bus was. He was saying
he lost his wallet and trying to kill time.
I found out later...
he was planning to miss
the last bus after all.
And? So?
What about it?
I pretended to go along.
What does a woman need
at a moment like that?
- Playing innocent...
- Oh, my god.
You're right. It's obvious what guys want
when they want to get out of the city.
That's their goal.
If he doesn't touch me on a trip like that,
it means he is not sexually attracted to me.
I will get so pissed off.
I'll get it all planned out today.
Jung Soo Young...
You can just come along.
Only come along...
- What's up?
- Oh, god.
What's that? What's up again?
Did you see a ghost or
something again? Huh?
Anyways...
You know, about outing...
I thought...
...about it a little.
Since it's our first time, let's make
it a trip. How about Namiseom?
I mean, we can ride a train.
Sounds good.
But...
I have something urgent to
do, so please excuse me.
What's up with her again?
She's so different. She
is not boring at all.
When I went on a trip with my
boyfriend and missed the last bus...
That night...
our history began...
It's obvious what guys want when
they want to get out of the city.
That's their goal.
Namiseom?
Soo Young, you're here.
So he's planning to spend some
time and stay there for one night?
- Oh, my... Really...
- Can you confirm it with the director and...
- Is he really?
- ...hand it over to the General Affairs Team?
Please?
That's what I was going to say...
...and you are gone. It's been
awhile since I was ignored.
One shot.
I was going on a date with my boyfriend.
Does he have any other intention?
What should I do?
FYI, the place is Namiseom.
I'll bet my whole porn collection
on that he has other intention.
Namiseom?
Isn't that classic?
100% impure intention! No, 200%.
Are you in elementary school?
Your boyfriend's intention is so obvious.
All guys are wolves.
What do you mean?
Go to the lingerie store
and get a sexy night gown.
I sent you the analysis of the teams
that we are going to have games with.
Study them thoroughly.
Oh, Coach.
He analyzed them really well.
What's going on?
What brings you all the way here?
This is the analysis from the Project Team.
This is the information on
the Y-Tower Mall remodel.
I don't like to come here anyway.
However, I have a special order from the
President to share it with the directors.
Oh, let's see...
I'm busy. It's messy here, so...
put it over there.
Look at it and give me your opinion.
And what? What's up? What? What again?
Let's move our meeting
next week one hour later.
I have something.
You can do as you like.
Sure.
Regarding Lee Hyung Suk.
You were suspicious of him, and...
you said you have a way to find out.
So...
is that going well?
I felt he was trying to hide something.
So I was going to find it out.
But it didn't work out well.
It didn't work out too well, you say...
There must be something
you can't do, I guess.
He seems to have visited Germany
after he joined the company.
I don't know what he's cooking up.
I can't even...
...guess in the least.
So...
Are you saying you are giving up like this?
No, I'm not.
I will try other routes.
He's up to something for sure.
I was going to buy you something nice.
What's up with spicy
rice cake on the street?
There's nothing as good as this.
Why do you keep staring?
I didn't.
You did.
Oh, no.
Is something on me?
Nothing's on you.
Oh, jeez. It's all over you.
Come on.
What is that?
There's rice cake here.
It's fine.
Oh, my.
Oh, Director.
Why are you so messy?
Oh, we are already here.
You can go now.
Already?
I want to talk more and...
Please go now.
I have no time.
You scared me.
What? What time?
You have an appointment?
No, I mean, we are going to be
together all day long tomorrow.
You need to go and take a rest.
Okay.
Oh, let's just do that then.
I'll go.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Go.
Go safely. Don't trip.
Okay.
See you tomorrow.
Welcome.
I'd like to look at some
comfortable underwear.
That's a new product.
It's hot item these days.
Are you going on a honeymoon?
It just looks so interesting.
- Take your time.
- Thanks.
Oh, my.
It looks so comfy.
So stretchy...
What?
Namiseom?
Yeah. What?
This, this...
You will go far. Really far...
How can you be so smart
about things like that?
So you're going there on a date, and...
what, what... you missed
the last ferry, and...
and you find a place for the night and...
Oh, god. It makes me so hot.
You punk.
That's the only thing you can think of.
- Here's the Donburi you ordered.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
You like that, don't you?
We are normal.
We are just young blood.
Jeez.
Namiseom?
Idiots.
What the hell are you looking at?
Yeah, I am Lee Min Suk, an
eighteen-year-old high schooler.
Then can I do it just because
I say I want to do it?
So the situation is rather...
what about it?
Huh?
Hey.
People's mind and body usually...
...don't go together.
We are eighteen-year-old high schoolers.
And we have someone we
love right next to us.
Then we grab like this...
Come here. Come on.
Oh, no, no, oppa.
- You said you were going to just hold hands.
- Come on.
Are you going to live...
...like that forever?
I think so.
Forever?
Stop playing dumb.
Hey, I'm eating.
You got scared, right?
Yeah.
How can you do this to me now?
I have an unexpected appointment.
Let's drink another time.
You can't, really.
I rejected all other invitations because
you asked me to drink with you first.
I mean...
I have to go and look after
my kid if you do this to me?
So what are you saying?
Do you want me to cancel my
appointment in order to play with you?
Of course, you should.
Okay then...
You can go.
Don't drink too much.
What should I do now?
Okay, okay.
Here you go.
Tell your wife to buy what she wants.
Managing Director...
I'll be loyal.
Oh, god.
Do you think you should do this?
I really... I won't get
caught, okay, Team Leader?
Team Leader.
Culture Money $5...
That little... I will...
What am I gonna do with this?
Team Leader Kim.
Oh, yes.
Director Yoo.
Are you going home?
Yes.
Are you going home now?
I finished work a while ago, but Managing
Director Han asked me to go for a drink, so...
What am I saying...
I was about to have a drink with my friend.
But we couldn't find time,
so I was just leaving.
Oh, I see.
Then shall we go for a drink
since both of us got stood up?
Excuse me?
I don't know. I really don't.
I don't know.
I'm home.
What are you doing?
What is that?
I put a hot patch on.
I stood up all day long,
and my legs are killing me.
What did you buy?
Hey, you.
Oh...
What is it?
Bag.
You said it's only for one day.
Why did you pack your make-up?
Are you going to spend the night, unni?
What...
You little thing. How can you say that?
Yoo Ah. You think this unni...
this unni...
...taught you like that?
You're fishy.
Give me your bag. I need to check.
What? What are you checking?
Go inside and study.
When did I ever study?
Don't even think about
spending the night there.
I'll tell on you to Mom right away.
Yoo Ah.
I've had it too long.
Oh, my.
There won't be any side
effects, will there?
It's such an honor.
How...
can you, Director Yoo...
...ask me to be a drinking buddy first?
This is where the Retail Team comes often.
- I don't know if you like it, too.
- Yes.
You can talk comfortably
when we meet privately.
I am way younger than you.
Oh, my.
Oh, I feel so good. Director Yoo...
Right, Jin Woo.
You punk. You're so cute.
Wait. This hyung will give
you an allowance today.
I'll give you an allowance. Here you go.
Allowance...
You can spend it. Freely...
Right.
Seriously, the Retail Team atmosphere is
very good since you make it so comfortable.
Oh, no.
Especially Director Lee Hyung Suk...
and you seem so special.
We are not special at all. Not at all.
I really don't like him. So annoying.
- Hoobae means lowerclassman.
- He is your hoobae from high school, right?
How was he in high school?
High school?
- He was picky.
- Picky?
That punk is so annoying.
He thinks of sunbae as shit.
When he passed by, it was like cold
wind started blowing. So cold...
Lee Hyung Suk...
That punk finally stabbed
me in the back, and...
Stabbed you in the back?
Oh, no...
A long time ago...
I'm saying he did it a long time ago.
As time goes...
You know him, too. That punk...
What do you think of him?
Is he like that anymore?
Now he is so sly. So sly. He is so...
He comes to work for fun. For fun.
Now he has changed.
By the way...
Did Director Lee Hyung Suk...
happen to visit Germany...
Lee Hyung Suk...
That punk is annoying.
That jerk...
He gives me such a hard time
that I feel like dying.
What? Why? What did Director Lee do?
I mean, that bastard...
That bastard always gives me bullshit.
I do all the work for him, and
he always orders me around.
It's all because of that Lee Hyung Suk.
Taxi, taxi!
Wait.
I'm not going home.
Come on, come on.
I won't go home.
I'm not going.
I'm a free man.
Please go.
I'm a free man. How about
a second round, huh?
Jin Woo.
- It's me, hyung.
- Please take him safely.
Hey.
So many nice places...
Oh, Son.
What are you doing?
Huh? Hm...
Strategy. I'm reading strategies.
Strategies?
Strategy analysis?
Yeah, right. Strategy analysis.
Yeah.
It's high time for you to read those.
Nothing like that.
Right.
I won't say a thing.
I'm serious.
If you don't have any training tomorrow,
do you want to go grocery shopping with me?
That's a good idea. Yeah, but
I do have training tomorrow.
Oh, my. When the game is over,
he should let the kids rest for a few days.
Alright.
Don't enjoy too much. Take a rest.
It's not like that.
I really mean it.
Goodnight.
It's not.
Adieu.
I'm saying it's not.
No.
No, Father. I mean. Really. God.
Perhaps...
Jung Soo Young.
Gosh.
What is it? Was I sleeping or what?
Let's just sleep, Soo Young.
Oh, my.
I'm so tired.
Let's sleep.
Oh, god.
Oh, no.
No, no. C'mon.
Really...
No way.
Oh, gosh.
I'm late. Gosh!
King of High School
Why is she late?
Director.
What is it? What took you so long?
I'm sorry. I overslept.
Jeez...
Just like a kid going on a picnic...
You didn't sleep soundly, right?
Yeah.
Just like a kid...
Oh, my.
What?
We are late. Let's hurry.
Let's hurry.
Who came late anyway?
Let's go together.
Wow...
Yeah, Namiseom.
The weather's so nice.
What do you want to do first?
What? Do what?
Again, again. Why are you doing this?
Huh? You skipped your
breakfast or something?
You want to stroll a little or...
...eat something?
I don't feel like eating yet.
Okay, then let's go.
Namiseom.
Hey, ahjussi, we want two bicycles.
Can I have your ID please?
You need an ID for a bicycle?
Oh.
Oh, I left my ID at home.
We can use yours. You can give him yours.
I don't carry it either.
I don't have it with me. What should we do?
What are you saying? I saw...
No, no.
I saw it for sure.
That's just a card.
There it is.
Your ID card.
I look exactly the same.
It's true.
So cute.
Baby fat...
So chubby that I feel like biting...
Please.
So cute. What am I gonna do?
It must be quite a long time ago.
Long time ago.
It must be. With chubby
cheeks and all that.
Thank you.
One, two, three.
Why?
Huh?
It's really nice. It's so nice coming here
with you and walking with you holding hands.
So romantic.
Wow, look at all those trees.
Wow.
That...
That must be a pension.
They all look the same and gather
together like that. So cute.
How can they be so cute?
Oh...
Pension?
Yeah, pension. Look over there.
Why did he start talking about
pensions all of a sudden?
Now that it's almost time to go...
is he working it?
With all the people here...
I need to take a picture of
this. Of course, I should.
It's gone.
What?
- My cell phone.
- Oh, no.
Gosh.
Your cell phone?
Look for it carefully.
I...
until a moment ago...
...remember holding it
with this hand. Wait.
There's no way I put it in the bag.
It's not here.
Where is it?
Oh, restaurant...
I must have left it at the restaurant.
Res... restaurant?
Yeah.
Oh, jeez.
He knew what time the last bus came, and he was
saying he lost his wallet and trying to kill time.
I found out later...
he was planning to miss
the last bus after all.
Oh, everything fits perfectly.
Is he putting up a show?
I was holding it the whole time.
It's absurd.
I was looking for it all over
the place, but I can't find it.
You don't have it?
This can't be happening. I was really...
I remember holding it in my hand
before I entered the restaurant.
Then...
why don't I...
...give you a call?
Oh, go ahead.
Can you try to look for it one more time?
- Sure.
- I'm sorry.
This is so strange.
I was holding it and going inside...
I don't remember leaving here,
but when I entered here...
Oh, right. Someone called and I got it.
Director.
Can you hear the vibrating sound from here?
I don't.
I do.
I hear it.
I can't hear it.
I just heard it. Just now.
- You heard it?
- Look in there.
It can't be.
I searched it already.
I don't see it.
It was here. Because of the tissues...
I couldn't hear it well
because it was covered.
What is it? What's up
with this awkward acting?
It's true.
He is playing a trick to kill
time and miss the train.
I found it. I got it here. Thank you.
Let's go. We ran so hard for nothing.
What should I do?
What if he makes up other
excuses and tries to kill time?
Should I just let it pass this time again?
What should I do?
It's almost time for the
ferry. I'm so bummed.
Is it just me?
So what?
What are you trying to say? Are you
saying we should spend the night here?
Right.
Let's take a picture to prove we were here.
Come on up here.
Let's take a picture.
Okay.
Take it with my phone and
I'll send it to you later.
Right.
Okay.
Come on. Take it now.
One, two, three.
What?
He looks just like Assistant Manager Park.
Oh, Park Heung Bae.
Assistant Manager Park.
Huh?
- That's Assistant Manager Park.
- What are you talking about?
Should I do that, too?
Sure, sure.
What, what? You want me to
buy mixed bean paste, and...
Oh, jeez.
Okay, got it. Sure...
Oh, god.
Why do all the mosquitoes
in Namiseom bite me?
Oh, boy... It feels so
good to be back home.
He's gone.
He's really gone. It's fine.
Wow, no way. Don't grab me. It's hot.
Nonsense.
Assistant Manager Park said he'd
visit his mom, and here is where...
Wow...
His mom lives here?
Oh, my. What a small world. This is
why you should be nice all the time.
Wow, crazy. Wait, it's hot.
I am so taken aback.
Wow!
Where are you going? Wait
for me. I'm in shock.
Wow!
It doesn't make any sense. So shocking.
How can we meet at a place like
this? It's beyond my imagination.
We don't have enough time.
We only have short time.
We don't have enough time. We should hurry.
Let's go quickly.
Why?
Why do we need to hurry again?
- We need to go. We are late.
- Why?
We are late. Please come with me.
Come on, come on.
Whew...
So scared.
I was so scared of missing the ferry.
It's so fortunate.
By the way... there in Namiseom...
If he doesn't touch me when
we're at a place like that,
it means he's not sexually attracted to me.
I will get so pissed off.
It's so amazing.
This...
If you just come back without anything happening,
then you are not a woman, and he is not a man.
Don't you think so?
It's nonsense.
Oh, jeez...
I ran so much, I'm hungry again.
Good. I brought this with me.
Would you like some?
Secretary Jung, want some?
You don't want any?
You go ahead.
Do you want some water then?
You don't feel like it either.
Oh, so tired.
What is it? What again?
You should tell me so that I'd
know. What are you mad about?
I'm not mad.
Please tell me. Come on.
I won't let this go until you tell me.
Please let go.
I need to go to the restroom.
You need to tell me what made you mad.
Then I can apologize or do something.
So frustrating...
Black bean noodles.
- Please enjoy.
- Thank you.
I think you'll go bankrupt pretty soon.
What did that jerk say?
I don't know.
Wang San's black bean noodles are the best.
I think he said something bad.
I don't care.
Hey, I wish...
yours is as good as this, so that
we don't have to order like this.
That's what I'm saying.
Huh?
Hey.
Who in the world is this?
Isn't this Director Lee Hyung Suk
who went on a date with a "woman"?
Hey, Duk Hwan. It's an SOS.
I'm not joking. I'm dead serious.
What, what? Did something happen?
No, I mean, we had a good time
so far. But the popcorn sister...
...got so pissed off all of a
sudden. What's up with this?
What should I do? I don't
know what to do first.
Hey, I'm all ears. Describe
what's been happening so far.
Since when was she like that?
Ah...
Oh, that... It was that.
What? You don't even know how women
think. You ignorant director punk.
Hey, okay.
Okay, I'll take care of it. Hang up, punk.
Oh, sorry. I'm so sorry.
I...
should have known women are
sensitive to that kind of thing.
What?
I mean...
when we took a picture in Namiseom...
I pulled myself back and that
makes your face look this big.
- What?
- I'm so sorry.
What are you talking about?
- Director.
- Huh?
- I'll go.
- Isn't this it?
That's not it?
I'll go.
You should tell me.
Please let go of me.
Jeez, what a temper you have.
Oh, no. Please.
What is it?
What is it? Why is it full
of underwear and toiletries?
Oh, no.
No, no.
What the...
It's a scarf.
Is this a scarf, too?
I was about to layer my clothing.
This. This is an arm warmer.
Arm warmers are all closed.
Why do you mean, "Ah"?
It's not what you think. I didn't
bring all this for tonight.
I mean...
Perhaps...
No one knows what will happen.
Tomorrow..
Something can happen to us.
So I was just ready.
You are right.
I came prepared.
People said...
when you go to a place like this,
men and women are thinking
about the same thing.
Otherwise, you are not even a man.
They said he is not looking
at you as a woman.
What am I to you?
Am I a woman to you, Director?
Am I a man?
Or am I a hermaphrodite or something?
Am I not attractive as a woman?
Why do you like me?
Why are you dating me?
Never mind.
What am I saying?
Jeez.
Really...
Oh god, please slow down.
Why do you walk so fast?
What?
This is so unfair.
This feels so unfair if
you think of me like that.
I also...
couldn't sleep last night because I was
so excited about being with you all day.
You really don't know...
...I like you, Jung Soo Young?
I like women for sure, not men.
What are you talking about?
Eh?
You will fall down.
Do you even know how much I held back?
I was next to you all day, and
my heart was pounding like crazy.
I had a hard time holding
it back. Shouldn't I have?
Shouldn't I have?
Then I won't from now. Like this.
Gosh.
Like this...
Look at you...
You are so unpredictable, Jung Soo Young.
Come here.
No?
One, two, three.
Oh, my.
Jeez.
You know how much I like you.
Don't ever doubt that, okay?
I'm crazy about you, Jung Soo Young.
So crazy, okay?
It's hot.
Jeez...
Let's stay like this for awhile.
I'm hot.
Really?
Are you really hot?
I'm hot.
Seriously?
If you are hot, let's go.
Where?
Director.
Where are we going?
Wow.
Director.
How did you think of this place?
You said you were hot.
It's not hot here.
Let's go in.
I'm really good, right?
So good.
How do you skate so well?
- Director.
- Huh?
What are you bad at?
That's right. I should be a
professional or something.
What about hockey?
- Hockey?
- Right.
Hockey players are so cool.
Cool? I don't like it.
Okay, then speed-skating?
What about figure skating?
Figure?
Figure.
I'll teach you. Come on.
Isn't it too hard?
Rhythm is important here. One...
One...
Two...
Gosh...
It's not that hard.
Oh, my.
Take my hand.
One...
Two...
It's so cold.
I'm so cold.
So cold, so cold.
Drink this.
Where did you get this?
This?
It was lying on the corner.
Someone must have thrown it away.
It's warm.
I brought it since it didn't stink.
You are a little...
...good at handling things.
Jung Soo Young, you are a little...
...tiring.
I need to take care of everything
for you. A little tiring.
Full of protective instincts.
So charming...
Full of chores for me.
Anyways...
From what I see...
you can skate quite well.
Huh?
I mean...
Wait. Secretary Jung that I know of is...
a person without a trace
of any athletic abilities.
You must have played on the ice.
In fact...
my father taught me a
little when I was a kid.
You know, around the place
where I used to live...
there was a frozen pond every winter.
So...
But...
when did your father...
...pass away?
He died of a traffic accident
when I was in high school.
It must've been so hard for you.
Then...
you've been living with your sister
ever since? How long has it been?
We came to Seoul together
when I was twenty.
It's been about eight years now.
Now that I think about it...
you said you have a hyungnim. Right?
Yeah.
I have one jerk hyung.
How is he? Is he like you?
Well, some say we are alike...
I think we are similar, too.
But then we have completely different
personalities. Completely different.
Your hyungnim must have such
a nice personality then.
Huh?
Just kidding.
I really want to meet him
someday. I'm curious.
Right, I want to see him, too.
You want to see him?
Your hyungnim?
I mean, I want to show him.
Oh...
Right. Show him...
Gosh.
I always mishear.
You, Jung Soo Young... Really...
Your ears must be full of wax.
Gosh.
Director.
Jeez.
By the way...
I really...
don't know anything about my girlfriend.
How were you when you were little?
Were you unique like this?
No, I wasn't.
Nothing unique about me.
Then were you cute and pretty like this?
You got that right.
You know that kind of kid...
who doesn't make any
trouble or stands out...
but then doesn't study at all...
That's me.
I used to daydream during
classes and imagine things.
I know those type of kids.
What were you like as a student, Director?
- Me?
- Yes.
I think you were cute.
Gosh. So scared.
Director.
Oh, my.
Oh, my. You might catch a cold.
We should...
go for something hot so that
we won't catch a cold. Hello.
Something hot, okay?
Oh, no.
I need to go home right now.
My sister will be so mad at me.
Why hurry? Going now or going in thirty minutes
won't make any difference. Let's just go.
You are here on Sunday.
I have some business to take care of.
I can't.
I really need to go.
My sister is waiting for
me to come home, so...
Look what happened.
You won't catch a cold if you eat this.
You really mind your sister a lot.
Is your sister hot-tempered or something?
No, not that.
Even though she is a
little younger than me,
she is more like unni than me.
Thank you.
Oh, it looks so good.
I can smell it.
I don't need salted shrimp.
You don't eat salted shrimp?
You, too?
Yeah.
I can't. I must be allergic
to it or something...
It gets itchy all over, right?
Yeah, it's really itchy.
Your lips get swollen.
Yeah, swollen.
We are the same. Speechless.
Speechless.
I'm not kidding. It's so serious.
High-five!
We are the same, the same.
Strategy analysis...
What is it?
Is he into hockey or something?
I'll take some of yours.
No, you can't.
How can he not have anything here?
Did he delete all his data already?
Hyung...
Oh, my. If you get this serious,
then I'll seriously take yours.
Come on.
From Lee Hyung Suk
- Am I too late? It's hyung.
I just will.
What?
You can go back to the office, Soo Young.
A secretary doesn't need
to join in this meeting.
Do you know how cheesy it is the way
you behave toward Secretary Jung?
She may be a special woman to you, but...
she's just a secretary to me.
I love someone.
Don't bother me.
Take this.
Why do you keep appearing before me?
Don't go. Stay with me.