Subtitles by DramaFever
- Should I order another bottle?
- No, this is enough.
Episode 8
I'll call you.
We have a room ready for you.
You can go with her.
No, that's okay.
- What are you doing?
- What?
Give me the key and go back.
I thought you wanted me to become
Lee Jin Sook's protege.
This is the first task Jin Sook gave me.
Stop it.
- Stop what?
- What you're doing now.
What are you talking about?
Ji Hyung Min.
I decide and act for myself.
Where is Soo now?
I know Hye Soo, the woman Soo loved,
was one of your girls.
It was you who put
Hye Soo with Soo.
And it was also you who told
Safari Soo's weakness.
Please, let's stop it right here.
So you knew that...
that bastard tried to kill me?
So you knew.
Were you the one who threatened
the prison warden?
Did you pressure him to erase
everything? Did you?
And that's why you told me
to leave the business.
It'll never happen again.
I promise. Soo promised, too.
Are you... praising that
bastard in front of me now?
Are you praising him that
he keeps his promises?
You started this fight,
so you should end it!
Now that I found out, there will be
no more war between you two!
You know what?
Soo was found out by Ji Hyung Min.
If you leave Soo like that,
it'll become dangerous for you.
You know that?
His name is Soo.
He's Doctor's Son's
right-hand man.
Make sure you remember him.
He tried to kill Jin Sook?
That's right.
You can leave after two hours.
That's what everyone does.
I guess you've done this many times.
The numbers on informants are from
entertainment establishments.
Am I doing okay?
Are you sleeping?
Do you want me to turn off the light?
What are you doing?
I'm going to be working for
Jin Sook from now on.
I don't want one of them
to be my first.
They'll like it that way even more.
If it's your first time.
Report to Lee Jin Sook
about an hour later.
Tell her I passed out right away.
Did you treat him well
before you sent him away?
Yes.
How?
Excuse me?
I don't think he's an
easy one to deal with.
Did you sleep with him?
No, not yet.
Good job. You got him
up to the room anyway.
And a man like Ji Hyung Min won't
change just because you slept with him once.
That man. He's police, right?
So?
I just wondering what I should do.
Let's see how it goes.
We don't know how things will turn out.
And it won't hurt to know police.
You can use that room from now on.
We need to see each
other often. Don't we?
And...
You can buy things
you need with this.
Soo Min.
Yoon Soo Min!
Clean your room, okay?
Am I your helper?
Am I your maid?
Why do I need to clean?
Do you know what time it is?
Why are you coming back so late?
I don't know. I'm coming back
from my part-time job.
This is your part-time job?
This? Huh?
I don't know!
Yoon Soon Min, you!
Hey, open up.
Open up!
Soo Min, are you hungry?
You're sleeping again!
Why aren't you studying?
Aren't you going to go to college?
I'm not going to college.
Why aren't you going to college?
What are you going to do then?
This is your sister's specialty.
Kimchi fried rice. Hope you enjoy it. Love you.
Goodbye, Gyung Mi.
It's me, Jin Sook.
I just moved in.
Okay, don't come by to my office.
And please don't ask why.
Okay?
Yeah, I'll see you tomorrow.
You can begin now.
I told you not to call
the guys into the office.
Who are you guys?
Who put you up to this?
Who was it?
Was it Lee Jin Sook?
Doc!
I just heard from Gyung Ho.
Apparently, Jin Sook has hit Soo.
Are you really going to continue this?
That depends on how you do.
Soo!
Let's just end it here.
I was... I was!
I was wrong, Auntie.
You should do better in the future.
I gave in because of you.
Thank you.
This is the end, right?
Okay.
- Should we go have a drink?
- Let's have some rice wine.
Sit down.
I guess you don't have much
stamina nowadays.
You wasted all the goods I gave you
and on top of that...
You sent Commissioner Kang
to the heaven. What a waste.
Doctor's Son is still living
happily ever after.
This is Safari Moon's report card.
What do you think?
How is it?
All your past memories are
flashing through your mind now. Aren't they?
Then you must know now.
Whether you've lived a good life
or lived a life with many regrets.
You have regrets. Don't you?
Considering our relationship so far...
I'll give you another chance.
It's been a long time,
Mr. Safari.
I heard it's a little noisy up there.
Mr. Safari, are you old now?
Why are you like this?
Why are you dragging this on and on?
Whether it's Doctor's Son
or Professor's Son.
Do you want me to
give a special lecture?
Dad, do you want me go up?
Please be patient.
Man, that's not it.
I still think I need to go up to
Seoul and have a clean sweep.
Excuse me. It's 15 days.
Don't forget what went through
your mind during those 15 days.
You understand?
15 days.
What? Did something happen?
No, it's nothing.
- Pil Joon.
- Yes.
Change all these guys.
Get out. I can't
stand the sight you.
Good. I had something
to talk to you about.
I wonder what you want to talk about?
You, did you use me?
Did you use me to get
Doctor's Son?
What the heck are you talking about?
Why would I use you?
Don't try to bullshit me.
I know everything.
I know it was you who
pushed Nang Mahn.
Nang Mahn?
You mean the one who was used
was Nang Mahn?
Don't strain yourself.
That kind of acting won't work here.
Would you believe me if
I get Nang Mahn in front of you?
If that'd make you believe me,
I'll get Nang Mahn right now.
Then, would you believe
my true intentions?
Hello.
Soo! Soo!
Help me!
Where are you?
Okay. I'll be right there.
- What is it?
- It's uncle Nang Mahn.
- He's asking me to save him.
- What?
Why on earth are you doing this to me?
What did I do wrong?
You did many things wrong.
It's tiring to go
back and forth, isn't it?
Who did you talk to just now?
Even if they kill him,
I think I need to go.
No, call him again.
It might be too late already.
Call him Soo.
Uncle Nang Mahn?
Is it Soo? You are one step too late.
It's your turn after Nang Mahn.
So until then, be well.
You understand?
Okay, come and get me.
Really, come and get me!
Where are you, bastard?
Come now!
Soo.
It was Safari.
Long time no see, big sister.
Did you come after you've
been working in the field?
You don't look that great at all.
Thanks for coming.
Where is Nang Mahn?
Why did you do this?
Did I ask you to bring him dead?
This old man was so feisty
that there was no other way.
So with this, you are not
going to doubt my intentions.
You want to have a
village party in a room?
I won't get any respect with that.
I heard even Confucius started
with a few characters.
Any beginning tends to be insufficient.
Then, what about the end?
Are you going to hook me up
with Pusan or something?
That all depends on how well you do.
I don't trust you, yet.
'To bloom a single chrysanthemum,
the cuckoo must have cried since the spring.'
Do you remember that poem?
Poem my ass.
I forgot all those things.
It still feels like yesterday
when I used have
stir-fried Soondae and
a shot of Soju with you.
The Doc has gone over the line.
You know what it means when
Chairman Jo mentions his name?
It's over for Doc.
I'm not going to let that happen.
You understand?
Do you want to save Doc?
If you to save your Doc,
then stop him now.
Soo? I'll take care of that bastard.
You just have to tell me where he is.
The only way both
you and Doc can survive is
for you to put your organization
behind and have power.
I'm going to say this one last time.
Please don't make me
pathetic like this, huh?
Do you know what I mean?
I'm not going to wait long.
The deal comes first.
I still don't trust you.
And yet, you want Soo's
whereabouts?
- I can't do that.
- So you want to make the deal first.
Isn't that according to
the proper business ethics?
I'll think over your proposal about Soo
after our transaction.
Are you really going to do
business with that woman?
This is the real deal this time.
You understand?
Why are you doing it
real all of a sudden?
The Doc and the rest of
his entourage.
Don't you need to clear them out?
Look at this.
Are the rumors true? Are you and her
pillow talking late at night?
Is that right?
You better think before
you open your mouth.
Safari killed Nang Mahn.
I wonder why he did that?
Do you think Nang Mahn looked
around again after he went over?
He could have.
Ah, man... I can't figure this out.
- So you must have a plan.
- What?
- A plan to get rid of Safari.
- Are you getting scared?
Scared? Who's scared?
I'm going to get Safari.
Meth Kim probably knows.
- What?
- Where Safari is.
Isn't the prosecutor's office
holding him now?
What's this?
You scared me.
Have you gone somewhere?
Yeah, I went shopping.
But you didn't buy anything.
There were no items.
Uncle Nang Mahn is dead.
It's Safari's doing.
I wonder why he did that.
I think you know the reason.
How would I know that?
I'll give you a hypothetical example.
In order for Safari to regain your trust...
He killed Nang Mahn to show you
he had nothing to do with the set-up.
I'm sure Safari must have called you.
He would have asked you to trust him.
And he would have wanted a deal.
When is the deal going to happen?
Yes, you're right.
But...
We have to do this deal.
That's the only way we can survive.
This deal is to keep you alive.
This deal is for you.
That's not for me, but
for your greed!
This is a plead as well as a warning.
Do not do this deal.
Chairman Jo from Pusan knows your name.
You know what that means.
I'm not going you let you die.
This time... we need
to do this deal.
Do you remember that
picture from long ago?
Was it Apel Tower?
You looked at the postcard picture often.
There were two cool foreign
models kissing in front of the Tower.
You told me then.
You wanted to make
a lot of money later.
And you wanted to pose in front of
the Tower just like those models.
You told me that was your wish.
You can do that now.
It's different now so,
you can go any time.
Then what about you?
If I go, will you come with me?
If you go, I can go, too.
Anytime.
Jin Sook.
I just want you to be happy.
I'm trying.
You have a phone call.
Who's calling?
It's me.
Is it you, Doc?
Let Jin Sook go.
Please.
Who's letting go of who?
You've spent enough time in this
business to know what you should know.
And yet, you still say
such naive things.
Well, let's just say you are still naive.
Then if I told you to leave this
business, would you leave?
Once you leave, what
are you going to do?
Are you going to get
a job at a company?
If not, would you
run a restaurant? Huh?
You, me and also Jin Sook
will never be able to leave forever.
You know...
There is an way into this
business, but there is no way out.
You can do the deal with me.
Without Jin Sook,
you should do it with me.
That's not a deal.
That's war.
Sounds like you still haven't
figured out the situation.
I'll tell you this one last thing.
You have to die.
That's when this will be over.
Then I'll see you soon.
Excuse me.
President Jung?
Did he want to see me here?
Long time no see.
That's right, President Jung.
I'll get to the point.
Where is Meth Kim now?
- You know, that's...
- I told you already.
What kind of friend I could be
all depends on what you do.
Are you Doctor's Son?
Turn around.
Turn around!
Who was it?
Who brought you here?
- Who was it?
- Doctor.
Doctor's Son.
Please find out where
Meth Kim is now.
What are you going
to do with Meth Kim?
Meth Kim knew who Doctor's Son was.
Okay. The prosecutors are shielding
him so it might be difficult but...
I'll give it a shot.
- But don't get your hopes up.
- Yes.
[Prosecutor Oh Jung Yeon]
Yeah, so what happened?
It was difficult.
I want you to know that.
Did you find out?
Yeah, I found out.
But Meth Kim is at a hospital now.
Okay, thanks.
You wait for us here.
Let's go.
Stop acting and let's go.
Aren't you going to get on?
Who was it?
Who did this?
I don't know.
They came in out of the blue.
It's me President Jung.
Yes, go ahead.
Meth Kim has disappeared.
Someone beat the crap out of
our guys and picked him up.
Did President Jung pick him up?
Someone took Meth Kim.
How did you find out
where Meth Kim was?
The important thing is
who took him.
It was probably Doctor's Son.
What's going on?
You dramatically rescued me and all.
I didn't get you out to chit-chat.
So shut up and sit tight.
Long time no see.
How did you get out this time?
Actually, I wanted to see you soon.
I told you it'd be your turn next.
Doc... Doc!
What's the matter?
You've been calling often.
Where is Soo now?
I'm taking good care of him here.
If you want to rescue your friend,
you know what to do.
Come on over here.
Come alone... quietly.
If not, your friend will be dead.
Don't touch Soo.
That's up to you.
Do you understand what I mean?
He's one of the ones you
are supposed to catch.
Soo... was found out by Ji Hyung Min.
Yeah, it's me.
Is everything okay?
Meth Kim disappeared
from the hospital.
Was it you?
No.
Then, do you
know who did it?
No.
Why do you sound like that?
There's something wrong. Am I right?
Shi Yun.
Mister... help me.
If it's something like that,
I can't help you.
I can get Safari today.
If something goes wrong,
you could get discovered.
I have to go.
Don't go. You need to give up
on Kim Hyun Soo.
I have to go!
You could put yourself
in danger because of Soo.
I will go.
Honestly...
This is too difficult.
Shi Hyun.
Please take care of Jin Sook.
Shi Hyun!
Jung Shi Hyun!
- Get out. I'm going alone.
- Doc.
I'm going alone.
Doctor's Son!
Let Soo go first.
In this situation you are
worried about your friend.
Coming here alone
meant you came ready to die.
I'm not sure whether
you'd believe me but
considering our friendship of the past,
I wasn't going to kill you.
It's all because of you that someone
as naive as me turned this way.
Let go of Soo and we'll talk.
Are you deaf? Once you step in here,
you can't go out.
Nobody can. You got that?
I understand.
- Come on now.
- Hit him.
Wow, then, are you Doctor's Son?
Doctor's Son.
You are truly alone now.
The only thing you can
trust is this and this.
Doctor's Son. Let's settle the scores today.
Whether you are or I am the hubby.
Doctor's Son.
Shi Hyun.
Doctor's Son, Jung Shi Hyun.
I'm going to ask you
for one last favor.
Would you like to go to China?
I'll find out about ferries.
Uncle Duk Bae.
Didn't you say one of us has to die?
That's right. I was talking nonsense.
I'm sorry.
Let me ask you a favor.
Him...
Let Soo go.
I'm sorry.
But I promise I'll protect Jin Sook.
Shi Hyun.
I'll ask you one last time.
Don't resist. It'll be more painful.
Got it?
Okay, let's stop getting sentimental
and finish it quickly.
Okay.
Thanks for understanding.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Sit here and wait for me.
I'll bring it right away.
If you have a lover, you can
meet when you feel down.
And it will make you feel better.
I just thought that it'd be like that.
What is he like?
My lover is a little busy.
You're not seeing anyone?
He doesn't even
think of me as a woman.
The true nature of Pusan has never
been revealed. They are like phantoms.
I believe Pusan's organization
definitely exists.
This one thing is for sure.
If you try to dig deeper,
a lot of your friends will die. It could be you next.
There won't be any deals for a while.
What are you talking about?
Connect me directly to Pusan.
Do you know what kind of place Pusan is?