Translate by
RavanPM
HAPPY WATCHING
Your wish will not come true .
From now on, you are me!
Ah... surprise me alone ..
Why do you say things that do not make sense?
There is nothing like it.
That's right. This is so well known to students of other schools came to the school.
What? although I was ghosts, scary remains scary
's always talk that does not make sense!
I better go tomorrow and pray a desire...
So I do not need to listen to the mouth again.
Wow. it would have been terrible.
If there are the same person's face with you.
You do this ..!
Everything you prepare lessons for school tomorrow
And return quickly. so it does not interfere with our work.
Ajussi, I may to school too right?
And matter what else would you do there?
No problem! I will not go!
Ah .. looks like the fragrance all the girls different schools.
I do not smell anything.
Ouch ..
stupid you
Do not you sense the energy?
It's like the phone and you feel like you're in charge.
They say the cost of going to school is about 5 million won.
And if you add the cost for special classes and dormitories
This all totals 16 million won.
What? 16 million won?
This is not a university, right?
Wait a minute.
What are they doing there?
Let them .. they were all like that at the age emang
Weve, I know, so how could I
silence.
Police  Ha.
Ah .. cop Ha!
Relax with them.
Let's go.
You know the rumors?
That said there are ghosts wandering around the school?
Look at me! You're crazy ..
I told you I would kill you kept saying ika absurd.
Enough! What are you doing?
What care you?
Why are you doing this?
You? You are spreading rumors that!
Think you are smart enough to protect you and your parents ..
Hey, hey. someone came.
What are you doing?
Why are you so changed?
What? After that night, between us is over ..
You do not know?
You okay?
They beat you, right?
Unnie is a police officer, can you tell me ..
Relax .
No nothing. We were just chatting.
Well if any of the front catch criminals.
Grab arm can you take with ..
Ajussi that plasticity is not as criminals.
Hey, it becomes a little...
Guru, we have to see this true?
What are you saying?
Detectives are trying to teach ..
I'm sorry.
What is this?
Hello. This DJ Hakll your school, Kang JaHee.
Today the weather was a bit overcast but this time it seems ..
This is really Kang JaHee!
He died, how can we hear his voice?
And this is a song that is requested by Kang Nayi.
Hey, hey, hey, calm quiet.
Teacher, something has happened.
Ow ..
What is this .. What happened?
He was student here. He had fallen dai stairs.
Why not call 119 ? I wish you the phone!
Yes, I understand.
Quick fast!
Do you hear that? it sounds JaHee.
Everyone says they also hear music at night last week ..
not that the songs are often played JaHee at lunch.
So JaHee, who did this ..?
Radio room was not locked after the incident?
Hey, it's a ghost!
Ghosts what?
Let's all get in kemobil fast.
Fortunately, the other just a little galling,
keliatannya nothing severe.
How do you care for school children?
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry, ma'am.
If you did not catch the person who did this to SeulGi.
You'll face the consequences.
Yes, do not worry.
Whatever happens I will be responsible.
Can you tell me what happened?
I get SMS invite met.
From JaHee.
SMS?
What are you talking about? of JaHee?
JaHee.? Who JaHee?
A friend ..
The month ago .. died falling down the stairs.
I want to tell you something.
Coming now to the staircase made of stone.
I went to the stairs in my spare time.
But after that, I can not remember anything.
Silence!
Who's driving that stupid and cruel?
What are you've heard all you need?
Why are you sitting here so glum?
Do not worry.
What? you pout because I'm not taking you to school?
What? I do not sit here and pout.
Detective. Ha.
How the students?
Fortunately, no injuries were severe.
But there is something odd in retrospect of the incident.
What?
A month ago there was a similar incident.
And student named Kang JaHee died.
So?
Incident that happened when we came in which a student was injured.
If we do not do anything,
opportunity for other attacks ..
Police Ha!
Do not live so boring.
I'll do it. You do not have to intervene.
Ja Kang Hee? Why did he suddenly asked?
I want to know the relationship of events yesterday
incident has been classified as an accident.
's Student SAT test was on the horizon.
So I want you to not make them anxious.
I have to go because there is work that I can not snooze.
I do not want to talk about a painful death.
But the students had a lot of problems.
Problem?
Yes. At the beginning of the school year is very good value and he is an example of exemplary
good for other students.
But slowly he ibergabung with other kids weird
and started to become chaotic.
Hyun Ji. Let me merekammu,
Do not. go there.
Friends. I can record you for a minute?
Many times he asked students to interview
laindan moral harassing them all.
Cheers!
Ah .. this spill
Children's. what did you do in school?
Out!
He persuaded a naive girl to drink with him
in class and often unnoticed by me.
Is there violence or peloncoan between pupils?
There is nothing like it. we set mutid students.
So that could be a good school  here
What cop Ha go to school again?
What happened to the chairman to go look for it?
Only worry to your partner alone.
There are many cases to be resolved.
And he was busy doing something useless.
Wait, I heard Detective Ha exposed some cases
When he was in high school and investigated by the police.
It why?
Where the reseh it go?
I'm a cop. calm.
Ajussi. My friend is in danger.
For me .. what should I do?
Search friend .. please!
Do not worry
Ahjussi. The school children who died. what happened?
Do not talk to me.
I'm just curious why he died at a very young age.
Wondered who hate it.
We still do not know.
I ask you to take me
I really want to go
Anyway ..
why do you want to go to school?
Maybe if I go to school, I'll remember.
When I watch TV how a student commit suicide
I really want to talk with them.
I mean I'm not the type pembully or so.
Probably a bad lesson,
I have no problem in learning with my brilliant pikirian.
Stop!
I wonder why I'm dead? What happened to me?
I said stop it!
Do you want me to worry about you anymore?
Who asked you worried about? I just...
I do not want to bother you, just ignore me. understand?
Do not sympathetic.
Police returned.
I think there is something going on
Did I tell you? JaaHee that someone pushed him to death ..
So JaHee become a ghost and want revenge.
Hey.
It does not make sense
boy, let me ask you something.
You know JaHee close to anyone?
Huh? JaHee?
SeulGi, MiHee, and HyunJae. They are always together.
True. they told me they made a movie
documentation and always talk together.
After JaaHee died, they act like
no nothing.
True, but they are the type that do not fit together
What do you mean?
Kang and Lee Hyun Jae Jahee sign up here for a scholarship social programs.
This school is like that.
We often never eat with them
Can you tell me what happened between them?
I do not know for sure . but I heard the reason they split because of her mother MiHee
Just ask him.
JaHee The day of the dead,
do you know what happened?
I do not know. I'm not feeling well.
So I came home early.
I know.
I hear you're close to them. So what happened yesterday?
There is something badly of you?
Other kids say you record something.
Initially, we made a documentary together.
We want to make something before graduation.
Yes, What is the dream of Hong Jang Hyun?
I want to be a psychology advisor.
I want to help the pain in my abilities.
Cut ~
Good!
I'm really good to be a reporter.
're Still stutter.
What is this?
That's good, that's good.
is in store we can get 1 winner at film festivals.
Course.
We're really pleased.
It was the first time I could feel so good
with anyone from this school.
Before that happens ..
Stop it!
I do not understand.
We are not doing anything wrong,
but suddenly he stopped us.
After that day, parents and SeulGi MiHee come.
To school and become a big problem.
Saying we create something strange and disturbing our lesson.
Omma, what are you doing?
And where do you think you're acting like you did?
You make our children go to school with the children of poor and ..
orphan like this and things like this happen.
Finally JaHee blamed for everything
And this group dissolved.
Then why you all away from each other?
No. .. Not like that.
Ginger says he's fine.
Because that JaHee.
Always concerned with others than himself.
Like a fool.
I have to go. I have to go to class.
It.
Notes JaHee Kang calls and SMS in the accident.
But why all the sudden.
What do you think?
After the lesson, meet me on the stairs with a stone floor.
That means someone could have been there with him.
-Founder of assistant-
I need to talk to you, meet me on the stairs with a stone floor.
Assistant head.
Hello, this is your DJ, Kang JaHee.
30 October, too late at night studying hard untu is right.
What is this?
30 October, too late at night to study hard is not it.
30 October, too late at night studying hard untu is right.
Let me plays music that will make you comfortable.
Who is playing this play?
Let me play the music that will make you comfortable.
Assistant head.
Yes. The investigators krimilnsl.
What?
Again?
Yes, I understand.
What is it?
From SMA female Hakll.
There are other accidents.
This time, head teachers were injured.
What did I say? I say it was a real ghost story!
Calm down .. and do you still
speed-yourself detective?
I do not know what the ghost is doing.
Do not talk like that.
Ghosts might not like him because he's useless.
Everything, be unattractive.
This should be reported to the department of children ..
-Chairman, I do not feel this was a simple accident.
Then what is this?
Did you say this act of real ghost or what?
A month ago, a student named Kang ginger
He was moved by the school but before he fell off a ladder and died.
But I think he does not stumble but ..
More precisely pushed and killed.
Do you have proof?
Do you have any evidence that the student killed?
-It-chairman ..
That day, of course she's with somebody
Chances are no witnesses,
but the school does not want to talk about it.
Plasticity is quite clear to me.
What say the child was hiding something?
So, what will you do next?
We need to find people who play as a ghost.
I think someone who knows what happened that night,
start this rumor was the work of a ghost and play that role.
Do you feel something is not it?
Justify?
Why do not you trust your own feelings alone.
Okay, you two soon settle this case
You too! Went to school with them tomorrow
and investigate around.
You said no nothing and should be reported to the department of child
.
Shut up!
I also parents with children age was
Or if you're not comfortable with this.
You can resolve such cases Cheo Yong Yun did.
Aihh .. not that it.
True true ..
I tell him to find a report of a female student
Immun-Dong 3 years ago
Where detective Yu Go?
Incidence of female students who disappeared?
Maybe ..
Bingo!
I believe that my case died here.
What are you looking for? let's go
You go ahead.
I have some interesting
What is it?
This document lists all new students
Hakll school girls from yesterday until this year.
If you look at it. This all new students who registered from social scholarship.
Ah I know. so why would they leave a great school
like this and choose to move?
So what's wrong with that?
Although Kang JaHee this dead under the auspices ..
social scholarship program and he's moved?
All pupils  still a little vague on the subject vague
There is something there.
There's a secret in school.
What do you mean people who play the role of a ghost could be Joan of arc?
Okay ..
I hate him. always so, really do not like it.
Pupils terbary pliers and moved his name JungHyunJoo
He went to high school MoonYoung for women.
Unnie, I have a request.
I thought maybe if I were looking for a ~
report, maybe I'll remember something.
Do you know?
Hot!
What the hell.
Not this.
Not that this, too.
Ha Sun Woo.
Chairman.
What are you Lukan here?
Do not you go to high school girls MoonYoung
to meet transfer student.
Maybe I need this document ~
Maybe bisarelevan.
Sun Woo  yes.
We open an investigation because you're so agile.
Let's move fast!
Yes!
MoonYoung But where high school girls?
Gangnam?
Gangsuk?
Gumbuk?
It Yi thud.
CASE unresolved
Are you looking for me?
You are reporting this yesterday right?
Yes.
I hear the music anymore so I came and
I heard no screams so I came here.
And the principal existing floor.
But why did you do it?
Because I need to make sure something, thank you.
Strange .. This place keliatannya familiar place.
Even plasticity familiar school building.
Still keliatannya school hours.
Hallo. what you are Ha Sun Woo?
Huh?
Oh Ha Sunwoo. \ I Oh Min Jung.
It certainly school
Nice to meet you!
I would not have thought it was you.
What are you doing?
Very pleased to meet you.
What is news?
So what are you doing?
I'm here to work. To meet a student.
Ah, you had to call the police.
I heard the story.
I am a teacher here.
That's good.
Are you here because NaYoung?
Na Young?
Sorry. sudden head pain.
True? let me drop off at the school office
take painkillers. Wait here.
Why now?
You're better?
You Min Jung, right?
Why is this? now you're scary!
You do not need this?
I'm fine.
But .. how long am I here?
What are you talking about?
None.
How come you never  story.
I mean I hear you but I do not believe the police.
Yeah, maybe so.
I mean how can you be a cop?
You look so great now.
Yet,
Wait here, I'll call his.
NaYoung Han, Ha Sunwoo. what each of you cheating?
Read what is written!
Huh?
Do you want to zero in your test?
Sun Woo. heart mark.
Stand!
Later after tests come on partying. let's play hot and wild.
Signs heart.
Read it until it runs out!
Come buy a lot of beer that you like.
.. Students who sat!
's Attention on your test!
Yes sir!
Angle  good face, ready!
It was a friendship ring V. Let us be good.
Like this.
Smile!
Did you photograph?
I think I closed my eyes.
Wait.
This is it!
Wait a minute let me photograph so.
Sun Woo.
Why is it so hard when I moved in there?
I do not want to remember that school anymore.
All right, shut up!
Field trip this time we decided to parts of Europe and Kyung Ju
Dae tub.
Kyung Ju would like galandangan. really disgusting.
That's good. I'm afraid that there is no money,
will whine to us to ask.
This is disturbing.
Can we get rid of them?
Silence! we decided after discussion later. so as you say.
Aigoo. they act rude.
What good is a great school.
If his judgment is another.
Do not heartless.
He ​​walked away when he saw it.
That's it. Other students who can get out and bother us.
We're out. So they could with rich children.
We were never a student's school.
Just a great system that is needed.
I had a woman tell police everything.
So why do you ..
I'm here to make something.
In the JaHee dead. What do you do when you meet?
What?
I hear you all going to meet,
All deny. Kadi was possible that something happened.
You fight?
Not like that.
Tell me what happened.
If there is no incident ..
Okay, SeulGi park. What are your dreams?
Do not record, I do not wear face makeup
What are you doing here?
Only child of a wealthy family who may enter.
Pose for me.
Get rid of the camera. I do not want to be recorded,
What do you hide here?
Go to your class!
Get out of here now.
I found it. Fortunately
.
Let the record. who is going to be recorded first?
I warn you, if you hang around with the camera once again
,
I will confiscate it.
What? Teachers, you can not. The only thing we were.
Here you go!
Give it to me. fast! I've said many times if you ..
Stop it!
Why we should not record? Recording is not a bad thing!
You pathetic fool.
You can be a bad score. understand?
What's up with him?
I mean why a teacher like that?
What are they doing to us?
Simply . This stop up here.
Bagimana can you say that?
What we are going to do something?
There is nothing we can do.
We have to be quiet while.
This is annoying!
Enough! I'm dizzy with it all. Let's have a beer.
Why beer?
What is your mood? You act like nothing ever drink beer just before.
Why do not act well and wisely?
We should not eliminate stress?
CHEERS!
Ah, this is almost spilled.
This beer tastes.
Okay okay. Let's toast again.
Cheers to us all!
You guys, what are you doing in school?
Get out now!
What should we do?
What happened?
Up fast!
Hello, ma'am.
Omma, what are you doing?
And where do you guys think of doing it
Mistress, calm down.
Calm? You made my son like this
And you want me to calm down?
You make our children go to school with substandard
orphans like this. and things like this happen.
Do you know how much we pay for this school
For scholarship money?
Think wisely what you do
After that, school JaHee
rumored move to another school.
But the incident was just an excuse.
JaHee registered to the social care program
So it was not the reason he was expelled.
It?
I just wanted to finish this before before moving on.
We record it.
So we have to finish this before I go.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry JaHee,
What do you mean? I'm fine.
What, for I moved we could not see each other again?
What are you going to go?
If I move. may be quiet.
Do you want to talk?
SeulGi, look at this!
What is this?
What are you doing with my son?
What are you doing, let the people here?
I of the Criminal Investigation and I need to investigate anything.
I've answered all the question proposed school.
I think what you're doing to the sick child.
Soon completed. So please partnership.
Caiklah, tell me. Where's the tape?
I told you not to say anything that is not useful.
See, after that night, she could not sleep because of restless
Do you know how hard it is for him?
He also attacked.
If you're here because the principal incident.
Security schools have already made a statement to the investigation department.
Ah yes. The day of the accident JaHee.
They say you found her first?
119  You call yourself?
Fortunately, I passed the time there was
If there are students who see it,
they will be a great shock.
I passed through the parking lot when there is something odd
So I get there.
So I reported to the paramedics immediately.
119? there are people here ..
There is a suspicious person around or there is something strange going on?
None.
Wait a minute.
You Mi Hee Han, right?
Yeah, so?
I want to ask you a few things about the accident yesterday.
Do you tell me who pushed her?
No, that's not what I mean.
I do not know who pushed SeulGi.
Danckematian Jahee death was an accident.
I've been told I did not meet that night JaHee Kang
If you do not believe me, ask the school about my statement.
I did not say anything. why still think I accused you?
I just do not want to lose my time studying,
Understand?
So you're going to tell him?
Caution!
What are you going to behave hypocritically until the end?
Do you know what happens to us if we report it huh?
You're strong behind your parents' backs, so it's fine for you.
It's true!
Everyone is afraid to family
keliatannya  So you want to be queen here as well.
You're done?
You think I do not know why you're acting like this?
Simply  friends. Let's just forget it okay?
What is a transfer student to say?
As expected school students accelerate removals.
But, why did you call me here?
We can end this ghost game.
If correct your misconception.
There is something that will happen this prophecy.
What?
Enough already we mess around. They began to groggily
mean .. You know who did it?
Who?
It... We will find later.
Ah yes. It was not a big deal.
Please do not worry.
Yes ma'am. it's late.
Why are you calling?
Ah... it was not a big deal.
Do not worry and please set the date to enter your son.
We will open the space for him later.
Yes, yes. Bye.
What time is it?
Ready  -prepared,
your ugly secrets will be uncovered! =
Who is playing this play?
Who are you?
Do you think I believe in ghosts?
What are you doing?
Help me, help me!
You.
You're supposed to be in the hospital, why?
Off me.
He's the reason why JaHee died.
This JaaHee you are recording sound right?
This DJ Hakll your school, Kang JaHee, say hello once again
why?
He JaHee edit the recorded voice?
It.
8 Hours 9 o'clock last night and tonight. Photos of Park SeulGi suspicious out of the hospital wearing full protective clothing.
And we found the fishing twine under the mattress.
Good job.
Tell me, why are you doing this?
It?
I just wanted to finish this before I moved.
We recorded it, so we had to finish it before I go
Are you okay?
I'm sorry JaHee.
What do you mean I'm okay?
What for I moved we could not see each other again?
Do you have to go?
If I moved, maybe I'll calm down.
Do you want to talk?
SeoulGi, let you see it!
What is this?
A student in gym class say nothing of stealing money from the locker?
I heard you were sick and stayed in class during gym hours.
That's not me. Another child who started the rumor accusing me.
I've said to the teacher.
Is not I do not trust you. but according to the school rules we have to move you
Please believe me.
It was not me!
Relax, this can be passed smoothly.
What are you doing?
Can not you hear? YeonJoo be moved?
Why are you thinking about it? with this, the rich students go to school here.
What can students who asked not to be moved?
If you did not hear me,
There is something that could happen to you.
Understand?
So just listen to me!
Stop!
It's enough!
So what should we do?
I'm going to report this.
This is criminal.
You can not. Are you crazy?
Think again. It is not our business
do not make trouble.
What do you mean do not create a problem? Is not there a bigger problem than this?
It's true!
There is no way other than to report it.
You will move another school tomorrow.
But what about us?
What will happen to us next?
True.
Let stand just as we do not know, okay?
True guys...
Be careful before thinking, who is going to hurt because you.
But ..
JaHee, he does not want to tell me and it changed all of a sudden.
Changed? why?
I really do not know.
I do not know what happened to him.
What? Let him alone?
Why so suddenly?
I think .. it's better.
What is the reason?
What MiHee say something?
Why are you like this?
Is it me?
Do you think I'm going to hurt?
I'll be fine. If this is allowed, you may not be transferred.
Give me the tape.
Seulgi.
Do not ask me why but
perminyaanku can you follow?
You, outrageous.
Kang JaHee I do not like this you're not a coward.
You're going to report it?
Caution!
Do you want to act a fool till the end?
Do you know what will happen to us if we can be a lot of trouble.
Well, you're strong behind your parents' backs so you can be safe.
What?
Everyone is afraid of your family so you think you can be a queen
here.
You're done?
You think I do not know why you're acting like this?
Okay. I bribe to get in this school, so what?
Honestly, who would want to leave this school?
Give me that!
Give!
What are you doing? release!
Choi Hyun Jae, what are you doing, help me!
I'm afraid, as did the others.
If the truth came, we thought we were all punished as a murderer.
He said he would take care of everything.
So there is no problem.
And the tape?
I do not know, we all panic and we tried to look but not see
.
Why did not you tell someone?
There, I've said.
But, no one wants to listen.
Just tell me to shut my mouth separately.
What is Hyun Jae?
What is it? Is she crazy?
HyunJae It was like, what if it falls?
What if he dies?
Hyun Jae wait!
Hyun Jae, go down and we talked.
DO NOT TELL ME  approaching!
Hyun Jae!
Do Hyun Jae, please do!
SeulGi.
I'm sorry.
You're trying our best to JaHee but I...
Even then ..
What are you doing? I take care of it!
You guys, shut your mouth.
I killed JaHee, he died for me!
I'm afraid...
Everything should be reported,
Choi Hyun Jae.
You were caught drinking beer
you know how when you go out?
I'll take care of this problem.
Mother expect much.
You've worked hard to get in this school.
You're also right end of the semester?
It all depends if you listen
Get it?
Why are you out of your room at night?
You .. do not tell.
JaHee ..
I have to tell everything later.
But I do not want to be moved.
I do not want to be separated from my friends!
HyunJae.
I think if the tape disappears, everything will return to normal.
I'm sorry JaHee.
I'm so sorry.
Yes, it was just an accident,
So do not be like that. right?
Hyun Jae please come down!
Well, Park SeulGi what your dreams?
Do not record me, I do not use make-up.
Well, let's ask HyunJae
-  What's this?
I?
Talk about my dream?
Ayii. I could not do it.
Do you record without me?
MiHee, seems to want to stand out.
Do you want to go first?
Not. SeulGi first record only.
Park SeulGi?
My dream is to become a film director.
Being a film director, and be able to Caan film festival.
Memagan trophy and ..
My name Park Seul Gi.
Not?
Seul Gi Park.
And next  .. MiHee.
Hey, do not turn around!
True Ah .. ahemm ..
My dream is graduating from Ivy league school and meet like Cho insung
husband and live happily ever after.
Wow, the dream of many.
You must be born again.
It's true!
Further Hyun Jae!
Wait .. I want to grooming first.
Artist?
Hey just so well-known reporter and did not stutter alone.
Wow .. you must be born again as well.
Okay .. KangJaHee now.
And JaHee want to be?
I?
Wow .. beautiful.
Mi Hee record it.
I .. so butterflies.
What kind . you cheated.
See it. look how pretty she is?
I can hand you forever.
Friends Friends, I love you.
Ooooooh .. horror!
Friends Friends,
Do not forget me.
Yes, okay?
Hyun Jae.
Come down now.
I know how you feel.
JaHee ..
I'm sorry.
You doing okay?
You can not die.
You're stupid!
JaHee
JaHee here.
JaHee real.
What?
Member-girls high school administrator arrested for soliciting bribes
From the parents so students can bribe the school entrance.
Members  board students also target some students
no reason to be moved so that they could open up opportunities for children who bribe.
Schools to utilize his advantage.
True True cheeky!
Aigoo. you solve the case why did not denganbaik
full day on holiday?
Ha Sunwoo
I think you're just spending time,
But it has entered into a major case.
Good job!
This is still lucky.
They could split the shared memory.
What I could have friends like them.
Do you think you could?
Detective Ha.
Is there something going on today?
No, no.
Today. What you really forget?
What do you do without me?
You do not know why he's like that?
Today is the birthday of Detective Ha.
I do not want to tell you
but I had to do it.
Take her to a nice place,
And buy her something nice I think.