Just before my father died,
he said the worst thing
about growing old
was that gets harder to protect
the things that matter.
HONOR, FREEDOM
JUSTICE and FAMILY
Those things are sacred
every man does
it's your shoreline
that's what guides you home
and trust me,
you're always trying to get home.
SEAL Team 7
HALO jump training - San Diego, CA
PHILIPPINES
Can I get some ice cream?
No, we gotta go
You always say no
Well, you gonna buy?
No, you buy!
Ok, what do we getting today?
Passion fruits.
Ok, passion fruits.
claim responsibility for the attack
at the International School in Manila ..
Your father was a reader
He loved Churchill
Faulkner, and books about
other wise men
He loved the heart of supreme
people with boxes for buddies
I don't give a hell about that
and he said, "you gotta look harder"
Ambassador Marguilles had long been a strong supporter of Joint
Counter Terrorism Operation conducted within this region.
Not one group has yet claim responsibility for
the attack on the International School ...
Here's your coffee, Rorke
Thank you, Maam
How is it going?
Great, you want the usual?
Sounds good, thank you.
Late again, Dave
SOC-Dave
sailor of the year.
PACOM-5 tours
CENTCOM-2 tours
I didn't say it..
What do you got going on over here?
THE EXPECTANT FATHER Facts, tips and
tricks for the expectant father
Are you serious man?
We're not telling anyone yet
You look nervous alot
Well, last time I checked they
don't come with directions
Yeah, tell me about it
Hey, my man here's having a baby.
Hey, congratulations!
Hey everybody, Rorke's having a baby!
What did I just said?
Oh, don't worry about it man,
you're gonna be awesome.
I'm so exciting for you man,
you're gonna be a good dad.
Hey tomorrow Jack, you know,
heading down to the beach
Bring Sandy and the kids, I'll
bring an actual board for you
You know I don't surf.
I know you don't surf, but it'll
good to get families together.
But now that you've told everyone in the
bar, trying to contained yourself tomorrow
I will try.
COSTA RICA
"Look harder", your father would say
I wish knew he wasn't just talking
about those strange box he paintings
Or ordering chaos enwrap the world.
One often disguise as the other
- It's hurt..
- No, you'll just feel a little bit tingling
How you guys doing, huh?
Christo!
Hey, I'll be right down, all right?
Whatever you say, Boss.
How was arrive?
I left Colombia this morning
Colombia to here in a day?
It's a gag
Anyway, estimate says that
Christo worth close to a million
That's he would be?
Yeah, and he gives back a lot to this community over here with
medical clinics, schools, political donations, you name it
So this is the deal, they are
extremely loyal to him over here.
When did the DEA have
a mobile dwarf?
When they intercepted a 707 of
his field with Soviet weapons
This is among us. These boys overheard NSA,
they found some interesting hints connecting Christo
toward Jihadist network out this South East Asia
Apparently, Christo one of the guys running the network.
They're childhood friends
Your father's grandfather gave up his
life piloting a B-24 on World War II
He kept to level her just long
enough for everyone else to jump
and then he went down with the plane
That's the blood that
courses through your veins
Daddy, can I come with you?
Wanna come with me?
Did you feel how cold it is out there?
I tell you what, go hang out with mommy for
a little while, help out with the baby
when I came back in, if you still wanna go out.
I'll take you out with me.
Promise?
I promise. Hurry up, go.
- What's going on, Sir?
- What's up, Brother?
Not too much, man
Oh, I know you got the New York heritage, but this
isn't exactly like sitting back on Santa Island
Yes, I know, I know
You're gonna actually work
hard to get through this Sir
twelve plus series of routines.
And you don't know how to do this?
Hey, wait until you have 5 kids, man.
Let's see how much time you got playing the surf.
You ready to get the drink or what?
All right man, you lead the way.
- All right, don't embarrass us!
- All right.
Your father was my boss
and I was his chief
We've saved each other's
lives more than once
It was a brotherhood between us
and we depended on each
other more than family
Wise men once said, although a single twig
will break, a bundle of twig is strong
Wow, this is unbelievable.
I can't still believe you
order Chinese in this place.
It's really good.
Double word score, 18 points.
DUMB?
You don't know which, Sugar
I try not to
look at this,
look at this, 38 points for me
ADUMBRATING?
That's even not a word.
Ok, first of all, it's pronounced "atombrading"
and it means "pretending", " foreshadowing"
Hmm..
Guess who's buying dinner tonight. Sugar?
Fine.
Most cases offices get tactical pardons
Language has me up for some sort of...
scrabble hustler
Scrabble Yoda, okay? Get it right.
- How much do I owe you?
- Nada
Our platoon was had it downranged
Weimy, he's our sniper. Ten years ago, he worked
a night stocking shelves at groceries store.
Now he's another watchman standing guard while
the world sleeps. He's a husband and a father
Ray was our communications guy,
our radio man.
He grew up in East LA gangland. He has a silver star
for deploying wounded team made out of a fried
Sonny, he was made of granite
This guy didn't even do push-ups 'cause was
afraid his chest was gonna get too big
Ajay, joined the team late in his 30's. He'd been a Muay Thai fighter
early in life. Before that, he grew up Derp Port in Trinidad.
Mikey had 20 years in the teams
As humble as he was, you'd
never even know it.
He kept a picture of his
wife in his helmet
and a lock of her hair in his pocket.
Quite as a breeze.
And finally Senior Chief,
couldn't really tell
you much about him
Rather than I'd take a knife into gun
fighting after being interogated by him.
That last night at home, you think about how you
could've been a better dad, a better husband
that bedtime story should've read
that our anniversary you forgot
You don't expect your family
to understand what you doing
just help them to understand
you do it for them
And when you get home, you hope you can
pickup right at where you left off.
- Put the wild bunch down?
- Yeah
Hey, Senior. Do you mind to give
us a scope for the ashburn?
No, I might got that thing.
Thanks
Hey fellas, you know how will I got so many speeches
and give in work-up for the deployment, but uh...
It's like Chief and I said, right
at the beginning of this platoon
Once we step off on campaign, once it reversed ready
for downranged, everything back home is be unbalanced
we will not worth the dead of each other or self,
we get over there, something out of recommendative
Things aren't right with the family, things aren't right with the
finance or something's off. It's gonna put us all out of balance. So..
We need to had that typed before we launch.
Have somebody got an issue, bring it on
Chief can take care, I can take care.
Everybody's got each other's back.
Let's make sure we lock that down, when we ride or roll.
All our focus is on the mission.
For all those been downranged, to us
and those like us, damn few. Cheers!
I still like the name James.
I'll think about it, it's a boy.
Come here
I'm proud of you.
Thanks, Baby.
Hey liitle one, you make sure you
keep mama away from mackerel.
I don't like that change smoking at all
- I got it, Lieutenant / OK
- It's gonna be okay / right
- It's gonna be fine
Try to keep these as long
as you can, for awhile
- Anything else, Commander?
- Yeah
I'd like to be able looking your eyes
when our first child is born
You know I'll do my best
- I love you, Baby
- I love you
War is a country of will
there's no room for sympathy
If you not willing to
give up everything
You've already lost
Get the phone to her, Gilberto
Here. Chief.
What do you want?
I am a doctor from Mexico,
what do you want?
Tell me, what is it about you Americans,
that make you feel entitle to fcuk with
the way I make my living?
UKRAINE
My name is Lisa Vaughn, I am a
Doctor from Mexico
I told you a thousand times
I don't know
I know who you are Miss Morales
and I know who you work for,
so why don't you save us both some time
and tell me exactly what
you think you know.
I take care the mothers
who give birth to your kind.
How does that feel Miss Morales?
Have a great day at the Spa.
Turn off the speaker!
Keep her alive and do not call me, anymore
Yes Boss
Going to talk?
- Nothing, nothing...
- Speak to me! Speak to me!
Hey fellas, what's up?
It's hard when two rats screwed
and we all suck up, didn't ya?
Africa had Tarzan. Can take a seat.
Anyway, here's the deal.
Time to get your frogmen on.
Lights
Three days ago two CIA agents, Walter Ross
and Miss Lisa Morales were ambushed
inside their hotel room here in Costa Rica
by eh.. unknown amount of
heavily armed assholes
Unfortunately, Mr. Ross was murdered,
and Ms. Morales
has been abducted.
We believe that
this is been a work of a guy
named Mikhail Troykovich
A.K.A Christo. LT's going to
give you the scanning on him
Thanks Senior.
Mikhail Troykovich A.K.A Christo
This guy's believed has been working
cocaine from weapon deals
between the Russian mafia,
the FARC guerrillas
and the Mexican drugs cartels
eversince the late 1990's
Now, before she was captured, Morales was working
on a possible link between our boy Christo
and this guy, Abu Shabal
Glory to Allah, Lord of the world, that has
created us as Muslims and delivered us with jihad
on His direct Path
Peace be upon those, who's on His
direct Path in the Day of Judgement.
On this explanation to you,
we are not separatists.
We're setting on all legal part of anyone
be you an agent are wilingly or unwillingly
assisting the agenda of genocide
of our people,
by demanding that we obey certain rules
and by your continous occupation
of all Muslim countries,
With the Grace of Allah,
we must exile to this heed
America, you'll never be safe, until safety
becomes a reality for us. Allahu Akbar.
Abu shabal is a Chechen terrorist that
associated with the Beslan school massacre
He's been jumping between training
camps in Indonesia and the Philippines
Now, the connection between Christo
and Abbu Shabal is so a little bit fuzzy,
But if this was the lead
that Morales was working on
it could be why she was abducted.
Senior?
All right, this is a personal recovery
of Miss Morales.
All right, who's got questions?
See, Chief. If you have any update
resource, and tell us numbers inside the
camp, what about roving patrols?
Maybe 8 to 10 Bro
but we don't know anything
about roving patrols
you just gonna have to assume that's all working
around the squared away you just did for a living too
Senior, what kind of weapons
on target are we looking at?
Heavy weapons. This guys are narco traffickers, so
they can have anything from Soviet block discus.
They can have a empty UHB for the
course out there, we don't know.
So, if there is a weapons in place out
there, I suggest you guys bring rockets
of course rockets and bullets don't match,
so make sure you got a clear shot.
All right, what else?
Any idea wether she's ambulatory or not?
There's ton of blood on the scene,
and alot of it was Mr Ross'
We confirmed that Ms. Morales
may has blood there too
But these guys are savages.
So, you're gonna have
to assume that she is..
Non ambulatory, so you gonna have
to bring stuff to carry her out.
Two minutes to drop
Hey LT, got this little know who that guy,
so we get back we can kick his ass!
What guy?
The guy that gave you
taht fcuked up hair cut
Fcuk. I'm sorry, this should be the last guy
to talk put back in Dominican Mr. Clean
I'm sorry my hair sounds
like your gold teeth huh?
- Don't be like that...!
- WE'RE UP!!
Masker.
Dave, I tell you what, the only thing better than this right here
is being a dad, except for not whole changing diaper thing, but..
Same will goes up for me anyway, so..
I'm actually looking forward to it.
Blackbeard, ready lauch in 10..
Five..
Blackbeard - Main, Blackbeard - Main..
This is Blackbeard Actual
radio check, over.
Blackbeard - Main, Blackbeard - Main
this is Blackbeard Actual, over.
Roger Actual, this is Main,
we have you Lima Charlie
Roger Main, all boots are on the ground.
I passed, T bird.
Any traffic for my station at this time?
Actual, Imagery picked up an increase
in traffic at secondary location
known to be enemy G-R-F-H-Quick
from primary target
The slick boat Windsored at 0600
for your extract. L, copy.
Roger, Main.
- You ready?
- Roger that Sir, we got about 40.7 clicks with 355
Take it out.
Whiplash, 1 minute out
30 seconds
10 by 10
Whiplash, go!
All foots are decked!
Line secure!
Whiplash, pack "the
morning" 2-1 out
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard
radio check, over.
Blackbeard
- Whiplash, have you loud and clear
Roger Whiplash, what is
your ETA to my post?
ETA 20 minus. Stand by.
Razor is in flight,
approching to your location
No more, please, please,
I can't, I can't take it anymore
Hey Sir, we gotta go
Roger, take it out.
If you like we put stay, and
I'd like take you guys with us
Chief, I got an SPT coming up on step.
We gotta it ready and push on my post
While I am here over watch position
and I got to keep reporting
back to back with Main
- Staying here.
- Roger that.
- Keep it tight
- Got it.
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard
Assault forces moving the target early
Request immediate fire support
Blackbeard, this is Whiplash, do it, copy.
Acquired fire support.
Proceed to your
location in 15 minus.
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard,
Prep positive control their item
Chief, are you set?
Chief, chick hold.
One O'clock, base on the tower
Done
Clear to the door
And what happened to the tomatoes?
I got two escorts coming from the back door
Move in!
Clear! All clear!
Weimy, 11 O'clock, driver side truck.
Got him
Clear! all clear!
Target secure!
Chief, I'm gonna get Mikey
LT, this is Chief. The target is secure.
Stand by for confirmation of package.
Be advised, Mikey is down, Mikey is down.
Status followed
Roger, you have the package
Chief, I got a cellphone
LT, LT!
Chief, it looks like you have two aggressor
vehicle approaching from the north
About one minus out
You can take the truck outside the
west door, meet us at extract
Miss Morales, I'm going you home
I just need to ask you a few questions
What's your mother's maiden name?
Rosales
what street you born on?
Hoffspring
All right, just hang on.
Whiplash, we have enemy at your
left approaching you from the north
Roger, we have identity cue
affirmative from the north
Chief, you need to start your X field now!
We just set secondary extract
Roger that.
Hey boys, we gotta roll!
Shit, Sir this truck by a thousand yards
Now, taking out.
Ajay, take around the yard, the X we got it here.
It's alive. We gotta get moving now!
Weimy, coming out!
Meet us at rally point!
Let's go, let's go!
Moving!
Right turn, right turn!
Hey man, we're not gonna
make this secondary extract
I gotta find us around employing this road..
Left, left, left!
Mikey, come on buddy
Hey Chief!
We're not gonna make secondary extract!
- You're not to figure it out man!
- All right!
Come on, stay with me, stay with me!
Stay with me, come on Mike!
Wake up, wake up, come on man!
Help Team, we can make it to rally point
Sounds good, pass it to LT!
LT, LT, this is Assault Team. We just lost secondary
extract, I say it again we just lost secondary extract
Move it to rally point, L copy, over.
- What about the click hour?
- Mike, wake up!
- Got it?
- Axis clear!
Rocket out!
Come on girl. He's not breathing!
We're up, we're up!
Mike, wake up!
Come on Mike, come on Mikey, wake up!
FIRE!!
Chief, let me get your N4!
Sir, what's the status on those boat?
I lost Whiplash on the run. Told you to hit
the target early, they're coming in hot
Roger that.
Breath Mikey, come on Mikey.
I got no pulse!
Contact wth, contact with!!
Holy shit!
Break it up, break it up!
Ajay, do it allright,
they're coming at our rear!
Whiplash, Whiplash!
Deck at the air extraction first
Moving to tertiary extract.
I have 8 packs
7 is around, 1 package.
Package is wounded Morales
"The Sierra" has downtown one to the head.
This will be a hard extract.
- What the fcuk?!
- Sit down, man. Get down!
- come down brother!
Mikey's up man, Mikey's up.
- Mikey, hang on Buddy.
- Where are we?
On our way to extract. We're good to go
- You took one tho the face man, you harm another fcuker.
- Do we get it? / Yes, - Oh, I get it / on our way to extract
Ajay, splash it, splash it!
Water!
Water, water!
I got her, I got her!
It wasn't for nothing
UKRAINE
Who are you?
- Is it Mendelsson?
- No, Brahms.
I am Kerimov.
You must be Shabal.
Ok, as I said to Christo on the phone,
I have the requirement you want
a vest
- Cool isn't it?
- It is simple but effective
over here
Inside them is tiny balls made of
ceramics-based.
Five hundred of them
woven into vest,
They contain explosive gel
It is our new technology
It is truly devastating,
please
Here is no big deal, you know this
It is designed for open spaces
You have to believe me
There are few weapons in the world
that they can operated only by one man
Look at this.
presented to you
kucing_gaul
They can go everywhere without get detected
You could take tour to White
House or wherever you like
Can I see a demonstration?
You kidding, you even have
no time to go to Siberia
Listen, when this explodes,
there is no safe place.
Imagine firing 500 bullets everywhere and
being scattered by a massive explosion.
Take one of these to the stage,
casino or shopping center
and create such a massal panic through American mass media.
A total collapse of economy will happened.
Buddy, look, you're never change
- Can I take his coat?
- No, thank you
And now from time to time, I get to
see my old friends by my old life.
And it's always, always disappointing.
Some become asshole, as other boring
And I can't believe I tried to get
them in bed all those years ago
Hey, it is nice not to be disappointed Yuri
It's not my name
I know. Muhammad Abu
Shabal, the son of Shabal
Come on, your father's name is Yevgeny
- It's changed.
- Yeah, I think it's changed
That's why this is the last time I might
have to see each other for quite some time.
For am I have to find a hole to hide in.
I don't understand
I'm being watched by the CIA, and
not there gonna be any chances
This is the most
oppotunities present itself
I'm taking my family South.
I need the help, the energy,
or the will to fight the Americans
What about Ardile and Michel,
and they have been in training
for almost a year now, I have
devoted much of my respect..
The deal stands, Yuri.
Just because I've taken early retirement,
does not mean I'm not holding
at my end into the bargain
There is so much to be done.
And it will be, just without me!
You have to use my trust in associates
- It's not so good for me!
- Hey!
Hey, shut up! Shut up! Stop! You're fcuking bullshit!
It's not good, it doesn't work
- You can't change it like that!
- Nothing changes, nothing.
You just told me everything change,
but what is it? What is that?
Do you know, what I do to get here?
Do you know, the man why has to sacrifice to get here?
Do you have any idea?
No, you shit, you live up here, this
ivory tower, you know I don't care.
USS BON HOMME RICHARD
- CENTRAL AMERICAN COAST
- Hey Chief, what's the status of Mikey?
- He's definitely lose the eye, but he's hang it tough.
Yeah, I'm gonna get read into this
Great job, small check in those
assholes, get Morales back
It's a blunt deal for Mikey better get
to tell you what was the solid work.
- So Chief, make sure you get that down of
the boys right away. Do you hear me? - Sure
All right.
And Morales.
Morales was one tough chick.
But she should've got in this stuff up to change a lot faster
because this thing is way bigger than we thought it was.
How was that? I thought this was
cut and dry arm search recovery
Yeah, wasn't until we got into that phone
that you guys picked up at that shit hole.
- It turn me out of something just not look right at all.
- And what's not right about it?
Christo and Shabal are a lot
closer than I thought they were.
Shabal is a wild core man
He's an old jahadi, that couldn't
give a rest-ass about money or drugs.
Yeah, that tells his friend
Christo, the dope dealer?
He's not a dealer man,
he's a smugler.
You've gotta be kidding me.
That is exactly what I'm thingking. Shabal wants to kill
Americans, Christo knows how to get fcukers inside America.
This could be big trouble in little timing fellas.
They're gonna hit us at home.
I just got done talking to boss, on the
spec of task force, this is gonna go down.
I need Ajay and Ray stand by to launch for NSR in 2 hours.
They gonna get some friggin' flower mouse on the way to Africa.
Why Africa?
We pended airfield there
by the phone that you got?
And I think that Shabal is gonna be there
during weapon transfer on his way West.
When you say "West", what
do we talking about?
Mexico West?
Yeah
Mexico West
It's the worst case scenario
You two and the rest of
platoon are gonna stay here
and standby, you'll be the primary assault for
worst case that goes down anywhere near America
Check
You gonna be around for any
questions as they came up?
No man. Christo, he put a Roman
Polanski at my ass and disappeared.
So I'm gonna link up for SEAL Team 4
and we're gonna go hunt his
ass down in the South Pacific
So straight up, my ties and
palm trees so maybe...
Yeah brother, I go get them
Be cool. take it easy
Good luck with that baby, Lieutenant
Does everybody know?
All the important people
The important people to who?
For you?
I guess so
I'm gonna go brood the boys
Hey hold on one second
I brought it here cause I
want you to read it before
I'm trusted officer...
and but to be honest with you
I was thinking to calling the commander
trying to get you home
And now worse picked up so much
I feel like we really need you here
You remember our last cruise on Alamar?
Yeah
When you got that final turn over op
you said I don't need to be there
I was lying in bed, and I realized all
the thing I need do now was go home
But if something went south in your op
I would always regret not
being there with you
I appreciate you're taking
care of me big time, Dave
But I'm working sometimes with the brass
If I can
And things slow down
I'm gonna get 2 weeks off
I'll leave the works now eitherway,
I really do
But if it doesn't
I'm gonna take this piece of paper and
I'll make it into nice paper airplane
Bid it
AFRICAN COAST
Good, we're good
- 601, emerge the ship at 160 feet
- Guide, guide
Hey guys thank you for being here so fast
Grab a seat, please
Thank you
You have Bulldog overhead
We need you te get in, grab the intel
and down to back to us
Do you have any questions?
Sir, I have a question
We have the rally point time
What if the meeting doesn't
take place as schedule
How long do you want us to stay on target?
That's one counts
So, I plan on B out there for awhile
Check
Are we good?
Think so Sir. Yes Sir.
- Ray - Ajay, I'll reached up and ready to check each other out
- Grab the door, clear.
SOMALIA
Do we have visual?
Yeah
Got three trucks moving in
a fuel truck, 2 jeeps,
Some skinnies in the back
One at the last fifty count
Do you hear that?
Yeah, think that our plan
Yeah, we get some inbound
About time he's gonna showed up, Jesus!
Give me my camera
Hey Ray, we got two birds
down here in the field
It's obvious our pass
No tail ID's
You got that?
Check, no tail IDs
Ray, last time I checked
you were in Africa, right?
Yeah
Why, what's up?
Dude, these like 16 Filipinos down there
all praying to Mecca right now
Filipinos?
Filipinos definitely not skinnies
Who pick up the praying?
Unless he's picking up some Russian
You two come here
Be very careful with
these boxes, do you hear me?
Drop one of these and
you are all going to heaven
Aircraft will change
And enter through two
different border crossings
be careful
Once on the island, your men will
have time to finish preparations
A friend will be
with you on the plane
and help the rest of the way
Bulldog, Bulldog
we have around and we checked, over
Get check, copy
Roger get check, be advised, we got 2
sterile aircraft departing to the East
at following location
Ten Kappa Lima Sierra
Please advise, when you
intel the target, over
Roger, copy two aircraft ...
Location Ten Kappa...
Hey Chief, you
are not gonna believe this
One of the planes Ray and Ajay tagged, just
landed on Cedros Island of the coast of Mexico
It has Shabal with unknown
number of jihadist
Are you kidding me?
No, it looks like we're
getting ahead of target
Well, Senior and his sweep
motor punching out,
they should call a liitle
more intel for shore sea
All right
SOUTH PACIFIC
I don't know how long we'll stay
Hold on Baby
Be safe
You know I will, I gotta to go, Honey
I love you
Joann, I don't want to play with these
Are you listening?
There's nothing to worry about
OK?
I'll talk to you soon.
Bravo Alpha, we're 200 meters out
We got you have a Tango on your starboard
side, Tango on your starboard side
Winky Charlie, we
have visual on Tango
Bubble, you have a
Viper on 12 O'clock
Get out! Get out!
Clear!
Bridge secure!
Senior, you're clear
Good afternoon, how are you?
Right. Do you speak Serbian Croatia?
Russian
Is it Russian?
Yes
Do not speak Russian
English ok?
English is fine
Let's do that
Can you cut him loose, please
If you cut loose, you will not
do anything crazy, right?
Crazy iron, so to speak.
So you Russian, yeah?
Yes, I am.
Are you all right?
Yes I'm good, thank you
You're welcome
I'm sorry, I don't know your name
I'm Otto
- Otto?
- Yes, nice to meet you
And you are?
Christo
Chrisko?
Traskovich?
Hey Brother, we need to make this hit count
Beause I'm ready promote new
Liutenant commander ...
I'm working at the White House
Oh man, looks carry football
- It was better let me carry that thing
- Oh I'm kidding, man
Hey you know Otto, eitherway, there has to be
some quality time for your the new family, Bro
Yeah man, now is gonna
be a good carrier move,
but, I'll be a powerful in-commander if I
suppose to shoot bad guys and few nurglars
Yeah, well, truth to be told you will
never good be an operator anyway
Come on man,
- you know you suck
- Yeah
Hey, come on, come on
You sitting on wonderful boat,
Fabulous
I believe it's called "starship"
"starship"?
I love the way you say "starship"
It's like Russian
Like guy in Star Trek, what's his name?
Scotty, I'm sorry, Scott
I would not
You never seen Star Trek?
No
That's insane
So, here's the problem, pal
You're with a lot of money
Or you were with a lot of money?
I believe I still have
You do?
Yes
All right
Let me tell you how the world works there
Chrisco ...
It's Christo
sorry?
Christo
oh, of course
Oh it's ok
Let me tell you how
the world really works
please
This is no longer your boat
Since I walk through that door, you're not
the same guy you used to be. You just not.
There's nothing I can do to stop that
Nothing I can do to help you right now
unless you let me help you
We need to do this together pal, you and me
So, how is you think you working
with these jihadi folks then?
Your're Jewish, right?
Shabal is ...what?
Have you ever had a
friend that you grew up with?
Sorry?
Have you ever had a
friend that you grew up with?
Yes
Like play interest, like soccer..
Or what would you play,
base ball probably, right?
probably
Ya
And anyone has his separate ways,
and some years later you meet up
And you totally didn't recognize the person
That's what I have been with Shabal
We share a common interest
So, he came up with his incredible idea
because of his beliefs
I don't necessarily share his beliefs
But he's a smart guy
You know?
Almost like ...
you know, almost like...
like, this is me.
And that's Shabal
Is it?
And America is in between
Yeah
Cool concept, no?
Right here?
Yes
You think this is some kind of game?
Do you? You find this amusing?
I'm not find ...
Do you realize what you're doing here?
Blackbeard actual to Blackbeard Main
Host nation counterpart
secured target Bravo
Report strike all.
You're clear to move on target Alpha
Roger Main, clear to target
The only people I answer to is my family
to my wife and to my child
and nobody else
Running late somewhere?
6 after 4
Really?
Yeah
So ...
Here's the problem pal
You do love your family don't you?
Yes I do
And what about your daughter?
What about my daughter?
Are you looking forward
to seeing her again?
Every minute on my life
I wanted you to see that,
so you can think about something
very seriously
Because you're gonna be sitting
in a box somewhere
You'll be treated properly and humanely
That girl is gonna grow up,
and she's gonna get married
and your wife is gonna find someone else
And you're gonna miss everything
If I had done something
that would endanger my family
I would feel just like you do right now
Do you promise not to touch my family?
I would never touch your family
I would not
Are you familiar with ...
"ceramic bullbearings"?
No
Just imagine 16 suicide vests
filled with ceramic bullbearings
Slipping by every metal detector
and every check-point in your country.
Do you think your economy's fcuked now?
Just think what the
Media is gonna do with this
It's gonna make 9/11 look like a fcuking
walking park, the Grand Central Park
So, you're telling me ..
There is 16 jahadis wearing suicide vests
they're gonna walk right accross the border
So, where are they going?
San Diego, San Francisco, Houston
You pick a city, they'll be there
And this is happening now?
It's happening as we speak
say what?
How can you stop this?
I can't
CEDROS ISLAND, MEXICO
presented to you
kucing_gaul
Blackbeard - Lee
Contain element set
Roger
Help!
Help me!
Done, done, done!
Blackpack This is Blackbeard, we're in
contact midtown south of the church
Blackbeard - Lee watch your post.
Over watch, prepare to engage
Going hot.
What are you doing?
Weimy, I got chaseborders heading south,
they pick up truck
I see them
Echo, two guys in the truck
Mortar!
Sir, sir!
LT, you all right?
Damn
You check that box huh?
Yeah
Good thing that was a dart,
how am I gonna hurt?
Woow
Jesus
These are not some bushky
vest from Iraqi hut
These some high speed shit
Maybe we should put
this somewhere else, huh?
Hey Sonny, find somewhere
to put this would you?
Target secure
set security
rest to the north, three south
Here are your objectives
Well ...
I'm proud of you
We are family now
Chief, target blasting
up, everything secure
Actual, mission not complete
Stand by for follow one
You only got half that you had at cell
Target secure, Sir
This fight isn't over yet
Now listen,
at 0700, we're
coordinating with State
but for now the principal job
you have outside the city
where your POC is Commander Pedros
I'll give you more details on route
Actual, are you copy?
Roger Maam.
Ok, we got the hill laming on the deck, we're
gonna meet a Mexican South Commander and his team
We're gonna help infiltrate the
target, and join us on the assault
What the hell are you talking about?
We didn't got all of them yet, Chief
Where's the rest of it?
They're in Mexicali, on the border
All right, and the rest of the boys,
how they getting back to the ship?
Bon Homme Richard stayed on station,
they're gonna send them Marine helmet
head all back split to target, and when they're
done, the boys will pull off with them
Ok
I'm thinking
squad 1 and myself roll out
- Perfect squad, Tuesday's here, buttons
up, pulls out of the marines - Ok
But now we know to put them to town
and crushing the sunrise
Gather group we're gonna take
as following day, the wadis
comprendors
Hey sir, who the hell clear us
had to go to Mexicali anyway?
This would do all that we up to the platform.
States Department on it.
Border Wall with Mexico
Hey Sir
channel 2
By this time on keep work like this, Jacky's
gonna be squeezed and kicked out on road
however, if we had this target quick enough,
he jump on the burrow right at shit home
Hey, I gonna need no burrow
you got it two weeks
on the time I was there on the plane hall
you were not convinced so let me go home,
but I'm convinced gonna
leave your ass in charge
MEXICALI,
US/MEXICO BORDER
Sir
Lieutenant
Seems our government have been very
busy to make this possible, huh?
All the way
the tough, from I heard
There is something that
you have to understand
my superiors, they're very
fearful of Mexican "mogadishu"
no black or down, that's
what they're saying, so
we do need to stay under the radar
I understand completely Sir.
Your team presence here
is greatly appreciated
But we're out of time, we need to move
Tell me where, we go
Help piece these together for me.
Our intel says they using a tunnel network,
but it's under a milk factory
This mean anything to you?
I know exactly where it is
It's not far from here
And that's where we going
From all of the places of Mexicali you
could have been, this probably the worst
The cartels control any of
that from all the angles
They had us heavily outgunned.
Simply reaching your target's gonna be very difficult
Sir we have a thorn national's
heading to our country
needless to say, they're no big fan of ours
If they are in that factory,
that's where we going
Lieutenant, I'll take you
anywhere you need to go
But prepare your men for a bigger
fight than you had imagine
You're not fighting at men
you're also fighting the
cartels that protecting them.
If your targets make it into those
tunnels, they'll disappear like ghosts
You enter the tunnels right here
You walk several miles to this fork
my men will tell you which way to take
Once you get to this point
My job is done
You're on your own
Lieutenant, we're going now
Roger that
Chief, We'll not stopping, we'll
rolling up on target hard
Roger that, should've
there about 30 seconds up
SA, on the roof!
We gotta go
Now!
Come on.
You stay here
Sir, leave two men here
You two, stay here!
Weimy!
I need you to lock this shit down
Watch out!
You guys got the gate
Go!
Go to the front door!
One moment
This is where you have to blow the bomb
What happens?
You will meet your husband in heaven
Boooooomb!!!!!!!!!
Damn it, sir
I could explain that one to my family
Keep back there, so I won't have to, huh?
Clear
Grenaaaaaade!
Chief, I got him
Keep going, I cover you
Chief!
Assault 2, this is Assault 1. Be advised, tunnel
is secure, and all threats are neutralized
LT and Chief are down.
I say it again, LT and Chief are down.
Your father was a good man
Growing up without him
is gonna be hard,
It's gonna hurt. You feel alone, out
to see with no shore and sight
Remember, you have your
father's blood in your veins
The code that make your
father who he was
is the same code that'll
make you a man
Your father's will, his
values live on in you
Like those people who is in strange
painting your father admired
We man made of the boxes
chambers of laws
and triumph
of hurt
and hope
and love
No one's stronger than a man
who can harness his
emotions and his past
use it as motivation to write the
most important letter of your life
Before he died, your father asked me to give you
this poem by Tecumseh, a man he greatly admired
I told him I'd fold it
into paper airplane
and I guess that's what I'm doing
Say on it on him, to you
Live your life that the fear of
death can never enter your heart
Trouble no one about his religion
respects others and their views
and demand that they respect yours
Love your life..
Perfect your life..
Beautify all things in your life..
Seek to make your life long
and of service to your people
When your time comes to die
Be not like those whose hearts
are filled with fear of death
So that one their time come, they
weep, and pray for little more time
to live their lifes over
again and indifferently
Sing your death song,
and die like a hero
going home...
Subtitle By Transporter