You should not touch weapons.
You should not touch diamonds.
And don't touch the wives of the staff.
Everything besides that is green.
As soon as you have decided,
Mr. Mads will contact Europe.
Now we're talking about the contract.
--We have already fixed the primary deal.
--You can have a lot of diamonds.
It's about the water. It has rained so much that...
--Did you understand that?
--No.
--He's saying that the work with one of the
mines has progressed so much
--that when the water disappears it is just about
digging up the diamonds as quickly as possible.
He needs a sum of 10 million CAF.
That would suffice to get the diamonds up
in a couple of weeks.
Actually I'd prefer to cooperate with
businessmen, but I do trust you.
--Who framed this picture? Done down here?
--Yes.
--Slanted...
--Very slanted.
--You got the business cards, right?
--Yeah, I'll go get them.
--A gin tonic? Vodka tonic?
--Vodka.
I am the representative of the secretary of state
and I am in charge of domestic security issues.
I am responsible for areas like espionage and counterintelligence.
--And he has been in the French Foreign Legion?
--Yes, for 26 years.
He was in the Foreign Legion for 26 years.
France gave me citizenship in 1986
as a thank you for my duty.
--They confiscated my passport in 2006.
--Aha! That says it all.
In December 2006 I was prosecuted for mercenary.
France considers the CAR as its piggy bank.
They consider everything underground as
belonging to France. Nobody else.
It is like savings that
we are not allowed to touch.
It belongs to France, and that seems
to be the opinion still, he says.
And underground there is copper, iron
manganese, cobolt, uranium, cinnabar...
He says that they have all sorts
of minerals underground.
We know where --
-- but every time we ask for a
contribution to start the mining...
-- ... there are problems.
--Are they obstructing you?
But how? What do they do?
When one wants to prevent someone from running,
they may put a stone in the runner's shoe.
--[France] puts stones in their shoes.
-- If one wants to prevent a country's development...
... all its resources will be used to hunt rebels.
Then the country ceases to develop.
--The bulldozer or the 10 millions?
--The millions.
We thought about making a preliminary investment--
-- with a man named Gilbert Dalkia.
Do you know him?
Yes.
Do you think it is a good idea?
It depends whether you are controlling
him or vice versa.
What should we do to control him in order
to prevent him from taking control?
Here you need to know what relations
people have with one another.
If he believes that you know people who are
mightier than himself, he will contain himself.
But if he believes otherwise
you will lose everything.
Then we end up losing everything.
Mr. Cortzen, perhaps you can ...?
[Minister for public administration]
You educate people so that they become productive.
Even pygmees.
He says that you are touching an issue
that is close to his heart--
-- that is thinking of the human development,
and the fact that you educate.
That is very important, especially with the
pygmees, that you seek to highen their level.
I am currently moving to a city where the
indigenous people are pygmees.
They are in the are where I live, so it
is easy to get hold of them if you want.
I can try to arrange a meeting with
the city leaders.
The baguettes. This is a frenchman.
And this is a Chinese.
--Chinese have narrow eyes.
--And the frenchman's hair should be more spiky.
Then the Chinese should have smaller eyes.
But it's pretty, isn't it?
With this contract, if M. Dalkia finds
diamonds that he wishes to export--
--he can take them out legally,
using the contract.
Then I can take the stones to Europe.
Definitely.
They dance to conjure up the spirits--
-- in the shape of a whirlwind.
They have made a whirlwind by taking
off their clothes and swinging them.
--Now you will get a chance to
meet them.
And then he gave me a driver's license--
--indicating that I live on
Clay Street in Monrovia.
We have a Danish businessman--
--who for many years has
shown an interest in Liberia.
We find it appropriate to apply --
-- for the [inaud.] privilege of serving
as our honoary consule in Bangui in CAR.
Put your phone over there. Then you'll have
an excuse if it starts ringing.
--Mr. Gilbert! How is it going?
--Very well. Long time no see!
--Is it good?
--It is not good.
Companionship and law is not in
my competency.
Can you ask Girad who of these two
will be my assistant?
It is him.
He represents the chieftan.
--They move about in pairs. Never alone.
Can they both participate on Saturday?
Come on, let's go to the boat.
When Bokassa was overthrown,
the French reinstalled Dacko
-- and by their order he gave the
people permission to plunder at will.
The French soldiers had orders to
just stand idly.
THey were only to protect the French
embassy and Dacko's residence.
--So there was violence?
--Everything was destroyed.
Did the French want it to collapse?
-- Yes.
--But why?
If the country kept Bokassa
it would be the Switzerland of Africa today.
Instead of exporting raw material,
we were to export refined goods.
But when I talk to other business diplomats
I often hear the same story.
The companies that try to establish
fly the country immediately.
The French taught the people a nasty
habit, that is corruption.
When a minister is exposed as corrupt--
-- he automatically gets visa, passport
and residency in France.
--My business card.
--Thanks.
Why is it heating up in Birao? Now and then
the trampling of boots can be heard.
-- because there is oil. And the forces...
The forces... that fight for the
oil from Birao...
... they are creating the problems.
It is not a Central African problem,
it is other forces standing behind.
-- And who are these forces?
--Forces that you know very well.
Two French planes, one in the morning, one
in the evening, fly over CAR every day.
Two military reconnaissance planes.
For three years we have requested
insight into their reports, but we'll never get it.
-- Where are the planes headed?
--They just overfly the country.
They take photos and sweep the area
with heat and movement sensors.
They know who is moving there but
they never tell us anything.
The column that attacked Birao
consisted of 27 vehicles --
--and came out of Sudan, 400 kilometers
away, three days before the attack.
The French knew about it, but they
never told us. There is your stone in the shoe.
Hello! How is it going?
--Is that a government soldier?
--Yes. All of them.
--How much time do we have left?
--An hour and ten minutes.
Let's go.
-- What is that?
--The mine.
There it is.
The diamonds.
My workforce.
Like this.
The biggest stones in CAR are from here.
I love you... The mine.
--We need to keep the time.
--It is OK. We have 35 minutes to go.
Then let's take a greeting round.
How long will it take to go to the plane?
--Don't force her!
--No one is forcing her.
--Leave her.
--Open!
How can you say that we are
forcing her?
Should we go? -- No! She wants me to go.
Don't ridicule us in front of the white men.
The plane. Yes, that is it.
99 percent of all matches sold here
come from Cameroun.
-- The brand Le Boxeur?
--Yes.
And the real owner--
--is a Lebanese with a French
diplomatic passport--
--who in secrecy works for the
previous French tobacco monopoly.
Can I expect him trying to hamper
me if I try to open a factory here?
It depends on your will to
go through with this.
Charles Massi was a minister. He
exploited his position--
--to embezzle state money,
procure weapons and start a rebellion.
He tried to carry out a coup
d'etat with the help of France.
If he disappears he disappears.
No one is exactly
crying over that.
He looks like a person of
progression, as a pioneer.
And I think the most important
thing to remember about the CAR is--
--that it is a young country with
many possibilities.
--Thank you for the visit.
--Thank you.
Cortzen Group will pay to Gilbert Dalkia
a sum of 10 million CAF.
Additional five millions?
I need to translate this into Danish.
--Are you aware that they want us to
pay five millions in addition?
--How much is that?
Besides the 10 millions you
have already agreed on--
--you have consented to
paying five millions extra--
--to facilitate Mr. Gilbert's paying of taxes and fees.
That was included in the ten millions.
How much can we afford to pay him?
--I need to have a look at that. I cannot say anything conclusively.
--But we need to conclude this now.
--Yes, yes, but --
-- it is completely ridiculous that they
now claim five millions that was never discussed.
I heard that if we went to Zako yesterday--
--we could have bought 17 carat
diamonds worth 90 million.
With five million we can
get hold of a large stone.
Or what? So pay me.
He is talking bullshit. He says that we
can find diamonds for 80 millions, blah blah.
I feel like telling him "Shut up. If you have
that much money you can pay yourself."
It is bullshit. It is all bullshit. But he wants
ten millions now. Otherwise there is no agreement.
The only thing I want to say that when there
are this many changes to a contract--
--it is quite common to re-read it thoroughly
and think about it before signing it.
I know that we're in Africa and there is
momentum now, I'm just saying that--
--I would never sign this if I were you.
I simply would not.
I found one stone wirth 34 billion.
But they took it from me.
Sodiam and Catadiam was oned
by a Lebanese, Hassan Al-Baqaash--
-- who by the way is on USA's list
of known terrorists--
--because he has supported Hamas.
--Do Gilbert and Sodiam still cooperate?
--Yes.
When he has left, I am to meet the president.
--Who?
--Him.
No, it is for MPs.
With this I conduct diamond politics.
When I become a member
I can negotiate for him.
When I get a diplomatic passport...
The brother of the consule of Senegal.
No problem.
I'm thinking of sending Liberia's
consule-to-be in Bangui to you.
Treat him as you would me. Thank you!
Thank you, your excellence. Bye.
Cortzen Group dispurses a sum
of 10 million franc--
--according to the agreement that
was signed in Bangui on November 21 2010.
How can it be that when
we were to sign the contract--
--then you tell us that we
must sign the other contract?
I have made four copies.
One for the notary, one for Mr. Gilbert, one for the archive.
I said I cannot do anything about it.
And by the way it is no problem.
--Gilbert! How are you doing?
--Well, thanks!
If they find those and the papers
aren't in order, you will be fined 50-100 millions.
There's one there if you lift your foot.
--Look under your shoes.
Just stuff them down like this,
then it is done and he can go.
And so many!
And there are more where
they come from.