[narrator]
'Twas a long time ago
Longer now than it seems
In a place that perhaps
you've seen in your dreams
For the story that
you are about to be told
Took place in the holiday
worlds of old
Now, you've probably wondered
where holidays come from
If you haven't, I'd say
It's time you begun!
Boys and girls
of every age
Wouldn't you like
to see something strange?
Come with us
and you will see
- [gate creaks]
-  This our town of Halloween
This is Halloween
Pumpkins scream
in the dead of night
This is Halloween
Everybody make a scene
Trick or treat
till the neighbor's
gonna die of fright
It's our town
Everybody scream
In this town of Halloween
I am the one
hiding under your bed
Teeth ground sharp
and eyes glowing red
I am the one hiding
under your stairs
Fingers like snakes
and spiders in my hair
This is Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
In this town we call home
Everyone hail
to the pumpkin song
In this town
Don't we love it now?
Everybody's waiting
for the next surprise
Round that corner, man
Hiding in the trash cans
Something's waiting now to
pounce and how you'll scream
This is Halloween
Red and black and slimy green
Aren't you scared?
Well, that's just fine!
Say it once, say it twice
Take a chance
and roll the dice
Ride with the moon
in the dead of night
Everybody scream
In our town of Halloween
I am the clown
with the tear-away face
Here in a flash
and gone without a trace
I am the who
when you call, "Who's there?"
I am the wind
blowing through your hair
I am the shadow
on the moon at night
Filling your dreams
to the brim with fright
This is Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
Tender lumplings everywhere
Life's no fun
without a good scare
-  That's our job
-  But we're not mean
In our town of Halloween
In this town
Don't we love it now?
Everyone's waiting
for the next surprise
Skeleton Jack
might catch you in the back
And scream like a banshee
Make you jump
out of your skin
This is Halloween
Everybody scream
Would you please make way
for a very special guy?
Our man Jack
is king of the pumpkin patch
Everyone hail
to the Pumpkin King now
This is Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
[water hisses]
In this town we call home
Everyone hail
to the pumpkin song
[all harmonizing]
Halloween, Halloween
[cheering]
[cackling]
- It's over!
- We did it!
- Wasn't it terrifying?
- [both] What a night!
Great Halloween,
everybody!
I believe it was
our most horrible yet.
- Thank you, everyone.
- No. Thanks to you, Jack.
Without your
brilliant leadership...
- [Jack] Not at all, Mayor.
- You're such a scream, Jack!
You're a witch's
fondest dream!
You made walls fall, Jack!
[woman] Walls fall? You made
the very mountains crack, Jack!
The deadly nightshade
you slipped me wore off, Sally.
Let go! [gasps]
You're not ready
for so much excitement.
Yes, I am.
- You're coming with me!
- [straining] No, I'm not!
- Oh!
Come back here,
you foolish...
Ow! Oh!
Ooh, Jack, you make wounds
ooze and flesh crawl!
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much!
[Mayor] Hold it! We haven't
given out the prizes yet!
Our first award
goes to the vampires
for most blood drained
in a single evening.
- [applause]
- [Mayor] A second
and honorable mention
- goes to the fabulous...
- [sighs]
- ...Dark Lagoon Leeches.
- [playing down-tempo music]
- [coin clinks]
- Nice work, Bone Daddy!
Yeah, I guess so.
Just like last year.
And the year before that,
and the year before that.
- [gate creaks]
- [gasps]
There are few who deny
at what I do I am the best
For my talents
are renowned far and wide
When it comes to surprises
in the moonlit night
I excel without
ever even trying
With the slightest little
effort of my ghostlike charms
I have seen grown men
give out a shriek
With a wave of my hand
and a well-placed moan
I have swept the
very bravest off their feet
Yet, year after year
It's the same routine
And I grow so weary
of the sound of screams
And I, Jack
the Pumpkin King
Have grown so tired
of the same old thing
Oh, somewhere deep
Inside of these bones
An emptiness
Began to grow
There's something out there
Far from my home
A longing that
I've never known
I'm the master of fright
and a demon of light
And I'll scare you
right out of your pants
[ghosts moaning]
To a guy in Kentucky
I'm Mr. Unlucky
And I'm known
throughout England and France
And since I am dead
I can take off my head
To recite Shakespearean
quotations
No animal nor man
can scream like I can
With the fury
of my recitations
But who here
Would ever understand
That the Pumpkin King
with the skeleton grin
Would tire of his crown?
If they only understood
He'd give it all up
If he only could
[gasps]
Oh, there's an empty place
In my bones
That calls out for
Something unknown
The fame and praise
Come year after year
Does nothing for
These empty tears
Jack...
...I know how you feel.
[thunder rumbling]
[mechanical whirring]
[man] Sally!
You've come back.
- I had to.
- For this!
- Yes.
- Shall we, then?
That's twice this month
you've slipped deadly nightshade
- into my tea and run off.
- Three times.
You're mine, you know.
I made you
with my own hands!
You can make other creations.
I'm restless.
I can't help it.
It's a phase, my dear.
It'll pass.
We need to be patient,
that's all.
But I don't
want to be patient!
- [Zero barks]
- No, Zero, not now.
I'm not in the mood.
- [barks]
- All right.
Here you go, boy.
[growls]
[snoring]
- [car rattling]
- [moaning]
Morning, gents!
[humming This is Halloween]
- [doorbell screams]
- [continues humming]
- Jack? You home?
Jack? I've got the plans
for next Halloween.
I need to go over them with you
so we can get started.
Jack, please. I'm only
an elected official here.
I can't make decisions
by myself.
Jack, answer me!
[screams]
- He's not home.
- Where is he?
He hasn't
been home all night.
[groans]
[yawns] Where are we?
It's someplace new.
[barks]
What is this?
[gasps]
- [wind blowing]
- Whoa!
[barks]
[yells]
What's this? What's this?
There's color everywhere
What's this?
There's white
things in the air
What's this?
I can't believe my eyes
I must be dreaming
Wake up, Jack this isn't fair
-  What's this?
- [singing indistinctly]
What's this? What's this?
There's something very wrong
What's this?
There's people singing songs
What's this? The streets are
lined with creatures laughing
Everybody seems so happy
Have I possibly gone daffy?
What is this?
What's this?
There's children
throwing snowballs
instead of throwing heads
They're busy building toys
and absolutely no one's dead
There's frost in every window
Oh, I can't believe my eyes
And in my bones
I feel the warmth
That's coming from inside
Oh, look, what's this?
They're hanging mistletoe
They kiss?
Why, that looks
so unique, inspired
They're gathering around
Hearing stories
Roasting chestnuts on a fire
What's this?
What's this? In here
they've got a little tree
How queer
And who would
ever think, and why?
They're covering it
with tiny things
Electric lights on strings
And there's
a smile on everyone
Correct me if I'm wrong
This looks like fun
Could it be I got my wish?
What's this?
Oh, my, what now?
The children are asleep
But, look
there's nothing underneath
No ghouls
No witches to scream and
scare them or ensnare them
- [snoring]
-  Only little cozy things
Secure inside
their dreamland
[sighs]
What's this?
The monsters
are all missing
And the nightmares
can't be found
And in their place
there seems to be
Good feeling all around
Instead of screams
I swear I can hear
music in the air
The smell of cakes and pies
are absolutely everywhere
The sights, the sounds
They're everywhere
and all around
I've never
felt so good before
This empty place
inside of me is filling up
I simply cannot get enough
I want it, oh, I want it
I want it for my own
I've got to know
What is this place that
I've found? What is this?
Christmas Town? Hmm.
[whistle blows]
[man] Ho! Ho! Ho!
Hmm...
- This has never
happened before.
- It's suspicious.
- It's peculiar.
- [both] It's scary!
- Stand aside. Coming through.
- [growls]
[grunts]
We've got to find Jack.
There's only 365 days
left till next Halloween!
Three sixty-four.
Is there anywhere
we've forgotten to check?
I looked in
every mausoleum.
We opened the sarcophagi.
I tromped through
the pumpkin patch.
I peeked behind
the Cyclops' eye.
I did, but he wasn't there.
It's time to sound the alarms!
[alarm wails]
Frog's breath
will overpower any odor.
[croaks]
[coughs, gagging]
Bitter!
Worm's wart. [gasping]
Where's that worm's wart?
[man] Sally!
That soup ready yet?
Coming!
Lunch!
Ah, what's that?
[sniffing]
Worm's wart! Mmm.
And frog's breath.
What's wrong? I... I thought
you liked frog's breath.
Nothing's more suspicious
than frog's breath.
Until you taste it,
I won't swallow a spoonful.
- I'm not hungry.
- [spoon clatters]
- Oops.
- You want me to starve.
An old man, like me, who
hardly has strength as it is.
Me, to whom
you owe your very life!
Don't be silly.
[slurping] Mmm!
See? Scrumptious.
[gulping rapidly]
Did anyone think
to dredge the lake?
[sighs] This morning.
[indistinct barking]
- Hear that?
- What?
- Shhh!
- [barking continues]
- Zero!
- [barking]
[all yelling, shouting]
Where have you been?
Call a town meeting and
I'll tell everyone all about it.
- When?
- Immediately!
Town meeting!
Town meeting tonight!
- [snoring]
- [Mayor] Town meeting!
Town meeting tonight!
[all chattering indistinctly]
- [gasps]
- [chuckles]
Listen, everyone.
I want to tell you
about Christmas Town.
There were objects
so peculiar
They were not
to be believed
All around things
to tantalize my brain
It's a world unlike anything
I've ever seen
And as hard as I tried
I can't seem to describe
Like a most
improbable dream
But you must believe
when I tell you this
It's as real as my skull
and it does exist
Here, let me show you.
- [all gasping]
- Oooh.
This is a thing
called a present
-  The whole thing
starts with a box
-  A box?
-  Is it steel?
-  Are there locks?
Is it filled
with a pox?
A pox?
How delightful, a pox
If you please.
Just a box with
bright colored paper
And the whole thing's
topped with a bow
-  A bow?
-  But why?
How ugly! What's in it?
That's the point of the thing
Not to know
-  It's a bat! It's a rat!
-  Will it bend?
Will it break?
Perhaps it's the head
that I found in the lake
Listen now
You don't understand
That's not the point
of Christmas Land
Now, pay attention.
We pick up
an oversized sock
And hang it
like this on the wall
Oh, yes
Does it still have a foot?
Let me see
Let me look
Is it rotted and
covered with gook?
Let me explain.
There's no foot inside
but candy
Or sometimes
it's filled with small toys
-  Small toys? Do they snap?
-  Or explode in the sack?
Perhaps they spring out
and scare girls and boys
What a splendid idea
This Christmas sounds fun
I fully endorse it
Let's try it at once
Everyone, please
Now, not so fast
There's something here
that you don't quite grasp
[all chattering indistinctly]
Well, I may as well
give them what they want.
And the best, I must confess
I have saved for the last
For the ruler of this
Christmas Land
Is a fearsome king
with a deep, mighty, voice
Least that's what
I've come to understand
And I've also heard it told
that he's something to behold
Like a lobster
huge and red
When he sets out to sleigh
with his rain gear on
Carting bulging sacks
with his big great arms
That is so
I've heard it said
And on a dark, cold night
under full moonlight
He flies into a fog
like a vulture in the sky
And they call him
Sandy Claws
- [applause]
- [cackles]
Well, at least
they're excited
But they don't understand
That special
kind of feeling
In Christmas Land
Oh, well.
[animal howls]
Hmm.
Hmm...
There's got to be a logical way
to explain this Christmas thing.
You've poisoned me for the
last time, you wretched girl!
[sighs deeply]
- [doorbell chimes]
- Oh, my head!
The door is open!
- Hello?
- Jack Skellington!
Up here, my boy!
Doctor, I need
to borrow some equipment.
Is that so?
Whatever for?
I'm conducting
a series of experiments.
How perfectly marvelous!
Curiosity killed the cat,
you know.
I know.
Come on into the lab and
we'll get you all fixed up.
Hmm. Experiments?
[Jack] Zero! I'm home!
Interesting reaction,
but what does it mean?
[Sally thudding]
[band playing up-tempo music]
You can come out now
if you promise to behave.
Sally?
Sally!
- Oooh! Gone again!
- [lantern crashes]
[chalk scraping]
Oh!
[crowing]
Something's up with Jack
Don't know if we're ever
going to get him back
He's all alone up there
Locked away inside
-  Never says a word
-  Hope he hasn't died
Something's up with Jack
Christmas time
is buzzing in my skull
Will it let me be?
I cannot tell
There're so many things
I cannot grasp
When I think I've got it
Then at last
Through my
bony fingers it does slip
Like a snowflake
in a fiery grip
Something here
I'm not quite getting
Though I try
I keep forgetting
Like a memory
long since past
Here in an instant
gone in a flash
What does it mean?
In these little bric-a-brac
A secret's
waiting to be cracked
These dolls and toys
confuse me so
Confound it all
I love it though
Simple objects
nothing more
But something's
hidden through a door
Though I do not
have the key
Something's here
I cannot see
What does it mean?
[doll plays a tune]
- [squeaks]
- [snorts]
I've read these
Christmas books so many times
I know the stories
and I know the rhymes
I know the
Christmas carols all by heart
My skull's so full
It's tearing me apart
As often as I've read them
Something's wrong
So hard to put
my bony finger on
Or, perhaps, it's really
not as deep
As I've been led to think
Am I trying much too hard?
Of course
I've been too close to see
The answer's
right in front of me
Right in front of me
It's simple, really
very clear
Like music
drifting in the air
Invisible, but everywhere
Just because
I cannot see it
Doesn't mean
I can't believe it
You know, I think
this Christmas thing
Is not as tricky
as it seems
And why should
they have all the fun?
It should belong to anyone
Not anyone, in fact, but me
Why, I could
make a Christmas tree
And there's no reason
I can find
I couldn't handle
Christmas time
I bet I could
improve it, too
And that's exactly
what I'll do
[cackles]
Eureka!
This year,
Christmas will be ours!
[all cheer]
[Mayor]
Patience, everyone.
Jack has a special job
for each of you.
- Dr. Finkelstein!
- [wheelchair whirring]
[Mayor] Your Christmas
assignment is ready.
Dr. Finkelstein
to the front of the line!
[cooing]
What kind of noise is that
for a baby to make?
- Perhaps it can be improved?
- No problem!
I knew it!
Doctor,
thank you for coming.
We need some of these.
Hmm... Their construction should
be exceedingly simple, I think.
How horrible
our Christmas will be.
No. How jolly!
Oh, how jolly
our Christmas will be.
Oh! Hey! [growls]
- What are you doing here?
- Jack sent for us.
- Specifically.
- By name.
- Lock.
- Shock.
Barrel.
Jack. Jack!
It's Boogie's boys.
Aah! Halloween's
finest trick-or-treaters!
The job I have for you
is top secret.
It requires craft,
cunning, mischief.
And we thought you
didn't like us, Jack!
Absolutely no one is to
know about it. Not a soul.
[whispering] Now,
you must go to the forest.
In the forest
you will see a tree.
...Christmas Town.
Ow!
- Hmm.
- And one more thing.
Leave that no account
Oogie Boogie out of this!
Whatever you say, Jack.
- Of course, Jack.
- Wouldn't dream of it, Jack.
Kidnap Mr. Sandy Claws?
-  I wanna do it
-  Let's draw straws
-  Jack said
we should work together
-  Three of a kind
-  Birds of a feather
-  Now and for ever
La, la, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la
Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Lock him up real tight
Throw away the key and then
turn off all the lights
First we're going
to set some bait inside
a nasty trap and wait
When he comes
a-sniffing
We will snap the trap
and close the gate
Wait, I've got
a better plan
To catch this
big, red lobster man
Pop him in a boiling pot
When he's done
we'll butter him up
Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Throw him in a box
Bury him for 90 years
Then see if he talks
Then Mr. Oogie Boogie Man
Can take the whole
thing over then
He'll be so pleased
I do declare
-  That he will cook him rare
- [laughing]
[smacking lips]
I say that we take a cannon
Aim it at his door and then
Knock three times
and when he answers
Sandy Claws
will be no more
You're so stupid
think now
If we blow him
up to smithereens
We may lose some pieces
and then Jack will
Beat us black and green
Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Tie him in a bag
Throw him in the ocean
Then see if he is sad
Because Mr. Oogie Boogie
is the meanest guy around
If I were on his boogie list
I'd get out of town
He'll be so pleased
by our success
That he'll reward us, too
I'll bet
Perhaps he'll
make his special brew
Of snake and spider stew
We're his little henchmen and
we take our job with pride
We do our best to please him
and stay on his good side
I wish my cohorts
weren't so dumb
-  I'm not the dumb one
-  You're no fun
- Shut up!
- Make me.
I've got something, listen
This one is real good
you'll see
We'll send
a present to his door
Upon there'll
be a note to read
Now, in the box, we'll wait
and hide until his curiosity
Entices him to look inside
Then we'll have him
One, two, three
Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Beat him with a stick
Lock him up for 90 years
See what makes him tick
Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Chop him into bits
Mr. Oogie Boogie
is sure to get his kicks
Kidnap the Sandy Claws
See what we will see
Lock him in a cage
and then throw away the key
Sandy Claws, huh?
- [cackling]
- [snake hisses]
It goes something like this.
[playing Jingle Bells]
How about it?
Think you can you manage?
A-one and a-two
and a-three and...
[plays Jingle Bells off-key]
- Next!
- Fantastic!
Now, why don't
you all practice on that,
and we'll be
in great shape!
Sally, I need your help
more than anyone's.
You certainly do, Jack.
I had the most terrible vision.
That's splendid!
No. It was about
your Christmas.
- There was smoke and fire!
- That's not my Christmas.
My Christmas is filled
with laughter and joy,
and this!
My Sandy Claws outfit.
I want you to make it.
Jack, please listen to me.
It's going to be a disaster!
How could it be?
Just follow the pattern.
This part's red.
The trim is white.
- It's a mistake, Jack.
- Now, don't be modest.
Who else is clever enough
to make my Sandy Claws outfit?
- [Mayor] Next!
- I have every
confidence in you.
But it seems wrong to me.
Very wrong.
This device is called
a nutcracker.
- We caught him! We got him!
- Perfect!
Open it up! Quickly!
- [gasps]
- [sniffs]
That's not Sandy Claws.
- It isn't?
- Who is it?
[sniffs]
Bunny!
[whimpering]
Not Sandy Claws.
Take him back!
We followed
your instructions.
- We went through the door.
- Which? There's more than one.
Sandy Claws is behind
the door shaped like this.
- I told you!
- [choking, grunting]
[all arguing]
- [roars]
- [all gasp]
I'm very sorry
for the inconvenience, sir.
Take him home first.
And apologize again!
Be careful with Sandy Claws
when you fetch him!
Treat him nicely!
- Got it!
- We'll get it right next time!
You will be
a decided improvement
over that treacherous Sally.
Master! The plans.
Excellent, Igor.
[chattering indistinctly]
This time
Making Christmas
Making Christmas is so fine
It's ours this time and won't
the children be surprised?
It's ours this time
-  Making Christmas
-  Time to give them
something fun
They'll talk about
for years to come
Let's have a cheer
from everyone
It's time to party
Making Christmas
Sticks and mice
get wrapped up so nice
With spider legs
and pretty bows
It's ours this time
All together, that and this
With all our tricks
We're making Christmas time
Here comes Jack!
I don't believe
What's happening to me
My hopes, my dreams
My fantasies
[cackling]
Won't they be impressed?
I am a genius
See how I transformed
this old rat
Into a most delightful hat
Hmm...
My compliments
from me to you
On this your most
intriguing hat
Consider though
this substitute
A bat in place
of this old rat
No, no, that's all wrong
This thing will
never make a present
It's been dead for too long
Try something fresher
Something pleasant
Try again, don't give up
All together, that and this
With all our tricks
We're making Christmas time
This time, this time
Making Christmas
It's almost here
and we can't wait
So ring the bells
and celebrate
'Cause when the full moon
starts to climb
We'll all sing out
"It's Christmas time!"
[man] Kathleen.
Bobby. Susie.
Yes, Susie's been nice.
Nice. Nice.
Naughty. Nice. Nice. Nice.
There are hardly any
naughty children this year.
- [doorbell chimes]
- Now, who could that be?
- [all] Trick or treat!
- Huh?
Yaah!
You don't look like yourself,
Jack. Not at all!
Isn't that wonderful?
It couldn't be more wonderful!
But you're the Pumpkin King.
Not anymore!
I feel so much better now!
Jack, I know you think
something's missing, but...
- Ow!
- Sorry.
You're right.
Something is missing.
But what?
I've got the beard, the coat,
the boots, the belt...
- Jack! This time we bagged him!
- This time we really did!
- He sure is big, Jack.
- And heavy!
- Let me out!
- [all exclaim]
Sandy Claws. In person.
What a pleasure
to meet you!
Why, you have hands.
You don't have claws at all!
- Where am I?
- Surprised, aren't you?
I knew you would be.
You don't need to have another
worry about Christmas this year.
- What?
- Consider this
a vacation, Sandy.
A reward. It's your turn
to take it easy.
But there must be
some mistake.
See that he's comfortable.
Just a second, fellas.
Of course!
- That's what
I'm missing. Thanks.
- But...
You just can't...
Hold on! Where are we going now?
Oh, ho, ho! No...
This is worse than I thought.
Much worse.
I know!
[man] Me on vacation?
On Christmas Eve?!
- Where are we taking him?
- To Oogie Boogie, of course.
There isn't anywhere
more comfortable than that.
Jack said to
make him comfortable.
Yes, he did.
[man] Haven't you heard
of peace on earth
and goodwill toward men?
[all] No! [chortling]
- This will stop Jack!
- [saw buzzing]
What a joy to think
of all we'll have in common!
We'll have conversations
worth having!
- [kids laughing]
- Don't do this!
Naughty children
never get any presents.
I think he
might be too big!
- [moans]
- No, he's not.
If he can go down a chimney,
he can fit down here!
- [grunting]
- [metal clanging]
[shouts]
[squeaking]
Well, well, well
What have we here?
Sandy Claws, huh?
Ooh, I'm really scared
So you're the one everybody's
talkin' about  [laughs]
You're jokin', you're jokin'
I can't believe my eyes
You're jokin' me
you gotta be
This can't be
the right guy
He's ancient, he's ugly
I don't know which is worse
I might just split a seam now
if I don't die laughin' first
Mr. Oogie Boogie says
There's trouble close at hand
You'd better
pay attention now
'Cause I'm
the Boogie Man
And if you aren't shakin'
There's somethin' very wrong
'Cause this may be
the last time
You hear the Boogie song
-  Ooh
I'm the Oogie Boogie Man
Release me now or you must
face the dire consequences
The children
are expecting me
So, please
come to your senses
You're jokin', you're jokin'
I can't believe my ears
Would someone
shut this fella up?
I'm drownin'
in my tears
It's funny, I'm laughin'
You really are too much
And now, with your permission
I'm going to do my stuff
- What are you going to do?
- The best I can.
Whoa!
The sound of rollin' dice
to me is music in the air
'Cause I'm a gamblin'
Boogie Man
Although I don't play fair
It's much more fun
I must confess
When lives
are on the line
Not mine, of course
But yours, old boy
Now, that'd be
just fine
Release me fast
or you will have to answer
for this heinous act
Oh, brother, you're something
You put me in a spin
You aren't comprehending
the position that you're in
It's hopeless
you're finished
You haven't
got a prayer
'Cause I'm
Mr. Oogie Boogie
And you ain't
goin' nowhere
[laughs]
[all laughing]
[band plays off-key music]
[chattering , laughter]
[all cheering]
Think of us as you soar,
triumphantly, through the sky,
outshining every star,
your silhouette
a dark blot on the moon.
You, who are our pride,
you, who are our glory,
you, who have frightened
millions into an early grave.
You, who have...
...devastated the souls
of the... living!
- Oh, no. We can't
take off in this.
- [all groan]
The reindeer can't see an inch
in front of their noses.
- Phew!
- This fog's as thick as...
- Jellied brains.
- Or thicker!
There go all of my hopes,
my precious plans,
my glorious dreams.
- There goes Christmas.
- [all moan]
- [Zero barking]
- No, Zero. Down, boy.
My, what a
brilliant nose you have.
The better to light my way!
To the head of the team, Zero.
- [all cheering]
- We're off!
[whip cracking]
Wait, Jack. No!
- Ho, ho, ho! [laughs]
- [whip cracks]
Goodbye, Jack.
My dearest Jack.
Oh, how I hope
my premonition is wrong.
I sense there's
something in the wind
That feels
like tragedy's at hand
And though
I'd like to stand by him
Can't shake
this feeling that I have
The worst is just
around the bend
And does he notice
My feelings for him?
And will he see
How much he means to me?
I think it's not to be
What will become
of my dear friend?
Where will his actions
lead us then?
Although I'd like
to join the crowd
In their enthusiastic cloud
Try as I may
it doesn't last
And will we ever
End up together?
No, I think not
It's never to become
For I am not the one
Ho, ho, ho!
[laughs]
[loud thump]
Santa!
[boy gasps]
Santa?
Merry Christmas!
And what is your name?
- Uh... uh, uh...
- That's all right.
I have a special
present for you anyway.
There you go, sonny.
[laughs]
[woman] And what did
Santa bring you, honey?
[both screaming]
Merry Christmas!
[phone ringing]
- Hello. Police.
- [woman screaming]
Attacked by Christmas toys?
That's strange.
That's the second
toy complaint we've had.
[chuckling]
[laughing]
[growling]
[giggling]
Wee!
- [quacking]
- [screaming]
Mom! Dad! Help!
[screaming]
[man screams]
[woman screams]
[both screaming]
[woman screaming]
[screaming]
[cackling]
You're welcome, one and all!
- [phones ringing]
- Where'd you spot him?
Fast as we can, ma'am.
Police. I know. A skeleton.
Keep calm. Turn off the lights.
Make sure doors are locked.
Hello. Police.
[woman] Reports are pouring in
from all over the globe
that an impostor is shamelessly
impersonating Santa Claus,
mocking and mangling
this joyous holiday.
Authorities assure us that,
at this moment,
military units are mobilizing
to stop the perpetrator
of this heinous crime.
Jack. Someone has to help Jack!
Where did they take
that Sandy Claws?
...come back
and save Christmas.
[alarm sounding]
Look, Zero. Searchlights.
They're celebrating!
They're thanking us
for doing such a good job!
Whoa! Careful down there.
You almost hit us!
- [Zero barks]
- It's OK, Zero. Head higher!
Are you a gamblin' man,
Sandy?
Let's play!
Mmm?
My, my!
What have we here?
[whispers] I'll get you
out of here.
Lovely!
Tickle, tickle, tickle.
[laughing]
What?! You try
to make a dupe out of me?!
[roaring]
[shrieks]
Who's next on my list?
Ah! Little Harry and Jordan.
Won't they be surprised?
They're trying to hit us! Zero!
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all a good night!
[all moaning]
[howls]
I knew this Christmas thing
was a bad idea.
I felt it in my gut.
Terrible news, folks!
The worst tragedy of our times!
Jack has been blown
to smithereens!
Terrible, terrible news!
Attention. Attention, citizens.
Terrible news.
There's still no sign
of Santa Claus.
Although the impostor
has been shot down,
it looks like Christmas will
have to be canceled this year.
I repeat, the impostor
has been shot down,
but there's still no sign
of the real Santa.
[whimpers]
What have I done?
How could I
Be so blind?
All is lost
Where was I?
Spoiled all
Everything's
Gone all wrong
What have I done?
Find a deep cave to hide in
In a million years
they'll find me
Only dust
And a plaque that reads
"Here lies poor old Jack"
But I never intended
All this madness, never
And nobody
really understood
Well, how could they?
That all I ever wanted was
to bring them something great
Why does nothing
ever turn out like it should?
Well, what the heck?
I went and did my best
And, by God, I really
tasted something swell
And for a moment
Why, I even touched the sky
And at least I left some
stories they can tell, I did
And for the first time
since I don't remember when
I felt just like
my old bony self again
And I, Jack
the Pumpkin King
That's right
I am the Pumpkin King
[cackling]
And I just can't wait
until next Halloween
'Cause I've got
some new ideas
That will really
make them scream
And, by God, I'm really
going to give it all my might
Uh-oh.
I hope there's still time
to set things right
- Sandy Claws!
- [growls]
You wait till Jack
hears about this.
By the time he's through
with you, you'll be lucky...
The King of Halloween
has been blown to smithereens!
Skeleton Jack
is now a pile of dust!
[gasps]
Come on, Zero.
Christmas isn't over yet.
What's that you were sayin'
about luck, rag doll?
- [Sally] Help! Help!
- [growling]
Shhh!
[Oogie] Seven!
It's Oogie's turn
to boogie now.
- [screams]
- One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven!
[laughs]
[Santa] This can't be happening!
Ashes to ashes
and dust to dust.
Oh, I'm feeling weak...
with hunger!
One more roll of the dice
oughta do it! [laughs]
What? Snake eyes?!
[grunts]
Eleven! [laughs]
Looks like I won the jackpot!
Bye-bye, doll face
- and sandman!
- [screaming]
What the...?
- [shrieks]
- Hello, Oogie.
Jack! But they said
you were dead.
You must be double dead!
Oh!
[laughs]
Well, come on, bone man!
[barking]
[moaning] Ha!
Fire!
[grunts]
Jack, look out!
So long, Jack! [laughs]
How dare you treat
my friends so shamefully!
Now look what you've done!
My bugs! My bugs!
[insects continue chittering]
Forgive me, Mr. Claws.
I'm afraid I've made a
terrible mess of your holiday.
Bumpy sleigh ride, Jack?
The next time you
get the urge to take over
someone else's holiday,
I'd listen to her.
She's the only one
who makes any sense
around this insane asylum!
- Skeletons and boogie men!
- I hope there's still time.
To fix Christmas?
Of course there is.
I'm Santa Claus!
He'll fix things, Jack.
He knows what to do.
How did you
get down here, Sally?
I... I was trying to...
Well, I wanted to...
- To...
- To help me?
- I couldn't let you just...
- Sally...
I can't believe
I never realized that you...
- [Mayor] Jack! Jack!
- [Lock] Here he is!
- Alive!
- Just like we said!
Grab a hold, my boy!
Whoa!
[woman] Good news. Santa Claus,
the one and only,
has finally been spotted.
Old Saint Nick appears to be
traveling at supersonic speed.
He's setting things right,
bringing joy and cheer
wherever he goes.
Yes, folks, Kris Kringle
has pulled it out of the bag
and delivered Christmas
to excited children
all over the world.
- [snoring]
- [sirens wailing]
[all vocalizing]
- Jack!
- Jack's back!
- Jack?
- Jack's OK!
- He's all right!
- It's Jack!
Jack's OK
And he's back
OK
He's all right
Let's shout
Make a fuss
Scream it out
Wee!
Jack is back
Now, everyone sing
In our town of Halloween
- It's great to be home!
- [Santa] Ho, ho, ho!
Happy Halloween!
Merry Christmas!
-  What's this?
I haven't
got a clue
-  What's this?
-  Why, it's completely new
-  Must be a Christmas thing
-  What's this?
-  It's really very strange
This is Halloween, Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
What's this? What's this?
[all giggling]
Careful,
my precious jewel.
[Jack]
My dearest friend.
If you don't mind
I'd like to join you
By your side
Where we can gaze
Into the stars
[both]  And sit together
Now and forever
For it is plain
As anyone can see
We're simply meant to be