- THE TRUE STORY OF SABINA SPIELREIN
CAME TO LIGHT ONLY RECENTLY... -
...THANKS TO THE DEDICATION
OF SCHOLARS AND RESEARCHERS... -
...WORKING IN VARIOUS
PARTS OF THE WORLD. -
- THIS FILM IS IN MEMORY
OF AN EXCEPTIONAL WOMAN... -
...AND THOSE
WHO WANTED TO DO HER JUSTICE. -
Richard,
I haven't run away...
...but I wanted to be alone
for my last meeting with Sabina.
There's something
I haven't told you.
My real name
is Marie Franquin Spielrein.
I was born in France, but my family
originally came from Russia.
My great-grandparents managed
to get out when Stalin came to power.
For years I've been longing
to come to Russia...
...to learn all I could
about Sabina Spielrein.
You'll undoubtedly wonder, when you
hear this message, if we're related...
...since we have
the same family name.
Maybe we are,
but that's hardly important.
I feel by now...
...Sabina and I
are closely related in our souls.
- ZURICH, 1904-
My head! I've left my head
in the carriage!
We really don't know
what to do, Professor.
She's been like this
for a year now...
...ever since her little sister,
Irina, died from pneumonia.
She's getting worse every day.
We've come
all the way from Russia.
We thought if we brought her here
to you, maybe you could help us.
I won't do it again!
I won't, I promise!
I won't do it again,
please believe me...
...but don't keep me here,
please don't keep me here!
No... no... no!
You filthy old pig!
Tell your slut
to get her hands off me!
You bastards!
I'm not your whore!
(Guardian angel... )
(... my mother and father have gone
back to Russia and left me here... )
(... frightened.
I don't want to be alone.)
(I shall stop eating... )
(... that way when they come back
all they'll find will be my clothes... )
(... to my shoes.)
(I'm sorry I shan't be here
to see their faces!)
(To my mother, I leave the notes
of Tumbalalaika, my favourite song.)
(To my father, I leave nothing.)
(What can grow without rain?)
(What can burn for years
without end?)
(A stone can grow without rain... )
(... but only love can burn
for years without end.)
So much has been written
and recorded...
...about Sabina's treatment
in Zurich.
But no-one's ever bothered
to find out what happened to her...
...after she returned to Russia.
That's why
I wanted to come to Moscow...
...to discover some facts
about the White Nursery...
...the infant school
where she was last seen.
I've often wondered
what fascinated you about Sabina.
Certainly I never imagined
that we'd meet...
...as a result of a theft.
(There are rabbits...
no, hares, in my room.)
(They're all black and they've got
long ears like sheep!)
(I get into bed and they're
already there waiting for me.)
(As soon as they see me,
they start laughing. I yell at them:)
(..."I'm tired, leave me alone!
I don't want to play any more!".)
Good morning, Miss Spielrein.
I'm Dr. Jung.
Professor Bleuler has put me
in charge of your case.
No, gently.
Go away! Let me die!
Leave us.
- Why do you want to die?
- Because I'm wicked!
That's hardly reason enough.
Anyway, I'm here to stop you.
So, which of us do you think
is going to win, Miss Spielrein?
I'd like to try
a new treatment with you.
Nothing forced.
No cold showers...
...no shackling you to the bed.
It consists essentially
in letting you talk.
Whatever comes into your head.
You talk, I listen.
Shall I tell you
what they do on Mars?
Please.
What do they do on Mars?
They don't have babies.
Why not?
Because no-one makes love on Mars!
How do you know that?
I've been there.
I wish I'd been to Mars.
No-one ever takes any notice
when I say things like that.
Do you like children,
Miss Spielrein?
Tell me...
...don't be afraid.
You can't cure me, Doctor.
Why not?
Because you are well,
and I am not.
- So?
- So...
So you can't understand me.
Do all Russian girls
read French newspapers?
Excusez-moi, je n'ai pas le temps!
- Sorry, what?
- Leave me alone!
I don't care if you're Russian
or you're French.
What you are is a thief!
Does the name Sabina Spielrein
mean anything to you?
Give it back!
My name's Richard Fraser...
...I teach history
at Glasgow University.
I think your acquisition
might be quite useful to me.
Can I at least have a look at it?
- And if not, you'll report me?
- Well, it's an idea.
Why don't we go and have a drink
somewhere and talk about that?
- Do I have a choice?
- Yes, tea or coffee!
I'm sorry if I came on a bit strong,
but I'm a historian.
Anytime a document is removed
from the official archives...
...it's lost forever.
- Monsieur Historian...
...here in Russia anytime a document is
consigned to the official archives...
...it is lost forever!
Look...
...I'm doing research
into the former Soviet Union.
I think the addition of psychoanalysis
could be very interesting.
I have an idea...
You speak Russian and English, and you
obviously know your way around.
- I need an interpreter...
- You want a thief to work for you?
Well, beggars can't be choosers.
Anyway, you can go on with your own
research. We can pool our resources.
It's a nice idea...
...but my research grant
was not exactly generous...
...and I've used it up.
I go back to Paris on Saturday.
Right, I'm not suggesting
you work for free. I'll pay you.
How much?
Board and lodging,
and six hundred dollars a week.
You sing beautifully.
I like sculpting myself, you know.
But I prefer stone to clay.
You're very talented.
Where did you learn?
My uncle taught me. In Russia.
- Is he a sculptor?
- No, he's an alchemist.
- He taught me how to make paper
out of rags. - Did he just?
I'm rather keen on doing
experiments that are somewhat...
...unorthodox.
- What kind of experiments? - I tend
to sense things before they happen.
Psychic intuition, if you like.
I've lost my legs.
Do you often fall like that?
- Who's that woman spying on us?
- What woman?
There's a woman at that window.
She's staring at me.
That's my apartment.
I don't see anyone there.
So, Miss Spielrein...
...have you ever
fallen like that before?
It happened once.
When?
My cat had some kittens.
I said I wanted to be like her...
...and my father lost his temper.
My mother said there was nothing wrong
with me wanting to have children.
After all,
I was a woman, wasn't I?
Don't be frightened.
I just wanted to show you
how I would have nursed my kittens.
Guardian angel...
...my doctor is fair-haired
and handsome...
...even more so
when he smokes his pipe.
Tomorrow I shall ask him
if he is married.
I saw you in the garden
this morning with your new patient.
- What's wrong with her?
- The clinical diagnosis is hysteria...
...but there's more to it.
Why don't you speak to Freud?
This is the first time
you've used his method, isn't it?
Yeah... Yes, I'll write to him.
Sometimes I feel
you allow your patients...
...to affect you rather too deeply.
It's the only way I know
how to heal.
Perhaps she doesn't want
to grow up.
Wants to be a child again.
I suspect there's
some unresolved Oedipal complex.
Makes her feel so guilty
she actually wants to be punished.
The two of you should get along
well together then.
I was thinking of you and Freud.
I mean, he's virtually
appointed you his son and heir...
...and you look upon him
as a father.
I wonder if you'll end up
trying to kill each other.
- Good morning.
Professor Fraser
booked a room for me...
...Marie Franquin.
- Marie Franquin...
Yes, Room 122.
I'm sorry.
What's going on?
- Did you ask for communicating
rooms? - Of course not!
Okay...
- Well, we can get you another one.
- If you want...
I mean, I'm not dangerous.
Anyway, we can always keep it locked.
Listen, while you're here...
...could you translate
page 138 and 139?
- Yes, of course. - Thanks,
and can you not smoke here...
...because the smelI'll come through.
- Oh yes, I'm sorry.
- Thanks. See you later.
- See you.
Chair.
Chair?
Don't think, just respond.
- Chair.
- Table.
- Soft.
- Warm.
Lake.
Water.
- Snow.
- Purity.
- Dog.
- Cat.
You know, you look like
a wild cat sometimes, Dr. Jung.
- Russia.
- Home.
I didn't know
this could be so much fun.
Just one word, please.
- French.
- Wife!
Wouldn't it be funny if your wife
ran off with a Frenchman?
One word.
Sabina.
Dies.
Father.
Punishment.
Sister.
Cemetery.
It must be so cold in there!
My father used to beat us
when we were naughty.
Go on. Father.
Come on, Miss Spielrein.
Make the effort.
- Father. - Why should I tell you
anything about myself?
You never tell me anything
about yourself!
Well...
...do you think it's right
to bring the dead back to life?
Look me in the eye, Dr. Jung!
- What's wrong?
- I have to go.
- Why?
- The Russian girl.
I dreamt she ran away.
Darling, come back to bed,
it's only a dream!
There she is,
sleeping peacefully!
Here...
...the translation you wanted.
- Oh, thanks.
Why are you so interested
in this Sabina Spielrein?
In German,
Spielrein means "fair play".
So?
History has forgotten her,
and that's not fair.
Yes, but why
is it so important to you?
I suppose, in a way...
...that's what I'd like to be,
a woman who plays fair.
We can't go on feeding you this way.
Your veins can't stand it.
- It's gone on long enough.
- Do you want them to sack me?
Because that's what'll happen.
Why should they blame you?
They'd see your death
as proof of my failure...
...the failure of my method.
I don't want you to suffer
because of me.
Well then...
...we should go somewhere a little
more cheerful for our session today.
So why don't you get dressed...
...and come with me?
- Two hot chocolates and some cake
and pastries, please. - Yes, sir.
The other day you complained that I
never told you anything about myself.
Apart from my wife,
no-one has ever seen this.
I keep a diary, too.
I take it everywhere with me.
The first girl...
...I was ever attracted to
was young, Jewish.
She had a long dark braid
that hung down over her shoulder.
- I'm Jewish too, you know.
- I know.
Now I feel it's fate
that my first patient should be.
- Do you believe in premonitions?
- I don't believe, I know.
I wrote my doctoral thesis
on so called "occult phenomena".
Do you remember the other day
in the garden I was telling you...
Did I ever tell you
my grandfather was a rabbi?
He was an expert on the cabala.
He foretold the exact hour
and day of his death!
Well, my grandfather...
...had a special armchair
set aside for his dead wife...
...and every day he spent
at least an hour...
...talking to her spirit!
Really?
Do you really
care about me, Doctor?
If I didn't,
I couldn't treat you.
No, I mean...
...do you care about me from head
to toe? - From head to toe.
Do you love me, Doctor?
All clinical cases...
...in one way or another,
involve an element of love.
Can I tell you
one of my secrets, then?
Sometimes, when I'm alone...
...I touch myself.
I'm terribly ashamed.
There's really no reason to be.
Many people do.
You too?
Certainly. Me too. Sometimes.
Tiring day?
No more than usual.
Were you at the hospital
all afternoon?
No, I had to go
and see a colleague about a case.
He wants my advise
on a patient of his.
What about your Russian girl?
How's the treatment going?
Much better.
She's finally started to eat.
It just occurred to me
that we never buy any cakes.
And with all the cake shops
there are in Zurich...
Anyway, I'm pregnant...
...and we never indulge!
Sabina!
Go away!
I don't want to see anyone!
Open it, Sabina!
Sabina! Open the door!
- What's going on?
- She's blocked the door!
Open it!
Take her to the second floor!
So much for the Jung method!
What in God's name
were you thinking of?
- You've destroyed months of hard
work! - She tried to kill herself!
- Release her.
- Professor Bleuler said...
I said release her!
Stupidity!
I leave for a few weeks
and we return to the dark ages!
Leave us!
- Go away, traitor!
- Sabina, listen to me.
I am not responsible
for what happened over here.
No, I did not abandon you!
I was called up!
In Switzerland we have to do
military service once a year.
Why did you try to kill yourself?
No-one here loves me.
From now on, I, and I alone,
will look after you.
Swear to me!
I swear.
Then let go of me.
My will.
When I'm dead, I want
Dr. Jung to have my head.
Only he is to open and dissect it.
I want my body to be cremated...
...and the ashes to be scattered beneath
an oak tree on which is written:
..."I too was a human being".
What's that?
My soul.
Your soul?
I've had it since I was a child.
Primitive men used to think
that stones had souls, too.
I want you to be the keeper...
...of my soul.
The keeper of your soul?
Silence! Silence!
You see what your patient
is up to, Dr. Jung?
Tell her to stop!
Miss Spielrein, please...
With pleasure, Dr. Jung!
(I'm going
to be discharged today... )
(... after being in hospital
for almost a year.)
(I've started eating regularly... )
(... and even having periods again.)
(Dr. Jung said
it would be enough if I see him... )
(... twice a week from now on... )
(... though I'd like
to see him more often.)
Would you like to tell me
one of your dreams?
We're going to get bored
always talking about mine.
Why don't you
tell me one of yours?
I'm not sure I should,
as your doctor...
...but, as it's you,
I'll make an exception.
I'll tell you a dream
I had last night.
There was this great big horse,
a stallion.
It was kicking and bucking.
Some men were trying
to get him under control...
...but he was having none of it.
A little foal
trotted by all peacefully.
He suddenly calmed down.
Stallion.
Trainer.
Disciplined.
Disciple.
- Master.
- Freud.
Freud frightens you...
...and you feel you have to behave like
a good little foal when he's around.
Maybe.
It could be that your dream was
a symptom of your dissatisfaction.
You see?
Our roles have become reversed.
What kind of dissatisfaction
did you have in mind?
Your sexual dissatisfaction.
Have I made you cross, Dr. Jung?
You see love everywhere,
don't you?
It's the force
that drives the world.
You said yourself there could be
no cure without love.
Remember?
Time's up.
- Forgive me. Forgive me.
- For what?
At times
I can't quite control myself.
I am glad
it happens to doctors, too.
Why do you think
Judith killed Holofernes?
Surprised to see me here?
Because God ordered her to...
...to save her people.
First she seduces him,
then she cuts off his head.
Look at her expression.
Does she really look like someone
who's carrying out God's orders?
What are you suggesting,
Miss Spielrein?
Look carefully, Dr. Jung.
Her eyes, the sensuality
of her mouth...
Her exposed breasts...
Her bejewelled hand...
...which holds his head.
No...
...Judith did not kill Holofernes
to obey God.
Why then?
She killed him
because she loved him!
You know...
...sometimes you say things
that really rather shock me.
Do I?
As an explorer
of the unconscious...
...I shouldn't think
anything could shock you.
- What's it going to be?
- A trickster.
A mythological figure...
...bringer of light and chaos.
- What happened to that...
...Russian girl
you were so interested in?
She was discharged.
The treatment was a great success.
Bleuler asked me...
...to write a paper on the case
for the International Conference.
- Have you seen her since?
- No.
Why?
Doctor/patient bonds are difficult
to break sometimes, aren't they?
What have you done to your hair?
It's nice, isn't it?
Dr. Jung!
I hear you've enrolled
in the Faculty of Medicine.
Congratulations!
It's all thanks to you.
You suggested
I should study psychiatry...
...so I took you at your word.
Please, come in.
Oh, this is for you.
I thought you might be interested.
It's my study
of a young woman's dreams.
I'm sorry,
it's such a mess!
- This place is so...
- No, it's lovely!
Please, sit down.
You see...
...I keep your soul
with me always.
Am I the young woman
with the dreams?
- No, it isn't a patient of mine.
- Can I offer you something?
No, thank you, I just came round
to say hello, and...
You can't leave yet!
You've only just arrived.
Would you like to know
what I dreamt last night?
Please, tell me.
I think...
...I'd prefer to show you.
Show me?
A dream?
You know, you...
- You seem so...
...different?
Transformed.
Butterfly.
Beautiful.
Nature.
Nurture.
Kitten.
Kiss.
In my dream it wasn't
as beautiful as this.
You make me feel things.
Things I've never felt before.
You have to leave.
I know.
Will we ever get to spend
a whole night together?
How does one get to be so brave?
Your love has to be
stronger than your fear.
Bravo professor!
Yes.
- Please...
- Thanks.
This is the White House.
This is the Russian
Government Building.
This is not the White Nursery.
- Excuse me...
- What is it?
The White Nursery,
not the White House.
- Ah, the White Nursery?
- Yes.
Never heard of it.
He's never heard of it.
Come on! Sabina Spielrein's
White Nursery!
The International
Solidarity School!
It was the first infant school
in the world to use psychoanalysis!
You must have a record of it!
Here Moscow Archives,
and not British Museum.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Now what?
- I have an idea. Fuck you.
Bye bye!
So, what's your idea?
If you can't find things via official
channels, you do it yourself!
Dr. Jung...
...there's a Russian gentleman
asking for you.
- Did he give a name?
- No, he just said it's urgent.
- Well, send him in.
- Please...
I don't think
I've had the pleasure.
Are you sure, Dr. Jung?
I didn't want
anyone to recognise me.
Maybe you don't like me
dressed like this?
- Good afternoon.
Dr. Jung and Miss Spielrein.
- We booked two single rooms.
- No. A double room! Remember?
A double room with a double bed!
- Of course.
- A nice big double bed, please.
Yes, Madame.
You're so cold.
What's the matter?
I'm just so happy.
Then why are you crying?
Damned happiness!
That's what my mother used to say
when we were small.
She meant to say "blessed"...
...but I think she was right.
Damned happiness!
I want to have your baby!
Here, now.
I want to conceive a child!
What are you saying?
You're mad!
Of course I am!
It was you
who first diagnosed it!
But then you cured me...
...so now I'm not mad anymore!
(My dear Professor Freud... )
(... a former patient of mine... )
(... who I have always treated
with the greatest respect... )
(... is now threatening
to destroy my entire life... )
(... solely because I denied myself
the pleasure of giving her a child.)
(She has fallen in love with me.)
(I have become her father,
her lover, her husband.)
(What can I do?)
(Asking her to control herself
is hopeless!)
I know you'll say
it's my fault, Professor.
But logic and reason have never had
much effect on passion, have they?
I am guilty! Yes...
...guilty of having fallen victim...
...to my own desire!
But as you yourself said...
..."Iove is as close
as one can get to psychosis".
Love is madness!
So someone sent
an anonymous letter...
...to Sabina's parents...
...telling them
about her affair with Jung.
Yes.
So, who was it?
- Emma.
- It had to be.
- She wanted to save her marriage.
- How did they react?
Papa Spielrein
wrote Jung a letter, saying:
..."My daughter made a God
out of you..."
"...and you have behaved
like a wretched mortal".
What did Jung do?
He wrote him a nasty letter,
saying, in essence...
...since he had treated Sabina for
nothing, he had no right to complain.
Nice...
Okay... What did Sabina do?
She wrote to Freud,
asking for advice.
What did he say?
He told her to break off
their relationship immediately.
Freud didn't care about Sabina.
Jung had behaved very badly...
...but, at that time,
he was still Freud's pupil, so...
Well, he was also a man!
Come in! Why are you
standing there like that?
I came here to tell you...
...we have to end
our relationship.
Sabina, be reasonable.
- My wife...
- Emma doesn't want to lose you!
For the good of all of us,
I beg you.
Please, try to repress
your emotions.
Please, try to understand.
- We can't have a scandal!
- You should try to understand!
You're rejecting
the best part of yourself!
Our love's the most beautiful
thing in the world.
You love me because I saved you.
- Now I need you to help me.
- Help you?
This passion...
It will destroy me!
- It will destroy both of us!
- But isn't that glorious?
No, no! No, it's not!
- Please, listen to me...
- I am listening.
We can still see each other.
Maybe you can come to my house...
...and become friends with Emma.
- What?
That's despicable!
Sometimes one must be
in order to survive!
Before I met you
I had my work, my family...
They didn't frighten me.
Now I'm ill, Sabina.
Give me some of the laugh,
the patience that I gave to you.
Don't punish me with your love!
You can't leave me!
What are we waiting for?
Something
that should interest you.
God, I hope they come.
Who?
You wait here.
I'll be right back.
So that's what historians do.
They run after receptionists!
Yeah.
What is it?
It's the names of all the children
who were in the White Nursery.
Listed by the OGPU
and inherited by the KGB.
It's a present for you!
Merci.
Merci beaucoup!
Come on.
The girl from the hotel...
her father was a KGB officer.
They're always
a good source of information...
...especially
if you're willing to pay.
Would you please tell Mrs. Jung...
...that Miss Spielrein
is here to see her?
- Come in, please.
- Thank you.
Repress my feelings...
...and become friendly
with his wife.
Repress my feelings
and become friendly with his wife.
What do you want?
I want him to love me still.
- Good morning.
- Ivan Ionov?
- Yes.
My name's Marie Franquin.
This is Professor Richard Fraser,
from Glasgow University.
You knew Sabina Spielrein
in the White Nursery...
...didn't you?
Yes.
Come in, please.
What?
I should stop
pursuing you, Dr. Jung?
Just because
you're afraid of love?
How do you do?
I'm Dr. Jung's mistress.
We haven't met before,
I'm so glad you could come!
I'm Dr. Jung's mistress.
Hello, Dr. Jung's mistress.
I'm sleeping with doctor Jung,
I'm his mistress.
My name is Sabina Spielrein,
I'm Dr. Jung's mistress.
I came here
in order to humiliate you.
But now that I'm here,
all I want to do is reassure you...
...tell you
that I shall always love you...
...and that I wanted to die,
but now I am alive.
And that's your doing.
I shall never forget it!
Pardon me, I believe you've
mistaken me for someone else.
I must leave now.
And, really, don't worry,
I shall never bother you again.
I should like your wife to know...
...that I hold
absolutely nothing against her.
I'm sure
she's a wonderful person.
She must be, if you chose her.
Tell her that I wish her
every happiness.
As I do for you, too.
Miss Spielrein!
In the 1920s, Sabina Spielrein...
...qualified as a doctor
in Switzerland.
While Lenin was still alive...
...she had returned to Moscow with...
...her husband, Pawel Schaftel,
who was also a doctor...
...and their daughter, Renate.
Dr. Spielrein was very keen...
...to make a contribution to the great
dream of the Russian Revolution.
Moscow at that time was a city
electric with passion...
...with new ideas. People
took to the streets every day...
...to demonstrate
their desire for change.
What were they looking for?
"Heaven on Earth",
as Sabina used to say.
And she was the first
to believe it could be attained.
How beautiful Moscow is!
How it's changed!
Do re mi fa sol la si do...
After qualifying, Sabina
had specialized in psychotherapy.
And, as soon as she was settled
in Moscow, she started running...
...an infant school,
known as "The White Nursery".
It was called that because all the
furniture in it was painted white.
From the very beginning,
Dr. Spielrein...
...put all her theories about
infant education into practice...
...and they were very advanced
for those days!
Her cardinal rule
was to give the children...
...the maximum amount of freedom...
...and the curriculum consisted
largely of encouraging creativity...
...teaching music and exploring
the mysteries of the human body.
One of the pupils
was tremendously violent.
He was always
hitting the other children.
He'd been enrolled
under a false name.
Only years later did we find out
he was Stalin's son.
Not even Sabina had known
who he really was.
Is that the one who became
a general in the Red Army...
...and went on
to become an alcoholic?
Yes.
Poor Vasily...
...another of his father's victims.
Excuse me.
Pawel Schaftel and Sabina...
...got together a few years after
her break with Jung.
So much for eternal love!
She wanted to live with love,
not die of it!
But she never forgot Jung.
(Dear friend... )
(... when I left Russia
there was a Czar.)
(I've come back
to find a Revolution.)
(Lenin's going to have
his work cut out... )
(... transforming
this almost illiterate country... )
(... into a modern democracy!)
(But everyone seems
to be rolling up their sleeves... )
(... and I shall try
to do my bit too.)
(I think it's the first time... )
(... a psychoanalyst has ever been
put in charge of a nursery school.)
(What I'd like to prove... )
(... is that if you teach a child
freedom from the beginning... )
(... he will grow up
to be truly free.)
(It's asking a lot, I know,
and it won't be easy.)
(But I feel passionately about it.)
(A few nights ago,
I dreamt I was a horse... )
(... galloping
across an endless plain.)
(Perhaps that's what my life is:)
(... an endless plain.)
(It's getting late,
and I can't keep my eyes open.)
(Best wishes.
The keeper of your soul.)
Sabina Spielrein
was truly extraordinary.
She always had time for those
children with particular problems.
There was a little boy there...
...who would sit
under a table all day...
...with his eyes closed.
His hands were clasped so tight...
...it was as if his fingers
were glued together.
Every morning,
Sabina would think up some way...
...of coaxing him
out of his isolation.
She refused to give up,
but however hard she tried...
...it was impossible
to get those hands apart.
Then, one day Sabina
had a brainwave.
That little boy...
...was me.
I felt as if my hands were melting.
For the first time in my life,
I smiled.
I shall never forget
what Dr. Spielrein did for me.
Inside the White Nursery
we were all happy.
But outside,
after Lenin's death...
...the country started
to fall apart.
(My dear friend... )
(... I should be happy today because
it is my daughter's birthday... )
(... and because my book of essays
is being published.)
(But I hardly
feel like celebrating.)
(Our great poet Majakovskij
is dead.)
(Accident or assassination?)
(On the radio Stalin said
he committed suicide... )
(... and now this is
the official version.)
(Will we ever know the truth?)
(With every day that passes, the
darkness grows more overwhelming.)
(It creeps
into one's innermost being... )
(... and sows seeds of terror.)
(Last month
my parents were arrested... )
(... without ever being told why.)
(The truth is... )
(The truth is
that no-one dares say loud... )
(... that we are ruled
by man who is mentally ill.)
(Do you remember
that phrase of Arthur Schnitzler... )
(... the Austrian writer?)
("God created him to be a hero...")
("...but the course of events
turned him into a fool.")
(Poor God! Stalin is mad!)
(He was certified by his own doctor,
a colleague of my husband's... )
(... who died shortly after
having eaten a cake... )
(... in the cafeteria
at the Bolshoi.)
Comrade Spielrein,
this is yours I believe.
Sign here to say you disown it!
Why?
You published it without party
permission, and the party...
...does not like what you've written.
- What is it the party objects to?
Your theories
on freedom of thought...
...and sexual liberation
for children...
...are provocative and contrary
to Marxist Leninist principles!
Not to mention
what you've written about the car!
The car is the symbol
of capitalist decadence.
But even Majakovskij had a car.
If I had been Majakovskij...
...I would have been
much more careful...
...about having an accident!
I advise you
to do as you're told!
"Even if you kill me, even if
you bury me, I shall rise again."
Majakovskij, comrade Zorin.
Get on with it!
It hasn't all been forgotten.
You're the living proof.
Pasternak's poems.
I'm going to buy it for you.
It's very nice,
but I can't read them.
Because historians
don't read love poetry?
- No, because they're in Russian.
- I could read them to you...
...if you like.
Well...
I'm gonna go for a walk.
It helps me sleep.
I'll see you in the morning then.
Take care. Moscow can be
very dangerous at night.
You've never been to Glasgow!
- Bye.
- See you.
(Guardian angel... )
(... now psychoanalysis too
has been officially banned.)
(It's forbidden to treat patients,
write about the subject... )
(... even talk about it.)
(I've persuaded my husband to go back
to Switzerland to cure his chest.)
(Today my daughter and I are leaving
for Rostov, where I was born.)
(I hope to open
a clandestine nursery there.)
(There is no news on the radio... )
(... but everyone says that
the Germans have invaded Russia... )
(... and the Red Army
is retreating.)
(Please God that the Nazis
won't get as far as Rostov.)
(We Jews will be the first
to suffer if they do.)
(Nonetheless,
I have faith in the future.)
(I'm still the usual dreamer.)
(If I don't keep dreaming,
what sense would my life have?)
Marie!
Richard, I looked in on you
before I left.
How strange,
we know everything about Sabina...
...but so little about each other.
There's a poem
by Pasternak that says:
..."When you can't see
into someone's soul..."
"...try going away
and then come back."
I haven't run away...
...but I wanted to be alone
for my last meeting with Sabina.
Renate!
My name was Sabina Spielrein.
When I am dead,
I want Dr. Jung to have my head.
Only he is to open
and dissect it.
I want my body to be cremated...
...and the ashes to be scattered
beneath an oak tree...
...on which is written:
"I too was a human being."
- SABINA SPIELREIN
AND HER DAUGHTER... -
...WERE MURDERED BY THE NAZIS
IN 1942 IN ROSTOV. -
- ONLY RECENTLY HAS THE VALUE
OF HER WORK BEEN RECOGNIZED... -
...AND ITS INFLUENCE ON BOTH
JUNG AND FREUD ACKNOWLEDGED. -
- IVAN IONOV
IS THE LAST SURVIVOR... -
...OF THE CHILDREN
IN THE WHITE NURSERY. -
- HE IS NOW 84 YEARS OLD... -
...AND ALWAYS KEEPS A PHOTOGRAPH
OF SABINA BY HIS BEDSIDE. -