Who is it?
Hello sir. My name is Biharilal.
What is it? I have heard
a lot about you.
I have come to give
you a little trouble.
This astrological letter
Hari Om. Hari Om. Hari Om.
Nothing. Nothing.
Tell me something priest.
She is my only daughter.
Will you be able to year?
Yes.
This is not astrological letter
of an ordinary girl.
She is an extra ordinary girl.
She was born on the
day of an eclipse.
Yes.
She is twenty one years old.
- Yes.
It is very difficult.
Her name is Anita.
Yes priest.
Anita.
On a very fair moon like face.
There are black eyes.
Neeraj is come. Where
are you Neeraj?
In your heart.
Don it be silly. Daddy
will hear it.
Daddy is not at home.
And the servants?
I have given them the Diwali
bonus and sent them.
You have become very smart.
What have I learnt in this love?
What have I gained?
I know all that.
But, where are you?
I have told you. In your heart.
You have rested a
lot in my heart.
Now come in front
of my eyes mister.
How can I come in
front of such eyes?
On a very fair moon like face.
You will lose your sleep
by looking at them.
Fair, very fair.
What is the use of putting
the sari on your face?
This cloud has got a current.
Stay away.
And killing eyes.
On a very fair moon like face.
Fair, very fair.
Except her everything
is darkness.
There is such a special
thing in her.
Eyes.
Every thing is similar.
But her eyes are special.
On a very fair moon like face.
Fair, very fair.
I am restless looking
at your eyes.
The people seeing.
He people seeing say that
they are innocent eyes.
I loose my sleep by
looking at them.
They are peculiar eyes.
There are black eyes.
A very fair face like the moon.
Why do you praise me so much?
Have you ever asked me in these
four years why I love...
...you so much?
I don it need to ask it.
I know you don it love me.
I don it love you.
- No.
On a very fair moon like face.
Killing eyes. Fair, very fair.
I am restless looking
at your eyes.
These are those eyes. Enough.
What sought of an attack
are you getting?
If it continues so you
will become mad.
Madam, I am mad since when.
So its solution.
- Marriage.
If I marry you what
will happen to me?
So simple.
But today I am not so mad
that I will marry you.
You are not mad?
How much mad?
How much very mad?
Very, very mad.
You are mad, I am mad.
I am mad you are mad.
Mad, mad.
- Mad is here.
Today I will meet
your dad and go.
If he does not agree we
will do a civil marriage.
No Neeraj. We will not
do a civil marriage.
Wait for five six months.
I will make daddy agree.
Run.
Anita.
Why did Neeraj come here?
I have told you.
...here at night also.
Anita.
Neeraj, I had told you
earlier that forget the water...
...not even on the land...
Neeraj.
- Wow!
I want to talk to you.
- Surely.
Your talks are like beautiful
chain of pearls.
I want to meet you alone.
Neeraj, the thing I want to
tell you very important.
For me, for you.
For both of us.
But what is the mystery?
Come along with me.
Do you love me?
- Love!!
Stop joking.
And that is you.
- So will you marry me?
You will marry me?
- Of course.
But you told next year.
- Today.
Today.
- Now.
Now.
- At this moment.
At this moment.
Why did you decide suddenly?
Don it ask me anything.
I cannot tell you anything now.
Come with me. Come to
the registrar is office.
But Anita we will first
apply for the marriage.
I have done all
the arrangements.
But we will need witnesses
over there.
I Neerajkumar kashinath.
According to this statement
accepts Miss Anita Biharilal...
...as my lawfully wedded wife.
I Miss Anita Biharilal.
According to this statement
accept Mr. Neerajkumar...
...kashinath as my lawfully
wedded husband.
Do the signature.
Anita.
If you sign here do you
know what will happen?
I am waiting outside
for you in the car.
I will wait for you
only for two minutes.
I am sorry sir.
There is no one at home.
- No one is at home.
I have told you so many times
there is no one at home.
Please go.
Yes sir.
You cannot meet her.
You don it have any right to
interfere in anyone is life.
Why?
Because you are
not a decent man.
Or else you would not have
tried to fool an innocent girl...
...and tried to marry her.
You are wrong.
We were getting married
by Anita is permission.
She was committing a mistake.
Did you understand?
Now you can go.
I will not go unless I meet her.
Before I push you out of the
house by the servants go...
...away from here.
Let is be sir. Don it get angry.
If he wants to meet Anita
what is wrong in it?
She is up in her room.
Your name.
- Neeraj.
Hello. Anita.
Mr. Neeraj wants
to speak to you.
Hello Anita.
I want to meet you.
I cannot meet you.
And I will never be
able to meet you.
Why are you doing all this?
You wanted to marry me.
And now.
- All that was a mistake.
Forget me.
- Anita.
If you don it come down I will
understand that you did...
...not want to marry me.
And that to because I am
poor and you are rich.
Very rich.
Your introduction.
- I am Mr. Anil Sharma.
Mr. Anil Sharma is a very
big businessman over here.
He has got many mills and
factories over here.
And very soon he is going
to get engaged to Anita.
No did you understand?
Now you may go.
Neeraj, what is this madness?
We will not let you go.
Come. You only make
him understand.
He has resigned.
I have tried to make him
understand all night.
But he is out focus.
My dear Majnu. This is
nineteen sixty seven.
Good morning sir.
- Good morning sir.
One minute please.
What is this madness Neeraj?
Why are you leaving the job?
It is due to some
personal problem.
If I would not know your
circumstances I would have...
...accepted your resignation.
That is why take this back.
- I am sorry sir.
I cannot stay here even
for a single day.
Listen, Neeraj.
I will make you understand
something.
This is at cost of your life.
Your entire life is
in front of you.
Your carriers, your ambition.
I know everything. I can
understand everything.
Then why are you leaving
your job for this?
If you want I can transfer
you to Delhi.
Transfer.
I will send the order
today itself.
Tell Delhi our hello as
soon as you reach there.
Ok Neeraj. All the best.
Take care of your health.
- Keep righting.
Congratulations sir.
- Congratulations sir.
You have got a wonderful groom.
Sir.
What happened. - Anita?
What happened to Anita? Why
is she not coming down?
Anita.
Again you are only saying
Anita, Anita.
Why are you not saying? What
has happened? - She has gone.
What are you saying?
Where did Anita go?
Daddy, I am going.
I will never come back now.
Don it try to find me.
Anita.
Anita has gone.
- Anita has gone.
Yes.
Hello. Police station.
I am talking from Mr.
Biharilal's house.
Yes. Just hold. Sir.
Hello. I am Biharilal speaking.
My daughter Anita has
run away from home.
Yes, We have got a note written
by her right now.
Age is nineteen years.
Fair complexioned.
Height five feet five inches.
Name Anita.
Neeraj, I am in a big problem.
You come back to Bombay.
Anita.
Please give me an ISD booking.
Hello.
- Neeraj you.
Yes it is me.
Who gave you the news?
What news?
You don it know anything.
About what?
She has written the letter
and called me here.
What is the matter?
Why are you quite?
When I heard it I
also felt the same.
But when I read the news
paper I came to know...
...that it was the truth.
How did this happen?
Why did this happen?
I don it know this.
But I met inspector.
- What did he say?
He said that...
...she was not in the house
for three days.
The police was searching
her for many days.
They did the post
mortem of the body.
And then handed the
body to her father.
I cannot understand
why she did so?
Why did she commit suicide?
I came to know just now.
I cannot understand how
all this happened.
Why did Anita commit suicide?
I know sir.
The grief of losing
your only daughter.
I want to forget all this.
Some days back I got her letter.
Anita is letter.
She had also written that her
self respect was in danger.
Why did Anita commit suicide?
...there would be no question
about suicide.
She was going to get
married very soon.
Was marriage the cause
of this suicide?
...her permission.
This is due to a doubt.
Doubt.
There was nothing.
You don it know it or you
don it want to tell me.
Think I don it want to.
Because you will not
be able to bear it.
I want to hear it.
She was going to become a
mother before her marriage.
Everything is dark without her.
There is a special thing in her.
Every thing is similar.
But her eyes are special.
On a very fair moon like face.
Fair, very fair.
You are not capable
to touch her photo.
What do you mean?
It means that Anita has not
committed suicide but...
...she has been murdered and
you are responsible for that.
Think about it.
If I would have forced Anita
then why would I tell her no.
...problem in it.
No Neeraj.
Who else?
Someone who was not successful
in Anita is love.
Someone who could
not achieve her.
And in this anger he took
revenge from her.
That she committed suicide.
Such a person.
Like you.
When you blamed me
I also got angry.
But now I am not angry.
Because you have gone
crazy in Anita is love.
I also have loved Anita.
And the people who love do
not spoil anybody is life.
Then how did all this happen?
Anita was not a spoilt girl.
The Anita which we
know is not spoilt.
But the other Anita.
Anita was a weird girl.
Different aspects, moods.
I also do not believe the
things which I hear.
But I have seen something
with my eyes.
Neeraj today I will tell
you a strange incident.
Once we all had gone to Shimla.
There was a fancy dress
ball over there.
You have done a very
good job in Shimla.
It is very enjoyable.
It is fun only if you come.
Thank you. Thank you.
What get up have you taken? -
Have you forgotten your history?
I have forgotten.
- King Chandra Gupt.
Cheers to the king. And you?
In this get up.
- Forget the get up.
I am his Queen for
all his births.
This is very nice.
Kiran, you scared us.
Yes I did see her but.
Take him away.
He is a non vegetarian.
- No he is a vegetarian.
Sir. Sir. Anita madam.
What happened?
- Ms. Anita is dancing.
Where is she dancing?
- Behind.
What rubbish?
- Please come and see.
Oh God! She is dancing.
How do I talk about love?
No, no, no.
The old man is coughing behind.
There are black bangles
on fair hand.
In fair hands.
Who will I show my face
in the morning the...
...noise of the bangles?
Who will I show my face
in the morning the...
...noise of the bangles?
I am joining my hands
applied with heena.
No, no, no.
The old man is coughing behind.
The bride wears the
Bindi like the moon.
The bride wears
the Bindi like the moon.
She has got a little sleep
in her big eyes.
No, no, no.
The old man is coughing behind.
Why are you removing my scarf?
Removing my scarf.
Everybody is seeing this.
They are saying look
at this meeting.
No, no, no.
The old man is coughing behind.
How do I talk about love?
No, no, no.
The old man is coughing behind.
Anita. Who Anita?
Be conscious. What
happened to you?
How did you come here?
Here.
Anita.
What happened? What happened?
She was a weird girl.
How did she come here?
How did she know our song?
And she had worn similar
clothes like us.
Please move behind.
I think it is a case
of split personality.
Split personality.
This is the name of
a strange disease.
When a person gets an attack of
this they forget themselves.
They continue in the
same way they are in.
You understand it as.
If they have worn a beggars
clothes they consider...
...themselves as beggars.
And if they have worn a kings
clothes they consider...
...themselves as a king.
Today when this girl wore
the clothes of the tribes.
She completely forgot herself.
...reached there.
Our rebirth is also
this, doctor.
...in a tribe.
And by wearing these clothes
she remembered about...
...her last life.
And she went with those people.
Today.
Today I think about it.
When did Anita take a get
up and what did she do.
Who knows who he was?
Who took the advantage
of Anita is that state.
After a long time she must have
realized that she was...
...pregnant.
So she committed suicide.
How do I believe you?
I have known Anita
very personally.
But I have never noticed
anything like this.
Come with me.
The Anita whom we know will
never agree to make a...
...painting like this.
But this is Anita is painting.
When I asked her I came
to know that she...
...did not know anything
about this painting.
She didn it even know who
made this painting.
The name of the painter
and his address.
It is written in my dairy.
Come with me.
Get out.
I have come to meet you.
But I have not come to meet you.
Out.
Who are you?
Why are you? What are you?
That is why I am telling
you to get out.
Out.
So then meet a devil.
Good.
Pick me up.
Very tall devil. Sit down.
Thank you.
- Devils are real.
All humans are unreal.
All those who come, they
come along with flies.
Do you understand modern art?
No.
- I also don it understand.
I kill flies over here.
But people understand it.
It flew away.
I cannot understand
anything about it.
You will understand
if it has something.
This is a cow eating grass.
But where is the grass?
- The cow ate it.
But the cow is also not there.
- She has eaten and left.
You do not understand
modern art.
Can you see this?
Yes.
This is a combination
beauty and youth.
Cleopatra.
But we cannot see anything.
I had made it at night
in the dark.
I have come to you for a work.
But you were talking right now.
Then it must be Monday. Tell me.
Do you know Anita?
I know her very well.
Anita is such a girl...
...that if you see her once, you
will remember her for life.
Help me up...
She is a great lady.
Great! A great slut.
What are you saying??
You have only seen the portrait.
I have seen the girl.
The portrait is art,
the girl a slut.
There is some misunderstanding.
Maybe you don it know.
Suicide?
- Yes.
Very good.
One should be very glad
or else she would...
...have died elsewhere.
Many men would ive turned insane.
Tell me what is your problem?
Anita was pregnant.
That is very natural, only
women get pregnant.
Anita was a lady and only
she can get pregnant.
I cannot do it.
But I only want to know who
caused her this misery...
...and lead her to
commit suicide.
It could ive been anybody.
She was a multifaceted lady,
you may have...
...seen one side of
her and me another...
Which side did you see?
Her true color.
I was once on my
way to Hong Kong.
I can see very closely.
I may or may not be
able to meet later.
I can see very closely.
I may or may not be
able to meet later.
This garden of my wishes
may blossom or may not.
I can see very closely.
I may or may not be
able to meet later.
My heart is craving for
one look from you.
Your one look is enough
for my entire life.
Show me your love by your eyes.
You lips are moving
or not moving.
I can see very closely.
Look up there is a beauty
standing in front of you.
This garden of my wishes
may blossom or may not.
I can see very closely.
I may or may not be
able to meet later.
Very nice.
Everybody says so.
You sing very nicely.
You also dance very well.
What is your name?
Sapna.
Aradhana.
Then.
Anita.
Where are you going?
Lmpossible.
Listen.
Anita was exactly as I said.
Listen to me.
Forget her. As I have
forgotten her.
A pretty women should be
remembered not a painful one.
She was not a pain.
Listen to another advice.
Get out.
Mr. Neeraj, whatever
information you have...
...given us about Anita,
we knew it already.
According to our information,
all these are known facts.
Mr. Neeraj, after all the
information gathered...
...we have closed the case.
Ok.
I will advise you to forget
all these things.
What happened, brother?
Nothing.
Police has closed the case.
They cannot solve my problem.
I told you before, the police
has nothing to do...
...with Anita is personal life.
The most famous detective
is my friend.
We can give this case to him.
Let is go.
Customer,
- New case.
Boss... office.
- Start working.
Get up, the customer is here.
Let him come in.
How are you?
Hello, sir.
Hello!
First of all tell me, since
when did you become an...
...English man.
Who are you?
He is my friend Mr. Neeraj.
My detective name is Rajdan.
People call me Roshandaan.
This is an important case.
Case number 9534.
What is all this noise about?
Is this an office
or a fish market?
Ok tell me what is the case?
Robbery? Dacoity? Bank robbery?
Love Affair?
Murder? Kidnapping?
No, it is a case of Suicide.
Oh! We are specialists
in suicide cases.
Let me know, which of you
wishes to commit suicide?
My dear friend, nobody wants
to commit suicide...
...it has already
been committed.
Very good. Then it is
a very simple case.
Have you heard about the
Anita suicide case?
Would you like to have
some coca cola?
Anita case? Anita suicide case?
I want you to take the charge
of complete investigation.
...I will make complete
chart and give you.
Oh no, right from Anita is
birth to her suicide...
...We will make a complete
chart and give you.
Just give me some details.
Please note them down.
- Tell me.
Yes, yes, she was a slut.
But why should it bother you?
You are aware of the
circumstances she...
...committed suicide in.
You know that she is dead
and with her all her vices.
The scar on her forehead has
been washed by her death.
But you are still not convinced.
But sir.
- Anita is dead.
When she was alive,
you were behind her.
You want to bring out her
vices before the world...
...and tarnish her name.
I say that not she
but you are a hag.
What is it that you want?
What revenge are you seeking?
What do you want?
Which life are you seeking
revenge for?
Get out.
Anita, my child.
There is no peace
even after seeing...
After giving I lost
my peace of mind.
Sleeping man.
What is this non sense?
Sleeping child.
Get up, get up.
What office is this?
Oh my God!
Sleeping family.
Mr.
I am not your husband.
- Yes.
My husband is lost.
Very simple. Please sit. Sit.
Where did your husband get lost?
He went to office yesterday
and did not return till now.
He did not come home yet.
So this means he is lost
somewhere between...
...the office and the house.
I searched everywhere
between the...
...office and the house.
Not to be found anywhere.
Where all does he go
other than office?
To his friends. But I
went to his friends.
Went to the police station,
hospital.
But he is not to be
found anywhere.
Does he have girl friend?
What are you talking?
He loves me a lot.
Do you have a boy friend?
You damn fool.
Idea.
- What?
Madam you stand up.
I want to see your figure.
Your height.
- Height.
Six feet half inch.
Your measurement.
- Measurement.
First fifty one.
Second sixty two.
Third seventy seven.
Madam second idea.
What?
Your husband is height.
Very simple. Four feet.
Madam your husband is not lost.
What non sense?
I am saying you have
to find my husband.
What are your fees?
- Very simple.
Rupees hundred per foot.
And twenty five for
a quarter foot.
Out of which rupees five is
the concession for you.
Twenty rupees after
we find your husband.
And four hundred rupees now.
I see. I will give you.
Hello Mr. Neeraj.
Please sit down.
I have seen Anita.
- Anita.
I saw her with my own eyes.
She also saw me.
I want you to go to that
house and investigate it.
Whose house is it and
who all stay there?
What relation did Anita have
with that house or what...
...relation does she have.
Its address.
- Note it.
It is such a big bungalow.
But we cannot see
anybody over here.
Then whose laughter was that.
Hello sir.
Hello.
Sir whom does this
place belongs to?
Why have you to ask about it?
Because if this place
is empty we may stay...
...here for some days.
No sir.
You cannot stay here.
- Why?
Because three people stay here.
Who three?
Tall, fair and thin.
Who else stays here?
And your two fathers.
The other one might be mine.
When do we get to see them?
At night twelve.
Night twelve.
Is it the time for them to come?
Who stays here?
- Ghosts.
Why are you getting scared?
Or else we both will be killed.
You are getting scared in
spite of being my disciple.
I have seen many big ghosts.
What happened to your voice?
He is the first ghost.
One is gone.
Now who is the second one?
Now a female ghost will come.
Female ghost.
Who is the third ghost?
I am the third ghost.
Unless we go in that bungalow.
Don it take the name
of that bungalow.
If it has got three ghosts
outside the house...
...what will it have inside.
Sacrifice.
- Sacrifice.
The ones given to ghosts.
After that the ghosts get
happy and leave the place.
What is this sacrifice?
Anything living.
- Like a hen or a cock.
Cat or a goat.
Boss a goat.
Goat.
No. Mr. Joseph.
Joseph Dekar.
Yes, yes. Come in Mr. Goat.
No son. I am not a goat.
Joseph Dekar.
Good morning Mr. Dekar.
What can we do for you?
Who much do you charge
for finding a husband?
Six hundred rupees.
And how much will you
take to lose him?
To lose.
There is such a case.
This case is here.
Take me away.
Take me away from my wife.
Where is my husband?
Where is he?
I am dead.
Dead.
Hey, not here. - Gorkha, move aside.
I have given him an advance
of rupees four hundred.
I will go inside and see.
As the people inside are mad
the watch man is also mad.
Now where is my husband?
Madam he is not here.
Idiot.
I also know that he is not here.
You both are cheats.
Where is he?
It is a statue madam.
- What happened to him?
His screw had become
a bit loose.
A little loose. All your
screws are loose here.
Unnecessarily.
Why are you keeping broken
things over here?
Now listen to me Mr.
If I don it get my husband over
here till six in the evening.
Not me. Not me.
Give you to the police.
- To the police.
Yes.
- Yes alright.
What happened? Who sneezed?
You. But the noise
came from here.
Madam everything is
automatic here.
Impossible.
Hey watchman, get out.
Sir, help me.
I have died. Save me.
Everything will get
alright to night.
Boss it is twelve o clock.
Now the ghosts will come.
And they will take
the sacrifice.
And then we both will go
and search the house.
You idiot.
You thought I did
not understand...
...anything in the office.
I had understood everything.
You have come here to
be the sacrifice.
I will take you home
and make you a cock.
Save me.
I am dead. I am dead.
We have got the first sacrifice.
They have got the sacrifice.
Boss they have got
the sacrifice.
Get another sacrifice.
He is calling you. I am going.
I also want the third sacrifice.
The third sacrifice
is also needed.
The third sacrifice.
Why do you want the
third sacrifice?
Three ghosts stay here.
Three ghosts, three sacrifices.
Sit down.
- Did you come to know anything?
Our decision is that Anita does
not have any relation...
...with this bungalow.
What do you mean?
- It is very simple.
It means that Anita
committed suicide.
...that he saw her.
Just like Majnu use
to see his Laila.
Like that Neeraj can
see Anita everywhere.
Anita.
We got your message but
we cannot come today.
Neeraj is fine.
Anita.
Neeraj what has happened to you?
It is alright.
You may go.
Do you know what Menencorea is?
It is a disease cause due
to sadness and depression.
Though it does not have
any effect on the body.
But it makes the person
very weak from within.
This disease has only one cure.
...you mind.
Listen, Neeraj. Anita is dead.
And you don it go searching
for dead people.
Forget her.
Have these tablets.
You will feel sleepy.
Good bye. - Thank you doctor.
...your heart says.
Tell.
You will get alright
on your own.
I have sent a letter to brother.
What will happen?
Hello sister-in-law.
- Hello brother.
There are so many turnings from
Cargodham to Nainital...
...that I still feel
everything is moving.
If you move about here for
some days then you will...
...be alright.
Sister-in-law you are
a great poetess.
You have not heard
anything till now.
Listen to her moppets? - Moppets?
Not only moppets but moppers
of the beloved is feet.
Great... wow. - Listen to this.
The mopper of the beloved is feet...
What does that mean?
If you want to hear
it seriously hear it.
Or else forget all these poems.
I am very serious.
Please tell me.
The mopper of the beloved is
feet was kept on the shelf.
Neither did it reach... nor did I.
But the news reached...
Wow! Great! What has happened now?
Is this a poem or a stone?
No. Enough. Please
no more poems.
The heart went with the
heartless beloved to her place.
The heartless beloved
nudged it and it died.
Once more. Did you see?
- I am getting so man y praises.
I would say...
The heart went to her place,
with the heartless beloved.
The heartless beloved
nudged it and it died.
If I do not get lunch in some time
I will go to with sang dil.
Lunch box is with you.
Start.
Sister-in-law I will
get water from top.
My friend where ever I see.
I can see my lover
in front of me.
My friend where ever I see.
I can see my lover
in front of me.
Love has made me a mendicant.
In the grief of love.
Like the ripples in water.
I have beard all the pain
in my grief by crying.
I have been quite while
bearing all the pain.
How do I say how the flute
was lost from his mouth?
The flute from his mouth.
My friend where ever I see.
The world is calling me crazy.
No one can understand
loves language.
My love, my love.
My love, I have become crazy
searching you everywhere.
My friend where ever I see.
Who are you?
Your name?
Mendicants don it have any name.
But you?
What is the matter?
The same voice, the
same face, the look.
What look?
- Her look.
You look like her.
Who?
Anita.
- Anita?
Where is she?
- She is no more in this world.
But by seeing you I felt.
I felt.
Does my face look
like hers a lot?
Not much.
Exactly.
The difference is only that
her eyes were black.
Listen.
Where do you stay?
Mendicants do not
have a fixed place.
Today they will be here.
Tomorrow they will be there.
Can I meet you again?
Me.
- Yes.
Why do you want to meet me?
Because your face looks
exactly like my Anita is.
You are losing your peace.
Forget her.
Listen.
You are a mendicant and
I am just a normal man.
How will you know
what a heart is?
It is time for the prayers.
I want to meet you again.
I might get some peace
by seeing you.
Life does not continue through
somebody is support.
It continues through somebody
else is support.
Then too you want to meet me.
Then you can meet me.
I come here every day.
Anita, if you would be alive
today and would have seen...
...this mendicant you
would be surprised.
Varsha, you are crying.
Look at that.
How much can someone
love somebody?
Thank you very much
that you came here.
It is such a strange place.
It is so calm.
Peace is not in the
outside world.
It is within us.
Yes. You are right.
...keep going everywhere.
As I was going everywhere.
Now have you stopped roaming?
Yes.
I have found little brightness
in the dark.
This is wrong.
This brightness will take
you in more darkness.
How?
...the world.
For someone who is dead.
She is dead for the world
but she is alive for me.
You are running behind
something which you will...
...never get.
I know it.
But my love is not a ritual,
it is a penance, a sacrifice.
And a penance is
never interrupted.
What is your name?
- Neeraj.
Nice name.
Maya.
Mendicant Maya.
Why are you coming behind me?
I also want to come with you.
In your family.
Do you think you will get peace
by coming in my family?
But when you will come to
know about my distance.
You will be hurt and fell sad.
And due to it I will
also feel sad.
Because I will be the
cause of your sadness.
My world is over here.
If I want I can come there.
But you do not try to
cross this boundary.
What are you thinking about?
Neeraj has not yet come.
I don it know what has
happened to him.
He is behaving strangely.
Varsh, I have a doubt.
Has he again got lost
in Anita is thoughts?
Ask my heart how my life
has been without you.
Ask my heart.
Ask my heart how my life
has been without you.
Ask my heart.
The monsoon have come and
brought along old memories.
Who will make me sit
near them with?
Ask my heart how lovely
and beautiful you were?
Ask my heart.
Ask my heart how my life
has been without you.
Ask my heart.
The waves of sea of
love are everywhere.
It goes on getting deeper
as I go in front.
Ask my heart what all
has drowned in...
...the flood of this sadness.
Ask my heart.
Ask my heart how my life
has been without you.
Ask my heart.
You are shining like glow
worm in my tears.
You have become a flower
and blossomed in some garden.
Ask my heart I have
cried on my fortune.
Ask my heart.
Ask my heart how my life
has been without you.
What is happening to you?
It is of sacrifice.
Come let is go.
What is the matter Neeraj?
Why are you sitting here?
Why didn it you come
home at night?
What happened to you?
She did not come.
Who?
Mendicant.
- Mendicant!
Sister-in-law, she looks
exactly like Anita.
The same face, the same look.
She lives on that side
of the mountain.
Listen, Neeraj.
We agree you have
met a mendicant.
But you have considered
her as Anita.
No.
This time it is not my doubt.
I met her.
I saw her.
I heard her song.
I spoke to her.
Not ones but many times.
No.
I will not go unless I meet her.
Ok. Where are we stopping you?
Make us meet that mendicant
and we will agree.
Or else you will have
to come home with us.
Alright. Come with me.
Radhe Sham. Radhe Sham.
Radhe Sham.
Priest.
Where does that mendicant live?
Mendicant. Who mendicant?
The one who stays here.
No mendicant lives here.
Priest.
Her name is Maya.
- Maya.
Mendicant Maya.
What relation do you
have with her?
I want to meet her.
Come with me.
Radhe Sham. Radhe Sham.
Radhe Sham.
Look at this.
It has been twenty
years she is dead.
Malak you may go.
Did Neeraj meet any mendicant?
I think you have also
become crazy like him.
If it is doubt then tell me.
How can he know about a
mendicant who died twenty...
...years back?
He told that mendicant is
name, her looks.
How?
How do I say? I say is.
The mendicant who died thirty
years back has take a rebirth...
...in the form of Anita.
And the mendicant Neeraj
saw must have been Anita.
All this is due to rebirth.
I do not believe in rebirths.
Then what answer do you have
about that mendicant.
I do not know anything.
I only know that it is
not right for Neeraj...
...to stay here anymore.
I will send him back
to Bombay today.
I am sorry.
I don it have any
right to ask so.
I just want to know whether
it is you know no.
Don it get scared.
I don it want to trouble you.
I just want to know that you.
You cannot go.
You are standing alive
in front of me.
But the other day we found
your body in the water.
Then I saw you at the same
place where you committed...
...suicide.
But you went away.
I saw your footprints.
And I met you in the form
of mendicant Maya.
Mendicant Maya who was
dead twenty years back.
And today I am seeing
you in this new get up.
Tell me who are you?
Tell me.
Who are you?
Don it try to find me.
I am neither of this
world nor of that.
I am neither alive nor dead.
If you are alive then
how do you go away?
And if you are dead then why
do you come in front of me.
Come I will tell you everything.
Mendicant, Anita, train,
gown impossible.
Whatever I told you
is absolutely right.
So what?
Can it any other girl
wear golden anklets?
She is tell me.
But she is Anita.
Anita had written a letter
to her father before...
...committing suicide.
Father, I am going.
I will never come back.
Never come back.
Your Anita.
This is the postmortem report.
It is clearly written
that Anita is body...
...was found on eight April.
It is proved by this that the
body must have been in the...
...water for nearly ten days.
From this letter and this
report it is proved that Anita has...
...committed suicide on
march twenty eight.
What did you say?
- March twenty eight.
This is the governments report.
There cannot be any
changes in it.
According to the postmortem
report Anita had committed...
...suicide on march twenty eight.
Correct.
How is this possible?
Wonderful.
...letter to Neeraj on
the second of April.
Inspector Sawant did you verify?
This is the report by
the handwriting expert.
Gentlemen we have got four
points in front of us.
A) Anita is alive.
B) She knows whose body that is.
C) That is why she is not there.
D) We are not investigating
a suicide case.
But a murder case.
And Anita is involved
in this murder.
And Anita had written in this
letter that her life and self...
...respect is in danger.
I think she will again
try to meet Neeraj.
Inspector Sawant keep a
watch on Neeraj's house...
...for twenty four hours.
Ok sir.
You know that I am alive.
I also want to meet you.
Ten o clock in the evening
at La Bella restaurant.
If anyone comes along with
you then I will not come...
...in front of you.
Anita.
Yes I have done all
the arrangements.
Ok. Then listen carefully.
It is eyes" hint to be careful.
It is eyes" hint to get careful.
Go away.
Don it come in the
matters of the heart.
It is eyes" hint to get careful.
Or else it will be
the same thing.
You will meet me.
It is day but it will
seem as night.
It is eyes" hint to get careful.
It will be difficult to live.
Get up from the get
together and go.
It is eyes" hint to get careful.
Extinguish this fire.
Don it increase the flames.
Extinguish it for me to come.
Don it let the eyes meet.
She will not come here now.
I also think so.
You!
Yes.
Why didn it you come there?
I could not come.
There was danger.
Danger.
I cannot tell you anything.
...stay here. You
go back to Delhi.
For me. For the sake of my love.
Don it ask me anything.
So much has happened and then
also don it ask anything.
Neeraj, I know you have
suffered a lot due to me.
But forgive me.
Listen to me.
You go back to Delhi.
I am not capable for your love.
Forget me.
- But why?
Anita. Nothing is
wrong till now.
Tell me the truth.
If you are alive then
whose body was that?
But the police does
know everything.
...unknown girl.
This is also doubted that Anita
has killed that unknown girl.
You have done it. - No, no.
- I have not done anything.
I am innocent.
Hello.
- Hello.
Inspector Sawant.
- Speaking.
Neeraj.
- Anita.
If you tell anything to
the police about me then.
Then the pistol will start.
I will kill myself.
Anita.
Neeraj, believe me.
I am innocent. Absolutely
innocent.
Anita then why do you want
to hide everything...
...from the police.
Till when will you
change your get up?
Till when will this
gown hide you?
SP sir. SP sir.
Anita is at Neeraj is
house right now.
Really. - Yes.
She is in a gown. We can
arrest her right now.
You tell the people
on duty to be alert.
When the person in gown come
from there to follow her.
I will also contact the control.
Ok sir.
- Hello. Hello. Control.
Instruct all the officers on
the P division to check all the...
...highways.
And also to make all the
other divisions alert.
First one car should
follow her car.
Then the car behind it will
relieve the second one.
...she is been followed.
If Anita does not have a doubt
that we are following her...
...we will come to know
where she stays.
Control calling Peter.
Peter.
- Peter speaking.
A lady in a gown will come
from Neeraj is house.
You follow her.
But she should not
come to know that...
...you are following her.
Ok sir.
Let is go.
Peter. Peter.
Peter speaking.
Now you stop following her.
Jeff will take over from front.
Park the car.
Jeff calling control.
The white car is going
in front of me.
I am following it. Over.
Alpha calling control.
The whit car is coming
and I am following it.
Over.
The car is going towards
the highway.
You keep watching it.
Ok sir.
The car has taken speed.
You arrest her.
Sorry sir.
You are being sent help.
Ok sir.
Fast, fast.
A little fast.
Sir I have pressed the
entire escalator.
Fast.
Yes sir.
Stop. Stop. Stop the car.
Radhe Sham.
Radhe Sham. Radhe Sham.
Neeraj.
The secret behind which you
were so worried, now is the...
...time for you to know it.
...secret.
Because if you are alive I
will be hanged to death.
Now you will be told
Anita is real story.
So that you will have no doubts
before you r death.
Every person is story starts
with some other person.
This story starts with Anita.
I was going to get
married to Anita.
But there was an interruption
in it.
And you are responsible for it.
Why are you calling
your death Bela?
Don it try to come in my way.
You know me very well.
Very well.
What will happen?
When Anita will come to know
you are an international...
...smuggler and are wanted
by the police.
Now I was going to
be hanged to death.
And to make that girls
body as Anita is body.
...come on top for ten days.
Then sir recognized the
body as Anita is body.
Through which everybody
believed that Anita committed...
...suicide.
Now I was just wanting for
the news to become calm.
Then I will send the daughter
and father to another...
...country with a different
identity.
I had done everything properly.
But I could not realize
your love.
I sent you to that painter
who was my worker.
Who told you another false
story about Anita being...
...a bad girl.
Anita is one letter and your
investigation made my entire...
...plan a failure.
I have done all the
arrangements...
...to escape from here.
Father you supported a murderer.
I didn it have any other option.
After that murder
Anil came to me.
What have you considered me?
I cannot do such injustice
to my daughter.
I cannot ruin my daughter is
life to save your life.
Be conscious sir.
Don it forget you are my partner
in smuggling and...
...many other crimes.
Yes I am a smuggler.
I am your partner in many
crimes but I am not a bad...
...father.
Or else I will be hanged to
death and this is the only...
...way I will be saved.
Listen to me.
Or else I will kill her.
I will kill her.
Anil.
Anita.
I was compelled.
Then why didn it you tell me?
If I would tell you.
You would never listen to me
even after knowing everything.
That is why I lied that
my life is in danger.
If you want me to be alive to
continue doing what I say.
And you listened to me.
That is why you were
sent to Nainital.
You became a mendicant.
You put a blue lens and tried
to hide yourself from the world.
You changed many get ups
and took different looks.
And today.
And today you all
will be killed.
Far away from this country.
Very far.
Anil Sharma. Anil Sharma.
You are being arrested for
murdering an unknown girl.
The police have surrounded
the entire bungalow.
Surrender yourself to the law.
I will give you two
minute to come out.
I have got three
innocent people.
Anita, Biharilala and Neeraj.
If anyone tries to come
in I will kill them.
Anil Sharma you already have
the blame of killing a girl.
...saved by being hanged.
You can hang me just once.
ACP I will arrest him just now.
He is desperate by seeing
so much of force.
Anil Sharma you have
one minute left.
Surrender yourself
to the police.
Or else action will be taken.
Come sir.
- Anil.
Anil.
Tear gas.
Throw.
SP sir this is the answer
to your actions.
Sir Biharilal's dead body.
Anand.
He is dead sir.
Superintendent sir.
I am coming down. If anyone
tries to stop me.
Its answer will be given
by Anita is dead body.
Let him go.
Arms down.
Do not try to stop him.
Superintendent sir. I am going.
Neeraj try to put
him away from you.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org