You sure you want to stay
on the other side of the wall.
They begin demolition on it
next Monday.
By the end of this month they'll be
opening a police station and schools.
What's with the long face
you don't seem too happy.
I just hope they keep their promises.
Listen, it's the law and the law
is always looking to some fool like me...
...to make sure these
matters are handled.
Three years later,
the government has changed.
...but nothing else has...
District 13 Ultimatum
Halt!
Stop!
Follow! Follow!
There he is!
What's going on?
Over here.
Hey, man. Now you bringing cops?
Sorry.
Think you're a Musketeer
or something?
- Yes, I'm Dartagnan.
- You mocking me?
Dudu, leave it alone.
Dudu, you're a bit dense.
You should have stayed in school.
- Say, you look like a kid.
- I am a kid.
You, take care of the others.
You come with me.
Have a seat.
What did you do now?
- This city is not a hotel.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm tired of it.
- This isn't the same situation
You're free, you have the whole
city to yourself.
They treat us like beasts.
It's like this from birth.
For three years they've been telling
us the same thing.
A government that doesn't keep it's
promises? Wow, that's rare.
If we do not do something,
they'll just keep ignoring us.
They keep us trapped here like animals in cages.
This isn't your culture dude.
This wall protects us...
...like a fortress.
And those that come
with talk of society, are no matter to us.
We have our own.
And we like it that way.
And frankly, I prefer to be the king
of a small kingdom...
...than some nobody out there.
So be cool and stop bringing the cops
to our wall...
...if not, I'll be forced to take
action against you.
Understand me?
This is the merchandise.
Takes this.
It's a gift.
Yes, boss?
Yes, boss.
Go in.
Leave it!
Let's go!
Your merchandise has arrived.
Should I go get the first client?
Don't be rude, let me enjoy myself
a while.
Get them all out, except that one.
Everyone out!
Not you.
Go see the boss.
C'mon, dance a bit!
Mr. Ou will see you in a moment.
Tell him my ass is falling asleep
from having to wait so long.
You can tell him yourself, sir.
C'mon get on your knees.
If you want to win more,
you have to lean more.
Get on your knees man.
Hands on top of your head.
- You're a thief?
- Worse.
Police.
You're under arrest, you have
the right to maintain your silence...
...until you are in front of the judge.
If you think I'm going to...
In French this means - shut up.
No! it's a vase from the Ming
dynasty.
Don't worry, it's a fake.
And the rest?
They're all fake?
Almost. Except for the Van Gogh.
Head office, I have the soap.
I repeat, I have the soap.
Understood.
Transmitting location.
- I am the soap?
- More like a shampoo.
- Bait is more like it.
- What do you mean bait?
Don't worry.
You don't have to understand.
Everything's calm.
Sanitary control.
We'd like to see the boss.
Sir, there is a police unit
at the door.
Two police and I'm sure
there are more hidden.
You're right there. Go.
Go.
- Asshole!
- See, they're already biting.
You'll never get out, this building
is completely monitored.
If it had been an easy assignment,
they wouldn't have sent me.
What is this?
It's simple, if you speak
your cheeks explode.
Want to test?
Good.
I'll be sure to say how cooperative you
were in my report.
Central, I'm going fishing.
Mr. Ou is expecting them.
They stay.
Remain here, it's cool.
Mr. Ou, what a pleasure.
Don't move.
Over there.
Walk.
After you, gentlemen.
So I'm last or what?
Them first.
- Hugo.
- You Know me?
Yes, I have photos of you all over my rooms.
Shit!
Go.
Raise your head.
- What is this?
- You should know, you invented it.
Gentlemen, follow me.
He's fucking with me.
Leave it alone, it's cool.
It's been a week... this fat...
Calm down.
Drink a margarita, it'll relax you.
To hell with your margarita!
I'm sick of these guys.
C'mon, he's beginning to get antsy.
Mr. Sam, Fair went to look for it.
This is how you treat
your best client?
Since when do I come last?
We always leave the shit for last.
Hands up.
What are you doing?
This fucker's crazy.
What's this shit?
It doesn't do anything to you?
I'm immune asshole.
Well, we'll fix that.
It's nothing, a vase fell,
that's all.
Central, fishing expedition finished.
Send in the boys.
Already did.
- Nobody move!
- Everyone face down, now!
Hands on your head!
- Go, go!
- Move in!
Go!
You'll never get out alive,
disgusting policeman.
You have no chance!
You're sure?
Let me go! Let me go!
- I'm assuming you're not going to give me the code.
- Go to hell!
Doesn't matter, I have a key.
Drive!
Sending them down now.
Send in the rest of the unit.
Careful with the feet!
Move!
Let him go!
Get out! Shit, get out!
Found it!
I told them there were traps.
What happened?
I'll kill you.
Open up!
Shit.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'll be right with you.
Don't move.
This painting is worth
200 million Euros.
It's a Van Gogh.
One stray bullet, one scratch,
and it's worthless.
Die motherfucker!
There he is, shoot that fucker!
Ok I see the keypad.
And you guys are...?
Lovely to meet you.
Head office, there is a bomb.
- A bomb?
- Any ideas?
- Where is it exactly?
- In the basement kitchen.
Ok,
we'll send you the necessary.
Careful!
It's on it's way.
Fantastic!
Lovely to see you guys.
Come on in.
- Any injuries?
- No, I think it's okay.
- I was referring to you Damian.
- I'm fine commander, thanks.
These guys aren't the only ones.
Go rest,
file the report tomorrow.
I prefer to keep working while
it's fresh in my head.
Tomorrow I'll go in early
if it's no problem.
No, I'll see you in my office
at noon. It's an order.
Thanks.
- Good Work.
- Thanks.
Everything okay.
All clear.
Send him in.
Gentlemen.
- What do you think of this site?
- Glorious.
How long does it take to erect a tower like this?
It depends on the start date.
But more or less,
eight years.
OK.
Yes.
Bring it out.
Just like Chantier...
...double, if they give us
the guarantee that they will build it.
The operation will begin
tonight.
Perfect.
- Thanks, have a good night.
- Good night, Damien.
Shit.
Damien?
Forgot about me?
No.
Just wanted to let you sleep
I've been sleeping for eight hours, I'm well rested.
Wait, wait.
Take it easy, easy.
My body hurts all over.
All over?
Almost.
Is this make-up?
Yes, for work.
For work?
You told me you spend all day
chasing paintings.
It's my job.
Well, you better show me that you were
worth the wait.
Yes ma'am.
Suspect is on Seventh street.
Great music.
Excuse me.
Repeat, blue car...
54, I'm near.
Copy that, 54.
So, Salim,
is it true?
- Yes, yes!
- Listen!
Yes, hello.
Are you home?
No, I am in a palace
with a view of the Eiffel Tower.
- And where is your palace?
- Champs-Elysées.
Nice neighborhood.
Well, we can hear you,
would you like to dedicate it to someone.
Yes, to Sofia.
Well, "Push the Air",
is for her.
Well, you know...
- No!
- Shit!
What's going on?
It'll be okay.
- Samir.
- What?
The police.
- Turn down the music.
- It's just music.
- We're not doing anything wrong.
- I'll decide that.
Your papers, both of you, now.
- Here.
- Take it.
- Who's car is this?
- My dad's.
Drivers license?
Don't have it, I took his car.
And your license?
I'm 17, I don't have a license!
We're not doing anything except
listening to music.
Since when is it a crime to listen to music?
We're not bothering anyone.
- C'mon get out of the car.
- No.
Hurry up.
Shit! Again.
Go see what happened.
OK.
- What the hell is this?
- Don't know.
Start filming.
- What's happening here, officer?
- Routine stop.
Girls listening to music in a car aren't dangerous.
Why not search the car? These girls transport...
...drugs in this neighborhood.
We'll give them the benefit
of the doubt tonight.
- Know how to drive?
- Yes.
- Then leave.
- But I don't have a license.
Leave!
Shit, he let them go.
She doesn't even have a license.
What do we do?
Follow them?
- No, no.
- Wait.
- Keep filming.
- That's what I'm doing
Which unit are you with exactly?
Secret Service.
Let's talk in the car.
Shit!
Don't you move, keep filming.
- And what's this?
- Keep filming.
And what's this?
Zoom in on the plates, zoom in.
Already did.
Shit, I've never
seen anything like this.
Give it here, I'll do it.
- Samir.
- What?
Police that murder
police, that's a fucking bomb.
Precisely, before seeing it explode,
we'll wait to hear the official version.
We'll do that.
What?
- A police cruiser here?
- What the fuck?
They crazy?
What are they doing?
Something bad, you can be sure of it.
Yo, are you lost?
- This ain't a parking lot.
- Damn right.
- Have them framed?
- Proceed.
Perfect.
They're firing!
Shoot!
C'mon you idiots...
- The clock is synchronized?
- Affirmative.
We got what we needed, let's go.
DISS.
Where you going?
Keep sleeping, I'm gonna catch a movie.
Get down, lie flat on the ground, hands up!
- Police!
- On the ground now!
Damien!
What's happening?
Who is the commander of
this unit? I want to speak to him.
I am.
I think you've got the wrong person.
Damien Tomaso, Captain of Special Forces. 31 years old.
What's the meaning of this?
Captain, we found
this in the kitchen.
Well, here's your reason, c'mon gather some things...
...you're coming with us.
This is bullshit.
Georges, explain.
For six months you've promised us results.
Mr. President, we don't have the means to search each block
and district.
Save your excuses, please.
There was a
contingency plan.
So something must have improved.
Explain to me, how it could get to this?
I assure you this isn't a normal case.
- What is it then?
- Well it's...
...an isolated incident, nothing more.
I hope you're right.
In the meantime put someone on the case.
Someone serious and effective.
This Tomaso, for example.
Is this a typical case for him?
Thought about him, but he was arrested
for drug trafficking this morning.
Tomaso? You sure?
Unfortunately.
I was about to promote him...
I also had Gazman in mind, the boss of DISS.
They are well informed on this district.
Yes, very well. Very Well.
Mr. President.
What? Already?
I guess they are aware of the
situation.
I've been briefed, Mr. President.
Very well.
If that film is leaked, we could
lose all credibility.
Put a civilian car in its place.
We have 48 hours.
That's exactly how long you have to solve this case.
- Use the utmost discretion.
- Yes, sir.
Will do, Mr. President.
He doesn't realize war has never been
at odds with democracy.
Special Report:
Last night in district 13...
...an altercation between a band of thugs
and law enforcement...
- Damn!
- Look, it's an internal camera.
This is shit!
This was not for fun!
Yeah?
And why are you here?
I was in the wrong place
It's no reason for them to lock me up.
You did good, now get out!
I have rights!
Go, see to your friends and tell them to watch their
backs.
Let's go!
- Which district?
- 13.
Perfect.
Boss, can I show you something?
They sent us this.
It's the camera that
transmitted yesterday.
But look at this.
Probably some boys intent on
looking for girls.
When I saw them,
I zoomed in...
...and saw this.
Shit, they filmed it.
Yes.
Find this license plate number immediately.
- I'm on it.
- Perfect.
Leïto, they're looking for me.
- I filmed it all and now they're looking for me.
- What are you talking about?
About the car of the television.
Shit!
Here!
Halt!
- That is Samir.
- Halt!
Let him go, let him go!
Let him go!
Calm down, or we'll take you too.
Open door 14.
Go.
- Can you loan me a cellular?
- Anything else you want?
My cellular.
Thanks.
C'mon, answer.
Leïto, it's Damian, I'm fucked dude,
I could really use a hand...
I'm not home right now...
...or maybe you don't have the balls
to say it in my face...
...so leave a message.
You have to help me Leïto,
it's Damian.
I'm in the basement of the central police station.
I've been framed.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count on you.
Let go of the telephone!
What's up, guys?
The police are everywhere, you crazy?
Yes, I know.
Everywhere.
Got you.
Be out in a minute.
Yes?
He called someone and explained the situation.
- Who'd he call?
- Some guy called Leïto.
We traced it to district 13.
- They know each other?
- Yes, they're close.
Bring me this Leïto,
let's not take a risk.
You have a new message.
Leïto, I've been calling you
but you're never there. Well, bye-bye.
Don't move!
- You can't pass.
- Think it over.
Good decision.
Let's talk seriously.
Someone has to die.
And it's you.
Up! Up!
- Shit, they left.
- But she does not have a license.
- What do we do?
-Should we follow?
- Go, go.
- No, stay.
- Keep filming.
- That's what I'm doing.
- What are you filming?
- Keep recording.
Shit!
Don't move, keep filming.
- And what is this?
- Keep filming.
And what is this?
The plates, zoom in on the plates.
Already doing it.
Shit, I've never seen anything like this.
Go, go.
Leïto, it's Damian, I'm fucked,
I could really use a hand
I'm in the basement of the central police station.
Somebody framed me.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count on you.
Leïto, it's Damian, I'm fucked,
I could really use a hand
I'm in the basement of the central police station.
Somebody framed me.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count on you.
What are you doing here?
Hurry up!
He just disappeared.
We'll look for him.
Hurry! Hurry!
This way!
There he goes!
Go the other way!
Wait! Wait!
Go! Go!
Go, shit! There he is!
Quickly!
Shit!
You were shopping?
- No, sir.
- So you're incapable of trapping...
...one boy with three units?
The individual is very skillful, sir,
never seen anything like him.
Next time ask him for lessons.
Return to base, I will go
see the President.
Yes, sir.
And how are things out there?
They're aren't going to take long
to escalate.
We didn't kill him on purpose,
I swear.
He tried to leave... what can you do?
Explain it to his mother.
Move!
Front and center!
Let's go!
Can I help you?
Can I see the boss please?
Boss, there is a guy out here who
wants to see you.
- Send him in.
- C'mon.
- What's this about?
- I'd like a room, please.
Are you joking?
This is not a hotel.
Outside it says
"Police Hotel."
Get out before you piss me off.
Get the hell out!
Listen, it's better for everyone
if you lock me up.
I'm a criminal of some potential
and I might do something stupid.
Have you committed some crime?
No.
Then you know what?
Come back when you have.
We'll give you a nice clean cell, okay?
Okay.
Get on the ground, on the ground!
Don't move you!
Do not move!
Open door 14.
You're in luck, the only cell we had left.
- But there is no linen or food.
- What is there?
What were you expecting?
Let him go.
I said let him go!
Security.
Security, the doors
are blocked off.
You sure took your time.
Want me to come back when you're
in a better mood?
No, that's okay.
- I'm glad to see you man.
- Me too.
Everything is going to shit out there,
you sure you want out?
Yes, I have scores to settle.
Let's get outta here.
You got a plan?
Why don't you have a plan?
I thought since you got in here so easily,
that you'd have a plan.
Getting in wasn't so difficult.
It's getting out that's going to
pose a little bit of a problem.
You're well trained.
Yes, more or less.
C'mon, I know a shortcut.
This is your shortcut?
Run! Run!
Tomaso escaped from his cell.
He's gone already?
No, he's still inside.
- Find him.
- Yes sir.
And fast.
...in district 13...
Gentlemen.
It's begun?
...of law enforcement...
...and the incidents
have multiplied.
Among the injured are numerous officials.
Well, commander,
how's it coming?
District 13
is out of control.
And there is a risk that the surrounding sectors
may join them.
The whole country could be
on high alert in 24 hours.
General do you still advise a military
intervention as a preventive measure?
Yes. But the army...
...doesn't have the time to
prepare for an internal invasion.
Unfortunately, time is a luxury
we don't have.
Mr. Gazman - your recommendation?
When gangrene spreads, the area must
be cut off.
Well, I wasn't elected due to my tolerance
for metaphors.
When I ask for a recommendation,
I expect one.
Well, Mr. President,
I'll be more direct
Evacuate the entire district 13
in twelve hours.
Tomorrow morning, we'll demolish the district
entirely, and no one will be able to return there.
And there are other advantages.
This will create new jobs.
We'll build a new neighborhood
full of citizens...
...that will probably vote for
you in the next elections.
It could not be more clear.
Gentlemen.
Any thoughts?
Politically, this solution
would be extremely dangerous.
What's your solution?
Well...
I notice that none of you have
any specific proposal...
...to defend
our democracy.
Very interesting.
Remember that our primary function
is to protect the French people...
...and look after their interests.
And to ensure that the values of
freedom, equality, and brotherhood...
...are still respected
in this country.
That is, how should I say?
The entire foundation of our republic.
And the only proposition you bring to
me, is to demolish the place? Disgusting.
Thank you.
Mr. President,
the idea is abhorrent...
...but we have priorities.
Perhaps in two hours
the situation will be uncontrollable.
Perhaps it isn't the best idea...
...but it is the lesser evil.
General...
...can we evacuate a million civilians
in twelve hours?
If you give the order now,
it's possible.
I suppose some clan bosses won't be
so easily evacuated.
Who will miss them?
General.
Proceed with the evacuation.
We'll begin planning tomorrow morning.
Mr. Gazman, I trust that all
the inhabitants of this neighborhood...
will be treated with respect
and dignity, and I mean...
...ALL.
I'll give the order personally,
Mr. President.
Dismissed.
Go that way!
Keep looking!
We're okay here.
- They weren't Police?
- They found drugs in my kitchen.
Don't you know how to hide shit?
Wasn't mine.
They planted it.
Classic.
Police that want to fuck
other policemen.
It's not common.
Above all, I have to ask, why?
To stop you from going anywhere.
They know how social you are.
I don't know.
I'm sure it's something dirty that
they don't want you to stick your nose in.
Super cops aren't good for everything.
They would have given me vacation time
or promoted me somewhere else.
Would you have taken a promotion?
No, of course not.
Do you know what's happening out there?
What's happening?
There is a recording that shows some
thugs riddling...
...a patrol car with bullets.
But there is another recording which
shows it was the cops...
...who shot up that patrol car.
What was the patrol car
doing in district 13?
It may have been transported.
And afterwards?
After I got the second video,
part of the building exploded.
It was the police.
But I managed to escape.
They are not police.
They must be criminals passing
themselves off as cops.
Why? For fun?
It's a strategy to do away with
District 13.
And afterwards build on top of it.
Remember the license plate?
They all have the same
license plate: DISS.
DISS, I don't believe it.
What is it?
Secret internal security division.
Damn, that's it.
They receive their orders directly
from the President.
The DISS boss is Gazman Multer.
- You know him?
- No, not really.
They wanted to transfer me there
six months ago. I turned it down.
Well there you go, you've got a
guilty party, motive, and a crime.
Only thing missing is proof.
What about this?
That won't be sufficient.
You need something that'll really
bother them.
- What are you doing?
- Thinking.
It scares me when you think a lot.
- We have to get to Walter's office.
- I was afraid of that.
- Where is it?
- First floor, office 17.
The old-fashioned way?
Fine, the old-fashioned way.
Can't you be discreet, like me?
Being discreet doesn't matter here.
Now what?
I'm thinking.
There they are!
I don't like this.
Any ideas?
I'll entertain them, you
get to Walter's office
Remember, first floor, office 17.
Bring whatever proof you have.
Will we see each other again?
I doubt I'll be going very far, go!
Now you'll see!
If you stay put, and remain silent, nothing
will happen.
You have my word, okay?
Which is Mr. Garzo's computer?
What's the password?
Good morning, any of you
have a computer...
...that moved by itself?
Yes, me.
Tech service, I'm here to install
the new server.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Found it.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Damien.
Be reasonable and let justice handle
this problem.
You know very well, I did nothing wrong.
Yeah I know. prisons are full of
innocents.
However, the farms...
Well, you ready?
The things I do for you.
Don't worry I'll pay up soon.
Don't let them go!
Shit!
We can follow on foot, right?
Put on the belt.
- What are you doing?
- Well, going ahead as planned.
Excuse me.
I'm listening.
- Damien escaped.
- How did he escape?
Leïto Came for him.
He came for him and they escaped together.
Explain to me how they escaped.
Through your office.
What should we do?
Pursue them?
No, too dangerous, there are soldiers
everywhere.
Stay alert anyway.
Understood.
Follow the instructions that were given.
And where will you take us?
There's always a watchdog somewhere.
Yes, it was you who promised me
things would change.
That there would always be some fool
to enforce the law.
Laws are not evil, the people who
enforce them are.
Yeah, like religion. Speaking of which,
what's yours.
They baptized me when I was a boy,
but right now my only objective...
...is the civil code.
What?
My only aim at present
is to enforce the civil code.
You're worse than a Mormon.
- Well, should we go or stay?
- Go.
- What you want?
- To Speak with Tao.
About what?
About the district
and its inhabitants.
He's kidding.
Business.
Let them pass.
What are you doing here?
Stole it from a national security team.
It's good.
Well?
We'll give it to you, if you help us get
some things that are of interest to us.
What's this?
A bit of catechism.
You've lived your whole life in district 13.
Where do you think you'll live
when they destroy it?
We must avoid that.
Aniel, take this out.
Okay. It's open.
- They're everywhere.
- Everywhere.
Where'd you learn that?
In books of course.
Go on, do it.
This is interesting to me.
- We're now over Iran.
- This is also interesting to me.
Here it is, district 13.
These are the objectives,
five towers.
There has to be something more.
Walter fixes it, so you take the blame.
The President orders the destruction
and they build everything new.
- Like in Iraq.
- Exactly.
Except now it's the French
And how are they going to destroy
the towers?
In position.
There are three helicopters.
They're up there already.
The choppers will light
the targets with lasers.
Next, the missiles.
How?
Probably from a command center.
Only the President of the Republic can
give an order like that.
How can we prevent it.
Better read the manual.
Because your little bossy voice...
...is beginning to piss me off.
It bothers you that I make jokes?
I apologize.
If I call you "cabbage head",
would you like this better?
- And if you call me by my name?
- OK.
What's your name?
Damien Tomaso, commander
of the French army.
A policeman, if you prefer.
Now I think it's better if we put our
differences aside...
...and give each other a hand.
Tao, a pleasure.
Likewise.
Now, what's your plan,
cabbage head?
- Thanks for coming.
- What's this about?
We'll explain it to you.
Hello.
It's through there.
Alika, guns.
Marcho, specialist
in machetes.
Carlos Skin,
specialist with cars.
Montana, bombs.
Excuse me.
Can they cover these areas?
Yes, they wouldn't let an opportunity
to show their skill pass them by.
Gentlemen.
Thanks to all
for coming.
It's been 19 hours since district 13
was evacuated.
Their intention is to level it completely.
I have everything that we need.
The idea is to avoid it.
All in favor?
Well, then I'll pass it off...
...to Damien to explain his plan.
We all have to come to an agreement in the
five hours we have left.
I'll need about thirty men...
...trained in combat,
with no need for weapons.
We're not going hunting.
We infiltrate in silence, neutralize the enemy...
...and go directly
to the centre of operations.
Questions?
Where is the command center?
Here, in Paris.
Through here, Mr. President.
Reinforce the security
around the building.
Go give the signal.
Remain in the air.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Take your seats.
So, General,
where are we on this?
The pilots are waiting for the order to
engage the targets.
I was talking about evacuation not destruction.
That's our priority is it not?
Yes, sir.
Mr. President.
We've evacuated 1,087,310
people in the last twelve hours...
...but there are sectors we can't get near.
Precisely all the people
located here.
We tried and there were casualties.
This could delay everything.
How many people have not been evacuated?
Long time since we did a census in this neighborhood...
...but a few thousand people.
Too many.
Continue the evacuation.
- Command sent us here.
- Us too!
Very Well.
Turn both keys
at the same time.
Five missiles, all will go out
To tell you the truth,
gentlemen...
...I do not like this at all.
- May I give you some advice?
- Please.
I know these types of men.
They don't respect anything, people,
laws, nothing.
They kill and steal only for profit
And you aren't responsible for that.
They were here before your arrival.
And what can we do with them?
Speak with them?
No.
The only way to rid yourself of them is
extermination.
Alert!
Mr. Gazman, I find your cynicism offensive.
No, Mr. President, I'm only
being pragmatic.
One of the causes of our
recession is this parallel economy.
With these types around, we lose millions in taxes
which should be coming to the state.
With this destruction...
...we can build a place that
will actually be earning us money
We can rid ourselves of this scar,
and build something new and profitable.
Destroy to build? That's your solution?
Makes sense to me.
Through here.
General.
Assault choppers are in the air.
Good.
Make them land.
I won't put this key in this lock...
...until I'm convinced that
there aren't any civilians in this neighborhood.
- Understood?
- Very well, sir.
My General, a group just entered the building.
Well, neutralize them.
They aren't armed,
but there are a lot of them.
Continue, I'll handle it.
Go see what's happening.
Go guys.
Montana, I said no destruction.
It's for
my personal security.
What's going on?
Don't worry, the building
is strongly reinforced.
Relax.
This one is mine.
So?
How do you prefer it?
Listen, you don't have...
The rules are to be respected.
But not with people like you.
We love to meet people like you.
And those ears?
You okay?
Strike!
I'll call you.
Mr. President, I'm pleased to inform you
that district 13 has been completely evacuated.
How? Just an hour ago we almost...
...weren't able to evacuate a few thousand civilians.
I don't know perhaps the message did not arrive.
In any case, district 13 is empty, I
guarantee it.
In that case.
Get them in position.
Signal received,
attack commencing in one minute.
We are in position,
Mr. President.
Don't move!
Stay put!
I say...!
This is the hand that I'll shove down your throat
if you don't shut up.
Gentlemen, I am the President
of the Republic.
- The one from the television.
- I have seen him on the Internet.
Captain Tomaso,
explain yourself.
Pictures speak louder than words, Mr. President.
- Keep recording.
- what is this?
Don't know, keep recording.
Shit!
What is this?
The DISS in action.
The DISS wanted to
discredit the entire district...
...to destroy it all
and afterwards go back and rebuild.
I'm sure they were compensated for it as well.
If the images
aren't satisfactory...
...I have here a disk of
special operations from the DISS.
Isn't this true, Walter?
It's why they sent him on a vacation.
Nobody move!
What are you doing?
Take out the key.
Fast.
Let's go!
Take out the key.
Do what I say, remove the key.
What's happening?
There's going to be new elections.
Go, release the
fireworks, turn the key.
Tomaso, do not move!
If you move I'll kill him.
C'mon, turn the key I said!
Signal received! Ready!
Go.
Stop, Gazman, you'll never get away with this.
A soldier goes on until
the end of the mission.
Even if it
costs him his life.
It's called honor.
That's a concept those people in district 13 have no
notion of.
Yes, we prefer another concept - family.
That's what unites us.
It's what protects us.
It's what we believe in.
Unity huh? I think I'm gonna cry.
Then you'll die united.
Enough of this shit, where you going?
Chill, I'm only going to... shit I was
sure that there would be tobacco.
Leave it.
Tomaso!
For my collection.
This is really nice Mr. President.
A gift.
Gentlemen.
Miss, excuse me.
I don't know what to say.
Thank you so much.
I owe you a debt.
I believe all of France
owes you a debt.
Well, I don't blame you for not trusting a
politician but...
...I assure you that in
the next 48 hours...
...I will do what I can
to undo these present laws...
...so that this district
can regain...
...its dignity and an important part in
our society.
Thank you.
- I have a question, Mr. President.
- Yes?
Instead of spending a fortune
hiding the rot...
...why not rebuild?
What do you mean?
A true neighborhood.
A true city.
With green spaces
and places to work and play.
I agree.
Damien, I'm appointing you head of this project
until it's finished.
Very well, Mr. President.
You have my word, as well as the government's.
Your word as a man?
My word as a man.
Gentlemen?
- Fine by me.
- Me too.
Yes.
Of course.
Very well.
Well, that's better
than mine.
Let's hope everything is for the better.