Hi, it's Marla.
I changed my mind.
I can't do this right now.
You're here?
At the club?
No. I can't meet you.
I have to get back to my daughter.
Mom?
Mom.
Mom! Where are you?
Lie To Me 02x03 - Control Factor
You don't trust me.
It's such a control thing.
Admit it. Admit it.
You're reluctant to leave me in charge.
Rubbish.
Then why haven't you gone yet?
What?
Why are you trying to get rid of me?
You haven't had a vacation in 6 years, Cal.
Come on.
You are trying to miss your flight.
I am not.
I am not. I am trying to find
The Anderson file.
I've got it, all right?
I can take care of it. Come on.
Stop stalling.
Where are you going?
Honestly, Cal.
The cab is outside waiting for you.
Grab your jacket and let's go.
You deserve this.
- Emily's waiting for you. Come on.
- Don't push me. Don't push me.
Come on, let's go. Here.
Here.
Oh, give me your cell phone.
You don't need to check in while you're gone.
It's just gonna stress you out. Come on.
No kicking and screaming?
I have absolute faith in you.
And my staff.
Here I go, then.
Have a good time.
Are you really working?
We've only been here 2 days.
You really need to learn how to relax, dad.
People who can't relax die younger.
I learned that in health class.
Don't worry about me, love, will you?
- What are you looking at, anyway?
- Nothing.
You're spying on the Office?
Look, I'm my own Boss.
That's a 24/7 job.
Someday, when I'm a stressed-out workaholic,
I'll have you to thank.
When did you become such a know-it-all?
We had an agreement that
if I behave maturely,
You would treat me like an adult.
So, as an adult, I'm telling you to relax
- And stop it with the creepy snooping.
- Hey.
If you don't,
I'll just go pick up boys by the pool.
All right, deal.
Oh, I'll have one of those, too, thanks.
Make it a virgin.
Dr. Cal Lightman?
My name's Lou Nemeroff.
I'm with the American Embassy.
There's an urgent matter
that we need your help with.
An American woman,
Marla Seeger,
Disappeared 2 days ago
from the Oceano Hotel.
It's just down the beach.
She was last seen at the Hotel bar.
This is local news footage.
La mujer Americana...
Muy borracha.
This is the bartender who last saw her.
He says that she was drunk,
Coming on to several men, and that
she eventually left with one of them.
Ahora, lo tenemos razon para creer que...
The Local Police,
they aren't doing anything.
They believe that she left voluntarily.
She's a really good mom.
I just want to find her.
Mom, if you're watching this,
Please come back.
And that's her 12-year-old daughter.
Oh, my God, that's so sad.
What's the State Department
doing about this?
Their official policy is to leave it
in the hands of local Authorities.
Oh, so nothing.
They're doing nothing.
Which makes me wonder why you're here.
Your Boss doesn't know about this
little field trip of yours, does he?
I can't ignore what's going on in Mexico.
Which is what?
More than 200 Americans have gone
missing in the last few years,
Mostly collateral damage
from the drug Cartels,
But unless it's some pretty blond teenager,
nobody even wants to talk about it.
All I need to know is if somebody on
this video is trying to hide something.
Yeah, the Detective in charge of
the case and, um, the bartender.
Dr. Lightman,
can you help us find Marla Seeger?
- Dad.
- What?
Come on.
Some people at the Hotel, they
said that they saw your mom crying.
Why was she sad?
I don't know.
Everyone's saying she was a bad mother,
but she always took good care of me.
Yeah, I'll bet she did.
You think you can find her?
Oh, absolutely.
He's definitely gonna find your mom.
I don't know.
I don't know, love.
You ever think that
grownups are full of crap?
Yeah. Lots of times.
Usually it's 'cause we've made a mistake,
Done something wrong,
but we don't want
To talk about it,
we don't want to admit it.
Which makes us Hypocrites.
I think you've got a secret.
And you're too scared to talk about it.
Mom always picks awful boyfriends, so
I signed her up for an Online dating service.
This is a guy you found for her?
He said he traveled a lot and
I told him we were coming here.
Well, what did he say?
He said he'd meet me.
I wasn't aware of this.
J-Rod25.
My mom was supposed to have
dinner with him last night.
What if he did something to my mom?
We rushed over here right away.
Did we hear right?
3 patients have been
infected by tainted blood?
The first patient died this
morning at Cottage Hospital,
And the second is in critical
condition at St. Mary's.
This is Gary Spar, the third patient to
receive a blood transfusion during surgery.
It should have been a routine operation,
but he never woke up.
I need you to seal off that O.R.
and gather and test everything.
So 3 different patients
at 3 different Hospitals?
It's no longer a coincidence.
We shut down the D.C. central blood bank.
Go help pat rule out any
other possible contaminants.
We're in a real quandary.
We need to protect people,
But if there's no blood available for
trauma cases and other emergencies,
Patients may die anyway.
Do you have any idea what's in the blood?
Oh, worst case scenario, it's a
biological or a chemical agent.
The FBI has been alerted in
case this is Bioterrorism.
I know.
I'm on my way to the Hospital CEO,
- Right now.
- What can we do to help?
The people who have
access to those blood units
All claim no involvement or knowledge.
I need to know who we can trust.
Should we get Lightman back here?
I can take care of this.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey. What have you got?
Well, the tainted blood units all came
from the overnight shift at the blood Banks.
There were 2 Techs on duty.
We're taking them down to the Lightman
group right now for questioning.
Dr. Cho,
I haven't forgotten about you.
As soon as I have a minute, we'll talk.
That little boy has Sickle Cell Anemia.
If he doesn't have a blood transfusion
in the next 24 hours,
He could have a stroke.
What about getting the blood
from outside areas?
There's a real shortage.
We're working on it,
But it's gonna take time
that we don't have.
Oh, Jack, thank God you're here.
Do you know Dr. Foster?
Gillian, this is a lovely surprise.
- What are you doing here?
- The CDC contacted the Rader firm
To help assist you since
Dr. Lightman isn't here.
Where is Cal?
He's on vacation.
And hell didn't freeze over?
Well, now it's a shame he's gone.
I was hoping he and I
could bury the hatchet.
- Is there a problem?
- Lightman and I are...
Friendly rivals, so to speak.
It won't be a problem.
Will it?
No. Not at all.
Oh, hey, hey.
The 2 Techs from the blood Bank are here.
So tell me, what's the deal
with Lightman and Rader?
What, they don't get along or something?
Cal despises him.
He thinks all he cares about
is money and publicity.
Well, for once I'm with Lightman on this.
Something tells me not to trust that guy.
Hey. Hi.
You're the Detective in charge
of the Seeger case, right?
Yes.
Hey. I'm Emily Lightman.
This is Dr. Cal Lightman.
He's a deception expert
And he works along with the
Police in the United States.
In the United States, yeah.
- This is Mexico.
- No, I knew that.
I knew it.
Um, now,
I saw some news footage,
And I think that the bartender at Marla
Seeger's Hotel is giving false information
About her disappearance.
Dr. Lightman,
There is no case here.
Ok?
We spoke to several Resort employees.
They said she seemed unstable,
more than likely a drug user.
Based on what?
We found several used needles
in her Hotel room.
She probably found a fellow drug user,
left with him.
She will be back when the drugs run out.
Ok. I still think you should
have another go at the bartender.
And I think that you and your daughter
should have a very lovely time here. Ok?
Por favor,
lleve a este gente afuera.
No, what about the guy that Tyler
said her mom was gonna meet?
- You spoke to Tyler?
- Yeah.
There are many people here
who would not like the fact
That you have shown interest in this matter.
Do you understand me?
So I'm gonna give you one piece of advice.
Stay out of this.
Mojito, por favor.
And a Margarita.
A Coke.
Coke for the Senorita.
Enjoying your vacation, Senor?
Yeah.
Well, no, I was until that woman turned
up missing. What's her name again?
Ah... Marla Seeger.
That's it, yeah.
Hey, you're the guy on the TV, right?
You saw her that night?
What do you think happened to her?
She was dancing with many different men.
She was looking for a good time.
She left with one of them.
They were sleeping on the beach
or getting high.
What did he look like,
the guy she left with?
Don't let this trouble get in your head, Senor.
Everything is fine.
You're an awful liar, Miguel.
Now you're terrified.
What is it?
- You work for the Police?
- Miguel.
Vete a la casa, ahora.
I'm so sorry.
We are closing this bar while we restock.
- Is there a problem?
- No.
If you're here on vacation,
please tell us whatever we can do
To make your stay more enjoyable.
If, however, you're here
conducting an Investigation,
You're not welcome here.
Yeah, Torres, it's me.
I need you down here.
Wait, for what?
Uh, a woman's gone missing.
Yeah. I'll tell you all about it
when you get down here.
Just bring something pretty
to wear, all right?
Yeah.
Dude, you're gonna find her.
For you,
I will move heaven and earth.
Hey. Lightman just called.
He needs me to fly down to Zulia right now.
He's on a case?
Yeah. A woman's missing.
I gotta go.
Uhh. He's on vacation.
Ok. Just give me one sec.
So, how is it working for Cal?
Been so long, I can't remember.
I work with Cal.
I'm an equity partner, you know.
Good for you. That means Cal's
been working on his control issues.
Jack... I meant that as a compliment.
Seriously, he was my mentor. I have nothing
but respect and admiration for the man.
Obviously, he doesn't feel the same about me.
Cal says he taught you
just enough to be dangerous.
He's the better scientist,
no doubt.
But I'm not going to apologize for having
ambition and a better Business sense.
If we're gonna work together,
I have some ground rules.
First, I'm the Boss around here.
Second, don't try using me
to get back at Cal.
So long as you...
Admit that there's just the tiniest
moment happening right now.
Will you admit that?
Hey, Romeo and Juliet,
you want to get this show on the road?
People could be dying right now.
You can leave.
Thank you for coming.
Agent Reynolds, could you escort him out
and bring Miss Bynes to a more private room?
Sure.
Will you come with me, please?
People hiding something never want
to draw attention to themselves.
That was awesome.
The old routine's a little rusty,
but she still works.
- I meant what I said about the ground rules.
- And I meant what I said.
Shall we go find out what
Miss Vines is hiding?
Nice work.
It was a regular night at the
blood Bank... nothing unusual.
Your Boss was about to fire
you for being late too often.
You knew.
Was this retaliation?
She's breathing faster.
Foster's getting somewhere.
You have no idea how good she is.
Lightman doesn't know. He has a hard time
seeing the true potential of his employees.
What was that?
Little flash of anger at
the infallible Cal Lightman?
You run this entire Lab. But I'll bet Lightman's
never showed you an ounce of appreciation.
So, you and Lightman...
- We had a falling-out.
- What, over a case?
Water under the bridge now.
You know, I never knew my own worth until
I got out from under Lightman's shadow.
Someday, you'll do that same.
It's been hard for me. My husband
left us. I'm alone with the kids.
Voice pitch is higher.
What's that look there?
Shame?
I just went through a divorce myself.
I can barely get out of bed.
I can't think straight,
I can't do my job right...
People are dying.
You feel guilty, but you're gonna feel worse
if you keep secrets and another person dies.
On my last shift, I didn't run the
full testing protocol on the blood.
So, you have to test on any
blood for different diseases.
I left early.
My daughter needed me.
There are so many other safeguards.
I didn't think.
I just...
I think we have our culprit.
No, we don't.
Someone else just died after
a transfusion at Euclid Park.
And this patient Banked his own blood.
Central blood Bank isn't responsible.
So, you're setting me up on a blind
date with a potential murderer?
Yeah. Why?
He's not your type?
I'll keep an eye on you.
You'll be fine.
- What are the Police doing?
- Nothing.
So, we're doing this on our own.
Yeah.
You know, you pulled me off
a really big case back home.
The CDC brought in the
Rader firm to work with us...
Jack Rader?
Yeah, he's at the Office
Working with Foster.
Why? What's the problem?
Not sure. Not sure. Get in.
Want to see the sights?
Yeah.
Who you with?
You, uh, with the Hotel?
Police?
Drug Cartel?
Who's that guy?
He's with the Police or drug Cartel.
Dont go anywhere.
Miguel?
How did you find me here?
I bribed a waitress at the Hotel.
You picked the wrong part of Town to visit.
So, you think I should call the Cops, then?
Eh?
Oh, are you scared of being seen
with me by the Police, are you?
Turistas estupidos.
Eso fue un "si"
Dinos la verdad sobre Marla Seeger,
y nos iremos.
The Police told us to say the American
lady was looking for a good time,
That it was her own fault.
Why?
Zulia depends on tourists.
Something bad happens,
you all disappear, the Town dies.
After the lady from Miami disappeared,
we were told not to talk to anyone about...
What lady from Miami?
Do you want me to call the Cops, or...
She came here 4 months ago.
She was found dead.
The Police kept it out of the news.
We should get out of here. I'm gonna
tell the cabby that we're ready to go.
Ok.
Hey,
Did you, uh,
Did you really see
Marla Seeger at the bar?
I saw her with one man.
I'm not sure if she left with him or not.
Was it this guy?
That's him. I'm positive.
Now go.
Cab's gone.
What?
The cab... it's gone.
Uh, here, hold that.
Um...
I'll give $200
To the person that gives
us a ride back to our Hotel.
Now, where's your car?
Quiso decir quinientos...
Dos ahora,
tres despues de que llegamos.
We're lucky they didn't kill us
and dump our bodies in a ditch.
That wasn't luck.
The driver was happy to make
some honest money for a change.
You read that?
Yeah.
Speaking of big and flashy...
I need you to find out
what Rader's up to.
You want me to spy for you?
No, I don't want you to spy for me.
I just want you to poke about a bit.
I'll do my own spying.
All right. Well, it's just my opinion,
but I think that might be a little overkill.
Your opinion? I don't need your opinion.
I didn't ask for it.
Just do it. All right?
All right.
Wait here.
Oi! Oi! That's my daughter!
Hey, she started...
That's my daughter.
She started talking to me.
You're having a conversation
With my teenage daughter!
She started talking to me.
What?
All right. Ok. I'm leaving.
Dad, that was the guy
that Tyler's been Emailing.
I know it was. And you shouldn't have
been talking to him, Emily. Bloody hell.
- You never said I shouldn't talk to him.
- Well, what am I supposed to do?
Tell you not to do every
potentially life-threatening thing?
No.
I figured if I kept him talking...
This is the last thing I need, Emily.
You know, I've got a con man
back in my Office!
And I've got you behaving
like Nancy bloody Drew!
I was just...
I was just trying to help.
Where are you going?
Don't.
Hi.
I'm Lola.
Jerry Conway.
Please.
You're a very confident woman, Lola.
I mean that in the most flattering way.
Well. Then color me flattered.
So, how long you been a masseuse?
Uh, just a couple of years.
Really?
No, seriously.
The last guy I dated was a complete nut job.
Oh, I've been there.
Oh. Really?
Ok. Well...
You tell me about your last
psycho, I'll tell you about mine.
Least interesting story does a body shot.
You're on.
I met this weird chick, Marla,
a couple nights ago.
Yes. The Hospitals trade blood with each other,
but Euclid Park's not at fault.
I've been here 10 years. Yager's been
here 9. We've never had a problem.
We're not the source of the tainted blood.
How can you be sure?
I mean, I can't imagine how.
There's been no change in procedure.
Lightman?
Ok. All right.
Dr. Foster, here's the
blue file that you needed.
Sorry for the delay.
- The blue file?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Do you know what this is, Mr. Dunst?
This is a file all about you...
Background check, interviews with coworkers,
family, friends.
My team compiled it. You know, we can
scour this to discover what you're hiding,
But why don't you save us the time?
Tomkins, the new driver in the Lab,
is a Felon.
He told Yager he left the conviction
off his job application.
And I should have reported it, but...
Maybe you should talk to him.
Lola...
Hey. All right.
He's married, goes online to meet women
while he's on Business trips.
He's a schmuck, but he had nothing
to do with Marla's disappearance.
Are you sure?
Positive.
They met.
She left after like a minute.
Uh, he says that she was crying and
talking to some couple in the lobby.
He seems truthful.
I can't believe you told him I like
role-playing and dirty limericks,
You...
Don't knock it till you've tried it.
Hang on.
You following me?
You have a lovely friend...
And daughter.
Is that a threat? 'Cause you really
shouldn't be confusing on that.
Not at all, Dr. Lightman.
Hey.
You sent someone to follow me,
and they threatened my daughter.
I didn't hire him.
Some people here do.
Yeah, well,
so do the drug Cartels.
I warned you not to get involved.
All right. 4 months ago,
another woman went missing,
Just like Marla Seeger,
but this one turned up dead.
Ok, listen.
I insist that you stop interfering. Ok?
All right, the night Marla Seeger disappeared,
she met a man named Jerry Conway.
Then she met a couple outside the bar.
Did you know that?
There is no Case here.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a young
woman who killed her own mother. Ok?
Hey.
Su madre la estaba abusando.
No tiene­a otra opcion.
Usted lo haba­a hecho lo mismo.
Por favor, quieto.
Quieto. Ok?
I think you should talk to this boy.
He's using his anger to hide something.
She's protecting him,
so just talk to the boy.
All right?
Lleala a la segunda sala, por favor.
Y tu?
Te sientas, por favor.
Sientate.
How many of your people are
involved in this Cover-Up?
There is no Cover-up.
Yeah, there is.
You may not be a part of it, but
you know one exists, don't you?
Ok. Ok.
The couple that met Marla Seeger
say that she seemed unstable.
You talked to them?
Yes. Well, who are they?
Dan and Stacy Felder.
But it's a dead end.
You know, there is a case here.
Actually, there's 2. But you
already knew that, didn't you?
You're lucky you survived this accident.
Why did you fail to mention your
Criminal history on your application?
I was 19 when I stole that car.
If I say I'm a Felon, who's gonna hire me?
They should have done a background check.
You've been in Health Care for a while.
Do you enjoy it?
It's very rewarding.
I missed my calling.
I should have been a paramedic.
I mean, the action, the glory...
I mean, this...
That's real life-and-death stuff.
It's not too late. Heh.
Yeah. I'm too old. I don't know
how we get to where we're going.
Are we even aware of our choices?
What, are they just chatting?
We're just getting a baseline right now.
You know,
let me ask you something.
Was your "aha" moment
when you stole that car?
I don't understand the question.
You stole that car and got into an
accident with a 23-year-old kid.
The Police found you
cradling his mangled body.
I mean, did you get into Health
Care because you realized
You could be around blood and
guts and death all the time?
That you wouldn't have to cause an
accident to get sexually stimulated?
Uh-oh.
Sicko alert.
Pupils dilated.
He's aroused.
From talking about blood and guts?
Yeah.
They've sussed that out.
What did you put in the blood
at Euclid Park Hospital?
- Nothing.
- You want people to suffer
And die at your hand.
I swear I had nothing to
do with the tainted blood.
I never did anything at Euclid Park.
Speech pattern's back to baseline.
He's probably telling the truth.
So, we're back to square one,
Again.
Why are you being so hard on yourself?
People are dying, and I can't stop thinking
about that little boy with Sickle Cell,
And I have nothing for the CDC.
Gillian...
You know, if Cal were here,
he would have solved this by now.
I should have just made him come back.
Hey.
We can do this. Ok?
Excuse me.
You can't come in here. Jack.
McKenzie!
How did you get in here?
I'm a Reporter who talked her
way into Attica once, remember?
Scheduled surgeries are being canceled
all over D.C. with no explanation.
Something's going on at the CDC.
And when a little bird told me you were
partnering with the Lightman group,
My Reporter antenna went off.
Heh heh. McKenzie, darling,
You have uncanny timing.
Let me fill you in.
Can we do it on camera?
Heh heh.
Oh, yeah. Thank you very much.
I'll tell him. All right. Thanks.
So, a woman named Ramona Posner came here
alone from Miami about 4 months ago.
10 days after she disappeared,
she was found dead in an alley Downtown.
State Department and Local Police
ruled it an accident.
Well, a cynic might call it a pattern.
Yeah.
Oh, by the way,
Rader seems to be making quite
an impression at the Office.
Is he, now?
Mm-Hmm. According to Loker,
Foster seems a bit gaga over him.
Lovely.
Oh, my God.
What?
Is that jealousy?
No.
Where are you going?
I left my hat out by the pool.
Don't worry, I won't do anything childish.
Why don't you take your extraordinary
powers of observation down to the pool
And use them to keep an eye on Emily?
You're jealous.
Marla came up to us in the lobby.
She said,
"I hope you experience the great joy I have,"
And then she left.
It was bizarre.
You work with the Police, right?
I mean,
didn't they tell you this already?
Yeah, but I wanted to hear this from you two.
Mrs Felder, do you have any idea why
she would approach you like that?
No.
Not true.
We're gonna be late for the Airport.
Here.
No, I'll hold that.
No, I'll get it. I'll get it.
You know, you're never gonna
get that through Customs.
Why not?
Because I'm gonna call them.
I'm gonna tell them
you got a suspicious package.
That's the kind of pain in the ass
I can be if I don't get the truth.
Look, it was just a hunch.
There's a Fertility Treatment Center here
that matches egg donors with couples.
We're from Canada and it's illegal
to purchase eggs there.
The donors stay anonymous, but they
can choose who they want to donate to.
These are our frozen embryos.
So you thought that Marla
Seeger was your egg donor.
Yeah, for a moment.
But then we realized that it couldn't be her.
She was nothing like the person
the Broker described to us.
Hey.
Did you find my mom?
No, love.
Not yet.
Well, that's lovely.
Welcome to the age when they need you
but think they're smarter than you.
Well, she always was.
All right,
I've got one for you.
Marla Seeger was a waitress
in a diner, right?
And, uh...
Ramona Posner was a Teacher's aide.
How do two women like that
afford fabulous trips to Zulia?
How?
Well...
Marla Seeger...
Came here as an egg donor.
She was giving herself Hormone injections.
Right.
And the needles that the Cops found.
Hence the mood swings.
- Hi, can I help you?
- Cal Lightman?
Yeah, he's here.
Just the man I wanted to see.
You need to call in some of
those Embassy resources.
Can't. Someone from the Police Department
called my Boss. I've been reassigned.
And threatened.
Our egg donors have high IQs,
are from stable backgrounds.
They don't have drug, alcohol,
or mental health problems,
And many of them are star Athletes.
How specific can we be
in how the donors look?
I have a couple here,
they're seeking someone at least 5'9",
Blond, blue-eyed, Athletic,
and an Ivy League School.
We found a match yesterday.
It's only 50,000
In the States,
it would be double that.
We're in here.
How do you harvest the eggs, then?
Our reproductive Endocrinologist,
Dr. Alvarez,
He's responsible for everything.
Right.
How much do you pay the donors?
The fee is generous.
Plus they get a free trip to Zulia.
But no one does it for the money.
They just want to help
the right couples have a child.
That's wonderful.
Yeah, it's great.
We actually are looking for a donor
with blue eyes and light-brown hair.
And 5'6".
I think I can arrange that.
Thought you were gonna say that.
Oh, Dr. Alvarez,
these are the garrs.
Pleased to meet you.
May I have a minute with you, please?
Can it wait?
Oh, no, no.
We've gotta shove off anyway.
- Yeah, we gotta go.
- We've got to think about it.
Yes. I mean,
it's a big decision.
Yeah.
I've got a question for you,
Dr. Alvarez.
Um, we've been told that
my wife's infertility
Is due to an Estrogen imbalance
caused by the Coriolis effect.
Is that possible?
That could very well be true.
Did you see Wynn when I described Marla?
Flared nostrils, quick breath?
Yeah, he's in this.
There's no way all those donors
fit the criteria he described.
Oh, wait.
See, they don't have to.
They find donors like Marla Seeger
who are desperate for money.
They insist the donors remain anonymous.
Wynn can give the buyers
any description he wants.
- It's a con.
- Yeah, absolutely it's a con.
Isn't the Coriolis effect
something about the Earth's rotation?
- Yeah, exactly.
- Alvarez agreed with your theory.
Yeah. That's because
Alvarez is not a Doctor.
He's a fake.
I'm in charge of blood orders here,
and Yager coordinates Trades.
For the other Hospitals in DC.
So why did I have to
reinterview these two guys?
Because we've got nothing else.
Well...
He's exhibiting extreme control.
I guess he could still be hiding something.
No, voice pitch is steady.
Dunst isn't lying.
But why does Yager keep looking behind him?
And why is he anxious?
What'd I miss?
What happened to the Reporter?
I took care of her.
That could mean so many things.
So the story won't be on the News?
That's what you wanted,
isn't it?
What, did Cal brainwash you into thinking I'm
some kind of Media whore without scruples?
Come on, guys, tell me you got something,
'cause the Tox screen's all negative so far.
And the CDC is getting all
kind of calls from Reporters.
I can charm one Reporter,
I can't control the entire fourth Estate.
Uh, we had the 5-car pile-up on the beltway...
Wait.
Something's different.
Oh, I had to change the battery,
So we took a little break.
But they're both more relaxed now,
and Yager's not looking behind him.
Go back to before the break.
He was looking at that.
They got rid of it.
Why didn't they want us to see it?
Dr. Foster.
What can we do for you?
We need to take a look around.
How often do you give blood?
Every 6 weeks or so. I have a rare
blood type. What are you looking for?
- Found it.
- That's sensitive equipment.
What's it for?
Processing patient fluid samples.
Could you be any more vague?
It's positive for narcotics.
So you've been running a drug Lab down here.
Hola.
Hola. ¿Que tal?
Hey.
Where's Marla Seeger?
- I don't know who that is.
- Not true.
You're the couple from
the Office today, no?
Your partner Wynn sold you out,
made a deal with the Police.
He said the Scam was your idea.
He never said that.
Dr. Alvarez is responsible for everything.
- That's a lie.
- No, I can assure you it's perfectly true.
What happened to her?
She was one of our egg donors.
She wasn't doing well on
the Hormone treatments.
She wanted to get the procedure over with.
But then she called to change her mind.
Wynn brought her in anyway.
This is all his doing.
What happened to Marla?
I started the egg extraction,
but there were complications
And I punctured something.
She started to bleed.
So where is she?
Wynn has an apartment.
She's dying.
One more day,
we would have lost her.
Yeah.
Listen, how did you know that
I wasn't part of the Coverup?
When I accused you,
you showed genuine anger, not guilt.
Listen, about that man you
sent to threaten my daughter.
That wasn't me,
that was my Boss.
You sure this man was
part of the Cartels?
If I was you, I'd keep him
away from the Evidence locker.
I'll keep an eye on my Boss, too.
Rader and Foster busted a drug Lab.
He's saying she's brilliant and has...
All right, keep it to yourself, huh?
Uh, Lou from the Embassy
asked me to stick around...
Lou from the Embassy?
That's Lou from the Embassy. That's nice.
Yeah, he asked me to stick
around for a couple extra days.
So I said yeah.
Is that all right?
And here I was thinking
we were happily married.
The two Techs were making
designer Fentanyl in the Hospital Lab.
They were using the blood
as a means of transport.
Yeah. Liquid Fentanyl
was injected into the blood bags,
Which would then be delivered to all the
Heroin processing Centers in the City.
A Lab within a Lab.
Pretty ingenious. Problem was,
The new guy Tomkins picked up
the wrong bags one day.
And the Fentanyl never triggered
any alarms in the patient Tox screen
Because it's a common
Anesthetic used for surgery.
Sorry I'm late.
They filled you in?
Well,
I guess we'll reopen the Central blood Bank
And track down all the units
that left Euclid Park Hospital.
Thanks to you.
By the way, you should both know that I taped
an Interview with McKenzie Dodd about the Case.
Should be airing in about an hour.
How could you do that?
The CDC hasn't had the Press Conference.
Oh, I forgot.
You love the spotlight.
I promised an exlcusive to buy us time.
This was all about getting back at Cal
and the Lightman group, wasn't it?
Gillian...
You know me too well.
It was fun.
Bye, Jack.
Here's my card.
In case you plan on making a life change.
Thanks, man.
Well, it's been a very tense time,
but the threat has been eliminated.
Dr. Cho credits you with helping a
little boy with Sickle Cell Anemia.
I knew he was slick, but, man...
You were the first person
that the CDC turned to for help.
Could I just say that I owe a debt
of gratitude to Dr. Gillian Foster,
Who really cracked this Case.
This potential Health disaster
Wouldn't have been averted without her.
Mommy!
So you're saying that you can just treat
me like a child whenever you want to.
No, I'm not.
I'm saying that on occasion,
It's my right as a parent to be
suspicious and overprotective.
Ok. Then on occasion,
I reserve the right
To throw Tantrums and spend all your money.
Deal.
Now, if you're done forcing me to work,
can I have my Holiday back, please?
How do you learn to live longer?
Well, there's Meditation and Yoga,
But for you,
I'd definitely say do both.
Yoga's that thing you do in a lounge
chair with a Mai-Tai in your hand, right?
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
Hey! Hey.
"Don't hate me too much because
I'm filled with admiration."
Give it to me.
So who sent the flowers, then?
'Cause you know I'm the jealous type.
Welcome home, Cal.
Rumor has it you never even left Town,
but that can't be true
Because you look like a different man.
I feel like a different man.
You know,
a vacation's a wonderful thing.
6 days of nothing.
Well, I heard you were working on a Case.
Well, it barely qualifies as a Case.
I feel so relaxed that...
I don't even care that Rader was here.
Then Torres told you.
Well...
So, uh,
he sent you the flowers, then?
Yep.
Have you checked them for Aphids?
No, no, I don't care.
But did he see any of my research?
I kept him out of your Library.
Oh. And is everyone still here?
He didn't poach anyone.
And did he break into
the Office supply closet?
He definitely didn't do that.
Except one thing...
The sprinkler system
was acting up a little bit.
That's odd.
What exactly happened between you and Rader?
Oh, I'd tell you,
But you'd think I was lying.
Loker. My card.
Just in case you're thinking
of making a life change.