- Hi, Lennart, it's Pelle.
- Hi, Pelle.
- This bloody cough!
- Terrible!
It was good of you to come.
- Sorry, Lennart, didn't catch that.
- It was good of you to come!
Well sure, you asked me to,
but I can wait outside.
No, no, no. Stay here.
I'm flying to Barcelona at 3.
Right then.
You're not pleased, so l hear.
No, actually I'm not, Lennart.
I think it's a shame.
This is no fun.
We'll soon be up to 700.
Who said anything about fun!
You know very well
we have to make it to a thousand.
You really mean that, Lennart!
I do.
Everything has its day, Pelle.
Yes, but...
The pyramids had their day.
Of course they did.
- Steam engines had their day.
- Sorry...didn't quite catch that.
Steam engines had their day.
That's true.
This is a new day and age, Pelle.
You have to realize that.
True enough, but still...
If this keeps up
we'll have to shut down entirely.
That would be a disaster
for a lot of people.
What's that got to do with us!
- You have a point...
- Then we will not be here, Pelle.
Sorry, Lennart, what do you mean!
I mean, what's the point of staying
where there is only misery!
No, there's no point.
When that day comes
I'll be long gone...
...and so should you!
Beloved be the one who sits down.
SONGS FROM THE SECOND FLOOR
Very nice!
Oh yes, the old boy
must look his best.
Pelle Wigert wants to
meet me today.
- And what does he want!
- We'll have to wait and see.
Lasse...
It would be nice if you could
stay home today-
-when I have my day off.
Sure, but how would it look!
I haven't missed a day in 14 years.
It would be nice all the same.
Everything has its day, dear.
There's a time for work,
There's a time for everything else.
No, no, no!
Everything has its day, dear.
You old dullard!
Bye.
Goodbye, you traitor!
- Would you please let go!
- No, no, no, no!
- Pull yourself together, Lasse.
Pull yourself together!
I've been here for 30 years!
I'm sorry,
there's nothing I can do.
- I've been here for 30 years!
- There's nothing I can do.
I've been here for 30 years!
There's nothing I can do.
There's nothing I can do!
- But I've been here for 30 years!
- There's nothing I can do.
I've been here for 30 years, Pelle!
I've been here for 30 years!
Yes?
Is there an Allan Svensson here!
No, there isn't.
He's not here!
Close the door!
Excuse me, is Allan Svensson here!
What are you doing here!
What the hell are you doing here!
- He's talking to you.
- What do you want!
- I look for man, he not here.
- Speak clearly!
- What did you say!
- I look for man, he not here.
What's up?
- Who are you looking for!
- Allan Svensson.
What the hell are you doing here!
Lasse... Yoo-hoo!
What happened?
Such heavy traffic!
Even though it's so late...
What's wrong, Pelle?
We'll buy a new golf club.
We'll buy a new one!
Could I have a volunteer?
Over here!
There's one there!
- Welcome up on stage!
- Could I take that for you!
- Sure.
When are you going to
get a divorce!
When will you do it!
Answer me!
Let's move along a bit then,
shall we!
Move! Oh. Right.
There we go.
You have to believe me, Krister.
You have to believe me!
I'm stuck here!
I haven't advanced more than
a few hundred yards in four hours!
- Hi.
Krister, I swear...
- Hiya.
Darling, what shall I do?
How are you?
What can I say?
It's not easy being human.
I agree.
- You noticed your boy's here.
- Yes.
He's been sitting and waiting
for hours.
You think I look like this
for no reason?
No.
Dare I ask what you've done?
Done! I'm ruined. The entire
business has gone up in smoke.
What's that?
I said, the entire business
has gone up in smoke!
Hi.
What have you done?
I'm ruined.
Don't you see?
The whole firm
has gone up in smoke.
Look at this...
The books!
Nothing could be saved.
It's a fortune!
Maybe it's just as well...
Is that what you have to say to
your father, when he's in trouble?
I've been waiting for you.
I want to talk to you.
About what?
You know - the future.
How everything's going to...be.
What we're going to do.
How we're going to get by.
How we're going to put
food on the table.
Enjoy ourselves.
Does anyone know
how to get out of here?
No.
You could have called.
Something terrible has happened.
The entire business
has burnt down.
Nothing but ashes...
I'm the one who set fire to it-
-and I think
I'm going to be found out.
- Don't you see!
- Dear God!
I'm the one who set fire to it!
I think I'm going to be found out.
Some traffic jam over there,
don't you think?
It's been at a standstill for more
than 8 hours. No one knows why.
The whole town
seems to be going somewhere.
Everyone in the same direction.
Makes you wonder
where they're headed.
The people...
Do you know where they're headed?
Where they are going?
Well...
- Do you want some bread?
- No, I'm fine, thanks.
- It's good. There's mustard on it.
- No, thanks.
You live around here?
Not any more.
What the hell are you doing here,
then!
I was just passing by.
I used to live up there.
At the top,
to the left of the drainpipe.
Really?
- I got thrown out.
- Thrown out?
Yeah, she didn't want me any more.
Gee, that makes me sad.
I'm really sorry to hear that.
Bloody hell...
Ask me, I know.
What was her name?
Susanne.
Susanne, don't be so cruel!
Open your door to a man
who hungers and thirsts.
Don't be so cruel, Susanne!
Bloody hell, what beasts!
Maybe there's more...
Susanne!
Don't be so cruel, Susanne!
Open your door to a man
who hungers and thirsts.
Who the hell is that?
How come you know him?
I don't know who it is.
You've got to believe me, Micke.
It's true...
I don't know who it is.
Yes, well naturally,
I tried to put it out.
But I couldn't.
I almost caught fire myself.
You see before you
a fortune turned to ashes.
Everything happens to me!
One catastrophe after the other.
Has there been a fire
anywhere else!
No, there hasn't.
There are other catastrophes
besides fires.
That are much worse.
I have two sons.
The oldest...
- ...he's seriously ill.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, he's lost his mind.
He wrote poetry until he went nuts.
Oh dear!
Yes, it's terrible.
What's a few charred pieces of
furniture compared with that?
Nothing!
Of course, they were expensive.
Well...not this one.
But there was a Chippendale suite
over there.
A sofa.
Two armchairs.
Top quality!
78,000.
Do you have that on paper?
Paper?
Obviously,
they've gone up in smoke.
But a Chippendale is a Chippendale.
Even if it's not on paper...
You, for example.
You are who you are, whether or not
anybody's written it down.
- Aren't you?
- Quite, quite.
Well, then we'll have to
count on that.
This, this is my youngest son.
They're from the insurance company-
-or so they say...
So, we'll just...have to take
their word on that.
In case you have trouble
understanding this-
-you may as well join the crowd
and do some good!
Stock prices are falling.
The bottom's falling out all over.
They're fighting for better times-
-and here you stand and quibble
over a sofa and a few armchairs.
Hi, Thomas.
Here we go again...
What have I done, Thomas?
What have I done wrong?!
He doesn't answer.
He doesn't answer today either.
Can't even say "hi"
to his own father!
He wrote poetry until he went nuts.
It's okay, Thomas.
The kids are fine.
Elisabeth too.
I drop by now and then.
You don't have to worry about them.
Or about the car.
I drive as much as I can.
Good thing someone cares!
He left his taxi and family
to fend for themselves.
Wrote poetry until he went nuts.
It's awful! It's just awful!
Beloved be the unknown man
and his wife.
My fellow man with sleeves,
neck and eyes.
Beloved be the one
who sleeps on his back.
The one who wears
a torn shoe in the rain.
Beloved be the bald man
without hat.
Beloved be the one who
catches a finger in a door.
Catches a finger...
What's so special about that?
It's happened to everyone.
He wrote poetry until he went nuts.
Beloved be the one who sweats
out of pain or out of shame.
What kind of nonsense is this?
Give me my smock.
The smock!
The one who pays with
what he does not have...
There was a wallet here too.
Where is it?
Beloved be the people who sit down.
Sit down?!
- What's with that?!
- Calm down now!
Beloved be the one who sits down!
Take it easy!
Why should you love him, eh!
- Look at that brother of yours.
- Take it easy!
He sits where he sits.
No yelling in here. Calm down now.
He sits where he sits!
Who's going to come along
and love him, then!
Can no one help him?!
It's good of the vicar to let me
come and talk to him.
See, it's like this...
My entire business
has gone up in smoke.
It's nothing but ashes.
And I have a son who's gone mad.
Makes you wonder
where you've gone wrong.
You can't talk to him.
He doesn't respond.
I'm at my wits end.
At the end of your wits...
So, who isn't?
I've been trying to get
my house sold for four years.
No luck.
I'm going to lose 200 thousand -
at least.
That's a shame.
A shame. A real shame.
What about me, then? I paid for
a trip and then the travel agency-
-went bankrupt, the money's gone.
It's all because of
the stock prices.
They...they go up and down.
- It's frightful!
- I quite agree.
Beloved be the one who sits down.
I beg your pardon?
When are you going to do it?
You could answer at least.
It's nice to sit down for a bit.
I've walked all the way
from the Station.
I thought...
"It'll be quicker to walk",
I thought to myself.
In chaos like this,
that just keeps up-
-without anyone being able to give
a reasonable explanation.
But it was along way.
Longer than I thought.
I'm in a hurry. I'm late.
I overslept.
- I had nightmares.
- Oh dear.
Where are we going?
I'm going to visit our former
Commander-in-chief-
-who has a birthday today.
- He's turned a hundred.
- I see...
Where does he live?
Where do you think someone lives
who's reached such a venerable age-
-and who doesn't have to
count his pennies.
- St George's rest home.
- St George's.
A lot of people will be paying
their respects.
Admiral Bengtsson
is going to make a speech.
And can you guess
who wrote the speech.
No.
I did.
That's my main job these days -
writing speeches...
But it still makes me nervous
every time.
Terribly nervous.
Fact is, I had to nip into
the Grand Hotel and have a drink.
I needed one.
Well, three...
to be perfectly honest.
So now I'm actually quite
pleased with what I've written.
My approach was a rather
philosophical one.
About being human -
year after year...
This is how l see it...
Life is time and
time is a stretch of road.
That makes life a journey, a trip.
- Don't you think so?
- Yes.
I guess you could
look at it that way.
And to be able to travel you have
to have a map and a compass.
Otherwise you don't know
where you are.
- Do you?
- No.
And our map and compass...
...are our traditions.
Our heritage, our history.
- Aren't they?
- Yeah, sure.
If we don't understand this...
Before we know it,
we're fumbling around in the dark.
Where are we?
Well, actually we haven't moved
more than a few yards.
- We haven't?
- No.
They keep delivering more flowers!
Sure they do - when someone
celebrates his 100th birthday.
And been so clever. Become both
general and millionaire.
Millionaire?
To put it mildly.
He's one of the largest landowners
in the country.
20,000 acres of cultivated land
and twice as much woodland.
How much is that?
60,000 acres.
How many square metres is that?
-240 million, isn't it?
- Exactly!
Two hundred and forty million
square metres of land.
And eight lakes on his property.
- Fantastic!
Unbelievable!
Really.
Uh-oh. I think it's time
for the bed-pan.
- Anna, the bed-pan!
- It's on the way...
They're here now.
Right honorable general and
Commander-in-chief Emeritus.
It is man's fate to grow older.
Year is added to year,
experience to experience-
-during our never-ending journey
around the sun.
Honored general and, if I may
say so, dear colleague.
Few people are privileged to-
-have made such a
large number of circuits-
-around the sun
as you, sir, have done.
When you now begin a new circuit,
your 101st-
-is in my capacity on-
-the headquarters joint staff-
-have the task, pleasure
and honor to-
-on behalf of all branches of
the armed forces-
-extend our hearty congratulations
to you, sir-
-as a person and as a human being-
-and as a representative of-
-the safeguarding of our country,
our traditions-
-our distinctive character
and our history.
My best to Goering.
- I beg your pardon?
- My best to Goering.
Sound the regiment's
recognition signal.
Hoist the flags!
- Where have you been?
- Sorry...
Hi!
What do you mean, "been"?
I've been all over.
I've driven all over town -
around and around...
...and listened to people
with problems.
I asked where you've been.
Yeah...and then...
Well, then I felt like
having a beer.
At least three, to be honest.
At least six, to be honest.
You could have called.
Seven, to be perfectly honest.
You didn't have to come.
Damn it, should just sell
that bloody car-
-this minute.
Thomas can't drive a taxi.
He's too soft.
He takes everything to heart.
What?!
I'm not allowed here?
- Why not?
- You don't love me.
Beloved be the one who sits down.
Beloved be the one who sits down!
...who sits down.
Beloved be the one...
Rune...
"Do unto others"-
-"as you would have them do
unto you."
In other words...
If you want me to make you happy-
-you have to make me happy.
Right?
But you haven't done that. You've
made me damned disappointed.
Have you seen the nails?
You come here, you sit down
and start talking business-
-without any dough.
Who the hell do you think you are!
I was thinking you could give me
them on credit, Uffe. 30 days?
30 days?! Who the hell knows
what's happened to you in 30 days?
I'm really in a bind, Uffe.
Kalle! Well, I'll be damned!
- You're here this year too!
- Yeah, so they say...
Alive and kicking! And here was me
thinking you'd been burnt to death.
How're you doing?
Oh, you know how it is, Uffe,
in times like these.
You have to struggle for
every crumb.
Try to find something you can sell
- with an extra zero on the end...
In that case you've come to the
right place, Kalle. Take a seat!
- Hi, Kalle.
- Hiya.
- Sit down.
- Sure.
I see, so you're tackling that
this year.
Yes, I have to survive too.
Here is the product you can put
two extra zeros on.
- You think so?
- Think?!
We're heading for the year 2,000.
Two thousand, Kalle!
And here's the one
whose birthday it is.
You only get a chance like this
once in a lifetime.
It'll be another thousand years-
-before this man
is so important again.
I won't be around then.
This, this suits you, Kalle.
It suits an old furniture salesman.
Come here. Between you and me...
check it out.
There are already too many in on-
-the champagne and fireworks.
Choose three sizes.
Take along an order-book.
Get out there and make some money!
Gee, I don't know, Uffe.
I'm so tired.
I already have a cross to bear.
The insurance company
is giving me a hard time.
And I also have a son
who's gone mad.
You what?
Yeah, he wrote poetry
until he went nuts.
Well, there won't be any money
but that'll blow over.
It'll blow over, Kalle.
- You think so?
- You shouldn't think so damn much.
It's not good.
- What happened?
- That's a good question.
He's stuck.
He's stuck in the door.
Well obviously, I can see that.
But how did it happen?
He slipped, I guess.
Slipped?
- Yes.
- How clumsy can you get?
- It could happen to anyone.
He slipped and fell backwards and
hit his other arm against the door.
- And it shut.
- Well, it's clumsy all the same.
Try to take it easy.
We'll help you in a minute.
My colleague will come and open
the door carefully from the inside.
Here he is now.
He's opening the door now.
- That's not so bad.
- It wasn't so bad, was it?
It wasn't so bad.
It wasn't so bad, was it?
Poor man!
It could happen to the best of us.
Our son got himself stuck
in a deckchair last year.
- No, it was three years ago.
- Wasn't it last year?
No, it was three years ago.
What about me? I got my finger
caught in a dresser drawer-
-and it really hurt.
And that was ten years ago.
And look,
you can still see the gash.
- Hi.
- It's been ages...
- Yes, it has.
It got empty all of a sudden.
- You really scared me, Sven.
- I did?
Yes, you did.
I suddenly felt really guilty.
When I caught sight of you, Sven.
You understand, I guess.
- You know what I thought?
- No.
As a matter of fact,
I thought you were dead, Sven.
I heard you'd committed suicide.
Yes, that's right.
But for God's sake, Sven,
why did you do that!
I had no choice.
Sven, am I to blame?
- Is it my fault?
- I didn't say that.
He's so unhappy, the poor boy.
- What does he want?
- He's gone astray, got lost.
- Are you looking for me?
- He's looking for his sister.
- Sister?
- Yes, his sister.
The Germans hanged her-
over in Russia...
Then they hanged him too.
He's so very unhappy,
because he didn't have time to-
-apologize to her.
- If I've understood correctly.
- Apologize, for what!
He'd done something mean.
Hurt her, I think-
-and regretted it, but he didn't
get a chance to make it up to her.
- Please!
- That's awful.
I can't bear to listen.
What had they done.
Why did they hang them?
Something to do with being from
the wrong race, I think.
They belonged to the wrong race.
It's terrible...
What happens now?
What's he going to do now?
- Who?
- The boy.
What do you mean, "do"?
He can't do anything.
That's why he's so unhappy.
Don't you see?
He didn't get a chance to make it
up to his sister before he died-
-while she was still alive.
Then he was hanging there himself-
from the rope...
That's why it's so tragic.
Because he can't do anything -
can't even try...
He's dead.
They both are.
Sven, how much
did I borrow from you?
Was it 280,000?
No, I know, it was 287...
Excuse me for saying so, Sven-
- I'm only being honest with you-
-but I was relieved
when I heard you were dead.
"Now I don't have to pay back
the money," I thought to myself.
There wasn't any papers.
I was free from my debt...
Good God, Sven, what should I do?
I can't very well pay back
the money now, can I?
To me? That would be difficult.
I'm only human, Sven.
A man does what he can -
struggles to get a bit...
...of food on the table.
And enjoy himself.
Jesus...
He wasn't the son of God.
He was just a nice guy.
That's why he was crucified.
- He was tormented and killed.
- What?
He was tormented and killed.
- Who?
- Jesus.
- He was crucified.
- Of course he was.
Because he was a nice guy.
Hi, Thomas.
Hello.
You could at least say "hi"!
- When your granny's here and all!
- Take it easy.
Forgive me, Thomas.
I had something fun to tell you.
- I've got a new business concept.
- Me too.
I've got a business concept too,
but it's secret.
Imagine, Thomas...
The insurance company gave in.
And why do you think they did that?
You've got to be able
to speak up for yourself.
Speak plainly
and you'll get results...
You can write poems with words too.
It's not that.
Why complicate things, Thomas?
Life is a market.
It's as simple as that.
It's all about buying something
so you can sell it later-
-with an extra zero.
Or two.
The whole world knows that-
everyone but you, it seems.
Is there no one who can help you?
- Is there no one who can help you?!
- Take it easy!
You wrote poems until
you went nuts, didn't you?!
Easy does it.
It's awful!
Is there no one who can help him?!
...that's why he was crucified.
...who can help him?!
Is there no one who can help him?!
It would of course
be an advantage if-
-the chairman of the Economic
Faculty's council of experts-
-could at this point present
at least the main features-
-of the long-term perspectives
and strategies-
-which the council would like
to propose to the government.
Long-term... I don't know if
I have those with me here today-
-but the short-term ones
should be here somewhere...
A moment, please.
Strange. I'm sure I had them
this morning.
This is obviously not good.
It would appear that we shall
have to skip the strategies-
-and concentrate
on tactics instead.
But before we do so, we should
perhaps attempt to summarize-
-what we've discussed here today.
It's difficult, I know.
Our discussion has lasted
over eight hours-
-but is there anyone who feels
they'd like to have a try?
Anyone?
Professor Frank, for example-
-hasn't said anything
for along time.
Well, I agree with what-
-most of the others
have had to say today.
All we can do is hope.
Would Dr. Wendt
care to comment on that?
The house on the other side
of the street - it's moving.
- I don't follow you.
- It's moving.
That house over there.
- What do you mean, "moving"?
- It's moving!
That's right, it is!
What kind of nonsense is that?
Hell...
It's moving...
- It is moving!
- It really is!
Take it easy! Take it easy!
Get back, get back,
the doors open inwards.
Get back! Otherwise we won't
be able to get the doors open!
Get back!
It's very important
we don't lose control.
Very...important!
What papers are you looking for?
What papers?
An official report.
A very troublesome report-
-which is supposed to clarify
why we can't afford to work.
You'll just have to write
a new one.
Try to remember what was in it.
Write a new one.
What was in it?
There wasn't very much in it.
It's hard,
it's very hard to explain-
-why we can't afford to work.
It's impossible.
It's not us who decide
that sort of thing.
We're not the ones who decide.
You've got to understand that.
It's fate that decides.
Not us. Fate.
Who can decide over fate?
Not us anyway.
All we can do
is try to appeal to fate.
That's all we can do.
You'll have to forgive me,
but I'm afraid I can't help you-
-because I can't understand
what you're saying.
Like I said, I can't help you.
Help!
Ow! I'm stuck!
Enough is enough. Get out of here.
Well now, Anna. From what
we've heard you're just fine-
-not sick or anything...
- She's completely healthy.
- She is, is she?
And you're doing well in school.
You're good at reading and writing
from what your mom and dad tell us.
I see.
- Have you read many books?
- Yes, a few.
I see.
You see, these ladies and gentlemen
sitting here...
-...they've read all the books.
- That's right! An awful lot!
- Yes, most of them!
- Yes.
And when you've read that much-
-well, then you also know
an awful lot.
Yes, and we also have
the benefit of experience.
Quite right.
- Long experience, I might add.
- Yes, indeed.
Then you know how
and what you should do.
And, Anna, there's one more thing
you know if you've read that much.
Then you know what can't be done,
what's impossible.
Exactly!
Because you can't do just anything.
Certainly not.
An ant, for example, can't eat up
an elephant. It's impossible.
Right.
And when it's your birthday-
-well, not everyone
can come to the party.
If they did, then no one would get
a bigger piece of cake than this.
- No bigger than a crumb.
- So small you could hardly see it!
- That wouldn't be such a fun party.
- No, darn it!
I can see you understand that.
But there are other things, Anna,
that are impossible-
-and that can't be done.
That you can't really understand
when you're small-
-only when you're big-
-and have read many, many books.
And then there's also experience.
You mustn't forget that!
- No, absolutely not.
- No...
I can't get up.
Help! I can't get up!
We have sacrificed
the bloom of youth.
What more can we do!
Nothing.
- What?
- Nothing, absolutely nothing
What more can we do?
- Where are we?
- Huh?
Where are we?!
At the Grand Hotel,
for Christ's sake!
Oh...
What more can we do?
What?
- But, where are we?
- I can't get up.
- Where are we?!
Where are we?!
What's wrong now, then, Robert?
It's heavy, Pelle.
I can't take it any more.
You have to, Robert.
You have to try!
Come on!
Hang in there, Pelle!
You've got to hang on!
Yes, I know. I know.
- There's a time for everything.
- Sure, right.
Pelle!
There's a time for misery.
Sure, I know there is.
But it'll soon be over.
Only a few more yards-
-and we'll have left this damned
dump under the clouds for good.
Yes. Let's hope so.
- As free men, Pelle.
- Sure, right. Sure...
- Free at last!
- Yes!
And then we'll only have ourselves
to think about.
Right, sure, that'll be nice.
- And do what we feel like!
- Sure. Sounds good.
Do we not deserve that, Pelle?
Aren't we worth it,
when we've worked so hard!
Only a few more yards!
A new day is dawning!
Yes.
Come on then!
There's a time for everything,
Thomas.
There's a time for everything.
Your time will come, Thomas.
It will... I know that.
It's not true that
no one cares about poetry.
They just pretend they don't.
Right now...
They're just pretending.
That's how it is. I know.
Beloved be the one who works-
-by the day, by the month,
by the hour.
Beloved be the one who sweats
out of pain or out of shame.
The person who goes, at the order
of his hands, to the movies.
The one who pays with
what he does not have...
The one who sleeps on his back.
The one who no longer remembers
his childhood.
Stop it, Stefan.
You'll only make him unhappy.
You mustn't be unhappy, Thomas.
You mustn't cry.
Take it easy, Thomas,
it doesn't matter.
Beloved be the one who sits down.
It's okay to cry.
That's what you should do
when you're unhappy.
- Jesus did.
- What?
Jesus cried when he was
on the cross. He hurt so much.
He was crucified...
...because he was a kind person.
Kind?
Thomas is kind, too...
...but he's got no head
for business.
Of course you're unhappy.
Jesus didn't either.
He just hurt.
Yeah, sure.
He was tormented to death
because he was kind.
He wasn't the son of God.
He was just a kind person.
Sure.
Beloved be the just man
without thorns.
The bald man without hat.
The thief without roses.
The one who wears a watch
and has seen God.
The one who has honor
and does not die.
Are you here, Uffe?
It's been along time.
I'm ashamed, Kalle.
I'm ashamed.
- It was a bad idea.
- Yeah...
The worst I ever had.
Shit!
Fucking hell!
How could I be so stupid?
Out of my mind.
How can you make money on
a crucified loser?
I bloody well blush
to think about it.
What a fucking idiotic product.
I haven't kept up with the times.
That's the bitter truth.
But I'm going to get
my act together, Kalle.
We'll have to find something else
to sell-
-with a few extra zeros on it...
If I think of something-
- I'll call. Bye, Kalle.
Is that Sven!
Is that you, Sven?
Why are you chasing me, Sven?!
Why are you tormenting me?!
I can't make it up to you.
How could I do that?!
You have no relatives.
What can I do?
Sven!
Can we not treat each other
decently?!
Forget it all.
The past...
Just look ahead!
I'd be really happy
if we could do that, Sven.
You have to understand me as well.
I can't take it any more.
I can't take it any more!
I just can't take it any more!
What the hell is this?
How much can you ask of a person?
You do what you can.
You struggle...
...to get a bit of food
on the table.
And enjoy yourself.