You are psychotherapist?
No, would like to be one.
Fucking handwriting, right? - Yes.
No, pyrotechnician. What exactly
Do I get for this. In cash, I mean?
Well we...
We thought of ...
... 1.900 Euro after tax?
Oh ... Wow! Oh!
l am your man!
You know computers?
- l have send an email once.
They caught me at the airport
Twelve years for two times
Bankrobbery.
And it was only plastic weapons.
Shit.
You are out on probation now?
- Hm, half a year.
ls this a problem?
- No, not at all.
Namaste. Namaste.
Good, Mister ...
Gopal Tscharan. Gopal Tscharan.
Good, Mister Shrin. Then, hmm ... tell us
Something about yourself.
I am from Hadravat in lndia.
Been living there.
Have been building airplane parts.
Five long years, machinery
Machinery, machinery.
Enough of machinery. And then I
Met this German woman.
And she told me to come to Germany.
1961 I came to Germany
Been working 20 years for Mercedes Benz
In Stuttgart
Machinery, machinery, machinery.
Enough of machinery.
I said: ''What should I do?''
l went to Berlin and started
To do pantomime.
Pantomime, Pantomime, Pantomime.
Me quiet, me quiet, me quiet.
Enough of me quiet
What should I do?
In the meantime me meet
Other woman.
Told me to come to Maibach.
Ok. - Small job, little one,
If you want to give me? Yes?
Well... You know computers
Technical things?
Computers?
I am a machine man.
You show me little Computer,
I make Computer for you.
I am working for telephone help line
One-Euro-Job.
But actually I would like to do something
More meaningful. You have been talking
About a project which makes people
Grow intellectually?
Well, yeah, it is about
Intellectual freedom, sort of.
Yeah, great!
- What kind of music are you listening to?
Oldies, Deejayed a little
Way back then in a youth club.
Have to say, sometimes I like to
Turn the volume up, yeah.
Bernd, you did telecommunication
Once, didn't you?
Yes, I've been learning at the German Telekom
Communications engineering.
And afterwards I was in the field service team.
Until 1996. They fired me back then.
And where do you live now?
- You met me there.
At the petrol station?
- Yes.
Hmm ... Bernd, sorry for asking,
Maybe a bit embarrassing,
But I have to ask you:
You have a drinking problem, don't you?
Not at all bad, no. Don't worry.
It is no problem for us, I only
Need to know wether you are able
To work. Are you ok with that?
Yes, got it under control, really
- Ok.
Bernd, you have the job.
And where are they supposed to live?
ln a container?
No, why? They can stay here in the pension.
Nobody else is living here.
No, that is ...
Look, that is not possible.
Now this is a nice house you have got here!
Beer?
We need a control center
You understand?
Not at my place.
Good.
Hey man, get down!
Are you crazy?
Hey man, this is no problem.
And then we need a gripper
To strip the coax-insulation.
Five times. - Everyone of the working guys
Needs a car of his own,
And ... equipment, mobile phones.
And finally where do you want
To get the 1.000 Boxen?
No problem. Been researching:
These boxes can be ordered
In Switzerland. A little bit of money
But not too much.
Here is the box, Phillip!
What are they doing?
- Would like to know.
Well, let's give it a try
So we will do it.
- Yes, ok, let's try it.
Ok, our mastermind Phillip here
Has developed a plan,
Allowing us to reach all of these targets
Within two months.
Two months? That would make it
4.16 boxes...
... a day for each of us.
Good mental arithmetic, Karl-Heinz,
Not bad but let's say, five a day.
That's easier, so are we ok
With five a day, yes?
Ok, then. Your employee ...
... is called lMA.
''lnstitute for media analysis''.
Get this into your heads.
Very important. Ok?
You visit people and tell them
You are installing the latest version
Of the quota box.
- How is this going to work, technically?
Phillip will tell you this in a minute. Ok?
If some guys want to know more
Or if there are any questions, you tell them
To call this emergency number.
This is important. The new emergency number
Is one page number one of your info folder, ok?
This is extremely important because if people
Call the real lMA, then we
Have a problem.
Do you understand? - Yes.
Gopal? Good.
Keyword under class television.
- Under class? Am I under class?
No, that is just like in India,
Simply the lowest class.
Boys!
- Ok?
This is what we are fighting for. Ok?
Now you are able to fuck these fuckers
Who make you feel like shit and who
Do everything to make you stay that way
To fuck them really hard.
- Nice thing!
This is it, right?
And this is the key to it all.
Cables counted?
- Yes, yes, yes.
''So let the earth grow
Grass and herbs
Let it grow
And be fruitful''
ls a great thing, right?
- Yes.
I am always so enthusiastic, you know what?
You can keep this.
l promise you will find advise
For whatever problem you may have.
And lots of good luck with the garden.
Thank you.
- Have a nice day. - Yes, and you.
Benni, put that thing back in again,
Or I have to beat you!
This is all possible because we
Have no death penalty.
My husband's saying the same thing.
Our German laws are simply too weak.
They should make Guenther Jauch
Rule the country.
He would know what to do.
- Yes, you might be right with that.
Sorry, I will put it all back in place.
Sorry, all back in order, ok?
No problem.
A little to the left
- Wonderful, Dieter.
What is this then?
Ouch!
Ouch, this hurts.
I am saying, ribs, Dieter. The ribs ...
Have to call emergency.
(Pegah) No.
We take over any damages.
Oh yes, of course the assurance
Will cover this.
Sure, furniture will be covered as well.
Exactly, don't worry. Ok.
Good, talk to you soon.
Thank you.
Harry slipped on a curtain.
He is not coming in again today. - What?
He had to go into hospital.
Didn't understand it all.
And how about you?
- How about it?
Fucking shit!
- I, hm ...
Don't know, must have mixed up some cables. -
Mixed up the cables?
Karl-Heinz, please!
Short cut, ok? Open fire.
Half the house burnt down.
l thought you are the electrician? -
Yes, I am sorry ...
l am no electrician.
l ... I lied to you.
I see.
Great! Well done!
Yes, but I needed that job. - And you have
To lie to me for that?
Well, have you got a clue,
How's that, jobless, no money?
Tell me,
What if we all have to go to prison?
And all this for some people
Who don't want to be saved at all?
This is not going to happen
Why are you not being able to sleep then?
I can't sleep since a long time.
Guggenheim has donated something?
Why haven't you been there?
Sorry, I  ... excuse me,
I'll call you back later?
Talk to you then, ciao.
Hello.
- Finished, So now I have to ...
Why's that? Excuse me!
- Yes, I have other customers as well.
Why don't you stay a little longer.
What's your name? ''Juergen''.
l've got a good glass of Whiskey, Juergen.
You have to ... - Sorry, gotta drive.
Come on, that's no problem.
l've got a chauffeur.
But my car is here.
- So what?
Cheers! On us!
In all countries on earth
The working class rules
Cologne is in strike
And Cuba is doing the work
Moscow is making the weather
And Beijing is doing the reform.
l am sleeping now.
- What? You cannot go to sleep now!
Sorry, I am so tired. -
And what about your chauffeur?
Good morning.
- Hello.
You are Mr Kaethner?
- Yes, what is the problem?
The problem is back there.
What has he done? - Mr Bauer
Drove into a bus stop.
That is an assurance case, isn't it? -
Not with so much alcohol.
Additionally I have to mention he is
A troublemaker. And Mr Bauer
Has no place to stay, that's why
We have to arrest him.
If he cannot pay for the damage, that is.
And how much would that be? - 50.000 Euro.
- 50.000 Euro for a bus stop?
That thing cost 100.000 and that's
Only the repair cost.
In the end it can get more expensive
Or cheaper as well.
I cannot pay this anyway.
Take him with you.
Rainer, what's up?
Something wrong here.
l am hungry.
He can't do this, really.
Wow. I am gone. I am out of this.
- Shit.
Let him do it by himself.
Fuck revolution.
How can he be that stupid?
You know what this means?
I am finished. I am dead!
This is a fucking mess.
We never should have started this
With these bums. Never!
Where is everybody?
Time was 8 o'clock for the meeting.
Nobody will come. Not any more.
- I see. And why?
Why's that...
Because you let Bernd down!
l didn't do that. There is exactly
50.000 Euro in this suitcase.
If I spend this right now,
It's all over.
Bernd is our buddy
And he trusted you.
Bernd did a Job,
And I paid him for.
''Me, myself and I''!
Who do you think you are?
You have the money, get some guys,
Have them go to jail for you
And turn around like nothing?
This is a human being?
He is in prison now! - Pegah, please.
And if that has happened to me,
Would you act the same?
But you are not like that.
Bernd is.
l will not pay this, forget it.
Ok. Then I am gone.
Pegah!
Pegah, wait a minute!
Maybe you are not completely wrong.
Maybe you are right
But please,
Don't go now and
Leave me alone with this.
Look, I know I can be such an asshole.
I know that!
I don't know why!
It's just a feeling that
If I am not like that ...
The only guys who help you now
Are different from the rest,
Not like the others.
Guys who still feel something.
And that's why they don't get along
In this fucking world!
But you don't fucking care!
You know you need them
But you cannot accept the way the are.
Sometimes I think,
If we should ever win this war
All stays the same - just like before
Only you are the boss then.
Just fuck off.
Ten.
Twenty.
Thirty.
Forty. Fifty.
Second door to the left, in the yard,
You can pick him up there.
Ok.
Yes? - This is Harry.
Karl-Heinz, is this you?
Ja. - Bernd is out!
- What? Since when?
This morning. Let's meet later. -
Ok, I am coming.
l don't believe this!
Hey, this is impossible!
Unbelievable!
Sober again, no?
It's good to have you back
Hello there, stupid.
- Just like you.
So, did you have a nice time? -
You have to tell us all!
Come on.
It's over.
l haven't got any money left.
l cannot pay you any longer.
Rainer, we have thought about this.
We go on without getting paid.
But we don't go into the houses any longer.
- The data,
All the date gets forwarded to IMA
Through the telephone line, right?
So we hook on right there.
No need to go into the houses.
Oh yes, really?
How's this going to work out then?
All houses have a general connection
That's where we connect, there is a code involved
Some new system from Switzerland
But Kalle can help us with that
And then we can make 7 or 8 a day.
Rainer, now watch this.
Simply some sort of rerouting
From the individual boxes
Right back to us here.
And then back there again.
Only we manipulate the files
Before we send them back.
And then the IMA gets all the
Manipulated files instead of the real ones.
And they have no chance to find out.
It's only a delay of five milliseconds.
Well, then ... Let's get going.
Yeah!
- Right!
I'd knew it!
Bravo!
Don't get tired.
- We will make it. - You bet.
Ciao!
- See you later!
Hare Krishna!
You got petrol? - Yes.
- And, did you pay?
No. - Why not?
- The queue was too long.
Well then just wait in queue.
- There was one already.
Liberated households
1, 2, 3 ... and counting...
Cheers!
So ...
Dear friends!
Gentlemen.
I have to tell you this:
Today at 14:36
Central european time
Our computers capitulated.
Oh!
- Fucking shit!
There was a specific reason:
To work for us totally.
Yeah!
- Wow!
Cheers to mother.
- Why mother?
It's the alien!
Computers.
The bonus will be raised today.
Now it is one beer each connection.
Yeah!
- Beer! A beer!
Well done, old man!
- Cheers!
No more fucking around.
Your breath moves in waves
Like the ocean.
Your eyes gettign tired.
You close your eyes.
Imagine a green meadow.
There is a lake now.
You jump into that lake ...
No. no.
- What do you mean, no?
l cannot swim.
(Bernd) Ok? - (Phillip) Stop it. No,
A little bit to the back.
Yes.
Yeah, this is ok now.
- Ok, fine with me now.
Ok.
Wait a moment, it moved,
Go on a little, 10 degrees westward.
So this is the real time quota.
With 500 boxes we can manipulate
One channel only, so far.
No further than that.
Do it then!
- Thry that one! - Ok.
Which one should we use?
- Which one's got the highest quota?
Here, this is TTS. - And what's on there?
- ''My new dream body''.
Oh my god, isn't that that shit,
With the beauty operations?
Fuck. Fat drainage ...
Disgusting!
Alright, let's do it on TTS, ok?
Do you mind, Rainer?
- Absolutely not.
Ok.
One Moment.
Nothing happening.
Now.
- Doesn't move. - It is.
It moved
- No, no, no.
Of course, see!
There! You see!
It's moving!
But we need another 1.000 boxes.
We need another 1.000.
No problem, Phillip.
- Not a big deal!
But that's the minimum, 1.000.
- You are a genius, Phillip.
Fucking great!
See you later, boys!
Look at this!
There is the seaside!
Hold it! Hold it!
Gentlemen, five boxes
That adds up to five bottle of beer
l'll do another one.
- One for me. - One more beer.
l am going down! l am going down!
Mr Gruendgens, do you want to comment
On the TTS quota crisis?
Crisis? What crisis? - The latest
Figures have been really bad!
We are stll leading the market.
Not like your fucking channel.
Bitch.
Maiwald, I want to see you
In my office within 20 minutes.
I don't give a shit.
Within 20 minutes.
Look, Maiwald. I don't care
How you move up the quota,
Just do it.
The customers want better content.
Thank you, thanks a lot.
Ok.
- You are ok? - Yes.
Look, this is always the same:
We once had a soap on air.
A typical soap: fucking bad actors,
Story totally predictable
Cheapest of the cheap.
The quota was terrible.
People said: What a stupid, fucking shit?'
But we went on with the show.
Day in, day out. No mery at all.
For six months. After three months
The quota started to get better.
After five months even better. And
After six months people loved it.
But why's that?
- They simply got used to it.
Understand? Adaption.
Adaption is the biggest power on earth.
You show them this shit for so long
Until they don't want to see anything else.
And now we simply turn this around:
We show them good things for so long,
Until they are adapted to it.
- And you believe this could work?
Sure! Look out, I have been working
On something, sort of a concept.
Shit.
(Phillip) Look ... Pegah, I've got a
Documentation here about ancient Egypt.
You like this?
- Guess this will be good for 7,03 percent.
Yeah. Cool.
Another thing, somehow ...
Ouch, 0,0 percent for
''Germany is looking for the superstar''.
Yeah ...
Kill them all!
''Angst essen Seele auf' (Fear Eats the Soul)
What's that then?
Early film by Fassbinder.
Thumbs up! Thumbs up, Phillip!
That's a teaching profession?
- No, a great director, trust me.
Fassbeer?
- No, Fassbinder. The director.
Hmm, Beer!
Gopal, you are the greatest!
Men hunters in lndia!
- Men hunters in lndia, Phillip!
- lndia, that's downhill Himalaja.
Yeah.
Yeah, ok. Good.
Look at this: Euro sport, they show
''American Choppers''. - What's that?
Customizing cars, real big cars.
Something for people into cars, bikes and stuff.
Here ... this is Kl.KA! (children channel)
That's ... ''Wicki and the strong guys''!
Hey, Wicki! Hey, Wicki!
Tie it up! Tie it up!!
What's the name of the captain again?
- Halva! - Halva's his name!
TV has changed a lot lately,
Some of my friends don't even
Switch it on any longer
Others changes their appointments
All the time because some
Terrible exciting documentation
Is on cable one. So I guess it's time
To ask you guys!
This is Mrs. Hagen.
Mrs. Hagen, do you like the new
TV programs? - Yes, it's simply awesome.
l think it is very interesting. They
Should go on with this.
I think it's fucking load of shit.
Hardly watch anything.
Me too. Yesterday I switched it on
And guess what?
Only stupid black and white movies.
I think the changes in TV programs
Is an excellent opportunity.
Earlier on we took it all as truth
And then we found out that
It is only garbage.
And nowadays the stuff we watch,
Is all about our own reality.
Many people like the changes
In TV programs.
This is a great thing: People
Are starting to think again.
Damn it, why the fuck I haven't got
At least 20 new scripts
Waiting for me on my desk?
All I got are some fucking musicals.
''Medley, a musical show''.
Are you mad? Thinking a musical
Has something to do with culture.
Didn't you say, we should take it easy?
But not for the whole of three days, asshole!
Out there, people are going crazy.
God knows why.
Did anybody, anyone of you
Think about our current status,
Our performance?
Sure the quota went down lately,
But what exactly are we supposed to do?
Something intelligent,
Something clever damn it!
You went to university, didn't you!
Morons! You heard it!
Buddhismus, Friedrich Nietzsche
Comparative studies, what the fuck?
Just gimme somebody who hasn't
Been drugged since ten years.
That's why I want to say,
We should be very determined
This so called "Intellectual Awakening"
Is only weaking our already
Slow growth of economy.
Of course it is a positive trend,
Our children will be comparatively
Better in school.
But what is the price for this!
Consumer electronics
The computer game industry,
A foremost growing sector
Now fell back of over a third
In overall turnaround
What, I am asking myself,
What else is going to happen,
Until we wake up?
Thank you very much. Thanks a lot.
Mrs Moll is here.
Let her in.
Anna! How are you doing?
You look gorgeous.
- Thanks.
It's a real pity that we don't have
The time to meet more often.
Come on. Let's sit down.
Now tell me, how's everything?
Great! Our new format about literature,
simply great. - Sorry? Which one?
''Hit and Read''. We have VIPs
Throw darts at book covers.
And whatever they catch, that's
Going to be read. Great idea.
Sounds brilliant! You want a drink?
- No, thanks.
And what's Rainer doing?
Have you heard anything?
No, quite a while since the last time.
Why are you asking?
Oh, nothing specific.
Well, he was a .. was a friend, right?
He was very much into this whole
Quota thing before he dissapeared.
Do you know anything?
I call you because you ...
You have that system,
To locate mobile phones.
Cheers!
To Pegah, guys!
Hey.
Ok.
Slowly. Ok, ok, ok. You go first.
Carefull, there's a small step coming.
Two ...
And ... Three.
Yeah!
We are in Berlin now,
Warsaw bridge, let's see,
What this naughty one has to say
About our new television.
I noticed this: Yesterday I saw this
lnterview, well sort of a discussion
Running much longer than usual.
Well, I liked it.
Can you give me a real good applause?
Please!
That's it then.
Televison has the tendency
To replicate reality now,
To be a picture of reality.
This is the original use of media:
Mediate and moderate.
Thus we are set free.
We can breathe
And live our lives.
A few months ago I watched TV
At this time of the day
And today I am going out for
A walk along the river.
Fuck the quota!
Hello?
Hello!
Yes?
l take care about this
Rainer!
Long time no see!
You look good.
Five years younger.
No anger?
What do you want?
Let me say one thing: Respect
Rainer. Great system!
Really, what you have done here,
I wouldn't have thought you are able to.
I have to warn you, don't mix with this.
- Cool down, Rainer, cool down.
One call and all of you
Go to prison. Understand?
Oh my god, Rainer!
Was it worth all this?
Well, I ...
I mean was it really worth
Throwing away a career.
What for? Only to proof that TV is dumb?
Something really new.
Look, twenty years ago:
People got upset
About the dying forests.
They went on street for peace in Vietnam.
These days it is all about
Brad Pitt and Paris Hilton.
And you know what?
They don't miss anything.
You started a ...
... Trend. - Yes, so what?
People chatted a little about books
Like they did about TV before.
But do you honestly believe
This changes anything?
Maiwald.
- Who is Maiwald?
That's his car, isn't it?
I burn it down!
Harry, stop it! Calm down ...
The old food chain, Rainer.
The whole shit about the 60ies,
Almost ruined us.
There can only be one on top of the stairs.
The rest has to be kept busy.
And that's not so simple.
Television gave us stability.
The best system we ever had so far.
People stay at home
And don't get into any stupid ideas.
We don't fuck up the world, Rainer.
We are the good boys, we do good things.
You fucking fascist.
This is stupid.
Bollocks, Rainer.
Plain bollocks.
There is no difference left among
The state and the media
Religion, politics, science
Economy, all one big machine
For the sake of humanity.
People have work and all what is left
Is here in this box.
You better get out of here
Or I I forget myself!
Do you really believe,
I'll let you ruin my career?
This is the deal: You go on
With whatever you want to do here,
Only the TTS-quota gets up by 10 percent
Within the next twenty days.
And I will finance all of this.
100.000 Euro for each percent.
You start right now or I report you
Right away. You choose.
Oh, by the way!
Greeting from Anna.
She is doing very well.
Good morning!
I vote for going on.
Let's give him his fucking quota.
I don't trust him.
There's something fishy.
He will report us as soon as
He's the boss over there.
True. We should not give in to this asshole.
I don't think so.
If we would do this now,
He is in it just the same.
We can proof it all.
Hey guys, quality and trash-TV
How is this going together?
We are betraying our own ideas.
But we need the cash.
One million, guys, one million!
New cars! Computers!
Money is the end of any revolution.
Same story always.
Good morning, Lore.
- Morning, Boss.
How was the weekend?
- Well ... Good! And you?
Wonderful, really wonderful!
My boat has got a new engine,
And now its fast as hell.
Really brilliant.
So these are the weekend's quotas?
So bad?
Please connect me to the
Minister of the interior. - Yes.
Oh, and Mr Gruendgens
Wants to talk to you.
I was expecting that.
Tell our chairman, I will meet him
At half past nine.
Please don't disturb me until then.
Close the door! - Yes.
Maiwald, I am sorry,
You know how things work.
The quota is a sheer catastrophe
Since months.
Things are not what they look like.
Rainer Kaethner,
You remember the name?
He ... is leading a group of saboteurs.
They manipulate the quota.
Sorry! - I don't know, how they do it.
Whatever.
Maiwald!
Brace yourself.
We are not in one of your shows.
Take it as a man.
You haven't made the change
And it is on me now
To make a decision.
And I will not sacrifice myself.
You know how things are.
Maiwald.
The compensation will allow
You a proper new start.
Didn't you have that boat?
What was the name?
''Lissy''?
Go and have a nice holiday trip
You look like you need it.
''Lucy''.
- Maiwald!
The boat is called ''Lucy'',
Fucking asshole!
I will tell them all
And you can go cleaning the toilets then.
Corrupt pig.
Fucking asshole.
Go.
Morning!
Coffee anybody?
Double or two single ones?
It's all empty upstairs.
All empty.
What do you mean, ''All empty''?
We have to be out of here in two days
My uncle is coming back.
I can take two guys to stay in my bus.
Not important. Point is, we have to get
The system back running again.
Phillip, we have to work on the system.
Get it back working.
They discovered this long ago. -
We cannot stop now.
We haven't done it long enough.
- They find out within three minutes.
And that's it then. All over.
At least we tried.
And what did we try to achieve?
Totally useless action.
Like warming up a whole winter city
With one single radiant heater.
Totally fucked up.
What have you got there?
Todays?
- Yes.
Phillip, look at this. - What is it?
- This is from today.
Here.
Impossible.
Todays? - Yes.
Holy shit!
- This can't be true!
18,7 percent! - That's the shit,
You wanted to see!
Yes, that's it!
You can watch it by yourself!
What's going on? - People still
Watch the quality stuff,
Despite we stopped manipulating
The quota a week ago.
Oh really!
Damn it, we did it!
Shit, man, I knew this,
People aren't that stupid!
I knew it!
Look at this, old man!
Rainer, what are you saying?
We should go on, right? - Yes.
Hassloch.
Hassloch!
Hassloch?
A small village in the south
With a typical average and
Representative profile.
People buy all things with a chip card.
All things going to be sold in Germany
Will be tested in Hassloch first. Get the idea?
Here it will be decided what is
Going to be produced and sold in the future.
Harry, how much is this?
1,39 Euro, Gopal.
- Thanks.
4,95, please.
Thanks.
That's 7,80 all together. And the bottle
Is on the house. I am the house.
35,95, please.
- I only got 20.
Whatever. Take it.
But I need your chip card before you go.