Now the story of a wealthy
family who lost everything...
and the one son
who had no choice...
but to keep them all together.
It's Arrested Development.
[Man Narrating]
Michael Bluth and his
family had gathered
at the courthouse...
to discuss George
Sr. 's upcoming trial.
Do not ask me how I did it...
they offered
us a plea bargain.
Really? There's a chance we
don't have to go to trial?
Absolutely, and
I say we take it...
because we will never get
an offer this good again.
- Wow.
- Great. What's the offer?
Well, I didn't read it.
I just got it yesterday.
F.Y.I., I'm trying to get
back into the dating world.
Hey, you're not
one of those silly men
that's dressed
like a woman, are you?
No, baby. I'm the real thing.
I don't understand
how a person can put
their sex life in
front of their work.
He's a man,
Michael. He needs a woman.
Can we get
back to work, folks?
We've only got 24
hours to respond...
and no matter
what this is, it
is better than going to trial.
Your father's not
here. I'll speak for him.
He loves it. He's
crazy about the plea.
He's dying to get out of that
prison and be
with a woman again.
[Narrator] In fact, George
Sr. had a woman in his life...
Cindi Lightballoon, a fan
ofhis Caged
Wisdom video series...
with whom he'd had
fleeting physical contact.
That morning however, she had
some startling news for him.
I'm a mole.
Well, you know, God doesn't
care how big your teeth are.
Yes, you could go to a
dentist. You could... Whoo.
You could grind
off about... I don't
know... 30%, maybe more.
Yeah, I wouldn't miss it.
No, no, no. I mean, I'm an
undercover government agent.
I was sent here
to investigate you.
Up until last
week, my being in
love with you was just an act.
Hmm.
- But now I
want to be with you
And I know you can beat this
case they have against you.
I know this for a fact.
I want to fight this thing. I
can beat it. I
know it for a fact.
- We're taking the plea.
-
Lucille, we're
not taking a plea.
We don't even know
what the plea is yet.
Is that a shot at me? 'Cause
that makes me
want to read it less.
You have
another  one of these?
- Yes, I do
- We'll both read it.
- You're going to read that?
- Yeah.
- It's pretty thick.
He thinks he's a lawyer
'cause he played
one in 10th grade.
[Narrator] In order to
satisfy an
English requirement...
Michael appeared in the
drama club's production...
of an original play,
The Trial of Captain Hook.
?? { Singing]
- I don't remember that.
-
Well, you left during my solo.
And I'm surprised my twin
sister can remember that...
considering she was repeating
the ninth grade at the time.
- I don't remember that.
- Big surprise, Mom.
It's not like you ever
took an interest in our lives.
Honestly, if I ever
did to Maeby what you-
[Narrator] Lindsay
recalled that
earlier that day...
she had received
a letter from the
high school
about her own daughter.
And so later,
Lindsay and Tobias tried
a more hands-on
approach to parenting.
We would like you
to tutor our daughter.
Now, of
course, we're having a
bit of a cash-flow problem...
but I assure you...
if you bring our
little girl's grades up...
I will pack your sweet pink
mouth with so
much ice cream...
you'll be the envy of
everyJerry and
Jane on the block.
We're the only
house on the block.
Perhaps we should
get somebody else.
Michael, meanwhile,
had gone to the bar
across the street
from the courthouse...
to read the plea offer.
"Not to exceed five
years, but no
less than three."
- So what do you think?
- I don't know.
I'm so mad at Barry I can't
even focus. That
guy's out dating?
- I mean, I'd love to be
dating, but  l...
- Can't relax?
No. I don't have time for a
relationship.
This is important.
No one said anything
about a relationship, Michael.
If you'd slept with more than
four women, you'd know that.
- I have, Gob.
- More than five?
Let's say "five". This is
a courthouse bar, Michael.
These are
professional,
aggressive women...
who are looking for nothing
more than a one-night stand.
No real names, no promises.
I'm not a
one-night stand kind of
guy. I don't
like lying to women.
These are lawyers...
that's Latin for "liar."
I can't believe I'm still
reading the same sentence.
How can something be "no less
than three" if it exceeds six?
I mean, six is still
more than three, right?
Yeah, and it's
still more than five.
- Oh! Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- I'm falling all over you. {
Chuckles]
- Let me move down.
I'm just working on this plea.
If you're
pleading with me to have a
drink with you,
you can stop begging.
{ Chuckles] No, no. It's a...
It's a plea
for this case that
I'm... I'm
sorry... you want a drink.
Well, I didn't
come here for the view.
- I'll have a vodka martini.
- I'll tell him.
- So, another lawyer, huh?
- Vodka martini!
I'm Maggie Lizer, as in
"Maggie lies her ass off."
{ Laughing]
One person
laughed at that once,
and I don't know
why I keep trying it.
- No, it's good. Yeah.
- What
kind of law do you practice?
?? [Young
Michael Singing In Play]
Maritime. Maritime
law. Lawyers of the sea.
Oh. Submarine chaser.
{ Giggles] What's your name?
- Chareth.
Oh. So then
what's your last name?
- Cute story...
- Cutestory?
Yes. Chareth Cutestory.
- That's an interesting name.
- Is it?
So here's the
test that I failed.
Oh, okay. Yeah, I see
the problem right away.
You, uh... You got
all the answers wrong.
You know you,
you even got your
name wrong here.
It says, "S. Fünke."
Yeah, well, see, what
they want you to do...
is put an "S" if you're
single, an "M"
if you're married.
I mean, most of
us are all single,
but it's a whole
government thing, so...
Yeah. Okay. The
first thing you want to
do when you're
dealing with fractions...
Yeah. So I'm gonna go, okay?
So just fill in
all the right answers
here, and I'll see
where I went wrong.
And you're getting
paid for this right?
There was talk of ice cream,
but not exactly on my terms.
Wow! Where did
you get all that?
Do you have a
job or something?
No, but you do.
Now, look. Don't feel guilty.
I don't really need
tutoring anyways, okay?
- Enjoy the 200 bucks.
- Oh,
there... there's six 20s here.
- That's right.
- Right.
[Narrator]
After an evening of
drinking, Michael,
being the sensible one...
offered to give
Maggie a ride home.
Oh-ho! { Giggling]
[Narrator] The next
morning,
Michael was wondering...
how to end his
first one-night stand.
- Coffee?
- Hi. Yes,
please. Thank
you. That's great.
But you know what? I
am going to have to read
that plea soon, okay?
'Cause it's a big case.
But I promise
later I will call...
[Narrator]
Michael struggled to
follow Gob's
instruction tojust walk away.
I'll... I'll... I'll
call, okay? All right?
- Hey. Who's this?
- Oh, that's Justice.
- Hi, Justice.
Is he as
handsome as he smells?
I didn't... I didn't
know that you had a dog.
- How else am I gonna get to
work?
- You  ride a dog to work?
{ Chuckles] You are
funny. Let me see that smile.
- Well, it's tough with your
hands in the  way.
- { Laughing]
- Say when.
- Okay.
And suddenly,
Michael recalled some
non sequiturs
from the night before.
So, tell me something
personal about yourself.
Uh, well, I have an
irreversible case of
ocular retinoblastoma.
Hey. I thought we
said no more law talk.
I really can't
see anybody right now.
Oh, well, I
can't see anybody ever.
- I'm blind.
- I'm wasted.
[Narrator] Michael
realized that the woman he
was attempting to
never see again was blind...
and he was
overcome with guilt.
When... can we go out again?
- Really
I thought you
were, like, just into
this one-night
stand kind of thing.
Come on. I took
a blind woman home
with no intention
of dating her again?
- Please!
- { Guffaws]
[Narrator] George
Sr. was continuing
to exploit his
relationship with Cindi.
What... What evidence
does the government have...
on old wise
George, by the way?
- Oh, I hate it when you
call yourself old!
- { Laughs]
- You're new to me!
- Oh, that's... that's nice.
Do they have
a... a file or tapes?
Oh, what's the
use? You're married.
Yeah. Let me ask you...
- We'll never be together
- Let me ask  you a question.
-
Let's just go back
to what we do best.
- Okay.
- Tweak me.
- George!
- Lucille!
Hi. Uh, this is
not what it looks like.
It looks like
you're tweaking her
nipples through
a chain-link fence.
- Yep. Yeah,  that's it.
- Is this
why you wanted
to fight this thing?
So you could run off with
this great redwood of a whore?
Listen to me.
She is a fan of mine.
She has seen everything I've
done. You
understand? Everything.
Well, so have I...
and I'm not going to
put up with it anymore.
Okay.
- You'll  be
hearing from Barry
All right. Hon? Honey? Hon?
Oh, God. I'm a home-wrecker.
- Oh, no
I never wanted
to  be that person.
- No, no
No. No, Cindi, it's... Cindi?
[Narrator]
Michael came home upset
that his
one-night stand wasn't over.
You should have
stayed with me last night.
You could have
seen me get some
major action
from a major blonde...
who just majored in marine
biology, if you
know what I mean.
I don't know what you mean. I
can't imagine what that means.
- I actually had a pretty
interesting  night myself.
- Really?
What'd you do,  read the plea?
- No,
didn't have a chance to.
I went home with someone.
What's wrong with her?
- Nothing's wrong with her
- She's blind.
- Are you serious?
I didn't know at
the time. And now I've
got to take her and
her dog to the park.
You've got work to do.
You've got to read that plea.
I know. That's
what I was trying to do
last night when you
put me up to all this.
- No, I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
I told you to walk away. I
told you to give a fake name.
I did. Thanks very much. I'm
Chareth
Cutestory, a pirate lawyer.
- It was  airtight.
- Boy, you had to
work hard to bag
this blind girl, huh?
- I certainly
can't take advantage of
her now, knowing  what I know.
- What? No
Michael, you can! Don't you...
You've just
won the gold medal
at the sexual
Special Olympics!
She can't ever
find you again.
Don't you see
that you're so lucky?
- God! How do you not s...
-
What's the matter with you?
- Didn't you "bag"
some woman you're never
going to see again?
- Well, I screwed up.
I broke a couple of
my own rules last night.
She knows that
I'm Gob Bluth...
and we got
married and I just...
- What?
- Well, she was a darer.
She's one of those girls who
just dares you to do things.
- You married her?
- I needed a dare!
[Narrator] What had started
as an innocent flirtation...
had turned into a series
of escalating challenges.
Unfortunately, the
evening was draining...
and the one thing
they never dared each
other to do was
consummate the marriage.
Well, guess it's
time to seal the deal.
Oh, wait! What time is it?
Oh, God! "Seal the deal."
My seal deal! I
gotta get to Sea Land.
I'm selling five of their
sickest seals to
a third-world zoo.
- Did you say  seals?
- Yes! I told
you four hours
ago, I sell seals!
God! Do you ever
listen to what I say?
I'm sorry I
don't memorize every
word that comes
out of your mouth.
Sometimes I just like to
think... think my thoughts.
We'll talk about
this when I get home.
It was hot.
Boy, the lengths you'll
go to sleep with a woman.
Believe me, we didn't do any
sleeping. I
had sex last night.
[Narrator] But
he  really didn't.
- Yes, I did
And later, Michael
arrived for his date.
- Hey!
- I'm so sorry that I'm late.
- I thought I smelled you
coming.
- Mm. Yeah, here I am.
I thought so.
Did you smell him?
- Did you smell the handsome
man, Justice?
- "Handsome."
- You don't have any evidence
of handsome.
-  Well, that's true.
But I can feel handsome.
Mmm.
- That feels
handsomey. { Chuckles
Mmm.
- That feels
handsomey. { Chuckles
So you didn't get a
case of"I just had a
one-night stand
with a blind girl"-itus?
No, of course not.
One-night stand? Please!
This is our second
date now. And I wanna see...
And I wanna see you
again tonight, so, um...
if it's a one-night
stand, I'm not
very good at it.
But now, listen, aren't
you busy with the trial?
Um, yes, of course. I'm very,
very busy. But
not too busy for you.
Not too busy for a
little walk right now maybe.
I'll be your Seeing
Eye dog. What do you think?
Okay?
- Oh. Should  we
leaveJustice here
Um, yes. He'll be
fine, won't you, boy? Huh?
Justice, stay.! Stay.!
Describe this to me, Chareth.
Describe to me how
beautiful the park is.
Oh, I wish you could
see it. It's just beautiful.
There's an elderly
couple walking hand in hand.
They're having
a  wonderful time.
- Yeah
"Already
served, not to exceed
six years but no
less than three..."
Uh, three years is
what I give them...
and then one of
them dies and the
other one is
not too far behind.
I can smell right through
you, Chareth. You're reading.
Leash your
dog, you... { Beeps]
- Uh, yes.
- { Chuckles] Yeah.
[Narrator] And
George Sr. was working
on a roadside
beautification effort...
brokered by
Warden Stefan Gentles.
- Inmate Bluth.
- Yes, sir?
I want you to
know that last night...
I watched a very impressive
videotape of the
title Caged Wisdom.
I was struck by the dual
life of the spiritual man.
And I did very much enjoy the
blooper bonus
footage at the end. { Laughs]
Well, you know, I almost did
strangle myself on
my own prayer shawl.
A self-choking for the ages.
- There's a Shasta can there
you seemed to  have missed.
- Okay.
- [Narrator] Moments later,
Cindi arrived.
-  Thank you, Warden.
George! I had to see you.
I'm sorry I left
before. I just felt so awful.
But I kept thinking about us.
- Yes.
- About our future.
- Yes, l...
- And I know
for a fact we can have one.
Okay. What
evidence do they have on me?
You keep talking
about a fact? You
keep saying, "I
know for a fact."
- What fact?
- Faith.
I have faith my
prayers will free you.
- Faith is not a fact!
- Oh, yes, it is.
You said so
yourself in Caged Wisdom.
[Narrator] George Sr.
had said "Faith is a fact."
Unfortunately, it was in the
Caged Wisdom
blooper bonus footage.
Faith is a fact.
No. Faith is a facet.
I almost said faith is
a fact. { Wheezy Laugh]
I am going to
trial because you don't
understand what a
blooper reel is? Guard!
[Narrator] Back at the high
school, George
Michael ran into Maeby.
I got an "A." Check it out.
Great job. Take
some more money.
Look. I gotta go.
I'm going to this
fund-raiser for
a sick girl, okay?
[Narrator] This rang
false to George Michael...
who knew that fund-raisers,
a passion ofher mother's...
were something
that Maeby would avoid.
And later, at
the courthouse...
- Good afternoon.
- Thank God.
So did you read the plea?
We've got
minutes here, not hours.
I did read it. Most of
it. Um, I definitely...
definitely read
this, uh... the
first part of this
first, uh, section.
- Uh, no. Did not read it.
- Oh, come on, Michael.
How many times are
you going to screw up...
before the
rest of this family
sees you for
the screwup you are?
I'm not the lawyer. All
right? Why didn't you read it?
Excuse me. I got busy
with my other clients.
- What other clients?
- He
doesn't know
about the divorce?
- It's an annulment.
- Oh, I looked into that too.
You can only get
an annulment if you
haven't consummated
the marriage first.
Well, I guess I'll
just stay married then...
because we all know that
I closed that deal, right?
[Narrator] But
he really didn't.
He was talking
about  my divorce.
- Your what
You and Dad are
getting divorced?
Oh, don't worry, sweetie.
No one is fighting over you.
And don't worry about
Barry reading the plea.
We'll let your
father rot in prison.
Take the plea.
We're taking the plea!
We're going to
trial, you're going to
lose, and you're
going to stay in there.
- That's enough, Mom.
- For him? Nothing's enough.
You'd think a
man locked up in
prison would be
able to abstain.
Your father, with
his disgusting tweaking!
I couldn't breast-feed any of
you kids because of that man!
- Aww!
- Shh.
They still look fabulous.
Lucille, for
God's sakes. She was an
informant. She was
working for the government.
The only thing I was pumping
her for was
information, honey.
An informant.
Dad, are you crazy?
You're gonna
blow this whole case.
It's blown. It's
over. It's dead.
Take the plea.
Get me out there.
Lets take the plea, okay?
Look. It's so nice and thick.
Oh, George, I should
have never doubted you.
Even when you slept with my
sister, it was
for a good reason.
Got her to stop
drinking, didn't it?
All right, listen. This is
all getting a little crazy.
We cannot accept
their conditions if
we don't know what
their conditions are.
Do you wanna read it?
Uh, no. It is thick.
Why don't we just take it?
- I could kiss
you on the... {
Beeps]
- Well, let's... What?
[Narrator] And so the family
gathered in the courtroom...
to announce their decision.
[Man] All rise. The
court is now in session.
The Honorable
Lionel Ping presiding.
Oh, we've got Ping again.
Please be seated.
The prosecution
has offered a plea?
- We have, Your Honor.
- We've got Lizer.
[Narrator] Yes,
Maggie was the most
feared prosecutor in
all of Orange County.
And, therefore,
I would like to
bring your
attention to Exhibit A.
[Narrator] Not
because she was
a particularly adept lawyer...
but because she
won the sympathy
not only of
thejury and thejudge...
And was that man in
the room, not you, Doctor?
but often times, the
defendants themselves.
l... I was in that room.
Is the defense
ready to respond?
- What are you  hiding from?
- {
Whispering] You've
got to call this off.
You gotta get more time. Get
more time. She can smell me.
She smells everything.
- Objection!
- What?
We haven't read it.
- It's very long, Your
Honor.
- { Whispers] Sit down!
We haven't read
it. We're gonna
get to it. I'm
gonna start right now.
That's the blind
chick you slept with?
Michael, you're in
bed with the prosecution?
It's genius. You can get
all the information we need.
Wait a minute.
How do we know it's
not a trap? Maybe
she's setting you up.
It's not a setup,
okay? She gave me her
real name. She said
that she was a lawyer.
I'm the one that lied to
her. I gotta go talk to her.
No!
- No, Michael!  You
can save this family
Please! Do the
right thing here.
String this blind
girl along so that Dad
doesn't have to pay
his debt to society.
The solution to all
our problems is staring
you right in the face
and it can't even see you.
- I gotta go talk to her.
- { Sighs]
Yeah, I better
get back to the wife.
I think I'm
going to take a scenic
drive down to
the City of Industry.
[Narrator] And George
Michael went to
the fund-raiser...
for the sick student
Maeby had mentioned...
but was surprised
not to see Maeby there.
We have been blessed
to have in our midst a
child who has shown us
the meaning of courage.
Now let's show her
the meaning of charity.
Please
welcome... Surely Fünke!
[Narrator] And that's when
George Michael realized...
Maeby had been
making money by
pretending to be
two twin girls...
Maeby?
- One of whom was ill.
- { Coughing]
Somebody get her a cupcake!
[Narrator] And
Michael went to
Maggie's
determined to tell the truth.
What a surprise. Come on in.
- Hey, I'm in. Hello. Sorry.
- Oh. Hey.
- I thought you
were going to be my
reader.
- Yeah?  Oh, you're working?
Yeah, I got a break. I
wasn't
prepared, thanks to you.
- Mm.
- { Chuckles]
What about you?
Don't tell me another
pirate is still
roaming the high seas.
{ Laughs]
Uh, hey. You
know, let's make a deal.
You don't have
to do this anymore,
cause I'm gonna
start laughing out loud.
- Okay. That's
gonna help me so
much.
- All  right.
Let's go sit down
So, uh, Maggie.
{  Clears Throat]
- Yeah
I am not trying a case.
That's fantastic!
They  settled. Great.
- Well..
Listen, I know I
shouldn't do this, but...
but I am so behind, and I
really do feel as
if I can trust you.
Yeah? What is this?
Well, you ought to
know. You can see. { Laughs]
{ Contrived Laughter] Maggie!
- What is it? Seriously.
- Well, basically...
it's an overview of the
government's case
against the Bluth family.
It's a summary of
absolutely
everything we've got.
And you're just
going to give it to me?
You're a lawyer.
What do you think?
Do we have a case?
{ Mouthing Words]
On the next
Arrested Development.
Maeby attempts to
deposit her check.
- Gob adapts to married life.
- Unbelievable!
The seal deal
fell through. Three of
the seals died on
their way to Chad.
How am I ever gonna
find a maritime lawyer?
I'm sorry, did
you say "seals"?
- Yes
I trade trained
seals for a living.
- Do you ever listen?
- Do you ever stop talking?
Tobias is sent to break into
Maggie's house
to steal evidence.
Only to discover
that she's not blind.
www.tvsubtitles.net