- Po Lazarus!
- Po Lazarus.
Well, the high sheriff,
he told the deputy
Won't you go out
and bring me Lazarus?
Well, the high sheriff,
he told the deputy
Won't you go out
and bring me Lazarus?
Get a break, boss?
No break.
Oh, bring him dead or alive
O Lord
Bring him dead or alive
Well, the deputy,
he told the high sheriff
Well, I ain't gonna mess
with Lazarus
Well, the deputy,
he told the high sheriff
Said I ain't gonna mess
with Lazarus
Pick up that hammer there, boy.
Yes, sir, boss.
Well, he's a dangerous man
O Lord, he's a dangerous man
Come on, get it! Go!
One evening as the sun went down
And the jungle fire was burning
Down the track came a hobo hikin'
And he said, boys, I'm not turning
I'm headed for a land that's far away
Beside the crystal fountains
So come with me, we'll go and see
the big rock candy mountains
In the big rock candy mountains
There's a land that's fair and bright
Where the handouts grow on bushes
And you sleep out every night
Where the boxcars all are empty
And the sun shines every day
On the birds and the bees
and the cigarette trees
The lemonade springs
where the bluebird sings
In the big rock candy mountains
All the cops have wooden legs
And the bulldogs all have rubber teeth
And the hens lay soft-boiled eggs
The farmers' trees are full of fruit
And the barns are full of hay
Oh, I'm bound to go
where there ain't no snow
Where the rain don't fall,
the wind don't blow
In the big rock candy mountains
You never change your socks
And the little streams of alcohol
Come a-trickling down the rocks
The brakemen have to tip their hats
And the railroad bulls are blind
There's a lake of stew
and of whiskey, too
You can paddle all around 'em
in a big canoe
In the big rock candy mountains
The jails are made of tin
And you can walk right out again
As soon as you are in
There ain't no short-handle shovels
No axes, saws or picks
I'm a-goin' to stay
where you sleep all day
Where they hung the jerk
that invented work
In the big rock candy mountains
I'll see you all this comin' fall
Say...
Any of you boys smithies?
Or if not smithies per se,
were you otherwise trained
in the metallurgic arts
before straitened circumstances forced
you into a life of aimless wanderin'?
Jesus! Can't I count on you people?
Sorry, Everett.
Well, all right.
If we take off through that bayou--
Wait a minute.
Who elected you leader of this outfit?
Well, Pete, I figured it should be the one
with the capacity for abstract thought.
But if that ain't the consensus view,
then hell, let's put it to a vote.
Suits me!
I'm votin' for yours truly.
Well, I'm votin' for yours truly, too.
Okay. I'm with you fellas.
Mind if we join you, old-timer?
Join me, m' son.
Join me.
You work for the railroad, grandpa?
I work for no man.
Got a name, do you?
I have no name.
Well, that right there may be the reason
you've had difficulty finding
gainful employment.
You see, in the mart
of competitive commerce--
You seek a great fortune,
you three who are now in chains.
You will find a fortune,
though it will not be the fortune you seek.
But first...
First you must travel
a long and difficult road.
A road fraught with peril.
You shall see thangs
wonderful to tell.
You shall see a cow
on the roof of a cotton house.
And, oh, so many startlements.
I cannot tell you how long this road shall be,
but fear not the obstacles in your path,
for fate has
vouchsafed your reward.
Though the road may wind,
yea, your hearts grow weary,
still shall ye follow them,
even unto your salvation.
No, the treasure's still there, boys,
believe me.
But how'd he know about the treasure?
I don't know, Delmar.
The blind are reputed
to possess sensitivities
compensating for their lack of sight,
even to the point of developing
paranormal psychic powers.
Now, clearly, seeing in the future
would fall neatly into that category.
It's not so surprising then,
that an organism deprived
of its earthly vision--
He said we wouldn't get it.
He said we wouldn't get
the treasure we seek,
on account of our obstacles.
What the hell does he know?
He's an ignorant old man.
Jesus, Pete. I told you I buried it myself.
If your cousin still has this here horse farm
and a forge and some shoein' impedimenta
to restore liberty of movement--
Hold it right there!
You men from the bank?
You Wash's boy?
Yes, sir. Daddy told me I'm to
shoot who's ever from the bank.
Well, we ain't from the bank, young feller.
Yes, sir. I'm also supposed
to shoot folks servin' papers.
We ain't got no papers, neither.
I nicked the census man.
Now, there's a good boy.
Is your daddy about?
Hello, Pete.
Who are your friends?
Pleased to make your acquaintance,
Mr. Hogwallop.
My name's Ulysses Everett McGill and...
And I'm Delmar O'Donnel.
How you been, Wash?
Been what, 12, 13 years?
Yeah.
I expect you want them chains knocked off.
They foreclosed on Cousin Vester.
He hanged hisself a year come May.
And Uncle Ratliff?
The anthrax took most of his cows.
The rest don't milk.
He lost a boy to mumps.
Where's Cora, Cousin Wash?
Couldn't say.
Mrs. Hogwallop up and R-U-N-N-O-F-T.
She must have been lookin' for answers.
Possibly.
Good riddance, as far as I'm concerned.
I do miss her cooking, though.
This stew's awful good.
You think so?
I slaughtered this horse last Tuesday.
I'm afraid she's startin' to turn.
Well, that winds up tonight's
Pass the Biscuits
Pappy O'Daniel Flour Hour.
This is Pappy O'Daniel hopin' you folks
been enjoyin' that good old-timey music.
And remember,
when you're fixin' to fry up some
flapjacks or bake a mess of biscuits,
use cool, clear water
and good, pure Pappy O'Daniel flour.
Well, guess I'll be turnin' in.
Say, Cousin Wash...
I suppose it'd be the acme of foolishness
to inquire if you had a hair net.
We got a bunch in yon bureau.
Mrs. Hogwallop's, as a matter of fact.
Help yourself.
I won't be needing 'em.
All right, boys!
How's my hair?
It's the authorities!
We got you surrounded.
Damn, we're in a tight spot.
Just come on out and grabbin' air!
And don't try nothin' fancy.
Your situation is pretty nigh hopeless.
Damn! We're in a tight spot!
What in the Sam Hill?
Pete's cousin turned us in for the bounty.
What the hell are you saying?
Wash is kin!
Sorry, Pete!
I know we're kin,
but they got this depression on.
I got to do for me and mine.
I'm gonna kill you...
Judas Iscariot Hogwallop!
You miserable, horse-eatin' son of a--
Damn! We're in a tight spot!
Damn his eyes!
Pa always said,
"Never trust a Hogwallop."
Come and get us, coppers!
You boys is leavin' us no choice,
but to smoke you out.
Damn! We're in a tight spot.
Light her up!
Hold up, boys!
Ain't you ever heard of negotiatin'?
Bet we could talk this thing out.
I hate fire!
You lousy, low-down, yellow-bellied goat!
Pete, we got to speak with one voice here.
Careful with that fire, now, boys!
Light the loft, son.
I hate fire!
Gapped-toothed, carpetbaggin',
motherless spawn of hell!
Step back, damn it. Look out.
Holy St. Christopher!
Get away from that vehicle, chaps!
She's liquid fire!
Take cover, boys! That ain't popcorn!
Let's get the hell out of here!
Scatter, boys!
Goddamn it!
Get in, boys!
I'm gonna R-U-N-N-O-F-T!
Come on, boys, come on! Come on!
What are you doing here?
You ought to be in bed, clump snatcher.
You ain't the boss of me!
You candy-butted, car-thievin' so-and-so's!
I curse your name!
Go back home and mind your pa!
What's the damn problem?
I can get the part from Bristol.
It'll take 2 weeks. Here's your pomade.
Two weeks?
That don't do me no good.
Nearest Ford auto man's Bristol.
Hold on, now. I don't want this pomade.
I want Dapper Dan.
I don't carry Dapper Dan. I carry Fop.
Well, I don't want Fop, goddamn it!
I'm a Dapper Dan man!
Watch your language, young fella.
This is a public market.
Now, if you want Dapper Dan,
I can order it for you.
Have it in a couple of weeks.
Well, ain't this place a geographical oddity.
2 weeks from everywhere.
Forget it.
Just a dozen hair nets.
Well, didn't look like a one-horse town,
but try finding a decent hair jelly.
Gopher, Everett?
And no transmission belt
for 2 weeks neither.
Huh? They dam that river on the 21st.
Today is the 17th.
Don't I know it.
We got but 4 days to get to that treasure.
After that, it'll be at the bottom of a lake.
We ain't gonna make it walkin'.
That's right.
Gopher, Everett?
But the old tactician has got a plan.
For the transportation, that is.
I don't know how I'm gonna
keep my coiffure in order.
How's this a plan?
How we gonna get a car?
Sell that. I figure you can only have
painful association for Wash.
"To Washington Bartholomew Hogwallop."
"From his lovin' Cora."
"Amor Fidel... is."
It was in his bureau.
I reckon it'll fetch us enough cash
for a good used auto voiture
and a little leftover besides.
You got some light fingers, Everett.
Gopher?
You miserable little snake.
You stole from my kin!
Who was fixin' to betray us.
You didn't know that at the time.
So I borrowed it till I did know.
That don't make no sense!
Pete, it's a fool who looks for logic
in the chambers of the human heart.
What the hell is that singing?
Appears to be some kind of a...
congregation.
Care for some gopher?
No, thank you, Delmar.
A third of a gopher would
only arouse my appetite
without beddin' her back down.
Oh, you can have the whole thing.
Me and Pete already had one.
We ran across a whole gopher village.
O brothers, let's go down
Let's go down, come on down
Come on, brothers, let's go down
Down in the river to pray
As I went down in the river to pray
Studyin' about that good old way
And who shall wear the starry crown
Good Lord, show me the way
O fathers, let's go down
Let's go down, come on down
Down in the river to pray
As I went down in the river to pray
Studyin' about that good old way
And who shall wear the robe and crown
Good lord, show me the way
O mothers, let's go down
Come on down,
don't you wanna go down?
Come on, mothers, let's go down
Well, I guess hard times flush the chumps.
Everybody's lookin' for answers.
Where the hell's he going?
The Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost.
O sinners, let's go down
Well, I'll be a son of a bitch.
Delmar's been saved.
Well, that's it, boys. I been redeemed.
The preacher done washed away
all my sins and transgressions.
It's the straight and narrow from here on out.
And heaven everlasting's my reward.
Delmar, what are you talkin' about?
We got bigger fish to fry.
The preacher said
all my sins is washed away,
including that Piggly Wiggly
I knocked over in Yazoo.
I thought you said you was
innocent of those charges.
Well, I was lyin'.
And the preacher said that
that sin's been washed away, too.
Neither God, nor man's
got nothin' on me now.
Come on in, boys. The water is fine.
Come on, boy. There, boy.
Good doggy.
All right, boys, we got the scent.
The preacher said it absolved us.
For him, not for the law.
I'm surprised at you, Pete.
I gave you credit for more brains
than Delmar.
But there was witnesses seen us redeemed.
That's not the issue, Delmar.
Even if it did put you square with the Lord,
the state of Mississippi's
a little more hard-nosed.
You should have joined us, Everett.
It couldn't have hurt none.
Hell, at least it would have washed away
the stink of that pomade.
Joining you two ignorant fools
in a ridiculous superstition...
Thank you, anyway.
And I like the smell of my hair treatment.
The pleasin' odor's half the point.
Baptism!
You two are just dumber
than a bag of hammers.
Well, I guess you're just my cross to bear.
Pull over, Everett.
Let's give that colored boy a lift.
You folks going past Tishomingo?
Sure, hop in.
How you doin', son? Name's Everett.
These two soggy sons of bitches
are Pete and Delmar.
Keep your fingers away from Pete's mouth.
He ain't had nothing to eat for 13 years
except prison food, gopher,
and a little greasy horse.
Thanks for the lift, sir.
My name's Tommy. Tommy Johnson.
How you doin', Tommy?
Say, I haven't seen a house out here for miles.
What are you doin' out
in the middle of nowhere?
Well, I had to be at that there
crossroads last midnight.
Sell my soul to the devil.
Well, ain't it a small world?
Spiritually speakin'.
Pete and Delmar just
been baptized and saved.
I guess I'm the only one
that remains unaffiliated.
This ain't no laughin' matter, Everett.
What'd the devil give you
for your soul, Tommy?
Well, he taught me to play
this here guitar real good.
Oh, son!
For that you traded your everlasting soul?
Well, I wasn't usin' it.
I've always wondered,
what's the devil look like?
Well, of course, there are all manner
of lesser imps and demons, Pete,
but the great Satan hisself
is red and scaly with a bifurcated tail
and he carries a hay fork.
Oh, no. No, sir.
He's white. As white as you folks.
With empty eyes and a big, hollow voice.
He loved to travel around
with a mean old hound.
That's right.
And he told you to go to Tishomingo?
Well, no, sir. Why, that was my idea.
I heard there's a man down there.
He pays folks money to sing into his can.
They say he pays extra,
if'n you play real good.
Tishomingo, huh?
How much he pay?
All right, boys, follow my lead.
Hello?
Who's the honcho around here?
I am. Who are you?
Well, sir, I'm Jordan Rivers
and these here are the Soggy Bottom Boys
out of Cottonelia, Mississippi.
Songs of salvation to salve the soul.
Uh, we hear that you pay good money
to sing into a can.
Well, that all depends.
You boys do Negro songs?
Well, sir, we are Negroes.
All except for our accomp... our accomp...
Uh, the fella that plays the guitar.
Yeah, well, I don't record Negro songs.
No, I'm lookin' for some old-timey material.
You see, people can't
seem to get enough of it,
since we started broadcasting it
on The Pappy O'Daniel Flour Hour.
So thank you for stopping by, but--
Sir, the Soggy Bottom Boys have
been steeped in old-timey material.
Heck, we're silly with it, ain't we, boys?
That's right.
That's right. We ain't really Negroes.
All except for our accompanist.
I am a man
Of constant sorrow
I've seen trouble all my days
I bid farewell
To old Kentucky
The place where I
Was born and raised
The place where he
For six long years
I've been in trouble
No pleasure here
On Earth I found
For in this world
I'm bound to ramble
I have no friends
To help me now
He has no friends
To help him now
Maybe your friends think
I'm just a stranger
My face you never
Will see no more
But there is one promise
That is given
I'll meet you on
God's golden shore
He'll meet you on
Whoo! Hot damn, son!
I believe you did sell your soul to the devil!
Whoo-ee!
Boy, that was some mighty fine
a-pickin' and a-singin'.
I'll tell you what.
You come on in here, you...
You sign these papers here.
I'm gonna give you $10 apiece.
Okay, sir, but Mert and...
Aloysious'll just have to sign Xs.
Only 4 of us can write.
That'd be fine.
Whoo!
Hey, mister, I don't mean to be
tellin' tales out of school,
but there's a fella in there
who'll pay you $10,
if you sing into his can.
I'm not here to make a record,
you dumb cracker.
They broadcast me out on the radio.
That's Governor Menelaus,
"Pass the Biscuits" Pappy O'Daniel.
And he'd sure appreciate it,
if you ate his farina
and voted him a second term.
Finest governor we ever had in Mississippi.
In any state.
Oh, Lord, yes. Every parish or precinct.
He was makin' the bigger point.
Well, ain't you gonna press the flesh, Pappy?
Do a little politicking?
I'll press your flesh, you dimwitted sumbitch.
You don't tell your pappy
how to court the electorate.
We ain't one-at-a-timin' here.
We're mass communicatin'!
Oh, yes. That's a powerful new force.
Mm-hmm!
Shake a leg, Junior.
Thank God your mammy died givin' birth.
If she'd have seen you,
she'd have died of shame.
Well, hi there! How you doin'?
Hard time yearnin'
where you go
Times is harder
than ever been before
And the people are driftin'
From door to door
Can't find no heaven
I don't care where they go
Say you had money
You better be sure
These hard times will drive you
From door to door
Let's bed down here for the night.
Yeah, it stinks in that old barn.
Suits me.
Pretty soon it'll be nothin'
but featherbeds and silk sheets.
Million dollars.
Million-point-two.
500,000 each.
400, Delmar.
Pete, what are you gonna do
with your share of the treasure?
Go out west somewhere.
Open a fine restaurant.
I'm gonna be the maitre d'.
Greet all the swells.
Go to work every day in a bow tie...
tuxedo.
And all the staff say "Yes, sir" and...
"No, sir"...
and "In a jiffy, Pete."
And all my meals for free.
What about you, Delmar?
What are you gonna do
with your share of that dough?
I'm gonna visit them foreclosin' son of a guns
down at the Indianola Savings and Loan.
Slap that money on the barrel head
and buy back the family farm.
You ain't no kind of man, if you ain't got land.
What about you, Everett?
What you have in mind
when you stole it in the first place?
I...
didn't have no plan.
Well, that hardly sound like you.
- All right, boys!
- It's the authorities!
Your situation is purty nigh hopeless!
Damn, they found our car.
We ain't got the time
and nary the inclination
to chat with you boys any further.
Damn, we got to skedaddle.
I left my pomade in the car.
Maybe I can creep up.
Don't be a fool, Everett.
We got to R-U-N-N-O-F-T.
Where's Tommy?
Already lit out.
Scared out of his wits.
Let's go!
Well, hell, it ain't square one.
Ain't no one gonna pick up
three filthy, unshaved hitchhikers.
And one of them a know-it-all
who can't keep his trap shut.
Pete, the personal rancor
reflected in that remark,
I don't intend to dignify with comment.
But I would like to address your general
attitude of hopeless negativism.
Consider the lilies of the goddamn field.
Or, hell, take a look at Delmar here
as your paradigm of hope.
Yeah. Look at me.
Now, you may call it
an unreasoning optimism.
You may call it obtuse,
but the plain and simple fact
is that we got close to...
...three days before they...
...dam that river.
Is this a road to ltta Bena?
Uh... Itta Bena?
Itta Bena?
Isn't that... Isn't that, uh...
Stay on this here road.
Nah, that ain't right.
I was thinking of, uh...
Take this road--
Nah, nah, nah, that ain't right.
It seems to me there's a road,
cow road that used to lead all the way...
Well, most of the way.
That ain't right, either.
Hop on in while you give it a think.
Right. Delmar.
Any of you boys know your way
around a Walther P.P.K?
Well, see, that's where we can't help you.
I don't believe it's in Mississippi.
Friend, some of your folding
money has come unstowed.
Just stuff it down that sack there, will you?
You boys aren't bad men, I take it?
Well, it's funny you should ask.
I was bad till yesterday,
but me and Pete here been saved.
I'm Delmar, and that there is Everett.
George Nelson.
It's a pleasure.
Grab the tiller, will you, buddy?
Hand me that chopper.
Say, what line of work you in, George?
Come and get me, coppers!
You flatfooted, lame-brained,
soft-ass sons of bitches!
No one can catch me!
I'm George Nelson!
I'm bigger than any John, live or limp!
I'm ten and a half feet tall!
Cows.
I hate cows worse than coppers!
Oh, George. Not the livestock.
Come on, you miserable,
salaried sons of bitches!
Come and get me!
Come on, boys, we're going for the record.
3 banks in 2 hours!
Okay, folks, hold the applause
and drop your drawers.
I'm George Nelson
and I'm here to sack the city ltta Bena!
He's a live wire, though, ain't he?
All the money in a bag.
What are you lookin' at, grandpa?
Pardon me, George.
You got a plan for gettin' out of here?
Sure, boys.
Here's my plan.
They ain't never seen ordnance like this!
Thank you, folks.
And remember, Jesus saves,
but George Nelson withdraws!
Go fix the auto voiture, Pete.
Is that Babyface Nelson?
Who said that?
What ignorant, lowdown, slanderizin'
son of a bitch said that?
My name is George Nelson! Get me?
She didn't mean nothin' by it, George.
George Nelson!
Not Babyface!
You remember!
And you tell your friends!
I'm George Nelson.
Born to raise hell.
Well, that was some fun,
now, wasn't it, George?
Yeah.
Almost makes me wished
I hadn't have been saved.
Jacking up banks.
I can see how a fella'd derive a whole lot
of pleasure and satisfaction out of it.
It's okay.
Hoo, dawgies!
Well...
I'm takin' off.
You boys might as well
keep my share of the riches.
Well, where are you going, George?
I don't know.
Who cares?
Now, what do you suppose is eatin' George?
Well, Delmar, they say that
with the thrill-seeking personality,
what goes up must come down.
On top of the world one minute,
haunted by meekness the next.
Yes, sir, it's as if our old friend, George,
is a alley cat and his own damn humors
are swingin' him by the tail.
I wouldn't worry, Delmar.
He'll be back on top again.
I don't think we've seen
the last of George Nelson.
Don't be saps for Pappy.
Homer Stokes for governor.
Let's sweep this state clean.
Vote for Stokes, brother.
Aw, shh shh. Hang on!
I'm gonna slap one on here.
Folks, here's my cousin Ezra's niece,
Eudora, from out of Greenwood,
doin' a little number
with her cousin Tom-Tom,
which I predict you gonna enjoy thoroughly.
Now, what can I do you for, Mr. French?
How can I lay ahold of them
Soggy Bottom Boys?
Soggy Bottom.
I don't precisely recollect them.
They cut a record in here a few days ago
with an old-timey harmony thing
with a guitar accompani... accompani...
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, I remember them.
Colored fellas, I believe.
Yes, sir, they a fine bunch of boys.
They sang into yonder can, then skedaddled.
Well, that record is just goin'
through the goddamn roof.
- They playin' it as far away as Mobile.
- No.
Whole damn state's goin' apey.
Well, it was a powerful air.
Hot damn, we got to find them boys
and sign 'em to a big fat contract.
Hell's bells, Mr. Lund, if we don't,
the goddamn competition will.
Oh, mercy, yes, we got
to beat that competition.
- Yes, sir.
Fly away
Like a bird,
from these prison walls I'll fly
I'll fly away, fly away
I'll fly away, fly away, o' glory
In the mornin'
When I die,
hallelujah by and by
I'll fly away, fly away
Just a few more weary days
and then
I'll fly away, fly away
To a land where joys
will never end
I'll fly away, fly away
I'll fly away, fly away, o' glory
In the mornin'
When I die hallelujah by and by
I'll fly away, fly away
When the shadows
of this life have gone
I'll fly away, fly away
Like a bird from
these prison walls I'll fly
I'll fly away, fly away
Delmar. Over here.
Do you have the Soggy Bottom Boys
performing "Man of Constant Sorrow"?
No, ma'am. We got
a new shipment in yesterday.
Sorry, but we just can't
keep 'em on our shelves.
I'll fly away, fly away, o glory
I'll fly away, fly away
In the mornin'
When I die, hallelujah by and by
I'll fly away, fly away
Just a few more weary days
and then
I'll fly away, fly away
To a land where joys
will never end
I'll fly away, fly away
I'll fly away, fly away, o glory
In the mornin'
How are you?
When I die, hallelujah by and by
Delmar, come on. Go.
I'll fly away, fly away
In the mornin'
Shut up, Delmar.
Pull over! Pull over!
Guess old Pete's got the itch.
Go to sleep, you little baby
Your mama's gone away
and your daddy's gonna stay
Didn't leave nobody but the baby
Go to sleep, you little baby
Howdy do, ladies?
Name of Pete.
Go to sleep, you little baby
Everybody's gone
in the cotton and the corn
Didn't leave nobody but the baby
Ain't you gonna introduce us, Pete?
I don't know their names.
I seen 'em first!
You're sweet, little baby
Honey in the rock
and the sugar don't stop
Gonna bring a bottle to the baby
Don't you weep, pretty baby
She's long gone with her red shoes on
Gonna need another lovin' baby
Go to sleep, you little baby
Ladies, my name is Ulysses Everett McGill,
and, well, you three ladies are about the...
You and me and the Devil makes three
the prettiest...
Don't need no other lovin' baby
water lilies...
Go to sleep, you little baby
Corn liquor.
You and me and the Devil makes three
Don't need no other lovin' baby
Go to sleep, you little baby
Your mama's gone away,
and your daddy's gonna stay
Didn't leave nobody but the baby
Go to sleep, you little baby
Come lay your bones
on the alabaster stones
And be my everlovin' baby
Everett.
My hair!
Look at this.
Pete!
Where the heck are you?
We ain't got time for hide-and-seek!
Now, we ain't got time for your shenanigans!
Sweet Jesus, Everett.
They left his heart.
What the... Delmar,
what the heck's got into you?
Can't you see it, Everett?
Them sirens did this to Pete.
They loved him up and turned him
into a horny toad.
Pete!
Pete! Pete!
Pete, it's me, Delmar.
It's me, Delmar.
Everett.
Delmar, what the...
What are we gonna do?
I'm not sure that's Pete.
Of course it's Pete. Look at him.
We got to find some kind of...
wizard can change him back.
I'm just not sure that's Pete.
You can't display a toad
in a fine restaurant like this.
Why, the good folks here'd go
right off their feed.
Hey. I just don't think it's right
keeping him under wraps,
like we was ashamed of him.
Well, if it is Pete, I am ashamed of him.
The way I see it, he got what he deserved.
Fornicating with some whore of Babylon.
These things don't happen
for no reason, Delmar.
It's obviously some kind of
judgment on Pete's character.
Well, the two of us was fixin' to fornicate.
You're gonna have to excuse
my rusticated friend,
unaccustomed as he is to city manners.
Hmm?
I guess we'll have ourselves
a couple of steaks
and some gratine potatoes
and wash it down with some
of your finest bubbly wine.
Oh, and I don't suppose you have any...
Maybe the chef could prepare...
Just bring us a couple
of leaves of raw cabbage.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
That kind of barnyard language--
I don't believe I've seen
you boys around here before.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Name of Daniel Teague,
known in these precincts
as Big Dan Teague.
Or to those who are pressed for time,
Big Dan tout court!
How you doin', Big Dan?
My name's Ulysses Everett McGill.
This is my associate Delmar O'Donnel.
I detect, like me,
you're endowed with the gift of gab.
I flatter myself that such is the case.
In my line of work, it's plumb necessary.
The one thing you don't want...
is air in the conversation.
Once again we find ourselves in agreement.
What kind of work you do, Big Dan?
Sales, Mr. McGill, sales!
And what do I sell?
The truth, every blessed word of it.
From Genesis on down to Revelations.
That's right, the Word of God,
which, let me tell you,
there is damn good money in
during these times of woe and want.
People are lookin' for answers
and Big Dan sells
the only book that's got 'em.
And what do you do
you and your... tongue-tied friend?
We...
We're adventurers, sir.
Currently pursuing a certain opportunity,
but we're open to others as well.
I like your style, young man,
so I'm gonna propose you a proposition.
You cover my bill, so I don't
have to run back upstairs,
get your waitress to wrap
your dinner picnic-style,
and we shall retire
to more private environs,
where I will tell you how there
are vast amounts of money
to be made in the service of God almighty.
Well, why not? If nothin' else,
I can use some civilized conversation.
Don't forget your shoe box, friend.
Languishin'!
Goddamn campaign is languishin'!
We need a shot in the arm.
You hear me, boys?
In the goddamn arm!
Election held tomorrow,
that son of bitch Stokes
would win it in a walk!
Well, he's the reform candidate, Daddy.
Yeah?
A lot of people like that reform.
Maybe we should get us some.
I'll reform you, you soft-headed son of a bitch.
How we gonna run reform
when we're the damn incumbent?
Is that the best idea
you boys can come up with?
Reform?!
Weepin' Jesus on the cross.
That's it!
You may as well start drafting
my concession speech right now.
Okay, Pappy.
I'm just making a point,
you stupid son of a bitch.
Give me back that hat! Hurry up!
Pappy's just makin' a point.
Shut up!
Thank you, boys, for throwing in
that fricassee.
I'm a man of large appetites
and even with lunch under my belt,
I was feeling a mite peckish.
It's our pleasure, Big Dan.
Thank you as well for
the conversational hiatus.
I generally refrain from
speech during gustation.
There are those who attempt
both at the same time.
I find it coarse and vulgar.
Where were we?
Making money in the Lord's service.
You don't say much, friend, but when you do,
it's to the point and I salute you for it.
Yes, Bible sales.
Now, the trade is not a complicated one.
There are but two things to learn.
One being where to find a wholesaler,
the Word of God in bulk, as it were.
Two, how to recognize your customer.
Who are you dealing with?
It's an exercise in psychology, so to speak.
And it is that which I propose
to give you a lesson in right now.
Why, I like to think I'm a pretty astute
observer of the human scene, too, Big Dan.
No doubt, brother.
I figured as much back at the restaurant.
That's why I invited you all out here
for this advanced tutorial.
What's going on, Big Dan?
It's all about the money, boys!
That's it!
Gol... durned... money!
I don't get it, Big Dan.
I just take your show cards...
...and whatever you got in the hole.
What the...
There ain't nothin' but a damn toad.
No, you don't understand.
That's Pete.
Pete.
You know these things give you warts?
End of lesson.
So long, boys.
See you in the funny papers.
Y'all seen the end of Big Dan Teague.
Where are they?
Talk, you unreconstructed whelp of a whore!
Where they headed?
Your screams ain't gonna save your flesh.
Only your tongue is, boy.
Where they headed?
Lump, I.O.
Sweet summer rain.
Like God's own mercy.
Your two friends have abandoned you, Pete.
They don't seem to care about your hide.
Okay.
Stairway to heaven.
We shall all meet by-and-by.
Goddamn it!
God forgive me!
Hold.
Believe me, Delmar, he would
have wanted us to press on.
Pete, rest his soul, was
one sour ass son of a bitch
and not given to acts of
pointless sentimentality.
It just don't seem right digging up
that treasure without him.
Maybe it's for the best he was squished.
Why, he...
was barely a sentient being and...
well, as soon as we get
ourselves cleaned up,
and we get a little smellum in our hair,
why, we're gonna feel
100% better about ourselves,
and about life in general.
Must be near Parchman Farm.
Sorry sons of bitches.
Seems like a year ago
we busted off the farm.
Pete got a brother?
Not that I'm aware.
Heat must be getting to me.
Oh, the storm and its fury raged today
Crushing hope
that we cherished so dear
The cloud and storm
will in time pass away
And the sun again
will shine bright and clear
Keep on the sunny side
Always on the sunny side
Keep on the sunny side of life
It will help us every day
It will brighten all the way
If we'll keep on the sunny side of life
That was wonderful. That sure was.
Yes.
Now, I know the Sunnysiders
would agree with me,
when I say the great state of Mississippi
cannot afford four more years
of Pappy O'Daniel!
Four more years of cronyism!
Nepotism! Rascalism!
Of service to the interests!
Now, the choice, she's a clear 'un.
Pappy O'Daniel, slave of the interests.
Homer Stokes, servant of the little man.
Ain't that right, little fella?
He ain't lyin'!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the little man has admonished me
to grasp the broom of reform
and sweep this state clean!
It's gonna be, "Back to the flour mill, Pappy!"
The interests can take care of themselves.
Come Tuesday,
we're gonna sweep the rascals out!
Clean government is yours for the asking!
Folks, now the little Wharvey gals!
Wharvey gals?
Did he just say little Wharvey gals?
Come here, girls.
What y'all gonna sing for us?
"In the highways"
Goddamn it all!
You know them gals, Everett?
In the highways
In the hedges
I'll be somewhere
a-working for my Lord
I'll be somewhere a-working
I'll be somewhere
a-working for my Lord
I'll be somewhere a-working
I'll be somewhere
a-working for my Lord
Hey, girls!
Daddy!
Daddy? He ain't our daddy.
Hell, I ain't. What's this Wharvey gals?
Your name's McGill.
No, sir. Not since you got hit by that train.
What are you talking about?
I wasn't hit by any train.
Mama says you was hit by a train.
- Blooey!
- Nothin' left.
Just a grease spot on the L & N.
Damn it, I wasn't hit by any train!
That's why Mama's got us back to Wharvey.
That's her maiden name.
You got a maiden name, Daddy?
No, Daddy don't have a maiden name.
- See--
- That's your misfortune.
That's right, and now
Mama's got a new beau.
He's a suitor.
Yeah, I heard about that.
Mama says he's bona fide.
Mmm.
He give her a ring?
Yes, sir. A big 'un.
- Gotta gem.
- Mama checked it.
It's bona fide.
He's a suitor.
What's his name?
Vernon T. Waldrip.
Uncle Vernon.
Till tomorrow.
Then he's gonna be Daddy.
I am the only daddy you got.
I am the damn pater familias.
But you ain't bona fide.
Where's your mama?
She's at the five-and-dime.
Buying nipples.
This way
To take me home
Kiss me more
Daddy!
Hello, sugar!
How's my little girl?
Hi.
Who the hell's that?
Starla Wharvey.
Starla McGill, you mean.
How come you never told me about her?
'Cause you was hit by a train.
That's another thing. Why are you
telling our gals I was hit by a train?
Lots of respectable people
been hit by trains.
Judge Hobby over in Cookville
was hit by a train.
What was I supposed to tell 'em?
That you were sent to the penal farm
and I divorced you from shame?
I take your point.
But it does put me in
a damned awkward position
vis  vis my progeny.
Hello, Penny.
Is this gentlemen bothering you?
You Waldrip?
Uh-huh. That's right.
Hmm.
You been using my hair treatment?
Your hair treatment?
Excuse me.
I got news for you.
In case you hadn't noticed,
I wasn't hit by a train,
and I have traveled many a weary mile
to be back with my wife
and my six daughters.
Seven, Daddy!
That ain't your daddy, Alvinelle.
Your daddy was hit by a train.
Penny, you stop that!
No, you stop it! Vernon here's got a job.
Vernon's got prospects. He's bona fide.
What are you?
I'll tell you what I am.
I am the pater familias,
and you can't marry him!
I can, I am, and I will, tomorrow.
I got to think about the little Wharvey gals.
They look to me for answers.
Vernon can support 'em and
buy 'em lessons on the clarinet.
The only good thing you ever did
for the gals was get hit by that train!
Why, you lying unconstant succubus.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You can't swear at my fiancee!
Oh, yeah?
Well, you can't marry my wife!
Who is that man?
He's not my husband.
Just a drifter, I guess.
Just some no-account drifter.
And stay out of Woolworth's!
I'll bet she does imitations, too.
Deceitful, two-faced she-wolf.
Never trust a female, Delmar.
Remember that one simple precept
and your time with me
will not have been ill-spent.
Okay, Everett.
"Hit by a train."
Truth means nothing to a woman, Delmar.
Triumph of the subjective.
You ever been with a woman?
Well, I've...
I got to get the family farm back,
before I can start thinking about that.
That's right. If then.
Believe me, Delmar,
a woman is the most fiendish
instrument of torture ever devised
to bedevil the days of man.
Everett, I never figured you
for a pater familias.
Oh, yes. I have spread my seed.
And look what it's...
Goddamn it. What the hell's going on?
Okay, boys. Enjoy your picture show.
Do... not... seek the treasure.
Do... not...
seek the treasure.
It's a bushwhack.
They're fixin' an ambush.
Do... not... seek the treasure.
We...
We thought you was...
a toad.
We... thought...
you... was... a toad.
Do... not... seek... the treasure.
- Quiet there!
- Watch the picture!
I signed that bill.
I signed a dozen agriculture bills.
Everyone knows I'm a friend of the farmer.
What do I gotta do, start tending livestock?
We can't do that, Daddy.
We might offend our constituency.
We ain't got a constituency!
Stokes got a constituency!
Well, it's a well-run campaign.
Midget and broom and whatnot.
Devil his due.
Hell of an organization.
Say, I got an idea.
What's that, junior?
We can hire us a little fella
even smaller than Stokes's.
You slump-shouldered sack of nuts!
Why, we'd look like a bunch
of Johnny-come-latelys,
breakin' out our own midget.
Don't matter how stumpy!
And that's the goddamn problem right there.
People think Stokes has got fresh ideas.
He's au courant and we're the past!
It's a problem of...
- Perception.
- That's right.
Reason why he's pulling our pants down.
Gonna paddle a little behind.
Ain't gonna paddle it.
Gonna kick it. Real hard.
No, I believe he's gonna paddle it.
I don't believe that's a proper description.
Well, that's how I'd characterize it.
I believe it's more of a kickin' situation.
God... God forgive me.
I could not gaze upon that far shore.
Pete.
Hold still!
Can't... stand much longer.
It was... it was a moment of weakness.
Quit yer babblin', Pete.
We gotta skedaddle.
That's all I got.
They lured me out for a bathe,
and then they dunked me,
trussed me up like a hog,
and turned me in for the bounty.
I should have guessed it.
Typical womanly behavior.
We're just lucky we left
before they came back for us.
We didn't abandon you, Pete.
We just thought you was a toad.
No, they never did turn me into a toad.
Well, that was our mistake then.
And we was beat up by a bible salesman
and banished from Woolworths.
I don't know, Everett.
Was it the one branch or all of them?
Well, I ain't had it easy, either, boys.
Frankly... Well, I...
I spilt my guts about the treasure.
Huh?
I'm awful sorry I betrayed you, fellas.
Must be my Hogwallop blood.
That's all right, Pete.
Awful white of you to take it like that, Everett.
I feel wretched.
Spoiling your play
for a million dollar point two.
It's been eatin' at my guts.
Oh, that's all right.
You boys are true friends!
You're my boon companions.
Pete, I don't want you to beat
yourself up about this, eh?
I can't help it, but that's
a wonderful thing to say.
Yeah.
Pete...
The fact of the matter is...
Damn it.
There ain't no treasure.
Fact of the matter is there never was.
But...
So, where's all the money
from the armored car job?
Never knocked over no armored car.
Sent up for practicing law without a license.
But...
Damn it, I had to bust out.
My wife wrote me she was
getting married, I gotta stop it.
I had two weeks left on my sentence.
I couldn't wait two weeks.
She's getting married tomorrow.
My added time for the escape,
I don't get out now till 19... 87.
I am sorry about that.
I'll be...
84 years old.
I guess they'll tack on 50 years for me, too.
Boys, we was chained together.
I had to tell you something.
Busting out alone was not an option.
I'm sorry.
84 years old.
Well, I'll only be 82.
You! You ruined my life!
You ruined my life!
I do apologize about that, Pete.
84 years old!
I'm becoming Papillon!
Delmar!
Oh death
Whoa death
Won't you spare me over till another year?
Well, I am death, none can excel
I'll open the door to heaven or hell
Whoa, death, someone would pray
Could you wait to call me another day?
That's Tommy. They got Tommy.
Noose.
Sweet Jesus, we got to save him.
I'll fix your feet till you can't walk
I'll lock your jaw till you can't talk
I'll close your eyes so you can't see
The color guard.
Death, I come to take the soul
Leave the body and leave it cold
Oh death
Whoa death
Won't you spare me over till another year?
Brothers!
Oh, brothers!
We have all gathered here
to preserve our hallowed
culture and heritage
from intrusion,
inclusion,
and dilution
of color, of creed
and of our old-time religion.
We aim to pull evil up by the root
before it chokes out
the flower of our culture and heritage.
And our women.
Let's not forget those ladies, y'all,
Iooking to us for protection
from darkies,
from jews,
from papists,
and from all those smart-ass folks say
we come descended from monkeys.
That's not my culture and heritage.
Yes!
Is that your culture and heritage?
No!
And so...
we gonna hang us a Negro.
Hooray!
I ain't never harmed you.
Neither of you gentlemen.
I ain't never harmed nobody.
- Hey, hey, Tommy.
- Huh?
Tommy, we come to rescue you.
That's mighty kind of you boys,
but I don't think nothing's
gonna save me now.
The devil's come to collect his due.
Don't be crazy, Tommy.
You don't want to get hanged.
Well, nah, I don't reckon I do,
but that's the way it seems to be working out.
Listen, Tommy, I got a plan.
No!
The color guard is colored.
Who made them the color guard?
Run, boys!
Whoa!
No, no, son!
Can't let that flag touch the ground!
- Leave me alone.
- Get your hands off me.
I can do this myself. Get away from me.
I'm saying we should hire this man away.
That's a good idea, Pappy.
Hell of an idea.
Can't beat 'em, join 'em.
Have him join us. Run our campaign
instead of that egghead's.
Enticements of power, wealth, et cetera.
No one says no to Pappy O'Daniel.
Oh, gracious, no.
Not with his blandishments.
And powers of persuasion.
What's his name again?
The campaign manager?
Yes.
Waldrip.
Vernon Waldrip.
Vernon T. Waldrip.
Hmm.
It's an invitation-only affair.
We'll have to sneak in
through the service entrance.
Hold on.
Wait a minute.
Who elected you leader of this outfit?
Since we've been following your lead,
we got nothing but trouble.
I've gotten this close to being strung up,
and consumed in a fire,
and whipped no end,
and sunstroked, and soggied.
And turned into a frog.
He wasn't turned into a frog.
Almost loved up, though.
So, you're against me now, too?
Is that how it is, boys?
The whole world
and God almighty.
Now you?
I guess I deserve it.
Boys...
I know that I made some tactical mistakes,
but if you just stick with me,
I got a plan. Believe me, boys,
we can fix this thing,
and I can get my wife back,
and we can get out of here.
Goddamn disgrace!
Made a travesty of the entire evening.
What I wouldn't give to get
ahold of those agitators.
I mean, whoever heard of such behavior,
even amongst the colored?
Or mulattos, maybe.
I suspect some miscegenation
in their heritage.
How else you going to explain it?
Using a confederate flag as a missile.
Crazy! No one's ever going to believe
we're a real band.
No. It's going to work.
I just got to get close enough to talk to her.
Taking off with us has got more future
than marrying some guy named Waldrip.
I'm goddamn bona fide.
I got the answers.
Everett, my beard itches.
Hey. Hey.
"In the Jailhouse Now", fellers,
neighborhood of "B."
Penny.
It's me.
No.
Honey, honey.
I had a friend named Ramblin' Bob
He used to steal, gamble and rob
He thought he was the smartest guy around
We're leaving the state.
Pursuing opportunities in another venue.
I got big plans.
Not minstrels, this here's just a dodge.
I'm going to be a dentist.
I know this guy who'll print me up a license.
He's in the jailhouse now
Well, I told him once or twice
To stop playin' cards and a-shootin' dice
He's in the jailhouse now
Bob liked to play his poker
Why, that is an improper suggestion.
I can't switch sides
in the middle of a campaign.
Especially to work for a man
who lacks moral fiber.
Moral fiber?
Why, you little pasty-face sumbitch.
I invented moral fiber.
Pappy O'Daniel was displaying
rectitude and high-mindedness
when that egghead you work for
was still messing his drawers.
Honey.
Go away.
I want to be what you want me to be, honey.
I want you and the gals to come with me.
What, dear?
To stop playin' cards and a-shootin' dice
What are you doing here, Pappy?
Well, I guess someone let on
we was giving out liquor.
Yeah, well, you'll be laughing out the
other side of your face come November.
Pappy O'Daniel will be laughing then.
Not out the other side of his face, though.
Oh, no, no, no. Just the regular side.
They're my daughters, too, Penny.
Ain't you ever heard of amor fidelis?
In constant sorrow
I am the man
Of constant sorrow
I've seen trouble
Hot damn! It's the Soggy Bottom Boys!
I bid farewell
To old Kentucky
The place where I was born and raised
The place where he
Was born and raised
Holy moley!
These boys are a hit!
But, Pappy, they's integrated.
Wait a minute.
Well, I guess folks don't mind
they's integrated.
You's miscegenated.
All you boys is miscegenated!
Give me the microphone!
These boys is not white.
Hell, they ain't even old-timey.
Look, I happen to know,
ladies and gentlemen
that this band of miscreants here,
this very evening,
interfered with a lynch mob
in the performance of its duties.
Oh, yeah, it's true.
See, I belong to a certain secret society.
I don't believe I got to mention
its name, you know?
Let 'em play! Go on!
And these boys here,
they trampled all over our venerated
observances and rituals.
Now, this here music is over, all right?
And I have... No! Hey!
Hey, I ain't... listen to me.
Folks, listen to me. I...
These boys desecrated a fiery cross.
We was all havin' a good time!
And they's convicts, folks.
Fugitives escaped off the farm.
Now, folks, these boys got to be
remanded to the authorities.
Criminals!
And I have it from the highest authority
that that Negro sold his soul to the devil!
Wait, wait, wait a minute, now, folks.
No! It's true!
It's true.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, folks.
Is you is, or is you ain't my constituency?
No!
Is you is, or is you ain't
my constituency?
No!
Is you is...
Is you is, or is you ain't
my constituency?
Oh, come on, folks.
No. It's Homer now.
Come on. I'm a friend of the little man.
This is not fair!
Hey! Come on!
Come on, now, folks.
We got a little misunderstanding here.
Goddamn!
It's fair to tell
My only lover
I never expect
To see you again
For I'm bound to ride
That northern railroad
Perhaps I'll die upon that train
Perhaps he'll die upon this train
Goddamn! Opportunity knocks.
Get out of my way!
I'm just a stranger
In case you ever
See your man
But there is one promise
That is given
I'll meet you on
God's golden shore
He'll meet you on
That's fine.
That's fine!
Ladies and gentlemens,
here and listening at home,
the great state of Mississippi
Pappy O'Daniel, governor
wants to thank the Soggy Bottom Boys
for that wonderful performance!
And it looks like
the only man in this great state,
who ain't a music lover,
is my esteemed opponent in the upcoming,
Homer Stokes.
Yeah, well, there ain't
no accounting for taste.
He sounded to me like he was harboring
some kind of hateful grudge
against the Soggy Bottom Boys
on account of their rough and rowdy past.
Looks like...
Homer Stokes is the kind of fellow
wants to cast the first stone.
Well, I'm with you, folks.
I'm a forgive and forget Christian.
And I say if their rambunctiousness
and misdemeanoring is behind them...
It is, ain't it, boys?
Yes, sir, it is.
Well, then, I say,
by the power vested in me
these boys is hereby pardoned.
And furthermore...
In the second Pappy O'Daniel administration,
these boys is going to be in my brain trust.
What's that mean, Everett?
Well, Delmar, it means that you and me
and Pete and Tommy are going to be
the power behind the throne, so to speak.
Oh, okay.
So, without further ado,
and by way of endorsing my candidacy,
the Soggy Bottom Boys
is going to lead us all in a chorus of
"You Are My Sunshine."
Ain't you, boys?
Governor, it's one of our favorites.
Son...
You're gonna go far.
You are my sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy
When skies are grey
You'll never know, dear
How much I love you
Please don't take
My sunshine away
I guess Vernon T. Waldrip
is gonna be going on relief.
Maybe I can throw a little patronage his way.
Get him a job digging ditches
or rounding up stray dogs.
So, is the marriage off, then, Miss Wharvey?
It's McGill.
No. The marriage will take place as planned.
With a little change of cast.
Me and the little lady are gonna
pick up the pieces
and retie the knot, mixaphorically speaking.
You boys are invited, of course.
Hell, you're the best men.
I already got the rings.
Where's your ring, honey?
I ain't worn it since our divorce came through.
It must still be in the roll-top in the old cabin.
Never thought I'd need it.
Vernon bought one encrusted with jewels.
Now's the time to buy it off him cheap.
We ain't getting married with his ring.
You said you'd changed.
Honey, it's just an old pewter thing.
Ain't going to be no wedding.
It's just a symbol, honey.
No wedding.
We'll go fetch it with you, Everett.
It's just a... Shut up, Delmar!
It's just a symbol.
I've spoken my piece and counted to 3.
She counted to 3.
Goddamn it.
Son of a bitch!
You have any idea how far that cabin is?
George?
Hello, boys!
Well, these little men finally caught up
with the criminal of the century.
Looks like the chair for George Nelson.
Yup, gonna electrify me.
I'm gonna go off like a Roman candle.
20,000 volts
chasing a rabbit through yours truly.
God damn!
Gonna suck all the power
right out of the state!
Gonna shoot sparks
out the top of my head
and lightning from my fingertips!
I'm George Nelson
and I'm feeling 10 feet tall!
Looks like George
is right back on top again.
Cow killer!
Well, at least you boys get
to see the ancestral manse.
The home where I spent
so many a happy day
in the bosom of my family,
refugin', if you will,
with a mighty oak tree out front
and a happy little tire swing on it.
Where's the happy little tire swing?
End of the road, boys.
No. Wait a minute.
Let's go, boys.
- It's had its twists and turns.
- Wait a minute now/
Now it deposits you here.
Wait a minute.
You have eluded fate
and you have eluded me
for the last time.
Tie their hands, boys.
You can't do this, now.
Didn't know you'd be bringing a friend.
He'll just have to wait his turn,
share one of your graves.
You can't do this.
We just got pardoned
by the governor hisself.
It went out on the radio.
Is that right?
Well, we ain't got a radio.
God have mercy.
You
Got to go
To that lonesome valley
It ain't fittin'.
It ain't the law.
The law?
The law is a human institution.
Nobody else
Can go there for you, no
Perhaps you should start
making your prayers.
Got
To go
Oh, my God.
Everett?
Tommy, I'm sorry we got you into this.
Good Lord...
what do we do?
By
Yourself
Oh, Lord...
please look down and
recognize us poor sinners.
Please, Lord.
I just want to see my daughters again.
I've been separated from my family
for so long.
I know I've been guilty of
pride and sharp dealing.
I'm sorry that I turned my back on you.
Forgive me.
We're helpless, Lord.
For the sake of my family.
For Tommy's sake.
For Delmar's and Pete's.
Let me see my daughters again, Lord.
Help us, please.
You got to go
To the lonesome valley
Yes, sir!
You, whoa
Got
To go
There
Hey
By
Yourself
Nobody else
Nobody else can go for you
You, whoa
Got
To go
There
Ohh
By
Yourself
A miracle.
It was a miracle!
Delmar, don't be ignorant.
I told you they was flooding this valley.
No! That ain't it!
We prayed to God and he pitied us!
Well, it never fails.
Once again, you two hayseeds are showin'
how much you want for intellect.
That ain't the tune you was singin'
back there at the gallows!
Well, any human being will cast about
in a moment of stress.
No, the fact is, they're flooding this valley,
so they can hydroelectric up
the whole durn state.
Yes, sir, the South is gonna change.
Everything's gonna be put on electricity
and run on a paying basis.
Out with the old spiritual mumbo jumbo,
the superstitions, and the backward ways.
We're gonna see a brave new world,
where they run everybody a wire
and hook us all up to a grid.
Yes, sir, a veritable age of reason.
Like the one they had in France.
Not a moment too soon.
Hey, there's Tommy.
Tommy, what you ridin' there?
Roll-top desk.
My latest sun is sinking fast
My race is nearly run
"All's well that ends well", some poet said.
That's right, honey.
Don't mind telling you I'm awful pleased
my adventuring days have come to an end.
Time for this old boy to enjoy some repose.
That's good, honey.
You were right about that ring, too.
Any other wedding band wouldn't do.
This here was fore-ordained.
Fate was a-smilin' on me.
You just have to have confidence.
- That's not my ring.
- What?
- Not your ring?
That's one of Aunt Hurlene's.
You said it was in the roll-top desk.
I said I thought it was in the roll-top desk.
No, you said--
- Or under the mattress.
- No.
Or maybe in my chifforobe. I don't know.
Well, I'm sorry, honey.
We need that ring.
That ring is at the bottom
of a pretty durn big lake.
Uh-uh.
A 9,000-hectare lake.
I don't care if it's 90,000.
That lake was not my doing.
Of course not, honey--
I counted to 3, honey.
No, wait, honey.
Finding one little ring
in the middle of all that water
is one hell of a heroic task!
And gives me victory
O, come, angel band
Come and
Around me stand
O, bear me away
on your snow white wings
To my immortal home
O, bear me away
on your snow white wings
To my immortal home
My latest sun is sinking fast
My race is nearly run
My strongest trials now are past
My triumph has begun
O, come
Angel band
Come and around me stand
O, bear me away
on your snow white wings
To my immortal home
O, bear me away
on your snow white wings
To my immortal home
O, bear my longin' heart to him
Who bled and died for me
Whose blood now cleanses from all sin
And gives me victory
O, come
Angel band
Come and around me stand
O, bear me away
on your snow white wings
To my immortal home
O, bear me away
on your snow white wings
To my immortal home
There's a dark
and a troubled side of life
There's a bright
and a sunny side, too
Though we meet with
darkness and strife
The sunny side be also with you
Keep on the sunny side
Always on the sunny side
Keep on the sunny side of life
It will help us every day
It will brighten all the way
If we'll keep on the sunny side of life
The storm and its fury
broke today
Crushing hopes
that we cherished so dear
Clouds and storms
again will pass away
And the sun will shine again,
bright and clear
Keep on the sunny side
Always on the sunny side
Keep on the sunny side of life
It will help us every day
It will brighten all the way
If we'll keep on the sunny side of life
Keep on the sunny side
Always on the sunny side
Keep on the sunny side of life
It will help us every day
It will brighten all the way
If we'll keep on the sunny side of life