(Live from Bucheon Gymnasium)
Survival audition K-Pop Star 6.
Let me introduce the two finalists.
You move so wonderfully.
Your dancing has no weakness.
(Kim So Hee, the perfect performer)
(YG wants to sign her right away.)
(Always lovely, Chrisha Choo)
(Never beaten yet, Kim Hye Rim)
(If KWINs wins this season?)
(They'll be the first ever girl group to win.)
(KWINs)
The first finalist.
The three ladies who shine on stage.
Kim So Hee, Chrisha Choo, Kim Hye Rim.
KWINs.
(KWINs: Kim So Hee, Chrisha Choo, Kim Hye Rim)
(The highest score of the season and the only 100.)
If they win...
(The youngest winners of an audition.)
(Singing! Dancing! Rap!)
(An amazing rise to the top)
(The judges are speechless when the 11-year-olds perform.)
(Let's wins this competition!)
(If they truly enjoy themselves on stage,)
(no one can stop them.)
(Boyfriend)
The second finalist.
The 11-year-olds who never cease to transform.
Park Hyun Jin and Kim Jong Seob are Boyfriend.
(Boyfriend: Park Hyun Jin, Kim Jong Seob)
These are the two finalists of K-Pop Star 6.
Please give them a warm welcome.
Survival audition K-Pop Star 6.
I'm your host Jun Hyun Moo.
It's the final show.
It's the final of K-Pop Star 6...
and you're watching live.
Which team will be crowned the winner of...
K-Pop Star 6?
Please stay tuned.
I'd like to introduce three people...
who put in a lot of effort to bring K-Pop Star this far.
Part of K-Pop Star's history, it's JYP's Park Jin Young.
(Park Jin Young, Yang Hyun Suk, Yu Hui Yeol)
YG's Yang Hyun Suk.
Antenna's Yu Hui Yeol.
We reached the final of K-Pop Star 6.
It's hard to say who will win tonight.
Jin Young, as a judge, how do you think things will go?
Both teams are so talented.
I think whichever of them wins, I wouldn't be surprised.
Who has more fun tonight and turns this into a festival...
will be whoever we decide will win the competition.
The winning team will create a new record.
If KWINs wins, they'll be the first girl group to win.
If Boyfriend wins, they'll be the youngest winners ever.
Which team will win tonight?
Stay tuned and watch.
Hui Yeol, you tried hard last week to give these two some courage...
- during Antenna Week. - Yes.
How did it go?
Jin Young and Hyun Suk did a lot over the past two weeks.
What they did during JYP Week and YG Week...
made me think they're so fake.
They're smiling so brightly.
I treated them as equals and as genuinely as possible...
and took them where no one else could.
You all went to a very special location.
Let's find out where they went and what happened...
during Antenna Week.
(One warm, sunny April day)
The weather's lovely.
(The Top 2 are invited to an unusual location.)
- A ram's horn. - Yes.
- Ram swag. - Ram swag.
Ram swag.
- It's hot. - Gosh.
(Antenna Week)
- I love this. - It's awesome.
- A sauna? - A charcoal sauna.
Let's get warmed up.
(A sauna to help them relax.)
This is amazing.
People who can't stand heat...
I'd love to jump in here.
It's nice.
We can crack our boiled eggs on Jong Seob's head.
You're good at this.
(Hye Rim folds the towels.)
You're good.
(So, where is Hui Yeol?)
(The weather's good. It's good enough.)
(It was a perfect day to spend in a sauna.)
What? What?
No, stay lying down. Don't get up.
Hello. You have great skin.
Hello.
Gosh, it's hot.
It's really hot. Hello.
(He's as popular as the host of a long-running singing competition.)
It's nice.
To Jin Young or Hyun Suk...
this is a luxury.
Renting boats that aren't his.
How lovely is this?
I come here often.
Hello.
(The sauna owner's here.)
- Hello. - Hello.
- Hello. - Hello, everyone.
- The clothes suit you. - You look good.
- Hello. - Hello.
(Gosh)
You look so cute. Seeing you in here now,
you don't look like K-Pop Star contestants.
You look like kids who are here with your parents.
Last week,
did Hyun Suk take you out on a boat?
- Yes. - Yes.
It wasn't his.
Jin Young took you out...
- for Korean broiled chicken. - Yes.
He doesn't like broiled chicken.
(Hui Yeol criticizes everyone.)
I invited you here for a reason.
To relieve fatigue.
Correct.
Drink this.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
You and I can share a glass of milk.
(Milk in a beer glass)
Let's drink and share our deepest thoughts.
Let's start with a cheer since it's the final week.
- Okay. - Okay?
1, 2, 3.
- For a beautiful meeting. - For a beautiful meeting.
- Good. - Bottom's up?
Well done.
They wrote down some questions for you to answer.
Okay.
- They're anonymous. - Okay.
What would you want to ask me?
Let's see.
"Idol singers aren't allowed to date."
"Don't you need dating experience to write good lyrics?"
"What should I do?"
That's right.
(Who asked the first question?)
- Hyun Jin. - Yes?
He can't hear.
He keeps doing this.
Keep your ears open.
Whenever I speak, he goes, "What?"
He's so cute.
Have you dated someone?
Long ago.
(She's surprised.)
Really?
- For a very short time. - For a short time?
For between 12 and 13 hours.
Did you date her for about 12 hours?
Yes.
- What kind of relationship was it? - I'll tell you.
She asked me to be her boyfriend in the evening,
and the next morning,
she broke up with me.
What did you do?
I pretended I didn't care.
Did you?
Have you ever liked a singer so much you joined her fan club?
I joined Shannon's fan club.
Did you joined her fan club before K-Pop Star began?
Yes, I was a fan of hers.
I came to like her more as I met her on K-Pop Star.
She got eliminated because of you.
(I'm sorry. That wasn't my intention.)
That's true.
- How did you feel when you saw her? - Pardon?
I first saw her in person in the third round.
I couldn't keep my mouth closed.
I saw him standing still like a rock.
She looked surreal and was difficult to approach.
It felt like I wasn't allowed to talk to her.
That's why you won't need dating experience.
It's not like a writer who writes mystery or scary stories...
actually kills someone.
- That's right. - Right?
Likewise, you can write the lyrics...
about the feelings you had when you saw Shannon.
You said you felt weird when you saw Shannon...
leaving K-Pop Star.
You can write about that feeling as if it's love.
Right.
Shannon was crying.
"What's wrong with my heart?"
"I feel like crying, but tears won't come out."
You can write the lyrics like this.
That's awesome.
Do you think so too? Will you come join Antenna?
(He's taken aback.)
(He's avoiding Hui Yeol's eyes.)
Look at his face. He just hates the idea.
The next question is...
"You cried when the contestants were eliminated in previous seasons."
(You cried when the contestants were eliminated.)
"It made me feel sad too."
"Do you cry often?"
I don't cry often.
When the contestant, Hong Jung Hee,
was eliminated...
It was season three.
It was the first season I joined K-Pop Star as a judge.
I was a new judge,
and I didn't know anything about K-Pop Star.
I think I was full of passion just like you guys.
When she got eliminated,
I thought it was my fault.
I burst into tears even before I knew.
I believe that the contestants gained a lot through the experience.
So did I.
You play a very important role.
You represent the hope of all the previous contestants...
throughout the series.
The two teams will compete intensely in the final round.
You have to do your best to give a good performance.
I think that's your job.
- I understand. - We'll do that.
I saved something for the final round.
The contestants who trained at Antenna...
left a gift in my office without letting me know.
They bought me a gift.
They bought a tie for me.
The five of them pitched in to buy it.
They left a letter with the gift.
So I decided to wear the tie in the final round...
as it's the last time.
There's nothing else I can do for them now.
The contestants whom I trained...
will probably see me wearing the tie.
Before then, I had talked to him only when he evaluated me.
It was the first time I talked to him personally.
I was grateful that he made me feel so comfortable.
He's always kind to us.
I'm very grateful that he prepared...
something that was of great help to us.
Good luck!
- We can do it! - We can do it!
Thank you.
(With his cheerful words, Antenna Week is over!)
Hui Yeol, we enjoyed watching Antenna Week.
You must be wearing the tie.
Yes, I am. This is the tie...
that the contestants I trained bought for me.
They left a tie and a letter in my office.
I felt bad that the contestants trained at Antenna couldn't move up.
As today is the last day, I decided to wear this tie.
It's a very meaningful tie.
Hyun Suk, what do you think of Antenna Week?
- I thought of two things. - I see.
First of all, Hui Yeol is a celebrity, singer,
and a show host.
It was hard to believe that he seemed like an ordinary man.
- That's what I thought. - I see.
The other thing I thought was...
Hyun Jin said he likes Shannon, right?
- I was a big fan of someone. - Right.
- She's Im Ye Jin. - Im Ye Jin?
I liked her when I was in middle school.
She might be watching this show right now.
She's currently working with YG.
I realized that life is...
- Life is unpredictable. - I realized it's unpredictable.
At his age, boys tend to like older girls.
I could see that Hui Yeol made a lot of effort...
to have a good time with them.
Thank you. The talk in the spa was very impressive.
I'll explain the rules of the final round.
The contestants will give two performances.
In the first part, they will sing...
the song they chose.
In the second round, they will sing the song each other sang...
in one of the previous rounds.
They have to perform a given song...
that each other sang in one of the previous rounds...
and received positive responses.
Please look forward to finding out which song they will perform.
Today's round is expected to be the most intense. In this round,
the judges' scores will count for 60 percent of the total score,
and the viewers' votes will count for 40 percent for both parts.
The total score will decide the winner of K-Pop Star.
Now I'll tell you the order of performance and each team's number.
The ace girl group who made their dream come true.
Number one, KWINs. Kim So Hee, Chrisha Choo, and Kim Hye Rim.
They're number one.
No one can stop them.
The 11-year-old dark horses who turned the game around.
Number two, Boyfriend. Park Hyun Jin and Kim Jong Seob.
They're number two.
Please stay tuned to the end of the two teams' final match.
This is the final round.
As it's an important round, you can watch many special performances too.
I'm curious about the special performances.
As this is the final round, we have special hosts.
Please come out!
- Hello. - Hello, we are the winner of...
- K-Pop Star 2, AKMU. - AKMU.
- It's nice to meet you. - Scream!
(AKMU)
It's nice to meet you.
Four years ago, we were here.
We won K-Pop Star four years ago.
I feel overwhelmed.
- You must be very nervous. - No, I'm not.
- Not at all. - You seem really nervous.
As this is the final round, there will be amazing performances.
The legendary performances that were ranked high in music charts...
and made K-Pop Star popular. Do you want to see them again?
- Yes! - Yes!
The six trainees who once competed against one another...
formed a group together. They will perform here tonight.
Also, the previous contestants who grew up so much...
will give a touching performance. Please look forward to it.
The winner of K-Pop Star 6 will be decided soon.
Everyone, your choice will...
- decide the winner. - That's right.
The final round will begin shortly.
Your choice will decide the winner.
I already said that. I'm sorry.
You can vote by sending a text message.
Press the hash key and 0606.
Type the team's name in Korean.
Or you can simply type the team's number.
Please note that you can also vote on the music website.
The final round of K-Pop Star...
will begin now.
It will begin with the performance of number one, KWINs.
You can start voting...
- right now. - Right now.
(The voting begins now.)
(Number 1, KWINs, number 2, Boyfriend)
(Vote for the team you love.)
(This is Chrisha Choo when she was 9 years old.)
When I was five years old,
there were a lot of DVDs of concerts at home.
I watched the videos and they fascinated me.
I wanted to become a singer.
You watched concert videos instead of cartoons at the age of five?
Yes, I did.
They were fascinating.
This is Kim Hye Rim. She's in sixth grade.
My teacher and my parents suggested me...
to participate in singing contests for children...
since I was in fourth grade.
So I participated...
in "Who's Great?" when I was 13...
and received an award. It let me have confidence in myself.
That experience really encouraged me to dream to be a singer.
I loved singing...
and dancing since I was seven.
I started to dreaming to be a singer who appears on television.
(Three members of KWINs have the same dream.)
(Now they will perform together in the final round.)
What does K-Pop Star mean to your life?
It's our very first stride.
For the first time,
we met other trainees and practiced to perform on the stage.
It's where our efforts to be a singer have begun.
(Hee Yeol is startled as he finds out the song selection of KWINs.)
(Gosh.)
I can hardly picture it.
It's a good choice.
It's great.
(Which song has Queens chosen? Why did the judges react differently?)
(A powerful duo performance, "Trouble Maker")
That's for a coed duo, right?
I can't get rid of the image of the original performers from my head.
Will the three girls be able...
to successfully reinterpret the performance?
I think they made the best choice in this final round.
Through this song,
they can show everything they have from singing, dancing,
ability to interpret the song, accuracy, flexibility...
and even their talents.
I think this performance will be their best one.
Boyfriend has earned a high score...
and is garnering great attention now.
We thought we should choose a challenging song...
in order to weaken their upturn.
(KWINs selected a challenging performance for the final round.)
We will show you how much...
our dancing and singing skills have improved.
We will show you everything we have...
and what we are capable of.
(KWINs)
("Trouble Maker" by Trouble Maker)
(Music Producer Kwon Tae Eun, Band Master Lee Jeong Hun)
(Number one, KWINs. Kim So Hee, Chrisha Choo, and Kim Hye Rim)
The first performance of the final round is over.
It was "Trouble Maker" by KWINs.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
All right. They said thank you. What do you think, Jin Young?
After they performed "Swing Baby"...
in the previous round,
I told you that Chrisha Choo was the only one who stood out.
And when you performed "Wannabe",
the only one who captured my eyes was Hye Rim.
And today,
So Hee stood out the most.
Thank you.
When you started dancing to the sound of clockwork,
you totally captivated my heart.
And the dance you showed during the dance break...
was gorgeous.
You proved once again...
why I picked you as the best dancer of this whole season.
I mentioned that your voice was smaller compared to others...
because you tended to be careful when you sing loudly.
You've finally overcome it.
- Thank you. - For the first time,
- your singing was loud and fine. - Thank you.
You all showed your talents, accuracy, flexibility,
feelings and basic skills very well.
JYP's score is...
He highly complimented the performance.
Let's see what score they got from JYP out of 100.
- It's 96. - Thank you!
It's a very high score. Hui Yeol, please.
I think their performance was very significant.
It was the third performance you showed as KWINs, right?
I realized how important...
the chemistry of each member...
and teamwork are.
I could hardly find flaws in your performance.
I think you now know what each other's strengths are.
Your voices really made my ears feel comfortable.
You fully understood the different charms of your voices...
and managed to divide the parts in a clever way.
Although you three have different tones,
it was very harmonious.
No matter who sings the music,
music exists to be listened by others.
As your voices were stable, I really enjoyed the music.
And your dancing and performance was very natural.
I almost thought you guys are professional singers.
It was quite flawless.
However, it wasn't as explosive as I expected.
Antenna's score is...
Let's see how many points the girl group expert gave to KWINs.
- 96 points! - Thank you!
He not only said the performance was seamless...
but also gave a very high score.
Hyun Suk, please.
Hui Yeol hasn't...
produced or directed any girl idol groups.
Did you have to say that?
- But Jin Young and I have. - Right.
So I think we have a different point of view.
I didn't mean to belittle him. I'm sorry.
I seriously love girl groups.
Okay.
- He's an expert. - All right.
There's a reason why I mentioned it.
KWINs was formed only a few weeks ago.
Most of girl groups practice together for 3 to 4 years.
And those in our company practice up to six years.
I understand how hard it is to create a chemistry in a short time.
After I watched your last performance, "Swing Baby",
I realized that it was such a short period.
Jin Young and I saw the imperfections.
Today, like Jin Young said,
last week, So Hee was pretty much unnoticeable.
Strategy and teamwork is very important,
but I also think you need a star player.
Today, So Hee did very well as the star player.
Thank you.
It was like a well-dribbled ball...
was passed well with a great assist and So Hee scored a goal.
I liked your performance very much. Well done.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- What's YG's score? - YG's score is...
So Hee's getting a lot of praise. YG's score is...
97 points!
- Thank you. - Thank you.
That's a total of 289 points.
The judges gave them 289 points.
If you want KWINs to win, text the number 1 to 0606...
or type KWINs in Korean.
That was Kim So Hee, Chrisha Choo, Kim Hye Rim, KWINs.
(Trust me, I'm older than you)
(Even holding hands makes me happy)
When I was five, I just loved music and dance.
Whenever I heard music or saw a dance, I just copied it.
Back then,
I didn't think about becoming a singer or what I should do.
I just copied singers because I loved music.
(Jong Seob aged seven)
Both my mom and dad have music-related jobs.
I just watched and listened to them and learned music naturally.
How close to your dream do you think you are?
For me,
I'd rarely performed on stage before coming on K-Pop Star.
This competition helped me get used to performing in public.
I think I'm 60 to 70 percent on the road to reaching my dream.
If I'd need to take 10 steps to reach my goal,
I would say that all the experience so far...
has given me the strength to run at full speed from the starting line.
(Last week's Top 4 performance)
(The first bar gave everyone the thrills.)
When I sang "let's get it started in here,"
the audience started to cheer.
That was when...
I thought I really had to keep my wits about me.
I worked really hard.
To be honest, through my whole life,
it was the best ever performance I'd done.
(After the show)
That was so much fun.
I can't believe we got a three-digit score.
(Gasping)
How do you feel?
So happy.
Can you get another 100-point score?
If we do really well.
Yes, if we do really well,
I think we can.
(What song will they sing in the hope of getting 100 points?)
(G-Dragon's "Crooked")
The song we'll sing at the final...
is G-Dragon's "Crooked".
How big of an explosion can they create?
Can they really let it all out and go crazy?
If they do it differently,
and give a great interpretation that's unlike G-Dragon's,
then these two will really be...
incredible talents.
The rap will be different from what we did two rounds ago.
It's a different style.
A whole new level.
What will it be like?
The slow parts will sound almost melancholy.
It'll sound like the autumn sky.
(Boyfriend's on the rise.)
It will definitely sound different from what we did so far.
(Will they become the youngest ever winners?)
(Boyfriend)
("Crooked" by G-Dragon)
That was "Crooked" by Boyfriend, our second finalist.
It's time to hear the judges' comments.
What will they say?
Let's start with Jin Young.
When I judge,
I have to focus on two sides.
The skill and capabilities of each individual,
and the whole performance.
First, I'll comment on each of you.
I've seen many singers and produced many singers.
To be this good at this age...
Even among the trainees in my agency,
it's very rare, you're that good.
To sing and dance like this at 11...
Now you reached the finals...
and Hyun Jin's singing has reached its peak.
You have a great voice and you sound so confident.
The flow of your rap, the way you followed the beat...
You're on the rise.
Also,
Jong Seob, when you rap, your voice is so clear.
Your delivery is great and the tone's so strong.
As individuals, your talents have reached a new high.
But as a whole, the performance was lackluster.
I know that...
it's hard for kids your age to keep planning performances like these.
It wasn't as great as I had hoped.
JYP's score is...
JYP's score.
Jin Young said that as individuals, you're definitely on the rise.
Out of 100...
- he gave 93. - Thank you.
Very well. Next up is Hyun Suk.
This is K-Pop Star's last broadcast.
If I look back on the last six years,
the success rate of those who sang Jin Young's songs was 90 percent.
The success rate of those who sang YG's songs was 10 percent.
I was concerned when I heard what song they'd chosen.
G-Dragon's "Crooked"...
G-Dragon performs at numerous concerts...
but this song has a little room for rearrangement.
When I saw how they rearranged the bridge part,
I was surprised.
It made me wonder why we didn't think of that.
It flew naturally.
Like what Jin Young said a while ago,
Hyun Jin's rap in the middle was very impressive.
He was in charge of singing for the most part,
so I was a little surprised when he rapped there.
I want to praise them highly...
for rearranging such a difficult song.
YG's score is...
He must've been very impressed by Hyun Jin's rap.
What's YG's score? It's 95.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Next is Hui Yeol.
Last time,
I gave Boyfriend 100.
I added unnecessary comments,
but I will give a score that bears a symbolic meaning.
For people of their age,
they put on a shocking performance. I was really shocked.
Today, my standard was up here.
Given that, I was a little disappointed than the last time.
Nevertheless, I am constantly amazed.
Here's why. On Antenna Week,
I got to see them up-close for the first time.
And the shocking thing was...
that they can't tie their shoes yet.
- They are just kids. - They are kids.
But on the stage...
How can they put on such performance? I was shocked.
I can't stop thinking about...
what they will become in 10 years.
I was especially shocked by the rap in the middle.
There was a part in the middle where there were a few beats.
It would've been hard enough to fit a short rap in there.
And suddenly, he started rapping...
so fast like those auctioneers at Noryangjin Fish Market.
How can they do such thing at their age?
I am still amazed.
Jin Young used to say things like this so much...
and I always laughed at him for saying this.
But I think you will grow up and become K-Pop Star's future.
This performance convinced me.
Antenna's score Is...
All right. What score did Hui Yeol give?
- It's 97. - Thank you.
The total score is 285.
If you want Boyfriend to win,
text number 2 to 0606...
or type Boyfriend in Korean.
That was group number two, Boyfriend.
We watched the two teams' free song mission performances.
If we only consider the judges' scores,
KWINs is leading by four more points.
However, only half of the finals is done.
There's Round Two, so please continue watching.
K-Pop Star has been running for six years.
You must remember many performances.
A lot of the performances became an issue.
Jin Young, among all seasons, looking back on the last six years,
which contestant left the strongest impression?
Well, if I were to choose the most shocking moments,
I'd choose the moment when Lee Jin Ah played the piano...
- for the prelude of "My Own Way". - Okay.
I was really shocked when she played that line.
Also, in terms of drama...
The most dramatic moment was when Hyun Suk saved Katie Kim,
- who was almost eliminated. - He saved her.
"Place Where You Need To Be" was her next performance.
- And I was so shocked by it. - It's your song.
- Yes. - Yes.
- Well... - It's g.o.d's song.
It's g.o.d's song. Right. Okay.
Was that the most memorable performance?
And the song Sam Kim sang on a roof...
Wait, but that's my song too.
Sam Kim sang "You're the One" while playing a guitar on a roof.
That was shocking too.
- All right. - There were too many moments.
- Right. - Lee Soo Jung's...
- "Girl" was shocking too. - Right.
There are too many. Who do you remember, Hyun Suk?
Having seen Jin Young for six years, I realized...
that Jin Young loves himself so much.
- He's consistent. - He's very consistent.
The song Katie sang was originally sang by g.o.d.
- But Jin Young wrote it. - Right.
He's got a lot of good songs.
- Of course. - Yes.
It would be nicer if he doesn't say anything.
The most memorable performance for me was...
Perhaps I'm biased because she now works with me.
But the moment I first saw Lee Hi on Season One was memorable.
I remember being amazed by her unbelievably husky voice.
The second memorable moment was when AKMU,
who stammered just now.
They kept saying same things again and again.
When they sang the song "Don't Cross Your Legs",
I was pleasantly surprised.
They didn't originally sing that song.
They sang another song at first.
But we asked them to sing "Don't Cross Your Legs".
And their life changed forever.
How about you, Hui Yeol?
They introduced almost all the legendary moments.
But the most memorable moment for me was when...
Kwon Jin Ah came out with a guitar and sang "See-Through".
I also remember the moment when a nerdy boy...
came out and started singing an amazing ballad song.
It was when Jung Seung Hwan sang "I Want To Fall In Love".
- Yes. - I remember the two moments.
Why are you only talking about your artists?
- You all are very egocentric. - I have another one.
Park Ji Young's "Who's Your Mama" performance on Season Four.
- That's enough. - I am sorry.
I won't ask you anymore.
The reason why I asked them this is this.
On K-Pop Star, there have been...
many legendary performances which fluctuated music charts...
and were viewed millions of times.
Today, we will revisit those moments.
The touching legend stage...
will open now.
(Many performances shone K-Pop Star over the last 6 years.)
("I Want To Fall In Love" by Jung Seung Hwan)
(He sang it on Season 4.)
There's no singer who sings like that.
We need you in the music scene.
You are the first one who captured all our hearts...
with a Korean pop song.
Thank you.
("Place Where You Need To Be" by Katie Kim on Season 4)
I can't judge this.
That was the best performance so far in four years.
That's the place where you need to be.
That was the best.
100. She got 100.
What's this? We've never heard this before.
(Since December 2011, for the past 6 years,)
(many contestants made K-Pop Star shine brightly.)
(Those touching performances...)
(will be put on once again.)
(K-Pop Star's legendary performances begin now.)
Hello, we are a sibling acoustic duo,
- AKMU. - AKMU.
("Don't Cross Your Legs" by AKMU)
("See-Through" by Kwon Jin Ah)
("I Want To Fall In Love" by Jung Seung Hwan)
("Where You Need To Be" by Katie Kim)
("New York State Of Mind" by Yu Jei)