"Save the planet."
Whenever I've read that bumper sticker,
I've had to laugh.
"Save the planet."
What for? And from what?
From ourselves?
Life's simple:
Kill or be killed,
don't get involved...
... and always finish the job.
The survivor's code.
My code.
And it all sounds great until the day you
find yourself confronted by a choice.
A choice to make a difference,
to help someone...
... or to walk away and save yourself.
I learned something that day.
You can't always walk away.
Too bad it was the day I died.
Get out here!
Come here!
Get back!
You remember me?
You sold me a gun that don't work!
You almost got me killed!
I paid $20 for this.
I want my money back.
Give me that.
This one's very good, very good.
Okay.
I owe you.
I'll save you some.
Hey, Toorop. Toorop.
Somebody came here looking for you.
Okay.
Boy, what a massacre.
At the peak of the rush hour,
bombs were detonated in...
Karl, is that you?
I thought you were in Sudan
killing babies.
Remember the last time we met?
I told you if you ever
point that gun at me again...
...l'd kill you.
Who would hire a baby killer
to get me?
Who?
No shit. If you wanted me dead,
you'd have blown up the building.
Who?
Gorsky.
Karl, you're a disgrace
to the profession.
You're not a mercenary,
you're a terrorist.
You need two things to live in this
business, your balls and your word.
You don't have either.
You know the difference
between you and me, Karl?
I still got both.
Take it easy.
Personal between him and me.
You are a hard man to find, Toorop.
I'm not hiding.
You could have knocked.
I needed to be sure
that you were the same idealist...
...who worked for me 10 years ago.
So you knew I was gonna kill Karl?
I don't like you, Gorsky.
You can't trust me
and I can't trust you.
Look at you.
Still in this shit hole, surviving.
No friends, no family, no future.
We are the same. You and me.
We're not the same.
What do you want?
I need a smuggler.
I don't do refugees anymore.
Use your own cargo.
- You own the borders anyway.
- Only on this side.
- This is an overseas delivery?
- A girl.
She needs to be in America
in six days.
Why are you playing with me?
You know I can't get back
into that country.
You know that U.N. passports
are impossible to fake.
This is not a fake.
Inject it in your neck
when you pass the official border.
This is your new life.
I'll do it for half a mil.
I can make you do it for free.
You can't make me do shit, Gorsky.
But you can pay me what I need
so I can get the job done right.
A car will pick you up outside.
Everything you need
will be in the trunk.
Cross me and you'll have no place
to hide anymore...
...Toorop.
It goes both ways...
...Gorsky.
Shit.
Good morning.
You must be Toorop.
I am Sister Rebeka.
I want to bring three simple rules
to your attention...
...before we start our journey.
We?
I'm here to pick up one girl.
Wherever she goes, I go.
That is rule number one.
Rule number two, the less contact she
has with the outside world, the better.
You're here to protect her
from outside influences.
That includes seeing,
hearing and feeling.
Now, it's a harsh world
out there, Sister.
I know. That is why we live in here.
Shit. Okay, what's your third rule?
No foul language.
Do we have an agreement?
You listen to my one and only rule.
Don't fuck with me...
...or I'll leave you standing
in the middle of nowhere...
...with nothing but your ass to sell
to get back here...
...your perfect world.
Do we have an agreement?
Obviously, you are not a gentleman.
Obviously not.
Now that we have an understanding,
pick up the bags.
No.
What's your name?
My name?
You don't have to talk to him.
You didn't introduce yourself.
My name is Toorop.
- Are you taking us to New York?
- Yes.
Now please get into the car.
Are you a killer, Mr. Toorop?
Look, lady. I'm just a delivery boy.
And to me you're just a package.
I'm not your friend, I'm not your brother,
I'm not your boyfriend.
In six days, I'm gonna deliver you
and never see you again.
Sister Rebeka's right.
We shouldn't even talk.
Come on.
Comfy?
Your Highness,
your child has left the convent.
At last.
Six days until we reveal our miracle
to the world.
Your Highness,
the press conference will begin shortly.
She's coming.
Let's pray.
Let's hurry up.
The train's gonna leave soon.
Take your bags.
Are you really going to need all that?
You can never have enough firepower,
Sister.
In fact...
Never touched a gun in my life.
Now would be the perfect moment
to start.
No, thank you. I can defend myself.
Stay close, this is the real world.
There's no mercy for the weak.
Just because we're peaceful,
that doesn't mean we're weak.
It does here.
Hurry.
Change.
What are you doing?
We've located the targets.
Contact New York.
Patch me through to Darquandier.
They found her.
Okay.
Be careful now.
Noelites would be watching too.
My daughter must not be harmed.
Put this on.
Come on.
I'm scared. Can I hold your hand?
Hold mine.
Hang on.
Okay, give me three.
Hey.
Where are you going?
What are you doing? Come on.
Hey.
Hey!
Hey, come here.
- She's on the run.
- Hey.
Aurora. Toorop.
- What are you doing?
- Stop.
- Don't go that way.
- She's not used to crowds.
We have to go. We have no time.
- Now.
- We have to get away.
What's wrong?
Make her walk or I'll carry her.
- Stop. Don't touch her.
- We gotta leave. We're going.
- Don't touch her.
- You will die. No!
Come on.
We're going to the train.
We need to catch it. Come on.
Move. Get out of the way.
Move!
Those tigers in the cage.
They weren't real, right?
Siberian tigers went extinct in 2017.
The last one died in the Moscow Zoo.
What is she,
a walking wildlife encyclopedia?
They were clones?
Second generation clones.
Not real tigers.
Copies of copies.
But they're living creatures.
Made by God.
No, they were organic machines
made by man.
God made man in his image...
...so, what man creates
is also God's will.
Is this what you teach her
in the convent?
You wanna talk?
Tell me what happened
at the marketplace.
How did you know
about the explosion?
If I'm gonna protect you...
...I need to know
what's wrong with you.
She was scared.
It's her first time out of the convent.
And you put us in that situation.
Your attention, please. We are about to
pass through high-radiation smog.
For your security,
the shutters will now be lowered.
First time out of the convent, huh?
Stay close.
- What are we doing here?
- Looking for a friend.
Must be somewhere around here.
Come on, come on.
It's a glorious game.
Marcus from gracious England...
...against the Killa from China.
Only one round.
You can make it.
I got them. They're right here.
Subtitle Created By : Mostofa Kamal™
Mostofa_Kamal_86@yahoo.com
www.Facebook.com/Mostofa.kamal.86
I'll be right there in a minute.
And you, don't talk to anybody.
They're splitting up.
What do we do now?
Everybody maintain their position.
Get up, Finn.
Hey, Toorop.
- How are you?
- How are you doing?
What you doing in this beautiful
part of Russia?
- Working.
- Working for who?
Hey, hey, two shots.
Gorsky.
He made me an offer
I couldn't refuse.
- What can I do for you?
- I need three passes on the boat.
And two snow bikes
on the other side.
- You crossing?
- I'm delivering.
A girl.
Her?
Who is she?
I don't know.
- Where are you taking her?
- America.
You're on the terrorist list there.
- Yeah.
- You know that. You need a passport.
You need an identity.
You're kidding me.
You got a passport?
Yeah, and I'm not coming back.
- That is a bold move.
- I got 50 G's saying you can help out.
When?
Now.
You don't have to look.
Who is he?
He's a lost soul.
See you at the landing at 0600 sharp.
You got it.
- Who is that?
- An old friend, a good smuggler.
- You trust him?
- I don't trust anybody. Come on.
- Sorry, kids, these girls are with me.
- Just let her go, Toorop.
- How do you know my name?
- We know a lot of things you don't.
- Yeah? Like what?
- Like you don't know what you're doing.
- I'm doing my job.
- Forget your job.
- What?
- One million, tax-free.
Take the money
and walk out without a fight.
Make it easy on yourself, Toorop.
Go!
Move!
Aurora.
Hey!
- Aurora.
- Hey, man, let the girl go.
Just let her go. Let her go.
Another one is about to die.
A new opponent for the Killa.
Hey, man, hey, hey. I don't...
Get over there.
Wanna fight? Let's go.
No!
Aurora.
Stop!
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop!
Don't kill him.
He doesn't want to hurt me.
He wanted to protect me!
Your father sent us.
- My father?
- Yes, your father.
Get away from her.
It's okay, Aurora.
- I have to know.
- No, Aurora.
Aurora? Aurora. Aurora!
Listen to me. Stop.
Toorop. Toorop.
Come on.
Let's go. Hurry up.
Move it.
Come on.
Go, go, go.
Let her go!
Next one dies.
Come with us.
They're ready to die for you.
I don't want anybody to die for me.
What do you think you're doing?
- What's wrong with you?
- Think this is a game?
- Why did you shoot?
- Trying to get killed?
- Why didn't you let me go?
- You don't know them!
And what are you gonna do? Shoot me
in the head? Swing on me like an animal?
Stop it.
I told you I'd take you to New York.
And I will.
You don't have to like me.
Is my father really alive?
No, baby girl.
He died.
This is way too many refugees,
man.
The ice is getting thinner every year.
We're losing cargo all the time.
We're not gonna all get on the boat.
Make sure we do.
This goddamn global warming
is bad for business.
What's happening?
Watch this.
There's not much time.
They don't wanna be spotted
by satellites.
Hurry, come on.
Diving in two minutes.
Diving in one minute.
One minute.
Go.
Come on.
No!
You can't do this.
They'll die out there.
No!
- You can't do this.
- Get away from the controls.
- What are you doing? Stop it. Stop it.
- No.
Don't do that. What's wrong?
- Put it down.
- No, don't.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- You, put it down.
- Hey, take it easy.
- Put it down.
- We go back up.
- Now.
- Okay, okay.
- Relax.
- We go back up.
- Easy.
- Now.
- Relax, stay put.
- No.
Calm down.
- Put her on the floor.
- I feel them dying.
No, no mercy. Dead!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
What the hell was that?
I was 17 years old,
living in San Francisco.
My life was a mess.
I met the wrong man.
I was lost in darkness.
But the high priestess of our church
opened the doors...
...that led onto the path of light.
I joined the Noelites...
...and I ended up in the convent.
It was a haven for women
who needed to heal.
I worked in the orphanage.
She arrived.
A little baby.
Her father was dead.
Nobody knew anything
about the mother.
I took her as my own.
I fed her.
I taught her.
Everything was fine
until three months ago.
The doctor came and gave her a pill.
He was with her for 10 minutes...
...and then she slowly started...
To change, huh?
Schizophrenia.
Spasms.
Nothing as violent
as what you saw today.
Now, how could she know how
to operate a 30-year-old Russian sub?
She's always known things
that she never experienced.
Aurora could speak
when she was 2 years old.
Yeah, but there are kids
that can speak at 2 years old.
Nineteen different languages?
Who else knows about this?
Nobody but the doctor.
He told me to keep it a secret
to protect her.
He said...
...that we would get
the best medical help in America.
She needs help.
Crew, prepare to surface.
Get her ready.
You know, two years ago...
...in Uzbekistan,
I saw this viral bomb go off.
I saw it from the air. It was...
...incredible. Everybody died.
She's carrying, ain't she?
All the symptoms fit.
All that weird behavior.
I'm telling you, man,
she's carrying a weapon.
Do you have any idea
how much money she's worth?
If she's carrying a virus...
...l'll kill her myself
and burn the body.
What happened to them?
Fighter drones.
Anything that moves
is shot on sight.
It's 10 miles to the DMZ.
Then let's make it 10 fast miles.
Let's go.
Toorop, they're coming.
Shit. Finn, we're spotted. Hit it!
Brake!
Finn, get close to me.
Jump onto his bike.
I'll draw them off.
- What are you doing?
- Toorop cleared our way out.
We're only a mile from the border.
- Toorop, we need help.
- Don't worry.
We're almost there.
Toorop, we need you now.
Hang on, I'm getting there.
Stop! We have to get Toorop.
Toorop.
He's not dead.
Oh, shit.
Hey, stay with me.
He's not reacting.
He's bleeding to death.
I need your help. Okay.
We gotta get out of here now.
It's a small piece of metal.
I'm gonna take it out.
- What do you need?
- Just hold him.
Look, we don't have time
for this, okay?
They're gonna send more drones.
Aurora?
- You got it?
- I got it.
- He's okay.
- Give me a bandage.
We should never have turned back.
He knows the rules.
I'll sew it up later.
Hey...
...now you
and the passport are mine.
- What are you doing?
- You, I don't need.
Like I said...
...trust no one.
Remember that.
It's good.
Where did you learn to cook?
Rule number one
in the mercenary handbook.
You never had a woman
take care of you?
Sorry.
No, not in my line of work.
Finished.
- She gets pleasure out of this.
- Crybaby.
Crybaby?
What is that?
Painkiller?
No, thank you.
- Live a little.
- No.
- Aurora, stop.
- Wait, let...
Spit it out.
Girls.
We made it across the border.
Here's to survival...
...and thank you for saving my life.
Maybe now you can trust somebody.
We protected each other like family.
We are all going to die in New York.
Good night.
She's just scared.
Yeah, right.
Go back to sleep.
We still have a long way ahead of us.
What are you doing?
We go through customs tomorrow.
Can't take these.
You know, when Sister Rebeka
first found me as a baby...
...it was a night like this.
Aurora.
That's where I got my name.
From the chaos.
It suits you.
You're risking your life for me.
Why?
I've done my time.
All this killing and pain...
...and war for what?
I'm tired.
I'm tired of it all.
You're my only chance
out of this hell.
And go where?
27 Cedar Grove...
...near Canada.
It's upstate New York.
My parents had a farm.
More like a cabin with a lot of land.
It's probably in ruins,
but I might be able to fix it up.
There is no place like home.
Well, Kansas ain't what it used to be.
The Wizard of Oz.
1939.
That's right.
Toorop.
Are you really going to kill me
and burn my body?
I hope I won't have to.
Thirty minutes.
The bus leaves in 30 minutes.
There's a plane to New York
in two hours.
Passengers for Flight 712
to New York...
... please proceed to Gate 211
for immediate boarding.
You are now leaving Canada.
We hope you enjoyed your stay.
Welcome
to the United States of America.
Welcome to America.
Stop.
Hold it right there.
- Hey.
- I said, hold it.
- Calm down.
- Hey.
A miracle in the making.
Tomorrow is the dawn
of our new age.
Harlem, we've changed.
We've changed.
Right here, girls.
It's okay. It's safe here.
Here.
Can we turn it off?
You can't turn it off.
You can change the channel.
Hey.
There's no food.
Because we're not
gonna be here long.
What's wrong?
They're all dead.
Sources report the destruction in
Kirghizstan of a 1000-year-old convent.
One of the oldest continually functioning
convents in Central Asia.
Now occupied by an ascetic branch
of the Noelites...
... the convent was struck by a missile
late last night.
There were no survivors.
Here, an initial reaction
from the Noelites.
It is a tragedy to think
that even defenseless women...
... who made the choice to withdraw
from society and lead a life of purity...
... should suffer the attacks
of terrorists...
... who have absolutely no respect for
the lives of decent, God-fearing people.
We shall mourn our Sisters.
The Noelites have been persecuted
for too long.
Tomorrow will be the dawn
of our new age.
Congratulations, my friend.
You made it safe and sound.
Gorsky.
- Did you destroy that convent?
- I'm not a terrorist, Toorop.
- I'm a mercenary like you.
- Bullshit.
What the hell is going...?
What the hell is going on over here?
- You didn't leave me a gun?
- You've done your job.
When you turn over the girl, I'll get paid
and you're home free.
And the tracking device in your passport
will be deactivated.
Deliver the package.
My men will be there
to be sure you do.
They never hurt anybody.
Maybe it was an accident.
It was not an accident.
It was destroyed
right after we crossed the border.
Would you like to pray with me?
I don't feel like praying anymore.
Toorop said
I'm just a package to him.
Is that all I am to you?
Of course not.
I love you.
How is she?
Scared.
Yeah, well, she should be.
Who are they?
To the left, the Range Rover goons
work for your sect, the Noelites.
To the right...
...the bikers work for Gorsky.
They're all here
to make sure I deliver.
And if we don't?
It's gonna be a free-for-all.
Look, Sister.
We traveled 6000 miles together.
The truth is this has been
a suicide mission from the beginning.
They won't let either one of us
walk out of here alive.
That's the doctor that came
to the convent three months ago.
Answer the door.
Act like nothing's wrong.
Okay.
- Good evening, Sister.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
Where is she?
In the room.
You're a bad man.
Thank you, Aurora.
Thank you so much.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
I have to run some more tests.
- More tests?
- Standard...
You just ran your test.
- What's wrong with her?
- Expect a call.
What is wrong with her?
Toorop.
Toorop, let him go.
If you please?
Thank you, Sister.
- Get over here.
- What's wrong with you?
I wanna know everything.
Don't you think that if I knew anything,
I would tell you?
No, I don't think.
You're a Noelite. You are like him.
You swore an oath.
Not to them. To God.
God has nothing to do with it now.
You understand?
If she carries a virus,
she could annihilate the city.
I'm not gonna have it on my conscience.
I'm pregnant. Twins.
It's not possible.
I've watched over you all your life.
No one's ever touched you.
- And nobody has.
- It's a miracle.
Shit.
- Hello.
- Mr. Toorop, this is the High Priestess.
- I am the...
- I know who you are.
Thank you for doing such a good job,
Mr. Toorop.
You're welcome.
Bring the girl to the limousine
and you'll be free...
- Toorop...
...and rich.
...if you deliver me to them, I'll die.
We're on our way out.
All right, guys.
Let's go get her. Are you ready?
We can't let her go, Toorop.
Look around. Do we have a choice?
She's your problem now.
Move!
We're going to the subway.
Thank you, Toorop.
What's wrong?
It's a missile linked to my passport.
How can you stop it?
- I got him!
- Only by death.
Go to the subway.
Toorop.
Aurora.
Get the girl.
It's you.
Protect them.
I need you to live.
Aurora was our miracle.
A true virgin birth.
This was to make ours
the dominant religion on earth.
Now we don't know
what's happened to her.
In this mess,
there's no sign of Aurora.
We can't find her.
We were finally on the verge
of becoming a bona fide religion.
Your incompetence has thrown 20 years
of careful planning down the tubes.
Who gave the order to use guns
to retrieve her?
You left Gorsky no choice.
What were you thinking?
- Your Highness.
- What?
The body stolen from the morgue
was Toorop's.
The police have found the van
that transported him to New Jersey.
Who would want to abduct
the body of a dead man?
He's back online.
Where are you taking me?
To Darquandier.
Jamal, Mr. Toorop is not our prisoner.
You can release him.
Good evening, Mr. Toorop.
I'm Dr. Darquandier. Aurora's father.
I thought you were dead.
It's sometimes useful to be dead.
It allows one a second chance.
You'll see.
Oh, yes. You we're clinically dead
for two hours.
We lost time
getting you from the morgue.
And then you went into a coma
for five days.
I fixed you up as best I could.
Now, Mr. Toorop, I believe
I owe you some explanation.
Twenty years ago, I was drummed out
of the medical profession...
...for trying to implant human babies
with artificial intelligence.
Around that time,
the Noelites came to me...
...to create smarter,
stronger, healthier human beings.
So I built a super computer
to be Aurora's artificial mother.
As a fetus, Aurora learned
to process information...
...just like a computer.
But when she was born...
...she became much more
than just an experiment.
She became...
She became my daughter.
She was beautiful. She was unique.
I couldn't give her away, so that's when
they hired Gorsky to kill me...
...and, well, he almost succeeded.
He took my baby away
and hid her for the Noelites.
I searched for her,
but I couldn't find her.
I knew that one day the Noelites
would present their miracle...
...to the rest of the world.
- What do you want from me?
- I want you to find my daughter.
We think she's alive
and that she's left you a message.
You died with your eyes open...
...but your brain recorded more
than you can actually remember.
We just need to rewind the tape.
You need to return to the same condition
you were in when we found you.
I was dead.
Quite.
What am I looking for?
What you missed the first time.
We'll guide your memory
with our computer.
Are you ready, Mr. Toorop?
Stay with the memory.
Move forward a bit.
Focus on his memories of Aurora.
He's seeing her. Very good.
Stop!
I'll die.
That's right. We're getting there.
We're getting there.
Now is good. Focus on his gun.
Easy, easy. Steady, steady.
- Way past the danger threshold.
- I know, but he'll be fine. He'll be fine.
Hey, slow down. Slow down.
Now. Slow down.
Let's wait, let's wait, let's wait.
I need you to live.
He's dead.
Wait.
Don't bring him back yet.
He's almost there. The last seconds.
Go home.
It's all right. You're back. You're safe.
You're all right. You're fine.
I know where she is.
Mr. Gorsky, I hoped
I wouldn't have to see you again.
Where is my money?
You haven't paid me.
You have an odd way
of killing people.
What are you talking about?
I'm on my way
to see our old friend, Darquandier.
Impossible.
I made his car explode myself.
Mr. Gorsky, when I kill, I kill for good.
- Are you threatening me?
- Bless your soul.
You will need a nuke to kill me.
Bitch.
How did she survive the blast?
It's the babies, you see.
They're gaining power.
They're the ones guiding her.
Her capacity for survival is greater than
anything we could ever have imagined.
Professor, your wife has found us.
She'll be here in two minutes.
Find her, Toorop.
You're the only one
who can save her now.
So where are we going?
North.
Hello, my dear.
It's lovely to see you.
- Where's my daughter?
- I see you haven't found her.
And you never will.
You selfish bastard.
Twenty years ago,
I gave you the opportunity you wanted.
Now it's my moment.
Where is my daughter?
She's not your daughter.
She comes from me.
- I designed her.
- For me.
She's my miracle.
- She belongs to my church.
- Your church is a lie.
You're peddling miracles
for your own profit.
Are you willing to die for her?
Yes.
Find Toorop. He knows where she is.
Wait here.
You're finally home.
What's left of it.
But I came back for you.
Have a little faith.
Toorop, they're coming.
By - MoSToFA K@MAL™
Break left.
Toorop, they need help.
No!
Take the wheel.
Toorop.
Thank you.
For protecting us.
You're their father now.
Aurora.
That's the first time
you've said my name.
You're gonna be okay.
Take care of them, Toorop.
Hey, kids.
There's a storm coming.
We need to go.
Ready?
Okay, Dad.