This story begins with a single plastic bag
to carry home a single container of peach yogurt
Once I got home I shoved the bag
in with all the other bags next to another bag full of other bags
And I never really thought about it
Maybe I tried NOT to think about it
I mean I’m an average guy I’m not what you’d consider a tree-hugger
I try to be informed. I try to do the right thing but I find
that it can be a bit overwhelming at times
I live in a small town in Colorado
and it wasn’t until my town challenged another town
a few hours away to see who could reduce
their use of plastic bags the most that
I first started to think about plastic bags and what we do with them
I mean we all have a lot of bags right
Everybody does the same thing
We collect them, we shove them anywhere they’ll go
like under the sink, into closets, junk drawers
We throw a pile away every now and then just to be done with them
because they're disposable, right?
They were created to be thrown away
But let’s face it: there’s a dirty little secret here
even if we won’t admit it
Just because plastic is disposable
doesn’t mean it just goes away
After all, where is away?
There is no away
It actually sticks around for a really long time
That got me thinking about all the endless products made of plastic
A lot of them designed to be used for less than one day
Heck, less than fifteen minutes even
Once I began looking around
pretty much everything seemed to be made of plastic
Could all this plastic in my life maybe be bad for me?
So I started looking into it
The fact that it is everywhere
The way it doesn’t go away
The way it pollutes
the way it flies and floats and drifts
and clogs and entangles
The way it gets into things so big and so small
the way we can't escape it anymore
the way, eventually, we may not have any recourse
we'll all just simply all have to stand up and say
Bag It
You know that thing when you learn something for the first time
and then it starts popping up everywhere?
Like, you meet someone for the first time
and everywhere you go there’s that person
That was what it was like for me with plastic bags
They were everywhere
Let me just say this
first of all:
Plastic is an incredible material
It’s lightweight, it’s moldable,
durable, versatile, inexpensive
You can do amazing things with plastic
In the 1960's, the idea of plastic being the wave
of the future seemed like a bit of a joke
I just want to say one word to you
Just one word
Are you listening?
Yes, I am.
Plastics.
Exactly how do you mean?
There’s a great future in plastics.
In retrospect, this scene seems less like a joke and more like a prophecy
We were fed the concept of disposable living
Life would be easier and more convenient
Why do the dishes when you can just throw them away?
Plastic is an incredibly valuable resource
It’s something that really has a purpose in this society
and it needs to be used for that purpose
Petroleum is way too scarce and way too important
to us to be thrown away as a plastic bag.
Plastic bags are made of polyethylene
which is a polymer made of ethylene monomers
which is made from
well, actually, what they’re made from is a really good question
The United States uses, you know, roughly
estimates are about 100 billion plastic bags per year
It takes about 12 million barrels of oil.
In North American because we have an abundant supply of natural gas
they’re predominantly made out of natural gas
The key feedstock for making plastics is petroleum
In North America we don’t use oil, we use natural gas.
Plastic bags
are made of polyethylene
The building block is oil.
The bottom line is, they’re made from fossil fuels
which are non-renewable resources
That means, once they’re are gone, there isn’t any more.
And in this very short amount of time
we’re up to consuming about a million a minute
World plastic bag consumption is estimated
at about 500 billion bags per year.
So how do we learn how to shop
like our grandparents did?
I mean we haven’t always had plastic. Right?
What if we shopped using our bags over and over
you know, old school?
Some say that plastic bags have been singled out
that they have become an easy target
That there are much bigger
environmental issues out there
So why pick on plastic bags?
It would be great to come up with
the real cost of a plastic bag
because that is the number one consumer item in the world
We are not going to use those little plastic produce bags
We have our own bags
Here we go.
I’m going to use my own bag
for some deluxe salted nuts
There we go
Anne is the creative director at a newspaper
Thankfully, she’s pretty much on board for all of this
Plastic bags are being banned around the world
From New Delhi India and Bangladesh
where bags were clogging storm drains
and were contributing to severe floods
to the kingdom of Bhutan
where bags were banned to better foster
gross national happiness
In 2008, China banned ultra-thin plastic bags
It’s estimated that in the first year
it eliminated 40 billion
In May of 2009
the state of South Australia banned plastic bags
hoping to set an example for the rest of the nation
Tanzania, Uganda, Rwanda, Kenya, Zanzibar
and South Africa have all banned ultra- thin plastic bags
Many countries and cities in Europe
have either banned
or placed fees on plastic bags
Ireland placed a fee on plastic bags
and reportedly reduced consumption 90 percent in the first year
What’s the policy on plastic bags?
Like plastic carry-away bags
They’re 22 cents each.
22 cents?
Yeah.
Okay.
It’s the government’s policy, it’s not actually the shop policy
Is that all of Ireland?
Do you find that most people
do most people not take them?
Do they bring their own bag?
Yeah, most people won’t take them.
How fast did you see a difference from when the tax went in?
It was instant. It was an overnight success as a campaign.
If you want to find out
what the people really think in Ireland
there’s only one place to go
to the pub.
Plastic bags in the bushes
plastic bags in the rivers
plastic bags in the canals
plastic bags everywhere.
Yeah, it has cleaned up the countryside an awful lot.
A pint of Guinness doesn’t come in plastic
Slancha
In England, the village of Modbury became Europe’s first plastic bag free town
when the local merchants got together
and decided to voluntarily do something to help protect
their coastal environment.
We live 4 miles from some of the most beautiful coastline in the UK
You know, what legacy are we leaving
It’s really not to be quite selfish for the moment
and to think about the next generations to come.
In environmental news
a top UN official is urging a global ban
on plastic bags
in part because
plastic is the most pervasive form of ocean litter
Achim Steiner, Executive Director of the U.N Environment Program
said quote “Single use plastic bags
which choke marine life
should be banned or phased out rapidly everywhere
There is simply zero justification for manufacturing them anymore, anywhere
So what are we doing here at home?
Thirty rural communities in Alaska have banned plastic bags completely
In June of ‘09, Washington DC became the first US city
to place a fee on plastic bags.
California has been at the forefront of the plastic bag debate
San Francisco becomes the first city in the nation to ban plastic bags.
In San Francisco, those ubiquitous plastic shopping bags
have been ordered to Get out of town
People think San Francisco is a bunch of crazy radicals
We didn’t want to pursue a ban
So we tried for a year
to move forward with a fee
We thought that’s the most progressive way to do it
it’s the fairest way to do it
If you don’t use bags, you don’t pay
But the plastic bag lobby of the American Chemistry Council
quietly pushed through a law
prohibiting charging fees for plastic bags
anywhere in the state of California
The plastic bag lobby basically
pushed us into a corner through
strong arm tactics, back door deals in Sacramento
with our legislature
We had no option
The predictions from the plastic industry was
doom and gloom
You know, San Francisco will grind to an absolute halt
How can they live without plastic bags?
In the two years since we’ve had it in place
not one single complaint in our office, not one.
After San Francisco, other towns in California tried to pass their own bans
The American Chemistry Council’s and other pro-plastic groups’ response?
Was to sue
They claimed
it would just make people use paper bags instead
which would be even worse for the environment.
Even though city governments are being fought every step of the way
a lot of retailers have decided to take matters into their own hands.
At Costo and Sam’s Club
people have never been given bags
On earth day of 2008
Whole Foods became the first U.S. Supermarket
to completely do away with plastic bags
It’s paper versus plastic
And what do you do?
And I guess tote bags are the thing.
That’s what I’ve heard on the streets.
You could get a nice tote to go with your sweaters
Yeah well you know once I get my Bedazzler
I could you know...
Oftentimes the plastics industry
will say when you’re making the choice between paper of plastic
plastic is the better choice environmentally
Plastic is very lightweight
It takes fewer fossil fuels to transport plastic
So what’s left out of the equation
very conveniently is
what happens to our plastic
when it winds up into the ocean
If that were quantified
and if that became part of the analysis
there would be no contest
The eternal question: paper or plastic
How did San Francisco justify using paper?
The paper bags in San Francisco
many of them are 100% recycled content
and that means that no new trees are being cut down
Paper bags are being recycled at least ten times
more than plastic bags are being recycled
That significantly changes their environmental impact
So I think we have to really watch out for
the lobbying efforts of the American Chemistry Council
and other plastics industry
They’re really trying to protect their market share and their profits
That’s the bottom line
So who is the American Chemistry Council, anyway?
Well, the American Chemistry Council, otherwise known as the ACC
with over 130 member corporations
basically protects the interest of plastics and chemicals
One of the ACC’s branches is the Progressive Bag Affiliates
and the Progressive Bag Affiliates
has formed groups with friendly names like the Coalition
to Support Plastic Bag Recycling
And then there’s Save the Plastic Bag...
you know, like Save the Rainforest
or Save the Panda, or Save the Manatee
Yeah, Save the Plastic Bag
Just reading our e-mails from the plastic industry
So far, this many people have agreed to be in the film
If we’re going to be more than one-sided
we need to hear from more than one side
and if one side won’t talk to us... kind of problematic
Ooh, ooh, no bag, no bag
Thanks. I didn’t bring a bag but...
Would you like a bag?
No, no, no. Thanks.
I’m going to do it commando style
Alright!
You don’t even need a bag for your produce
Did you know that?
Yeah.
Yeah. I like my lettuce loose... like my ladies!
Are you sure you don’t need a bag?
We’ve got bags on sale for 99 cents.
I got it covered. I got it covered. I can do it. I can do this. Oh thank you. K.
Thank you so much. Have a good day.
People kept referring to plastic bags
as this thing called a single- use disposable
Single-use disposable plastic
Think about it
Why would you make something
that you’re going to use for a few minutes
out of a material
that’s basically going to last forever
and you’re just going to throw it away?
What’s up with that?
From things like yogurt containers, yogurt tubes
plastic forks, plastic spoons
don’t even get me started on Snackables
stackables, Lunchables
pizza on a cookie
to- go containers
all kinds of packaging created to be ripped off then tossed off
sandwich bags, snack bags, candy wrappers
drinking straws...
and of course, the big three
the three things that we Americans love to use and throw away the most.
Bags, bottles, and cups.
So I just went into a very well known coffee chain
Which will remain nameless
Let’s just say that it rhymes with “Marbucks.”
And everybody’s sitting around drinking coffees
and lattes, and chais,
and soy mochas
and everybody has a to-go cup
The to-go cup is for things to go
Which, uh, coincidentally has a little lining on the inside made out of plastic
Did you know that?
Your cardboard coffee cup has a lining made out of plastic?
Let’s take a disposable, single-use coffee cup, of which we use 300 million a day
You drink the coffee in 10, 20 minutes.
If it’s a Styrofoam package, that package is going
to be around longer than the statue of David.
Now, we’re being convinced by marketing geniuses
that we’re supposed to use to go cups... in our own homes!
So we just found out some very exciting news
Yes
Didn’t we?
Yes, we did
We’re going to have a baby.
We’re having a baby.
We’re having a baby!
Well I’m a little freaked out
Yeah, well, so am I.
You are? Yeah. OK. Good.
And excited
Yup. Better clean this place up. Pink... or blue?
How about yellow or green?
Green!
OK, let me just clarify something: when I said I was freaked out,
I am freaked out, but not in a bad way.
I’m very excited about having a baby
But I’m also freaked out about this whole plastics issue.
You know, how it's going to affect our baby. Our baby's health... I gotta find out more.
Why should we make a cup or a piece of cutlery
that you gonna be using for five minutes,
why should we make it out of a drop of oil that takes 70 million years to make?
It’s not making sense
In 1970, the United States was one of the largest exporters of oil.
And here we are in 2008, and we are the largest importer of oil.
The sheer numbers of packaging that we’re each individually responsible for are staggering
The average American contributes 800 pounds of packaging
to the waste stream per person per year
This is packaging rage, an affliction suffered daily by millions.
Think about how ridiculous it’s become
We package everything in plastic
Even things that are already perfectly packaged by nature come packaged in plastic
We package paper in plastic
We even package plastic in plastic
One single-use disposal item we can definitely avoid is disposable diapers
It says “Buy cloth diapers instead of disposables and save up to $1,200.”
That’s good. That’s the diaper right there?
It’s beautiful
It’s very stylish
It’s very stylish.
It also says reusable cloth diapers prevent up to one ton of landfill waste.
So you don’t have to throw them away
You don’t throw them away
That’s good.
You wash them
Alright. I’m in.
I’ve done several images on single use disposable plastics.
One of them is an image of 60,000 plastic bags,
which is the number of plastic bags, sacks, and wraps
consumed in the United States every 5 seconds
Plastic water bottles
That to me is another one of the most insane things in our world right now.
There are 1.2 billion people -- almost 20 percent of the world’s population --
who lack access to safe drinking water on a daily basis.
And at the same time as that is happening,
we’re spending untold amounts of money and resources shipping tap water from Fiji to Miami,
Bottled water has now surpassed sales of beer and milk
and analysts think that within three years it may surpass soda sales
We go through the equivalent of 17 million barrels of oil making the
bottles that are used in the United States each year
Making those bottles generates two and a half million tons of carbon dioxide.
They had hundreds of millions of dollars to spend telling us to drink more water.
They used celebrities and models and used athletes so that their product was linked with wellness.
Utilities don’t have millions of dollars hanging around in their budgets to spend on advertisements saying
"Drink from your sink;" you know,
And so the category grew and grew, and in 2008,
What is plastic made out of? Do you know?
Not really. No
I have no idea what the chemical compound is
Plastic is made of... plastic
Plastic is made of Yellow Dye No. 5
It turns out one of the biggest environmental consequences
of making bottled water is making the plastic that makes up the bottle.
If you were to fill any bottle about 25 percent of the way up with petroleum
that’s the amount of oil required the make the bottle itself
But that’s not the whole story
On top of it, we then have to transport it
If you’re moving it a long way, it requires a lot more energy,
maybe as much as another quarter.
It would be nice if people started to think of
buying single use bottled water like driving a Hummer.
Because it’s basically what it is.
They don’t necessarily do it this way in the rest of the world
Enter Germany, home of the bratwurst, Beethoven, BMW and Oktoberfest oompah bands
They also take the recycling of plastics very seriously.
I basically collect all the plastic bottles, and just carry them to the supermarket,
and you put them into this machine and you get a receipt back and with this receipt it’s worth money.
This bottle is getting used a couple of times
As you can see there are like the little marks on it which says how often this bottle is in this recycling circle.
And this one is 22nd times.
They’re getting cleaned, refilled, relabeled and coming back into the circle.
So this is all the plastic that I collected this year so far
This is Beth Terry
Two years ago she decided to stop using plastic altogether,
and whatever plastic she can't avoid, she saves
These are like used spaghetti sauce jars
And so I just take them with me to the store. So there’s sugar that I can get in bulk... and lentils.
I stopped using plastic bags because I just... hate them
But Michael is a real conservation, use-what-you-have kind of person,
so he washes out the plastic bags that we already have.
This is our bathroom
The easiest thing in the bathroom is just not to use liquid soap
You know. So we use bar soap
Beth uses an antique all-metal razor
She swears by it.
- You need three blades, you know why? - But you don’t
Because the first blade pulls the hair out, and then the second blade pulls it out a little more and smacks it around
You’re a product of marketing!
When I was growing up, we didn’t have bottled water
I mean, people made jokes about Evian being “naive” spelled backwards
I think that, for me, it was the idea of harming other living creatures
and other people and harming the planet.
That’s what really woke me up.
Making changes in your own life gives you a sense of ownership
It makes you feel like We’ve got to do so much more
I’ve got to talk to other people
I’ve got to talk to my representatives.
I’ve got to start writing to companies
I’ve really got to up my game
But I think it starts on the individual level.
When we started our film, Seattle’s City Council had already approved legislation
placing a fee on disposable plastic and paper bags;
They dropped $200,000 into a campaign to get signatures to put the ordinance on the ballot
By August of 2009, the ACC had upped their spending to 1.4 Million dollars
So why would the plastics industry spend over a million dollars fighting a bag tax in Seattle?
Well, it’s not all about Seattle. They worry about other cities and want to get the message out fast.
I feel a real responsibility as an American to stand up to these American corporations and say,
I’m angry. They have no business being here: I want their hands off Seattle!
So, I just want to say that we took on the most powerful industry in the country
So, I think we won.
Thank you so much for everything you’ve done
Keep on the good fight
Every time we go and we buy something,
we decide who we give our money to
This machine can stop as soon as we decide to say
“No. I do not want that plastic bag
I do not want to buy your stuff and throw it away.”
So here’s a recap of the basics
The way I see it: Bring your own bag
Bring your own coffee cup.
Bring your own water bottle.
Oh and bring your own brain
Consider less packaging
Go single-use free for a single day
Start there
Become aware of your habits.
It’s not as easy as you think
But guess what?
It makes you think!
Ice cream doesn’t come in plastic
So, it seems like in this society, we like to consume
And a lot of the stuff that we like to consume is made of plastic or it comes in plastic
But once we’re done with that, where does it go?
We put out garbage at the end of the driveway
and the sanitation crew comes and picks it up and it goes away
Where’s away?
You know?
There is no away!
If you can imagine Yankee stadium, as a Tupperware container
We fill it three times a day with garbage here in New York City
And certainly a huge amount of it is also plastics.
Here we are in New York City
I’ve got my man purse. OK?
Something. Oooh, look at that. Oh sorry. Yeah, see that thing?
Look at that
Okay, that is not wildlife, people. Okay?
That is not nature. That’s a plastic bag
It’s a bit of a workout  to chase them around.
I don’t have to go to the gym now.
If I just say “plastic bags,” to you, “in New York.” What do you say?
We use them,
They’re a convenience for a couple of minutes, a couple of hours,
and they remain an environmental burden for hundreds of years.
One of the biggest problems in the city is that we use about a billion plastic bags a year
People joke that the New York City flower is a plastic bag stuck in a tree.
That’s a bad emblem.
Hi, welcome to Wendy’s, what can I  get for you today?
Um, I have a question for you
I’m trying not to use packaging and I brought my own plate and my own cup.
Is it possible to get it served on my own plate?
Hold on one second
Thanks
We cannot put it on ourselves, but we can give it to you and you can put in on though
Me taking their food out of their packaging and putting it on my own plate,
sort of defeated the whole purpose.
So, I decided to try Taco Bell.
I’m sorry, sir, we can’t do that.
That’s called cross contamination, and we can’t take anything from the outside in.
Oh. Are you able to put a soda in my own glass?
Cross contamination. Okay!
It’s not exactly true they can’t take anything through the window.
They’re fine taking our cross- contaminated money
I'm sorry you can't film here, ma'am!
There’s no ah-haa moment, it’s just sort of hacking away at it little by little
And that’s how you can  go a year and end up with 32 pounds of garbage
Okay, I get this whole concept of using less and producing less waste,
but with plastic packaging, can't we just recycle it?
I spend a lot of time in my book asking “Is recycling doing any good?
Is it worthwhile, should we continue to do it?”
And the short answer is a resounding “Yes, yes, yes.”
It saves enormous amounts of energy to make new goods from old goods
instead of continually pulling raw materials from the earth,
and transforming them, transporting them, and then
sending them on this one way trip to the landfill.
For every barrel of waste we put on the curb,
there are 71 barrels of waste generated upstream
in making all these consumer goods.
And every time we recycle whatever we can,
we’re chipping away at those 71 barrels upstream.
This stuff isn’t recyclable-
It’s recyclable.
ANNE No, it’s not.
That’s recyclable.
No, it’s not.
You put it all in there and they’ll figure it out.
There, there’s the thing.
See? Recycle.
Why would they put that on if you can’t recycle it?
Right. Okay.
I’ll do it.
Thank you.
You shouldn’t be carrying stuff.
No, you shouldn’t.
I thoroughly believe people are recycling because they think it’s the right thing to do
As soon as they get rid of it, into that container, they never think about it any more
I don’t even think they know where it goes after it leaves our site
I don’t know where it goes after it leaves this site!
I think it could be a feel-good thing for people.
I have such a love-hate relationship with recycling.
Because I love recycling in that it’s sort of an on-ramp
or a gateway drug to bigger, better environmental activism.
But what I hate about it is it lulls people into thinking that they’re making a difference.
You know, you buy this thing, you know that it’s overpackaged.
But at least you can recycle it. You put it in that blue bin and it’s like Ahhhhhh.
This is recycling arrows
Yeah
It’s a chasing arrow
So most people would assume that means, “Hey I can recycle that.”
Yeah, that was brilliant marketing on the American Chemistry Council
and the American Plastic Council’s part.
They use that chasing arrow to make us all think that it’s all recyclable.
Turns out, there’s no regulation with the recycling symbol.
We’ve been duped into believing that all these products are getting recycled.
The truth is that really only a few of those numbers, 1 and 2, are highly recycled.
Those other  numbers are going straight to the landfill or the incinerator.
Okay I’ve seen these numbers on the bottom of plastic before,
and I always wondered what they meant...
And now the society of plastics industry coding system:
Number 1: polyethylene terephthalate
Number 2: high density polyethylene
Number 3: polyvinylchloride
Number 4: low density polyethylene
Number  5: polypropylene
Number 6: polystyrene
And number 7?
Other!
I was feeling pretty confused as to which plastics could and couldn’t be recycled
So I decided to put on a recycling challenge,
in order to find out if other people were as confused as I was.
I recycle, so I think I know things that should be recycled.
Here’s your recycling bin. Here’s your trash can
Aaaand, Go
Well, guess what.
It turns out that everyone was pretty much as confused as I was.
Especially the bagpiper.
For those of you looking for an easy answer, there isn’t one.
Every municipality across the country has different guidelines
as to what they do and don’t accept.
With a lid, you can’t. My wife taught me that one.
Good, good, good.
Do you recycle these?
Well, I’d be giving it away wouldn’t I?
Yeah, you’re pretty sharp.
The most common items taken are Number 1 and Number 2, but only the bottles.
Currently in the U.S., recycled plastic bottles are not made back into new bottles
but are downcycled into products that can not then be recycled.
So they tend to get just one more life.
Unlike an aluminum can or a glass container that can theoretically be recycled forever.
The plastics industry, they like to buy, fresh out of the refineries,
plastic pellets that they can turn into really clean high grade material;
so they don’t really even want the recycled content back.
Their only incentive in promoting recycling
is to be able justify to the consumer that this product is good.
If they don’t want it, where does it go?
Well, as a matter of fact, a lot of our plastic goes to Asia.
Shiploads of our plastic garbage is going over there.
And the reason it’s going over there is it’s yucky to reprocess it.
It’s technically impossible to really recycle it.
It’s dirty and stinky and gross and we don’t want that stuff here.
What they do is they take it into a big yard and they pop it open
open and they have people working under very low wages
with very bad working conditions,
and they will cherry pick out the things that they can melt down and do something with.
But the human rights and labor issues related with that
the toxicity issues of some of the open plastic melting that they do
-- to me those do not fit in a recycling model.
Recycling can’t do everything for us.
It’s more important to reduce what we consume
and to reuse things that have already been made.
But even more important is this fourth R, which comes ahead of these three.
And it’s Redesign: redesigning goods to last longer,
to contain fewer toxins, and to be easier to take apart and rebuild or repair.
Michael Braungart is a German chemist well known for his cradle to cradle concept.
So you define everything no longer from cradle to grave but from cradle to cradle.
So you always plan the next life of a product in it.
We have this idea that our worth as a nation is based on gross national product.
And that consumption and a high standard of living equals happiness.
The number one thing that makes people happy is the strength of our social relations.
If we stop putting so much of our life energy into getting more and more and more stuff
we take it out of that system
and we plug it into our communities and families and friends,
not only do we create less waste, but we actually have more fun.
Buy less stuff, that is the simplest thing that I can say to people.
How about not using something that needs to be disposed of or dealt with in the first place?
Use it up, wear it out, make it do, or do without.
If you don’t need it, don’t buy it.
We think of a lot of plastic products as being cheap and disposable.
If it breaks, no problem, just get another one.
But here’s the thing: disposable plastic isn’t really that cheap.
Someone has to pay.
Whether it’s the cost of making it, transporting it, or the cost of throwing it “away.”
And how about the unquantifiable amount it costs
when plastics end up loose in the environment?
who pays for that?
So I recently found out that there is all this trash sitting in the middle of the ocean.
And a lot of this trash is plastic.
And, my first thought was, well, alright, but that’s...
I didn’t do that.
Where does that trash come from?
Trash gets loose on the land, it blows into a river,
and the trash goes into the ocean.
So, that is our plastic out there.
And there’s a lot of it.
People ask me: Why should I care about the ocean?
It seems so obvious.
The ocean is the cornerstone of earth’s life support system.
It shapes climate and weather; it holds most of life on earth.
Ninety-seven percent of earth’s water is there.
It’s the blue heart of the planet.
We should take care of our heart.
It’s what makes life possible for us.
We still have a really good chance to make things better than they are.
They won’t get better unless we take the action
-- and inspire others to do the same thing.
No one is without power.
Everybody has the capacity to do something.
How bad is the situation with plastic in the ocean?
I think it’s bad because it’s unnecessary.
It doesn’t have the be there.
There are clear environmental consequences in terms of that we know
that over 260 species that are affected by plastic debris,
through entanglements and ingestion.
So just based on the statistics of production,
how we’ve gone from half a million tons of plastic per year produced
in the 1950's to over 260 million tons today.
To put that into context, okay
-- the first decade of this century, by 2010,
will have produced more plastic than the whole of the century that preceded.
And most of that material is going to make throwaway items
that are then ending up in landfill or the ocean.
Eighty percent of all marine debris actually starts from a land-based source.
All drains do lead to the ocean.
We dump things.
They end up going down a storm drain or into a wetland,
going down streams and rivers, straight into the Atlantic or Pacific Ocean.
It’s estimated that about six million pieces of litter enter the oceans
every day and that the majority of this is plastic.
Camillo Beach has a very white sand look,
and it’s not really sand at all,
it’s mostly white plastic covering the beach,
sometimes up to a foot thick of plastic pieces.
Wait a second. This is Hawaii?
I’ve seen pictures of Hawaii. Hawaii is beautiful.
This is not what a beach in Hawaii is supposed to look like.
There’s just far too much of it in our ocean right now,
and what is washing up on our beaches is a small indication of what’s really out there.
Mainly what we find are fragments of plastic.
Stuff like this.
And all this debris is coming from the North Pacific Subtropical Gyre,
or the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.
There are actually five major “gyres” --
swirling systems of currents in our oceans.
One in the Indian Ocean, two in the Atlantic Ocean and two in the Pacific Ocean.
The gyre that has been studied the most is the North Pacific Subtropical gyre
-- otherwise known as the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.
Estimated to be anywhere from twice the size of Texas
to the size of the entire United States.
Debris of all kinds floats into this gyre and there it stays.
Swirling.
Now the problem is that when this debris is made of plastic,
it doesn’t biodegrade, it photodegrades.
That means that sunlight breaks it down into smaller and smaller pieces,
which marine life can mistake for food.
So what exactly does this garbage patch look like?
We went to the Algalita Marine Research Foundation for some answers.
They have spent over a decade studying plastic in the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.
It’s not a floating island of trash that can be cleaned up or scooped out.
It’s way worse than that.
It’s tons of little bits of plastic floating under water,
like a plastic soup.
It’s our thickest sample yet.
We’ve been finding more plastic by weight than plankton.
And the ratio keeps going up. That’s our concern.
Over the years, they have seen in their trawls through the Patch,
plastic-to-plankton ratios that have gone from six-to-one to as high as forty-to-one.
What that means is that in some parts of the ocean,
there is now 40 times more plastic than food.
No bueno. (No good)
To raise awareness about plastic in our oceans,
Dr. Marcus Eriksen and a fellow scientist
decided to set sail across the pacific on a boat made of plastic.
Hi!
Hi Dr. Eriksen. Why exactly are you making this trip?
The point is to get the nation talking about
how do we end the age of disposable plastics.
We need to end this mass consumption of single- use plastic materials.
So the idea here is to sail from California to Oahu
on a boat made of 15,000 recycled plastic bottles, correct?
Exactly. And those bottles are held together by derelict fishing nets.
It’s name is Junk, because it’s made of junk.
What has to happen is a global recognition
that disposable plastics have no place in our environment.
According to Dr. Eriksen, the plastic in the ocean is carrying toxins at high concentrations.
Animals are then eating the plastic fragments.
They think it’s food.
They just open up their mouths and take a big gulp.
What amounts to a big gulp of Persistent Organic Pollutants, or POP’s.
These are chemicals and toxins -- like DDT, DDE and PCB’s among others
-- that latch onto plastics and become super- concentrated.
The plastic acts like a sponge!
And then when the plastics are mistakenly eaten by marine life,
the toxic chemicals go with them.
When you eat a large fish like a swordfish,
it might be the fifth step in the food chain
because it’s eaten a smaller fish that ate smaller fish
and they ate zooplankton and eventually they ate phytoplankton;
and at every step you’re getting a multiplication factor of ten times
or a hundred times or even a thousand times those chemicals.
And the plastics are facilitating this:
they sort of sop up the toxic chemicals and concentrate them in their flesh
so that we can end up eating them on our dinner plates.
This is Midway Atoll, a tiny speck of land in the middle of the Pacific Ocean
where plastic is having a direct impact on the fate of the Laysan albatross.
Midway Atoll National Wildlife Refuge is home to the largest albatross colony in the world.
These birds are fantastic flyers, they forage throughout the Pacific,
but because they forage so far,
they're really good indicators of the health of the Pacific
and what's happening out there.
In the 1950s when people looked at dead albatross at Midway,
they didn't see any plastic at all; and it wasn't until the '60s
that we started to see in at Midway and in the Northwestern Hawaiian Islands.
Every dead bird at Midway has plastic in them.
So this is kind of the extreme:
plastic everywhere and very little food.
Nineteen caps of some sort,
and then of the 19, there were about 14 bottle caps.
The plastic they use for the top isn’t recyclable right now --
so maybe that’s one of the reasons why you find so many plastic tops around.
The albatross that are surrounding us here today
face numerous threats over the course of their life,
to successfully come back here and
have chicks of their own
They’ve got to fly hundreds of miles to find food;
they’ve got to survive for several years at sea;
and the plastics in the ecosystem are just
another hurdle in that path to come back here.
All the plastic that you see here was brought to the island by an adult albatross and fed to a chick.
We can calculate how much plastic is brought to Midway each year by the adult albatross
and it comes out to be five tons of plastic.
That’s every year. Five tons.
What’s happening to Midway will soon be happening around the globe
unless we change the way that we operate as a people.
And he totally agrees.
He thinks that was very well stated. I know.
It’s not just albatross that are feeling the effects of plastic in the oceans.
Over 260 marine species are being impacted by plastic,
either through ingestion or entanglement.
This 26 foot long Bride’s whale was stranded on a beach in Australia and died.
It was found that the whale’s stomach was packed with over 19 square feet of plastic.
In fact, it is estimated that plastic kills 100,000 marine animals each year.
Just about every big animal in the ocean is down 90 percent.
Animals aren’t going to be fine unless we figure out how to help them.
But imagine if every morning your breakfast was a bowl of cereal
and half the stuff in the bowl was little Styrofoam balls and half of it was cereal.
In some parts of the ocean, there’s enough plastic out there that animals are eating a lot of it.
And it’s not good.
Sea turtles are fascinating animals that have been on our planet since the time of the dinosaurs,
but now all sea turtle species in U.S. waters are listed as
threatened of endangered under the Endangered Species Act.
They just eat what’s out there.
And, not that long ago, everything that they would find was edible, or at least biodegradable.
If you could envision what a plastic bag would look like floating in the ocean,
it looks like a jellyfish;
and many sea turtle species eat jellyfish.
Ach, it’s another No. From the plastics industry.
To be interviewed in our film.
So far, everybody from the plastics industry has declined to be in our film.
Even the ones that we interviewed.
See Jeb, this marine debris issue is way overblown.
To say that “Oh, we cut open a dead animal and
we found a bunch of plastic fragments in it
therefore the animal died because of plastic?”
How do we know that the animal wasn’t sick and dying
and that it just ate a bunch of plastic at the end of its life
because it was sick and dying?
Did they do a toxicology autopsy on them?
No, they don’t do that on animals, they do that on people.
When scientists are conducting necropsies,
which are animal autopsies,
they’re finding that sea turtles’ stomachs are full of tiny little pieces of plastic.
Some sea turtle species like the Pacific leatherback,
it’s estimated that they could go extinct within the next couple of decades.
We’re really in a position where every dead sea turtle counts,
and we need to do whatever we can to keep them alive
and to recover healthy sea turtle populations.
Here’s a question I’ve got...
When did they start doing this?
On milk... and juice.
It’s supposed to open like this.
I don’t get it.
There’s really no cleaning it up.
I’ve heard the scenario that to clean up the North Pacific Gyre,
it would be akin to vacuuming the entire continental United States three times over.
That’s a monumental task.
So we’re stuck with that plastic in the ocean as it is.
Although there’s no real way to clean all this plastic out of the ocean,
some people are at least trying.
We’ve been here for approximately two weeks now on our marine debris trip.
We do this every year in conjunction with NOAA.
We brought two cargo containers because that’s what they filled last year.
There’s so much debris this year that we’re going to
overflow the two containers that we brought.
I think maybe if people saw the amount of debris we that collected in these quantities
it’d make them think twice about the amount of plastic they use in their daily life.
We need help from industry and people
involved in product and packaging design to help with material reduction.
Reducing the quantities of plastic that we use for single-use one-trip items
and then they’re thrown away --
and that’s to my mind, you know,
a third of all the plastics we make,
that’s what we’re using them for --
that’s the area that really needs to be targeted
if we want to help to reduce the problems
of contamination in the marine environment.
Nature solves its problems.
nd if we’re a problem, nature will solve us as a problem.
To be an environmentalist, to be a conservationist is really a question of self-preservation.
We’re really working to make sure that we survive.
The earth will survive.
But if we don’t learn to live in harmony with its ecosystem then we will simply disappear.
Even though we can’t clean up what’s already in our oceans,
we can make sure that we do all we can to not add more to it.
Can I use my own container?
If plastic is affection our oceans so dramatically,
could it be impacting human health?
And what about our child?
I’ll take the free-range chicken.
You know I’ve never been one of those people
that worried about chemicals and toxins and stuff;
I thought it was a little bit overboard.
But, when you’re going to have a baby,
you do start to worry about that kind of thing.
And you start to look around at your house at the stuff that you have.
The stuff that’s for your baby, that’s going to go on your baby’s skin.
And the stuff that people start giving you for your baby.
I don’t even know what kind of chemicals are in this stuff.
All day long you’re getting exposed to very small amounts
of many different things and each industry will say
“Oh it’s just a little bit of our chemical,”
but the problem is,
we think the cumulative impact during that whole day
is what’s causing that health effect in the human.
Basically there are no requirements
for testing chemicals for health and safety effects.
The current regulation is so weak
that the EPA tried to use this law to ban asbestos,
and they failed.
There’s something like 125,000 chemicals
registered for use around the globe and
very few have been tested for the effects on human health.
The Europeans put in the program REACH
where chemicals had to be proven safe
instead of the reverse where in our system,
first they have to be proven harmful.
So a chemical is innocent until proven guilty.
In this country.
Maybe we shouldn’t give chemicals the kind of rights that people get.
The chemicals we’re testing for now include
phthalates, which are the chemicals that are used to soften plastic,
bisphenol A which is a chemical used to harden plastic.
Phthalates and bisphenol A have been getting a lot of attention lately
because they’re both known as endocrine disrupters,
meaning they disrupt or inhibit our normal hormone function.
Let’s start with bisphenol A, otherwise known as BPA, which is a synthetic estrogen.
BPA is the main component of polycarbonate,
the hard, clear plastic sometimes used to make such items
as water bottles, food storage containers, sports equipment, and electronics.
But wait! There’s more.
So you think you’ll avoid plastic
you’ll do the right thing and you’ll buy something that comes in a can
and then you find out that the can is lined with...
guess what... You got it: plastic.
And this plastic that lines this very can contains bisphenol A.
Which means it also lines soda, juice, and beer cans, and -
guess what else BPA is in?
Infant formula can liners and baby bottles.
That’s right, baby bottles.
Bisphenol A exposure at phenomenally low doses
during the early period after birth
when babies are drinking infant formula laced
with bisphenol A out of baby bottles made with bisphenol A.
What you get is animals that are hyperactive
and show learning impairment.
Remind you of a human condition called Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder?
This is a poster chemical for that.
Basically, we have released a lot of chemicals into the environment
that can interfere with the way our children are constructed
from the moment of fertilization until they’re born 38 weeks later.
Not only health-wise but also in the way they behave and in their intelligence.
Academic and government scientists are showing an array of harm from bisphenol A
that is frightening to the brain, to the reproductive system.
And one of the things you see happening
with Bisphenol A is gender neutrality.
That means our boys are become feminized feminized and our girls are becoming masculinized.
And furthermore, many scientists believe that BPA exposure is linked to prostate cancer,
breast cancer, hypospadias, low sperm count, early puberty, uterine fibroids,
miscarriage, polycystic ovary disease, obesity, type 2 diabetes, ADHD, and autism.
Right now, it is predicted that one out of every third child --
and if you’re a minority, it’s one out of every two children born --
is going to develop diabetes sometime in their life.
Autism -- one in a hundred and fifty children.
This can’t be genetic because it’s happening too fast.
And in most instances, they were rare disorders before the 1970’s.
Of the more than 200 government funded studies, 92 percent show harm related to BPA exposure.
Of the less than 20 studies funded by chemical corporations, 0 percent show harm.
A Centers for Disease Control study detected BPA in the urine of 95% of adults sampled.
Those with the highest levels had more than twice the risk of heart disease and diabetes...
The FDA cites two studies, both of those studies funded by the plastics industry.
Scientists have measured BPA in the blood of pregnant women, in umbilical cord blood,
and in the placentas, all at levels demonstrated in animals to alter development.
Where is the FDA?
Have an FDA warning to tell you about this morning.
Now in a shift in the agency’s position
the FDA is saying that the chemical is of some concern.
...Especially on the brain, behavior and prostate gland in fetuses, infants, and young children.
The government agency is encouraging families to limit their children’s exposure...
The American Chemistry Council says BPA is safe.
I’m calling Rob Krebbs from the American Chemistry Council.
Rob Krebbs-
Hey Rob Krebbs, it’s Jeb Berrier, from the Bag It movie.
From Bag It movie?
I e-mailed you a few weeks ago. We’re doing a documentary.
Uh, okay, I’m sorry.
Jeff, I’m literally on the phone with someone else right this second.
Can you shoot me an e-mail, again? Just to remind me?
Okay, no problem, I’ll e-mail you again. Thanks.
Honey?
Yes dear?
I’m doing the dishes.
Thank you.
Because you are so... pregnant!
There are certain plastic containers that we stopped getting.
We kind of cut back on can usage altogether.
We stopped reheating anything in plastic.
The other chemical we’re concerned about,
phthalates, is actually a family of chemicals.
Phthalates are commonly found in polyvinyl chloride plastic,
otherwise known as PVC.
Phthalates are “plasticizers” that are used to soften plastic.
They’re used in a wide variety of products --
anything from vinyl flooring and all other things vinyl
to personal care products to... children’s toys.
You take a rubber ducky.
In order to make that brittle material seem like rubber,
you actually have to have more phthalate in it than you do polyvinyl-chloride.
When a baby puts that in its mouth, it’s like a phthalate lollypop.
Phthalates have been linked to:
renitis, eczema, asthma, allergies,
premature birth, obesity, premature breast development,
thyroid dysfunction, insulin resistance, lower sperm counts,
decreased sperm motility, shorter ano-genital distance,
undescended testicles and smaller penis size.
It’s not just our Johnsons that are suffering,
it’s our swimmers as well.
Over the past several decades scientists have found
the sperm counts have been dropping dramatically.
Paul McCartney knew about this far earlier.
You know “Yesterday.” The second part.
“Suddenly, I’m not half the man I used to be.”
We’re loosing dramatically fertility.
So taking us compared to our fathers, we’re only half the men.
What we found with the human study is that
the moms that had greater exposure to phthalates
were more likely to have sons with feminized reproductive organs
was that those were at everyday levels of phthalates,
those were not unusual exposure levels,
those were at levels that people are being exposed to in the U.S. today.
You’re constantly being washed in phthalates every day.
That chemical is not required to be on the label for any personal care product.
So if you see “fragrance” on the label,
that is often phthalates.
Basically it’s an industry loophole that prevents the consumer
from finding out what ingredients are in the product.
Fragrance can be a collection of hundreds of chemicals,
or it might be just a handful, we really don’t know.
One question that you may have is “Are phthalates safe?”
The answer is “Yes.”
My name is Steve Risotto of the American Chemistry Council,
and we represent the companies that manufacture
a family of versatile chemicals called “phthalates.”
The University of Washington tested dozens of babies’ urine
and found that the more of these baby products they used,
creams, lotions, powders, shampoos,
the higher their levels of man-made chemicals called phthalates.
Phthalates are used in baby products to help the fragrance stay on the babies’ skin.
Babies are not little adults.
Nothing you learn about a chemical in an adult
can be applied to tell you what that chemical will do in a baby.
This was pretty shocking news for Anne and me.
I mean wouldn’t anyone want to err on the side of caution?
Um, I had a question about one of your products. It’s a baby lotion.
It’s called Grins and Giggles.
I wonder if it has any phthalates in it.
I’m on hold.
The music’s really nice though.
Peter Coyote is a well-known actor.
What most people don't know is that he's also
a committed activist and has been for many years.
He is one of few people in this country
to have his body burden tested.
That's a test that identifies and quantifies
hundreds of chemicals present in your body.
When the results came, I was really shocked,
and then I was angry because I had in my body,
stuff that should not be in a human being.
And when I was reviewing it I thought -- quite literally --
who gave these sons of bitches permission to poison the commons?
I decided to do my own Body Burden experiment
I wanted to see how much my levels of BPA and phthalates
would go up simply by using normal, everyday, supposedly safe consumer products.
I did a pretest to find out what my normal levels were.
And then I spent two days in a friend’s apartment eating canned food,
microwaving in plastic, using shampoo, lotion, deodorant, air fresheners.
These are all products that will supposedly be safe for my baby.
You know this place just needed a little... something.
Air Fresh. Freshen it up....
I’m about to shampoo with kids’ shampoo.
This is all stuff that people use pretty much every day.
This is my last supper. I don’t get to eat like this very often. I don’t feel good.
At the end, I got tested again.
By the way, whatever the levels are, they’re reversible.
So, it’s never too late to stop ingesting, absorbing and inhaling these chemicals.
And now we’re just waiting for the results.
Hi Catherine, it’s Jeb Berrier.
Calling you back from the movie Bag It, the documentary about plastic.
And I’m really hoping to get an interview with you,
about, specifically about BPA and phthalates.
We are keeping chemicals afloat in our environment
in the face of overwhelming scientific evidence from other countries.
Because the information is being systematically withheld from us.
Who are the people that allow this? They’re supposed to be our leaders.
They’re supposed to be mediating between the needs of the citizens and the needs of the corporations.
Not giving the corporations everything they ask for and asking the citizens to pay the bills.
If you don’t want a deadly poison in the biosphere, you don’t make it. Period. End of story.
Okay. I finally got my results.It’s 144 pages of numbers.
So, I am at the house of Dr. Theo Colborn. World renowned environmental health analyst,
and she is going to help me decipher what my test results mean.
Your results were very interesting. Why don’t we start with bisphenol A?
Okay. So, my BPA levels went up 110 times.
Yeah, that is high, I’ll be quite frank with you. You really spiked.
Now these are the phthalates. This one went up 53 times.
Okay now, here we are. This one went up from 2.7 to 143.
So if you sum this overall and then take the difference,
you had about 11 times increase of phthalates.
If Anne who’s pregnant had those levels, what would that mean? For the baby?
It could mean that that baby would be partially feminized. In other words, reduced  ano-genital distance.
You know. Maybe a smaller penis.
Wow.
Yeah. I always feel uncomfortable talking to people
who are expecting children or planning to have children.
Because this is the critical period,
from fertilization to birth.
As a citizen, don’t you feel
that we have enough evidence now to say we should not be using these products.
Absolutely. I don’t want any of these in my body.
I don’t want any of these in the mother of my child’s body.
I don’t want them in my child’s body.
No. They’re going to be.
It’s not about being against chemistry or against plastic;
it’s about being against stupid plastic. Silly, stinking, toxic stuff.
When you reach the point where it becomes a public health issue --
and this is a major public health issue at the population level --
the government has to step in.
But I will frankly say, government is no longer government -- it’s corporate control.
What we’re asking for is for a law that will make sure
that chemicals are tested before they go into products.
We want to be able to go into a store and buy any product.
The products on the shelf should be safe for us.
We have lost a whole generation of children already
because we haven’t even begun to take action on one of these chemicals.
Though you may feel that going up against corporations is impossible,
and that government moves way too slowly,
what we cannot forget is that we are the government, that we influence industry.
Thanks to the outcries of concerned parents,
a law was passed in 2009 banning six phthalates from children’s toys.
And due to consumer demands, Wal-Mart and Toys R Us
decided to remove all baby products containing BPA from their shelves.
This led six different baby bottle manufacturers to completely remove BPA from their baby bottles.
I’m trying to find out whether people in town would support a fee on paper or plastic shopping bags.
Yeah to try to reduce the amount people use disposable shopping bags.
Go big or go home.
Would you guys support some kind of measure in town....
Remember that part about how we were expecting a baby? Well, it’s happening.
Well, I did start out making a movie about plastic bags,
but like any journey, things developed and changed along the way,
it became about so much more.
I still think plastic is an incredible substance.
But it’s not supposed to end up in our oceans or in our bodies.
And just to make sure I really, really got all this, Anne got pregnant;
and it became about the fate of our child and all our children.
I’m still an average guy... but even average people can make changes.
You know, everybody keeps asking me: So what can I do? Well.
Here are some things we’ve come up with while making this film.
Things you can do, too. Starting today, right now.
You can cut way WAY back on single-use disposables.
Don’t drink bottled water.
Choose products with less packaging
When you need something, buy it used.
Think outside the bag -- bring your own container.
Buy less stuff.
Remember, recycling comes after reducing and reusing.
And how about volunteering in your community to do litter clean ups?
But most important, you can simplify... your... life.
I keep coming back to how my grandparents lived.
They didn’t have all this plastic in their lives, but that didn’t seem to make them any less happy.
When it comes down to changing your life and living with less plastic,
And look at that: foam cups.
Stay back.
We just have to rethink how we do things. It all comes down to common sense.
Well there you have it. The end of one odyssey, the beginning of another.
We’ve decided to live life with a little less plastic.
How about you? Is your life a little too plastic?
Cause if it is, there’s only one thing you can do about it...
Bag it.
Alright. I think I got it that time.
Buy bulk food, don’t buy small packaged things
and suddenly your trash is really minimized.
Hey look everybody! It’s a single-use disposable camera.
Use it once, and throw it away!
I’d put no plastic into a microwave or an oven.
When you don’t use a lot of plastic... you eat better.
That’s my girl.
You really should think, when making decisions,
of how this is not only going to impact yourself and your children,
but your children’s children’s children. Out seven generations.
Look at that. No plastic bag in the bathroom garbage can. You don’t need it.
Plastic’s a useful thing, but single use plastics are just instant garbage and... we don’t need it.
Maybe you’re forced to eat a plastic bag if you use one, to know how the fish feel.
That’s a good idea.
I’m still waiting to hear back from the American Chemistry Council.
I’m starting to think that maybe they don’t want to talk to me.
Babies don’t come in plastic.