Hello members of the press.
Thank you for joining me for this
satellite conference today
to discuss the new "Decorum Act"
As you know, domestically we
are dealing with a war
far more destructive and insidious
than our ongoing wars in
Australia, Africa and Canada.
It is the war on
our population explosion.
The new laws of our
great President Han,
may seem harsh ...
but they have been made with the
good of our country in mind.
This great nation of ours
has been built on the
extermination of its people.
What??
Uh,
the DEtermination ...
the determination of its people.
Oh, God.
Okay ... okay.
Don't panic ...just, don't panic
Forget it!
Uh!
- Senator?
Surveillance went down,
I got worried.
I turned it off.
Is it true, the death penalty?
- Yes.
Well, as least you're not ...
Senator, ...
Are you okay?
Huh, uh.
Bar Karma  1x06
"The Expectant Mother"
Subtitles by josmndsn
# o-o-o, yeah,
# aaaaah,oooooooo,
# Yo-o-u-u will always
# reap what
# you sow.
What's going on?
Would you like a
glass of water?
Oh, my!
Zack?
Go in there and
tell me what you see.
Sure.
What am I supposed to be...
looking for?
Is that a bathroom?
Yes, of course.
You're not in a bar with
three people in it?
Okay, ...
so, you're halucinating.
I'm going to call med services.
- No, don't do that.
It's probably just that virus,
the same one that my wife
and son had.
I'm going to get you some aspirin
and some chicken soup.  - Okay.
I'll be right back.
Hello, again.
Feeling better?
What's your name?
Senator Knowles.
Sarah.
Do you know why you're
here, Sarah?
Well, that's a first.
I'm here because I have
a high fever.
So, you think we're a ...
halucination?
Where's that music
coming from?
The jukebox.
- Aah!
Jukebox! Oh!
I've seen these in pictures.
Oh, , ah, oh.
He can't have me arrested
for listening
to music, in my own
halucination, can he?
Who?
- Him.
Who is that?
President Han, of course.
Your President has people arrested
for listening to music?
He'd have you arrested for
wearing that dress.
By the Fashion Police?
- It's a bad influence.
It makes people think about sex,
which equals offspring,
which equals overpopulation,
which equals starvation.
What year is it?
- 2058.
Oh, ...
oh, I get why I'm having
this halucination.
Why?
Ny mind wants me to remember
what the world was like
before it got so dark
and sad and ugly.
So, we're figments of
your imagination,
representing a
happier time?
Yeah.
You remind me of
my grandfather,
when I was
a little girl.
And, you, are like
one of those sexy,
charming, punks I used to
fall in love with
when I was young.
You think I'm a punk?
Better than being
her  grandfather.
So, who am I in
your halucination?
I think ... you're me
when I was young
and happy
and I could hang out in bars
and have sex and ...
and read whatever I wanted to
and laugh.
And, you can't do those
things now?
You can't make a move without
being watched.
But, I'm ever hardly allowed
to see anyone.
Why are you so isolated?
... Because everybody
wants to kill me.
They think, because I'm
a Senator, I have a say
in the laws of
my country.
They don't realize that
I'm as powerless as they are.
In America?  How?
Apathy. Complacency.
Fear.
This is fun, ha.
I feel so free here.
(Sarah chuckles)
I think am just going to
dance naked on the bar.
Yeah, go for it.
No, no, no, no, no.
Wait ...
is that a television?
I remember these.
Let's watch a television program.
Let's watch a Sci-Fi
classic, Fringe.
Let's try this one over here.
How could they know yet?
Know what?
That I'm the only one who knows.
Sarah, wake up.
You fainted.
So, this wasn't a halucination,
was it?
No.
Are you going to arrest me?
No, we're here to help you.
Who's the man in the newscast?
Who is Zack Sizer?
He's my Chief of Staff.
So, its true then,
he's dead?
He's not dead, yet.
That was a projection of the future.
That's what could happen,
if you don't
dramatically change
some path you're
about to go down.
Sarah, what's the
"Decorum Act"?
What do you have
to do with it?
We're not judging you
or threatening you.
You're here because your life has
been thrown off balance, somehow.
We're here to help you ...
- I have to go find him.
Well, that went well.
Oh!  My God!
Oh, my God.
Are you still alive?
Oh, what am I doing.
- No, wait, it's all right.
Surveillance is still down.
Here's some aspirin
and soup tabs.
Aaw.
Hey, where's your wig?
Uh, ...
Are you okay?
I have to talk to you.
Is it about this?
Yes.
You should have let me
follow her out.
Patience, Doug.
There's a time and
place for everything.
But these gadgets are
all your thing.
And, someday they'll be yours.
You gotta learn
how to interpret them.
And, it takes focus.
What's it telling you?
President Han's Health
and Safety law
requires mandatory sterilization
for married couples after their
first child.
And, ...
makes it illegal for unmarried
women to parachute on Sundays?
You went south and
back in time.
That's Florida.  Wrong state.
Wrong century.
That makes no sense.
I know.  Parachuting is
just as dangerous
any other day of the week.
No-o, if Han is so
worried about a population
explosion,
Why doesn't he just lift
his ban on
birth control and abortion?
- Because then he'd have to
admit he made a mistake.
How many dictators do you know
who would do that?
So, what does he do instead?
Pass the Decorum Act.
What is the Decorum Act?
It says, any man who
refuses sterilization
and has more than one child,
in or out of wedlock,
is branded a traitor to his country
and given the death sentence.
Decorum Act, sounds more
like Hold on
to Your Balls
for Dear Life Act.
It's my pregnancy test.
And, it's red because ...
I'm pregnant.
Zack is already married
and has a son.
Shouldn't he have been
sterilized, then?
A lot of people were refusing
to do it, that's why
President Han created the
Decorum Act
to motivate them.
I'd say, execution by
one of those scary
futuristic laser things would
motivate men sufficiently.
I knew Zack hadn't been
sterilized.
I knew he's married ...
I knew he had a little boy.
And, now their going to kill
him and take my baby away from me.
That's where we come in,
to help you through this.
I already know my options,
they're all bad.
Wanna bet?
What? We're going to
play a card game?
It's no game.
What does that mean?
Possible outcome for you.
If another man marries you
and claims that
the child is his,
that could get you out of this.
I don't even have contact
with anyone else, except Zack.
It's just a possibility.
The Decorum Act will safeguard
our resources,
which are currently
threatened by our
surplus population.
This card requires that
you break the law.
But, the option shows you
back at work as if
nothing ever happened.
Abortion.
Do I ever get pregnant again?
What is that image mean?
Not sure.
But you're alone.
Whew, I don't want
to be alone.
There is one more card.
That can't be me?
- It's you.
This place exists, Sarah.
And, it appears
you'll find it.
How?  I can't just
get in a car
and hop on a
plane somewhere.
I am tracked.
Wherever I go.
They can't have cameras
everywhere?
Forget cameras, I have a
security chip inside my body.
There is no escaping
from that.
(sobbing) I hate my life.
I hate my life.
Then, change it.
Haven't you been listening?
How can I change if my
hands are tied?  I can't
do anything!
The cards say otherwise.
The question is, Sarah,
what is it you really want?
I want to marry Zack.
I want to have my baby.
I want my country to be a
beautiful place to live again.
Can you wave your magic wand
and make all that happen?
Do you see this?
Beautiful.
It was my grandmother's.
And, she was a woman
who never compromised.
Not in love, marriage
or anything.
I wish I were more
like your grandmother.
You can be.
You can lead the life
you want,
if you have the courage
to fight for it.
I'm so tired
of compromising.
I have been compromising
all my life and
look where it's gotten me.
I don't want to
do it anymore.
And, we can help you.
So, you'll follow me out and
then what?
I'll figure it out when I get there.
How do I know you'll
even show up?
We're asking you
to trust us.
All right.
Thank you ...
for giving me hope.
You're up.
Finally.  Thought
I'd never make it out.
UH!
What the hell just happened?
Security.
President Han runs
a tight ship.
How are we going to
get around it?
Remember that chip Sarah
had implanted
inside her body,
Yeah.
We need to get
one of those.
Hi.
I'm Dayna.
Wow.
I only see women like you
in my dreams.
Let me buy you a drink.
Waiter.
God, I have such a weakness
for men in uniform.
Cheers.
I need to get a body
scan of you.
Take your clothes off.
Ouh!
You're being very
brave Irving.
Thanks.
Huh.
So, there.  What war
were you fighting?
Australia.
What did we ever
do to you?
It's nothing personal,
just following orders.
Huh.
If it was up to me,
I'd be home with my family.
Well, that's a decision you
can now make for yourself.
So, am I going to
see you again?
That depends on what
you decide.
You're next.
You know it's
the only way.
I understand.
Surveillance is still on.
They're waiting.
(Sarah, off screen) Members of the
press and dignitaries ...
Who are you?
- Thank you for joining me for
this satellite conference today.
As you know ...
I'm Lieutenant Irving
Grossman.
I'm here to ...
I'm Sarah's husband.
Could I borrow
that for a minute.
Take good care of her.
... our great leader President Han,
the Decorum Act.
Hold that thought ... Senator.
Allow me to
introduce myself,
I am twice decorated
Lieutenant Irving Grossman.
And, I think the Senator
is being a little shy.
I believe the people of
this great nation,
under our leader President Ho ...
- Han.
President Han would like
to hear the happy news.
Sweetie.
Senator Knowles and I
secretly married got married
last week.
See.
Now, unfortunately,
we have to run
because I'm stationed in ...
a top secret location.
So, even though, right now,
she's too choked up
to talk, she would like
to say goodbye
and good luck to
you all.
Actually, I would like
to say something.
Go right ahead.
I would like to choose Zack Sizer,
my Chief of Staff
to replace me.
Because he is a great patriot.
And, also because it is
my right to do so
under the Wasilla Act of 2016,
which says that government
representatives who leave
office early are allowed to choose
their own successors.
We have to leave, goodbye.
Military escort is outside.
Thanks, Senator.
Good luck.
I love you.
How did it go?
Good.
Good news and bad news.
I'll take the good first.
Aah, our plan went
off without a hitch.
Sarah's going to be just fine.
Well, let's not make
any assumptions.
We all deserve the right
to choose how
we're going to
live our lives.
It is time to rise up
against the
monster who has oppressed
our great nation,
for 21 long years.
Who has tried to make
us forget the beauty of music
and love ...
and family
and self expression.
It is time to rise up
against
President Han.
Pregnant and leading
a revolution.
And, they say, woman
can't have it all.
So, what was the bad news?
Oh, you didn't get a chance
to see me in my uniform.
Looked pretty good.
Huh.
Try this one
on for size.
Subtitles by josmndsn