Himalaya mountain range
Tibet, NEPAL
Tibetan monastery
Mount Everest, North Face
Tibet, NEPAL
Hot springs
Nagano, JAPAN
Durbar Square
Kathmandu, NEPAL
Pasupati temple
Swayambhu Temple
Kathmandu, NEPAL
Bhaktapur: Hanuman Ghat
Pasupati Temple
Kathmandu, NEPAL
Swayambhu Temple
Sadhu (Shiva devotee) praying
Kathmandu, NEPAL
Wailing Wall
Jerusalem, ISRAEL
The Whirling Dervishes, Galata Mevlevi Temple
Instambul, TURKEY
Muhammad Shrine
Mecca, SAUDI ARABIA
Emam Mosque
Isfahan, IRAN
Church of the Holy Sepulchre
Jerusalem, ISRAEL
Reims Cathedral
Reims, FRANCE
Church of the Holy Sepulchre
Jerusalem, ISRAEL
Light offerings, Jokang Temple
Lhasa, TIBET
Swayambhu Temple
Kathmandu, NEPAL
Oil fire
KUWAIT
Ryoan-Ji Temple, Zen Karesansui rock garden
Kyoto, JAPAN
Tokyo, JAPAN
HONG-KONG
Big Sur
California, USA
Uluwatu Temple
Bali, INDONESIA
Rice fields
Preah Khan Temple
Angkor, CAMBODIA
Angkor Wat
Prambanan Temple
Java, INDONESIA
Borodour Temple
Prambanan Temple
Java, INDONESIA
Gunung Kawi, Tampak Siring Temple
Bali, INDONESIA
Kecak (Balinese Monkey Chant)
Mount Bromo
Java, INDONESIA
Puuoo National Park
HAWAII
Haleakala National Park
Maui, HAWAII
Arches National Park
Utah, USA
Canyonlands National Park
Mesa Verde National Park
Colorado, USA
Arches National Park
Utah, USA
Galapagos Islands
ECUADOR
Ayers Rock, Uluru National Park
AUSTRALIA
Cave drawings, Kakadu National Park
Darwin, AUSTRALIA
Al Aukre, Kayapo Village
BRAZIL
Masaai Mara, Masaai tribe
KENIA
Kayapo tribe
BRAZIL
Pukamani ceremony (Funeral Dance), Tiwi Tribe
Bathurst Island, AUSTRALIA
Flamingoes
Lake Magadi, KENYA
Iguazu Falls
ARGENTINA
Lake Natron
TANZANIA
Serengeti
KENYA
Thompson Gazelles, Masaai Mara
Rainforest
BRAZIL
Kayapo Leader
Serra Pelada gold mine
BRAZIL
Al Aukre
Kayapo tribe
BRAZIL
Favela da Rocinha
Rio de Janeiro, BRAZIL
Walled City, demolished in 1992
Kowloon, HONG-KONG
Ciudad Blanca, Cemeterio General
(The White City, Cemetery)
Guyaquil, ECUADOR
INDONESIA
Gudang Garam Cigarette Factory
Kediri, Java, INDONESIA
JR Shinjuku Station
Tokyo, JAPAN
Green Plaza Capsule Hotel
Japanese Buddist monk
Tokyo, JAPAN
Belo Horizonte
Sao Paolo, BRAZIL
Park Avenue
New-York, USA
Great Mosque
Mecca, SAUDI ARABIA
Shibuya Station
Tokyo, JAPAN
Grand Central Terminal
New-York, USA
JR Shinjuku Rail Station
Tokyo, JAPAN
JVC Yokosuka Factory
NMB Keyboard Factory
Bang Pa-In, Ayutthaya province, THAILAND
Gudang Garam Cigarette Factory
Kediri, Java, INDONESIA
World Trade Center, North Tower
New-York, USA
Chicken farm
Park Avenue
New-York, USA
Silent scream, Buto dancer
Tokyo, JAPAN
YEMEN
City landfill
Calcutta, INDIA
São João Avenue
São Paolo, BRAZIL
INDIA
CAMBODIA
BRAZIL
Bangkok, THAILAND
Buto dance
Tokyo, JAPAN
B-52 bombers, Aerospace Maintenance and Regeneration Center
Tucson, Arizona, USA
Wailing Wall
Jerusalem, ISRAEL
Oil fire
KUWAIT
Highway 80
Bytom foundry
Bytom, POLAND
Konzentrationslager
Auschwitz, POLAND
Tuol Sleng Museum
Phnom Pen, CAMBODIA
CAMBODIA
Great Hall of The People, Tianenman Square
Beijing, CHINA
People's Heros Monument, Tienanmen Square
Terracotta Army, Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor
Shaanxi province, CHINA
Persepolis, IRAN
Pyramids at Giza
Cairo, EGYPT
Temple Of Ramses II
Luxor, EGYPT
Angkor Wat
Angkor, CAMBODIA
Angkor Ta Proum courtyard
Ganges River
INDIA
Ghats
Varanasi, INDIA
Dasaswameth Ghat
Uttar Pradesh
Varanasi, INDIA
Benaras Ghat
Ganges River
INDIA
Ryoan-Ji Temple
Kyoto, JAPAN
Masaai Mara
KENYA
The Whirling Dervishes, Galata Mevlevi Temple
Instambul, TURKEY
Wailing Wall
Jerusalem, ISRAEL
Church of the Holy Sepulchre
Isfahan, IRAN
The Ka'aba
Mecca, SAUDI ARABIA
Grand Mosque
Hagia Sophia
Instambul, TURKEY
St. Peter's Basilica
VATICAN, ITALY
Mausoleum of Shah-e-Cherach
Shiraz, IRAN
Church of the Holy Sepulchre
Jerusalem, ISRAEL
Funeral Lights on the Ganges
Varanasi, INDIA
Ryoan-Ji Temple
Kyoto, JAPAN
Angkor Wat
Angkor, CAMBODIA
Temple Of Ramses II
Luxor, EGYPT
The Turret Arch, Arches National Park
Utah, USA