Subtitle Credits - P.NARASIMHA
Thank you. Hi.
I'd like to go to the Adelphi Hotel.
This is my cab.
I was here first!
Oh, God.
Let's go across. Come on.
We'll get one down the road. Hurry.
For God's sake, Harold,
can we please get a taxi?
I'm trying to get a... Taxi!
We're going the wrong way!
Put that away. We look like tourists.
Let's cut over to Seventh.
- Seventh is that way.
- I know where we are!
Hey, give me a dollar.
How about it? One dollar.
Are you deaf? You don't speak English?
Come on! Up here.
Hey, lady...
...do the kid a favor. Don't scream.
Hey, all right!
American Express card.
"Don't leave home without it."
Get out of here.
I don't like it up here.
Are you scared of heights?
I don't know.
After what happened to Johnny Gobs...
Look, Johnny Gobs got ripped and
took a walk off a roof. No big loss.
That ain't what I heard at all.
I heard that the Bat got him.
The Bat? Give me a break, will you?
Five stories. Straight down.
There wasn't no blood in the body.
No shit. It was all over the pavement.
- I'm getting out of here.
- Shut up. Listen to me.
There ain't no Bat.
You shouldn't have turned the gun on that kid.
You want your cut of this money or not?
Now shut up! Shut up!
Don't kill me!
Don't kill me! Don't kill me!
I won't kill you.
I want you to do me a favor.
Tell all your friends about me.
What are you?
I'm Batman.
Across this nation...
...the words "Gotham City"
are synonymous with crime.
Our streets are overrun,
our public officials are helpless.
As mayor, I promise to root out
the source of this corruption...
...Boss Carl Grissom.
Now, our new District Attorney, Harvey Dent...
...will carry out that promise.
Thank you, Mayor Borg. Thank you.
People of Gotham City...
...I'm a man of few words.
But those words will count,
and so will my actions.
Commissioner Gordon informs me
that he has targeted those businesses...
... suspected of fronting for
the syndicate in this city.
Before this week is out...
... we are going to knock down their doors...
... and shed the light of the law
on that nest of vipers.
Together, we can make this
city safe for decent people.
Decent people shouldn't live here.
They'd be happier someplace else.
Pretty tough talk about Carl.
Forget about it.
If this clown could touch Grissom,
I'd have handed him his lungs by now.
If Grissom knew about us...
...he might hand you something.
Don't flatter yourself, angel.
He's a tired old man.
He can't run this city without me.
And besides...
...he doesn't know.
You don't worry about anything, do you, Jack?
You look fine.
I didn't ask.
Yeah. Hanging on.
Let me guess.
Giant, menacing, supernatural form.
Kind of like a bat.
That's it. What are they seeing up there?
They're drinking Drano.
It's weird.
Thanks for the tip.
Christ. Knox.
Lieutenant, I hear we had another Bat attack.
That's eight sightings in a month.
I hear the Commissioner's opened a file.
Sorry, Knox.
These two slipped on a banana peel.
I'm telling you, a giant bat!
Don't write about this.
It will ruin your already useless reputation.
Lieutenant, every punk in this town is scared.
They say he can't be killed.
They say he drinks blood.
I say you're full of shit, Knox.
You can quote me on that.
Is there a six-foot bat in Gotham City?
Is he on the police payroll?
What's he pulling down, after taxes?
Brought you a little snack, Eckhardt.
- Why don't you broadcast it?
- Shut up and listen.
Harvey Dent has been sniffing
around one of our front companies.
That's my territory.
If there's a problem, I deal with it.
Your problems are our problems.
I answer to Grissom, not to psychos.
You ought to think about the future.
You mean when you run the show?
You got no future.
You're an A-1 nut-boy,
and Grissom knows it.
Better be sure.
See?
You can make a good decision when you try.
Where've you been spending your nights?
I don't care if this festival is in debt,
I want a parade.
I want hot dogs, balloons, everything.
We'll celebrate this 200th
anniversary proudly and publicly.
We may celebrate in bankruptcy court.
It's $250,000 in debt and we
haven't seen one balloon.
You fill the square with people,
and businesses will come back.
A lot of people may stay away.
They're scared.
They won't be scared when you
get Grissom in the courthouse.
I promised that, remember?
Welcome, Count Dracula.
Had any sightings of Big Foot lately?
- They buried your story on Batman.
- They bury garbage.
This is Pulitzer Prize stuff.
I got something for you.
Very funny. You should have
put more gore under the fangs.
What a dick.
Hello, legs.
I'm reading your stuff.
Well, I'm reading yours.
Hi, I'm Vicki Vale.
Yeah, photographer. Vogue, Cosmo. Yeah.
If you want me to pose nude,
you'll need a long lens.
Actually, I was in the Corto Maltese.
You could get hurt doing this stuff.
What brings you here?
I'm here to see the wildlife in Gotham City.
Wildlife? Like what?
Like... bats.
- Who sent you?
- Nobody, really.
I just loved your story, and...
...I like bats.
My pictures, your words.
Pulitzer Prize material. Just think.
Okay, you're a visionary,
and also the only one who believes me.
I need something tangible.
Gordon's got a file.
I can't even get him on the phone.
He'll be at Bruce Wayne's benefit, right?
Yeah. I don't seem to be on the guest list.
No.
Yes, yes. Vale, will you marry me?
- No.
- Buy me lunch?
- Maybe.
- I eat light.
Say this...
...son of a bitch...
...makes a connection with
us and with Axis Chemicals.
What kind of damage are we looking at?
If he ties us with Axis Chemicals,
we're dead and buried.
We should move immediately.
I say we break into the place...
...trash the office...
...and make off with the records
and say it was industrial espionage.
Smart thinking. That's the way to go.
In fact...
...I'd like you to handle
this operation personally.
Me?
Would you mind waiting in the next room?
That's all, gentlemen. Thank you.
That's all.
Can somebody else do this?
The fumes in that place...
It's an important job. I need...
...someone I can trust.
You... are my number one guy.
Now...
...don't forget...
...your lucky deck.
My friend...
...your luck is about to change.
Police Department.
Get me Lieutenant Eckhardt.
Can I help you, sir?
- Good evening.
- A little crowded.
Could you tell me who is Bruce Wayne?
I'm not sure.
Thanks anyway.
Eight. I can make that eight.
I can make that eight.
Commissioner!
Mrs. Gordon, you look lovely.
Is it true the Commissioner
has a file on the Batman?
There is no Bat. If there were,
we would find and arrest him.
Be straight with me, Commissioner.
How're you making out?
Mr. Dent, I love that tie.
We were discussing winged vigilantes.
What's your stand?
We have enough problems in this city...
...without worrying about ghosts.
Pardon me, but that's not a denial.
Excuse me, I'll be back.
Won't anybody go on record?
- Your Honor, great suit.
- No comment.
What's up?
Anonymous tip.
Napier's cleaning out Axis Chemicals.
Why wasn't I told? Who's in charge?
- Eckhardt.
- Oh, my God!
Come on, let's go.
Mr. Gordon?
Wait, wait. Living room,
dining room, arsenal.
Look at this stuff.
Who is this guy?
He gives to humanitarian causes,
and then collects all this stuff.
He probably does it to get chicks.
They like his charity balls.
Don't leave out his very large bankroll.
The more they've got, the less they're worth.
This guy must be the most
worthless guy in America.
Check this out. He must have been
the King of the Wicker People.
Where'd this come from?
I have no idea.
It's Japanese.
How do you know?
I bought it in Japan.
- Who are you?
- Sorry. Bruce Wayne.
Alexander Knox.
I read your work. I like it a lot.
Thanks. Can I have a grant?
Vicki Vale.
Bruce Wayne.
Are you sure?
Yeah. I've seen your pictures
from Corto Maltese, haven't I?
You've got a wonderful eye.
Some people think she has two.
This is an amazing house.
I'd like to shoot it sometime.
We need more champagne.
Is that all right?
Sure. Go ahead.
How many cases? Six? Six?
Six is good.
Will you be in Gotham for a while?
I'd love to. I'm intrigued by
Alex's "giant bat" stories.
Oh, right. The bat... Batman.
A bit light after the war in Corto Maltese, no?
What do you do for a living?
Commissioner Gordon was compelled to leave.
Very unexpectedly, sir.
Will you two excuse me?
I think perhaps this way, sir.
They need wine in the front room, and
a Mrs. Daley needs a copy of the menu.
And give Knox a grant.
Nice talking with you, Wayne.
The rich...
Know why they're so odd?
They can afford to be.
Look at this mirror.
Maybe it should be Bruce Vain.
- What's up?
- Anonymous tip.
Napier's cleaning out Axis Chemicals.
If we could get him, we'd have Grissom.
Why wasn't I told? Who's in charge?
- Eckhardt.
- Oh, my God!
Come on, let's go.
Get a good look.
Shoot to kill. You know what I mean?
Let's move out.
We've been ratted out, boys.
Watch it.
Freeze!
You take the right. Move it.
What the hell's going on?
- What are you trying to do?
- I'm in charge, not Carl Grissom.
This is Commissioner Gordon.
I want him taken alive.
I repeat. Any man who opens fire
on Jack Napier will answer to me.
Let me down!
Oh, my God!
Get up on the catwalk, on that side.
You take that side. Be very careful.
Jesus!
Let him go... or I'll do Gordon.
Nice outfit.
Come on, Jack, let's go!
Come on!
Eckhardt!
Think about the future.
Goddamn it, we had him!
Hold it right there!
- Who is this guy?
- I don't know.
Until we find out, keep a lid on it.
If there's no Bat,
then who dropped Napier into the acid?
Suicide? I want to get this on tape.
He hung up. What have you got?
Here's the inner city.
Here's the sightings so far.
Maybe Batman has some sort of flight pattern.
This is very good. Tonight we'll go
to dinner, then we'll walk the trail.
No can do. I got a date. Bruce Wayne.
Wayne! Wayne! Oh, no!
The guy's a stiff.
You could do much better.
Thanks for being so concerned.
How's the soup?
Excuse me?
The soup. How is it?
It's great.
Could you pass the salt?
Did you have trouble finding the house?
- It was no problem.
- Good.
Do you like eating in here?
I don't think I've been in this room before.
You want to leave?
Yes.
There was young Master Bruce...
...leading his gray pony
with me on its back...
...like a sack of old potatoes, covered
in mud and nursing a sprained ankle.
That was the first and last time
I gave him a riding lesson.
I think I've embarrassed him for long enough.
I'm off to bed.
Please, leave everything.
I'll tidy up in the morning.
He's really wonderful. He loves you a lot.
Alfred's great.
I couldn't find my socks without him.
He reminds me of my grandfather.
Were you close to him?
I used to spend summers with
him and my grandmother.
They had a house on the lake.
Nothing like this, but...
...it was fun.
That sounds nice.
What about your family?
Actually, Alfred is my family.
This house and all this stuff
doesn't seem like you at all.
Some of it is very much me.
Some isn't.
That dining room is definitely not you.
The dining room isn't.
Let's see how we did.
Oh, my God!
Mirror.
Mirror!
You understand that the nerves
were completely severed.
You see what I have to work with here.
There are an awful lot of stairs in this place.
My feet are killing me.
I feel a little drunk.
And you're not anything.
One drink and I'm flying.
Why are you afraid of flying?
That you, sugar bumps?
Who are you?
It's me.
"Sugar bumps."
You're alive! I heard you'd been...
Fried?
Is that what you heard?
You set me up over a woman.
A woman!
You must be insane.
Don't bother.
Your life won't be worth spit!
I've been dead once already.
It's very liberating...
...if you think of it as... therapy.
Jack, listen.
Maybe we can cut a deal.
Jack?
Jack is dead, my friend.
You can call me...
...Joker.
As you can see...
...I'm a lot happier.
Oh, what a day.
Gotham City.
It always brings a smile to my face.
"Winged Freak...
"...Terrorizes..."
Wait'll they get a load of me.
I've got an idea. How about lunch at
my place? I'll show you some photos.
Sure. Okay.
Wait a minute. No, I can't. I can't make it.
Okay, we'll do it later in the day.
I can't make it then, either.
I've got a very important meeting today.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I have to leave town for a few days.
Okay, we'll do it when you get back.
I have to go. I'm late.
- Nice to see you again.
- Nice to see you, too.
I'll talk to you guys when you get back.
Back, Miss Vale?
We'll be here for quite a while.
You'll never believe what happened to me today.
So, gentlemen, that's how it is.
Until Grissom... resurfaces...
... I'm the acting president.
And I say, starting with
this anniversary festival...
... we run this city into the ground.
Why don't we hear this from Grissom?
Yeah.
And what's with that stupid grin?
Life's been good to me.
What if we say "no"?
Nobody wants a war.
If we can't do business,
we'll just shake hands and that'll be it.
Yeah?
I got a live one here.
There'll be a hot time in the old town tonight.
Antoine got a little hot under the collar.
You're crazy.
Haven't you ever heard of the
healing power of laughter?
- Now get out of here!
- Let's go! Move it!
You think it over.
Go to the Globe, follow that reporter Knox.
Take your camera.
See what he knows about this Batman.
And, Bob...
...remember... you...
...are my number one...
guy
Yes, sir.
Your pals...
...they're not bad people.
Maybe we...
...ought to give them a
few days to think it over.
No?
Grease them now?
Okay.
You are a vicious bastard, Rotelli.
I'm glad you're dead.
I need that.
I'm losing confidence in you.
I thought we were a team.
Is this a personal issue for you?
I just want you to do your job.
I am doing my job.
And I'm protecting my partner.
There's nothing in these files.
Who is this guy?
Who cares?
Forget Bruce Wayne. I'm onto Batman.
They'll be out any second.
I can't wait to hear the explanation.
What is this affidavit you filed?
Grissom gave you his business?
Mr. Grissom asked me,
as a personal favor...
...to take over all his
businesses until he returns.
That's a big favor.
You two must have been very close.
Did you do time together as children?
Our accountants are looking into it.
The affidavit is legitimate.
I smell fresh ink. You can prove this?
Of course you can.
We have witnesses.
Grissom's signature is legitimate.
It is legitimate.
I saw it. I was there.
I saw it all.
He reached up with his dead hand...
...and signed it in his own blood.
And he did it... with this pen.
Hello, Vinnie. It's your uncle Bingo.
Time to pay the check.
The pen...
...is truly mightier than the sword.
Get down!
Won't this gang war dampen
the city's 200th anniversary?
The festival opens.
The police will stop these gangsters.
What about the theory that
the Batman is a Mob enforcer?
I don't have any comment.
Batman.
Can somebody tell me what
kind of a world we live in...
...when a man dressed as a bat...
...gets all my press?
This town needs an enema!
May I have a glass of... water?
I'm relieved that you're home.
Miss Vale telephoned.
She was rather concerned.
I feel there's a certain weight
that lifts when she is here.
Alfred...
...why don't you marry her?
That's not exactly what I had in mind, sir.
I can't go on with that right now.
If not now...
...when?
I don't know.
Jack Napier's still alive.
He's running Grissom's men.
I need any information on him.
She is great, isn't she?
Yes.
Knox.
Check something out for me.
Find out what's special about
the alley at Pearl and Phillips.
Pearl and Phillips?
You got it.
Mister Wayne.
So much to do and so little time.
The photos.
Who's that loss?
Knox.
Bad tie. No style.
Stop the press!
- Who is that?
- Vicki Vale.
The photographer working with Knox.
That girl has style.
Jesus marimba!
A lovely beast like that running around...
...could put steam in a man's strides.
She's dating some guy named Wayne.
She's about to trade up.
It's hard to stay inside the lines.
I'm about...
...to get a new girl.
I'm of a mind to make some mooky.
Phone book.
So much to do...
...and so little time.
Have you shipped a million of those?
Ship them all! We're going to
take them out a whole new door!
Ten seconds to transmission.
Five... four... three... two... one.
Cue music.
Cue Becky.
Good evening.
The fashion world was stunned today...
...by the sudden deaths of models
Candy Walker and Amanda Keeler.
Cause of death has been attributed
to a violent allergic reaction...
... although authorities have not
ruled out the possibility of drug use.
Plans continue for the city's 200th birthday...
... as Mayor Borg announced today,
the unveiling...
This just in.
Three mysterious deaths at a beauty parlor...
... were discovered today.
What's going on?
This is hardly the...
Kill the camera.
This is Rene on the news floor.
I need paramedics up here now!
New and improved Joker products!
With a new secret ingredient.
Smylex!
What's that?
Let's go over...
... to our blind taste-test.
Love that Joker.
- Where's it coming from?
- I don't know.
He doesn't look happy.
He's been using brand X.
But with new Joker Brand...
... I get a grin again...
... and again.
That luscious tan...
... those ruby lips...
... and hair color so natural,
only your undertaker knows for sure.
You're saying:
"Where can I get these fine, new items?"
That's the gag. Chances are,
you've bought them already!
Love that Joker.
Remember...
... put on a happy face.
The information you requested.
"Jack Napier, assault with
a deadly weapon, age 15.
"Results of psychological profile...
"...violent mood swings, highly intelligent,
emotionally unstable.
"Aptitudes include science,
chemistry, and art."
Chemistry.
Let's go shopping.
...six new deaths, with no clues
as to the Joker's deadly weapon.
And what is the pattern?
Foods, alcohol, or beauty and hygiene products?
Cologne, mouthwash, underarm deodorant?
Or worse yet, there may be no pattern.
The search goes on through
Gotham's shopping nightmare.
We are having a festival, if I have to
use a gun to get people there myself.
Do you hear the words coming from
my mouth? The festival is on!
Find out what this madman is poisoning us with.
Do you read me?
We're working on it.
I need all the help I can get.
Hi, it's Vicki.
I'll be ten minutes late to the museum.
I'll see you when you get there.
A message from Miss Vale.
She'll be late meeting you at the museum.
Okay, thank you. Wait a minute, Alfred.
I'm not meeting her today.
Jack, where are you going?
Daddy's going to make some art, darling.
Mr. Wayne's table?
He hasn't arrived yet.
We have a table waiting.
Miss Vale, this just arrived for you.
Gentlemen!
Let's broaden our minds. Lawrence.
Give him a shave.
Terence, brush.
The one-dollar bill.
Hold it!
I kind of like this one. Leave it.
You can take that off now.
You're beautiful...
in an old-fashioned kind of way.
But I'm sure we can make you more...
today.
Your portfolio?
I'm meeting someone who wants to see my work.
Crap.
Crap. Crap.
Now that's good work.
The skulls, the bodies.
You give it such a glow.
I don't know if it's art, but I like it.
Let me tell you what I'm thinking about.
I was in the bath one day...
...when I realized why I
was destined for greatness.
You know how concerned people
are about appearances.
This is attractive, that is not.
That is all behind me.
I now do what other people only dream.
I make art... until someone dies.
See?
I am the world's first
fully-functioning homicidal artist.
What do you want?
My face on the one-dollar bill.
You're joking.
Do I look like I'm joking?
No.
Listen.
We mustn't compare ourselves to
regular people. We're artists.
For instance, let me challenge you
with a piece I did.
Bob. Alicia.
You will photograph and record my work.
You will join me in the
avant-garde of the new aesthetic.
Jack, you said I could watch
you improve the paintings.
I'm in trouble now.
Why is she wearing a mask?
She's just a sketch, really.
Alicia, sit down. Show the lady
why you wear this mask.
Alicia's been made over in
line with my new philosophy.
So now, like me...
...she is a living work of art.
I'm no Picasso, but... do you like it?
It's great.
So... what can I do for you?
A little song, a little dance.
Batman's head on a lance.
What do you know about...?
I don't know anything about Batman.
Really?
Well, how about a little "you and me"?
You're insane.
I thought I was a Pisces. Come on.
Let's make up. Have a little...
...whiff of my posy.
Help me!
I'm melting!
I'm melting! Help me! I'm melting!
Hold on.
Where does he get those wonderful toys?
- Get in the car.
- Which one?
Let's go.
Shields.
How much do you weigh?
About 108, I think.
Hold on.
Grab that thing on my belt.
Don't let go.
No blood.
Who is this guy?
Check his wallet.
- Wait.
- What is that?
Some kind of body armor.
He's human after all.
Take off the mask.
Shoot her!
Shields open.
You weigh more than 108.
- Really?
- Let's go.
Stop.
Where are we going?
Be careful.
Bats.
They're great survivors.
- What is all this?
- The police have got it wrong.
They're looking for one product.
The Joker's tainted hundreds
of chemicals at the source.
Then whole shipments would be poisoned.
And we'd all be dead.
No.
The poison only works if the components
are mixed. Hairspray won't do it alone.
But hairspray mixed with lipstick and
perfume will be toxic, and traceable.
How did you figure this out?
Take that to the press.
I might have trouble with that.
A lot of people think you're
as dangerous as the Joker.
He's psychotic.
Some people say the same thing about you.
What people?
Well, let's face it.
You're not exactly normal... are you?
It's not exactly a normal world.
Why did you bring me here?
You could have sent that
stuff to the press yourself.
You're right.
There is something else you have that I want.
What?
He took the film.
Where have you been? Are you okay?
Should I come over?
No, Allie.
If I bring something to you,
can we make the evening edition?
Just barely. Is it hot?
Yeah, it's real hot.
Copy!
Avoid the following combinations:
Deodorants with baby powder,
hairspray, and lipstick.
Safe products are flying in
as Gotham City goes on a forced fast.
And all of Gotham is wondering
what to make of Batman.
Friend or foe?
I have given a name to my pain...
...and it is Batman.
You must possess strength to inflict pain, Bob.
We've got a flying mouse to kill...
...and I want to clean my claws.
Sir, Miss Vale called again.
Dare I suggest that your
present course of action...
... might simply strengthen her resolve?
She is quite tenacious.
You're right.
And quite special.
Perhaps you could try telling her the truth.
Coming.
May I come in?
This is a nice apartment.
Lots of space.
Listen, I came over to...
...clear...
- I don't know who you think you are!
- You hurt me.
- I know.
I called you and called you. And you lied!
You lied about leaving town.
- Let me tell you why.
- Let me tell you!
I thought we felt something.
And I trusted you.
I even slept with you.
Then you wouldn't return my calls.
You must be some kind of jerk.
You're a real nice girl and I like you a lot,
but right now, shut up.
I have something to tell you.
You know how people have...
different sides to their personality?
Sometimes...
...a person will have to actually
lead a different life.
Oh, my God, you're married.
No, I'm not married.
You see...
...my life is really...
...complex.
All right, listen. You know how
a normal person gets up and...
...goes downstairs...
...and eats breakfast...
...and kisses somebody good-bye,
and goes to...
...a job, and, you know...
No.
Look.
What I'm trying to tell you is...
Hey, it's okay.
You can tell me.
What I'm trying to tell you is...
I'll be right back.
Miss me?
Nice place you got here. Lots of space.
Vicki, we've really got to talk.
We were having dinner.
I was a man doing well with a beautiful woman.
And without so much as an apology...
...you ran off with that sideshow phony.
You know...
...I've recently had a tragedy in my life.
Alicia...
...threw herself out a window.
Oh, my God.
But...
...you can't make an omelet
without breaking eggs.
Well, Miss Vale...
...another rooster in the hen-house?
Take thy beak from out my heart.
Bruce... Wayne, n'est-ce pas?
Most of the time.
I know who you are.
Let me tell you about this guy I know.
Mean kid. Bad seed. Hurt people.
I like him already.
You know what the problem was?
He got sloppy. You know, crazy.
He started to lose it.
He had a head full of bad wiring, I guess.
Couldn't keep it straight up here.
He was the kind of guy who...
...couldn't hear the train
until it was two feet from him.
You know what happened to this guy?
He made mistakes.
Then he ended up with his lights out!
Now you want to get nuts?
Come on! Let's get nuts!
Tell me something.
Have you ever danced with the
devil in the pale moonlight?
What?
I always ask that of all my prey.
I just like the sound of it.
Never rub another man's rhubarb.
Why is it, every time I come for you...
...somebody always gets in the way?
I'll need a moment alone.
I'm only laughing on the outside.
My smile is just skin deep.
If you could see inside...
...I'm really crying.
You might join me for a weep.
You really wouldn't believe it.
While you were entertaining, I've been
finding out about your street corner.
I think your friend is screwed up.
More good news.
Oh, my God!
His parents were murdered in that alley.
That's why he went there.
He watched it happen in front of him.
Look at the look on his face.
It was the same at City Hall.
What do you suppose this does to a kid?
Don't get personal!
Did you get the file on my parents?
It's on your table.
What's on your mind?
I have no wish to fill my few remaining years...
...grieving for the loss of old friends...
...or their sons.
The 200th anniversary birthday gala
has been indefinitely postponed.
We cannot guarantee public safety.
Joker here.
We got interference.
Now you fellows have said
some pretty mean things.
Some of which were true under that fiend...
... Boss Grissom.
He was a thief... and a terrorist.
On the other hand,
he had a tremendous singing voice.
He's dead now, and he's left me in charge.
I can be theatrical...
... and maybe even a little rough.
But one thing I am not...
... is a killer!
I love a good party.
So, truce.
Commence au festival!
And I've got a surprise for Gotham City.
At midnight, I will dump 20 million in cash...
... on the crowd.
Don't worry about me. I've got enough.
We are not prepared to discuss any deals.
You heard it, folks, 20 million.
And there will be entertainment.
The big dukeroo. With me in one corner,
and in the other corner...
... the man who has brought
real terror to Gotham City...
... Batman.
Can you hear me?
Just the two of us.
Mano y mano.
I have taken off my make-up.
Let's see...
... if you can take off yours.
Tell me, kid.
Have you ever danced with the
devil by the pale moonlight?
Let's go!
Let's go, Jack!
See you around.
Am I crazy?
That wasn't just another night
for either of us, was it?
We both got to each other, didn't we?
Why won't you let me in?
You got in.
I've loved you since I met you.
But I don't know what to think of all this.
Sometimes I don't know, either.
It's just something I have to do.
Why?
Because nobody else can.
I tried to avoid all this, but I can't.
This is how it is.
It's not a perfect world.
It doesn't have to be a perfect world.
I just have to know,
are we going to try to love each other?
I'd like to.
But he's out there right now.
And I've got to go to work.
Into the air, Junior Birdman!
Miss me?
Yeah! Watch me!
Get them. Take the pictures.
Gotham's greed.
And now, folks...
... it's time for, "Who Do You Trust?"
Money, money! Who do you trust?
Me? I'm giving away free money.
And where... is the Batman?
He's at home, washing his tights.
Winged battle flies through
the night and finds me ready.
Bob. Mask.
Masks! Put them on now!
And now...
... comes the part...
... where I relieve you, the little people...
... of the burden... of your failed...
... and useless lives.
But, as my plastic surgeon always said,
"If you've got to go...
"...go with a smile."
My God.
Smylex gas.
He's going to kill everybody!
Get in the car. Get in the car!
Hurry!
My balloons!
They're my balloons!
He stole my balloons!
Why didn't somebody tell me
he had one of those... things?
Bob. Gun.
I'll need a minute or two alone, boys.
Get out of here!
Come on, you gruesome son of a bitch.
Come to me.
Darling.
I've got to get you to the church on time.
Gotham City Cathedral.
Transportation for two.
- Right away, sir?
- Five minutes.
Better make it ten.
Let's go.
Point those searchlights at the tower.
Now! Move!
It can be truly said that
I have a bat in my belfry.
Shall we dance?
You know, without you...
...I just wouldn't want to go on.
We were made for each other.
Beauty and the Beast.
Of course, if anyone calls you "Beast"...
...I'll rip their lungs out.
Mr. Joker?
You say such beautiful things.
And you're so powerful. And purple!
I love purple!
Excuse me.
Have you ever danced with the devil
in the pale moonlight?
I'm going to kill you.
You idiot!
You made me, remember?
You dropped me into the chemicals!
That wasn't easy to get over!
And don't think I didn't try.
I know you did.
You killed my parents.
What?
What are you saying?
I made you, but you made me first.
I was just a kid.
I say you made me, you say I made you.
How childish can you get?
You wouldn't hit a guy with glasses on?
What are you laughing at?
Let me lend you a hand.
Lend you a hand!
They don't make them like they used to!
Hey, Batsy!
There he is! Down there!
It's time to retire.
Feel free to drop in.
Sometimes I just kill myself!
Hold on!
Our police have rounded up
all of the Joker's men.
The reign of crime is over.
Public safety in Gotham City is
no longer a laughing matter.
- Aren't you covering the press conference?
- No.
What about our Pulitzer Prize?
What about us?
What about your picture of Batman?
Take care.
We received a letter from Batman.
"Please inform the citizens of Gotham...
"...that Gotham City's
earned a rest from crime.
"But if the forces of evil should rise again...
"...to cast a shadow on
the heart of the city...
"...call me."
Question. How do we call him?
He gave us a signal.
I thought champagne would be in order, ma'am.
Hi, Alfred.
Mr. Wayne told me to tell you...
...that he might be a little late.
I'm not a bit surprised.
Subtitle Credits - P.NARASIMHA
HOPE U ENJOYED :) THE SUBTITLE.