- You can't sleep here.
-Get away from me.
Why don't you go to an inn?
- Why do you think?
- Did you knock on doors? Ask people?
I asked. I asked everywhere.
Leave me alone.
You didn't ask there.
Knock on that door.
Who can that be?
- Do you have any food you can spare?
- Come in.
Look, I'm a convict.
My name is Jean Valjean.
I've served 19 years' hard labour.
They let me out four days ago.
I'm on parole.
I have to go all the way to Dijon
to report by Monday...
...or they send me back to prison.
My passport.
I can't lread,
but it says I'm dangerous.
You're welcome to eat with us
as my guest.
I'm a convict. You saw my passport.
I know who you are.
You're gonna let me
inside your house?
What crime did you commit?
Maybe I killed someone.
How do you know
I'm not going to murder you?
What's that? A joke?
I suppose we'll have to
trust each other.
I didn't kill anyone. I'm a thief.
I stole food. I stole, but I paid for it.
Nineteen years in chains.
So they let me out
and give me a yellow passport.
What can I do
with a yellow passport?
I have to go to my parole officer in Dijon
and then what? Starve to death?
Nineteen years, and now
the real punishment begins!
Man can be unjust.
Man? Not God?
All right, whoever you are.
Thank you.
A meal and a bed to sleep in.
A real bed.
And in the morning,
I'll be a new man.
Is anybody there?
So we'll use wooden spoons. I don't
want to hear anything more about it.
- I'm sorry to disturb you.
- You caught him.
But I had my eye on this man.
- Oh, thank God.
- I'm very angry with you, Jean Valjean.
- What happened to your eye?
- Didn't he tell you he was our guest?
Oh, yes. After we searched
his knapsack and found all this silver.
He claimed that you gave it to him.
Yes, of course I gave him
the silverware.
But why didn't you take the
Candlesticks? That was very foolish.
Madame Gilot,
fetch the silver Candlesticks.
They're worth at least 2,000 francs.
Why did you leave them? Hurry!
Monsieur Valjean has to get going.
He's lost a lot of time.
- Did you forget to take them?
- Are you saying he told us the truth?
Of course. Thank you for bringing
him back. I've very relieved.
Release him!
- You're really letting me go?
- Didn't you understand the bishop?
Madame Gilot,
offer these men some wine.
- They must be thirsty.
- Thank you.
And don't forget, don't ever forget...
...you've promised
to become a new man.
I promise. Why are you doing this?
Jean Valjean, my brother,
you no longer belong to evil.
With this silver, I bought your soul.
I've ransomed you
from fear and hatred.
And now I give you back to God.
Good afternoon, captain.
I'm Javert, the new police inspector.
Here are my orders
from the Paris prefect.
Oh, yes. Hello, Inspector Javert.
I've been expecting you.
I'm Captain Beauvais.
- How was your journey?
- You haven't looked at my orders.
Oh, I'm sure they're all right.
Have you eaten, or would you--?
I'd like you to follow procedure.
Well...
...everything seems to be
in order, inspector.
You are now in charge
of the Vigau police.
In Paris, things are miserable.
Crime is rampant,
the streets are filthy.
- Conditions here are much better.
- Life in Vigau has never been better.
Shall I take you to our tile-and-brick
factory? Our biggest business.
- Very well.
- This way.
- Who owns the factory?
- The mayor.
He was just one of the workers. But
when it went bankrupt five years ago...
...incredible to think of now, he bought
the works for less than 500 francs.
On second thought, captain,
I should report to the mayor first.
- Yes.
- The mayor seems to be the force...
...behind everything.
Must be a man of genius.
He is extraordinary. But I should
warn you, he's also a little eccentric.
- Eccentric? In what way?
- Well, he's shy. Lives like a hermit.
Didn't even want to be mayor.
Tried to refuse.
But the town fathers insisted.
- Not ambitious, yet this successful?
- He's a mystery.
Some people think he's crazy,
but I like him.
- I like him and I feel sorry for him.
- You feel sorry for the mayor?
Because he's lonely. Here we are.
- He lives here?
- Strange, isn't it?
Little better than a worker's house.
Good afternoon, mayor.
The new inspector has arrived.
He wants to report.
That's all right. He doesn't have to.
Monsieur Ie maire, if you don't permit
the inspector to report...
...I think he will burst into tears.
Monsieur Ie maire,
I'm Inspector Javert.
I have the honour of reporting to
my post as your prefect of police.
I'm sorry. What's your name?
Inspector Javert.
You were expecting me.
- Paris should have--
- You have papers?
Yes. I apologise. I should have
presented them immediately.
Good. Thank you for coming.
Captain, make sure the inspector's
settled comfortably.
- Yes. Good day.
- Good day.
- The men and women work separately?
- Yes. Monsieur Ie maire...
...redesigned the factory
in order to keep the sexes apart.
- I told you he's eccentric.
- Not eccentric, captain, no.
He cares about honest working women
and wants to protect their virtue.
Very Proper, very wise.
- I'm sorry.
- Excuse me, sir.
- I didn't mean to.
- You ruined another!
- They'll dock my wages--
- All right. Enough!
Get your things.
I'm going to move you.
- It was an unforgettable--
- Good riddance!
- But I'll forget it anyway!
- Let's go! Back to work!
Come on. Fun's over.
Come on. Back to work.
I'd feel safer if you had an escort.
Don't worry, I can look after myself.
I haven't much time.
I must leave right away.
I hope this urgency
does not imply distress.
May I ask why you are withdrawing
your entire fortune?
I trust you are aware
this institution is at your service.
Thank you. But this is
a business opportunity, no crisis.
- I'll be back tomorrow.
- I received disturbing information...
...about one of the girls.
I have reason to believe...
...she has a child
and is not married.
- What? Is she a whore?
- I don't hire--
I don't hire women
who sell themselves.
Of course you don't, I apologise.
It's just I don't want our ladies
to be exposed to corruption.
- I suggest dismissal.
- I trust your judgement.
Thank you.
Fantine, come with me, please.
Come on.
She's caught the tart.
Please don't let me go now, madame.
My little girl is sick.
You read it in that letter from the people
who take care of her. The military fever.
They need 40 francs for medicine
or she'll die.
Who are these people,
the Thenardiers?
- Are they relatives?
- No, not relatives.
You deliberately left your child
with strangers to conceal her?
You dismiss me for having a child,
then you--
Not for having a child,
for having a child out of wedlock...
...pretending to be honest.
I have to earn money to feed her.
How can I work and take care of her?
I have to lie.
You make it sound like
your lie is my fault.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm upset.
I don't mean to argue, madame.
My Cosette is a sweet little girl,
an innocent little girl.
Don't punish her for my sin.
- I was stupid. I fell in love.
-"In love." That's always the excuse.
Yes, you're right. I'm a bad person.
But the Thenardiers are good people.
They have two daughters.
My Cosette can play with them.
She won't be so lonely.
She's better off with them.
Only I have to make money
to pay for her medicine.
Please. Just a month. I'll work hard.
The mayor cares about his workers.
He cannot have women of questionable
morals influencing the girls. I'm sorry.
- What's going on?
- Five sous for the chair.
Nice doing business with you.
- Are you skipping out?
- I sold it for extra money.
Well, you owe me a month's rent.
- Not till next week.
- Well, pay now or you're out.
Thirty francs. Come on,
you've got 50 in your hand.
Fifteen. Get you the rest next week.
- How? They fired you.
- Who told you I was fired?
This is still a small town.
- I have a job.
- Don't lie.
Start next week as a washerwoman.
Everybody knows your story.
You've got a bastard kid.
Nobody's gonna give you work.
Please take half. I'll get you the rest.
Don't look so worried.
Things aren't that bad.
You've still got a bed.
Yes. Good hair quality.
Ten francs.
Dear Reverend Mother.
The bishop of Digne,
may he rest in peace...
...often told me of your convent
and its good works.
In his memory,
I would like to give a--
Or is it "I Should like"?
"Should" is preferable.
And "endow" is less brutal than "give."
- I should like to endow--
- Monsieur!
There's been an accident.
One of the workers. Lafitte!
- Get me out! I can't breathe!
- Stand back. Let me through.
- Let him through.
- Help us. We need leverage.
- Come on, move!
- Gather round!
- Together. All together.
- Let's go, boys!
Get me out! It's breaking my rib!
- Get ready.
- Come on, pull. All together. Pull!
Boys, push. Push. Come on, push.
- Marla.
- Good evening.
- Where's Claudette tonight?
- Oh, monsieur.
- There are more than ever.
-Inspector, you startle me.
Yes, I counted four new girls.
You see, captain, when a town grows,
crime grows with it.
- Shall I get the men and make arrests?
- No. Did you check off the regulars?
Yes.
- And I've noted the new girls.
- Good work.
- Marla.
- Good evening.
- Is it 10:00? I didn't hear it ring.
- I'm early. I was restless.
- You heard about Lafitte and the cart?
- Nothing else.
Incredible feat.
Has the mayor
always been that strong?
Well, he's a big man,
but I didn't know he was that strong.
- Didn't he show it when he was young?
- I didn't know him when he was young.
Oh, that's right. He moved here.
Where's he from?
Well, he came here from Paris,
but that's not where he was born.
- You know, I think he told--
- Didn't you check his papers?
- I suppose I did. Don't remember.
- Perhaps you didn't.
Why should you?
How about her?
Who are you?
- Push off!
- Yeah, get off.
- Hi, dearie.
- Oh, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
She's new.
Who is it?
I'm buying your horse and cart.
The doctor says your kneecap's broken.
You won't be able to do your old job.
I've written to the Sainte Marie Convent
in Paris.
The sisters need
a new caretaker and gardener.
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Sorry for what?
Monsieur, I used to--
I was angry at you.
Because when you came here,
you were a worker like me...
...and you grew rich...
-...while I had troubles.
- We've all had troubles, Lafitte.
And we all need help
from time to time. Rest.
And I'll let you know when
I have word from the convent.
"Thank you for...
...our new..."
C-A-R-E. Caretaker.
- That's it, caretaker.
- Excuse me.
-Inspector Javert is here to see you.
- Tell him to wait.
I have exciting news, monsieur
le maire. Paris is interested in my plan.
- What plan's that?
-It's in the letter, sir.
Why don't you tell me?
You said it's your plan.
I forgot. I apologise.
- Apologise? For what?
- I forgot you don't read.
Your clerk mentioned it.
Neglected your education
to make your fortune?
What is Paris interested in, inspector?
I'm all ears.
Because of Vigau's extraordinary
growth the past five years...
...I've proposed that
we make a detailed census.
Well, that would be interesting.
But how is it a police matter?
Modern law enforcement
demands modern methods...
...and that means information.
For example, how many people
have moved here in the last decade?
Where did they come from?
What's their background?
Is our criminal population home-grown
or are they outsiders?
Without information, we cannot know
how to control the dangerous elements.
- You might be making a mistake.
-It's a mistake? What mistake is that?
Sometimes people move to a new town
to start with a clean slate.
You might be doing more harm
than good by prying into their lives.
An honest man has nothing to fear
from the truth.
For example, Paris knows my father
was a thief and my mother a prostitute.
If my mother or father moved here, I'd
want everyone to know what they are.
- Even if they had reformed themselves?
- Reform is a discredited fantasy.
Modern science tells us that people are
by nature law breakers or law abiders.
A wolf can wear sheep's clothing,
but he's still a wolf.
I was just thinking, inspector,
that you have been unlucky.
Unlucky? I don't understand.
Unfortunately, you've been assigned
to a dull post.
You'd be happier in Paris,
where everyone...
...either by nature or experience,
is dishonest.
Indeed. Well, I'll see if I prefer Paris.
They've asked me to report to
the deputy prefect to explain my idea.
I'll be gone for four days.
We'll miss you. Good luck.
Thank you. And goodbye.
Inspector? One moment.
Please.
- Here's a farewell gift.
- You're offering me a gift?
Yes, inspector, my papers.
Baptismal certificate, passport...
...working papers
from the Marseille docks.
I want to get your census
off on the right foot.
Pleasant journey, inspector.
Move on. Have your papers ready.
It's Paris. We don't waste time.
- Inspector Javert. Let me through.
- Papers!
Inspector Javert, the prefect
was impressed by your proposal.
I expect him to approve a budget
for your census within the month.
Thank you, sir.
That's excellent news.
You are known in Paris now, Javert.
Your future is bright.
So I suggest you drop this request...
...for an investigation of the mayor.
Sir, I was a guard for a year
in the quarries of Toulon.
I saw Jean Valjean perform
the same feat of strength...
...as the mayor did with the cart.
The hard labour makes them
incredibly strong.
Once the connection was made in my
mind, no longer dazzled by his wealth...
...I've grown more certain every day.
Indeed, now I recognise his face
and voice so clearly, I'm amazed...
-...I didn't know him right away.
- I don't doubt--
Sir.
- I'm prepared to denounce him.
- Denounce him?
Without proof?
If I force a trial,
the evidence will be found.
He showed you papers
and they were in order.
I checked the baptism certificate.
It's a copy. Eleven years ago,
there was a fire at the parish.
The authentic records were destroyed.
His documents are based on that copy.
Your identification alone is not enough
to subject the mayor of Vigau to a trial.
File a report and I'll recommend
we investigate.
Sir, Jean Valjean is a thief. It makes
a mockery of our institutions...
...to have a corrupt and depraved man
in charge--
Javert. I said file a report.
I'll investigate on this end, discreetly.
But do not denounce him
without proof.
Be patient.
He's not going anywhere. Is he?
"Madame, the 10 francs a month
we agreed on is no longer enough.
Cosette grows bigger by the minute.
She enjoyed her sixth birthday party
and the new doll we bought her.
We love her so we won't charge
for her present...
...but she needs a new coat and shoes.
We can't afford to pay for them.
And she eats more than
both our daughters put together.
Beginning right away,
you must send 20 francs a month...
...or come and fetch her.
Sincerely, Thenardier."
- So, what's your answer?
- I can't move.
I don't have money
to pay in advance for a room.
Am I a charity?
You haven't paid me in four months.
- I paid you.
- I have bills too...
...and I can't spread my legs. It's not
good business to rent to a whore.
What about your necklace?
That's worth something.
No, not this.
-It's for my daughter.
- You better come up with something.
I want 10 francs or you're out.
No.
This time I want cash.
Good evening, monsieur.
My God, you're hideous.
Well, how much?
A franc.
- You're joking.
- Fifty sous.
Fifty sous? Fifty sous?
To screw a corpse?
- Hasn't got a drop of blood in her veins!
- Mademoiselle. Mademoiselle.
- How about a sou?
- Stop it!
I have a sou. I have a sou
to spend on you.
But first, let's give your tits
a bit of colour!
Something to drink!
Down you go, tart.
She's attacking him.
Sir, this is a disturbance. May I?
I'll take care of this.
That's enough!
It's not my fault. They started it--
- Go home! And be quick about it.
- Come on, let's go.
- Captain.
- You asked me to tell you...
...if he went too far. Well,
I've kept my mouth shut long enough.
Have her taken to the prison.
You get six months.
Six months? What about Cosette?
What'll happen to her?
Who is Cosette?
My daughter. If I don't send
them money, they'll turn her out!
Is your daughter here in Vigau?
- No, sir, she lives with--
- Then she's not my concern.
Inspector. Inspector.
Inspector, please listen to my side.
I know I hit the gentleman.
I know I was wrong.
But do they have the right
to put snow down my dress...
...especially when it's the only one
I have and I need it for work?
I'm sorry. I don't mean to argue.
It won't happen again.
Inspector, please.
Please be merciful.
All right, I've listened to your side.
You're still getting six months.
- Not even eternal fire will change that.
- One moment, inspector.
It was you. You did this to me.
You fired me.
- You slut! Come here.
- Get over here.
Let her go.
- What?
- Let me explain, inspector.
I was crossing the square
when you arrested her.
People said it was the fault
of the men who attacked her.
In fact, they should be under arrest.
Now that you've heard this,
I want you to release her.
He said I can go.
He is the mayor, isn't he?
Well, I'll be going, then.
I won't be any bother to anyone.
- Sergeant, who said she could go?
- I did.
I am the final judicial authority
here in Vigau, and I say she's innocent.
- She spat on you.
- She was upset.
She insulted you.
In front of my men, she defiled you.
- That's my concern, inspector.
- No, sir, you are wrong.
You personify order, morality,
government. The whole of society.
You don't have the right to forgive. You
haven't the authority to destroy justice.
I do have the authority. Under Articles
9 and 11, I can order her release.
Sergeant, she is free to go.
I cannot allow that, monsieur.
I was there. She attacked a man.
The decision is mine. She's free.
- She won't go free while I am in charge.
- In that case...
...under Article 66, you are relieved
of command until tomorrow.
You are dismissed, inspector.
Leave! Now!
You're free to go.
Water.
Water!
I doubt she'll survive.
She talks continually about Cosette.
- Who's that?
- Her daughter.
She needs all the will
to fight the infection.
Perhaps if the girl were here...
- I understand. Thank you, doctor.
- You'll need nurses.
I can't arrange for them till morning.
What about tonight?
I'll take care of her tonight.
Keep her body warm
and her head cool. Good night.
Why did the gossip bother you?
You didn't have to fire me.
Your clothes are damp.
We have to get you some dry--
It's all right. There'll be no charge.
You deserve it.
But I don't understand
why you're being so kind.
I was preoccupied. I didn't know.
If you had come straight to me,
none of this...
You need to rest.
- You don't want a kiss?
- I want you to rest.
And don't worry.
I'll bring your daughter to you.
- Are you going to the Thenardiers?
- No, I can't.
I'll send the money
to bring Cosette here.
- She can't live with me.
- Of course she can. She will.
She'll attend the school...
...and you won't have
any more worries.
When you're better,
I'll find work for you.
But you don't understand.
I'm a whore,
and Cosette has no father.
She has the Lord. He is her father.
And you are his creation.
In his eyes you have never been
anything but an innocent...
...and beautiful woman.
Monsieur.
- You look better every day.
- Liar.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Fantine, look.
- Is that Thenardier's handwriting?
- Yes.
- Is something wrong?
- Read it.
I don't know how.
Would you read it to me?
- Well, I'm learning myself.
- We're a fine pair.
My clerk tells me this man can't bring
Cosette because you owe him money.
- I don't. I paid him.
- I've sent him money as well. It's a lie.
He could have brought Cosette
and been paid.
- I'll go get her.
- No, no, no. Stay where you are.
It's all right. There's no need.
He thinks you've come into money.
He's become a little greedy, that's all.
I've sent him what he's asked for
and extra to bring Cosette.
She should be here in a few days.
- How wonderful to see her.
- You must eat, my dear.
- I'll let you have your lunch.
- What about you? Don't you eat?
"Our little lark, our darling Cosette...
...is eager to be with her mother,
but she has a cough.
'Like my mummy's,'
the sweet angel said.
The physician advises
she's not well enough to travel now.
I'll bring her when she's stronger.
Meanwhile the medicine is expensive
and the doctors' bills are criminal.
- Fantine owes us another 50 francs--"
- All right. I've had enough.
- You want to dictate a reply?
- No.
Instead, write this note
for Fantine to sign:
Monsieur Thenardier. You will
hand Cosette over to the bearer.
Regards.
I'll be leaving right away.
- Javert.
- I need to see you immediately.
Alone.
Thank you, Pierre.
I'm in a hurry, inspector.
Monsieur, a serious...
A grave violation of the public trust
has been committed.
An inferior has shown a complete
lack of respect for the law.
- He must be exposed and punished.
- Who is the offender?
I am.
I slandered you, monsieur. I'm here
to ask that you demand my dismissal.
Inspector Javert,
what are you talking about?
You may say I can resign. Resignation
is honourable and I don't deserve it.
I must be punished.
You treated me unjustly over the--
About the woman.
This time you must treat me justly.
You must dismiss me.
God's sakes, Javert. For what?
I denounced you to
the Paris prefect of police.
I swore that you were a convict.
- You said I was what?
- A convict.
I had no proof.
Only a memory of this man,
Jean Valjean...
...whom I guarded 20 years ago
in prison.
I denounced you
without a shred of evidence.
- You denounced me?
- Yes.
I was a fool.
They told me I was wrong, you couldn't
be Jean Valjean, and they were right.
I've just returned from Arras,
where I saw the real Jean Valjean.
- The real Valjean?
- Yes.
Two weeks ago, a man
who called himself Carnot...
...was arrested outside Arras
for poaching apples.
At the prison, a convict
took one look at him and said:
"I know this man. We were in prison
in Toulon 20 years ago.
He's Jean Valjean."
I didn't believe it.
I went there to see for myself.
Well, there's no question.
Carnot is Valjean.
I apologise, monsieur.
I look at you now...
...and it's obvious
you're not a convict.
So now you don't think
I'm a convict?
Of course I don't. I've seen Valjean
with my own eyes.
Must have been out of my mind
to think you could be a criminal.
- This man, he admits to being Valjean?
- Of course not.
He pretends to be a half-wit
who can't understand the charges.
Valjean has broken parole.
That calls for life imprisonment.
- When is the trial?
- Tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
- How long will it take?
- No more than an afternoon.
- Tomorrow.
- The evidence is overwhelming.
I returned so that you could dismiss
me and press charges for slander.
I must consider.
I was just on my way home.
Walk with me, Javert.
You are a stern man,
but you're honourable.
- I want you to remain prefect.
- That's impossible.
You've exaggerated your of fence.
I've not exaggerated, monsieur.
I resented you.
I chafed at your authority.
And out of revenge, I slandered you.
If a subordinate of mine had done
that, I would have broken him.
You must punish me, monsieur,
or my life will have been meaningless.
Then blame me, Javert.
- You, monsieur Ie maire?
- I order you to forgive yourself.
Blame me for that mercy.
You will remain prefect.
Those are my orders.
Will you go get her today?
Yes. Tonight.
Is something wrong?
I'm going to do my best.
I'm going to get better for my girl.
But if he chooses to take me,
will you look after Cosette?
- I know I have no right--
- You and Cosette...
...will always be safe with me.
I swear it.
- Is this the courthouse?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
- May I go in?
- I can't let you in. It's full.
It's full? There are no seats?
Jammed. We've got two great cases.
- So I can't get in?
- No. Not a chance.
Unless... Unless monsieur
is a public official.
There is a seat reserved for them
right beside the judge.
Best seat in the house.
I am the mayor of Vigau.
Gentlemen, you'll be so kind
to remain seated...
...while my lords, the judges,
re-examine the prisoner's records.
The prisoner to remain standing
at the bar.
- It is an honour, monsieur le maire.
-Welcome, sir.
Thank you.
- Continue the examination.
- You pretend to be simple...
...so I give you a simple question
to answer.
Are you or are you not
the convict Jean Valjean?
In the first place...
What's the first place?
Answer the question.
You're wicked. That's what I was going
to say. Only I forgot your name.
I'm a man who...
Oh, what's the word for it?
I'm one of those
who doesn't eat every day. I'm...
I'm hungry. That's the word.
You've already been found
guilty of poaching.
- Answer the prosecutor's question.
- Did he ask a question?
Are you or are you not Jean Valjean?
Well, you say I was born
in Faverolles.
That's very clever, telling me where
I come from. It's more than I know.
My parents were tramps.
Monsieur le président...
...in view of the shrewdly contrived
denials of the accused, who is trying...
...to pass himself off as an idiot...
-...I call the witness Brevet to the stand.
- So ordered.
Brevet. I remind you...
...that what you say
may destroy a man's life.
You must be absolutely certain
of your testimony.
My memory is good.
- The best thing I have.
- The accused will rise.
- Do you recognise this man?
- Yeah.
I was the first to recognise him.
I ought to get credit--
- Never mind who was first. Who is he?
- That's Jean Valjean.
We served 19 years together
in prison.
He looks older of course.
Looks stupider too.
- That's probably age.
-Monsieur le président, I call...
-...the convict Lombard to the stand.
- You may step down.
The accused should remain standing.
I repeat my warning: A man's life
can be destroyed by your answer.
Do you recognise the accused?
I can't help but recognise him.
We did five years on one chain.
What's the matter with you, eh?
No hello, eh? Did you miss me, eh?
Hello.
I call Bertin to the stand.
I warn you as well:
Your answer can ruin a man.
Do you recognise the accused?
Yeah. He's Jean Valjean.
Monsieur le président...
...may I address the court?
Yes, sir. Yes, certainly,
monsieur Ie maire.
Brevet, Lombard, Bertin.
Look at me.
Do you recognise me?
I recognise you, Brevet.
You were an informer in Toulon.
I see you're still a snitch.
- Valjean.
- Hello, Brevet.
And you, Lombard.
Don't look at my fancy clothes.
Don't look at my scraped chin.
Look at my eyes.
You called yourself godless, right?
You got a scar on your shoulder. I gave
it to you the night you tried to kill me.
- When I pinned you over the stove.
- It is you.
Show the court your scar.
Bertin, the hollow of your left arm.
There's a date tattooed,
1789, the year of the revolution.
Show them.
I know these men, monsieur
le président. And they know me.
I am the man you want.
I am Jean Valjean.
-It's him!
- Oh, my God!
Monsieur Ie maire,
I know you to be a kind man...
- A kind--? A kind man?
-...but this?
In prison, I was as ignorant,
mean and devious...
...as these men here, but not kind.
I wish I could keep my mouth shut and
let this poor wretch suffer for me, but...
Continue with the investigation.
You will find further proof
that I am Valjean.
I need you in the office right away.
- Monsieur, you're back.
- I don't have the child yet.
- I'll leave in an hour. How is she?
- Her cough's worse.
There's more blood now. She's...
I think she's just holding on
to see her daughter.
- Wait.
- I have an urgent message for Javert.
- I'll take it.
- To be delivered by hand.
This is a special warrant from Arras.
I knew it.
I knew it!
- Monsieur, you're back.
- Fantine, if something were--
I was just dreaming.
- About you and me and Cosette.
- Don't excite yourself.
We were at her confirmation...
...and she looked so beautiful.
- Fantine, if something were--
- But then she didn't know me.
And I was crying.
I have to tell you.
- I know I'm not going to live long.
- I won't be able to--
Would you give this to her?
I saved it for her.
Yes.
- Could you give it to her, please?
- I'll give it to her.
She can come and stay with you,
can't she?
You will raise her, won't you?
- Yes, I'll raise her.
- Promise me, monsieur.
I promise.
He lies well, doesn't he?
He's had a lot of practice.
A lifetime of lies.
- Save me.
-It's all right. He's not here for you.
He's not here for you.
He isn't mayor anymore.
- Let's talk in private.
- Speak up. Don't mumble.
- I need a favour.
- Speak up.
- Give me two days to fetch her child.
- Are you joking?
- I'll pay you anything you want.
- Do you think I'm that stupid? You do.
You must have laughed when
you forgave me. Generous, kind mayor.
No. No, you can't fetch things
for your whore.
You're going where you belong.
This bitch is going to jail.
You'll never see your daughter.
You're going to prison.
He can't save you.
- Javert.
- Scum of the earth.
Get up!
It's a pleasure to see you
again, Valjean.
You killed her.
Where will you go, Valjean?
You don't have papers.
I'll find you.
She repented, didn't she?
She made her peace with God?
Yes, monsieur.
Are you a convict? Is that true?
Yes.
- Where's the inspector?
-Inside.
Did you kill him?
That's a pity.
You'd better hit me hard enough
to make a lump.
- Where is he?
- He left half an hour ago.
- On foot?
- On a wagon.
- Which way?
- The southern road.
- Commandeer the mail coach.
- Yes.
- Not you, Beauvais. You two, go.
- Ask anybody. Everybody saw him leave.
How much money has he taken?
- He didn't take any.
- Show me the book.
I don't understand.
He transferred ownership.
To all the employees.
Shares have been apportioned by
seniority. He took nothing for himself.
Quickly.
Faster! Faster!
Come on, drive them there!
- Morning, monsieur Ie maire.
- Good morning.
What are you doing? Don't slow down.
Give me the reins.
Come on!
Yes. Yes.
We're going too fast, sir!
Look out!
You're... You're under arrest.
The whore, who did she write to?
The address, give it to me.
There you are, you little slut.
What took you so long?
-It's heavy.
- Don't let me hear you complaining.
You don't bring a sou.
The least you can do is clean
the rooms. I feed your greedy mouth.
Do I get thanks? No, I get
smart answers. Now get to work.
I want those stockings finished
or no supper.
You have to earn your keep.
What do you want?
- A room, please.
- A room costs 20 sous.
I'll pay in advance.
Very well, monsieur.
My dear, my sweet, my precious,
you've forgotten. Haven't you?
I've forgotten.
I do that. I forget things.
What have I forgotten?
We've rented the regular room.
We've only got the wedding chamber
left. I'm sorry, but that costs 40 sous.
- You want a meal?
- Bread and cheese.
Is that all? There's rabbit stew.
- What's she knitting?
- Who?
She's making stockings
for my daughters.
- She's not your daughter?
- Not that creature. No.
Why? Does she interest you?
Perhaps.
- What's her name?
- Cosette.
- What are they worth?
- The girl?
- The stockings.
- Oh, the stockings.
I don't know.
- You can buy the stockings.
- Probably 30 sous.
I'll buy them.
I'm paying for her time.
I want her to play.
Of course, understand
I meant 30 sous for each stocking.
Cosette, get up. Come on.
Get out of there.
Cosette! Get out. Get out of there!
Get out!
You're working for me now.
You can rest or you can play.
What would you like?
Madame, is it true?
Am I allowed to play?
You heard, didn't you? Yes, you must
play. Go on, hurry up, start playing.
Perhaps monsieur would like Cosette
to play on his lap.
I'm heading to Paris.
ls there a mail carriage I can take?
It's gone already.
Next coach to Paris arrives at dawn.
- You like our Cosette?
- I want to take her with me.
Monsieur, I have to tell you the truth.
- I adore that child.
- You adore her?
Yes, it's true. I'm not rich.
I've had to pay over 400 francs
for her medicine.
But I'm a stupid man.
I have no sense...
...just a heart. A big heart.
- You paid over 400 francs?
- Five hundred.
Five hundred. All right.
I want to leave right away.
I'm sorry, monsieur, but her mother
gave her to us to protect.
- I can't let a stranger take her.
- How much?
This isn't a question of money.
What right do you have to the girl?
- You don't want money?
- Of course not.
Even if you were to offer 1000 francs,
even 1,200, I couldn't give her to you.
It's true, I owe 1,500 francs...
...and my whole life would be solved
if only I had 1,500 francs, but...
No, I can't think about money.
It's a question of law.
All that matters is
who has the right to the child.
That's a relief.
Here's a letter from Cosette's mother
authorising me to take her.
Cosette, quick.
- Do we have to walk all the way to Paris?
- Yes. Are you tired?
No, monsieur. I'm all right.
Cosette, best not to
call me "monsieur."
- People will think we're strangers.
- Then what shall I call you, monsieur?
Well, "papa." What about "papa"?
But you're not my father, monsieur,
are you?
Want me to carry you?
- I can reach the branches.
- You're the tallest lady in France.
- I'm the queen of France.
- That's right...
...you're the queen of France.
You're the queen, Cosette.
You're the queen.
Have your papers out and ready
to be inspected when it's your turn.
Wake up. This is Paris.
Form an orderly queue.
Have your papers ready!
- Keep in line back there!
- Have your papers out...
...and ready for inspection!
Let these carriages through!
We must get to here.
Have your papers out
and ready for inspection.
Cosette, listen.
Wait here. Wait here.
I won't be long. All right?
Have your papers out
and ready for inspection!
Don't leave me!
Wait your turn!
You have to be quiet.
I'm just having a look at the wall.
I'm not leaving you.
- Are we gonna climb that wall?
- Yes.
All right?
- Come on, move along, then!
- Papa!
But you told me to call you Papa.
You, where are your documents?
- No luck yet.
- He's on foot.
The little girl would slow him down.
Well, Javert...
...you said he was Valjean,
and we ignored you.
Rather than apologise,
I want you to know...
...that I've asked the prefect
to transfer you to Paris...
...to work as my deputy.
- Monsieur, I'm honoured. Thank you.
- Have your papers out!
Meanwhile, these men are
at your disposal to find Valjean.
Have your papers out!
All right, Cosette, give me your doll.
Now, climb on my back.
Go on. Here, put your foot here.
Go on.
That's it. Big jump.
That's a girl. All right?
You, where are your documents?
- Papa, I'm frightened.
- Don't look down.
Of course he won't.
Pardon me, Javert. He won't what?
Have your papers ready!
I want three of you
to walk around the wall.
Look for a gap where someone
could jump onto a roof. Go!
- I don't understand.
- He has no proper papers, sir.
He won't come through here.
- Watch here.
- Yes, sir.
Stay down. Stay down.
We'll have to cross here.
Shut up!
Do you wanna get us killed?
Cosette, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
I'm sorry. But we have to be quiet.
We can't make a noise.
This is the only place
we can get over.
Listen to me. We have to jump.
Valjean!
Come on. Take my hand.
- What's on the other side of this wall?
-It's a convent.
Javert, I am not going to wake up
a building full of nuns...
-...and search their beds.
-It's for their protection.
This is a strict order. The nuns aren't
permitted to look or speak to a man.
It's a school for girls.
They must be protected.
The girls are daughters of the
aristocracy, whose parents would...
-...have you guillotined if you're wrong.
- Sir, I know he's in there.
What?
Who are you?
Now I'm trapped
under the cart, Lafitte.
If you would collect all the nuns,
sisters and schoolgirls...
...in the chapel, my men
could search everywhere else.
We are not afraid of men.
We are here to adore Christ.
- I can't protect you from here.
- A search of our school or convent...
...is impossible. I'm sorry, inspector.
I've told the mother superior you're
my brother. You'll be the new gardener.
Good, thank you. And tomorrow...
...can you arrange for her
to go to school here? I can pay.
Who is she?
She's an orphan.
She'll be with me now.
- Pity.
- What?
I was thinking of next year
when it'll be Cosette's turn.
Is it a pity to be devoted to Christ?
A beautiful nun is a tragic waste.
Well, even though Cosette
will be stuck here...
...at least you can see the world.
Or Paris, anyway.
Aren't you curious?
You haven't been outside now
in how many years?
The world never changes, Lafitte.
It is changing.
You should have a look for yourself.
You'll be surprised.
- What are you looking at?
- Just watching the people go by.
- I don't want to take my vows.
- You promised the mother superior.
I want to leave. Please.
- But we're safe here.
- Safe from what, Papa?
We have everything we need.
I can work here, be near you.
- We have a good life here.
- Please, Papa.
I'll think about it.
We're very grateful
for everything you've done...
...but my daughter's happiness
is what's most important to me.
Naturally I'm disappointed
Cosette has changed her mind.
- But I too want to see her happy.
- Thank you.
We shall leave as soon as
I can find a suitable home.
I was wondering--
I don't know anyone in Paris.
--If you could help me find a house
in a decent area.
But, Lafitte, how could you
afford such a house?
Before we came here, I had money.
Family money that I saved
to help provide for us.
Well, I hope you're certain that
you've made the right decision.
I am.
Look,Papa.
- I shan't be long.
- I'll wait here.
- All right. Don't leave the cab.
- I'll stay put, Papa.
I'll be back soon.
Ma'am, you got any money?
Spare some money?
--Can't provide for your family.
Strike for a decent wage. Why not?
Because it's against the law to strike.
The king has declared that everything
is a crime. Writing is a crime.
Two weeks ago, the police destroyed
Egalite', the workers' newspaper.
- They smashed the press.
- The man making a speech...
...he's the leader of the ABC Society...
...the largest and most dangerous
of the student groups.
They want the king out.
They want suffrage without limitation.
I don't care what they want.
I want to know who they are.
- Speaking out is a crime.
- Marius Pontmercy.
- Rents a room above the Cafe Musain.
- Being poor is the worst crime of all.
And if you commit these crimes,
you are condemned for life.
- Concentrate on him.
- Our government has no mercy...
...no pity, no forgiveness.
- And it has no work for us!
- And there's no work.
And because there is no work,
our children are starving. Tell me...
...why are we powerless
to save the people we love?
You know. Tell me why.
- The king lied!
- The king betrayed us.
We were promised the vote.
- Do we have the vote?
- No!
Where is the Republic
our fathers died for?
- Where?
- Here.
It's here, my brothers.
It lives here in our heads.
But most of all, best of all,
it lives in our hearts.
In our hearts, we are the Republic!
We are the Republic!
Where have you been?
I told you not to leave the cab.
I was just going out for some air.
- Who's that?
- I don't know. He was making a speech.
Come, we're going home.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
You again. I looked this time.
You weren't at Mass.
- I was, Father.
- Go on, get out of the line.
- They won't let us in.
- He's all right. Let him through.
- We made extra today.
- How are you, Gavroche?
Thank you. No one is as kind
and as beautiful as you.
You're such a convincing liar.
I fear for your mortal soul.
- Who are your little friends?
- These are my babies.
I found them wandering the streets.
Don't I make a good father?
You'd make a better father, Gavroche,
with a real coat. Wait a minute.
My friend wants to know if you'll
take a walk in the park with him.
Here you are. Bring your babies back
tomorrow and I'll give them jackets.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
- He never leaves her alone.
- He's not a father, he's a jailer.
Go. Go on, here they come.
Go. Go, go, go.
Come on, boys. Hurry up.
- Let's go home.
- May we go for a walk?
It's so sunny and mild.
I'm tired. Would you read to me
in the garden?
Why don't you go lie down?
I'll go for a walk.
- Alone?
- I'll have to walk alone some day.
- Some day, not today.
- I know.
- Why don't you sit and relax...?
- Stop playing games.
- I'm not playing games.
- Are you disobeying?
I'm your father. Get in!
It's Thursday. Madame Toussaint
made your favourite dessert.
What do you say, Cosette?
Strangers can be dangerous.
- Will that be all?
- Yes. Thank you, Toussaint.
You're not, you know.
- Pardon?
- You're not my father.
You never said you were until
you became angry and behaved...
...so strangely today.
That was the first time you said it.
- The very first time.
- Yes, you're right.
Well, are you my father?
Cosette, I promised your mother
I would take care of you.
I know you think I worry too much...
-...but strangers can be danger--
- All right.
- What?
- I don't want to hear that speech again.
There's something shameful.
It must be me.
- My child, no.
- Or you.
You're the shameful secret.
Or maybe both of us.
It doesn't matter. I can't go out.
- I can't talk to people.
- Stop this.
I think you're lying. I know the secret.
The secret is you want me
with you night and day...
...because you're lonely and
you want me to be alone forever.
Cosette.
You're right. I'm not a father. I don't--
I just want to protect you, that's all.
The world isn't a safe place,
believe me.
You're the only person I have...
...and this is the only way
I know how to do it. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
- Come, have your meal.
- I won't be long.
Fine. Toussaint will save it.
- Hello.
- What's your name?
- Marius.
- And yours?
- I'm Cosette.
Cosette.
- I have something for you.
- Thank you.
Cosette!
- I can warm up your soup.
- I'm coming, Toussaint.
I'll be here.
Tomorrow night. Outside.
See you tomorrow.
Any guns?
- Maybe this is moving too fast.
- Revolution should be rushed.
Progress doesn't have time to waste.
This is pathetic.
Two weeks and what have we got?
Barely enough guns for ourselves.
Then we'll tear up the streets
and we throw stones.
Oh, come on, Marius, throw stones?
They won't attack us with sticks!
- Well?
- They have two kegs of gunpowder...
...stored in the back.
Guns are another story.
- Is there a plan?
- No one can agree on...
...how to make a move.
They argue about whether the people...
-...are ready. Truth is, they're scared.
- These puppies seem harmless.
We should move you to another group.
- Thank you.
- What about this Marius? Anything?
He's in love. He has to go to the food
tent to get a glimpse of his beloved.
Who is the father?
I know you like me to be thorough,
so I checked. He's behind the charity.
I didn't find out much,
only his name. Lafitte.
- Do you know him?
- I don't think so.
Aren't we going for our walk?
Not tonight. I want to finish my book.
But we missed it last night and you've
been in. You need your exercise.
- I'm too tired.
- Are you all right?
Yes, of course. I have my book
and Toussaint is here.
Goodnight, my dear.
Your letter was beautiful.
It was really beautiful.
- Tell me everything.
- Everything? About what?
- About you.
- There's nothing.
There's nothing to tell.
I'm a very simple girl.
I live a very simple life.
I grew up in a convent...
...with lots of other girls, of course.
My father lived there too.
My father's a very good man.
I grew up in his love.
His love was my home.
You know what I mean?
And then I met you.
And you, what about you?
You're a genius, aren't you?
A genius?
A poor student. No brighter
or smarter than anyone else.
Your speech was wonderful.
I didn't breathe while you talked.
I was afraid I'd miss a word.
This week was the same as last?
Every night?
Inspector, they're in love.
It's perfectly nauseating.
She sneaks out the door
and they're together till dawn.
They even stay out there
when it rains.
I haven't caught a gun supplier,
I've caught pneumonia.
- And the father knows nothing?
- This too to me is not a surprise.
I admit the whole experience
has disillusioned me.
I certainly don't plan on having any
children, especially not a daughter.
Can I be reassigned?
Perhaps I could infiltrate...
...some nice anarchists
with a roof over their heads?
Yes. Yes, I'll handle this.
You're relieved.
Take two days off and report to me.
You'll be reassigned.
Thank you. Just out of curiosity,
sir, what are you going to do?
From what you've said,
Lafitte is respectable and well-off.
- Yes.
- A little soft-hearted perhaps...
...but a churchgoer, a loving father?
The neighbourhood
speaks well of him.
Then he deserves to know
his daughter...
...has been seduced
by a dangerous radical.
- Monsieur.
- Toussaint...
...leave your cooking. Come sit
in the garden. It's a glorious day.
- There's someone here to see you.
- Who is it?
-Ins...
- Oh, it doesn't matter.
Inspector Javert. From the police.
- Could you w...
- I'll wait.
- Who was that?
- That w...
- Yes?
- Was a gardener.
- But why? Why say you're away?
- There's no time to explain.
Tell him I've gone away for a week.
If he asks about your past...
...say you have a headache
and excuse yourself.
All right? No details.
- You're frightened.
- No. No, no, no.
Please, just go.
Try not to be nervous.
He'll sense it.
Stay calm and composed.
My father instructed Toussaint to say
he's out when he's on one of his trips...
...so that no one will know we're
two women here by ourselves.
Isn't it ridiculous that he worried
about it with you, a police inspector?
When will he return?
Oh, a week? Hard to say.
- I'll leave him a note. Have an envelope?
- Right here.
Lafitte. I knew a Lafitte.
Where did your people come from?
- Here. Paris.
-Paris?
Probably no relation.
This is for your father's eyes alone...
...and I'd appreciate it if you
gave him the letter yourself.
What a horrible man.
How do you know him?
What does this mean?
"Your daughter has been seduced
by a dangerous radical...
...named Marius Pontmercy.
- She betrays you every night."
- I don't know.
Don't lie to me! Have you
given yourself to this person?
Is it true?
Do you see him every night?
Go ahead, hit me! Is that why I should
tell you, because you'll hit me?
- Tell me the truth.
- How dare you ask for the truth...
...when you only tell me lies?
Why does a policeman
frighten you out of your wits?
Who is he? Who are you?
You don't understand.
You've ruined me. You've ruined us.
You're right. I don't understand.
How can I when you
won't tell me the truth?
What is it? Who are you?
All right, I'm not going to lie.
It's true, I love Marius.
I'm not ashamed.
I only have a corner of a bench
to be with him...
...but that corner is mine.
It's my life.
Is that what's going to ruin us?
Please tell me what this
is all about, Papa.
Please.
Please tell me. What is it?
Please. Please.
What is it?
L----
I am a convict.
A convict?
When I was young, just your age...
...I was very poor. I was starving.
One day I stood in front of a window.
A window full of bread.
There was just glass...
...between me and
not being hungry anymore.
It was so easy.
So I broke it and took what I wanted.
And then they caught me...
...and put me in chains
for almost 20 years.
They did things to me.
I can't tell you about it.
And I did things there in jail.
Terrible things.
I became an animal.
They took my dignity.
They took everything from me.
Inspector, where do you
want me tomorrow?
Should I go back to the Café Musain?
Not right away.
Mingle with the crowd at the square,
see where it takes you.
All right.
Lafitte, did you find out anything
about his background?
He's from Vigau, born and raised.
Lafitte and his daughter Cosette
lived there until 10 years ago.
Cosette? You didn't tell me
her name was Cosette.
You didn't ask.
- Not up here, sir.
- The place is empty, sir.
No one and nothing.
Clean as a whistle.
He moves fast.
Yes, he does.
But there's a way to find him.
- Marius. Have you seen my babies?
- Not now.
Not tonight.
We have to plan tomorrow's action.
We are not having an action.
A revolution.
We can't tolerate this. We can't allow
the king to bury Lamarque as his hero.
- I promise. One hour. One hour.
- No. Marius, this is not a game.
- Tomorrow you have to mean it.
- I mean it.
We'll plan our tactics
when I get back.
When those bastards try to bury
Lamarque, we'll bury them instead.
You hurry back. After tomorrow...
...you can make love to her
as a free man.
Maybe.
Cosette!
"Go to 18 Rue de L'Ouest."
Why? Why?
- He has to leave. I have to go with him.
- What's wrong, Cosette?
- His life is at stake.
- His life? How?
It's a secret, Marius,
I can't give it away.
I was an orphan. He saved me.
He gave me everything.
- I can't leave him right now.
- That means I'll never see you again.
I know what we can do.
We'll talk to him. He'll agree.
- You can come with us to England.
- England?
Cosette, are you crazy?
Tomorrow we're going to fight.
We're going to restore the Republic.
I can't run away now. Why do you have
to go to England? Why now? Why?
- He needs me, Marius. He needs me.
- Why do you have to go now?
He took care of me,
and now he needs me.
I understand.
Don't be sad, Marius. Please.
Don't be sad, Marius.
When? When? When do you leave?
Tomorrow no one can leave Paris
because of Lamarque's funeral.
He's not sure.
He said we might leave the next day.
I'll be here tomorrow night.
Promise me. Promise me
you'll meet me here.
It's obvious
we have them outnumbered.
There are 24,000 troops in the city...
...and they can be reinforced
by another 30,000 in two days.
So the question is,
where to deploy them?
My informers say the critical moment is
when the procession passes the square.
That's where they'll start the fighting.
Well, we won't fight them
for every inch. We'll surround them.
Long live the Republic! Long live...
It's frightening, Papa.
Why are they so angry about this?
Lamarque was a hero
who fought for the Republic.
Why is the king giving Lamarque
a state funeral?
He's trying to claim Lamarque
as his own hero.
It's a lie, it's the final insult.
That's why they're angry.
Long live the Republic!
- Long live the Republic!
- Long live...
Long live Lamarque!
Long live the Republic!
- Long live the Republic!
- Lamarque is ours!
- Come on!
Let's bury Lamarque!
Lamarque is our hero!
Come on, everybody, pull!
Come on!
Long live the Republic!
To the barricades!
Get down!
Move up!
Your information is as good as gold...
...but the idiots
in the municipal guard...
...ignored your advice
about the arsenal.
Javert, why are you dressed
like that?
Because I'm on the trail of someone
who is very dangerous.
It will be an important arrest. Possibly
the most important of my career.
Indeed? Who is it?
I'd rather not say until I've got him.
At the very least,
show me where you're going.
Past the perimeter. Here.
There are dozens of barricades.
Anything could happen.
We have no control in this area.
It's under control, sir.
As soon as it's dark, we'll go through
the barrier. Hundreds are fleeing.
Police don't care who leaves. More
concerned about people coming in...
...so it's a perfect opportunity.
Cosette, please!
How bad is the fighting?
I didn't go anywhere near it.
I went the other way.
- What are they saying?
- No one really knows what's happening.
The streets are full of barricades.
Everyone says something different.
Whatever the truth is,
a lot of people will die tonight.
Is it too dangerous for us
to wait till the morning?
He's not in the barricades?
I promised I'd wait.
Even if he can't come, I have to wait.
- It hurts this much?
- I'm sorry.
I've known him only a few weeks,
that's what you think.
I'm only a silly girl, he's little more than
a stranger. But that's not how I feel.
I understand, my dear.
Your papers.
Right.
Marius. Not tonight.
One hour.
I'll be gone one hour.
- I found my boys.
- Well done, Gavroche.
Marius.
The law is here
to protect you, Cosette...
...from criminals like this scum.
Is Valjean here? Is he alone?
I'll never tell you anything.
Do you know who and what
you're protecting?
Didn't he tell you
he's a common thief?
- I know exactly who he is.
- Oh, yes? Did he tell you who you are?
Did he tell you
you're a bastard child?
your mother was a whore?
- You're breaking the law.
- Untie me.
There'll be no turning back.
Who are you?
I'm Chief Inspector Javert. If you
surrender, things will go better for you.
Surrender? I'm taking you
to face the people's justice.
At the barricades?
You fool. Don't you know
your revolution has no chance?
If we die, you die with us.
Goodbye, Marius.
I love you, Cosette.
Go on!
He came to say goodbye.
He loves me, Papa.
He loves me.
Take her to our old house.
It's going to be all right.
I promise you.
Fire at will!
So here we are.
I was right.
You know him?
When we have a spare bullet,
we're going to kill him.
What are you doing here?
Where is Cosette?
Waiting for you in the house
where you fell in love.
- Go to her. Go to her.
- I can't. Not now.
- Not now.
- She's your future.
If we can't win,
then none of us have a future.
You have love.
That's the only future God gives us.
Go.
Gavroche, get back!
- Gavroche!
- I need bullets.
- Get back here!
Come back!
- Gavroche!
- Get back here!
Gavroche! Come back!
Come back!
Papa!
'Papa!
'Papa.
Let's do it now.
- You proud of your work?
- You're next.
Let me do it.
You kill him in the alley.
We don't want his blood
in here with ours.
A knife. That's right.
It suits you better.
Why? Why couldn't you
leave me alone?
- I'm nothing. I'm no one!
- Yes, but you've managed to beat me.
I'm not trying to beat you.
I want to live in peace!
Then hurry up and do it.
Your friends need you.
That way. Through the gate.
You'll be safe.
- You plan to shoot me in the back.
- I'm letting you go, Javert.
You'd better hurry.
They won't be merciful.
Go on.
You should kill me.
I won't stop.
Understand?
I won't let you go.
You should end this.
Kill me.
You're dead, Javert.
- Get back!
- Everybody, get back!
- Yes, sir!
- On the back! Back!
Take them in two!
Have at them, lads!
Surrender!
Surrender or be shot!
- Well done! Men, search the building!
- Yes, sir!
Stand. Stand.
- Look on the other side of the street!
- Sir!
Follow me!
You men in there,
check that doorway!
Come on. Do it. Jump.
Long live the Republic!
- Long live the Republic!
- This way, lads. Be quick about it.
Long live the Republic!
- Aim!
- Long live the Republic!
Long live the Republic!
Fire!
- You two, look on the roof.
- Sir.
Get some lanterns. Hurry.
- This way.
- He's smarter than that.
He'll go downhill to the river.
Come on.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's all right.
Now, come on, help me.
You must help me.
Push.
Push!
Pull. Pull!
Is he alive?
Careful.
- He needs a doctor.
- To make him healthy...
...for the firing squad?
You know there'll be an amnesty
in a few days. It's me you want.
- Yes.
- Arrest me.
Let him go.
- Is that all you care about?
- You've caught me.
That's what you care about.
Let him take the boy where he wants.
Then bring him back hereto me.
- Marius. Marius.
- He'll live.
- Toussaint, find a doctor.
- Yes, monsieur.
Marius.
Take some money.
Promise him more.
- Yes, monsieur.
- Go, go!
I promised I would give you this.
It was your mother's.
She was a good woman.
I loved her, Cosette.
- No.
- I've told you everything.
- Take care of him. Live a happy life.
- No!
I made an arrangement, my dear.
I have to go.
- Promise me you'll be happy.
- No. Not like this, Papa, not like this.
This is right, my dear.
I stole something, I did.
I stole happiness with you.
I don't mind paying.
- Go to him. He is your life now.
- Please.
No.
Bring him here.
That is an important memo
for the prefect.
It explains what I've done
with the prisoner.
- Make sure he sees it before breakfast.
- Sir.
I'm glad I had time to myself.
I needed to think about
what you deserve.
You're a difficult problem.
Move to the edge.
- Why aren't you taking me in?
- You're my prisoner. Do what I tell you!
You don't understand
the importance of the law.
I've given you an order. Obey it.
Why didn't you kill me?
I don't have the right to kill you.
But you hate me.
I don't hate you.
I don't feel anything.
You don't want to go back
to the quarries, do you?
Then for once, we agree.
I'm going to spare you
from a life in prison, Jean Valjean.
It's a pity the rules don't allow me
to be merciful.
I've tried to live my life
without breaking a single rule.
You're free.