This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Episode 8
Mi Nam.
- Yes, this is it!
- Yes.
The feeling is just right. This will do.
It's totally different.
Manager Ma, is Go Mi Nam sick?
I don't know. Where did he go?
Mi Nam.
What's going on?
Did something happen before the recording?
What should we do?
You saw how Mi Nam's feelings burst out, right?
That's why I'm asking you!
I told him to sing your song
with an explosive feeling of love.
I think it has really exploded now.
What?
I think her heart is exploding for Kang Shin Woo.
Go Mi Nam.
I thought it was strange that she came back with
Shin Woo after refusing to return for so long.
Why does she have to like him?
She should have just liked me.
Hey, Tae Kyung, what do we do?
Where is she?
I'm sorry, Shin Woo hyung.
What's this?
Don't go.
I think it's better to leave him alone.
Mi Nam?
He went somewhere to calm down.
I wanted to follow him,
but it looks like we should leave him alone.
He didn't say anything else to you?
He just said that he's having a hard time.
He must be stressed since it's his first recording.
Looks like he doesn't know anything.
Should I talk to Mi Nam? Tae Kyung!
Why are you asking me that?
We are on the same side.
I never thought I was on the same side
as you and Go Mi Nam.
You guys solve it yourselves.
Tch! Go Mi Nam's love exploded for Kang Shin Woo?
The absurdity is explosive!
Mother Superior...
My feelings keeps flowing out.
I wish I could become invisible
so that no one could find out about my feelings.
If I slowly disappear,
No one will notice me, right?
Go Mi Nam.
Jeremy. Can you see me?
Of course.
I've been looking at you for awhile.
So I didn't disappear
because Jeremy was watching...
You can't disappear...
Because we need to have a celebration
for your first recording.
Whoo!! Hello! Hello!
Go Mi Nam, you should say hello too!
Hello, everyone!
Jeremy, you really do like celebrations.
Celebrations are good things.
But you're not happy at all, right, Go Mi Nam?
I'm sorry.
Really?
Then I'll just let you cry a lot.
I really can't stop my tears.
It's really spicy, right?
This restaurant has ten levels of spiciness.
This is level eight. Level eight.
Should we challenge it until the end?
I accept the challenge!
I need to melt this with some ice cream.
We were really great.
If there were 12 levels,
I'm sure we would have succeeded too.
Of course.
We would have been able to eat it all.
Ah this is a cookie!
Go Mi Nam, since you've cried your eyes out,
I'll let you laugh this time.
Let's go.
Jeremy. This is really fun.
Right.
Hello everyone. I love you all!
Please look forward to our sixth album!
This bus is a precious secret that I found.
I'm only telling you about it.
Like you said, there are really
not that many people here.
It takes this bus an hour
to make exactly one round.
Whenever I'm feeling down,
I ride on this for one round,
And my heart calms down.
Then will my heart calm down too?
Of course! My precious bus is magic.
Let's meet again in an hour.
Can my heart really calm down in an hour?
For this one hour, I like you, Go Mi Nam.
I'm glad you had some fun with Jeremy.
Everyone must have been
shocked when I ran out like that.
I'm very sorry.
It's all right.
You sang really well.
Your outburst during the recording was really good,
But you have to control your feelings.
If it's too much, it'll bring trouble.
So I couldn't control it well?
I was thinking about a way to control it.
You know about pressure points, right?
When you're really hungry,
press your ears here.
And when you need to go number 2...
When you really need to poo, push this part.
When you can't stay awake, push here.
Ah, I think I've heard about this.
Just like that, when you can't control your feelings...
Nose... Touch your nose like this.
Here?
That's right. That's right.
When you can't control your feelings,
Or you feel your heart beating fast
when you see someone,
Press this part hard.
But won't someone think
it's weird if they see this?
Even though it seems strange, it'll work.
The harder it is to control,
the harder you should press.
It'll be better.
Press hard.
Thank you for taking care of these things for me.
Well, of course.
I'll remember it.
The innocent sister really believes my words...
I'm really sorry.
But at least if she does this,
The other party won't realize her feelings.
Go Mi Nam, come here.
I helped organize your situation.
What are you doing?
I'm just pushing a pressure point
Pressure point?
It's something I have to do.
Don't worry about me and just continue talking.
Are you messing with me?
Ah, you're trying to imitate the pig that chased me.
This guy that is like the rabbit
I hate now dares to imitate a pig?!
It's not like that.
I won't do it.
Don't move your hand.
Just listen like that.
I'll kill you if you put your hand down.
Listen carefully, piggy rabbit.
I'll tell you the path you should take from now on.
First, you should tell Shin Woo that you're a girl.
Huh? Why?
I heard you like Kang Shin Woo.
What?
Of course I thought it was absurd
when I first heard about it,
But thinking about it more,
I see how it could have happened.
Go Mi Nam.
I'll hand you over to Kang Shin Woo.
It's not like that. You've misunderstood.
Hand!
There are two possibilities when you tell Shin Woo.
First, he'll accept you.
Even though I feel sorry for Shin Woo,
it's good because you can be open about your feelings.
And it's good for me because I can get rid of you.
Second, he won't accept you.
Even though this is only advantageous for me,
If something like that happens,
you'll just have to beg and hold onto Shin Woo.
If you can be half as persistent as you were with me,
I'm sure you can hold onto him.
Hyung-nim. This is really a misunderstanding.
It's not like that at all.
No matter what, I'm advising you to tell Shin Woo.
Work hard, Go Mi Nam.
Even though he didn't find out,
he misunderstood.
This situation is not good for me.
What is it?
I was doing origami.
What are you making?
A plane.
Ah, I can't do it like this.
You're really clueless.
You have to fold it like this
so that no one can see what's inside.
Ah, I see.
Do you want me to tell you
a story of a really clueless girl?
This girl carried a really big secret and entered a group.
A really clueless girl?
Yes. How clueless was she?
As soon as she got in, a member
in the group found out about her.
But she didn't know and kept on with her activities.
Why does the member keep quiet?
At first he just wanted to watch for the fun of it.
That person was really bored.
But as he watched on,
the girl was just so clueless.
It was funny, yet he pitied her.
- Go Mi Nam.
- President.
Let's go to the sauna.
My skin here is very sensitive.
- Then you should go to the sauna.
- I really don't want to go to the sauna.
We're all guys. What's the problem?
I know a really pretty massage lady.
A lady?
Yes.
President! Don't go to the sauna.
Let's just eat together.
Guys need to go to the sauna
to have heart-to-heart talks.
Then got eat with me, Mi Nam.
Eat?
I like eating!
He was sucked in as he kept watching over her.
Getting a massage is good.
It was his first time keeping an eye on someone else.
And without realizing it,
he started helping that girl.
Mi Nam, help me with this.
Then the girl should be really thankful to him.
That girl doesn't know.
I told you she's really clueless, right?
Then why won't he tell her?
It's for the sake of the group members and her safety.
So he has to keep quiet for now.
When the time comes,
that feeling will get through, right?
Accept this.
Thank you.
It's cold. You should go inside.
Shin Woo hyung is a good person.
I can't tell him.
Even though it's hard, you have to endure,
And keep holding onto Hyung-nim.
I can't do my work because of that kid.
Her feelings burst for who?
She sang well.
So she likes him so much that she can't stop her tears?
So this was the trouble she caused?
I really can't let my guard down.
You rabbit-like guy
She's so ungrateful.
It's been a long time and she's not back yet.
Don't tell me she's already begging
Shin Woo after telling him?
Well, that's her specialty.
She could have decided quickly.
Is she there again?
She's not here either.
Don't tell me she really went over
to tell Shin Woo everything.
Where the hell is she?
Hyung-nim.
Please don't hand me over to Shin Woo hyung.
I really won't cause you
any more problems in the future.
Go Mi Nam, did you decide to only drag me down?
You know that you've brought me a lot of trouble, right?
If you're aware,
then don't take up that much space.
Just sleep on half of the blanket
so you won't cause me any problems.
Ah, so troublesome.
Mi Nam's song really came out well.
We just need to shoot a nice music video now,
And it'll be a hit.
It would be good if Hwang Tae Kyung
and Yoo He Yi come out in the music video.
Good idea. At last, you've come up with something I like!
Right?
The best hot couple as main characters of the music video.
That's like winning the jackpot.
The story of the music video...
It should be something spectacular with lots of action,
like blockbuster scenes.
Just like this...
A lonely killer meets a sexy killer.
They're saving the world from an evil power.
They go to Paris, France,
Rome, Italy,
And the desert in Egypt.
No. No. No.
We don't have that kind of budget.
And going overseas, shooting guns, and blowing
things up won't necessarily make it good.
It doesn't match the song's concept.
Something else.
President.
What about an erotic, adult, love version?
What do you think?
That doesn't sound too bad.
It gives people a sticky sweet feeling.
Just like this.
That lonely killer and sexy killer,
Wrapped in passion, advance toward each other,
With burning feelings,
The two of them finally...
Approach each other,
And touch each other slowly with their hands...
Slowly...
Advancing... Gradually...
Sexily.
No. No. No.
What kind of concept is that?
The singer and main characters
have very clean images.
We can't have any bed scenes.
What about a love story,
Without words.
We just have to shoot their youth,
cuteness, and passion.
- It's a hit.
- GO!
- Go.
- Okay. Jackpot!
It would have been good to have an explosion scene.
Mi Nam, you don't have to do any complicated acting.
Just look at Tae Kyung and Yoo He Yi.
Tae Kyung, you've shot this kind of thing a lot,
so please take care of Mi Nam.
I have to take care of him again?
Ah, this is getting tiring.
I'm sorry, Hyung-nim.
Please do well.
Because of the scandal,
Yoo He Yi's movie made a lot of money.
We should also...
Ah... I'm sorry for using your love for business.
No. Since it's already like this,
You should make a lot of money.
Right? That's right.
Yoo He Yi will be here once
she finishes her performance.
Don't just take care of your girlfriend.
Take care of Mi Nam too.
Do well!
Director Oh!
What girlfriend?
I won't disturb you two.
Please don't worry about me.
Go Mi Nam.
When Yoo He Yi is here, stick with me at all times.
No. I'll stay far away so that I don't disturb you.
Go Mi Nam, I'll decide where you stay.
Don't interrupt.
Then I'll stay this close.
Come closer.
Are you like gum? That's too close.
Stop.
We have to shoot all that's planned
before the sun sets, so listen carefully.
Yes, Hyung-nim.
He looks like Mi Nam.
Can I approach him?
Yes. I'm shooting.
Raise your head higher.
Chin higher.
Good.
Closer together.
Very good.
Good.
Be brighter!
Very good.
Okay.
- Where are you going?
- Shin Woo.
Excuse me. I'm looking for this woman.
I think she was with Hwang Tae Kyung
after the stage performance that you guys had.
Do you know who this woman is?
Performance day?
I think Tae Kyung hyung was with Go Mi Nam.
Go Mi Nam? That can't be right.
Yes, I'm sure he was with Go Mi Nam.
I don't know this woman.
Really?
Then I'll just have to meet Go Mi Nam and ask him.
Thank you.
All right, everyone pay attention in class.
Only Tae Kyung stares out the window and thinks of He Yi.
And thinks some more...
More hazily...
She's walking over.
Mi Nam, glance at Tae Kyung.
Student, there!
Pay attention in class!
Why are you looking back?
I'm sorry.
CUT!
Only the lighting technicians move.
The others stay put.
Don't move an inch!
What's wrong?
That guy keeps looking at you.
Who is he?
Who?
He's been acting weird.
Maybe you know him?
Maybe. I don't really know anyone.
He's my oppa's friend.
They were best friends in high school.
What should I do?
It'd be strange if I couldn't recognize my best friend.
Then just pretend to know him and say hi.
But I don't remember his name.
Hyung-nim...
You've been looking at me for awhile.
Looks like you're a fan.
But... I wasn't looking at you.
I'll sign an autograph for you.
What's your name?
It's all right.
What is your name?
Kim Dong Jun.
Kim Dong Jun?
Hey Dong Jun.
Mi Nam!
You did recognize me after all.
Of course. You're my best friend.
You jerk!
Hey! Do you know how bummed I was, thinking you
were ignoring me now that you're a celebrity?
Hey, that wouldn't happen.
Dong Jun, calm down.
How long has it been, Go Mi Nam?
It was your dream to be a singer,
And you really became one.
You're really cool, my friend.
You punk!
Go Mi Nam?
You have to get ready for filming.
Hurry in.
Yes, Hyung-nim.
Ah, right, you must be busy.
After all, you're the star.
Oh...
- What?
- Where's the scar you had here?
Huh?
You split your hand here after you fell
when we were riding bikes, remember?
It was a pretty big scar.
But, it's gone now.
Oh! Th-that, that...
There's no need to hide the surgery from your friend, is there?
Didn't you say you had work done
in several spots before your debut, Go Mi Nam?
Yes, I did.
Ahh. You must have done that
now that you're a celebrity.
Now that I look closely, your face looks thinner.
Yeah, I had some work done here and there. Don't keep staring.
It's okay. I totally understand.
We're going to start shooting,
so everyone who needs to should use the restroom now!
Hey, Mi Nam.
It's been a long time.
Wanna go take a leak together?
Huh?
C'mon!
Hey, do you remember how we used to
bet on whose could reach the farthest?
Should we give it a go today?
Uh... Hyung-nim!
Let's take a leak.
It's been a really long time
since we've peed together.
Kim Dong Jun?
It seems like you're a fan of ours.
Which song is your favorite?
I'm sorry. I don't really know A.N.JELL's songs.
Then,
You must know this song.
I will promise you
I will live with only you in my eyes.
Ahhh!
I will promise you...
- I will live holding you in my arms...
- Ah, I'm done.
Already?
Yeah, I'll be going out now.
Getting to sing in the bathroom
with a top star like you, Hyung-nim,
That was an honor.
If I had just taken off then,
Kang Shin Woo would probably be standing here singing.
So, here I can find Yoo He Yi,
Go Mi Nam, Hwang Tae Kyung...
All the people I need to prod.
Now!
We're filming the lunch hour.
Since no sound will be recorded for the music video,
Chatter naturally as you eat.
Hey, you must be playing a wealthy kid.
Your lunch looks really good.
Hyung-nim is playing a poor kid,
so he just has dried anchovies.
He wants some of the omelet,
But the situation won't allow it.
Seeing the omelet reminds me of your sister.
You always gathered stuff she liked
from the other kids and took it to her class.
Mmm. I did, didn't I?
So, even though I don't like eggs,
I always asked mom to pack me omelets.
Because she'd be eating it.
You did?
Tch, I guess you liked her, huh?
It took me this long to say anything,
But I really liked your sister.
I couldn't say anything because it was a friend's sister,
But your sister...
Was my first love.
Tch, now I've seen everything.
I really never knew.
Actually, I'm leaving for the army tomorrow.
And I was thinking about your sister a lot.
Seeing you makes me feel like I saw her.
Really?
Go Mi Nam?
You're a guy. Isn't it bad thing to look like your sister?
Uh, yeah, you're right, Hyung-nim.
Wow, you've totally got it!
She's smiling.
She's totally lost it.
Go Mi Nam?
You'd better restrain yourself.
It looked like sparks were gonna fly
when you guys were rubbing your heads together.
He's his closest friend. What can I do?
Hey, Mi Nam!
Hyung-nim, please distract Dong Jun
so I can go to the bathroom.
Mi Nam!
Kim Dong Jun.
Ah, Hyung-nim.
Have one of these.
I hear you're living together.
I bet Mi Nam's a lot of trouble.
Mmm, he's a lot of trouble. A ton.
By any chance, does Mi Nam's sister come and visit?
Well, I've seen his sister.
Ahh, she's really pretty, isn't she?
Why don't you ask Go Mi Nam if you can see her
before you go to serve in the army?
That's okay. I'll see her after I serve.
After?
I'm studying to be a pharmacist.
After I graduate, I'm going back to
my hometown to open a pharmacy.
And I'll make sure I find her then.
And what will you do when you find her?
My dream is to quickly get married and live a cozy life, running my pharmacy.
Ahh, can you keep it a secret from Mi Nam?
Go Mi Nam,
After you leave, it looks like
you'll be a pharmacist's wife.
Hello.
Yoo He Yi!
Looks like you're late.
I have to get to dress rehearsal.
Ah, because your scandal with Hwang Tae Kyung,
Your movie was well-promoted, wasn't it?
Don't imply that we created
a scandal to promote the movie.
And the music video will be such a hit with you in it.
Hwang Tae Kyung must be thrilled.
Our relationship is not a business deal.
It's real.
Ahh, is that so?
Um, you remember this picture, don't you?
At the time, we weren't sure how things were going,
so I couldn't say anything.
I'm sorry I said it wasn't me.
Aye... What are you lying for?
Excuse me?
You weren't with Hwang Tae Kyung, were you?
This isn't you, is it?
You're making things quite difficult.
I heard Hwang Tae Kyung was
with Go Mi Nam during that time.
Then, I guess I can go ask Go Mi Nam
whether this is you or not.
Please, go ahead.
Now, then...
What has he sniffed out?
I'd better go talk to Hwang Tae Kyung.
After all, it wasn't Yoo He Yi.
Go Mi Nam will have already have matched up his story.
So how should I pierce through that?
Now, now!
Have a conversation like you're good friends.
Ready, action!
Go Mi Nam.
I didn't recognize you as a future pharmacist's wife.
I'm not a pharmacist's wife.
Stop it.
Later on, why don't you send me vitamins
and supplements occasionally?
Considering the mishaps you got me into,
shouldn't you do at least that much?
Hyung-nim, we're supposed to act like
we're close friends in this scene.
You can give me a hard time later.
So you have the nerve now to give me warnings?
Even if you quit A.N.JELL,
You'll be a pharmacist's wife in the future,
So I guess you're not afraid of anything?
Mi Nam!
Play like good friend and throw some leaves.
Ha ha, Hyung-nim, cut it out.
Ha ha ha.
Ah, ah! Really!
Hey, hey...
That mood, it's good.
Like you're close friends. Like close friends.
Cut!
Very nice!
That last piggy nose was especially a nice touch.
Now, next scene!
Go Mi Nam,
Why are you doing that again?
I just thought it would be a funny to ad lib.
Thought it would be funny? Ha! Funny, my foot.
Just try that again, you little rabbit pig.
Try it. Try it again.
Ah! Yoo He Yi is here.
Right.
I heard the two of you put on a great act.
Oppa and Mi Nam, you guys are so good and natural.
Compared to your outstanding acting, we're just posers.
Oh, that's a compliment about my acting, isn't it, Oppa?
You've really gotten dusty. Is it because of the leaves?
I'm bad at acting and feel like my limbs are shriveling up, so let's cool the act.
Why? You were acting pretty well just now.
Laugh like you were earlier.
If your acting is good, I'll give you a prize.
That wasn't acting earlier.
So then you were laughing because of her?
Fine. Go ahead, laugh and have a good time.
I won't tell you what Reporter Kim suspects.
Wow. That looks good.
Auntie, have you tried that?
How can I eat that?
- Such a fresh-looking thing.
- Totally, fresh.
It's good!
It is good.
Hey, hey, now we need to get down to business.
Here. I thought you might want these,
So I brought a few things.
Now, let's see some excitement.
Pick, pick, pick.
This.
Oh. It's Jeremy's.
Jeremy oppa must have washed his face with this today.
What about this?
That's Shin Woo's.
Oh, it's Shin Woo oppa's razor!
I wish I could be his whiskers.
You don't have anything from Tae Kyung oppa?
Hey, Leader is like a phantom.
I touch his stuff and he'll know right away.
The supply stream would be cut off.
Instead, I'll give you some top secret info.
In my Mi Nam's music video, Leader...
Will be sporting a school uniform.
- A school uniform?
- Yeah.
- Tae Kyung Oppa will be wearing a uniform like us?
I bet he'll look so good!
Do you guys like them that much?
The way I see them,
Those scrawny, soft, wimpy guys don't seem like much.
Soft and wimpy?
Nothing much? Ahjumma!
Ahjumma,
Don't you know they're legends?
Legends?
The A.N.JELL legends!
If you heard Kang Shin Woo's story,
You wouldn't be able to say "wimpy".
Look for more on him.
Aye, what the hell is this?
Get him!
Under Busan's Nampodong Overpass,
Seventeen to one... Complete victory.
That's our Shin Woo oppa.
That gentle little Mister Kang... fights?
Aye...
And if you heard Jeremy's legend,
You wouldn't be able to say "nothing much".
Jeremy!
You've heard that Jeremy's grandfather
was a phenomenon in Scotland, haven't you?
Britain's 23rd in line for the throne,
Princess Amy, was Jeremy oppa's fiancée.
So you're saying that little snail
gave up his princess to come to Korea and sing?
Aye...
From Princess Amy's point of view, it's sad,
But to us it's a blessing!
Aigoo, aigoo, you sure can tell the stories.
Then what's Leader's legend?
There is an incredible mystery
around Tae Kyung oppa's birth.
They say his mother is a really famous
and beautiful woman.
But who she is, nobody knows except
Tae Kyung and his father.
Really?
Yes.
His birthday is even a mystery.
The day that his birthday is celebrated
Is just one that is told to the public,
But I hear it's not his real birthday.
Only those two people know his real birthday.
Yes, Father.
I didn't even realize it was my birthday.
Anyhow, there's another day that people celebrate it...
Today has no meaning to me.
Still, I sent a gift.
I sent it so it would arrive today,
so you should be getting it.
Did the Seattle performance go well?
And you and Joanna are doing well?
Give her my best.
Yes.
Couldn't he have just let it pass?
Why remember it every year
and make me think about it?
Aish, where did Hwang Tae Kyung go now?
Is he with Go Mi Nam?
What's he doing?
With yet another guy...
Is she pretending to be a guy
so she can hang out with guys?
I'll be sure and wear these sneakers
as I go off to serve in the army.
Here.
Mi Nam.
Have you seen Tae Kyung oppa?
Weren't the two of you filming together?
He took off right after we finished and I can't find him.
And this is?
I'm a high school friend of Mi Nam.
Hey, I'm talking to a lot of famous
people today because of you.
Thanks, bud.
High school friend?
Mi Nam must be pretty different than he was in high school.
He's just like he was back then.
Ah, is that so?
Well, then...
Tch, what a pair.
Sending reporter Kim over would be pretty fun, I think.
Shall we see Go Mi Nam scared out of her wits?
Wow.
Thanks a lot, Mi Nam, really.
What do you mean thanks? You're my friend.
Smell it.
And I'll smell yours.
Hey, hey!
Huh?
Mi Nam,
Are these really your shoes?
Yes, why?
It's nothing...
Go Mi Nam?
Dong Jun, take care,
And when you get out, contact Go Mi Nam.
Mi Nam and I had the same shoe size.
Is there surgery to make your feet smaller?
Excuse me!
Yoo He Yi tells me you're Go Mi Nam's high school friend.
Is that correct?
So did you get a guarantee for that
pharmacist's wife position?
Don't tease me.
He's really a close friend of my brother's.
And you said your farewells?
Yes, but his final expression didn't look so good.
I wonder if it was because he was sad.
I even signed his shoe.
Why not exchange shoes to seal your promise?
Shoes.
Mi Nam,
Are these really your shoes?
The shoe size... is different.
My brother and I have really different sized feet.
It's a reporter.
Dong Jun has probably figured out I'm not my brother.
Go Mi Nam?
Mi Nam is my closest friend.
He's a good kid,
And a really cool... guy.
Since I'm going into the army tomorrow,
I won't be seeing any other people.
And you know I don't have loose lips, right?
I'll go then.
Take care, Mi Nam.
Goodbye, Dong Jun.
I... really liked your sister.
Bye! Thanks!
That, that... She may really become a pharmacist's wife.
Hwang Tae Kyung.
You brought your car, right?
I didn't bring mine. Give me a ride.
I came in the van.
I don't have a car.
Really? Then take me in my car.
Aren't you embarrassed,
changing your story in one breath?
You already know I'm like this.
So what do I need to be embarrassed about?
As long as people who don't know
continue not to know, it doesn't matter.
I guess you're threatening, bullying,
true nature isn't entirely dishonest.
On that point, you're quite impressive.
I'm pretty impressive on another point.
It seemed like Reporter Kim was trailing
Go Mi Nam earlier, so I diverted him.
That's a threat, isn't it?
Think whatever you like.
When people are looking, open
the door for me and drive for me.
If I ask you to carry my bag,
you won't, will you?
Hey, you think it's heavy?
Can't you just carry it once?
I can't bother Hyung-nim.
Mi Nam, we're taking off now.
Did the filming go well?
Shin Woo hyung.
Kang Shin Woo sure is nice to Go Mi Nam.
He doesn't know she's a girl, does he?
If he found out, he'd probably feel pretty lousy.
I guess that's why she doesn't want Shin Woo to know.
Tae Kyung is leaving separately?
You didn't have to come. I can take the van.
Well, since I came all the way out here,
let's take my car.
Hwang Tae Kyung,
Aren't you hungry?
I'm not.
I'm hungry.
I have to have spaghetti.
If you go a little further,
there's this spaghetti place I like.
I want to eat their spaghetti, so stop there.
Who's this?
What are you calling about?
Let's meet today.
After all, I made a mistake at the restaurant that last time.
I won't forget today,
and I'll prepare properly,
So let's talk over a meal.
Meet me there.
Just like her to dictate a meeting
on her own schedule.
Who is it?
Where is the spaghetti place?
What? Over there. You can go in right here.
Hey!
I brought you like you asked.
Enjoy your spaghetti.
Hey!
Where are you going?!
Oppa, thanks for giving me a ride!
Bye!
Auntie,
How can you open Hyung-nim's package
from the states like this?
It was no big deal.
It's going to be opened anyway, whether by him or me...
Oh, I gotta go pee...
How am I going to tape this up so he can't tell?
It's the record you wanted so much.
Happy birthday, from your father.
Birthday?
Is today his birthday?
Still, it's been ten years since
she called me on my birthday.
It's really been a long time
since I've released a record.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
Congratulations.
- I'll need a lot of your help this time.
- Of course.
Rather, you'll be helping us out.
He's here.
Young Mr. Hwang Tae Kyung, you've come?
I'm Reporter Choi from the Asia Times.
I interviewed you before. Do you remember?
We heard you were doing a remake of Mo Hwa Ran's song,
And we asked for an interview right away.
Thank you for agreeing to meet with us.
Please have a seat. Let's talk while we eat.
You can't eat shrimp, right?
I was careful this time.
Watching out for his food preferences and aversions...
It seems that you two have a very close relationship.
I'm sorry. I have a personal matter and can't stay.
I'm sorry.
It's good I saved it.
I bet he'll like it as a birthday present.
Since he's a fan.
Tae Kyung hyung is a fan of yours.
He is?
My fan?
I've seen a bunch of your old movies
and records in his room.
Jeremy.
Aren't we having a party today?
Huh? For what?
It's Tae Kyung hyung-nim's birthday.
But today's not his birthday.
We had a birthday party in the spring in May.
That's strange.
It said birthday.
I'll ask Hyung-nim when he comes in.
Tae Kyung said he wasn't coming back tonight.
He just told me on the phone that he was
going to work all night at the studio.
Jolie.
Then why did his father send him a birthday gift?
How dare you humiliate me like that.
You were so angry about it that
you came all the way over here?
I guess you're no longer afraid
that people will find out.
Right, I'm not afraid any longer.
What do I have to lose?
Frankly, I'm considering revealing that you're my son.
Then people will notice us more.
What, are you afraid now?
Where is he?
I don't want to this song I'm re-releasing to be overlooked.
I want the world to take notice and listen to it.
To that end, I need you.
Did you love him that much,
the writer of that song?
That love is the reason you abandoned me, isn't it?
Don't mock me like that.
That was the most precious thing to me.
It was the most horrific thing to me.
Please go.
But I gave birth to you!
Because of you, because I gave birth
to you, I lost what was precious to me.
Okay, you must have thought
it was horrific because I left you.
But when I lost him because of you,
it was horrific for me too.
Since I gave birth to you,
At least help me to keep that love as a memory.
If you're going to claim some credit
for giving birth to me,
At least...
At the very least, you should have
remembered when that was.
Was it today?
Main Translators: hot_saranghae, meju
Spot Translators: adorabelle, karened
Timer: szhoang
Editor/QC: Athaclena42
Final QC: ay_link
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Mother Superior,
my star is crying in the dark...
What should I do?
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Watch dramas legally @ dramafever.com
STOP illegal streaming sites