Sixteen-fifty for you, 16.50 for me.
Loretta, I'm leaving.
What do you mean?
Soon as I get my check, I'm gone.
I'll be back.
-Dwight, I need my check.
-Payday's at the end of the month.
Haven't paid us for last month.
I need money, Loretta's got a kid--
Problem with management?
Put a note in the suggestion box.
-I'm serious. I'm quitting.
-I'll be back for the dinner shift.
I sure as hell won't be.
What are you doing?
I'm taking what he owes me,
not a penny more.
You take that money,
he's gonna come after you.
-Gotta find me first.
-What you gonna do?
This ought to cover that bike
for little Keith.
You're late to pick him up.
Go. I got everything covered here.
You're really going?
I'm really going.
That bike can wait till Christmas.
You keep what he owes you.
I'll deal with Dwight, okay?
See you later.
♫Oh, sometimes I get a good feeling, yeah
♫(Yeah)
♫I get a feeling that I never, never, never, never had before no, no
♫And I just gotta tell you right now, that I
♫That I believe, I really do believe that
♫Something's got a hold on me, yeah
♫(Oh, it must be love)
♫Oh, something's got a hold on me right now, child
♫Let me tell you now, I got a feeling, I feel so strange
♫Everything about me seems to have changed
♫Step by step, I got a brand new walk
♫I even sound sweeter when I talk
♫I said, oh
♫(Oh)
-♫Whoa
-♫(Oh)
-♫Oh
♫I said, baby, oh, it must be love
♫(You know it must be love)
How much to Los Angeles?
-One-way or round-trip?
-You're kidding, right?
♫Let me tell you now my heart feels heavy, my feet feel light
♫I shake all over but I feel alright
♫I never felt like this before
♫Something's got a hold on me that won't let go
♫I never thought it could happen to me
♫Got me happy when I'm in misery
♫I never thought it could be this way
♫Love's sure gonna put a hurting on me
-♫I said, oh
-♫(Oh)
-♫Oh
♫Oh, I said, baby, oh, it must be love
♫(You know it must be love)
-♫Yeah, he walks like love
-(♫You know he walks like love)
-♫He talks like love
-(♫You know he talks like love)
-♫Makes me feel alright
-(♫Makes me feel alright)
-♫In the middle of the night
-(♫In the middle of the night)
-♫La, la, la, la
-(♫La, la, la, la)
♫Oh, yeah, uh, hey
♫Hey
♫Yeah, uh
Hey, Coco. Coco Puff, you're on.
Come on. You're on, you're on.
We may not have windows...
...but we do have the best view
on Sunset Strip.
Twenty bucks.
What is this place, a strip club?
''Strip club''?
I should wash your mouth out
with Jugermeister.
The only pole you'll find in there
is Natasha, the shot girl.
Babycakes, I got a club to fill here.
Right, sorry.
Enjoy.
♫Show a little more
♫Show a little less
♫Add a little smoke
♫Welcome to Burlesque
♫Everything you dream of
♫But never can possess
♫Nothing's what it seems
♫Welcome to Burlesque
♫Oh, everyone is buying
♫Put your money in my hand
♫If you got a little extra
♫Well, give it to the band
♫You may not be guilty
♫But you're ready to confess
♫Tell me what you need
♫Welcome to Burlesque
♫You can dream of Coco
♫Do it at your risk
♫The triplets grant you mercy
♫But not your every wish
♫Jesse keeps you guessing
♫So cool and statuesque
♫''Behave yourself, '' says Georgia
♫Welcome to Burlesque
♫Oh, everyone is buying
♫Put your money in my hand
♫If you want a little extra
♫Well, you know where I am
♫Something very dark
♫Is playing with your mind
♫It's not the end of days
♫It's just the bump and grind
♫Show a little more
♫Show a little less
♫Add a little smoke
♫Welcome to Burlesque
-Can I get you a drink?
-Only if you're buying.
-Welcome to L.A.
-Thank you.
-Where you from?
-Iowa.
-Kentucky. We're practically related.
-Thought you looked familiar.
Hey, sweetheart?
You wanna do your job? Let's go.
Who does a girl have to flirt with
to get from here to up there?
Is this you flirting?
With someone wearing more eyeliner
than me? Yeah.
Through that door over there.
Ask for Tess.
-She's your guy. Flirt away.
-Thanks.
-Iowa.
-Yeah?
Use my name.
Thanks, Jack.
Hold it! Hold it. That's good.
We're on in five minutes.
Five minutes, ladies.
-Get over there.
-All right, I'm coming.
Ladies! Let's move it, ladies!
Does anyone know where Nikki is?
Both spotlights are
supposed to pull in.
Georgia, your boyfriend is so cute.
So tonight, takeout and a movie?
Both.
-Casablanca and Oreos.
-Yes.
Tess! I lost a contact on the stage.
Okay, if you fall off the stage,
leg extended, boobs up.
Remember, you're a goddess.
-Thank you, Sean.
-You're welcome.
''Thank you, Sean.''
Come here, give me.
-Wait.
-What? The foot?
Yeah, the foot, the back, the neck.
The hips, the breasts, the face....
Vince, the sink's busted
upstairs again.
I'm not calling a plumber, Coco.
Tess, have you read this letter
from the bank?
How many times have I told you?
No business during business hours.
-Marcus Gerber is coming in tonight.
-So what?
This isn't going away.
You won't talk to me before the show,
after the show.
It's like you're avoiding me.
I didn't divorce you
to spend more time with you.
I may not be ''Mr. Tess'' anymore,
but I still own half this place.
''Mr. Tess.''
That is so hot.
Nice, but it won't pay the bills.
Wait. Wait. Zip me up.
Excuse me, I'm Looking for Tess.
Hi, are you Tess?
And you are in my mirror because?
Oh, sorry. I'm friends with Jack,
and I'm Looking for a job.
And where have you danced?
At home, mostly. But I can move.
Okay, give your name
and number to Sean.
Let you know
when we're having our audition.
When will that be, exactly?
Sean?
-Where the hell is Nikki?
-I don't know. She's Late again.
Oh, I'm never Late. Ever.
That's great.
We're trying to put on a show here.
Come back another time.
I've never seen anything like this.
-I need a job. I wanna work here.
-Great enthusiasm, terrible timing.
So leave your name and your number
with Jack, your friend downstairs.
And we'll call you. Okay? Promise.
Hey, can you fix this for me?
Let's move it, ladies!
-Hello.
-Oh, my God. Nikki.
You're probably not
gonna believe this...
...but Sean and I were talking,
and he said....
I said, ''It's so sad that Nikki couldn’t
join us for the opening number...
...but it would be so great
if she joined us for the next one.''
Paws and claws.
Took longer than I thought.
So is finding a new job
when I fire you.
Yeah, right.
-Get ready.
-Yeah.
Hey. Bring me a martini.
Extra dry, straight up, three olives.
-And hurry back.
-She doesn't work here, Nikki.
Then she's not busy.
Twenty minutes and we're back.
Didn't your mama tell you
it's not polite to stare?
You're just so damn beautiful, I--
Well, in that case, screw your mama
and stare away.
No one would ever know.
Know what?
That you're a dude.
-God.
-Can I use this?
Goddamn it! Don't touch my stuff!
Hey, waitress!
Sweetheart? Hey, over here.
One second.
Yo!
-Ladies?
-I'll have a vodka.
What can I get you?
One shot of Patron...
...and tough guy with the hat
over there, he wants a Cosmo.
-What are you doing?
-One night.
If I'm not twenty times better than boobs-for-brains
over there, you don't have to pay me.
♫A kiss on the hand
May be quite continental
♫But diamonds are a girl's best friend.
♫A kiss may be grand. But it won't pay the rental...
Isn't that the girl
that was backstage?
I think so.
Hey, Jack, what's she doing here?
She really wanted a job.
And so she is our new waitress.
And when did I make you
head of personnel?
She just picked up a tray,
started working.
-Really?
-Well, her name is Ali.
Ali.
Hey, Ali.
Look, this is cute, but come on.
Push up those boobs.
Got them, show them. Work them.
And don't ever
go behind my back again.
-Yes, ma'am.
-And don't ever call me ma'am again.
-Yes, sir. I mean ma'am. I mean Tess.
-Get on the floor.
''Ma'am''?
What am I, my mother?
Yes, ma'am.
Up yours.
♫Tiffany's!
♫Cartier!
♫Black Starr! Frost Gorm!
Talk to me Harry Winston. Tell me all about it!
Excuse me.
Dewar's rocks and a bottle
of your best champagne.
Oh, and will you tell Nikki
that I'm here?
And you are...?
A member since '91 .
Marcus Gerber. And you are?
-Ali.
I'm here.
You're Late, you're Late
for a very important date.
Georgia went on for you.
What is that waitress doing here?
I want that bitch out now.
What did she ever do to you?
-She told me I look Like a drag queen.
-Can't be the first time that's happened.
Get my spot.
Nikki, what are you doing?
♫I've heard of affairs.
That are strictly platonic
♫But diamonds are a girl's best friend.
♫And I think affairs
That you must keep liaisonic
♫Are better bets
♫If little pets get big baguettes.
♫Time rolls on,
And youth is gone
♫And you can't straighten up when you bend.
♫But stiff back, or stiff knees
You stand straight at Tiffany's.
♫Diamonds! Diamonds!
♫I don't need rhinestones!
♫But diamonds are a girl's best...
♫...best friend.
Hey!
Ali. Ali.
Ali. Ali. What do you need?
Dewar's rocks, bottle of Dom--
And keep it coming.
Yep. So he's a regular, huh?
Marcus Gerber, real estate guy.
Dating Nikki. This week at Least.
I wanna be up there.
I wanna do that.
Question is...
-...do you have the talent?
-I do.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
-Positive?
-Yeah.
Good, because you're on.
♫I got a dentist
♫Who's over seven feet tall
♫Ooh, I've got a dentist, baby
♫The man is over seven feet tall
♫His name is Dr. Long John
♫And he answers
♫Every call
♫You know
♫I went to Long John's office, I said...
It's simple.
I assume all
your financial obligations...
...buy you out...
...pay you a million
right off the top.
Five hundred each.
Where is the partnership that--? You
said there was gonna be a partnership.
How about a partnership?
Partnerships don't really
work so well with me.
-And that deal is--
-Very generous.
Good. Because I lead
with my final offer.
Not that I give a shit, but why is it
that you want my club so badly?
I Like it.
I see something I Like,
I have to have it. Since I was a kid.
That must have made you
very popular in the sandbox.
I did okay.
You know what you could
do with that?
do with that money?
-Not now.
-Don't ''not now'' me.
The way I see it...
...you're in a fix
and I'm in a position to help.
We play this thing right,
and we all come out winners.
Yeah.
You got that balloon payment
due on the first.
Did you also tell him
I have a tattoo on my ass?
No. It's business.
I don't think you're gonna get
another opportunity Like this.
So take it.
-No.
-She means not now.
No, no.
''Not now'' means not now, Vince.
No means no.
Marcus, I don't care
what you're offering.
My club is not for sale.
Well, offer's on the table.
Thanks.
See you in the sandbox.
Wendy! Do you have my makeup?
Drinks, Ladies.
All right, white wine.
Tom Collins.
Which one is Nikki's?
-Both.
-Shit.
That was my shot.
Here's mud in your eye, Nik.
All right. Now I got a buzz,
and you gotta change. You're on.
What are you, my mother?
In case you haven't noticed,
Vince was talking to Marcus.
Well, that's because Marcus
is trying to buy my club.
Mother of God.
Tess? Probably not a good time.
I know you're busy
and I don't mean to interrupt.
Hey! Did anybody talk to Dave about
the new vocals?
That's what I've been
thinking about. Vocals.
-All the girls lip-synch--
-Except for Tess.
Except for Tess.
But wouldn’t it be great if we
actually heard the girls sing?
No. It wouldn’t be great.
Honey.
People come here
to watch the dancers dance...
...and to watch them Lip-synch
to the great singers.
I hear you. I get it.
I'm just thinking
of ways to make it better.
I don't understand why we can't try--
You don't understand
because it's above your pay grade.
I don't get what that means.
Hear me out. This is a good idea--
Ali, Ali, no-- No. No. No.
Stop. Take her and remove her.
Okay, let's go. Come on.
They need you on the floor,
but thanks for visiting.
All right. Oh, this is not for anybody.
You Look so beautiful right now.
I can't even tell you.
And you are so full of shit.
Goddamn it!
Ali?
You can just have a seat.
I'm gonna grab us
both a drink, yeah?
Oh, and here.
Call whoever you want.
Long distance, whatever.
-I can't.
-What do you mean?
I don't have anyone.
No parents or siblings,
aunts, uncles, anyone?
No one.
So you're not here to use my phone.
No, no, stop.
It's gonna be all right.
You can crash here.
Just please, please, stop crying.
Okay. Okay.
I'll take that.
Better?
Good.
Just one night.
Till it's light out and I can
figure out my next move.
Deal.
That's beautiful.
Who wrote that?
I did.
You wrote that?
Jack, that's.... That's really good.
Thank you.
-You have more?
-Yeah.
Nothing that's ready to be heard.
Hey, Jack...
...why did you Leave Kentucky?
Why did you Leave Iowa?
Because I Looked around
and realized...
...there wasn't one person
whose life I wanted.
Exactly.
Hey, Jack.
I'm really glad I don't have to
be alone tonight.
Get some sleep.
Morning.
-Coffee?
-Black.
Like my soul.
I took the liberty
of making breakfast.
I hope you don't mind.
It's the Least I could do.
Smells great.
She's pretty. Your sister?
-Fiancée.
-You're straight?
-You thought I was gay?
-Yeah.
-Wait, why?
-I don't know. The day bed, eyeliner.
It's a very straight Look.
You know, it works at the club,
Tess loves it--
Okay.
I should put on some pants.
Probably.
So where is she, this fiancée?
She's in New York doing a play.
Now that you're straight
and engaged...
...I feel really weird I came here
in the first place.
I'm all right.
-I'll be out of your hair in no time.
-You don't have to Leave.
-Don't worry about me.
-It's pouring outside.
I got a plan.
If you could just get the door for me.
Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-See you at the club.
Ali! What are you doing?
Come back inside!
No, Jack, I'm fine.
It's pouring.
It's just water, for chrissake.
Damn it.
Get your ass back in my house.
You've done enough. I'm fine.
All right, all right, fine. Here we go.
Put me down. What are you doing?
You have nowhere to go
and I have a couch.
Like it or not, you're gonna stay.
Hey, Natalie.
Really? That's great.
Georgia?
Yeah.
Oh, God, please don't have the flu.
Oh, God.
Please have the flu.
Why do they call it
morning sickness...
...if it hits you at every freaking
moment of the day?
Have you told Damon yet?
No, not yet.
Well, sweetheart, you know,
at some point he's going to notice.
He's a guy.
He's not gonna notice
until my belly's blocking the TV.
Well, what are you gonna do?
I don't know, Tess.
I'm really scared.
Oh, honey, don't be scared.
Whatever you decide,
we will take care of you. Okay?
But you've got to tell Damon.
I figured as Long
as he doesn't know...
...I can still pretend he's gonna be
excited about it.
He's gonna be thrilled.
Are you kidding? He'll be thrilled.
Excellent. That was great.
Thank you very much, Ladies.
What happened to
all the great dancers in L.A.?
They're all dancing with the stars.
Call Andre and ask.
He might have somebody.
Okay.
Don't like her, I don't like her.
I don't love any of them.
She's the best one.
What is that?
What is she doing?
I think she's auditioning.
Hey, Dave, cut it!
Hold on a second, I can do this.
And I think it's sweet
that you think you can.
-Tell me what you're Looking for.
-Someone who can do the routine.
Excuse me? I'm talking to you!
Oh, shit.
Just tell me what you want.
I can't tell you.
Nobody can tell you.
You gotta make me believe
that you belong up there.
That you own that stage and that
nobody's gonna take it from you.
That's the way it works.
You wanna show me something,
show me that.
All right.
Which number do you wanna see?
I know every one.
-Every number?
-Which one do you wanna see?
''Wagon Wheel Watusi.''
What's going on?
Well, I couldn’t keep
my eyes off her.
Try harder.
You were off the whole Last half.
Come on, Tess. Come on, I'll practice
till I bleed. I know I can do this.
You know, we have better dancers.
Then say thank you very much
and goodbye.
If you just give me a chance.
I swear I won't disappoint you.
Didn't anybody ever
give you a shot?
Please, I want this so bad.
-If you just give me a chance, I'd--
-All right. God!
You got the job.
What are you so excited about?
She's your replacement.
Thank you, Tess.
You won't regret it.
I am so gonna regret this.
What is Ali short for?
-Alice.
-Alice?
Well, welcome to Wonderland.
Meet me upstairs in five.
Well, sorry for the short notice...
...but I quit.
It's okay.
And with my new raise,
I will be off your couch in no time.
Here we go.
Black corset, first number.
Second number, ''Wagon Wheel,''
that's that.
Swarovski bustier,
that's for the third number.
And this is for ''Miss Otis Regrets.''
And remember, with that, don't...
...pull the trigger.
♫Zephyr in the sky at night I wonder
♫Do my tears of mourning sink beneath the sun?
♫She's got herself a universe gone quickly
♫For the call of thunder threatens everyone
♫And I feel like I just got home
And I feel...
You Like her. I know it kills you,
but you have to admit it.
No. You know, she pulls focus,
she doesn't blend in.
A girl that doesn't blend in?
Oh, my.
That is so beneath you.
Here we go, here we go.
Don't lose those again.
How you doing?
My boobs are pushed up to my ears,
my thong's a mile up my butt...
...and my eyelashes are so thick
they could kick up a stiff wind.
Fun being a girl, isn't it?
Come on, Let’s go, Let’s go.
-You guys wanna go grab pizza?
-Yes, please.
-Yeah.
-I'm starving.
Good, Let’s go.
My day was so Long.
Ice cream sounds so good.
That's so bad.
-I'm gonna get so full tonight.
-What?
Where is everybody?
They went out for pizza.
I wasn't hungry.
That brush isn't working.
It's too old.
Well, it's the only brush I have.
I'll Let you use mine.
-Here.
-Thanks.
All right, here. Let me help you.
Wet it if you're gonna get
a clean line.
Close your eyes.
When you are putting on
your makeup...
...it's Like you're an artist.
But instead of painting
on a canvas...
...you're painting your face.
My mom was a model
and she was beautiful.
Tall, blond.
Not Like me.
Body that could stop a truck.
And she had these girlfriends,
beautiful girls, Colleen and Shirley...
...and they would come over
in the morning...
...and put their makeup on together
before they went on jobs. Up.
We had a window in the back
of our house with a ledge...
...and they would put their mirrors
side by side and put out their makeup.
They had lipsticks and blushes,
and it was fabulous.
I kept thinking, ''God, I cannot wait
till I get old enough to play with this.''
Didn't you ever watch your mom
put on her makeup?
My mom died when I was 7...
...and it's my first lesson.
You know,
you won't be the new girl forever.
Beautiful.
Shit.
Ali.
Ali. Did you use my towel again?
I found it soaking wet on the floor.
-I don't know. Maybe.
-How's that apartment hunt?
I've been Looking.
Everything's over 1 000 bucks a month.
How can you put a price
on privacy Like that? Freedom?
Your own bathroom? Clean towels?
Okay, I get it.
It's Natalie.
Hey, babe.
Oh, hey.
What about Beachwood Canyon?
Great.
If you have a car.
I mean, truth is...
...you really should get a car first.
I mean, this is L.A. after all.
You know?
I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna suck it up...
...and Let you stay a Little bit Longer.
Throw in something for rent,
we're good.
-A second ago you wanted me out.
-I don't Like my towel wet.
I don't Like the lack of privacy...
...but you're in a jam.
And I'm the kind of guy...
...when a friend is in trouble, I help.
It's just who I am.
What did Natalie have to say?
Nothing. No, she....
What did she say?
''Hi.'' That was it.
-And?
-And....
Her play got extended
three months.
She has to pay
everything there in rent...
...so I have to cover
everything here.
So if you wanna stick around
and chip in, it would--
-Save your ass?
-Help.
Well, will you Look at that?
The shoe on the other foot.
One minute I'm a freeloader...
...and the next...
...I'm the only thing standing
between you and eviction.
Just yes or no?
What's the proposal exactly?
Wonderful apartment.
Bathroom included.
I'm listening.
-Use of the kitchen.
-Keep going.
-Six hundred a month.
-Closet?
-Half.
-Oh, Look.
''Fabulous apartment
with a great view.''
Fine, fine.
The whole closet.
-I want the bedroom.
-No way.
Oh, Look. ''Hot tub, Beverly Hills.''
All right. You can have my bedroom.
Are you in?
Oh, Jack.
See, I'm the kind of girl...
...if a friend's in trouble, I help.
That's just who I am.
Oh, boy.
Your dream is killing me!
It's killing me!
What was that?
And what's this?
It's something about
the two mortgages.
To be perfectly honest,
I haven't got a goddamn clue.
But if I can't raise
the amount of money...
...on that paper by the end
of this month, I Lose the club.
It's just money.
It's just a number.
I know...
...but do you think I could do it?
Okay, tell me a lie.
I need your expert sewing skills.
Tell me a new Lie.
I don't Love you.
Come here. Come here.
It's okay.
Stage right.
Wait a minute. Hey, hey.
What's in that?
Iced tea.
Iced tea, my ass. Go home.
Yeah, right. I'm about to go on.
You're not gonna go on. Go home.
Relax. It is one drink.
What is the big deal?
Ali, you're gonna take Nikki's spot.
-She can't dance my part.
-She can and she will.
No, no. My God, I can't do that.
It is Nikki's number.
You said you can do
any number, right?
-I don't wanna step on any toes.
-Then don't.
I don't ca-- Listen to me.
You're gonna go on,
and you're gonna go home.
Here, put this on.
-Dave.
-Huh?
Tess wants to see you.
Says it's urgent.
I can't leave right now. I'm working, girl.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Ugh. Dave this, Dave that,
Everybody wants Dave to do something.
Y'all gonna have me singing
by the time I'm done here. Jesus.
♫Hum... Well I've got a lover that moves me so
He show an old kind of rock'n'roll
♫'Cause he's a tough lover (yeah, yeah)
He's a tough lover (whooooo)
♫Tough Lover (yeah, yeah)
Tough Lover (hum, hum)
♫When he kisses me I get a thrill
But when he does that wiggle I--
Tess, what's up?
What are you doing back here?
-Nikki said you were Looking for me.
-Nikki? What is going on?
Lower the curtain. Let's go.
Bye. Thanks for coming.
♫Ooh
Hold it.
♫Oh yeah yeah
♫Oooh yeah yeah
Raise the curtain.
♫I need a tough lover, yeah yeah
♫I need a, a tough lover, woo
♫I need a, a tough lover, yeah yeah yeah
♫A tough lover, yeah yeah
♫When he kisses me, I get that thrill
♫When he does that wiggle I won't keep still
I wanna a tough lover (yeah, yeah)
♫A tough lover (woo)
I need a tough lover (yeah, yeah)
♫Tough lover (hum, hum)
♫The seven sisters got nothing on him
♫I'm talking about a lover who's fast as the wind
♫Everyone will talk about how he got me fixed
♫It ain't voodoo, it's just that twist
♫He will be the greatest lover that ever come to pass
♫Don Juan ain't got the half the chance
♫He's a tough lover (yeah, yeah)
A tough lover (woo)
A tough lover (oh oh)
♫Hey, hey, heyah
♫He'll make me laugh, he'll make me cry
♫He'll be so tough he'll make Venus come alive
♫He'll do anything that he wants to do
♫Step on Jesse James's blue suede shoes, yeah
♫A tough lover (yeah, yeah)
A tough lover (woo)
A tough lover (hey yeah, yeah yeah)
♫A tough lover (yeah, yeah)
A tough lover (oh oh)
Oh, my God.
Am I the only one that has no idea
what just happened?
Whatever it was--
The music stopped,
I didn't know what to do.
I had to sing, I'm sorry.
Never told me
you could sing Like that.
I tried to tell you.
Okay, okay, all right.
This is what we're gonna do.
You know the songs, right?
Oh, yeah.
So tomorrow we're gonna rehearse,
then you're gonna sing.
We're gonna go
straight through the show Live.
-So any questions?
-No.
Okay, good. Good.
You go with the guys.
Find out what keys
you're comfortable singing in...
...and I'm going to go up to my office
and plan an entirely new show.
-Okay?
-Oh, my God.
Thanks, Tess.
I'm gonna build a show around her.
''They don't come to hear us sing''?
They'll come to hear her sing.
So how do you feel?
-Amazing.
-I've never seen anything Like that.
Thanks. Are you sure Tess
really Liked it? She wasn't...?
I was bringing down the curtain.
She stopped me.
She's the one who Let you sing.
-Really?
-She wants to build a show around you.
You're crying with happiness, right?
Good. Okay.
Brava.
Clearly one of us
has underestimated the other.
I can't believe Tess has you
buried in the kick Line.
She didn't know I sang.
Well, you certainly can.
And you are way too good
to be doing it here.
How about a drink?
The bar's right over there.
Tell Jack I sent you.
Where the hell did that come from?
-Who knew that you could do that?
-Thanks, Jack.
Who knew any white chick
could sing Like that?
How do you do that?
I don't know. It just happens.
I just do it.
I know how that feels.
I gotta pee again, so....
Stop.
We're gonna get something to eat.
You wanna come?
Yeah, I would.
Let's go.
Look at you.
What? What?
Well, no, just the way
you're gazing after her.
I have a fiancée, remember?
Yes. No, I do. I know.
Three thousand miles away.
We talk every day.
You do? About what?
Let me guess, don't tell me.
About her.
Her.
And, I don't know....
All I'm saying is that
that one there...
...is beautiful
on the inside as well...
...and she's not going to be
available forever.
Relationship advice from
Mr. One-Night-Stand himself.
That is....
Forgot my purse.
-What?
-Oh, no.
I was just telling Jack here
how every opportunity has a shelf Life.
Come here.
Look there.
Awfully pretty, but too much.
See, I Like that.
No, I'm not cutting my hair.
Who said anything about you
cutting your hair? You can wear a wig.
I'm wearing one right now.
♫Where have I been all my Life?
♫The dress is Chanel
♫The shoes YSL
♫The bag is Dior
♫Agent Provocateur
♫My address today
♫L.A., by the way
♫Above Sunset Strip
♫The Hills all the way
♫My rings are by Webster
♫It makes their heads twirl
♫They all say, ''Darling, what did you
Do for those pearls?''
♫What?
♫I am a good girl
♫The age I adore, the day, oh, no more
♫Breakfast Polo Launch
♫And pools at the shore
♫The Chateau for cocktails
♫The Courtyard at night
♫Downtown is for dinner
♫The hell is divine
♫You know I have found the words going round
♫They all say my feet never do touch the ground
♫What? I am a good girl
♫I am a good girl
♫Ah, ooh, ah, yeah, ah
So good.
Hey there, big boy.
So, what do you think?
I think you Look....
I mean, it looks....
Jack, we're friends, for chrissake.
It's not Like we're brother and sister.
No, we certainly are not.
I don't get why everyone's
having a conniption.
She's just a tacky farm girl
from Iowa.
And we know a cow
when we see one.
Don't underestimate us farm girls.
Vince.
This round's on me.
I don't normally do this...
...but, Vince, I'm doubling my offer.
It's either you or the auction house.
No, I am not selling.
Know what happens
when you default on a Loan?
No, hum a few bars.
I'm not screwing around here.
Where's the money coming from?
Ali's a hit.
We can charge 50 bucks a head now.
Raising the admission?
That's not good enough.
You have been saying
that the sky is falling forever.
Everything always works out fine.
Tell that to the people
losing everything.
I don't wanna be one of them.
-I Love this place too.
-No, you don't.
-I do.
-No, you don't!
-Yes, I do!
-Oh, no, you don't.
Look, you have many
fine qualities, Vincent.
And then you've got
some iffy qualities.
But you've never been a phony.
Just tell Marcus no.
Jack?
Yep. Just got in.
I'm in here.
Can you come zip me up?
Hey, where you been?
Writing music.
Can I hear?
-It's not ready.
Who's that?
Me and my mom
on my 7th birthday.
She died a few weeks Later.
You must miss her.
Every single day something happens
that I wish I could tell her about.
And what happened today?
Nothing yet.
You should get that.
It's probably Natalie.
Probably.
Hey, babe.
Yes, I know.
♫A guy what takes his time
I'll go for anytime
♫I'm a fast moving girl who likes some slow
♫Got no use for fancy driving
Wanna see a guy arrival in low
♫I'd be satisfied, electrified to
know a guy what takes his time
♫I hurry up a fare
I always give the air
♫Wouldn't give any rushing gent a smile
♫I would go for any single who
would condescend to linger a while
♫What a lullaby would be supplied to
have a guy who takes his time? Oh.
♫A guy what takes his time
I'd go for anytime
♫A hasty job really spoils a master's touch
♫I don't like a big commotion
I'm a demon for slow motion or such
♫Why should I deny that I would die to
know a guy who takes his time?
♫There isn't any fun in getting something
done
-Check it out, girls!
-♫If you rushed when you have to make the grade
♫I can spot an amateur
appreciate a connoisseur in trade
♫Who would qualify, no alibi,
to be the guy who takes his time
♫Oh, oh, oh, oh
I'm starved. You ready?
I can't. I'm so sorry.
I have to do inventory tonight.
Want me to call a cab?
No, that's okay.
I'll get a ride with Coco.
Sorry.
Watch your back. Coming through.
You ready?
-For what?
-I'll drop you off.
Coco Left five minutes ago.
I was coming to talk to you.
I caught the end of your conversation.
-Talk to me about...?
-Dinner. With me. Give me that.
If you ever expect to see
this bag alive again...
...you’ll follow me.
Hold on a second.
Where you going? Hey!
Where are you taking me?
This is not the way to my place.
I told you. Dinner.
Dinner?
I'm not going to dinner with you.
You're seeing Nikki.
We're just friends.
Where I come from, friends don't
chew on each other's earlobes.
Aren't you glad you Left?
-Oh, damn it.
-What?
I gotta make a quick appearance
at a party.
You just remembered.
It's on the way. We'll be quick.
Ten minutes, tops. Do you mind?
And if I do?
Then you've been kidnapped.
Hey, Marcus.
Nice house.
What are you doing?
You can't just take that.
Put that back.
You're gonna get us kicked out of here.
Not if we sneak out. Come on.