In the 1 960s, my generation
set out on a journey of change.
Coming out of an atmosphere
of conformity,
a new spirit began to appear.
One of the first signs
was a demonstration
organised by Berkeley students
in May of 1 960
against the House
Un-American Activities Committee.
What we are here to do
is to gather information
as we are ordered to do
by an act of congress
with respect to the general operation
of communist conspiracies.
I'm not in the habit of being
intimidated and I won't start now.
- Next question.
- What was your question?
Are you a member
of the Communist Party?
We came out to protest
because we were against HUAC's
suppression of political freedom.
In the '50s,
HUAC created a climate of fear
by putting people on trial
for their political beliefs.
Any views left of centre
were labelled subversive.
We refused to go back to McCarthyism.
If you think
that I am going to cooperate
with this collection of Judases,
of men who sit there in violation
of the United States Constitution,
if you think I'll cooperate
with you in any way, you are insane.
As witness after witness
denounced the committee,
the hearings grew stormy.
The halls outside were filled
with students seeking admission.
Suddenly the police
turned fire hoses full force
on the demonstrators
inside the rotunda
and then dragged them down the steps
of City Hall.
It turned out to be
a political baptism
that transformed fear
into determination.
Something had changed.
After this, it would never be the same.
The whole thing might have died down
except for the fact
that the committee made a film.
It was called Operation Abolition.
The film presented all of us...
I had been in these demonstrations.
It presented all of us
as, somehow or other,
engaged in a vast communist plot,
not only to try to overthrow
the US government,
but, worse, to abolish the House
Un-American Activities Committee.
Operation Abolition.
This is what the communists
call their current drive
to destroy the House Committee
on Un-American Activities
and to render sterile
the security laws of our government.
You will see revealed the long-time
classic communist tactic
in which a relatively few
well-trained hard-core communist agents
are able to incite non-communists
to perform the dirty work
of the Communist Party.
That movie was scheduled to be shown
at the Harvard ROTC class.
The ROTC had a class on campus.
They were going to show
Operation Abolition.
I'd heard all about Operation Abolition
and I was opposed to it.
So a bunch of us
decided to go to the class to protest.
I remember very well
the way we protested.
In the film, the students stand up
singing The Star-Spangled Banner
to show HUAC don't pull
you're more American than us on us.
The group of us stood up
in the ROTC class
to show that we're in solidarity
with the students in San Francisco.
But what I really remember clearly
is thinking, ''Wait a minute.
What am I doing here?''
''Why aren't I there?''
And I checked this story out
with people who were at Berkeley
and they told me
the exact same story,
that Operation Abolition
had recruited them to Berkeley,
that they had seen it
round the country
and gone in to see it as a protest
and they'd thought,
''Wow! Let's go there.''
The university's been called upon
to educate previously unimagined
numbers of students,
to respond to the expanding claims
of national service,
to merge its activities with industry
as never before.
Characteristic of this transformation
is the growth
of the knowledge industry
which is permeating government
and business and to draw into it
more and more people raised
to higher and higher levels of skill.
The production, distribution
and consumption of knowledge
is said to account for 29 percent
of gross national product.
Knowledge production is growing
at about twice the rate
of the rest of the economy.
What the railroads did for
the second half of the last century
and the automobile
for the first half of this century
may be done for the second half
of this century
by the knowledge industry
and that is to service
the focal point for national growth.
When we went to college, President
Kerr's vision became our reality.
The University of California
was a knowledge factory,
the biggest public university
in America.
It did research
for major corporations
and it ran the government's
nuclear weapons labs.
Of the seven campuses,
Berkeley was the jewel in the crown
with the most prestigious faculty.
Within the sea of students, there was
little evidence of political life.
But a few of us, who were interested
in politics, found each other
and started an organisation
called SLATE.
Some radical students
had gotten together
to run a slate of candidates
in the student elections.
Although SLATE was not solely
about student elections,
the student elections
were used as a kind of platform
through which we could educate
other students
and reach them
about the various issues
that were alive during that time.
Friends wrote me letters
of the discussions happening
in the coffee shops of Berkeley.
People were interested in politics
there.
They'd already organised some little
student activist group on campus
that was starting to experiment
with doing things.
I grew up in a small ethnic community
in Buffalo, New York.
I knew I couldn't live
within its limitations.
I had a couple of years at college.
I quit. I hitchhiked around.
I ended up in San Francisco.
I got married.
Then I went back to school.
I came to Berkeley really...
I was looking for truth.
I was looking for meaning in my life.
One of the most distressing tasks
of a university president
is to pretend
that the protest and outrage
of each new generation of undergraduates
is really fresh and meaningful.
In fact, it is one of the most
predictable controversies we know.
The participants go through a ritual
of hackneyed complaints
almost as ancient as academe,
while believing that what is said
is radical and new.
From the beginning,
the administration at Cal
was trying to undermine
and prevent what we were trying to do.
They were very upset
about the introduction
of what they called off-campus issues.
Anything to do with civil rights
or with the testing
of nuclear weapons
or apartheid in South Africa,
these were off-campus issues.
This was what we were attacking.
We were opposed to sandbox politics.
The administration
started turning the screws.
They disenfranchised
the graduate students,
because that was
a big block of the SLATE vote.
Then they threw
the organisation off campus.
There was a big outrage at that.
We got reinstated.
So there was a growing community
of people
who wanted to make
liberal or left or radical,
however they thought about it,
politics legitimate in a country.
When we look at modern man,
we have to face the fact...
..that modern man suffers
from a kind of poverty
of the spirit...
..which stands in glaring contrast
to his scientific and technological
abundance.
We've learned to fly the air
like birds.
We've learned to swim the seas
like fish.
Yet we haven't learned to walk the earth
as brothers and sisters.
More than any other cause,
the civil rights movement
became the wellspring
of student activism
and inspired our entire generation.
In 1 963, Berkeley students
began to band together
with black activists to protest
discriminatory hiring practices
of Bay Area businesses.
We sat in at restaurants,
supermarkets
and automobile showrooms.
Our biggest challenge came
when we tried to secure jobs
for blacks and other minorities
in the hotels of San Francisco.
A picket line formed
around the Sheraton Palace,
while negotiations with the Hotel
Owners Association took place inside.
It was getting to the point
where we were saying,
''We are going to create
a confrontation.''
''We're going to create a situation
that's intolerable
and we're going to force you
to respond to it.''
''We're willing to get arrested
in order to do it.''
''And now the ball's in your court.''
All of us in this elegant lobby,
I can't convey to you the effect.
It was like the riffraff
coming to the White House.
The real democratic masses
had moved in and taken over,
saying, ''No, you cannot continue
to run this hotel
in this racist fashion.''
''The world is being redefined.
Things cannot continue on that way.''
We just entered into discussions
with the Sheraton Palace
for the last eight hours.
We were given a seven-page document
which was supposed
to summarise the agreement.
But there was a hitch, the Sheraton
Palace wasn't willing to sign.
It was the first major victory
of anything l'd been involved in.
The Sheraton Palace Hotel arrests
and convictions and trials
and so forth
led to the first agreement, that
I knew of in the north, of its kind.
That was an agreement
between the entire hotel industry
and the ad hoc committee
to end discrimination,
to hire minority individuals
in all levels of employment,
including management.
It was very historic
and very elevating
and it really pumped us all up
to think,
''My God, we really could have
an effect on history.''
''We could have an effect on lives
of people we'd never know or meet.''
It was simply by taking seriously
the words of the Constitution
and the preamble
in The Declaration of lndependence
and all that stuff that we believed
in with great vim and vigour.
Here we just saw it happen
and it worked.
It was a very thrilling experience
for us,
but the flip side of it is other people
saw it in a different light.
That is, the business community
saw it as a threat,
as something
that would cause them problems.
The fact that 1 00 Berkeley students
were arrested,
probably 500, 600, 800 Berkeley students
were involved in the thing,
it was a portent of things to come.
Very quickly pressure
was put on the university.
''You've got to stop this.''
The terms that were used were,
''The university cannot be used
as a base for attacks on the community.''
In the fall of the school year '64-'65,
we returned to campus to find out
the tables on Bancroft and Telegraph
which had historically been
the campus political activity lifeline
were banned.
Tables have been permitted
out in front of Bancroft and Telegraph
to distribute literature,
including the ideas of policy
and advocating stands.
At this particular point,
we have been denied this.
We think,
whether or not this is true or not
as far as why they're doing it,
the effect of cutting this off
is to stop political activity
on this campus.
We knew at the time that it was aimed
at the civil rights movement
and at progressive organisations
and at those interested in
the peace movement and civil rights.
Mainly civil rights.
But by banning all of us,
they created an enormous reaction
because they united a group of people
around the need to have those tables
that couldn't have united themselves
under any other circumstances.
We told them
they had to go back on the streets
for this kind of activity.
They then took the position
that, ''We want to undertake these
activities on campus property,''
and we said, ''This is not possible.''
When the university banned political
action at Bancroft and Telegraph,
they said it was the same
as the rest of the campus.
We said, ''If it's the same
as the rest of the campus,
then we can do this anywhere.''
We decided to move our tables
to Sather Gate.
Five students were sitting at tables
and deans came by
and said, ''If you don't leave,
we have to cite you.''
One of the students said,
''I'm sorry, sir,
my organisation
has not authorised me to leave.''
And so he was cited.
As soon as the student was cited,
the dean would cite the next student.
Somebody would sit in their place.
After they cited the five people,
they didn't want to be there all day,
so the deans started leaving.
People said, ''Me, too!''
At three o'clock, 500 people
marched into Sproul Hall saying,
''Whatever you do to those people,
you've got to do to us.''
If you don't stand up for your
freedom now, you're dead, guys.
The deans wanted the students
who were cited
to go into the deans' office.
We said, ''We all did it.
You have to treat us all the same.''
We were out in the halls
and nobody would go into the office.
At about nine o'clock,
they announced that those five people
plus three demonstration leaders
were suspended.
The next morning, we really knew
it was going to happen.
We set our tables up
in front of Sproul Hall.
I guess I was one of the more noisy
people so a dean came up to me.
He asked me to identify myself
and I refused.
He said if I didn't identify myself,
I would be arrested.
It wasn't the first time that
I had been threatened with arrest.
Two policemen took me under the arms.
I went limp.
They dragged me into the police car.
Before I got into the police car,
it was surrounded with people.
It was two minutes to 1 2.
There's a commotion going on.
Some people are joining in
or stopping to watch.
This police car is going nowhere.
I just did
what any of my fellow students
or fellows in other organisations
would've done.
I was just singled out.
Chance selected me. l'm no martyr.
I couldn't understand why people were
prohibited from speaking in the plaza.
And if this demonstration
around this police car
was some way to indicate it was wrong,
it seemed like a good idea.
I didn't like the idea
of seizing a police car very much
but it was certainly a peaceful seizing.
People began to speak.
The only reason I took part in this
is because I like Cal very much.
l'd like to see it better.
And they'd stand on the car.
People were very careful about the car.
People would take their shoes off
and gently climb up on the car.
They moved from the hood of the car
up onto the roof of the car.
Then the argument raged.
Are you with us or against us?
I wasn't either. I was watching
and listening to speeches.
There was an open microphone
on top of the police car.
Anybody who wanted to speak
signed up on a list.
They had three minutes
to say anything they wanted.
Hour after hour,
people were getting up and orating.
It was like an explosion of ideas.
Aristotle said,
''lf you are not a citizen,
you are either a beast or a god!''
Now, I ask you a very simple question...
People start talking,
bringing in the Greek philosophers,
the French Revolution,
talking about all the ideas,
constitutional liberties,
as if they had meaning.
Late at night
some fraternity people came down.
There was some confrontation.
They were heckling from the back
so someone said, ''Come on up.''
They got one of the fraternity boys
to say his thing on the mic.
By the time he got there,
he forgot why he was against it
and his friends booed him.
It really was a political awakening.
There was a political issue
and we were all part of this.
We weren't observing it
on television.
We were part of deciding
what would happen,
as was the university administration.
No one from the university
administration came to speak.
No one came to present
any reasoned point of view
about why the arrest had occurred
or why the rules restricting
political speech were justifiable.
Nothing.
I ended up sitting in that police car
for 32 hours
and, at the maximum time,
there were as many as 6,000 people
sitting down around the police car.
At various points
when arrests were threatened,
people didn't run away.
More people sat down.
People felt they had to sit down.
People were saying,
''Join us. Join us.''
Mario and a delegation is off
negotiating with the administration.
At the final minute, they arrive
and a settlement has been reached.
May I please have a decision?
What's the word now?
- There's been an agreement signed.
- An agreement signed?
Yes, by the student groups and by me,
as president of the university,
which has several points to it.
The first point
is that the student demonstrators
shall desist
from their illegal actions,
protesting university regulations.
We've also agreed to set up
a committee to examine the rules.
The remarkable thing
about this entire situation
is that there's been a coalition,
that I think is unusual in politics.
A coalition from Youth for Goldwater
to the Young Socialist Alliance.
Usually these groups
don't speak together,
let alone sit on the same table
and work out policies and platforms.
l'm proud to say that American students
are united on one issue
and that's the First Amendment
privileges of freedom of speech,
the right to advocate and discuss
at any time, at any place,
as long as it doesn't disturb
classes and interfere with traffic.
Our meetings lasted
1 0, 1 2, 1 5, 1 8 hours.
People slept at different times
during some of them and came back
because we had two goals,
to figure out what to do
and to try to keep
this enormous coalition together.
Understanding the power
of all of these groups
moving in the same direction
around this issue.
That takes a long time because
you can't do it by a majority vote.
The minority just says,
''OK, l'm gone.''
It had to be by consensus.
People had to agree.
And it took forever.
We called it boring, disgusting,
time-consuming democracy.
I remember one administrator
described the Free Speech Movement
as a civil rights panty raid.
That's not such a dumb description.
He did see kids having a good time.
It was very exciting.
Instead of being about panties,
it's about civil rights.
But what he failed to see
is that there was a real underlying
seriousness to this.
There was a tremendous
sense of community.
It's as if all these students
had been waiting to work together
and suddenly they did it.
Six weeks ago, they promised us
that they would negotiate
on their regulations of free speech.
Yes, they negotiated. They have
blocked every attempt we have made.
If they refuse to come to a stand,
we will also consider negotiations
as being broken by them.
However we will continue to try
and get them to come to a vote
or take a stand or make a decision.
As Mario Savio
would talk about a meeting
and tell what happened in the meeting
and explain the positions
taken by the administration
and, from what I could tell, would
tell exactly what had gone on,...
..l would then contrast that with
the administration's explanation.
Muffled, guarded.
The administration would not explain
what had happened.
They wouldn't tell the truth.
A lot of people became very upset
about what administration spokesmen
would say was going on
when they knew it wasn't true.
What you have there
are a few of these rather bearded,
unwashed characters
with sandals and long hair
who normally would be regarded
tolerantly as a lunatic fringe
which you put up with
but you do not necessarily encourage.
In effect, the campus has been
turned over to these characters.
Somewhere in the process of the FSM,
for the very first time
the young, privileged,
affluent children of the culture
began to see themselves
as an oppressed class.
It was an astounding perception
because here we were
at the height of the privileged,
the best students
at the best multiversity
destined to be the managers
of the society.
In the middle of this,
we turned around
and looked at our education and said,
''Wait a minute.
Somehow the best is the worst.''
It put us out of touch
with the society.
It severed technology from values,
the intellect from the heart.
For many people, this was
the only educational activity
that we were involved in
that was deeply meaningful.
In late November, it became clear
that the administration
had finally figured out
how to break us apart as a coalition.
That was they said
we could have our tables back.
We could do the things we wanted to
but we couldn't advocate
unlawful activity,
less we'd still be liable for
discipline as students on the campus.
It was very clear to us
that the only groups that last part
of the rule were aimed at
were those who used civil disobedience
in their strategies.
That meant the left
and the civil rights movement.
We felt quite defeated.
This position on the question
of advocacy,
which the president recommended
and the regents approved,
is far severer than any recommended
by any faculty committee
and, of course, is totally unacceptable
to the students.
It constitutes, in fact,
prior restraint on speech,
on political expression on campus.
So, you've lost a lot of ground?
Well, it's very hard to say.
Fortunately, the university
committed another atrocity.
They could not end this whole incident
without punishing somebody
and teaching a lesson
that this should never again happen.
So when students got back
after Thanksgiving break,
they found out that the eight people
originally cited
had received letters saying
that disciplinary proceedings
leading to expulsion
had begun against them.
So here we are.
Four students are getting the axe,
six organisations are getting the axe
for standing up this semester
and for fighting for these things.
They're getting the axe not for what
they did but for what we have done.
They spoke for us.
They were part of us.
They have been singled out
and will be chopped off.
We were told the following.
If Kerr tried to get something
more liberal out of the regents,
why didn't he make a public statement
to that effect?
The answer we received
from a well-meaning liberal
was the following.
He said, ''Would you ever imagine
the manager of a firm
making a statement publicly
in opposition to his directors?''
That's the answer.
I ask you to consider
if this is a firm
and if the regents are the directors
and if President Kerr is the manager,
then, I tell you something,
the faculty are a bunch of employees
and we're the raw materials,
but we're raw materials
that don't mean
to have any process upon us,
don't mean to be made into a product,
don't mean to end up being bought
by some clients of the university,
be they the government, industry,
organised labour, be they anyone.
We're human beings.
There's a time when the operation
of the machine becomes so odious,
makes you so sick at heart
that you can't take part.
You can't even passively take part.
You've got to put your bodies
upon the gears and upon the wheels,
upon the levers, upon the apparatus
and you've got to make it stop
and you've got to indicate
to the people who run it
that unless you're free,
the machine will be prevented
from working at all.
How could you not
go into Sproul Hall?
Everybody was going into Sproul Hall.
It was a...
What other alternative did you have
to say that you weren't happy
with the way things were going?
I hesitated for about two seconds
and I thought...
I got a picture of my husband's face
and I thought,
''What is this going to do?''
''What is it going to do to my career,
to my life?''
Then I just said, ''To hell with it,
I don't care what it does.''
''This is my chance to do something.''
The fourth, third and second floors
are filled. Stay downstairs.
Members of the Bay Area Civil Rights
Movement in the stairwell over there.
People were dancing in the hallways.
People were studying.
People were just sitting
on the cold floors,
wandering around,
talking with each other.
It was chaos and confusion
and it was sort of like a party
and it went on and on and on.
Finally, the police decided
that if you wanted to go out,
you could go out,
but you couldn't get back in.
I debated about this for...
I don't think I was in the position
of deciding to make witness
or not make witness,
a great moral decision.
It was getting to be dinnertime.
It was getting in or not getting in.
I had no idea this was going
to go on for a long time.
When I came back,
people were climbing with ropes
up the front of Sproul Hall.
It was clear that something was
happening but it wasn't clear what.
May I have your attention, please?
I am Dr Edward Strong,
chancellor of the Berkeley campus.
I have an announcement.
This assemblage
has developed to such a point
that the purpose
and work of the university
have been materially impaired.
Please go.
I wanted to run.
My impulse was to run.
I was hanging on to the people next
to me to keep myself from jumping up.
Then something really neat happened.
That was... Art Goldberg
was the leader of our floor.
He was in charge of us.
He was standing there.
He heard they were coming up
so he was giving us a speech
on what you do,
how you go limp.
He said, ''When the cops come at you,
don't fight them.''
''You just want to go limp.''
As he's saying this,
the cops are coming at him.
He talked all the way down
to the floor.
I know this because I was looking
between their legs.
It was really an inspiration.
I said, ''lf he can do that,
that's what l'm going to try to do.''
When they got to me, they said,
''Do you want to walk out like a lady
or get dragged out?''
I said, ''l want to get dragged out
like a lady.''
With the arrests came
a massive collapse of the authority
of the campus administration.
Now, they made a desperate attempt
to regain that authority
in a big meeting
at the Greek Theater.
The departmental chairmen believe
that the acts of civil disobedience
on December 2nd and 3rd
were unwarranted
and that they obstruct rational
and fair consideration
of the grievances
brought forward by the students.
There are a small number
of individuals, I regret to say,
who are interested in fomenting
a crisis merely for the sake of crisis.
They hope that continuing chaos
will bring about a total revolution
and their own particular concept
of utopia.
The university supports
the powers of persuasion
against the use of force,
the constructive act
as against the destructive blow,
respect for the rights of others,
opposition to passion and hate,
the reasoned argument
as against the simplistic slogan.
The academic world
and the people of this state
expect of us conduct commensurate
with our past achievements
and our high capacities.
We should expect no less of ourselves.
Thank you.
We want Mario!
The police have got Mario.
They are pulling him away...
The police have pulled Mario away
from the speaker stand.
He tried to exercise free speech.
When he stood up here,
the police took him away.
That shows the entire process
that's going on campus.
We, of course, had no notion
that Mr Savio was going to try to
speak at the end of this meeting.
He asked... Just a moment.
Just a moment. He asked...
- Just a moment.
- Just let him speak.
He asked...
He asked me at the beginning
of the meeting
whether he would be allowed
to speak at this meeting.
I said he would not
because this was a structured meeting,
not an open forum,
and we had a programme
which had been approved.
They're hypocrites and bastards.
Even if the Greek Theater
had gone exactly according to plan,
it still would've been a flop.
But it was worse than a flop,
it was a fiasco,
and there was a kind of pandemonium
on the campus.
There was a power vacuum.
Who the hell was in charge?
Nobody knew.
A bunch of us drafted a resolution.
We took that resolution
into the academic senate
and it passed by over seven to one.
The overwhelming majority of the faculty
had come down firmly
on the side of free speech.
So when the faculty marched out
into this cheering mob of students,
we knew that was it,
that was victory.
We had achieved everything
we had set out to achieve in the FSM.
Student rallies
at the University of California
over the past two months
have become commonplace.
But today's rally in front of Sproul
Hall has taken on a different tone.
Several thousand students
have gathered
for what has been billed
as a victory celebration,
a victory the students feel is assured
as a result of yesterday's action
by the academic senate.
We're asking that there be
no restrictions
on the content of speech,
save those provided by the courts.
That's an enormous amount of freedom.
People can say things
within that area of freedom
which are not responsible.
Now, that's... We've finally
gotten into a position
where we have to consider
being responsible
because now we have the freedom
within which to be responsible.
l'd like to say
that at this time l'm confident...
l'm confident that the students
and the faculty
in the University of California
will exercise their freedom
with the same responsibility
they've shown in winning their freedom.
People thought, ''This is it.
This is day one of a new era.''
We're going to have
a different university.
We can re-plan the whole
structure of the university.
If we want, we can have the
administrators sweeping sidewalks.
That was a popular slogan
in those days.
We can have a different
conception of education.
Worse yet, we attracted to Berkeley
the worst collection
of kooks and nuts you've ever seen.
Everybody saw this on television
and they had
a distorted conception of it.
They thought what you do is you go to
Berkeley, riot and have a great time.
lt's one big political,
sexual, drug feast.
Didn't Ronald Reagan
himself say
that it was all drugs and sex
and radical politics?
They had this absurd conception
of what was going on.
The media exaggerated it
in a certain way.
We had created a set of expectations
that were really not satisfiable.
What irritated me most in the stuff
that came out about that period
was the description of us
as alienated and cynical.
We were the absolute antithesis
of that.
We were so committed and so involved,
we risked our careers,
our jobs, our education
and we did it because
we were so tied into this system,
to this country, to this culture.
We believed in it so much
that we were willing
to take those risks
at a time when it wasn't
popular to do so.
l'd never realised people would lie
to maintain their positions of power.
Then I saw it.
I don't think people were evil to lie,
but they did it.
They altered the way things were
to maintain their positions of power
and they did it in a way
that was wrong.
And then I saw that,
then I saw that everywhere.
I saw that in the structures
of political power in Oakland.
of political power in the South.
I began to see
that the mechanisms
that the Free Speech Movement
was attempting to change
were mechanisms
that operated everywhere.
I was at a rally
where Mario was speaking.
He was the speaker.
It was some kind of wrap-up rally.
Maybe it was right after the trial
or something like that.
It was sort of like,
''Well, the FSM is over.''
''We've got it all.
That's all settled.''
My feeling was, ''OK, that's settled.
I can go on with my life.''
I was even walking away from
the rally before Mario was finished.
I have this very clear memory
of his voice ringing out
as l'm leaving Sproul Plaza.
He's saying, ''Don't walk away
because we've still got a war to stop.''
I just looked around real startled
and I thought, ''War? What war?''
Then it turned out
that it was the Vietnam War.
If I can have your help,
if I can have your hand,
if I can have your heart,
if I can have your prayers...
If the good Lord is willing,
I will continue
to try to lead this nation
and this world to peace.
Victory in our struggle
for civil rights and free speech
made us confident that we could
change the course of history.
Then we learned about Vietnam
and stopping the war
became our consuming cause.
The first large activity
in opposition to the Vietnam War
was Vietnam Day in May 1 965.
There was a parade of speakers
that, one after another,
started telling us
something that we really didn't know
which was what our country
was doing in Vietnam.
Most of us grew up thinking
that that United States
was a great and humble nation
that involved itself in the affairs
of other countries reluctantly
as a last and final resort.
But now, the war in Vietnam
has provided
the incredibly sharp razor
that has finally separated thousands
and thousands of people
from their illusions
about the morality and integrity
of this country's purposes
internationally.
Never again will the self-righteous
saccharine moralism
of promising a billion dollars
of economic aid
while we spend billions and billions
of dollars to destroy them,
never again will that moralism
have the power to persuade people
of the essential decency
of this country's aims.
What kind of a system is it
that allows decent men, good men,
to make the decisions
that have led to the thousands
and thousands of deaths
that have happened in Vietnam?
What kind of a system is it
that justifies the United States
in seizing the destinies
of other people
and using them callously
for our own ends?
We must name that system
and we must change it and control it,
else it will destroy us.
The war escalated rapidly.
Every month another 20,000 soldiers
shipped out to Vietnam.
Many of them came through Berkeley.
Some of us decided to stop the trains.
I was walking next to a woman
and she told me that she was a Buddhist
and that she had been pulled into
stopping the war
by the immolations of the priests.
She said she was going
to sit on the tracks
and so I said, ''OK, I will, too.''
As the train came around the bend,
I thought, ''lt has to slow down.''
But it sped up.
Then as it got closer to us,
it began shooting out steam.
As the steam hit me,
I jumped out of the steam.
I looked at the woman
l'd been talking to
and she was sitting in a full lotus
position in the middle of the tracks.
As the train went rushing by,
I thought she was under it.
When the train got past, I expected
to see a big pile of blood.
There was nothing.
She had just disappeared.
A few days later, the woman walked
into the museum where I was working,
leading a big group of children
on a tour.
I said, ''What happened?
What did you do?''
She said,
''The plain-clothes policeman
snatched me off the track
before the train got there.''
I said,
''Were you going to stay there?''
''Were you going to let the train
kill you?''
She said, ''Yes, I was going to,
but that isn't what happened
so now l'm here taking these children
through the museum.''
And it really struck me.
It really hit my heart
that here was a person
who was ready to give her life
to try to stop the war.
That's when it came through to me
just how important it was.
What we have to do
is get rid of this tactical point.
In the fall of '65,
the Vietnam Day Committee
organised its first anti-war march.
The destination
was the Oakland army terminal.
The City of Oakland refused a permit.
The VDC voted to march anyway.
All in favour of the motion
to march regardless of permit?
All opposed?
The Vietnam Day Committee
intends to have a peaceful march
through Oakland.
We intend no civil disobedience.
We do not intend to break any laws.
We've made this point quite clear.
We think it's incredible
that the Oakland authorities
have denied us a permit
for this march.
Our policy is the following.
We are going to march
down Telegraph Avenue.
We hear that a cordon
is very likely to be formed
right past the Oakland City line.
It is a very dangerous situation.
We can create a great peace movement
or destroy it.
We urge your cooperation.
We had a problem. The police had put up
a barricade at the Oakland line.
We had to deal
with what we were going to do
when the march got to that point.
Some of us ran ahead to see
if we could bluff our way through.
It was clear it was going
to be a bloody situation.
I just decided that we were turning.
l, basically, was the person
who made that decision.
For years afterwards,
I got great degrees of shit for it.
Never knew if I did right or wrong.
I still don't know
if it was the right decision.
The next day, a larger march made a
second attempt to cross into Oakland.
Once again,
a police cordon was waiting.
This time the marchers faced
another obstacle. Hell's Angels.
Why don't you people go home?
Get out of here!
Back off. Back off.
Each attempt to stop
the anti-war movement
seemed to make our numbers grow.
A month later, a third march,
far greater than the first two,
finally made it into Oakland.
The whole national mythology
was that Vietnam was a consensus war,
was bipartisan foreign policy,
all significant sectors
of the American public accepted the war
and the people who opposed it
were marginalised freaks, kooks,
unimportant people.
It was a real statement to say,
''Yes, I am willing to march
against the war.''
When thousands of people did that,
it broke that consensus.
That's what the anti-Vietnam War
movement did.
It broke that consensus.
- Go ahead, react.
- React to what?
React to the greatness of the march
on the day. Are you happy with that?
Ronald Reagan walked
onto the political stage
as a candidate for governor in 1 966.
During his campaign,
he found that attacking what
he called ''the mess at Berkeley''
pleased the crowds.
It began a year ago when
the so-called free speech advocates,
who in truth have no appreciation
for freedom,
were allowed to assault and humiliate
the symbol of law and order,
the policemen, on the campus.
That was the moment
when the ringleaders
should've been thrown out
of the university once and for all.
He won by pandering to a citizenry
that was outraged
by what these insolent,
ungrateful children
were doing on the campuses.
As a matter of fact, I have here
a copy of a report of the district
attorney of Alameda County.
It concerns a dance sponsored
by the Vietnam Day Committee,
sanctioned by the university
as a student activity,
and was held in the men's gymnasium
of the University of California.
The incidents are so bad,
so contrary to our standards
of human behaviour
that I couldn't possibly recite them
to you here in detail.
But there is evidence of things
that shouldn't be permitted
on a university campus.
Let me just read a few excerpts.
''The total crowd at the dance
was in excess of 3,000,
including a number
of less-than-college-aged juveniles.''
''Three rock'n'roll bands
were in the gymnasium
playing simultaneously
and all during the dance
movies were shown on two screens
at the opposite ends
of the gymnasium.''
''These movies were the only lights
in the gym.''
''They consisted of colour sequences,
different coloured liquids
spreading across the screen,
followed by shots of men and women
on occasion.''
''Shots where the men and women's
nude torsos on occasion...''
''And persons twisted and gyrated
in provocative and sensual fashion.''
This portion of the Gray Line
in the city
is the first and only foreign tour
within the continental limits.
The fountainhead
of the hippie subculture.
The hippies' is often a strange world
which they live in.
They take many trips.
And the trip of a hippie
is generally an unusual one.
Across the bay from Berkeley,
a counterculture emerged
on the streets of San Francisco.
Descended from
beatnik era hipsters,
hippies further exposed the chasm
between our parents' generation
and our own.
By 1 966, more and more of us
were turning on, tuning in
and dropping out.
Our alienation ran much deeper
than political protest.
We were all beginning to see
that it was much bigger than the war.
It was much, much bigger
than the civil rights movement.
There were major things wrong.
I think the people who got involved
in the counterculture
perceived that they did not want
to be a part
of what was wrong with a culture
that was destroying the world.
I can see that much better in
retrospect than I could right then.
But the point is that it was
the culture that was sick.
It was the whole American way
of looking at things that was sick.
So I think we came to a realisation
that one way to change that
is to just live it differently.
lnstead of trying
to change the structure
in a direct confrontational way,
you just drop out and live it
the way you think it ought to be.
Do you play anything
besides a sweet potato?
Just the drums and the trumpet.
Yeah, and I go up in the mountains
and yell now and then.
- You do what?
- Go up in the mountains and yell.
Way up high in the mountains
and yell as hard as I can.
- What's the purpose of that?
- To greet the dawn
and the greet the noonday sun
and to greet the sunset.
You stay all day
yelling at morning, noon and night?
Right. And standing on my head
and making gardens
and painting pictures.
You not only play the sweet potato,
you also grow them?
Right.
Why do you indulge in smoking
this... these narcotic cigarettes?
Why do people drink alcohol?
- lt's the same reason.
- lt's a big Ping-Pong table.
You say why do we do this
and we say, ''Why do you do this?''
We don't agree... You're the mess.
We're trying to change it.
Why? What are you trying
to change it to?
What are your principles?
Do you have any?
We're not trying to change anything.
We're just trying to be ourselves
- and do what we think is right.
- Why don't you go out in the desert
instead of dirtying up a community?
We're not dirtying up anything.
My parents sent away to the Bay Area
a serious young folk singer.
I came back with long hair
down to there.
I was wearing an enormous
amount of beads around my neck.
They figured I had abandoned
everything I was taught.
I realised...
We had big arguments
about this stuff.
I tried to convince them to sell
their furniture and go to lndia.
And they weren't going for it.
I realised that no matter how far out
their political views were,
because they were mighty unpopular,
my parents were pretty left wing,
that really they were materialists.
They were concerned about
how the wealth was divided up.
At that point, in my consciousness,
I didn't care about wealth.
We were actually living communally,
rather than talking about communism.
Sell that radio.
Get rid of the subscription.
Tune in to those other bands
that do not broadcast in words,
that broadcast in joy.
The form of God
is the joy of his discovery.
Up, up, up.
Everybody goes up.
The counterculture
burst onto the Berkeley campus
during a strike in the fall of '66.
At the close of a meeting,
students started to sing
Solidarity Forever
then suddenly switched
to Yellow Submarine.
They're singing,
''We all live in a yellow submarine.''
- What does this mean?
- Again, it's difficult to explain.
I think... We take this music seriously
and there's a meaning.
A meaning which everyone
can interpret differently
about the yellow submarine.
lt's a sort of...
lt's an understanding
that we're banding together
in a yellow submarine
and it represents
a new way of looking at life.
The radicals of Berkeley
and the hippies of Haight-Ashbury
had a natural affinity.
We were visionaries,
critical of conventional society.
But we disagreed
about how to change the world.
This running argument came to a head
over the war in Vietnam.
Sometime in late 1 966,
Bill Miller, who'd been active
in the Vietnam War movement
and ran a bar in Berkeley,
called some people
active in the anti-war movement
to a meeting behind his bar.
Some people from Haight-Ashbury
were organising some kind of activity.
They wanted to tell us about it
and ask for support.
It was going to be the first be-in.
There was one this fella
in particular,
he was trying to really get us
excited about the plan.
He said, ''We're going to have
so much music
and so much love and so much energy
that we're going to
stop the war in Vietnam!''
The politics of hip is that we were
setting up a new world, as it were,
that would run parallel
to the old world
but have as little to do with it
as possible.
We just weren't going to deal
with straight people.
And to us, the politicals,
a lot of the leaders of the anti-war
movement were straight people,
as they were still concerned
with the government.
They were going
to march on Washington.
We didn't even want to know
that Washington was there!
We thought that eventually the whole
world would stop all this nonsense
and start loving each other
as soon as they all got turned on.
lt's amazing that these movements
coexisted at the same time,
and were in stark contrast
in certain respects,
but as the 1 960s progressed,
they drew closer together
and began taking on
aspects of the other.
As Burns stumbled out of that bunker
dazed, with blood on him,
parts of his friends on him,
he collapsed
into the arms of Larry Craig,
and he mumbled to Larry Craig.
He didn't mumble,
''Those bastard Vietcong.''
''Those bastard communists.''
He didn't mumble,
''Those slope-eyed bastards.''
He mumbled only one thing
over and over.
''That bastard Johnson.
That bastard Johnson.''
The aim is to build
a powerful peace block
that can really have influence
in the 1 968 elections,
and we must make it clear
that we are not going to let our
political forces and the politicians
ignore Vietnam in 1 968.
This must be an issue
if that tragic war is still going on.
And so, as the war hawks
escalate the war in Vietnam,
we must escalate
our protest against the war.
We're in front of
the Oakland lnduction Center today
because this place
is going to be closed down
October 1 6th to 21 st.
We are declaring a draft holiday
for that period,
and we're going to
close this building down.
The movement
from protest to resistance,
which was the official slogan
of Stop The Draft Week
and became a major slogan
within the anti-war movement,
had something to do with the logic
of the anti-war movement.
There'd been six, seven, eight years
of educating people about the war
and of protesting it.
Meanwhile, the war
was being escalated all the time,
getting worse and worse,
and there was a feeling of impotence
in the face of the further escalation
of the war.
We were becoming much more
alienated from American society
and much more willing
to be disruptive of that society,
and, basically,
we began moving toward the view
that we wanted to make the cost
of pursuing the war abroad
the ungovernability
of the society at home.
l'd been very influenced
by Martin Luther King and Gandhi,
I believed very deeply
in non-violent civil disobedience,
and here were these leaders on campus...
I was a graduate student,
and they were saying,
''We have to raise the stakes.''
''We have to stop the war
in a much more militant way.''
I found their rhetoric seductive.
I think we were pretty convinced
that we were going to shut down
the induction centre when we went there.
We felt strong,
there were a lot of us,
we felt well organised,
we had a lot of planning meetings.
We didn't want to say,
''We don't cooperate with the war.''
We wanted to say, ''We aren't going
to allow you to wage the war.''
''We're going to fight you.''
Tuesday morning, the police came in,
wielding their clubs.
They took us seriously.
We said we were going to fight them,
so they fought us. lt was a disaster.
We just melted. They wiped us out.
Now it was, ''Here come the buses,
and there is not a damn thing
you can do about it.''
I began seeing all these young faces
in the windows going by me
and I just wanted to reach out
and just grab them and stop them
and say, ''Listen, this is your life
you're putting on the line here.''
But what came out was, ''Don't go.''
Join our lines. You don't have to go.
All you do is say no.
Say no. You don't have to go.
You don't have to go.
There were bus-load after bus-load
after bus-load
of young men that day,
and they were going off to die.
And I remember
being physically sickened,
realising that I couldn't affect
even that part of the war.
Here I was, face to face
with these young men,
and yet not one of them turned back.
I don't think we stopped one inductee
from making that critical choice
of stepping across the line
and going to Vietnam.
I don't think we made one bit
of difference that day.
- Does the demonstration bother you?
- No, I think it's funny.
All them bums running round,
doing nothing.
Tomorrow we go down there
twice as strong as we did today.
We go down there with
twice as many shields as we did today,
and we go down there
with everybody wearing one of these.
If you can see the dents in there,
I don't know
if you can see it from here,
but that's what stands between me
and a cracked skull
from the highway patrol
of the state of California.
- Where do we get the hats?
- Where do you get the hats?
- Army & Navy Surplus.
We didn't give up.
We didn't say, ''lt didn't work.''
We were able to build
for another demonstration on Friday,
and on Friday
we, in fact, had our riot,
the riot that we had planned.
The event that I remember the most
was when the students surged
and pushed against the police
and pushed them back,
block after block.
I remember thinking,
''This is like a metaphor.''
''lf enough Americans believed the war
were wrong, we could end it.''
We controlled the downtown area
of Oakland for most of the day,
and the cops were outnumbered
and confused and scared.
We shut down the induction centre.
We did what we said we'd do,
we shut the mother down.
I went
to the Stop The Draft Week protests.
And what I saw there
made me convinced
that action in the streets
of that sort
was not going to lead to the kind
of change necessary to stop the war.
I saw a lot of people from Berkeley
tear people's fences down.
Fences that belonged to people
that probably made $5,000 a year
were ripped out
to block people's cars.
Bobby Avakian, son of a judge,
a well-known young would-be radical,
let the air out of the tyres
of the district attorney.
This was going to stop the war?
I just thought this was a burlesque
of opposition to the war.
There's nothing else to do.
The picketing and all of that
wasn't working.
lt's time for confrontation.
We did stumble upon a strategy
where we said,
''lf you continue that war in Vietnam,
there's going to be chaos here
in the streets of the United States.''
''Every place you try
to do anything to do with the war,
there's going to be
thousands of young people rioting,
trying to stop you from doing it.''
While it was a great success
a turning point,
it was also
the first clear demonstration
that the radical part
of the anti-Vietnam War movement
was coming up
against its own limitations.
It didn't really have the weight
in society to stop the war.
I think that it was after that
that the Berkeley radical scene
became more and more
cut off from reality,
and the question
of moving American society,
changing people,
really was getting lost.
- Move. l've got to go to work.
- There's a war on.
I don't care. l've got to go to work.
We began to see ourselves as,
you know, glue in the keyholes.
We began to see ourselves
as obstacles
in the way of the system
fulfilling its potential
for wreaking destruction
all over the world.
I think we began to see ourselves
as being as big a pain in the butt
as we could,
and I think we lost the idea
that we could be victorious.
As confrontation and sit-in
and street demonstrations escalated,
the rest of the United States'
political community was left behind.
I was interested in the rest of the
United States, in the Newport Beach.
Those people l'd failed with
in the Thanksgiving vacation
Free Speech Movement
were the people you had to reach
if you were going to stop the war,
and the way to do that was not
to go down and sit in in the streets
in front of
the Oakland Draft lnduction Center
and tear up fences
and block streets.
The way to do that
was to be active electorally.
After the Tet Offensive,
when Westmoreland came to Johnson,
and said, ''ln order to continue
the land war in Vietnam,
we're going to need a million men,''
Johnson was told by J Edgar Hoover
that if we tried to get a million men
out of this country,
he could not ensure
the domestic security of this country.
And that was one of the questions,
one of the considerations he made,
when he decided to end the land war,
to begin to pull back
from the land war, and to resign
as an expression
of the failure of his policy
to win the war in Vietnam.
And Hoover saying
that he couldn't protect,
he couldn't ensure domestic security,
was a truthful statement
about the power
of the anti-war movement at that time.
We did put limits on America's
ability to wage the war in Vietnam.
I shall not seek
and I will not accept
the nomination of my party
for another term as your president.
We want to talk about this thing
called violence
that everybody is so afraid about.
Here you are, talking about
you're afraid of violence,
and the honky drafted you
out of school to go fight in Vietnam.
You sit in front of your TV sets
and listen to LBJ tell you
that violence never accomplishes
anything, my fellow Americans.
You ought to tell him clear,
''lf you don't want any trouble,
keep your filthy white hands
off our beautiful black skin.''
Keep them off. Keep them off.
In the streets of Oakland,
a few miles from the Berkeley campus,
the Black Panthers came forward
as the cutting edge of Black Power.
Their militancy had a magnetic effect
on the student movement.
We want the Panthers to be our friends.
We want to follow their lead
in some fashion that's confusing,
that's mysterious.
All we are aware of, we want to go,
black and white together,
into some positive future
against the oppressor
who was feeling ever more oppressive.
Bobby Seale and Huey Newton
formed the Black Panther Party
in the fall of '66.
They drew up a ten-point platform
addressing community needs
from education to housing.
The most pressing issue
was police violence
against Oakland's black community.
The Panthers decided to arm
themselves and patrol the police.
People might imagine
we were right behind the police car.
No. We may be four blocks away.
We just drive through.
If we see the police arrest somebody,
we'd get out of the car
with our guns, tape recorders,
law books.
By now, we have six, seven members
doing this, all with guns.
How we got our guns
was fantastic, too, the first guns.
The Little Red Book, The Thoughts
Of Chairman Mao Tse-Tung.
Huey calls me and says, ''l know how
we can raise some money for guns.''
I said, ''How?'' He said, ''The Little
Red Book. lt's all over the news.''
''l heard you can buy them
at the China bookstore in Frisco.''
''How much money have you got?''
I said, ''50 bucks.''
We run to the China bookstore,
buy about 1 00 of these books.
We got our guns strapped on our side.
I got a .45,
Huey's holding a shotgun,
Little Bobby's got a Carbine.
We got these bags over our shoulders
with Little Red Books.
''Red Books! $1 !'' We were buying them
for 20 cents and selling them for $1 ,
Berkeley Campus,
at Sather Gate right there!
We sold out in the matter of an hour.
We took this 1 00 bucks
and we'd buy some more Red Books.
We made $200, $300. We went out
and bought two shotguns that day
with The Little Red Book!
We hadn't even read the thing.
People think we came up with this
hardcore ideology related to Mao...
We must have sold the book
two or three months
before we decided to open the thing
and actually read it.
Anyway, the next thing I know,
l'm marching on the Capitol.
Because we were up there to protest
a bill they were trying to put in
to keep us from carrying guns.
Ronald Reagan is over here
on the big front lawn.
I got a statement to read.
The Black Panther Party calls upon
American people in general
and the black people in particular
to take note
of the racist California legislature,
which is considering legislation
aimed at keeping black people
disarmed and powerless
at the very same time racist police
agencies throughout the country
are intensifying the terror, brutality,
murder and repression of black people.
Ronald Reagan is escorted off the lawn
by the state capitol police.
I said, ''We can go inside somewhere.
lsn't there a spectator section?''
I have these Black Panthers up here.
Can we get in here?
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
- Are you going to arrest him?
- Am I under arrest?
- Did you place him under arrest?
Am I under arrest? Take your hands
off me if l'm not under arrest.
- Am I under arrest?
- Take your hands off me!
They've put trumped-up charges
of conspiracy and felonies
on everyone who went in
to exercise a constitutional right
and said they had no right
to bear arms in a public place.
The California penal code,
section 1 2020 through 1 2027,
and the Second Amendment
of the Constitution
guarantees the citizen a right
to bear arms on public property.
Our organisation was like a social
evolutionary accident, so to speak.
When you compare
the NAACP from 1 908
and other organisations, etc,
and all the years they put in
to become established,
in just six months the Black Panther
Party has international notoriety.
We're on the front page of the London
Times and papers in Africa somewhere.
We were a broke little organisation
with a number of shotguns,
a very weak treasury, and we were
worried about how to pay the rent.
And, boom.
I mean, we were shocking people.
We have probably said
to white America...
The people who were observing us
when we came out with the guns
are saying, ''Niggers with guns!''
lt's like a fear.
They don't even have to say it.
Their faces said it.
''There's too many niggers with guns.''
Like they know
that they repressed us,
and now we were organised with guns.
This is the new step.
lt's symbolic that, ''They're not
going to be non-violent any more.''
On the night of October 28th 1 967,
Huey Newton was stopped by police.
There was gunfire.
Officer Fry was killed, and Huey
Newton was arrested for murder.
His trial drew the student movement
into an alliance
with the Black Panthers.
''Free Huey'' became our rallying cry.
The organisation just propelled.
It took off like a prairie fire,
it spread everywhere.
Certainly beyond my imagination.
After Huey's arrest,
that's when things
really started rolling.
Free Huey now or else!
The Panthers
exercised a heavy influence
in the imagination of the white left,
partly because the white left
was confused about who it was
and what it ought to do.
They were fascinated
by this tough, macho image
and they followed it not so much
wilfully but involuntarily,
because it was a projection out there
of the thing in their own actions
that thrilled them most.
We had captured the imagination
of the white radical left
to a point
that its whole identification
became connected with what
the Black Panther Party was doing,
how it was personifying things.
And it was like we influenced them
in whatever direction
we thought that they should go.
I don't like to say suck up,
but they were awed by the Panthers.
The Panthers were somehow
confronting the white power structure
the way they would have liked
to have done, some of them.
But not all. Many of the whites
who led the Stop The Draft Week
could have been involved with it.
Many of those people who had been
in some parts of the early SDS
was as sceptical as I was.
But no one would, of course,
say any of these remarks publicly.
I mean, you didn't need that hassle.
So, what a lot of us did,
I think to the detriment
of the black movement, perhaps,
and to the left movement in general,
a lot of us with years
of political experience
and organisational skills
dropped out.
If not dropped out,
stepped to the side in this period.
Huey P Newton is the only leader
that black people should recognise!
A man who is willing to stand up
and face that pig,
and on his own terms.
Gun for gun if necessary.
This must be done!
You cannot sit there
and allow that man
to be railroaded any more.
You must free our leader. He must
be freed, and he will be freed.
Two days after the assassination
of Martin Luther King,
the war of nerves between the
Black Panthers and the Oakland police
came to a climax.
On April 6th 1 968,
a shoot-out erupted
in which Eldridge Cleaver was wounded
and Bobby Hutton was killed.
Bobby Hutton
was instructed by the cops
to run from here to the police car,
or the area where it was,
and was literally shot down.
He was shot over ten times.
He had five pistol bullets
in his head.
A clear-cut case of murder.
As brother Huey P Newton says,
racist pig cops must stop
their wanton murder and brutality
or suffer the wrath
of armed black people
and the black communities
defending themselves.
Historically, in retrospect,
those guns
were somewhat our nemesis.
We were never really able
to play that down.
The police, the media, used that.
We got hung up into a confrontational
thing with the police over those guns
that we were never really able
to live down.
We say, bring it on.
If you want war, let there be war.
This is what we say. ls that clear?
In other words, if he is convicted
and sentenced to death,
Oakland will erupt.
This whole country will erupt.
We're going to do everything we can
to see to it that the whole world
erupts. ls that clear?
The Panthers
seemed even crazier than they were
because they were playing the media
and the media was loving them.
The media picked up their current,
fed the narrowest parts
of their image back to us
in the most dramatic, hyped terms,
that the Panthers themselves
wanted them to be projected.
It drove the police crazy.
They were furious and wanted
to get them all over the country,
and it drove some of us...
Well, it incited some of us
with superficial fantasies
of a kind of revolution
that was completely inappropriate.
It had nothing to do with
the actual landscape of possibility.
It was interesting to me
more deeply and metaphorically.
If that was what they were doing,
what was appropriate
in our community?
The Panthers, in a sense,
let, in my opinion,
white radicals off the hook,
some white radicals, not all,
some white radicals off the hook
for what SNCC had challenged them
about three years earlier.
That was to organise
the white community.
They could say they supported the
Panthers as they were the vanguard.
They assumed the movement
could only be led by blacks.
They made it clear blacks would be
the group to start the revolution,
and that the Panthers were the army
of that black vanguard.
I was taken up with,
''Now we're not only
a protest movement,
we're not only a movement
to end the war in Vietnam,
but we are a revolutionary movement.''
We were wrong.
It wasn't a revolutionary situation.
But it was a mistake.
Everybody can make a few mistakes.
And, at the time,
it had a lot of the aspects to us
of a revolutionary situation.
'68 was a real high time,
what we were doing.
We identified
with the student movement
and the large protest movement
in Paris.
There was the Prague Spring
and the feeling that revolution
was in the air, east and west,
capitalist and communist.
It was all coming apart
in a new spirit.
A new wave of liberation
was in the air.
I felt that the world was unravelling,
history had speeded up,
that the world
was swirling around me.
The movement had expanded.
The anti-war movement was immense.
The women's liberation movement
had begun.
The world was undergoing change at
a rate that I could hardly comprehend,
and yet I was in it and I was
part of it, and I was changing.
I always remember
this particular period of time,
because the change
was so phenomenal.
I went to sleep one night
and I was a woman
who was dissatisfied
with my position
as a woman in society,
but I felt solitary
in that dissatisfaction.
And suddenly I wake up
and, right and left,
everybody is speaking about it.
I have women
who agree with me everywhere.
We start to form a sisterhood.
Everything in my life that has
disturbed me is being challenged.
Things that haven't disturbed me
before, suddenly they do.
When we began
to try to take a more active role
in steering committees
and decision-making forums
in the movement,
we began to see our comrades
resisting our input.
And we looked at them
and we said, ''What?''
''How can they do this to us?
These are our brothers.''
''Why aren't they interested
in what we have to say?''
''They're only interested in the fact
that we're always there for them.''
''And we always make the coffee
and we run off the leaflets
and we make all the telephone calls
late into the night,
and yet when we try to participate
on a more active level,
we meet resistance.''
What you see here
is the beginning of a movement
that women are human beings
and that we have equal rights.
We intend to go to school and have
childcare so we can go to school.
We want the university to run classes
that teach us about our history,
the same as black people
want to learn about their history.
That's what is happening today.
This is just the beginning.
One of the ways the women's movement
is the logical and maybe even
inevitable conclusion of the '60s
is that throughout the '60s
we were trying to imagine
how to live differently,
how to change the world.
The women's movement took much
from the civil-rights movement,
the new left, the anti-war movement,
but we brought it home.
We brought it into the kitchen,
we brought it into the bedroom,
we brought it into the most personal,
intimate aspects of people's lives.
It was hard to deny there.
It was hard to ignore those issues.
When I thought of revolution then,
the whole idea had assumed
complex, enormous dimensions.
It didn't mean a simple change
in the institutional order.
It meant a coordinated change
in all the dimensions,
all the aspects of life.
How we were with ourselves,
how we were with each other.
This was so complex a programme,
you couldn't write it down
as the 1 3-point programme
of the Berkeley Revolutionary Front.
This was something that would take
thousands, millions of people
engaged all their lives in exploring
this end of it and this end of it
and how these ends
might fit together,
and it was clear by then
that all this exploration
was there to do.
People had begun
each part of the exploration.
I forbear to list them, OK?
And, at the same time, it seemed
impossible. There was no time.
The war got worse faster,
the political activity got worse faster,
they were killing
more and more people.
Every time you placed some degree
of hope in a national leader...
So much life, so much death.
So much possibility,
so much impossibility.
There we were,
attempting to change national politics,
and found ourselves
at the Chicago Convention.
It changed American politics
in unpredictable ways.
We had not anticipated,
speaking for those involved
in the electoral side of politics,
we did not anticipate
the arbitrary exercise of authority
that Mayor Daley
would bring to bear in Chicago.
And it was phenomenal.
Mr Chairman,
most delegates to this convention
do not know that thousands
of young people are being beaten
in the streets of Chicago.
And for that reason
and that reason alone,
I request the suspension of the rules
for the purpose of adjournment
for two weeks to relocate
the convention in another city
of the choosing
of the Democratic National Committee
and the presidential candidates...
Wisconsin is not recognised
for that purpose!
There was a side of American politics
that was vicious and violent,
and that's what we saw in Chicago.
Daley rolled over
the anti-war forces,
and it was a destruction
of the Democratic Party.
It seemed impossible
that there could be any significant
electoral path toward ending the war
following the convention.
It seemed that what had happened
in the parks of Chicago
made the anti-war movement
destined for direct action
for quite a period of time.
The violence in Chicago
triggered confrontations on campuses
across the country.
Berkeley students calling for
a Third World College initiated a strike
which provoked daily battles
between police and protestors.
After eight weeks, Governor Reagan
sent in the National Guard
and the strike died down.
Eventually, an ethnic studies programme
was established,
but in the wake of the strike,
an atmosphere of tension remained.
A month later,
student and community activists
came together
to create People's Park.
I was one of those people
who believed that the counterculture
could be revolutionary.
lt's hard to talk about that
without talking about People's Park.
A group of people
took some corporate land
owned by the University of California
that was a parking lot,
turned it into a park
and then said, ''We're using the land
better than you used it,
and it's ours.''
For a brief moment in history,
in People's Park,
the counterculture
and political activists
had a magical fusion.
It was a way of looking
at the future. lt was utopian.
It was a way of saying,
''lf we had control of our lives,
this is what it would look like.''
In a down-to-earth way,
we were showing in our very activity
the image of a new society.
Our job is to form a counterculture,
a more rural culture,
a more decentralised culture,
to develop counter-values
of cooperation,
of a production for use
rather than a production for profit,
develop that culture in hope
that that culture would be
in revolutionary contradiction
to a bourgeois culture.
And that we should view ourselves
as revolutionaries
but really as founding mothers
and fathers of this counterculture.
I can almost convince myself now!
As I see it, the great hope
implicit in the People's Park
is that in our leisure time,
so to speak,
we will make the social revolution.
Property is not a thing
to keep men apart and at war,
but rather a medium by which
men can come together to play,
a people's park.
People's Park managed to focus
all of the frustrations
as well as some of the ideals
of the '60s.
There was a belief
in the environment,
a belief in the participation
of ordinary people
in political decision-making,
a belief that a lot of things
ought to count
that traditionally don't count
when they're caught up in government
and university bureaucracy.
There was all of that.
But the fact remains that
I believe the People's Park incident
was extremely cynical
on the part of the demonstrators.
They wanted a confrontation.
What mattered was getting people
out in the streets, demonstrating.
Roger Hinds and the regents
and Ronald Reagan
can't allow this to go on.
If there's one liberated territory,
people may get the idea there
could be other liberated territories.
The park issue is not the issue.
The issue is, ''We must have
a confrontation throughout the summer.''
They were
out of confrontation issues.
And as soon as you give them a park,
they'll dream up another confrontation.
We have been invaded by people
outside of the state,
outside of the cities,
we have been invaded by militants.
This is... We're in a revolution,
and the only thing, don't ever say
we're going into a revolution.
We're in a revolution!
Now the question is, who will win it?
When Jesus disrupted the foreign
recruiters, his followers said...
''Power to the people.
Out, demons, out.''
I declare this place decontaminated
from poisons, chains and lies,
from the abomination that defiles.
The demons have returned to
the nothingness from which they came.
Earth, water, air and fire,
witness our liberation.
This property is private.
You are now trespassing.
Unless you leave,
you will be arrested for trespassing.
If they didn't want the park, they
should've stopped us when we started,
and not let us work on it every day
and then just take it away.
lt's their park now. What can we do?
I have a suggestion.
Let's go down to the People's Park,
because we are the people!
We want the park! We want the park!
Here they come.
Those people told you
for days in advance
that if the university sought
to go ahead with that construction
on that property, they would
physically destroy the university.
Governor, we offered to negotiate
many times.
Negotiate? What is to negotiate?
What is...?
Wait a minute. On that issue, don't
you simply explain to these students
that the university has a piece
of property that it bought
for future construction of the campus
and it was now going ahead with
the plan? What do you mean, negotiate?
Governor Reagan, the time has passed
when the university
can just ride roughshod
over the desires of the majority
of its student body.
The university
is a public institution,
an important institution
for all of its own community
and for the Berkeley community
around it.
All of it began the first time
some of you who know better
and are old enough to know better
let young people think
that they had the right
to choose the laws they would obey,
as long as they were doing it
in the name of social protest.
When the fence went up, the whole
experience of People's Park changed.
Governor Reagan
brought in the National Guard,
the city was occupied for a month,
and what happened is, the worst
aspects of the movement emerged.
People did things
that were totally counterproductive.
They tried to provoke the National Guard
into fixing their bayonets.
They tried to cause skirmishes
on the campus.
I found it possible
to resist the feeling,
the collective hallucination,
that we were involved
in a revolutionary struggle.
But there was one moment when
I became immersed in that feeling.
There was a peaceful demonstration
on Sproul Plaza
denouncing the university's
overreaction to the park,
the police brutality
towards students,
the National Guard on campus,
occupying the city.
My boyfriend and I and a friend of mine
went down to the plaza
to hear the rally,
and as we got there,
we realised that the police
were letting people into the plaza
but they were not letting people out.
My friend, by that time, had already
gone through the police lines
and I motioned for her to come back,
and they wouldn't let her out.
Pigs off campus! Pigs off campus!
Killers off campus!
..requesting you all
to leave the plaza.
If you don't leave, you're going
to be shot in the next five minutes.
I started hearing
the sounds of a helicopter,
and it came closer and closer
and the sound got louder and louder
and suddenly the helicopter
swooped over the whole campus,
over all the students, and I thought,
''We're going to be shot at.
We're the Vietcong.''
Everybody on the outside
of the police line was running
to try to get away from the gas.
Everybody on the inside of the police
line was trying to get out.
And the police were beating people
as they tried to get out.
We went back to Kroeber Hall
and waited for my friend to show up.
She'd been through the mill. She had
been throwing up, it was nausea gas.
So we drove up to the rose garden.
We were standing there, looking out
across the roses and the campus,
and there were still helicopters
circling around.
She looked at me and said, ''l can't
stand this. l'm going to get out.''
I said, ''l think you're right.
I think it's all over.''
''l don't think we can stay here any
more.'' lt was a poignant moment.
And a year later, we were all gone.
We all felt very defeated.
It was a horrible experience
to gas students at a peaceful rally.
And it was one reason
why people began to feel that we had
to reassert what we really stood for,
that we really had to protest the park
in a dignified and peaceful way,
and recapture the original spirit
of the park.
And that led to
the Memorial Day march.
We'll get People's Park
back eventually.
Everybody who's ever done
any hitchhiking
knows that basically we can't lose.
When you sit out and hitchhike,
in the front seat are the parents
and they give you this real scared,
contemptuous look as they drive by,
but then, in the back seat, as they
drive away, you see the kids going...
We got the kids on our side
and we can't lose. We just can't lose.
When you're in a mass movement
to change society,
when you're in this experience
of this democracy breaking out,
you don't want it to end.
You want the storm to continue.
You want to keep that sense of change
and overwhelming power
that one gets from the ocean.
You might not be able
to keep the rowboat straight or up,
but you don't want the storm to die.
There was no vision,
no articulate philosophy,
no conception of social organisation
and social change.
What there were
were a series of emotional moments,
a series of passions, a series
of desperately important issues.
But you can't beat something
with nothing,
and if you're going to fight
this kind of long cultural battle,
you are bound to lose
if you don't have a coherent,
articulate, well-worked-out vision
of what you're trying to do
and that they didn't have.
We had taken what we had
as far as we could go.
I think that it's important
not to lose sight
of what that movement accomplished.
That is, it was part of the struggle
for civil rights.
It was part of the movement
in this country
that broke down
the Jim Crow barriers
and changed the caste relationships
of blacks and other minorities
in our society.
It was part of the movement
that liberalised American culture.
that gave way
to the ideas of women's equality
and women's liberation.
It was part of a movement
that ultimately made it impossible
to carry out so blatantly the kind
of imperialistic foreign policy
that characterised
the period after World War Two.
American society was profoundly
changed by the movements of the '60s.
In the '60s, we came
at a certain point in the Cold War
to reject the ideologies
of both sides,
and our declaration of freedom
was a political freedom,
but it had a larger dimension,
that is, the freedom of imagination.
Having gained the freedom
to see the world freshly
and the ability to act for change,
we carried what we'd learned
into the rest of our lives.
From personal issues
to planetary concerns,
we continued to explore
the potential for change.
And as we watch activists for human
rights and democracy around the world
challenge the powers that be,
we know that each generation
has its chance to make things change,
and that no generation
can do it alone.
We shall live in peace!
Subtitles by lMS