T.J.: I have a 1962 Impala.
It's all original.
Previously on "Betrayal"...
T.J. was with me that night.
How much is Thatcher Karsten
paying you to say that?
THATCHER:
It's not over, not by a long shot.
They brought the battle to us,
so this is war.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
JACK: What do you want, Zarek?
I want to be a full member
of the team.
That's between you and Thatcher.
It's more complicated now.
Don't threaten me.
I'll take it.
It's a lot of space for one person.
It is just you, right?
Yes.
I'm a lone wolf.
Free. Unencumbered.
Very greedy.
Hmm.
I'm not sure you're
the right buyer for this.
Oh, well, I flew
all the way here from Lisbon.
Oh, I'm sorry that you went
to so much trouble.
Are you, uh,
are you sure
there's nothing I can do...
to change your mind?
Like what?
I'm sorry, but what do you think
you're doing?
[ Clicks tongue ]
Miss, this is highly inappropriate.
I just really...
want...
this apartment.
[ Cellphone buzzing ]
[ Buzzing continues ]
1.05 - ...Nice Photos
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
Jack McAllister...
Leave a message.
Hot wine guy is here for the tasting.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
[ Clicks tongue ]
Uh, have him come back tomorrow
when Paulette's in.
He wants you.
He always wants you.
He knows you're married.
What's the harm?
Part of being married is knowing
when not to put yourself
in certain situations.
[ Dialing ]
Jack McAllister...
Leave a message.
Hey, uh, the father of some kid
in Vic's class called for you.
Maybe it's a dad's-night-out thing.
I know how you love those.
Um, all right. Talk later.
Aidan!
You know, I-I actually do have
a few minutes now.
ANNOUNCER:
Using the latest in sustainable design,
Karsten Allied will build
a mixed-use enterprise...
- Is that for the investor presentation?
- And the city council.
They're obsessed with green buildings.
So I got us a shipment
of solar panels out of China.
- China?
- Mm-hmm.
No, no, no. Let's wait on that.
Look, if we can get some more
out of our U.S. suppliers...
Look, Thatcher.
I'm working on it
with a customs official.
We're not going through customs.
So, what, we smuggle them in?
10,000 panels are arriving tonight.
I want you to be there
to receive them.
[ Scoffs ]
That is not part
of my job description.
Well, your job description
is changing.
Need some help with that, Jack?
No, I don't think
that will be necessary.
Oh, look at him...
Such a stand-up guy,
everything above board.
On second thought,
maybe you should come.
Good.
The panels should be there
around 10:00.
You'll need to break the seal.
Once you've checked out the sample,
I want you to get those trucks
in and out of there as fast as you can.
Tariff evasion,
trade exploitation, commercial fraud.
Here we go.
ALISSA:
Sara.
[ Telephone rings in distance ]
Janet, hi.
My name's Sara Hanley.
I'm so pleased to meet you.
Sara's shooting the photos
for the Boyd piece.
Oh.
I'm really looking forward
to working with you.
I loved your series
on the revolution in Egypt.
I think it was in Newsweek.
It was... It was so powerful.
Two years ago, I was covering
rebels in Tahrir Square.
Now I'm doing a profile of a local C.E.O.
for a local magazine.
Uh, well, you know,
Boyd's actually more complicated
than I expected.
Could be good for the story, so...
I'm heading over there now
if you want to share a cab.
That's okay. I have a car.
She is talented
but requires special handling.
All right, then. I'll handle her.
I like it, but what's with you?
You're so agreeable lately.
I don't know. New shampoo?
Really? Mm.
- See you later.
- Mm-hmm.
[ Insects chirping ]
The wine guy's got a crush on me.
The wine guy?
His name's Aidan.
He's 29.
Hmm. Really?
Aidan?
Is that a man's name?
[ Chuckles ]
Is it so hard to believe?
What, a crush on you?
Of course not.
Thanks for telling me, I guess.
Well, wouldn't you tell me
if some hot, young thing
had a crush on you?
[ Chuckles ]
So he's hot and young.
Mm-hmm.
And he's got good taste.
Impeccable.
He's a wine guy.
Hmm.
I got to go to work.
Uh, don't wait up.
It's a bunch of sun panels,
not heroin, not C-4.
What's the big deal?
Trade rules are complicated.
It shouldn't be illegal, but it is.
It's all good.
I'll get my trucks in.
[ Static ]
Does it make you sleep better at night
thinking this shouldn't be illegal?
[ Static ]
Drive in. We're good to go.
Sounds like someone
doesn't have the stomach
for his job anymore.
Well, at least I still have
the brains for it.
[ Laughs ]
- Hey, Henry.
- Hey.
How's your little girl?
[ Door closes ]
Better. She's in rehab now.
Thanks for your help with the cops.
You doing okay?
It's a bad night, Jack.
You under the weather?
Real bad night.
You should go home.
We're being watched.
We have to turn the trucks around.
Turn around!
Out of here, out of here!
[ Truck engines rev ]
Where are they going?
Why are they turning around?
If they don't move the contraband,
we've got nothing.
How did they know?
I'll figure it out,
but we have to stay within the lines
and make sure nothing
could be used against us.
We have a rat, Jack.
[ Cellphone buzzes ]
Someone inside this company
has turned on us.
DREW:
They're guilty. It's obvious.
Sneaking around
in the middle of the night,
covering their tracks.
A fleet of trucks
drove in and out, empty.
That's enough for a warrant,
Your Honor.
There was a time no one
had the balls to cross me.
This is the time to strike.
We have to stay a step ahead.
We have to catch them now.
This whole thing's about to blow up.
[ Elevators ding ]
We've got nothing.
They destroyed it all.
I love you.
[ Lens whirs, camera shutter clicks ]
Anything missing?
Oh, yeah.
[ Bell rings in distance ]
The bulb from the lid.
Other than that?
Anything wrong with this picture?
Yeah, I replaced the cardboards
for a 1960, not '62.
- Keen eye.
- [ Laughs ]
You're good to go.
Hey, y-you don't need any extra
help around here, do you?
I can pull engines out and...
and take off hoods.
Seriously?
Know a hell more about cars
than you do.
I'm happy to clean tires.
I know how to use that gel
to make them look new.
I guess we could try it out.
Oh, that'd be great. Thanks.
- Thanks.
- [ Laughs ]
I've hired a new security team
to sweep the office for bugs.
We'll have them start
in Thatcher's office...
MAN: McAllister, Jack McAllister.
Is he in?
- Sir, if you don't have an appointment...
- Uh, w-what's the trouble?
Mr. McAllister,
do you know this man?
- You Vic's dad?
- Yeah. Who are you?
- Vic attacked my son with a baseball bat.
- What?
Ricky's in the hospital!
- Look, I know they had a fight, but he...
- After that!
Your kid hit him with a bat
and left him bleeding on the sidewalk!
Hey. Easy now, pal.
Yeah, look, I don't know what
you're talking about, all right?
Hey!
[ Shouts ]
I'm not letting him off the hook,
and I'm not letting you off the hook!
Wow.
You screwing his wife, too?
Shut up.
JANET:
Hey.
SARA:
I got some really interesting
stuff today.
And I got a call from
the company's publicist.
I hear you're taking up
a lot of their time.
Well, Boyd's a difficult guy.
There are a lot of angles here,
like his ex-C.T.O.
You photographed her?
Well, she sued him
for hostile work environment
and won.
Her story's pretty intense.
This is your first cover, isn't it?
[ Telephone ringing in distance ]
You know what?
I'll leave my prints on your desk.
I think you might find them useful.
Let's see.
My story will be in the magazine queue
by the end of the day.
Read it.
[ Ringing continues ]
After we broke up, I moved here,
but she kept the ring,
which would have come in handy
for first and last month's rent.
Oh. Yeah, that's rough.
How long were you together?
Six months.
Six months?
What, then it wasn't meant to be?
[ Scoffs ]
Well, I mean, you really should
still be in the honeymoon phase
at that point.
You know, you...
You want to be together all the time.
You can't keep your hands
off each other.
And after the honeymoon phase?
The mystery turns into security.
And you have kids,
and then you just stop...
needing so much.
Wow.
Marriage sounds awesome.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Oh, sorry.
This is about my son.
Teenage boys...
That's another awesome thing.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Device beeping steadily ]
Look, we need to monitor
everyone coming in and out.
More cameras, access control points.
[ Device beeping rapidly ]
Why is that beeping?
Well, the computer and phone
may be setting it off.
We'll remove them after
we've finished the general scan
and sweep the area again.
Hey, can we talk?
[ Beeping continues steadily ]
Hi. Uh, I'm sorry.
Could you excuse us, please?
Oh. No problem.
Be here all week.
Are you all right?
Well, after I, uh, got your text,
I talked to Vic,
and he says he didn't do it.
You believe him?
I want to believe him.
I-I mean, I do, but, uh...
He's been boxing.
Did you know that?
- No.
- With my father?
No, I didn't.
[ Scoffs ]
I just feel like we're living
in separate worlds.
We have no idea
what's going on with each other.
Well, you know, they're teenagers.
I mean, this is what happens.
Not just them.
Us, too. You and me.
You forgot the sprinklers.
The tomatoes are dried up.
The turnips are dead.
Well, I never
really liked turnips anyway.
I'm sorry.
Uh, I've been distracted...
You know, T.J.'s case.
This A.S.A. guy's all over us.
[ Sighs ]
Are we okay?
Look, I-I'm stuck here late
with security, but...
How about we, uh,
go out tomorrow night together?
Does that sound good?
Yeah. I would like that.
I'll talk to Vic.
[ Silverware clacking ]
She ignored everything I gave her.
I mean, her article could have
been written by Boyd's P.R. flack.
Guess I shouldn't be so surprised.
Photographers can see things
that reporters don't.
Why?
I don't know.
We just get at stuff
from a different angle.
[ Ball thudding ]
Careful, buddy.
Go wash your hands.
Hey, do you think it's okay
that Ollie eats
mac and cheese every day?
I mean, Joelle's turned
her whole family vegan.
Grows their own veggies
in the backyard.
It's a thing now.
McAllister's wife
does turnips and tomatoes.
[ Utensils scraping ]
[ Utensils clack ]
Oliver, dinner's ready!
I love this picture.
Remember?
You could get him to stop crying
by handing him a balloon.
[ Chuckles ]
We need to go at this
from a different angle.
Our warrant expires in 24 hours.
Look, the problem is,
we've been trying
to get Karsten on the big stuff,
the hard stuff...
racketeering, corruption.
Instead, we need
to go after something easier,
more attainable.
Like what?
Witness tampering.
We get the hooker
to go to Karsten wearing a wire.
She gets him to admit
he paid her to be T.J.'s alibi.
That's asking a lot.
She already planted a bug for us.
And it's too dangerous.
We can't train her in 24 hours.
Larry, you are retiring.
We need to get you
one big victory to ride out on.
The party tonight's more than enough.
This girl has spent her entire life
pretending she thinks
and feels things she doesn't.
She can do this.
She's great at lying.
Business, where are we
with the Michael Boyd article?
Cover line...
"Chicago's best C.E.O.: Mr. Cool."
Photos?
Uh, fine. I'm still working on them.
Culture?
Column on why the national media
loves to beat up on Chicago.
Wow. That old chestnut.
Alissa,
could the three of us talk after?
Is there a problem?
No.
I'll tell you later.
Tell me now.
That's what this meeting is for.
It's just, I don't think
that the photos
and the story match up.
[ Laughs ]
Dear God.
You're like a little
wind-up toy that won't stop.
What's the problem?
Okay.
[ Papers rustle ]
This is Boyd accepting the award
for most eco-friendly C.E.O. in Chicago.
And this is the hummer
that he keeps at his lake house.
We're all hypocrites. So?
This is Boyd screaming
at his head of H.R.
Alissa, this is ridiculous.
The woman in accounting he fired
after she refused to go out with him.
Boyd's not the best anything
in Chicago.
He's just a phony jerk
who made a lot of money.
- For his company and his shareholders...
- So he's talented.
Which is how we judge...
Does that mean he gets away
with whatever he wants?!
It's not our job to protect his image,
and I would have thought
you of all people
would agree with that.
I'm gonna need
a different photographer.
Who was that in there?
Okay, maybe I was out of line,
but weren't you a little bit glad
I said what I said?
But what came over you?
I thought I was doing my job.
Janet's writing a total puff piece.
And we run those sometimes.
Why?
Does Boyd's company
buy a lot of ads or something?
Look, Sara, we can't use
these pictures, okay?
But they are fantastic,
so I'm gonna call my friend
at the New York Times
and see if they want
to order up reporting.
- Are you serious?!
- [ Laughs ]
Thank you!
This new Sara, this...
this whole transformation,
it's because of him, isn't it?
- It's not just that.
- The crazy fling that you're having.
- It's not a fling.
- Then what is it?
I told him I loved him.
Damn.
You are in trouble.
What the hell?
I'm in the middle of a game.
Ricky's father came to see me.
[ Sighs ]
Yeah, I know. Mom said.
Did you do it?
No!
[ Slams table ]
I didn't do it!
I mean,
Ricky's got like a million enemies.
You better not be lying to me.
Why? 'Cause you never lie?
I mean, you're never home.
It's like you don't even
live here anymore.
I sleep less,
but I have more energy.
Colors are brighter.
Everything is clearer.
It's like...
I can finally see,
and I don't ever remember
feeling this way.
Not even with Drew?
With Drew, it was different.
It was... It was never like this.
What's the deal with his marriage?
I mean, does he ever talk
about his wife?
Well, it's like we've been living in a...
a bubble.
There are a lot of things
we don't talk about.
[ Sighs ]
T.J.
I thought you were
coming back to the office.
No, dad, I...
I work here now. I told you.
T.J., get in the car.
I'm in the middle of my job.
This isn't a job.
Yes, it is!
I'm fixing a broken spring.
Why do you think
they want you here?
Because I know about this stuff,
and I'm good at it.
No, because you come from money.
That's what they want.
They're just using you.
Yeah, to replace a front suspension.
It doesn't make any sense!
Look, son, I-I just don't
want to see you get hurt.
That's all.
Now, come on.
No, I-I-I have to align it
after I repair it.
T.J., use your head.
Of all the people in Chicago
who can fix a car,
why do you think
they would hire you?!
Get in the car.
[ Engine turns over ]
Do you ever feel
we don't know enough
about each other?
JACK: Mm, no, I think
I've done a pretty thorough,
head-to-toe examination of...
You know what I mean.
You have a whole life, a home.
I want to hear about it.
[ Clicks tongue ]
I can't always pretend
I'm a nymphomaniac from Lisbon.
[ Both laugh ]
Okay.
What do you want to know?
Your daughter.
What's she into?
Uh, folk music with lots of shouting.
[ Chuckles ]
Lesbian computer nerds.
Well, she sounds cool.
And your son?
Oh, Vic... He's going through
a bit of a rough time.
Uh, we're working through it.
Teenagers.
And Elaine?
You want to talk about Elaine?
Yeah, I do.
Um...
Okay, well, she's... [sighs]
She's strong, smart.
Um, she's a great mother.
Um...
She has a-a restaurant
that she's doing really well with.
She, uh, she gardens, right?
Turnips and tomatoes?
How did you know that?
Uh, Drew.
He was talking about the case.
Why was Drew talking
about my wife?
I don't know. Um...
I shouldn't have said anything.
No. I don't think I like this game.
Keep an eye on T.J.
I don't want him
going back to that garage.
I'm on it.
Jack, that little snafu
with the solar panels
is costing me $20,000 a day.
Got any ideas?
You know what we should do?
Go to that prosecutor,
raid his house. Right, Jack?
[ Picture frame clacks ]
There you go. Problem solved.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Indistinct cheering and applause ]
Number seven with the pigtails.
She's yours, right?
Amy?
What are you doing here?
I love soccer.
MAN: Go, go, go, go!
[ Cheers and applause continue ]
I already did you a favor.
This will be the last time I ask.
They will kill me.
We can protect you.
We can ensure your safety.
[ Sighs ]
No. I'm done.
Look.
[ Sighs ]
If you help us with this,
we can put Karsten away for good,
and he won't ever
be able to hurt you.
Men like you.
You want what you want,
like my clients,
only they don't pretend
to be anything.
But you...
You pretend to be good.
[ Sighs ]
I'll take an honest thief any day.
Happy anniversary, you two.
Dmitri, table 24 is ready
for dessert,
but you need to crumb
that table first, please.
Oh, Romy, that reminds me,
I packed that chocolate cake
for your mom's birthday.
And now your present's
better than mine.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, excuse me.
Would you mind giving that a try?
It's not on the menu yet.
Uh, sure. I-I don't mind.
Thanks, but promise me
you'll be honest.
[ Chuckles nervously ]
It's delicious.
You don't like it.
No, it's good.
Now, you don't have to lie
just to be nice.
Isn't it crazy
how women always do that?
Yeah, it really is.
I wonder if maybe it needs
a little cilantro.
Honestly, I have no idea.
I can't cook.
My son eats mac and cheese
out of the box every night, so...
[ Laughs ]
Well, you know that cooking is just
about practice and familiarity.
My mother spent
her life in the kitchen,
so if I wanted to talk to her,
that's where I had to go.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, my mother was a perfectionist.
She hated mess,
so the kitchen was off-limits.
You know what, though?
I made nutritious meals for my kids
from the time
that they were very little,
and I really don't think it made
much of a difference at all.
[ Chuckles ]
Hi. You're back soon.
Yeah, well, you know,
I had to bring you
this '09 Syrah from Napa.
Okay.
I heard it has a smooth finish.
Yeah, and nice legs.
- Maybe we should give it a taste.
- Okay.
I need to get going, so...
Oh, I'm Elaine, by the way.
I own the place.
Oh. Sara.
You look familiar.
Have we met?
No, I don't think so.
Well, it's nice to meet you now.
Yeah, you too. Bye.
Hey, listen, if you get
that whole-wheat mac and cheese
and you throw in egg whites
and carrot puree,
voilà, healthy meal.
Kind of.
[ Chuckles nervously ]
Thank you.
Okay.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
DREW:
Snack mom it's a thankless job.
Kids... They want candy.
Parents want fruit.
[ Cooler thuds ]
[ Sighs ]
Get away from my car.
Yeah, I used to play t-ball here...
Well, back when it was a field,
not a parking lot.
Let me get that for you.
[ Sighs ]
I grew up over in Humboldt Park.
I used to spend my summers
reading all day at the Pulaski Library,
then I'd go over to Nebbie's
where my mom worked
to help her serve red-hots.
You seem like a gold coast kid.
Nope. Single mom, four kids.
She struggled, but she was tough.
Like you.
We go to Nebbie's all the time.
- Mm.
- Konstantine is still there.
Good, old Konstantine.
- You knew him?
- Yeah, of course.
'Cause there is
no Konstantine there.
Not only are you a liar,
you're not even good at it.
[ Sighs ]
The thing about my family,
that's all true.
[ Laughs ]
- What's wrong with you?
- Look.
There is one thing that I care about,
one thing I need,
and time is running out.
- Well, I can't help you!
- Why not?
Why are you gonna let Karsten
use you like this?
What, I should be your pawn
instead of his?
You got to have dreams, right?
Something you aspire to.
Haven't you ever
wanted anything that badly?
Yeah, I want things.
A place in a good school district,
my record cleaned, a green card.
No questions asked.
You make me an American,
I'll be whatever you want.
Whoo!
You did such a good job.
GIRL:
Thank you.
Yes, and you were running so fast.
So, they're not gonna use
the photos?
No, but Alissa's sending them
to the New York Times.
Wow. That would be a step up.
Standing up to Janet like that
could have been a disaster,
but it felt kind of good.
Might even work out better in the end.
What do you think of this tie?
It's fine.
You look pretty, Mommy.
Where are you going?
My boss' retirement party.
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
Oliver, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
What are you doing?!
[ Both laugh ]
[ Cellphone beeping ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Here it comes!
I'm not done!
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughs ]
Larry, you are totally irreplaceable.
That being said,
I am on the list of people
to replace you, right?
How close to the top
of that list am I?
Closer than you were yesterday.
You got Brandy Korskaya
to thank for that.
She's gonna drive this thing home.
Hope you're right.
I know I'm right
'cause I'm gonna put her
in training first.
That's a change.
Uh, she's not as ready
as I thought, and...
She's got this little kid.
No reason
to pull the trigger tonight.
There he is...
The last good man! [ Laughs ]
Congratulations, Larry.
I hear you're taking your wife to Rio.
10-day cruise.
Good for you.
I love this song.
We're dancing, Larry.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
You look great tonight.
You seem good lately.
Happy.
Yeah, I guess I have been.
It's been a long time
since we've done this.
What, dance?
Gone out.
Had a good time together.
Let's try and make it happen
more often.
Yeah, that would be nice.
[ Knock on door ]
I wanted to apologize for this morning.
I didn't know who you were
or what really happened.
Agh!
[ Groans ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
[ Sighs ]
Ohh!
[ Barking continues ]
[ Sighs ]
Okay. Okay.
That's enough.
Get the hell out of here!
Look. [Sighs]
I hope Ricky's feeling better.
This should cover your expenses.
Hey, my son is in here
drinking his dinner through a straw!
I ain't taking your blood money!
I know who you are, man!
You're Thatcher Karsten's bitch!
Don't come back here again!
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Music plays in background ]
Our warrant dies in 15 hours.
We'll get another one.
- The whole point...
- She's not ready.
I see that now. Thank you.
I don't understand.
What happened?
[ Sighs ]
This girl got to you, didn't she?
What we are asking her to do
is dangerous.
I don't want to rush into anything.
[ Engine idling ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Music continues ]
[ Applause ]
[ Laughs ]
Thanks, guys. Thank you.
[ Applause continues ]
[ Cellphone beeping ]
Yeah!
Oh, yeah!
Thanks, guys. Thank you.
Thanks a lot. Thank you all.
[ Applause continues ]
[ Distorted applause ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
Sara.
Sara, what's wrong?!
What... What is it?
[ Crying ]
Hey.
[ Breathing heavily ]
What... What... What is it?
What are you saying?
I want to go.
I just want to go home, okay?
What? What?
- I just want to go home.
- Okay.
- I want to go home.
- All right.
- Want to go home.
- We'll go home, baby.
[ Sighs ]
Never knew so much could come
out of such a little person.
- [ Laughs, sniffles ]
- Take blue bear, mommy.
Oh, thanks, love bug.
I'll be fine, okay?
You just go back to bed, okay?
So, night-night.
Okay.
[ Footsteps fading ]
- I'll go get you some water.
- Thanks.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Footsteps approaching ]
There you go.
[ Sniffles ]
Thanks.
I love you, babe.
[ Sniffles ]
Oh, thanks for taking
such good care of me.
[ Sighs ]
[ Rock music playing in headphones ]
Damn. What happened?
[ Music stops ]
I went to visit Ricky's father.
You could have a life full of...
lying and cheating and guilt.
You could look like a good person,
and you could fool everybody.
You could get so good
at deceiving people
that you'd never get caught.
But you would know.
And you wouldn't be able
to look at yourself in the mirror.
And I don't want that life for you.
[ Sighs ]
You're grounded.
You can use the kitchen computer
for school.
When do I get my stuff back?
When you tell me the truth.
Hey, Vic, I...
What happened to your face?
Jack. What's going on?
Huh? Let me see this.
Where were you?
I went to see the kid's father...
The kid that Vic put in the hospital.
Jack, we don't know
that Vic put that kid...
[ Scoffs ]
We know. Come on.
We know.
Why would you go to see him?
[ Sighs ]
To fix it.
What does that mean?
I fix things.
That's what I do.
Got to go clean the yard.
Babe, where's your camera?
I want to see those pictures Oliver took.
On the dresser.
Drew said it would be next week.
Change of plan.
Now, if anything goes wrong,
slip the word "Friday"
into the conversation,
and we'll get you out.
[ Sighs ]
We won't let anything happen to you.
T.J.:
Sorry.
Hey.
I'm sorry I...
I took this by accident.
And I'm sorry I left
in the middle of my shift.
Whatever, man.
If I were you, I'd be sipping cristal
and sailing around on my yacht.
Just do whatever you got to do, man.
Rodney, I-I can tell
you're a good person.
I-I trust you.
You know, I-I promise you.
I-I'll be here every day on time,
ready to work if you'll still let me.
What about your old man?
He didn't seem
to want you hanging around here.
No.
But I'm not gonna let him
tell me what to do anymore.
Let's go get you a locker.
[ Both laugh ]
♪ Come to me ♪
♪ When things go wrong ♪
♪ Cling to me, Daddy ♪
♪ Whoa, yeah, and I'll be strong ♪
♪ We can get along,
we can get along ♪
♪ Oh, if only you trust in me ♪
Hello, Brandy.
Sorry to bother you so late.
It's okay.
I assumed when you called,
you must have thought
it was important.
Please.
Would you like a drink?
No, thank you.
How can I help you?
Things have been a little slow,
Mr. Karsten.
I-I lost a day of work
giving my statement
to the police, and...
What statement was that?
The one saying I was with T.J.
the night of Lou's murder.
Now the prosecutor is threatening to...
to deport me
and take away my daughter.
I'm under a lot of pressure.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
So...
How can I help you?
I need more money
for being T.J.'s alibi.
How are things at the club?
And your daughter.
What's her name?
Amy.
[ Sighs ]
Look, Mr. Karsten, I...
You do something for me?
What?
Take your clothes off.
What's the matter?
Isn't that what men pay you to do?
[ Sighs ]
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Water running ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Chirping continues ]
[ Ball thudding ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Water running ]
[ Inhales deeply ]
Nice photos.
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com