No, that's not faster.
I know, but it's dark, and we
could fool around. Dude, tunnel.
India's Grill on 6th Street,
please.
Is that where we ran into...
Yes.
When she was still with...
Uh-huh.
You know, part of me thinks...
I could not agree with you more.
(Horns honking)
Ah, I hope your sister
likes me.
Don't worry. She will.
It has to work with this kid.
I'm always the only guy
at your family dinners.
Oh, I know, baby. I know,
but I have a good feeling.
My sister says
he's totally different
from other guys she's dated.
Yeah, but she said the Sam
thing about Nate a Mike...
And Emma.
You know, the girls
are having dinner tonight.
Maddie's gonna meet
Mia's new fella.
I kinda wish we were joining.
We are going to have
a lovely evening...
go home, have a nice meal,
really reconnect.
You're gonna fall asleep
in your clothes.
Yeah.
Almost there.
How do I look?
Like someone
who's about to get kissed.
How do I look?
Not fat.
Oh, honey, please, let's not fight.
♪ I don't know where I'd be ♪
♪ without someone to see ♪
♪ this thing through ♪
♪ I'm such a mess ♪
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Hi. We have a reservation
under the name Coles.
Oh, yes,
your table will be ready
in just a few minutes,
Mrs. Coles.
Oh. No, he's Mr. Coles,
but I'm not Mrs. Coles.
We're not married.
Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
Oh, no, don't be.
For real, there's no need
for the sad eyes.
Neither of us
want to be married,
but we love each other.
We're very happy.
It's a valid life choice.
Show me your eyes again.
Honey, stop. She, uh,
she just has sad eyes.
Oh, a text from Mia.
"One minute away.
Are you there?"
Why does that need to be texted?
We said we'd meet at 8:00.
I don't get this generation's need for constant
communication. You're only four years older.
But it's a big four years.
None of the famous people
her age wear underwear.
Oh, here they are.
(Gasps) Oh, he looks okay.
No weird hat. No bird.
I like what I'm not seeing.
Hey, you guys.
Hey.
Oh, sorry we're late.
Traffic.
Casey, this is my sister Maddie.
Hi.
And that's Ben.
Hi. Oh!
Strong shake. Better watch what
I say around him. Tough guy.
Tough? I'm not tough.
I mean, I work out a little.
(Whispers) Love this guy.
Hey, I'm headed to the bar. You want a shot of tequila?
Uh, thanks, perfect. Yeah.
You hate tequila. (Whispers) Shh!
Not in front of Casey.
Hello?
Hey, I'm so busy with work,
but I'm dying to know. What did you think of Casey?
Oh, my God. Loved him. Loved, loved, loved him.
Oh, that makes me so happy,
Maddie.
You know,
you never ask my opinion
about this kind of stuff.
You were, like, 12 when I started dating Ben.
You just thought it was cool he could drive at night.
(Singsongy) Found your size.
Where are you? You said you were working.
I telecommute, Maddie.
When you're an inventor,
you can do things like that.
You're not an inventor.
You and your friends
just copied the idea of evite.
Paper free post features
stylish custom online stationery
and offers a hip alternative
to first generation invite web sites.
Ooh, that sounds nice.
Thank you. It is.
(Chuckles)
Now do you think mom and dad
are gonna like him?
Oh, honey, you care way
too much about their approval.
Well, it's easy for you to say.
You're their favorite.
I was at their house
the other day,
and I did a picture count
on the fridge.
You're winning seven to three.
Well, that sounds like a great use of your time.
I'm gonna let you go.
You probably have some
important inventing to do.
(Knock on door)
Hey.
Casey?
Mia doesn't know I'm here.
I need your help.
Oh, God.
Do you need legal help? Ugh.
What was it, shoplifting?
Drunk driving?
Selling weed?
These guesses are really
hurting my feelings.
What do you want?
I need to figure out the best way
to propose to Mia. (Gasps) Wh...
yeah, so she won't
react like that.
Ben?
Yo!
Oh. We need to talk.
Casey came to my office today.
Really? Did he... did he say
anything about me, or did...
He wanted my advice
on how to propose to Mia.
Getting married
after two months?
What is she, a Kardashian?
Well, the good news is,
I bought us some time.
I was able to slow him down
a little bit
by stalling the proposal.
How do you stall a proposal?
Some quick thinking on my part.
Told him it's always been
Mia's dream
to get engaged
at the summer Olympics.
So he'll have to wait
till the next ones in 2012.
Stuff like that.
So quick thinking.
Not good thinking.
I think I have to tell Mia this is all
just way too fast. I don't... I don't know.
Whenever you butt in, it only
makes her do the opposite.
You remember
when she was in college,
and you told her not to take
that Spanish class?
What did she do?
Majored in Spanish.
And?
Went to Spain for a year?
And now what does she dip her chips in?
(Imitates Spanish accent) Guacamole.
Exactly.
Can I ask you somethin'?
Hmm?
Is there any part of you
that's upset about this
because we're not married? No.
I know why we aren't married.
It's a valid life choice.
You know, in the beginning,
we were too young,
and then we wanted
to establish our careers,
and then everybody
was getting married,
and we were like, "maybe,"
and then everybody
was getting divorced,
and we were like, "no."
Well, hey, I love
that we wake up every day,
and we make the decision
to be together,
not because some
piece of paper tells us to.
That's what you always say, right?
I don't just say it. I believe it.
Oh, me, too. I love saying it.
I love believing it.
You know what?
Maybe I'm overreacting.
I mean, she's only known
this guy
for seven and a half weeks.
Even if he does propose,
what are the chances
she says yes?
Casey just proposed!
We're engaged! I said yes!
Wow.
(Door closes)
You proposed.
I know. I'm sorry.
I so appreciated
all your great ideas,
but I couldn't wait for the
perfect moment. (Giggles)
I used some of your stuff.
I could re-enact it for you
if you want. Oh, no, no.
It's really okay.
I'd kinda like to see.
Mia, baby, I know it's not
your dream proposal.
It's not the summer Olympics.
Or the year social security
becomes insolvent.
I hope you'll take me anyway.
I love you, and I can't wait to
start our life together. Oh.
Will you marry me?
Yes! (Laughs)
Mmm, and then I cried.
Let me try.
Everyone be quiet.
Ugh. Nah, I can't get ere.
I need some more wine.
Are you okay? Oh, sure.
This is just such a surprise.
Not to you.
I know you helped,
and I cannot tell you
how much I appreciate it.
Although some of your ideas
were a little wacky.
Why did you say I thought
the Olympics were romantic?
Because... swimmers...
Like dolphins, mate for life.
Do mom and dad know?
Not yet.
I want them to at least
meet him first, but I'm nervous.
I mean, you know Casey.
No, I don't.
Not really.
I love the way he looks
at the world,
but he can be a bit of a...
Oddball.
Yes. (Chuckles) So, Ben,
I-I was hoping that you would,
you know, give him
a few pointers, coach him a bit.
Mom and dad love you so much.
Oh, I don't know.
Come on, Ben. You owe me.
Who supported you when you wore
that goatee for a month?
That did mean a lot to me.
Some people didn't handle it...
So elegantly.
So... you wanna come over
for breakfast tomorrow?
Great. How's 3:00 sound?
It sounds late.
How's 8:00?
2:00?
9:00.
Okay, dude,
but I'm gonna be late.
Thank you, Ben.
This is gonna be so great.
You work with Casey
a little bit,
then tomorrow night, we go to
a nice dinner with mom and dad.
Maddie says how much she loves him... me?
How did I get involved?
Hey, at least you don't have to
wake up at 9:00 for your thing.
To be clear, we're meeting at 9:00.
You have to be there.
I need you there.
You know how critical
mom and dad can be
about the guys that I date.
They find the tiniest reason
not to like them.
I didn't like him. How much hair
does one person need?
Did he seem just a touch...
French. Yes. Awful.
What kind of a guy
is named Emma?
I'll be there.
Really?
Yeah.
Yay. Oh!
Okay, this is so exciting.
Come on, honey.
We gotta go get started
on the wedding planning.
Are you thinking
something small?
I don't know. I have all
those half brothers and sisters.
You do? Isn't this fun...
how fast this is going? Oh!
(Door closes) I thought
we were against this.
We are. Then why am I having two
meals with this guy tomorrow?
Because I wanna protect her.
But you're right.
She's not gonna listen to me.
She will listen to my parents.
So let's let them do
what they're great at...
tearing apart the guys their daughters date.
Just out of curiosity, when they first met me, what did they...
you don't wanna know.
I can take it.
You can't.
Yeah, you're right.
I have jotted down a few notes
about how to deal
with Mia's parents.
Oh. That is a lot of stuff.
Well, I run a hotel,
and it's successful
because I'm good at picking up
on people's wants and needs.
See, I treat Maddie's parents
like a couple of clients,
and you should do the same.
Like, uh, what do you do?
Uh, I play
in an avant-garde metal band
with a performance art
component.
(Pen clicks)
"Don't... mention... job."
Okay, let's see.
Their dad is
a huge grammar snob,
so think about
your sentence structure.
No
"my friend and me went out."
No, "that's the gym
exercise at."
You have no idea
why those are wrong.
Grammar's not really my thing.
Hey! Does your hotel ever have
an event where you need a band?
Oh. We already have an in-house
avant-garde metal band
with a performance art
component.
Uh, let's see. Call them
"Mr. and Mrs. Putney,"
even though they'll say,
"call us whatever."
Oh, and don't try
and make a joke
and actually call them
"whatever."
Why would I do that?
That's stupid.
Well, it's an ice breaker.
People like gentle comedy.
Oh, don't give Mrs. Putney
your e-mail address.
That woman has never met
a cutesy e-mail
she hasn't forwarded.
And don't make any jokes
about plastic surgery.
Five years ago, Mr. Putney's
ears stuck out like this.
Now they're fine.
I don't know what happened.
Never asked.
(Whispers) Don't wanna know.
So stick to the safe topics
like wine, theater,
and the Yankees.
Wow. Sounds like you work
pretty hard to keep 'em happy.
I really do, Casey.
You know what?
I think I'll just be myself,
and hopefully, they'll like me.
And if not... (Crunches)
If not, what? What is the end
of that sentence?
(Scoffs)
You... you really don't care
if they like you?
Oh, I mean, it'd be nice
if they did,
but all those rules
you just laid out... I'm me.
I like myself just fine.
The one mistake I could make
is to pretend to be
something I'm not.
They're gonna eat you alive.
I don't see them yet.
Babe, you seem nervous.
I just want this to go well.
I love you, and I want them to love you, too.
And hopefully, they will, but we need to listen to them.
They gave us life.
Oh, my God. Here they come.
Just be yourself. But better.
I'm sorry. But I mean it!
Sorry we're late.
It took us forever to get here.
Your father's
on a huge walking jag.
No, I'm on a huge
not-paying-for-taxis jag
because our net worth went on
a huge losing-75%-of-itself jag.
And she's on an acting-like-
it-didn't-happen jag.
Uh, okay. Uh, mom, dad,
this is Casey.
Great to meet you, Vicky.
Joel, I like your ears.
Hey, you know what you're gonna
hear with those ears this year?
Cheers for the Yankees!
Ah!
Oh!
Yes, sit down.
Great to see you, Ben.
(Under breath) Stick to the script!
(Mouths words)
Oh, before I forget, Casey.
I need to get
your e-mail address.
I find that it's the best way
to communicate.
It is Captainorgasmo...
one word.
He doesn't have an e-mail.
Champagne?
Oh.
What's t, uh, occasion?
Oh, um, Mia has news.
Yes.
(Chuckles nervously) Mom, dad...
oh, my God! Maddie and Ben
are getting married.
It's a miracle.
What? Why would that be
my news?
"It's a miracle"?
Like I don't have anything
of my own going on?
I could see "surprising,"
but "a miracle"?
I'm sorry.
I guess I-I misunderstood.
Can we please just
get to the news?
We really should
start walking home soon.
Well, this isn't exactly
the mood that I wanted to set,
but, um, I'm getting married.
To who?
Whom.
To me!
To... I?
Um...
Anyway... that's the news.
(Chuckles nervously)
There's going to be a wedding.
(Laughs)
We're so happy for you, pumpkin.
Yay! (Chuckles)
What is going on?
Your sister's getting married. Keep up.
No, I get that. I just... I can't
believe you're okay with this.
Well, honey,
if there's one thing
our financial reversals
of the last year have taught us,
it's that life is short,
and you should grab all the joy
you can find when you find it.
You really don't think
this is too fast?
Well, not everyone
is going to wait 15 years.
Oh, darling, stop. (Chuckles)
Was that directed at me?
No, it was directed at Kurt
Russell and Goldie Hawn. (Laughs)
Okay, guys, this is my moment.
I just got engaged.
Make fun of Maddie
when she gets in engaged...
In 2044.
(Both laugh)
Hey, our not being married is a valid
life choice. Valid life choice.
Okay, she said it.
Everybody has to drink.
(Clinking)
So wait.
Is our not being married
something you talk about
behind our backs?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
You never put any pressure on us at all.
Well, the therapist said...
oh, there's a therapist?
Therapists have been consulted?
Therapists, clergymen, waiters.
Ooh, and there was
that valet Parker who raised
some pretty tough questions
about Ben's sexuality.
I sat down.
I didn't know he hadn't gotten
out of the car yet.
I'm sorry.
Call me old-fashioned,
but I think it's appropriate
to apply a little though
before making huge life choices.
Where is this coming from? You were so happy for us.
Well, I didn't wanna burst
your bubble,
but I thought somebody would
have the sense to say
this is crazy. You two don't even
know each other. We know ch other.
Oh, really?
What's his favorite movie?
Favorite color? Flavor of ice cream.
Whoa, hold on.
We've been together nine years,
and we don't even know
stuff like favorite ice cream.
I absolutely know your favorite ice cream.
How? I don't even have a favorite.
Mint chip.
(Whispers) It is mint chip.
Oh, this is so insulting.
Does it make you feel better
to use your lawyer logic
and grill us like
some kind of...
(Imitates Spanish accent)
Geraldo Rivera?
Huh?
Yeah. Get used to that.
Let's just calm down here,
okay?
This is what I want.
Why does it have to be now?
Honey, stop.
No, I'm sorry.
Why in the world does she have to get married right now?
'Cause she's pregnant. Ohh!
I can't believe this.
You're pregnant?
Yes. I'm sorry
I didn't mention it earlier.
I was just trying to think
of the perfect way
for Ben to say it.
I didn't mean to tell him.
He was giving me all
this advice. We were bonding.
(High-pitched voice) It was
real early in the morning.
We're going to be grandparents.
(Laughs)
Oh.
A bond portfolio dies,
a child is born...
circle of life.
You see that, Maddie?
They're happy about this, too.
Wanna tell them why they're wrong?
No, that's not fair.
Fair? How about going
to your sister for support
and finding out she's trying to sabotage you?
I just wanted...
no, no, no. You wanted
to ruin my engagement,
only you just ruined my night.
You'll have to be satisfied
with that.
Do I follow?
Yes.
Yeah.
Hey. You guys,
you love each other.
Don't leave it like this.
Oh, do you guys want this cab?
Or do you wanna think about it
for nine years? Come on.
Casey, wait.
Can you talk to her?
I tried.
She's not interested.
Maddie, I'd like to apologize
for something. What?
For this.
Whoa!
Go, go, go. Wait.
Th-that's a $50.
Get change for that!
(Horns honking)
Why didn't you tell me
you were pregnant?
Because I wanted you
to like Casey first,
not because you had
or because we're stuck with him.
Oh, who cares what I think?
I do.
Oh, please.
You don't get it.
The person whose opinion
I care most about is you.
Really?
You're my big sister.
(Sighs)
I remember being 14 years old
and watching you
go off to college
and thinking to myself, I wish
I could be that beautiful,
that smart...
(Voice breaking) That together.
I'm sorry.
It must be the hormones.
(Voice breaking)
No. I'm not pregnant,
and I'm doing it, too.
I'm... I'm sorry I blew
the pregnancy news.
Ah, people were gonna
figure it out anyway
once she starts getting fat.
Showing.
You might wanna call it
"showing."
(Chuckles)
You're gonna be Uncle Ben.
(Laughs)
That's... that's good stuff.
Like the rice.
No, I got it.
Maddie, I need you
to be honest with me.
Having all this happen
at once... a marriage, a baby,
I mean, do you think
I'm making a mistake?
You're gonna be great.
I've seen you jump into things
feet first a million times.
And it scares the hell
out of me,
but you always make it work.
And you'll be there to help me?
I will read every baby book.
I will make
baby activity flowcharts.
I will research the crap out
of crib safety. (Chuckles)
You think I'm making
a mistake?
About what?
Should Ben and I have gotten
married a long time ago?
Is my life choice not valid?
You want my opinion?
Oh, my God.
I've dreamed of this day.
You wanna know
what I think. (Laughs)
So what do you think?
No idea! (Laughs)
(Laughs) Oh.
You know, Maddie does like you,
and she loves her sister.
It's just that you guys,
you know, are moving
a little fast for her.
Yeah, I got that.
You guys... valid life choice.
Us... too fast.
You're getting married
after seven weeks.
It took us that long
to settle on a new coffeemaker,
and I'm still not sure
we didn't make a huge mistake.
But what you're doing... is
threatening our very existence.
I'm sorry, man.
Condom broke.
You should know...
The way I feel about Mia...
We were gonna get married anyway.
This just kinda sped things up a little bit.
You know, I believe you.
And by the way,
nice job with her parents.
You didn't even need my list.
Maybe I learn from you
and worry a little less
about offending them.
I guess I can throw out
that stupid card.
Oh, no.
"He gets chatty
at the urinals"?
"She's a little bit racist"?
So you wanna fool around?
Totally. It's been,
like, six hours.
So... you wanna fool around?
Yeah. It's been, like,
a week.
So you wanna fool around?
Oh, your earplugs are in.
Can't hear me.
That's right.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com