THE BlC YCLE THlEF
Ricci?
Is Ricci there?
Are you deaf?
Come on! Get a move on.
And because I'm a bricklayer
I should die of hunger?
What do you want from me?
Just be patient.
We'll see what we can do.
We'll try to find something.
- Ricci, you'll hang posters.
- Posters?
Go to the employment office.
They'll give you a work permit.
My God, a job!
Hey, what about us?
I've got two jobs,
but they're not for you.
Because it's not for me
I must continue to rot?
There's just no work
for you people!
Ricci, don't forget
to take your bicycle.
You need one.
It's written on the slip.
A bicycle?
I have one, only it's broken.
I can get it in a couple of days.
Well, they won't take you then.
Why not?
I'll walk for a while.
Do you have it or not?
If no, somebody else'll get the job.
I have a bicycle!
You're not the only one!
I do too.
You're a bricklayer.
That's a different category.
- Then change it!
- I can't.
Ricci, either you have
a bicycle or not.
I have it.
I'll pick it up now.
Remember: if you don't have
a bicycle, nothing doing.
I won't wait around another year.
Don't worry, I'll have the bicycle.
Maria!
What is it?
My rotten luck, that's what.
I found a job
and I can't take it.
What are you talking about?
Stop, Antonio. Tell me.
And a good city job too.
All right.
We'll take care of that, Antonio.
Take care of what?
I need my bicycle.
I must be there this morning...
or I lose the job.
What can I do?
Did you have to hock your bicycle?
What would you have eaten?
I've been cursed
since the day I was born!
I feel like a man in chains.
Get up!
- What are you doing?
- You can sleep without sheets, no?
They're all sheets, six of them.
They're linen and cotton.
Real good stuff.
Belonged to my dowry.
They're used.
Not all of them.
Two are new.
How many pieces?
Six. Three doubles, three singles.
- 7,000.
- 7,000?
Couldn't you make it a bit more?
They're used. They're used.
All right, take them away.
7,500.
- Name?
- Ricci.
Maria Ricci.
Valmelaina.
It's for a bicycle.
- 6,100.
- Why?
Interest. It's the 31st.
A Fides. Next to the red one.
I know, I know.
Wait a second.
Where's the man in charge?
Over there.
Put it down.
What's the matter? Are you afraid?
Put that bicycle down.
My name is Ricci.
The employment office
at Valmelaina sent me.
You'll start tomorrow morning.
Go to the storeroom.
They'll give you what you need.
Tomorrow at 6:45.
- How did it go?
- Good.
You had to wait,
but everything is okay.
There's some work for you.
It's the belt of my cap.
It's loose.
You have to take it in.
Come over here and have a look.
Everyone has his own locker.
See how big it is?
They used to give shoes also,
but the pay is still good.
6,000 plus an allowance
for the family.
And there's the overtime!
Could you stop
at Via della Paglia?
- What for?
- I have to pay someone a visit.
It's up there.
Who lives here?
I told you.
I'll only be a minute.
Hurry up!
- It's mine!
- No, it's mine!
Hello! Is anybody here?
Excuse me.
Does the Santona live here?
Santona?
Yes, the one that sees.
I don't know.
Let's try to first floor.
- Is the Santona here?
- Yes, last door.
Could you watch it
for a while?
How is he?
He's been sick over a year.
Last door.
How long has he been in bed?
Almost a year.
You could have brought him to me!
This one yes and this one no.
Dear God, bless me with light.
Your son will be out of bed
before the first leaf falls.
What do you mean
"before the first leaf falls"?
Your son will be up by autumn.
Maria, let's go.
- What are you doing here?
- I owe her 50 lire.
Come on, don't be stupid.
She predicted you would
get a job. You did.
- I want to do my duty.
- I'll tell her what I think!
How can a woman with two children
and a head on her shoulders
think about such nonsense,
such stupidity?
What are you doing now?
You must have money
to throw away.
I don't know what got
into your head.
Some woman!
Couldn't you spend it better?
Better? I'm grateful.
Because she's the one
that got me to job?
Let's go.
Let's go home, dumb-dumb.
Hurry up, Bruno.
It's almost 6:30.
I can't clean it good
because it's still dark.
Daddy, did you see
what they've done?
It's dented.
Maybe it was there.
No, it wasn't.
This is where it got hit.
Who knows
how they take care of them.
They don't pay for the repairs!
Shut up!
I'll shut up,
but I would have told them.
Is my cap ready?
- Something good?
- Omelet.
- Handsome?
- Boy, you look like a cop!
Stop it!
You're hurting me!
Will you behave? Stop it.
You'll wake the baby.
Here's the omelet.
Let's go.
Bye, Bruno.
See you tonight at 7:00.
Wait for me here.
Good day.
First, you give it a coat
of glue... like this.
Then you put the poster
over it like this.
Then you attach
the poster like this...
to flatten the poster
and to smooth out the lumps.
Got it? Shut up, kid!
Because if you leave any lumps...
the inspector will see them
and he'll fine you. Got it?
See, Ricci...
to do this job,
you've got to be very intelligent.
You must have a good eye
and work fast.
Here, it's done.
I'll see you, Ricci.
So long.
Thief! Thief!
What happened?
Get in! Get in!
Go after him! Quick!
Go into the tunnel!
I saw him!
Faster!
What is it?
I was mistaken.
I was so sure he went this way.
It turned out
to be another fellow.
Yes, there were people around.
Then I started to run.
Come over to the meeting.
But Capece's going.
Everything's changed.
Capece stays, and you're going.
Sign this.
Quadrone!
We have to go to the meeting.
You'll look for it?
Look for it yourself.
I can't look all over Rome.
You're the only one
who knows it.
I gave you the description
and the license plate.
Sure. It'll take me the whole
mobile unit to look for it.
What's the use
of my complaint, then?
Suppose you find it tomorrow
in a pawn shop.
You can call a policeman,
you're on file.
Anything, Captain?
Nothing. Just a bicycle.
- Then it's up to me?
- I've already told you.
You've filed a complaint.
There's nothing more I can say.
Daddy, it's 7:30.
I came by bus. Let's go.
And the bicycle?
Is it broken?
Yes, it's broken.
You go inside.
I'll be back later.
It's not a question
of not working.
The point is that people
are not placed.
We have talked about it
to the Department of Labor.
Nothing is resolved
with the subsidy.
The welfare check
humiliates the worker
and doesn't help things
get any better.
We need
a sociologically-oriented program.
At the meeting,
they said the same thing:
"We can't do miracles."
Will you keep quiet?
"You can be sure...
that we'll do our best
to get you jobs..."
I've got to speak with you.
They stole my bicycle.
Really?
Where did they steal it?
At the Florida
as I was starting work.
How could you...
You've got to help me, Baiocco.
I have to find that bicycle.
I'll help you.
Excuse me, Baiocco, listen.
We'll be here all night.
I'm listening.
Silence, everyone!
Keep rehearsing! I'm coming.
They'll sell it
at Piazza Vittorio.
They unload their stuff there
as soon as it's stolen.
They won't waste any time.
We'll go first thing tomorrow.
Is it true?
I avoided going home,
so don't start crying here.
I'm not crying.
But when you hear such news...
Did you do something?
Did you look for it?
Don't cry.
You look like a baby.
We'll find it.
It'll turn up in the market.
We'll examine
every bicycle in sight.
We'll bring it back.
Right, Antonio?
Tonight you
may not sleep too well...
but tomorrow the bike'll be back.
Don't worry.
Ah, no! You can't meet here!
Go back or I take my group out.
- Tomorrow, then.
- Good night.
And please... don't worry.
Give her a little gas.
We'll never leave this place.
Get that pushcart out of the way!
Meniconi and Bagonghi,
come over here.
What make was it?
A Fides. Frame number: 12033.
He knows it better than I do.
Good. So we can divide up the work.
Stolen bikes are always taken apart.
Bagonghi, let's go this way.
No, let's go this way.
It's better here.
You two look only for the tires.
You, the frames.
Bruno, the pump and the bell.
Let's go.
A Fides frame.
We'll look for it piece by piece,
then we'll put it together.
There's only vegetables here.
We're not looking for that.
Remember: don't let on
why we're here.
Look how many there are!
Isn't this something?
The place is loaded with bicycles.
Remember, Bruno, pump and bell.
That's all.
And if you see something, whistle.
Bruno, if we find it,
we'll celebrate.
Wake up, Bagonghi!
A Fides.
Hey, you want to buy or touch?
Let me work, and get off my back!
Just stop it and get lost!
It's useless to stick together.
Antonio, you look for the tires.
Bagonghi for the frame,
the kid for the pump.
I'm going on my own.
Take a look at this frame.
Well?
- What make is it?
- You're buying?
Don't touch. It's just painted.
What's the serial number?
Why? You're collecting
serial numbers?
No, he's not.
Just show him the frame number.
What if I don't?
Then I'll call a cop.
Go ahead! Call one!
You think it's stolen stuff?
Who says it is?
You must show the number
when you're asked to.
Do I ask for the size
of your shoes? No!
So I won't show you
my number!
You play the lottery?
No, I don't.
Don't you want a bell?
You've been here half an hour
just looking.
How much does this bell cost?
150 lire.
He has to show you
the number.
Show him that frame.
Go ahead, look!
A man can't even work in peace!
Don't you trust me either?
12024.
Is it yours?
Here. You got paint on you.
Listen, a man who's been robbed
has the right to look.
You see it's my bicycle.
We all make mistakes.
Hey, friend!
Here we're all honest.
Come on.
Remember, a Dudes.
- Where is my son?
- Must be near the carts.
There's nothing more here.
It's difficult. Difficult.
Want something else?
I told you to stay close to me.
Come on.
Antonio, he'll go with you.
We'll stay here. You never know.
I say it's better here.
It's too late for the other market.
Come on.
Take him to the Porta Portese.
Can't win.
Every Sunday it rains!
Sundays I'm through at 1:00.
And where can you go?
Movies bore me.
I'm stuck at home.
Look at him!
You stupid jerk!
I ought to run him over.
They get under your car,
you don't even know it.
Look at how it's pouring.
It's hopeless.
Every Sunday, it rains.
What happened?
I fell down!
Here, use this.
100 lire?
That's your split.
You're lucky to get that much.
That's all get?
It's the thief!
Stop him! Thief! Thief!
We have to find
that old man!
There, Daddy! There he is!
Damn it! Where did he go?
Come back, Bruno!
I found him! Come on!
Excuse me.
I want to ask you something.
That young fellow...
where can I find him?
What fellow?
The one on the bicycle.
He did something wrong?
No, nothing.
It's a personal matter.
It's nothing urgent.
What can I do?
I don't know him.
You were together under the arch!
Lots of people stand together.
Wait a second!
I must talk to him, understand?
Where did he go?
Please! I'm an old man.
Leave me alone!
I mind my own business.
I bother nobody.
And what do I get? Trouble.
Again? You're supposed
to be here before 10:00.
Isn't the mission always open?
Come, you must get ready.
- And the soup?
- I see you have no mess kit.
All you newcomers must bring
your mess kits out into the yard.
All right. Come, come now,
let's line up quickly.
Let's try
to keep some order here.
Need a barber?
Then go inside.
Almost finished, counselor?
Almost. Just these two...
No, not me.
We can begin, then.
Don't shave the chin.
Just the sides. I'm growing a beard.
Please hurry, counselor!
Everyone's waiting.
Some job for a lawyer!
Will you let me in?
Listen, I must find that young man.
I must talk to him.
Will you tell me
where I can find him?
Listen, I don't even know
the boy you're talking about.
Why don't you leave me alone.
Page six.
"O my Lord, we your poor souls
yearn for sanctity.
"We embrace the trials
of our lives...
He'll profit by it.
It involves some money.
- Where is he?
- I don't have to tell you.
Talk, or I'll get the police.
What have I done to you?
Leave me alone.
Don't bother me.
"Send us, O Lord,
guidance from within..."
I'm sure he'll be grateful.
Just tell me.
What can you lose?
I don't expect this for nothing.
I'll pay you.
- What do we get to eat today?
- Pasta and potatoes.
So... will you tell me?
Jail is worse.
You'll rot there.
Where is he?
All right. Via della Campanella.
What number?
I think it's 15.
You're coming with me.
Me? I won't go.
Either you come with me...
or I take you to the police!
Silence! Talking is disgraceful
during services.
Are you coming? Yes or no?
Leave me alone.
I'm nothing but an old man.
What can you lose?
- I'm losing my patience!
- Lose whatever you like.
For the last time, will you go?
What do you want?
I'm not leaving this place!
You're going with me,
you hear!
I'm not mixed up with anybody.
Leave me alone.
I've got nothing to do with him.
Come on, let's go!
Let me have the soup first,
at least.
I'll go with you.
I'm entitled to the soup.
- Where are you going?
- To get the soup.
Ladies, did you see an old man?
Please attend the service.
It's too early.
Wait! What do you want?
- I want to get out!
- The door's closed.
You can't get out.
The lawyer has the key.
Stop making so much noise!
You're in a church!
You're disturbing the service.
It's better if you just leave.
I have to find him!
Did you come for Mass
or to make trouble?
I'm looking for an old man
who was here!
I've got to find him!
You'll find him after Mass!
See, he was here!
Who knows where he's gone.
He didn't just fly away.
Why did you let him
go for the soup?
Shut up!
Where are you going?
Come back here.
Let's go! Some kid I have.
Come on, Bruno!
Why did you hit me?
Because you got on my nerves.
Let's go.
Why'd you hit me like that?
Will you come on!
You act like a father-in-law.
Big mouth!
I'm going to tell Mama.
In a second you'll have
more to tell her.
Wait for me by the bridge.
Just stay there.
I'll look for the old man.
Help! A boy's drowning!
Bruno, put on your jacket.
Tired?
Sit for a minute.
There isn't much we can do now.
We'll go home.
Hurray For Modena
Think Modena will win today?
Are you hungry?
Would you like a pizza?
Let's go.
Why should I kill myself worrying
when I'll end up just as dead?
Come on.
Let's get something to eat.
Let's forget everything.
We'll get drunk!
Half a bottle?
- A whole bottle and a pizza.
- No pizzas in this restaurant.
This is not a pizzeria.
Give us something else.
You want mozzarella on bread?
Two mozzarellas and a full bottle.
We'll drink wine with our meal,
but leave room for dessert, okay?
What's the matter? Drink.
If Mama could see us!
We can do anything we want,
because we're both men.
We'll eat and be happy for now.
There's a cure for everything...
except death.
To eat like them, you have to...
earn at least a million a month.
Eat, eat. Don't worry.
You like it?
To think, if I had my bicycle...
how much I'd earn.
We could live again.
I figured...
I'll show you.
12,000 a month to start.
Write it all down.
12,000...
2,000 overtime...
plus the family allowance...
which is 800 a day.
30 times 800 makes...
Add it all up.
Who would want more?
Am I to lose it,
lose it after one day?
I don't want to lose it.
See why we must find it?
Otherwise, we don't eat.
What can we do?
We'll go every day
to the Porta Portese.
They've already slipped away.
Your mother and her prayers
can't help us.
Nobody can but the saints.
...and the following soccer games
will take place as scheduled.
Last door.
She knows everything.
Put your faith in her power.
I only hope you're right.
Easy, easy.
This one yes and this one no.
You must plant your seeds
in another field.
Do you understand what I mean?
I don't understand.
It's simple, my boy.
What good is planting seeds...
if the soil rejects them?
You plant and don't gather.
Understand?
I haven't understood a word.
She doesn't love you!
Forget her!
Dear boy, you're very ugly.
Yes, ugly.
There are so many other women.
Go and plow a new field.
Mama, the tea's getting cold.
- Good day.
Daddy, here! Look, come on!
Excuse me, we've all been
waiting here for hours.
Wait your turn.
It's very important.
I'm in a hurry too,
and I came first.
Please understand, I beg of you.
It's good.
Look here, the lady is first,
and then me.
I shed my light on all.
This one yes... this one no.
Dear God, send me your light.
What's wrong, my son?
They stole what?
- My bicycle.
- Your bicycle?
What can I tell you, my son?
The Blessed Lord
sends his light from above.
Now listen carefully:
unless you find it this morning,
you won't see it at all.
Either you find it now
or you never will.
So, look.
Now? But where?
There's no more to say.
Try to understand me.
Find it now or not at all.
It's that simple.
What happened today, Adele?
My husband's still drunk.
It's your cross to bear.
Stop giving him money.
What can I do?
He takes it.
We're closed!
The ladies are having breakfast!
Where are you going?
And with a kid too!
You can't go upstairs.
It's closed!
When it's closed,
it's closed for everybody!
No one is allowed
in the dining room!
I must talk to him.
Me? Go ahead.
That's the dining room.
You can't stay! Get out!
Maria, stop shouting.
I've got a headache.
Throw him out.
Give me my bicycle back!
Come out in the street with me!
This is the first house of Rome.
If the Captain finds out...
Give me back
what you stole from me.
What did I steal?
The bicycle!
What bicycle? I'm no thief.
Leave me alone
or you'll have trouble!
I'll kill you
if you don't give it back!
Give it back! You hear me?
Look at him! He's crazy!
Leave me alone.
Get your hands off me!
I didn't do anything to you.
I won't move from here
until you give it back.
You stole it at the Florida!
I wasn't even there!
You were there yesterday
wearing that German hat!
Get a pair of glasses.
You can't accuse people like that!
You're not getting away with it,
understand?
Alfredo! What is it?
Lay off!
Yesterday I was at the fruit market.
Excuse me.
This man here stole your bicycle?
Yes, and I want it back.
You're sure it was this man?
I'm absolutely sure!
Where was it stolen?
- At the Florida.
- If you're so sure, get the police.
No, you're not leaving!
Don't touch me!
Get him away from me!
You've been accusing a man
and you're not sure.
Alfredo! He's trying to kill him!
Put his head down!
I think you better go!
And next time, be sure!
You know you could be sued
for libel?
Get him out! He's a murderer!
My God, look at my son!
Alfredo, my son!
Blessed soul of your mother!
You already lost your bike, stupid!
Want to lose your wallet too?
Stay back!
You're all alike!
You're thieves!
- Are you crazy!
- No, just trying to cool him off!
Where is the bicycle fellow?
There he is, putting on a show.
I said I've nothing to hide.
You can't accuse my son!
He has a clean record!
Everybody knows it!
Just because he wears
a German cap.
I should be arrested then, too.
- Come on, get up.
- He can't be moved!
Let him rest awhile.
He's very sick, Officer.
Well, show me your house.
We're honest people.
You can look.
I'd sue you for slander.
Don't pick on him.
He wouldn't hurt a fly.
One room we live in.
Look for your bicycle.
Here's his bed. You see there's
plenty of room to hide a bicycle.
My daughter, another kid
and I sleep here.
Instead of insults,
you should give my poor boy a job.
Bless his soul.
They're my brother-in-law's
car tires.
He used to have a car.
Look! Look everywhere.
Are there any witnesses?
I'll testify myself.
Could you wait outside?
Talk as long as you want.
What do I care?
Are you sure it's him?
You're not mistaken?
He's the man.
Come here.
Look at them.
All those people
will testify for him.
You're sure you saw his face?
Yes, as he was
making off with it.
- You saw the back of his head?
- No. His face I remember. Really.
- Were there people who saw it?
- Yes.
Did you get the names
of any witnesses?
I couldn't stop to take their names.
Then you're out of luck.
You hardly saw his face,
and you have no witnesses.
You may be right,
but you have no proof.
And suppose he's innocent.
Then you're in trouble.
With these characters, you have to
find the stolen goods right on them.
If I don't get it back,
I'll break his head.
Then I'd have to arrest you.
If you only knew
what this means to me.
I have nothing to hide.
Satisfied?
What did he find? Nothing!
I've got a clean record.
What's your name?
Want to press charges?
He's got a clean record.
Remember to send us a postcard!
Don't forget:
stay out of the Via Panico!
Don't ever come
around here again!
Here, take the streetcar.
Wait at Monte Sacro.
You heard me. Go on!
Help!
He's got my bicycle!
Here! I'll teach you
to steal bicycles!
Criminal! Scoundrel!
- Where to?
- To the police station.
Wait, let him go.
You're not filing a complaint?
I don't want the bother.
The man has enough trouble.
A fine example
you set for your son.
You're lucky you got off easy.
If it had been me, you'd be in jail.
Be thankful the man
didn't have you arrested.
And you can thank God.
Subtitles processed by C.M.C.