I was hurt because I liked you as a kid,
I made money for you,
And I came back here for you,
You can trust me,
As you date me,
you can learn that there is a man,,,
you can trust,
Goodnight,
I love you,
Hae Ra,
I'm happy,
Where is time flowing to?
I do not know yet
Please stay with me
- Do not leave me - Do not leave me
I still love you
I'm surprised there's still,,,
a place like this left in Seoul,
You must be drunk,
How many times are you going to repeat that?
How can you make,,,
both men's and women's wear?
You already said that too,
Because I'm a genius,
Plus I had a lot of time,
Then make a suit for me too,
We'll see,
Wake up,
Five more minutes,
I didn't think he was a poor drinker,
How do you know,,,
Choi Ji Hoon?
Through Jung Hae Ra,
Jung Hae Ra?
He was a boyfriend of,,,
someone I know,
I have a friend named Jung Hae Ra,
She works at a travel agency,
Do you know Hae Ra?
Ji Hoon was,,,
Hae Ra's boyfriend?
When did you come home last night?
- Around 1:30am? - 1:45am,
Did something good happen?
- No, - No,
Hae Ra, Let's go,
I'll give you a ride,
Wait one second,
Hae Ra,
Coming,
Don't get mad at the chief director,
Don't be impatient,
Okay,
They applauded you at the meeting,
which means they think highly you,
Right, I'll take the calls cheerfully,
You can swear at rude customers,
Okay, I'm good at that,
Thank you,
Anything you want to say to me?
Have a good day,
Other than that,
I love you, Have a good day,
Bye,
Cheer up,
Good morning, Mr, Moon,
Hi,
I'll make my own coffee that suits my taste,
Don't do this from now on,
Why not?
I don't want to be that kind of boss,
I got you this coffee as a thank you,,,
for saving me the other day,
Don't worry about it,
Okay, Thanks,
By the way, did you hear?
Remember Yoon Dal Hong who betrayed us,,,
with the surface rights?
His son had a terrible car accident,
So he's out of his mind,
How badly did his son get hurt?
He's in a coma,
That wouldn't have happened,,,
if he had worked with us,
Don't say that,
I'm just upset,
You should go and do your work,
Okay,
This is nice,
It must've been fine liquor,
I don't have a headache,
I loved coming to a bathhouse in winter,
I used to play like this,
You were a prosecutor, right?
I guess Hae Ra didn't tell Mr, Moon yet,
Seeing that you're still his trainer,
I'm not sure what you're talking about,
Hae Ra, me, and my girlfriend are,,,
friends since childhood,
I know very well,,,
about what happened,
That's why you know about law so well,
It was all settled, and the problem was solved,
I wasn't charged or sent to jail,
Nothing like that happened,
I'll keep it a secret, Don't worry,
You'd have no merit as an informant,,,
if Mr, Moon looks down on you,
Let's go have a hangover soup later,
I won't get intimidated,
I had no choice,,,
because I tripped over in my life,
How did you choose to fake being a prosecutor?
My parents ran a residence in Sillim-dong,,,
where people gather and study for the bar exam,
I saw and heard a lot of stuff since I was young,
What about Hae Ra?
How did you fool her?
Goodness,
I didn't mean to fool her from the start,
Of course, you didn't,
I went for some paperwork at the district office,
I saw a middle-aged woman crying,
I helped her with my knowledge,
Then she suddenly went,
"Thank you so much, Mr, Prosecutor,"
I went to a travel agency,,,
to make a reservation for my grandma's trip,
I ran into that woman again,
She must've said,
"What brings you here, Mr, Prosecutor?"
Yes,
Hae Ra helped me with the reservation,
She was kind and pretty,
I asked her out first,
I found out that she was a lonely person,
so I kept acting like I was a prosecutor,
It's heartbreaking,
You can go tell Mr, Moon everything about this,
Everyone makes mistakes at least once in their lives,
Liking her isn't a sin, is it?
Fooling her is a sin,
Just tell me what you want from me,
Mr, Moon is in trouble,,,
due to the landlord's change in mind,
He must be looking for another way,
Sir,
Chairman Park sent people to the bathhouse again,
I'll be back,
Mr, Han,
You heard the news about Mr, Yoon's son, right?
Yes,
Send him a basket of flowers,
Include a message saying, "Hope he gets well soon,"
It's a business manner,
Are your curious about that alternative?
(Bookstore, Bathhouse)
It'll be better if it's more specific,
(Yoon Dal Hong)
Moon Soo Ho, out!
- Moon Soo Ho, out! - Moon Soo Ho, out!
Redevelopment is the way to live,
Moon Soo Ho is stopping the redevelopment,
Moon Soo Ho, out!
- Moon Soo Ho, out! - Moon Soo Ho, out!
You made a good choice,
You should live more at ease now,
Right,
I'm leaving you a message,,,
since you won't take my call,
It's a piece of cake,,,
to find your place if I order my kids,
Don't make things difficult,
Just have brunch with a newspaper delivery boy,,,
who has become rich,
Let's have elegant brunch,
It's new to have palbochae as brunch,
Seo Rin always took me,,,
to a Chinese restaurant,
Thank to her,
I got to eat palbochae for the first time in my life,
It has become my life's dish,
I found the last item amusing,
Can I see other items as well?
Seo Rin isn't dead, is she?
I'm sure,,,
you're still in touch with her,
It's better you don't meet your first love again,
She's alive,
She's grown very old,
She wants to be remembered as a pretty girl,
What does her husband do for living?
No one will marry that crazy brat,
She's still single,
Is that right?
(Jung Hae Ra)
Why aren't you answering your phone?
What are you doing?
Hello?
Can I visit you with my colleagues today?
It's about work,
No,
What about we have delicious lunch,,,
at my friend, Young Mi's shop?
- I'll take out,,, - No, thanks,
What's wrong with her?
She's making me want to curse now,
What a manner,
That wasn't nice,
What do you think about this shirt?
Whatever,
Take a look,
I spent all night making this,
It looks like it's for men, It's lousy,
It's not mine, It's for a man,
Who?
Is that for,,,
that model yesterday?
No,
Someone I want to deliver my body heat,
Excuse me,
I don't want another toy you gave me last time,
Do you have something fancier?
What do you mean by toy?
That's upsetting to hear,
What was that?
Do you have things like,,,
portraits, prayers,
or letters?
You must be looking for treasures,
These are too common,
Be careful,
That's worth 100,000 dollars,
You don't have what I'm looking for,
I'll just take a few toys then,
I'll pay you in cash right now,
Are you sure you're not interested in these?
If you're acting to buy them cheap,
please stop it,
I'll give them for free,
I've done this a lot,
You're giving me those because they're cheap,
This ring was found,,,
in the stomach of a yellow tail caught in winter,
I told you,
I lost it when I jumped down the cliff,
It came out,,,
from the stomach of a yellow tail in winter,
It's a lucky ring,
so I paid quite a lot for this,
Thank you for the lucky gift,
I gave you the lucky gift,
so let me meet Seo Rin just once,
I'll talk to her,
The building owners aren't in for the redevelopment,
Once the redevelopment starts,
they will have much less profit,
They call it redevelopment,
but it's rather like uniformity of the town,
Did you check the register copies of these places?
Yes, in case of the 28th street,
the landlord owns the building,
It's different in the 32nd street,
Its surface rights will soon expire,
Meet with the building owner and tenant,
Okay,
(Bookstore, Bathhouse)
We have to surround this area,
so that the contracts will be canceled,
Oh, the landlord of the 32nd street,,,
owns the bank building at the intersection as well,
These places too,
Who's the landlord?
It's an old woman named Choi Seo Rin,
Go see her right away,
Check this out,
What's this?
(Handsome guys who are 100 years older than us,)
I told you she'd come,,,
if we sent her the picture,
What are those pictures?
You came here because you think you look like him?
Why did you place them here?
Why are you mad?
You're at fault, Young Mi,
She's such a beauty, so she'd be upset,,,
to hear that she looks like men,
You must be upset, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry,
My friend is a bit slow-witted,
She's been like that since young,
Don't be upset,,,
and have a seat here,
Should I dust it off one more time?
- Ju Hee, come on, - Okay,
Right, I'll dust it off too,
My goodness, This is,,,
Goodness,
Goodness, this is really clean now,
- This way, please, - My goodness,
First of all, we need outfits,,,
to dress sharply in Paris and London,
So we will go there empty-handed,
dress sharply in your awesome clothes,
take pictures in them,
tour around, take them off,
and return home without any baggage,
My business instinct says,,,
this will thrive,
What do you think about launching your brand?
I don't want to,
And take down that picture,
Don't you think your talent is wasted?
You're such a genius,
That's what I'm saying,
You have a completely different style,,,
compared to those mundane designers,
The clothes you designed for Hae Ra are so unique,
They're the best,
I am,,,
all for this idea,
Sharon is a genius,
But she never works hard, I think it's because,,,
she has a lot of real estate properties,
Hey,
Anyway,
I hope she does not waste her talent anymore,
When this business thrives,
you will become a world-renowned designer,
Imagine that,
How long have you been designing clothes?
Well,,,
I'll just have to say that it's been a while,
Just say that I'm a new designer,
Congratulations,
Do you acknowledge my talent too?
I came out to the world,,,
to be acknowledged by you,
despite the danger,
Sharon,
- Sharon, - Sharon,
I was her assistant,,,
when I was 16,
But she still looks the same,,,
even after 60 years,
There was a reason why she opened and closed,,,
her shop from time to time, never making,,,
any regular customers, living under the radar,
Sharon never grows old, and she won't die either,
She's a monster,
(New Designer Sharon)
(Real name, Choi Seo Rin, 250 years old)
Let's do this together,
I can bring you some design references today,
Sell that picture to me,
Oh, if you decide to do business with us,
I'll give it to you as a present,
Goodness, miss, Are you insane?
Hey, call the police and report her,,,
for interrupting business and property damage,
My gosh,
Wrap it up and send it over,
And bill me for the picture,
My goodness,
She's crazy,
I need to go get some salt,
I need to sprinkle salt all over this place,
What's with her?
Is she an attention seeker?
It looks like she needs love and attention,
And some treatment,
Let's leave her out,
- What was that? - My goodness,
Did I ask to see you when you're busy?
You did,
Goodness, what will you do?
You should go, then,
Okay,
I'm glad you called,
I needed to get some healing,
I came because I needed courage,
What can I do for you?
When you work,
if things don't seem to work out,
should I quit right away, or should I keep going?
In that case, d, o, i, t,
D, o, i, t?
Your name is the answer,
Hae Ra, meaning "do it",
That was lame,
Be more specific,
In a businessman's eyes, how does the owner of,,,
Sharon Tailor look?
Is this for the outfit rental business?
Yes, I want to,
She's way too unique,
But her style is too cool to give up,
She doesn't look very ordinary to me either,
Right?
What you need is Sharon Tailor's talent,
Yes,
If you feel confident enough,,,
to humor her and train her,
you can give it a try,
I had enough taffies, but I still feel depressed,
I need something sweeter,
Let's go get some cake,
Let go of me,
I'm going to quit,
I don't want to work for a rude employer,
You can quit after we get some cake,
Stop pronouncing it like a grandma,
It's cake,
Are you leaving to get some cake?
If you want to use someone's talent,,,
for your business,
you need to be ready,,,
to do something big,,,
for their sake,
One of the reasons why,,,
I got lucky was that I worked hard,
But not everyone makes it even if they try hard,
And some don't get the chance to work hard,
Even so, you must try,
Even if it doesn't work, you must work hard,
Is that how you lived your life?
Yes,
Soo Ho, you're a big boy now,
I don't mind you talking to me like that,
but don't do it in the public,
But why?
Why are you concerned about others?
We had fun that day,
All right, then,
Becky,
Perhaps one day,
we might become the clowns of this world,
Is it impossible for us,,,
to grow old with the ones we love?
It's a shirt made with the finest cotton,
Why are you giving this to me?
You let your employees get trained with me,
I was thankful,
No, I should thank you,
I will work hard in the future,
What will happen,,,
when Mr, Moon puts this on?
I wished that he and I,,,
will get to live under the same roof,
I haven't seen Hae Ra for a while,
She's working outside,
Is she doing interviews with other companies?
Chief director,
Hae Ra loves this company,
Why does she?
Yes, I'm on my way,
You can do it,
I have to go back to work,,,
after I stop by the tailor's,
Don't wait around and go to sleep early,
Okay,
Bye,
Hae Ra,
Have some tea,
It took Sharon half a day to make that,
and then she was knocked out,
Thank you,
You must be tired, I'm sorry to bother you,
What is it?
These are,,,
the draft proposals I made,
Please take a look,
I said I didn't want to do it,
Then please review it later,,,
after you get some rest,
I can't be bothered to do anything,
Those dresses are so pretty,
May I take a look?
E10 Black Knight "Don't You Mess With Me"
Do you make wedding dresses as well?
I've never made one for someone,
I make one when I'm sad,
then I rip it apart,
That's a waste,
It's up to me,
I wish you'd make wedding dresses too,
Why?
What do you mean why?
It'd be a huge blessing if you could,,,
wear a beautiful dress like this,,,
on the most important day of your life,
Someday,,,
when I get married,
I'd love to wear a dress made from Sharon Tailor,
There's a veil hat,
Who do you think you'll marry?
I'm not sure,
Baek Hee,
Should I just kill her,,,
and run away?
I'm an expert at living in hiding,
I wish you'd remember,,,
your past life at least once,
He'd feel sorry for me,
It's not the man you live with, is it?
It'd be nice to be married,,,
to him,
I don't know why I attached a veil that way,
It looked horrendous,
so I couldn't stand it,
Are you crazy?
Are you insane?
How can you thrust scissors like that?
Why are you wearing that stupid veil?
I should cut it here too,
Get away,
How dare you,,,
Get out right now,
I won't do that work,
Apologize to me first, you ignorant woman,
Apologize, now!
Take your hands off me!
You!
How dare you!
You,,, Come here,
Come here!
Boon Yi, that wretched girl,
She used to be my slave who made my clothes,
How dare she bite me and scratch me?
What are you saying?
Didn't you see what she did to me?
Wait,
Did you get a tattoo here too?
If you want to use someone's talent,,,
for your business,
you need to be ready to do something big,,,
for their sake,
D, o, i, t,
Hae Ra, Do it,
What?
Hae Ra,
I'm sorry,
I apologize,
I should've been more understanding,
But I failed to do that,
Please forgive me,
I thought about it,
Master potters break perfectly fine ceramics,,,
if they don't suit their taste,
I'm sorry, I didn't grasp that earlier,
Hae Ra,
You have an amazing personality,
I've never seen anyone so cool,
Please bring us some plates,
I brought a lot of,,,
tteokbokki, sundae, and fritters,
Please forgive me,
and consider,,,
working with my company at least once,
I'm sure you'll change your mind,,,
if you look at the proposal,
I sincerely beg you,
Hae Ra,
Circle Tour will,,,
start the clothing rental business,
I think our idea leaked,
Theirs is exactly the same as ours,
What?
It's for the better,
It takes too much work and leaves no profit,
I'm sure they'll cancel it after one term,
Hae Ra, don't be disappointed,
Didn't I tell you not to brag about your idea?
Gosh, you make me tired, I'm so tired,
You tire me out,
How can he say that?
Hae Ra, Are you in there?
Stop crying,
I'm not crying,
What are you doing in there then?
I have constipation,
Don't lie,
Come out,
We have a problem,
Eagle Airline pilots,,,
are having a strike,
We need to book new flights for group tours,
After we take care of this,
let's cry together,
Mr, Song,
Our situation is really urgent,,,
because of the strike, Please take 30 people,
You haven't been giving us good deals,
Please help us just this once,
30 people connecting to Frankfurt will do,,,
Hello? Mr, Song?
Hello?
- Yes, - Please hold,
- Yes, - Okay,
- Yes, - Please help us,
- We need your help, - Please,
Hi, there,
I thought you'd need roasted chestnuts today,
What happened to your face?
What's wrong? Did something happen?
Did things not work out right?
There's no need to cry for such a thing,
I'm upset,
Don't cry,
Hae Ra,
Yes?
My heart,,,
is burning,
It's so hot,
I'm in a bad mood,
I'm not in a mood to hear your joke,
I'm not joking, It's really hot,
Hold on,
Gosh, it's hot,
Just in case you don't like chestnuts,
I bought roasted sweet potatoes too,
Didn't you smell it?
It's not fun?
You just smiled, right?
You know what happens when you smile after crying?
Hey,
Stop it,
Stop what? I'm serious,
When I went to med school,
someone came to the hospital because of that,
He came to the emergency room,
What's that?
Joke around according to situations,
It's all right,
I don't know what happened,
but it's all right,
You have me by your side,
You'll have a lot of struggles in your life,
Still, it's fine,
I'm here by your side,
Let me see your face,
Don't,
That's my girl,
Goodness, seriously,
You'll reunite,,,
with your owner tomorrow,
Hae Ra, look,
Should I put it here?
That's perfect,
Who's your guest today,,,
that you called in a chef?
Someone whom I'm very grateful to,
Join us for dinner later,
No, thank you,
It's uncomfortable,
There's no need to,
You and my guest,,,
are all family to me,
This should be enough,
I'm the only one who's lonely in this world,
What do you think?
If the two get married,
what will happen to me?
Are you the guest for today?
I told you 15 years ago,
I told you to take care of a poor child,,,
in exchange for paying all your debt,,,
and that I wouldn't show up until she gets married,
Then why are you here?
I can't predict how the world goes,
I did what I could do,
I did enough,
I could've abandoned her,,,
after receiving money from you,
I would've,,,
killed you then,
What?
Who saved me from drowning,,,
in the first place?
I was betrayed by my own husband,,,
and had a huge amount of debt,
But you saved me,
You paid for all my hospital fees,,,
and took care of me like a family,
I know you wouldn't have killed me,
Right, I wanted you to take care of Hae Ra,,,
with those guts of yours,
Except for the failure in the hanok investment,
I did the best I could do,
I never siphoned off the money,,,
that you sent me every holiday,
All right,
Let's say we never met before,
Excuse me,
What is it?
Hello,
I'm here to see Ms, Choi Seo Rin,
She doesn't live here,
But her address is here,
Why are you looking for her?
If you get in touch with her,
please call me,
(Ahn Chan Ki)
Thank you in advance,
"Blacksmith's"?
Wait a second,
Isn't the CEO of this company, Moon Soo Ho?
That's right,
What is the matter?
I'm very happy and lucky,,,
to have a precious time with you,
It's like I'm in a dream,
I've never imagined,,,
having a wonderful meal at Soo Ho's house like this,
I'm tearing up,
Don't cry,
I'm going to cry too if you do,
How do you know each other?
I have two people who saved my life,
They're Ms, Jang and Hae Ra,
You're the second person who saved my life,
Did she save you from drowning or something?
When I couldn't do anything,,,
and wanted to die,
she gave me huge courage to stand back up,
When I was younger,
I delivered green juice in the town,
I knew who lived where and their circumstances,
I saw a math genius boy with a scar on his face,,,
crying in the reed field one day,
I lied that I could predict the future,
"Nothing is in your way,"
"You'll achieve everything you want,"
I had nowhere to lean on,
so I decided to trust her lies,
I prayed for Soo Ho even when I donated a coin,,,
in the Salvation Army charity pot,
How nosy of you,
I know it's there even though I can't see it,
What is?
A desperate prayer,,,
or poignant longing,
Can you see where such a thing reaches?
You can't,
But can you say it doesn't exist?
My prayers piled up and came true before my eyes,
I believe in the power of heart,
I believe in karma as well,
It's all a coincidence and a superstition,
There's no such thing,
Here,
Today is a day I'd love to leave as a diary entry,
I'm so happy,
I think,,,
I'll die very early,,,
for all the luck I had,
I hope this is just a pointless concern,
Show me your hand,
Don't worry about it,
You will live a happy life,,,
until you turn 300,
I'll believe you again,
Right,
Isn't Geumseong 1-dong and Geumseong 2-dong,,,
where you've been working on?
You're right,
I heard Chairman Park Chul Min,,,
has been convincing people to do a redevelopment,
Do you know him well?
We have a bad history,
How so?
I'll tell you later,
I want to talk about only good things tonight,
Okay,
I think she's weird,
She might act like,,,
your mother-in-law if you marry Soo Ho,
Come on, Aunt Sook Hee,
It'll be a while until we get married,
I need to achieve something in my life too,
Don't you think?
Oh, right,
Take this,
Melt this in when you make,,,
matching rings with Hae Ra,
This looks very old,
I hope you trust what I say again,,,
and do that,
Okay, I will,
Come have some desserts,
I made some delicious coffee,
Really?
I look forward to having some,
I'm better at it, Why didn't you call me?
No, this time, it turned out very well,
Really? Let's take a look,
I brought coffee,
- Okay, - Coffee,
- Have some coffee, - Coffee,
- This is yours, - Why on earth,,,
do we say working hours begin at 9am?
He calls us out for meetings,,,
at 6:50am every other day,
Hey,
It's the peak season for traveling,
We can't have meetings during working hours,
Have some coffee,
"Merci beaucoup,"
Now, show me what you brought,
(A Trip with a Theme)
Simple package tours are decreasing in demand,
So we thought of a trip with a theme,
A trip of taste,,,
with a famous chef,
Or a South American trip after Che Guevara,
For the trip of taste,
you can enjoy your trip as well as food,,,
with explanations of the chef on the trip,
So we thought of trips with such themes,
Sounds good,
I told you to think of something like that,
You did?
I don't remember you saying that,
I told you to do this last time,
You practically took my idea,
Chief director,
We came up with this among ourselves,
We thought of this after we lost,,,
the outfit rental business,
The chairman will love this idea,
See? You came up with a great idea thanks to me,
Right, Hae Ra?
What's with that face?
What's wrong?
I wonder why,
What do I have to do at times like these?
Do I have to stay calm? Or should I be angry?
I'm really frustrated right now,
Hello, Mr, Moon,
Come in, please,
I'm a bit late, I'm sorry,
Everyone, say hello,
This is Mr, Moon Soo Ho, who will work with us,,,
on the Seoul Neighborhood Project,
- Hello, - Hello,
Hello,
I'm really glad to see you,
Hello, Nice to meet you all,
Of course,
What's going on?
What are you doing? You should go,
It must be cold here, I'll get a small heater,
Forget it,
Goodness, this means we'll see you,,,
twice a week in our meetings,
I know you're all busy,
so we'll prepare a lot to not waste your time,
Thank you,
Go, I'll see you outside,
Sure, Ms, Jung,
What happened?
Your chief director is really interesting,
He called me at 6am,,,
and wanted to meet me,
Goodness, this is so embarrassing,
I chose this agency as the one,,,
I wanted to work with,
It might be inconvenient for us to work together,
Does this place have a security camera?
It doesn't,
I'm so glad that I get to work with you,
I'm busy today,
I'll see you at home,
Bye,
Go!
This looks good,
- Hello, - Hi,
- You're back, - Hello,
That's hot,
- Mr, Moon, are you okay? - Yes,
Oh, goodness,
You have a meeting with a property owner,
- I'm sorry, - It's fine,
Get back to work,
I'm sorry,
(Blacksmith's)
Hello,
Will you sit on that sofa and wait for a little bit?
I wished that he and I,,,
will get to live under the same roof,
This is Ms, Choi Seo Rin,
I inherited the land from my ancestors,
but there was an error on the papers,
Hello, I am Moon Soo Ho the CEO,
Hello, I'm Choi Seo Rin,