You are too harsh on me.
Can't you just hug me once?
Be born again.
I will wait.
(Hae Ra)
Your call has been forwarded to...
Wine was like a pie in the sky.
This time, the chief director...
Why isn't he picking up?
- I'm tired. - Gosh.
But I'm not drunk.
Hae Ra.
(Episode 17)
Full moon.
When the moon is full.
What is she trying to say?
I know.
If the ring receives
a ray of full moon beam,
it gains strength to grant your wish.
Boon Yi, what would you like to wish?
Secret.
It is cold. Let us go inside.
Tell me when we go inside.
What is your wish? Let me hear it.
My wish is that...
you would not receive poison as punishment.
That is a difficult wish to come true.
I asked that...
you would not die...
even if you drank the poison.
Even if you drink the poison...
Whatever comes your way...
I asked that...
you never let go of your life...
easily.
You wished upon that ring.
Okay. Boon Yi.
I will wear that ring...
when I receive poison.
Which finger would fit?
I do not like jokes.
I am not joking.
You made an earnest wish upon that ring.
So it should be in contact with my skin.
I will put it in my inside pocket at least,
so I would never die.
Please do not die.
I will not die.
Never.
Not ever.
I will not die.
Never.
Not ever.
Die in there!
Melt this ring, and make a new blade for this.
On the tiger's month, day, and hour,
make a knife that is extremely hard and sharp.
What is this?
What is this dress?
Answer me!
Baek Hee.
We have to leave.
I...
killed him.
Soo Ho. Wake up.
Open your eyes, Soo Ho.
Soo Ho.
No. You can't die.
Please come back.
Please make him come back.
Please save him.
Sharon. I brought stuff from Dongdaemun.
They're...
What happened...
to Mr. Moon?
Call an ambulance.
That's Sharon's.
I said call an ambulance!
Sharon.
Sharon. Where are you?
- Sharon. Where are you? - Wake up.
Please come back.
Please let him live.
Charge 200.
Clear!
Mr. Jung.
Soo Ho.
It's been so long.
You've become a decent, young man.
I had so much to talk to you when I met you.
I'm sorry,
and thank you.
Hae Ra and I are getting married.
Soo Ho.
Yes?
You...
shouldn't be here. Go back.
Did you forget your promise with Hae Ra?
Soo Ho.
Soo Ho...
His pulse is stable,
so he'll regain his consciousness soon.
Let's wait and see.
His heart stopped due to excessive bleeding?
Yes.
Strangely, he didn't have any external injury...
that could've caused excessive bleeding.
We did a checkup on him to see if it was a stroke,
but it wasn't.
We've never had such a case before.
So we need to wait and see his condition first.
What happened?
Are you the one who called the ambulance?
Where was he?
Let's talk outside.
At Sharon Tailor?
I think he came to try on his wedding suit.
What do you mean?
We're supposed to make...
a dress and a suit for your wedding.
What?
You didn't get any call from Sharon, did you?
Don't meet her even if she does.
When did he ask you...
to make them?
Mr. Moon didn't ask it himself.
Then who...
It was Baek Hee.
That was why Mr. Moon said he'd wear it.
Why did she ask such a favor?
I don't know.
And...
I really don't want to say this...
I saw Sharon's silver knife...
dropped next to Mr. Moon.
I didn't see it in the ambulance.
When he was down unconscious,
Baek Hee was with him.
Where's she now?
Get changed.
I don't want to see you in that.
Are the police looking for me...
to arrest me as a murder suspect?
He fortunately saved his life.
He's alive?
I am...
giving up on you.
I don't want to see you anymore.
Baek Hee.
Leave this country.
Don't think about showing yourself before the two.
Don't you think you're too harsh on me?
Shall I report you to the police...
that a 200-year-old monster...
tried to hurt a person?
You made me this way.
Yes.
Just kill me instead, Sharon.
And have your revenge.
What happened?
Tell me in detail.
He's a bit hurt.
Don't worry too much. I think he'll recover soon.
Where did he get hurt that he's in the hospital?
He got into a car accident?
He sort of overworked.
He'll recover soon.
Did you call his employees?
Not yet.
I'll go nurse him from tomorrow morning.
I'll call you later.
Goodness, what's going on?
He went to work with a smile on his face earlier.
(Sharon Tailor)
Hello?
Yes, you heard the news.
Right.
He's in Haneul Hospital.
It's okay.
Don't mind me,
and take your time, Hae Ra.
I'm not hungry.
I think he's reacting to sounds.
I told you he'll regain his consciousness soon.
I'll check his condition,
so you may stay outside for a bit.
His guardian will arrive soon.
Well, then.
Mr. Moon Soo Ho.
Do you hear me?
Move your fingers again.
Good.
Open your eyes.
(Dr. Park Ji Yeon)
I told you to be born again.
Soo Ho.
Are you awake?
Where am I?
You're in the hospital.
(Haneul Hospital)
Don't worry about me, and get to work.
Do you feel pain, or does it ache anywhere?
Not at all.
I feel much better than usual.
Do you not remember why you came here?
I suddenly felt dizzy...
and feverish, so I came to the emergency room.
Yesterday,
it was odd that there was no wound...
even though you bled a lot.
I didn't bleed.
I walked in here myself.
Do you know where you left your clothes?
That's what I don't know.
That's odd.
You'll be late. Get to work.
I'll be fine.
The temperature dropped to minus 16.3°C.
I'll call you.
But the wind is less harsh than yesterday.
You can't tell what will happen with the weather.
Bye.
But it will stay pretty cold.
Other areas may drop to minus 8°C.
Soo Ho.
Forgive me.
For you,
Hae Ra, and Sharon,
you must forget about today.
What happened last night?
Next news.
The town that was selected for the city revival...
demands the decision to be cancelled.
For whom...
are we reviving this town for,
and for whom are we preserving this?
The taxpayers' money will be used for this,
and people point out that this profits no one.
Do we have to continue this project?
She's slacking off right after her promotion.
Hae Ra, I mean.
You have to give her a break.
Mr. Moon suddenly got hospitalized.
She did send the proposal late in the night.
She sent an email while she was nursing him.
Really? I'll check.
Oh, right. Sir.
We're going to go...
and visit Mr. Moon during our lunch time.
- I'll let you go. - Okay.
Only if I like your proposal.
- Come on, you... - Understood?
You clearly told me that yesterday.
You saw Sharon's knife, but not in the ambulance.
You said...
Baek Hee was there when Soo Ho collapsed.
I did?
Yes, you did. In front of the emergency room.
When did I say that?
Why do you suddenly need your passport?
Something came up.
Please take care of...
Sharon Tailor while I'm gone.
You're the owner...
and the chief designer for a while.
How long will you be gone for?
I don't know.
And what happened yesterday?
Why was your knife...
on the floor next to Mr. Moon?
What happened?
Seung Goo.
Come here.
Let me give you a bottle of perfume as a gift.
Yesterday,
nothing happened, Seung Goo.
Nothing.
Then why were you at the hospital?
Yesterday? I was there because my stomach...
suddenly got upset, and I saw you there.
I got sick after eating a bowl of noodles...
as I shopped for materials in Dongdaemun area.
(Blood Test Result, all normal)
I've never seen anyone who recovered so quickly.
This is unique.
Any headaches or dizziness?
Not at all.
But let's stay another day and see how you feel.
I'm feeling great.
I think I can go home right away.
Then...
come back immediately if you feel weird.
I will.
Where did you go last night without telling me?
At my shop.
I saw that you cleaned up everything.
Did you get a call...
from the hospital?
Why do you want to know?
You're going to leave soon.
He's...
alive, right?
He's not someone you can recklessly hurt.
If you do that again,
I will tell the police.
Remember that.
Soo Ho...
I have to forget about last night...
because of what you just said, correct?
Ms. Choi.
It looks like you were about to run away.
Are you insane?
You lived over 200 years, and you can do magic.
You can go anywhere without that.
Do you remember that?
I do remember, but it means nothing.
What's important is that you're a killer.
I came to ask a question.
Did you...
stab Soo Ho yesterday?
Ms. Jang, you know something, don't you?
You're hiding something. Are you not?
Seung Goo said...
he saw Sharon's knife next to Soo Ho.
Although he said something different today.
Let's go to the police station. We'll talk there.
I made them wedding garments.
That means I can probably die now.
I...
still don't know what I did wrong.
What?
Someone jumped off!
Someone jumped off the bridge!
Goodness. Call an ambulance!
Hi. I need an ambulance.
Someone just jumped off a bridge.
Yes, a person jumped into the river.
Goodness, Mr. Moon.
Are you all right?
Are you okay to be out of the hospital so soon?
I'm fine.
What was wrong?
The hospital misdiagnosed.
What's wrong with Hae Ra?
Aunt Sook Hee. Please make her a hot cup of tea.
Okay.
Let's go.
That woman...
I hope the police find her.
Right. Get some sleep.
I didn't dream it, did I?
You saw what I saw, right?
Don't think about it, Hae Ra.
The police will find her.
Have you found the body yet?
We haven't found her yet.
We'll keep looking.
Please continue the search.
I want you to show the document...
and the letter of prayer to Hae Ra.
Wouldn't that confuse her?
It's up to her to believe it or not.
All right.
Is there something...
you want to tell me?
Sharon...
stabbed you with a knife
I felt your pulse,
so I hid the knife.
Why?
To protect the three of you.
Nothing good will come of it,
if the story gets out.
So you tried to erase...
what happened from my memory.
It doesn't really work with you.
Did Choi Seo Rin...
really die?
No.
But...
you can consider her as dead.
Because she won't come between you two anymore.
She had...
jumped into the river twice before.
After 30 years.
And after 50 years...
She came back.
4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
Mr. Moon. You've been busy lately, haven't you?
No, because my business isn't going well.
Still...
I feel a good vibe.
Everything will work out.
Since it's been a while,
let's do just 10 first.
One.
Two.
96.
97.
98.
99.
100. Mr. Moon, you can stop now.
Mr. Moon, have you been eating healthy food?
Our stocks are crazy.
Amazing.
Mr. Moon.
Good morning.
Yes, good morning.
Mr. Moon, it's really strange.
What is?
The Jinju stock you recommend...
has been going up for four days straight.
Thank you, Mr. Moon.
Did you know A2 Group was going to be taken over?
No. I recommended it...
because the company seemed reliable.
Be careful since it can be a strategy.
Also,
the Red Techno stocks you told me to sell,
the value went down as soon as I sold it.
Do you have a sixth sense or something?
After you arrive,
it'd be good to take a rest...
before going to dinner, right?
Sure.
- Of course. - Of course.
Relax in your hotel room for a little bit.
Get changed into nice clothes.
Fix your makeup too.
I bought new clothes.
We'll have to put on a nice lipstick.
There are 55 of us,
but you planned the itinerary so well.
I think you're the best in Korea.
No, you're the best in Asia.
Isn't she the best in the world?
- You're right. - Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you for your compliment.
Hae Ra.
Do I look any different?
No. Why do you ask?
I think I'm feeling better,
and I've gained more muscles too.
That's good.
Also...
Never mind.
What is it?
I recommended a stock to my employees,
and that hit the jackpot.
Don't do such things. It's dangerous.
I told them not to.
I just thought it was interesting.
I'm meeting Ms. Jang this evening.
She asked to have dinner with me.
Okay. Have a good time.
I can trust her, right?
I trust her.
Why did you want to see me?
I had a dream.
I was on top of a shiny building,
and I looked down...
at the streets of Seoul.
It's a dream about falling.
Be careful.
Let me...
meet with Seo Rin.
You two are so similar.
You have crazy obsessions.
Where is Seo Rin?
She's dead.
Seo Rin doesn't get old, and she never dies.
Find her if you can.
I'm curious too.
Seo Rin.
I loved her so much.
Even if he manages...
to escape from the lab fire case,
There are many ways to corner him...
like preferential loan and embezzlement.
We have to put him in jail for the fire case.
Don't worry. Things will work out well.
Okay.
Mr. Yoon cannot be reached.
You suspect us...
whenever something happens.
No, I really don't know anything.
Give Yoon Dal Hong his land back already.
Dad.
Don't ever see him again.
Don't be curious...
about his whereabouts either if he disappears.
Young Mi.
We need to talk.
Hye Young, can you clean up the second floor first?
Okay.
Speak.
Tell me honestly...
about what you know.
I know nothing.
You said my father set a fire to the lab...
and killed Hae Ra's father.
You wanted to break up with me,
so I made up a story out of anger.
I told you it was a lie.
My father is a pathetic man...
who became evil because he was ignorant.
Help him stop from becoming more evil.
Did anything else happen that I don't know of?
Tell me.
Tell me what you know.
- Drink it. - You know I hung out...
with delinquents for a while, right?
- Will we become men too? - Goodness.
I want to pee.
Here. Do it here.
- Here. - Hey, I'm sophisticated.
Sophisticated, my foot.
You think you're a noble woman or what?
- Gosh, it's cold. - Drink up.
I won't.
You set a fire on the lab, didn't you?
How could you do that?
Don't accuse an innocent man.
Let's go to the police. Let's talk there.
Are you all innocent?
You snuck out Doctor Moon's research paper...
to earn money.
You'll be the first to be suspected.
And I'll take the responsibility for it.
I'm prepared.
So you earned enough money, is that right?
I can't let it slide.
You may kill me too in the future.
Right.
You two always treated me like I'm the bad one.
You're twisted out of inferior complex.
Inferior complex?
You punk. You're insane.
You jerk.
Hey...
Hey, get up.
And...
he carried Hae Ra's father on his back...
and got on his car.
I thought he was going to a hospital.
But I heard a different story later.
Why didn't you tell others then?
Because of Park Gon,
the class president of Hanguk Middle School.
I kept silent because of you.
Your family moved to an expensive apartment.
You got a new car.
I liked seeing you live a better life.
Young Mi.
I lied to Hae Ra...
that my parents...
checked how he died in the hospital.
Until now,
we've made it without any problem.
No one knows about it.
Let's keep it a secret between me and you.
It's surprising...
that your story was found in the grave.
But I don't believe in a past life.
It doesn't matter even if you don't believe it.
But it's true that such things happened...
in the past.
If your story is all true,
and Choi Seo Rin is an immortal being,
then she'll appear again.
Maybe when you two...
become a happy old couple.
If she appears before my eyes again,
I think I'll be able to believe in all this story.
When you're upset or confused,
tell me anytime.
Is Sharon Tailor...
still closed?
Seung Goo is working hard to run it.
Pay a visit some time,
and keep him company.
He must be lonely.
Okay, I'll visit there one day.
Stop it.
Did you talk with her all right?
Yes.
But...
I don't believe in the old story.
Then don't.
But...
I think it's true that we're meant to be.
Hae Ra.
Do you know what my dream is?
What is it?
To grow old with you like them.
Is that all?
That's all.
That's very simple.
Let's make our wedding pictures...
look really great and wonderful.
Okay.
Let's live a happy and healthy life.
Let us do that.
Hey, stop the car.
- Did you see that? - What?
This is Lee Hyun Sik of patrol car three.
Was there any other suicide report?
None. There has been no other suicide today.
That's odd.
What is it?
I just saw a woman's head right above the water.
What are you talking about?
Han River is completely frozen today.
Let's go.
Okay.
Hey, Sharon!
I got confused for a second.
You must miss her a lot.
No, I don't.
I was going to brag about my new design.
Seung Goo.
For the next 30 years,
no, maybe 50 years,
can you keep this place as good as today?
Is Sharon...
gone for good?
I don't know either.
No.
I don't think I can.
If she doesn't come back,
I'm going to ruin this place and sell it off.
Sharon.
I guess...
there is someone that misses you.
Father.
Mother.
I am here. It is me, Seo Rin.
Please come out.
I am here.
Yes.
Father.
There used to be people that loved you.
Once you graduate from dressmaking school,
let's return to Joseon.
I'm sure everyone who remembers us...
are all long gone.
How long do you think we'll live like this?
One day, when you meet Boon Yi,
make her some clothes.
Can people really be born again?
People who lived a great life...
or a very wicked life...
probably don't.
But...
those who left...
with great sorrow and regret...
may get...
one more chance by fate.
How do you know?
If not, then never mind.
I don't want to make any clothes.
The only two things you are good at are...
making yourself look pretty...
and getting jealous.
Make use of that.
Let's go play mah-jong.
Go study.
It's just for today.
Let's go.
I don't know where you are,
but atone for everything you did there,
and never return.
Baek Hee.
Can you get some forks?
Did you two hold a photo exhibit yesterday?
I put them up. I'll take them down.
They look great. Leave them up.
Don't take them down.
Are you going to the construction site later?
Yes, after I stop by my office.
Then can you drop me off at the subway station?
It's the weekend. Do you want to come?
Should I?
I'll call you later.
Do you want some milk?
What was that?
Are the lights changing just for you?
What?
I guess so.
Sharon will be surprised to see this.
I have a feeling...
that she will come back in May.
She likes roses.
Who is it?
Hae Ra.
Goodness, you're so awful.
I haven't seen you in ages.
I'll visit from time to time.
Everything looks the same.
I'm going to leave it as it is...
until Sharon returns.
When will she come back?
Baek Hee said...
she'll be back in 30 or 50 years.
But who knows?
I came to return this.
What?
After I put this on,
I went through a series of odd events.
It was a turning point in my life.
Anyway, I became happy.
This is a very special coat,
so I want to return it.
Really?
Did your life change...
after you put this on?
Yes.
I'm thankful for the coat,
but I'm also scared of it.
Yes, dark brown.
Seung Goo, I'm leaving.
One second.
Have a cup of tea before you leave.
Then I'll tell Soo Ho to come here.
We have to be somewhere later.
That'd be wonderful.
Yes. Hello? Yes.
Who are you?
(Black Knight - The Man Who Guards Me)
I think she's pretending not to know me.
I came back very soon this time, right?
You don't remember?
The chic Sharon style.
She's back.
I'm marrying Soo Ho.
My employees prepared this.
How about champagne?
Let's stop. Please!
I'm a son of a criminal.
Hae Ra said she'd work...
in the office in Rome for two years.
I don't want you to go.
All I need is you.
This isn't a dream, is it?