The year was 1972.
June, 1972.
A small party of us left Television
Centre in London in a minibus.
We were heading for this marvellous
West Yorkshire countryside.
In the bus, was the director
Jimmy Gilbert, three actors -
Michael Bates, Bill Owen
and Peter Sallis,
a small very crew...
But what we did have
was an absolutely wonderful script.
I read the script in bed.
I got about halfway through
and I rang Jimmy Gilbert.
"What do you think?" he said.
I said, "It's pure gold.
Count me in!"
It happens sometimes
in an actor's life,
if you're very, very lucky,
that something special turns up.
When I read Last Of The Summer
Wine, I thought, "This is IT."
He's still calling for me
in broad daylight!
Say he doesn't belong to you,
you're just looking after him
for somebody!
I was at home, watching a series
called The Misfit -
a show which was a drama,
but with comedy undertones.
I thought the phrasing of the
writing, and the whole style of it,
was worth pursuing. The writer
was a guy I'd never met, Roy Clarke.
When Duncan invited me
to come and see him,
and would I be interested
in having a crack at sitcom,
the answer was... I nearly bit
his fingers off! Yeah, sure,
I wanted to have a go at sitcom.
The BBC seemed to have
in their mind, at that time,
an idea that they had a requirement
for a series, a comedy series,
based around three old men.
'For a long time,
I struggled with this idea
'to try and get some enthusiasm
about it, and I had none.
I had none at all, really,'
until almost at the point
of turning it down,
it occurred to me
that if these three old men
were totally free,
they had no responsibilities,
no ties, they each lived alone,
they were...
unmarried or widows,
they were unemployed or retired,
'therefore,
they were able to wander about
'in the same way
that young adolescents can do.
'That pulled it out of the fire for
me. I saw these, not as old people,
'just kids that happened
to have got a bit older.'
Your left-hand oar! Your left-hand
oar! Starboard, do you mind?!
'Because this story
was going to be about older people,
'I wanted to emphasise
that summer was still around.
'It might be the last of summer,
but it was still summer
as far as they were concerned.'
And so that's why I called it
Last Of The Summer Wine -
to emphasise the summer
as against the autumn.
And it was never well received.
It was taken for granted that
I'd change it. It'd be a working
title, till we got a better one.
One of the alternatives
was The Library Mob
because, in the first series,
they used to visit their library
and sit in the reading room,
leafing through the newspapers
and chatting.
He's been useless all his life!
You only say that cos it's true.
As kids, WE'd go for a swim and HE'd
go for a dip in his mam's handbag!
There weren't nowt in it, though.
We was poor.
We can see how far you've come(!)
It's our family tradition.
It used to be a tradition here, if
you were hungry, you could knock on
any door and, without hesitation,
they'd slam it right in your face!
Fortunately, it was abandoned...
just before the show went on air.
We reverted to
Last Of The Summer Wine.
After we'd done the pilot,
I had a deputation
of the three actors who said,
"We don't think this is going
to work as Last Of The Summer Wine.
Nobody will remember it."
The characters came fairly easily
with Compo coming first,
because Compo was a composite of...
of people I knew
in my own environment,
'in my own area,
who lived that totally feckless,
but quite cheerful, existence.
'Always wore wellies!'
Having got him,
then it made obvious sense
to go straight to his opposite,
'who was regimented,
'straight up and down,
'authoritarian.
'So you got the two extremes...'
Now you wait here.
It's not only me City & Guilds,
it's the social chasm between us.
Hey, Cyril! Give us a fag.
I'll give you a sniff of me socks!
'..which left a nice slot for Clegg
in the middle,
'who'd take the blows
and balance the three out.'
'I wanted Peter Sallis for Clegg
from the word one, if he was free.'
I'd written it
very much with Peter in mind.
The other two,
I had no fixed ideas about
and left it to Jimmy Gilbert.
I thought that
Bill Owen would be right
because I'd seen him
play a Compo-like character
in a play with Spike Milligan
called Oblomov.
I'd seen him in Davie Storey's play,
The Contractor,
where he played a tough northerner.
Putting the two together
and having seen him in comedy,
he seemed to be the perfect casting.
This went down like a lead balloon,
because I was raised on film
and I remembered Bill
in all his films,
always the cockney airman,
the cockney AC2, or whatever,
and I couldn't see Bill as Compo.
Oh, hello, sir.
Hello, Sergeant.
Sorry about making a clot of myself.
What do you mean? That landing? Ta.
I've seen worse! Old Bill Thompson
was my pilot till he bought it.
He did some real shakers.
Broke every bone!
It's only when I saw Bill on screen
that I realised what
a wonderful physical clown Bill is.
His movements...
when he does odd walks.
Bill is magical, physically.
'There's no question about it.'
The next one I met was Peter Sallis.
I hadn't seen him since we were
at drama school together, at RADA,
20 years before.
When I saw him coming in with this
rather battered jacket on, and
a cardigan and ill-fitting trousers,
I thought, "Poor old Peter.
He's down on his luck."
But as he left, he said, "I think
this would do for Clegg, don't you?"
Well, it was a suit
that I'd had for...donkey's years.
I was very fond of it.
But I thought,
"Yes, this would do for Clegg."
It was a sort of
library-lounger's suit.
Anyway, what I didn't realise
was that was that it was going to
run, the programme, for 20 years!
And after about 20 years,
the suit was falling to pieces.
What the BBC wardrobe department
did, which was cunning of them,
was that they took a small amount
of the cloth to a local mill
and they asked them to run them up
a whole roll of the stuff,
which they did.
So they were able to make me a new
suit and one or two other suits,
just in case they were
needed by the, um, stand-ins.
I felt it should be
in a small market town,
surrounded by beautiful countryside,
and preferably with valleys.
I was speaking to Barry Took
about this
and he said,
"Why don't you try Holmfirth?"
I went there
when I was a young comic. It sounds
exactly what you're looking for.
I rang up Roy and went to Holmfirth.
We stood on the hill, looked down
on the town and said, "That's it!"
And that was it.
When it first appeared on
the screens, as a situation comedy,
Last Of The Summer Wine
was something of a breakthrough,
in visual terms, for a sitcom.
Certainly, it wasn't studio-bound.
You did get outside.
You got outside with a purpose.
You saw that scenery and,
from the beginning,
that's been a major element,
I think, in its success.
'When Michael Bates sadly died,
'Brian Wilde was brought in
'to play a modified character
and put the series back on track.'
The view. The grandeur.
The valley spreading out beneath us,
lacking only one thing
which we are going to supply.
I don't think that's all that funny!
Come on! I know you're there!
Right! God knows - I try to
raise the tone of our activities!
Who introduced you to astronomy?
..Right!
Who brought you out here one night
and taught you how to navigate
by the stars
And had to get a taxi back
from Clayhidon?
Well, I'd just finished Porridge
and they asked me
to be in Last Of The Summer Wine.
I said I'd love to read the scripts.
They sent them and I read them.
They were quite different
to anything I'd read.
Foggy was a lovely character.
He was different to Mr Barraclough,
who dithered.
Foggy was positive.
Positively incompetent!
Steady there...
Easy...
Sneaky old Napoleon!
Ow!
We were very delighted,
may I say even proud,
when we read in the press that
the Queen's favourite TV programme
was Last Of The Summer Wine.
This brought back memories to me...
of Foggy with illusions
as the royal corgi walker
to Her Majesty, the Queen!
And, one day, it's going to happen.
The phone's going to ring
and it's going to be THEM.
Them?!
The royal corgis.
On the telephone?!
Not in person, no.
You know what that means?
Sharp teeth in the ankles?
It means the royal warrant!
"By appointment" on our letterheads.
In with a chance of the OBE!
I like it!
WC Dewhurst, OBE...
Mr WC Dewhurst, OBE...
Sir Walter Dewhurst,
OBE.
Of course, privately amongst the
Household, I'll be known as Foggy.
"Has Foggy come back
with the corgis yet?" "No, ma'am."
"They've never been so healthy!"
When Brian Wilde chose to
leave the series, Michael Aldridge
joined us, happily,
and played Seymour and, again,
put us straight back on track.
The door remains closed to
strange voices, even when they are
in possession of the codeword.
The reason is, of course,
that a person's voice print
is as distinctive
as a set of fingerprints.
This genius little beauty
which simple justice
demands should make a bob or two.
It is programmed to obey the
commands of his master's voice only.
I don't care who stands shouting
at this door, it'll never answer.
Codfingers!
You have to
get the pitch exactly right!
Codfingers!
HE VARIES THE PITCH
Codfingers! ..Codfingers!
..Codfingers!
C-od-fin-gers...
Codfingers!
It's me, you stupid door!
One of the great reasons
for the change of direction
in Last Of The Summer Wine
from less film to more film was
the arrival, many years ago now,
of the still current producer,
Alan Bell.
Alan is, by instinct,
a film man
and quietly behind the scenes,
whether we realised it or not,
the moment he arrived,
we moved towards more film.
When we were doing
Uncle Of The Bride, the episode
that introduced Michael Aldridge -
he played the uncle -
we had the scene where we were
leaving his house and going
to the church for the wedding.
Everything was ready. The house
'and the lovely pond beside it,
'the car with the camera mounted
on it, and I was to be driving.'
Put her in reverse!
Unfortunately,
Peter got a little over-excited.
It was probably the thrill of it
all. Or he forgot what he was doing!
He put his foot hard down on that
accelerator and we backed, boy,
right into the middle of that pond!
The car began to sink.
The water was coming in all through
the doors and we were sinking.
Then a voice was heard
from the director.
"Save the camera!"
I replied.
I can't tell you what I said.
The BBC don't allow it.
Even then, when we got on the shore,
he said, "That was wonderful!
We'll do it again in a long shot."
He turned to us. We weren't there.
We were in our caravan.
He got the shot, but not with us.
Here we go, then.
ENGINE REVVES
BUBBLING
Well, you said reverse...
Hi. This, you see,
is the inside of the cafe,
where we've had many an incident
with the tin tray.
Like the other sets, it's been made
in the film studios at Shepperton.
It's through this that I used to
keep my eye on the customers.
See they behaved themselves!
It's in here I played
many a romantic scene with
that marvellous actor, John Comer.
Do you remember?
He played my husband, Sid.
Open it carefully!
I am!
I don't want it scratching before we
start. You started already!
You can't dig in with a screwdriver!
Pass me something sharp -
like your tongue!
Will it work? In my experience of
technology, it doesn't always work.
I thought that were men.
First electricity, then electronics.
My Barry's most accomplished
on his mobile.
There's no need to tell everybody!
We established a pattern first,
I think, of, in odd episodes,
having a guest character appear
as a one-off and then disappear.
And this worked very well.
But some come and are so attractive
you're reluctant to let them go.
'For instance, Thora Hird.'
Start the engine.
Clutch down.
Into first gear.
Into first gear...
GEARS CRUNCH
Final check in the mirror.
The mirror...
Handbrake off,
clutch out and gently accelerate.
Handbrake off, clutch out
and gently accelerate...
ENGINE ROARS AND GEARS CRUNCH
Sometimes, she does that...
ENGINE ROARS
Sometimes, she does that!
I still look at her on screen
and think of the Thora
I sat in the cinemas watching,
or the theatres watching,
and it's a great,
warm feeling for me
to think I closed that circle
between being a fan and being
involved with a professional.
It's been a great pleasure.
The funny thing about it
is when I'm stopped in the street,
it's always about something simple.
You know without me telling you.
People laugh at things THEY do.
And when I put newspapers down
for Wesley to step on,
the number of women who stop me
in places like food stores
and say, "When you put the papers
down! I did that as a child."
Did you want me?
Alan Bell, our producer-director,
was very clever. Very lucky.
He managed to get
hold of Gordon Wharmby, who was
a wonderful character actor,
to play the part of Wesley Pegden,
who was married to Edie.
Between the two of them,
that is Wesley and Edie,
they gave us some interesting
insights into marital bliss.
What are you looking at?
I am just making sure that,
under all that grime,
I am not talking to a stranger!
I'm busy. What is it?
When are you going to
fix that dripping tap?
I fixed it first thing this morning.
Now you're acting like a stranger!
I've got to go. I'm onto something
up at the shed. It'll be terrific.
Don't forget where you live!
I shan't forget.
It's the only house in the street
with paper on the floor(!)
Everyone will remember Thora Hird's
scenes in Last Of The Summer Wine
as some of the funniest. I'll
remember her as a fine professional.
Michael Aldridge, for family
reasons, had to leave the programme
and we were lucky
to get Brian Wilde to come back
and get us involved
in some more Foggy escapades.
Are we ready, then?
Ready!
I think so.
I told you I'd get us out.
..We're ready.
Off you go!
Oh, Howard...
Oh, Marina...
Oh, 'eck!
What I particularly like
is the development
of this eternal triangle,
because, hopefully, the way that
we play it doesn't make it tacky.
It could be tacky,
but the director makes sure it isn't
because we play it for comedy.
Everybody knows that Howard's
not going to do anything.
But what I like, as Pearl,
is just knowing enough
to present him
with just that little threat.
I didn't know Norman Clegg
was one for the women!
It's always a surprise, isn't it,
who's a one for the women?
I keep telling you, love.
I don't know how the note got there.
I think it was planted on me.
Mmm...
I must have enemies.
There's me, for a start.
One of the exciting things
about each year's
batch of new scripts
is to find out
where Howard and Marina will meet.
We do meet in some wonderful places.
Ah! A-ah!
'There was one episode where
Compo had a home-made submarine...'
It's so difficult to find places
where you can REALLY be alone.
I know.
I think you've cracked it here,
Howard.
I have, haven't I?
Sheer genius...
If only we had a bigger boat!
If only...
Still, as long as we are alone...
My God!
It's Pearl in a submarine!
I was delighted to be asked
to do a Christmas show.
The following year, I did another.
Two years later, I was thrilled
when they said, "Would you be
a permanent character?"
Two years later, I was thrilled
when they said, "Would you be
a permanent character?"
'And it's such fun to be in.'
Time-wasters!
"Could they have a look round?"
"Course," I said,
but it's a different game
when you charge a shilling!
You'd think you were asking
for the earth! I suppose
you'd all like a nice cup of tea?
ALL: Oh, aye!
That'll be 10p each!
One of the problems we had
was finding the right location
for Auntie Wainwright's shop.
We were lucky. We stumbled
on just the right thing.
It was a period shop
and looked absolutely right.
And so we filmed it,
and it was great.
Unfortunately,
when we came back a year later...
..it was somebody's house!
But our inventive designer,
Stefan Paxi, solved the problem.
He simply built a facade of a shop
and bolted it
onto the front of the house.
For obvious reasons,
the camera can't show you
what is actually inside the house.
Since I came to this programme,
I've met so many people
I've admired for so many years.
And one, in particular is... He's
dear Danny O'Dea who plays Eli.
He creases me every time
he opens his mouth!
Eli!
Listen.
What's up?
Lend us a quid.
No problem!
No problem at all...
Ely!
CRASHING
They want to put something
round these holes!
The contribution of the music
to the series...
..has got to be recognised.
Firstly, it's got to be recognised
what a ground-breaker this was
at its time, 25 years ago.
Sitcom music was funny music,
more or less declaring, "Watch me,
this is going to be funny."
Who'd have expected the beautiful
melody that Ronnie came up with
for Last Of The Summer Wine?
MUSIC:
"Last Of The Summer Wine"
'And with the larger orchestra,
the Summer Wine theme
'was given
an extraterrestrial feel.'
Me brakes have gone!
Help!
Ah!
Ohh...
Welcome to Earth!
It makes you wonder
what sort of planet they come from!
Stars appearing in the series
for the odd episode -
very satisfying.
Very pleasurable for me,
in terms of people like Ron Moody.
I wasn't in the business
when I saw Oliver and that
wonderful performance as Fagin.
Then, it's almost the completion
of a little dream
when you see someone like Ron Moody
appearing in a major part,
even if it's only in one episode,
it's very pleasurable.
I have this weak heart.
Weak heart?!
Yes, I'm afraid my life is dated,
circumscribed by the palpitations
of a faulty ticker.
I have the satisfaction
of knowing that I overstrained it
in the service of humanity,
but you can understand why I
couldn't risk hunting for treasure.
I couldn't stand the excitement.
What about the barmaid?
It wasn't like that.
The good woman merely reminded me
of the lady...
who was once my wife.
LOUD SNORT
RESOUNDING CHORDS
When Alan Bell said, "Cut!",
which is the end of the scene,
and he rushed over,
"Are you all right, Norman?"
I looked up at him,
"Yeah, I think... Course I am!"
Sometimes you do hurt yourself,
but I think of the money
and I'm all right!
Just before I started filming,
I picked up a minor ailment
which would stop me filming.
They had to recast
and I suggested Frank Thornton.
I remember Alan Bell was talking
to me on the phone. I was in
the kitchen. I can see it all now.
He said, "It's a great pity about
Brian Wilde having to leave us,
"but we've managed
to get Frank Thornton."
And I said, "Spot on!"
Stay calm! I'm on my way.
If there are any smokers down there,
this is not a good time!
Just stay there!
I'm coming down no-o-ow!
Oops!
Is this yours?!
I was only due
to make about six episodes
as a sort of temporary stand-in
for Brian.
But due to the fragmented nature of
filming - a bit here, a bit there -
and problems
with Brian's availability,
it was impossible for him to come
back and I made all 11 episodes.
Leave this with me.
I can handle policemen.
In two minutes,
they'll be asking for autographs.
Now, then, constables.
It's your lucky day.
How often do you meet
Truly of the Yard?
Thou made a big impression there(!)
They've been up all night.
They're in a bad mood.
I have been invited to go back.
Perhaps one day I will. I'm relieved
not to have to climb those hills!
'In 1999, when we were filming
the millennium special,
we were in France.'
What's this, then?
Your coffee.
I ordered a drink, not a bath!
Where's the basin?
'Bill confided in me that he wasn't
feeling very well.'
And when we got back to England,
I insisted that he get in touch
with a specialist, which he did.
And, sadly, he was diagnosed
to have terminal cancer.
Bill wanted to finish filming.
He wouldn't give up.
We only got him
for the location scenes
shot in Yorkshire.
We then had the problem
of having £1.5 million-worth
of unfinished programming,
so I was forced to take liberties
with the script, put doubles in
and take scenes of Bill that were
shot earlier and electronically
drop them into the finished films.
I think we got away with it.
I don't think anyone noticed.
We were able to see Bill
in his final performance.
MUSIC: Final notes of "Taps"
Those of us who were connected
with the programme, most of us,
thought that that was the end
of Last Of The Summer Wine.
And then, quite extraordinarily,
Roy Clarke, our author,
wrote,
in the passage of three weeks,
three episodes
which he called
Elegy For Fallen Wellies.
They were the most touching,
the most moving,
most hilarious programmes
that I've ever seen on television!
# ..Start by admitting
From cardle to tomb
# It isn't that long a stay
# Life is a cabaret, old chum
# Only a cabaret, old chum
# And I love
# A cabare-e-e-et! #
Once again, gals. From the top!
'Nora in fishnet tights
'had proved too much for Compo.'
I wonder what put the smile
on his face.
Never you mind!
'The final scene with 200 pairs
of painter's overalls
'broke all records for letters
from viewers to the BBC...' There!
'..saying how touched they were.'
See ya, Compo.
Bill Owen had made Compo into
one of TV's most popular characters.
I thought, "How can they
replace the irreplaceable
No-one would have accepted
another actor playing Compo,
but Alan and Roy
came up with the idea
of having Bill's real-life son Tom
playing Compo's long-lost son Tom.
I'm looking for
a Mr William Simmonite.
Now's your chance. Tell him.
Father!
Oh, no! Not me!
'The problem was solved!
We had a link with dear old Bill.'
I recognise the ears!
Daddy!
I'm not your daddy.
I'm a retired policeman!
Some years ago, Stephen Lewis
joined for one episode
to play a man in hospital,
but he was so well liked
that it was decided, eventually,
to keep him on as a regular.
'He's provided hours
and hours of unsmiling pleasure.'
I want you to judge the performance.
See if you can see the lips moving.
My name is Waldo. A funny thing
happened on the way to the kennel.
What are you waiting for?
To hear what the funny thing was
on the way to the kennel.
I haven't written it yet!
Did my lips move?
Yes! He was moving his lips
all the time.
Not him, me!
Did you see MY lips move?
I wasn't watching your lips.
HE was the one that was speaking!
And a few years earlier, Billy
Hardcastle had joined our company.
'Billy Hardcastle,
distant relative of Robin Hood,
played by Keith Clifford.'
It will penetrate steel, will this.
I'm really going to enjoy this.
Somebody keep that sheriff quiet!
On my sitcoms, even though now
we do Summer Wine
entirely all on film,
we still show that finished film
to an invited audience
and we record their laughter.
The BBC go to
some considerable trouble to ensure
the audience have a good night out.
# U make my life complete
V means you're VERY sweet
# W-X-Y-Z... #
I don't like to see the shows going
out without hearing any laughter.
It alters the atmosphere
completely.
I don't want canned laughter, but
I don't want no laughter at all.
I enjoyed it. People don't think it
is for young people. I think it is.
It's the best show on the air!
Worth the licence fee.
Wonderful. It really was...
Wonderful!
And what of the future?
Who would have thought that we
would have happened upon a Chinese
electrical engineer from Hull?!
What's your name?
It's on the van.
Electrical?!
Entwistle!
Don't think I'm being nosey,
just because I am,
but how come
you've got a name like Entwistle?
I changed my name, didn't I?
From McIntyre. I was forever
being mistaken for a Scot!
What are you, then?
A Yorkshireman, what else?!
TRANSLATION:
Now I will interpret.
I am delighted to be doing
Last Of The Summer Wine.
And what of poor old Nora Batty?
She never thought
she'd wake up one morning
and find an Alvin living next door
to her in Compo's old house.
What's he smiling at?
You do me good, love.
Reminds me I used to be married to
one of them. Can't believe me luck!
I have watched
Last Of The Summer Wine,
man and boy, for 30 years.
It is a great pleasure and privilege
to be asked to join the company,
because many of the actors
are old colleagues and friends.
But I have to tell you
that for many years I had
a dragon of a wife called Mildred.
It is with great trepidation that
I am going to have to face up to
an even bigger dragon in Nora Batty.
Just in time for tea, ladies!
You'll have us all on fire.
I don't think you'd burn,
old asbestos breeches!
If it begins to slide,
then it wants burying peacefully,
with great fondness,
but if the audience
is still out there,
I'd love to do another one.
Subtitles by BBC - 2003