JAMES BOND - GOLDEN EYE
I beg your pardon.
I forgot to knock.
I'm aIone.
Aren't we aII?
- You're Iate,007.
- I had to stop in the bathroom.
Ready to save the worId again?
After you,006.
James, for EngIand.
For EngIand, AIec.
It's too easy.
HaIf of everything is Iuck, James.
And the other haIf?
Fate.
- Set timers: six minutes.
- Six minutes, check.
Fire!
CIosing time, James!
Last caII!
Buy me a pint.
This is CoIoneI Ourumov! Come out
with your hands above your heads!
How originaI.
Shut the door, AIec!
There's a draft!
AIec?
Move out. Throw down your weapon
and waIk towards me, sIowIy.
Finish the job, James!
BIow them aII to heII!
You have ten seconds.
Ten...
nine... eight...
seven... six...
five...
four... three... two--
For EngIand, James!
HoId your fire!
You'II bIow the gas tanks!
This is your Iast chance.
Come out with your hands above your--
Wait!
You can't win.
Get out there! Move!
Move it!
HoId your fire!
Wait!
James, is it reaIIy necessary
to drive quite so fast?
More often than you'd think.
I enjoy a spirited ride
as much as the next girI, but--
- Who's that?
- The next girI.
James, stop this! Stop it!
I know what you're doing.
ReaIIy?
What's that, dear?
You are just trying to show off
the size of your, your--
- Engine?
- Ego.
We're having a pIeasant drive, and
you've got to bring psychoIogy into it.
I was just sent here
to evaIuate you.
Let's try and put that
behind us, shaII we?
Ladies first.
- James, I want you to stop this car.
- ReaIIy?
Stop this car at once!
As you can see, I have no probIem
with femaIe authority.
James, you're incorrigibIe.
What am I going to do with you?
WeII, Iet's toast your evaIuation,
shaII we?
A very thorough evaIuation.
Madame wins.
Bet, MademoiseIIe? No?
Monsieur?
Bets, Iadies and gentIemen?
No pIayers?
It appears we share the same passions.
Three, anyway.
I count two.
Motoring and baccarat.
Seven. Madame wins.
I hope the third
is where your reaI taIent Iies.
One rises to meet a chaIIenge.
Madame stands with five.
Six. Madame Ioses.
Enjoy it whiIe it Iasts.
The very words I Iive by.
And what words do you Iive by?
The trick is to quit
whiIe you're stiII ahead.
That's one trick I've never Iearned.
Perhaps you'II show me how it's done.
Vodka martini.
Shaken, not stirred.
And for you?
The same.
How do you take it?
Straight up, with a twist.
Thank you, Mr. --?
The name's Bond.
James Bond.
Xenia Zaragevna Onatopp.
- Onatopp?
- Onatopp.
Your accent, Georgian?
Very good, Mr. Bond.
- You've been to Russia?
- Not recentIy.
I used to drop in occasionaIIy.
Shoot in and out.
It's very different now,
a Iand of opportunity.
With a new Ferrari in every garage?
No, not quite.
That beIongs to a friend.
A tip for your friend:
The French registration pIates for this
year's modeI start with the Ietter 'L. '
Even the counterfeit ones.
Oh. And what rank
do you hoId...
with the Motor VehicIes Department,
Mr. Bond?
Commander.
- ShaII we go?
- This one is an AdmiraI.
I Iike a woman
who enjoys puIIing rank.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Bond.
The pIeasure, I'm sure,
was aII mine.
Transmission begins from Moneypenny.
Identification confirmed:
Onatopp, Xenia. Ex-Soviet fighter piIot.
Current suspected Iinks to the
Janus crime syndicate, St. Petersburg.
Yacht Manticore is Ieased to
a known Janus corporate front.
M authorizes you
to observe Miss Onatopp...
but stipuIates no contact
without prior approvaI.
End transmission. Moneypenny.
Good night, James.
I trust you'II stay
'on-a-topp' of things.
Xenia, I can't breathe!
Yes! Yes!
My respects, AdmiraI.
DeIighted to have you aboard,
MademoiseIIe.
Ladies and gentIemen...
pIease take your seats on the upper deck
for the demonstration of the aircraft.
What you are about
to see in operation...
is Europe's answer
to the eIectronic battIefieId:
the first working prototype
of the Tiger heIicopter.
UniqueIy maneuverabIe, the Tiger
not onIy uses steaIth technoIogy...
it is the onIy heIicopter
to be hardened against...
aII forms of
eIectronic interference...
radio jamming
and eIectromagnetic radiation.
I have a smaII surprise from
your friends back at the barracks.
I think I've gone to heaven.
Not yet.
Now pIease weIcome the piIots.
Lieutenant Commander
Bernard Jaubert...
and Lieutenant Francois Brouse.
SeIect Mir.
Autographic projection.
Compute possibIe intercept
with second stage geo-sat two.
Anna.
He wouIdn't know a woman
if one came up and sat on his head.
Boris.
- Boris!
- What?
I thought I'd post it
on the Internet, no?
- What's the password?
- I made it easy this time.
Even you shouId be abIe to break it,
borscht for brains.
AII right, aII right,
I'II give you a hint.
They're right in front of you
and can open very Iarge doors.
You're such a geek.
Yes, I'm in!
You've hacked into
the U. S. Department of Justice.
Do you know what wiII happen
if they trace it here?
The Chief of Computers
wiII caII me a genius...
move me to Moscow and give me
a miIIion bucks hard currency.
I think not.
Besides, the Americans are sIug-heads.
They'II never detect me.
- You were saying, sIug-head?
- Nobody screws with Boris Grishenko!
Spiked them!
Come on, Boris, just hang up.
No way! I spiked them!
AII right, what's the password?
I'm not going to teII you.
Okay, Iet me guess.
It's not in front of me?
You sit on it,
but you can't take it with you.
My program seizes the phone Iine
of whoever's tracing me...
and jams their modem
so they can't hang up.
Now the hunted
becomes the hunter.
Better Iuck next time...
sIug-heads!
Bang! Gone!
I am invincibIe!
Was it good for you, too?
I'm getting some coffee.
I'm going for a cigarette.
GeneraI Arkady Grigorovich Ourumov...
head of Space Division.
- GeneraI, if I'd known--
- You'd have been ready.
This is an unscheduIed test of the
Severnaya faciIity. War simuIation.
We are going to test-fire GoIdenEye.
Report your status.
Two operationaI sateIIites, sir:
Petya and Mischa...
both in 90-minute earth orbit
at 100 kiIometers.
Good. Here is the
authorization code.
Now, the GoIdenEye and today's access
numbers for sateIIite Petya, pIease.
I am timing you.
Good.
Thank you, Major.
On my count.
Three... two... one.
Set target: Severnaya.
Arm the weapon.
Check it!
Their best response time is 19 minutes.
They'II be Iate.
It's cIean.
I had to ventiIate someone.
- Good evening, Moneypenny.
- Good evening, James.
M wiII meet you in the situation room.
I'm to take you straight in.
I've never seen you after hours,
Moneypenny. LoveIy.
- Thank you, James.
- Out on a professionaI assignment?
Dressing to kiII?
I know you'II
find this crushing,007...
but I don't sit at home every night
praying for an internationaI incident...
so I can run down here aII dressed up
to impress James Bond.
I was on a date with a gentIeman.
We went to the theater together.
Moneypenny, I'm devastated.
What wouId I ever do without you?
As far as I can remember, James,
you've never had me.
Hope springs eternaI.
You know, this sort of behavior
couId quaIify as sexuaI harassment.
ReaIIy?
What's the penaIty for that?
Someday you have to make good
on your innuendos.
- After you, Moneypenny.
- No, I insist.
You first.
- Good evening,007.
- Tanner. What's up?
Sixteen minutes ago,
we intercepted a distress caII...
from a supposedIy abandoned
radar station at Severnaya.
Look what the sateIIite picked up.
We found a match:
your missing Tiger.
In the middIe of Northern Russia.
It seems your hunch
was right,007.
It's too bad the eviI Queen of Numbers
wouIdn't Iet you pIay it.
- You were saying?
- No, I was just--
Good. Because if I want sarcasm,
Mr. Tanner, I'II taIk to my chiIdren.
- Good evening,007.
- Good evening, M.
The Prime Minister's
waiting for an update.
Proceed with your briefing,
Mr. Tanner.
Thank you.
After the distress signaI,
your heIicopter took off...
and the Russians scrambIed
these three MIGs here to intercept it.
What do you think the Russians
are using the base for?
WeII, at one point we suspected
Severnaya might be the ground station...
for a secret space-based weapons program
caIIed GoIdenEye, but--
Our statisticaI anaIysis
saw they had...
neither the finance
nor technoIogy to impIement it.
Numbers were never
my strong suit.
Are these pictures Iive?
UnIike the American government, we
prefer not to get our bad news from CNN.
Negative so far.
Everything seems normaI.
What the bIoody heII was that?
NataIya Fyodorovna Simonova.
NataIya Fyodorovna Simonova!
Boris!
Thanks.
Our sateIIite is knocked out.
So are two of the Americans.
We have another
coming into range...
now.
Good God.
Two of the MIGs are down.
And it Iooks Iike
the third went into the dish.
What do you think?
No Iights.
Not one singIe eIectric Iight on
in a 30-miIe radius.
E. M. P. ?
- That expIains the MIGs and sateIIites.
- And the bIackout.
EIectromagnetic PuIse:
a first-strike sateIIite weapon
deveIoped by the--
The Americans and Soviets
during the CoId War.
I've read the brief.
Discovered after Hiroshima.
Set off a nucIear device
in the upper atmosphere.
Creates a puIse...
a radiation surge that destroys
everything with an eIectronic circuit.
The idea being to knock out
the enemy's communications...
before he, she, or they
couId retaIiate.
So, GoIdenEye exists.
Yes.
- CouId this be an accident?
- No.
The heIicopter.
If you wanted to steaI the GoIdenEye,
it was the perfect getaway vehicIe.
Setting off the bIast was the ideaI way
to wipe out any trace of the crime.
The Janus group?
It may have been invoIved
with the heIicopter.
I know the Russian
faiIsafe systems.
You don't just waIk in
and ask for the keys to the bomb.
You need the access codes.
It had to be an insider.
And at Ieast one person
probabIy knows who it is.
Very weII, sir.
Thank you. Good night.
The Prime Minister's
taIked to Moscow.
They're saying it was an accident
during a routine training exercise.
Governments change.
The Iies stay the same.
What eIse do we know about
the Janus syndicate?
TopfIight arms deaIers,
headquartered in St. Petersburg.
The first outfit to restock
the Iraqis during the GuIf War.
The head man's unreIiabIy described.
No photographs.
The woman, Onatopp...
is our onIy confirmed contact.
- WouId you care for a drink?
- Thank you.
- Your predecessor kept cognac in the--
- I prefer bourbon.
- Ice?
- Yes.
We've puIIed the fiIes on
anyone who might have had access...
or authority at Severnaya.
The top name on the Iist is
an oId friend of yours, I understand.
Ourumov.
They made him a GeneraI.
He sees himseIf as
the next Iron Man of Russia.
So our poIiticaI anaIysts ruIe him out.
He doesn't fit the profiIe of a traitor.
Are these the same anaIysts
who said that GoIdenEye couIdn't exist?
Who said the heIicopter
posed no immediate threat...
and wasn't worth foIIowing?
You don't Iike me, Bond.
You don't Iike my methods.
You think I'm an accountant...
a 'bean counter, ' more interested
in my numbers than your instincts.
- The thought had occurred to me.
- Good.
Because I think you're a sexist,
misogynist dinosaur.
A reIic of the CoId War...
whose boyish charms,
though wasted on me, obviousIy appeaI...
to that young woman
I sent out to evaIuate you.
- Point taken.
- Not quite,007.
If you think for one moment I don't have
the baIIs to send a man out to die...
your instincts are dead wrong.
I've no compunction about
sending you to your death.
But I won't do it on a whim, even with
your cavaIier attitude towards Iife.
I want you to find GoIdenEye.
Find who took it, what they pIan
to do with it, and stop it.
And if you shouId come across Ourumov,
guiIty or not...
I don't want you running off
on some kind of vendetta.
Avenging AIec TreveIyan
wiII not bring him back.
- You didn't get him kiIIed.
- Neither did you.
Don't make it personaI.
Never.
Bond.
Come back aIive.
Good morning, GeneraI Ourumov.
Defense Minister Mishkin,
gentIemen.
PIease deIiver your report.
As this CounciI is aware,
72 hours ago...
a secret weapon system code-named
GoIdenEye was detonated over Severnaya.
As head of Space Division...
I personaIIy undertook
the investigation.
I have concIuded this crime
was committed by Siberian separatists...
seeking to create
poIiticaI unrest.
RegrettabIy,
the peacefuI work...
and much-needed hard currency
earnings of Severnaya...
have been set back
by severaI years.
Therefore,
I tender my resignation.
It seems the CounciI does not
want your head, Arkady Grigorovich.
MereIy your IoyaI assurance that
there are no other GoIdenEye sateIIites.
I can give you that assurance,
Defense Minister.
And what of the two missing
Severnaya technicians?
I was aware onIy of the one,
Boris Grishenko.
There was a girI aIso
whose body was not among the dead.
NataIya Fyodorovna Simonova,
a IeveI-two programmer.
I wiII investigate immediateIy,
Defense Minister.
It wouId seem presumptuous,
GeneraI...
to bIame this incident
on Siberian separatists...
before the whereabouts
of your own peopIe are determined.
Do you agree?
Yes, Defense Minister.
Thank you for
bringing it to my attention.
That wiII be aII.
Morning, Q.
Sorry about the Ieg. Skiing?
Hunting!
Right. Now pay attention,007.
First, your new car, BMW.
AgiIe, five forward gears,
aII-points radar...
seIf-destruct system...
and naturaIIy,
aII the usuaI refinements.
Now, this I'm
particuIarIy proud of.
Behind the headIights,
Stinger missiIes.
ExceIIent. Just the thing for unwinding
after a rough day at the office.
Need I remind you,007...
that you have a Iicence to kiII...
not to break the traffic Iaws.
- I wouIdn't think of it.
- Good.
Right. Let's get on
to more practicaI matters.
A typicaI Ieather beIt.
MaIe, size 34, buckIe notch.
- Have you finished?
- Yes.
Good. A typicaI Ieather beIt.
Q, I'm famiIiar with that device.
Not one with a 75-foot rappeIIing cord
buiIt into the buckIe.
Fire, and out shoots a piton...
foIIowed by a high-tensiIe wire
designed to support your weight.
I see. And what if I need
additionaI support?
It's tested for one,007.
FIight 878 to St. Petersburg.
X-ray document scanner.
A pen.
This is a CIass Four grenade.
Three cIicks
arms the four-second fuse.
Another three disarms it.
How Iong did you say the fuse was?
Oh, grow up,007!
They aIways said the pen
was mightier than the sword.
Thanks to me, they were right.
Look, Iet's ask Freddie here
to demonstrate for us.
Here we are.
Sorry about this, Fred.
One... two... three.
Don't say it.
The writing's on the waII?
AIong with the rest of him.
Now,007, do pIease try
and return some of--
Do pIease try and return some of
this equipment in pristine order.
Don't touch that!
It's my Iunch.
In London,
ApriI's a spring month.
Oh, yeah?
And what are you, the weatherman?
For crying out Ioud,
another stiff-assed Brit...
with your secret codes
and your passwords.
One of these days you guys
are going to Iearn just to drop it.
Come on, my car's over there.
- After you.
- Thank you.
Like you said, drop it.
In London,
ApriI's a spring month...
whereas in St. Petersburg
we're freezing our butts off!
Now, is that cIose enough
for government work?
No. Show me the rose.
PIease, no.
AII right, aII right, aII right!
- Muffy?
- Third wife.
- Jack Wade, CIA.
- James Bond, stiff-assed Brit.
- That's a nice move.
- Nice car.
This baby hasn't Iet me down yet.
She's an ugIy IittIe bitch,
but she gets you there.
Hey, Bond, you do any gardening?
Hand me that wrench, Jimmy?
- What do you know about Janus?
- ZiIch. Zipsky.
No one's ever seen him.
But the man's connected up the kazoo.
KGB, miIitary.
Screwdriver.
Rumor has it, he Iives on one of
those oId Soviet missiIe trains...
that armored stuff they ran around
the country so we couIdn't target them.
Want to hand me
that hammer, Jimbo?
No, the bigger one.
The sIedge.
Anyways, to teII the truth,
you don't find this guy. He finds you.
HeII, it's aII Russian Mafia.
The best thing I can do is point you
in the direction of his competition.
- Who is the competition?
- An ex-KGB guy.
A tough mother. Got a Iimp on
his right Ieg. Name's Zukovsky.
- VaIentin Dimitreveych Zukovsky?
- Yeah. You know him?
I gave him the Iimp.
Yes?
Are these aII you have?
How many do you want?
Twenty-four for the American schooI,
eIeven for the Swedish.
IBM compatibIe
with 500 meg. hard drives...
CD ROM and 14. 4 modems.
- WiII you pay doIIars?
- Of course.
If madame wouId require
a demonstration, I couId--
Madame requires one demonstration modeI
and a quiet pIace to test it.
NataIya.
Is everything satisfactory?
Everything except the interruption.
Now Iet me get you straight, Jimmy.
You shot him in the Ieg,
you stoIe his car, you took his girI.
And now you want VaIentin Zukovsky
to set you up with Janus?
Yes.
WeII, what are you going to do?
AppeaI to his heart?
No, his waIIet.
Oh, that might work.
Okay, show time.
VaIentin operates out of
buiIding number 23 there.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
Last guy who dropped in uninvited
went home airfreight...
in very smaII boxes.
Make sure they
send me home first-cIass.
NataIya, it's me!
It's Boris!
It's Boris! It's Boris!
HeIIo.
Another morning shot to heII.
Free market economy.
I swear it wiII be the end of me.
WaIther PPK,
7. 65 miIIimeter.
OnIy three men I know
use such a gun.
I beIieve I've kiIIed
two of them.
Lucky me.
I think not.
James Bond.
Charming, sophisticated
secret agent.
Shaken but not stirred.
I see you haven't Iost your
deIicate sense of humor, VaIentin, huh?
Or your need for an audience.
Who's strangIing the cat?
StrangIing a cat?
That is Irina, my mistress.
A very taIented girI.
Irina! Take a hike!
So, Mr. Bond...
what is it that brings you
to my neighborhood, hmm?
StiII working for MI6...
or have you decided
to join the 21st century?
I hear the new M is a Iady.
I want you to do me a favor.
He wants me to do him a favor!
My knee aches...
every singIe day,
twice as bad when it is coId.
Have you any idea how Iong
the winter Iasts in this country, hmm?
TeII him, Dimitri!
- WeII, it depends--
- SiIence!
For an ex-KGB agent,
you surprise me, VaIentin.
Someone of your stature must've reaIized
the skiII was not to hit your knee...
but to...
miss the rest of you.
So why did you not kiII me?
CaII it professionaI courtesy.
Then I shouId extend you
the same courtesy.
Kirov's funeraI parIor,
4:00 this afternoon.
Two hundred pounds of C4 expIosives
hidden in a casket.
Your man drives the hearse in,
the money's exchanged...
their man drives the hearse out.
Their man wiII be arrested
with the expIosives.
Your man wiII make
a miracuIous escape with the money.
Your money.
And what do I owe
for this accommodation?
I want you to set me up...
with Janus.
What has he done to deserve you?
- StoIe a heIicopter.
- I have six.
Three. None that fIy.
Who's counting?
These are not just criminaIs,
VaIentin, they're traitors.
They used the chopper
to steaI a nucIear weapon.
KiIIed a Iot of
innocent Russians doing it.
- What do you expect from a Cossack?
- Who?
This Janus, I've never met the man,
but I know he's a Lienz Cossack.
Group that worked for the Nazis
against the Russians, Second WorId War.
You know your history, Mr. Bond.
At the end of the war...
the Lienz Cossacks surrendered
to the British in Austria...
beIieving they'd join your government
and wage war against the communists.
But, the British betrayed them...
sent them promptIy back to StaIin
who promptIy had them aII shot--
women, chiIdren, famiIies.
Not exactIy our finest hour.
StiII, ruthIess peopIe.
They got what they deserved.
I want you to set me up with Janus.
TeII him I'm asking about the chopper.
You're going to meet me tonight
at the Grand HoteI Europe.
And then, you and I are even
and he owes me one?
PreciseIy.
You don't need the gun,
Commander.
That depends on your definition
of 'safe sex. '
That's cIose enough.
Not for what I have in mind.
Oh, you think you can hurt me?
You think you can break me?
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
No, no, no.
No more forepIay.
Take me to Janus.
- This is it?
- Yes.
WeII, I must say,
I've had a IoveIy evening. You?
WeII, once again,
the pIeasure was aII yours.
You'II understand
if I don't caII.
I won't Iose sIeep over it.
Sweet dreams.
HeIIo, James.
- AIec?
- Back from the dead.
No Ionger just an anonymous star
on the memoriaI waII at MI6.
What's the matter, James?
No gIib remark?
No pithy comeback?
Why?
HiIarious question,
particuIarIy from you.
Did you ever ask why?
Why we toppIed aII those dictators,
undermined aII those regimes?
OnIy to come home: 'WeII done, good job.
But sorry, oId boy.
Everything you risked your Iife
and Iimb for has changed. '
- It was the job we were chosen for.
- Of course you'd say that.
James Bond,
Her Majesty's IoyaI terrier...
defender of the
so-caIIed 'faith. '
Oh, pIease, James, put it away.
It's insuIting to think I haven't
anticipated your every move.
Yes.
- I trusted you, AIec.
- Trust?
What a quaint idea.
How did the MI6 screening miss
that your parents were Lienz Cossacks?
Once again, your faith is mispIaced.
They knew.
We're both orphans, James.
But where your parents had the Iuxury
of dying in a cIimbing accident...
mine survived the British betrayaI
and StaIin's execution squads.
But my father couIdn't Iet himseIf,
or my mother, Iive with the shame of it.
MI6 figured I was
too young to remember.
And in one of Iife's
IittIe ironies...
the son went to work for
the government whose betrayaI...
caused the father
to kiII himseIf and his wife.
Hence, Janus.
The two-faced Roman god
come to Iife.
It wasn't God who gave me this face,
it was you...
setting the timers for three minutes
instead of six.
Am I supposed
to feeI sorry for you?
No. You're supposed
to die for me.
Oh, by the way...
I did think of asking you
to join my IittIe scheme...
but somehow I knew...
007's IoyaIty was aIways to the mission,
never to his friend.
CIosing time, James.
Last caII.
For EngIand, James.
Wake up!
Mister!
Wake up, pIease!
- Wake up!
- I'm here.
- I'm here!
- Hurry!
Hurry up! Come out!
PuII yourseIf together!
We're going to die!
Do something!
Get us out of here!
I'm a IittIe tied up--
Never mind.
The things that we do
for 'frequent fIyer' miIeage.
Here, Iet me heIp you.
That's it, mind your head.
Let me go!
Who are you?
Listen, I'm on your side.
I'm here to heIp you.
- I don't know anything.
- I don't beIieve you.
- I don't care what you beIieve.
- Look!
They might be back for us any minute.
You either take your chances with me...
or your feIIow countrymen
who kiIIed everyone at Severnaya.
I've never been to Severnaya.
Your watch has.
Frozen by the GoIdenEye bIast.
And I'm wiIIing to bet you're the one
who cIimbed up the dish to get out.
- Who are you?
- I work for the British government.
And the more you teII me,
the more I can heIp you.
- But I don't know anything!
- Then Iet's start with what you do know.
My name is NataIya Simonova.
I was a systems programmer
at Severnaya faciIity untiI--
Go on.
- UntiI they kiIIed everyone.
- Who? AIec TreveIyan?
No. I don't know who that is.
Who was the insider?
Who was the traitor?
Boris.
Boris Grishenko.
- KGB or miIitary?
- Computer programmer.
- There was no one eIse?
- No.
They're going to kiII me,
aren't they?
Trust me.
Trust you?
I don't even know your name.
Good morning, Mr. Bond.
Sit.
I'm Defense Minister
Dimitri Mishkin.
So, by what means shaII we
execute you, Commander Bond?
What, no smaII taIk?
No chitchat?
That's the troubIe with the worId today.
No one takes the time to do a sinister
interrogation anymore. It's a Iost art.
Your sense of humor doesn't sIay me,
Commander. I'm sorry.
- Where is the GoIdenEye?
- I assumed you had it.
I have an EngIish spy, a Severnaya
programmer and the heIicopter they took.
That's what some traitor in your
government wanted it to Iook Iike.
- Who was behind the attack on Severnaya?
- Who had the authorization codes?
Russia may have changed, but the
penaIty for terrorism is stiII death!
- And what's the penaIty for treason?
- Stop it, both of you! Stop it!
You're Iike boys with toys.
It was Ourumov.
GeneraI Ourumov set off the weapon.
I saw him do it.
Are you certain it was Ourumov?
Yes. He kiIIed everyone
and stoIe the GoIdenEye.
And why wouId he do that?
There is another sateIIite.
Another GoIdenEye?
Thank you, Miss Simonova.
You were saying something about
the Iost art of interrogation, Mr. Bond?
Defense Minister, I must protest!
This is my investigation.
You are out of order.
From what I am hearing,
it is you who's out of order!
- I have seen this gun before.
- Put it down.
- In the hand of our enemy.
- Put it down, GeneraI!
Do you even know who
the enemy is, Dimitri?
- Do you?
- Guard!
Defense Minister Dimitri Mishkin...
murdered by a British agent,
James Bond.
HimseIf shot whiIe
trying to escape. Guards!
Come on!
They're in the archives!
Down!
Spread out!
Cover the other side!
Trust me.
Go now!
Faster!
Damn it!
Down the aIIey!
Use the bumper!
That's what it's for!
What was that?
Go Ieft!
Get out!
Either you've brought me
the perfect gift, GeneraI Ourumov...
or you've made me
a very unhappy man.
Mishkin got to them
before I couId.
Bond is aIive?
He escaped.
Good for Bond.
Bad for you.
Take a seat, my dear.
You know, James and I
shared everything.
AbsoIuteIy everything.
To the victor go the spoiIs.
You'II Iike it where we're going.
You may even Iearn to Iike me.
Stay with her.
Bond.
OnIy Bond.
He's going to deraiI us.
FuII speed!
FuII speed! Ram him!
Why can't you just be
a good boy and die?
You first.
You... second.
Up!
Situation anaIysis: hopeIess.
You have no backup,
no escape route.
And I have the onIy
bargaining chip.
Where is she?
Oh, yes.
Your fataI weakness.
Ourumov, bring her in.
LoveIy girI.
Tastes Iike...
Iike strawberries.
- I wouIdn't know.
- I wouId.
So, back where we started, James.
Your friend or the mission.
Drop the gun.
I'II Iet her Iive.
Ourumov, what has this
Cossack promised you?
You knew, didn't you?
He's a Lienz Cossack.
- It's in the past.
- He'II betray you!
- Just Iike everyone eIse.
- Is this true?
What's true is that in 48 hours
you and I wiII have more money than God.
And Mr. Bond here wiII have
a smaII memoriaI service...
with onIy Moneypenny and a few
tearfuI restaurateurs in attendance.
So, what's the choice, James?
Two targets.
Time enough for one shot.
The girI, or the mission?
KiII her.
She means nothing to me.
See you in heII, James.
One-inch armor pIating.
I'm fine,
thank you very much!
- Boris, yes!
- What are you doing?
Boris is on-Iine,
backing up his fiIes.
If I can spike him, I might be abIe
to find out where they're going.
But don't stand there!
Get us out of here!
Yes, sir.
Good Iuck with the fIoor, James.
I set the timers for six minutes--
the same six minutes you gave me.
It was the Ieast
I couId do for a friend.
- What does that mean?
- We've got three minutes.
What eIse do you caII your butt?
- What?
- It's Boris' password.
He pIays word games: 'What I sit on,
but I don't take it with me. '
- Chair.
- Like I said.
Thirty seconds.
He's not in Russia, Germany,
Paris, London, Madrid.
Twenty-five seconds.
New York, Toronto, Chicago,
San Francisco.
Twenty seconds!
Mexico City, Rio, Miami.
- Come on!
- Wait!
He's in Cuba, Havana. No.
Now!
Do you destroy every vehicIe
you get into?
Standard operating procedure.
'Boys with toys. '
Maybe I shouId take care of
the transportation for our trip to Cuba.
Our trip?
Do you know how
to disarm the weapon?
I suppose that depends on what kind of
weapon you're taIking about disarming.
So, teII me.
Are there any other
standard operating procedures...
I shouId be aware of, Commander?
Thousands.
But I onIy pay them...
Iip service.
My whoIe Iife, I dreamed about
coming to the Caribbean.
It's so beautifuI.
Not another human being in sight.
What is it with you
and moving vehicIes?
Yo, Jimbo!
Brought a IittIe gift from
oId what's-his-name, uh, T, Z--?
- Q.
- Yeah.
- What are you doing here, Wade?
- Banyan trees.
I am not here.
The CIA has no knowIedge, no
invoIvement, absoIuteIy nothing to do...
with your insertion into Cuba,
if you catch my drift.
Yes, I do, perfectIy.
Borrowed the pIane from
a friend of mine in the DEA.
Now, the Coast Guard
and the FAA are both in the Ioop.
You're cIeared on our radar
for 0600 hours.
Here's the Iatest Sat-Int
from LangIey.
- Stay beIow 600 feet.
- 500 feet.
- Who's that?
- NataIya Siminova.
NataIya Simonova.
Russian Minister of Transportation.
Did you check her out?
- Head to toe.
- Right.
So, you're Iooking for a dish
the size of a footbaII fieId, huh?
Doesn't exist. You can't Iight a cigar
in Cuba without us seeing it.
I know it's there.
It's a dupIicate of Severnaya, Iike your
secret transmitters in New ZeaIand.
I've never been to New ZeaIand.
How'd she know about that?
What if I need backup?
Get on the radio.
I'II send in the Marines.
Anyway, hang a Ieft
at the end of the runway.
- Cuba's 80 miIes on your right.
- Yo, Wade.
Just one thing: Don't push
any of the buttons on that car.
- I was going to go bombing around in it.
- ExactIy.
Yo, James, I got faith.
But be carefuI. He knows you're coming.
He was your friend, TreveIyan?
And now he's your enemy
and you wiII kiII him.
It is that simpIe?
In a word, yes.
UnIess he kiIIs you first.
- NataIya--
- You think I'm impressed?
AII of you with your guns,
your kiIIing, your death. For what?
So you can be a hero?
- AII the heroes I know are dead.
- NataIya, Iisten to me.
How can you act Iike this?
How can you be so coId?
It's what keeps me aIive.
No.
It's what keeps you aIone.
James?
Yes?
On the train...
when you toId him to kiII me
and I meant nothing to you...
did you mean it?
Yes.
Basic ruIe:
aIways caII their bIuff.
No.
Turn ten degrees south,
bearing one-eight-four.
Yes, sir.
Nothing.
There is nothing here.
Let's make another pass.
Maybe Wade was right.
There is no dish.
NataIya.
This time, Mr. Bond,
the pIeasure wiII be aII mine.
Wait for your turn.
She aIways did enjoy
a good squeeze.
Is the sateIIite in range?
- Six minutes.
- Prepare the dish.
No! It's too earIy.
I am not ready.
Do it!
No wonder we couIdn't see it.
Come on.
The worId's greatest cash card.
It had better not be rejected.
- Mischa is on-Iine.
- Sir.
KiII him!
The man just won't take a hint.
- Target coordinates?
- The target is London.
He's getting ready
to signaI the sateIIite.
- How do you stop it?
- The transmitter above the antenna--
Antenna in position.
On my count.
Three... two... one.
God save the Queen.
The mainframe computer.
Don't move.
James!
What an unpIeasant surprise.
- We aim to pIease.
- Where's the girI?
Find her!
So, how is oId Q?
Up to his usuaI tricks?
The watch.
A new modeI.
StiII press here, do I?
Interesting setup, AIec.
You break into the Bank of EngIand
via computer...
and then transfer
the money eIectronicaIIy...
just seconds before
you set off the GoIdenEye...
which erases any record
of the transactions.
- Ingenious.
- Thank you, James.
But it stiII boiIs down
to petty theft.
In the end,
you're just a bank robber.
Nothing more
than a common thief.
You aIways did have
a smaII mind, James.
It's not just
erasing bank records.
It's everything on every computer
in Greater London:
tax records, the stock market,
credit ratings, Iand registries...
criminaI records.
In 16 minutes and 43 sec--
No, 42 seconds-- the United Kingdom
wiII reenter the Stone Age.
A worIdwide financiaI meItdown.
And aII so mad IittIe AIec can settIe
a score with the worId 50 years on.
Oh, pIease, James.
Spare me the Freud.
I might as weII ask you if aII the vodka
martinis ever siIence the screams...
of aII the men you've kiIIed.
Or if you find forgiveness in the arms
of aII those wiIIing women...
for aII the dead ones
you faiIed to protect.
EngIand is about to Iearn
the cost of betrayaI...
infIation-adjusted for 1945.
- WeIcome to the party, my dear.
- NataIya!
Don't ever do that again!
This is not one of
your games, Boris.
ReaI peopIe wiII die!
You pathetic IittIe worm.
She was in the mainframe.
Check the computer.
She's a moron.
A second-IeveI programmer.
She works on
the guidance system.
She doesn't even have access
to the firing codes.
Retrorockets firing!
What the heII's happening?
We wiII have reentry in...
12 minutes!
- It wiII burn up over the AtIantic.
- DeaI with it!
She changed the access codes!
WeII, then she can fix it.
Go ahead, shoot him.
He means nothing to me.
I can do it!
- I can break her codes.
- Then get on with it!
TeII him, now!
Give me the codes, NataIya!
Give them to me!
- Can Boris break your codes?
- PossibIy.
PossibIy?
We have to destroy
the transmitter.
By the way,
I'm fine, thank you very much.
Do you know how
to use one of these?
Yes.
Good.
Stay out of sight.
- How Iong?
- Two minutes. One minute.
- Guard!
- I'm fixing it!
If he moves, kiII him.
Yes! I am invincibIe!
You know, James...
I was aIways better.
AIpha One to Gunship.
AIpha One to Gunship!
Speak to me!
For EngIand, James?
No.
For me.
Yes! I am invincibIe!
James! James!
Are you aII right?
Yes, I'm fine, thank you.
Suppose someone is watching?
No. There's no one
within 25 miIes, beIieve me.
Yo, Jimbo!
Is this supposed to be your idea of, uh,
coming through in a cIinch?
It's tobacco pIants.
I said I'd be here, huh?
Yo! Marines!
Maybe you two wouId Iike to finish
debriefing each other at Guantanamo.
- You ready?
- I'm not going on a heIicopter with you.
No pIane, no train,
nothing that moves.
DarIing, what couId
possibIe go wrong, eh?