(Heartbeat pounding)
(Panting)
(Fence clanging)
(Hodgins)
Help me!
(Brennan)
Hodgins?!
Help me!
Hodgins!
Dr. Brennan!
(Gasps)
Hodgins!
Dr. Brennan, help me!
Booth (Echoing, distorted):
Bones... Bones... Bones!
Bones!
Booth!
God!
Stay with me.
(Murmuring)
Booth!
(Pounding)
(Grunting)
(Groaning)
(Gasps)
(Yelling)
Bones!
(Pounding)
(Muffled gasping)
Bones!
(Booth shouting)
(Gasps)
(Panting)
(Screaming)
(Sinister laughter)
Help!
(Gasps)
(Panting)
(Newscaster)
The gravedigger case
finally begins today with an
evidentiary hearing.
The defendant, prominent federal
prosecutor Heather Taffet,
will be defending herself
against multiple charges
of kidnapping and murder.
One charge involves ten-year-old
Terrence Gilroy,
who has never been found.
Testimony is expected
from three kidnapping victims:
Seely Booth,
an Agent with the FBI,
as well as scientist
Jack Hodgins
and Temperance Brennan
of the Jeffers...
(Booth)
You okay, Bones?
Of course.
Why wouldn't I be?
Well, we're about
to come head to head
with the woman who
tried to kill both of us.
So are you.
Aren't you okay?
Sure. Yeah. You know,
I'm just checkin' in.
I just want to make sure
you're okay
and if you need
anything, I...
It's just
another case, Booth.
Right.
Dad!
(Booth)
Max?
What, what are you doing here?
I just thought you should have
a little support
from somebody who's been through
the legal system a few times.
Why is everyone treating me
like a child?
Because I don't want you
to get your hopes up.
This is far from a slam dunk.
(Booth)
That's exactly why
Caroline is here, all right?
We have five cases,
multiple counts:
Bones, Hodgins,
the ten-year-old boy...
whose body has never been found.
Your prosecutor's getting
desperate.
Max, she knows
what she's doing, okay?
I thought you were here
for support, dad.
Okay, you all ready
to play nice?
Always, your honor.
Your honor, since
I'm representing
myself, I'd like to request
that my shackles be removed
while I'm in court.
This is only
an evidentiary hearing,
your honor.
There's no jury to prejudice.
And frankly,
I feel a bit
more secure
with her in chains.
Spare us the dramatic
flourishes, Ms. Julian.
When we go to trial,
we can revisit the request,
Ms. Taffet.
First witness.
Burn marks were found
on the victims that were
consistent with injuries
one would sustain
from a three-million volt
stun gun.
(Booth)
The stun gun was found
in the suspect's storage locker.
It matches the stun gun
that was used
in the attack on me,
as well as...
The suspect's steel-toed boots
were also found
in the storage locker.
This storage locker was found
with information obtained
illegally, wasn't it?
(Saroyan)
We didn't know that at the time,
your honor.
We obtained a legal warrant
to search the locker.
The fact that Agent Booth's
brother gave you the lead
didn't make you suspicious?
He was an officer assigned
to homeland security.
We had no reason to question
the information he provided.
The warrant was obtained
without malice.
(Taffet)
That's irrelevant,
your honor.
Everything found in that storage locker
should be dismissed.
I submit that a warrant wasn't
even necessary.
Under precedent
of imminent danger,
law authority had the duty
to enter that storage locker
without a valid warrant.
Agent Booth's life was
in danger.
Imminent danger
applies
only if law enforcement hears
a violent threat
or struggle
at the scene.
(Judge)
I'm sorry, Ms. Julian,
but no matter how pure
the intention,
the warrant was obtained
illegally.
Therefore, any and all evidence
gathered
during the search and seizure
is inadmissible.
(Taffet) Thank you,
your honor.
(Judge) This was not a personal
favor, Ms. Taffet.
I am restrained by the law.
I'd like to move that all
charges be dropped, your honor.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
We still have dirt samples
from the crime scene,
the ransom tapes...
Your honor,
this is a waste
of the court's time
and the taxpayers' money.
If I lose, I'll send everyone
a note of apology.
You aren't left with much,
Ms. Julian.
Are you sure you want
to proceed?
(Sighs)
Yes, your honor.
Okay. The charges stand.
We're going to trial.
Court is adjourned.
(Gavel raps)
(Shackles jangling)
If you're so brilliant,
Dr. Brennan,
why couldn't you
find something
as simple as the number?
Let's go, come on.
You all right?
What'd she say to you?
She says I missed some evidence.
Evidence?
She doesn't think I can find it.
♫ Bones 5x21 ♫
The Boy With The Answer
Original Air Date on May 13, 2010
♫ Main Title Theme ♫ The Crystal Method
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
(computer trilling)
Booth is getting
her arrest records, as well as
old case files from when
she was a prosecutor.
Okay, uh, I'm pulling every
record we have so far
associated with Taffet
social security numbers,
birth dates,
blood test results.
Ages of the victims?
Got those.
I'm using
a recursive search algorithm
which analyzes
and cross-references the data.
Since they're related,
any inconsistencies can raise
a red flag.
I think Taffet is
just messing with us again.
(Sweets) No, I have
to disagree. I mean,
her pathology is
consistent;
this is all
a game to her.
She won the first round,
so now she's upping the stakes
by challenging Dr. Brennan.
Yeah, or maybe she knows there's
something in the soil samples
we already have, so she's
just trying to distract us.
You analyzed those soil samples
a hundred times.
Are you telling me
to give up, Sweets?
No, of course not.
But I mean,
I understand
the need to cling to anything...
"Cling"?
Okay, so I'm crazy now.
That's not what I meant.
Go, Dr. Hodgins.
Look at the soil again.
You might find something.
You know,
he still gets nightmares.
Says he wakes up
in a sweat.
(Sweets)
I should have been
more sensitive.
This must be difficult
for you, too.
If you need any...
I'm fine.
What about the weight
and size
of the victim's remains?
Yeah, it's a good idea.
I'll check it out.
(Clears throat)
Here are the first set
of documents you asked for.
More numbers than I've ever seen
in my life.
Right. Thanks. You okay?
Oh, you mean because
this case is a career killer?
I'm cute.
I can always find a job.
Come on. Look, they're gonna
come up with something.
They always do, right?
Do you really believe that,
cherie?
Well, they saved my life,
remember?
And that was impossible.
I'll give you that one.
So, how's your girlfriend
holding up?
She's fine.
She's not my girlfriend.
Oh, so those little looks
between you...?
Nothing.
Right.
I hope you're more believable
on the stand.
Have Angela run
these numbers
as quickly as she can.
The judge isn't gonna give me
more than a day.
(Gravedigger distorted)
if I don't receive the money
in the numbered account
within eight hours,
your child will die.
This is the last time
you will hear from me.
There will be no further
communications.
What happened to the numbers?
Well, I came up dry.
Brennan and Booth are compiling
another set.
But until then, I'm trying
to drag Taffet's voice
from these ransom tapes.
Well, any luck?
She used a variable band
inversion, so the wave is
broken up into hundreds of small
sections, each section scrambled
with different frequency
sequencing.
You didn't ask me
if I found anything new
in the soil samples.
Did you?
No, of course not.
I mean, Sweets was right.
You knew that.
I'm barely keeping it together
here, Ang.
Well, you were, uh,
you were sane enough
to marry me.
But I don't feel
strong enough
to tell anybody yet.
I feel like she's still got me
locked up, you know?
I mean, when I see her,
there's just this, um,
anger, I mean, this kind
of helplessness that...
I know, I know.
When I was buried
in that car,
I didn't think I was ever gonna
see you again.
And now I feel
like she's still in between us.
Well, she's not.
Look at me.
She's not.
Nobody can get between us.
(Murmurs)
Come on, Bones,
you've been at it for hours.
You gotta eat something.
In a little while.
Her old court documents from
when she was a prosecutor have
case numbers,
criminal code numbers,
and then there
are zip codes.
Well, that's great and all,
but you know, it's not
gonna be any good
if you starve
yourself to death.
She was laughing
at me, Booth.
I-I can't let her win.
She won't.
You hope.
She may be amoral,
but she is brilliant.
Well, you're more brilliant.
What if her dispassion
makes her more logical?
What if that gives her
an advantage over me?
Wait a second.
Now you're upset
because you're not more
like a psychopath?
I just think maybe
I've lost my advantage
because of all the people
I'm involved with now.
All of the relationships--
they complicate logical thought.
You don't mean that.
Could we please just work?
Sure.
Salt Lake City?
What?
When they arrested Taffet,
she used her one phone call
from jail to Salt Lake City.
Area Code 801.
Well, she's representing
herself,
so it couldn't be
to a lawyer.
Who would she call
in Salt Lake City?
Hmm...
(Phone line ringing)
(Woman) Larry's pizza,
how may I help you?
None of the employees
at the pizza place
have a connection
to Taffet, and...
none of them here have
any criminal records.
Well, the phone
records show
that Taffet hung up
after ten seconds.
She didn't request
another call.
Angela's matching the number
with a numerical
sequencing program.
This is the
number, Booth.
This has to be the number.
(Montenegro) So, I'm running a numerical
sequencing program to see
if there's a match
with any of her victims.
But I'm coming up
with nothing.
Oh, my God, the number is
a GPS location.
(Siren chirps)
(Booth)
Let's go, everybody out.
Oh, God.
(Booth)
(Creaking)
It's the kid, isn't it?
Terrence Gilroy had
a remodeled right ulna from
a break when he was eight.
This is the boy she kidnapped.
I'm going to call the parents.
Why did she lead
us here, Booth?
Why did she want us
to find him?
(Caroline)
Hands off!
Ma'am?
No one touches a thing.
(Alarm blaring)
What are you talking about?
This is our chance to get some
hard evidence they can't dismiss.
Not if you touch it.
You can't act as an
expert witness in a case
when you are also a victim.
We aren't victims in this crime.
We filed one complaint
with seven counts.
Since the trial started,
you and Dr. Brennan are
linked to all the crimes.
That's why Taffet wanted
us to find the boy.
She knows we're the only people
who have the skills
to connect her to the crime.
And now our hands are tied.
Not if you drop our case.
Excuse me?
If Caroline doesn't prosecute
our kidnappings,
we'd be free to testify
as expert witnesses
in the boy's case.
U'd be willing to do that?
(Hodgins)
No.
No. Caroline has to prosecute
our case--
Taffet tried to kill us.
All of our evidence
has been throw out.
The rational thing to do is to pursue
a case with fresh, untainted evidence.
Are you kidding me?!
Is it really that easy for you
to forget what happened to us?
I will never forget
what happened to us,
or to Booth, or this boy.
You are not the only
one suffering, Dr. Hodgins.
But your emotions
have no relevance--
not if we want
to convict Taffet.
(Glove snaps loudly)
This better work.
(Footsteps receding)
I'll have the charges
dismissed in the morning.
You can start right after that.
(Knocking at door)
Okay, so the Gilroy kid--
he was last seen at the
Rockland Mall on June 23.
I'm gonna check all Taffet's credit card
records for that day, too.
Caroline said you can't give
expert testimony
if she's prosecuting
your case.
I told Caroline to drop
my charges, too.
I'm not gonna let
you do this alone.
She's going to see the judge
tomorrow morning at 10:00,
and then we can dive in
on all this.
Thanks, Booth.
We're partners, it's what we do.
Right?
If Taffet is acquitted
on this count,
she can never
be tried again.
Maybe that's why she wanted us
to find the boy.
Yeah, well,
she's arrogant--
like Sweets said.
And she's misjudging you.
I have nightmares, Booth.
Hodgins is bleeding...
you're drowning...
I-I can't help anyone.
Look, all right, you know what?
She's never gonna get the
better of you, all right?
Just know that.
All right? I promise, okay?
(Brennan)
These are perimortem fractures,
bilaterally on the fifth,
sixth and seventh ribs
on the posterior axillary lines.
And injuries
to the greater cornu
and the left lateral
thyroid and cricoid cartilages.
I see injuries like this in
victims who've been strangled.
Perhaps he struggled, and Taffet
was trying to subdue him.
Taffet tasered
all her victims.
Three million volts. That should
be enough to knock out
a ten-year-old boy
for at least a few hours.
He wasn't unconscious.
These are defensive wounds,
consistent with the boy
resisting being placed
in the freezer,
arms outstretched.
I'll take samples
from under his fingernails.
Maybe he scratched her
during the struggle.
Maybe she knew the facts
in this case
wouldn't be consistent
with the other crimes,
and would give her
reasonable doubt.
We have evidence from
credit card charges
that the defendant was at
the Rockland Mall
on the day that Terrence Gilroy
was abducted.
The team at the Jeffersonian
discovered
that the number Taffet
called...
turned out to be
the same GPS coordinates
as to where the boy
was buried.
The same M.O.,
same ransom tape,
the same demands
as the other kidnappings.
Do you have any evidence
that the Gilroy boy
was abducted from the mall?
It was the last place
he was seen.
So, no.
Did anyone else
make any purchases at the mall
that day, or was it just me?
Of course they did, but...
As for the phone call
that I allegedly made,
is it possible that the number was
placed in my file by mistake?
(Caroline)
Objection.
Conjecture.
Sustained.
Did you know that
the officer on duty
the night I was arrested
was from Salt Lake?
Answer the question,
Agent Booth.
No.
(Taffet)
Isn't it more likely
that he made that call,
and the number
was placed in my
file by mistake?
Objection. Conjecture again.
I thought it was
reasonable doubt.
Very reasonable.
Your honor...
withdrawn.
No further questions,
your honor.
(Sighs)
You know that Taffet's
playing you, right?
We're fine, Max.
No, she's got you
all on defense.
We got the boy, all right?
It's because she wanted you to.
Every psycho takes
one step too far
and hangs themself.
Not before a lot
of innocent people get hurt.
I'll see you later.
(Knocking at door)
Hey, sorry
to bother you.
You have a minute?
Yeah, sure.
(Sighs)
How's it going?
I don't know, actually.
That's why I'm here. I-I'm...
I'm worried,
Dr. Sweets. I-I...
this case is taking
its toll on everyone.
Including you?
Including me, yes.
It's a very stressful
situation.
I mean, you're not immune
to that.
I feel like everything's fraying
around the edges.
We're all searching for some
piece of evidence
that can put Taffet away.
But we keep
coming up empty.
Everyone feels
manipulated by her.
And I-I should be able
to pull everyone together--
keep them on track.
You want to guarantee
the outcome.
I wish that were possible.
But you know, we knew this was
going to be an uphill battle.
But did we really
believe that?
We all knew she was guilty.
So someplace, we assumed
that in a just world
she'd pay for what she did.
That assumes a just world,
I'm afraid.
These...
are my people she hurt,
my friends.
I should...
...be able to do something.
I know.
(Rifle cocking)
Max, you didn't think I
was going to follow you?
(Grunting)
(Panting)
Max, is this what you want?
Don't trust the system, Booth.
You miss, you compromise
the case, Taffet walks.
I don't miss!
(Groans)
When are you
gonna learn
to stop messing with me, huh?
You're making a big mistake.
Tempe could die.
Yeah, come on.
He tried to kill her?
Well, he had a rifle
pointed right at her,
so you do the math.
Why?
Why would
he do that?
To protect you.
And a career criminal
like Max--
he obviously doesn't
trust the legal system.
I'm sorry, Booth.
I wish he were different.
Yeah, me, too.
You know, he socked
me in the eye, too.
(Cell phone ringing)
Brennan.
Hey, honey.
I need you to bail me out.
What?! No, dad.
I was doing it for you.
No, I don't want you
to kill people for me.
Just buy me a sweater,
like a regular dad.
Leave her alone, Max.
Booth says you're not
getting out
until after the trial over.
I have to go.
Whoa.
I've got a bad back.
You know what the beds
are like in jail.
Good-bye, dad.
(Snaps phone shut)
Look,
I'm sorry, Bones.
I'm sure this is the last thing
you want to deal with.
Yeah.
Part of me wishes he'd done it.
Well, not the good part,
so let's just keep
our eye on the ball.
So, any news about the boy?
I'm getting an accurate
recreation of the assailant
from the fracture patterns
on his remains,
and it's a match for Taffet.
I'm putting a presentation
together for court.
The kid-- he put up
a good fight, huh?
There's evidence
of strong resistance.
Yes.
Yeah, at least he
didn't go easy.
Parker... he'd do
the same thing.
Probably bite
her ear off and run.
He'd bite her?
Yeah.
Ten-year-olds--
it's kind of their thing.
They bite.
I have to get back to the lab.
(Brennan) If the boy bit her,
there should be some evidence
on his maxilla,
mandible or his teeth.
(Hodgins) The teeth seem to
have been cleaned.
Taffet probably wiped them off.
Second left premolar is chipped.
There might be some trace
in the abrasion,
maybe some tissue
from Heather Taffet.
Saliva contains amylase
that would have
broken down any bits of tissue.
Not if it were imbedded between
the teeth or under the gum line.
(Gravedigger)
If I don't receive the money
in the numbered account
within eight hours,
your child will die.
This is the last...
Okay, this encryption
is a rolling code
split band voice
inversion.
Individual frequencies
between the clicks
are inverted and recombined.
I applied software
that decrypts each of
the 423 separate segments
until the voice
becomes clear.
(Semi-distorted):
if I don't receive the money
in the numbered account
within eight hours,
(clear, female voice)
your child will die.
This is the last time
you will hear from me.
There will be no further...
You did it, Angela.
It's Taffet.
Like to see her
explain away that one.
(Taffet)
If I don't receive the money
in the numbered account
within eight hours,
your child will die.
This is the last time
you will hear from me.
There will be
no further communications.
And in your expert
opinion, Ms. Montenegro,
whose voice is that?
It's Heather Taffet.
The frequency and vocal patterns
are an exact match when compared
to unencrypted recordings
of her voice.
(Caroline)
Thank you.
No further questions.
(Taffet)
That was very
impressive, Ms. Montenegro.
Could you share your credentials
with the court?
I have a bachelor of fine arts
from the University of Texas
with a minor
in computer science.
And I've also studied
biomedical illustration
at American University.
But you do not have a degree
in sound engineering,
is that correct?
No.
(Caroline)
Objection. Ms.
Montenegro has
numerous patents pending from
her work in auditory
forensic reconstruction.
The homeless man on my street
has a patent pending
for a time machine.
That doesn't mean I'm going to
ask him to testify in court.
(Judge)
That's enough,
Ms. Taffet.
Do you have anything else
for this witness?
Yes, your honor.
I'd like to
introduce into evidence
item 461b,
which is a deconstruction
of the same ransom tape
by former FBI special
Agent Graham Steele,
who has a Phd
in forensic auditory analysis
from the University
of Pennsylvania.
(Montenegro)
If I don't receive the money
in the numbered account
within eight hours,
your child will die.
(Montenegro)
Th-that isn't me.
He obviously manipulated
the pitch and the timbre
of the voice.
Isn't that what you did?
No.
Those sound waves have
an underlying pattern
of frequency modulation.
Like a fingerprint.
(Taffet)
Whatever the
technical jargon,
it seems clear that anyone,
even someone without
any credentials,
can make one voice
sound like another.
(Caroline)
Objection!
Counsel is making speeches.
Sustained.
(Taffet)
I'm sorry, your honor.
No further questions.
Hey, Bones, you ready for court?
Yes.
I have a video presentation
which shows the victim
sustained rib fractures
as well as a fracture
of the lateral
epicondyle of the left distal...
What do you say we ease up
on the scientific stuff, okay?
The science gives us
the height of the assailant.
162 centimeters--
Taffet's height.
That's, that's,
that's good and all,
but Taffet's kind of
had a field day,
you know, trashing the whole
technical goobledy stuff.
And the jury seems
to like her for it.
But those are the facts.
It's how you present
the facts that
win or lose a case.
Bones, the jury needs to know
what that little boy
went through.
I've...
I've testified before, Booth.
I'll be fine.
We-we should go.
Okay.
(Brennan)
Terrence Gilroy's
left greater cornu of
the hyoid was compressed,
indicating that the assailant
strangled the young boy
using only one hand--
the dominant left hand,
in this case.
(Caroline)
I'd like to submit
writing samples
which confirm that the defendant
is left-handed.
(Taffet)
No objection, as long
as it's also noted
that eight percent
of the general population
is also left-handed.
Including you, your honor.
(Gallery chuckles)
Continue.
The victim sustained a fracture
of the lateral epicondyle
and the shaft
of the left distal humerus.
Perhaps I can be clearer.
Terrence Gilroy's bones
could only have been broken
by someone kneeling
on top of him
as they pushed him
into the freezer.
The radiating
fracture lines show
that this assailant
had to be between
125 and 135 pounds--
the weight of the defendant.
Objection. This is speculation.
Are you questioning
my qualifications?
Because you will not find
a more experienced or respected
forensic anthropologist
anywhere in the world.
So I'd appreciate
not being interrupted
until I finish testifying.
(Judge)
Dr. Brennan,
I'll make the rulings here.
Overruled.
Continue.
Since these broken bones were
caused by the assailant's knees
and the chipping
on the boy's kneecaps
was caused by the toes of
her heavy boots,
we can determine the length
of her shin.
And what is the significance
of the shin length?
It gives us the height
of the assailant,
which is five feet, four inches.
The same height
as the defendant.
It is clear from
the circumstantial evidence
and these facts
that this child was attacked
with vicious cruelty
by Ms. Taffet.
Objection.
The jury makes that
determination, not the witness.
The five-foot-four assailant...
...crushed the boy's chest,
choked him,
and finally caused him
a torturous death
by burying him alive.
Objection.
Speculation.
She can't know
what the witness felt.
I was buried alive.
Which makes me
uniquely qualified
to comment on its horror.
Objection, your honor.
This is grandstanding.
Unless the witness has
any additional facts...
Sustained.
Do you have
any further questions
for Dr. Brennan, Ms. Julian?
No, your honor.
I learned everything
I need to know.
Your witness.
(Taffet)
Dr. Brennan,
don't you think your trauma
as a kidnapping victim
prevents you
from being objective?
(Caroline)
Objection.
She is testifying as
an expert witness, not a victim.
She brought up being
buried alive, your honor.
(Judge)
She did, Ms. Julian.
Overruled.
It's only natural
that you would want
to construct facts that would
give you some closure and peace.
I resent your implication.
I do not let my emotions
cloud my findings.
No, not intentionally,
of course.
Is there a question coming?
Yes.
Sorry.
Dr. Brennan,
you are currently seeing
an FBI psychologist,
are you not?
What... that has
nothing to do with...
A yes or no
is all that's required,
Dr. Brennan.
Are you currently
seeing an FBI
psychologist?
Yes, but...
Thank you.
No further questions.
No, that has
nothing to do with this case.
My findings are sound.
You may step down, Dr. Brennan.
(Saroyan)
A dust mite?
So that little bug
is gonna save us?
Oh, don't
call him a bug.
Sounds insulting.
We reexamined the boy's teeth
and found it wedged
between the right lateral
incisor and canine.
Dust mites eat
dead human skin cells.
And this one's
stomach sac is full.
If the boy
bit Taffet,
the skin cells
are probably hers.
Whatever's left is
gonna be small, but there
might be enough to give us DNA.
(Hodgins)
This is a
dermatophagoides farinae.
(Caroline)
For those of us who don't
speak insect,
what is that, exactly?
It's a dust mite--
an insect found on clothes,
but it also feeds on
the cells of the person
wearing those clothes.
(Caroline)
And where was this
dust mite found?
Between Terrence Gilroy's teeth.
It was transferred
there when the boy
bit the person
who kidnapped him.
And how do we know that?
The dust mite contained
human female epithelial cells.
We extracted those cells
and ran them through
several DNA databases.
The cells belonged
to Heather Taffet.
Nothing further, your honor.
Your witness, Ms. Taffet.
It seems that you have
neglected to include
a sample of the evidence that I
could have tested independently.
Since there were so
few cells in the mite,
the testing destroyed
the sample,
but the procedures and results
are all contained
in our documentation.
Let me get this right.
I have access to your notes,
but I can't examine
the actual evidence
because you destroyed it?
Your honor, in California
versus Trombetta,
the Supreme Court ruled
that the prosecution
could destroy a sample
to test for DNA
because there was no bad faith.
Bad faith?
The motives of
every single person
at the Jeffersonian are suspect,
and now their only physical
evidence is gone--
if it existed at all.
(Caroline)
I've just about had it
with your snide,
unsubstantiated allegations.
As have I.
That's enough, Ms. Julian.
(Taffet)
Your honor, I would
like to file a motion
to have this unverifiable
DNA evidence dismissed.
Protocol has been followed,
Ms. Taffet.
It's up to the jury
to decide how the evidence
will figure
in the outcome of this case.
Your motion is denied.
Did you see Taffet's face?
She was completely blindsided.
Okay, Caroline's
closing--
it's going to kill.
All right,
so here we go.
That's it, huh?
Are you okay, Bones?
Your team just nailed Taffet.
I'm just tired.
Yeah. Yeah.
It's been a...
it's been a tough case.
It's not just the case.
I'm tired of...
of all of it.
I'm tired of dealing
with murders
and victims and sadness
and pain.
Well, Bones,
that's what we do.
All right?
We catch the bad people,
and we make the world
a better place.
No, Booth.
That's what you do,
and somehow,
I got caught up into it.
Wait a sec.
Hold on. You were dealing
with dead people
long before we got together.
As a researcher,
an anthropologist.
That's how I can make
the world a better place.
And you do. Come on.
You make the world
a great place.
Hey.
Cheers to that, all right?
You're just anxious.
All right?
And tomorrow,
when we have won,
everything will be perfect.
It'll be fine.
(Caroline)
We are here to seek justice
for this ten year-old boy
who was kidnapped,
brutally beaten
and buried alive
by Heather Taffet.
Taffet was seen
where this child was abducted.
She matches the size
of the assailant.
She's left-handed.
Her voice was discovered
on the ransom tapes.
It all sounds very reasonable,
doesn't it?
These so-called facts
were compiled by people
who themselves
were victims
of a vicious criminal
who has not yet been caught.
They need a scapegoat.
But only Heather Taffet
could have the DNA
that was found
in this child's mouth.
That evidence was delivered
to us in death
by this brave boy.
And yet, the only people
who saw that dust mite,
the only people who touched
the alleged epithelial cells
were two kidnap victims--
one a known
conspiracy theorist,
the other a traumatized
anthropologist
who's currently being
treated by a psychologist.
And Dr. Saroyan,
who couldn't perform her job
without destroying the evidence,
conveniently preventing me
from mounting a defense.
Because she has no defense,
except slandering these experts.
They have told you what
Heather Taffet did to that boy.
The law is clear.
You cannot convict a person
based on innuendo
or groundless accusations.
I weep for that boy.
No child should
suffer like that,
and whoever did this...
...should never be allowed to
walk among decent people again.
For that boy, for justice,
you must return a verdict of...
...Not guilty.
Because it's clear
that I am a scapegoat.
I am innocent.
Thank you.
What'd I tell you, huh?
Caroline nailed it in there.
Taffet was pretty convincing in there, too.
You know what, Hodgins?
You ever see the bright side
in things?
(Hodgins)
You know what, Booth?
You're right.
Because no matter what happens
in there,
I've got Angela.
(Montenegro)
Hodgins.
(Hodgins)
It's okay.
I don't care, Angie.
Look, Taffet's not going
to make the rules anymore.
I want our friends
to know.
I want everybody to know.
Okay.
Angela and I are married.
What?
(Others murmuring and gasping)
Ohh...
Hey, look at that, huh?
What? When, Ang?
In jail.
Hodgins wanted to wait
until this was over,
so everybody
could be happy for us.
This isn't another
pregnancy scare, is it?
No. No, this is...
This is love.
(Sweets)
So...
Why were you hiding this
from us?
Oh, I was having trouble
dealing with things
because of the trial.
Then I thought...
screw it.
The jury's back.
♪ ♪
♪ I've seen enough to know ♪
♪ I've seen enough ♪
♪ seen enough to know... ♪
(Judge) The defendant will rise
for the reading of the verdict.
♪ So I keep them closed ♪
in count one, the kidnapping
of Terrence Gilroy,
the jury finds the defendant,
Heather Taffet,
guilty.
(Murmuring)
Order, or I will
clear the court.
In count two,
the murder of Terrence Gilroy,
the jury finds the defendant...
Guilty.
(Cheering)
The defendant is remanded into
custody until sentencing.
We are adjourned.
(Gavel bangs)
(Handcuffs clicking)
This isn't over.
♪ Once more into the crowd ♪
♪ temptation wears you out ♪
♪ go home ♪
♪ your heart's too large ♪
♪ oh, please, oh... ♪
♪ ♪
(laughter)
(Max)
I was out of town
for a couple of days.
Well, I knew Tempe had
everything under control.
She didn't need me.
Uh-huh.
All right, let's just
raise our glasses here.
To the squints, okay?
Come on.
To Booth.
Hey!
Oh, and Caroline.
Hear, hear.
You know, I never doubted any
of you-- not for a minute.
(Booth)
Where'd you come from?
Oh, come on.
Oh, please.
(Laughter)
Okay, let's not forget
the happy couple
over here.
(Brennan)
Yes, best wishes
for a successful blending
of familial obligations,
as well as monetary
and property consolidation.
What?
(Cheering and laughter)
(Saroyan)
Congratulations!
(Indistinct chatter)
(Sighs)
I guess I'll go home.
A real bed is probably
going to feel good.
I'm sorry that I, uh...
that I doubted you.
Sweets would say
that subconsciously
you wanted Booth to catch you
so you and I wouldn't have
to be separated again.
Smart guy, that Sweets.
I love you, honey.
(Booth)
Thanks for leaving me
with the bill again.
That's nice of you.
Your fault, Booth.
My wallet got
stolen in jail.
Yeah.
Bye.
Can't believe they
actually got hitched.
(Brennan)
I know.
I have this sense that
everything's changing, Booth.
Well, not everything.
Look-- we're
still partners.
Right?
And-and Taffet...
She's... she's put away.
I mean, you're feeling good
about that, right?
You almost died, Booth.
That can happen again.
What if, next time,
I can't get to you?
It's not going to happen again.
I envy your ability to
substitute optimism for reality.
You know what?
Maybe you just need
to take some time off.
Go to a beach.
Lay in the sun.
I might need more
than a little time.
Don't make any decisions
about your future right now.
I'm just staying...
You know when a dentist
gives you anesthetic
and tells you not to operate
any heavy machinery
or make any important decisions
within 24 hours?
All right, this case
was bigger than a root canal.
Come on, let's just
go back inside
and have one more drink.
Come on.
Just one.
No. I'm tired, Booth.
I-I-I'm going to go home.
(Sighs)
All right. Come on.
Let's... we'll get you
in the cab.
I know, it's... it's been
a long, long day.
All right, get in there,
all right?
Hey.
I'll see you tomorrow,
all right?
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.com --