Can I help you?
They told me to take a
streetcar named Desire...
...then transfer to one
called Cemeteries...
...ride 6 blocks and get
off at Elysian Fields.
There's your car.
Thanks.
When he got home, she was waiting.
You never heard nothing...
What's wrong? You lost?
I'm looking for Elysian Fields.
This is Elysian Fields. What number?
642.
Don't need to look no further.
I'm looking for my sister, Stella
DuBois, I mean, Mrs. Stanley Kowalski.
That's the party, all right.
You just did miss her, though.
This...
Can this be her home?
She lives downstairs, I live up.
She's out?
You notice the bowling alley?
- I'm not sure I did.
- That's where she's at.
She's watching Stanley bowl.
Blanche!
Stella!
Oh, Stella for a star!
My darling. Now, then,
let me look at you.
But don't look at me. I won't
be looked at in this glare.
- Did you find our place?
- What're you doing in a place like that?
Never, never in my worst
dreams did I picture...
Only Poe, Mr. Edgar Allan Poe,
could do justice to it!
What are you doing in that horrible
place? I didn't mean to say that.
I meant to be nice and say,
"What a convenient location!"
- You haven't said a word to me.
- I haven't had a chance.
Now open your pretty mouth and talk.
- Come say hello to Stanley first.
- No, not now.
Just say hello.
Which is he? Which one is he?
Is he the one...
The one making all the rhubarb!
Isn't he wonderful-Iooking?
I can't meet him now.
Not till I've bathed and rested.
- Would you like a cold drink?
- Bless that lovely inspiration.
Oh, baby.
Would you like some pop?
Honey! Pop!
Not with my nerves tonight.
A scotch please.
Grape.
You haven't asked me how I happened
to get away from school...
...before the term ended.
Thought you'd tell me if you wanted to.
You thought I'd been fired?
No! I thought you might have resigned.
I was so exhausted by all I'd
been through, my nerves broke.
I was on the verge of lunacy, almost.
So Mr. Graves... He's the
high school superintendent...
Thank you. He suggested...
...I take a leave of absence.
I couldn't put all those details
into the wire. This feels so good.
Like another?
One's my limit. You haven't
said a word about my appearance.
You look fine.
God love you for a liar.
Daylight never exposed so total a ruin.
But you've put on some weight.
You're as plump as a partridge.
It's so becoming to you.
Yes, it is! Or I wouldn't say it!
You just have to watch
around the hips a little.
I wanted you to look at my figure.
I haven't put on one ounce in 10 years.
I weigh now what I weighed the
summer you left Belle Reve...
...the summer Dad died and you left us.
It's just incredible,
Blanche, how well you look.
Sure you don't want another?
Maybe I will take just
one tiny nip more...
...to put the stopper on.
Don't worry, your sister's not a drunk.
She's just all shaken up
and hot and dirty and tired.
Waiter!
You want it hot?
Scalding.
What is it?
There's only two rooms.
Where will you put me?
We'll put you right here.
What kind of a bed's this?
One of those collapsible things?
You all right?
Wonderful, honey. I don't
like a bed that gives much.
There's no door between the two rooms.
Will it be decent?
Stanley's Polish, you know.
Something like Irish, isn't it?
Well...
I bought some nice clothes to
meet all your lovely friends in.
Well, I'm afraid you won't
think they're lovely.
I bought nice clothes
and I'll wear them.
I guess you're hoping I'll
say I'll put up at a hotel.
But I'm not going to.
I must be near you. I must be
with people. I can't be alone...
...because, as you must have noticed...
...I'm not very well.
You do seem...
Will Stanley like me or will
I just be a visiting in-law?
I couldn't stand that.
You'll get along fine.
Try not to compare him...
He was an officer?
He was a master sergeant,
decorated 4 times.
- He had those on when you met him?
- I wasn't just blinded by the brass.
I wasn't...
There were things to
adjust myself to later on.
Such as his... civilian background?
How'd he take the news I was coming?
- He's on the road a good deal.
- Oh, he travels?
Good. I mean, isn't it?
I can hardly stand it when
he's away for a night.
- Lf he's away for a week, I go wild.
- Gracious!
When he comes back, cry
on his lap like a baby.
I guess that's what's
meant by being in love.
I haven't asked the things you
probably thought I would...
...so I expect you to be understanding
about what I have to tell you.
What?
You're going to reproach me. I know
you're bound to, but before you do...
...consider the fact that you left.
I stayed and struggled.
You came to New Orleans. I stayed at
Belle Reve trying to hold it together.
I'm not meaning to reproach you...
...but all the burden descended on me!
It was best I came here.
But you abandoned Belle Reve, not I.
I stayed and almost died for it!
- Tell me what happened!
- I knew you'd take this attitude!
About what? Please!
The loss.
Belle Reve? Lost, is it?
Yes.
But how did it go? What happened?
You're a fine one to ask me how it went!
To stand there accusing me of it!
I won't stand it!
I! I took the blows on
my face and my body!
All of those deaths!
The long parade to the graveyard.
Father, Mother...
...Margaret, that dreadful way.
You just came home for the funerals.
And funerals are pretty
compared to deaths.
How'd you think all that
dying was paid for?
Death is expensive, Miss Stella.
And l, from my pitiful
salary at the school.
Yes, accuse me.
Stare at me, thinking
I let the place go!
I let the place go! Where were you?
In there with your Polack!
That's enough!
Oh, Stella, Stella, you're crying!
Does that surprise you?
We playing at your house?
No, my mother's still sick.
- You bring the beer.
- Break it up down there.
- I made spaghetti and ate it myself!
- Now, honey...
...told you we were playing.
You never phoned me once.
- I told you at breakfast.
- Why don't you just get in here.
Do you want it in the newspapers?
You must be Stanley.
I'm Blanche.
You're Stel's sister.
Yes.
Hi ya.
Where's the little woman?
In the bathroom.
Where you from, Blanche?
I live in Auriol.
Auriol.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
Auriol, that's not my territory.
Liquor goes fast in the hot weather.
Want a shot?
No, I rarely touch it.
There's some people that rarely
touch it, but it touches them often.
You mind if I make myself comfortable?
Please do.
" Be comfortable," that's my motto.
Mine too. It's hard to stay
looking fresh in hot weather.
I haven't washed or even powdered and...
...here you are.
You must be careful sitting
in damp things. Catch cold.
Especially when you been
exercising hard, like bowling.
What do you do? You're a teacher?
Yes.
What subject?
English.
I never was a very good English student.
- How long you here for?
- I don't know yet.
Shacking up here?
I will if it's not inconvenient for you.
Good.
Traveling wears me out.
Take it easy.
What's that?
Those cats.
What'd you do, fall asleep in there?
I guess I'll strike you as
being the unrefined type.
Stella's spoke a good deal about you.
She said you were married once.
Said you were married once.
Yes.
When I was quite young.
What happened?
The boy...
The boy died.
I'm afraid...
...I'm going to be sick.
Fresh fish!
Fish!
Looks like she's fixing to stay awhile.
So, we playing tonight?
Maybe we ought to...
Don't figure no maybes.
- Put it down.
- Right.
Shall I get the other one?
Thanks, darling.
Is Stanley back with my trunk?
Yes.
Honey? Will you get my blue net for me?
All right.
It was good of Stanley to get my trunk.
He was glad to do it.
- I'll see you later.
- Just don't forget.
I'm taking Blanche to Galatoire's
for supper, then to a show...
...because it's poker night.
How about my supper?
I'm not going to Galatoire's.
I put you a cold plate on ice.
We'll be back after the party's over
as I'm not sure how'll she'll take it.
Isn't that just dandy.
You better give me some money.
Where is she?
She's soaking in a hot tub to quiet
her nerves. She's terribly upset.
Over what?
She's been through an ordeal.
We lost Belle Reve.
What, the place in the country?
How?
It had to be sacrificed.
When she comes in, say something
nice about her appearance.
And...
...don't mention the baby.
I haven't told her.
I'm waiting till she calms down.
And try to understand her
and be nice to her, honey.
She wasn't expecting such a place.
I tried to gloss things over
a little in my letters.
Admire her dress.
Tell her she looks wonderful.
It's important to Blanche,
her little weakness.
Okay, I get the idea, but...
...let's just skip back to where
you said the place was disposed of.
How about a few more
details on that subject.
It's best not to talk about
it until she's calmed down.
Is that the deal? Blanche can't
be annoyed with details right now?
You saw how she was last night.
I saw how she was. Now,
let's see the bill of sale.
I haven't seen any.
She didn't show you no papers,
no deed nor nothing?
It seemed like it wasn't sold.
Was it given away to charity?
- She'll hear you.
- I don't care. Let's see the papers.
There weren't any. She didn't show
any papers. I don't care about papers.
Wait, listen. Have you
heard of the Napoleonic code?
No, I haven't heard of
the Napoleonic code.
Let me enlighten you on a point or two.
We got here in Louisiana what's
known as the Napoleonic Code:
That what belongs to the wife, belongs
to the husband, and vice versa.
Will you listen?
For example, if I had that property...
My head is swimming.
Well, all right, then.
When she's done soaking in the tub...
...I'll inquire if she
is acquainted with it.
Stanley! Don't be so silly!
It looks like you were swindled.
And, under the Napoleonic Code, I
got swindled too. I don't like that.
You've no idea how
ridiculous you're being...
...when you suggest my sister, or...
...anyone else of our family,
could have swindled anyone...
Come on, where's the money
if the place was sold?
Not sold! Lost! Lost!
Come here.
Open your eyes to this stuff here?
She got this out of a teacher's pay?
Oh, hush!
Look at these fine feathers and
furs that she preens herself in.
What is this article?
A solid-gold dress!
And this one here.
And what is that, a fox-piece?
A genuine fur-fox, a half a mile long!
Where are your fox-pieces?
Bushy, snow-white ones, no less!
Where are your white fox furs?
Those are inexpensive furs
Blanche has had a long time.
An acquaintance deals in these items
and he's going to appraise this.
Don't be an idiot!
I'll bet you there's $1000 invested in this stuff.
Now, is that the treasure
chest of a pirate?
That's pearls. Ropes of them.
Is your sister a deep-sea diver?
Where're your pearls and gold bracelets?
Be still.
A diamond crown for an empress.
A rhinestone tiara she
wore to a costume ball.
What is rhinestone?
Next door to glass.
An acquaintance works in a jewelry store.
He'll come to make an appraisal.
Here's your plantation.
You're being stupid and horrid!
You stay away from these
things before she comes out!
The Kowalskis and DuBois got
a different notion on this.
Indeed they have, thank heavens.
I'm going outside.
Go ahead.
Come out with me while
Blanche is getting dressed.
Since when are you giving me orders?
Are you going to stay
here and insult her?
You bet your life I'm staying.
Hello, Stanley.
Here I am, freshly bathed and scented
and feeling like a new person.
That's good.
Will you excuse me while I
put on my pretty new dress?
Go ahead.
I understand there's to be
a card party here tonight...
...to which we ladies are
cordially not invited.
That's right.
Where is Stella?
She's out on the porch.
I'm going to ask a favor of you soon.
What's that going to be, I wonder?
Some buttons in back.
You may enter.
How do I look?
You look okay.
Many thanks. Now, the buttons.
I can't do no more with them.
You men with your big, clumsy fingers.
May I have a drag?
- Have one for yourself.
- Thank you.
It looks like my trunk has exploded.
Me and Stella helped you unpack.
You did a fast and thorough job of it.
It looks like you've raided
some stylish shops in Paris.
Clothes are my passion.
How much do furs like that cost?
These were a tribute from an admirer.
He had a lot of admiration.
In my youth I excited some
admiration, but look at me now.
Will you think it's possible that
I was once considered attractive?
Your looks are okay.
- I was fishing for a compliment.
- I don't go in for that.
- What?
- Compliments to women on their looks.
Every dame knows if she's good
looking without being told.
Some give themselves credit
for more than they've got.
I once went out with a dame who
said, "I'm the glamorous type."
She says, "I'm the glamorous type."
I says, "So what?"
What did she say then?
Nothing. It shut her up.
Did it end the romance?
It ended the conversation.
That was all.
Some men are took in by this Hollywood
glamour stuff, and some men just aren't.
- And you're in the 2nd category.
- That's right.
- I can't imagine a woman bewitching you.
You're simple, straightforward
and honest. A bit on the...
...primitive side. To interest
you a woman would have to...
She must lay the cards on the table.
I never did care for wishy-washy people.
When I saw you last
night I said to myself:
"My sister has married a man."
That was all I could tell...
How about cutting the re-bop?!
Come with me while Blanche dresses.
- I'm done.
- Come out.
- Your sister and I are chatting.
- Do me a favor.
Go to the store and get me a
lemon coke with chipped ice.
Will you do that for me, sweetie?
Please?
All right.
The poor thing was listening to us.
I have an idea she doesn't
understand you as well as I do.
All right, let us proceed
without any more digression.
I'm ready to answer all questions.
I've nothing to hide. What is it?
In the state of Louisiana we've got
what's known as the Napoleonic Code.
According to which that what belongs
to the wife belongs to her husband.
You have an impressive judicial air.
If you weren't my wife's sister,
I'd get ideas about you.
Such as what?
Don't play so dumb. You know what.
All right.
Cards on the table.
I know I fib a good deal.
But a woman's charm is 50º% º illusion.
But when a thing is important,
I tell the truth.
This is the truth:
I never cheated my sister...
...or you, or anyone else on
earth as long as I lived!
Where are the papers?
Everything I own is in that trunk.
What are you thinking? What's in
that little boy's mind of yours?
I'll do it, it'll be faster and simpler.
I keep my papers in this tin box.
What are those underneath?
Some love letters...
...yellowing with antiquity.
- All from one boy. Give them to me!
- I'll just look.
- Your touch insults them.
- Don't pull that stuff!
Now that you've touched
them, I'll burn them!
What are they?
Poems... the dead boy wrote.
I hurt him the way that you would
like to hurt me, but you can't.
I'm no longer young and vulnerable.
My young husband was and I...
Never mind about that.
Give them back to me.
What'd you mean, you have to burn them?
I'm sorry.
I must have lost my head for a moment.
Everyone has something they
won't let others touch...
...because of their intimate nature.
Ambler and Ambler!
Crabtree!
- What's Ambler and Ambler?
- A firm that made loans on the place.
- It was lost on a mortgage?
- It must have been.
I don't want no ifs, ands, or buts!
Where's the rest?
Thousands of papers, stretching back
over centuries, affect Belle Reve.
As piece by piece our improvident
grandfathers exchanged the land...
...for their epic debauches,
to put it mildly.
Finally all that was left,
and Stella can verify it...
...was the house itself, and 20 acres
of ground including a graveyard...
...to which now all but
Stella and I have retreated.
Here they are, all of them.
All papers.
I hereby endow you with them.
Peruse them, commit them to memory.
It's wonderfully fitting
that Belle Reve...
...should be this bunch of
papers in big, capable hands.
I wonder if Stella's back with my coke?
I got a lawyer acquaintance,
we'll straighten this out.
Present them to him with
a box of aspirin tablets.
Under the Napoleonic Code...
...a man has to take an
interest in his wife's affairs.
Especially now that she's having a baby.
Stella's having a baby?
I didn't know she was having a baby.
Oh, Stella for a star!
How lovely to have a baby!
Everything's all right.
We thrashed it out. I feel shaky,
but I handled it nicely.
I treated it as a joke. Laughed,
called him a boy and flirted.
Yes, I was flirting with your husband.
The guests are arriving for the party.
I'm sorry he did that to you.
I guess he's just not the type
that goes for jasmine perfume.
Maybe he's what we need to mix with
our blood since we've lost Belle Reve...
...and have to go on without
Belle Reve to protect us.
How pretty the sky is!
I ought to go there on a
rocket that never comes down.
Which way do we go now?
This way?
No, honey, this way.
The blind are leading the blind.
Red hots!
Go upstairs and tell her to stop that.
If I go up, I won't come down.
Forget it.
Remember when she poured boiling
water through the floor cracks?
- I gotta go home soon.
- What do you say?
- No, I'm out.
- Every time you win a pot you're out!
My mother doesn't sleep
until I come home.
What do you say?
I'm going to wash up.
You tell them guys the
kettle's on the stove!
I'm going to break up the game.
Wait.
Let me powder. I feel hot and
frazzled. Do I look done-in?
You look fresh as a daisy.
One that's been picked a few days.
Why don't somebody go to the
Chinaman's and bring back chop suey?
- When I'm losing, you want to eat.
- I see you are still at it.
- Where've you been?
- We went to a show.
This is Mr. Gonzales and Mr. Hubbell.
Hello. Please, don't get up.
No one's getting up, don't worry.
Poker's fascinating. Could I kibitz?
You could not!
Why don't you go up to Eunice's?
- How long will you play?
- Till we're ready to quit!
- Wish you'd quit after the next hand.
Hey, that's my coat!
That's not fun, Stanley.
Makes me mad when he does
that in front of people.
- I think I will bathe.
- Again?
My nerves are in knots. Is it occupied?
I don't know.
Good evening.
Hello.
This is Harold Mitchell.
This is my sister, Blanche DuBois.
- How do you do?
- How do you do, Miss DuBois?
How's your mother?
She's about the same, thanks.
She appreciated that custard.
Excuse me, please.
Excuse me.
- That one seems superior to the others.
- Does he?
He had a sort of sensitive look.
His mother's sick.
Is he married?
Is he a wolf?
Why, Blanche!
- No, I don't think he would be.
- What does he do?
He's on the precision bench in
the spare parts department...
...the plant Stanley travels for.
Is that something much?
Stanley's the only one
likely to get anywhere.
Flush, win!
Blanche, you're standing in the light!
Am I? Gracious!
You should see their wives!
I can imagine. Big,
beefy things, I suppose.
You know that one upstairs?
Hey, you hens! Cut out
that cackling in there!
You can't hear us!
You can hear me and I said, hush up!
This is my house and I'll
talk as much as I want to!
Don't start a row.
He's half-drunk.
I'll be out in a minute.
50 cents.
All right. See you.
Well, Steve?
I'm out.
Two bucks.
What do you say?
Come on, are you in?
I'm out!
Who turned that on in there?
I did. Do you mind?
- Turn it off!
- Let the girls have music.
Sounds good.
There you are!
- I didn't hear you name it!
- Didn't I name it?
- I wasn't listening.
- What were you doing?
- Looking through the drapes.
- I wasn't.
We're dealing this hand over again.
Play cards, or quit.
Deal me out!
This game'll be Spit in the Ocean.
Hello.
Excuse me.
The little boy's room
is occupied right now.
Excuse me.
Have you got any cigs?
Sure.
What a pretty case.
Silver?
- Yes. Read the inscription.
- There is an inscription.
Why, I can't make it out.
"And if God choose...
...I shall but love thee
better after death."
That's from my favorite
sonnet by Mrs. Browning.
- You know it!
- Certainly.
There's a story connected
with this inscription.
A romance?
A sad one. The girl's dead now.
She knew she was dying when she
give me this. Strange, sweet girl.
She must have been very fond of you.
Sick people have deep,
sincere attachments.
They do.
- Sorrow makes for sincerity, I think.
- It brings it out.
The little there is belongs to
people who have known sorrow.
- I believe you're right.
- I'm positive.
Deal me out. I'm talking to Miss...
DuBois.
It's a French name, meaning, "woods."
And Blanche means "white." So the
two together mean, "white woods."
Like an orchard in spring.
You can remember it by that...
...if you care to.
You are Stella's sister, are you not?
Stella's my precious little sister.
I call her "little" though
she's older than I am.
Just slightly. Less than a year.
- Will you do something for me?
- Yes. What?
I bought this adorable paper
lantern at a Chinese shop.
Put it over the light bulb, will you?
I'd be glad to.
I can't stand a naked light bulb
anymore than I can a rude remark...
...or a vulgar action.
I guess we strike you as
being a pretty rough bunch.
I'm very adaptable...
...to circumstances.
- That's a good way to be.
- You're not...
- Married? Oh, no, no!
I'm an old-maid teacher.
You may be a teacher, but you're
certainly not an old maid.
Why, thank you, sir.
I appreciate your gallantry.
So you're in the teaching profession?
Grade school or high school?
Coming!
Gracious, what lung power!
I teach high school in Auriol.
What subject do you teach?
Guess.
I bet you teach art or music.
Of course, I could be wrong.
You might teach math.
Never math, sir. Never math.
I have the misfortune of
being an English instructor.
I try to instill a bunch of bobby-
soxers and drugstore Romeos...
...with a reverence for
Hawthorne and Whitman and Poe.
I bet they are more
interested in other things.
How very right you are.
Their literary heritage is not
what they treasure above all.
But they're sweet things.
In spring, it's touching to see them
making their first discovery of love.
As if nobody had ever known it...
...before.
Sorry.
Excuse me!
Have you finished?
Oh, yes.
- I have.
- Wait. I'll turn on the radio.
Turn on the light now.
Oh, look!
We've made enchantment.
3 bullets, moustache!
Straight! I got you!
- What are you doing?
- Let me alone!
Drunk! You animal thing!
Get out!
- What're you doing?
- Get out.
My sister's going to have a baby!
Lunacy! Complete lunacy!
You come up to my place.
Did he hurt you?
- Make him go away!
- Poker shouldn't be played around women.
Take it easy, will you?
Get him in that shower!
Come on.
Get his feet, will you?
Grab his feet. Come on.
Come on, get under there. Stay.
Get under there.
Get him a little higher, that's right.
- How you feel?
- There you are.
Wake up.
We should remove his clothes.
What're you doing?!
Poker should not be played
around women!
Where's Steve?
Take it easy!
Honey?
Where are you?
Hey, baby!
You can sleep over here.
Blanche can have Steve's place.
He ain't coming home if he
knows what's good for him.
Look! She ain't coming down and she
ain't going to talk to you neither.
Stop hollering and go to bed.
I want my girl.
Shut up, or you'll get the law on you.
You can't beat up a woman then
call her back. She ain't coming.
- They'll haul you in like last time!
- I want my girl down here.
You stinker!
I wouldn't mix in this!
Please, don't ever leave me, baby.
Come back!
Miss DuBois?
All quiet along the Potomac now?
She ran down and went back in with him.
- Sure, she did.
- I'm terrified.
Don't be. They're
crazy about each other.
- Shame it happened your first day.
- Violence is so...
Sit down and have a cigarette with me.
Why, I'm not properly dressed.
That doesn't matter here.
Such a pretty silver case.
I showed you the inscription, didn't I?
There's so much...
...so much confusion in the world.
Thank you for being so kind.
I need kindness now.
Bananas!
Oh, my baby. My baby sister!
- What's the matter with you?
- He's left?
- Will he be back?
- He's getting the car greased.
I've been half-crazy.
How could you come back last night?
Please, he was as good as
a lamb when I came back.
He's really very ashamed of himself.
And that makes it all right?
Stanley's always smashed things.
On our wedding night, as
soon as we came in here...
...he snatched off my slipper and
rushed around smashing light bulbs.
He did what?
He smashed all the light bulbs
with the heel of my slipper.
And you let him, didn't run?
I was sort of thrilled by it.
Eunice and you had breakfast?
Do you suppose I wanted any breakfast?
You're so matter of fact
about it all, Stella.
Well, what other can I be?
He took the radio to get it fixed.
It didn't land on the pavement
so only one tube smashed.
- And you stand there smiling?
- What should I do?
- Face the facts.
- What are they, in your opinion?
You're married to a madman.
I have a plan for us
both to get out of here.
Stop taking it for granted
that I want to get out.
I take for granted you have
sufficient memory of Belle Reve...
...to find it impossible to live here.
- You take too much for granted.
I can't believe you.
I understand how it happened.
You saw him first in uniform,
an officer, not here...
That doesn't make any difference.
We're talking about his desire.
His brutal desire.
The name of that streetcar that
bangs through the quarter.
Up one narrow street and down another.
Have you ever ridden on that streetcar?
It brought me here...
...where I'm not wanted.
Where I'm ashamed to be.
Isn't your superior attitude
a little out of place?
- A man like that.
- I love him!
I tremble for you.
I can't help your trembling
if you insist on trembling.
May I speak plainly?
Yes, do. Go ahead.
As plainly as you want.
If you'll forgive me...
...he's common.
Yes, I suppose he is.
Suppose?
You can't have forgotten that
much of our upbringing...
...that you suppose there's any
part of a gentleman in his nature.
You're hating me saying
this, aren't you?
Go on. Say it all, Blanche.
He's like an animal.
He has an animal's habits.
There's something subhuman about him.
Thousands of years have passed
him by and there he is...
...Stanley Kowalski,
survivor of the Stone Age...
...bearing the raw meat home
from the kill in the jungle.
You wait. Maybe he'll strike
you... or grunt, kiss you...
...if kisses have been discovered.
His poker night, you call it.
His party of apes?
Maybe we are a long way from
being made in God's image...
...but, Stella, my sister...
...there's been progress since then.
Such things as art, as poetry, as music.
In some kinds of people, some tenderer
feelings have had a little beginning...
...that we must make
grow and cling to...
...and hold as our flag in this march
toward whatever it is we're approaching.
Don't, don't hang back with the brutes!
Hi ya.
Is Blanche back yet?
Yeah, she's back.
Oh, hi there, Blanche.
Looks like you got under the car.
That jerk mechanic down at Fritz's
doesn't know grease from 3rd base.
Don't throw that thing at me!
I can fix things.
- Just what I gave your brother.
- I'll call the police.
He hit me. I'm calling the police.
You saw!
Your sister's friends have
stayed in the city awhile.
Did Eunice get the police?
- No, she's getting a drink.
- That's much more practical.
Blanche is making us new slipcovers.
Is she here?
She went to the Four Deuces.
That no-good, rotten...
I can't find my other pair of shoes.
We cleaned in there.
I'll get them.
I can't find nothing
around this dump anymore.
What sign were you born under?
What sign?
Astrological sign.
I bet you were born under Aries.
Aries people are forceful, dynamic.
They dote on noise.
They love to bang things around.
Stanley was born five
minutes after Christmas.
Capricorn. The goat!
Say...
...do you know somebody named Shaw?
Everybody knows someone
by the name of Shaw.
This somebody named Shaw
believes he met you in Auriol.
But I figure he must of mixed you up
with someone else because this party...
...he met at a hotel
called The Flamingo.
I guess he does have me mixed
up with this other party.
The Hotel Flamingo is not a
place I'd dare to be seen in.
You know it then?
I've seen it...
...and smelled it.
You must've got close to smell it.
The odor of cheap
perfume is penetrating.
You use expensive stuff?
$12 an ounce. I'm nearly out...
...if you want to remember...
I figure that he must
of got you mixed up.
But he goes in and out of
Auriol all the time...
...so he can check and
clear up any mistake.
See you at the Four Deuces.
Don't I rate a kiss?
Not in front of your sister.
Don't cry. I only do that with
other girls because I love you, baby.
It's a fact.
You still scared of thunder?
What've you heard about me?
What have people been telling you...
...about me?
Telling?
You haven't heard any...
...unkind gossip about me?
Why, no, Blanche. Of course not.
Honey...
...there was quite a lot of talk...
...in Auriol.
People talk, who cares?
I haven't been so good
the last year or so...
...since Belle Reve began slipping away.
- We all do things.
- I was never hard enough.
Soft people...
...have got to court
the favor of hard ones.
They must shimmer and glow.
How much longer I can turn the trick?
It isn't enough to be soft.
You must be soft...
...and attractive.
And I...
I'm fading now.
Have you been listening to me?
I never listen when you're being morbid.