♪ Fixed & Synced by
bozxphd.Enjoy The Movie ♪
Our story begins
high over New York City...
in the luxurious
penthouse apartment...
of perhaps the most unlikely
genius the world has ever known.
Oh. Sorry. You caught
me doing my yoga.
You were expecting
downward dog, perhaps?
My name is Mr. Peabody.
And since we're going to be
spending some time together...
I'd like to tell you a
little bit about myself.
You see, ever since
I was a pup...
it was clear that
I was different.
I tried to fit in...
No, thank you.
...but never could.
As I grew, I saw more and
more of my littermates...
being chosen by their new families.
But for some reason,
I never was.
Come on, boy! Fetch the stick!
But why? Won't you
just throw it again?
It's an exercise in futility.
I don't want this one, Mommy.
He's sarcastic.
Wait, wait! Come back!
Throw the stick.
I'll stay, I'll heel,
I'll even shake hands.
Bark, bark?
So, without a
family of my own...
I dedicated myself to the
pursuit of knowledge...
culture, and athletics.
I received my degree at Harvard.
Vale-dog-torian, of course.
Yay!
And then, I devoted myself
to helping mankind.
I pioneered new techniques
in alternative energy.
Yay!
Resolved geopolitical
conflicts around the globe.
And in my spare time...
I invented the fist bump,
planking, tearaway pants...
Auto-Tune...
the backside ollie...
and Zumba.
Now go
Stop
Drop
Pause
But what I'm most proud
of is my son, Sherman.
Hi, Mr. Peabody.
Oh!  Have you
told them about the WABAC?
I was just
getting to that.
When I adopted Sherman, I vowed
to be the best father I could be.
To prepare him for all the
wonders of the world,
present and past.
And so, Sherman inspired the
greatest invention of my life...
a time machine.
Of course, time travel can
be a bit unpredictable.
There are bound to be a few
mishaps along the way.
Let's just say, the
Leaning Tower of Pisa
wasn't always leaning.
But there's
nothing like learning
the lessons of
history firsthand.
Right, Sherman?
Where are we going today, Mr.
Peabody?
Not "where," Sherman.
"When."
Whoa! This is the
biggest house I've ever seen!
It's the Palace of
Versailles, home of Marie Antoinette.
You know, she was mostly
famous for one thing.
Cake!
I love cake so much.
Marie Antoinette sure likes cake, Mr.
Peabody.
Oh!
Indeed she does.
Marie was a woman with a
prodigious appetite...
for all things covered
with frosting.
But her expensive tastes made her
the target of much criticism.
Why? Because, Sherman...
during Marie's reign,
the common people
of France were exceedingly poor.
You've got any bread?
No! I'm exceedingly poor.
Now, can we have some cake?
Mais, oui.
Oh, yeah, sorry.
"May we" have some cake?
Mais, oui!
Maybe she can't hear
me through the hair.
Sherman, what the
queen means is...
Ah!  Let them eat cake!
When the queen heard the poor of
Paris could not even buy bread...
she said, "Let them eat cake."
No!
I heard it myself.
It's a scandal! It's an outrage!
Down with the queen!
Down with the monarchy!
Wait!
What kind of cake?
Smashing party, Your Majesty.
But now, I'm afraid
Sherman and I must be...
Sherman? Sherman?
Sherman!
Sherman?
Sherman! Here, Sherman.
Hey, Mr. Peabody.
What are you doing in here?
Trying these other cakes.
There's one in here with whipped
cream and strawberries that's...
pretty fantastic!
Sherman...
don't you remember why
I told you to stay
close to me during the
French Revolution?
Because after the
French Revolution...
it was gonna rain? Close.
I said, "After the French
Revolution comes...
the Reign of Terror!"
Round up the aristocrats.
The queen and her
aristocratic cronies...
must pay the price
for their gluttony.
We will slaughter them
like the dogs they are.
Starting with this one!
Mr. Peabody!
What should I do?
Nothing, Sherman. Just
stay right there.
But, Mr. Peabody!
Everything is going
to be fine, Sherman.
Just stay right there.
Off with his head!
Mr. Peabody!
A cantaloupe?
The lowest of the fruits.
Who dares to insult
me with this melon?
Get that dog!
Mr. Peabody,
how did you escape?
It's simple, Sherman.
I noticed the distance
between the sewer lids...
reasoned that there must be one
directly under the
guillotine platform...
noted the loose board
under the basket...
computed the angle at
which the setting sun
would bounce off your glasses...
momentarily blinding
the executioner...
and chose that moment to swipe
the executioner's melon...
giving me the added weight to tip
the boards, facilitating my exit.
That's amazing!
It's not amazing.
It was just a matter
of keeping my head.
"Keeping your head."
I don't get it.
There he is! After them!
Come, Sherman, quick!
Oh, this water
tastes terrible.
Interestingly, that's not water.
Ha-ha!
I've got you now.
Indeed you have,
Monsieur Robespierre.
And what a master of
the chase you are.
Oh, you noticed?
Of course.
Doubling back on me like that.
That was genius.
Thank you.
I just hope you don't take
my little confederate, here.
I depend on him so completely.
Get over here, you.
Drats! You're devilishly clever.
I know. And much quicker
than you as well.
But are you quick
enough for this?
Ha-ha! See? Quick!
Quick, yes, but not too smart.
Oh! Another cantaloupe!
Your sword!
All right, Sherman,
looks like it's time
for a little pop quiz
in the art of fencing.
Go!
Attack! Parry! Thrust! Repeat!
No. Remise!
Good boy!
Oh!
Huh?
Ha-ha! You missed!
I never miss.
Hop on!
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Yeah! Whoa!
Yeah!
Do you smell that, Sherman?
It wasn't me, Mr. Peabody.
I know it wasn't you.
It's the methane gas
in the sewer system.
And given the fact that it ignites
at 306 degrees Fahrenheit...
we're about to use it...
to blast out of here!
Hang on!
Whoo!
Wow!
Nice landing, eh, Sherman? Oof!
So, what did you learn
today, Sherman?
That French
Revolution was crazy.
How so?
All those guys getting
their heads chopped off...
and nobody standing up and
saying it wasn't right.
And think, Marie Antoinette could
have avoided the whole revolution...
if she'd simply issued an edict
to distribute bread
amongst the poor.
But then, she couldn't
have had her dessert.
Why not, Mr. Peabody?
Because, Sherman, you can't have
your cake and edict, too.
I don't get it.
Where are we gonna go tomorrow, Mr.
Peabody?
Ancient Rome? The Wild West?
1492?
No, Sherman, tomorrow we won't
be going to any of those places.
Oh. Why not?
Because tomorrow's adventure...
is one that you're going to
be taking all on your own.
What do you mean, Mr. Peabody?
Don't you remember?
It's your first day of school.
Oh. Can I drive? Of course not.
Remember, Sherman, "i"
before "e," except after "c."
I know, Mr. Peabody!
And don't forget about the
commutative principle.
Two plus three equals
three plus two.
I know, Mr. Peabody!
And if you have to go
to the bathroom...
just raise your hand proudly
and say, "I have to go."
I will, Mr. Peabody.
And remember, the No. 2 pencil
is standard for most uses...
but there are times when a No.
1 comes in handy.
I left a little pencil
chart in your backpack...
which you can consult if it
ever becomes a judgment call.
I think I'll be okay!
Okay, bye, Mr. Peabody.
Wait.
See you after school. Sherman!
I gotta go. I gotta
sign up for the clubs.
No one is more in favor
of participation
in fraternal
organizations than I.
But before you go, I
want you to have this.
Thanks. What is it?
A dog whistle.
It doesn't work, Mr. Peabody.
It works fine, Sherman.
It's just a frequency
only dogs can hear.
Oh, cool.
Let that little keepsake
be a reminder to you...
that no matter what
challenges you face,
no matter how far
away I might seem...
Bye, Mr. Peabody!
...I'm with you.
George Washington.
Who can tell me who he is?
Oh, me! I can! I can!
Uh... Sherman.
The first president of the
United States of America.
Good job.
And when President Washington
was a little boy...
what kind of tree
did he cut down?
Ooh! Ooh, me! Me! Me!
Penny? A cherry tree.
Apocryphal.
What kind of tree is that?
It's not a tree. It's a word.
"Apocryphal."
It means that story is not true.
Really? Yeah.
George Washington never
cut down a cherry tree...
and he never said
he couldn't lie.
People made those stories up to
teach kids a lesson about lying...
but they're not true.
He did cross the Delaware River,
Christmas night, 1776, though.
My dad took me there this summer.
We crossed it, too.
I fell in.
Looks like someone really knows
their history, huh, Penny?
It's really
great meeting you guys.
Maybe you can come over
to my house sometime.
I could bring my new model.
It's a hydrogen atom.
You've only got one, huh?
Guess we'll have to split it.
Good one!
Check it, guys.
What do you
got there, Sherman?
Kibbles or bits?
Actually, I've got baby carrots,
organic apple juice,
and a tuna sandwich.
It's super-high in omega-3s.
So, you eat human food, huh?
Yeah. Why wouldn't I?
Because you're a dog.
No, I'm not.
Sure you are. Your dad is a
dog, so you're a dog, too.
I think you're confused. It's
an adoptive relationship.
Zip it, Carl. Okay.
Here, I'll show you. Fetch!
Go on, doggy. Go get your lunch.
Go on.
Go get it.
Ugh. The humiliation.
Sherman,
go get your food.
Make like a good little doggy.
Ruff-ruff!
What's this? It's mine!
Give it back!
What is it? A whistle?
Ugh! Stupid thing
doesn't even work.
It's a dog whistle, Penny.
It operates at a frequency
that only dogs can hear.
Back up, Carl. Okay.
Penny, that whistle is
my private property.
Give it back! Jump, doggy, jump.
I am not a dog.
Come on, Sherman!
Just admit it. You're a dog.
Say it.
Let me go!
Not until you beg like a dog.
Come on, Sherman.
Beg!
Fight, fight, fight!
Mr. Peabody, thank you for
coming in on such short notice...
to discuss the problem
with Sherman.
Oh, it's not a problem
at all, Principal Purdy.
I fully expected this.
You did? Yes.
And, as with all things
Sherman-related, I prepared for it.
Here's a curriculum
that takes Sherman's
advanced preparation
into account...
but won't require you to have
him skip one or more grades.
Mr. Peabody...
Here are some pre-algebra worksheets,
an advanced reading list...
and a link to a
website I created
so he can start studying
Mandarin Chinese.
It is, after all, the
language of the future.
Mr. Peabody!
I'm not saying he shouldn't study
French, too, Principal Purdy.
I'm saying have him do both.
Mr. Peabody!
What? Not enough? Swahili?
Sherman got into a fight today.
Oh, dear.
Pictures were taken...
for insurance purposes.
He bit her.
I must say, it doesn't look
good for you, Mr. Peabody.
After all, you are a dog.
Who, may I ask, are you?
I am Ms. Grunion from the Bureau
of Child Safety and Protection.
We're required by law to contact
them whenever there's an...
incident.
Sherman has never done
anything like this before.
I'm sure he must
have had a reason.
Well, the girl was being
a bit of a bully...
Quiet, Purdy!
It's normal for
children to tease.
It's not normal
for them to bite.
Clearly, it's because of
how he's being raised.
In my opinion, a
dog can never be
a suitable parent
to a little boy.
I must point out, Ms. Grunion...
that I won the right
to adopt Sherman
in a court of law.
And the court can take
it away from you.
I'll be coming to your home tomorrow
evening to conduct an investigation.
If I discover that you are, in
any way, an unfit parent...
I will see to it Sherman is
removed from your custody.
Permanently.
I hope I've made myself clear.
Crystal.
I'm sorry I bit her, Mr.
Peabody.
I won't do it again.
You're darn tooting you
won't do it again.
This kind of wanton violence
is totally unacceptable.
And rather uncharacteristic, given
how you feel about Mr. Gandhi.
What on earth provoked it?
She called me a dog.
Well, all right then.
Thank you for telling me.
Try and get some sleep.
I love you, Mr. Peabody.
I have a deep regard for
you as well, Sherman.
Close your eyes
Have no fear
The master's gone
He's on the run
And your daddy's here
Beautiful, beautiful,
beautiful, beautiful boy
Say a little prayer
Every day, in every way
It's getting better and better
Beautiful, beautiful,
beautiful, beautiful boy
A hard road to hoe
Yes, it's a long way to go
But in the meantime
Take my hand
Life is what happens to you while
you're busy making other plans
Beautiful, beautiful,
beautiful, beautiful boy
Mr. Peabody...
you are a Nobel
Prize-winning scientist.
An advisor to heads of state.
A captain of industry.
Why would you want
to adopt a boy?
Because, Your Honor...
when I found Sherman, it reminded
me of how I started out in life.
And now, I want to give him the
one thing I always wanted.
A home.
And you're sure you're capable
of meeting all the challenges...
of raising a human boy?
With all due respect,
how hard could it be?
Very well, then.
If a boy can adopt a dog...
I see no reason why a
dog cannot adopt a boy.
Da-da!
No, Sherman, not "Da-da."
You shall call me "Mr. Peabody."
Or, in less formal
moments, simply "Peabody."
That's right.
"Mr. Pea-baba."
Beautiful, beautiful,
beautiful, beautiful boy
What's cooking, Mr. Peabody?
Oh, nothing much.
Just a little Dungeness crab with
a passion-fruit basil concassé.
Some truffled quails in a
juniper-berry reduction.
And Baked Alaska.
Wow! Is today some kind
of special occasion?
You could say.
It's not my birthday.
No, it isn't.
It's not your birthday.
Right again.
It's not Father's Day. Is it?
Nope. It's not Father's Day.
Is the president coming
to dinner again?
No. Oh.
So, who's coming to dinner?
Let's just say, if the
evening is a success...
we can put this whole
"biting" business behind us.
The Petersons! Welcome.
So, he's literally a dog.
Paul!
No, that's all right.
Although, I prefer
"literate dog."
That's funny.
Isn't that funny, Paul?
He's not
a big laugher.
We're so delighted you could
make it on such short notice.
Aren't we, Sherman?
Yeah, we're interested in what's
going on, that's for sure.
Say hello to Penny, Sherman.
Hi, Penny.
Hello, Sherman.
Now, why don't you go show Penny
your mineral
collection, Sherman?
I'm sure she'll find
those new geodes
of yours fascinating.
Come on.
I am so glad you
accepted my invitation.
Now, the kids can resolve their
differences before Ms. Grunion arrives.
You're barking up the wrong tree, mister.
In fact...
if it weren't for Patty, I would
have pressed charges already.
And I have to tell
you, Peabody...
where my daughter is concerned,
nothing is more important than...
Hello. Sure, I'll take a survey.
Everything going swimmingly?
Ugh.
Why didn't you tell me she
was coming over here?
Because I didn't want you to worry.
Okay, because I didn't want to
listen to your bellyaching.
Thank you for your honesty.
You're welcome.
I don't know what you think we're
supposed to do in here anyway.
She hates me.
Share your interests.
Tell a witty anecdote.
Mr. Peabody...
I hate her.
Sherman, every great
relationship...
starts from a place of conflict,
and evolves into
something richer.
Bonne chance.
Make it work.
But don't tell her
about the WABAC.
Don't even
think about it.
Ah.
Peabody,
that was amazing!
Paul, wasn't that amazing?
I'm more into rock-'n'-roll.
I meant flamenco.
Bagpipes?
Uh, didgeridoo.
Sitar.
Steel drums.
Trombone.
Xylophone.
Djembe?
Calliope.
Oboe. Piccolo.
Tuba. Dobro.
Slide whistle. Yodeling.
Hurdy-gurdy. Ocarina.
Harmonium. Musical saw.
You know what? This
has been great...
but a complete waste of time.
Now, let's get Penny and go home!
Are you all right, Paul?
I'm... fine.
This happens
whenever he's tense.
Paul, if I might...
Stay away from me, Peabody!
Just get back! I need traction.
You can trust me, Paul. I'm
a licensed chiropractor.
Ow! Huh.
Ooh...
Ah...
Peabody...
I feel great.
I...
I really feel great!
Peabody, you're
a miracle worker.
Ha-ha! Look at me!
I'm dancing!
You know, Penny...
Sigmund Freud says if you
don't like a person...
it's because they remind you of something
you don't like about yourself.
What do you know
about Sigmund Freud?
More than you think.
Sure. Just like you
know all that stuff...
about George Washington not really
cutting down the cherry tree.
Ugh. What a crock.
But it's true!
How do you know? I just know!
Did you read it in a book? No!
See it in a movie? No!
Did your brainiac dad tell you?
No!
So, how do you know, Sherman?
How do you know?
He told me.
Who told you?
George Washington.
George Washington?
Yeah.
Ugh! Liar.
But don't tell her
about the WABAC.
He calls it the "WABAC."
So, where have you gone in it?
Not "where," Penny, "when."
Okay, smart guy, when?
Oh, 1965, 1776, 1620...
1492, 1215, 4.
Can it go back to an hour ago?
Why?
Because I could take it
home, pretend to be sick...
and not come to this
lame dinner party.
Ha-ha. Mr. Peabody says you
should never use the WABAC...
to travel to a time
when you existed.
How come?
There would be two of you.
Oh, yeah.
I guess the world's
not ready for that.
Wow.
Um, well, now that we've seen
it, maybe we should go back.
Are you kidding? Where
should we go first?
Mr. Peabody says I'm not
allowed to drive it till I'm older.
Do you do everything Mr.
Peabody says?
Yeah.
You know what that
makes you, Sherman.
An obedient son?
Nope.
A dog.
Ooh! Nice control.
Look at him go! Take it, Patty!
Heads up, Paul! Whoa!
Here you go. Zing!
Oh, yeah.
Oh!
Hey, look at that.
This is fun!
This is a little homespun
concoction I like to call...
"Einstein on the Beach."
Yummy.
To the kids.
To the kids!
Mr.
Peabody.
Sherman?
Can I talk to you a second?
Of course.
Excuse me.
I've really hit it off
with Penny's parents.
I think we can file this night
under "Unqualified Success."
Uh, I would hold off
filing it just yet.
What do you mean? Where's Penny?
Uh... Ancient Egypt.
You used the WABAC?
What's happening, big guy?
We're running low.
I'll be right there, Paul.
How could you do such a thing?
She called me a liar...
for saying George Washington
never cut down a cherry tree.
So, you took her to see
George Washington?
Yeah. She was into it.
Hey, Pea-buddy.
Hey.
Where's Penny?
Playing hide-and-seek. Pooping.
Pooping. Playing hide and seek.
Well, which is it? Uh...
Hey, what's going on here?
Yeah. What's going on here?
What have you done with Penny?
Penny?
Penny? Penny!
Oh, my gosh! Where's
our daughter?
It's
hard to say, Paul.
She could be here, or
here, or here, or here...
or here.
That will hold them.
I learned that
trick from a swami
at the Begawan Giri
in Ubud, Bali.
Let's go!
Ancient Egypt.
Land of the Pharaohs.
A beacon of progress on the
horizon of humanity...
but a cruel and barbarous
civilization just the same.
I just hope Penny isn't
suffering too badly.
I got it.
What are you doing here?
We have come to take you home.
Ugh! What's the Egyptian
word for "tattletale"?
But that's beside the point. Get
your clothes on, we're going home.
Who died and made you Pharaoh?
Now, bring on the mani-pedi.
See, Mr. Peabody? Lmpossible!
Indeed, but watch
what happens...
when an immovable object
meets an irresistible force.
Penny...
come here, right now.
Penny, come!
I'm not Penny anymore.
Now, I'm Princess Hatsheput,
precious flower of the Nile.
"Precious," perhaps,
but if you think
"we're going to
leave you here...
you are most definitely
in "de-Nile."
I don't get it.
Now, come along.
Unhand her!
What's the matter, my sweet
little desert blossom?
Are these barbarians
bothering you?
As a matter of fact, they are.
Bow, barbarians.
As you wish, Your Highness.
Who's that, Mr. Peabody?
That, Sherman, is the
living image of Amun...
son of Akhenaten, lord of the 18th
Dynasty of the New Kingdom...
King Tutankhamun.
Otherwise known as "King Tut."
My boyfriend.
King Tut is your boyfriend?
Mmm-hmm.
Would you like me to have them
skinned, covered with honey...
and laid in a pit of fire ants?
You would do that for me?
Anything, my desert flower.
Consider it a wedding gift.
What? You can't marry this guy!
Why not?
Well, for one, his name
rhymes with "butt."
I don't care. I'm gonna have a
big, fat, Egyptian wedding.
Spoiler alert, King
Tut dies young.
Are you sure you've
thought this through?
Oh, trust me, I've thought it through.
I'm getting everything.
The royal astronomers
have decreed...
the wedding must take
place tomorrow at dawn.
Who is he?
He is Ay. He is you?
I am Ay. The Grand Vizier.
Yeah, that's his name. Oh.
Oh, Grand Vizier, would you mind
telling the precious princess, here...
precisely what it means to
marry the young Pharaoh.
Gladly.
It means she will be bound
to him in eternity...
through the sacred ceremonies
of disembowelment and
mummification...
as described in the holy texts.
Um, hold up a second.
Can you walk me through
that, somebody?
What he means, Penny, is that
when I die they'll kill you, too.
And then they'll rip out your organs,
stuff them in canopic jars...
and then mummify
whatever is left.
Okay, I'm seeing this now.
Thank you. I'm going
to go with them.
There's
no turning back now.
To the palace!
Let the wedding
preparations begin!
Mr. Peabody!
Sherman!
Do something!
Don't worry, Penny!
We'll save you!
Hey, wait! You can't just...
Leave us here.
Mr. Peabody?
Yes, Sherman?
Can I hold your hand?
Of course you can.
Boy, your hand is cold, Mr.
Peabody.
Sherman? Yeah?
That's not my hand.
That's disarming.
Now, to find a way out of here.
Yuck!
Look around, Sherman.
These tombs are lined
with hieroglyphics...
designed to assist
the pharaohs' souls
in their journey
to the afterlife.
And they may assist us as well.
Oh, this depicts the god Anubis
sailing the boat of
Ra to the underworld.
It appears the boats of Ra
are the key to our escape.
We must find them in time
to stop the wedding.
Well, if you ask me, we should
let her marry that guy.
They deserve each other.
What's that, Sherman?
Tut? Give me a break.
Bald, wears a skirt, and makeup.
If I didn't know any better, Sherman,
I would say you were jealous.
Jealous? Of what?
Tut's affection for
Penny, of course.
You think I like Penny?
Mmm-hmm.
Give me a break!
It's not like I want to hold
her hand, or go to the park...
or watch her while she's
brushing her hair.
Or anything.
Hmm.
A-ha!
Quickly, Sherman.
Ah, ah, ah! Careful, Sherman.
It's a booby trap.
What's so funny?
You said "booby."
One wrong step and
we're done for.
"The boat...
"of Ra sails straight...
"to day.
"Take the wrong boat...
man will pay."
All right, Sherman,
now it's your turn.
Do the puzzle exactly as I did.
Huh?
Think it through,
one step at a time.
The boat of Ra sails straight...
play.
Uh, I mean, "pay."
Oh, my.
Uh-oh.
Run!
The boats of Ra!
One boat is the way out,
the other will send us...
plunging into darkness
and certain death.
What?
Sherman, get in the boat.
As soon as I move these blocks together,
it's going to move very fast.
Which boat, Mr.
Peabody?
What?
Which boat is the "not-certain-
death-plunge" boat?
That one!
We did it, Sherman!
Sherman?
Mr. Peabody!
What are you doing over there?
I thought you pointed
to this one!
Ahhh!
Sherman? Sherman?
Are you all right?
I'm good.
The sun god, Ra...
commands us to begin
the sacred ceremony!
Bring forth the blade
for the blood oath.
Where blade meets flesh
in this sacred rite...
We pay tribute...
to the sun god, Ra!
Wait!
Anubis!
The god of death!
The wedding
must not continue.
Why, Anubis, why?
Plagues. Plagues!
If this marriage
pact is sealed...
I will shower down upon the
land uncountable plagues.
Oy, again with the plagues!
Why did I ever move to Egypt?
But, Anubis, the sun
god, Ra, has decreed...
that this girl is to be
the boy-king's wife.
That's so funny.
I was talking to the sun god,
Ra, just the other day...
and he told me he
changed his mind.
Really?
Old "Flip-Flop Ra," we call
him here in the underworld.
But it's too late. We've
already paid for the catering.
Too bad! You're going
to lose your deposit.
More smoke, Sherman. This
canine subterfuge is working.
Deliver the girl...
to the gates of the city,
and leave her there...
where the gods will
retrieve her forthwith.
Only in this manner may the plagues
upon this land be avoided.
The girl must go!
Ow!
Anubis has spoken!
Take this girl to the gates!
Ow.
Anubis, you sound unwell.
Well, I have been feeling a
little under the weather...
but I'm feeling much better now.
Thank you.
Phew! Huh?
Penny, Sherman, quickly.
Come on, Penny.
Sherman!
Ah!
Runaway bride!
Stop them, you fools!
Ah!
Penny, Sherman, climb aboard.
Whoo-hoo!
They're getting away!
Ah!
Whoa!
I got it.
Whoo-hoo!
We made it.
Where do we go next, Mr.
Peabody? Home.
We've got to get back
to the dinner party...
before Penny's parents
realize she's missing.
We don't have to
mention the whole...
uh, King Tut wedding
thing, right?
Certainly not.
Anyway, as far as I'm concerned,
they get married too
young in Ancient Egypt.
Or, perhaps, I'm just
some old "Giza."
Huh?
Warning.
WABAC power supply insufficient.
Charge now. Warning.
Uh, what's the matter, Mr.
Peabody?
All this zipping about the cosmos
has drained our power supply.
We're going to have to
make an unscheduled stop.
As luck would have it...
we have just enough power to
make it to the Renaissance.
I can't even tell my
left brain from my right anymore!
How many times I got to
tell you, Mona Lisa?
Mona Lisa?
I can't
paint the picture...
until you smile!
Leonardo, tell me one thing
I have to smile about.
The sunshine, the pasta.
All the things that make Italy such
a popular tourist destination!
But I have not seen any
of them, Leonardo!
Because I'm sitting here
all day on my abbondanza!
I don't think that means
"chair" in Italian.
Ah,
Peabody, my old friend.
What a welcome interruption!
Believe you me, this
woman is making me nuts.
So, how you been?
Good to see you.
What do you want?
We're in a desperate
hurry to get home,
but the WABAC needs
a jump start...
and we thought, who better than
Leonardo da Vinci to
help us on our way?
Peabody, I would
love to help you,
but you come at a very bad time.
I don't know what I'm going
to do with this crazy woman.
You see what I mean?
What seems to be the problem?
"What is the
problem?"
I am halfway done with the
painting, she won't even smile.
Fine. I smile.
No! That's a fake smile!
Everybody knows that!
Why don't you make
it a real smile?
Why don't you say
something funny?
I paint the paintings.
I make the machines.
I don't tell the jokes!
Perhaps, I can be of assistance.
You see...
humor is not immune to
the laws of science.
Using algorithms,
we can extrapolate
what is universally
considered "funny"...
thus producing a formula that is
scientifically certain
to cause laughter.
Case in point, the pratfall.
Is everyone amused?
Hmm.
The data was so clear. Ooh!
Don't worry, Mr. Peabody.
I got it! Sherman... Ahh!
Oh!
Hold that smile!
Hold it right there!
No move! No move!
Well, Leo, if my
calculations are correct...
this machine of ours should generate
enough centrifugal force...
to send us home.
I got one last piece I
gotta pound in place.
Sherman, why don't you fetch
the hammer for Mr. Da Vinci?
Okay, Mr. Peabody.
Mr. Peabody!
Well done, Sherman.
But, Mr. Peabody!
Very helpful.
Sherman!
Yes, Mr. Peabody?
The hammer.
Da Vinci.
Oh. Okay, Mr. Peabody.
Oh!
Here you go, Mr. Da Vinci. Ahh!
Do you need any help?
No, no. That's quite all right.
Thank you.
Psst! Sherman.
Huh? Let's go. Let's go explore.
Uh, well, I'm
supposed to be having
father-son time with Mr.
Peabody.
Wouldn't you rather
have fun with me?
Uh...
Okay.
Sherman...
where are you going?
Exploring.
But we need your help.
No, we don't! I mean,
we can manage.
Somehow.
He's a boy, Peabody.
Let him have his fun.
Let him go.
Thanks, Mr. Peabody!
He's growing up, Peabody.
Like a baby bird
leaving the nest.
Isn't it wonderful?
It's like a museum.
It's like a toy store.
Wow.
Check this out.
It's the world's biggest
model airplane.
It's not a model, Penny.
It's a prototype.
And we should probably
just leave that alone.
Okay.
But wouldn't it be cool
if we could fly it?
I don't think Mr. Peabody
would like that.
Well, Mr. Peabody isn't here.
Just tell me how it works.
Please?
For learning.
Oh. Okay.
The thrust comes from this kind
of crossbow doohickey here.
Then it shoots along the track
until the wind catches the wings.
But how does it go? Huh?
How do you take off?
Oh, you just pull
down that lever.
This one?
Oh, boy.
Ah!
Wow! Whoo-hoo!
This is crazy!
No, it's not Sherman. It's fun!
We're gonna die!
Oh, stop being such a party
pooper and enjoy it!
Ah...
Nothing is as beautiful
as an elegant equation...
translated into
perfect engineering.
Why can't children be so simple?
Because children are
not machines, Peabody.
Believe me, I tried
to build one.
Oh! It was creepy.
Here, Sherman! You fly it!
But I don't want to fly!
Sure you do. It'll be fun!
No, seriously, Penny,
I don't want to!
I'm letting go. One...
Don't let go!
Two...
No! Three!
Penny, fly the plane!
No, Sherman!
You're going to have to save us!
But I can't do it!
I'm serious, Penny. I
don't know how to fly!
You can do it! I know you can!
Come on, Sherman.
Fly!
Ah!
Phew!
See? You got this, Sherman.
You're right. I have got this.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Da Vinci's at it again!
You ever see that child he made?
So creepy.
Papa. Mama.
All done up here, Leonardo.
And I am all done down here.
It is beautiful, isn't it?
Every piece in its place doing
precisely what it's supposed to do.
Look, Peabody!
It's my flying mach...
My flying machine?
Sherman.
Sherman?
Sherman, what are
you doing up there?
I'm flying!
But, Sherman, you don't
know how to fly!
I don't?
No!
Turn!
Turn, Sherman!
Lean!
Oh, no!
Sherman?
Sherman! Are you okay?
That was pretty fantastic!
Oh! I can't believe it!
My flying machine! It's work!
Sherman! You are
the first flying man!
Oh, you should be
very proud, Peabody.
Very, very proud!
"Proud" doesn't begin
to describe it.
Leonardo, will you please
fire up the mechanism?
Papa. Mama.
Mona!
The kid!
I'm sorry I broke the plane, Mr.
Peabody.
Well, you should be. You
could have been killed.
What are you talking about?
Sherman flew a plane.
He was amazing!
Sherman destroyed a priceless
historical artifact.
Whatever. You should be happy.
It turns out Sherman is not a
complete and total loser, after all.
Yeah, Mr. Peabody.
It turns out I'm not a complete
and total loser, after all.
Ms. Peterson...
stop turning my son
into a hooligan.
It's not my fault
he's a hooligan.
Yeah, it's not her
fault I'm a hooligan.
Well, it's certainly
not my fault!
I've spent the last seven years
teaching Sherman good judgment.
If you're such a great parent...
why is Ms. Grunion trying to
take Sherman away from you?
Is that true?
Is someone gonna take
me away from you?
No, Sherman, I'll never
let that happen.
You just need to trust me.
Oh, dear, a black hole!
What's happening?
If I can't pull
us out of here...
we're going to be smashed to
smithereens on the event horizon.
There's not enough power to
resist the gravitational pull!
I've got to divert everything
to the reverse thrusters.
Why didn't you tell me?
Tell you what?
Why didn't you tell me Ms.
Grunion
was trying to take
me away from you?
It's not your job to worry
about these things.
You just didn't think
I could handle it.
We'll discuss it later.
Now, sit down.
I don't want to
discuss it later!
Sherman, sit!
You can't talk to me like that.
I'm not a dog.
What did you say?
I said, I'm not a dog!
You're right,
Sherman, you're not.
You're just a very bad boy!
T-minus 10...
Nine, eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four, three...
Two...
One.
Sherman?
Penny?
Sherman, are you okay?
Sherman?
He's gone.
Where are we, anyway?
Oh, no.
We're on the brink of one of history's
most ferocious conflicts...
Delivery.
How are we doing,
heroes of Greece?
Feeling good?
Feeling strong?
Okay, let's get warmed up!
We don't want to pull
something out there.
Remember what
happened to Achilles.
That whole thing with his heel.
Looking good, Diomedes.
Menelaus, my man!
My man.
Are you ready to get on
the field, Shermanus?
Sure thing, Mr. Agamemnon.
That's cute.
Shh.
Odysseus, what
news do you bring?
Someone left this for us.
A present. Nice.
It looks just like our horse.
Should I bring it inside?
It would be rude not to.
I did not see that coming!
Ugh! Jeez Louise,
what is that smell?
Oh!
Ooh. That is the
smell of victory.
Yeah!
Victory!
Greetings, men of Athens,
Sparta and Thebes.
Peabody, here.
I've come for Sherman.
Do you know this guy?
I thought I did...
but now I'm not so sure.
Then he must be a spy. Kill him!
No!
He's my dad.
Your dad? Huh?
It's an adoptive relationship.
Aw!
Thank you for taking such good
care of my son, Agamemnon...
but it's time for
him to come home.
Sorry, Mr. Peabody, I've
joined the Greek army.
Shermanus is one of us now.
He's a brother. I'm his brother.
He's my son.
He took an oath. I took an oath.
He's seven!
And a half!
All sons must prove
themselves to their fathers.
Today...
Shermanus will prove himself
on the field of battle.
But he's only a child.
Your dad may not think you're ready
to become a man, Shermanus...
but we do.
Yeah!
Yeah, Mr. Peabody.
Now, I'll show you
what I can handle.
FYI, a lot of heroes
have father issues.
My old man is a minotaur.
Half man, half bull,
all judgment.
Ajax, here, strongest
guy in the world...
but his father never accepted
that his real dream was to sing.
I wanted
to be in the Greek chorus.
Uh, yeah, and don't even get
me started about Oedipus.
Let's just say that
you do not want
to be at his house
over the holidays.
It's awkward.
Sherman, I'm concerned you
haven't thought this through.
This is war. Do you realize
what's about to happen?
I'll tell you what's
gonna happen.
We're gonna destroy
their houses!
Pull down their temples!
And make the streets
of the city run red...
with Trojan blood!
Yeah!
Blood! Blood! Blood!
Zeus on three! One!
Sherman, I absolutely forbid you
to fight in the Trojan War.
It's not fair! All my friends
are fighting in the Trojan War.
Two! Sherman, it's dangerous.
I'm wearing a helmet.
Three! You're not going!
Oh, yes, I am.
Zeus!
Zeus! Zeus!
Eat my bronze, you Trojan dogs!
Eat my bronze, you Trojan dog!
Ahh!
Well, that's cutting it close.
This is why I ask you
to obey me, Sherman.
Because I'm your father, and
it's my job to keep you safe.
But are you sure Ms. Grunion
won't take me away?
Not as long as I'm around.
Mr. Peabody!
Help me!
Penny!
Smell my victory!
Smell it!
Hey! That's my ride!
Mr. Peabody...
hurry!
I'll take that.
You did it, Sherman!
Mr. Peabody helped.
Now, let's get to
the WABAC, go home,
un-hypnotize Penny's parents...
finish that dinner party,
eat my Baked Alaska...
charm the pants off Ms.
Grunion...
and make sure none of this ever
happens in the first place.
Sounds good.
I'm in.
Ah!
Sherman!
Penny! Sherman, no!
Whoa!
Mr. Peabody...
Mr. Peabody?
Mr. Peabody!
Dad!
Oh, Mr. Peabody! What should I do?
What should I do?
There's nothing you
can do, Sherman.
I just want to go home.
Home.
That's it.
I got an idea.
Come on!
Where are we gonna go?
We're going home.
There's only one person
who can help us...
and that's Mr. Peabody.
What are you talking about?
How is that even possible?
We've got a time machine, Penny!
I can set it so
that we'll get home
when Mr. Peabody is still there.
But I thought
you're not supposed
to go back to a time
when you existed.
What choice do we have?
Error. You are attempting to
travel to an era in which you exist.
This could alter the
fabric of space-time.
Error. Error.
Hang on!
This is fun!
This is a little homespun
concoction I like to call...
"Einstein on the Beach."
Yummy.
To the kids.
To the kids!
Mr. Peabody.
Sherman? Penny?
Can we talk to you a second?
Of course.
Excuse me.
I've really hit it off
with your parents.
I think we can file this night
under "Unqualified Success."
I'd hold off
filing it just yet.
What do you mean?
Why are you two dressed
like ancient Greeks?
You used the WABAC! I did.
I know, it's terrible!
But why?
Penny and I got into an argument
about George Washington.
So, I made him
show me the WABAC.
And I lost her in ancient Egypt.
And I got engaged to King Tut.
So, I came back and got you.
Then we ran out of gas.
In Florence. Went
into a black hole.
And then you died
in ancient Troy.
Died? I have a hard
time believing that.
It's true!
But now you're here, and
everything's gonna be okay.
I told you never to come back
to a time when you existed...
because there would
be two of you!
Yeah, but the other one of
me is in ancient Egypt.
Ahh!
Who are you?
He's you, but from
another timeline.
But I thought you said never to come
back to a time when you existed.
Exactly! I know.
But what was I supposed to do? Mr.
Peabody died in ancient Troy.
Died?
I have a hard time
believing that.
Thank you.
What are we going to do?
Well, for starters, both
Shermans can't stay here.
Why? We could get bunk beds.
I was thinking the same thing.
That's so weird. It's
like we're twins!
I was thinking that, too!
Ow!
You see? We can't have two
Shermans in the same timeline.
It puts too much strain on
the space-time continuum.
What to do? The Petersons
can't know any of this.
Hey, Pea-buddy.
Hey.
How's it going?
Patty and I are working
up an appetite.
Mmm. The smells coming from
your kitchen are yummy!
Especially that Baked Alaska.
So, what's going on here?
Yeah, what's with the getups?
Toga party!
Toga party?
Yes, it is a toga party!
Well, what about dinner?
I'm starving.
Why don't we head into
the dining room...
and tuck into those quails
you've been yakking about?
No! Why not?
Because it's so fun right here!
Whoo-hoo!
Ms. Grunion!
How delightful.
We were
having such a good time...
I almost forgot you were coming.
Oh!
Well, why don't you
join the party?
I'm not here for a party. I'm
here for the investigation.
Good. Why don't you start
investigating over here?
Or here, or here, or here...
Stop waving your hands around!
Sherman?
Wait! Is that...?
Sherman!
Dos Shermanos? What's
going on here, Peabody?
Oh...
Um...
Nobody move!
Sherman, I've got to get you out
of here before you touch yourself.
Mr. Peabody! You didn't die!
Of course I didn't die.
Thank you.
Hey. How did you get back?
Well, after a few
failed experiments...
I hit upon a combination of
bones, stone and yak fat...
and constructed a
rudimentary WABAC.
You know what they say...
"If at first you don't
succeed, Troy, Troy again."
This is no time for puns!
Even good ones.
Penny, Sherman, quickly!
You're not going anywhere.
I've seen quite enough
to remove the boy...
both boys,
from this home.
No, don't, Ms. Grunion, please!
This is all my fault.
I started it.
I'm so sorry, Sherman.
You have nothing to
apologize for, Penny.
A dog should never
have been allowed
to adopt a boy in
the first place.
Now, come along.
Ms. Grunion, be careful!
Ah! Oh!
What's happening?
Mr. Peabody, help!
Sherman! Sherman!
Oh!
Hey! Where did the other two go?
Our cosmic doubles combined
in order to reconcile a paradox...
in the space-time continuum.
Okay, that makes sense.
I don't know what
just happened here...
but I know it was wrong!
This boy is coming with me!
Mr. Peabody!
No, Ms. Grunion! Ow! Let me go!
Get back here!
Ow! Ow! You're hurting me!
Oh! Oh!
He bit me!
Yes, hello, police.
I'd like to report an assault.
A bite.
Mr. Peabody, what
are we gonna do?
Get here as
soon as possible.
Run!
He's kidnapping the children!
Oh!
I can't believe
you bit her, Mr. Peabody!
I know, Sherman, it was wrong.
"Wrong"?
It was awesome!
And now, to return to our proper
timeline and erase this mess.
There he is! He's got my daughter
in that giant space apple!
My face is numb.
Whoo-hoo! Yes!
What's wrong?
Time travel failed.
Oh, dear.
What is it, Mr.
Peabody?
Our cosmic doubles colliding...
ripped a hole in the
space-time continuum.
That's why we didn't
get to the past.
Hey, Peabody!
Looks like the past
is coming to us.
Oof! I will get you, dog!
And your little boy, too!
Penny!
My bride!
What?
Oh, dear.
Follow that orb!
Incoming!
What sort of creature are you?
The name is Grunion!
I'm in love!
I just need to find a wormhole.
Hey, Einstein, it's a red light.
Hey, I'm walking, here!
Cake!
Mmm!
There they go. Don't lose them.
I'm trying to find
another wormhole...
but they all lead
back to the present!
Time travel failed.
Whoo!
There he is. After them!
Penny, my queen, I
know you're in there.
We're coming, Shermanus!
Time travel failed.
Mr. Peabody!
Look out!
Whoa!
Shermanus, hold on.
We shall release
you from this egg.
Drop the saber and step away
from the futuristic orb.
I take orders from no man!
Don't tase me, bro.
Come out, Peabody, with
your paws in the air.
Mr. Peabody, you're
under arrest...
for kidnapping, reckless
endangerment...
And a multiplicity of
major traffic violations.
You don't understand.
There's a rip in the
space-time continuum!
If you arrest me, I
won't be able to fix...
Blah, blah, blah.
For too long...
you've bamboozled the world
with your fancy jargon...
and that little red
tie of yours...
and look what's come of it.
Take him away!
Wait.
Mr. Peabody!
Sherman!
What's gonna happen to Mr.
Peabody?
Don't you know what happens
to dogs that bite?
Let me go.
You don't know
what you're doing.
Please, before it's too late.
Wait!
Give him another chance.
He's through with chances. Now,
he has to pay for his mistakes.
But I'm the one who
made all the mistakes.
I'm the one who used the
WABAC without permission.
The only mistake Mr.
Peabody ever made...
was me.
Sherman.
You're absolutely
right, Sherman.
What kind of a father could
this dog ever be to a boy?
Maybe you're right, Ms. Grunion.
But there's one thing
you haven't considered.
What's that?
I'm a dog, too!
If being a dog means you're like Mr.
Peabody...
who never turns his
back on you...
and who's always there to
pick you up when you fall...
and loves you no matter how
many times you mess up...
if that's what it
means to be a dog...
then, yeah, I'm a dog, too!
I'm a dog, too.
I'm a dog, too!
I'm a dog as well!
A poodle dog!
I am a dog, too.
Ditto on that dog thing!
I'm a dog, too.
I am a dog as well.
I'm Spartacus!
All right, fine, you're all dogs,
but you can't change the law.
I know someone who can.
George Washington.
We hold these truths
to be self-evident...
that all men, and some
dogs, are created equal.
I hereby award Mr. Peabody
a presidential pardon.
Me, too.
I've done worse.
Huh?
Uh, Mr. Peabody, look!
Ahh!
Ooh!
It's getting closer!
What are we going to do?
This is the greatest collection
of geniuses ever assembled!
Surely we can come up with another
way of getting to the past.
I can build a catapult.
We go very fast.
But, remember, as you approach
the speed of light...
gravity will get too strong.
Oh, indeed. "For every action, there
is an equal and opposite reaction."
How about we just punch
that big hole in the face?
I have an idea.
Hey, everybody, I have an idea!
Yes, what is it, Sherman?
Why not go to the future?
The future?
I've never been there before, so
it's probably not as messed up.
Sherman, that's it!
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Not usually.
It's exactly what you
all just said...
except the total opposite!
If we set the WABAC for the
future, and go very, very fast...
we'll create our own
gravitational field...
that's equal and opposite...
to the rip in the
space-time continuum!
Oh, my...
I don't get it.
We're gonna fly up there and
punch that big hole in the face!
Yes!
Sherman, you're a genius.
But, Peabody...
how far into the
future must you go?
Just a few seconds
ought to do it,
and then we'll
slingshot right back.
Are you sure this
is going to work?
Don't worry, Penny.
Just remember, I'm a...
Genius!
Sherman...
I need to reprogram the WABAC.
All right, Mr. Peabody.
That means you have to drive.
In order to make the
leap into the future...
the WABAC will have
to go very fast.
Faster than it's
ever gone before!
Are you ready, Sherman?
I'm ready.
Come on, Sherman, you can do it.
Now, Mr. Peabody?
Sherman, we need more speed.
Now?
Just a little more!
Not yet, Sherman.
Not yet.
Now!
Whoa! Whoa!
Farewell!
Ooh!
You haven't seen the
last of me, Peabody.
You'll make a mistake
eventually, and when you do...
I'll be there!
The Grunion is mine!
Ooh!
Come on, Sherman. Come on!
Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
If you want to watch
television before I get home...
simply press "input"
three times...
and then use the remote
control as usual.
Yes, Sherman.
And if you're worried about making
friends at the PTA meeting...
consider bringing
snacks for everyone.
Bagels are always appreciated.
Yes, Sherman.
And remember, Mr. Peabody...
I have robotics club
after school today.
Sherman, wait.
Yes, Mr. Peabody?
I...
I love you, Sherman.
I have a deep regard for
you as well, Mr. Peabody.
Hey, Mr. Peabody!
Hey, Sherman!
Wait up!
No doubt about it.
Every dog should have a boy.
Oh!
Ooh!
Ah!
A-ha!
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the Grunion.
Come here, soldier.
There's always time for living
Can we just do it again?
One more time like it
once was way back when
You gave me something
to believe in
We were the best of friends
Well, I remember the
good times way back when
Memories will fade if you
wanted me to let you go
I've got you on your way I feel
it for you, don't you know
We're superheroes and villains
When we used to pretend
We'd go wherever our minds
would take us way back when
Memories will fade if you
wanted me to let you go
I've got you on your way I feel
it for you, don't you know
It's a promise that I
made Never be afraid
I know we'll be okay This
luck we have, it cannot go
'Cause you're on your own
You're not alone
I know I'll see you again Again
And if all these things
Come to an end
We'll always have
a way back when
Memories will fade if you
wanted me to let you go
I've got you on your way I feel
it for you, don't you know
It's a promise that I
made Never be afraid
I know we'll be okay This
luck we have, it cannot go
♪ HI Removed - bozxphd.Hope it Helped ♪