A girl on a chair with a glass of wine.
It's as if she's on a date.
- Who are you talking to?
- It must be L. H.
No!
- You see all my fault.
- Do not keep an eye on me all the time.
Can you do one thing for me?
Follow me away for the weekend.
How are you, my friend?
- Who is she?
- Sofia. She is new.
- You arranged imagination parties, huh?
- I have not done anything.
It is not him.
- You have destroyed yourself.
- I beat a fucking monster.
- You beat a sitting marked fairway.
- I have nothing, Mike.
Hunter sometimes hangs up deer
and to empty them of blood.
- It was probably what they did.
- Crawl forest at the site.
"The line between good and evil
runs through every human soul. "
Wake up, you pig.
Wake up.
- No no no!
- Shut up. Do not move.
Listen.
It gets you,
if you do not start talking.
- Okay.
- It was Amir, huh?
He warned you
to point him out.
No, he did not.
- Who was it?
- No.
Careful. There was none.
- I did it myself.
- Shut up.
It was well Amir
which you rented the premises to?
- Yes.
- It was ...
No!
Shut up!
Breathe in and start talking.
Give me the truth now. Talk!
Are you having breakfast?
Let's talk a little?
- I loved your mother and I know ...
- I know. We need to hold on.
- We can talk about it.
- We can not change anything.
It is as it is.
And I do not hate you.
I just have to make
how I'm going to like you again.
I need some time for it.
I study day today.
I'm going to Jessica's summer retreat,
so I will not be home.
- When will you come home, then?
- Tomorrow or on Sunday.
You may well Text,
so that I know that everything is fine?
Yes.
Hello. Yes, I go home now.
So see you soon.
Goodbye.
Göran?
Seal off here
and get technical here at once.
Hello.
- Are you ready for an awesome weekend?
- I can hardly wait.
Good. For now we'll check it out
from mobiles and Computers
-and be ouppkopplade all weekend.
It sounds absolutely wonderful.
You have not told anybody, huh?
Can I trust it?
- Yes, you can trust it.
- Can I do it? Good.
- Hello.
Do you want to buy a bottle of champagne?
So we can get to know each other.
I think
you are completely magnificent.
- You are an artist.
- Yes.
I'd like to paint you.
- You're kidding?
- An artist always tells the truth.
From the depths of his soul. Otherwise
one is a deceiver and useless.
Therefore, I want to paint you.
It would give me great pleasure.
It should never deny.
Do not you agree?
- I want twice as much.
- There will be.
- How did you know where I lived?
- I followed you.
- Why you do not live at home?
- She threw me out.
- Why did not you say something?
- That I drink, and play?
You knew well already.
We have to sell the house. I have not
been a good husband or man.
So you steal to pay
mortgages and gambling debts?
No, because I'm
a simple fucking thief. Grip me.
- You do well that you get caught?
- I do not care anymore.
Do you feel that life is shit now,
what happens when you get caught?
We are doing this ... Henry!
Somehow
we fix this with the home loan.
You can of course not stay.
Meanwhile, move in with us.
We have an extra room.
- Okay.
- Good.
- See you at home, then.
- You ...
It was not the first time
I beat the bastard.
What?
I wanted to give back
for all the crap they gave us.
So when Hammar fired me was
the end of a fucking shit.
World downfall
begins with small, small things.
But Henry ... Do not go, then! Damn!
- I have not done anything.
- You cut open her wrists ...
... And let her bleed to death.
You do not want to hear what you did.
Stop!
Hello.
He killed probably not Sophia,
but he's hiding something.
Yes, he's a pimp.
Without witnesses, we can not
keep him much longer.
Josephine
he has a residence permit?
I check.
- His case is under investigation.
- We use it.
- Give me a copy of it.
- Absolutely.
Hello.
- Was it difficult to find?
- No not at all.
- Is that the key to the house?
- Yes. I'll show you a little bit.
I do not see the inside.
Nähä?
I am an artist,
and it is natural I am looking for.
- And the silence, of course.
- Yeah.
- You take cash, I hope.
- Yes, I do.
- This should be enough.
- Even money, I hope.
Good.
Well, then you get to have it so fun out here.
Thanks, I will.
- How are things?
- Now we get this over with.
I have things to do.
Amir Alsuwaidi ...
You came from Syria
24 months ago ...
... And waiting clearance
for a residence permit.
- I have a right to be here.
- You are here now ...
... But not if we link up
a murdered girl.
It was not me who killed Sophia.
You are the pimp. The
who presented the murderer of her.
According to whom?
I know that.
I rented the premises to Amir.
He organized sex clubs.
I did not get involved,
for he is dangerous.
I will die if I go home.
- You can not send me back.
- I think so, actually.
Yes. It only takes a phone call.
- What do you know?
- Everything.
I arrange parties
where people live out their fantasies.
And then they return to everyday life.
- And Sofia?
- She was always fun to be with.
- There was a customer ...
- What's his name?
I have never seen his face.
- Come on.
- It's true!
He is always hidden.
He takes the money,
then I will arrange the imagination.
How did he find you? What?
- A friend recommended him.
- What's his name?
Her name is Asha.
Asha Warsame. She's my girl.
- She could not have known.
- Is she a fantasy girl?
- No. My girl.
- Where does she live? Write down the address.
We go there, but it takes
she tells who the stranger is.
- That's all I know!
- I doubt it. Tell me.
- Then you promise not to tell me.
- I can not promise.
I need to know what you know.
A corrupt police.
- The interests well you?
- Write down his name.
Write it down.
Göran Hansson?
He comes and lies
with my girl without paying.
Fucking scum.
And he was interested in Sofia.
- Can you prove this?
- He sells movies to me.
Sex tapes.
Are you satisfied?
So you kept him from a rooftop,
where people could see you?
- You crossed the line.
- I did not throw him down.
It was the only way to get the info.
That's not how we work.
You went over the limit.
I know. Talk to you later.
- What is it?
- We have a problem.
Amir revealed a corrupt police.
- From here?
- Yes. Göran Hansson.
Is it true? Do you have proof?
- We'll check it out now.
- He used to work well with you?
- But you never noticed anything?
- No, he seemed schyst.
If he is corrupt
he probably looking for something.
Go. Find out
if this is really true.
See you inside.
I'll just have coffee.
- It is the first time.
- Like what?
I feel
that you are hiding something for me.
Do you want to tell me?
- No.
- Okay.
This is Hanna. Say something.
It is the father. It's really important
you call. It has happened a thing.
- I thought we had a deal?
- What?
Yes ...
Give it to me.
Come on - it's more fun that way.
So.
- Do we have anything on the container?
- Blood consistent with Sofia Salas.
- What do we have?
- He was at a gas station an hour ago.
- Do you have his file?
- No remarks.
There is no Naivasha at the address.
- So Amir lied.
- She lied to him.
- She must go to find.
- We can ask Amir again.
We release him.
L.H. might be looking him up.
- Should we use him as bait?
- Sometimes you have to take risks.
Here are the cameras outside.
- He's somebody in your car.
- I'll find another angle. Here.
Damn.
He bought food, so he lives nearby.
I want a list of
all cabins nearby.
You can reach me on the phone.
Eklund! I'll go with you.
It is not necessary.
Help them to find Asha.
No.
- This is personal.
- Yes, and when you find Goran ...
... You will go over the limit.
And I do it better than you.
Come on.
- What do you think?
- It is absolutely fantastic.
I pack up.
Feel the water, so we swim ago.
- What do I do now, then?
- Have a seat.
And so we can show the breast.
Not the left - the right.
- Will it be good?
- Perfect.
Should we put in the time, then?
Well, so here it is ...
You are sitting on an Inn.
You have an admirer. He is a little
drunk but think highly of you.
- He has given you the wine glass.
- So I'll just sit here?
You laugh at him
because you like his attention.
- So we look a little that way.
- What do you do?
- What the hell is that?
- For the portrait.
Hell, no.
This does not feel good.
- Do not touch me.
- I'll just paint by you.
- Come on!
- No.
- Come on, Hannah.
- It's too cold.
- Wait.
- No, you are wet.
- Yes, we were supposed to swim, of course.
- I do not want.
Have you made them yourself?
Yes.
- Yes I have.
- Why?
In order to ...
To occasionally
is a pain better than another.
- Do you know?
- No?
- I have something to show you too.
- What kind of something?
That is my secret.
Staircase.
- Where are we going?
- Trust me.
Goran bought gasoline and food.
The treasurer remember him.
But he had never seen him before.
Hey, there are 42 cabins where.
We go through the owners now.
- I have him.
- Jonsson has something.
I have checked up George's family.
His mother named Anja Holgersson.
There is a cabin owned by her
south of you, at the lake.
We might have him. Hurry up.
- Are you ready?
- Yes, I am prepared.
You know what I want to do?
I want to film us when we love.
I want to do everything ...
... As we ever dreamed of doing.
And I want to film it.
I would like to
that we can have it forever.
I want to do everything
that makes you feel alive.
- Why?
- Because I want you.
I want to have you forever.
Whatever happens in the future.
No, I do not like it here.
- I can not do this.
- Wait!
It makes very painful. Let me go.
You said you would do
everything that I asked for.
Yes, but I can not do this.
Oh well.
But ... I do not understand.
You wanted
that we would try again.
- You've pushed for this.
- Not for this.
There you damn certain!
But take your clothes
and go from here. It is perfectly okay.
So ...
You, like this:
We actually have something that is good.
We have,
as you might have to work on.
But if you go from here now ...
... Then there's no more you and me.
Then you are dead to me.
Death.
Thank you. A home owners saw a man
assaulting a woman in the woods.
- Send it to violence.
- She was dressed as a peasant maid.
Text me the address.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Drop the knife.
I do not want to shoot you!
Camera equipment.
Where is she?
Where is Hanna? Where is she?
Reply!
No no.
- Where is Hanna?
- Calm down.
- It's okay.
- Okay. Stop.
- Where is she?
- She has stuck from here.
Hello?
- Where are you?
- I'm with Jessica.
I know you were with Goran.
Are you okay?
Yes, please, I'm fine.
I can not talk about it.
- Should I pick you up?
- No. Can we do this later?
SexFilm are Amir was talking about ...
We found them on George's computer.
A whole lot of ill movies
of young girls.
- interrogated him about Sofia?
- Nothing binds him to her ...
... L.H.. or something of the other murders.
We take him for bribery, illegal
threat, gross misconduct, purchases of sexual services.
- How's Jonsson?
- He looks to be okay. Okay.
We should not be seen when you're done?
To go through everything ...
No, I do not want it.
- Are you okay?
- Yes. It's Jonsson, who is injured.
- How are you, then?
- It's okay.
There is a lot of evidence.
All right.
- Can I get photos then?
- I send them away.
- Is that OK?
- We sew it, so it heals nicely.
What happened?
Nothing.
Henry Renberg.
Leave a message.
Henry, do not you call back?
You ...
Everyone makes errors.
It is human.
We can do this - I promise.
We fix it,
as we have always done.
How did you know?
- Do you hate me yet?
- Not yet.
Okay ... A few years ago
I was working undercover.
I was looking for
an arms dealer in the Bronx.
He was horrible,
but he had a beautiful sister.
She had long, red hair.
I'm a sucker for redheads girls.
We fell in love.
She was fantastic.
I told him I was a policeman,
and she accepted it.
She chose me and not her brother.
And the evening
when we would grab him,
- She wanted that we did it at
her, so he did not do anything.
The Task Force was outside
waiting for my signal.
They were waiting for my signal.
But they screwed up. He saw them,
and all drew their weapons.
It was chaos,
and both he and she were shot.
There was blood from her head.
Much blood.
There was so much that I ...
tried to push it back.
The last thing she said was my name.
Then she died.
She died there.
In my part of the world
you should take care of people.
I also got to learn
not to forget my own.
But there, I forgot.
Maggie was mine.
And I did not take care of her.
Now I no longer own.
In this way, mister, I no.
There was little about me.
There was little about this and about us.
Do you hate me now?
Tell me how I do not get it there
to a farewell ...
... I promise
To really give it a chance.
I do not know how ...
... You do not
can get it at a farewell.
Thanks for the whiskey.
- You killed me.
- You are wrong.
I knew you would die
but did it anyway.
Do not you understand?
I am the police.
Translation: Mark Smith
www.btistudios.com