'In a word, the bourgeoisie
creates a world in its image.
'Comrades,
we must destroy that image.'
'A spectre is haunting Britain,
the spectre of communism.
'All the forces
of the old and new imperialism
'have entered into a holy alliance
to exorcise this spectre:
'British Petroleum and pop music,
'the Eurodollar
and anti-trade union laws,
'Elizabeth the dunce
and Wilson the traitor.'
'The bourgeoisie have destroyed
all human relationships,
'except those of naked self-interest
'and the callousness
of cash on the line on the never-never.'
'Masses of labourers
herded into factories and offices
'are organised like soldiers.
'As privates of the industrial army,
'they are put under the command
of a hierarchy of sergeants and officers.
'Not only are they slaves
of the bourgeois class
'and the bourgeois state,
'they are daily and hourly enslaved
by the machine, by the overseer
'and, above all, by the individual
bourgeois manufacturer
'and his representatives.
'The more openly this despotism
proclaims gain to be its end and aim,
'the more petty, the more hateful
and the more embittering it is.'
'But does wage labour
create any property for the labourer?
'Of course not. It creates capital.
'That is, that kind of property
which exploits wage labour
'and which cannot increase,
'except upon condition of obtaining
a new supply of wage labour
'for fresh exploitation.
'In bourgeois society
'human labour is but a means
to increase accumulated labour.
'In communist society
'accumulated labour
is but one means
'to widen, enrich and promote
the existence of the worker.
'In bourgeois society
the past dominates the present.
'In communist society
the present dominates the past.
'For the worker
'labour and the expression
of the power of his labour
'is his own vital energy, his way
of making his life meaningful to himself.
'And this, his vital energy,
is sold to a stranger
'in order to obtain
his necessary means of subsistence.
'Hence, his vital energy is transformed
into no more than a means to exist.
'He labours in order to live.
'Work is not part of his life,
it is a sacrifice of his life.
'It is merchandise
sold to the highest bidder.
'This is why what he produces
is not the aim of his labour.
'What he produces for himself
is not the car he assembles,
'the oil he extracts from a well,
nor the luxury hotel he builds.
'What he produces for himself
is the wage,
'whilst the MG, black gold
and the Hilton
'dwindle to a precise quantity
of essentials,
'whether a bicycle,
two gallons of petrol, ten cigarettes
'or a room in a council flat.
'To claim that the worker has an interest
in the speedy growth of capital
'only means that the more the worker
'rapidly increases the riches
of the capitalist,
'the more substantial
the leftover he receives.
'The more workers one engages
'and makes them reproduce,
'the more one multiplies the mass
of slaves under the yoke of capitalism.'
'Hence, as the satisfaction
of work decreases
'and loathing for work increases,
'competition between workers grows
and wages fall.
'Workers try to maintain
their relative wage
'either by working longer hours
or by increasing the rate of productivity.
'Driven by fear
they multiply the disastrous effects
'of the division of labour.
'The result is the more one works,
the less one receives,
'for the simple reason that,
by competing against his workmates,
'the worker turns them into competitors
'who will sell themselves into conditions
equally as onerous as his own.
'For when all is said and done,
he, as a member of the working class,
'is only competing against himself.'
'In 1368...'
'...peasants led by Tyler...'
'...and Ball...'
'...rose against
feudal oppression.'
'In 1648...'
'...peasant soldiers...'
'...called Levellers...'
'...fought
for the new cooperative...'
'...cooperative commonwealth.'
'Workers must understand
that existing society,
'with all the misery it heaps upon them,
'also gives rise to the material
conditions and social forms
'necessary
to its economic transformation.
'They must replace
the conservative slogan,
'"A fair day's wage
for a fair day's work,"
'with the revolutionary slogan,
"Abolition of the wage system."'
'In 1791...'
'...artisans...'
'...formed a free association...
'...to forward the ideas
of the French Revolution.'
'In 1844...'
'In 1844,
'cotton workers
seized and held their town...'
'That's correct.'
'The relation of man to man
'is imparted through the relationship
between man and woman.'
'There is a science
of the image.
'Let's begin to build it.
'Here are some pointers.
- 'Materialism.'
- 'Dialectics.'
'Documentary.'
'Fiction.'
'War of national liberation.'
'People's war.'
'...less likely to be unionised.'
'The present setup of the family
puts great strains on us.
'Either we're struggling
to combine badly paid work
'with bringing up a family
'or unable to do work
for which we've been trained.'
'Ideology and beauty.'
'The area of taboo on
our sexuality is much more extensive
'and the double standard
is still pervasive.
'Some women
still never experience orgasm.'
'Hitler and Hollywood.'
'When we complain,
'it's about little things.
We want to drive buses. Play football.
'We don't want to be brought
with bottles or expensive wines.'
'Exploitation of women.'
'We don't want
to be wrapped up in cellophane
'or sent off to make tea
or shuffled into the social committee.
'When you complain
about the little things,
'you get stuck in the little things.
'It's difficult to get out of them.
- 'It's difficult to get beyond them.'
- 'The jungle of sex.'
'They can be dismissed
because people say,
'"Well, you're just trying to be as men."
'But it's the little things
which happen to you all the time
'every day,
wherever you go, all your life,
'which make revolutions.
'Revolutions are about little things.
'It's here that the subordinated
relates to the dominated.'
'The problem of women.
The problem of the farm labourers.
'Here the experience
is felt, is expressed,
'articulated,
resisted through the particular.'
'Man. City.
Woman. Country.'
'The particular
pummels you gently into passivity,
'so that you can't even see beyond
the little things, beyond the particular.
'We don't how to find one another
or ourselves.'
'Freudian revolution.'
'We are divided like
oppressed groups..'
'Marxist sexuality.'
'divided by real situations
'and in our understanding
and consciousness of our condition.
'We're in different classes,
as we devour and use one another.
'Emancipation is often
only the struggle of the privileged
'to improve
and consolidate its superiority.
'The women of the working class
remain the exploited of the exploited,
'oppressed as workers
and oppressed as women.
'We're divided, too.
'Sometimes we're with families
and sometimes we're without them.'
'In 1919,
Lenin refused four days of rest
'to women workers
during their periods.'
'...is suspicious
of the women with no ties.
'She sees her as a threat, a potential
threat to her territorial security.
'And the single woman feels the married
woman is being subtly critical of her
'because she's not fulfilling
her role as homemaker,
'her function as child bearer.
'She feels that she's being accused
of being unable to be a woman.
'They tell us what we should be.'
'Marxist-Leninist analysis
of the most natural position to fuck.'
'...we're under
intensive pressure to be acceptable,
'not to put ourselves
outside the safety net of marriage.
'We're taught from small girls that failure
means not being selected by men.'
'Sexuality and surplus value.'
'The sign of intelligence
and subtlety
'is being able
to secure the contractual bargain,
'handing over your virginity
for a marriage document.
'Orgasm is a matter of merchandise.
They don't like us to be too clever.
'Remember, you might go to university,
but men want someone who can cook.
'The emphasis in our education
tends to be much more on integration.
'The encouragement of active criticism,
of intellectual aggression, is very rare.
'It's the cautious virtues
which predominate.
'This is difficult when you find yourself
in an intellectual confrontation with men
'because there's a double bind...'
'Proletarian eroticism,
for a family to love a woman profoundly.
'Bourgeois eroticism, to sleep
with as many women as possible.'
'It's very difficult to stray
from the definition of what they want
'because there's a danger
of being rejected in a double sense.
'You're not only rejected as a rebel,
'but you're rejected
for a moral reason too.
'It's much more difficult
to cope with the moral thing.
'There's still the whole dirty
frightened patronising world
'behind slut, tart,
old slag, nymphomaniac,
'dolly, bird, chick,
bit of stuff, bit of crumpet,
'old bag, silly cow, bluestocking.
'These words have got
no male equivalents
'because there are
no male equivalents.'
'In 1841...'
'...the first mining unions...'
'...is founded.'
'...limited liberated areas.
'You give up struggling
on every front
'and you ease
into a niche of acceptance.
'You become the educated housewife
with your cooking recipes.
'Or the image of the suffragette,
which is a distorted image,
'tweedy, sensibly struck by...'
The educated housewife
with her recipes!
'...advancing aggressively
in a male world in the boardroom.
'The sexual oppression of this
is to be treated...
'It's a profound distaste for the male.
'Emancipation becomes simply
doing without men.
'Sexuality is another retreat.
'You haven't had the choice, the free
choice, of what to do with your bodies,
'because they've been part
of somebody else's belongings.
'You prove that you have got control,
that you are liberated,
'simply by fucking.
'But if you can't extend the definition
of your constraint beyond this,
'you're in an even worse hang-up
'because you're just caught,
you're reacting.'
Well, she says that's not emancipated
enough just to go around fucking.
'You're reacting
not because you're trying to say,
'"I want to be something else."
You're just reacting to...'
'In 1911...'
'...Liverpool Town Hall...'
'...is stormed by strikers...'
'...and their wives.'
'...through your class.'
'Conceal your sex.'
'"Times," "Pravda," "Figaro."'
'Keep the existence
of workers' councils a secret.
'BBC, Radio Moscow,
France Inter.'
'...when they talk
about the subordination of women,
'that it's part of the total, mutual
devouring process called capitalism.
'They've said that capitalism
forces people to eat each other...'
'Miniskirt
and counterrevolution.'
'That the false relationships
'between men and men
and women and men,
'are part of this process.
'But sometimes this has been twisted
into a rather glib distinction.'
'The revolutionary silence
of lovers. Bureaucratic verbiage.'
'They've said,
"Wait till we get the revolution,
'"then we'll deal equality."
'"We'll give you equal pay,
and we'll give you nursery schools."
'Another thing they've said is that
the way that women are subordinated
'is through the family...'
'Solitary pleasure
and fascism.'
'...through
a particular kind of historical process,
'which developed
along with capitalism.
'And therefore they've said,
'" When we abolish capitalism,
'"we can then go on
to abolish the family."'
'Sexual perversion
and Stalinism.'
'...so you can't do anything about it.
'And in a way you can't do anything
'about any of the situations
of capitalism, ultimately.
'But in every other area,
'in the situation of the working class
or in the situation of Negroes,
'where there's an idea of struggle...'
'Neurosis and revolution.'
'You work firstly
for reforms
'and then you put forward
strategic demands.
'These are kinds of reforms
which cannot be granted in the system,
'but they lead on
to new kinds of possible alternatives.
'And it seems that it would be
a good thing to apply this to women.
'That is by asking certain things,
you not only get a better condition,
'but you expose the inadequacies and
the contradictions within the system.'
'Sometimes
the class struggle is also the struggle
'of one image against another image,
'of one sound against another sound.
'In a film, this struggle
is between images and sounds.'
'1926. General strike.'
Workers have come to expect
too much.
High wages, short hours,
the whole lot.
We've got to produce them cheaply.
That means
keeping workers' wages down
until we, the employers
who really run the country,
decide that higher wages
can be afforded.
...bad industrial relations.
Productivity and trade
are being sabotaged
by unofficial strikes,
go-slows, work-to-rules.
...very bluntly
to these wreckers and shirkers
that there's no place
in this country any more for saboteurs
who are out to prevent their fellow
workers from serving their employers.
From now on collective agreements
between unions and employers
will become enforceable by law.
Those who refuse to play the game,
those who are intent
on disrupting the economy,
will be dealt with by industrial courts
and will pay the price
like any other common criminals.
'Organise.'
The capacity of British business
to hold its own in the world.
If families have to wait a few years
before finding somewhere to live,
then they'll just have to wait.
And as for education...
...the nation's youth need to be trained
to play their part in industry.
This is the age of the specialist,
the technologist, germ-warfare expert,
graduate policeman
and management in industry.
These people have to be trained.
Aren't they filling their heads
with a lot of fancy ideas
that only give them
an exaggerated idea
of their own importance?
They behave
as if the world belonged to them,
as if the world owed them a living.
'Organise.'
What about respect
for their elders and betters?
All these young hooligans
seem to think about is sex and drugs
and running wild in the streets.
'Unite.'
We must call a halt
to this so-called permissive society.
The students don't only want a bigger
slice of the cake, they want the whole...
Most students are glad
to be at university
and are willing to do some work
in return for the money
the country pays them.
Many of them foreigners here
at the taxpayers' expense
who are not at university to study,
but to disrupt
and undermine British institutions.
These academic thugs, these window
smashers, these policemen baiters,
we will deal with them very severely.
Those who attack our institutions,
who destroy respect for authority,
who spread discontent and anarchy,
who claim that they should control
the places of education,
they're lucky enough to attend,
as if these pipsqueaks
could run anything,
all of these communist rabble
must be swept out of the universities
and out of the headlines
they love to hog so dearly.
Let's repress
these long-haired sex perverts
and make room for decent,
respectable, clean-living young people
who understand
that politics and education
have nothing whatever
to do with each other.
Send the offenders to labour camps.
They'd soon learn how to work there.
And as for the war in Vietnam
they're always going on about...
'Organise.'
...step by step as this war has gone on,
we've agreed
with what the Americans have done.
'Unite. Unite.'
A magnificent sacrifice
of men and money
in the defence of our freedom.
They want a fight.
So let's give them one.
War's a nasty business.
People are going to be killed.
But I believe we must take this risk.
In this kind of game
it's necessary to shoot and bomb.
Sometimes it is necessary
to burn women and children.
Sometimes to torture people.
Sometimes to slice their stomachs
open and cut women's breasts off.
Let's not kid ourselves,
you fight wars to win them,
by whatever means are necessary.
And we don't like coloured people
and I'll tell you why.
'Organise.'
...money and materials
into their primitive homelands
because they simply
can't handle their own affairs.
If the people of India breed too fast,
it's no concern of ours.
We're supposed to feel sorry for them
because they're starving.
Well, some of us don't feel sorry,
we feel glad.
Let them starve. Let them die.
Let them starve at least or...
'Strike. Strike.'
Built factories,
sent them tanks and tractors,
helped them build
and run their governments.
And in return we don't just take
the raw materials we need,
we buy their shoddy clothes
and trinkets too...
Perhaps in the house next to you,
with their laziness,
promiscuity and sordid homes.
Now, we're not racialists,
but the way these people live is filthy,
as you'd see
if you went to look at the backstreets
of Wolverhampton today.
These people just don't accept
our standards of civilisation.
They live in filth and squalor.
They breed like rabbits
and they suck our social services dry.
Unless we put a stop
to the influx of this horde,
our cities will soon be so full of aliens
that we won't recognise them.
...seeing whole areas of our land
transformed into alien territory.
'Workers, strike! Strike!'
...people who very often
don't even speak our language,
who are unable
to adapt to our way of life,
who persist
in maintaining their native customs...
The immigrants themselves
suffer from the racial bitterness
that is created when they swamp
our houses and our jobs.
In their interest, as much as ours,
let's send them packing.
Let's sterilise them.
In fact, and this is really
the simplest solution of them all,
let's exterminate them.
Let's kill these people, too,
like the old-age pensioners,
like the Vietnamese,
like anybody who interferes
with the democratic progress
of big business and capital.
Thank you and good night.
'A political film must analyse
what it has discovered,
'just as Lavoisier analysed oxygen,
discovered by Priestley,
'and Marx analysed the theory of value,
discovered by Ricardo.'
We had a system
where, on the moving line...
...the quicker you worked,
the more space you had in hand.
The more space you, you had in hand,
the more time
you would have to do your job.
But if you got a bad job,
if you were doing a job where,
we'd say, you had a cross-threaded nut,
it meant you were knocked
straight back down.
In other words, you had a point
where, if you went further than that,
it meant that you were in trouble then
because you had to work twice as hard
to get back to the original position
of where you started.
So, consequently, two bad jobs
would knock you
right back down the line,
so it was constantly a question
of advancing or retreating.
Er... the one dread you had
was that if you did get a bad job,
you were going
to be knocked back down the line...
'In 1650...'
'...Cromwell announces...'
'...the new Enclosure Acts...'
'...driving them
off the land into poverty.'
Nobody else could do it
at 30 an hour.
There wasn't a man made.
This bloke had grown up with the job
and he could do it.
But there wasn't a man made
who could, er...
...who could do this job
at 30 an hour.
To this day they've got
about three people doing this job,
which one man used to perform
because they couldn't find another man.
They couldn't slow the line down
to teach him.
They couldn't teach him
at 30 an hour.
There's a perfect example
in the mine itself,
where you've got
a senior steward on nights
when he's called into the office
to take up a case...
'In 1834...'
'...workers from Dorchester...'
'...are shipped into bondage...'
'...for being members...'
'...of a trade union.'
You can never
overcome industrial problems
whilst they belong
in the hands of the employing class.
The only way that you can ever
overcome any industrial problems,
indeed, in this country,
is the question of the property
relationship of the industries concerned.
I think that management
realises the hardships
that night work puts on workers
because they're prepared
to pay their own staff...
Their own staff gets
eight pounds a week on nights...
'The fraternity
of hostile classes,
'proclaimed in the speeches
of industrial magnates,
'inscribed on the blackboards
of grammar schools and universities
'and transmitted by television networks
'is based upon the exploitation
of one class by the other.
'Its genuine, authentic
and prosaic expression
'is civil war in its most hideous form,
the war between capital and labour.'
And when they used to shake hands
they used to stand about ten feet apart.
Their arms would stretch.
This is an absolute fact!
And if you go in Morris Motors,
what it is...
'In 1872...'
'...a dockers' strike...'
'...broken
by gunboats and troops.'
The atmosphere
of depression
was absolutely awful.
My daughter said to my wife, she said,
"Mum", she said, "is daddy dead?"
she says,
"No, he just works at BMC."
You can get the effect from a person
actually working on the 1100.
He puts window... window winders on.
He has ten screws
to put in each door.
He makes up 2,200 screws a night
himself and puts them in.
He's got just...
just over... over two minutes
to... to do one car.
And this, this...
Every job, 2,200 screws a night.
That man goes home in the morning,
straight to bed.
Even when gets up that's all he can
think on. He can't do anything else.
He has to use his breaks...
'1888...'
'...Bloody Sunday
in Hyde Park.'
Ah, you're a lazy car worker!
I go off then to the pub,
have a drink.
I don't even bother to change.
I'm too tired for that.
- Your senses are dulled.
- Just dulled, yeah.
'Street demonstrations
lead to a tumult,
'which inevitably affects
the most forlorn
'and timid sections of society.
'Many are the times
we will be bludgeoned in the streets.
when the government will be the victor.
'But the more they triumph,
the more certain their defeat.
'Victory today
prepares their final defeat.'
The point about
the psychological effect
of piecework on human beings,
I mean, can be seen very easily
in the conflict between human beings
when they're on piecework.
I mean, I-I-I know of a case
where the mildest,
most non-aggressive man
you'd ever meet in your life,
after having worked
seven hours' piecework,
hit one of his mates over the head
with a pump screwdriver
because he'd tripped over
the air line.
This is the sort of thing that's
continuous and the tension is enormous!
There's one point on the 1100 line
where five men get into a car at once.
Yeah.
There's arms and legs
everywhere...
'In 1901...'
'...the Taff Vale decision...'
'...almost destroys...'
'...the trade union movement.'
...whether they continue
with this job or lose the job
because it's a reasonably high-paid job,
but it needs to be
because of the effort that goes in.
'In 1915...'
'...the first shop steward committees...'
'...the first shop...'
'...shop steward committees...'
'...steward committees...'
'...were set up.'
...this system of society of capitalism,
where all wealth
is in the hands of a few individuals...
'In 1919,
'Luton Town Hall
is burnt down by the workers.'
If the boss wants
to automate it, the workers resist it
because it throws them out of a job.
The boss on the one hand and the
capitalism, this dilemma for the bosses,
if they bring in
completely automated plants
that could release all us
for more productive work
and to spend a better life,
what it means is that they haven't got
any people to sell the cars to.
So you've all got
to be stuck in the blasted places,
hammering on things
and all you do is producing for profit.
I mean, you take 1960.
I mean, we were all put
on three days
and in 1966 there were 1,300 sacked
and yet I wanted a car and dozens
of other people wanted a car.
Yet because we didn't have the money
to buy them and nobody could buy them,
everybody is sacked.
This is capitalism.
As far as I'm concerned,
we've got to have a socialist world.
We've got have a world
where the production is planned
for the benefit of all the people
who live in the world.
Well, this is it.
"The Times" has produced figures,
not so long ago,
of the idle rich
and the profits that they're living on.
And just purely living off the interest.
They're going
to the racecourses and that
while we're slogging our guts out
in the factories.
It's about time that we had a distribution
of the wealth in this country
and there's a fairer share for all.
It's not fair that we should be working
our fingers to the bone
day in and day out
while these people
are at the racecourses and elsewhere.
'The basic error
of modern social democracy
'is to suppose that all one has to say
'is that there is a place to speak
for that place to exist.
'Whereas the problem is to create
the conditions for that speech.
'Speech as the expression of a power.
'Everyone may agree
to allow the right to speak,
'but no one, no one,
will allow it to be taken.'
So capitalism surely
is much more even than this.
Capitalism is far more
than just the inequality of wealth
within a capitalist nation state.
It's far more than this.
I mean, capitalism is that.
Capitalism to exist
must have millionaires
and it must have people
who are impoverished.
It must have this,
but more than that, more than that,
it must internationally have sections
of the world which are impoverished.
'My sympathy
for the solitary terrorist
'halts where tactics begin.
'But where ten men gather together
in the cause of creative violence,
'rather than
of the painful agony of survival,
'their despair ends and tactics begin.'
The workers thought
that they were putting into power
a socialist government
that would implement...
Yeah, I'd say they did!
Every man that voted Labour
is suddenly awake, all of a sudden,
to realise that it is
not a socialist government.
It is a capitalist government!
It's a better
capitalist government!
'In 1916...'
'...the government threatens...'
'...to send striking workers
to the front.'
Ramsay MacDonald done it.
He cut the dole in 1931.
You've got the Tory party
that is swinging rapidly to the right,
which will be under the leadership
of Enoch Powell,
which will be
a right-wing racialist government
of the type that Hitler
had in Germany.
So what's before the working class?
Do we carry on supporting
these tired old traitors? No, we can't.
What is needed in this crisis
is the building of a new political party
for the working class.
A political party
that is committed to Marxism,
that is committed to communism,
that is prepared
to lead the working class
in their struggles to overcome
all these other parliamentarians.
'The Vietnamese people's struggle
'is the first wave
in the tide of world revolution,
'the culminating point of the common
struggle of all labouring men.'
...for 18 months.
And without any previous knowledge
of what was going on,
I was tapped
on the shoulder one day.
This, mark you,
was after 18 months
and, as I say, having drawn out
a mortgage on a 4,000 house,
they tapped me
on the shoulder and said,
"Would you go to the office?
Collect your cards.
"Take a week's notice...
A week's pay in lieu of notice."
And I was out on the road,
believe you me,
before you could say
"Jack Robinson".
I didn't know what hit me, actually.
'To break with the Hollywood system
'induces a radical change
of aesthetics.'
'Is the Marxist concept
of surplus value the best weapon
'with which to unmask
the bourgeois concept of presentation?
'The first task of the anti-imperialist
cinema is to answer that question.'
A word that goes with...
High and low.
Something less specific.
- If you want to replace...
- Stop the record.
If you want to replace...
Look, if you want to replace...
The whole point of the song
is I say "high" and you say "low".
It's two opposites.
So if you want to replace it, you've got
to put it with something that is opposite.
What are you trying
to change it round to anyway, exactly?
Well, from what it is to...
You can substitute some very nice
things like "Ho Chi Minh" and "Castro"
and things at the end of the lines.
- Look, it's got to be a...
- Has somebody got a fag?
It's got to be opposites all the way
through. "You say US. I say Mao."
"You say..."
Uh-uh. I've got a feeling
this is going to end up in tragedy.
"You say war..."
No, you can even say,
"Say US. I say Mao."
Wait a minute.
Let's think of an opposite.
"You say..." What?
- Let's make it meaningful.
- US...
Yeah, you've got to say, "Look,
I'm a fascist and you're a revolutionary.
"I'm a reactionary
and you're a revolutionary."
So, "You say US, I say Mao.
"You say, you say war..."
I think, actually,
that if I say "ho" instead of "no"...
"You say Vietnam and I say..."
Something that compels.
Yeah, but it doesn't fit in
because "stop" is a very short syllable.
You've got to have something...
We're not having xxx in it.
The ruddy guy's a bureaucrat!
Hang on.
No, "You say Nixon, I say Mao."
No. No, that doesn't go.
"Say US."
"Say US when I say Mao."
'In 1947...'
'Labour government...'
'...Labour government...'
'...end a dock strike.'
'Television and films
do not record moments of reality,
'but simply dialectics,
areas of contradictions.
'Let us illuminate these areas with
the blinding light of the class struggle.'
'In 1947...'
'...workers
opt to go on strike...'
'...in protest...'
'...against lack...'
'...of housing.'
'Good.'
'Self-evident truths
belong to bourgeois philosophy.
'There are neither self-evident images,
nor images that speak for themselves
'in the way the Russian revisionist films
'and the mass-circulation magazines
in the West pretend.
'There is only a fabric of contradictions,
whose pat...
'There is only a fabric of contradictions
'whose pattern
comprises the whole of society.
'To make a film is to penetrate this
fabric by following the correct line.'
'In 1949...'
'...the government
decided to spend money...'
'...on arms
and not on housing.'
'...on arms and not on housing.'
Yeah, so if you say,
"You say you want a revolution,
well, we know...
"...you never want to change the world.
"You tell me... You say it's evolution.
"Well, you know..."
"Well, we know
you don't want to change the world."
It's a good idea
to stick "the constitution" in somewhere.
- Yeah, why don't we put...?
- The constitution.
"You say you'd change
the constitution."
It comes further down, actually.
We don't want a constitution.
Can we write beside it?
- Lovely!
- That again!
That... I really like that.
"We're fucking up the institution."
Can you play the guitar?
'1968.'
'Bill Locker...
'...and the trawler men.'
'1968.'
'LSE.'
'Hull.'
'Hornsea.'
'Guildford.'
'Cambridge.'
'Essex.'
'Bristol.'
'Good.'
'Photography
is not the reflection of reality.
'It is the reality of that reflection.
'Photography was not invented
by chance,
'but on the day the bankers of reaction,
financing railways and telegraphs,
'invented modern means
of mass communication.
'That is, when the bourgeoisie
found they needed,
'by other means
than painting and the novel,
'to disguise reality to the masses.'
'1968.'
'No job and still no job.'
'The party controls the gun.
'Production controls
consumption and distribution.
'If a million prints
are made of a Marxist-Leninist film,
'it becomes "Gone with the Wind".'
'1888.'
'General strike.'
'During the projection
of an imperialist film,
'the screen sells the voice
of the boss to the viewer.
'The voice caresses
and beats into submission.
'During the projection
of a revisionist film,
'the screen is the loudspeaker for a voice
delegated by the people,
'which is no longer the voice
of the people.
'In silence people see
their own disfigured face.
'During the projection of a militant film,
the screen is no more than a blackboard,
'the wall of a school offering concrete
analysis of a concrete situation.
'In front of that screen,
the living soul of Marxism,
'the students criticise,
struggle and transform.'
'1911.'
'...tanks and gunboats...'
'...are used
against women and children.'
'The history of mankind
'is one of continuous
development from...'
'...to the realm of freedom.'
Well, it's a nice tune.
In a small way,
I think it's very reactionary.
And, and...
In fact, they're putting over an ideology,
putting over a capitalist ideology.
Actually, look.
I mean, just to show exactly that
this song could be quite revolutionary,
we could, in fact, rewrite it probably,
and put over
completely different ideas.
It could be putting over
a completely different ideology.
...to the million-dollar songs.
You're not making me crazy.
"You're not even a money pie,
you're just crazy."
No, you're not crazy...
She's not making him crazy.
"Honey pie, your position is tragic.
"You've lost all the rest
of the person you were.
of the person you were."
There isn't any magic in your...
Yeah, this is fucking awful.
'Seizing the revolution with
one hand and production with the other.
'What does that mean
for militant filmmakers?
'It doesn't mean
bringing films to the people,
'but making films
from and through the people.'
'But there is only one way
to eliminate war
'and that is to oppose war with war,
'to oppose counterrevolutionary war
with revolutionary war,
'to oppose national
counterrevolutionary war
'with national revolutionary war
'and to oppose counterrevolutionary
class war with revolutionary class war.'
'Wherever there is struggle,
there is sacrifice
'and death is a common occurrence.'
'People all over the world
are now discussing
'whether or not
a world war will broke out.
'On this question, too,
we must be mentally prepared
'and do some analysis.'
'Of course, the atom bomb
is a weapon of mass slaughter,
'but the outcome of a war
is decided by the people,
'not by one or two
new types of weapons.'
'Ideological education
is the key link
'to be grasped in uniting the whole party
for great political struggles.
'In any society in which classes exist,
class struggle will never end.
'In classless society the struggle
between the new and the old
'and between truth and falsehood
will never end.'
'The oppressed
peoples and nations
'must not pin their hopes
for liberation
'on the sensibleness of imperialism
and its lackeys.
'They will only triumph
by strengthening their unity
'and persevering in their struggle.'
'We have
the Marxist-Leninist weapon
'of criticism and self-criticism.
'We can get rid of the bad style
and keep the good.'
'Fight, fail, fight again.
'Fail again,
fight again till their victory.
'That is the logic of the people.
'The people's democratic dictatorship
'needs the leadership
of the working class,
'for it is only the working class
that is most far-sighted,
'most selfless
and most thoroughly revolutionary.'
'The masses
are the real heroes.
have boundless creative power.'
'Solidarity with the wildcat strikes
'of Ford's workers at Dagenham
'against the fascist laws
of Barbara the Scab.
'Solidarity with the struggle of the
revolutionary students and the teachers
'at the London School of Economics
'against the Gestapo
of the humanist university.
'Solidarity with the artistic offensive
launched by open films and agitprop
'in the factories, on building sites
and in council flats.
'Solidarity
with "The Workers New Daily,"
'"The Newsletter,"
'and the efforts of the printers
and editors of "Keep Left"
'to provide news that is real news.
'Solidarity with the squatters'
occupations of empty flats
'and houses in Ealing
'and the help given to them
by the anarchist movement.
'Solidarity with the courage of our
Maoist comrades in their determination
'to politicise every anti-imperialist
street demonstration.
'Solidarity with the wages rises
won by the dockers and railwaymen,
'which will aggravate
the commercial deficit
'and make the arrogant jackals
of the City howl with rage.'