Creating Destiny
Episode 31
Mom.
What?
Bring forward the wedding?
Maybe tomorrow,
let's get their wedding done.
Why?
Why are you doing this?
Ah, that is...
We won't be the only ones
keeping Sang Eun with us,
I want Yeo Jun to be with her
as soon as possible.
It's good to add one more to our family.
Yes, I see, that's why Yeo Jun says
he wants to go to America?
Yes, that seems to be the case.
What should we do, Mother?
What else can we do?
Let's do according to the children's wishes.
I have already given approval to the wedding.
Yes, Mother,
I approve of their wedding too.
Why are you looking at me?
Now, Noona, you are the problem.
Don't you know?
What illness is Sang Eun's mother having?
Why do you have to know that?
Are you going to object to their
wedding because of this illness?
Honey!
Hey, if you dare speak nonsense
again then I'll really...
divorce you, do you understand?
Final Episode
Here, cappuccino.
Do you think I can swallow this now?
At such a time, you must keep your spirits up,
your sister's fighting it too.
Is there really no other solution?
Aren't you a doctor too?
Well, I don't know of a solution.
I knew it.
You're just useless.
It's not that I'm useless,
but this surgery is tough for anyone.
Then what's going to happen to my unni?
Hey,
if I can heal your unni's mother,
can you not go to America and marry me here?
What did you say?
Marry me!
If I settled this matter,
let's get married.
Your call cannot be connected right now...
Doctor,
who will do this operation?
Why do you care about this matter?
Sang Eun is your wife, isn't she?
Of course I care.
My wife!
Are you out talking nonsense again?
If only the director can do the operation.
No matter how I look,
no one else can replace him.
The director is at Seattle right now.
How did you know that?
Don't I have ears?
That's the problem.
Looks like we have to transfer her
to another hospital.
Director's on the plane, coming back now.
Oh, you don't have to get up.
No, I should.
My heart was worried so I came.
Since I know about it,
I can't just let it be.
This is not something for you to worry about,
Yeo Jun's mom.
My health has always been like this.
But why aren't you agreeing to do the surgery?
When I first heard the hospital telling me
it's cancer and a difficult operation,
I thought it was a justified punishment
for my abandoning Sang Eun.
How can you say that?
It's not like you did it purposely,
you didn't even know she was alive,
others who are worse than
you are still living happily.
I too,
said horrible things,
from my perspective for my child's sake.
So I feel a little guilty.
I mentioned things I shouldn't have said.
I'm sorry, Sang Eun's mother.
No,
please show favor to my Sang Eun.
That's the only wish I have.
Dad, I want this one.
Let me see.
Isn't this a little heavy?
What do you think?
It's pretty and looks sturdy too.
Jin Ju, you want this one?
You like it?
We'll take this and those other stuff too.
What do we buy next?
I need stationery too, over there.
Now, everything's ready, right?
But what about a lunch box,
don't we need that too?
Not sure. It's such a rush,
does she need a water bottle too?
Jin Ju's really starting school now.
Yes, I was so excited when I received
the school's notification of acceptance.
It was just a piece of paper.
Now, being with Jin Ju is so great.
I lost out so much in the past,
I'd never thought I'd be a father myself.
Yes.
I don't know why I'm so nervous.
She's still so young, will she do well?
No problem, she's our daughter, you know.
Dr. Kim.
Director, I thought you were
on your way to Seattle?
I heard there was a difficult operation
waiting for me so I came back.
I tried so hard to reach you but in vain,
how did you find out?
Well, because this fella called me.
How exactly are you related to the patient?
I told you she's a family member.
If this surgery fails,
I won't get to marry, Father.
Father?
I didn't ask you.
Dr. Kim, is she a parent to you?
What? Ah, yeah.
She's my future mother-in-law.
I've looked at her medical reports,
it's not easy.
You know that, right?
Yes, I know.
Let's make all the preparation,
and decide on the surgery schedule.
Yes.
Your mom wants you to call.
All this time, thank you
for watching over this stupid fella.
Get busy now.
What's this?
Professor Min is your father?
Yes.
Impossible. How can you...?
Who do you take after?
Why can't you believe I'm his son?
So why did you hide it from me?
My father refused to let me reveal it.
If I'm not careful,
the whole hospital might find out.
But since I'm showing some result now,
I guess it's alright.
That's true,
I think I can appreciate
the director's sentiments.
How he must have been so burdened,
not to be able to reveal this in public!
Doctor!
No matter what you say, Hyo Eun is out!
- Hyungnim!
- Hyo Eun is out!
Now,
did you tell him I keep hitting your head?
I'm going to tell him now.
Doctor! Hyungnim!
Stay lying down.
I heard the surgery has been scheduled.
Dr. Min told you?
Yes.
He chats with me occasionally,
I think he likes Hyo Eun.
He's so impulsive.
But don't count on him too much,
Hyo Eun will be wasted on him.
When will your family
members come from America?
They must be very worried too.
They will arrive before the surgery.
They were shocked about
why I changed my mind.
I really wanted to attend
your wedding before the surgery.
We plan to get married after your surgery.
So if you want to attend the wedding,
recover well from the surgery then.
I want to show you something.
What is it?
It's one month after the surgery.
It's held at the hospital here so
you can attend it without any worry.
When did you get that ready?
You fixed the date yourself too.
I told you, I can't wait any longer.
Hesitating, going back and forth like this.
Why? Aren't you happy with it?
It's not about whether I'm happy or not,
Grandfather and Grandmother will
surely blow their top about this.
No matter what,
the date cannot be changed.
I've made arrangements for everything.
It's still a little tight on time,
how can we get everything ready?
That's why our honeymoon has to wait,
I can't get away from work.
And Mother-in-law will
still be warded here too.
You're really thorough in your planning.
Of course, I've always been very meticulous.
But Mother's surgery will be fine, right?
Yes, don't worry.
I can't help worrying.
I really hate hospitals.
What can you do?
Now, your husband is a doctor too.
That's right.
Yes, I mentioned this the last time,
marriage is out.
This marriage is detrimental to us.
I never ever make such a bad deal.
Dad!
Am I some product?
What deal are you making?
Can you explain why it is a bad deal to you?
What is it you can do for our Hye Rim?
It seems nothing at all.
Well...
I heard you're so busy with work,
so you have no time to
take care of our Hye Rim, do you?
And the elders in your family is a problem too.
We can handle it well.
What's the use of just talk?
His family member even left home,
why must you find your way in then?
That's exactly what I mean.
There might be a chance
if you leave home like your brother,
otherwise no way.
Of course.
Since we're done talking, you may leave.
I have to make a trip to the beauty salon.
Stepmother!
I'll come on time to get you.
If your mother doesn't feel well, just call me.
- I'll come right away.
- I know.
Thank you.
Mother-in-law, don't tire yourself out
before the surgery, alright?
I know, my son.
Yeo Jun is such a good man.
That's him now, he wasn't
like this at the beginning.
I know.
I heard you guys quarreled a lot.
Quite a lot, all right.
If I stayed with you for good,
what is it you most wanted us to do?
Nothing special to others, I guess,
like picking out your clothes,
tying up your hair,
my daughter linking arms with
me on a walk, things like that.
I have such memories actually.
Yes, that's great.
In Australia,
on weekends when my friends and their moms,
go to museum galleries or amusement parks,
Hyo Eun and I only get to go to the park.
I didn't get to appreciate paintings,
so I've always been envious.
I don't know how to appreciate paintings too.
Even so,
just looking at you is good enough for me.
Shall we sit?
After the surgery,
I think I can call you 'Mom'.
Hyo Eun already calls you 'Mom',
did you know?
Yes, I know.
That you're not all alone,
I'm so grateful there's Hyo Eun with you.
I've always been so curious about
how and who you grew up with.
I was too ashamed.
Just once before I died,
just look at you from afar and leave.
But I got greedy when I saw you.
To fill my eyes with you,
to talk to you
and to hold you.
I will wait for you so be well.
If you left me again this time,
I'd really get angry with you.
The surgery's tomorrow?
Yes, Sang Eun is with her mother right now.
Have you heard from
Yeo Jun about the wedding?
Did he say he wanted to marry right away
and gave you the invitation card too?
Yes, too soon,
it's ridiculous to marry right away.
There's nothing we can do,
Yeo Jun already fixed the date.
Whether we're there or not,
they will get married.
Yes, no matter how much they want it,
what are we doing to do?
What else can we do?
Let them marry then.
We need to make preparations,
we can't skip that.
Where to live?
She can just move in here.
What else is there to prepare for?
Let them live apart,
why must they live here?
Daughter-in-law!
- If you hate Sang Eun that much, let's just...
- No, it's not like that.
Yeo Jun and Sang Eun both
have their own jobs,
if they lived here, it'll be tough on them.
I don't want to bring other people's
daughter in here to suffer.
So have you been suffering all this while?
Yes, Mother-in-law, it's tough.
Since we're on this topic,
of course it's better for two persons
to live alone.
Also I heard from Yeo Jun that Sang Eun's
mother can't go to America right away,
so Sang Eun will be kept busy.
Just let them live apart, Mother-in-law.
Did you have fun?
Long overdue.
Well done.
What?
Everything.
Yeo Jun.
Yes, Mother-in-law?
There's something else I want to do
before I go back.
Kyu Han, no single shots.
No need for that yet.
Yes, no single shot
but we'll do family shots then.
What are you doing?
Yes, Yeo Jun should be in the picture too.
Alright.
When you get married,
I won't be in the picture.
Mother-in-law.
With cancer treatment, I'd lose my hair.
I'd look terrible.
Before that, I'd take a picture with
my son-in-law looking good like this.
Ready, 1... 2... 3!
- Oh my.
- Aigoo.
What brings you here?
Am I not supposed to come here?
This is my daughter-in-law's house.
Who is your daughter-in-law?
Since my granddaughter is here,
of course this is my in-law's house.
How can you act as you wish?
I've always been an unreasonable man.
I'm going to have my way again
this time so I came.
I already told Yun Hee
but there was no response.
So I thought maybe there was
family objections.
Well, it's not that we object,
Yun Hee hasn't decided yet.
Then the elders should chase her,
what are elders for?
Please give Yun Hee to us.
It wasn't so long ago he objected
to her now he wants her.
That was then, it's been so long
after that now.
You have your grandson, granddaughter
and even a great-grandchild in your house,
don't you feel sorry
for my son who lives alone?
And I who live in a big house alone,
don't you feel sorry for me?
- Ah, really.
- What?
So you want them with you after marriage?
Can't I?
No, you can't.
Definitely not.
Then I will lie down right here in this house,
no matter how, I won't leave
without my daughter-in-law.
Let's go.
Oh, Father.
This stupid kid, let's go.
Father.
So, you will be getting married?
Is that true?
Not right away but we will in future.
I'm sorry.
I should have informed you earlier.
Sorry.
Why wait for later?
Just get married now.
Yes, isn't it better to do it
before Jin Ju starts school?
We should let Yeo Jun get married first.
Can we do it at the same time?
You can sure do so.
Mom,
I'm finally getting married for the first time,
unlike someone who's
doing it second time round,
am I adopted so I do it in a hurry?
I want my second marriage
to be a good one with smiles.
And I'm busy currently,
orders for new products
have risen significantly,
Uncle can't manage by himself.
Yes, do things appropriately.
Earning money is good,
but to neglect the family while
earning money, that's not good.
I understand.
I will never make this mistake again.
And once the current things are all done,
I will take care of Jin Ju and Yun Hee
for the rest of my life.
To me, nothing is more
important than the family.
Alright, that's good.
Now I can trust you and give Yun Hee to you.
Thank you, Father-in-law.
But about this marriage thing,
it is her decision,
I have no power over her.
Mother-in-law, I will be good
to Jin Ju and Yun Hee too.
Of course, what else will you say?
But will you move home after the marriage?
Will you be living with your father?
Stay calm, you will collapse
if you go on like this.
Why hasn't the surgery ended yet?
I shouldn't have been stubborn
and just followed her to America.
I still don't know what she likes,
we have yet to go traveling hand-in-hand,
we haven't slept together neither,
nor have I told her I love her.
You can still do all that, surely.
Everything you want to do,
your mother will be able to do it.
Sang Eun, your mother is fighting hard
in there by herself,
you mustn't waver out here.
We can't give up yet.
I made a mistake,
I should have called her 'Mom' everyday,
I should have called her that.
How's my mom?
The surgery went well.
The parts it spread to, have been removed,
the cancerous parts have been
taken out successfully too.
Her condition is good,
you can expect a good recovery.
Thank you very much, Director.
Thank you, thank you.
Are you awake?
Mother-in-law.
Can you hear me?
That's good.
Sang Eun was so anxious.
Mom.
You've worked hard.
I didn't do anything,
Director, you did the surgery.
You knew how risky the surgery was, right?
Without God's help,
she may not have survived.
You and your fiancé must have moved God.
Oh yes, I heard you're getting
married soon, congratulations!
Thank you, for everything.
[3 months later]
You are my love
Open your heart
and let me shine in you
So that my heart towards you can grow
What time is it?
Oh dear! We're late.
Mother.
Hey, you're leaving without breakfast again?
Yes, we're late.
Why are you late everyday?
The two of you work so hard,
are you taking care of yourselves?
We're leaving now, Mother.
Sang Eun...
- I'm sorry, Mother-in-law.
- Come over here for a minute.
- Drink this.
- What?
You skip breakfast therefore
you must at least drink this.
And mine?
You're late, right?
Go get the car first.
Sang Eun, drink slowly.
Alright.
This is the x-ray for a typical case
of rheumatoid arthritis in the knee.
Different from osteoarthritis,
the bones aren't eroded
and the bone around the joint...
You look very busy.
Not just look like, I'm really very busy.
I've drafted out the contract,
and I've prepared the materials for
the special lawsuit case, alright?
Okay.
But don't perform too well,
recently there's been rumors that
you're working so hard,
while I'm enjoying the fruit of your labor.
Performing well as a newly-wed too.
Yeo Jun?
Yes, this cake is good.
Oh honey, the phone's ringing.
Hello, this is the rice cake shop.
Welcome.
Ah, yes. Yes.
Noona is inside.
- I know.
- Welcome.
- Yes, thank you.
- Yes.
- Please look around.
Why come back so early?
Take Sang Eun out to a restaurant,
then go visit her family.
You're really... treat your wife better!
- Was that Yeo Jun?
- Yeah.
You're too nice to
your daughter-in-law, aren't you?
That child is so well-mannered and obedient,
at times she's closer to me than a daughter.
Why are you laughing?
They say when people change, they die.
Don't you remember not too long
ago you objected to this marriage?
After she became family, I realized
there are no others better than her.
Is that why you don't bother
about the rice cake shop anymore?
I saw Bok Man having a good time there.
I've been doing it for 30 years,
I'm sick of it already.
Luckily, Bok Man and his wife reconciled too.
I decided to spend time at home instead.
Without ordering
your daughter-in-law around?
You're really... she's so busy,
why get her to do housework?
She's so busy that
my heart's already aching for her,
told her to live apart but she wouldn't.
You're so lucky.
The rice cake shop's doing well
and you got yourself a smart daughter-in-law.
What else is there to worry about?
Why?
Kyu Han's not intending to settle down?
Well...
Ah, what time is it now?
- It's past 3pm already.
- Oh my.
Hey, you just came, you're leaving already?
Hey Jin Hee!
Kyu Han, Kyu Han!
I thought so.
You didn't go again?
Oh, what wrong with you!
Aigoo, I forgot.
There are some things you shouldn't forget.
You know how hard it was for me
to fix up this matchmaking session?
You know how good a woman she is?
But you stood her up!
I was busy.
I won't forget next time, I'll show up.
How can you be so laid back?
Your sister's about to marry
into a rich family, you know.
Hye Rim is going to marry that man?
I don't know.
No matter how much we object,
she insists on marrying him.
That's worrying.
What will happen to her
if she marries into that family?
Thank you so much.
- Have a good day.
- You too. Bye.
I'm not late, am I?
Earlier than I expected.
I didn't want you to wait,
so I dashed over like the wind.
Really?
Let's go eat.
Mother wants me to take you out.
Kalgooksoo*?
(*knife-cut noodle soup)
Am I being punished again?
No,
I just feel like eating this today.
Is it true you just feel like eating this?
That's what I said.
If there's anything you're
upset about, just tell me.
I will apologize or explain for it.
I feel like eating this, that's all.
But I feel like eating soojaebi* too.
(*dough soup)
Whether it's kalgooksoo or soojaebi,
I can have it for one meal.
Wow, you can really eat.
For dessert, would you like
red bean bread and cake also?
Cake...
Shall we?
Please give your approval, Father.
But Hyo Eun doesn't want to,
what am I to do?
You ridiculous man.
Really.
Hyo Eun, what do you think
of this young man?
What can I think about?
Just so-so.
She thinks you're so-so.
So you'll get just 71 points, dang!
Grandfather!
If there's anyone else
who's better qualified than me,
So what kind of qualifications have you got?
The one who did the surgery for
that aunt was my father, right?
Then we should just thank your father.
Why must I marry you, Chul Ho?
Yes, that's true.
That makes sense, that's right.
Hey, so are you going to marry my father?
You should marry me, of course.
Ah, that sounds correct too.
But I...
- We're here.
- Yes.
Sang Eun, you're here.
Sang Eun,
hey Yeo Jun,
why did you come along?
Just let Sang Eun come on her own.
Father-in-law, that's too much.
Have you eaten?
Yes, we have.
Why do you keep bothering
my sister-in-law?
Brother-in-law, settle it for me quickly.
It must be really quiet at that health center.
I'm busy, you know.
Doctor, the rest won't help me
but you ought to help me, right?
Whether you want to marry or to date,
finish your studies first
then I'll think about it.
But what do you possess that
I will give my sister-in-law to you?
Doctor...
Hyungnim!
Aigoo.
This is my room, how dare you enter!
Hyo Eun, let's get married.
Didn't you hear Yeo Jun oppa?
He told you to finish up
at the health center first.
I have to stay there for some years,
you know. How can it wait till then?
That's what I mean.
So how long must I wait for you?
Why wait? You just have to leave
and go somewhere, that'll work.
The air in my hometown is really good.
Hey, let's get married, alright?
Han Hyo Eun!
- I told you no!
- Why not!
Ah, really! Ah! Ah, really!
We have to check it out.
Two of them in there alone.
Don't bother, every month
they put on the same show.
Sang Eun,
does Grandmother mistreat you at all?
Aigoo, Father-in-law, really.
- Really!
- Nothing like that,
she treats me so well.
I don't think so.
The grandmother at your in-laws
doesn't have such a nice personality.
Although I approved because your mother was
sick and we got your wedding done in a hurry,
I will still keep an eye in future.
If ever one drop of tear flows out of
my Sang Eun's eyes,
you will cry 100 drops of tears of regret,
do you understand?
Sang Eun is not one to just cry, you know.
Yes, my daughter sure has a violent temper.
Oh yes, have you seen your mother?
Of course, whenever I have the time I go.
- What? What?
- What?
Father, Hyo Eun is violent enough,
why do you teach her Judo too?
My arm's about to break.
I haven't used all my strength yet.
Yes, you haven't used all your strength yet.
That's why I'm never worried
about my granddaughters.
You learn Judo too?
I'm at a higher level than Hyo Eun too.
What's wrong with our family
that you have to keep objecting?
Well...
Your family is not the usual family, right?
I'm not sure what you may have heard,
it's all in the past.
Actually we're hoping for a son-in-law
who will marry into our family.
This man has only Hye Rim, one child.
That's fine.
I have one other son,
although he keeps me worried,
we've decided to live together.
Really?
So you mean it's not a problem?
Yes, just one daughter-in-law
is good enough for me.
Ah, Yun Hee?
Is it true they're getting married next month?
Well, that's good.
For the sake of Yun Hee,
it's better not to have Hye Rim around.
- Honey!
- You scared me.
But is it alright for you to approve so easily?
It's all the same,
people think they're the most special in the
world but the world revolves without them,
and they think money solves all
the problems but it's not true.
I know I've done too many things
I shouldn't have.
So I've told my younger son that
he should do whatever he likes.
I didn't expect that he
likes working in the company.
Do you mind that?
The most important thing is that he likes it.
If he likes it, he should continue to do it.
So I'll take him as my son-in-law then.
But do you quarrel like this everyday?
Father says I can go back to school.
So?
But I don't want that,
I'd like to work in the company.
That's fine.
Do the work which you like to do.
Then I'll be really busy.
Is that alright with you?
We'll just be busy together.
I'm confident I can be a good wife to you.
You will do very well,
you always try your best.
I like busy men,
I like ambitious men too.
But if you should stray,
I will make you disappear
without anyone knowing.
To keep my life,
I mustn't go astray then.
So about your mother-in-law,
there's nothing to worry about, right?
Of course she has to continue with her treatment,
this is only the start of the treatment.
- You must spend some effort.
- That's right.
Your mother-in-law is family too, understand?
Yes, I understand.
Sang Eun, are you not feeling well?
You don't look too good.
I don't think my stomach's
agreeing with the kalgooksoo.
Kalgooksoo?!
I told you to take her out to a nice restaurant,
and you got her noodles instead!
It wasn't me,
Sang Eun insisted on having it so we went.
Why are you looking at me like that?
If you must find me guilty,
I'm only guilty of eating it with her, that's all.
It's alright, I'm fine.
Aigoo, oh dear.
Go on up and rest.
- Why do you still sit here? Go on up.
- Yes, go.
Alright.
Aren't you going with her?
She's not feeling well as it is.
Do you know how uncomfortable
an upset stomach feels?
Aren't you a doctor?
You don't know anything.
Who does he take after?
Why? Are you still feeling sick?
I should have guessed.
You ate so much noodles,
of course you'll get indigestion.
This won't do, take some medication.
Forget it.
I'll just drink some plum tea.
Strange, why is my stomach
so uncomfortable?
What?
Strange.
Pregnant?
Aren't you?
Of course not,
it's only been a few days.
It can't be!
You're too slow as usual!
Where are you going?
Hospital!
Look at the time.
What's wrong with now?
It's already 11pm. You can't be telling me
to go to the ER for being pregnant, right?
But what if you're really pregnant?
Why? You don't like children?
No, I like children.
I'm the only son in 5 generations, you know.
Then what's wrong?
Of all the cuisines,
why must it be noodles?
That's true.
So for the next 10 months,
you'll just eat noodles?
Judging from today,
I think so.
What? You hate it?
No, I like it.
When did you get here?
Have you settled all the problems?
Yes, all settled.
Since I was in LA,
I bought the master franchise for America.
Now you, I and Jin Ju,
our family can truly be together now.
Even though your father said
I don't have to get anything,
I'd like to get the bed,
study table and wardrobe changed.
And the sofa at the upstairs
lounge has lost its bounce too,
can you pass the message to him for me?
You went to our place?
Yes.
Yun Hee!
What?
So you're really going to live at our place?
You don't have money, right?
No matter what, I'm the elder
daughter-in-law in your family, right?
Moreover, what if that cunning
Hye Rim changes her mind?
I'm afraid if I don't move in there,
Hye Rim will do so.
What?
I'm so moved.
I... I'm eyeing your family assets,
since my husband himself is so poor.
No, I mean this feels like
we're back to old times,
like how naggy you were years ago...
Naggy?
it's how sweet and happy,
always with a smile on your face,
everything's good about you.
Is that true?
It must be, except for those 6 years
I suffered because of someone.
Sorry, sorry.
Yun Hee! Yun Hee!
Mother's birthday cake...
Uh, that... that...
Uh... come downstairs.
- Yes.
- Yes, yes.
That's right,
today is my grandmother's birthday.
That's why they say daughters are useless.
I didn't help my mother with anything.
Then our next child should be a son,
no, we should have twins.
You! Go on!
I know. Oh, more patrons here now.
Welcome!
Yeah, please sit over there.
So my great-grandchild will be born soon.
What do you mean by your great-grandchild?
That's my great-grandchild too.
Sang Eun's child is my great-grandchild,
of course.
Mother, Father-in-law,
who cares whose great-grandchild that is?
Anyhow, it's good news for our family.
Sang Eun's mother, how do you
feel being a grandmother now?
I'm already very happy as it is.
In-law, you must look after yourself.
Then you can see how
grandchild will act coy to you.
Have some tea.
- Does it taste good?
- Yup.
Go sit down.
You're pregnant now, you know.
You can't be doing so much.
I'm fine, Mother-in-law.
Who says you're fine? Go and rest.
Everyone's so busy and I have to lie down,
I won't feel good, Mother-in-law.
I told you to live apart but you won't listen.
It's better two of you live apart, right?
It's better to live with the elders.
And Yeo Jun says that
we move to America next year,
he will serve my mother too.
Yes, that's fair.
Only daughters-in-law should suffer?
As a daughter-in-law, I never suffered,
but Yeo Jun may have
to marry into my family.
Aigoo, let him suffer it out over there.
You, make sure you have full control,
don't be like me.
She's already got her hold on me.
Really?
So you think that's not enough?
Be good to your wife.
So that you'll live a good life.
Yes, Mother.
Yes, my honorable wife.
Will that do?
We're here!
See, they're always late.
Can't they be here earlier?
But why must I sit here with this old man?
Aigoo, did you think
I like sitting here with you?
Our birthdays are a week apart,
I didn't want to trouble the kids,
so I'll just celebrate my birthday with yours.
Anyhow, I just don't like it with this old man.
Old...?
If I ever step into this house again,
Sang Eun, let's go.
Father-in-law, be nice.
You guys keep this up,
we'll head straight to America
and you both won't get to
see your great-grandchild.
Oh this...
- Ah, Please bear with it.
- Mother-in-law.
Aigoo, Father-in-law!
That's nothing to me but
a big problem for your grandmother.
What's a problem for me?
I believe I'll get to see
my great-grandchild get married,
but that's going to be impossible for you, right?
Gosh, aren't you naggy?
You want to live till then?
This world is so good, why should I leave?
Pretty old ladies everywhere here.
What I'm trying to say is,
how about we share the rest of our lives?
I'll introduce to you a stylish
and handsome old man too.
Aigoo, stop saying such stupid things.
Blow out the candles.
It's traditional cakes, you see.
But why didn't we use cakes from our shop?
Ah yea yeah...
The next birthday, we'll use western cakes.
The combined age of you two is 150 years,
happy birthday.
We hope you two have live till 150 years each.
Wishing you good health and long lives.
Yes, wishing you good health and long lives,
Father and Mother.
Thank you, thank you.
Madam, let's put our faces
together and blow out the candles.
Happy birthday.
Good health and long lives!
- Grandmother, Grandfather, wishing you long lives.
Wishing you good health.
Wait, have we all done it?
I'm sorry I'm late!
It's not time for you yet, right?
But since it's a happy day,
I'll accept a bow from you.
- Live a long life!
- Grandfather, wishing you long lives.