Three years earlier.
Sergeyevich found him.  Hiding in the jungles of Burma.
In a Karen village.
Largo lived there for three months.
They met earlier, when he  illegally crossed the border
between Thailand and Burma.
She took him to her village to heal him and he never left.
While he's there I'm counting on you to watch him
And if he returns?
Freddy don't say anything.  One day,
he will have to come out of hiding.
Like it or not, Largo is my successor.
Three years later.
God, oh my God!
Autonomous Republic of Bashkortostan .
Use the GPS to find the airport.
This press conference was a total failure.
I shouldn't have offended Nazachov.  He won't forget it.
Bring me that sonofabitch, Winch!
And bring that damn journalist!
Is it really necessary to go so fast?
D'you prefer to let them kill us?
Find the airport!
- I want to..
help, but I don't understand Cyrillic writing.
Let me do it.
I don't want to die here!
I have a wife and four children, I have a career.
I graduated from Harvard, so I hired you, huh?
He's right.
The route is wrong.
Turn left..
You were right, Nazachov is a little upset.
It's all your fault.  You made
him angry with your stupid questions.
That's my business, I'm a reporter.
And I do my work lady, a Managing Director
of a company with 394,000 employees.
Don't you care if Nazachov is a crook?
The contract I was supposed to sign with
Nazachov was vital for all these people.
Look out, be careful!
What are you doing?
No!
- Wait!
After 100 meters, turn...  - What are you doing?
The satellite connection has been lost.
Your plane is surrounded by police.
- Forget the airport!
Nazachov will never let us go!
In this country, everything belongs to him.
Police, military, everything!
- And in your opinion, is that normal?
Maybe..just shut up!
I know a guy who will get us out of here.  Lazarevic.
A mercenary,..a specialist in crisis situations.
Expensive, but effective.
Bosnians are often overly sensitive!
Be careful with your team choices.
This could easily turn into a massacre.
Lake Leman, Switzerland.
Hello, sir.
- I met with Mr. Jung.
He's waiting.
Come in, come in.
Thank you for seeing me.
We meet, eventually.
Mr. Jung, it is time for your medicine.
- No, later.
I told you later!
She has an exaggerated concern for
me,..it's probably love.  Help me.
Look.  This picture was taken here.
You guessed it.
I think you were my father's only friend.
Ah..  oldest friend, yes certainly.
This photo was taken in October 1947.
He had just arrived from Yugoslavia with his mother.
They both lived here under this roof.
Your grandmother remained in the
service of my parents, until her death.
My grandmother?
Yes, Nerio's mother, your grandmother, Largo.
I think I was the only one who knew of her existence..
Moreover, Nerio cried when she died.
Although he did not want to know he has a mother.
Please!
Relationships between parents and children are not always simple.
Nerio did not want a son.  He wanted an heir...
and gave me no choice.  Now
this property that he left me, I will use it my way.
I read your letter, the plan is amazing.
As a former president of the
Red Cross, I can only be excited, but...
But?
In our world, humanitarian organizations are owned by powerful people,
and so it always has been.
The rich give money to the poor, but little.
Very little.
If you decide to give the entire fortune to charity,
Largo, it will cause disruption.
So?
- You will make many enemies.
Very many.
And..  very influential.
A man with no enemies has no value.
A Boznian Proverb.
You cannot even keep track of it all.
Mr.  Jung.
Mr.  Jung?
Syringe, syringe!
It's there.
I'm glad we met.
- You'll be fine.
My wife died of cancer 10 years ago.
My son died in an accident.
It's now been almost three years.
No one else has needed me.
I need you.
Hong Kong
You brought me back to life.
Monsieur, captain just said
we passed the limits of territorial waters.
Thanks Gauthier.
Gentlemen...I will open some champagne.
Do you have a preference?
For this occasion, I recommend the bottle from 1901,
that your Dad received personally from Mikhail Gorbachev.
at the paper factory opening in Minsk.
On the other hand, as bad weather
is expected make you want to try...
pink champagne, the Laurent Perrier 2003
- Gauthier.
Whatever you decide.
Yes, Monsieur.
Please...
Not without regrets, Largo?
The sale is irrevocable,
in addition, the signing of
your access to the group accounts
until the completion of the transaction will be blocked.
While waiting for access to money from the sale, you will be poor again.
This is a standard contract, Mr.  Winch.
Kronberg Partners that I represent,
and you will be bound for two months to
guarantee that the transaction price will be indexed to the value
of the shares since the contract was signed.
If the transaction would take place today...
it's value would be, for example, 53 billion Mr.  Winch.
That's all?
If the stock rises, you will receive much more.
Just kidding Mr Beaumont.
Your initials and signature.
I did not really understand why signing should be done in the middle of the sea.
This allows us to conclude the contract
in Switzerland, where Kronberg Partners offices are located,
so under the tax laws of this country.
Just your signature.
Stop the boat immediately!
Attorney Francken would like to talk with you, Mr. Winch.
You could call my office to schedule an appointment.
It's probably already waiting at your office.
Ah, can you open this door, Mr. Winch?
This cabin is for my father's assistant,
Fred Kaplan, and he alone has the keys to it.
I told you?  - Then, I'll break the door.
Do what you want, just make it quick.
Lord!
Freddy?
He was strangled, perhaps 12 hours ago.
Now I understand, why you didn't want to open this door.
You're accusing me of murder now?
- Mr. Winch?
Calm down Mr. Winch.
Notify the police.
For many years, I hated Freddy,
I ran away when he found me.
Always.
- They were watching you.
They were spying.
Freddy knew very well what I was
doing in Burma three years ago.
He knew I had no contact with Nerio.
He would have had to testify about it.
Do you think that's why they killed him?
Many influential enemies, you were right.
Too bad I cannot help.
Do you think that Nerio was able to order it.....
a massacre?
- No!
Of course not.
He was my friend, I don't believe he was capable of it.
Muong Nam - Burma
Three years earlier
Malunai!
- Kadjang!
Largo is my friend.
Come with me, I want to introduce him to my friends.
A permit to pass from the Burmese army,
signed by General Kyaw Min.
That's right
Lie!
Stop, stop!
Stop!
Do not meddle in it!
Want to help him, right?
Want more?
Maybe I ought to kill
immediately.  No, let him hang,
learn how to talk to us.
You are part of the resistance?
- Something like that.
You're efficient.
Time to get out of here.
My name is Simon.
Simon Voralla.
- My name is Largo.
So one day, Leonor tells me he
found a job at the French School in
Bangkok. As for me, I worked in
a Chinese restaurant and that's it.
I didn't wait too long and followed after Leonor.
I found myself some work.
Not that I have succeeded without her help.
I'm lost without her.
Eleanor is not a beauty, but she's nice.
We've known each other since I was about 12.
Her mother is my mother's best friend.
Next year we should get married.
Thailand.
She took care of everything.
Hong Kong
Three years later
John Waterhouse, Pandora 1896.
John Waterhouse...
Good morning, the password please.
Pandora.
Thanks.  Which service would you like sir?
I want to know my account balance.
One moment sir.
Your account balance is US$ 65,824,127.
Bangkok Airport - Thailand.
I'm not sure I'm the right person for this job sir.
I'm very bad with vehicles.
You must take them regularly, the only thing
that kept me alive on board your yacht.
Caraway, mixed with dried cassava and bamboo shoots..
..it's excellent.  Acts directly on nerve endings.
I'll take this to avoid potential problems.
I heard about it from one of my old friends from Peru, whom
I met while working for Marco Lueda.
Long before I started working for your father.
I met with Lazarevic your friend, here at the airport.
I know it's effective, but we need security, you can keep your dog.
What heat! Aren't you uncomfortable?
Welcome to Bangkok. The Thai authorities informed us of your arrival.
Gauthier, I'm counting on you.
Yes sir.
Rights for Karen.
I am sorry sir, that you called
and apparently really hoped to talk,
so I will leave a message on your voicemail.
As you asked, I tried to find one Simon Ovronnaz.
I got in touch with Eleanor, his fiancée.
Now it seems his former fiancée, but she was very un-cooperative.
She said that Mr. Ovronnaz left her three years ago.
Judging by the little she said, it's no way to find him.
So I gave up and did a little private investigation.
We talked a bit with the school guard.
A tiny man with bad breath.
He gave me an address, a new friend of Mr. Ovronnaz.
In fact, more true to say ex-girlfriend.
Thanks, you're charming.
Mr. Ovronnaz has gone to live in the south,
in Kasunkom, with another friend,
if you understand what I mean?
Count on me, I'll go to...
Damn, the line's cut.
I thought your commando Lazarevic devised an operation to free me...
I'm disappointed.
I received your message.  I haven't had
any contact with Dragan Lazarevic, since the Nazachov affair.
He landed in Bangkok, with a Winch Air plane.
It seems that half of his fee, quite expensive
was paid in Winch Air flights.
They do what he wants and go where he wants.
Lazarevic is a simple mercenary,
he works for whoever pays more.
For your concern Largo, the Thai Minister of Justice's staff arranged
for you to be released.
- Sorry.
I assure you I had nothing to do with it.
Of course, someone found out what happened.
You are an influential person, you have connections worldwide.
....and judging by everything, Thailand has
no desire to upset the Winch Group.
They managed to convince Francken I'm innocent?
Francken has no proof.
- There is a witness.
There was..as I said.  Thai authorities took care of everything.
Let's go, Largo.
Largo!  Excuse him.
Military Base Makiling, Burma
Enter.
Go.
Hong Kong
Hello, Mr. Cochrane.
Mr.  Winch, isn't here?  - That's right.
I heard that he...disappeared.
Mr.  Winch assigned me to act
on his behalf to find a buyer.
As I said, we have a serious offer.
OK, so where is it?
- Please come with me.
Mr. Cochrane.
UN Headquarters in Geneva - Switzerland
Vladimir Podolsky chief cabinet minister.
How was your trip?
- Thanks, well.
This is my assistant.  - Nice to meet you.
We apologize for the delay.  He has already come?
Are like Swiss watches
Their punctuality, legendary.  Welcome.
Why are you interested to know what is with this secret bank deposit, Ms. Prosecutor?
Let us know.
Wear it.  I dine with a real woman.
That will not be a violation of the rules in our fair.
Go and change you!
You did a good job.
Winch, has done everything possible to find out where you are.
I contacted.
Wonderful.
Truly magnificent.
Sit.
After a Winch Peter to give me the money your release,
I will leave this jungle.
In this country sucks.
You become a different person.
And to begin a new life.
You could go with me.
I'll take care of you.
I'll treat you like a princess.
You forget that you cannot refuse me anything?
Have you forgotten so soon?
Maine sent a jeep to bring him on Winch.
Just give us money
we will kill.
Both.
I feel bad again, sir.  As you asked me sir,
my mission of looking for Mr.  Ovronnaz,
despite their efforts, it is far from complete.
I must mention that pregnancy
I said, it is not so simple.  Oh my God.
Despising all possible risks,
continue my investigation without rest,
and do not hesitate to venture through a Thailand
which I would call it picturesque.
My old scout skills,
help me handle the country that odd, but not hostile
and to get in touch with the local population.
I would say that sometimes some people are really warm.
Returning to Mr.  Simon Ovronnaz,
I have not found Kasunkom.  He had problems of a financial nature.
If I understand correctly from his fiancée, former fiancée,
luckily managed to find a new path.
in Bangkok.
I hope Monsieur, you do not
angry for what happened, I worry for you I
Where are you?  Call me...  Hell, was interrupted.
General awaits us, wants to see this guy.
I am aware.
Pass.
Want to split?
What's with this depravity?
Hey, are they!
What are you doing there?
We bring a prisoner.
- What's this?
Answer.
You where you come from?
Get out, quickly!
Go to the jungle, come, hurry up.
Malunai!
No!
- Malunai?
Hello, you password please!
Pandora.
Move faster.
Let's not sit.
Move.
Want to stay alive.
- Faster.
Yes authorize the transaction.
Do not move!
Do not be afraid.  Mama's here.
My mother came to pick you up, do not be afraid.
My baby.
Yes.
Perfect.
- Come to me.
Everything is OK.
My baby.
How old are you?
Two years.
What is your name?
Noom, come over here.
Come on.
Let's see you play..
Simon! Please, come in.
Are you Simon Ovronnaz?
I'll take a break to rest.
I was on the brink of death.
Believe me, it changed me.
After all that, I could not return to Eleanor.
I should enjoy my life now.  Girls, fun...
Your boss saved my life.
I hope you understand.
I have already repeated 11 times, to be sure.
11 times.
Your boss saved my life.
Hello, sir, sir.
Is it you?
I have Simon Ovronnaz here, I found him sir!
Excuse me, excuse me, sir.
You've waited three years,
you can wait another three minutes?
Yes, Monsieur, all is in order.
And you, where are you?
Not so near Gauthier.
On the
Confirm transfer from of $25 million from your
Pandora account to account 6034TIH49?
This account belongs to Kyaw Min.
Yes, I confirm the transaction.
My Saviour.
- In the resistance.
You know he saved my life?
I need to know what was between
Gen. Kyaw Min and Nerio Winch.
The man with the driver...
you must find him, he knows everything.
That will be complicated.
He's dead.
Maybe I can help.
You know why your father refused to pay the General.
THREE YEARS EARLIER
- That guy hired me for a week.
He wanted to visit Burma.
Business trip, he said.
There, he spent several days in a military camp.
He spoke many times with the General.
He didn't tell me anything.  But I realised something.
One day, the soldiers went on a mission...
and they returned with prisoners.
Women, children and many wounded.
They told me how the soldiers burned their village.
Completely. This, of course, was part of their plan.
Then, everything changed.
But Mr. Winch, if you don't send the money,
Yes I know,
but he took the risk in bringing these mines.
But I couldn't...
- From what I understood
of the conversation, your father paid for getting these mines.
Mr.  Winch!
- It's not what you imagined
about this  massacre of the local population.
Excuse me.
I spoke with Nerio Winch, he won't pay.
You need to talk to him.
Go see him.
OK.
He said he needed to get away.
Very quickly.
Then I went outside, I waited for him outside the camp.
Listen, damn it.
I'll explain.
I will arrange everything, give me time.
Talk, where are they?
I was near the road.
I pulled out and left immediately
Your father didn't finance a massacre sir.
What did you call this guy?
Thomas, just Thomas.
Did you know his surname?
Never sir.
Why should I have known?
Relax son.
Tilt your head.
Gauthier, come, get ready to...
Mommy.
Mommy?
Let's go change?
My mother dressed me before.
We gotta get out of here.
And Mom?
Mommy's gone already.
You've never seen a child?  Go!
Where is my mommy?
Where is mommy?
Noo, mommy won't be back.
Mommy died.
She's gone forever.
She'll be watching you and always love you.
What'll you do now?
Don't let fucking Nazachov get it?
This sucks, this son of a...
I don't care about Nazachov.
Wait, is it because the boy's mother is dead?
You cannot leave the group to disintegrate.
Imagine what a man like him can do with so much power.
It would be your responsibility, sir.
Too late Gauthier, I signed away my rights,
the understanding cannot be cancelled.
You know the Pandora legend sir?
Zeus gave her to Epimetheus to be his wife,
she was the first woman on earth.
She possessed a box that Zeus forbade her to open.
One day, overcome with curiosity, she opened it
and freed all the misfortunes of mankind
old age, disease
and stupidity.
Pandora was scared and closed the box.
Fortunately, something was left in the box,
a small but very valuable item.
Hope...
and from that moment, even when a man hears trouble knocking,
he always keeps a small shred of hope.
We must not lose hope sir, while you're alive.
Hello, the password please.
Pandora, I would like to make a transfer of $ 7.
Did you say $ 7, 4 add 3?
Exactly.
- To which account do you want to transfer the funds?
In a few minutes, I'm getting on
an aircraft to Geneva....tell everyone.
And what exactly is your plan?
Card?
Simon!
Ignition switch is on here.
- So there's enough information, right?
Don't you think?
The guy who taught me to fly is dead.
Oh,...an accident?
Assassinated.
He strangled him.
D'you need help?
Yes, just stop shaking.
Not eating?
Not hungry?
Sleeping they don't seem so dangerous.
Now I'm worried about you.
Geneva Tower, Winch Air requesting to land.
This is Geneva, landing allowed.
- Beginning descent to 13000 feet.
You don't know how much pleasure I got from that.
I want to kill you, you son of a bitch.
Simon!
Are you OK?
- Yes.
Fine.
Yes.
Largo, where are you?
Yes, of course.
I'll send my driver.
Tell me exactly where you are.
Hello.  Passports please?
D'you often bring such weapons with you?
A doctor will examine you.
Alexander Jung, and your name sir?
Simon Ovronnaz.
Mr.Winch didn't want to come with you.
He went to a meeting with the prosecutor.
And you want to leave it like that?
That's crazy, she's extremely dangerous.
Climb!
I'm worried Largo.
- Everything is going well. I just spoke to Mrs Francken
Nazachov is a peasant.  How'd he
manage to invent such a complex plan.
Sometimes among the peasants is a genius.
I agree, but how do you think he knew what happened in Burma?
Three years ago?
I was told...
..people in the group.
I'm coming with you.
You're an angel, I hardly hurt.
May I have another?
- Yes.
Thanks.
And if Nazachov is not the head of this operation?
If he's just a front for someone else?
- If it's not him..
..to organize such a conspiracy
needs a more powerful motivation than greed, Largo.
It takes a fierce desire to humiliate,
to destroy a man's reputation forever.
Name, company.
Money cannot be the motivation.
Just revenge....
...and hate.
My son actively supported Nerio.
Thomas.
Thomas Jung.
My son used my relationships..
..to help the Winch group to obtain new markets, concessions.
Taxi!
Nerio didn't hesitate to use bribery.
So they created the Pandora account.
After a new market was won,
Nerio paid my son Thomas a commission.
All this money was gathered illegally.
He wanted more.
When I saw you for the first time, young, handsome, rich,
so alive.
I'm going to die,
but you gave me a reason to live.
Revenge.
Nazachov is a moron.
He just complied and paid.
Tonight, you have killed Prosecutor Francken.
The only one who can prove your innocence.
Give him the second injection.
Take the gun from the glove compartment.
Do what I say!
Simon?
Call the cops, quick!
No, no!
Alexander, don't do it!
- Also..
also I asked Nerio to save my son.
I asked him to send the money, I asked.
I begged on my knees before him, Largo.
Always my friend, my brother.
On my knees!
Stay there, don't come nearer!
Your son Alexander became a criminal.
You know, he ordered the massacre in Burma.
He was my son, my blood.
I cannot say I'm upset.
- Mr.  Cochrane, what will happen
And did you have a good time?
Excuse me?
The girls!
In Hong Kong.
Largo told me that you stayed there a while.
Lord, my God.
O Lord my God?
Want to try?
You know, you and I'll make a great team.
Yes, my partner.
- I'm not your partner.
You are about to become.
Shall we go yet?
- No!
Son, you can come back as often as you want.
You know, I live on a big boat.
No, I didn't know.
All around it there are very tall houses that reach the sky.
Dad's office is on top of them all.
Do you live all alone?
Not anymore.