Wait...
By using...
words?
King...
Would you like to know your name?
How would you know my name?
My subordinates were present at the
moment of your mother's passing.
She uttered your name
with her dying breath.
And my subordinates may have died
fighting your Royal Guard by now.
Interested in fighting me now?
If you can force me to admit defeat,
I will tell you your name.
Force you to admit defeat
without killing you?
So, similar to a bishop
and rook handicap...
No matter.
I shall checkmate you shortly.
Centipede x And x Memory
As the King and Netero prepared
for their final battle...
Beneath the palace,
Ikalgo was still sobbing,
having failed to finish off
the unconscious Brovada.
Fire! This is the best option!
There's no one else to help me!
I h-have to...
kill him!
This is no time to be crying...
I have to find Palm!
Huh?
The door to the warehouse area is open.
So is the door leading to the garage!
Why?
Don't move!
If you move, I'll attack.
Welfin...
I have a lot of things to ask you.
If you seem to be trying anything funny,
I'll kill you!
What he wants to ask me
is obvious!
The number of my allies,
their roles,
and their abilities.
And he intends to use any means
necessary to get the answers.
People could die if I leak information.
If he's a Manipulator,
he can obtain the information
against my will.
Huh?
D-Don't move!
I really will kill you!
Go ahead... Kill me.
That's what I want!
Stop!
If the alternative is betraying my buddies,
I'll take you with me!
Ouch!
Bastard! Now you've done it!
Damn it!
I'll kill you!
Missile Man!
I'm... not dead...
I didn't sustain any damage.
What was that attack?
Damn, that hurts...
You little punk...
Damn...
That bastard... How did a wimp like
that figure out my weakness?
Missile Man requires questions
and answers to work.
If an enemy attacks before I can ask
a question, it's null and void!
The wound isn't deep...
I'll take my time beating him to a pulp.
Huh?
He planted something inside me?
Those were created by my Nen
They're black centipedes.
Black Centipede
They grow by feeding on your resistance.
If you disobey my orders or try to hurt me,
you'll suffer excruciating pain,
then they'll tear your
body apart and you'll die!
Wh-What are you doing, fool?
Weren't you listening to me?
If you try to do that...
That's fine with me.
If my life is all it takes, I'll give it!
S-Stop!
No, wait...
If he wanted to kill me, that's the
ultimate form of resistance.
Now, it'll take no time for the black centipedes
to grow large enough to kill him instantly!
Don't worry.
I'm not interested in killing you...
I just need to make sure
that you can't leave.
I still...
have plenty of bullets.
Bastard! Don't mess with me!
I'll kill you!
You're dead! I'll kill you!!
It's so easy.
When I'm prepared to offer my own life,
it's so easy to pull the trigger.
I g-get it...
I get it, already.
I won't go anywhere!
I surrender.
Please... Don't fire!
The pain is going away.
The creatures inside me are suffering?
I lose, damn it...
I can't move anymore.
Is it because Welfin admitted defeat?
Man, I knew it...
I had a feeling this
would happen eventually.
But still...
I didn't think I was this weak!
I didn't think it'd be so scary
to face someone who fights
with no regard for their own life!
Hey.
What?
The pain has stopped, but can
you get rid of these bugs?
Stop complaining...
I'm in too much pain to
think about that now!
Hurry up.
Give me a minute!
I don't have a way to
deactivate Missile Man.
But if I tell the truth,
I'm in real trouble...
Damn, how do I get out of this?
I need to buy time...
Until I can come up with a good idea.
The pain is making me...
feel faint...
Wait! Okay!
I was lying! I won't do it again!
Then get rid of these.
Yeah, uh...
So, the thing is...
Forget it. I see how it is.
Wait! Hold on!
I can't remove them!
Not once they've been activated!
That's why I didn't want to say anything.
It's the truth! Believe me!
I'm not trying to trick you!
The insects are in pain again.
Maybe because Welfin is telling the truth?
Can you really blame me?
I only use this attack when
I want to kill someone.
I never cared what happened after that.
I never gave any thought to
what happened to my enemy.
Nen abilities are really something.
My abilities reflect my own personality.
My personality? His true intentions?
Welfin...
What do I ask him?
What do I want to know?
I once knew someone just like him.
Do you have any memories from
when you were human?
Wh-Why are you asking about that?
I can't remember...
You're lying.
Wh-What?
Stop! Hold on!
Calm down!
If you don't tell me the
truth, I'll shoot you.
When I woke up,
my first thought was...
Damn...
I can still remember it.
I'm sure those monster
bugs killed me in NGL.
I was fed to the Queen,
and reborn as something new...
But I still...
I still remember the one thing
I most wanted to forget.
The sight of my father strangling me,
and the woman watching behind him.
At first, I only had flashbacks of it.
Over time, I remembered the
entire sequence of events.
I was saved by...
my little brother, who
was unrelated by blood.
I remember now!
He looked just like Gyro!
Gyro?
You know. The king!
We used to brag about whose
life was more miserable.
He was the only one I could
turn to when I needed
to laugh away my tears...
We were both empty.
So we had nothing to hide.
I wonder what he's doing now...
I want to see him one more time...
Yes, I just want to see Gyro.
I'm tired of dealing with Ants and humans,
with money and nations...
Go.
The bugs are gone.
You still have something to do.
Why did you open the doors?
Oh, I was letting those weaklings
reach the treasure in the back.
They can't put up much of a fight.
I was watching you and Bro on the monitor.
And I told them to pass while
you were on the way back.
A coward!
It was that simple.
Once I saw that you couldn't finish Bro,
I thought
you'd be an easy target.
I couldn't have been more wrong.
Go on.
I'm too tired to move...
I have one last question.
Did you see a woman in the palace?
A woman?
Not sure if it's the one
you're talking about,
but the Royal Guard captured a human,
and put her in a cocoon.
Where is she?
Take the elevator up, then turn left.
It's the room at the end of the hall.
They called it ?1.
Thank you!
What's so funny?
Telling the truth
feels really good...
Welfin had spent his life unable
to trust himself or others.
Telling Ikalgo the location of
the one he searched for
was the first time he'd opened
up and spoken honestly.
Next time: Breakdown x And x Awakening.
I'm just... I'm just...
What's wrong, Killua?
I'm here for you.