I found him!
Ko Dongjun!
Stop right there!
Hey!
Dad, I'm going to find you.
So please be alive.
What do you think of Chunsik?
He's a good person.
Isn't that Ko Dongjun?
Stop the bus!
Hey!
This is all his fault.
If he hadn't died like that...
I wouldn't have to lie to my family.
What's wrong with being a loan shark?
I thought they'd be hiding,
but they were in Seoul?
Hey...
Where's your husband?
I saw him with my own two eyes.
Husband
This is the Yeongdeungpo police.
Are you Ko Dongjun's wife?
Is this your husband?
Where did you see my husband?
At the alley full of used book stores
in Cheonggyecheon.
Dongjun used to go there often.
Did he really see my husband?
Have you seen this man?
I heard he was here earlier.
He bought books here a few days ago.
Why do you ask?
Episode 17
Were you alive this whole time?
Then why didn't you come back?
- Have a nice day. / - Thank you.
Choi Suhui?
This is our new roast.
Would you like to try it?
You got a package.
A package for me?
Yes.
Take it.
Sure.
Who is it from?
Is it from your wife?
No, I don't know who this is.
You don't know who it's from?
Maybe there's been a mistake.
Look.
It has your name on it. Kim Chunsik.
See?
But I don't know who it's from.
Well, open it first.
See what it is.
Oh!
Who'd do such a thing?
Are you sure you don't know who it is?
I really don't.
That's strange.
Jieun.
The package probably arrived by now.
Thanks.
I got $5 off the delivery fee, so it was $15.
You can keep the rest.
Thanks.
If you need any more help,
just let me know.
Okay, bye.
Okay.
Hey, Jieun.
What?
That guy's been staring at you for a while.
I think he likes you.
Wipe it.
What's up with him?
Oh...
It's yours.
Wipe your face off.
Do you like me?
What?
If you like me, then stop.
Why?
Because I can't help you in any way.
I'm fine with that.
I still can't?
You can't.
Did you meet with the informant?
Yeah.
Did you find him?
It was a false tip.
Again?
We keep getting tips
from anyone with the slightest suspicions.
I'm not sure if that's such a good thing.
Well, the reward is quite substantial.
This happened with Jeong Jinuk too.
We got a lot of tips then too.
I thought it'd help us find him sooner.
Me too.
Seongil hasn't come in yet?
He just comes in whenever he pleases.
He only comes in when he feels like it.
Let him be.
He's not very useful anyhow.
Don't let him distract you from your work.
Fine.
Will you make me some coffee?
We're out of coffee.
Then get me some water.
Okay.
Just get it yourself.
That's not fair!
Chiwung and I already planned everything.
I told you, not Jeju-do.
Shoot it in the studio!
Why are you being so stubborn?
Did you have a honeymoon planned?
What?
That's not even funny.
We wanted to go abroad,
but we settled for Jeju-do.
This isn't fair.
You went to Jeju-do last year.
That's because Jeju-do is awesome.
Let's do something different this time.
Thrifty vacations, that kind of thing.
That's Yangsun's specialty.
Keep your mouth shut.
Yangsun, cover it with Chiwung.
What? What did you say?
I don't want to.
Can't you two work it out?
How can you do this to us?
I'm your boss.
Suri, you're out.
Yangsun, you're in.
Did you put her up to this?
Why would I do that? Are you insane?
I'm being tossed around back and forth.
If we were partners, there'd be no problems.
Right?
I'm not so sure.
In any case, those are your assignments.
Dismissed.
What's with that look?
I hate your guts.
Suri!
What did I do?
Maybe they're really dating.
I don't want to work with Yangsun, either.
Is that true?
Of course.
After working with someone as nice as you,
when I think about working with Yangsun,
my head already starts to ache.
I know!
It's so stressful to work
with someone you hate.
What if you get cancer?
I don't think it'll come to that.
You don't know her like I do.
You don't know what you're in for.
Is she that bad?
Yes.
When are our models coming?
Soon.
Are those all the props we have?
No, there's more.
Have you done a shoot before?
This is my first time.
I've done so many shoots over the years.
Swimwear, too.
We're doing a vacation shoot.
Is this the right place?
Are you here for the shoot?
Yes.
This is the spot.
Follow me.
What?
Why take vacation photos here?
It's a backyard summer party concept.
Just take the shots the way I explained.
I'm the photographer.
I don't have to take orders from you.
I know you're the photographer.
It's not like you're a judge.
If you don't like it, go study for the bar.
Now you're not going to take the shots?
No. I'll take the shots.
But I'm going to do it my way.
I get what you mean now.
Fine.
The models are here.
You again?
Are you a model now?
Yeah, so?
What is it that you do exactly?
That's none of your business.
Why is this set so lousy?
Who hired you for this job?
I did.
Suri, it was you?
Yeah.
I'm trying to be a good neighbor.
I thought I'd be working with Suri.
Do I have to work with her then?
Yes.
But what brings you here?
I was checking to see how it was going.
It figures.
Yangsun, this is totally your style.
We're going to start right away,
so go get changed.
Where do I get changed?
Do you see our car?
You can change in there.
Oh come on. This is embarrassing.
Isn't it hot today?
Take some.
Don't you need to prepare?
I will.
You're busy. Go ahead.
I'll be fine on my own.
Okay then.
Did you hire that guy
just to mess with me?
Of course not.
He's trying to become a star.
He even studied modeling.
What's your problem?
The weather's already getting on my nerves.
Why are you fanning the flames?
Now I have two issues to deal with!
You're right about one thing,
but you're wrong about the other.
Stop acting like a little kid.
I'm not interested in that guy.
He's not interested in you, either.
So why are you doing this to me?
I didn't volunteer for this job.
Because it's hot.
What?
Can't you see I'm fuming?
Hey!
What?
They want a new elevator?
And the bathrooms fixed?
A full remodeling of the building?
Are they insane?
I can't. Tell them that I can't!
The building's forty years old,
so we have to do something.
Or else, everyone's going to leave.
Let them leave!
But if they all leave,
we won't get any new tenants.
Who'd want to move into this building?
Decide whether you'll do the repairs or not.
The tenants are waiting for you.
Fine.
I'm already in the red.
They're out to ruin me.
Ugh.
Where did Hwangtae go?
Just when I need him the most...
I should've been more intimidating.
I was too weak.
Next time, I'll have
them shaking in their boots.
Scrooge
He was the one who asked me to leave.
Why does he keep calling me?
He should've been nicer to me back then.
So he wants to cut all ties with me now?
Good afternoon, boss.
What brings you here?
Where's Hwangtae?
Why do you ask?
I can't reach him.
He quit.
I knew it.
Is he in trouble?
Yeah.
How deep?
$20,000.
That's why he...
Are you in contact with him?
I need him for a job,
but he won't pick up my calls.
That little...
He's a gambling addict.
Why would you give him money?
I know, right?
That little...
If you don't call me back,
I'm going meet with your mother.
What am I going to do?
I found a way to get some money.
Give me time.
I'll pay you back for sure.
What did he say?
He told me to wait.
He found a way to make money.
A way to make money?
You did a shoot for a magazine?
Yes.
My phone's been ringing off the hook.
I guess I've just got that look.
But I do have other important work to do.
Other work?
I'll explain later.
About Chunsik.
I'm going to invite him
for dinner on his day off.
You don't have to do that.
There's a lot that I owe him for.
It's just dinner, what's the big deal?
Wouldn't it be awkward?
Of course not.
He's living on his own,
if we invite him over, it'll make him happy.
Doesn't he have any family?
I'm not sure.
He doesn't have a wife or kids?
He doesn't talk about himself.
So I don't know either.
Who's Chunsik?
The guy who works at mom's cafe.
Chunsik must be a common name.
Sherlock is looking for a missing person
named Chunsik, Kim Chunsik.
That man's name is also Kim Chunsik?
Yeah.
How did that man go missing?
He has Alzheimer's.
He looked about the same age as Mr. Kim.
He's young. It's sad.
Does Chunsik have Alzheimer's?
What do you mean?
Do you know anything about his past?
No, you don't.
That's because he won't tell us.
Maybe he can't talk about it.
Because he lost his memory.
Jieun may be on to something.
There's no way.
In any case, he's suspicious.
Don't say that.
Just eat your food.
Maybe there's been a mistake.
Look.
It has your name on it. Kim Chunsik.
See?
But I don't know who it's from.
Is Jieun right?
No, there's no way.
What are you doing?
I was just thinking about something.
No, it can't be.
I'm home.
Hey.
Do you know what this is?
What?
Coffee mugs.
Aren't they pretty?
You bought new ones?
I always have to buy cute coffee mugs.
It'd be so nice to have coffee with that man.
How much did you save up for your wedding?
Why do you ask?
I was just wondering.
I can't.
I can't give away that money.
I worked so hard to save up.
Don't even think about it.
Do you understand?
I didn't say anything.
I wonder who took it.
I'm sure it would have won the grand prize
if it had just made it through the first round.
Are you working?
Yeah.
What is it?
Yangsun.
Do you have any money saved up?
I haven't saved anything.
I'm busy paying off our debts.
I know. I shouldn't have asked.
But, why did you ask?
Do you think we can take out a loan?
Probably not another one.
What's up? Did something happen?
No, it's nothing.
Nothing?
You're asking for money. What's up?
It's no big deal.
Forget about what I said.
I'm sorry if I interrupted you.
Get back to work.
What is it this time?
What's all that?
I don't know.
It came from Yeonggwang-gun.
Oh, it's a package from my folks.
Your folks?
Yeah, we live in Yeonggwang-gun.
It's croaker fish.
This is all croaker fish?
Yes.
I told my mom I'm living at a friend's house
so she sent this to us.
She said she'll keep sending more to us
so please eat to your heart's content.
Your mother is so generous!
Everyone in our family has a big appetite.
You all have big appetites?
I told them to send rice too.
So don't worry.
My family runs a rice field.
You don't have to do that.
Can I put this in the kitchen?
Sure.
Mom, we can eat croaker fish now?
Yes, he said we could eat it too.
We'll get free rice and croaker fish.
He's not just a renter.
He's a blessing!
Croaker fish?
So stop nagging Segi about his eating habits.
He brought his own food...
He brought enough food for the whole family.
Does he really eat that much?
They had to send us a box of croaker fish?
In any case...
In any case, Segi must have felt guilty
about all the food he was eating.
That's probably why he called his folks.
I guess he's got a conscience after all.
Thanks to him,
our family can eat all the croaker fish we want.
Ask him if they grow peppers or beans.
Why?
So we can get those for free too.
What's wrong with you?
I told you, I'm not doing it.
Don't be like that. Do it for my sake.
I'm not doing any interviews.
Ms. Choe's pressuring me so hard.
Just help me out this one time.
How is she pressuring you?
She's making me partner up with Yangsun.
She's only doing it to punish me.
Do you hate that girl that much?
She's scary.
I thought she was pretty cute.
What's wrong with your eyesight?
You think she's cute?
She looked cute to me.
In any case, help a friend in need.
Do the interview.
Is it that bad?
Yeah.
Good morning.
Sure.
I guess nobody's here yet.
Yup.
I printed the pictures.
They're better than I expected.
That's why you should do as I say.
My experience is valuable.
I wasn't trying to ignore you.
I was just upset that our plans had changed.
I know you don't like working with me.
But we have to work.
So let's not burden each other.
You said it yourself.
Let's try to get along.
Sure.
I was going to get some coffee.
Do you want some?
Sure, if you want.
Hold on.
I had to try so hard not to yell at him.
Why is she being so nice all of a sudden?
That's even more terrifying.
Ms. Choe, you're here!
Yeah.
Let me buy you a cup of coffee.
No. I don't drink vending machine coffee.
I see.
Oh, right! I think it'll work out.
What will?
Segi's interview.
Are you serious?
I begged him and so he changed his mind.
Really?
Yes.
I think you can go ahead with it now.
Okay. Thank you.
It was nothing.
Should I make an appointment now?
No.
If I go now,
it'll make me look desperate.
I'll let him wait.
Has she come in yet?
What are you doing?
Oh, you're here.
Thanks to you, the shoot went well.
Well, if you say so.
I wanted to buy you a meal to thank you.
When are you free?
That's okay. You don't have to do that.
Oh, but I insist.
If that's the case, buy a meal for him.
I didn't take the photos, he did.
What?
What were you talking about?
Forget about it.
I think she asked you to buy me a meal.
I told you to forget about it.
He's so rude.
She's not easy.
How can I make her my baby?
Why didn't you come in yesterday?
I had other work to do.
I told you I'd be wandering about.
But you should show your face at least.
Or call in and say you can't make it.
Does he have a crush on me?
Am I wrong?
Fine.
How's work coming along?
Why isn't she studying?
Don't worry. Get back to your studies.
Fine. I better act like I'm working.
Do you want something cold to drink?
Oh, that's all right.
Why is this place so empty?
When it gets busy, it gets really busy.
I know you're doing this as a hobby,
but still, you're running a business.
It's fine. We're not in the red.
I'm not going to get greedy.
I don't know how you became such a softy.
It must be nice to have free time.
Oh, you're here.
There aren't any customers.
Just come outside.
Why are you hiding back there?
I feel more comfortable here.
You're a unique fella.
What do you do on your days off?
I do the chores that I've been putting off.
I head to the saunas.
I read.
It makes time go by rather quickly.
Really?
We should go to the sauna together.
That sounds good.
Okay.
Oh that reminds me.
Come over for dinner on Sunday.
Oh, that's all right.
It doesn't have to be awkward.
We've known each other for a while now.
It doesn't seem like you have a family.
Just come over and we'll treat you like family.
Thank you for being so kind.
I've been living alone for a long time,
so I totally understand how you feel.
Where are you?
If you're alive, why won't you come back?
Did you hate me that much?
Even if you did,
what about Yangsun?
Yangsun misses you so much.
Did you leave me for a woman?
What are you doing in the dark?
Are you drinking?
Do you want some?
No.
Did something happen?
You've been acting strange lately.
I told you, I'm fine.
She's acting strange.
There's definitely something going on.
What's eating at you?
Tell me.
Yeongsuk!
Eunsuk.
What?
I know I shouldn't ask you this
but can I borrow
the money you saved for your wedding?
What?
I know I shouldn't be asking.
But please.
Will you please help me one last time?
How could you?
Eunsuk.
I gave up on my education and
opened a clothing store to pay off your debts.
I couldn't make ends meet as a teacher,
so I gave up my dream
of becoming a professor.
I know that.
But I never blamed you for it.
Because Dongjun paid for my college tuition.
I knew I had to pay for Yangsun's education.
So I worked like a dog
to pay off all those expenses.
I know all that.
So how can you ask me for more?
You know how much I gave up.
How can you ask me for more?
How can you do this to me?
I don't know what's going on, but...
At this point, I don't even want to know.
It's my turn to live my life.
I'm not asking you because I want to.
This is killing me inside.
Will you stop saying that?
You haven't changed one bit!
What is it?
What's going on?
Ask your mother.
I don't know anymore.
Tell me the truth.
Is something going on?
Yangsun.
Yeah?
Mom.
Let's move out.
Move out?
Let's sell this house
and start a new life somewhere else.
Do you get it?
You have to earn money.
Don't you dare try to mooch off your brother.
I can party too.
And I can be sexy.
Back off.
What?
When we first met,
you were trying to kill yourself.
Why were you doing that?
I thought it was all over.
But it never seems to end.
Then how much do you need?
Mom, you can't deal with a guy like that.
I'll meet him and figure this out.