♪ Keith Murray, UGK
and oh, my lord, Jamar...
♪ The east to the west...
♪ Up north to the down south
Live wires connect...
♪ So if you swingin' on things
Or down to gangbang...
♪ Or waitin' on the train
It's still the same thing...
♪ The east to the west...
♪ Up north to the down south
Live wires connect...
♪ So if you swingin' on things
Or down to gangbang...
♪ Or waitin' on the train
It's still the same thing...
♪ You cut your mind and your body
with the rhyme and the shotty...
♪ Go and find me or hidin',
with wine and Bacardi...
♪ Get down like John Gotti
then I gotta get lost...
♪ I'm goin' in to win, my momma
keep on tellin' me we was born into sin...
♪ I guess I'm hell-bound destined
to learn my lesson...
♪ Sets in my chest and it burns,
but I keep on puffin', no bluffin'
♪ They don't call me Big Bun for nothin'
♪ No homeboy, you goin' dead
- ♪ Well put him to rest...
♪ Both my clocks are goin' dead
- ♪ With two in his chest...
♪ Batty boy, you goin' dead, and if
he no die, well, you wounded him again...
♪ Well, go on buddy, let 'em fly
That's how it is in my city...
♪ And your city, sir, it gets no prettier
Just more gritty per capita...
♪ All around, from the five boroughs
On down to the mighty Bro town...
♪ The east to the west...
♪ Up north to the down south
Live wires connect...
♪ So if you swingin ' on things
Or down to gangbang...
♪ Or waitin' on the train
It's still the same thing...
♪ The east to the west...
♪ Up north to the down south
Live wires connect...
♪ So if you swingin' on things
Or down to gangbang...
♪ Or waitin' on the train
It's still the same thing...
♪ Your watch is covered, I can cover it
like a sentence for a triple homicide...
♪ Cripple any drama that
reside in the mind...
♪ Of those livin' outside my stateline
Let 'em know we all the same kind...
♪ With the same crimes, catchin' the same
time which translates to hang time...
♪ Organized gang slinger jive...
♪ Lord Jamar is black Jesus,
I sees this everywhere I go...
♪ Brothers hustlin'
to make the dough, fast or slow...
♪ Ya wanna see your cash grow like grass...
♪ But meanwhile take a blast of the 'L '
and let the smell resonate...
♪ Never hesitate...
when it comes to puttin
' food on your plate...
♪ Devise schemes by all means
Like a sunrise when it beams...
♪ Keep your eyes on the cream
Live Wires on the team...
♪ Connect, get respect for they realness
I know you feel this...
♪ The east to the west...
♪ Up north to the down south
Live wires connect...
♪ So if you swingin ' on things
Or down to gangbang...
♪ Or waitin ' on the train
It's still the same thing...
♪ The east to the west...
♪ Up north to the down south
Live wires connect.
Y o. I'm fixed to tell you
how it is in the 'hood.
See, 'cause in the 'hood,
everybody's a target.
It ain't Like that, I'm gonna tell you
the real deal what goes on.
See, in the 'hood,
most of us won't reach the age of 21,
♪ Happy birthday, homie...
For me?
- Yeah,
♪ Happy birthday, homeboy...
For me?
- Yeah, Make a wish,
[gun shot]
No, Lord. No, Lord.
Not my baby.
I know you didn't do me wrong.
Oh, my junior.
I nursed him with these, Lord.
Oh, not my baby.
- Yo, Yo.
Yo, Yo, Yo.
This ain't your baby,
This ain't your baby.
Huh?
Ain't that some shit?
I'm gonna tell you
what it's really like livin' in the 'hood.
I moved back into my father's house after
livin' with my mom for most of my life.
Tray.
I don't want you hangin' out in the streets.
I want you to finish school
'cause without an education,
the only kind of work you're gonna get
is sellin' drugs, pimpin' women,
or workin' security for Eddie Murphy.
Now, I've done all I can.
I got my education,
I worked two jobs to support you.
But I can't teach you how to be a man.
Only your father can do that.
Now give me a kiss and be a good boy,
I Love you, Tray,
- I Love you too, Mom,
So will I see you again?
- Sorry, baby.
You know there ain't no
positive black females in these movies.
Sorry.
My father tried his best to give me advice.
Problem was, he was only
a couple of years older than me.
Fool. I told you,
I don't want no damn Watchtower.
Hey. What's up, nigga?
- What's up, Pops?
Yo. How are you doin', man?
How's it goin'?
Oh, man,
- Look at you, nigga, It's gonna be on,
Look at you, You got big, man,
- You know what I'm sayin'.
Last time I seen you,
you was this tall.
You didn't get on the amusement rides,
We had to go to Kiddie Land.
All good, Know what I'm sayin'?
I was about to eat breakfast, Hungry?
No, I'm full, I had some Red Hots,
- Is that right? Cool.
Hey, man, Come on in, Please allow me,
You a guest in my house, man.
Make yourself at home.
Are those Girbauds?
Shit, I'm gonna be sportin' them, man.
It's good to have you up in here too.
I'm gonna finish gettin' my swellin'
on right, so have a seat, man.
Hey. Make sure your ass is on that plastic.
So we're not bumpin' heads, if you gonna
be stayin', you have to follow some rules.
No smokin' my shit,
Don't Let me catch you drinkin' my shit.
And if you bring
any of them hos up in here,
make sure I fuck 'em first.
And you're gonna have some chores,
Chores?
- That's right, This ain't no free ride.
Keep track of my Matchbox cars,
organize the Sega Genesis cartridges.
Do my homework,
since you wanna be a such a smart-ass.
And at nighttime,
I want you to cut the hair on my balls.
Hey, hold up,
Can I ask you a question, Pop?
What you gonna be doin'?
Hey. Look, nigga.
I ain't got to do nothin',
My momma take care of me.
Look, I know you think
I'm bein' hard on you,
but I guess I'm tryin'
to teach you some responsibility.
You right, Pop.
Hey, could you Line me up in the back?
Nigger, that's gonna run you about $1 3,
$13? Oh, come on, The Spanish dude
down the block only charges six.
Take your ass to him
and Let him fuck your head up.
Nah, I'll Let you cut me up,
Let me ask you a question,
- What's up?
Are you still a virgin?
- Of course.
There was this one dude who rubbed up
against my butt one time, but I didn't Like it.
I'm talkin' about girls, man.
Oh, girls, Come on, Pops,
Now, you know I be gettin' mine,
You gettin' it or you gettin' it?
- I'm gettin' it,
I ain't told you about that little honey dip?
- What honey?
I met the finest little brown-skinned cutie
down at the corner market.
She had big breasts and big legs,
Her ass was pow.
Ghetto booty,
- Oh, yeah.
So I knew she Liked me
'cause we Locked eyes.
So I start to get into my mac daddy
Denzel mode, you know, Yeah.
I fixed my eyebrows,
made sure they were straight.
Fixed my hair,
made sure it was slick and greasy,
Makin' sure my breath wasn't stinkin', , ,
- Get to the damn fuckin' part.
OK, So anyway, , .
I went over her house one Sunday mornin'.
Her mom had just gone to church.
And we had the place all to ourselves.
So, you know, we got
to kissin', lickin', slobbin'.
You know, doin' the wild thing.
When we got up there,
it was like heaven.
Better than my wildest fantasies.
Apparently, her mom
must have forgot her purse or somethin',
'cause she came back home.
I guess she could smell the sex in the air.
I got a surprise for you.
And that's when things really got freaky.
Before I knew it, the door burst open
and there was her momma.
Oh.
Hold him down, baby,
Let Momma have him.
I grabbed my things and got out of there.
Yeah,
I sure do hope you get her number,
- The girl?
Hell, no, Her momma, She the freak,
Don't go up too high in the back,
- Don't worry.
You all done, There we go.
I got somethin' for you to make
the girls think you're smellin' good.
All hooked up, partner,
Give me my $1 3,
.
Give it up.
This is a jack move, fool.
Just don't shoot.
Come back here with my truck.
Give me that truck back.
Man, you got any spare change?
Sorry, bro, I'm all out, man.
Man, I got these cheeseburgers, man,
I don't want any cheeseburgers,
- Please, man,
I'll suck your dick,
- Ew.
Get outta here, man.
Get outta here.
It hurt me to wake up
and see my beautiful black people suffer.
Victimized by the oppressive
harsh realities of the 'hood.
I guess, even though we were free,
we were still slaves in the mind.
Message.
Luckily, I wasn 't alone here in the 'hood.
My cousin Loc Dog
lived right across the street.
Loc Dog was America 's worst nightmare.
Raised in a house with three generations...
of hopelessness, poverty and profanity.
.
Loc Dog, turn that
Loud-ass motherfuckin' music down.
You wakin' up the babies, motherfucker.
This still my house, motherfucker.
Who the fuck is that on my porch?
Hey, Miss Dog,
- Hey, Ashtray,
You stayin' with your daddy for good?
- Yeah.
Come on in.
You tell your pretty-ass
motherfuckin' daddy I said hello.
Yeah.
Baby, do me a favor
and pass me that shit over there,
Care for a little soup?
- No, thanks, I'm cool, Is Loc Dog here?
Yeah, that Lazy-ass motherfucker's
back there doin' nothin' as usual,
OK, well, I'll see you Later,
- All right, then.
Hey, Grandma.
Ashtray, you little bitch-ass motherfucker.
Come over here
and give your grandma a hug.
That's my nigga.
You been wearin' them jimmy hats
that Grandma gave you?
Yes, ma'am, How are you?
Oh, my old stinky ass is fine.
Except for my arthritis in my trigger finger,
But I can still stick and move,
- I'll bet you can.
That beatin' the police give me
didn't slow me down a bit.
Come on, motherfucker,
Give me your best shot.
Come on, Grandma,
I don't wanna do nothin' Like that,
Come on, nigga,
- Come on, Grandma, I don't wanna.
Damn, them fake teeth are hard.
Bye-bye.
You still hit Like a bitch, motherfucker.
Loc Dog was gonna teach me to survive
in the 'hood, even if it killed me.
.
Tray, is that you?
You better start announcin' yourself
before you get smoked up in here, nigga.
You know that chronic
make me paranoid, baby.
Come here, you old fool-dog,
mark-ass trick, Give me some Love,
What's up, cuz?
- What's up?
That's enough of that Love, I don't play
that sentimental shit, Come on, come in.
Quick fashion question.
Should I wear this TEC-9, , ,
with the high tops?
Or should I wear this Uzi, , ,
with my Low tops?
I'll just wear these then.
Tray, scoot over, Rumor has it your
bitch-ass is in town for good, nigga.
Yeah, man, Mom says
it's time for me to become a man.
Nigger, my mom said the same shit,
Sweatin' me, nigga.
Yeah, man,
I don't care, though.
I told her,
I don't wanna be on welfare my whole Life.
For real, I got bigger and better plans.
Figured I'd get me a job at the post office,
maybe at a bank,
That's all good, man,
- Work hard, Work my way up to manager,
We need more black people Like this,
- Learn the system.
Then I'll rob that motherfucker blind.
Break all yourselves.
Hold up,
Whatever happened to your pops anyway?
That old mark-ass nigga
ran out on us Like a little biznitch.
You know, it's, , .
It was kinda tough, , .
Growin' up in the 'hood without a, , ,
without a positive
male role model to Look up to.
Message.
Nigger, come on, Let's go get Preach and
Crazy Legs and go to this picnic real quick.
Come on.
Damn.
This is some good shit.
You have your black ass
back here by Friday.
The social worker's comin'
and I'm still claimin' your ass.
Quit sweatin' me, Shoot.
Grandma, you better stay off my end
or I'll smoke your ass.
Oh, go fuck yourself, nigga,
Preach was
a former gang member turned activist.
But now, he's just plain confused.
Preach, What up, nigga?
- Y'all need to stop usin' the word 'nigga, '.
You see, it's terms Like the word 'nigga'
that the white man uses...
to take away
the self-esteem of another race.
Word.
Remind me to pick my Laundry up
from that Chink motherfucker up the street,
Crazy Legs used to be
the best dancer in the 'hood.
But now he's paralyzed
from the waist down after a drive-by.
What's up, Crazy?
- What's up, y'all? I'll be right there.
That's the way to start the day,
How you doin'?
My little pigmy brother,
- All right, African brother,
Loc Dog didn't have the fliest ride,
but it was reliable in rain, sleet or snow.
Hey, you guys,
Y'all wanna see a dead body?
- Yeah.
Come on.
I told you he was dead.
Man, he stinks,
...
♪ Here comes Lil' Bud with another hit...
♪ Yeah, I got the hits
that the busters can't get with...
♪ So everybody just get on down.
What's up, baby boy?
Damn. Hey, Tray, if you can't
get nothin' here, you're gonna die a virgin,
Hey, y'all, Look at them freaks
gettin' busy on the dancefloor.
There's all kinds of bitches up in here.
What did I tell you
about disrespectin' my Nubian princesses?
Quit disrespect, , ,
You need, , .
Oh, my God, The mother of Mecca
is right here before me.
Do my eyes not deceive me
or am I Lookin' at the goddess Isis herself?
Can you, , , Can you do me a favor,
my brown-skinned angel?
Can you tap that white girl for me?
My milk of magnesia.
After the devil made you,
he broke the mold.
Maybe you and I
could make a little jungle fever?
This one to all my dead homies,
you know what I'm sayin'?
I remember
the first time I saw Dashiki.
She was fine enough
to be 'Jet' Beauty of the Week.
Yo, Loc, Come here,
- Hey, what's up? What's up, nigga?
Yo, man, Who's this fine girl over here?
Oh, nigga, that's Dashiki.
Stay away from that, Everybody
in the 'hood 's been up in her,
She got more kids than Ms, Wayans,
- Damn.
Anyway, that's Toothpick's ex-girl,
You don't want any of that boy's old scraps,
Toothpick got used to bein' in jail.
So much so, that, even on the outside,
he lived like he was still on the inside.
Give me a knife, boy,
Keep it down, man, Keep it down,
Bone check, homie, Bone check,
- Five dollars a head, nigga, Five dollars,
What are they in for, man?
- Five dollars, buster.
Oh, I got that,
I can cover that.
Here.
Here we go.
What?
Oh, my money ain't good?
Do you know how many crumb cakes I can
get for that? How many chocolate milks?
How many bars of soap?
Deal my cards, nigga, Just hurry up.
Deal, deal, deal.
- All right, nigga, Chill.
Hello,
She wants me,
- Why waste your time with that trick?
We need you someone with some class,
Someone you can take home.
Get yourself a real woman.
Real woman,
Tray, you see that bitch over there?
- I see her.
Now that's a Lady.
I bet you I'd get the number,
Nigger, you ain't gettin' nobody's number,
- Fool, Watch me.
Hey, sweetheart.
Break yourself.
Give me your goddamn number. Come on.
Hurry up. Come on.
Cool, cool, cool.
I'll give you a call
about five o'clock, all right?
I said all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
Hey, beautiful,
- Please,
Hey, mister,
- What's up, little man?
Are you just tryin'
to get some from my momma?
Snap, No, little man.
Give me a dollar and I'll Leave you alone.
Cute little kid,
Oh, by the way, my name is Ashtray,
- My name is Dashiki.
That's Swahili for doggy style,
Oh, that's pretty,
- Those are my kids.
Hello, everybody.
Now, children, What do you say
when you meet a nice man?
Are you my daddy?
All I know is I'd really Like to take you out.
Oh, you and your seven kids.
That sounds nice, but I'm Leavin'
the 'hood in a couple of days.
Really? Man, I can't wait for the day
I can move out of the 'hood.
Well, Look, I know I just met you,
but you're welcome to come along.
I need somebody to help me
change all them diapers.
Is that it? Diapers? I used to change my
father's diapers all the time, Ain't no thing.
Listen, , .
You think about it, OK?
And if you're serious, Let me know.
Hey, man, Ain't that Dashiki over there,
kissin' that fool, man?
Man, Right there,
Yeah,
- Oh, damn, man.
I should go shank that fool, right now.
Toothpick, you're trippin', man,
Nigger, that's old news.
Think about it, nigga,
You've been in jail five years now.
Man, it's only been 1, 825 days, six hours
and 1 3 minutes, She could have waited.
Whatever, I'm just sayin',
why go back to jail?
I ain't worried about jail,
What the fuck? You sound Like a bitch.
Bitch.
I ain't worried about jail,
Shit, I don't give a damn about goin' to jail,
You can take me to jail.
- Take me to jail.
Lock me up.
- Lock me up.
Throw away the key.
- Throw away the key.
I ain't afraid to fuck somebody in his ass.
- I ain't, , , Whoa.
This fool is trippin',
- I'm outta here.
You on your own there, bro.
Y'all, , , Come on, man, Y'all ain't
ever been in the shower with a man.
And you see the suds roll down
the crack of his ass and you just, , ,
be turned, , .
I was foolin' y'all, man.
I was foolin' y'all,
Those was jokes.
Hey, man, Fuck this, I'm goin',
♪ Gettin' shackled on the bus
First thing come Monday...
♪ Hopin' in your mind
you'll be released one day...
♪ But knowin' home is a place
you're not goin' for a long while.
I don't usually be kissin' Like that
when I first meet someone.
But you special,
Cigarette?
- Ashtray.
Yeah, Ashtray.
Come on, kids.
Hey, stupid, you realize
you just kissed every nigga at the party?
Come on, I gotta go to the store
and get some more 40s.
OK, yeah, All right.
Whoa. Now, that there is somethin' special.
How come you talk all that noise about
white men and then go date white women?
No, you see,
I'm just tryin' to do to white girls...
what the white man's
been doin' to us for 400 years,
Yeah, what's that?
- Fuck 'em.
Amy-Jo.
Oh, you cold, You cold.
Yeah, yeah, Forties and 9s,
That's my favorite store.
I'm gonna go in here
to get me a malt Liquor Slurpee,
Get me some barbecued potato chips,
- Can I keep the change?
Hell, no, fool, That's a ten-dollar
food stamp, Better bring back my change.
What's up now,
you pretty punk chick?
Yeah.
What's up?
We got a problem, Toothpick?
I said do we have a problem?
Oh, we got a problem, partner, Right here,
Right there, Right there,
- Yeah.
All right,
Let's play a little game.
I said do we have a problem?
Huh?
- USSR?
Get your stinky asses outta here
before I cause a nuclear holocaust, fool.
Let's go. Let's go, fool. Come on.
It'll be Hiroshima and Nigga-saki,
- Yo, fool, Let's go.
That's right, fool, you better
get on outta here, And don't come back,
Punk,
- Tray, bring your simple behind on,
...
Hello,
- Yo, man, You page me?
Yeah, You ready to be out?
- Yeah, Let's move,
...
♪ Niggers.
I go and check them.
Hurry up and buy.
Break yourself.
Hey. Hey.
You dropped something.
Yeah. Break yourself, fool.
Yeah, You better recognize.
Give me my money back.
Oh, word, Candy bars.
Hey, Miss Lady Bitch,
Hey, I'm talkin' to you,
How much for this candy bar?
- Five dollars.
What? You better give me some
sucky-sucky for five dollars,
Some 'love me Long time' or somethin',
- You don't Like? You don't buy.
Look here, Just charge us
for the chips and the ice cream, All right?
Let's go, before I Loc up on these people.
Quit Lickin' Like that or I'll put you
outside to make me some money.
I feel sorry for your mother.
What did you say about my momma?
I don't wanna have trouble,
Just go. Go home, Don't come back.
What did you say about my momma?
Break yourself.
No.
You break, you buy.
Soda, five dollars.
Loc, what are you doin', man?
Pickles, ten dollars, Come on,
give me money, Give me money, right now.
Shirt. $1 9, 95.
On sale, Come on.
Are you crazy?
What the hell did you do?
Hey, fool, it wasn't me,
I didn't hurt nobody.
Catch.
The man.
Have a nice day, Oh, yeah.
He's good.
Come on, Tray,
Let's get outta here,
...
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ Yes, the hour's four,
I told you before...
♪ Prepare for mic fights
and plus the Cold War.
Hey, man, Check out that six-four,
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ Yes, the hour's four,
I told you before...
♪ Prepare for mic fights...
What up, nigga?
- Oh, damn, What up, Grandma?
Tell your daddy to page me.
All right then.
All right playa. Stay up.
Peace,
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ Yes, the hour's four,
I told you before...
♪ Prepare for mic fights
And plus the Cold War.
Now, I realize that every now and again...
some of you women folk,
you get hot, you get bothered.
And every now and again
you get hot and bothered.
Well, what I want you to do when you get
that hot and you need a little relief.
I want you to, , ,
I want you to call me,
Don't ask no questions,
- Good to see you today, Gloria.
Good to see you too, Miss Williams.
Tired heifer.
His only son,
Didn't he do it?
Abraham didn't ask no questions,
- Thank you, baby.
And that's what God
expects from His sheep.
Here at the Greater Ebenezer
New Revival Tree Of Life.
Institutional Double Rock
On The Side Of The Road To Jericho.
Missionary Baptist Church Of Zion.
When I say Mount Calvary,
y'all gonna hear me.
Preach on, Reverend.
- Ain't that the truth.
God expects you to do
what the Lord wants you to do.
Like those of you who realize...
that the Lord wants you
to give generously to His church,
Amen.
- Don't ask no questions.
Don't ask how come, , ,
or why come the pastor
have to have him a nice house.
Or why come the pastor
got to have a nice car.
Don't ask. I said don't ask.
I said don't ask no questions.
- ...
Just give the money,
-  Amen. I got $1 00 right here.
Get the collection plate round on that side.
Nigger, get it around on that side.
We will now have a B selection
from the choir,
.
I feel the spirit.
Watch yourself now,
Sister Williams,
Ain't that the truth.
-  Go, Grandma.
Yes, Lord.
Praise the Lord.
♪ Hey, fat momma,
you know you gotta be from Harlem...
♪ Hey, big easy, she know you gotta be
from nick, nick, nick, nick...
♪ Know you gotta be from nick, nick,
nick, nick, know you gotta be from Philly...
♪ Where the party at?
- ♪ Where the party at?
♪ Booty makers, put our hand in the air
Booty makers, put our hand in the air...
♪ How you makin' young ladies
scream and shout?
♪ What you do?
- ♪ Bust her out, bust her out...
♪ And if she cries on the very next day,
what you do?
♪ Freak her out, freak her out...
♪ What you do?
- ♪ Eat her out...
♪ Butt naked, baby, get busy...
♪ Butt naked, get busy...
♪ Freak it out, freak it out now...
♪ Freak it out, freak it out, freak it out now...
♪ Cali, freak it out, freak it out now
Freak it out, freak it out, freak it out now...
♪ Detroit, freak it out, freak it out now.
Y o, Malik, kid,
How's it feel? Your first day at college?
It ain't nothin', dog,
You'll be up in there next year.
I'm thinkin' about
goin' away to college myself.
Thank you, brother,
Thank you very much.
Loc, you better stop clownin', get your GD,
before you end up Like that brother,
There you go, brother,
- Thank you.
I'm gonna get me my g-o-b - a job.
They're hirin' down at BM Motors,
Come down there with me.
Not today, Loc,
I gotta take my driver's test,
♪ I know the day is dim...
♪ Chances may be slim...
♪ Hold on to what you believe.
This is what fresh air smells Like.
You Livin' it, man,
All right, man,
- All right, man,
Stay up,
- All right, man.
All right, That's enough
of all that sentimental stuff.
Yo, Malik,
Don't forget about us, baby,
Hey, one Love, baby,
- Big baby.
You know, Malik is the first one
in the 'hood to go to college.
Finally, someone from the 'hood
is gonna make it.
Yeah, there's hope,
.
Yeah.
Hello, I'm Mr, Walker,
I'm your examiner for today.
Put on your seatbelt,
check your mirrors, Let's begin.
Make a right, right there.
And make another lef there.
Park right there.
Wait here,
...
Come back here.
Somebody call the police.
Drive, motherfucker. Drive.
It was nice meeting you,
We'll be in touch.
Hey.
Yes, may I help you?
Yeah, I heard y'all niggas is hirin',
What's up?
Oh, yes,
Why don't you fill out this application?
Makin' me write and shit.
If I was white,
you wouldn't be makin' me write.
Well, actually,
originally I'm from the East Coast.
But after my master's,
I thought I'd take a break.
So here I am.
I was tired of Living off of Daddy.
Age - 1 9.
Height - six deuce, baby.
Father's name - I don't know.
Sex - hell, yeah, nigga.
Salary desired,
$3 million, Cash.
You know, being an Ivy Leaguer
can be such a Leg up,
You know, I spent five years at Harvard,
- Really?
I just spent six months at County.
Anybody ever try and take your manhood?
Then he sees the warden comin',
so he hides you.
But you've still got that plunger in your ass,
So you're cryin',
Don't you hate that?
-  Let's go,
Hey. Where y'all goin'?
- Loc Dog,
Mr, Loc Dog?
- That's me,
You're next,
- Mr, Loc Dog,
What's up, baby?
- Yeah, right,
All right?
- Yeah.
Energy, Eager man,
Yes, I Like that.
Right this way.
Let me just move this.
So Let me see.
Very interesting, I see your hobbies
are drinking, smoking weed,
and 'all types of ill shit, '
- Yeah.
Do you drive an automobile?
With or without the boot?
- Doesn't matter.
Well, congratulations,
You got yourself a job.
Right on, huh?
Hey, where the seatbelts at?
Don't worry,
They won't be necessary,
Hey, man, How do you work this radio?
- .
One more time.
Ooh, boy.
Yeah, I told you
you ain't got no game for me, boy.
Now I'm gonna wear you out,
you little punk,
What's that?
- My gat, fool,
Where did you Learn how to use a gun?
- Cartoons and 'hood movies.
Doo Rag, don't you know
that you and I are an endangered species?
Why? Because we're black males?
- No.
Because all the rappers
are takin' all the good actin' jobs.
Listen, Doo Rag,
Havin' a gun doesn't give you any power,
Know where the real power is?
- In the bullets.
No. In the books.
See, , .
Doo Rag, your mind, , ,
it is Like a gun.
And you wanna Load it up...
with little, itty-bitty...
bullets of knowledge.
Message.
Hey, what are you doin'?
Writin' a poem.
See, my poetry helps me escape
the harsh realities of Livin' in the 'hood.
Ah, that's deep.
Hey, you wanna read me one?
OK.
Let me see.
Love is by far
the most precious thing on Earth.
Like a rose's fragrance or a child's birth.
Love me and Leave me.
That's the story of my Life.
But it won't happen again, see.
Since I bought a butcher's knife.
Yeah, see, the next man
who Loves me and Leaves me so quick.
I'm gonna cut off his balls
and chop off his dick.
I'm gonna shoot that motherfucker,
Kill him.
I'm gonna stab that motherfucker
for fuckin' with me.
I'm gonna run him over with my car, see.
He fuckin' with the wrong motherfucker,
I will kill that motherfucker,
- Baby, baby, baby,
I get the point, That was, , ,
- You Liked it?
That was good.
It touched me in a really special place.
You wait right here.
I sure will,
'
by JOE.
Psst,
Dashiki was far more
sexually experienced than I was.
She taught me all about foreplay.
Until then,
I ain't never done foreplay before.
But then again, who needs foreplay
when you're jackin' off?
♪ Treat you like you're nothing...
♪ When you're worth more than gold...
♪ Girl, to me, you're like a diamond...
♪ I love the way you shine.
Are you thirsty?
♪ I'll put a string of
pearls right in your hand...
♪ Make love on a beach of jet-black sand...
♪ Outside in the rain...
♪ We can do it all night...
♪ I'll touch all the places he would not...
♪ And some you never knew
would get you hot...
♪ Nothing is forbidden when we touch.
Nuh-uh, fool,
That's the baby's Lunch,
♪ I wanna do
all of the things your man won't do...
♪ I'll do them for you...
♪ Oh, baby, I wanna do...
♪ All of the things your man won't do...
♪ Every little thing...
♪ I'll do them for you...
♪ I'll take you out
on a night cruise on a yacht...
♪ Just can't lose
'cause we've got a lot to look forward to...
♪ One, two, what you gonna do?
♪ What good is a diamond nobody can see?
♪ I hear he got you all locked down,
♪ But I got the master key...
...
♪ Tempo slow, lights down low.
Damn, girl.
You're so tight.
Wrong hole, fool.
My bad.
I couldn't believe this was happenin' to me.
I was losin' my virginity
to the woman of my dreams.
Talk dirty to me,
- I'm comin'.
What did you say?
Never mind.
I'll tell you when I wake up.
Ashtray, wake up,
What's up, baby?
- I need to tell you somethin'.
What's up?
I'm pregnant,
- Already? Are you sure?
I got seven kids,
I think I know what I'm talkin' about.
Dashiki, I'm not ready
to be no father right now.
You man enough to come up in me, but
not enough to take care of what comes out,
get my nails done, get my hair done,
pay my rent and get me a new car?
You know what?
You ain't nothin' but a little boy.
It ain't all about the size of the boat,
It's the motion in the ocean.
That's not what I'm talkin' about.
As a matter of fact, get out.
Get out of my bed. Get out of my house.
Get out. And take your shit with you,
Why you trippin'?
- I don't wanna see you no more.
I don't wanna talk to you.
- Wait.
Take your shit.
- Oh, girl, come on, This ain't mine.
Get out of my house.
Get out.
Order up.
Yo, Loc, man,
Dashiki's pregnant.
Fool, Dashiki was born pregnant,
What else is new?
What else is new? It's mine,
Thank you, Lord,
-  Are you sure?
She said I was the only one she'd
been with in the past 20 minutes.
Yes. Yes.
And you believed her?
Here you go, sucker,
I mean, brother,
That'll be 1 0, 38,
- Wash them filthy hands.
So what you gonna do now, Tray?
I don't know,
I might move out of the 'hood with her.
What?
Oh, fool.
Look here,
Let me tell you somethin', Tray.
You could take Dashiki out of the 'hood,
but you can't take
the 'hood niggas out of Dashiki,
...
Damn five-o,
- Damn.
You there. Get out of the truck
and put your hands in the air.
Stand on one leg.
With the tip of your finger,
touch the tip of your nose.
Now in a circular motion,
rub your stomach and pat your head...
while saying,
'Rubber baby buggy bumper. '
Rubber baby buggy bumper,
Strike a pose. Now Vogue.
.
Now walk slowly toward the car.
We didn't even do nothin'.
What?
You think you're tough.
You don't Look so tough now,
little nigga.
I hate you black bastards, You stink.
I hate your black skin.
I hate your black pants.
I hate black pepper.
I hate black keys on a piano.
I hate my gums, 'cause they black.
I hate Whoopi Goldberg's Lips.
I hate the back of Forest Whitaker's neck.
And most of all,
I hate that black ass, Wesley Snipes.
Move it.
Come on,
- Let's go,
We got arrested
for bein' black on a Friday night.
Don't try anything, all right?
It was a misdemeanor,
so I thought we'd be out right away.
Right there, right there.
All right get in there.
What's up, young blood?
- What's up?
Swine, my brother?
No, thanks,
- Now Let me tell you somethin'.
If you hit a man,
in time, his wounds will heal.
And if you steal from a man,
you can replace what you steal.
And always cross in the green,
never in between.
Because the honorable
Elijah Mohammad Ali...
floats Like a butterfly and stings Like a bee.
Thinkin' about
another minute with Farra-convict...
made me never want
to do time in the joint again.
Boy, am I happy to see you, man,
- Always remember, my brother,
one fish, two fish,
red fish, blue fish.
Knick knack paddy whack,
give the dog a bone.
Two thousand zero zero party, oops.
Outta time.
My bacon's smellin' fine,
What's up, Toothpick?
- What's up?
All ready to go jump this fool in?
Let's do this, AI Dog,
What's up, homie? Ready to do this?
- Yeah, man, I'm ready,
What's up?
- What's up?
You've been hangin'
with the homies for a while,
It's about time we jump your punk ass in,
- That's right.
Let me tell you somethin',
In this world, if you can't swim, , .
You bound to driz-own.
And if you fall,
you better pick your punk ass up.
And the rest of y'all, , .
Don't cut him no slack.
Y'all fools get busy.
Work him, Dog, work him,
...
♪ G, that is his name,
If he can't hang...
♪ He's got to get out the game
Yeah, get out the game...
♪ G, that is his name,
If he can't hang...
♪ He's got to get out the game,
get out the game...
♪ He's little G,
if he can't hang...
♪ Then he can hang...
We're gonna have to play
Po'Nopoly again sometime,
You ain't winnin' nothin', anyway.
And the money that you do win,
I'll jack you for it.
Hey. Which one of y'all's Ashtray?
What's up? Heard you got my boy
Toothpick's girlfriend pregnant?
Me?
- Yeah, you,
Hey, brother, man, , ,
- What's up?
I don't want no trouble, man,
- You must not have heard me.
Tray, Let me handle this Like a gentleman.
My man, my man say
he don't want no trouble.
Got you. Come here, you punk.
Get the head.
Come on. Move your body.
What's up now, partner? Huh, partner?
Stay right there. Stay there.
- We shouldn't, , .
Nice execution.
I'm gonna give that a 8.
Yeah, make him cripple. Make him
cripple Like me. Stomp him. Yeah,
After stompin' one of Toothpick's
boys, we knew we had to get backup.
So we went to our homie
Old School's house.
You sure this guy's gonna have our back?
Let me tell you about Old School.
He's the most dangerous OG on the set.
Let me tell you young punks somethin'.
I've been down on this 'hood a Long time,
I seen a Lot of things.
I survived the Watts riots gang wars,
And you know how I did it?
How?
By standin' my ground
and havin' my homies watch my back,
Word.
- So don't Let nobody mess with your set.
And Like me,
don't Let nobody give you no shit.
Yeah, Old School.
- Bartholomew.
Bartholomew.
Come here, boy.
- Oh, shit,
What did you say, boy?
- I said, 'Oh, shoot, ' Ma, Shoot.
Didn't I tell you to clean your room?
Oh, Ma, come on,
The gang needs me, I'm their Leader.
Gang?
Get in there and clean that room
in the next ten minutes...
or else you gonna be walkin'
down the street with three shoes.
Two on your feet
and one in your ass, sucker.
Thank you, Momma.
So you gonna roll with us?
I can't,
- Why not?
Oh, the police is after you, huh?
Nah, I'm on punishment,
My mom says I can't Leave the porch.
Come on, Let's hold the porch down.
Say, that's a nice walker, Lady,
Cough it up. Turn around. Snap.
Give it up.
Man, I need to get out of this place.
What you talkin' about?
Leave the 'hood?
This is home sweet home.
I Love the smell of gun smoke
in the mornin'.
Yo, Preach,
at Least Ashtray got a dream.
That's more than most homies in the 'hood.
Why, little Foots, you got a dream?
Yeah, I got a dream,
...
♪ U can't touch this...
♪ Break it down...
♪ Stop. Hammer time.
Hey, Loc, I hope you ain't sellin'
out on me with no jive-ass dream.
Oh, hell, no,
You know I ain't got no self-esteem.
I ain't gonna grow up to be shit,
just Like you, baby.
Where are them busters hidin' at?
Probably over that trick house,
- What trick?
Dashiki, fool,
I miss makin' Love to her,
- Me too,
What you talkin' about?
- I was helpin' you,
Hell you was helpin' me.
- You was Locked up, fool.
Just give me the book.
Man, can you hook me up
with directions to Crenshaw?
Fool, get your crusty behind away from me.
Man, I'll suck your dick, man,
What did you say to me?
- I'll suck your dick, man.
Oh, man.
All right, so what you wanna do, my man,
is go to the corner,
go about three blocks down and make a
right and you'll be right there on Crenshaw.
Go Old School, go Old School,
...
What shall we do?
- Run Like a bitch, fool.
Momma.
Let's go.
I'm hit.
Yo, Legs. Legs.
Are you OK, man?
You got hit by the bullets, man?
No, I got hit by a car.
Come on, nigga, Let's help him, , .
Let's get him in the truck,
Get his baby shoe.
All right nigga, help me out. Come on.
Why?
Bring your simple ass, Tray.
My head. My head.
J-Nug, are you all right?
Answer me, man. You all right? J-Nug.
Sister. We need a doctor fast.
I went to see Jason's Lyric this weekend.
Gee, wasn't he cute? Did you see
his butt, though? It was hairy.
I didn't think that ass-fro was cute.
We need a doctor right now,
I'm gonna have to call you back,
- Right now, Sister.
What I'm gonna need you to do
is fill this form out.
OK, Thank you.
May I have a pen, please? Thank you.
Excuse me,
You know where I could get some water?
Oh, God.
Here,
Thanks,
- You're number 1,012,
1,012,
Number 213.
Now serving number 213.
Damn.
- Damn, I hope I'm next.
Come on, We're gonna do it,
Between Crazy Legs bein' hit
in a drive-by, the Korean store shootings,
jail and Dashiki bein' pregnant,
I felt I was about to explode.
What are you doin'?
Tryin' to win Best Actor
on the Soul Train Awards.
Look, Dashiki,
I'm sorry about Last night.
I thought about it
and I wanna be a father to my child.
And another thing.
I also realized how much I Love you.
And I wanna Leave the 'hood with you.
But there's somethin'
we need to do before we go.
I'm takin' the kids
and I'm movin' out of the 'hood.
I wanted them
to say goodbye to their daddies.
Give me the man.
You're a good brother, Tray, Dad.
Me?
I've been in jail a Long time, T.
Sometimes I feel Like a caged animal.
How come you never came
to see me, man?
Nigger, I don't know you.
Oh, yeah.
You don't know me, That's right.
Well, dig this here, Tray.
Teach my son how to be a man, Tray,
How to be a man.
Give me some.
Jif.
Hey, what's up?
Hey, man, you got everythin'?
Cool,
I'm gonna get some, right?
- Don't even play me Like that.
Come on, man,
♪ Hush, I'm comin' through
with the bum rush...
♪ Feelers for style and dealers coke rush...
♪ What? My style's ridiculous
Who's gettin' with that spectaculous...
♪ Miraculous word directs us,
I'm from New York...
♪ I'm fallin ' like Dom P
I once popped the cork...
♪ I feel a need for real dope...
♪ I'm the one who came from the back and
blew the brains out of Al Pacino...
♪ Word up Welcome to this tradition...
♪ Of lyricism I'm on a
Doug E Fresh mission...
♪ Somebody stop me
I'm out of control, please...
♪ Before I do autopsies on these MCs...
♪ Open them up,
they're hollow on the inside...
♪ No heart pumpin '
Their organ missin ' somethin '
♪ Trueness, yeah, they get no props...
♪ Without doubt,
I come with the real hip-hop.
What's up, Crazy?
Hey, brother,
How you feelin', man?
How you doin', brothers?
Doctors say I ain't ever gonna walk again,
No.
- Oh, no.
It's gonna be all right,
- Hold me.
Fool, get off me.
You been paralyzed for the Last five years.
Oh, yeah.
Don't worry, Legs, man.
If we ever find that Toothpick,
I'm gonna smoke him.
No. We need to put an end
to all this black-on-black crime.
We need to call a truce.
What about that time you shot Byron?
Ain't that black-on-black crime?
No, Byron was Light-skinned,
- Oh, yeah,
You're about to go to this party?
- Yeah,
You gonna be doin' some drinkin'?
- Just a little.
Let me tell you about drinkin' and drivin'.
That shit is fun, man,
What you do is get yourself a 40.
Then get on the freeway,
punch it to 85.
Turn off your Lights,
Let go of the steerin' wheel,
It will bug you out. Try it.
- I'm gonna try that.
Why didn't y'all invite me to the party?
Come on, Pop, You gotta be 1 8 and older,
Oh, man.
- Besides, it's past your bedtime.
Did you brush your teeth?
Let me see.
No, There we go,
All right, I'm out,
- All right.
Before you go,
won't you read me a bedtime story?
All right, just one,
- That's all I need.
Get to a good one, There we go,
'This is the story of Dick and Mary,
'Mary Lies on the bed
and spreads her thighs,
'Dick thrusts his Large member
into her waiting vagina,
''Fuck me. Fuck me. ' Mary screams,
'Dick covers her
with a pillow 'cause she's noisy,
'Dick continues to pound her
swollen opening until he climaxes,
''I'm comin'. I'm comin'. '
And he falls asleep, '.
Good night, Pops,
.
Domino, nigga. Yeah.
Hey, what's up, niggas?
What's up?
Hey, you makin' some, Jiffy Pop?
What up?
- Hey, what's up? How you doin'?
What's up, nigga?
Black-on-black crime.
What's up, man?
I got one question,
Who got that chronic, nigga?
Man, I got that ill killer shit,
Guaranteed to fuck you up.
Hey, nigga, Light that shit up,
Fuck me up.
Toke, toke, nigga, Toke it. Toke it.
Look at that shit, nigga.
Hey, man, he's goin' into convulsions.
Man, he ain't breathin'.
- He's foamin' at the mouth.
Yo, he dead.
Yo, pass that shit.
Yo, pass that.
Hit it.
Hit it. Hit it. Hit it. Hit it.
See, that's what
I'm talkin' about, Sabomboo,
Suck it,
- Niggers tryin' to hide the good shit.
Hey, baby, you wanna dance?
Yes, I do, But not with you.
Her right, Her right,
Her right, Her right.
Hey, girl, How you doin'?
My name is Loc Dog,
What's your name?
- La Quanda.
La Quanda, do you have a boyfriend?
No, You know, men always seem
to be really intimidated by me.
But I don't know why.
Well, you know.
I can understand how a pretty girl Like
yourself might make a man a little sick.
I mean nervous.
Yeah, well, it takes a really special
kind of man to be with me,
...
You know?
- Yeah, well, Let me go find him.
Damn, girl,
you need to slow down with that.
You ain't my daddy
and you ain't payin' any of my bills.
Mind your business,
Oh, this is my song.
.
Hi.
Hi, my name is Loc Dog,
What's your name?
Keisha,
- Keisha,
You always this shy, Keisha?
- Mm-hm.
Keisha, what do you say we go back
to my place and have a nightcap?
I don't know,
I just met you.
Hey, girl, the dog don't bite
unless you ask me,
OK,
- All right, come on.
I guess it'd be all right.
Baby, you really Love me.
You know I do, girl.
I really shouldn't.
Come on, girl,
It ain't gonna hurt you.
It's just that, when I drink,
sometimes I get a little crazy.
And that's what l want.
I don't want you to think
I'm a freak or nothin' Like that.
I usually don't even go home with guys
when I first meet them.
But I just feel so comfortable with you.
Hey, that's good, girl.
Whenever you with me, I want you
to just relax and be yourself.
You are so nasty,
I should be goin'.
Whoa, come on, baby, Relax.
Just relax.
Don't you go nowhere,
You're in good hands now, girl.
Loc Dog's gonna take
good care of you, baby,
Are you sure it's OK?
- Mm-hm.
I want you to just be yourself, OK?
I told you I could get a little crazy.
Yeah, you get crazy, Come on.
OK,
All right, motherfucker, Let's get it on.
- .
Oh, no, nigga,
you ain't goin' nowhere,
.
Fresh air, fresh fish.
Nothin' Like the great outdoors, huh, Pop?
Pop, can we talk,
teenager to teenager?
See, I met this girl,
She's pretty special.
She's movin' out of the 'hood in
a couple of days and I wanna go with her,
Man, who is this girl?
- Her name's Dashiki,
Dashiki. From Penetration Avenue?
- Come on, Pop.
Don't tell me you slept with her too?
- Oh, no, it ain't nothin' Like that, son,
She sure could suck a dick, though,
- What?
Nothin', son, Go ahead,
Tell me about this girl.
Anyway, I think I'm in Love,
So what? You knockin' boots yet?
- Yeah.
Hold on, You use a condom?
No,
- Good. That's my boy. That's my boy.
Never use condoms, son,
They take away all the feelin'.
Yeah, only thing is, now she's pregnant,
I don't know what to do.
Man, Look, , .
Let me give you the same advice
my father gave me, all right?
Give up hope, Look at me,
Dreams are for suckers.
Ain't no future for you,
And don't think about gettin' no job, Tray,
'Cause the black man
ain't got no place in the workforce.
So hold up, Let me get this straight,
What you're tryin' to say is...
don't get caught in the white man's
self-perpetuatin' unemployment...
and tryin' to survive on welfare checks?
Wrong. Ain't nothin' wrong with
welfare checks, It's free money.
Our family survived six generations on it,
Thanks, You always know what to say,
- Thought you knew, boy.
My boy Tray gettin' himself some sex.
Gettin' Locked up in the city ain't the same.
Get the map, Get the map.
Fuck it, Let's go twist
these niggas in a cat bag, man.
Read it, Man, read this,
Come on, Let's go,
Drive,
- Let's go,
What's up, Loc?
- What's up, Tray?
I can't believe your mark ass
is finally Leavin' the 'hood.
Yep, yep, yep,
Me and Dashiki's gonna tie that knot,
- Tie a knot in that bitch's tubes.
Really.
I actually think we're gonna be all right,
Why don't you come with us?
- What?
Take a road trip in a mail truck?
That's the stupidest idea I heard.
Well, anyway, you just be careful.
Come on now, baby,
you talkin' to Loc Dog.
You know I'm gonna be all right.
Shoot.
Hey, Tray, , .
Never forget, man.
Either they don't know,
don't show, or just don't care...
about bein' a menace to South Central
while they drink their juice in the 'hood.
That's what it's all about, Tray.
I'm sorry, man.
What the fuck is he talkin' about?
What's up, little homie?
- What's up?
Hey, you want some of this?
Make you grow hair on your little nuts.
Don't be givin' that little kid no alcohol,
Nigger, you ain't his daddy,
- I ain't?
Dashiki. Bitch, you better
give me back my child support money.
What's up, little man?
- Shh.
Like I was sayin',
what's up with them hoes tonight?
Take care of my baby, all right?
And my truck,
What?
- Come on, Tray, you know I'm only playin',
Just shoot everythin' in sight,
.
Fool. Break yourself.
Somebody help me.
I'm comin'.
Is you OK, snowflake?
- Oh, yes, my big chocolate warrior.
You know you fucked up, right?
Yeah, you fucked up.
Hear what I'm sayin'?
Hey, Grandma,
You got the juice now.
Oh, go to hell.
Where else will I find a pussy-whipped fool
to take care of me and seven kids?
Oh, Ashtray.
Listen, sister, Listen.
You are a strong African-American woman,
It's because of that, I can't be with you,
- .
Oh, Look at that, Time for me
to take out the poor, white trash.
Who are you callin' whipped, girl?
You're alive,
- Ow.
Oh, Lord, why you do this to me?
Oh, I can't take it. I can't take it.
I can't take it. Oh, my Lord.
Oh, my baby.
Oh, Momma, Momma,
I swallowed my toothpick, Momma.
Oh, baby, you're OK.
Now where's my money you stole,
you little hoodlum?
Give me my money, I want my money.
I'll beat the shit outta you.
Where's my money?
Well, that's my story.
As for Dashiki and I, we got married.
Loc Dog went into show business.
Suck my dick and, , ,
Lick your ass.
Preach, he settled down.
Crazy Legs' dream of becomin'
a dancer finally came true.
And as for Grandma...
Well, she's still Grandma.
Damn. This is some good shit,
...
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ Yes, the hour's four,
I told you before...
♪ Prepare for mic fights
- ♪ And plus the Cold War...
♪ This rhyme you digest
through the RZA console...
♪ Ask why I slam nine diagram pole...
♪ Raekwon dropped the bomb,
Hunchback, Notre Dame...
♪ Golden Arms is bronze,
buddah palm hit Qu'ran...
♪ It blows extreme,
mean stream be the theme...
♪ Supreme team, America's Cream Team,
redeemed Vidal Sassoon...
♪ Chrome tones hear the moans
of Al Capone...
♪ Gun power to the dome
And split the bone...
♪ Wig blown off the ledge by the alleged,
full-fledged, sledge RZA edge...
♪ One dose of my ferocious
handheld trigger cuts...
♪ Acapella spittin ' shell
paralyzed when you get touched...
♪ And critical mic cords, hangin ' like
umbilical cords, dope swords...
♪ Five star general
Raw be the quote rap style, sore throat...
♪ Through the fully operational,
handheld totem...
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin ' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ More than a thousand times one,
snatch up my styles get done...
♪ I hold a title,
enhanced how my belt was won...
♪ Check it, slick majestic,
broke mics are left infected...
♪ Germs start to spread through
your crew, drew like an epic...
♪ You asked for it,
shot up the jams like syringes...
♪ My technique alone blows doors
straight off the hinges...
♪ Masked Avenger,
I appear to blow your ear like wind...
♪ With a freestyle,
sharper than the Indian spear...
♪ So sit back and let the king explore...
♪ Describe me,
the kid's nice and he holds swords...
♪ And his name,
black attack's the nerve like migraines...
♪ With more games than beggars on trains
livid sharp pains...
♪ Poisonous Rebel like Deck,
you can't destroy this...
♪ They get ambushed, skate,
try to avoid this...
♪ Side effects of hot raps and hot tracks...
♪ A duffle bag full of guns, son,
dipped in black...
♪ My culture, glides and attacks
just like a vulture...
♪ Ghostface in Madison Square
is on your poster...
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ Yes, the hour's four,
I told you before...
♪ Prepare for mic fights
And plus a Cold War...
♪ Be on the lookout
for this mass murderous suspect...
♪ That fills more body bags
than apartments in projects...
♪ And as far as the coroners know
the autopsy show...
♪ It was a Shaolin blow put on by my
family brought to the academy...
♪ Of the Wu and learned how to
fuck up yo' anatomy...
♪ Steadily, calm and deadly...
♪ Splatter-head lyrics
I lick through your transmit...
♪ MC's submit to the will
as I kill your juvenile freestyle...
♪ Civilize the mental,
devils worship this like an icon...
♪ Bear-huggin' mics
with the grips of a python...
♪ Yes, the shit is raw,
comin' at your door...
♪ Start to scream out loud,
Wu-Tang's back for more...
♪ You heard other raps before
but kept waitin' for the sun of song...
♪ I keep dancehalls strong
Beats never worthy of my cause...
♪ I prolong Extravaganza,
time sits still...
♪ No propaganda,
be wary of the skill...
♪ As I bring forth the music,
make love to your eardrum...
♪ Dedicated to rap, nigga,
beware of the fearsome Lebanon Don...
♪ Malcolm X beat threat CD massacre,
murder to cassette...
♪ I blow the shop up,
you ain 't seen nothin ' yet...
♪ One man ran,
tryin' to get away from it...
♪ Put your bifocal on,
watch me a-cometh...
♪ Into your chamber
like Freddy enter dream...
♪ Discombobulate your technique
and your scheme...
♪ Four course applause,
like a black dat to dat...
♪ You're stuck on stupid
like I'm stuck on the map...
♪ Nowhere to go except next show, bro...
♪ Entertainin' motherfuckers can't stop oh...
♪ In battlin',
you don't want me to start tattlin'
♪ All upon the stage
cause y'all snakes keep rattlin'
♪ Bitch, you ain't got nothin' on the rich...
♪ Every other day
my whole dress code switch...
♪ So just in case
you want to clock me like Sherry...
♪ All y'all crab bitches ain't got to worry...
♪ Can't get a nigga like Don dime a dozen...
♪ Even if I'm smoked out
I can't be scoped out...
♪ I'm too ill,
I represent Park Hill...
♪ See my face on the twenty-dollar bill...
♪ Cash it in,
and get ten dollars back...
♪ The fat LP with Cappuccino on the wax...
♪ Pass it in your thing,
put valve up to twelve...
♪ Put all the other LP's back on the shelf...
♪ And smoke a blunt,
and dial 9- 1-7- 1-6-0-4-9-3- 1 1...
♪ And you could get
long dick hip-hop affection...
♪ I damage any MC
who step in my direction...
♪ I'm Staten Island's best son
fuck what you heard...
♪ Niggers still talkin' that shit is absurd...
♪ My repertoire is USSR...
♪ PLO style got thrown out the car...
♪ And ran over, by the Method Man jeep...
♪ Divine can't define
my style is so deep like pussy...
♪ My low cut fade
stay bushy like a porcupine...
♪ I part backs like a spine, cut you
like a blunt and reconstruct your design...
♪ I know you want to diss me,
but I can read your mind...
♪ 'Cause you weak in the knees, like SWV...
♪ Tryin' to get a title like Wu Killa Bee...
♪ Kid, change your habit,
you know I'm friends with the Abbott...
♪ Me and RZA ridin',
name printed in the tablet...
♪ Under vets,
we paid our debts for mad years
♪ Hibernate the sound, and now we out
like beers and blunt power.