Gosh, my cellphone.
I think I left it in the car.
I'll go get it.
Hey, he pulled the car and received
gifts from his fans yesterday.
Are you serious?
Why didn't we go there yesterday?
I thought he'd drink all night long.
I mean, why do I always
not get to see him?
Even a passing dog sees him,
and I don't.
I hope I can see his face
at least once.
Why did it have to be
yesterday of all days?
It's all good.
We're all ready. We just
need Anthony to walk in now.
Okay.
Go, go. Let's go.
- She's so pretty.
- She's really pretty.
Camera five, are you
getting the corner?
Yes, that's it.
(We Got Married)
Here you go.
(You are now a couple.)
(Come up with a sweet nickname
for each other.)
Do you want something? Coffee?
A soda? Or water?
I made him feel uncomfortable.
I should not. I'm remorseful.
Let's be careful.
What nicknames should we go for?
Shall we think about that?
People are saying you look nicer
than Rain and Kim Tae Hee.
I knew it.
You should exchange phone numbers,
get together with a beer
if you can, and get closer.
For the sake of the show.
Sure. It was a long day.
- Great job.
- Bye.
What a downpour.
- See you for our next shoot.
- Okay, bye.
- Let's go.
- Well done today.
Yes, thanks.
Jin Jin, can you wait here?
I'll get you an umbrella.
I'll walk you to your car.
I love the smell of autumn rain.
Hello?
50,000 dollars?
Sure, I'll see what I can do.
It's no trouble at all.
Did you skip dinner again?
- You'll get sick doing that.
- Jin Jin.
Just a moment.
Thanks.
Okay, take care of yourself.
Fess up while we're being nice.
Real friends celebrate
a friend's good news.
We're ready...
to celebrate your great news.
Now fess up.
Stop grinning so hard.
What happened today? Tell us.
How dare you?
This won't do.
You evil witch. We shall punish you.
Fess up right now. Confess.
Confess. Tell us.
What happened today?
- Tell us or else.
- Stop! Stop it!
- Go on.
- I won't!
(The fifth story:
Everybody has secrets)
Tell us right now.
What was your first impression?
(Anthony's first impression?)
Jin Jin? What was
your first impression of him?
(Zoned out)
It was good to see her.
I watched her movies and dramas.
Jin Jin said she's been
a long-time fan of yours.
(Jin Jin is a long-time fan.)
Right. I'm always
thankful for my fans.
It's a secret, okay?
Keep it a secret.
That's it? It's nothing, really.
It's "We Got Married" with Anthony.
It's a virtual relationship.
It's not real. It's fake.
Still, you never know
what will happen.
I love it.
- Ji Won, let's play a game.
- I'll be right there.
(In 1999)
Who is this woman?
Don't call her that.
That's my mother.
This is...
the only photo Anthony has
of him with his mom.
She died giving birth to him.
He never got to say "mom" to her.
Jin Jin.
- Look at this.
- What?
Her eyes and Anthony's
are the same, aren't they?
Jin Jin! Sa Jin Jin!
What?
You just redid your interior.
Our upstairs neighbor's
boiler exploded.
Oh, dear, your house must be a mess.
Come over to my place.
It's fine. I'm staying
at the house upstairs.
- Upstairs?
- Yes.
- It's my friend's place.
- Won't you feel uncomfortable?
It'll be fine.
We're really good friends.
Yes, that's right.
- With the parents.
- Still?
Your friend doesn't have a wife yet?
That new dye job really...
I'll call you back.
Sorry, I thought
you were my brother.
What are you doing here?
Sorry, I didn't know.
What should I do?
I don't care.
- Alone?
- Yes.
- Why? What about your...
- Come on, let's play a game.
Okay. I have a lot to say.
Let's take our time.
No. You can't talk to a pig.
You play Real Madrid,
I'll play Barcelona. Deal?
- Deal.
- At last, I can play with a human.
- Are you good?
- I always played against the PC.
Here you go.
There.
Don't look.
You'll ruin your eyesight.
You're such an embarrassment.
Aren't you ashamed?
Why should I feel ashamed?
We're friends,
- aren't we?
- Yes.
It's good to see her
eat so well after a long time.
I heard the construction
starts tomorrow.
While we're at it, we should get...
the ceiling and
the walls redone too.
I was going to do that.
There's a lot to tend to.
You don't have to mind it.
You can relax, my friend.
Thanks, my friend.
How did your first night go?
Remember this.
Your body is still like
that of an infant's.
My body is different from yours.
I get it.
Right, Ji Won is
staying at my parents' place.
His boiler ruptured,
so he's staying for a few days.
Why would he stay there?
It'll be uncomfortable.
Is his wife pretty?
He's here by himself.
There must be a long story.
He's full of stories.
You should ask him about that
while he's there.
Ask what?
You said you were
really conscious about that.
Do you have time?
It'll only take five minutes.
Sure.
Anyway, what is it?
I met this person for work,
and I have to be really close
with him, so I'm worried.
- Is it a guy?
- It's work.
What kind of smell do men like?
What do you think about this one?
It's okay.
Really?
What about this one?
This is okay too.
Okay.
Right, don't you
have to get to work?
- Oh, I should go.
- Right?
I'm late.
- Goodbye.
- Okay, bye.
We must grow away from
our image as a latecomer.
By launching a new brand line,
we must emphasize the importance of
reaching the customers aggressively.
How's the natural ingredient project
of India going?
India came up with a natural product
that fights insects and diseases.
We decided to make use of
the materials from Egypt.
This product has been tested
and confirmed for safety...
in Indonesia, Malaysia,
and Thailand as well.
Let's move on.
Kimchi?
You can eat it.
I don't eat kimchi anyway.
You should still
be considerate of Mother.
Your passcode is the same, right?
Jin Jin, we're here.
I'll come up right now.
No, I'll be there.
I already walked out the door.
Here. President Jang said you can
take time and look over them.
Oh, and one of them is
Producer Choi's new project.
It's a blockbuster with
60 million dollars in budget.
Oh, my. Okay.
Something smells great.
I don't think it's coming from
you though.
No, it's not me.
Oh, the actress lady
must've been here.
Hong Hee, I heard you were
visiting your parents.
You can give this to them.
And send them my regards.
It's for them, not you. Take it.
Thank you.
Gosh, you don't look like the type,
but you're pretty considerate.
Did you say
you have a younger brother?
You definitely seem
like the eldest daughter.
I'm the youngest daughter.
I have an older sister.
What? How come I never heard
that you have a sister?
I'll get going.
Jin Jin.
Take this.
It was buy 1 get 1 free.
You're a newlywed bride, so
you should take care of your skin.
I'm a model for a cosmetics company.
You can keep this
for yourself next time.
Bye.
Jin Jin, have this. Open your mouth.
- Bye, Jin Jin.
- Goodbye.
Do you live here?
My brother lives here too.
His brother?
But he doesn't have a brother.
It looks like
you two will get married.
My gut feelings are always right.
When you two get married,
I'll give you a huge present.
Do you want a fridge?
Ms. Han, I'm sorry.
I should've told you before.
I didn't want this to happen.
Ji Hye, you are horrible at
reading between the lines.
I was joking.
I'm already 35.
Do you think I'm crazy?
Look at her, she's so naive.
I know that. Like I said,
you had nothing to worry about.
Ms. Han, Ji Hye was
really worried about this.
I told her numerous times
that you'd understand.
There's nothing to understand here.
Forget about that. Let's eat.
It's my treat today, so eat up.
Okay?
Hey, you fool.
Me? I'm at
the riverside of Han River.
The riverside of Han River.
Try to find me if you can.
Am I at Yeouido? or Jamsil?
Where am I right now?
Let's grab a drink.
Hey, you're going to fall.
I need water.
I need more male energy!
I have enough.
- Let's go.
- Hey, hey.
- I'm sorry.
- All right.
- This is great.
- Will you stay still?
I'm the virgin ghost!
Let's go! I'll get you.
Will you please stop?
- Stop it.
- I'll get you!
Hey, you know,
- I lost weight once too.
- Sure.
- Oh, keep drinking.
- I did it.
I can be sexy too.
Tall and sexy. Tall and sexy.
I can do it!
Tall and sexy. Gosh, I'm tired.
Where are you going?
I'm going for a walk.
Again?
What?
- Give me that. Let it go.
- No, no.
You told me to clean up my room.
I wanted to throw them away
on my way out.
Goodness.
You might get a hole in your stomach
even before you get married.
Stop drinking too much already.
Why would I drink if I was
going to drink only a little?
How did I give birth to
a brat like her?
And my mom made me seaweed soup
she got from Wan Island...
for giving birth to
that troublemaker.
I'm so tired.
It's a delivery.
The resident of unit 1301
told me to put the package here.
(From your vitamin)
Yes, my package is here.
It's Ji Won's.
I think his wife sent it to him.
What is she saying?
Ji Won, I came back safely
from my school field trip.
I used up all the pocket money
that you gave me.
Enjoy your chocolate. With love.
Oh, right. I'm going to Seoul soon.
I'll let you go on a date with me.
Let's go eat delicious food.
- Is it the girl you talked about?
- Yes.
Right? I knew she was your sister.
Then why did Jin Jin say
such nonsense?
What?
She said you are married,
and your wife sent you this.
What?
- Alone?
- Yes.
- Why? What about your...
- Come on, let's play a game.
Okay.
Goodness.
Are you busy?
The gather of the Bongos.
The Bongos was established in 1999,
but its earliest beginning goes back
to 1983, the year of our births.
It's the social gathering
with a long history.
We didn't have you for 17 years,
but staring today,
we'll be complete again.
Our main job is to have
fried chicken.
Koreans have a total of
80 million chickens a year.
The Bongos is contributing
a lot to it.
What I mean is that the Bongos
is a very healthy gathering.
So...
Tell your wife not to be mistaken
about our relationship.
She absolutely...
doesn't need to.
Men and women can't be friends as
long as there are drinks and nights?
That's ridiculous.
We're friends.
We're just best friends.
Who said that?
Okay, we're just friends,
not best friends.
Who said that I was married?
I'm not married.
Let's not spread false rumors.
- You're not married?
- No.
Not even once?
- How about wedding...
- Quiet.
I almost got married.
Then you called off...
Quiet.
Let's leave the past behind.
What?
We won't ask about your past.
- Let's make it clear first.
- What?
We've never dated anyone before.
And we don't have boyfriends.
Then I'll make it clear too.
Make what clear?
I'm not dating anyone now.
That's great. That's perfect.
- Then let's settle it within here.
- Settle what?
I hate to admit it,
but objectively speaking, he's okay.
It's hard to meet someone
as handsome as he is.
And we don't want him
to date other girls either.
You're right about that.
So choose one among us.
Date one of us.
Choose one. Who do you want?
- Among you three?
- Yes.
Of course, it's you, Young Shim.
I missed you every day.
Why do we have to do this?
It's obviously you,
Ah Reum.
What? You're not
getting nervous, are you?
I'm more nervous than you.
I missed you, my Jin Jin.
What's there to think?
I choose Jin Jin.
Why?
She's my first love.
Your first love?
First love, my foot.
You think I don't know?
- What?
- You're after her money.
You're such a scumbag.
Where on earth did you go
that you're being like this?
Right. Where did you go?
- We looked everywhere for you.
- Right.
Didn't I tell you?
It's pouring down.
- Goodness.
- It's raining so hard.
Why is it raining so hard?
I hate it when it's cold.
It's terrible.
Hey, let's take the shortcut.
Okay.
Get home safely.
It was nice to see you.
Bye.
- Bye.
- Hold the umbrella.
How old is your brother?
- He's three years older than me.
- I see.
- And your sister is a junior?
- Yes.
- She must be so cute.
- She's cute.
You were cute too when you
were a junior in high school.
(Sa Jin Jin)
But...
why did we do it then?
What do you mean?
Why...
did we break up?
Don't you really remember?
No, I don't. What is it?
Forget it.
I'll just ask the others then.
Are you crazy?
They don't know we dated.
Why not?
- Because it's a secret.
- A secret?
Yes, so don't tell them
until the day you die.
I refuse.
You want to die?
How could you say such a thing
as an actress?
Anyway, don't tell them.
- I refuse.
- Stop it.