No... What did she do
so wrong that she has to apologize?
Because she didn't do what she was suppose to do, my
daughter just showed what was supposed to be done.
What do you mean? Say something that makes sense.
Just because Bin is not doing well right now,
she expressed her frustration physically!
Bin's mother is no joke.
Ah, geez.
You... Apologize to Bin!
If you don't, I won't send you home today.
Who are you not let to my daughter go home?
Wow, you really have no conscience.
Everyone knows that not one scene can
be shot because of her NGs (No Goods).
While filming, NGs are possible.
How are you going to make her into a child
actress without even understanding that?
Why don't you just do well yourself?
Aigoo... What to do? She can't act. You should
have had her practice more before coming.
If she has no talent, why
do you have her in acting?
This is her first shoot. Her very first!
Is there a kid who is good from start?
My mom is right.
You! Apologize to Bin right now!
Won Shik! Won Shik!
Yes, Director?
Let's rest for ten minutes.
Okay! We'll take a break!
A ten-minute break!
Let's go.
Excuse me.
I'll have Bin practice her acting. Why don't have Ji Young
to apologize for pushing Bin earlier, however she wanted?
Pushing me was wrong on your part.
Apologize.
Sorry. Sorry for pushing you earlier.
Okay.
Enough? Let's go.
Mom is pitiful.
You're not hurt?
I'm not.
It's a break, let's practice.
Okay.
You did so well at home, though.
But still, that's fascinating. How can
you fight during the first shooting?
She and her mom were terrible.
Let's say that she endured it for hundred times and
couldn't hold in the anger any longer so she pushed Bin.
Then the mom should scold her child, but
instead was talking all righteously.
That ahjumma is truly a strange ahjumma.
That's right. When the
filming ended, I heard
that the kid was famous in her neighborhood and
that her Mother was known as a major crank.
She picked the wrong person. You're not
someone who would take that kind of behavior.
Jye Yeong got a serious
scolding from Mom today.
Bin, that today you called Mom, "Mom",
Mom was extremely happy.
Unni, you're now calling my Mom, "Mom"?
Then, I'll also call my
stepdad, "Dad." Daddy!
Of course you can, our youngest daughter.
Ah, right. Bin, what about Mom?
Finish what you were saying.
Mom said to Jye Yeong that she wouldn't
let her go home until she apologized.
So, Jye Yeong said to me she was sorry.
Your Mom, since she was this little,
she never came home from
a fight she didn't win.
But, what if she torments Bin again?
That's why, for now, I need to
go to the filming location.
That way those people won't dare
bother Bin. Don't you think so, Bin?
Also, if I had gone with Grandpa it would have been a
disaster. He wouldn't have known how to do my hair, right?
True. Next time, I'll do your
hair and make-up even prettier.
Will you do my make-up
if I pass an audition?
Of course!
If you get picked to be filmed,
I'll be really happy for you.
I would like that.
What's the matter? Are
you in pain somewhere?
No. I'm fine.
What happened with Bin today, thank you.
You don't need to thank me. If there's any thanking to do, then I should
be saying it. When Woo Ri was crying about her dad, you were by her side.
And I'm grateful to you for always trying to
fulfill the dad role with Woo Ri and Woo Joo
That's given since I'm their dad now.
Still, is it easy to decide to do that from
the start? I'm in awe of you every day.
Why? I guess you're not doing
that with Soo and Bin, huh?
I'm not saying that I'm not. But honestly, I'm more careful
around them than I would be with Woo Young or Woo Ri.
And at times, eyes from the
second floor are watching me too.
In any case, thank you for
opening up Bin's heart.
Soo and Bin don't even remember their mom.
Today, I was much happier
because Bin called me "Mom."
Thanks to you I got to hear
Woo Joo call me "Dad."
Daddy, read a book to me.
Ok, Woo Joo. What shall we read?
Let's read over here with me.
What should we read?
"Let's figure it out together."
"We can tell what it is just
by looking at the shape."
"It's time for school." It's written here.
"I will call it the lucky fin."
Call it a lucky fin.
"It will bring you luck."
- Wait a minute. Bellflower root. There is Bellflower root in the fridge.
- Okay.
Get that out too.
Let's see if the fish is done grilling.
What's going on? What's with the
sumptuous feast for breakfast?
I'm trying to feed Teacher Kim.
Teacher Kim? Tae Min? Why would
Tae Min be eating at our house?
You said that Teacher Kim is
not eating at his home lately.
If he is not being fed at his house, then we
should at least feed him before sending him home.
They said they're coming; I
wonder why they're not here yet.
I might not know how Teacher
Kim's mom treats you, but
take a look at Teacher Kim.
Look at how hard he is trying even
though we are objecting to him.
He says he'll handle everything
to change his mother's mind.
He even comes here in the
morning to run with your dad.
I also tried to behave well.
Calling her "ahjumma" is behaving well?
If you showed your temper once that's
enough. Also, you still like Teacher Kim.
Then you should also lower your head and get
in there if you're not planning to break-up.
Let's see.
I have octopus that I bought. Should I
cook it quickly in the pressure cooker?
Madam, there's no space on the table.
Really? Bin really said "Mother"?
Yes. So our whole family
were all surprised. Right?
Yeah. That's right. I was
really surprised, too.
Woo Joo called me "Dad" too,
after hearing Bin say it.
That's great, I'm glad. It boosted the
kid's confidence and gave affection too.
I'm glad that the kids' mom
went there instead of me!
Then I'll be on my way.
You're not thirsty today?
Why don't you eat with us before you go?
Where? On the third floor?
Mother-in-law asked me to make sure
he eats with us before he goes.
Really? Can I really do that?
Well, I didn't allow it yet.
My principles are unchanged.
I can only allow it after you convince
your parents. Before then, there's no way.
He's trying his best to convince
them right now, Father.
Don't be like that and
please open up your heart.
It's hard enough for them. It'll
be nice to lessen their burden.
Come on, let's go in. Come
on kids, let's go in.
Yes. Let's go, Teacher.
Let's go. Hurry up.
Let's go.
I don't want to eat breakfast, Grandma.
How can you go to work on an empty stomach?
Just have a little at least.
It's okay. My stomach doesn't
feel good, that's why.
You still don't feel okay?
Then... You should go to the hospital.
I was going to, but I'm too busy with
work because there's an event going on.
I'll go once it's over.
- Go and wash up.
- Yes.
The kids must be back.
Make sure to wash well.
Teacher Kim, please eat.
Yes. I will eat well, Mother.
Okay.
But... Where's Jin Joo?
Let her be. I think she doesn't know
what to do after asking to break up.
You prepared so much food. She's usually
really good to her sons-in-law.
Teacher Kim, don't think
about anything and eat up.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
Side dishes are really delicious, Mother.
Really?
I'm relieved the taste is to your liking.
- Eat this as well.
- Yes.
- What would you like, Honey?
- Me?
Why are you making a face?
Hurry up and eat.
I am eating.
I want to see Tae Min, too.
I want to have breakfast with Tae Min, too!
Then we'll do a separate photo session with Kim Sang Min
instead of sending out reporters to his One Point lesson.
VIPs are sensitive to being photographed,
so let's pay special attention to that.
Myung Jae, please redo the
time table and upload it.
Yes, I will.
Then our meeting for today is over.
By the way, Manager Do stopped
by the business management team.
I had a short conversation with him,
and he said that Kim Sang Min's parents
were on the One Point lesson guest list.
Really?
Did you check the guest list?
Yes, I did. Manager Do told
me not to mind it too much.
He said he only mentioned it so that it doesn't
come as a surprise on the day of the event.
How did we not know about it
when they're our brand's VIPs?
There are a lot of people who don't take
part in events even if they're VIPs.
On top of that, Kim Sang Min doesn't
really go around with his parents.
That's true. The agency has always followed him
around instead, since the beginning of his career.
What do we do during the One Point lesson?
Shouldn't we take the 2nd floor
adults off of the guest list?
We already made calls and
sent out the invites.
It's one thing if they said they're not coming,
but we can't prevent them from attending.
What if they fight again that day?
Come in.
Where are your parents?
Oh, they went down to Ganghwado in
the morning for something urgent.
Come over here. Sit here. I'll be
back after putting the cake away.
Okay.
It was hot coming over here, right? Why did you insist
on coming by yourself when I offered to pick you up?
Why should you bother yourself?
It was nice to look around the apartment
complex after getting off the bus.
When I came over last time for dinner, I didn't get a
chance to look around, but the house is very clean.
Where's your room? Mom told me to
look and see if you need anything.
I don't need anything. Over there is my
room, and over there is Tae Min's room.
When we get married and Tae Min moves
out, I'll make his room into your study.
Really?
Then, what we need first
is a desk and a bookcase.
I'll get those things ready myself, too.
How can I just move in empty-handed?
I should buy things we need.
I told you, I'll get everything ready.
Sang Min, what is all this?
Isn't it nice that there are many of me?
Once we get married, let's keep one
here and keep one in your study.
When I'm traveling for competitions,
you'll be scared being home by yourself.
Won't it be reassuring? Look at me as
much as you want whenever you miss me.
I'll think about it...
We should get a new bed.
Yeon Tae. Sit down over here.
Why?
Sit over here.
Since you're in my room like
this, it finally feels real.
The fact that we're getting married
and becoming husband and wife.
After we get married, this room
will become our newlywed room.
Right.
Let's live really happily and well.
I will make you very happy.
I will make you very happy, too.
Just having you next to
me is happiness for me.
Yeon Doo. Yeon Doo, what's the matter?
I think we should keep the
life-size photos out of our home.
Why?
I like the real thing.
Huh? That...
Why not finish what we started...
I was going to buy some dishes, but you live better
than I expected for two men sharing a house together.
Since I have to watch what I eat, I try
to eat at home as much as possible.
Tae Min was the one in charge of cooking, but I've
been working really hard to learn how to cook.
You saw last time, right? My lunchbox.
Then when we get married,
you're going to cook for me?
Of course! Come and sit. It's all done.
I will eat well.
Ouch!
That's why you should watch it.
You were cute, so I tried
to do a cream-kiss...
Ouch, it hurts.
What about the trip? Have
you thought about it?
Don't be like that and let's go. Even
if it's somewhere close by, huh?
To be honest, I wanted to go see the
ocean before the summer was over, but...
Really?! Then how about Gangneung?
Have you been to Gangneung?
Go on a two day and one night trip?
Yeah. I have another morning off.
Since the shoot is in the afternoon the next day, I can take
my time coming back in the morning. Let's go, Soon Young.
But still, is it okay that we go off on a trip by ourselves
when your parents are working at the restaurant?
Of course it's okay. You know my parents aren't the
type to make us self-conscious about those things.
Also, you will soon start to show, so it'll
be harder for you to move around as easily.
While I have the time, let's
go on a short trip, huh?
Hello.
Yes, where are you off to?
I'm going to Father-in-law's restaurant
to take back the kimchi container.
Ah, I was on my way to the in-law's too.
That's great. Let's go together.
Okay.
Let's go.
Please come this way.
What brings you by at this hour? We
were about to close and leave soon.
And you too. You could have brought
this back another time, too.
Why would you bother bringing
it back so late in the evening?
I had indigestion, so I
walked here as exercise.
By chance I met her by the stairs.
And she said she was coming
by here so I came along.
I'm glad you did.
But, are the wedding preparations going well
for your daughter? Do you have a date set?
We're thinking about a fall wedding.
Omo! You found a wedding venue?
Well...
Oh don't worry. She's
marrying someone nice,
so why would you bother to think about me?
Jin Joo is Jin Joo, and your
daughter should get married.
But, I don't think it'll be easy on
Jin Joo to go through a breakup.
Apparently, Teacher Kim comes
over every morning for exercise.
Son-in-law and the kids
exercise every morning.
And he comes over all the way from
his house to here every morning.
Today he ate breakfast with
us before he went home!
I see.
In-law, you're okay with Jin Joo and Yeon
Tae marrying into the same family, right?
Of course she doesn't like it.
I don't like it either.
Our Jin Joo will get compared to
Yeon Tae for the rest of her life.
Tell me. You don't mind, right?
Well, what is there for me to mind?
It's just that... you should first...
Right? You're happy too, right?
Becoming sisters-in-law as friends will bring them
together for family events and family get-togethers.
I think it'll be fun for them.
Don't you think so?
I heard the brothers get
along really well, too.
Yeon Tae will become Jin Joo's hyungnim.
Is that okay with you?
Who cares about those titles these days?
I heard that young people nowadays
just call each other by their names
as equals. Isn't that right?
Well, that's true. You can always
change those titles later on.
In-law, I'm determined to get
Teacher Kim and Jin Joo married.
How?
You should pretend you don't know anything. It
could make it awkward for you with your in-laws.
I mean, how will you get them
married when they're so against it?
I will have to think of
ways from this moment on.
They say that even if the sky
falls, there's a way out.
I'm sure there will be a way
if I use any and all methods.
Is she...
Right? I think she's pregnant!
Why? You have indigestion?
Yes. I've been like this
since a while back.
Really? Since when?
It's been a little while.
Maybe she's pregnant with her sixth?
I know, right?
Then they'll have six kids... I
just can't be happy about it...
Well, who cares? There's
us on the 2nd floor.
Don't worry. If you have a
baby, I'll raise the baby.
Pardon?
Oh... Are you pregnant?
No, Mother. Oh, no. It's not like that.
Really? Are you sure?
Yes. I'm not, Mother.
Is it possible you're pregnant
with your third child?
It's not like that.
I've had indigestion and felt
uncomfortable since a little while back.
It's not a baby, Mom.
I've had a bit of indigestion and felt
uncomfortable since a little while back.
I think it's because I've had a lot of things
on my mind these days with work and our kids.
- Are you taking medicine?
- I should.
You should make sure to take medicine.
There's no use in ignoring pain away.
Oh, I thought you were
pregnant and was so surprised!
I thought you might be going
from having five kids to six!
But then again, it wouldn't be hard to raise
six when you're already raising five.
You don't understand me, right?
You think I'm bothering my in-laws
with their wedding preparations.
It's about your child.
How can I not understand
when I'm a mom, too?
Oh, it's something to congratulate of course
when her daughter is loved and getting married.
But I worry about Jin Joo.
Aiyoo... I'm wondering what I was doing
while she was suffering so much.
You were taking care of Soo and Bin well.
I hope my in-laws will do
well with the wedding.
And, when Jin Joo has a good man,
I'd like to marry her off fast.
By the way, Woo Young's mom...
You were nauseous earlier...
I really am not pregnant!
How long have you been that way?
It's no big deal. I used to get like
that when I was under a little stress.
By the way, you're coming to our company
tomorrow for One Point lesson, right?
Ah... Because of Jin Joo, I don't even know if I want
to go see Kim Sang Min. I don't know if I'll go or not.
They said Kim Sang Min's
parents will be there also.
They will be there?
Yes, I'm giving you a heads up.
Why are you standing here?
Let's go in, huh?
Mom.
What?
I really hate being in Seoul.
I want to go down to Kyung
Joo, to Aunt's house.
To Kyung Joo?
I want to go to Aunt's pension
and help a little with chores.
I want to escape from here and
live in a new environment, Mom.
I want to go down there and
forget about everything.
Where is So Young?
She was frustrated so she'll go home
early, after getting some fresh air.
Why don't you leave the shop to me and
go down to Kyung Joo with So Young?
Kyung Joo?
So Young wants to go down to her aunt's in Kyung
Joo because she really hates being in Seoul.
She's really not living. Her
mind is somewhere else.
She's like a shell, moving around.
I'm sorry.
I'm not saying it to hear that from you.
So Young is not in her
right mind, right now.
I'm afraid to send her down all by herself, so
please go with her and take a good care of her.
What's the matter? You don't want
to do it because of your kids?
Because I just started meeting Woo Ri...
No. Since So Young became like
this, how can I say anything?
I'll try to discuss itwith So Young.
When your spouse is having a hard
time, you should be by her side.
I knew nothing good would come out of
this kind of marriage, but I let you
because So Young said she
couldn't live without you.
You became a couple after all that.
You can't end it like this, right?
Go down there with So Young.
I'll call my younger sister.
Did they go to work already?
Son-in-law Lee! Son-in-law Lee!
Talk to me a bit before you go.
I just need five minutes.
- I'll wait in the car.
- Okay.
You know we'll have the One Point lesson today,
don't you? Did you get an invitation card?
Oh... Yes, I got it.
Do you know that your wife is ill?
Pardon?
When we were at the restaurant
yesterday, she was having dry heaves!
She's not pregnant, but her stomach
doesn't feel good and has indigestion.
Look, you must take her to the hospital. You can't
leave her like this, and let the disease progress.
If something doesn't feel right, even a tiny bit, you
have to take her to the hospital fast! Got that?
Yes... Mother-in-law.
Thanks for your advice.
Get going. Go.
She wasn't pregnant, and
yet she was nauseous?
Yes, I didn't sleep at all last night.
I couldn't bring myself to tell
Son-in-law Lee about that.
When I saw the kids' mom like
that, I thought of Jin Young.
Aigoo, this is so worrisome.
Our Jin Young went to the hospital like
that and got diagnosed with stomach cancer.
Don't talk like that!
It's only morning and you're
already making me nervous!
Aren't we going to get going?
Are you... sick?
Me? Where?
They said yesterday... that you
threw up at the restaurant.
They also said that you had heartburn
and you couldn't digest your food well.
Oh, that. When I get stressed and
tired, I get stomach distress...
Why... didn't you tell me about that?
Why didn't you tell me?!
If you are sick, you should say so. I
should be the very first one you tell!
It hasn't been that long.
It was a little ache and...
What do you mean, "It wasn't that bad"?
Are you a doctor?
Why are you angry? If I got any worse, I
was just going to go to the hospital.
My wife had stomach cancer.
We had two thirds of her stomach cut
out and we thought she could live,
since we said, "Let's overcome
this and have another kid."
And that's how she died.
No way. It's not that at all.
How can you know that? Like I
asked before, are you a doctor?
Really? They said they would
let Jin Joo get married too?
But I hear that the potential
In-Laws are against the marriage.
They said they would find a way. I
don't understand what they mean.
Doesn't that mean they would just forget about the means and
ways and just force her to get married? Aren't I right, honey?
Jin Joo getting married
will make us feel better.
I, too, really want things
to go well for Jin Joo.
But you know, we'll all be intertwined. Once she gets
married, things won't always be so quiet anymore.
Um... Mother and Father...
Yes?
I have something I need to tell you...
What is it? Tell me.
Is it okay if we go somewhere nearby for
a trip? Just for one night and two days.
Go ahead since the weather is hot.
Get some fresh breezes.
Of course! But why are you talking so carefully?
You worried we would catch on to something?
No, no. It's not that.
But anyway, thank you!
Where are going to go?
Somewhere in Gyeongpodae. Gangneung.
Gangneung is great, of course!
You are pregnant so go
and come back carefully.
Yes, Father!
Um... Mom...?
What is it?
I have to... go out for training too.
What kind of training?
Oh, Oh... A kind of support training.
Huh?
You should go then if it has to do with
school work. How long will it take?
One... One night and two days.
Then, you should prepare.
Did you pack things?
Yes, I did...
What? The second Hyungim couple
are going on a trip to Ganeung?
I think we should go somewhere
else, other than Ganeung.
We have to go to Ganeung though.
Where should we go?
The new Unni talked about Gyeougpo dae. There's a
hundred-percent chance that we'll run into each other.
I even lied to them saying that I have to
go on some training. I can't be caught.
Of course we can't be caught. I
even lied about going on training.
Then, then, then...
Then, how about Ganghwado? Since it's
not too far and I know the area.
Also, it's totally opposite
direction from Ganeung as well.
I like it. Then, let's go to Ganghwado this
time and let's go to Ganeung next time.
Well, that's that!
Why are you trying to
buy this type of thing?
What can we not do for our child? Teacher Kim
even bought flowers when he came to our house.
Is that the same thing?
I don't know. I don't know.
I'm just going to give what I give
and you just worry about the price.
Wait a minute... This...
Are you going to eat that, ma'am?
I'm going to give this to someone important
so be sure to wrap it up very well.
Yes, I understand.
I can eat this, right?
Yes, of course. You can eat it.
- Come this way please.
- Okay!
Honey, you buy a box for yourself.
Shall I?
Hae Seuk, the face portion is drooping.
Can you stretch it a bit?
- Like this?
- Looks good!
Phantom Pro Kim Sang Min, One-Point Lesson
The invited guests total ten.
Before it starts, we are going to receive
questions and put them all on here, and
then you can choose a few of
those questions and answer them.
Yes, I understand.
There's not much time left so go and rest.
Yes, ma'am.
Yes. Can we schedule
gastric examination today?
At three o'clock? Yes.
Ah yes, okay. The name is Ahn Mi Jung.
Yes, yes. Okay. Okay, I understand.
Goodbye.
Did you make an appointment
at the hospital?
Honey, you are doing
this because of trauma.
Even if it is trauma, there
is nothing I can do about it.
You didn't eat breakfast, right?
From now on, don't eat anything.
As soon as the event is over,
let's start with endoscopy.
Alright. Don't worry too much. Okay?
As you may know already, the most important
thing a about golf swing is the shoulder turn.
When you are turning
during your back swing,
you should be able to hit the golf ball
with the energy from the back swing.
The problem here is that your head knows
what to do but your body doesn't.
When your shoulder turn doesn't
generate enough energy,
there is a tendency to overkill
with your motor skill.
So, from here, I'll teach you how
to control your shoulder turn.
Initially, I'll demonstrate it.
So awesome!
As you saw, I just showed you how you can properly
use the energy from your back shoulder swing.
Whatever club you may have you
can, from the standard position, move
it toward the right side a bit...
Good job!
Did it end now?
You worked hard. Really hard.
You worked very hard.
You really worked hard.
Nothing at all but your participants'
knowledge was really high.
We purposely raised the standard
of the participants this time.
Last time, a customer who had begun his lessons only
two weeks before, held Pro Choi Jin Ki for an hour!
It feels so horrible when I think about it.
We had such a hard time
as well as Pro Choi.
You really prepared a lot for today though!
You know I try hard when I have to.
What should we eat?
It's so nice to see you guys here!
How proud you must be to
have such an amazing son.
You really raised your son well.
Ah, thank you.
We feel the same way
about Teacher Kim, also.
Um... Did you know that Teacher Kim
comes to our house... every morning?
Excuse me?
He exercises with me in the morning.
Since when?
As you can see, he and Jin
Joo haven't broken up yet.
Standing here, having such a long
conversation is a bit awkward, so...
- take this with you please.
- No, no. We can't.
No. Please accept it.
You know our Jin Joo got the money
for her schooling from Teacher Kim.
The two of them are close like that, but
since it's awkward for us to pay
back in money, we bought this.
Because it's good for health, we bought it.
Wait a minute! This is a bit...
Um. Listen. We are going to get going.
Please take care, then.
- Congratulations.
- Ah, yes.
- Congrats, again.
Ah, wait!
I really can't believe this.
Why are they doing this?
- Oh, my.
- Oh, yes.
Geeze.
Since they are In-laws of the
In-laws, I can't be harsh on them.
But... What was she talking about? Tae
Min goes to their house every morning?
Because they are also against them getting married,
he is trying to get them to change their minds.
Excuse me!
Yes, ma'am?
Do you possibly have this in a large size?
I'm planning to give this to my mother.
Yes, we do. Just a moment.
I think this one will be a little too big for her. Can
you find me this in just a bit of a smaller size?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh! No, no. Instead of this one...
Give me this! In the same size too.
- Yes, just a moment.
- Okay!
Mystery Shopping Check List
I might not know how Teacher Kim's mom
treats you, but take a look at Teacher Kim.
Look at how hard he is trying, even
though we are objecting to him.
He says he'll handle everything
to change his mother's mind.
If you just sleep for a while, the
examination will be finished.
I know. Am I a kid? Wait outside.
Dang, Han Mi Hung. You have no fear coming
to the hospital and you don't change.
Of course. Would be right for
people to change so easily?
Just a moment. Yes, would
you lie down for a bit?
Yes.
Endoscopy Room
- Oh?
- Omo!
You're leaving now too?
Yes. Unni, I see that
you have not left yet.
Yeah, because Oppa is having
some difficulties renting a car.
But he says he just got here.
Ah, let's go together. We'll
drop you off on our way.
Ah, no! It's okay!
You go first, Unni. I have to
check something in my room.
Unni, hurry up and go.
Oppa will be waiting.
Go first, Unni.
I'm leaving first then!
Why isn't he answering?
Sang Min, are you in front of the stairs?
Sister-in-law and my brother are coming
towards you. Quickly, get out of there.
Oh, Yeon Tae, when are you coming out?
In fact, I'm with your brother right now.
Your brother was asking with insistence, so
I explained I'm taking you down
personally to your training.
Yeah, yeah. Okay. Come out soon.
It's really suspicious.
What's suspicious?
As a matter of fact, the thought of being
apart from Yeon Doo for couple of days
makes my heart ache, so please stop.
Where are you going?
I'm taking my pregnant wife to
get some ocean breeze. Why?
Ah, I see.
The two hyungnims are really romantic.
Of course. Our entire family is like that.
Thats why you better be good to our Yeon Tae.
I"m really being good to her.
So don't think of secretly going on a trip.
Hyungnim!
Oh, Soon Young! Stay there, stay there!
I'll take that.
Oh, Yeon Doo!
Sang Min, you're here early.
Of course. Our Yeon Doo is going to a
training. Naturally I should be here early.
What a relief. I was thinking we
should take her to the train station.
You're too bashful to say
he was coming, right?
- No.
- Aigoo.
No matter how much I think about
it, these two are suspicious.
They seem like they're going
on a trip, just like we are.
Oppa, what are you talking about?
I'm joking.
But, where are you guys traveling?
Somewhere far?
Ta-da!
I even rented a car. We can go anywhere.
Why? I can't tell you because
you might try to avoid us.
Ah, seriously. Hyungnim.
I'm joking, I'm joking.
Drop off Yeon Tae and then leave.
Yes, then, we'll leave first.
Let's go. We'll be late.
Go safely!
No matter what, something seems fishy.
Fishy? What's fishy? We should go too.
We'll get stuck in traffic.
I think we have to go to
Gangneung another time.
Why?
Tomorrow's shooting was supposed to be in the
afternoon, but the schedule changed to morning.
I have to be there by 11AM, so it
would work if we wake up early.
But to do that, Gangneung is a bit far.
Then, where should we go?
What about Ganghwado Island? It's closer
and it has the ocean you want to see too.
Sounds good.
Let's go!
Your youngest brother really is
scarier than your oldest brother.
I was so surprised. I thought we would get
caught before we even left for our trip.
Anyway, the two of us are leaving for
our trip. This moment is precious.
Yes.
48:12
So we did a biopsy after
removing that area.
Biopsy?
Biopsies aren't anything new to endoscopy.
But it's true that some concerns were
raised from the shape around the area.
The biopsy results will
come out in three days,
so you can come back when after
receiving a call from the hospital.
You don't feel dizzy from anesthesia?
I was already all awake when we
went to the doctor's office.
You have less strength than I do
even though I got the checkup.
It worries me since they're doing a biopsy.
The doctor told us earlier,
it's not a big deal.
Also, it's nice to do it
if it prevents an illness.
I like this hospital
because they seem kind.
Don't worry, Honey.
Ever since I was young, I was told I look
weak, but I've never gotten seriously sick.
I had three kids, after all.
Hey, it's nice.
My little Pebble, you're excited
since we're at the ocean, right?
I'm even more excited
than our little Pebble.
After you started filming, I
thought you'd be really busy.
Every time you spend time with
me and we go out on dates,
I'm really happy.
There's no need to be thankful for things I
should be doing. My manners will get worse.
Right. Thank you.
This is so nice.
- Come over here.
- No, it's okay.
- Didn't I say so last time?
- The water got on me!
- I'm good at swimming.
- Then go swim.
No... I didn't bring my swimsuit.
It's cold! Look at this!
Stay still for a second.
Lee Yeon Do. This is your first time going on
a trip with Kim Sang Min, how do you feel?
I'm not sure. I don't really know.
What? You don't know? You don't care?
Should we go back to Seoul? Let's just go.
I like it, I like it.
How much do you like it?
I'm not sure.
My phone's okay.
Ah, seriously. Sang Min, stop filming.
I'm too embarrassed.
Why? You're so cute.
Your expression is really funny.
What the heck? Delete it.
- Delete it!
- Why?
Come on!
Don't!
Can you check and see if Woo Young and Soo wrote
his report on the field trip to the museum?
Also, check to see if Bin and Woo
Ri did their summer homework.
I'll take care of it, so just go to sleep.
I am kind of sleepy.
Oh, and take the beef out of the fridge
so I can make soup in the morning.
I got it. I'll make it.
The soup you make isn't good.
I'll make it taste good, so don't worry.
Just rest.
Mom.
Oh, Binnie, what is it?
We're not going to practice reading?
Oh, Bin. You rest. Do it with Dad.
Let's go. Let's go quickly.
I want to do it with Mom. Why can't I?
Ah, Mom is going to sleep. Do it with me.
Why is she going to sleep without dinner?
She didn't even eat breakfast.
She got a examination earlier.
What kind of examination? Is mom sick?
Why? Where is she sick?
What's wrong with Mom?
Aigoo. I told her to go to the hospital
earlier, but she wouldn't because she was busy.
Will she be cured quickly?
Yeah, we got the examination today so we should
get the results in the next couple days.
So today, you guys have to be quiet. Okay?
Mom has to get some rest today, that's why. Woo Young and Soo,
have you written your reports for the field trip to the museum?
I was going to ask Ahjumma
about it before I started.
I'll take care of it.
Hurry up and bring it.
No, go eat dinner. It's all done
- Hurry up. Let's do it after dinner.
- Let's eat dinner.
Let's eat, let's eat.
Woo Joo, come here.
We have arrived, my dear.
It's a triplex so I was worried about finding a
vacant room but I lucked out in getting a room.
Just as if this place was
ready for us all along.
I'm so excited.
Yeon Doo, what's wrong?
This car!
What's wrong? You're scaring me!
Yeon Tae?
What the heck?
You bastard!
Lee Yeon Tae!
Hyungnim! What are you doing here?
I knew it. I knew something was fishy.
Hey, Lee Yeon Tae, is this
a training institute?
What happened was...
Hyungnim, Yeon Tae did nothing wrong. I...
Shut up!
Oh my goodness.
What's so wrong about taking a trip with my girlfriend
that I'm going to be married to soon, Hyungmin?
That's right!
Of course, it's not wrong if I don't find out
about it. But I found out about it though.
That's where it went wrong, you punk!
But are you proud of
what you did, Hyungnim?
You also did something, even
before you got married.
Anyhow, your sister here
shouldn't be repressed because I feel
that it's wrong for you to do that.
Go and ask anybody in the streets,
if they meet their little
sister at a motel like this,
how the big brother must feel.
It would suck.
Stop it, Honey. They are here
to have a good time, you know.
Why don't we just go grill some
meat together since we're all here.
Miss, you haven't had
anything to eat yet right?
Yes, that would be nice.
What do you think, Sang Min?
If it's okay with Hyungnim.
Alright then. Why don't we
go and drop off our stuff?
Yes, I understand, Hyungnim.
Where are you going right now?
What? Our room is this way.
Oh, really?
Then, you sleep with me. And Yeon
Tae can sleep with Soon Young.
Doesn't this feel like we are on a college
field trip? Isn't this quite nice?
Yes sir. If I had known this was going to happen, I could've invited Yeon Tae's
big brother and his family so this could be more like a family outing, right?
Why are you playing along, buddy?
Hyungnim.
Don't worry about my parents.
I won't tell them anything.
I am a guy who's good at keeping secrets.
Yes, I'm really grateful.
By the way, you don't snore when you sleep,
right? Because I'm a sensitive sleeper.
I sleep like a dead mouse (really
quietly), so don't worry.
I could really just die because
I'm so freaking upset you know.
Ah, it's so hot.
You're so funny.
I don't know.
We suddenly changed our destination,
so I wonder how we met like this.
We barely made reservations
for this inn, you know.
Yes.
My husband can be a bit particular, right?
You could have at least told me
about it before you came here.
I know, right? Oh, that's not true!
I think that it's meaningful that I'm
able to be here with you like this.
I bet that's not true.
Really.
Here we are. Yeon Tae, you should
eat to your heart's content.
Okay, I'm going to eat a lot.
Brother-in-law, come here and eat!
- Soon Young, this is the perfect timing, so you should eat now. Okay?
- Alright, Honey.
Eat.
Yes, I'm coming.
Yeon Doo, are you sleeping?
Ah.
You didn't wake up because of me, right?
I couldn't sleep.
You didn't wake up because
your brother scared you?
No. What will you do if you can't sleep?
Starting from early morning you drove us here and then you grilled the meat. And I'm
sure you're tired because you did all that. Is my second brother sleeping well?
He said that he is a very light sleeper but
he started to snore the moment he laid down.
I feel sorry towards my
brother and his wife.
They came here for a trip.
I should've listened to you.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about our trip. I think our plans
got messed up because I rushed into it.
That's not true. My second brother is too
much when it comes to playing around, huh?
But I can understand where
he is coming from though.
There's nothing your brother could have done if he
hadn't found out about it, like he said earlier.
It could have been even more strange.
What's up? You seem more
disappointed than me.
No, that's not it.
But we are here on a
trip together like this,
and we get to see the ocean together and
look at the late night sky together, too.
I like it. I'm happy.
If I'm this happy now, how
much happier can I get?
Thank you.
♪ When I quietly think about you ♪
♪ I have a smile on my face
without realizing it ♪
♪ One day I looked up at the night sky ♪
What happened? Why is
everyone looking at me?
We have to take the pictures!
Assistant Manager Ahn, you have
to go to the hospital right now.
The lights are back on so we should
hurry up and start filming again.
Let's quickly take them and finish up.
♪ Day by day I'm becoming more like you ♪
You're not resting?
- What?
- I asked if you're not resting.
You didn't sleep last night since you had to
take all those tests. Are you not resting?
It's because I came up with a good idea all of
a sudden while I was in the middle of resting.
Why is she doing everything herself?
♪ You make me smile ♪
Did you get some rest after going out?
No. I had to bathe the kids
and make some side dishes.
I haven't even taken off my apron yet.
♪ It always makes me feel excited ♪
Wikiki. Kimchi. Spaghetti.
♪ Coz I love you ♪
Team Leader.
It seems like you are still upset because of
Woo Ri. You are working on your smile again.
Even If I have things going on at home, I still
have to leave that behind and do my job, you know.
Let's just hire a housekeeper.
I thought about it and I don't want to hire someone to help us do the housework.
I think it would be better to save that money for our children's education.
I don't regret making up
my mind to remarry at all.
What would I do if I failed twice?
I didn't want to do that at all.
I want to live a happy life
for myself and the kids too.
I really want to do that.
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
What's wrong with you? The second floor
grandmother was like this too...
Perhaps, was it like this before too?
Was Soo and Bin's mother like this too?
♪ A love like a destiny to me ♪
♪ You are my one and only love ♪
♪ Even if I complain you're the only
one for me because you're so lovely ♪
♪ Today you are my love again ♪
♪ The love that came to me like a dream ♪
♪ Just like this ♪