Chelsea: Not too long ago,
I pulled a real
bonehead move and got a dui.
Since then,
my roommate Dee Dee
has become
my designated driver.
She's perfect for the job because
she doesn't like drinking,
and her initials are,
well, "D.D."
[Groans] I have to go
for to the courthouse
to get my community service
assignment tomorrow.
I hope they don't make you pick up
trash by the side of the road.
Mmm.
Oh, maybe they'd let you
dirty Skype the troops.
Oh. I would be honored
to share my foxhole
with the soldiers.
All right, you guys.
Go ahead
and try this.
Oh, Rick, I'd hate to say this
about alcohol in any form, but...
- Uhh.
- What?
What do you mean, "uhh"?
It's great.
It's lavender-infused
vodka
with a hin cream
and a cactus liqueur.
That's not a drink.
It's a candle you buy
at a lesbian bookstore.
I like it.
Thank you.
It smells like
my Nana.
And her roommate
Millie.
Wait. I just
realized something.
Hey, look, at least
I'm trying, OK?
I'm gonna open up my own bar
one day, and I'm telling you,
the central and north
Jersey mixology society,
it's a great
networking opportunity.
Yeah, so's sleeping with people.
Why don't you
try that, Rick?
Well, I do,
but unlike you,
not enough
to fill a bar.
Chelsea, you should
give him the recipe
for your bang-bang.
I don't need
your bang-bang,
whatever that is.
I'm sure I can come up
with something better.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
All right,
don't look.
You too, fella.
Hey, you know
straight vodka
is not a cocktail,
Chelsea.
And straight men don't
have your haircut, Rick.
Ahem.
Here you go.
Mmm.
OK, that's good.
Wait for it.
Holy God.
And the's
the second bang.
Yeah, I admit it's
got a kick to it,
but not sure it's up to
the standards of the CNJMS.
I have TMJ, fyi.
You can
make fun of me,
but at least
I have a goal.
Now, come on.
Seriously.
You know,
Olivia wants to bea.
And Todd's studying acting.
What do you want?
Todd's studying acting?
That's great.
Yeah. Well, not when
one man has the monopoly
on every great role
for little people.
- Peter Dinklage.
- Who?
Peter Dinklage
from "game of thrones."
Oh, he is cute.
Do you know him?
Not all little people
know each other, Olivia.
But, yes, I... I do.
Ah, come on.
You didn't answer my question.
What do you think
you want?
Hey, I am happy
in my life. You know,
I love my friends.
I loy job.
I don't really
want anything.
Oh, come on.
There must be something you want.
Well, last week,
something hit me, but...
Forget it.
No, what is it?
Come on. Tell us.
Well, I was just
walking down the street,
and suddenly I realized
there is something I want.
Ohh.
- Rick: You want a baby?
- Are you nuts?
I want boots,
$700 hand-crafted French
thigh-high leather boots.
So your big goal
is a pair of boots.
I wouldn't really
put it that way.
It's more like...
[Bubbly] My big goal's
a pair of boots.
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.Addic7ed.Com/
So, Melvin, I was talking
to your daughter yesterday.
You know what
her big goal is?
Pair of thigh-high
leather boots.
Really?
That's your goal?
- Yeah.
- Thigh-high boots?
I'm proud of you,
honey.
You would look
terrific in those.
Thanks, dad.
You're serious?
Ah. She's
a leggy knockout.
She's only
gonna be young once.
My wife,
rest her soul,
cause she anything was
always saving for late.
What if there is
not a later?
Have fun, Chelsea.
You have a terrific
figure now,
but time is not kind
to a busty girl.
You know what?
I'll buy you those boots.
What do you need?
700 bucks.
700 bucks?!
Mm-hmm.
You're gonna
700 bucks for boots,
your head's so far up your ass,
you won't be able to see 'em.
Don't worry about it, dad.
I'm gonna find a way
to get those boots on my own,
because I don't need to rely
on anybody or anything.
Chelsea, did you
forget I'm driving you
to the courthouse
for your dui assignment?
No, I did not.
I made you a sandwich.
Did you remember to eat lunch
no, I did not.
And here's your wallet.
You left...
All right,
let's just go.
You know what? You don't have
to wait with me here, Dee.
Are you kidding?
I wanna meet the clerk.
Why?
Why? I love everything
about a courthouse.
When I was
a little girl,
I used to love to play
bailiff with my dad.
How do you play bailiff?
Well, you stand quietly
by his desk,
sometimes for hours,
while he does his work.
That's the hard part.
When he leaves the room,
you get to say,
"all rise
for judge daddy."
Then when he comes
back in, you get to say,
"all rise
for judge daddy."
- Was your dad a judge?
- No. He was a cartoonist.
Hello, ladies.
Now, that is
a handsome man.
Oh, yeah. Imagine
without the glasses.
Oh.
I'm so sorry
to keep you waiting.
I just came from
another budgetary meeting.
I came this close
to losing my job today.
Oh.
5 other guys did.
[Chuckles]
But enough about me.
Chelsea...
Yeah, that's me.
You need to be assigned
your community service, huh?
Mm-hmm.
What would
make you happy?
Uh, getting
my license back.
Yeah, walking up
to the drive-through
is getting
really embarrassing.
No, no, I'm serious.
I need you to be happy,
and then I need you to
fill out this online survey
and rate my performance.
It'll just take you 5 minutes,
and you could
save my pension.
[Laughs]
So don't make me beg.
I think my friend Dee Dee would
love to see you on your knees.
Chelsea!
Um, well, if I say
nice things about you,
can I get out of
my community service completely?
Mm, no.
I can't do that.
But just pick
any dumb charity you want.
I'll pretty much sign off on
anything that has a letterhead.
I know, right.
Lemon drop?
Certainly.
I volunteer tutoring
at-risk kids.
Maybe Chelsea could
help me with that.
Oh, yeah. And then she could
sign off on it for me, right?
Absolutely! Yeah.
I'll just give you these forms.
Fill these out.
But you do have to get them back.
Otherwise, the sheriff'll
come after you.
Unless he loses
his job, too.
Um, OK. Well,
thank you, Mr...
Mills.
Marty mills.
Oh. My grandpa
died in a mill.
I don't know
why I said that.
Down, girl.
Dee Dee, your boyfriend
at the courthouse
said you could
just sign this for me.
[Scoffs]
He's not my boyfriend.
Then why are
you blushing?
Maybe I have rosacea.
Get off my back.
After you tutor for 2 hours,
I'll sign the paper.
- Ok, how 'bout an hour?
- Don't play me, girl.
I learned that here.
Oh. All right, fine.
Who am I
sued to tutor?
Hmm. Oh, I know
Warren needs somebody.
Warren, this is my friend Chelsea.
Chelsea, Warren.
Chelsea's really excited
to jump in and help you,
but it's her first time doing
community service, so be nice.
Community service?
What'd you get arrested for?
Being too hot?
You didn't tell me this
was the gifted program.
Here's Warren's
work package.
Speaking
of packages...
All right, stud,
dial it back.
All right,
let's see
what we got there.
Pre-algebra?
[Scoffs] "E" equals mc
that's never gonna happen.
Oh, "lord of the flies."
You're gonna
love this book.
They kill a wild boar
and a smart kid with glasses.
You know, I would kill a smart
kid with glasses for you.
If you were my woman, I would
shower you with gold and diamonds.
I'm glad you ended that
with diamonds.
All right, do you wanna
read this book or not?
Well, that depends.
Can we read it
at your place?
OK, dude, listen.
You will never get
a woman like this
if you don't graduate
from High School.
Do you know why?
Because I'm
an expensive woman.
I want a pair
of $700 boots.
Do you think your job at
the chicken processing plant
is gonna pay for that?
All right, get started
on your history homework.
And, uh, I'll be right back.
Hey, Dee, I got him
started on his reading,
so I'm gonna
go on my break.
Quick question.
The faculty lounge,
is that a full bar
or just beer and wine?
It's 2 hours, Chelsea.
There are no breaks.
Come on. I just got my period.
I gotta go to the nurse.
Welcome to fast times
at this sucks high.
Hey. All right, so do you have
any questions about history
or life or...
I don't know...
[Cell phone ringtone]
[Rings]
[Ringing]
Hey, Warren,
why does your crotch
have the same ringtone
as my phone?
I wasn't
stealing your phone.
Ah. Sure you weren't,
you little thief.
We don't have a computer,
and I was just use it
to do research on
the Louisiana purchase.
Of course you were. And that's
why it's between your legs,
so you can attach it to that
printer that you've got down there.
This is
Nana's candle.
Enjoy.
Ahh. All right.
Ahem.
Hey, dude.
Yeah?
What have you got
for ro2?
Oh, see the drink
with the live goldfish
and little castle in it?
It's the aquariumdaiquiri.
Are you kidding me?
You're trying too hard.
OK. Chelsea.
Hey. What's up?
Just got your text.
You didn't need
to text her, Todd.
I can handle this.
You put an animal
in a drink.
You need
the bang-bang recipe.
Whoa. Why would I give
you the bang-bang recipe?
Because Rick's gonna split
the $1,500 with you.
Todd.
Don't push me away
I'm here to help.
[Sighs]
All right,
yeah, fine.
If we win, you get
half the money.
All right. First I need
2 shots of vodka.
All right.
All right,
let's get to work.
OK.
- See what's happening here?
- Hmm?
We are gonna win
that contest.
- OK.
- Because someone up there
really wants to see
me in those boots.
So God wants to see you
in thigh-high boots?
Look, all I'm saying
I wear a white t-shirt,
it rains.
You do the math.
Yay. We did it.
The bang-bang
came through.
Yeah. Well, you did it.
That's the thing.
I'm just so tired of being,
like, average at everything.
Like, in school, I was
an average student.
I was kind of
an average athlete.
Well, how are you in bed?
I mean, I'll be honest.
I don't blow me away.
Shut up.
You've done a lot
of really cool things.
Didn't you, like, model
when you were a kid?
Yeah.
I was a husky model.
Are you kidding?
No. You know,
then I hit puberty,
and I thinned out,
so all the jobs
and the free
giant pants dried up.
Did you ever
do underwear ads?
If they were tasteful.
Ho ho ho!
If you love me,
you would find those pictures,
blow one up, and give it
to me for Christmas.
Well, I'm glad you
think this is funny.
Oh, shut up, Rick.
Come on.
You're great-looking now.
Everyone loves you.
And one day,
when you open your own bar,
in tribute
to your childhood,
you can call it
tgi fat-ass.
Ah, go on.
Get out of here.
Get your hooker boots.
There are so many shows
about judges and lawyers.
What about the clerks
and the secretaries
and the midlevel
administrators?
That's the show
I want to see.
- You know what show I want to see?
- What?
You kissing that clerk
at the courthouse.
Can I tell you a secret?
When he showed Chelsea
and me to the door,
he smelled like
a heavenly mixture
of stetson cologne
and copier.
Honey, are there any
chunks of your childhood
that you
don't remember?
Whoo!
What do you think?
Worth 700 bucks?
Yes!
Oh, my God.
I'd ask to borrow them.
Except they would
chafe my armpits.
Chelsea,
you look so great.
You're gonna turn
so many heads in those.
And hopefully
raise a few.
Dee Dee, you have
got to try these on.
They will change
your life.
That's the way I feel about
my Nate Berkus Fanny pack.
Oh, here.
Take a picture.
Heh. Why were you googling
the Louisiana purchase?
What?
Let me see that.
Heh.
Oh, my God.
Warren really was googling
the Louisiana purchase.
Oh, yeah. I lend him my phone all
time. They don't have a computer.
But I thought he was trying to
steal it. I called him a thief.
Oh, don't worry. He's got
much bigger problems than you.
His mom's in jail, and he has to
take care of his little brother.
Oh, my God. Really?
Mm-hmm. Don't worry.
Warren's fine.
Tonight's about you
and your fancy new boots.
I just bought this amazing
new boots.
I should be feeling
good right now,
not feeling bad about kids
who don't have computers.
Nobody said
you had to.
Chelsea, before you
have another drink,
can you do that online
survey for Marty Mioh, right.
Right.
Look at me,
using a computer
like I deserve to.
The only thing I use this computer for
is to online shop
and watch goats kicking
people in the nuts.
My grandparents had a carrear
until Kim jong-il
ate it.
You know what?
Give me the computer.
There's no way in heck Marty
was only "somewhat prom."
God, poor little Warren,
you know, with his mom
on death row
and that ugly
little backpack.
How is he ever gonna learn
about the Louisiana purchase
if he doesn't have
a computer at school?
He's gonna learn
from good tutors like you.
Now, are you drunk enough
to sleep yet?
Why? Is Marty mills
coming over?
That's crazy.
I don't even know his number.
[Gasps] We should
Facebook him.
Does he have Facebook?
Everybody has Facebook.
Except little Warren.
Ohh.
Good morning,
sleepyhead.
Or should I say,
good afternoon, alcoholic"?
Oh, God. My boots even look good
in the morning.
Why is
my credit card out?
Oh, you went online
and bought the kids
at the tutor center
a computer.
What?
Oh, crap.
I have done some awful
things when I'm drunk,
but buying a computer
for needy kids,
that's a new low.
Nonsense, Chelsea.
Admit it.
You've got a big heart.
Oh, look it.
Olivia has a big man.
Thank you
for everything.
Take a powerbar and a complimentary
toothbrush on your way out.
Um, when did
that happen?
I perked up
around 4 A.M.,
walked across the hall,
and knocked on Duane's door.
That was not Duane.
I know. Duane moved out
2 weeks ago,
but I have to say,
I think we traded up.
All right, I need your advice
on a decision I have to make.
I bought these boots,
but I also
bought a computer
for needy kids,
and I can't afford them both.
What do I do?
Oh, I already told
the kids about the computer.
I couldn't hold it in.
I'm sorry, Chelsea.
Oh, it's OK.
I know what
I have to do.
God, this is the saddest I've ever
been pulling down a zipper.
[Applause]
You've gotta
feel good.
Yeah. It does feel good.
And it didn't even
require batteries.
- You bought us the computer?
- Yeah.
Aren't you worried
I'll steal it?
I'm sorry. I got that
one completely wrong.
Don't feel that bad,
'cause I was going to steal it.
Really?
Nah. I just didn't want
you to feel that bad.
Really?
Nah. I was
gonna steal it.
I'm just
messing with you,
but thanks for the computer.
You're welcome.
You know how you
could pay me back?
By hooking you up with
some of the insane chronic
my cousin grows
by this garage?
Well, I was gonna say
by reading a book,
but if something were to
just appear in my purse...
Hey, Chelsea...
I was kidding.
Good news. We just
got a new volunteer,
so since you were
so nice and generous,
I'm gonna sign
your paper
so you don't
have to come back.
Oh. Thanks, Dee Dee.
Absolutely.
You've gone above and beyond.
Great.
Ahem. You know, I think I might
hang out for a little bit.
I think... I think
Warren needs me.
Yeah?
Yeah, look at him.
He's typing away.
He's probably
looking up porn.
You know someone's
gotta teach him
how to clear
the browser history.
All right, you guys.
Taste the bacontini.
Ooh.
Oh, that is fantti
yeah?
You know, gin usually
make me mean,
but the fat has
a calming effect.
Good. Good.
You know, I'm gonna enter
the greater New York
event next week.
Good luck,
you son of a bitch!
Oh, hey. Uh, I heard you did
something nice for some kids today.
[Scoffs]
Yeah, don't remind me.
Yeah, well, I wanted to
do something nice for you.
Oh, my God.
You bought me those boots?
Open it up.
[Laughs] Man!
So this is the future
inventor of the bacontini.
Yeah, I liked bacon
back then, too.
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.Addic7ed.Com/