Timing and subtitles brought to you by Gone With the
Shirt Team - Opening Song: "To Ask the Moon" by Yisa Yu
♫ Don't get helpless. The bright
moon being blocked by the clouds ♫
♫ is just because of the
wind's love for it. ♫
♫ If we say that the stars
are the sky's ocean, ♫
♫ then the moon is
the waiting tide. ♫
♫ When the clouds
scatter, Ooh... ♫
♫ the moon shines over
the world's haze. ♫
♫ The world becomes
silent at this moment ♫
♫ and drops (forget) all
the wins and losses. ♫
♫ Who's infatuated with
the shine of freedom? ♫
♫ Loving freely but
stubbornly leaving. ♫
♫ Maybe promises are like the deep blue sea, as
long as the piano's sound would not change, ♫
♫ It is one's life last worship. ♫
♫ Who is the one playing (a
tune of) world's love? ♫
♫ Making anyone wanting to be
dripped to one's content. ♫
♫ Burn out the dark night ashes. The
wind will push the clouds away ♫
♫ and he will tread with the piano's
(harp) sound back. ♫ Green Hill Fox Legend
Love Fox Chapter: Feng Sanniang
I wonder what kind of treasure
it is to be so powerful.
Can you let me see it?
I know! It is some kind of rare
treasure from the strange lands, right?
Like, fruits that
have super powers?
It is something not
of this world.
It took a very long time
to get our hands on it.
- Let me take a look at it!
- No-no-no.
Anren, stop teasing. Just
let me take one look.
Not even one look.
Please, please, just
one look, please.
Fine-fine-fine.
You're hurting my bones
from your shouting.
How about this!
If you are able to abide to a
condition, besides one look,
I will even give it to you!
What condition?
Marry me and be my wife. Okay?
No?
Pretend I didn't ask. It belongs to the
Princess now, so I won't let you see it.
- Just one look?
- Definitely not.
Fine, I agree.
You're serious?
I can now look at it, right?
What's the rush?
This stuff I originally planned to give you during the Qixi
Festival (Lunar's July 7th) as my proof of love to you.
Then wouldn't it be
more meaningful?
You're being serious? Are you
trying to trick me again?
Shouldn't I be the one who's scared
since you might run off with it.
Then I'd really be at a loss.
I'm not you. I wouldn't
go back on a promise.
Right now besides Brother
and Sister-in-Law,
the one I can trust
is only you.
Qianru, every time I finish your soup I
feel something running through my organs,
a rush of warmth, like
some kind of energy.
What can I do to repay you?
I don't need you to repay me.
I only ask that you can be by my side, a
day more is a day earned being with you.
We cannot cheat our time when the
heaven's have decided our time.
If there comes a day when
I leave, let's promise
that in the next life we
will be together again.
This time when I cross over the Styx,
I will drink less of that soup
and come find you in the next
life and take care of you.
I can't ask much for
the next lifetime.
I just wish that I can be with you
this lifetime and live everyday well.
Qianru, is it because you're taking
care and worrying about me everyday;
hence, you feel tired already?
An De,
if one day I turned old
and became a white haired
wrinkly old woman,
would you still
love me like now?
Qianru, what are this nonsense
you're talking about?
When we first met, I was
like a disabled person.
But you never avoided me and,
instead, willingly became my wife.
How can I then leave you just
because you turn into an old woman?
That is because you
don't know that I am...
Never mind.
It's not like what
you are thinking.
Enough.
Qianru,
no matter what happens in
the future, I promise you
that I will always be by your
side, never leaving you.
Fei Yue, you're cousin
is here to visit you.
- Who? - Your cousin.
He's currently playing chess with
Second Young Master in the garden.
Cousin? When did
I have a cousin?
Unless it's...
The logic of the game of chess is
to move one's chip to gain victory.
Master Meng's chess skills are impressive.
You really are a very smart person.
Brother Liu also
hasn't lost to me yet.
You are also interesting.
I've never heard Fei Yue
talk about having a cousin.
Maybe she doesn't
want you to know.
Zhu...
Cousin, so it was really you.
Zhu (Pig) Cousin?
You're the one who's the pig.
I didn't inform her beforehand
and just came here.
For Fei Yue to curse me as
pig head is also not wrong.
Brother Liu, do you know about
me and Fei Yue's relationship?
I think it's that you want to marry
Fei Yue and Fei Yue doesn't want to?
Doesn't want to?
She didn't tell you the truth.
Sect Leader, it's not proper to talk
here. Let's go to another place.
For Sect Leader to personally come here,
is it because I did something wrong again?
I am here to look for
the female thief.
Any new discovery?
Nothing yet. Fei Yue, about the cloth I asked you to
place in a corner, did anyone else know about it?
I only told Little Miss about it but
I didn't tell her where I put it.
I checked the cloth the past few days and
it's still there without any changes.
I already took the cloth away.
Why?
I have my own plan. But for you, have you thought about
how to respond to Meng Anren's wedding proposal?
He said that during the Qixi Festival, he will give me
the treasure that he was supposed to give the Princess.
If it's not the Magical Fruit, then I will continue to
get entangled with him until I get the Magical Fruit.
What if it's really
the Magical Fruit?
Then I'll get the Magical
Fruit and just go.
Just doing that... won't that
make you go against your promise?
This stuff I originally planned to give you during
the Qixi Festival as my proof of love to you.
This way, won't it
have more meaning?
Are you telling the truth? You won't
be intentionally tricking me again?
The one who should be afraid now is me. What if
you get the object and just run off with it?
Then I'll really be someone who paid
with his wife and also lost a soldier.
I am not you so I won't do things
like going against my words.
Right. Other than Brother and Sister-in-law,
the only one left that I can trust
is you.
But...
But I don't want to marry him.
When I was playing chess with him earlier, I don't know if it's
due to his arrogance; hence, he doesn't want to lose to me.
Or it's because of you; hence,
he treats me as an enemy.
But if he is really willing
to change for the better,
will you still lie to him and pretend
you're sincere when you are not?
Sect Leader, what should I do?
Just like you said, maybe this person
is not as bad as we think he is.
And also humanity's love
relationships are not my forte.
Whether it's just playing along or
turning a fake act into reality,
I'm afraid it's up
to you to decide.
Think about it clearly.
I'll go now.
Fei Yue!
Little Miss
What are you doing?
Cross-stitching to
make fragrant pouches.
This is really pretty.
Qixi Festival is near already. Every
Qixi, girls will make a fragrant pouch
to give to their lover as
a proof of their love.
Oh right, you should
make one for Anren, too.
I...don't think I
need to anymore.
You should still make one. The
two of your are engaged already.
But... I... I don't
know how to make these.
No problem. I'll teach you.
It doesn't matter if you didn't sew it well, the
important thing is that you were the one who made it.
It's the thought that counts.
Like this. Look at me.
Making an 'X', I can do that.
Why is it so ugly?
Fei Yue, it doesn't matter
if you didn't sew it well,
the important thing is that you were the one
who made it. It's the thought that counts.
I heard from Xiao Hong that
your sewing skill is bad.
The fragrant pouch you made for Second
Young Master allegedly looks ugly.
Who said that? I think
it's quite good.
And also, Little Miss said that
what's important is the thought.
Look at my fingers, their
all full of needle pricks.
- Second Young Master
- What's wrong?
Fei Yue,
I've been looking for you.
Why are you looking for me?
Didn't I say earlier that I'm giving you
a present during the Qixi Festival?
I must do what I said.
This a treasure that is one
of its kind in this world.
Look at it once you're
back in your room, okay?
If it's really the Magical
Fruit, will I really marry him?
Magical Fruit! It's
really the Magical Fruit!
Fei Yue,
will you marry me?
I will.
I'm willing to marry you.
No way... If I caused him to faint
from shock, won't my sin be greater?
Let's open it first.
"In the evening, at the pavilion beside the
lake. Won't leave if I don't see you."
What is he doing?
- Are you Miss Fei Yue?
- Right, it's me.
Look there.
I've let you wait long.
This is really the gift
that belongs to you.
Open it.
Everyone, this is
my beloved girl.
She hopes that I give
her a rare treasure,
then she'll be
willing to marry me.
But I always hoped that my
sincerity can move her.
In everyone's eyes, I am
a treacherous official.
But from this day on, I want
everyone to be my witness.
For Fei Yue, I am willing not to do
any deceitful things from now on
- and get rid of my bad nicknames.
- Good...
Meng Anren, what is it
that you really want?
Fei Yue, marry me, okay?
Marry him...
Fei Yue!
Let's go back to the palace.
Fei Yue, what's wrong with you?
I did everything
to make you happy.
You...even if you are not
moved, you shouldn't get mad.
I am not mad. It's just that what
you did is putting me at a loss.
I don't know how
to respond to you.
I know already. Maybe because there were a lot
of people there earlier; hence, you were shy.
Now that there are only the
two of us, please answer me.
Can you accept me?
I don't know what's good in me
that's worthy of you
doing all these for me.
Do you really want to marry me?
Until now, I'm still suspicious.
I know. I've never been serious to any
woman or any relationship before.
But since I saw my Big Brother
marry my Sister-in-law,
my thoughts changed.
I saw my Big Brother
happy everyday.
I never saw his face
having so many smiles.
From that point on, I also wanted
to try to treasure someone.
I want to get the
same happiness.
But I haven't decided if I'm
going to marry you or not.
Millet! Sweetened millet!
♫ then the moon is
the waiting tide. ♫
Wait for me for a while.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
♫ the moon shines over
the world’s haze. ♫
♫ The world becomes
silent at this moment ♫
♫ and drops (forget) all
the wins and losses. ♫
Here, sweetened millet, it's still warm. ♫
Who’s infatuated with the shine of freedom? ♫
Here, sweetened millet,
it's still warm.
- How did you know I like these?
- Of course I know.
The most important things
are those that we like.
Now, I want to use
something you like
in exchange for
something I like.
- Why is this with you? Give it back.
- I won't.
You made this for me
so I'm wearing it.
No way. It's too ugly.
Hurry and give it to me.
Who said it's ugly?
I like it. I'll
carry it everyday.
This is your thought.
This is a thought that you
were willing to endure pain
from a needle
pricking your fingers
but still finished the
fragrant pouch for me.
♫ Asking the moon, how
long more must I wait? ♫
- Here. ♫ Unknowingly sitting
on the cold window sill. ♫
♫ Suddenly, he put on the moon’s
color and entered my dream. ♫
- It's beautiful! - Look.
Look. ♫ Fulfilling my
lifetime of true love. ♫
There.
Thank you Buddha for allowing me and
An De to meet here in the temple.
We are here today to repay
you for fulfilling my wish.
Thank you, Buddha.
When I came here previously, I
was usually carried by others.
Right now, I can walk in by myself.
The feeling is really very good.
Don't overdo it. If you feel tired already,
we can rest here first before going back.
Don't worry. I'm fine. Let's go.
- Husband... - Taoist Master...
Taoist Master, I beg you to let
my wife go. Taoist Master...
Taoist Master, even if she's a monster,
but she never really harmed anyone.
- Taoist Master... - Humans and
monsters cannot fall in love. Get lost.
- Taoist Master... - Husband!
- Taoist Master... - Husband...
- It's right to catch her...
Let's take another
path home instead.
What's wrong?
I really don't understand.
If both love each other, why can't
humans and monsters be together?
Since monsters came to the human world,
they mainly bewitch healthy males
to get their spirit energy
and are never sincere.
Don't generalize. All creatures
have spirits (soul).
Humans can have feelings. Why
can't monsters have feelings?
Humans and monsters are
two different beings.
How can they fall in
love with each other?
An De, if one day,
I became a snake, a fox,
or a weird creature,
then do you think my feelings
for you are sincere or fake?
Wife, why are you doing this?
I know that you are kind. You
feel hurt for those lovers.
But humans are humans, monsters are
monsters, they are two different beings.
They must not have romantic relationship
with each other. They must not.
- Go get some logs and bring them here.
- Yes.
Timing and subtitles brought to
you by Gone With the Shirt Team
Sect Chief, there's movement.
Sect Chief's hunch was correct.
It was indeed her.
Fei Yue was always cursing that Meng Anren, but she
didn't know that the one who was lying to her the most
was the one she considered as
her true sister, Miss Fan.
Whether Fan Qianru is really the thief who stole the
Magical Fruit still lacks one important evidence.
Why do we need more evidence? When Sect Chief went to the
Meng Mansion and noticed that the cloth had been replaced,
while she's the only
one who knew about it.
If she's not the thief,
then who else would it be?
That may be correct.
But to cure An De,
she's willing to use up her powers.
This is the legendary story of
the Golden Fox who stayed in the human world
for hundreds of years to wait for her lover.
How can a person like this be someone
who wants to destroy the world
and will covet the
Magical Fruit?
So she is the
legendary Golden Fox?
If she's not the one who stole the
Magical Fruit, then who could it be?
Things are getting complicated.
Should we tell Fei
Yue about this?
While we still don't have evidence that
Fan Qianru is the female fox thief,
I don't want to destroy
their relationship.
Sister... your white
hairs are increasing.
Don't tell me anymore.
Just pull them out.
How can that be okay? This
is also not a good method.
Maybe you should eat something
to supplement your health.
It won't work. Just do as I say.
If even a small problem like
my hair would make me worry,
then things I should worry
about everyday would be many.
Sister, what are you worried about?
You can tell me.
I can help you share the burden.
I am worried about
you and Anren.
How come we got
involved in this?
Because I am the matchmaker.
If you hadn't went with
me to Meng Residence,
then you and Anren wouldn't
have that deep destiny.
Me and An De are sincerely wishing
that the two of you marry soon.
A few days ago, he said that the Emperor was going on an outside
trip so he needs to take care of some things in the palace.
I haven't seen him for
several days already.
Several days? That can't be...
He visits An De everyday.
This Anren... Don't worry,
I will talk to him.
Don't do that, Sister.
Maybe he's really busy.
On the contrary, you appear sick.
You should rest more.
Don't worry anymore
about our problems.
Prime Minister Zhao, are you still insisting
to send more troops to suppress the rebels?
Training troops for thousands of days are for this type of situation.
We must suppress the rebellion to bring stability to the government.
Of course, I will
send military troops.
Prime Minister Zhao, right now
there are a lot of calamities
and they need a lot of money
to help the affected.
I think that you should listen to
Minister Meng's suggestions...
I will think about Minister
Meng's suggestions.
The two of you
need not say more.
Prime Minister, stopping the rebellion
and bringing stabilization is important,
but helping those affected by calamities also need to be addressed
now. Right now, the government's fund is not enough to address both.
Regarding increasing the troops, I hope that
Prime Minister can consider the citizens
and think about
delaying it for now.
I also feel for the
calamity affected citizens.
But it's just that the war on the
front lines is very intense.
It's the best chance to suppress the
rebels and should not be delayed.
If we missed this chance and
His Majesty would blame us,
this responsibility
is not yours to bear
but it's mine.
If that time you allowed
me to lead the troops,
I would definitely bear
the responsibility now.
But at that time, you, Prime Minister Zhao,
would not give up the rights to the military.
Minister Meng and I have
something different.
What you think
highly of is power,
while I think highly of
are promises and loyalty.
Since His Majesty gave me the full
responsibility with regards to the rebels,
I will surely do my best
and will definitely not
disappoint His Majesty.
Prime Minister...
Saying words that sound to be reasonable in a stern and powerful
way and dignified but are all hypocritical to the highest level.
Suppressing the rebellion saves citizens, but giving
help in calamity stricken areas also saves citizens.
Why should we prioritize his
suppression of rebellion?
If at that time you were the one who led the troops,
the rebellion would have been suppressed already.
Right. In terms of tactics
and intelligence,
Minister Meng is way
better than that Zhao Gao.
This Prime Minister
position should be yours.
Master Meng...
Master Meng!
Princess! What a coincidence!
Why are you so happy? I've already
heard about the matters in the court.
Princess knows that I am not someone who cares much
about the state of the country and the citizens.
Don't lie to me anymore. Right now, there are calamities
everywhere and the citizens are waiting to be saved.
But my Royal Brother gave all the money to Zhao
Gao to fund his suppression of the rebels.
You must be worrying about how to get funds
to help the calamity stricken areas, right?
His Majesty likes him so I
can't do anything about it.
He is a loyal subject,
an old subject.
But if the rebel suppression was
given to me from the start,
we surely wouldn't
have this problem now.
You also know that among us siblings,
the Emperor loves me the most.
Do you want me to say some good
words to my Royal Brother for you
and let the calamity fund
be given to the citizens.
If Princess is willing to
help the affected citizens,
then I will be forever grateful.
I am thanking you now.
Just by saying is not enough.
How do you plan to thank me?
What does Princess want?
Just tell me. Gold, silver, pearl, treasure,
make-up, or perfume? I'll give them all to you.
I want...
this one.
This one's so ugly. Why
would you like it?
Your taste is really
getting worse.
If my taste is bad then
wouldn't your taste be worse?
But it really does
look quite ugly.
I have never seen such a
poorly made fragrance pouch.
Not talking about he embroidery,
even her sewing is not straight.
Just return it to me then.
Who gave you this?
I get gifts from a lot of women every
year. How can I remember all of them?
If you don't remember it already,
then this belongs to me.
I'll look for another one tomorrow that is
more well made and will fit your high status
and then gift it to you.
Is that okay?
What if I must have this?
What's going on?
Don't think I don't know. During the day of the Qixi
Festival, you and her were at the lake side. I saw it all.
She's called Feng Fei Yue.
I thought that you would never
really fall for any woman.
But looking at it now,
I might be wrong.
I'm just fooling her.
Really?
But I can see that when you are
with her, you laugh happily.
She's really stupid.
She can't differentiate between what's true
and fake. If not, why would I lie to her.
Fine.
Then I want to see how
you will trick her.
If it will make me happy, then I will definitely
say good words for you in front of Royal Brother.
What calamity funds? Just
give them to the citizens.
But if you can't,
then I'll report you
to Royal Brother
and have you killed.
It's really beautiful here.
Yes. So beautiful.
It's just sad that sometimes
when flowers blossom,
the good scenery
doesn't last long.
Close your eyes.
Close my eyes?
Why?
I told you to close them,
so just close them.
Raise your arms.
Despite closing one's eyes, one can still
smell the bursts of a flower's fragrance.
One burst of wind blowing by,
you can then hear the sound of
bursts of flowers falling down.
Isn't it the scene you see
with your eyes closed
more beautiful than when
your eyes are open?
Are you willing to marry me?
I'm willing.
I'm willing to marry you.
Princess!
Meng Anren, I'm really
impressed with you.
You can't find any other person who is
as mean and lowly as you in this world.
The truth is I have a more darker damaging
technique. Do you want to try it Princess?
What do you mean by this?
How come you still cannot get it until
now? This woman is really so dumb.
You think I will like you?
I've already seen a lot of women
with features like yours.
I will never marry you.
Anren, you must be lying to me. You're
just playing a joke with me, right?
You swore once that you would never
marry even if you had to die
and you even conspired
with Zhao Gao to frame me.
You think I have forgotten
about all these?
You did all of these
just to take revenge on me?
Right.
I already let you hit me once. I won't let
you have the chance to slap me again.
Timing and subtitles brought to
you by Gone With the Shirt Team
Grandma...
Being a Mythical Fox of Qing Qiou, you failed to find the Magical
Fruit and even got yourself followed by more disastrous debts.
You even have the face to
come crying back here?
Grandma, it's all my fault.
It's all because I'm
so dumb and stupid!
Why did I believe his words?
But... other than Qing Qiou...
I really don't know where to go?
At the start, you were courageously moving forward.
But right now you want to hide and retreat?
What's that? Dare to do it, dare to
live with it. You better go back there!
- Grandma... - Go back!
Grandma, don't drive me away...
Grandma, don't be like this.
Why are you doing this?
If you don't sharpen a knife it will not slice fast.
A soft hammer will not be able to hammer iron.
If she doesn't go through this experience,
how can she learn to be good and grow up.
This is her time to train. We
must not become soft-hearted.
♫ Your tenderness
slashed open my wound ♫
♫ Turned the whole night sky into fresh red. Heartache so
splendid that you can’t open your mouth to say a word ♫
♫ My suspicions took me to a never ending fall from
grace. Didn’t have enough time to undo all the silence ♫
♫ Didn’t have enough time to undo
all the silence and finally drown ♫
- Magical fruit... ♫ Not begging you to understand.
Just begging you not to make me cry. ♫
Magical fruit...
Give me back the
Magical Fruit...
Magical fruit...
Give me back the
Magical Fruit...
Give it back...
- Magical fruit?
- Magical fruit...
Magical fruit...
- Fei Yue...
- Give it back. Magical fruit...
Wake up. Fei Yue
You're awake.
How come I can still see
you even if I'm dead?
You're not dead.
Then why are we here?
I am the one who
brought you back here.
You still have a fever.
- Second Young Master, the medicine
is here. - Okay, give it to me.
Hurry and drink it.
You can hate me but you
must drink the medicine.
Do you know that your body
is very weak right now?
Continue to brew the medicine.
Brew it until she drinks it.
I won't drink the medicine
you made even if I die.
You listen.
I'll leave Fei Yue to
your care from now on.
Brew medicine for her to drink. If she
doesn't drink it, I will blame it on you.
If she doesn't drink it once, I'll
hit (with planks) you 10 times.
Doesn't drink it twice, I'll hit
you 20 times. Do you understand?
- Yes, Young Master. - Go then.
How's that?
I won't fall for
your trick again.
- Get away! - Hey, Fei Yue.
- Fei Yue, what are you doing?
- Get lost.
Where are you going?
A place where I won't see you.
- Young Master - No need.
- Okay.
- Miss, what's wrong with you?
- Fei Yue, come.
- Are you okay? - Get lost.
Fei Yue!
Get out of the way...
- Fei Yue... - Get lost.
Disperse quickly!
- Men! - Second Young Master!
- Call the Royal Physician!
- Yes.
How is it?
The fever is due to a cold.
And also, Miss seems to have experienced
great shock or provocation,
such that her anger is accumulating in her
heart and causing disarray in her pulse
and weakens her breathing.
This...
But Master Meng shouldn't
be too worried.
As long as you prevent Miss to
experience anymore shock or provocation,
let her take her medicines on time daily, and let her
recuperate peacefully, she will be cured in no time.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- No need to be polite.
Hurry. Escort Royal Physician Zhang
back and get the medicines, too.
- Yes, Young Master.
- Sorry to have troubled you.
Please.
Meng Anren!
Sister-in-law.
What scene (act) are
you acting now?
Yesterday, the two
of you happily left.
Just one night and everything
was different. Why is that?
There are some things...I
don't know how to say it.
What do you mean by not knowing how
to say it? I understand everything.
Fei Yue is a naive, nice girl.
She doesn't do schemes.
If you treat her well,
she will treat you well.
You exerted a lot of effort
just to make her like you.
Are those really just
to hurt her feelings?
If it's like that, then why
did you still bring her home?
I like Fei Yue very much. She's
simple, naive, just, and kind.
She also treats you very well and I can see that
you also treat her differently from others.
I also sincerely want to
bring you two together.
But since you cannot treat her
well, then just let her go.
Don't...
Royal Physician said that she cannot have
any more provocation. I'll go on ahead.
Wait a moment.
Think about my words well.
There are people and things that once you let
them pass by, they won't return anymore.