Episode 57
What do you mean Phillip invested in Shuwei?
When?
The time frame fits perfectly, too.
He did it just as Shuwei signed with Cloud.
Then Phillip invested in Shuwei so that
they'd break the contract with us?
I'm afraid so.
That despicable bastard.
He made a plot to invade us.
I believe Attorney Seo was bought off as well.
He was in charge of the Shuwei contract
and he probably re-drafted it.
Seo suddenly quit and disappeared
just before Shuwei broke the contract.
That means he's not after profits.
He's trying to takeover our company.
I'm certain money isn't his objective.
Are you sure he's not doing this
because of you and Areum?
He must've thought the failure with Dio
was a big deal.
I hear he asked Areum to work in his office.
Yes.
You should've gotten her to resign
when I asked you to.
Why put the company in danger for her?
No use crying over spilled milk.
I'm sure Phillip won't act for a while,
so we'll have to come up with a resolution.
We shouldn't have given him authority
over business affairs and human resources.
I'll figure out Seo's whereabouts.
If we find a witness for the manipulation
of the contract, we can get Phillip.
You think Seo will be that easy to find?
We'll have to at least try.
Did you go somewhere?
Yeah. The president's office.
Is something wrong?
No.
Is everything going well for you?
Yes. I'll show you the designs
as soon as I'm done.
Look them over and give me feedback.
I'll update them and keep you posted.
Okay, if you need fabric or anything else,
feel free to ask me at any time.
Okay.
You know the clothes
that we collected from Dongdaemun?
Yeah.
If you don't need them, may I have them?
Well, I paid for them myself, so sure.
They were going to be thrown out anyway.
What are you going to do with them?
I just need them.
Thank you. I'll put them to good use.
Okay. Sure.
Bye.
What did Seo's secretary say?
Just before he disappeared
was he acting strangely at all?
Not really, but at his office,
there were copies of plane tickets.
Plane tickets? To what destination?
Los Angeles International Airport.
He cut contact with his family and went to LA?
Get Attorney Seo's schedule for the week
before he quit from his secretary.
Find out who he met, where and when.
Yes, sir.
You can hate and torture me.
But don't do this.
The company...
Seongun has nothing to do with this.
If you want, I'll quit.
So please, stop this.
Hello, Mr. Park.
Can we talk in my office?
Please bring the other board members, too.
Did you get a good grasp of the company?
Yes.
There are many issues all across the board.
Which part in particular?
How is it that after Director Cheon's
major debacle in entering the Chinese market,
he faced no repercussions?
Well, that...
That's because he's the son of the CEO and...
This is how Korean companies
get criticized for nepotism culture.
Without any effort, for being the CEO's son,
he has 10% of the company shares?
After such a catastrophic failure,
the company lets him off the hook?
Let's talk more about this
during this week's board meeting.
That's all.
Here's the K-project strategy report.
A charity business for an orphanage?
Interesting.
Was this your idea?
No, it was Director Cheon's idea.
I thought he was a complete waste of space,
but I guess he occasionally uses his brain.
What? Are you upset by what I said?
You're the absolute worst.
Don't just blame me.
If you have the courage, then try.
You have the courage to kneel for Seongun,
but not enough to admit you love him?
You already revealed that you're a single mom.
While you're at it, why don't you
tell everyone you're a single mom in love?
Keep trying to hurt me. I won't flinch.
Gladly.
Are you looking into Tiffany's custody rights?
If you can't come back to me,
we should settle Tiffany's custody issues
before you go to another guy.
Hello?
I scheduled a consultation with Attorney Lee.
I'm pressed for time. May I see her this week?
Okay, I would appreciate your help.
Please call me.
I asked Attorney Ko for information on
legal provisions for export customs clearance,
so ask her for them.
Hello.
Is Attorney Ko out?
Yes. She's out and she'll be back later.
May I help you?
Yes, I'm here for the files Phillip asked for.
Attorney Ko prepared those files already.
Just a moment.
Here you go.
Great. Thank you. Have a good day.
Detailed Summary of Suspect, Ha Yunsu
Ha Yunsu...
Ha Yunsu.
You're Ha Yunsu, correct?
Who are you?
I was designed those clothes.
I know you're the one who distributed them.
Don't you know how to knock?
What's this?
Why do you have this?
These are classified.
Were you snooping around in my office?
At least you're not denying
that this was in your office.
You know that Ha Yunsu is the suspect
I talked to about the circulation
of my designs, correct?
What in the world are you talking about?
I had a feeling that the woman
in the subway security footage was you.
But I didn't want to believe it.
I hoped that it wasn't.
So?
You're saying I stole your designs?
As this company's lawyer,
I'm allowed to look at these files!
You lined up the evidence
just to frame me, didn't you?
If you threaten me without proof again,
I'll show you how frightening the law can be.
If you know the law so well,
how could you do this?
Shut your mouth!
I felt guilty towards you.
I hurt you
and I never apologized properly.
You have every reason to dislike me
and perhaps even hate me. I get it.
Shut up!
I don't want to hear that from you.
But I didn't do it deliberately.
I didn't do it because I didn't like you
or because I hated you.
I hope you know that.
And...
I'm sorry for all the grief I caused you,
but now we're even.
Let's let bygones be bygones.
Don't let something like this happen again.
How dare you act so high and mighty!
This is so unlike you, sir.
You're letting me join you two for drinks?
Seongun's having a hard time at work lately.
I invited him here to console him.
Oh, my. What's the matter?
You're worried?
Of course.
Sir, this isn't enough.
Why don't we take Seongun
on a family trip this weekend?
Should we?
I'd rather just go on a trip with you, Ms. Lee.
Really?
I'd be happy to. Where to?
- Bundang. / - Bundang?
To my mother's charnel house.
It'd console me quite a bit if you came with me.
Really?
I've been meaning to go see your mother.
That'd be nice.
You can pick the date.
Oh, about Seongho's boarding school.
Yes?
You can send him abroad for a year or two.
I can really do that?
Sure.
But I want you to go with him.
What?
We can't send the boy alone.
He needs his mother close by.
You should also go to clear your head.
Okay, I'll give it some thought.
Let's drink.
You're eating so well.
You're done now?
Let's see.
Baby food...
2:20, milk.
4:00, milk.
7:00, baby food.
- Mom. / - Hey.
You're home early.
Yeah, I wanted to work from home.
I'm home.
I just fed her baby food.
Mom.
Are you still really upset because of me?
I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
Let go. I have to make dinner.
That's okay, mom.
I'll do it. Just a second.
Where's mom?
She doesn't feel like eating, so she'll eat later.
Dad, about the home for single moms
you told me about before...
Yeah?
Can you give me the address?
I want to send them some
overstocked children's clothes from work.
- Children's clothes? / - Yes.
There are lots of children there, right?
I'd like to go visit the place
and meet the mothers and children myself,
but I got assigned a new task at work
so I'd like to just send the clothes for now.
Okay, I'll give you the address tomorrow.
Okay.
Is mom not well?
Just as grandpa said,
we have a place to call home
and you have grandma, grandpa and an uncle.
We're truly blessed, aren't we?
Tiffany, I have to work
so play by yourself for a bit.
Honey.
What?
A while back on TV,
there was a woman who had dementia,
so her husband quit his job
to nurse her with great care.
What would you do in that situation?
What a silly question.
When I saw that, I wondered
what we would do if we were in that situation.
We're getting older.
They say there's no cure for dementia.
Rather than make the family suffer,
it's best to just accept it.
Really?
Squandering money and energy on treatment
will only make the family hurt even more.
That's what dementia is.
A nursing home would be the best option
for both the patient and the family.
I guess you're right.
Go to sleep now.
Okay.
I'm going to go to the bathroom.
They say husbands are merely strangers...
- You're just getting in? / - Yes.
Father.
Are you and Ms. Lee having issues?
You two seemed pretty distant last night.
You even asked her to follow Seongho
to boarding school.
I'm concerned about her these days.
Why? Is something going on?
I think she's plotting with Mr. Park.
With Mr. Park?
Act like you don't know.
And keep your eyes on Phillip.
Be on your toes.
Yes, sir.
Good morning.
Were you at the storage room this morning?
Yes.
How's it going? Working there's tough, right?
It's alright.
It felt nice to touch chalk
and use the sewing machine again.
I'm happy.
And don't call it the storage room anymore.
Call it the studio.
Sorry.
Storage room does sound pretty shabby.
Don't overdo it.
I can't pay you since this project is a secret.
I know.
Have a great day.
Okay. You, too.
Bye.
Hyeokmin.
Take good care of the business.
I can't believe my son lived in a rented room!
- Hyeokmin! / - Father!
My son!
All ready.
Now that I got a job,
I'll bring each and every paycheck to you.
Yes, please do just that.
Hyeokmin, let's eat.
What are you doing? Are you feeling sick?
I'm fine.
What are you saying?
Come over here so we can eat.
Mother, father.
I feel the "storm and stress" period upon me.
Storm and stress?
What do you mean by that?
My mind is endlessly filling with thoughts
that I should not be having.
I'm thinking about...
Never mind.
What am I saying in front of my parents...
I think I will skip one meal.
Hyeokmin...
Father, mother. Enjoy your meal.
Hyeokmin!
What will we do?
What's wrong with him?
You heard what he said.
He's hitting puberty.
He must be thinking about, you know...
What will we do? How embarrassing.
Tell him about the birds and the bees.
The birds and the bees?
Hyeokmin? Already?
I heard kids grow up quickly these days but...
Well, I can't talk to him about it.
What if he starts looking at dirty stuff?
You should sit him down and teach him.
I'm not an expert in that department either.
The birds and the bees...
Yes.
I'll run away at night if I have to.
I can't let Yujin take over my life.
Busy?
No. What's up?
I actually need your help with something.
How can I help?
Well...
Oh!
Of course.
Hyeokmin's already got a mustache.
He's a man now.
I just feel so awkward about it.
You should've come to me sooner.
Ta-da!
This is the perfect textbook
for an elementary school kid.
You think? Thanks.
I have one for middle schoolers, too.
I'm okay. Next time.
The high school version?
Close the door and come here.
Sit down.
I have something to show you.
What will you show me this time?
Father!
It's okay to look at this with me.
Father, how...
How can you show a child such a thing?
You mentioned storm and stress, and so...
Father and son may have a close bond,
but how can a father show his own son
such obscenities in broad daylight?
Obscenities?
You ought to be ashamed of yourself!
I'm really disappointed in you, father!
Was it that extreme?
Tonight, that good-for-nothing Sua...
Who's Sua?
My daughter.
Oh, your daughter.
Was being so harsh on me that I got mad.
What's the use in raising kids?
She should be grateful, that brat.
My journal is full of complaints.
It's good, it's very real.
When you praise me like that,
I don't know what to say.
This is my gift to you.
A gift?
They're a collection of poems written by
women who learned to read later on in life.
Read this and try to write a poem yourself.
A poem, you say?
Each day, with a baby on my back,
I work the fields
and go to the forest to gather wood.
I weave straw by a kerosene lamp.
Then I wake again to make breakfast.
I found I have no time to be loved.
Oh, my.
The tears are keeping me from reading.
Though I've lived for so many years,
I have never been loved.
Maybe I should try writing a poem.
You're home early.
Shall I draw you a bath?
No, I don't even have the strength for that.
I'm just going to wash my face and lie down.
Oh, no.
Things must be really tough at work.
They are.
Phillip's poking his nose into everything.
He seems to be making quite a mess of things.
I can't let this go on.
I'll have to sell your shares and Seongho's.
What? What do you mean?
You'll sell our shares?
Not all of them, just some of them.
The company's facing hard times
so we have to give up our shares first.
I'll give them back when things get better.
I told Seongun the same thing.
If things are tough, we have no choice.
I knew you'd understand.
- Thank you. / - You're welcome.
I'm hungry. Will you get dinner ready?
Sure.
I'm sorry for all the grief I caused you,
but now we're even.
Let's let bygones be bygones.
Don't let something like this happen again.
Yes, Ms. Lee.
Are you at home?
I'm still at the office. I'm about to go home.
Did you meet with the accounting team leader?
Not yet. I'm carefully biding my time.
Hurry up!
What'll you do if you miss the timing?
Are you sure we should be doing this?
Messing with accounting is a big offense.
Yuni, are you still hesitating
even after what Seongun put you through?
It's not that.
After what Seongun did to you,
you could be doing far worse things!
No matter what, I won't let you take the fall,
so get moving.
We can't wait any longer.
Okay.
It's cold in the storage room,
so take an electric heater with you.
What's this?
She's still fraternizing with Seongun?
And take a cab home if it gets too late.
Unbelievable.
The storage room?
I should call home to say that I'll be late.
Where's my cell phone?
Did I leave it in the office?
Anyone out there?
Anyone?
I'm locked in here! Help!
Why isn't she responding to my texts?
She's probably not sleeping yet.
Is she watching Tiffany?
Anyone out there?
Anyone?
I'm trapped in here!
Help me!
I'm trapped in here! Help!
Anyone out there?
Anyone? Please open the door!
I'm trapped in here!
Open the door!
About the custody rights...
I'm raising Tiffany.
She's mine, too.
How can you decide that alone?
For unmarried couples,
courts tend to rule in favor of mothers.
The law may be set, but the verdict is not.
Do you mean I could win custody?
Of course.
The contract was switched out.
I think someone fabricated it.
Did you find any sort of proof?
I was wondering if you had any good news.
Don't worry. By tomorrow,
Seongun will be gone.