Outside of the world you know...
...there exists the Realm Eternal,
Asgard.
The shining light of the Nine Worlds...
...Asgard is home to the gods...
...all of whom bow down
before the All-Father...
...Odin.
Odin's lifeblood
flows through Asgard...
...and Asgard is Odin.
His power is all...
...and he keeps
the Asgardian realm safe.
But once each winter,
the All-Father must rest...
...and enter the Odinsleep.
While Odin slumbers, his absence
leaves Asgard vulnerable...
...and this is when the wicked
descend upon his kingdom.
Charge!
For seven days,
an onslaught of trolls...
...giants, dark elves and demons...
...seek to take control
of the Nine Worlds.
But they are eternally defeated
by him...
...my arrogant,
oafish brute of a stepbrother...
...Thor.
I don't understand.
Where--? Where am I?
Hear me, human.
You have been brought to Asgard
because in all the universe...
...only you
have ever brought near defeat...
...to the Mighty Thor.
What?
I-- I couldn't.
Not thee, Bruce Banner.
You are but a sniveling, sad creature.
I speak of your other half.
I speak of the Hulk.
There is one day left of the Odinsleep.
The cycle is nearly complete.
As always, the Asgardians
will emerge victorious...
...against the siege of darkness.
My brother will seek peace,
and then....
Then I shall destroy him.
Verily, ye must say...
...that went far better than last winter.
Tell us, Volstagg...
...are you going to dispatch that troll
beneath you...
...or are you saving him for dinner?
That all depends
on how much mead I partake in.
Did my ears deceive me?
Did Hogun the Grim make a joke?
And here we thought
you were still in a foul mood...
...because you didn't get
to slay a frost giant.
I've still slain more than thee, Fandral.
But we shall see
whom the maidens reward more.
In mere hours, the All-Father
will awaken, and then we may rejoice.
The Lady Sif would know
what vexes thee.
Aye, we won the day.
All is well in the realm of Asgard...
...but only until the next Odinsleep.
It is as it has always been.
We must learn
to savor the moments of peace.
And accept the cycle of death?
How many of our brothers and sisters
have fallen to this madness?
Must we be chained
to this eternal struggle?
Be careful what you wish for,
my love...
...for when the cycle does break,
when things do change...
...then comes the end of days...
...then comes Ragnarok.
Perhaps our fates
are not ours to choose.
But come.
Let us return to my father's palace
and prepare for his awakening.
Please, I'm begging you, don't do this.
I've fought all my life
to keep the Hulk inside.
You don't know the destruction
he can cause.
Don't know?
You fool. I'm counting on it.
Look at you, so weak.
Were it not for you
inside the Hulk's mind...
...suppressing his power...
...he would rule Midgard
with his rage.
I won't let him out.
I won't let you do this.
You won't let me?
How amusing you mortals are.
Let me see if I recall correctly.
It is anger that unleashes the beast.
I seem to have forgotten the frailty
of mortals.
Look, Amora,
I do believe he's going to weep.
No.
It's impossible.
Now.
And so begins the end of Thor.
Well, what think thee, Balder?
One last troll
with dreams of conquest?
Perhaps.
Come, Hogun, Fandral...
...let us give unto this scoundrel
the gift of battle.
Oh, the creature's power
is incredible.
Take care, Loki.
My spell bonds you to the creature...
...and while you are master to it,
I can feel him fighting you.
You have to listen to me.
It can't be controlled.
Do not try my patience, worm...
...lest I turn my attentions to thee.
You are no troll, monster.
'Tis Balder's horn,
but this is not right.
Asgard's enemies are all defeated.
And yet the alarm has sounded.
Stay at Odin's side.
Should I fail to meet this threat,
you must protect him.
But if Thor should fall,
what hope has Asgard?
You will have to kill me, monster...
...for I shall not yield.
Thor, the creature...
...like nothing I have ever seen.
Aye, my friend.
This is no immortal evil
that we face now.
The Hulk has come to Asgard.
Dr. Banner,
can you hear me inside the beast?
Why have you come here?
Why, to kill you, of course,
dear stepbrother.
Loki?
I have waited an eternity for this.
To crush you with my bare hands.
To match your might.
To feel your life fade away...
...as my hands
wrap around your throat.
Never!
Come to your new master, Mjolnir...
...and let us smite my stepbrother...
...for there are none stronger
than Loki now.
Rise, cursed hammer.
Loki, enough.
Your own rage fuels the beast.
I can feel the spell breaking.
I will have this hammer!
Nay, you will have its thunder.
For Odin. For Asgard!
The monster...
...it is rage incarnate.
It has shattered the spell.
The Hulk is free.
Will thou yield, Loki?
Truly, this is the best of both worlds.
I need not control the beast
to enjoy its wrath.
Goodbye, brother.
This.... This is not what I wanted.
There's no going back, Amora.
After all,
if not for your black, broken heart...
...none of this
would have been possible.
You don't know what you've done.
With no one to reign the Hulk in,
he'll tear down your entire world.
I find your prattling useless, mortal...
...just as you are now useless to me.
For Odin.
For Asgard.
Thor.
My love, I....
I was angered
when you chose Sif over me.
I did not--
I wanted thy love, not your death.
Please.
Please come back to me.
-Amora.
-Yes, my love.
Where is Loki?
What is that monster doing?
It travels towards Odin.
Loki, I would have words with thee.
No. You were at Hela's door.
I defeated you.
You. You dare cross the god of--
The Hulk will be sent back to Midgard,
and then you will answer to Odin.
Fine, take the creature.
It provided me
with amusement enough...
...seeing it pummel you
nigh unto death.
Loki, you fool. You killed him.
Do you know what you've done?
Because the mortal died here,
Hela claimed his soul.
Without his soul,
I cannot return him to Midgard.
Without Bruce Banner,
the Hulk cannot leave Asgard.
Valkyries, warriors,
your seats in Valhalla are promised.
Protect Odin with your lives.
For Asgard!
I saw the beast's eyes, brother.
It will not stop
until all of Asgard is destroyed...
...until Odin is broken.
You have brought a new Ragnarok
down upon us all.
Possible I made a poor choice.
Amora, I need you by Odin's side.
Protect him along with Lady Sif.
As you wish.
Loki, you will send whatever dark
forces you have left to battle the Hulk.
Then you and I,
we go unto Hel this day.
Rest your weapon, shield maiden.
I have come to aid thee
in Odin's defense...
...at Thor's request.
His request, you say?
More likely his penance, witch.
No doubt he saw your hand
in this attack.
A punishment more cruel
than you can imagine, cow.
Loki, the god of mischief,
bids you death, mortal creature.
Long have I wished
never to see this realm.
I always forget what a busy time
the Odinsleep is for my daughter.
Dost thou see any
newly arrived friends here, brother?
Have a care, Loki, lest ye stay here.
Where am I?
No. This doesn't make any sense.
Bruce?
Are you okay?
Betty?
I thought....
I don't understand.
-I was alone, and then--
-You're not alone, Bruce.
Not anymore.
Daddy.
Come play with me.
Hail Hela, goddess of the dead.
We seek an audience.
The sons of Odin risk much
entering my realm.
The Nine Worlds of Asgard
are in great peril, mistress...
...including Hel and Niflheim.
A new Ragnarok is upon us,
and we need your help.
We need Bruce Banner.
The mortal's soul is mine, Asgardian...
...as yours nearly was this very day...
...and may well be again.
You would risk everything
for the sake of one soul?
Just as you would, Odinson.
But you do not have one soul,
daughter, you have half a soul.
You have Bruce Banner.
You need the Hulk
to complete your prize.
-Are you all right?
-I feel....
I feel great.
I can't imagine anything better.
Bruce Banner.
Wake from this dream.
Betty?
Betty? Where are you?
The world of the living
has need of you.
Who are you?
What do you want with me?
Not I, he.
Friend Banner,
for the sake of all of Asgard...
...you must become the Hulk
once more.
Betty.
Where's...?
No.
No!
No. No, you can't ask me to do that.
I finally had peace.
You don't know what you're asking.
Your time in Hel certainly has not
made you less of a worm, mortal.
Bruce Banner,
I know thee to be a man of honor.
I know thee to be a hero.
The lives at stake are not
your concern, not even human...
...but I ask you anyway.
Be that hero now.
No.
I can't.
Die, beast.
The Hulk's soul is rightfully yours,
daughter.
Take it. Bring the Hulk to Hel.
Merge the two halves of his soul
and claim him.
Bruce Banner...
... I will not force you
to forsake the rewards of the afterlife.
-But you must be whole.
-No. I won't.
You don't understand.
No!
Curse you, Loki...
...for convincing me
to bring this creature to my realm.
Stay thy hand, Hela.
We shall retrieve the Hulk.
We?
The Hulk's fists have addled
your mind, thunderer.
Fight with me, brother, or die alone.
Not much of a threat,
considering we're already in Hel.
Have at thee.
My apologies.
I was enjoying the performance.
Hulk!
Let them go. I'm the one you want.
Come on.
Dr. Banner.
Hulk tired.
You called him weak, Loki...
...but there is more strength
and courage in that man...
...than you will ever know.
This soul is too dangerous
to keep in Hel...
...and too valuable to lose
to Valhalla.
I will return him to Midgard.
Enough of this ridiculousness.
To think that Loki,
prince of darkness...
...should waste his time
with defending Asgard.
Nay, brother.
We leave together,
for you still have much to answer for.
Indeed, you both do...
...for today,
Hela has relinquished a soul...
...and she demands one in exchange.
You may try to take my soul,
death goddess...
...but I will make you fight for it.
And your realm
has suffered much already this day.
You speak the truth.
So I shall take his soul instead.
What?
Thor. Thor!
I helped you. I--
I could fight you for Loki's soul.
-Will you?
-No.
He is my father.
His stay will not be eternal.
But know this, Odinson...
...your soul will be mine,
and I will keep it forever.
Your fate is inescapable.
We shall see.
Thus, the cycle begins anew.
Asgard is safe once again...
...defended to the end by its heroes.
I am proud of each of you
that stand before me.
The day was saved by loyalty
and sacrifice.
We honor those who fought
beside us...
...those who are no longer with us.
And we defy those
who would see us brought to ruin.
And while the rewards of Valhalla
await all of Asgard's heroes...
...this day we honor
a hero of Midgard...
...a mortal who sacrificed everything
for a land not his own.
This day, a human showed the gods
what legends are made of.