Hello. Is it Eric? Erik Moller, yes.
Condolences. Now, it does not.
Anna Moller. Yes, you know it as well.
Shall we?
So here we are again. It is some years ago?
We have not spoken together since I was 22.
I've never been allowed to meet him.
I wrote 900,000, but we need up to a million if some buyers leader.
I do not millionaires? And.
They had made a brand new kitchen, just before he died.
I can see that.
Your father looked like it was in the family.
He can forget. For a million.
I do not know anything your finances. It must not talk too loudly about.
Just get it launched. Getting rid of it.
Bleach.
Not? A million. Yes ...
Man disappears from each other in such a big house.
Is it documented? There are plenty of studies.
The difference between living together or not is that you can see and hear each other.
Or are you a little person to stay small, Erik.
An architect must live in a big house.
I am not an architect that way. Why do you keep it?
I am a teacher, and it disappears from each other in the big houses.
It's also quite peg to spend so much money to stay.
It is then a part of it. 450 square meters.
It's too big. Final, period.
Freya ... Freya, come. We gotta try something. Are you following?
We must find the furthest away.
Are you mad that far down. Sit down.
Should we close the door? That we agreed. It is us first.
So high you can not? Are you ready?
No, wait a minute.
No mom. It's cheating. No.
Just a little.
Okay.
(Whistles)
(Erik whistles)
We can easily hear you. It is then a completely ridiculous play.
It's true what mom says. See if you can find me. Bye bye.
Where did he go? Sheep! Just because you lost.
Sheep? Where did you go? Erik?
Is he agreed to, we sleep here? Yes, that is just in the night.
Wake me when you get home, right? Jo.
Kiss.
I love you. I love you too.
Hello. Hello.
... After several years of terrorism, hijackings, killings and kidnappings.
This is mind control
where people are being subjected to interrogation and intelligence control.
Now for news in brief. The ratio of LO top and the Social Democratic Party
is now so bad that LO's president threatens to terminate the partnership.
Beach Road. Here came my childhood.
We just can not afford to be here. Not even to greet someone.
Her er poletter.
She needs to Østerbro Lilleskole. I know very well where I should of.
Anna Moller! An autograph? Now go with you. We are busy.
I have a pen.
There's harbor. Kæft, a tennis court.
Come on. Here I have spent many years. Are you insane.
Do you remember Torben? He was professional. Ham, I played with.
On the other side. You and Torben?
Lob.
Hey! I!
It is yacht club. We had our dinghy up here. An old trapeze dinghy.
If we lived here, then you could play tennis.
Then you could go down here and sail. Honey, we do not have the money for it.
Take my panties off.
Ah!
Wow. Yes.
Sol ... Sex ...
So the sun.
I've double-checked the numbers. Do not be just above the articles.
Pardon. Do not you just? Thanks. I've double-checked the numbers.
The 570 kronor a month for heat is too much.
We can not afford to live in this house. It is also too large.
We will call you as just some more. We can call Ditte and Ole.
No, we do not. I know what you want, Anna.
I will not stay in something collective. I get tired just at the thought.
I am also too old. I've called Ole.
I'm bored, Erik. Something needs to happen.
Not? You talk all the time.
You're so cute when you do that, but it's as though I've heard it all before.
Now.
I need to hear some others say something soon.
Otherwise I become insane.
This huge, fabulous house must then be filled with amazing people.
What for some people? Ole.
Ole is very interested. He has not had it so good for long.
Ole's nothing amazing human being.
You love when Ole. Yes, as a friend to watch football with.
Try to imagine what would happen. It is exciting.
Can one be allowed to sleep on it? Come on, old man.
What the hell, there's servants? It was good you could come.
This is where you grew up, Erik? Yes I am.
So I can better understand you are a bit worldly.
Yes, it's a big house. And orangery and all, what?
Nice to see you. You look good. You too.
What's in the bags? My clothes in one and then ...
And leftist literature? She is not so stupid, what?
You are also skidesød. Do I get there numbers?
Or I may be sticking together in this company?
It is a job interview it here. It can as well call it.
How are you? I have it as well, Anna. Thanks.
Ah ...
I've been a little out of a galaxy. I have damn.
Now. Did Marianne? Mm.
Yes, she progressed with a singing teacher. The high C, we called him.
There was nothing but skim milk in pencil, she was on.
I'm damn sorry.
It's damn funny idea to stay with you.
And I love you the suit. Not Frejsen?
But you, Erik, in a collective? Reach. Do you have any money?
I got you. I forgot what we were talking about.
Money are we talking about.
We will do something great together. Well it here then can be huge.
The rents are slightly deropad. We will find out.
Are you aware that I have seen your father passing out of temper again? What?
Over in Bellahøj Badet. And so, I caught you, Erik. Do you remember that?
I do so again, because I'm your friend, Erik.
There I got the job. Did you feel it, Frejsen what?
What the hell are you laughing?
I must call some others too. We must also.
What about Ditte and Steffen? She has been an associate professor.
It's too fancy for me.
Is it Ditte Johansen, you think? But then there's this.
No! Yes Yes. It's just me, here.
Ole? Ditte Johansen, it's her? Yes, she is a violation bitch.
We just go from the start, and then we mark where it is Done.
Should not we call someone else? You may know some others.
We mark completely hard. It will not be a problem.
We mark completely. We mark completely from the start.
Have you made some rules of the house?
Should I? The fact is slightly below ... So ...
Yes. They are a little under preparation.
Yeah, you could say that. They are somewhat incomplete remains.
Can you talk a little bit about them, perhaps? Yes.
Uh, yes, they are ...
Have you made them or not? We have not made any yet.
There must be some house rules. Yes Yes.
We would like to help with it.
Let me just add that the rent probably is right at the high end.
Because of the house conditions. It is not a problem.
It's so long since I've seen you.
Honey, you can not say your name? What?
It is Vilads. He is six years. Hello, Vilads. Hello.
He has no heart, so he takes it a little quiet sometimes.
Okay. Oh no, it sounds serious. I die when I am nine years.
Do such know? We dont know.
He gets much of the sentence. The girls love it.
Such! They gave him only a few years.
But there are some things he should try first.
Thats how it should be.
How old is she? How old are you, Freya?
I am 14 14? Do you think she's cute?
I will just nine years.
He is fast. I've probably soon something with heart.
Well, what do you do?
Voting right? It makes man.
I am damn ... I'm for. Me too.
So do I. Me too.
Are you also? Well then it's a reality.
Have not you got a beer for Steffen? Jo.
Beer? I really want to ask for a beer.
It will be damn cozy. Welcome to.
Now, it's Mona tomorrow.
Do you speak our language?
(latter)
I try on it.
What are you living on Allon?
Uh, different jobs.
I ask because the rent is at the high end here ??
we have all been made aware of.
Do you earn ... earns money?
So, he speaks Danish, Mona. Not?
I do not understand what he says. I get it to stick together.
What do you say? He makes it to hang together.
Steff says you work a little here and so you work a little there.
Then I thought ... Why change constantly work?
It is almost always odd jobs. Yes.
Do you like it?
I imagine things I would rather do.
What, for example? What would you like to hear?
I will not stomp around in it all the time ??
but I get the feeling you do not voluntarily switch between jobs?
It can simply sense?
Yes I can.
It makes me really quite curious.
That makes him curious. What are your future plans?
What would you like?
In plan ...
I will arrive. What?
What? You will arrive?
I will arrive. Yes.
Arrive? What the hell is that for an answer?
Why do you vocally? Will not you please answer?
I have asked you some questions, and those you can answer.
Why would you like to stay with us?
I assume you are the boss here?
No, I'm not the boss.
This is a collective! Here we shared the dishes! There is no boss here!
Here we shared the dishes! Can you understand that?
Can you understand that? Erik!
What? So you stop.
Breathe. I draw since the weather all the time.
Well so sorry!
It always happens to me. What do you say?
It always happens to him. That people are irritated with me.
It is my charisma. It is his charisma.
It was nice meeting you. No ...
Come on, dammit. Do not answer him that way.
I tell him that rents are at the high end.
I have since asked all about. He stands and cries?
I can not talk to a man standing and crying.
Allon?
I'm sorry. It did not mean.
No, it's fine. In choosing the right.
I do not have any money. Forget the money.
We will figure it out. I ... I vote for Allon.
And. And.
He has no money. Welcome.
Welcome, Allon. Come on in.
(Cars bumping)
Then you fucking come on the polished floors.
I have not seen the design before. Is it a dairy construction?
Like you, Mona.
So you put the house to the other. Are you sure you want that road?
Yes, I'm sure. Fucking Good! Well, Erik!
Lovely! You make just seven copies.
So, Vilads, now you should damn officially with Ole.
Try to feel how cold my ass is.
(Loud talk)
But, uh ... Anna? Tax? Anna?
Anna? What?
I got a great idea today. How to integrate the harbor.
She trenches and gizmos on him all the time.
What did you say? Pardon. I think I've cracked the nut.
I have thought of a good idea. A fun idea?
On how to integrate the quay at the port facility.
You have a lot more heat. You are much more charismatic.
Here you go. A completely with no. Good morning.
Have a good time. Have a good day, Ole.
Good morning. Hey darling.
Take care, all. Hello. Hello.
Hi.
Put the guitar and came up.
Not something to be leaking. Jesper, close the door as the last man.
So let's get a little specific to your ... What did you call it?
Grade. Marks of, yes.
Train your last submission based on tepees?
Mm.
(latter)
No, but it might be very funny. Teepees. Why tepees, Jesper?
A tipi is a removable space, which can be placed in different contexts ??
and has the potential for variation and reciprocity in world of dreams.
Just as with the tribes ... I'm sorry, what some dreams?
All sorts of dreams. Dreams must be free. That I feel is important.
Have dreams anything with architecture to do at all? Do you feel it?
Your dreams in your project has absolutely nothing architecture to do.
It contains no vision of how people can live together.
Why should I listen to this nonsense?
Why do I need 35 minutes to hear about your experiences in Peru?
And then your notes on some music, something flute work of some kind.
This is interesting for one person, Jesper. Can you guess who it is?
(Knocking on door) Yes?
I just came in.
I want to hear your reasons for being so violent in your appearance.
So violent in my appearance? Well, Jesper him, yes.
Do you know him? Yes.
You know him. That in itself I think can be quite unbearable.
You probably do not humiliate him? The humiliation he himself stood for.
Han er and fæhoved. In grønskolling og and fæhoved.
What can I do for you?
I must borrow a cigaret? You must get one.
What's your name?
My name is Emma. I am third year.
And you go in my ... Yes.
Hm.
Excellent, Emma, ​​third year. What will you?
In addition to defending your friend? Talk about my project.
Fine. Well, let's find a day when we can do it.
So I think we need to say on Tuesday. The canteen, for some lunch?
What about now a fag?
It's ... We can as well. It is also an option.
I have not so damned much time. I need to catch a bus.
Reach. Exciting, is not it?
Jo. Do not you think well, we can reach it anyway?
I've looked a lot on Le Corbusier's modular system ??
and his view of human needs.
(Snore)
It seems you are not exciting?
You have already read so much about modular systems and Le Plan Voisin, ??
you do not have any independent attitude to it.
Find something else. How old are you?
Why do you ask?
What excites you?
I do not know. What you find out.
Do you have a view of Nyhavn? It is Nyhavn.
It is the view. If you lean way forward, you can see Kongens Nytorv.
Lovely.
And.
The Copenhagen Squad.
I danced there when you were a student? Yes. Did not you know?
You can swear, I did, but it's fucking long time ago.
You may.
Do like what?
Give me a kiss.
I see who you are.
And him I like.
Vil have and the wine knell? Ja.
I write in my essay that the end product of anarchy is order.
Anarchism dictates just that no man rules over another.
Do we have an agenda? Yes. "How are we" Round.
I get a sinking feeling when I wake up ??
in this fantastic house with all of you fools running around.
And I think that I actually have my family now.
Anna, how did we do it?
Well I'm happy. I am happy with you.
Bravo! Beautifully.
We've talked a little about that one must be able to fold if you will not vote.
Vilads, what should you say? Bum.
So join one himself neutral. Or pas. Is it that? The write down, not?
We have something we'd like to. It's actually you, Mona.
There has been little traffic in and out of the house.
A lot of traffic on the land register. Yes, once in the store.
We would like to know how many men you really see?
What?
We want to just find out how much it is, you pay for?
Is it one or is it all this bunch of men in and out of doors?
I'm not stingy with my body, and you know it too well, Ole.
You know it, Ole? Well, did you not, Steffen.
It is many years ago!
Steff how we have it with you? Well, uh ... We have it then ...
No, it's you, right? How are you?
Well, uh ... You can write that I feel good 90% of the time.
90%? Now. It is then very.
Allon how we have it with you? I feel good.
Although you have not paid the deposit? I knew you'd bring that up!
When I find a job, so you get all my money!
You live in a huge house with a lovely garden ...
If you think I can contribute something, so I move just again!
Now he sits and howls again. Should I call your mother down in Oh oh?
Erik, what about you? How are you?
Erik?
What? How are you, Eric?
How I am? Well I have it as well.
I'm fine. Yes yes. Fine.
So ...
Yes, but it's hard to get it to accommodate it all.
I sketch and I outlines.
I try to keep it simple, but make it more complicated ??
so it loses the clarity. It was so clear in her head.
It was clear in a sketch. The one I showed you yesterday?
You collect all the Ministry's functions in one prismatic form.
As a living sculpture in the middle of the city.
So, on the day it is a building full of movement and life, right?
But at night it's more a quiet lantern, which is located in havneløbet.
It's your idea. What you need to stick to.
It can be really impressive and at the same time sensual.
Not? Jo. You are so smart.
I miss you. I miss you when we're not together.
I miss you too.
Always.
(Singing "A Child is Born in Bethlehem")
Look at that. It's a bit small, it there, right?
No, over there, man. There is damn a really nice, little one.
I do not think we should take. No, it is so fine there.
In addition to her mother. What about this?
No ... Why, Mona?
I do not think you should save it.
It is so beautiful here. You can see that, right?
Will you be sorry, what? I saver does not in any tree, right?
(Singing "Now it's Christmas again")
Vent, stop! Vilads!
Vilads fall! He draws breath?
Vilads? What happens? Call an ambulance!
He is not breathing! We need to get him out of the car!
Vilads!
Come now!
No, we're not family. You gotta understand ??
that it is important for us to know how he feels.
So, they are completely closed. Let me just talk.
Good evening, whom am I talking?
You talk with Anna Moller. Ask me to the doctor on the ward.
I'm waiting.
She sounded good enough curt.
And.
But you can probably understand, that we live with Vilads.
We live in the collective. The kind you have not heard about.
I do not understand your procedure. If I lived in a nuclear family, ??
I would have had better rights?
What if it was my cousin? It is Vilads.
They come out in the car now. It does not matter.
Hello, brother Vilads. Just beware.
What did they say? At the heart rhythm to normal.
It swings the little, right? No, my boy? You swing.
Should we not have gifts? Jo!
Not dancing. We dance no more. We dance no more.
Not, thank you. I'll take one.
Yes we shall. Where is there still here. Here are just wonderful, Ole, what?
(Footsteps)
(running water)
Hello. Hello.
Who are you? I live here.
Now. I Troed, In all along was up Oles Odegaard?
I did not want. And we practice a piece in my school.
Who are you? I am visiting.
With whom?
At Erik.
I was actually also on the way home.
(the phone is ringing)
Hello.
Hi, it's mom.
Hello, mother.
Am I disturbing you?
Lay you and rested a little?
No, I just got home.
Went well with the samples?
Mm.
You can just call if you like. I have the house to yourself.
We have the absolutely fantastic. It's too bad you could not come up with.
I have put money for you on the table for spring rolls.
He Erik of?
No, I'm home alone.
We need to put a boat in the water.
I must run. Father has come home.
Okay, honey. Greet him.
Hello.
Hello Freja.
Hi.
What ... Should not you sleep with Sille?
I have spoken with the mother that it was okay to be home alone.
Yes, yes, it is indeed. It's more ... I ...
I follow just Emma, ​​right? Yes. Hello.
Yes, it was not meant. What do you mean?
I know you well can figure out what's been going on here.
It was not supposed to ... She should not have been here.
I'll talk to mother. Do you need it?
Is not it best to leave it? I do not think it is.
It's ... I think it works unhealthy to lie about such things.
I just do not want that happening.
I see another girl. Or I have seen another girl.
What do you say?
Yes, I have been with a few times.
I have not made those competition presentations, as I said.
Reach. I'm sorry.
It was not planned. It was ... It just happened.
Is it serious?
It must be, otherwise you do not then tell me.
Yes I believe.
Is she beautiful? It should she be.
Yes she is. Uh, students.
So she must be really young. Yes, she is young.
 Tredjeårs.
 Hold da op.
Do you go away from me?
No, I'm not going anywhere. Well.
But we'll have to find out the rooms in a way, right?
Yes Yes of course. It is clear that we must figure out how.
Freja know. Why?
Because I told happen there. Now.
Because Emma ... It's her. Her name is Emma ... was over here.
I did not know Freja was here. I thought she was over at Sille.
Now ...
But I ... It was when we were on tour.
In here, actually. Here?
You do not make it easy for me, Erik. No.
But I think we should find out.
Good night.
Good night. I love you.
I love you too.
Freja. Do you love him? Who?
Johannes.
No.
Is the helmet? He can just take it away if it is.
I go down and talk to him for you.
See you. Ses lose.
Freja? Freya, what are you doing? Nothing. See you.
Freya, he is too old!
What are you doing?
How long have you been following me?
Can not you talk?
I think you are too young to be out at night.
Pardon.
Well, then came in.
Just remember to take off your shoes and wipe them right of also.
You can simply turn off the lamp and then begin to undress.
(He groans)
How about the portrait of Pol Pot?
I may well use 15 seconds?
Anna's birthday and she is well and it is today
Anna's birthday and she has the today
and look here what we all drink will
It will!
look here how we drink will
boy boy boy boy boy boy boy boy
Violently. When should I? Yes, it was really violent.
How old are you going to be? Congratulations.
You stay well. You have a great connective tissue and a firm butt.
I was 43 when I went into menopause. You should be happy.
Now with that presentation to the portrait of Pol Pot, I think ...
Eight ... I'm ready.
Seven, six, ??
five, four, three, ??
To, en.
TV newspaper. Good evening.
I need to see what you have found until today.
No! No, where is him. Is that you, Kirsten?
We just wanted to make sure that you were celebrating.
There are lots of people. Congratulations.
Congratulations Congratulations.
Hi.
The others are waiting. Do we just see you at home?
Should not we be together us three little?
How did my husband that? I have not seen you for weeks.
You look tired. I'm fine.
We live in the school, so it's very. Yes, that's clear.
But anyway, I ... yes.
I miss you.
I do actually. That I will not say, but I do.
Yes, you may say. I can not live without you two.
But it is not. I also need to find something else to live.
We have a daughter together.
She's there, right? But ...
I am bloody completely confused.
I think you should do what you have to do.
What feels right. Things come in phases.
You do not know what happens the next few months.
We can not stay on a floor. At one school, under a desk.
We have since done. It was kinda romantic.
It was after all an apartment. What did your brother it?
We must find another place to stay. I love her damn. I do.
If she can not ... be a little bit with us?
Jo ... so, yes ... It ...
Perhaps. I do not fucking.
It makes Mads and Kirsten too. I know.
But she can not stay with us. Not, but stay and stay.
Right now we live together anyway in a way.
There must also be room for you. That's what it's all about.
Take her. Take her out, and then we find out.
Freja. We are leaving now.
What about Dad? He is also, I think.
Take my cigarettes. Do we have an agenda?
We start with "How's it." Allon how we have it with you?
Yes, I have a little problem. I've lost some things.
(Steffen laughs)
What have you lost? My brown jacket.
Yes, and one LP with the French chansons.
And then the sheath to my guitar. Yes.
What happened to those things? What happened to them?
But you burned them, Ole. You're an asshole.
When things flowing, people did not need them, and then they burned.
So Allon feel good, since he has no other problems.
I do not have any problems. Anna!
Anna!
There are house meeting!
Ølregnskabet has proceeded in coke.
You do not set lines. We've looked at it.
Did you not a line for me? A, right?
That's what I got. I also put my strokes.
Hello.
There are drinking more beer than is being put dashes.
Hello. Hello.
It's Emma. Hello.
You seem skidesød. Hi, I'm Ditte.
Hello. Emma. Oh, she's fine, what?
Steffen. Nice to meet you.
You too.
Holy shit. Allon.
You look like a French love story. It will not allow you to see.
We had just started a house meeting. I am Ole. I'm the flock leader.
He's not. Yes, come, Ole.
We were doing a ølregnskab. My name is Mona.
I suggest a beer amnesty. What?
Where remember assen exceptionally go in and cover the deficit in the beer crate.
So those of us who do not drink beer, pays?
It's gone completely bananas, so ...
Yes. Well, then it is adopted.
We start afresh on Monday. This is how we do here.
So you remember to put the dashes. Yes, now stop it.
Next point, it's you, Emma. Yes.
Erik and you've paired some time by now, ??
and now, Erik has expressed a wish that you move into the collective.
So, Emma ... what are you for?
Me? Mm.
I am ... No, whew, it's hard. Yes.
The next I was not.
How old are you? I am 24.
Alright.
I went on Eric's course for the Rational architecture.
It must be so careful.
It is a very interesting course. Are you here only for Eric's sake?
Or is the whole idea of ​​living here in a collective appealing to you?
Now it's Eric, I'm in love. I would just make me finish.
I've been looking forward to meeting you. You too.
Reach. But Anna, we've been through ølregnskabet.
And it went well. No, it did not.
Then there is a proposal to Emma as a possible tenant, ??
and then Steffen talk about his dishwasher.
Got something to the agenda? No.
There is continued.
Possible tenant? Yes.
Now. Anna, what do we have talked about.
You suggested it yourself. I have said that we should discuss it today.
I have not understood as concrete. I said she could be there a little.
But it sounds as otherwise exciting. That's what you have suggested, is not it?
Yes, it might. Sorry, I've been a little busy.
I'm sorry, Emma. It is fine.
I actually do not know that we will vote on a possible tenant, ??
if we do not have the same opportunities for it.
It is fine. It is just me. I did not know it was now.
You just have not seen it. That is not for me.
That is how things are, so let's just move on.
Maybe Anna did not want to understand it. It can be difficult.
What are you trying to say? I think it can be difficult.
I do not understand anything. I'll get a couple of beers.
Should we continue with the point? We will vote on it.
Should we not vote on Emma's occupation?
No, now we are voting damn right about whether we vote on it.
How many think we should continue the conversation and then proceed to vote?
Well, as we continue the conversation before we proceed to the vote.
That, I thought I had done. Well, I just go again.
It's not you, that makes it hard.
It was nice meeting you, but it's a conversation I need without me.
I follow you right out.
Hi. Hello Emma.
Clearly minus points that she goes. Plus Point, I think.
It's fucking dignity. I think like this about it.
Emma is part of Erik now, and Erik is an inseparable part of this house.
If we suppress it, we betray the basic idea of ​​living in a commune.
Not, I think damn, she's cute. You know her really well.
It would be easier if it was a new person who came with two women.
Coming in and had two women. That would be fine.
Yes, in theory, right? So it's fine for me too, but that is ...
Anna, that is. When I see you like that, do it for evil.
I would like to give it a try.
I think it must be possible for anyone to stay here.
I can also understand that Erik has fallen for Emma.
I am not naive. I know that ...
... That people have that kind of needs, let's see what happens.
Well good, then determines the well matter? We are damn just have to vote.
Is there anyone who has anything against that Emma move into a probationary period?
Mona, come now. I ...
I vote bum. Fine. One two three four five.
The community is not prepared to accept Emma as anything other than a guest.
So it's you, Steffen. The dishwasher?
I have looked at a copy from Mrs Flint, and she is waiting for us ??
in order that we can buy her.
Take some dishwashing with.
Is not it great? It is HUGE.
Steffen, I just think ... I like to do the dishes.
But there is just so much hassle.
Come back again. We're going to ...
Come back again. Now?
Come back in and sit down. We're heading over to Mrs Flint.
Come back in and sit down.
Come back in and sit down. I thought we were finished now.
How long do you need to pack up and find another place to stay?
This is my house. I've lived here since I was a boy.
I will not dictate how I should live my life. This is my house!
You gave the house to the community! Getting there papers on it?
It is technically Eric's house. Why did no paper on it?
Only half of you have paid your share!
I and Anna pay every penny for this!
So, are you still the boss now. It may well be that I'm the boss.
What you do not get involved in! Do what I say!
Find another place to stay! This is my house!
Be quiet, Ole! Be quiet, Allon! Listen to what I say!
I'm tired of your shit, so I need to find another place to stay!
I need to pack your things and find some other, I can decide over!
I do not want to anymore! I do not want to anymore! I do not want to anymore!
I feel bad ... Now he faints.
No! No, no, no!
Take just some water, Mona. Erik, Erik, Erik?
So ...
Here is some water. We find out, Eric.
I do not want this anymore. Then we damn right ...
Sit right down, friends.
We do. I do not want this anymore.
Hey.
Hi.
Are you going to the party? Oh.
I will just nine years. Well, it was not so much.
Tell me, do you know where the others are?
Should we fuck?
What do you say? What do you say?
Not, I think right, we should wait a bit.
Hello Freja. I'm here a little early, but your father come with moving loaded.
Now. Is your mother home?
Yes, she's up on top.
Will you follow me up there? I would like to say a proper hello.
Well, she's not here. I believe she is gone.
I just go back down. Do you? Reach.
Hello. Hello.
Sorry, I would have taken properly against you.
Thanks. Freja has just followed me up here.
Reach. I'm going out and shopping. Yes.
It is me who is cooking tonight. Do you want to?
And buy into? Yes, I would like this.
Yes. Well.
Not? Ja.
Then we descend to our butcher.
It comes to charm him, you get a good price.
He is to fold for beautiful ladies.
Such. Thank you. Should I wear it? I get the gold.
We know Ole completely from the old days. He was the first person I called.
Reach. That has Erik not told. No.
I've always had a secret dream to live with Ole.
I can understand that.
You have brown eyes. Yes.
You have blue.
Have I even suggested that you should move in.
 Ja, det var han glad for.
 Ja.
I imagine after all that we can be here all three.
I think after all that Erik should just be allowed to ...
To pursue his feelings, right? I am very grateful.
So, if you do not think it will be uncomfortable.
Do tell. I think it will be exciting.
I've also been looking forward to meeting you. I've seen you on screen.
And and ...
You have such a good insight when reading up.
Do you think so? That was sweet said. I've been there for many years.
Yes, I remember you from when I was quite small.
Now ...
It is also good to Anna. It is Anna who made it.
It tastes really good. Give your son some more gravy.
I am opposed to unlock the door. I think that too.
Do you have a schedule? We have a meal plan, right?
If you have to, then man. Where is the silly.
It is rare, it is so beautiful here.
When someone something about locks? Lock?
It may be, Steffen know. There is no one who knows anything?
We need to turn up in Miss Jensen.
Now be careful. When you're in heat?
(Sexlyde)
Hello. I'm going home to Sille and eat.
Want something to eat? The hair is set up to shenanigans.
I'm going home to Sille and eat. I'm just going home to Sille.
You will be completely red. Is he just as red in the face?
Now I think I am a little strict. You must not listen to them.
What time are you home? I am leaving now.
That is so sweet.
Come here.
Although the Vietnam War is over rising tensions.
Attempting to avoid war between Vietnam and Cambodia are stranded.
A new war is fact.
Try to hear. We are up to 17.48 now.
If you must have a live guest in, then I think max. 2.40.
It's almost breakfast. We have a deadline.
The main story, we provide a proper peel. Cambodia.
If Cambodia is ... That's fine.
How many dead children should be in the feature?
Do not show the dead children. Death toll of millions.
Millions? Yes, when this is over.
Then we take the worst pictures from, and then we say three minutes.
Last we had something down there, there was seer storm.
It was as though.
I would be happy 3:30, then we are up at 27.42.
(Groans)
(Is cry)
Is there something wrong? I do not know exactly what is happening.
You must have some wine. I have something stronger in my bag.
This so.
We have a good time. Yes, it is fine.
I take it yourself. Yes.
We have plenty of time.
It will be fine. Yes.
There was once a king ... who made a terrible experiment.
Where he took 60 newborns and gave them food and so on ??
but half of them were not to be touched by any man.
So no physical contact in any way ever.
But otherwise they were just as much sleep and food and vitamins as the others.
What happened? Yes?
They died.
Should not he have a hug? We must be touched!
Up to father.
We are ready now.
Ti, ni, ??
eight, seven ...
... Sex ...
Five ... ...
... fire ...
... Three ...
... to ...
I can not.
Get straight Anna out. We Preben takes his place. You'll fix Preben.
Come on.
Come on with the sign.
I'm going to DR.
You've got the message? It is I, like have.
It will not have to, Leif. You do not feel good for the moment.
Yes, but that is ... It has been on the road awhile.
Do not take me off. It is you do not.
So, the decision is taken. You can not do that.
You must not decide on my life that way.
I do not decide anything. You have no right to take me out!
Calm. Breathe deeply into your stomach, and look deep into yourself.
Drop it there. You have some problems.
I can easily do it here. I'm a professional. You know that.
You need to do something else.
You must be doing something good for yourself and make some common things.
Take to India, talk with Sai Baba. Do not talk to me like that!
I've been here for so many years and you will not speak to me like that!
(Groans)
Will not you give me Vilads' plate?
Yes sorry. Where's Erik?
At the school. He works late. Do you want chicken, Freya?
I would also like to have a little. I usually have that glass.
Thank you. Hey darling.
Hi Anna.
Hi.
There is little food, if you want.
May I ... Yes go ahead.
Where have you been?
Where have you been, baby?
What do you mean? I have been at work.
I have not seen you for several days.
You have some sand on hand. Have you hit you?
What do you care?
What? Pardon.
How are you?
I have not seen you on the screen.
Now.
I go to work, and she then goes to school ??
but apart from that, I do very much the same.
We get up in the morning, and we eat at the table ??
and we drink some wine and go to bed ...
... With Erik.
What do you say?
No, it's not that way. This has of course not been long.
Only in my small, stupid, stupid, old head.
No.
I lie in my bed alone, but apart from that, we do the same.
I should probably also soon have some children?
Nej, I'm not pregnant. Now.
I by the, that ye all the time ... Or I could hear the ...
That the whole time ... All the time what?
Located and ... Do you listen at their door, sweetheart?
No, I have come just to stand a little too close to the door.
You should not do. No, that's wrong.
You should not do.
Anna, are you sad? Oh.
I dream very much for the time. You know, like half asleep.
I dream for example, that ...
That he goes on up the stairs.
While you sleep, so you do not notice it.
Who? Erik.
Maybe then you know it well. But you accept it in your sleep.
He goes on up the stairs ??
determined with such a firm grip on the handrail.
He opens the door to my room ...
And he moves certainly in the dark.
He knows how to take me, he knows my body.
And he knows that ...
... That he will keep me hard onto such a very specific way.
And it takes just three minutes, I'll come.
Take your plate, Vilads. Go up, eat, Vilads.
More would not take. Just once in a while.
If you ask Emma about it? What?
If you ask Emma, ​​you also have to go to bed with Erik?
And.
Yes, but it was only a dream.
Well, it was just a dream.
Lovely food. Yes.
Is there more chicken in the kitchen? No, there is what is.
I could eat a piece of.
Hello. Hello.
What now? Erik, can not we just talk?
Honey, I have all really busy. It must wait.
Fine, we take it now.
Sit right down. Where have I done now by the fags?
How are you? Come on.
Anna is going crazy. You must do something.
Well I have not time for hell. I have not time.
I have a competition, I will deliver.
I do not want to be a teacher and can not take care of woman problems.
Can Ditte not talk to her? It is the idea of ​​the whole collective.
Man back each other up. It is what is the idea of ​​it.
Can Ditte not talk to her? I am the last person who can fix it.
Erik, I have been together for 15 years.
So I understand, she breaks.
She is completely out of it. She is very unhappy.
She can not imagine living without you.
It is different for women.
I listen to your problems all the time. Incessantly.
I sit in a hole in my own house and trying to work out ??
but I must relate to some women's problems all the time.
I can not! Where the hell ... I have to work.
When should I work? When should I sleep?
There is nothing, I get peace. When should I work?
Take it easy. Hell!
Now, how we have it in ... Steffen, nej.
It was as much relevant. That's fine, Anna.
It should probably go.
Okay. It works damn, as though that things have run a little off track.
And I work incredibly sad, and it's fucking sad, simply.
I think we should hold a meeting. I think we should find the book forward.
Let's just get cleaned out a little.
If you would like the house to be, ??
then we find out which one of you must remain, I think.
Otherwise we are second on. It's also nice enough.
That is certainly not? Jo.
We are voting on who should move? Yes, well, then we do it.
We take a round, right? Mona?
No I will not ...
Companies. Bum.
Steffen. Also bum.
Bum. Yes, boom.
Well all ... Then comes we are not on.
No, we do not. Because it is you who must solve it here.
We can not fucking voice one in which we love, dammit.
You have to solve it themselves. That's what we're trying to say to you.
So you must find out what you two or three.
Hi Anna. Hello Erik.
Yes ... so we reached so far.
And.
Would you like to move?
No.
What about you, Erik? Would you move?
No. No, I will not move.
I do not think there is anyone to be moving at all.
I also want to stay with my daughter here ??
as long as possible.
I would also like to.
And what do you say, Freya? What?
You are perhaps the that this means the most to.
It should Freja as not decide. For now quiet. Let her say anything.
What do you say? It is irresponsible.
Who is irresponsible? You shut me completely out.
You will not touch me. You will not touch my skin!
Let however be screaming like that. You can not figure it out here!
Who was it who would do this?
Sit down now, and stop shouting.
Fun now.
Erik, dammit. It solves nothing that you yell at each other.
It was you who wanted it here. It is your fault.
I would like to just say something.
I've never seen someone be so sad that mom is right now.
Mom, I think this place destroy you.
You are not yourself anymore. I can see that.
It's actually quite terrible.
So I think you need to move. As quickly as you can.
Well, I think you can.
Mom, I think well, you can handle it.
Freja, honey. She just went.
Freja ...
Freja?
We can just do it quietly.
Do what? Burn her stuff.
Mom, come on! Mother! Please do not!
Be here now!
I burn it just! Mom, we love it!
(Anna screams)
So ...
So, Mom. So ...
It should probably go. It should probably go. So ...
It should probably go. So ...
So ...
I would like to say sorry, Freya.
You have helped me. What you need to know.
Travelling so?
Yes, but only for a few weeks. I gotta just find something to stay in.
I love you.
Come on.
Ole! What are you doing?
Have you seen?
It is a dishwasher. Allon bought it.
Where did you get the money to go?
What is it? A dishwasher.
What, then, Ole? I'm not interested in it.
Why do the machines come and take over?
Ej, Allon.
You are cold as an icicle and churlish.
Then you can wash your shit up yourself.
Hey darling. Hello Freja.
Sorry, we're late. You may damn well say.
Peter. Sid ned.
What the hell, you've got lady on, Freya?
She is damn skidesød, man.
Now stop it, then, Ole.
Pardon. I am joking.
I think so ... What do you think?
It is a lovely dish. Allon, sorry. I love you.
Stop it. Come here, sorry.
I love you!
If you read the newspaper, you will experience exactly ??
how love disappears in the world ??
and a new and exciting time begins.
Perhaps that is precisely why Vilads have found a better place to be.
Vilads could only live in the time of love.
Peter is waiting for me. I am leaving now.
Now.
So feel good, darling. Hi there.
See you. Hello.
See you later? No, I'm leaving now.
Vi her. Ja. Hej.
Hello Emma. It was really beautiful, I think.
(Erik crying)
Sorry Sorry.
That's fine, Erik.
Hi.
Try to take them here.
What is it?
Peter.
I love you.
Her.
Then the damn thing to have legs to walk on the gallop pretzel.
Why do not we just send a small, friendly thought up to Vilads?
Bowl.
Danish texts: Louise Munk Commonly Scandinavian Text Service 2015