Dave! Callie! Hey!
What's going on in there?! You guys okay?
Dave, Callie, what's happening?!
Quit messing around!
Come on, guys, what's going on...?
Please... No more.
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
Just breathe deeply, baby.
Your grandma's gonna be here real soon.
- She's gonna take you to...
- Hey, Sullivan.
Sergeant wants you back at your post.
Emily and I are having a visit.
You don't want to make the sergeant wait.
I'll take that chance.
Easy, Sullivan, I'm just trying
to save you a reprimand.
Excuse me, baby.
That girl just lost her parents.
Yeah, and social services is on its way.
I'm done listening to you.
I said... Enough!
Shots fired! What was that?
It's okay, he didn't do anything.
It's okay. I'm sorry.
It's okay. Come on, let's go.
Hey, hey. Get up, get up.
You got to get up right now.
Get up! Wake up.
- You got to go right now.
- Good morning, sunshine.
Oh, wait a minute, w... What is it?
It's, uh... It's Nora.
Right.
Uh, yeah, it's time to go. Here's your tie.
- Get up.
- Or we could just stay in.
I cook a wicked breakfast.
Bacon, eggs, sausage, beans, tomatoes.
Perfect islands in a sea of grease.
No, um, my boyfriend just called,
he's gonna be here any minute...
You didn't tell me last night
you had a boyfriend.
Yeah, I did, get up,
come on, get your stuff.
I'll set the table for three, then.
Hey, Nora, you up?
Oh, he said "Nora," I was right.
- Get your ass out of bed!
- Yeah. Go.
Oh, hi, honey.
I was just in the bathroom.
Okay, Zed's in our class.
You're my problem today.
So, where do you want to start?
Back in bed.
Just being honest.
Chas, I know what I need to do,
and I'll get it sorted, all right?
As soon as you go home.
I'm not going anywhere.
Fine.
Let's see.
Birmingham... That's like
what, two hours away?
Well...
We'll be there by lunch.
Looks like we're late to the party.
Local police blotter reported
a double homicide last night.
Man and his wife.
Battered beyond recognition.
Bite marks?
Puncture wounds?
Flesh torn asunder?
No details in the report.
They had a young daughter.
Untouched in the attack.
We'll start by figuring out
why she was spared.
I'm breaking in, you stand watch.
If I need you...
I shall give you a little whistle
that suddenly chokes into silence.
Oh, sh...!
You know, I've never punched an angel,
but you are begging for it, mate.
I could announce my arrival with trumpets.
Used to have a tight horn
section back in the day.
Mm, I'm sure you did.
Smells of burning,
but there's no sign of fire.
Some serious telekinetic energy
was spent here last night.
What is it you want?
Battle plans, John.
Time to draw them up.
Battle plans, eh?
You know bugger-all
about what we're up against.
I know there's a darkness rising, John.
It's ancient beyond measure.
You're going to stem the tide
of its attacks.
And, uh, what makes me so special?
Nothing that I'm aware of.
St. Peter.
Ignatius of antioch. Joan of Arc.
Oh, John, they were special.
Mmm. You're more of a...
Desperation move.
Story of my life, mate.
Well, as long as you're here,
might as well make yourself useful.
Why was that girl spared from the attack?
I can't tell you that.
Well, you're a divine messenger
with an omnipotent boss.
Don't be stingy.
When humanity was granted free will,
angels lost the power
to directly influence events on earth.
That's just the kind of double-talk
I expect from your type.
The broken coffee mug
pieces are on the floor,
but the coffee stains are on the counter.
Doesn't add up. Would
it make you feel better
if I told you you were getting warm?
I need to see what happened here.
The rules have changed, John.
The things you're used
to dealing with have more power.
They move faster. Hunger deeper.
Your old ways might not work.
Be open.
Step aside, sunshine.
Ximbatik kaajal
ak bin-ka-aak-abtal.
Mayan.
Impressive.
She was possessed by the spirit of a child.
The daughter survived the attacks
because she was the attacker.
That entity inside her,
it was controlling her.
Now that it's loose,
it'll be looking
for a new child to possess.
What's going on?
There's someone in my room.
Again?
Come here, sweetie.
You're just fine.
There's no one here.
Or here.
Oh...
I know.
He's in the closet, right?
It's just a closet, Henry.
Hey.
This happens at Halloween.
Your imagination runs wild.
Remember last year you didn't
want to trick-or-treat
'cause you were afraid of the monsters?
Yeah.
Don't worry. I handled that.
Darrell.
There's a whole costume
that comes with this.
You wear that and the kids will
be scared of you... I promise.
You honestly think this is helpful?
Honestly?
Henry's a strong kid if we just let him be.
Hey...
You are strong, you know that, buddy.
But you need to believe it.
You're just fine, sweetie pie.
Now try and go back to sleep, honey.
Have sweet dreams.
No...
Is everything all right?
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I screamed.
You can go back to bed now.
Really?
I'm feeling much better.
You'll see.
You know, I could lose my paralegal
license meeting you here like this,
but I owe you, honey.
I sweet-talked this
from a guy in child services.
Cute, but clingy.
Here's your girl.
Emily Cooper.
Any chance I can get close to her?
She's untouchable.
Not only is she under
psychological care,
but she's in protective custody.
Why?
The coppers can't possibly have a suspect.
No, but there's been
a series of killings like this
across the southeast.
Dead parents, beaten to a pulp?
They all had one child.
The children all survived the attacks.
Cases were never connected,
because of the time between the killings.
First one on record, 35 years ago.
One after that,
16 years later, then 18 years.
Now three
in the last month.
That's when the cops smartened up.
These children,
have they got anything in common?
What, you mean, like horns
growing out of their heads?
No, but they did start
throwing fits days before the killings.
Just angry outbursts at home, at school.
I suspect that's because they had
a malevolent spirit inside them.
You mean like my Roger?
No, luv.
Your dearly departed husband wasn't
inhabiting bodies, he was just
pissing and moaning about being dead.
Well, it is a lot quieter around my house
since you helped him cross over.
I need to find out who this
spirit was when it was alive.
Sometimes they can forget who they are,
and just naming them
releases them from our world.
I wonder if any of these survivors
remembers the name of the soul
that possessed them.
Well, you won't get near the
kids from the recent cases, but
one of the early survivors lives nearby.
Marcello Panneti.
He'd be in his 40s now, I suppose.
Where can I find him?
Local mental hospital.
Perfect.
I'll feel right at home.
Marcello introduced his
daddy's head to an axe.
Mommy's head went into the thresher.
At least they think it was her head.
So I'm not surprised
nobody comes to visit him.
Especially not his...
Family.
Ten years old, dismantled
two fully grown adults.
Bit unlikely, don't you think?
Oh, no. Kids are sponges.
They soak up whatever you give 'em.
And Marcello, well,
his handiwork with an axe
is something of a...
Family tradition. Rumor is there's a bloody
tree stump outside the
farmhouse where he grew up.
Whenever Marcello misbehaved,
his punishment was...
Severe.
Ah.
It's beautiful this time a year, innit?
Not one for a wee natter.
Then you're my kind of bloke.
But I'm trying to prevent
someone from going through
the same experience that you did as a kid.
Bloody hell.
Hello?
Henry?
Who's there?
Aah, aah! Oh.
Did you do this, Henry?
No.
I just walked in.
I heard noises out here.
Yeah, same here.
I think somebody was in the house.
Gonna go back to my room now.
Hey, dad?
What?
Be careful.
Marcello was useless, the poor bastard.
Fully catatonic.
You know, most people
who survive a possession...
They're downright chatty about the ordeal.
Tough break for him.
Not entirely.
His parents got what they deserved.
But we have to stop this evil entity, mate.
It's a bloody serial killer
through the ages. Well, if it's
been around for that long, maybe we can
track down another living survivor.
No time to mess with that.
With the rising darkness,
we got to stop this thing before
it has a mind to kill again.
Take a look at this.
What kind of map is that?
These are ley lines.
Mystical trackways
flowing with electromagnetic energy.
These x's mark the home
address of every victim
whose parents were slaughtered.
They all fall
- on the same line.
- Yeah.
Ley lines are a psychic railroad,
easy for a child's soul to travel.
To find the next victim, we just...
Follow the line.
Follow...
The line.
We know which ley lines
the spirits are following.
Now we just need something
to detect the malignant thing.
What's this do?
Oh, put that down, that can't help us.
That's not what I asked.
I asked you what it does.
But you're too self-involved
to hear me, like always.
Like Renee. She's gone.
I'm afraid I wasn't enough
to keep her from leaving.
Can't bring myself
to tell you about it, though.
Not that you'd hear me...
This is the sword of night.
It compels the holder to speak the truth.
Oh.
Is there anything you...
Want to talk about, or...
- No, no.
- Well, you got to hand it to Jasper.
This old mill's a treasure trove, eh?
Yes!
There she is.
What is it?
Oh, there's no time
for explanations. You'll see.
Right... Now all I need
is some frankincense.
Let these cool.
They'll make a good snack while we work.
What are they?
Your favorite... Pumpkin seeds.
Oh, markers.
I'll be right back.
Got 'em.
Henry, what did you do?
Carved the pumpkins.
You know you're not allowed
to pick up knives.
- Give me that.
- I'm not done carving.
Henry, hand me the knife.
Now.
I'll put this inside.
How long do we got to do this for?
We walk until the frankincense directs us.
According to Jasper's maps, the
ley line continues on this road
for a quarter mile and then we veer right.
Whoa, stop.
Look.
Wrong way, mate.
Frankincense flees the
presence of malevolent energy.
What we want... is behind you.
So, now what? We knock on the door?
No, that never works.
Why not?
Oh, hello, we tracked an
evil spirit to your house.
It might be inside your kid.
Do you mind if take a look?
Yeah, that won't work. No.
Our best bet is
to hunker down for the night.
We wait, watch and listen for an attack.
I didn't do nothing.
Hey, hey, teach?
You got a couple of kids
getting shirty over there.
- What's in that trench coat?
- I am.
Now, go and stop that row, will
you, before someone gets hurt.
- You got a kid at this school?
- No I don't got a kid at this school.
Will you just turn around?
You're just a little baby. Want your mommy?
You're just a little punk. Get up.
Bollocks!
That boy
came into my hospital with
a fractured skull. What did you do to him?
Were you defending yourself, buddy?
Don't "buddy" him.
There is never any reason
for anything like this to happen, ever.
Hello. My name's John Constantine.
I'm the new counselor at the school.
I've come to check on your son.
We really do hate sending
him home like this.
Come on in. I'm Darrell.
This is my wife, Clair.
We were just trying to figure out
why he acted out today.
It's just not him.
You are right about that, ma'am.
What are you doing?
What the hell is that?
It's a mandrake root. Malevolent
spirits can't stand 'em.
I had to show you what you're up against.
I'm an exorcist. Your son's possessed.
- We don't have much time.
- Get out!
I told Chas this wouldn't work.
Look, you said so yourself...
That's not your Henry... And you're right.
It's an indwelling spirit,
been murdering for decades.
- And you're next in line.
- Get out!
Look, you know your son best.
Just keep and eye on him, and, uh, call me
if something happens.
You know what? I've got a better plan.
You didn't manage
to sneak a bottle past
our friends out there, did you?
I should be ashamed of myself.
Time was, you'd be asking me for a favor
and now look at me.
No bail money, no booze...
It only took me, like,
six months in the loony bin
to turn me into a bloody amateur.
I'm cursed when it comes to kids.
Hmm.
Probably on the account
that I was such a wretched
little bastard myself.
Wow.
You really should get therapy for that.
Piss off.
You made it perfectly clear
you're not allowed to help me.
I said the exact opposite.
What, did shock therapy
destroy your hearing?
All right, then.
Go and warn mummy and daddy
about their little demon seed,
send it back to hell,
oh, and pick us up a gin and tonic, eh?
Guidance, John.
I can offer you guidance.
Oh, thank you very much.
I've made it through my life
without any help
from you.
You sure about that?
How do you know I wasn't by your side
when your father burned
you with his cigarette?
Or stayed you from suicide
when your sister left you alone with him?
That's enough of that, you.
You didn't have it easy, John.
If you want to save a child,
just remember what it was like to be one.
Well, aren't you a regular
little clever clocks?
You know what I think
of that dog's breakfast?
Oh, bloody hell. I hate
it when he does that.
Oh.
Nice.
Lovely.
Your temper could've
gotten us killed, Darrell.
You are lucky he didn't have a gun.
Wouldn't have mattered. I knocked him flat.
We have a son now; He's watching you.
Stop fighting.
I'm glad that he's watching!
Because he needs a male role model.
Be a mom, fine, coddle him.
But he's gotta learn
how to handle himself in life.
Oh, like he handled himself
on the playground?
- It's an elementary school...
- Stop fighting!
Henry?
What happened
in here?
What's that burning smell?
You gonna hurt me?
No. No, of course not.
Henry...
Violence?
This isn't the way to
express your emotions.
How did you even do this?
You have to clean this mess up...
Rise and shine.
You got a visitor.
Johnny, I told you not to bother me
unless you bring me breakfast.
What did you mean when
you said my son's possessed?
Every one of these parents
had a little nipper
that was exhibiting the exact
same behavior as Henry.
What you said was true.
Henry...
Something's not right.
Not all souls go gently into the night.
A violent death can leave behind
a bewildered or traumatized soul.
Child spirits are the worst.
They act out, like all brats...
Only their tantrums end in blood.
Okay.
I need to do something.
What can we do?
If we knew who the spirit was
when it was alive,
we could find a way
to release it peacefully,
but this little bugger
could be hundreds of years old.
I could try and cast it out...
But forceful exorcisms
with young children...
What?
Kids present challenges.
Even if we dispelled the spirit from Henry,
it would just find another host.
Is there another option?
I could bind it to one spot,
but that presents a danger for us.
And you'd have to be part of the team.
I have a friend who can help us out, but...
Well, you need at least three
people to hold a séance.
I will do whatever it takes
to get my son back.
You did say you were a doctor, right?
Henry.
You've been looking a little
under the weather lately,
so I brought some vitamins home from work.
- What is it?
- Just some vitamins.
B-12.
I give them to you all the time.
You do?
Yeah. Here.
Just give me your arm.
Stop...
Stop!
Henry's asleep on the couch.
I'll be back soon.
Yeah. See you, hon.
This was a longer drive than I expected.
We only have a couple more hours
before that sedative wears off.
Well, let's get to work then.
Clair, meet Chas.
Hello. Thanks for helping my son.
Chas, take a look around back.
Make sure we're alone.
This one could get messy.
- What is this place?
- This is the home
of the first possession victim
we could find on record.
A young boy killed his mother
and father here 35 years ago.
The property never sold again.
Who was he?
Marcello Panneti.
Nice bloke.
Doesn't say much.
Now, I can't release the soul
from our world without its name,
but I can bind it to one place so it can't
go on killing.
You want to trap it in this house.
That thing inside your son
has a powerful connection to this land.
It's just the spot for a summoning.
It knows we're here.
The spirit?
The house.
Anyplace where tragedy occurred festers
with energy.
You learn to sense it after a while.
You okay?
All clear.
The murders happened in this room.
This is where we'll hold the séance.
Shall we then?
Now, we must hold hands.
And not break contact.
Not until I recite the binding spell.
Is that clear?
You'll do fine.
Oh, clever spirit of the dead,
invader of flesh, traveler through time,
we present you offerings
from life into death
and invite you into our circle.
Move among us.
Oh, cursed spirit of the dead,
spiller of blood, destroyer of families,
we command you into our circle.
Move among us
now!
Don't break the circle!
It's coming.
A three-legged deer? What does that mean?
It means we're wasting our bloody time.
What went wrong?
Maybe Marcello was never possessed.
He killed his parents on his own.
The spirit would have no
connection to this location.
No! This house is on the ley line,
just like all the other places of attack.
Oh, come on, John. What are you missing?
Henry is going to wake up
any second. I'm afraid
he's gonna go after my husband.
We need to get this thing
- out of him.
- You do not want an exorcism, Clair.
Trust me.
I do.
Trust you.
Maybe I don't trust myself.
John...
I need you to save my son.
Oh, hey, buddy.
Costume looks great.
What did I tell you, little man?
Darrell? Where have you been?
- I've been calling.
- Listen. I need to explain.
- What's he doing out of jail?
- Your wife dropped the charges.
I'm here to exorcise
an evil spirit from your boy.
And you're blaming me
for filling his head with ideas?
I know how it sounds crazy,
but you need to listen to him.
No, I'm not listening to you anymore!
You're out of control!
Stop fighting!
- Darrell!
- Conflict.
That's the trigger.
Henry!
Hold it, kid!
Aah! I'll be okay!
He went down the street!
I'll be back for you!
Hey! You can't go in there!
Hey, kids!
Any of you see a short zombie?
Yeah, he's in there.
Hey, man! You need a ticket!
Sorry, mate, we're closed.
I wouldn't try anything if I was you, mate.
This mirror's gonna
throw it back in your face.
Be a good lad now.
Come home with me, yeah?
An axe.
Of course.
I know what you are, boy.
Even if you've forgotten.
Your name is Marcello.
I know why you're doing this.
Your parents weren't
good people, were they?
Your dad...
He chopped off your fingers
on a bloody tree stump!
And what... You're gonna piss
and moan about it forever?
You're not the only one who
had it rough growing up, boy.
This world's dark and full of pain.
For everyone!
Only most people don't leave
a trail of dead bodies
and shattered lives in retribution!
Oh, what? You want me
to feel sorry for you?
What about that poor girl
whose parents you murdered,
to seek your retribution, eh?
You'll get no such pity from me, boy!
Marcello Panneti!
As the one who named you,
I bind you to your rightful place!
Where am I?
Come on...
Let's get you home, Henry.
I thought Henry was possessed
by the soul of a dead person.
But it was the soul of a living one.
Marcello was the oldest survivor on record
because he was the first killer.
But the act was so traumatic
that his soul fled his body
and went right on killing.
A soul can't cross over
while its body is still alive.
So I sent Marcello's
to the only place I could...
At least he's locked in
a high security facility,
where qualified doctors
can heal his inner child.
Who knows?
Maybe one day he'll even find peace.
And what of my rotten inner child?
If humanity's what can save us,
then overcoming the damage
and weakness in my nature,
it may be the part of this
battle that I dread most.
I don't have the answers.
I only know that a darkness is rising.
And unless I can stop it,
the world will change forever.