♪ Allen Gregory 1x07 ♪
Van Moon Rising
Original Air Date on December 18, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪ Ya, ya...
♪ Ya, ya
♪ Allen
♪ Gregory
♪ Allen, Allen.
Oh, little Judy.
You had your whole life
ahead of you.
Ahead of... us.
You'll never have her now.
Not like I did.
And I had her all day,
every day.
You son of a bitch!
Don't crush me,
Allen Gregory!
Don't do it, best friend,
he's not worth it.
Hell, I'd love nothing more than
to watch you smoke this clown,
but that's not gonna
bring your lady back.
You're right, it's not!
She's dead,
and she was only 86!
Now, get out of here
before he changes
his damn mind, old man.
Okay.
Sid's right, you know.
I never made a play,
and now...
clock's run out.
I thought I lost you, babe.
Julie... if I were your clothes,
what size would I be?
Oh, no, not another
fund-raiser.
That's right, it's not
just another fund-raiser.
This one's for Africa,
which is where you're...
not from.
It might be fun, Jules.
Get all dressed up,
eat a fancy dinner.
Have Richard nudge
me and whisper,
"Be more ethnic" every
time I meet someone.
Well, if you took
the note the first time,
I'd only have
to give it once.
I don't even know what it means.
I'd explain it to you,
Jules, but guess what?
I don't have the time.
Because the clock...
it doesn't stop for any of us.
One day you wake up and wonder,
"What's my purpose?
"To be flaunted around
"like a piece
of Asian street meat
or some useless boy toy?"
Well, it's too late
for you two, yes,
but it's not for me.
It's time, bitch.
I wonder which one of you
he was calling "bitch."
I, uh, heard the water
shut off,
so I thought you might
like your coffee
while you get yourself
made up.
Although why you bother
with makeup is a mystery to me.
Very sweet, Sidney.
I hope you think
the same about this.
Happy Anniversary.
Oh, Sid.
What happened to us
not making a fuss?
I know, I know, I just
couldn't help myself.
Oh, a new pill case.
Nope, your old one.
I was able to repair the plastic
hinge on the Thursday box
with a little help
from Mr. Glue Gun.
Go ahead, test it.
I see.
It's very... nice.
You know, since it is
our anniversary,
and you're in
that very sexy towel...
Gotta get to work.
Yeah, me as well,
me as well.
No, no, no, no, no.
This is all wrong.
Jeremy, why did you
bring me here?
We should've gone to one
of those secondhand shops.
Don't you want to find something
nice for Julie to wear?
It's a charity benefit,
you bonehead.
You really think Julie should saunter
in wearing Oscar de la Renta
in front of all those
underprivileged people?
- Well, no, but...
- Oh, no.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Don't look.
Jeremy, what did I say?!
What did I say?!
- Who is that?
- It's Perry Van Moon.
The guy from college
who makes you hate yourself?
No, the other Perry Van Moon who
makes me hate myself, Jeremy.
Ooh, I despise him.
- De Longpre?
- Oh, Perry!
Dickles De Longpre.
Well, I don't actually go
by Dickles anymore.
Never did...
Classic Dickles.
Who's your buddy?
Oh, this? This is
my husband, Jeremy.
Ooh, you got a tight grip
there, Jeremy. I like it.
Oh, thanks.
So, you still doing nothing
with the ol' life there,
or...?
Uh, no, actually, really
into my charity work.
Africa.
Don't know if you've
heard, but...
lot goin' down
over there.
Oh, yes, well aware.
I'm actually on
the board, so, uh...
On the board
of Africa?
I don't think there's a board
of Africa, huh, Jeremy?
Well, I actually meant
the board of the charity.
You were with me,
right, man?
I was totally...
on board.
Ah, he was on board.
That was good, Jeremy.
So I guess I'll see
you guys there.
Oh, I know--
we should sit together.
I'll set it up since
I run the whole thing.
Yeah, great.
Great idea.
But FYI-- it's gonna
be three of us.
We went ahead and adopted
a starving Cambodian child.
Just trying to make a dent,
one life at a time, you know?
Oh, do I ever?
Babatunde.
Hello, Dad.
You adopted an
African boy?
Well, I don't think
of it that way.
I mean, he's just
my African son.
Babatunde.
You ready for
the cages, pal?
Ooh, you keep him
in a cage.
No. The batting cages.
Kid loves sports.
- You got it, didn't you, Jeremy?
- Yeah, Per.
It was a meatball
right down the middle.
Meatball right down
the middle.
That was good.
I love this Jeremy.
Who was that, Daddy?
Oh, that's absolutely nobody.
65 years of marriage...
Judy, I need you to listen,
and I need you to listen good.
Get the hell out of here.
I won't get the hell
out of here.
I'm done getting
the hell out of here.
I mean, what are
we doing, Jude?
What are we waiting for?
Let's pull the trigger
on this thing.
Allen Gregory,
not today.
Well, then when?
Tonight? Tomorrow?
'Cause the following night
is no good for me.
I can maybe squeeze something
in late afternoon-style, but...
Okay. I don't have
time for this.
I don't either,
and that's the whole point.
You were in my dreams
last night, babe.
Oh, my God.
It's okay,
it wasn't sexual.
I mean, there's always
a sexual undertone, but...
I'm gonna count to three,
and when I turn around
you better be gone.
One...
Wait, so I have till three?
...two...
Well, stop for one second,
'cause I'm just trying
to clarify whether...
...three!
I had a new thought...
Hey, Allen Gregory.
Just leave it alone, Pat.
It doesn't
concern you, okay?
Hey there, sluts.
What's with the shades?
Yeah.
What, do your eyes hurt
from looking up Patrick's butt?
I feel weird having
to say this, Ian,
but it's dark inside
people's butts.
You wouldn't need
sunglasses.
It's literally called
"Where the sun don't shine."
Yeah, you guys are
right. Stupid Ian.
So back to the glasses.
They're lame.
I want 'em.
Wait, just...
It was covering a blemish.
Allen Gregory, what's
that on your face?
It's nothing.
I-I walked into a door...
at the bottom of the stairs
I fell down.
- Oh, gotcha.
- What do you want to hear, Patrick?!
You want to hear that the door I
walked into was named Gottlieb?
Or that the stairs I fell down
had the same name as that door?
- Gottlieb?
- You weren't there.
She's a good woman, damn it.
She loves me,
but I egged her on.
I practically dared her
to do it.
This was all my fault.
Don't take it out on her,
Patrick.
Well, if it's your fault,
maybe you should apologize.
You said a mouthful
there, boy-o.
So much wisdom locked up
in that big, red tomato can
you call a head, huh?
Thanks.
Oh, and Patrick--
pop into that middle stall,
give that toilet a big
old flush for me.
Of course Perry Van Moon adopts
a perfectly-themed African boy
for the fund-raiser.
He knew I was
gonna be there,
so he ran down to that
adoption agency and he said,
"Give me an African one
that I can pretend to know
in front of Richard."
Or he didn't consider
you at all,
and adopted the kid
for the right reasons?
Okay, new idea.
We take Julie back,
tell them it's not working,
we can't crack her,
we want to swap her out
for something else.
Richard...
Hang with me.
We skip this benefit
because Van Moon's
got us on the ropes,
find out the theme
of the next one,
and get a kid that fits that.
- Thoughts.
- Uh, I think maybe there's an easier,
and possibly more sensible
way to go about this.
Oh, really?
Jeremy's got the fix?
Can't wait for Big Bad
Jeremy to storm into town
with his
fancy idea machine.
What is it?
Well, you could
talk to Julie.
Actually get to know
your daughter.
Jeremy, you sneaky bitch.
Obviously this is awkward.
Things were said,
things went down.
Certain people
were struck in the face.
Look, about that...
No, no. Let me finish.
What happened
shouldn't have happened,
and an apology
is definitely in order.
So, Judith...
I'm sorry!
Don't interrupt me,
this is hard eno...
You're sorry.
Yes. And I'd appreciate it
if you kept this between us.
I'd lose my job
if it got out.
You'd lose your job
because you hit
a defenseless child,
who is in no way responsible
for what happened.
What do you want?
- Excuse me?
- In exchange for keeping your mouth shut.
Judy, that hurts me.
You think I would use this unfortunate
incident as leverage?
Dinner.
- What?
- Say 7:00?
Say it.
Dinner at 7:00.
I'll make a rez.
It'll be under,
"Let's do this."
Uh!
Okay, give me an easy one.
Okay, here we go.
What is Julie's middle name?
Coming out of the gate
with a stumper.
Cory.
You think my
middle name is Cory?
Rory?
Oh, give me a hint.
First letter.
"L." And it's not Lori.
Well, it's not Lori,
it's not Rory.
At this point,
I'm starting to think
it doesn't rhyme
with Cory at all.
Um, okay.
Hey, how about a simple
"yes or no," huh?
Does Julie like movies?
Does Julie... like movies?
I feel like I know this one.
We've been to the
movies together.
Yeah, that
doesn't help me.
Well, it could.
Think back, try to remember.
Okay. I know we went to see
Going the Distance.
That's right.
Justin Long starred as
Garrett, a young hipster
who recently got out of
a long-term relationship,
he's still licking his wounds,
doesn't want anything serious.
Okay?
Sure enough, he meets Erin,
a journalism grad
who's only in town
for the summer.
You know more about
Going the Distance than me.
I know more about
it than anybody.
That movie's like
a daughter to me.
Come on, Gottlieb.
He's just a kid.
You fought in Korea
for God's sake.
What?!
Delivery for Judith Gottlieb.
From Allen Gregory
De Longpre.
Oh, my God. Okay.
"Wear this and nothing else."
Oh, for Pete's sake.
Poops?
Oh, Sid.
This isn't really
a good time.
Okay, gotcha.
Just wanted to float an idea
by you for tonight--
couple of Hungry-Mans right
into a little Bones-a-thon.
The show, not...
Can't.
I-I'm working late tonight.
All right, not a problem.
That's what a DVR is for.
That's why we pay $4.99
a month to lease it.
Smart, Sidney.
Oh.
You guys in
for my BBQ later?
It's gonna be
pretty tight.
I can't.
I have to go to a fund-raiser
with my dad.
Sounds more like
a "fun" raiser.
See what I did there?
You dropped the "D."
Yeah, dropped the "D."
She's lovin' it, Jules.
What's the cause?
Anything we can get behind?
It's for Africa.
Oh, is everything okay?
Uh, no, Beth,
it's so not okay.
Africa's got problems.
I know it's hard to hear,
but it's the cold, hard truth.
Oh, there you are.
So many kids, it's like
a salmon farm in this place.
Dad, what are you doing here?
We need a last minute
"get to know Julie" cram sesh.
Girls?
Ew.
Okay. Let's get
to the nuts of this.
- For you to memorize.
- What is this?
Well, since it's impossible to
remember all the stuff you like,
I figured that you
should just like
all the stuff
that I can remember.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, makes sense to me.
This is Drew Barrymore's
character description
from Going the Distance.
Ooh, Erin.
Such a great role.
You could really sink your
teeth into that, Jules.
But it's not me.
And I'm not gonna memorize
this because I'm not going!
Mmm. You're from Africa,
huh, bud?
Well, no, my family's
from India, but...
Ugh, you're the worst.
Wow. Look at you.
I've never seen so much beauty
squeezed into so little
Vera Wang.
Let's just eat our food
and get this over with.
Oh, there's three
kinds of bread.
Mama loves her carbs.
So I was thinking we'd do
a round of hors d'oeuvres,
maybe a cheese plate,
some truffled quail eggs...
I know what you're doing.
Don't drag this out.
I eat it, then I beat it.
Sure, as you wish.
Jean-Michel!
Ah, Mr. De Longpre.
Welcome back.
Would you like to hear
the specials?
No.
Just bring us our trays
and we'll get our stuff.
Oh.
- This is not that kind of place.
- Huh?
You see, this is a fine
dining establishment.
Not a-a... a food court.
I'm what you call a waiter...
Jean-Michel, you
heard the lady.
But, sir, we don't have...
Two... trays.
Very well, sir.
Ugh, I feel so naked
without Julie.
It's like no one even knows
we have her.
But that's not why
we have her. Right?
Richard?
Is this seat taken?
I'm kidding, of
course it's not.
I run this whole thing, I could
take your seat if I wanted.
Oh, Perry.
Is that an empty spot
there, Dickles?
Geez, I put you
down plus two.
I see Jeremy there--
what's up, homes?
Ah, hey, Per.
Hey, Babatunde.
And-and remind me,
the other seat was for...?
Julie, my adopted...
Julie, right, your
adopted daughter from...
- Cambodia.
- Yeah.
And that's not in Africa?
No, they're separate
continents, actually.
Okay, Jeremy.
Actually, a lot of people would
say it's worse over there.
Well, I guess
the Times wouldn't.
They did a piece ranking
the world's most
impoverished regions...
Oh, and you have it...
Let's see here...
number one, Africa-- knew that--
two, three, four...
Beep... beep... beep... beep.
Boop! 17, Cambodia.
There it is.
So, where is Julie?
Did we get to
the bottom of that?
She's... with her boyfriend.
He's moving away,
which she knew,
but now there are
real feelings involved,
so they're trying to figure out
if the relationship
has legs to...
Go the distance?
That's our favorite movie, Papa!
We watch it every night!
Ah, don't beat
yourself up.
No way you could've known.
Does somebody want to help
Dickles find his face?
Probably somewhere on the floor.
Oh thanks, Barb. That's where I
was gonna suggest people look.
So tell me about you.
I want to hear
about Judy.
What do you want to know?
Everything, really.
Were you always this beautiful,
or did you go through an
awkward phase at some point?
- Huh?
- I mean, before you were principal,
you obviously
started out modeling
and then made the transition.
How did it...?
- Modeling?
- I've never done any modeling.
Allen Gregory, stop.
Never.
Oh, awkward.
Pill time.
"Ah, Sweet Judy Blue Eyes.
Take one of these for every day
of the week that I love you."
Always...
Sidney.
Aw, Sid.
Anyway, focusing back
up for a second.
I... I shouldn't be here.
- I have to go.
- What?
Was it-was it
something I said?
Judy?
Judy!
Woman, right?
You're telling me.
No, I'm asking you--
that was a woman, right?
Dinner over already?
Oh, no, it's still going on.
Richard was really flailing.
It was painful to watch.
Wish I could've seen that.
There's still time.
Sorry, I'm busy.
Julie...
Wait, is this
Going the Distance?
Yeah.
I'm trying to figure out why
it's more interesting than me.
It's not.
Look... Richard loves you.
I don't have any
actual proof,
but I believe in his
own very limited way,
he does love you.
He loves us.
Does he?
I think he does.
I'm not sure I do.
Julie, please.
Just let me believe this,
it's all I have.
If you pull that thread,
the whole thing unravels.
Okay, okay,
he loves us.
And... we love him.
Okay, how about this...
if Perry Van Moon wins tonight,
your dad's not gonna
take that so well.
If he loses...
we lose huge.
I'm scared, Julie.
We could really use a hero
right now.
But it's up to you.
But, Garrett, it's so far!
Babe... come on,
get in the car.
This is crazy already.
- What are you gonna do, walk home?
- Yes.
Can you honestly tell me
you didn't enjoy tonight?
It was a nice time, okay?
It was a welcome change of pace,
with the big napkin
that covered the whole table,
and the man coming over,
but it's done now.
Okay. If that's really
the way you feel about it,
then I guess
Superintendent Rossmyre and I
have some catching up to do.
I knew you'd come around.
Now, come on.
Quit being silly,
ya goose.
Do what you have to do.
I'm going home to my husband.
Good night, Allen Gregory.
He has just never been
a sleeper.
There was only one way
that I could
ever put the little sucker down.
Remember what it was, buddy?
"Breathe."
"Breathe"
by Faith Hill.
I would sing it to him
every night.
Aw...
Aw, what a great dad.
♪ 'Cause I can
feel you breathe ♪
♪ It's washing over me
♪ Suddenly I'm melting
into you ♪
♪ There's nothing left
to prove ♪
♪ 'Tunde, all we need
is just to be ♪
He loved it when I would
sub in his name.
♪ Caught up in the touch
♪ The Babatunde rush
♪ And, baby,
isn't that the way ♪
♪ That love's supposed to be
Two, three.
♪ I can feel you breathe.
Oh!
Oh, that is so funny, Perry.
That is so laugh-out-loud
funny, Perry.
Because my Julie
was the same way.
Couldn't sleep a wink.
I'd have to sing
to her every night.
- And what did you sing?
- Huh?
The song, Dick, what was it?
♪ I can feel you breathe...
The same song?
Was it?
Oh, I didn't put that together.
But, yeah, now that you mention
it, it is the same song.
- So weird.
- Yeah,
you'd think you would've noticed
it when he was just singing it.
Seems like you
made up that story
just like you made up
your fake daughter.
What?!
Table of friends, I think
somebody's lying about
having an adopted child from
a poverty-stricken nation.
- You gotta be a giant jackass...
- Perry knows when people are lying.
No! I'm not lying. She's...
Right here.
Sorry I'm late, Dad.
Julie.
How did you...?
I was at the airport
saying good-bye to Garrett.
Right...
your boyfriend.
We're gonna try to make it work,
see if we can go the distance.
And when I say
"go the distance,"
I mean both emotionally
and the physical distance
that will be between us.
Yeah, I guess it has
two meanings.
Two.
Well, speaking
of distance,
Babatunde, go long!
Damn it, Babatunde!
What's the matter with you?
I'm sorry, Perry.
I don't like football.
I don't like sports at all.
What? You don't mean that.
He doesn't mean that.
Baba!
Julie, I...
I know, Dad.
I love you, too.
Oh, I wasn't gonna...
Oh.
Yeah. I was gonna say...
thanks for coming.
You're welcome.
And your middle name,
it's Leslie, isn't it?
Sure, Dad. Sure.
Uh, Ms. Gottlieb, Superintendent
Rossmyre is in your office.
Judith, you out there?
- Yeah...
- Well, get your ass out of park
and back that camper on
in here. We got business.
You and I need to have
a very serious conversation
and I'm gonna need you
to come back around
and sit in one of these chairs
in front of me.
Oh, okay.
Judith,
a faculty member hitting
a student is a major offense.
I know.
Not only is it a career-killer,
but it's a freedom-killer.
As in... jail time.
- Oh, God.
- Oh, God, is right.
We need to do something
about the fact that you...
let his teacher
do such a thing.
Wait, he said Gina hit him?
Of course.
Seems kinda weird
the way you told me.
I know. Allen Gregory
was very specific
about how he wanted me
to break it to you.
I didn't quite
understand it myself,
but he's the boss.
You wanted to see me?
Gina! You look good.
And you hit a student.
Jude, you taking off?
I thought you wanted my help.
Oh, I got it from here.
And I'm gonna need
the office for a few.
No, don't leave me alone...
Oh... what to do
about this pickle?
Oh, please don't
use "pickle" again
as a way to show me your...
== sync, corrected by elderman ==