Welcome.
I have heard many things about you.
I came to meet a child
called Hwang Seon Ah.
Is it true that she is here?
Yes, she is.
How is she doing?
She has recently been very shocked to find out that
former Headmaster Hwang Moo Song is not her real father.
However, isn't everything in the process
of returning back to it's place?
Moorim Association is hoping
you'll find your daughter
as well as the key to Cheon Ui Joo that
Hwang Moo Song hid within the school
in order for everything to
return to its original state.
Please let me meet Yeong.
Do you really think the barrier
Hwang Moo Song erected
is there solely to protect you?
Everything leading to the
Headmaster's departure
was well planned by your father.
I won't avoid it.
In my own way, I'm going to fight, head on.
Moorim School - Episode 15 -
What are you doing, Yoon Si Woo?
Do you remember me?
Oh, you at that time...
If you're going to go to Seon
Ah, please give her more time.
She is very confused right now.
Even if you are her real dad, if you meet her
before the headmaster commotion is dealt with,
you will only make things harder for her.
Yoon Si Woo! You are crossing the line.
What qualifies you to say such things?
I am speaking as her friend.
If you are her father, I believe
that you will understand.
Alright.
I will do so.
What is it?
Don't be shocked and listen.
Your real father came here to see you.
What?
If you're not ready, no one will
force you to meet him immediately.
He also seems to have
understood that you need time.
If the man I've thought was my father
and I've lived with
wasn't really my father,
but could everything he said to
me during that time been true?
I really don't know what's true anymore.
You should know best.
The fact that the love and care of the Headmaster
for you all of this time wasn't a lie.
I'm sorry, but today will be difficult.
Alright.
I guess I only thought too much of myself.
When Yeong's feelings are
ready, then I will return.
But can I ask you something?
How come you are here with
people from the Shanghai Group?
What do you mean?
Not long ago, Chairman Wang orchestrated the
kidnapping of a fellow student called Sim Soon Deok.
It was an incident stemming from
mistaking her with Seon Ah.
Although he said it was to let
Seon Ah know the truth, but
there are many aspects that
make it very doubtful.
Could you have known about that?
Right now,
I can't really understand
what you're talking about.
Chairman Wang said that Headmaster Hwang set fire
to the house and kidnapped Seon Ah that day.
However, I think differently.
Can I ask what your opinion is?
The headmaster said he
went to save his friend
but he was too late.
I think what he said was true.
Yes.
It could be.
If it's too hard by yourself, tell me.
You can share everything with me.
After all,
I'm your daughter.
I thought I could understand
everything about my dad,
but I didn't even ask Dad directly,
while looking into his
eyes, what the truth is.
Did you really kill my real father and
make me live in a lie all this time?
- Seon Ah... - I never want to
see someone like you again.
Dad... Right now, I
really don't like this
hateful image of myself
who is suspicious and resentful.
What did you discuss with that student?
I think Chairman Wang is
the destructive force.
His goal is the Cheon Ui Joo.
He doesn't even hide his intentions and
will do whatever it takes to get it.
Did you know all those things?
He was just being concerned, as a friend.
You arrived.
Did you know I was coming?
Please come inside.
You know what is the Cheon
Ui Joo key, don't you?
Eighteen years ago, were you there?
I don't know who they were, but
I only know that those people
were after the Cheon Ui Joo.
I did not come here to blame you
or make you repent for anything.
Please tell me everything about that day.
I am sorry, but I cannot
take you to Shanghai.
I told the Chairman you
were planning to leave.
He couldn't have welcomed that.
- Yes, so now it would... - Do not
tell me to calm down.
If anything like Soon
Deok's kidnapping happens,
I will not remain still.
Keep that in mind.
I will never be fooled again like that.
As I was leaving with the
child, I was attacked by them.
And unfortunately lost the
child in the process.
I kept thinking he would've died
in the burning house anyway
that it's not my fault
and I should just forget it but then
- But?
- He was found in the woods and saved.
That child is in that
school with Soon Deok.
I guess this is a case of fate
eventually returning like this.
What do you mean?
This child... is in the school?
Didn't you come here being
aware of everything?
Yoon Si Woo... haven't you
heard everything from him?
Is it really the child that
you rescued from the fire?
Are you saying it is Yoon Si Woo?
The people back then who
set the house on fire,
are looking for that child
and are watching you.
If you don't want to suffer any
consequences from that event,
please don't tell this story to anyone.
I still don't understand
everything about my dad.
Still, the day that I
will see my dad again,
I think I shouldn't let him see me as weak.
I will ask this to my real dad,
why is he with people
from the Shanghai Group?
I want to see you, Dad.
Are you okay?
Your skills are indeed
quite underdeveloped.
Who's next? Go Sang Man.
- Go Sang Man?- Y-yes?
I'll do it.
♪ I don't know if you were ready ♪
Student Yoon Si Woo. You
should use a weapon.
I'll do it with my bare hands.
You're going to fight a spear
with your bare hands? Good.
You will soon realize how
absurd your confidence is.
♪ Come to me, follow me, what are you
doing now? I'm controlling you now ♪
♪Everyone go crazy finally
on a hot stage.. ♪
♪ Let's intentionally
play out of our minds.♪
♪ I'm fast, fast. ♪
♪ Feel me, I'm the king. ♪
You said because we've been fighting with
our bare hands or with wooden swords,
no one could feel true
panic or fear, right?
You were wrong.
What was I wrong about?
What we learned here isn't terrorizing
people with knives or weapons.
You can feel that once you take one
step outside of the school anyway.
So what is the greatest fear
that you experienced in this school?
Overcoming people without having
real skills, like you do,
your never ending greed
that has mercy for none...
That scares you?
Those rotten thoughts...
Right now, how I want to make you
feel powerless exactly like you do..
Right now, I'm most scared of how I feel.
You could do something about it,
but you won't, is that what you are saying?
Please don't hurt my friends anymore.
This is my last warning.
♪Everyone go crazy finally
on a hot stage.. ♪
♪ Let's intentionally
play out of our minds. ♪
♪ I'm different, different.
I'm different, different. ♪
♪ I don't know either. I'll show you. ♪
♪ I'm fast, fast. I'm fast, fast. ♪
♪ Feel this, I'm a king. ♪
Shanghai, China
You'll be back, right?
If you're like this because of me...
Don't be like this.
From the start up to now, I
made things hard for you.
If you change...
Father. It's Chi Ang.
Please tell me everything.
I need to know all you
know and planning to do.
What did you just say?
I asked if Yoon is alive.
Right...
He's under Chairman Wang's protection now.
Could Yoon have joined forces with him?
If Yoon is on the same
side as Chariman Wang,
and if they know that you
know that Yoon is alive,
irreversible events will occur.
I need to meet Yoon and
tell him everything myself.
I'm positive Wang Hao
is scheming something.
It's dangerous for you to meet him alone.
I will gather some people for you.
That is one of the three missing key
parts that were lost 18 years ago.
The one that Hwang Seon Ah had
is probably with Hwang Moo Song.
And the other is probably
with Chae Yoon's lost son.
Is this the real reason why
you sent me to that school?
Yes.
Did you think I would help you?
I am a businessman.
I will not spend money, time or resources
on people I don't think will succeed.
I believe in you.
You believe in me?
Don't look back if you're going
after something you want.
Also, remember the promise I made.
If I receive something, I will give
something at least as valuable in return.
I didn't come here for this give-take talk.
I'm here for the truth.
Tell me something that could truly
make me feel I need to help you.
Sincerity?
You still talk like a young child.
With such a desperate mind, I came here.
It means, that's how much you are wavering.
When I was little, you told me this.
Even if I fall, I should survive
and thrive, like a lion cub.
You said that's how fathers
should raise their children.
If this time, I don't do
what you're asking me to do,
what will become of me?
And...
what about Mom?
What do you think?
This isn't just for my personal gain.
It's dangerous, but it
absolutely has to be done.
More importantly, it's for the sake of
you, your mom and our whole family!
If you don't believe me, I will bring your mother
back to China right now. That is, in your own words,
it's not a reward, but my true feelings.
I didn't cause the incident
from eighteen years ago.
I didn't know about the key to
the Cheon Ui Joo back then.
I heard about it three years ago.
Is that true?
Yeah.
It's because of Soon Deok.
I love Soon Deok.
Love, you say?
I'm won't neglect someone
I love, unlike you.
I will definitely make that person happy.
Happiness, you say?
That's overrated.
Those who want happiness can't have power.
Because they get too entangled in emotion.
You.
Didn't you want to become powerful?
Do you really know nothing
about Yoon's son?
If you know the whereabouts
of the last part of the key,
it's an opportunity to erect
the Moorim Association again.
If we join forces now, it's
not too late to have a shot.
I don't want to have a shot at anything.
For this to end without anyone
getting hurt is what I want.
Do you, by chance, know the
whereabouts of Yoon's son?
Not that long ago, Yoon Si
Woo entered the school.
It was a coincidence that the child
was brought to the school by Seon Ah.
Yoon Si Woo?
The child who used energy
control at the Tournament?
I have to hurry and go back to the school.
To do that, I need to see Yoo Di.
First, we need to meet Chae Yoon
without Chairman Wang knowing.
You need to be very careful.
I will send some people.
You're here?
Dad, what is all this?
Sit over there.
I know you want to go back to school,
my answer is... this.
Dad, I can't just go like this.
Soon Deok.
Before I hear a complete
explanation, I'm not going anywhere.
Why exactly are you going this far?
Is it really because of
Moorim that you can't see?
Actually, it involves Yoon Si Woo.
Hwang Seon Ah.
I'm sorry.
And...
thanks.
The one who is thankful is me.
Thank you, Seon Ah. For
coming out of that room.
You know you were the one
who helped me do it.
I, too, wanted to get the key.
It's true.
But I saw what they did, got a grip
and saved that kid from the fire.
I was told my life would be in
danger if I stay with that child, so
I thought he died.
No, I thought I killed him.
So that's why I had no choice but to leave that
child alone in that bed of leaves and run away.
That's impossible.
Back then, I hurt my
eyes with their attacks
and with that thought I paid
back for my sins, but...
By any chance, that child...
Yes.
Yoon Si Woo is the very child.
This child survived and is going
to the same school as you.
You're lying. Dad, Si Woo... Si Woo...
I know he is dear to your heart.
I know very well that you went
back to school because of him.
Thus I can't hide this from you anymore.
That cannot be. Do you know how
Si Woo has lived up to now?
You should have looked for him! You
should have gone to see if he was alive.
Or try to find out why all that happened!
Even if it was later, you
should have looked into it!
I was just so afraid that the ones after
Cheon Ui Joo would be hunting me.
With my damaged eyes, I could only think about the
need to get you and leave as soon as possible.
I needed to live somehow because of you.
I couldn't stop thinking about it.
In the end,
it was because of me.
The very reason that Si
Woo was like that...
was me.
Did you have a nightmare again?
The dream about the kid in the fire.
When did you come here?
You called me.
It's a dream, isn't it?♪ The countless
tears which flowed past me ♪
Even so, that I get to see you like this...
♪ were like the end of unknown darkness ♪
It's really nice.
♪ Both when I take another step ♪
♪ and let out a long sigh ♪
♪ Where does the road end? ♪
I wish there'll be no more reason to have
nightmares again. ♪ Good Bye Good Bye ♪
There won't be.♪ the
words to me Good Bye. ♪
Si Woo.♪ You please don't say goodbye ♪
I'm sorry.♪ Baby, it looks
like I was young then ♪
It's because of me.♪ Baby, it
looks like I was a coward then ♪
♪ I knew just a connection was there ♪
What are you saying? It's because of you?♪
I thought I could just reach out to you ♪
I'm sorry.♪ Baby, I'm not
afraid of anything ♪
♪ Will you stay with me? ♪
♪ Will you hold me tight? ♪
♪ Good Bye Good Bye, you
please don't say good bye ♪
♪ Good Bye Good Bye you,
Have you checked whether
Chi Ang is back in Korea?
Yes.
From now on everything depends on him.
If we have to cut down a tree we have to make
sure his roots are strong so he doesn't sway.
Will Young Master do well?
I've made sure he cannot be swayed,
so don't worry and go help him.
Yes.
I understand.
Seems like I have to go to Korea.
You take it.
Father...
I believe in you,
because you are my son.
Seon Ah!
- Shannon! - Are you better now?
It must have been so hard
for you guys all this time.
It couldn't have been harder
than what you went through.
I am so sorry about the Headmaster.
I was rash and stupid.
Since Hwang Seon Ah is
back in business too,
they should watch out. Let's
be strong till the end!
One, two, three, fighting!
Yoon Si Woo.
What is it? Did anything happen?
I think Soon Deok left this behind.
Soon Deok came here?
I seriously don't understand
what she's trying to say.
I don't know how I should put this
or how should I start.
But I think there are words
I need to say to you
so I am leaving this letter.
Eighteen years ago, a great fire
took over your house, Seon Ah.
That's how you lost your family, right?
My dad was there.
He took your brother out that house on fire
but lost him in the woods while trying
to fight off the destructive force.
That child was actually Si Woo.
I know how Si Woo has lived until now,
how lonely he was,
and all of that was because of my father.
I know that I cannot apologize
to you by any words.
Si Woo, Seon Ah, I am so sorry.
Si Woo, Seon Ah, I'm so sorry.
♪ Even in a small room, always
smelling only your perfume ♪
♪ When you the person I will love ♪
Is this...♪ are sad and
cry again it is certain♪
What does this all mean?
♪ You are my love ♪
♪ It’s okay if it’s unsaid. It’s
okay if it just must be hidden.♪
♪ There's only you and I
beneath the empty sky ♪
Is this all really true?
You too can...
Yeah
That should be right. You had a
memory of a fire too, right?
I just thought it was a coincidence, but...
why couldn't I pick that clue up sooner?
You and I survived that fire.
So the piano lullaby...
That's why...
I slept well for the first time
in my life after hearing it.
Seems like you remembered it too.
Mom's lullaby.
♪ If I take your hand when I see you♪
From the first time I saw you...♪
My day will fly by too quickly♪
who told me to come here, too...
♪ That love ♪
Yoon Si Woo...
I can't really figure things out right
now.♪ is happiness rather than pain♪
We should take it slow. Slowly. ♪
Is the love which I have learned.♪
♪ That's the love which I have learned.♪
What am I doing?
There were three parts of the key to
the Cheon Ui Joo at Chae Yoon's house.
Chances are one is with Seon Ah
and another is with the lost child.
It's a heirloom of mine. It protected
me in a fire when I was little.
So your father wants the key.
He's someone who can
do anything to achieve his goal.
Are you Headmaster Hwang Moo Song?
That's correct.
I am from the Moorim Association.
Meeting Chae Yoon as is would be
dangerous, so we came to take you there.
Thank you.
Yes.
I'll be there in a moment.
It seems like you're busy. Go. I
will go up and have some rest.
I think Chairman Wang is
the destructive force.
His goal is the Cheon Ui Joo.
He doesn't hide or hold back
from doing anything to get it.
Yes, sir.
Are you alone right now?
Yes.
That's good. I have something to tell you.
Can we meet now? But don't tell anybody.
Yes, I understand. Where do I go?
Chi Ang. Your father came.
He said we'd be able to go to China soon.
That's great! If you were to go, you should've
gone earlier. What took him so long?
Nothing bad is going on with you, right?
Here you go again. There's nothing wrong.
Are you really okay, Son?
Of course.
When are you leaving?
I will take you to the airport.
Don't worry, I can go by myself.
I will go with you.
Go first.
Start to think about what you
want to do and to eat with me.
I'll soon be there too.
I will do that.
Mom.
Yeah?
If you go to China, you
will be happy, right?
You always said you wanted to move there.
If you're also coming, there's
nothing else I could hope for.
Then, it's fine. I'll see
you at the airport, Mom.
♪ The countless tears
which flowed past me ♪
♪ were like the end of unknown darkness ♪
Is it my turn to keep the promise to my
father?♪ Both when I take another step ♪
♪ and let out a long sigh ♪
♪ Where does the road end? ♪
♪ Good bye good bye the
words to me, Good bye ♪
♪ You please don't say good bye ♪
♪ Baby, it looks like I was young then ♪
♪ Baby, it looks like I was a coward then ♪
♪ I knew just a connection was there ♪
If... Really, if...♪ I thought I
could just reach out to you ♪
Even if you can't come back to school,
♪ Baby, I'm not afraid of anything ♪
We aren't breaking up.♪
Will you stay with me? ♪
Yeah.
We'll never separate.♪ Will you hold
me tight? I also worried a lot ♪
♪ I was afraid perhaps
you would be far away ♪
♪ Without your smile ♪
Back then, the feeling of love I've experienced for
the first time...♪ Without Your Love My Life~ ♪
why did I fight it for so long?♪
I'm not afraid of anything ♪
♪ Now I will take care of you ♪
What do we do now?♪ Will you
stay here as you are? ♪
Did I promise that we wouldn't break up too
easily? ♪ Will you just take my hand? ♪
Why...♪ I will be the light for you ♪
Why couldn't I see your hesitation?♪
If you also think the same way I do ♪
♪ Will you stay with me? ♪
How could I have known you'd leave me by saying
you love me?♪ Will you hug me close to you? ♪
♪ Good bye ♪
I really didn't know then.
♪ Good bye good bye, You
please don't say good bye ♪
He's coming.
Tell them to start.
Chae Yoon will soon arrive.
What should I do? Should I
keep following that car?
I have something to tell you.
Can we meet now?
If anything happens to me...
Will you keep scaring me
like this before you leave?
Can we meet now?
Can you come to Moorim headquarters?
It's urgent.
Don't tell anybody anything.
No one must find out.
Yeong, Joon!
Yoon, please take care of the key.
You cannot leave like this. I will
find the destructive force with you.
Your friend and partner, Hwang Moo Song...
What?
Don't trust him too much.
It's already started.
Didn't you start everything
eighteen years ago?
Who are you?
I am the Chairman to
Shanghai Group, Wang Hao.
I know very well that you
are the destructive force.
I also know that now neither you nor
the Moorim Association has any power.
So what?
I came here to negotiate.
You want to negotiate with someone
who is on the verge of death?
Didn't you want to save your
life through the Cheon Ui Joo?
I can help you with that.
Give one of the parts of the Cheon Ui
Joo that you stole that day to me.
Did you find the last part of the key?
How could someone so impatient
not have found the other part until now?
There should be no problems
with Chae Yoon, right?
Since I called him, he should
be in the headquarter's
meeting room waiting for me.
Hwang Moo Song is now done for.
Where is the third part?
Trust me and hang on for just a while.
Moo Song!
Wake up, Moo Song!
Here.
I'm sorry.
I really needed to say this.
I misunderstood you.
I should've trusted you and
come to find you earlier.
Eighteen years ago...
And even now... I didn't
protect you like this.
It's not your fault.
Yeong, Yeong is alive.
I know.
Also...
That's enough. Right now.
Joon...
Joon is... alive.
Yoon Si Woo... Joon went to our school.
He is... your son.
He resembles you quite a bit.
Yoon Si Woo?
I thought I could go back to see Seon Ah.
Let's go to Seon Ah.
Let's go back to the kids and
please don't lose consciousness.
Yoon, the key Yeong has...
is in the school.
The barrier...
The headmaster surely hid part of
the key here, inside the school.
Let's find the Cheon Ui Joo.
Us?
We have to protect what the
Headmaster was protecting.
The school, the ones we love...
and
ourselves.
There was nothing wrong with the barrier.
But, why now?
By chance... Nothing
happened to Dad, right?
Hwang Moo Song disappeared.
- What?- I'm sorry.
We're looking for him right now.
What did you just say?
Yoon Si Woo is Chae Yoon's son?!
What have you been doing in that school?
I... I will look into it.
If you leave Yoon Si Woo to me...
It's fine. I'll call you later.
Did you meet Chae Yoon yesterday?
No. But I'm still looking for him.
We've been fooled by Hwang Moo Song.
I can't find Chae Yoon either.
My Son. Don't do this and
go back with me, huh?
No. I promised Dad.
If this promise is because of me...
Don't worry about me, Mom.
Chi Ang.
Mom, if you go to China,
and stay by Dad's side, you'll
be happy.♪ When I look back ♪
♪ I was so young ♪
Chi Ang, all this time,
♪ In the last diary, ♪
"I'm okay, don't worry", ♪ Just
a child filled with worries ♪
you always said that. I'm very sorry.♪ I'm leaving
everything here from the past which was difficult. ♪
Why are you sorry? ♪ Without
even anyone I can go to ♪
Seeing you happy is enough for me,
that's all. ♪ I will run far away. ♪
True happiness shouldn't be for anybody else
but you.♪ I’m running to you, just For You. ♪
If you aren't happy, everyone around you won't be either,
eventually.♪ I will be right there, believe in me.
So you have to be happy, okay?♪
I gotta run, run, run, ♪
♪ I must see you smiling widely ♪
Okay. I'll do it. ♪ When the
day I dreamed of comes. ♪
♪ Facing an unknown future ♪
♪ Totally worn out I Am Gonna Run To You ♪
♪ With a totally lost past ♪
♪ Left here by everyone ♪
♪ Without even anyone I could go to ♪
♪ I want to run very far away ♪
♪ I'm running to you, just to you ♪
♪ I will be right there, believe in me ♪
♪ I gotta run, run, run ♪
♪ I gotta run, run, I've got to run. ♪
Yes, Father?
I found the last part of the key.
Where is it?
With that kid you fought
at the Moorim Tournament.
Yoon Si Woo?
Yoon Si Woo is Chae Yoon's son.
That kid has the last part
of the key for certain.
If it's him, leave it to me.
I will for sure get that key.
Seon Ah come out, Professor
Beop Gong is strange.
What are you doing here right now?
You knew it all along.
Where is Yoon Si Woo!
How can you let him have the
key to the Cheon Ui Joo?
Why are you looking in this room?
It's because Yoon Si Woo
is your little brother!
Now not even the school is safe?
We've followed you since
you were our professor,
but if you are going to abandon
that, we will not hold back either.
What?
We won't watch you destroy
this school anymore..
The Headmaster is back!
The Headmaster came back!
What?
Dad!
Chae Yoon. Why are you
with Headmaster Hwang?
Dad.
If I wondered about what you said.
You wanted to know if I had space
for Soon Deok in my world.
There is no such place.
Because she is my world.
I have to find Soon Deok's happiness.
I'm not really sure but,
I can be happy in her world.
Wang Chi Ang.
Soon Deok... what about Soon Deok?
She left.
Where to?
I don't know yet.
The necklace that Soon Deok
had, you gave it to her, right?
Is it really a part of the key?
Is it?
How do you know it? How much do you know?
Everything. What's going on between
you and Seon Ah. All of it!
So your Dad too...
Yeah. My Dad knows everything.
Because of you, Soon Deok is in danger.
Because of the necklace you gave her!
Does she know this?
Do you want Soon Deok to be
happy by being in danger?
Why would she be in danger?
Because of whom is Seon Deok in danger? Do
you have the qualifications to say this?
Qualifications?
I was always somewhere in
the background with you.
Soon Deok always looked
at you and only you.
But now... Soon Deok left.
What in the world did you say to Soon Deok?
If Soon Deok gets hurt or if
something happens to Soon Deok...
I won't stay still.
Even if you are a friend or not.
You are not a friend to me anymore.
♪ Yeah I am alive ♪
♪ Look straight at me. ♪
♪ For dozens of times I
will get up once again ♪
♪ Yeah I am alive ♪
♪ Watch me. Now close
both eyes and feel me ♪
♪ In the deep pitch-black darkness ♪
♪ Like a child who has lost his way♪
Moorim School-Preview -
We should do everything
to find Sim Soon Deok.
Where in the world are you?
Take the students and leave this place.
The school is under threat,
but we cannot run anymore.
Let's go together.. Let's
start things with me.
You found it.
I'm sorry. I left you alone for so long.
I'm so late.
Si Woo. If you find Soon
Deok don't come back.
I will rescue her no matter what.
I want no one to get hurt.
I am asking you for the last time, Dad.
Is it me or the key?
♪ Look straight at me.♪
♪For dozens of times I
will get up once again ♪