Subtitles: Robert Gray,
Joan Irving Kinograph
An espresso, please.
Hi.
Another.
CINEMA, CAMBODIA, HOSTAGES
TIME DRAGGING
Another.
Morille...
don't blame me if you explode.
- Fine.
Another.
Planning to fuck a gorilla?
Worse.
POLITICAL SITUATION IN CAMBODIA
CINEMA & WAR
ROLE OF JULIETTE
Getting violent won't help.
I don't know what's wrong.
I parked it here,
and now it won't start.
I absolutely have
to get it running.
I bought it just for today.
It's gotta start. It's gotta.
It must be the cold. It's hard
on cars, especially old cars.
It ran fine yesterday.
Cars are like women.
Yesterday, yes. Today, no.
It's ok, all it needs is boost.
I can do it.
Don't worry, there's
solution to every problem.
And if it won't run,
I'll drive you in my cab.
No, it's not that.
The car's a surprise.
For a friend,
to boost his morale.
Know how this works?
It's simple.
A question of contact.
Positive with positive.
Negative with
negative.
Careful,
you'll short the system.
Red is positive. It's dangerous,
it carries the current.
Connected to positive
on the battery, no problem.
Got it?
So, your friend is feeling low?
Did he lose his mother?
Did he lose his job?
Ok, now start your car.
You saved my life!
Now, something
very important...
Keep driving long enough
to recharge the battery, ok?
If you stop too soon,
it may conk out again.
How long should I drive?
An hour.
Just an hour? You sure?
- Yeah, yeah.
Sorry.
MISSING
You're a lousy bastard!
One, it's my only vacation
all year.
Two, I'm supposed to defend
your client
who has absolutely
no chance of winning.
Ever won against
a handicapped woman?
Shut up! Shut up!
Three, and above all,
you're going
on our ski trip without me.
Shut up, I said.
Bring me the trial papers
in person at my hotel.
Simon, you're a goddamn rat.
No, that's alright.
Could you wait one second?
Hello, this is
Fanny Grandmaison.
Alas, I'm away from the phone
at the moment, so please
leave me a message after
the following little beep.
That's not why I was calling.
We received the new collection.
Yeah, gorgeous.
No, spring.
Tops, skirts...
Yeah, short. Very short.
You better have nice legs.
Yeah, it's really beautiful.
I bought myself a few things.
No, a sort of top.
In fake fur. Black and white.
Like zebra skin. Amazing.
Better hurry, it's going fast.
Hold on a second, ok?
Can I help you?
No, thanks, I'm just looking.
If you need anything,
I'm right over there.
Sorry.
I can't this weekend.
I have to work.
Bummer!
I told this friend a while ago
I'd fill in for her.
No, I can't.
An eclipse Saturday night?
No, two eclipses in a row,
I prefer to stay home.
You have another call?
Yeah, hurry, I'll wait.
Is it a present?
Yeah, I'll take this one.
Sorry, I thought...
Forget it.
A very good choice.
$49.95 with tax.
When you came last week
I didn't know this one
would be vacant.
A young couple, and, well,
they're splitting up...
It'll go fast,
it's a great location...
it's bright,
it's got everything.
And, if you want to repaint,
we'll supply the paint.
We prefer pastel colors,
but it's up to you.
The carpeting was changed
last year. It's very clean.
I think it's perfect.
You don't have to touch it.
It's very soundproof.
Because...
An older lady lives next door,
she's very nice.
No complaints.
Also two students, very quiet.
Yes, the bedroom...
You see, behind here, a closet.
Very practical.
The bed's not very
practical there. You could...
God, I almost forgot.
Here there's a spot
for an air conditioner.
It's practical
because the sun comes in...
Well, that's it.
You're so pale.
Are you feeling alright?
Yes, I'm fine. I'll take it.
Great!
You've made a good choice.
Is a parking space included?
- Yes.
Is it possible to see it?
It's so handy, not to have
to worry about parking.
I'll show you your locker.
It's easy to remember, P-2...
What am I saying?
I mean, P-3.
Excuse me.
- Bless you.
Pine and St Urban.
Montreal police arrested
a suspect earlier today in the rape
and murder of Julie Dumouchel
who disappeared last week
and whose body...
All three women were found
with a flower in their hands.
A man, whose identity
cannot be released
will be questioned shortly.
They should cut off his balls!
Did I wake you?
What's that?
- Surprise!
I thought we should do
something special.
What for?
The clinic at 2:00...
Changed your mind?
Would you prefer to be alone?
No, it's not that.
- Wait a sec.
Take a good look.
It's the same!
It's not an Austin Healy,
but I repainted it.
I'll get dressed.
Quite the spicmobile!
Spicmobile? Joel Cadieux!
If Antonio were here,
he'd blast you!
Come off it, no one would
dare blast a homosexual.
We're a protected race, too.
Some privilege!
You said it.
It's just like my little car.
How'd you remember?
You only mentioned it
a million times.
Don't exaggerate.
It's true.
So what? It was my lucky charm.
Well, where to?
Yannie, it's getting late.
Joel, hand me your watch.
We have time, ok?
We have plenty of time.
Excuse me,
I think I'm going to be sick.
Could you?
I think I'm going to throw up.
Too much booze, huh?
A good coffee
and you'll be set for the day.
No, it's not booze.
I don't know what it is.
My nerves, maybe.
Ok, let's go.
- Feeling better?
Yeah, thanks.
If you're ok...
Can I ask you
why you're so nervous?
I'm going to be interviewed.
- Interviewed?
Like on TV?
Yeah, on TV.
It's about a film I made.
A film?
You mean, with a big camera
and beautiful women?
No, a small camera and...
well, one beautiful woman.
That's good, I like films.
What's it about?
A guy and his girlfriend
who are trapped
by fighting in Cambodia.
Yeah, and they find
themselves...
Well, not really
find themselves...
They get taken...
taken hostage, and then...
No, not hostage,
it's more like...
No, it sounds complicated,
but it's simple.
They're forced, to escape,
to take some of the rebels...
So the hostages
take their guard hostage.
Yeah, exactly.
The hostages' hostage.
Great idea.
Kaputt the fascists!
Not much bang-bang in my film.
Then what's it about?
It's about vulnerability...
fear and...
time stretching out.
Oh. Vulnerability
and time stretching...
Like an elastic?
HOSTAGE OF HOSTAGES
Sounds good.
But why do a film about that?
Well, it's because
something similar
happened with my ex.
It's more about her
than anything else.
I see.
Once my brother and I
were shot at by the militia.
When you're young
is the time to get shot at.
Later you're too old.
Were you scared?
Very scared. Many bullets.
We had to find a solution,
the right solution.
It went on for... for...
It seemed like...
How do you say...
the time it takes
a tree to grow?
An eternity.
Right, an eternity.
Eternity.
Fear, elastics...
I like it. You have good ideas.
Brings back memories
of my youth.
That's the point.
- Listen...
I have good idea. I like you...
If you're going to be on TV,
you need better hair.
So, for you, $15.
Everyone else, $25.
But for you, $15.
Thanks, but...
- Listen, for TV...
For TV you need good hair.
It's very important for TV.
Believe me, with good hair,
you're less nervous.
It's not that. I'm not nervous
because of my hair.
I don't know if
what I say makes sense.
It takes many cents
to make a film.
That's true.
Here we are.
Hair Shop
It's for hair, not TV.
It has to be here.
- Ok.
You'll do fine.
- Thanks.
Good luck.
Can I help you?
Yes, I'm...
- Morille Zootrovski?
I'm the show's researcher.
I told Marie to invite you.
Today we talk painting,
film, music...
Of course, for hair,
Madrid is really huge.
Body painting:
Michael will focus on armpits.
And a huge surprise, you can feel
it, everyone here's super pumped.
The Cyberdogs!
Ok, cool. An in-depth
2-minute interview.
Your film, prizes in Berlin,
background, friends,
and your look.
I'll take you to Tekno.
Ok, Smooth, hurt me!
In art what's important is
to look convincing.
Hesitation kills you.
Take you, you look really
convincing. You an actress?
Which bar?
I love the smell of this gel.
It smells like...
I can't describe it.
like L.A.
- Exactly!
Tekno, this is Morille,
our third guest.
Hi, Morille.
Ok, Maurice, I'll take care
of you. Who are you?
I'm lost.
Morille makes films.
Ok, ok, that inspires me.
Trust me.
Leave everything to Tekno.
David Bowie changed
his hair color.
Technitium copper 45.
It was excellent.
Gilbert, bring me
the atomic gloves please.
I'm Nadja,
I'll be interviewing you.
I'm Morille.
- Hi, Maurice!
I haven't seen your film.
Do you do videos?
No, I think...
We don't have much time.
Know the net?
Perfect!
Questions will come from me,
on the web...
Callers will have questions...
in Tokyo, Paris, N Y. You'll be
bouncing off satellites.
Ready for this?
I guess.
You're lucky cause
the Cyberdogs
are on just before you.
Know them?
Geniuses!
They're post-hallucinatory,
it's so cool!
I can introduce you after.
Keep cool, Tekno's doing you.
She's a babe.
You do videos, Maurice?
Do you really have to?
And now on Media-TV the boys
whose megahit made
a big splash:
I Miss You. You know
who I mean. To welcome them...
Gilles Ouellette, leader of
the Québec band Cyberdog.
Welcome to Media-TV.
Your last video was huge.
The whole province is singing
I Miss You.
It's fresh, hip, real hot.
Gilles doesn't
speak French, so...
Their success,
it's really wild.
From garage band to megaband
in a week.
A Media-TVscoop! They've signed
a megacontract with a megalabel.
I'll ask him
if they're influenced
by the Wetfuckers
or Holy Analphases.
He agrees they're like
the Analphases,
but with more hip and pulse.
Ok, we have a question for you
via satellite from Paris.
You're on, Paris.
- Hi, Gilles!
We love you here.
I'd like to know which gel
you use for your hair.
He's amazing! Thanks, Gilles!
Perfect, cool. Your turn.
Great, Tekno. It's perfect.
I could stick a feather up my ass.
- There isn't time.
Five, four, three...
Ok, Maurice is here to talk about
his film. It's very special.
Hi, Maurice. Things ok?
Before we talk about your film
and upcoming videos
I want to ask Tekno
what he did with your hair.
Hey, baby.
Ok, one big job for Tekno...
It's hip, fashionable,
totally too much.
For the director,
Tekno created a concept...
We used Asa for more light,
more sheen.
Look at the shaping
around his ear.
Move and I shave her!
Keep cool, Maurice.
Relax, everything's fine.
We're your friends.
Your hair!
What did TV do to your hair?
Antoine! Antoine!
I don't have time!
I have to tell you my dream!
Your dream?
Not now.
- The worst yet, with those atoms.
Atoms?
100 years ago we discovered
what makes up atoms.
Now we're seeing it's not true.
- Oh yeah?
Atoms aren't made up of matter.
They're made up of energy.
Matter doesn't exist.
We're made up of nothing.
It's completely absurd.
Yeah, it sure is absurd.
What was your dream?
I'm being chased by 30 hit-men.
I'm exhausted.
I fall, and a plane hits me.
A plane? Not bad.
I open my eyes. I can't see
or hear or smell anything.
Like atoms...
So you're...
- I'm dead.
But then I realize
only my body is dead.
My conscience
is still alive, see?
So I'm stuck with myself and my
bloody ideas for all eternity.
It's hell, huh?
Not bad.
I'll do some research.
See you, ok?
Ok, thanks.
Bye, Antoine.
- Bye, Julien.
Part one is the fear of others.
Part two is the fear
of yourself. Hi, Julien.
Jules. You only called me Julien
when I got on your nerves.
That's true.
Or when I wanted to fuck.
How are you?
You haven't changed a bit.
I haven't?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You've changed.
Think so? Funny.
Haven't smoked in 3 years.
- It's been 3 years?
Hold on, 5 years.
I left you on my 25th birthday.
Yeah, you said
we'd stay friends.
You answered:
Like brother and sister.
But you, there's something
different about you.
I'm older.
No, it's...
you're not so granola.
Your zits are gone.
- Zits?
Not zits,
but you had skin trouble.
Now your skin looks good.
I got new breasts.
- What?
Three months ago.
Go on, look.
May I?
Sure.
Like, I always look
at women's breasts.
Always, with every woman.
But I wait
for the right moment.
When they're not looking,
or when I have on sunglasses.
When they sneeze... you always
close your eyes when you sneeze.
You haven't changed, Jules.
You're exactly the same,
but worse.
Worse?
Don't feel embarrassed.
I'm the same with men's butts.
You are?
You're embarrassed to look
because you know I'll see you.
Staying on, Mme Grandmaison?
Did you get married?
I changed my name.
Stéphanie Little didn't cut it.
Yes, I'm staying. But my
luggage is with the concierge.
But I did get married.
Antoine,
bring Mme Grandmaison's bags.
I'm afraid we're fully booked,
Madame.
Shit!
There's a king-sized bed
in my room.
I mean, if it's of any help.
Sorry, but several floors
are being renovated
and with the hearing-impaired
convention...
Deaf, not hearing impaired.
Even the deaf say deaf.
Take them to this
gentleman's room, please.
See you later.
Jules...
I need an office where I can
work all night, not a bed.
Is that clear?
No sex, got it?
What do you think I am?
- The same old guy.
What are you up to?
I read.
I study languages, I read.
I mean, professionally.
I'm an interpreter. My client's
here, she's very nice.
May I see your breasts?
What?
Your breasts.
Look me in the eyes
and repeat your question.
May I see
your breasts... naked?
No way.
- No?
As a friend.
- What do you mean?
I haven't seen you in 5 years.
It may be a while again.
Your renovated breasts
are amazing.
Amazing! You exaggerate.
I just want to see them, that's all.
- That's all?
As a present. Just an innocent,
teeny-weeny peek.
Like that,
with no ulterior motives.
You must want them
to be admired, if they're new.
I mean, for the price you paid.
It wasn't just for yourself
that you bought... had them...
Enlarged.
Blown up, if you prefer.
Silicone?
I'm old enough to know it's
impossible for a 30-year-old man
to have just a teeny-weeny peek
at an old girlfriend's breasts
especially in a hotel room.
Why?
Oh, Simone.
Simone, this is...
Fanny, this is my client,
Simone Leduc.
Simone Leduc?
Hello.
She's charming.
What exactly is your job, Joe?
Joe!
I'm interpreting
for her in court.
Tomorrow at 10:30,
room 24, at the courthouse.
You know her?
Your client is my rival. She's
the reason I'm not going skiing.
I have to work through the
night to make sure she loses.
We'll be seeing a lot
of each other this week.
No, wait, conflict of interest.
I can't do this.
If my client finds out...
There's no conflict.
We won't mix work and pleasure.
Pleasure, Jules?
Coming?
- If you insist.
I insist.
Hold my hand. I've become
claustrophobic in elevators.
Poor guy.
- No, it's true, I swear.
I liked your breasts. I mean...
they weren't big, but they were
nice. They had guts, character.
They were well-proportioned
soft, round...
pointed, too, sometimes.
Why are you scared
to show me them now?
I'm not scared.
I just don't feel like it.
Feeling...
a word you don't know.
All that drives you
is your pseudo-brain
your little ego.
You've no instincts, Jules.
You're lost in your head,
in your world of theories.
Ah, nostalgia!
Sweet memories flood back.
Your body's going to rot! When's
the last time you exercised?
You don't like my body?
At least it's mine.
I didn't have my dick enlarged.
Maybe you should.
What's with this incredible
fad in society today?
Is it because we're
approaching the year 2000?
Everything's fake, Stéphanie!
Stéphanie?
Athletes take steroids.
We manipulate genes
to create the perfect human.
Fashion's replaced politics.
Machines think for us.
Our value system disappeared
along with religion.
The result: An enlarged risk
of breast cancer.
To think I used to
listen to you.
Good thing I saw the light
after a few months.
No, we left each other,
after a year.
A year? Incredible what you'll
put up with for a lay.
May I see your breasts?
What's the point?
I mean, I've seen your body.
I've seen you naked.
How many times? 200? 250?
No, correction!
The student will remind
her master of his teachings.
With recycling...
our atoms, our dear atoms,
are replaced...
The conclusion: You never saw
this body. It's a new model.
And new models are expensive.
Expensive! My God,
how can I have been so dense?
I see, expensive.
How much?
I reveal my precious jewels
in exchange for
a tiny little favor,
quite harmless.
Broken telephone.
Broken telephone?
Tomorrow, in court...
you're your client's
only means of communication.
You become
Simone Leduc's voice,
so you can manipulate
her answers
and make her lose, like that.
She'll lose
her case - tomorrow.
I can prove she's guilty
in a few days
but why waste our time,
and the judge's?
You'd do that?
Relish, mustard
and lots of ketchup.
It's been a while.
On vacation?
No. Five hotdogs, please.
Coming up!
What do you want on them?
Thanks.
Shit! Would you pass me
the cloth from the back?
Thanks.
The Santa Claus parade
was here.
I was so excited,
I wet my pants.
Parades are so dumb.
I caught my dick
in my snowsuit once.
It was during a parade.
Dad took me aside to pee.
It was freezing out.
I tried to hurry, so I pulled
hard to do up my suit and...
in the zipper!
I cried so hard.
I am, Yannie.
I'm certain I am.
No, Yannie, don't!
Yannie, don't!
Don't do it!
What'll it be?
Ok, to recapitulate
the situation.
I make my client lose her case
and in exchange...
in exchange you show me
your breasts, right?
Right away.
Just give me the signal.
What are you looking at?
You've changed, so much.
Being a lawyer is a way
of life, not just a job.
Did your class vote you Bitch
of the Year? It's unethical!
Ethyl alcohol?
- Unethical!
It's completely ethical,
since your client's guilty.
Says who?
- Trust me.
Last time I trusted you
you screwed my best friend.
Fuck off! You don't want
to see my tits, you won't.
You're such a pain!
Ok, I accept.
I accept.
You accept?
Mr. Ethics accepts to double-cross
his handicapped client?
You pig! Think I'd ever
sell my body for that?
I'd never ever
accept that kind of deal.
You're the one who's changed.
Anyway, I know your game.
You're not interested
in seeing my breasts.
What you really want
is for me to reveal them.
Pardon me?
- To reveal them.
You want to see me strip,
not what's underneath.
Only natural,
that's the turn-on.
That's what you want.
That's what we all want.
If you could prove
it's my breasts
you're after,
and not that thrill
I'd show them to you gladly.
Reveal them.
Quite a theory.
Yes sirree.
Hi, how's it going?
Hi, Antoine.
Bliss is near, I feel it.
And my dream?
Is it linked
to the death of matter
at the dawn
of the second millennium?
I dunno.
Here, for your girlfriend.
My girlfriend says thanks.
Oh, by the way...
Would you
happen to have a condom?
Be right back.
Fanny?
What?
In art nudity is completely
respectable, is it not?
No, I mean, if...
if you show me a photo of your
breasts, and I admire it
as a work of art,
then your problem
of supposedly sacred revelation
is eliminated, right?
Jules?
Do you want to fuck me?
Make love?
Never crossed my mind.
I don't know,
unconsciously perhaps.
Julien!
Jules.
All I want now
is to see your breasts.
The rest is the future,
beyond our grasp.
Thanks for being so frank.
If you were me, would you?
Yes, definitely.
Then you go first.
If you mean it.
I'll follow you.
Shit!
Fanny...
Jules!
Be right there.
I'm here, you can...
I have to go. It's urgent.
My partner sent a plane ticket,
not the trial papers.
He felt so guilty,
he's taking the case.
I fly from Quebec City tonight.
Fanny?
- What, Julot?
Nothing, nothing...
You're going?
You want to see
my breasts, huh?
No, I don't. This breast thing
is dumb. Dumb.
Ok. It's up to you.
Here.
My cellular number.
Join me skiing,
after the trial.
I have a condo,
and Simon won't bother us.
Simon?
My partner,
and future ex-husband.
Let's stay friends.
Don't ever change, Julot.
Jules... it's for you.
Take my bags
to the lobby, please.
In a moment.
I've interpreted your dream.
I think...
The plane crash represents
an intellectual situation
in conflict with
your material aspirations.
But you don't die,
so near death is a condition
of reaching
a higher life plane.
Another time.
- Another time.
Thanks, huh.
- Sure.
Bye, Jules.
- Bye, Antoine.
Thanks.
Vacation time...
Gimme that skin cancer.
Think we'll tan?
Am I tanning?
I don't wanna know, Yannie.
Not now.
Ok, fine.
We won't go. We won't, ok?
Sure.
We won't go.
- We won't go.
I don't need to know.
I bit my tongue.
What're we doing here?
What am I doing here?
If I am, I am right now.
Not as of 2 o'clock.
I am right now!
Think positive, pal,
maybe you're negative.
Why pretend life is beautiful?
We're not pretending.
Wake up, for Christ sake!
What if you're not?
Come on, I'm getting
on your nerves.
C'mon, might as well find out.
Yannie
I prefer to go by myself.
It's for you.
Thanks for the day.
When will we do this again?
I'll wait for you.
Go on in.
It's 8. I'm freezing.
What the fuck are you doing?
Where are you?
It's starting.
Shit!
Well, have a nice evening.
Still there?
We used to call it
being stood up.
You're not missing anything.
It's terrible.
Give the actors a chance.
If it's a disaster,
you know right away.
Seen the play?
I acted in it.
Actress!
No, for an audition
at the Theater School.
I wanted to see Sylvie Drapeau.
Everyone says she's great.
Everyone...
You should have seen Delphine.
The magic of seeing the Shrew
that first time, in Paris in 53.
Her Katharina was so beautiful,
so timid.
And I married her.
Did you tame her?
Not really.
But you're cold.
- It's ok.
I cannot accept a woman
having cold feet. Come with me.
Did you see a girl
waiting for someone?
You sure?
A brunette was waiting
a while ago, but she left.
Has it been long?
What direction did she go in?
Next time, be on time.
To avoid all these questions.
You'll feel better in these.
My wife's stage fright
went to her feet.
Every night before a show
I massaged her.
After the show I did it again.
She'd become completely relaxed
and fall asleep like a baby.
How long were you together?
How old are you?
Nineteen. Well...
I'm turning 20.
It's my birthday.
Ah, your birthday.
So the play was..?
A present.
Perfect, huh?
Allow me...
She was your age
when I married her. Twenty.
Transparent as rain.
Happy birthday...
Dawn.
Beautiful.
And you are?
Dusk.
Dawn and Dusk,
like in the poem.
Play out the play!
It's a bad night.
Not just a bad night.
I'd have liked to live
in your day.
It was harder for some,
better for others.
Like today
nothing has changed.
No, I think a lot has changed.
I knew I was born
at the wrong time.
Speed, competitiveness
aren't for me.
Yet, your game
is ferociously combative.
Yeah, my game.
But in life I'd like
a bit more...
Don't know,
but it's not coming.
Even on my birthday.
I wonder if I still love him.
You're delightful, Dawn.
My shot. Won't be long.
There!
If I'm still with him at 70
I'll think of you
on my birthday.
Has she been dead long?
She's not dead, she left me.
She was right. It was time.
I'd never have done it.
I don't know if I'll stay.
Of course.
Adolescent dawn,
who dreams of the golden sun.
A winter sun,
rays without fire.
Adolescent dawn,
who rises slowly, so softly
that one can see her shiver
and begin to blush.
Never will dusk
defeat the dawn.
Let evening surprise us, but
bring on the morning.
Apollinaire was right.
Never will dusk
defeat the dawn.
Marriage, you know
is an association.
Association?
That's romantic.
With time,
that's what it becomes.
You don't believe in it?
- Some associations
are very enriching.
We all wait for the miracle.
I always thought there'd be
someone, maybe far away
I could make my life with.
Very far or very near.
Maybe it's my boyfriend.
If I decide it's him.
You must've decided,
it lasted 50 years.
Yes.
And I never
went back on the choice.
You're handsome.
You could've had
several associations.
Don't tempt the devil.
Chance is strange.
Life is strange.
Always work nights?
Night, day, sometimes
round the clock.
There's less traffic at night.
You must meet
some strange ones.
All kinds of people.
One guy today vomited,
he was so nervous.
Lots of things,
you can't imagine.
Tonight I met a wise man.
A wise man.
That's not wise. Those guys
always have something in mind.
Probably.
Was he young or old,
your wise man?
It was as if he had no age.
I think he was 20 with me.
We met 'cause of my birthday.
Your birthday?
That's great.
Happy birthday!
What is it in your language?
Happy birthday?
We say several things,
but I prefer, Dolgie lieta!
It means, many years.
Many years.
A sandwich and coffee.
Chicken?
Chicken's good.
Good morning, coffee, please.
Cosmos!
Janvier!
Wake up without any problem?
Almost. You done?
So?
$83.
Cheap.
Anyway...
- Anyway, what?
Anyway, winter's the pits.
For sure. Big disadvantage
of this country.
Huge disadvantage.
- Well...
winter's the price
of the advantages.
Huge price!
Happiness doesn't depend
on the season, or the weather.
It's all here,
a matter of altitude.
Of attitude.
Yeah, but in winter
people are less open.
Very conservative.
They don't even look up.
No one talks, no one smiles.
It's depressing.
I'm depressed!
Don't get depressed.
Spring's coming.
Anyway, people tip less
in winter. That's serious.
Summer's what I like.
Right on. Me too.
None of this crap in summer.
People are much more open,
you know.
They tip like civilized people.
The problem with society today
is that people...
You know how people are?
I have no idea.
Let me tell you...
People are alone.
Lonely, very lonely.
It's true, you're right.
I read a book on it.
The author said it all started
with one thing.
Can you guess what?
- What?
Guess.
The industrial revolution.
- No.
Come on!
- Not that.
Women's liberation!
No, before.
I don't know. TV? Plastic?
No, pal.
All our problems started
with agriculture.
What do you mean?
Are you crazy?
Agriculture is good.
It gives us food.
It gives us...
gives us everything.
Agriculture's
great. I'm not against it.
It depends on how
you look at it.
You're talking nonsense again.
The problem
isn't agriculture per se.
The wheat and tomatoes
aren't to blame.
It's the consequences
of agriculture.
Agriculture has resulted
in an abundance of food.
Without that,
no population growth.
Without it, no big cities.
Without big cities, pal...
Where's your car?
Yeah, where's my car?
I don't get it. It was...
Maybe you loaned it.
Don't you see, they stole it!
Hey, there it is. Look.
Isn't that your car?
Let's follow them!
Not just follow them.
Catch them.
We're gonna kill them.
Massacre the dogs!
I'll strangle them
one at a time. Got a rope?
Put on your seat belt, ok?
What're you doing?
Can't get too close.
How'll we catch them?
If I stay back
they won't know
we're following them.
Are you stupid?
You finished?
Don't call me stupid.
Have I ever called you stupid?
Never, not once.
I respect you.
They might be dangerous,
never know.
I think they have guns.
- What?
Can't you see it in their eyes?
Their eyes say "guns".
Never seen that?
Not much of a driver.
Like Dionysius fleeing
Hermes's garden.
What? Who?
- What? Who?
You're Greek.
- Only part.
You should know
your own mythology.
Fine, but right now
all I want is to kill them.
There you go again.
Kill, kill.
You're out of control.
Know what? I don't want
to follow those guys.
I'm scared, I'll admit it.
Got insurance?
No, I don't.
- You're lying.
You mentioned the payments.
Let's call the police.
No, they're right
in front of us.
God, see that?
See that money?
I just wanted an easy start
to my day, and see?
It's getting more
and more strange.
Isn't that your car?
That?
It's my car?
You ok, pal?
Want a closer look?
One last time?
No, not a last time.
And them?
Still want to kill 'em?
No, not kill.
Not kill.
Agriculture invented cars,
you know.
And it's the reason
they stole your car.
I told you. Everything
started with agriculture.
Everything bad.
- You got it, pal.
Even what's good is bad.
Yeah, it's ironic.
Why me? What did I do?
You nibbled on a carrot or some
broccoli, and the devil smiled.
Oh.
You know
in some ways
agriculture maybe isn't so bad.
It's bad all the way.
Yeah.
It's ironic.
It's as if everything was
meaningless.
I forgot to tell you
what happened.
A woman came out
of a hotel. Seemed upset.
She looked at me
and she bared her breasts.
No way.
- I swear, pal.
Can you imagine?