Sub edited and resynced by: PEEAN91
Blood pressure: 120 over 70.
Normal.
All right, open wide.
Looks fine. Healthy as a horse.
Just one more thing, Luther.
You got to whiz in the cup, Frank.
Then we're done.
Medical exam completed
Fuck them!
We going to argue
the merits of journalism?
You trying to tell me
that's journalism?
Look, Michelle...
...it's been a long weekend.
Everybody's shooting one another
and I've got to write about it.
I'm serious.
I'm tired of the crap, you know?
I should get my Ph. D. Then I could
write about stuff that matters.
Michelle you're 23 years old.
You don't know anything that matters.
Well, fuck you too, Ev!
All right, here's a shoulder.
- What did they do to you?
- Not "they. " He.
- Alan.
- Alan?
Yeah. He killed my sidebar
on the Frank Beechum murder.
If you asked me the whole case
stinks anyway, but that's not the point.
- I read that sidebar.
- It was good. Admit it.
It's the best thing
I've written in months.
That was the one where you say
that the media...
...glorified Beechum's victim in order
to mask our patriarchal culture...
...which created the violence
that destroyed her. Exactly!
Yeah. You're right.
He should have never killed that.
- You Fucking-Right!
- I would've tortured it.
Well, I might have enjoyed that.
I think you would've enjoyed
every second of that.
Another round?
Another margarita for the lady,
and I'll have my usual.
Not your "usual" usual?
No, my new usual.
Virgin Mary.Yeah
And heavy on the...
...virgin?
Alright. Tell me something.
If you're such hot shit, why are you
stuck here in Bumfuck, California?
Looking for love.
Well you've come to
all the wrong places.
Not from where I sit.
It's not good. Not smart.
- What's smart got to do with anything?
- I can't do this.
I got to go.
You're married and you're...
I can't do this.
I got to go.
Next time?
Yeah, next time.
Frank!
We're out!
Just hold on. I can't hear you.
Morning, Frank.
Can I get you anything?
6:21 prisoner awakes
Some breakfast?
Well, if I can get, like...
...a roll and some coffee.
I'll get that right away.
You're not wearing
your protective glasses.
- You heard about it?
- Yeah
What a tragedy.
The fucking Raiders that's a tragedy.
Was she drunk?
I don't know.
It was at Dead Man's Curve.
They ought do something
about that place
Did we had to cover for her?
Did she have anything big on?
She had the interview
with Frank Beechum...
...at San Quentin, then she's going
to witness the execution tonight.
Christ!
It's a little worse then Michelle, Alan.
You think so, Bob?
If the warden will okay
a replacement for the interview...
but I thought I'll take Harvey out
of that meeting.
- Put Everett on it.
- Steve has the day off.
Not anymore he doesn’t.
He can do the interview and
witness the execution.
And what's-his-name, the warden
down there at San Quentin...
Plunkitt, Steve can dealt with
him before I can get him in.
You think Everett's
an asshole don't you?
I don't think he's an asshole
You're wrong. He is an asshole.
Trust me, I know him.
But a lot of people who are good
at their jobs are assholes Bob
Look, I know that, Alan, all right?
It's not about that.
Everything with Everett is a
big investigative witch-hunt,
you know like that
Mike Vargas piece.
He's not a drunk then. He isn't now
Two months ago he's a drunk,
now he's Mother Teresa.
The point is this is not a Steve
Everett slash-and-burn job. Okay?
This is a sidebar.
It's an issue piece.
"An issue piece. "
Well, dog my cats!
It's a capital punishment, Alan.
We are putting a man to death tonight.
We are killing a human being.
Stop the presses!
By the way,
that Amy what's-her-name...
you know...the pregnant broad
that Frankie shot in the throat...
...was she a human being?
Is that part of the issue?
Yeah, that is part of the issue.
Bob Let me tell you something...
Pumpkin?
- No
- Okay
Issues are shit we make up to give
yourself an excuse to run good stories.
Okay?
"Judge Grabs Female Attorney's Tits. "
Hey that The sex discrimination "issue. "
"Nine-year-old blows
his Brother With an Uzi. "
The child violence "issue. "
People want to read
about sex organs and blood.
You know what?
We make up issues so they don't have
to feel too nasty about it. Got it?
So I might as well call Steve Everett,
because that's his attitude exactly.
A little sarcasm?
How long you been here? Three months?
I've been worked with Steve Everett
for three and a half years.
And let me tell you something, Bob.
The guy is good, he's as good as anybody
I've ever worked with.
You know why he was
run out of New York?
You know the story?
I heard a couple of things.
He busted the mayor. Bob
The mayor of fucking New York City!
Everett found a secret memo
on a contract bribe...
...between His Honor and an ex-borough
president and he ran with it in his column.
- So?
- So..
The paper try to killed it because
the owner was in bed with the mayor.
What did Everett do, Bob? huh?
Well he didn't whine...
...and he didn't back down.
He just fucking walked.
- That's Steve Everett.
- Okay
- Okay? Alright? Good?
- Yeah.
How're you going with the
quitting smoking, good?
Going great.
Hey listen when you send the flowers
to the, you know...the dead girl
- Michelle?
- Michelle's family
...can you include my name?
Thanks, I appreciate it.
Yeah
- See you.
- Alright.
- Okay?
- Yeah
The mayor of New York City, Bob.
The mayor, you gullible asshole.
Yeah, I could have stayed
in New York forever.
They were about to put me
in charge of an investigative team.
That would have put me
on the Pulitzer track.
I really liked it there.
Broadway shows, downtown jazz clubs...
...dinners at Elaine's,
veal chops up the old wazoo.
Not veal chops like that, though.
Jaws!
Now you have to kiss it
and make it better.
So you were the king of New York.
Why are you hacking out metro stories
at the Oakland Tribune?
Well, that's a long story.
I got caught in the supply room
with a very young lady.
Turned out to be the owner's daughter.
How the hell was I supposed to know
she was underage?
She looked 18 to me.
Anyway, I got blackballed
all over town.
You bad man!
What did your wife say?
We'd just had the kid,
so she took it kind of hard.
But you know Alan offered us
this gig out here.
Another town, another change.
Bad man!
First the owner's daughter,
now the editor's wife.
Do I detect a little...
...hostility towards authority figures?
Only ones I work for.
Is that what you'll say
in the next town with someone else?
"I got caught with the editor's wife.
You know how that is?. "
I get caught
with the editor's wife...
...not too many more towns
that'll have me.
So playtime's over?
You've got to go to work.
I've got to get home...
...see if the wife and kid
still recognize me.
You won't tell me how awful
we're being, are you?
Bob, he's a decent sort.
Good newspaperman, solid editor.
So this all just stinks...
...right?
What we're doing?
Patricia...
...you and I are just two people
swimming through the passions of life.
You know what I mean?
Look, it's all right.
It's not like I love you or anything.
That's good.
Because I don't love you too.
Hello?
All right.
Yes, all right.
You are going to believe this.
What?
That was Bob.
What'd he want?
He was looking for you.
Who told him?
How in the hell should I know?
Morning, Frank.
Mr. Plunkitt.
Anything I can get for you?
Anything you need?
No, not anything I can think of.
There's some matters
I gotta discuss with you.
Figured we'd do it first,
get it out of the way.
Your dinner tonight,
for one thing...
...can be pretty much
anything you want.
You go ahead and tell Reedy here
when you decide.
Now, about your personal
effects and belonging...
My wife will take them.
And your remains?
That go for your remains too?
If she can't afford the funeral...
Our church raised some money.
It's all right.
So your wife will be claiming
your remains?
Yes, sir, that's right.
I want to give you some idea
of what's going to happen tonight.
We'll have to ask your visitors
to leave at 7 p. m.
You'll be given your dinner
and a fresh set of clothes.
We'll come for you about a half-hour
before the procedure.
You'll be taken
into the procedure room.
They'll hook an EKG up to you
and the intravenous lines.
But nothing's going to happen
early or anything.
Right up until 12:01,
we'll be monitoring the phones.
We got lines to the attorney
general and the governor.
And those we check to make sure
they're in working order.
You have any questions
about any of that, Frank?
No.
Just one more thing,
and then I'll leave you in peace.
- It's about the sedative.
- I don't want no sedative
Sedative's completely optional, Frank.
I just like to advice you again
it can make things a lot easier.
I don't want it.
I appreciate it, Mr. Plunkitt...
...but I want to be clear in my mind.
When I see my wife, I want to
be clear for that. Alright?
Fair enough.
You change your mind,
you let the duty officer know.
I just had to give you my
little sales talk that's all.
Badges will be at the gate.
Got the witness list.
What else?
Roadblocks are up.
Demonstrators are light so far.
- Visitors all squared away?
- Wife and kid.
Your girl from the Trib,
Michelle Ziegler, she'll be here at 4.
Mea culpa.
- She was pretty persuasive.
- Let her persuade me next time.
Arnie, what do you think of Beechum?
Well sometimes I think about the girl
he shot dead over $96.
Mostly I think about doing my job.
Warden! Sir!
I repent!
Jesus, Atkins!
Give me some of that pussy, baby.
Give me some pussy on toast!
I need some of that pussy on toast!
Go ahead, baby, shake that thing.
Excuse me.
Can I have some pussy on toast?
I just need some pussy on toast.
Give me some pussy on toast!
- Is that you, newspaperman?
- Back off.
You got money.
Give me some on toast.
Come on, I need it.
Promise me you will not
spend this on food.
Five dollars?
You can give me more than that.
Steve give me five, give me 10.
Come on, give me 20, Steve.
You can give me $100,
you got so much money!
You got money on toast, baby!
I know you do.
- Hey, sister!
- Get away from me.
- I know you got some sweet pussy!
You nasty motherfucker!
Shut your nasty ass up.
I want something on the toast.
Nothing wrong with that.
Put some on the toast for me.
I know she likes me.
I know I'm going to give her
my phone number.
Hello, everyone.
You got my message?
Yeah
Apparently, you and I
have a little problem.
Do we?
Yes, we do.
Look, Bob...
Michelle Ziegler was killed
in a car wreck last night.
What?
Michelle?
That couldn't be.
I was with her last night.
Oh, no!
She was only 23 or something.
Dead Man's Curve.
My God!
That poor kid!
Just out of school
and 23 or something.
I should have driven her home.
She had an interview set up
with Frank Beechum this afternoon.
The poor...
Beechum.
Yeah, I heard that they were going
to juice him today.
She said she had a seat
for the show.
Yeah. Four o'clock face to
face in the deathwatch cell.
Alan wants you to cover for her.
Beechum, Is he the one
who killed that pregnant girl?
College student, Amy Wilson.
Working the summer in Richmond.
Place called Pocum's Grocery.
Owed Beechum 96 bucks.
Repairs he did on her car
or something. Shot her dead.
Anything else I should know about him?
He's tough, black mechanic
at the Amoco station in Clayton.
But I'm warn you, do not pull
a Dick Tracy on this again.
I don't want a big
investigation piece.
You can depend on that.
Don't worry.
Says here, Beechum's
one of those born-agains.
Yeah, aren't they all on death row?
Biggest birthrate in the country.
Cynical.
He came from Michigan.
Broken home, alcoholic mother.
He's been in and out of jails,
violent assaults, drugs, more drugs.
He did two years for beating a cop
who tried to give him a ticket.
Sounds like a reasonable fella.
Then another three for breaking
into a store.
Then he got out of the slam,
met his wife. Nice girl, born-again.
Led him straight to Jesus.
They had a daughter,
bought a house in Richmond.
Yeah, now he's Mr. Nice Guy.
I guess not. Six years ago,
he walks into Pocum's...
...Amy Wilson's is working
on the register.
Yeah. Let me guess.
He asks Amy for his $96
and she says she doesn't have it.
And old Frankie, gets
his wicked temper up.
I don't suppose he's expressed
any heartfelt remorse?
Nope. Get this.
He still says that he just went
to the store for some A-1 Steak Sauce.
Steak sauce?
Wow, that's a nice touch.
Looks like Nussbaum had
two strong witnesses.
Black or white?
Let's see. Both white.
Looks like a woman in the
parking lot saw him running away...
...and this poor guy, an accountant...
...drive in the parking lot
because his car overheated
and he goes in the store
to use the phone
and then there's Beechum standing
over the body with gun in hand,
blood all over him.
Okay. Okay. Don't over look it.
All I'm looking for here is the
human-interest angle. You know?
Final days, what it's like. Alright?
-Got it?
-Yeah, I got it.
Anything else you need from me, Bob?
Nope.
Good. Okey-dokey.
I'll get right on it.
Something else on your mind, Steve?
The witness...
...the one who found Beechum
with the body...
...he must have heard the shots.
Right?
- Shots.
- Yeah I mean
You know, he comes in...
...his car's overheated,
he's got the hood up.
Must be working on it.
While, there's a robbery going on.
He had to have heard shots.
So he heard the shots.
But this is a white
accountant in Richmond.
and you're telling me
he's going to walk
into a store when
he heard shots?
You know what Steve? I don't
know if he heard the shots or not
Maybe he did. I don't care.
What I'd like you to
do is please interview
Frank Beechum about
his feelings today.
and turn it into a
human-interest sidebar.
Think you can handle that?
Yeah, I'll get right on it.
No problem.
Bye-bye.
Fuck!
Close one!
I don't know what you did,
but he's on your case.
I'd we're about two seconds away
from a full Bob Findley explosion.
What are you, crazy?
You're lighting up after
Bob's "no smoking" speech?
I missed that.
Yeah. That was smart too.
Try to be a good boy, okay?
Beechum case.
Victim: Amy Wilson, married, 20
years old, shot in the chest...
...with a.38 as she stood behind
the counter at Pocum's Grocery in Richmond.
Six months pregnant at the time.
Both she and the baby died. Okay let see
Two witnesses.
If I'm right, First witness:
Nancy Larson, housewife...
...mother of three.
Drives car into the parking lot at Pocum's.
Larson couldn't see
whether he had a gun or not.
No weapon was found.
Later she picked Beechum out
of a police lineup...
...and it was the same lineup
where Beechum was picked out...
...by Dale Porterhouse, CPA.
He was in the neighbourhood
His car overheated, so he
drove into Pocum's to call AAA
Porterhouse call the cops  and picks
Beechum from the lineup that same day.
Records later show that Amy Wilson
owed Beechum $96...
...for working on her carburetor.
Note for future essay:
Why so few female car mechanics?
Want coffee, Ev?
It's back in fashion
as a late-morning pick-me-up.
I appreciate it. Thank you
Yeah. Make it a big one.
Women are allowed to
fetch coffee in the office now...
...because some improve
job opportunities
has given us a new confidence.
Brigett, don't you think being
the trends editor's getting to you?
I don't know. Was I an
insane person before?
You're a great person.
You take it black, right?
I do.
Oh Shit!
- Hello
- Hi
Steve, thank God. Where are you?
I'm at the paper. They roped me in.
Oh no did they call
you at the gym?
They tried here but I won't
tell them where you were.
I stopped by to pick something
up and they grabbed me.
Did you have a good workout?
Yeah, decent.
Good. Anyway, you really did promised
Kate you'd take her to the zoo.
The zoo!
God, I forgot!
Steve, she really is expecting you.
I'm sorry about that.
I really just forgot.
Look you worked all weekend.
She didn't see you at all.
You know how she loves her daddy.
Steve, I know it's work...
...but I feel it would be a bad idea
to let her down like this again.
Look Barbara, there's been an accident.
Remember Michelle Ziegler?
You met at the Christmas Party.
Yeah
She piled up her car
on Dead Man's Curve.
Oh my gosh that's terrible. There's
been so many accidents there.
They ought to do something about that place
What was that?
I said they ought do
something about that place.
- Is she hurt?
- "Not if I heard anything like that."
What?
Yeah, dead.
Oh that's awful.
Do they had you filling in for her?
They've got a ticket
for the execution tonight.
Steve don't tell me they couldn't
get someone else for this.
You were working all weekend.
Finally!
What? Where are you?
Barbara, look, I don't have
to be at San Quentin till 4.
Why don't I come by,
I pick up Katie,
I take her to the zoo and
bring her back at 3. How about that?
Coffee time!
What about her nap? She's suppose
to have her nap right after lunch.
- Her nap?
- Yes
Isn't today your day off?
You know how cranky she
get without her nap.
Well, I'll bring her
a double espresso.
Steven
- It's just a joke.
- and I'm busting a gut.
Alright, I'll be there in a
half-hour, 12:30 at the latest.
Why'd you go in there
on your day off?
Are you still trying to make up
for that Mike Vargas thing?
I'll be there at 12:30, all right?
More and more office workers insist on the
right not to breathe secondhand smoke.
And more and more scumbags don't care.
Well, Bridget,
you're an adorable person.
Sexual harassment.
What are the guidelines?
Who can say?
I hate my job, Ev.
But I love watching you do it.
Don't look now.
Gosh, Mr. Reporter, is that what
real newspapermen get to read?
Well, Dale Porterhouse:
"No, I couldn't have heard the shots.
Because all the windows
were rolled up and I had
the radio playing and
the air conditioner on.
That's probably why
the car overheated. "
Close quote.
That's another wild hunch
down the drain.
My condolences.
No great loss.
Look, anybody calls...
...I'm at the zoo.
Me too.
Good morning, Frank.
I thought maybe...
...if there's anything
I can do for you...
Is there anything you'd like
to talk to me about...
...I want you to know I'm here,
I'm available.
I understand you're
a Bible reading man
That's right, isn't it, Frank?
But, you know...
Frank,...just reading the Bible
isn't enough, isn't it?
No.
Man can't go to his Maker with
the sins of his soul unrepented of.
With the hurt he's caused
folks just, you know...
...unrepented of.
A lot of folks would feel
better to hear...
...you were remorseful
for the pain you caused them.
You could do a lot of good
with those words Frank.
I don't have anything to tell you.
Frank..
Reverend Shillerman...
...I want you to leave.
I have my own pastor coming later.
Well son
Son, I don't need to tell you...
That there's will come a time,
and I'm afraid that time is not far off
Reedy!
...when you'll wish you'd made
a different decision.
But it will be too late.
Reedy!
What can I get you, Frank?
I want you to get this damn
fool out of my face!
He call himself a man of God.
Reverend Shillerman!
Reverend Shit-For-Brains.
Now, Frank...
...I myself wouldn't want to
be strapped to that table tonight...
...with the wrongs
I've committed unrepented of.
Because when they stick that
needle in your arm...
Jesus Reverend. Come on
...feel your blood run to ice!
Reverend, that's enough!
Reverend. Come on
Get him out of here!
I feel sorry for you, Frank.
I feel sorry too. Believe me.
I mean it.
We don't want no trouble.
All right.
I just felt it's my job.
It might be upsetting...
Everyone wants in on the
action, right, Frank?
Frank?
Well twelve hours from now,
convicted killer Frank Beechum...
...will be executed
by lethal injection.
Beechum was convicted six years ago...
...of the brutal
slaying of 20-year-old
coed Amy Wilson and
her unborn child...
...at Pocum's Grocery in the
Richmond section of the county.
Wilson, who was married
with six months pregnant...
...was working
when Beechum shot her...
...during an argument over $96
she owed him and was unable to pay.
Now the weather:
Morning low clouds with
some afternoon clearing.
Mostly cloudy tonight
Help you?
Yeah, I'm a reporter
from the Oakland Tribune.
Isn't this where
Amy Wilson was killed?
It sure is.
She was right behind
this same counter.
Almost six years ago exactly.
Mr. Pocum says...
...the needle's too good for him.
For Beechum.
They ought to bring back the chair.
That's what I say.
Really let him have
a jolt of something.
What's back there?
Bathroom.
Mr. Pocum was always nice...
...about letting folks come in
and do their business.
Well I'll come back
some other time maybe
and maybe do some really
serious shopping.
Am I going to be in the newspaper?
Was there something here before?
Yes sir, that's where
the potato chips used to be.
But Mr. Pocum moved
the rack over here...
...so it'd be what you call...
...an impulse kind of purchase.
This in that story you're writing?
That's a good point.
No. I'm writing a human-interest sidebar.
Do you know what that is?
No, I don't think I do.
I don't think I do either.
Sorry, I got hung up.
Daddy!
Aren't we going
to the zoo today?
Yeah
Well, what's holding us up?
Don't you want to get dressed?
- Come on. Let's change your clothes.
- What animal do you want to see?
Daddy, I want to go see
the hippopotamus.
Come on, let's change your pants.
I tell you,
looking into those eyes...
...I don't think...
It was like looking into the eyes
of a goat. Something like that.
They were that cold.
I can't honestly say that
I've ever wished anyone dead.
But I think I'll feel a lot safer
when Frank Beechum's gone.
That's Dale Porterhouse, an accountant
with the firm of Stokes and Whitney.
Mr. Porterhouse was the
state's key witness
in the Wilson case
six years ago...
...a case that will finally culminate
at one minute past midnight...
...with the execution by lethal
injection of Frank Beechum.
Information. What city, please?
For Oakland please, for
a Stokes and Whitney.
It's an accounting firm.
The number you requested is...
Come on, let's go. Daddy's here.
Steve, what is it?
Just a hunch I've got.
Bear with me.
Tonight, finally, is the execution.
It's been a long six years. Do you
feel justice is finally being done?
Hi. Is Dale Porterhouse there, please?
- Mr. Porterhouse is at lunch.
- Get off the phone, Daddy.
Right now!
This is Steve Everett. I'm a reporter
with the Oakland Tribune.
Could you have him call me?
It's about the Beechum case.
Nothing will end that rage
except the death of the monster...
...who killed my daughter
and my unborn grandchild.
I'll give you my beeper number.
You're not taking that beeper!
Just a second, it's just a hunch.
No big deal.
Yeah, it's 5-5-5...
...1-4-3-9.
- I'll make sure he gets it.
- Thanks.
Okay, sweetheart, what do you think?
Are you ready for the big hippo?
Come on
You want to go in the den with Dad?
I'll show you something
Dad's got to take with him.
Not the beeper.
Right? Not the beeper.
Let's pick up my beeper.
This goes "beep, beep, beep. "
Yeah, it goes "beep, beep, beep. "
Come on, get your jacket on.
And now we're just hours away
from the actual time of execution.
Daddy, I want to go see
the hippopotamus.
After a break,
we'll be talking to someone...
...who thinks capital punishment
is never the solution.
I love you!
Bye, Katie!
Have a good time! I love you.
I love you too, Mama.
Wait!
You forgot the car seat!
Mother, I'm too big for a car seat.
We'll put her in back.
How about that?
Put her in the back seat.
Seat belt!
Daddy
Don't forget the seat belt!
The seat belt, Steven!
It's fine. It's fine.
I should've never stopped
by that grocery store.
Oh, God!
Beep, beep beep
Hi. Dale Porterhouse, please. This is
Steve Everett the Oakland Tribune.
Be with you
in just a second, darling.
This is Dale Porterhouse.
What can I do for you?
I'll be ready in a second, darling.
We'll go in a second.
Mr. Porterhouse, this is Steve Everett
of the Oakland Tribune.
I'm covering the Beechum
execution tonight.
I thought you were one of
the chief witnesses in that.
Just a second. Just a second,
sweetheart. Okay?
I was wondering if I could
have 10 minutes with you.
It'll be 10 minutes tops
I'd be glad to.
I can't talk right now.
I could meet you later though.
Yeah, where?
How about we meet down stairs at
a restaurant call Bread Company.
You know it?
Yeah, I know it exactly.
- On Ninth Street, isn't it?
- Yeah
How about I meet you
there in a half-hour?
Okay. Half-hour it'll be.
Thanks. Bye.
Okay, baby.
Come here. Come on.
But I'm too big to sit in a stroller!
That's nonsense. We're going
to play this game called Speed Zoo.
Speed Zoo?
Monkeys!
- Giraffes!
- We go fast.
Birdies!
Speed Zoo!
Camel lips!
We go fast.
We go fast!
Where's the hippopotamus?
Elephants! Look at the elephants.
Speed Zoo!
I want to see the hippopotamus!
We go fast.
I want a hippopotamus!
I'm sorry. I wouldn't have
this happen for the world.
I want my mommy!
I know, sweetie.
Daddy's sorry.
Oh, my God! What happened to you?
She's a real trooper,
I've got to tell you.
What the hell's the matter with you?
How you holding up?
Like I said, there's always a chance.
But with all the feeling
about the girl and all...
You know how the governor's
tough on crime.
So Mr. Berris says that maybe...
...if you just tell him
about how remorseful you feel...
You know what I'm saying?
- I didn't do it.
- I understand.
I'm just telling you that's what
we're facing here, all right?
I can't say I'm sorry
for what I never did.
I'll call you as soon as
the appeal comes down. Alright?
Hi, Daddy.
I brought you a picture,
but it's not finish...
...so I have to finish it, okay?
Hold on a second sweet heart.
They're going to let me in.
Don't be sad now.
We're not going to be afraid. Huh?
Give Daddy a big hug, please?
Come on, don't be sad. Don't be afraid.
We're not gonna be afraid.
I'm gonna finish my picture now,
Daddy, okay?
You do Daddy a favor, okay?
Now, walk over here with me, okay?
I want you to sit right here while
I have a little talk with Mommy, okay?
Give me a kiss.
Come on.
Come on, now.
You know I'm just going home
to dreamland, that's all.
Look. It's green pastures, Daddy. See?
Here's the blue sky.
I made it at the motel.
Gonna be holding two places
at the table for us. Okay?
We're not gonna cry.
I'm sorry. Okay.
We know I'm going to a better
place beyond this place, right?
Okay
The thing I worry about most
in all this...
No, she loves you.
She loves you.
I don't want her
to ever think her daddy did...
She won't think that.
She knows you.
I can't find green, Mama.
Do you have it?
All the crayons are
in the box, honey.
Well, I can't find it.
Don't you ever let her think it.
You do that for me, okay?
I swear.
It's lost.
I can't find it anywhere.
Can you use another color, honey?
I have to have green.
It's green pastures!
Just look for it baby.
It's got to be in here somewhere.
I'm sure daddy won't mind
if you use another color dear.
Okay, baby.
Calm down.
Calm down, honey.
Mrs. Beechum?
What parking area did you use?
Yeah, just a moment.
It's your lawyer again.
- Frank?
- Yeah
We lost it.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Berris will be at the governor's
desk this late afternoon.
Alright?
We got to be honest
about what's going on.
- You know what I'm saying?
- Okay
I'm really sorry, Frank.
We tried, but you know,
it just didn't work.
Okay
I don't know what else to say.
I'm so sorry.
Okay
God bless you, Frank.
- So is there anything?
- No, nothing yet.
You know how these legal things are.
They probably take forever.
Control, we've located the material.
Copy that.
Good news.
They found the crayon.
It'll be here momentarily.
You hear that, sweetie?
Now you can show Daddy
some real pastures.
- Green pastures.
- That's right. Baby's green pastures.
Come here.
Your green is coming.
Told you they would find it.
I believe there's such a thing
in this world as good citizenship.
A man sees an injustice, let alone
a cold-blooded murder, I believe he has...
Let me get this straight.
You didn't really see the murder.
Of course not.
I never said I did.
Well, what did you see?
Mr. Everett, I've been
through this so many times.
I can't tell you how many...
I have trouble getting
it into my head.
It's simple.
I went into Pocum's to use the phone.
My car had overheated.
As soon as the door
slammed behind me,
Beechum jumped up from
behind the counter.
They was covered with blood
and he had a gun in his hand.
I guess it was the point when
he was bending over Amy...
...I mean, Mrs. Wilson,
stealing her ring and her necklace.
He got one good look at me, and
then he ran out the service entrance.
My concern is for the girl,
so I immediately dial 911.
I figured...
...why should I run after a killer
who's got a gun in his hand...
...when I can let
the police do their job?
And they sure did it, didn't they?
Yeah, they sure did.
Like I said, we live in a country
where there's a rule of law.
I mean, an ordinary citizen
who does...
Aren't you going to take notes
or something or use a tape recorder?
Usually when I'm talking
to a reporters...
...they want to keep a record
of what I've been saying.
I've got a photographic memory.
What?
Is that some kind of joke?
No, I have a notebook right here.
Just having an off day.
You'll have to excuse me.
Slow day.
Yeah, well...
- My point simply was this: A man...
- Mr. Porterhouse...
...let me cut to the chase.
Are you absolutely sure
about your testimony?
Absolutely. Why wouldn't I be?
You saw Frank Beechum's face
and the gun?
If I had doubts about my testimony
Mr Everett, I would've told the police.
That must have been scary, having him
point that gun right at you.
No. Thank God, no.
It wasn't like that.
Was it above his head?
No, he had the gun down
by his side in a very normal way.
How could you have seen
over the potato chips?
What?
What potato chips?
I had a perfectly clear view.
Look, right here. Here's where
you come in the main entrance.
You look across and see Beechum
going out the service entrance.
Right here in the center
is a rack of potato chips.
I don't know how
you could have seen a gun there...
...unless he was waving it
over his head or something.
Why would I say I saw a gun
if I didn't see a gun?
I don't know.
Maybe you like telling the story...
or...telling the police or reporters
something they didn't already have.
Maybe you like telling the
girls around the office
around the coffee
machine, stuff like that
This is absolutely absurd.
You actually think that
I would jeopardize a man's life...
...in order to impress the girls
around my office?
I don't know, Mr. Porterhouse.
We only just met.
That's right, Mr. Everett.
But I did some checking on you
before I returned your call.
You're the guy who led
that crusade to get the
rapist released last
year, aren't you?
That lying what's-his-name?
You wouldn't be referring
to the Mike Vargas case, would you?
Had all your facts straight
on that one too, didn't you?
Then they threatened him with
the DNA test. The guy confesses.
I'm surprised
they didn't fire you on the spot.
So am I.
Look, I'm sorry.
I just thought...
I don't know what I thought.
Hello...
Can I tell you about our
specials today?
All right, lunch is here
and the drinks are cold.
Who gets the roast beef?
Over here, Zach.
Here you go.
Seems like there's more fat
and less meat every time I get this here.
Ain't that the way you order it?
Hold the meat, leave the fat?
Hey Arnold's all right.
The more of him, the better.
Okay, what do you say we do some
work while we feed our faces?
You all know that at 1800 hours...
...the whole staff meets here
for a final briefing.
Excuse me, Warden.
Right
Reverend Shillerman here will hold a
prayer meeting at the end of the briefing.
Which is optional for anyone
who wants to stay.
Also be advised...
...there's a change
in the 1600 interview thing.
The girl had some kind of accident.
They've replaced her with
a guy name Everett.
Damn!
Now I realize his butt ain't quite
up to the standard of Michelle's...
...but that's who's coming anyway.
Everyone clear on that?
Well, speak of the devil!
Alan here tells me I'm
paying you too much.
You can rest assured I'm frittering
it away on women and booze.
You're a real dyed-in-the-wool
son of a bitch Everett.
Anybody ever tell you that?
Just close friends and family.
- I'll come back later.
- No, I was just leaving.
Still sober as a judge, right?
Well I guess you haven't been partying with
the Alameda County judges lately.
Yeah, sober as an ex-drunk, sir.
Good to see you, Steve.
Alan
Stop fucking Bob's wife.
He doesn't like it.
What'd he do, put it in
the company newspaper?
Listen, if he comes to
me and wants your ass,
I going to have to give it to him.
and then you'll just be a hole
with no ass around it.
You know what, Ev? You're a fucking
womanizer, that's what.
You been fuck up your whole career,
you fucking up your marriage.
and If you can't keep your
prick in your pants,
then I can't god
damn protect you!
How was she?
None of your damn business.
Not bad.
Lucky bastard! I always liked her.
I respected her.
Hey did I ever tell you
about that assistant
D. A. I was banging in New York?
No, and if you start telling me now, I
gonna come across that desk and rip
your throat out
with my bare hands.
I'll save it for another day.
Edifying story though.
- Look I've got this problem.
- The nickel finally drops!
You do have a problem.
Didn't I tell you that
Bob has been gunning
for you since the
day he got here.
In his quiet, earnest, reasonable way.
He's probably glad
you banging his wife.
Now he has an ethical
mandate to annihilate you.
That's great, I live to make
him happy but that's not the problem.
You should've fuck my wife.
I'd just punch you out!
I did fuck your wife.
Lucky bastard. How was she, good?
A real wildcat but
that's not the problem.
What's your problem, huh? Tell Papa.
You can come to Papa, you soulless
sack of shit. Come on. What is it?
It's a..
Frank Beechum.
I think he may be innocent.
After the briefing, Arnold going
to be checking the phones in the chamber...
...make sure the whole
telephone lines are working.
Don't want the governor
to get a busy signal.
Don't worry. I got call waiting
for him on that line.
Christ, Atkins!
Reuben, make sure the clocks
are synchronized.
And the one in the press room too.
You've got the strap-down team.
I myself had
a personal heart-to-heart...
...with the prisoner myself
this morning.
And going by my experience with the men,
he won't be any trouble.
In my opinion.
All right.
What have you got on Beechum?
Oh Ev
- Ev
- Alan. Yes
No
- Look, listen to me...
- I don't have to listen to you!
I'm looking at you. I'm looking and...
...I can see a reporter who's
about to tell me he has a hunch!
I've been checking some things.
You know my opinion
of reporters who have hunches?
I interviewed this witness who said
he saw a gun. I don't think he saw a gun
I can't fart loud enough
to express my opinion!
Even Michelle thought
the whole thing stunk.
She thought there
were discrepancies.
Discrepancies?
After a police investigation,
a trial, what? Six years of appeals?
and you found discrepancies? How long
did it take you, what? Half an hour?
You know the court system goes.
His first attorney was probably
some 12-year-old legal-aid guy.
He couldn't object
enough for the appalet
court to even make an
intelligent decision.
- If they could make one.
- Ev, Come on.
I got your appeal.
Come on, they're going
to kill the guy tonight.
All right.
Man, I must be on acid!
So you're trying to tell me that you want
to turn a routine execution piece...
...into some fight-for-justice
story...and what?
...that would give me an excuse
to stand up for you...
...when Bob asks me to transfer
you to the toilet. Is that it, huh?
Alan, I need this.
You not going to get your
wife and kid back. You know that
No, she gonna find out.
I'll fix that.
I can't tell you
what will happen
if this turn into another
Mike Vargas piece. Okay?
So you come up with something, fine.
I'll run it.
But man it had better be good.
The Mike Vargas thing,
I was drinking.
You lose your nose
when you're drinking.
My nose is back.
Well, we'll both find out, won't we?
Just one thing.
If I do come up with something,
we can't wait till
tomorrow to run the story
Oh my god! I know what
you're thinking. You know,
It's like dogs that hear a hyphen
sound that humans can't hear.
I can actually hear your little brain
ticking away. I really can.
and let me just remind you
if you go to Lowenstein
thinking he'll call
the governor...
The governor will listen to Lowerstein.
It better be awfully
fucking good.
Or he not only won't
call the governor...
...he'll eat your heart and throw
carcass you to the dogs.
You won't have to bone his wife, pal.
He'll fire you for free. Okay?
Thanks Alan.
Ev, you don't have to thank me.
Because honestly god,
I don't know whose ass
you're trying to save,
Beechum's or your own.
But if your nose for a story is gone,
my friend, you are gone too.
Because I not going
to run this paper...
...to salvage what's left
of your smarmy existence.
So look you stand there
and you look me in
the eye and you tell
me, man-to-man:
Was she pretty good?
- Seriously.
- Fuck you.
Lucky bastard!
Go get them, tiger.
I don't know what to say to you.
Been trying to thinking all
morning figure out
...what it was I wanted to say
to you, and I don't...
I'm sorry, Bob.
I really am sorry.
I don't think you are.
I don't think you're
capable of feeling sorry.
You're not capable of feeling
anything for other people.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe you're right, Bob.
How'd you find out?
She told me.
She told you?
She saved your cigarette
butts and put
them in an ashtray by
the side of the bed.
It's her way of letting me know.
Well I guess that's all I was, a
way of getting your attention.
If it helps any, I feel awful.
It doesn't help.
That is so beautiful, sweetheart.
I'll keep it with me always.
I promise you.
Can we come back tomorrow?
Can we stay at the motel again?
Tomorrow.
Well..
Tomorrow you and Mama get to go home.
I don't want to go home.
I want to stay with you.
Come on, sweetie.
You're a big girl now.
You know what's going
on here, don't you?
Yes
Now, you know, after today...
...you won't see Daddy no more.
But I will be there in spirit.
I promise.
You can talk to me
whenever you want, all right?
You remember when we talked
about little baby Jesus?
Remember that?
Well, I will be up there with Him.
And I will be watching you.
And I'll wait for you.
And if you want to talk to me anytime,
I will be there...
...listening.
I'll miss you so bad, honey.
I wrote you a letter.
And your mama will have it...
...when you need it later on, okay?
You go on now.
Gail, you want to take these, honey?
Take these, okay?
Come on. It's time.
I love you.
I'll always love you, Gail.
Okay?
Why can't you just come home?
Why can't you just kill
all these people and come home?
Don't say that, Gail. Please!
Don't ever say that, okay?
Don't ever say that. Okay?
I love you, baby!
I'll always love you.
Goodbye, Daddy!
Goodbye!
Oh, God!
It's too much.
She loves you. I know, honey.
Remind me not to start
a life of crime.
They lie, you know?
- Who's that?
- Prisoners.
That's what they do.
Every word they say is a lie.
Well, everyone lies, pal.
I'm just here to write it down.
You've got 15 minutes, Mr. Everett...
...by order of Warden Plunkitt.
Reporter arrives for an interview
Keep to 15 minutes.
Mr. Everett, Frank Beechum.
All right, have a seat.
I got them.
So how's that girl?
The other, Michelle?
I heard she was in
some kind of accident?
Yeah, she was.
She was in a car wreck.
She didn't make it.
Oh, man.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Thanks.
I guess you want to hear...
...about how it feels to be in here.
Yeah, it's a human-interest piece.
I feel isolated.
I feel fear.
Fear of pain.
Fear of prison.
Fear of being separated
from my loved ones.
All those fears rolled up into one.
Never having a chance to see
my daughter draw pictures like this.
She says it's Green Pastures.
I want to tell everyone that...
...I believe in Jesus Christ,
our Lord and Savior.
I believe I'm going to a better place.
And there's a better place,
better justice there.
I came into my faith...
...late in life.
Did a lot of bad things
when I was younger. You know?
Anyway...
...I believe the crookeds will
be made straight.
That's what the Bible says.
I believe that.
So that's how I feel about it.
Is that all right, Mr. Everett?
You got nine more minutes.
I mean, is there any more
that you want?
Mr. Beechum, you don't know me.
I'm just a guy out there
with a screw loose.
Frankly, I don't give a rat's ass
about Jesus Christ...
...and I don't care about
justice in this world or the next.
I don't even care what's
right or wrong. Never have.
But you know what this is?
What is this, some kind of joke?
No, it's no joke.
That's my nose.
To tell you the pitiful truth,
that's all I have in life.
When it tells me something stinks...
...I have faith in it,
like you have faith in Jesus.
When my nose is working well,
I know there's truth there somewhere.
But if it isn't working...
...you may as well drive me off
a cliff because I'm nothing.
Lately...
...I'm not 100% sure...
...my nose has been working that great.
So I've got to ask you...
...did you kill that woman or not?
What?
What happened at that store that day
Amy Wilson was shot?
I went into the store to buy
a bottle of A-1 Sauce.
and you paid for it at the counter...
No, I never got it.
I told everybody this.
Why are you asking me this?
Tell it again. To me.
I went into the store...
...to buy a bottle of A-1 Sauce.
I didn't know where it was.
So I saw Amy standing
behind the counter.
- Hey, Amy.
- Hi Frank
Where you keep the steak sauce?
It's in the back. See where the
ketchup and relish is?
You know Frank I've been
meaning to talk to you.
I don't have it.
I mean I could give you 30 now,
but I don't have it all.
When can you give me the whole 96?
When I get paid, July 15th.
You're not gonna always
do me like this, are you?
No, I swear. It's just, the end of
school year. We have extra expenses.
All right, then.
July 15th?
July 15th.
Mind if I use the bathroom?
You know where it is, right?
So you weren't mad about the money?
I just wanted her to know I didn't
do business that way.
She was cool. I liked her.
- Were you carrying a gun?
- No
So then what?
I asked her, could I use her restroom.
I went in to use the restroom,
and the next thing I know...
...there was a gunshot.
That's all you got?
It's the Fourth of July
and we're not that busy.
- Give me the fucking chain!
- Not that!
Give me the fucking chain!
Oh, God. Amy!
Oh, Jesus!
Oh, God!
Sweet Jesus!
Can you breathe, Amy?
Somebody help us!
Hello
Anybody here?
Help!
- "Please, not that. "
- That's what I heard.
Why'd you run?
It was stupid. But I've been running
from something most of my life.
There I was, covered in blood
next to a dead girl right next to me...
...a white man staring at me
like I was... I just panicked.
- Who shot her, Frank?
- I don't know.
Did Porterhouse..did he see a gun?
- You got five minutes.
- I told you there wasn't no gun!
Did Porterhouse see the shooter?
I don't know. How would I know?
Of course he didn't see the shooter.
because by the time he
pulled in the parking lot,
the shooter had already left.
That's why he didn't
hear the shots.
Mr Everett
I don't know. I don't know
anything that happened.
You don't know because
you don't know how long
you were on the floor
trying to save poor Amy's life.
What was this, a random shooting?
Or was there someone else there?
I don't know.
I didn't see anything.
Give me something! God damn it!
What do you want?
What do you people want from me?
Alright that's it.
No
You believe us, don't you?
Do you believe us?
- Bonnie, don't.
- Do you believe us?
Yes! I believe you.
For Christsake!
Where's your god damn heart?
Don't these people have enough?
What do you think this is?
Then where were you?
Dear God! Where were you
all this time?
It wasn't my story.
There was an accident...
Where were you?
Everett?
Warden.
You know, people come
in here, the press.
Prisoners tell them things.
All kind of heart-wrenching things.
And the next day in the paper,
we're the one come off
sounding like hard guys.
It can get pretty frustrating, is all.
Yeah, of course.
We have to do what
the state tells us to do.
Makes it a little tough on us...
...if we show up in the paper
as bloody murderers or anything like that.
Yeah, I understand. Completely.
Knew you would.
You know these things go through
all kind of trials and appeals...
...before they get to us.
There's no use trying to figure out
who's naughty or who's nice...
...and then come sliding down the
chimney like a hero.
Not on execution day.
You're not Santa Claus.
No such thing as Santa Claus.
Warden?
You're not really sure, are you?
You drive safe now.
- Cecilia, I want to talk.
- Not a good time.
- No I got to talk to you
- Not now. Call my office.
- This is important, really is
- Please, just back up.
Back off, will you?
What are you, a court
attorney or something?
Go ahead and hit a reporter.
See how long you keep
your god damn job.
- Why don't you get in the car?
- Yeah, why don't you get in the car?
New York asshole!
- What is it?
- Frank Beechum. Who else was there?
Are you back on the bottle again?
There was Frank Beechum, there was
Nancy Larson, there was Porterhouse...
- Who else was there?
- What's the difference does it makes?
Come on. The one that shot Amy.
I don't know what kind of
cock-a-many-conspiracy
theory you're working on this time...
...but we've got a solid case here.
I don't send innocent men to death house.
I know that. I do.
But you made a
mistake this time.
Look, he was just in there
using the bathroom.
He went in there for some steak sauce.
You've always been
a gullible son of a bitch.
Read the transcripts.
A witness saw Beechum with a gun.
He couldn't have.
Not through the potato chips.
Are telling me he said that?
I saw it in his eyes.
I could tell.
- You haven't got jack shit.
- How much jack shit do I need?
Now come on. There was somebody,
wasn't there?
A kid. He bought a
Coke from the machine.
He didn't even look inside.
He's the one who killed Amy.
We interviewed him.
We issued a description of his car.
It came in
His story checked out...He wasn't even
The plain fact is you had
Frank Beechum in custody.
So you thought you had the
right person but you didn't
- This was the right guy.
- He was nothing to the case!
He even put him in a
lineup with Beechum.
Both witnesses look right at him
and still fingered Beechum as the killer
The fact is, he was long gone before
the witnesses even got there.
Just give me his name.
How can I suppose remember
after six years?
- He was nothing to the case!
- You've got files! God damn it!
Call my office in the morning.
I'll try to help you out if I can.
You wait till morning,
you better sleep god damn well tonight.
Because after today, I'm gonna haunt
the shit out of you Cecilia
I'm gonna haunt your ass all over
this goddamn town.
I am not Wally.
I'm a lot bigger than Wally.
You threaten me again,
I'll have pieces of your
life thrown in the gutter...
...and I'll blow the rest away.
One more thing, barfly.
I think you ought to know this before
your latest lost cause confesses.
Did anybody ever tell you that Beechum
volunteered for a lie detector test?
And he flunked it big time.
Sure, it's inadmissible.
It you didn’t read it
in the transcripts...
...but it certainly captured
our attention.
So why don't you just go pour yourself
a tall one and think about that?
- Hey Ev
- Tom
You want a nip?
No, thanks. I'd better not.
Sorry, I forgot.
What's with you and Bob? He's been
giving you the evil eye all day.
You know something,
it's starting to work.
Oh really?
Did something happen up at the
prison? Some big uproar?
Tom why would a guilty man volunteer
for a lie detector test?
Happens all the time. Perp gets
cocky, thinks he can slide one by.
Of course, innocent men
flunk them sometimes too.
Why, does Bob want you to take one?
That's a cute idea.
No. I don't think
my guilt's in any doubt.
Where's Bridget? I want her
to do some scutwork for me.
Women feel much more secure
in the workplace now these days.
She we home. But I'll get
your coffee if you give me head.
Better yet, why don't
you track down an
investigator in
the Beechum case.
See if they can find out
there was another...
...witness on the murder scene.
A kid. Just an address
and a name will do.
You got it.
After that, get me some
coffee will you tom?
Oakland Police.
Sgt. Bartlett speaking.
Yeah. This is Donaldson at the Tribune.
Who headed the Beechum case?
Anyone there know the Beechum case?
All of us. Anyone here.
Before Beechum comes to the store...
...there's another witness
come into the parking lot, right?
Wrong. There's nothing
like that in the files.
- How do you know? Have you looked?
- Believe me, we know.
Everybody here has
memorized these files.
There are no other witnesses.
Porterhouse and Larson, that's it.
But a lot of circumstantial.
This is Donaldson over at the Tribune.
On the Beechum case, was there
a record of a kid who was a witness?
- A kid?
- Yeah
I don't think so.
- You're sure?
- Thanks anyway.
All right, thanks.
That was the whip in the investigation.
He says it rings a bell. But turn up to be
nothing he doesn't remember any names.
Ardsley, who headed the investigation,
retired. Florida somewhere.
Shit!
Everett! Come here.
Everett
- Don't look so happy about it.
- Who said anything about being happy?
I understand your
prison interview went
beyond the requirement of
a human-interest sidebar.
I colored outside
the lines a bit,
but I don't think the warden
wasn't sore about it.
Now he just probably thought
you were back on the booze, Steve
By the way, there's no
smoking in the building.
You got a minute?!
I can't put up with this. Okay?
Steve, say you're sorry.
Bob, punch his lights out.
This is not a personal matter.
I gave him an important story
with very specific instructions.
The newspaper made a promised...
- The guy is not guilty.
- Oh Come on!
This isn't a human-interest sidebar.
It's a cruci-fucking-fixion.
Want me to look at the cross and say
"How's the weather up there?"
I've got all the personal crap
right here in this book.
He believes in God.
He thinks he's going to heaven.
He's happy as shit.
He's glad they're juicing him.
- Go ahead write up your sidebar!
- That's not the point. Okay?
Of course it's not the point.
Fine.we take Steve off the
execution and put Harvey on it.
- That's still not the point.
- Well Bob we know what the point is.
You know what the point is?
I can't work with you anymore, Steve.
Maybe you're a good reporter...
everybody seem to think so
...but there's a room out there full of
good reporters who don't have your attitude
and they follow instructions.
I'm done with him.
I can't work with him.
Bob, why don't you hit me in
the fucking face will ya?
I'll fall down. I'll bleed.
I'll do all that. I deserve it.
Then go home and hit your
wife because she likes it.
Nice one, babe.
We can't all live in the world
of your fucking imagination here. Alright?
I not going to hit anybody
no matter what they want,
because that's exactly
what you'd want.
as far as Patricia goes, she
need to find something
outside of our relationship,
she can go ahead find it.
My marriage is none of your
fucking business, number one.
Number two, you're a thoughtless...
...mentally unbalanced man and
I can't work with him anymore, Okay?
I've enjoyed this episode of Oprah here...
Allan I got the shooter.
What?
I don't think we shouldn't
confuse the issues.
The guy who killed Amy
Wilson, I got him.
- Even if it's the guy who shot JFK...
- Bob, shut up!
How do you got him?
I've got him. I know who he is.
All right, who is he?
He's a guy.
He's a guy who was there.
You're telling me that the shooter
is a guy who was there?
Great Steve!
Should I hold the front
page or you want to wait for
two unnamed sources, or what?
The D.A. knows Bob. She knows
about it, she just won't give me the name.
- What about the defense?
- The defense doesn't have it on file.
This is ridiculous.
Bob..
Shut...
...up.
What about the cops?
Well they're sitting on it
if they know about it.
Jesus!
Sorry, Alan. This is just too much.
Alan, I gotta be clear
on this, okay?
This is causing problems for everybody.
I love the paper
but I'm ready to leave.
I can't work like this. This environment's
become intolerable for me.
"Intolerable environment"?
What are you? Some fucking feminist?
Are you a cooze?
What's wrong with you?
Alright, you gotta give me notice.
My contract, if you dump me,
you gotta give me notice.
How much notice do you want Steve?
Six hours and seven minutes.
Testing red. Testing red.
Correction Department
Testing tan. Testing tan.
Testing white. Testing white.
Governor's Office
Testing black.
We're standing in San Quentin's
former gas chamber...
...which is then converted
for lethal injection.
The first syringe delivers five grams
of sodium Pentothal...
...and that will basically
put him to sleep
within a matter of a few
seconds, we're told
Then the injection line will be flushed
with 20 cc's of saline solution...
...and then he'll be given 50 cc's
of pancuronium bromide.
Now that is a muscle paralyzer,
and his muscle will be paralizied at that point...
...he won't be able to breathe.
And finally, 50 cc's
of potassium chloride.
And that'll stop his heart.
Hello..
Yes, this is...
Yeah. This is Steve's wife. Why?
What's the matter?
Something happen to him?
Already, the vultures come...
So steal. Go ahead.
Mr. Ziegler?
Mr Ziegler I'm not a thief.
I'm a friend of Michelle's,
a colleague of hers at the paper.
My friends, most of them knock.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about Michelle too.
She was really topnotch.
A really fine reporter.
So you came to give the eulogy?
Michelle was working on a story.
There's a man at San Quentin who's
going to be executed tonight.
I think he's innocent.
I think the answer may be in
Michelle's papers.
Something Michelle did?
Something she was onto, yeah.
So look!
Great.
I've been going through her things too.
See this?
Gave her this when she was 9.
She loved it.
She saved everything.
Look at this.
I don't know when she did it.
Must have been 4 or 5.
Where'd this come from? Over here?
This anything?
"Warren Russel, 17 years old.
4331 Knight Street. Interviewed
July 7th at own request. "
"Says he bought a soda and left.
Saw nothing.
Something fishy here. "
Mr. Ziegler, that Michelle, she was
really on top of things.
Great!
Sorry, Frank.
We're going ti have to ask
Mrs. Beechum to leave now.
Give us a minute, okay?
Sure.
- Oh God
- No
I don't think I can do this.
I won't get a chance
to say goodbye later on.
So I need you to take care of
yourself and our little girl, Bonnie
You know I will, baby.
- I will.
- And give her this.
And don't forget.
It ain't much, but it's...
It'll be precious to her.
It will be her most precious thing.
I really hate that you have
to go through this Bonnie
I know.
Okay, I love you.
I love you.
I wanted to be there for you.
God knows I wanted to see
my little girl grow up.
If we had just a little bit more time...
We have to be thankful
for the time we had.
It's that it was short.
At least we made Gail.
We made Gail together.
We made something beautiful
in this world.
You look at her and you remember
how much I love you. Okay?
Can you do that?
God, Frank, I'm so scared.
If I can see your face...
I'll talk to you every day.
- If I can see you at the end.
- Come with me!
You going to be talking to me?
If I could see your face!
How did this ever happen to us?
The only thing in my life...
...that made it worth anything.
God bless you for that.
Who's there?
I'm Steve Everett. I'm a reporter
for the Tribune.
Go home!
And quit casing that man's car.
It's almost your dinnertime.
Go home!
- Sorry about them kids.
- That's all right.
I'm just glad to find
you here after 6 years
What, you thought I might've
moved to the suburbs?
Come on in.
And you are...?
Angela Russel.
And Warren?
My grandson.
Is this Warren right here?
It is.
You want to tell me why you're here?
Mrs. Russel, it's very important
that I talk to Warren.
It's important I talk to him tonight.
Oh It is? And what could be so important,
if you don't mind my asking?
There's a man on death row, and
they're gonna execute him tonight.
They say he killed
a grocery store clerk...
...six years ago. An Amy Wilson.
I think he's innocent.
I think Warren knows
something about it.
Why would you
think a thing like that?
Because he's the only other
person that was there.
And how do we know that?
The witnesses didn't see anyone else.
Wait a minute. So, there were witnesses,
even though nobody else was there?
- Yes, that's right...
- No, wait. Help me out here.
I am getting confused.
There was an accountant
and a housewife.
- White people?
- Yeah
And I bet...
...that girl that got killed,
that Amy Wilson...
...I bet she was white too, wasn't she?
Yeah that's right. But I don't think...
You don't think those nice
white people...
...would ever kill that nice white girl.
But they all looked around...
...and what do you know?
There was a black boy.
Look, it isn't like that.
Will you just think
back in your mind?
Think back Six years ago.
Was Warren using drugs
or anything like that?
Yes. He was into drugs.
Did he own a gun?
They all own guns, Mr. Everett.
Don't you know that?
All those black dope-fiend boys,
they all own guns.
Can I just talk to him?
Do you know where he is?
Yes, I do.
And no, you can't.
Look, an innocent man
is gonna die tonight.
Well I have seen a lot of innocent folk...
...die in this part of town,
Mr. Everett.
But it's funny.
I ain't never seen you
around here before.
Mrs. Russel, you're making this into
a racial thing, and it's not like that.
The man on death row,
he's a black man too.
Did you know that?
They'll kill him at midnight.
Now, I can't help unless I
have the facts in this case
The only fact I know, Mr. Everett...
...is that my grandson, Warren...
...he's been in his grave now
going on three years.
Stabbed out there in the park.
My Warren...
...was a loving child.
But I don't remember you
coming around here...
...looking for the facts
when he was killed.
Nobody came around here
looking for the facts then.
Fucking loser!
Goddamn it!
and We're told he's now having
that last meal he requested earlier...
...steak and french fries.
and oddly enough...
...he also requested two
six-packs of Coke.
and in you're just tuning in,
we'll repeat our top story.
Convicted killer Frank Beechum has,
for the first time, confessed his crime.
The confession was made
to the chaplain...
...as an expression of remorse...
...for the murder of Amy Wilson
and her unborn child six years ago.
A source posted to the governor's
office says however that despite this...
...the execution will proceed as schedule
at one minute after midnight tonight.
And in other news, the market
slumped badly...
I am tired.
Aren't you supposed to be sleeping?
Why are you here, Daddy?
I'm here to see you, you little goon.
Where did you go?
A wild-goose chase.
You went chasing?
Yeah
Chasing salvation and
never did find it.
Just disappeared. Poof
- Poof
Poof. Yeah
- Hey
Let me tell you...
About today, I'm sorry.
How about this weekend we'll...
...go and spend the whole
day play Slow Zoo.
Yeah
And this time, could we see...
...the hippopotamus?
Yeah. I've already talked to him.
We have an appointment.
My little Daddy.
I'll go to sleep now.
Okay, I think that's a good idea.
Close them, now.
If this were a bullet...
...you'd be dead.
Bob call you?
What difference does
it make who called me?
I know you're going to apologize.
I know you will try to do better.
But I don't want this anymore.
Because I'm tired.
I just think this'll be hard on her.
It is
Barbara, I can change.
Can't we just erase all this?
I just had a terribly
ridiculous day.
It isn't just today.
But today is the end of it.
Today I understand.
Hell, I know I've been...
...tempted a lot, but...
But I love you, baby.
It's just that I...
I'm just kind of coming apart here,
and I didn't...
I know it's nobody's fault
but my own.
I need you. I got to put
these pieces back together.
I feel sorry for you.
You and your famous nose for a story.
You think you can just...
...sniff your way along, you know?
From one hunch to another...
...one girl to another, one drink to
another when you're drinking.
But I'm not one of your stories, Ev.
I'm your wife.
You can't line up all the facts...
...and think you know something
about me.
Your hunches...
...are shit.
Even when they're right, they're shit.
They're all I've got.
I hope they do somebody
some good someday...
...because they sure as hell didn't
do us any good, did they?
I packed all your stuff.
You can take it now,
or you can come back later.
Please, just get out.
Get out of here, Ev, please.
Just get out.
Sometimes, the governor's aides call me
on matters that concern the governor.
In the course of spiritual
guidance and ministrations...
...I might have misunderstood what
the prisoner said to me.
But these things happen
from time to time.
If he says, meaning the prisoner...
...says, "I'm sorry,"
under these extreme...
You know what you've done, don't you?
Now I have to call the governor.
I have to issue a
retraction to the
press and tell them there
was no confession.
Beechum has his own
pastor anyway.
What the hell do you
think you were doing?
Well sir I..
You made me look
unprofessional Shillerman
Not a good thing to do.
Spiritually speaking.
If any of the men
feel they need counseling...
...I'll be here.
Long as they need me...
You sure you want to do this, Ev?
Does a bear shit on Goldilocks?
I don't know.
I've never been asked that before.
That's the trouble with having kids.
It screws up your quips.
So you're seriously rolling off
the wagon. Must have been a rough day.
Yeah, lost my wife, lost my kid...
...lost my goddamn job.
Is that rough enough?
Did you lose your automobile too?
Because if you start
driving in this...
I'm the best fucking driver
on the planet.
I'm talking to a dead man.
Will you leave me
your stamp collection?
How about filling this up?
I ain't eaten anything all day, either.
Jesus Christ!
Go the fuck home, will you?
Ain't got no home.
I ain't got no fucking home.
You have full confidence...
...the state should sanction an execution
to go ahead satisfy your rage.
Wait. This is got nothing to do about
my rage. Let's be honest.
My daughter was shot and killed
in cold blood for no reason.
He took $96...
...and he  took a ring
and a locket I'd given her...
...for her 16th birthday.
My Warren...
...was a loving child.
That's someone who doesn't deserve
the same rights as a human being.
- Will you be there tonight sir?
- You bet.
July 15?
July 15.
Mind if I use your bathroom?
You know where it is, right?
The fucking money!
Don't hurt me, please.
What the fuck?
This is all you fucking got?
The 4th of July.
We're not that busy.
Give me the chain!
- Fucking chain!
- No, please, not that!
Amy?
Jesus! Amy?
Still on the Beechum's execution story...
...the report we got
just about an hour ago...
...in which Frank Beechum
confessed to his crime...
Are you driving? Hey Ev
Hey Ev
You sack of shit! Let's get going!
There are two executioners.
Each one of them has a button.
and that button is connected
for each of them to a computer...
...that scrambles the circuits
so no one knows who does it the deed.
Brother Beechum, let me
tell you of the Lord.
He is my refuge
and He is my fortress.
He is my God.
And therefore, even in the darkest
moments, even when there is no hope...
...He will deliver you from the snare...
...of the fowler.
Step in there.
That Robinson man on TV, I saw him.
And I started remembering that night
Warren gave me that locket.
Her maiden name! And I started
remembering Warren's face.
I can always read that boy's face.
He did a terrible thing, Mr. Everett.
He wasn't a bad boy, but I know
he did a terrible thing!
They're gonna kill that man
in less than a half-hour.
We can't get to the prison
in that time.
You're right, lady.
Fasten your seat belt.
Reverend, it's time.
Set him up.
There's this boy sold
Warren a gun around that time.
This boy, he's in jail.
He might talk to them
if they give him time off.
Mrs. Russel, I could kiss you.
Release your hands.
Gun it, mister!
We go fast.
Pull over! Pull over
and stop the car!
Don't stop now!
Prepare yourself, all right?
I'm going to attempt this maneuver.
They really ought to do
something about that place.
Boy, something must be going on.
Maybe a fire, another accident
on the curve.
"To all whom it may concern,
be it known...
...whereas the Superior Court and
county of Alameda...
...ordered that Frank Louis Beechum
suffer the death penalty...
...within the walls of
San Quentin prison...
...for the crime of murder in the first
degree with special circumstances. "
I love you.
McCardle. Yes, sir.
We have a go.
Yes sir
But it's too late.
Go! Go!
Frank!
What's up? It's official,
it's for the kids.
I need some charity.
It's charity on toast, baby. Come on.
How you doing?
Thank you very much.
How you doing, sir?
Hey Ev! Kate like that dalmatian?
She loved it.
Even my ex managed to muster up
a little enthusiasm.
In fact I've got to get something
better for Christmas.
Sheepdog, collie,
we got Saint Bernards...
How about a hippopotamus?
Check it out! Local designer,
based on the one at the zoo.
Yeah, this is a beauty.
Think a homeless man can afford this?
You're not homeless.
Well, I'm wifeless and jobless...
...and I live in a hotel.
That's unless...
...you'd be interested
in putting me up.
First of all, everybody said
you have a big fat book contract.
Money's already spent.
Second of all,
everybody says you're
about to win the Pulitzer
Prize or something.
I think everyone's being
a little bit optimistic.
And third of all, I have a boyfriend.
Well, that's good!
Maybe he's out of town
for the holidays.
Cash or charge, Ev?
I better charge it.
I'm charging everything else
these days.
Give me some charity, baby.
It's for the kids.
It's official!
I need some charity on toast!
Come over here, help me out.
Steve!
I know you got some charity.
You famous baby! Rich and famous.
I know you got charity on toast.
Give me some charity. Come on.
It's for the kids.
That's right, come on.
Give me 20, give me 100.
Come on, Steve.
Take it before my wife does,
and get out of here.
A 10?
Steve, you got more than that.
Come on, now. It's for the kids.
It's official.
Come on give some more
All right. All right, newspaperman.
I been here two hours
freezing my ass off.
I'm going home.
You haven't got a home.
I got no wife
and no elves, either.
You want to be Santa Claus these
days, you on your own.
You're right there, pal.
Santa Claus rides alone.
It's for the kids!
Daddy!
Come on!
Come on, Daddy.
Come on, now, Daddy.
Sub edited and resynced by: PEEAN91