CARTER: Colombia is the world's second
largest recipient of U.S. military aid,
receiving approximately $1 billion a year
for training and equipping
the Colombian armed forces.
The revolutionary
armed forces of Colombia
are Latin America's oldest, largest
and best-equipped guerrilla insurgency.
Known by their Spanish acronym FARC,
they have waged a cruel,
50-year campaign of terror
against the government
and the people of Colombia.
Their tactics include bombings,
murder, mortar attacks, kidnapping,
extortion and hijacking.
American soldiers are frequently deployed
to assist in anti-narcotics
and anti-guerrilla operations,
and the American government has posted
over $70 million of reward money
for any information leading
to the capture of FARC leadership.
The Colombian people frequently
take to the streets
to protest the FARC's brutal methods
and to call for the end to the violence
and for the release of
hundreds of hostages.
Although, with its massive cocaine revenue,
the FARC has been able to equip its army
with the most modern weapons of any
terrorist organization in the world.
We have movement on Lago.
GREG ON RADIO: Principal acquired.
Flashpoint Bravo, what is your count?
We are minus two.
Three minutes to full count.
Flashpoint Charlie, slow him down.
I got him, but if I engage now,
this thing blows wide open.
No choice, Charlie. Move for intercept.
Copy that, Alpha.
Abort, Charlie, abort!
(INAUDIBLE)
First rule of engagement,
always know your target.
All right, Charlie,
that's going to take him five.
Proceed to jump point.
- Bang!
- ALL: Surprise!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(IN ELDERLY MAN'S VOICE)
Hey, special delivery for that old bastard.
- CARTER: We got you something else.
- Where is she?
(ALL WHOOPING)
(MEN WHISTLING)
God bless "America".
(FAST MUSIC PLAYING)
(GIRLS WHOOPING)
GIRL 1: Yeah, baby.
(ALL CHEERING)
Very nice. Very nice.
(COMPUTER-GENERATED VOICE SINGING)
For he's a jolly good fellow
(DISTORTED)
Which nobody can deny
- That wasn't supposed to happen.
- STEVE: Again?
Derricks, what the hell
is wrong with you, man?
Don't get hot about it, all right?
Least the brew is cold.
(ALL CHEER)
KEVIN: Cheers.
STEVE: That's a small drink.
- One more thing!
- KEVIN: All right.
In order to maintain the element of surprise
when surveilling from a tall structure,
make sure to watch your shadow-throw
so as not to reveal your position.
(ALL LAUGH MOCKINGLY)
(TOMAS SPEAKING SPANISH)
(ALVARO SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MARIA SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(PLAYING FLUTE)
(MARIA CHEERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- Tomas?
- Tomas!
(BOTH CHATTERING)
(TOMAS EXCLAIMING)
(CAR ALARM BEEPING)
Maria!
(MOURNFUL SPANISH MUSIC PLAYING)
(PRAYING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- Good morning, sir.
- Morning.
Still got you at the desk, Commander?
Fastest way to kill a SEAL
is give him some pencils to push.
I'd rather be pinned down
in a fire fight any day.
Some of us are just born to it.
Let's get out of this prison cell.
What do you know about Colombia?
Specifically the FARC?
Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia?
The most powerful, most dangerous
Communist guerrilla force on the planet.
They have territorial control of
almost half the country.
Been at war with the Colombian
government for 40 years.
NSA intel has the FARC responsible for this.
They kill about 3,000 Colombians a year.
They stay funded by protecting
the cartel drug operations down there.
Right. People up here buy their drugs,
and that money keeps these guys
in bullets and body bags.
- Exactly.
- So what's the Op?
Operation Ghost Watch. Strictly recon.
NSA Keyhole picked this up in
the deep jungle outside of Puerto Limon.
It's about 150 klicks south of Bogota.
Now, this...
One month ago.
This, yesterday.
(WHISTLES)
Roughly triple the under-roof capacity.
So these guys are either
storing up the coke for a long winter,
or prepping for a serious
rumble in the jungle.
Exactly. Our job is to find out which.
We got it on good intel, something major
is going down tomorrow morning.
We're going to ghost in, see what's what.
Go in with cameras rolling,
get it all on tape.
Wait, wait, wait.
You say tomorrow morning?
Yeah. That's right.
We're running this Op in the daylight.
We're all for catching some rays, LT,
but that's coloring way outside the lines.
Got no choice.
They want eyes on the action.
Not before. Not after.
- Questions?
- Yeah.
What about the Colombians?
We're not jointing with them?
Negative.
FARC's got too many hooks in
with the National Army,
and a lot of Ops already have
been blown because of tip offs,
which is why we're going to mission-plan
in the air and helo into the Rio Ariari.
Should be fun.
Wheels-up 1700 hours.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Sir, given the extreme sensitivity
of this mission,
I believe it is my sworn duty
to respectfully inform you
that you are now much too ancient
to effectively lead this team
behind enemy lines.
My ancient memory recalls something about
me almost tackling you to get you from
ringing that bell
at the end of BUDS training.
Okay? Who's dragged you out of
half a dozen bar fights?
That would be you.
Who's got your back 24/7?
Who makes sure that
you come home alive all the time?
- That would be you.
- You're damn skippy.
See you guys on the tarmac.
STEVE: Copy that, LT.
New intel says that it might be a meet
between FARC and Colombian sympathizers.
Now, you have evac here, 20 klicks east.
Safe location and DEA contact here
if you need it.
Now keep in mind, FARC's not just
some hillbilly rebel insurgency.
They don't play.
Every year we pump half a billion bucks
of military aid into the region,
and the guerrillas are still coming.
They are heavily armed and well trained,
and we're playing in their sandbox.
Stay frosty and get ready.
PILOT ON RADIO:
We are entering drop zone.
Word is, Ghost Watch is a go.
Stay on your triggers and watch your back.
- I will see you at happy hour.
- The only easy day...
- Was yesterday!
- ALL: Was yesterday!
(ALL EXCLAIM)
- PILOT: Green light. Green light.
- Give it some!
Prepare to release.
Now!
(WHISPERING)
Stingray Alpha, rally point Bravo.
Careful with these vid packs.
Had to sign for these babies.
Vid on.
Weapons hot.
Commander, Stingray insertion is green,
en route to target.
BOYTANO: Let me know when you have visual.
OP-TECH: Yes, sir.
JENNINGS: Hi, Commander.
Like what we did with the place?
Used to be a radio station.
Works for me.
Nicole Jennings, U.S. Embassy liaison.
Visuals coming up now, sir.
JENNINGS: Your boys better stay invisible.
The Colombian government catches wind of
this unauthorized operation on their soil,
and you will devastate our anti-drug relations.
CIA pulled up a name, Carlos Rivera.
But they think he's been bought
by the FARC.
He set up the factory bombings in Bogota.
And he's got a handler, codename Apotequil.
KEVIN: Nothing blowing.
Switching to spectra.
Got something.
About 10 meters out, 1 o'clock.
SEAN:
Looks like they're paranoid. Stay alert.
STEVE: Magnetic AT-12 mine, Cuban-made.
It's old.
SEAN: Do the job.
STEVE: They're not messing around.
Rendered it inop. Repeat. Repeat.
Inop.
OP-TECH:
Stingray's in the objective perimeter, sir.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Looks like we're losing the satellite, sir.
Get it back.
OP-TECH: Working on it, sir.
Trying to get another bird.
Find someone with another sat.
SEAN: Turn starboard.
We're ghosts here, boys,
spirits of this jungle. You copy?
This is it. I want overwatch in five.
I am on it.
Spectra is on and recording.
SEAN: All right. We eyeball
what they got in their cookie jar,
we catch it on tape, make it back
in time for two-for-one beers, on me.
Stingray Delta. Ready to move.
How's the neighborhood?
Quiet streets, good schools,
no nosey neighbors.
Switching to EM.
Clear on cams, no infrared trip-lines,
no motion sensors.
Going to thermal.
We have got 25 sparks inside,
fairly clustered.
All the guards have two-ways,
RF short range.
Copy that.
- Door is open.
- Alpha advancing.
See you around the punch bowl, boys.
GREG: Stingray Echo, hold your position.
Bogey in truck.
Stingray Echo, watch your six,
you don't want to get splashed.
(ZIPPING PANTS)
He's wearing Colombian Army fatigues.
The Colombians are compromised.
Let's go.
Tango-niner, I am looking at MREs.
Great for waging war on your stomach.
Nothing suspicious.
Affirmative. FARC soldier at Tango-one.
Something feels off about all this.
Delta, what's the count?
Twenty-five spark hits. Fairly clustered.
Taking a look. Wait, one sec.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
SEAN ON RADIO:
Looks like we got big fish.
Some kind of peace conference
between FARC and the Colombian Army.
Looks like we just walked
into the history books, boys.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Tango-six, fuel depot.
Diesel, maybe 1,500 gallons.
No munitions. No nothing.
(SOLDIER 1 SHOUTING)
Thermals moving in from the jungle.
Twenty or more, carrying heavy.
Get the hell out of there!
(CHEERING IN SPANISH)
(GUNSHOTS)
SEAN: Back to insert. Move!
SOLDIER 2: No!
(MEN SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(SOLDIER WHIMPERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
STEVE: Clear! Cover me!
GREG: LT, on your right.
Delta, left flank.
KEVIN ON RADIO: Cover me! I am moving.
GREG: Road's clear. Quick!
Kevin, watch your back.
SEAN: Carter, diversion.
Grenade!
(SOLDIER SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
Overwatch taking fire.
(GREG EXCLAIMS IN PAIN)
SEAN: Now on wheels.
STEVE: Lower defense. Watch my state.
(EXCLAIMS IN PAIN)
I am hit.
(HEART BEATING)
SEAN: Give him some cover.
Let's go! Let's go!
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SCREAMS)
Move out! Come on!
SEAN: Carter, give me a hand.
CARTER: Guys, fall back.
Fall back, fall back.
SEAN: Go, go, go!
Come on. Get him to the boat.
CARTER: He's not breathing.
SEAN: Move, move, move, move, move.
Who are these assholes?
SEAN: Must have been here the whole time.
Knew exactly how far to lay back
and not be detected.
Overwatch, overwatch, come in.
Greg, do you copy? What was his last?
- Taking fire.
- FUBAR, man.
That was some really great intel
on this shitstorm.
You know, if they got Greg,
they knew we were coming.
It's time to leave. Now.
(GUNSHOTS)
Ambush! Ambush!
Take cover! Take cover!
We're naked out here!
Take it back to the jungle.
KEVIN: Carter! Go!
Now! I am coming!
(GRUNTS)
SEAN: Stay down.
CARTER: It's no good! It's no good!
- We're not leaving him here!
- We have to go.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Goddamn setup, man. We walked right
into an ambush. Those guys got skills.
I am thinking AFEUR,
Colombian Special Forces.
Our own Green Berets trained
those sons of bitches.
Something didn't feel right.
I should have seen it.
Bro, look at me.
What's our next play?
(GRUNTING)
(NECK SNAPPING)
We got com.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SOLDIER CHATTERING IN SPANISH ON RADIO)
One of ours is still breathing.
They're moving him to Villavicencio.
What are you thinking?
I figure we get our boy.
Get some payback.
That's definitely not
standard operating procedure, LT.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTING)
They got two jeeps, one truck.
King shit sitting up front in the Hummer.
Oh, just say the word.
I will put one through his right eye.
I got an idea.
Go.
We need a phone.
All right. This village here.
Should make it there in a full day,
if we haul ass.
- We need to stay close to Kevin.
- Yup.
They're going to have teams out tracking us.
Yeah. Well, we'd be out of work
if this shit was easy.
Let's move.
- Anything?
- They have missed two com checks now.
Did you ping their sat phone?
Monitor their ground coms? Something?
Sorry, sir. No bounce-back.
All coms have been down now
for eight hours.
Call NSA, DEA, anyone
who's got a sat overhead.
I want to know what's going on down there.
I just got off the phone
with our embassy in Bogota.
- There's word of an incident.
- What are you talking about?
Sources are calling it an unauthorized
incursion of U.S. military forces.
The story is still developing,
but there is a claim
that the incident involves
the assassination of high level officials
of both the FARC and the Colombian Army.
Holy shit.
SEAN: There's a phone line.
(GOAT BLEATING)
Runs right through the center of town.
- Hold down the fort. I gotcha.
- Reach out and touch someone.
(ROOSTER CROWING)
LT, take cover. Bogey at 2 o'clock.
Spotted it.
Stay down. Stay down. Please.
(WOMAN SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Go, go, go.
(TRUCK APPROACHING)
Hey, we got wheels at 12 o'clock.
Let's go.
And apparently that was rush hour.
(PHONE DIALING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Sir, you got a call here.
It's collect.
What?
Hello?
SEAN: Deep Blue, authenticate.
Sierra Niner Foxtrot Romeo 1-4-7.
Alpha Stingray,
this is Deep Blue authenticating,
countersign Lima 3 Whiskey 1-7.
Stingray, sitrep.
SEAN: We were engaged.
Say again, we were engaged.
They were waiting for us.
Guerrillas took out
some kind of secret peace talk
between FARC and the Colombian Army.
- I need a secure line to the Ambassador.
- OP-TECH: Yes, ma'am.
Take me off speaker. Now.
Stingray, what is your count?
Minus two. One capture.
Sir, these were AFEUR,
Colombian Special Forces.
Stingray, confirm your last.
Minus two. One POW.
Affirm.
Proceed to LZ for emergency exfil.
Negative. We have a location
on our captured asset.
Not going to happen.
We reassess and mission-plan a rescue.
I am not leaving him behind!
You make sure your ass
is on that chopper.
We will get our boy back.
We will do it the right way.
I lost two men!
We lost two men,
and I am not going to lose two more.
You hear me, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
Proceed to emergency evac coordinates.
Rendezvous at 1300.
This is Deep Blue, out.
Son of a bitch!
Get me General Burlings.
Son of a bitch.
- Your call, LT.
- We follow orders.
I knew you were going to say that.
Let's do it.
(MEN CHATTERING)
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
KEVIN: What's going on?
Making you a star.
(KEVIN GRUNTS)
Smile for the camera.
(EXHALES)
You and your friends made quite a mess.
So who sent you here?
I am looking for Colombian chicks.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
- Commander, we have tasked a sat.
- Good.
Bring up the evac LZ.
Go thermal.
Move your asses.
- Where's Swordfish?
- OP-TECH: Swordfish, time to contact?
This is Swordfish, roger that.
Ninety seconds inbound.
Here! Come on!
We got them.
- We have a problem.
- Not now.
PILOT:
Daisy Forge, say again your last, over.
MAN: You are ordered out of Colombian
airspace immediately without pick-up.
What?
But we have them on sight.
Abort. Do not land. They're right here.
- MAN: Return to base.
- What are you waiting for?
MAN: I repeat. Abort. Do not land.
Return to base.
- God damn it.
- Come on!
What the hell is going on?
Why aren't they landing?
They have just been ordered not to.
- From who?
- The Colombian Army.
Commander, we have got vehicles
moving into the area.
LT, we got company.
Turn left!
That was close.
Yee-haw!
Pedal to the metal, Carter.
You best talk fast.
Your men have been declared war criminals.
When the hell did Colombians
get into our chain of command?
- Who ordered the exfil abort?
- Washington.
What? They want this handled
through diplomatic channels.
We can't afford to start swapping
bullets with an ally of the U.S.
REPORTER: FARC leaders have vowed
to increase their terror campaign
against the U.S. controlled
puppet government of Colombia.
This is insane.
This footage is from our own vid packs!
REPORTER: The Colombian government
has issued a statement
condemning the actions of the U.S. military,
and is calling for an immediate withdrawal
of all U.S. armed forces of the region.
They have also released this video
of a captured American serviceman.
It seems talk of peace regarding
Colombia's 40 years of internal strife
is now all but history.
Holy God, this has gone tits-up.
Commander, your men have lost control.
No. I know my men. This is wrong.
This is not right. They have been set up.
Carl Dobb, CIA.
Commander, you are ordered
to stand down immediately.
- I still have men in the field.
- This is no longer a military operation.
Listen up, people.
This is a high priority situation,
I have full NSA authority.
Are there any questions?
(DOOR OPENING)
ALVARO: I am sorry.
I can't untie you.
You Navy SEALs don't know when to give up.
- Who are you? FARC?
- No.
- Colombian Army?
- The FARC killed my wife and my son.
Colombian Army was also at that meet.
You murdered your own countrymen.
Anyone who wishes to make peace with
those monsters are no countrymen of mine.
They are traitors.
(ALVARO SIGHING)
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
(DOG BARKING)
Think it's empty.
I will secure the site.
Everyone went home for the night.
This is awesome.
It's like junior high all over again.
So, why didn't they pick us up?
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH ON TV)
It's the Colombian President.
He looks pissed.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He's calling us assassins.
An American military hit squad
sent to derail the peace talks between
FARC and the Colombian government.
Assassins?
That's not even off our vid packs.
Yeah, somebody wanted
that peace summit stopped.
They wanted us to take the blame for it.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Now he's saying we did it
because the U.S. believes
that as long as FARC is a problem,
Colombians will be dependent upon us for aid,
and therefore will remain America's puppet.
No, no, no, no.
We saw the guys that ambushed us.
The Colombian Army hit
its own peace talks. Why?
(FEMALE REPORTER SPEAKING SPANISH)
- First, we get Kevin.
- I agree.
They're only going to keep him alive
for a few more photo ops.
- Check the radio.
- I am on it.
Got static.
We're too far out of range.
We're going to need a trace,
and we're going to need wheels.
(SCOFFS)
Maserati, Ferrari?
What do you want?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait! This guy.....
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He is the one I saw doing most of the
talking before the bullets started flying.
- Okay. Who is he?
- He's a witness.
REPORTER ON TV: Protesters have been throwing
firebombs at the American Embassy,
shouting "U.S. out of Colombia."
Look, I am sorry about your men.
I need the CIA intel on Rivera
and this Apotequil character.
I want to know who sent my men
into a meat grinder.
Don't know if I can do that.
You and I both know that if the
Colombians get a hold of my men,
there will be no handling it
through diplomatic channels.
- The Colombians are an ally of the U.S.
- They will say my men resisted.
They will say there was a fire fight.
It will be an execution.
Okay.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Boytano.
SEAN: Hey, I had to call your wife
to get your number.
You okay?
What's your status?
Well, we have got everybody in Colombia
on our ass.
You know we didn't do this.
BOYTANO: You're being hung out to dry.
The Company's calling the shots,
trying to save face.
You know, there was a general.
He survived.
He can confirm we're not the shooters.
Yeah, well, he's not talking.
The Colombians are calling it
an act of war.
The FARC has gone apeshit.
They're burning down entire villages.
SEAN: Yeah, great job on the extraction,
by the way.
Washington...
Washington wants to talk this out.
They want you to surrender.
Is that what you want?
(WHISPERING) What do you need?
I need a trace on a radio frequency
in Villavicencio.
What are the numbers?
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Cluster of radio signals, 118 degrees,
four minutes, six seconds east.
Twenty-four, twenty-six, forty-six north.
Traded my last favor for that.
Get our man out alive.
God, this building's poured concrete.
I can't get any heat signatures.
- We're going to have to go in blind.
- It's a tactical nightmare.
- Hostile count?
- Principal's location unknown.
Trident.
CARTER: It's our boy.
All right, I got this. Two guards
on the roof. Two on the ground.
We're going to need a big show.
Give me two minutes.
I will be there for you.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(DOOR OPENING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Where's my gear?
(MEN SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GUNSHOT)
SEAN: Get down!
Goddamn, am I happy to see you.
For the record, I am only here
because you owe Carter ten bucks.
KEVIN: Stop at the ATM on the way out.
SEAN: Let's go!
The gate, it's locked!
Grenade! Get out of here!
CARTER: Meter's running, boys.
- Oof.
- Go.
KEVIN: What took you guys so long?
This thing got seatbelts?
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
- Sure you're all right?
- Bastards made me eat McDonalds.
What the hell are you guys
still doing here?
Carter will fill you in.
We need fresh wheels.
- Where are you going?
- See a sick friend.
(WOMAN CHATTERING IN SPANISH OVER PA)
- Carlos?
- Shut your mouth.
Because you and me,
we're going to have a little talk.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
- What do you want?
- I was there. I saw what happened.
And I know that
you know we weren't the shooters.
- You understand me?
- Understand. I understand.
I am sorry about
what happened to your people.
(EXHALES)
But your government's blaming us.
They're calling us assassins.
Yeah, well, I cannot contradict them.
Why not?
Americans are not very popular
in Latin America.
There are people in my government
who want to see the U.S. out,
completely out of South America.
Then we need to do something about that.
Who were the shooters?
Their uniforms had no markings.
I didn't recognize anyone.
You know they weren't American.
We were set up,
and you have to tell the media that.
I saw the news report.
They say you were the only survivor.
- You're a national hero to them.
- No.
The government will discredit me
and call me a liar.
And then they will shoot me for treason.
No. No, it's too late.
Wait.....
Wait.
Unless you have proof.
I am going to give you a number.
You find anything, you call me.
It's the only thing that can stop this.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
- God, this car smells like boiled ass.
- Hey, sorry.
Okay, it was the only thing I could find
that didn't have goats, chickens,
or people sleeping in the back, okay.
So, did you and the general
solve our little problem there, LT?
His hands are tied
unless we can get him solid proof.
Kevin, tell him what you told me.
The guy in charge's name is Alvaro.
Real intense.
Said his family was killed by the rebels.
There's not a chance in hell this
guy wants to make peace with FARC.
Anything else?
Got a guard to spit out
the location of our gear,
along with a few of his teeth.
I was going to grab the sat phone
as soon as I blew out of that joint.
And that'd be a great idea, except for
the fact that the bastards fragged our phone.
Right.
Our vid packs.
Yeah, the vid packs.
Maybe we have got these assholes on tape.
Proof.
- Let's get our gear.
- 10-4.
This is a major shitstorm.
Colombia's ordered our military and
diplomatic personnel out of the country.
My priority's my men.
(WHISPERING) The intel about the base
was leaked through the CIA through Rivera.
- He was the only source.
- Son of a bitch.
Dobb.
You and your Langley gang
got played by your source.
We need to stop this madness right now.
We are. We're putting together
a scenario linking your men
to a rogue arm of the Ruiz-Mendoza Cartel.
- What?
- You can't do that.
This puts their actions
outside of any political agenda.
Operating on their own.
Bought and paid for
with Colombian drug money.
You're not going to burn
those SEALs' reputations!
Those men have families.
They fought and died for us.
Their sacrifices will not go unnoticed,
just unsaid.
Not by me. Your lousy intel
put my men in this FUBAR situation,
and I am going to get them out.
You will do exactly
what you're told, soldier.
Unless you want to be reassigned
to a cell in Leavenworth.
It's Commander,
and I'd advise you to back off.
So, Kevin, let me ask you,
that fence is wired and hot
and you were going to break into there?
When the guy said barn,
I thought barn. Cows, chickens.
Open space. Cheap, easy to secure.
CARTER: Buildings look old, but they have
had some high-security retrofitting.
Think you can get us in the doors?
KEVIN: No problem. They get all their
security tech protocols from us.
Wait a minute.
- The well.
- Yeah? What about it?
This water tower, that well,
got to be connected, right?
- Some kind of pipe.
- Would be a hell of a thing.
No way.
- All the air we have got.
- He doesn't have enough air.
Hypothermia will get him
before his air runs out.
That is if he doesn't get strangled
first by the root of a tree.
Right. You know what?
You guys suck as cheerleaders.
You're right. Blast our way in,
fight a battalion. It could work.
The only easy day...
- Was yesterday.
- ALL: Was yesterday.
Yeah.
Push the car. Don't start it.
I will go this way.
Come on, come on.
(GRUNTING)
Got anything?
Nada.
I hate to say this, amigo,
we need to start thinking Plan B.
(WHISPERING) He's still kicking.
I know it.
(GASPING)
Come on, come on.
Son of a bitch. He made it.
He made it.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Get ready.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(WHIRRING STOPS)
(ALARM WAILING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SOLDIER SPEAKING SPANISH OVER RADIO)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
CARTER: You don't think they will mind
if we crash the party, do you?
(MACHINE RESTARTS)
(ALARM STOPS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Got this from the security guard.
- Good to see you.
- Yeah.
Let's do this.
They didn't bother to change
the factory pass-code.
(ALARM BLARING)
KEVIN: Here's our gear.
SEAN: Triggered the alarm.
Carter, you have got security.
Watch that door.
Kill that alarm.
CARTER: All right, find those vid packs.
KEVIN: Got them.
CARTER: Good. Check them.
(BEEPING)
- (SIGHS) Nothing here.
- What do you mean?
Nothing. Damn gausser
must have wiped them all.
What do you mean, we have got nothing?
KEVIN: Nothing.
Damn it!
Boys, we got company.
I got the door.
Carter, smoke, ammo.
Got it!
(JEEP HONKING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Damn it.
SEAN: Let's rock and roll.
KEVIN: All good. I am right behind you.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Kevin, let's go.
Fall back to the car.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
KEVIN: We need help.
SEAN: Pop a smoke.
We're in some real pretty shit now.
- Damn it, they got here fast.
- Hoof it or drive?
We will never lose them.
Probably got a helo on the way.
Holy shit. You're right.
Okay. How much smoke we got left?
- I got four.
- CARTER: I got two.
SEAN: That will do.
- I am going to need some cover.
- KEVIN: Got it.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Rock and roll!
- Whoo-hoo! That shit worked.
- SEAN: Go.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
BOYTANO ON RADIO: Yeah.
Commander, we took our shot.
We tried recovering the vid packs.
We came up empty.
BOYTANO: What's your play, Lieutenant?
Play? We can't come home.
Well, how about we go back downrange
and get ours before they get us?
How about that? That an idea?
That's a one-way mission, and you know it.
What's your situation like there?
FARC has started their attacks.
They bombed a school bus, killed 12 kids.
The Pentagon's projecting
civilian casualties to be
a quarter million in the first three months.
Maybe it's time we get our pound of flesh.
Look, we still have time to make this right.
I want you to go back over the mission
in your head.
Everything you heard, everything you saw,
every branch snap, every bullet hit.
- SEAN: Why, what's the point?
- Because I trained you, Sean.
And I sure as hell
didn't train you to give up.
The bogus intel on the Venezuelan alliance
came from Carlos Rivera,
Colombian national,
and a handler, codename Apotequil.
Rivera was responsible
for the bombings in Bogota.
- And I don't know how... Commander!
- But they're tied into all this.
Do what you can, but do it smart.
May I see your phone?
I could give it to you,
but you'd need a proctologist
to read my text messages.
Consider yourself relieved of duty.
You don't have the authority to relieve me.
Actually, Commander, I do.
- What now?
- I still got a few cards to play.
Thanks.
All right. Shut it down.
All right. Mission walkthrough.
- We split up in the jungle.
- Greg had the overwatch.
Greg radioed in starter positions.
SEAN: Right.
CARTER: Greg saw the black hats coming.
SEAN: Greg was watching the base
through the Spectra.
CARTER: Yeah?
Which wasn't with our
gear in the barn, right?
No. It wasn't.
God, it could still be out there.
Yeah. Would have got everything.
Our position, the bad guys.
- Yeah.
- Gear up.
(DIALING PHONE)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I have proof.
Are you absolutely sure?
Everything the world needs to know,
to know that we didn't do it.
Okay. Excellent. Where can we meet?
Puerto Limon, 1700 hours.
Okay, I will be there,
and I pray that what you say is correct.
For if not,
tomorrow will be the bloodiest day
in the history of my country.
Lucky for us, we still have today.
Keep looking, it's got to be here.
Gotcha. Attagirl.
- KEVIN: Yes.
- This clears us.
- When's the General due?
- (SIGHING) One hour.
- Shit.
- Wait a minute, guys.
- What?
- Down there.
Son of a bitch.
How did these bastards find us?
LT, we're against the mountain here,
and the only way out of here
is through them.
I am getting too old for this shit.
This guy stops a war. Don't lose it.
- Great. No pressure.
- CARTER: Options?
Thin the herd. Quiet. No guns.
How did I know
you were going to say that?
This is who we are, brother.
For Greg and Steve.
(NECK SNAPPING)
(SOLDIER GRUNTING)
All you Americans think you're Rambo.
(GUNSHOT)
I prefer John McClane.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
- Alvaro!
- Stop!
(SCREAMING)
- Do it.
- Go on.
Tell your people the truth.
What about your wife, your son,
is this what they would have wanted?
Help me to end this.
Death is all I have left.
Kill me, or I will kill you.
Stand down, soldier.
General Valez, Carter?
We have secured your man.
Where is your proof?
This man's a traitor.
Give him the vid pack.
We have footage of him
killing your soldiers on that.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Alvaro.
You're working with him?
He works for me.
I am his commanding officer.
What?
When I was a little boy,
the guerrillas cut my father's throat,
and they made me watch.
That's why I became a soldier,
to hunt them down.
What about your talk of peace,
those innocent men you killed?
They were your allies.
They sacrificed for Colombia.
They are heroes.
The bogus intel on the peace talks,
and my men... You set us up!
Alvaro, kill him.
Rivera. Videotape the bodies.
Make it look like
they tried to bomb the base.
Rivera, Carlos Rivera.
The factory bombings of Bogota.
It wasn't FARC. It was you.
That is a lie. Kill him, Alvaro.
No, no. Rivera has a handler,
his codename is Apotequil.
Apotequil.
You?
My wife.
My son.
They died heroes for Colombia.
Their sacrifice brought us together.
- You killed them.
- No. America killed them.
The guerrillas killed them.
But now we will win.
We will crush the guerrillas
and we will kick the Americans out,
and Colombia will belong to us again.
Alvaro, I will lead us into a new era.
Two lives? What is that compared to
the destiny of our country?
(GUNSHOT)
You are no soldier.
You die a traitor to Colombia.
He betrayed our country.
He betrayed us all.
This is so wrong.
Then make it right.
BOYTANO: "There is a special breed of
warrior ready to answer our nation's call,
"a common man with uncommon desire to succeed.
"Forged by adversity, he stands alongside
America's finest special operations forces
"to serve his country, the American people,
"and protect their way of life.
(MARSHALING)
"I am that man." SEAL creed.