♪ Food, sex, sleep ♪
♪ Money, health, flow ♪
♪ Speed, love, nurse ♪
♪ Peace, hair, clothes ♪
♪ Dreams, space, fate ♪
♪ Trouble, home, flower ♪
♪ Push, murder, breeze ♪
♪ Water, curves, tan ♪
♪ Alone, mirror, truth ♪
♪ Mother, risk, fall ♪
♪ Shock, color, caress ♪
♪ Hands ♪
♪ Good ♪
♪ Nasty, heat, please ♪
♪ Wit, whims, sperm ♪
♪ Just, you, fool ♪
♪ Empty, laughs, skin ♪
♪ Different, smell, third eye ♪
♪ Hunt, time, fight ♪
♪ Sacrifice ♪
♪ Nicotine, youth ♪
♪ Sane, lies, blue ♪
♪ Info, clear, noise ♪
♪ Reason, teasing ♪
♪ Honesty, hard, soft ♪
♪ Beauty, danger ♪
♪ Curves, tan ♪
♪ Alone, mirror, truth ♪
♪ Mother, risk, fall ♪
♪ Shock ♪
♪ Pain, body, fame ♪
♪ Hear me, free me ♪
♪ Eat me, kill me ♪
♪ Give me, form me ♪
♪ Game me ♪
♪ Heaven, cold ♪
♪ Jealous, release ♪
♪ Subtle, nature ♪
♪ Shelter, energy ♪
♪ Flavor, control ♪
♪ Dirt, street ♪
♪ Scream, ideas ♪
♪ True, hell ♪
Here, let's go.
Open sesame.
Boom.
Big Blue's defense
step it up again.
Look at that big sack
by Justin Tuck
on the Giants' 7-yard line.
Right, right, right.
Little more, little more.
This show in New York
which we call
"Shinohara:
Wham! Pow! Vroom!"
is the idea of action
and also "Vroom!"
for his motorcycle,
because Shinohara has been
making sculpture, you know,
since the beginning
of his artistic career.
He's been famous
for, you know, years.
But now is maybe
one of his key moments.
In the 1960s,
a Japanese painter
came to New York
seeking to create art
that would reflect the city's
prosperity and chaos.
This artist is Ushio Shinohara.
Early morning in SoHo:
cardboard has been discarded
in the streets,
and by walking a couple
of blocks from his loft,
Shinohara can collect all
he needs for his day's work.
At the moment, he is preparing
a new sculpture
using great amounts
of cardboard
while his wife, Noriko,
works on her own paintings.
As a young man in Tokyo,
he emerged as a leader
in Japan's
avant-garde art movement
with his imitation
of American pop art
and action painting.
The quality
of Ushio Shinohara's art
is, to say the least,
in some doubt,
but it does illustrate
the rather frenetic spirit
of rebellion
among some young people--
and not only in Japan,
throughout the world.
When he arrived
in the United States,
he was at once in the limelight
of the mass media.
It is said Shinohara
is the most famous
of the poor and struggling
artists in New York.
While his works
are exhibited across Japan,
American collectors often say,
"That's a wonderful image
but not my taste,"
so most of Shinohara's pieces
have never sold.
Really, what's most important
is that moment when he created
the painting.
This is a result,
but--and a beautiful result--
but also it's the action,
so that's where--
the energy is in there.
- You've met Ushio.
- Nice to meet you again.
Pleasure seeing you.
This is wonderful.
And he also made this
extraordinary new sculpture.
- It gets very good mileage.
- Yeah, I'm sure.
So you put some foam
on the top of it, right?
Yeah.
Two and a half!
Hold on, please.
She's coming soon.
Hi.
Good morning.
Fine, thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, bye.
How are you?
Nice to see you.
Congratulations on your show.
Okay, and we'd also like
to talk also about
the one we're gonna buy
for the Guggenheim Museum,
which one it will be.
Also, there's a piece
that he created.
It's larger,
and in fact, this is the detail.
I'm interested in one that
has, like, a real historical...
No, no, no, no.
Yeah, exactly.
And they're interested--
we're just trying to get--
You know, he needs support,
and he needs to be, you know--
and he's getting it now,
and so you're also very key,
you know,
which is really wonderful.
That's great.
Fantastic.
That's good.
- Can I get a picture with him?
- Okay.
Fantastic. Fantastic.
Fantastic.
That is fabulous!
It looks like a poppy field.
Poppy field? Oh, yes!
Afghan poppy field.
Looks like
an Afghan poppy field.
Yeah,Poppy Field.
It's definitely a poppy field.
Yeah.
It's so important
he's not thinking.
He's doing.
It's so visceral.
It's so different from Pollock.
Pollock was actually
consciously...
It's very, very powerful.
You know, I want to work
to try and find funders
who can help us
acquire the work.
We want one that has
some historical resonance.
But what other ones exist?
The Kamakura one
was photographed in the...
Art in America.
It showed in Art in America.
Okay, so that's the kind
of thing that they like.
That's the kind of thing
I need.
Can you show me a picture
of that?
- We have a copy of...
- We'll give it to you, yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
let's go take a look.
Noriko, I like this one.
I'd prefer this one.
Oh.
Oh, okay.
But there--
maybe we can work it out.
We have to be sure
that Ushio and Noriko benefit.
Exactly.
No, no, that's--
- But we can work this out.
I mean, it's all--
we can negotiate this.
No, no, no,
arigato, arigato.
No, I appreciate that.
Okay, so I need to do something.
It's gonna take some time.
I mean, I'm sorry.
You've already been
so patient with me.
It's just, you know,
we're just...
I'm doing a start-up.
Ready?
One. Two. Three.
Yahoo!
Uh, I'm okay.
Hey.
Can I have a little bit?
- Hi.
I like this very much.
Even from afar I could see
something stronger here.
Something strong is here.
Very nice.
Oh, thank you.
Ooh, good smell.
Huh.
Hello?
How are you?
I bought 15 pounds
of white pigment color.
- 15 pounds?
- Yeah. It was--
- Why?
I'm gonna have an exhibition,
and now I'm painting
at the gallery.
I'm using a big brush
and a small brush
and big Cuties.
Jealousy, jealousy.
Big jealousy.
Mm.
Celery, okay.
both: Quick, quick, slow.
Quick, quick, slow.