- Is this the last one?
- I don't know.
There's no ether, either.
Jesus Christ.
You there! Is this the last one?
God, what a mess.
At least there's no gangrene.
There will be if it doesn't come off soon.
I can't saw if I can't keep my eyes open.
I'm sorry.
Let's coffee up.
He can wait a few more minutes.
God!
Glass.
- Is that Tucker's men?
- Yes, sir. I think it is.
How long has it been like this?
We found 'em this morning, sir.
They've been here for two days.
Is that you, Lieutenant?
Sons of bitches.
Come on. You better take cover
I ain't kidding. These boys are shooters.
Come on. Go under cover
There you go.
You went to the hospital?
It was no good
What's going on here?
That seems to be the question, all right.
See, you could ask the major...
but he don't know
He's busy.
He's busy trying to figure out
how come the officers' mess...
run out of peach ice cream.
Then, of course, you got the general.
He comes up to see the show.
All he knows is there ain't no show...
which ain't entirely correct
'cause we started a balloon up...
but they shot her down
before we got off the ground.
Nobody's made a run either way.
It's been a standoff all damned day.
Now, the major, he's
looking at the general.
He's thinking to himself,
I better do something.
You know what that means.
I sure as hell don't want to be
the first one across this field.
They're supposed to be beat up just like us
Hell, everybody knows
Tucker's men are tough as cobs.
So far, the only thing been killed out here
is three milking cows.
Course, that's about to change
You son of a bitch.
You know, some of the boys are saying
if we ain't gonna fight...
we could just settle
this whole business with a little...
high-stakes poker.
Wouldn't that be a sight?
A bunch of fellas
sitting in the middle of this field...
drawing cards.
What is it, sir?
Looks like a suicide
Tucker!
What's he doing?
- What did you say to him?
- I didn't say nothing.
Come on back, you son of a bitch!
- You won't make it no second time!
- All right by me.
Forgive me, Father.
- He's coming back again!
- Here he comes, boys!
- Ready!
- I got him
Don't...
Don't take off my foot.
You rest easy, son. You'll keep your foot.
With God as my judge, you'll keep it.
- Bring up my ambulance.
- Sir?
Bring up my ambulance,
and bring my surgeon with it!
We got an officer
who's worth something lying here.
The strangeness of this life
cannot be measured.
In trying to produce my own death...
I was elevated to the
status of a living hero.
I was also awarded Cisco...
the trusty mount that carried
me across the field that day.
And on full recovery, was given
transfer to any station I desired.
The bloody slaughter continues in the east
as I arrive at Fort Hayes.
A tiny island of men and material surrounded
by a never-ending sea of prairie.
Lieutenant.
Where can I find Maj. Fambrough?
Down at the end of the hall.
Thank you.
Lt. John J. Dunbar.
Lt. John J. Dunbar?
- Yes, sir.
Indian fighter
Excuse me?
It says here that you're
to be posted on the frontier.
The frontier is Indian country.
I quickly deduced that
you're an Indian fighter.
I did not ascend to this position
by being stupid.
- No, sir.
- No, sir
It says here that you've been decorated.
Yes, sir.
And they sent you here to be posted?
Actually, sir, I'm here at my own request.
Really? Why?
I've always wanted to see the frontier.
You want to see the frontier?
Yes, sir.
Before it's gone.
Such a smart lad, coming straight to me.
Sir...
Knight.
I am sending you on a knight's errand.
You will report to Captain Cargill...
at the furthermost outpost of the realm...
Fort Sedgewick.
My personal seal will assure your safety...
through many miles of
wild and hostile country.
- I was wondering...
- Yes?
I was wondering, sir, how
will I be getting there?
You think I don't know?
- No, sir.
- You think that.
- It's just that I don't know...
- Hold your tongue.
I am in a generous mood
and I will grant your boon.
See that peasant out there?
He calls himself Timmons.
He's going there this very afternoon.
You can ride with him if you like.
He knows the way. Thank you. That is all.
Sir Knight?
I've just pissed in my pants...
and nobody can do anything about it.
To your journey!
To my journey!
Haw!
Over a little bit, Jim!
- Have this by tomorrow.
- Yes, sir.
I'll have my crown now.
- Sir?
- I'll have my crown now!
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Are you deaf, fool?
I said I'll have my crown right now!
Now!
No.
- I'll get your crown.
- No.
Sir?
Major?
The king is dead.
Long live the king.
Get these kids out of here, come on!
Haw, Jim and Jake!
Gee a little bit, Jim!
The hell was that?
What is that?
What the hell is that?
Why don't you put that in your book?
Were it not for my companion...
I believe I would be having
the time of my life.
I know he means well...
but he is quite possibly
the foulest man I have ever met.
How far you make the Fort?
Far.
How far?
Forty, fifty mile, maybe.
What's the big hurry on Sedgewick?
It's to be my post.
My home.
You ain't hard to please,
I'll give you that much.
Look yonder
What you got there?
Somebody back east is saying,
Why don't she write?
You stupid bastard.
Get up, Timmons.
Get up!
Come on. Get up.
Someone poked me in my butt. Was that you?
Goddamn it!
I'm gonna have a welt.
Cpl. Guest?
You don't have to talk to me,
just please come out.
It's the end.
Assemble the men in front of my quarters.
You hate me
But I feel none of the same for you.
You men stayed.
You stayed after they took all our horses.
You stayed after all the others deserted.
You stayed after the army
failed to resupply us.
I have looked for that
wagon from Fort Hayes...
just as you have...
day after miserable day.
And all I can say is that I'm proud of you.
Now get your things, men.
We're leaving this place.
The army can go to hell.
Go.
Get your things.
How come we haven't seen any buffalo?
You can't figure the stinking buffalo.
You can't.
Sometimes you won't see any for days.
Other times, they'll be thick,
like curls on a whore
What about Indians?
Indians? Goddamn Indians!
You just as soon not see 'em
unless the bastards are dead.
They're nothing but thieves and beggars.
Ho, up there!
Not what you would call
much of a going concern now, is it?
Go down there
- Why? There ain't nothing down there.
- Because I said.
Go down there.
There, son of a bitch!
There ain't nothing here, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant!
Everybody's run off or got killed.
All right. Let's unload the wagon.
What? What, and leave it all here?
I'm staying, too.
There ain't nothing here.
No, not at the moment.
We don't know what's happened.
Things being as they are...
we might as well
just turn around and get headed back.
This is my post.
This is my post?
Jesus H. Christ.
What, are you crazy, boy?
Fast son of a bitch.
- Jesus H. Christ.
- This is my post.
All right, put it down.
And these are the post provisions, all right?
Now get your ass off the wagon...
- Put it down!
- And help me unload.
We're just havin' a conversation,
now put it down.
I'll let them know where you are.
Good.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Jake and Jim!
Good mule!
Haw up there now!
Good mules!
Have arrived to find
Fort Sedgewick deserted.
Am now waiting for garrison's return
or word from headquarters.
The posits in exceedingly poor condition...
and I have decided to assign myself
clean-up duty beginning tomorrow.
Supplies are abundant...
and the country
is everything I dreamed it would be.
There can be no place like this on Earth.
Bad horse.
The animals in the pond
had not been poisoned.
They had all been shot.
But why? Was it for sport?
Could it have been out of spite?
My first guess would have been
that the men here were starving.
But this rotting waste
speaks to the contrary.
The caves are an even bigger mystery.
What could have driven
men to live in caves?
Perhaps they were frightened.
Maybe there had been some sort of revolt.
I can make no sense of
the clues left me here.
Perhaps my relief will provide the answers.
Come on, Cisco. One more time.
Git up!
Come on! Git up, Cisco.
Git up! There you go!
Easy.
And if I...
Look at me.
Don't hurt my mules.
Stop.
Stop it.
Please don't hurt my mules.
I am pleased with my efforts thus far.
For all my improvements, though, there
remains an ugliness here I cannot dispel.
An injury that goes beyond neglect
and like a bruise, it will be slow to heal.
It's been almost 30 days.
I have come to enjoy
the patterns of my life at Fort Sedgewick.
Especially my daily
reconnaissance rides with Cisco.
Each day, we go further into the prairie
and every discovery...
big or small,
becomes etched in my mind forever.
It would seem I've been marooned,
as no one has yet come for me.
I can only assume that there is a problem,
which the army will solve shortly.
Maybe I am being foolish in my optimism...
but when I look to the eastern horizon...
I never fail to hope
that a column might be out there.
Still no sign of Capt. Cargill's command.
Though well-supplied,
I've decided to ration my goods...
as if I were part
of a post instead of the whole affair.
There's a wolf who seems intent
on the goings-on here.
He does not seem inclined
to be a nuisance, however.
And aside from Cisco,
has been my only company.
He's appeared
each afternoon for the past two days.
He has two milky white paws.
If he comes calling tomorrow...
I will name him Two-Socks.
Almost a month and no one has come.
The longer this condition persists...
the less inclined I am
to believe that anyone will.
Rain has forced me indoors
for most of two days now...
and I have begun work on an awning.
It is the loneliest of times for me now...
but I can say honestly
that I am not unhappy.
How can I marry a pretty little girl
When I got no coat to put on?
Soldier, soldier
Won't you marry me
Before the fight comes home?
How can I marry a pretty little girl
When I got no shoes to put on?
When I got no hat to put on?
Soldier, soldier, won't you marry me
Before the fight comes home?
How can I marry an ugly little girl
When I got a pretty wife back home?
You there!
Have made first contact with a wild Indian.
One came to the fort
and tried to steal my horse.
When I appeared,
he became frightened and ran off.
Have decided to bury excess ordnance
lets it fall into enemy hands.
Keeping only the barest
necessities for myself.
My afternoon rides have been pared down
to short circular patrols...
always keeping the post in sight.
Am taking steps to prepare
for another visitation.
Do not know how many more
might be in the vicinity...
but am assuming that where there is one
there's sure to be another.
Most of my work has been geared
toward creating the illusion...
of strength and stability.
I'm still alone, however,
and unless troops arrive soon...
all may be lost.
It's been two days now, and nothing.
My presence here must
have been reported by now.
Have made all the
preparations I can think of.
Cannot mount an adequate defense
as I am still alone.
But will try to make
a big impression when they come.
Waiting.
Post-script...
The man I encountered was
a magnificent-looking fellow.
I realize now that I have been wrong.
All this time, I've been waiting.
Waiting for what?
For someone to find me?
For Indians to take my horse?
To see a buffalo?
Since I have arrived at this post
I have been walking on eggs.
It has become a bad habit
and I am sick of it.
Tomorrow morning,
I will ride out to the Indians.
I do not know the outcome
or wisdom of this thinking...
but I've become a target
and a target makes a poor impression.
I am through waiting.
What are you looking at?
Son of a bitch!
No. Wait.
Wait.
You need help. You're hurt.
- You need...
- No!
Let me... You need help.
You need help. You're hurt.
Let me help you.
You're hurt.
Don't.
She's hurt.
No. She's hurt.
Welcome.
Hi!
Come.
Please, sit down.
Sit down.
Wait just a... Just a minute.
Tatanka. Buffalo.
- Buffalo.
- Tatanka.
Buffalo. Tatanka.
The fierce one, as I call him,
seems a very tough fellow.
I hope I never have to fight him.
From the little I know,
he seems to be honest and very direct.
I like the quiet one immensely.
He's been patient and inquisitive.
He seems eager to communicate.
I would conclude that he is a man
of some weight among his people.
Buffalo.
I believe I made an even greater impression
on their next visit.
I produced a coffee grinder,
something none of them had seen before.
Is the coffee not good?
It's too strong, maybe.
Sugar.
Put in.
Taste it.
Sugar.
You want some?
That's a lot.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's good to finally have some company.
So much goes unsaid
and I have the feeling that these people...
the quiet one in particular,
want something from me.
Made presents of coffee
and most of the sugar.
It didn't figure to last anyway.
Don't believe I go too far in saying...
that a foundation
for good relations is being laid.
Christinel
Get 'em, Joe! Get them chickens!
Billy, you get away from those puppies!
Damn!
Get the kids, and get them in the house.
Go on!
Christine!
Christine! Where are you?
I'm up here, mother.
- Get down now.
- Why?
Just do it.
Stay right where you are. Get back.
Do you hear me?
Joe, get in the house right now!
Willie!
- Who is it, Willie?
- They look like Pawnee.
My father and your father
are talking to them.
- What do they want?
- I don't know.
Go on. You heard him. Get out of here.
Run, Christine!
I said run!
Joe!
Christine!
Mommyl
Come on, Two Socks. Bacon.
Two Socks, like Cisco,
has become a trusted friend.
He still won't eat from my hand...
but his keen eyes and ears never fail
to alert me when something is wrong.
Tatanka.
No.
No, I haven't seen any buffalo.
Sorry.
Are you hungry?
I have food. I have a lot of food.
Nothing I've been told
about these people is correct.
They are not beggars and thieves.
They are not the bogeymen
they've been made out to be.
On the contrary, they are polite guests
and have a familiar humor I enjoy.
Real communication is slow, however...
and the quiet one is as frustrated as I am.
Most of our progress
has been built on the basis of failure...
rather than success.
I've thought to inquire
if the woman I found lived or not...
but it seems far too complicated a subject,
given our limitations.
One thing is clear, however.
There are no buffalo.
And it weighs heavy on their minds.
Yesterday's meeting was the best yet.
It seems I've been invited to the village
and I'm looking forward to going.
Hello.
You...
Here...
Good.
Thank you. I feel good.
I feel good.
The soldier fort.
Wait.
What is your names?
- Our names?
- What is his name?
He...
Kick.
Kick?
More.
More kick?
More kicking?
Kicking.
Bird? Bird, kicking bird.
Kicking Bird.
What is he...
Is he chief?
No.
A holy man.
Holy man.
Your name?
- I don't...
- How are you called?
Get up?
Stand up?
Stands?
Stands. Your name's 'Stands'?
Stands.
- With.
- With?
- Stands with?
Fist?
Yes.
Stands With A Fist?
Stands With A Fist.
I'm John Dunbar.
John Dunbar.
Dumb Bear.
No, not Dumb Bear.
Dunbar.
Dun...
Bar.
Not Dumb Bear.
Dunbar.
There's been an exciting breakthrough
with the Indians.
The woman I found
on the prairie speaks English...
and today, clear progress was made.
She is white, and though I cannot be sure
how she came to be with these people...
I can tell she is not a captive.
While I'm not afraid...
I don't feel completely
welcome by everyone in the village.
My being here must be Kicking Bird's idea.
He is very enthusiastic
and like two children...
we are both anxious
to know more about each other.
But I find myself holding back.
For some reason,
I am reluctant to answer all his questions.
Maybe it's my sense of duty...
but something tells me not to say too much.
It was good to see Fort Sedgewick again...
and yet I look forward
to another visit with my new neighbors.
This is still my home, however...
and I remain watchful
for my relief and can only hope...
that my negotiations with the wild
people of the plains will bear fruit.
Buffalo!
Buffalo! I've seen buffalo!
Buffaloes!
Tatanka.
Tatanka?
Yeah.
Riders were sent out to pick up the trail.
In the time it took to gather
my things at Sedgewick...
the entire tribe was well on its way.
Their efficiency and speed
with which they moved...
was enough to impress
any military commander.
Spirits are high, and overnight
I've gone from a person of suspicion...
to one of genuine standing.
I am greeted with open smiles
and looks of appreciation.
In short, I have become a celebrity.
Loo ten tant!
- Loo ten tant!
Scouts picked up the trail
exactly where I said it would be.
It was not hard to find...
a gigantic swath of torn-up ground
extending to the horizon.
The numbers it took to create
this impossible image...
was hard to imagine.
Loo ten tant!
Who would do such a thing?
The field was proof enough...
that it was a people
without value and without soul.
With no regard for Sioux rights.
The wagon tracks
leading away left little doubt...
and my heart sank,
as I knew it could only be white hunters.
Voices that had been joyous all morning...
were now as silent as the dead buffalo
left to rot in this valley...
killed only for their tongues
and the price of their hides.
Loo ten tant.
It was suddenly clear now
what had happened...
and my heart sank
as I tried to convince myself...
that the white men who'd been killed
were bad people and deserved to die.
But it was no use.
I tried to believe
that Wind In His Hair and Kicking Bird...
and the others who shared in the killing
were not so happy for having done it.
But they were.
As I looked at familiar faces,
I realized that the gap between us...
was greater than I could
ever have imagined.
As they celebrated into the night
the coming hunt...
it was hard to know where to be.
I don't know if they understood,
but I could not sleep among them.
There had been no looks,
and there was no blame.
There was only the confusion of a people
not able to predict a future.
Are you all right?
I can't.
No, I'm full.
I'm full, and I can't
tell the story anymore.
No.
You want to try it?
Here.
I can't. This is too much.
Good trade.
This is a good trade.
No, no, I can't. I'm full, I'm tired.
No!
Loo ten tant! Loo ten tant!
Tatanka. Big tatanka.
Big tatanka.
That's my hat!
You're wearing my hat.
It's my hat.
No, you...
My hat.
Good trade.
There you are.
Come here, Cisco.
It seems every day ends
with a miracle here.
And whatever God may be,
I thank God for this day.
To stay any longer would have been useless.
We had all the meat we
could possibly carry.
We had hunted for three days,
losing a half a dozen ponies...
and only three men injured.
I'd never known a people
so eager to laugh...
so devoted to family,
so dedicated to each other.
And the only word
that came to mind was 'harmony.
Many times I've felt alone...
but until this afternoon...
I'd never felt completely lonely.
Made a long patrol today.
There's nothing to report.
Time seems irrelevant
except for the fact that I am bored...
and these hours alone are endless.
It is difficult for me to
muster any enthusiasm...
for my regular duties here.
And the fort is showing
serious signs of neglect.
The truth is,
I am missing the company of my friends.
I can see all of their faces,
but somehow it is not enough.
Tomorrow I will pay them a visit.
It may be forward of me,
but what can it hurt?
After all, they are my neighbors.
The night sounds have become so familiar
as to be comforting.
My life on the prairie's a good one
and for the most part, I am content.
The Indians have a great pull for me
that goes beyond curiosity.
There's something wise about them
and I'm drawn to them...
in ways much stronger
than my obligations to the military.
Go home!
Damn him.
God! Go home!
Go!
Go home, Two Socks!
Bad wolf!
It is autumn now and I am spending
more time than ever with my friends.
They have given me my own lodge
and I feel comfortable there.
We talk every day, but I know
Kicking Bird is frustrated with me.
He always wants to know
how many more white people are coming.
I tell him they will most likely
pass through this country and nothing more.
But I am speaking in half-truths.
One day there will be too many,
but I cannot bring myself to tell him that.
I am sure that Stands With A Fist
knows that I am holding back...
but to her credit, she says nothing.
A war party is going against the
Pawnee soon and I have asked to go.
I sense I made a mistake in doing so...
but I could not bring
myself to take it back.
They are my friends,
and from what little I gather...
the Pawnee have been
very hard on these people.
I hope I have not overstepped my bounds.
Come in, please.
Sit down?
Kicking Bird want to know...
why you want to make war on the Pawnee.
They have done nothing to you.
They are Sioux enemies.
Only Sioux warriors to go.
Tell him that I have been a warrior...
longer than many of the young men
who will go on this war party.
Tell him.
He said that the Sioux way
of being a warrior...
is not the white way.
- You are not ready.
- I know, I understand.
Tell him I cannot learn these ways in camp.
He also asks that you...
watch over his family while he is gone.
This thing he asks is a
great honor for you.
Tell him that I would be happy
to watch over his family.
He thanks Dances With Wolves for coming.
Who is Dances With Wolves?
It is the name which all the people...
are calling you now.
Dances With...
That's right.
That day.
Dances With Wolves.
How do you say it?
I'm here.
We walk.
I cut this off.
I shaved it off. More.
Grass grows on the prairie.
Grass grows on the prairie'?
- Wrong.
- Wrong?
You said, "Fire lives on the prairie"
I did?
No laughing, though.
That man is a fighter.
Again.
- That man is a fighter.
- Okay, I have it.
Yes.
Hoo hoo, right?
No?
Try this.
What's the word...
for beautiful?
How did you get your name?
I was not very old...
when I came to be with the people.
And I was made to work.
I worked every day, very hard.
There was a woman...
who didn't like me much.
She used to call me bad names,
and sometimes she...
Beat me?
And one day, she was...
calling me these bad names...
with her face in my face...
and I hit her.
I was not very big, but she fell down.
She fell hard and didn't move.
And then I stood over her with my fist...
and I asked if...
there was any other woman...
who wanted to call me bad names.
No one bothered me after that day.
No, I wouldn't think so.
Show me.
Show me where you hit her.
Why are you not married?
- I'm sorry.
- I have to go.
I'm sorry.
Can I help you?
I don't...
Bet you were thinking:
Now, why don't he write?
Hello, Two Socks.
Come on.
I won't hurt you. Come on. You can do this.
You can do this.
Come on.
This is easy.
This is easy, Two Socks.
I am in mourning.
No, we cannot.
- Yes.
- We must be careful.
We must be careful.
Okay.
Wait!
What?
Trouble.
The Pawnee are coming.
A big party of 40 or 50 men this time.
Hunters found them not far to the north.
Soon be here.
Okay!
Shoot the gun!
It was hard to know how to feel.
I'd never been in a battle like this one.
There was no dark political objective.
This was not a fight for territory
or riches or to make men free.
It was fought to preserve the food stores
that would see us through the winter.
To protect the lives of women and children
and loved ones only a few feet away.
Stone Calf was a great loss,
but even the old men could not remember...
such a one-sided victory.
And I gradually began
to look at it in a new way.
I felt a pride I'd never felt before.
I'd never really known who John Dunbar was.
Perhaps the name itself had no meaning.
But as I heard my Sioux name
being called over and over...
I knew for the first time who I really was.
The whole village was eager
to take up a collection on my behalf.
The generosity of the
people was astonishing.
The more valued the gift,
the more easily it was given.
Even the poorer families wanted to give
up animals they could not afford.
It was hard to turn them away.
Black Shawl was a mystery.
I couldn't guess what she was thinking
and she offered no advice...
no words of encouragement.
I may have been the brunt
of an inside joke...
that included the entire village...
but I was determined.
Wind In His Hair told me if all the
gifts were gone in the morning...
my offer had been accepted.
I spent a sleepless night
wondering what misstep, if any, I had made.
I had no idea
what Kicking Bird's decision would be.
And for me.
I had never been married before.
I don't know if all grooms
have the same experience...
but as Kicking Bird began to speak about
what was expected of a Sioux husband...
my mind began to swim in a way that
shut out everything but her...
the tiny details of her costume...
the contours of her shape...
the light in her eyes...
the smallness of her feet.
I knew that the love
between us would be served.
Yes.
Good.
Bye.
You have everything from the soldier fort?
Yes.
There's nothing for me there.
The journal.
Stands With... Wait!
Words are important!
The words in the book
are like a trail for people to follow.
Now, it tells everything about my life here.
I must get it.
Enough.
I'll catch up.
Injun!
Get him! Injun!
No!
Stay down. Stay.
My God.
God.
It's okay.
Spivey.
- Spivey!
- Yeah, Sergeant.
Tell the major he's waking up.
Move your worthless ass.
You got yourself a hell of a shiner...
didn't you?
Major's coming through.
Does he speak English?
I don't know, sir.
Speak English?
Talk English? Talk!
I speak English.
Who are you?
Lt. John J. Dunbar. This is my post.
Why are you dressed like this?
I came out from Fort Hayes last April,
but there was nobody here.
Do you have proof of that?
My journal's on the bunk in my quarters.
My orders are in the journal.
It will tell you everything.
Spivey, you and Edwards
were the first ones here.
Did you find anything? A journal?
No, we didn't find nothing, sir.
Where's Edwards?
He's outside.
He didn't find nothing either.
Somebody find me Edwards.
You turned Injun, didn't you?
Didn't you?
What did you say your name was?
Dunbar.
D-u-n-b-a-r. John.
You say you're an officer?
- God. Did you read my orders?
- No.
They're in my journal.
There are no orders.
There's no journal.
Why are you out of uniform?
I have to relieve myself.
- Sergeant, take care of him.
- Yes, sir.
Let's go.
- He's a white man.
- Doesn't look white to me.
- They say he's a soldier.
- He's an officer.
Do you salute him or shoot him?
Here, you. Eyes front.
I said eyes front!
Don't shoot him! Hit him! Get him!
Get him!
Why are you out of uniform?
What's the army doing out here?
- Lieutenant's asking the questions.
- Bauer.
We're charged with apprehending...
We're charged with apprehending hostiles
and recovering stolen property...
retrieving white captives
taken in hostile raidings.
- There are no hostiles.
- We will ascertain that for ourselves.
If you'll guide us to these camps
and serve as an interpreter...
your conduct will be re-evaluated.
- What conduct?
- With all due respect...
Your status as a traitor might improve
should you choose...
to cooperate with the United States Army.
There's nothing for you to do out here.
Are you willing to cooperate or not?
Speak up!
What's that?
Sergeant, form a detail
and take this man down to the river.
- Let him clean up his face.
- Yes, sir.
Not you, Spivey.
Lieutenant.
Major wants to see you.
Spivey.
Spivey. You got paper?
- What's it to you?
- Give me some, shit-bird.
Can you read?
No, I can't read.
What the hell's the difference?
You can't read either.
Now just give me some.
- Quick, give me some!
- All right. Hold your horses.
Bauer!
Let go of me!
Lap it up, Injun. Go ahead. Lap it up.
You son of a bitch!
It's all right.
He's going to get hungrier, that's all.
But maybe that don't matter.
Word is they're going to
ship you back to Hayes.
And once you get there,
they gonna hang you.
Come on. Forget about him.
Go on. Get out of here.
Get up in there!
Spivey, what is that?
Looks like he's following us.
Hell, I'm going to shoot him.
Dang. You missed him.
- Don't shoot, damn it. It's my shot.
- Wait. I seen him first.
- Get down!
- Look at that stupid bastard.
He ain't even moving.
- Wait a minute! That's my shot.
- Shoot him!
Shoot him, Edwards. He's standing there.
Shoot him!
Jesus Christ! Holy shit!
Bauer, get him off him!
He might have killed you.
I'll get that son of a bitch.
Sit down, goddamn it!
That's it. I got him!
Dead shot, boys. Come on.
Son of a bitch!
Get up!
I mean it! Get up!
Get up! Come on, get up!
What?
You bash that prisoner one more time,
I'll put those shackles on you.
You men get back here!
Goddamn it!
Boo.
Clear behind that stand of trees?
All right. Let's go.
I don't see nobody.
Indians!
No.
With Ten Bears,
it was always more than a while.
There was purpose in everything he did
and I knew he wanted me to stay.
But I was sure of myself.
I would be an excuse and that's all
the army would need to find this place.
I pushed him as far as I could
to move the camp...
but in the end he only smiled
and talked of simple pleasures.
He reminded me that at his age
a good fire is better than anything.
Ten Bears was an extraordinary man.
You have nothing to say?
What can I tell you?
What's ever on your mind.
You've made the decision.
My place is with you.
I go where you go.
You're not afraid?
No.
I told Ten Bears
we'd leave when the snow breaks.
Did you tell everyone?
Not everyone.
You...
finish your pipe?
Good pipe.
How...
does it smoke?
I've never smoked it.
We come far...
you and me.
I will not forget you.
Sergeant! Over here! Now!