As we sit here today,
we are all complicit in the genocide.
Indifference is complicity.
They were saying, you know,
"We need help. We need support.
We need you to do something.
Do something."
It's part of my responsibility
as a human being.
I think you need to ask yourself,
"What's the threshold?"
I mean, at what point
are you going to not make excuses?
And I think, for me, it's genocide.
That's the bar.
This is the first time in history that
our government has declared genocide...
...while it's still actually happening.
That's another level.
I mean, that's a level of inhumanity...
...that affects us all. And I think...
...requires us to do something.
- Where do you have the pens? Good.
- I have them in the bag, with the postcards.
All right, you wanna grab the dog?
Two hundred enough,
or do you wanna bring more?
- Come here, Lucky. Let's see if we match.
- Here, Dad, hand him to me.
- How do we look?
- Good. He looks better than you.
Well, it doesn't take much.
Okay.
I grew up learning about the family
members that escaped the Holocaust...
...but it always wasn't real for me.
In college, there were certain students
that were the activist type...
...and I definitely didn't consider myself
one of them.
Do you have a moment?
Stop genocide in Darfur, Sudan.
- You have a moment, sir? Okay.
- Sorry, no.
Back then I felt I had perfected...
...the art of walking through
without taking a single flyer.
It involved avoiding eye contact.
I would pretend to make a cell phone call.
Could you sign a postcard for us...?
- Online.
- Do you have a second?
You know what's happening in Sudan?
In Darfur?
And then I took a class in what happened
in Rwanda, and it opened my eyes.
This will be given to the governor.
- Just sign...
- Just sign there.
Help stop the genocide in Sudan?
It'll take a second.
And then, you know,
for my last two years at school...
...I was the person
passing out flyers every day.
You know what's going on over there?
It's not funny, man. It's a genocide.
It's mind-blowing that...
...you learn about what's happened in the
past, what happened in Nazi Germany...
...what happened in Rwanda, and
we've got a chance to make it right...
...and we've just fallen flat on our faces.
It makes me angry.
Yes. This is a picture of Labado village...
...immediately after an attack...
...by the Arab militia
and government forces.
- This is catastrophic for them, no?
- It is catastrophic.
This is the sort of description
of the burning of villages...
...that some of the witnesses gave.
- Amazing.
This was taken
soon after the attack in Labado.
- The village had been destroyed.
- Okay.
- Is this the garrison, this...?
- Yes, this is a military garrison.
You see, here are the Janjaweed
and the government forces...
...sharing the looted property.
This was happening in such
close proximity to the military...
...that they can't possibly deny
not knowing.
In fact, they were actually
providing protection to them.
Yeah.
Let me show you one move,
then I'll stop meddling.
If you were able to do this, and she didn't
respond, then you can take these two out.
I guess every experience changes you.
Offense or defense?
But as an actor and the son of a
psychologist and the son of an educator...
...I think I am predisposed
to want to know...
...and to want to investigate
and to understand.
And sometimes you come up against
something that you just can't understand.
The first time I went to Africa was for
the filming of the movie Hotel Rwanda.
Maybe because I'd been sensitized
by that experience...
...I was struck by the similarities
to what's happening in Darfur.
I was invited along with
a Congressional delegation to the area.
We flew in and then went to see the camps.
I was just kind of getting hit
by this wave of hopelessness.
Then I just tried to engage personally
with these kids.
Yeah, they can come with us.
All of the kids had drawings
depicting bombers...
...soldiers and Janjaweed,
people being shot, and fires.
And then you start feeling like:
"Well, I wouldn't want horsemen riding
down on me and killing my children.
And maybe their plight is in some way
tied into my plight...
...or their journey is in some way
tied into my journey on this planet."
You can see that the potential...
...for what's there,
that kids really are just kids.
"I'll play with a rock.
I'll play with a stick. I'll roll around
in the dust. Let's make up a game."
And that that spirit
is that same spirit everywhere.
It's so sad when you just see that light
get dimmed down, and it's just gone...
...and you don't know if it'll ever come back
or what that's gonna turn into.
But that light is what...
You know, you fight for that light
because it's right there.
In everything they've dealt with,
and everything they've seen...
...and everything they've come
through. Bang, you know?
Open. I'm here, I'm alive.
I'm here. My spirit is here, you know?
That's you, man, that's me.
Power.
Despair.
I think if you put the two of them together,
you have what the Darfur crisis is about.
- Godfather to base, Godfather One.
- Godfather One, good morning.
Moving from
Alpha-Oscar to India-Gulf, over.
My job as a humanitarian
is to provide food to save lives.
And this we're doing.
We're feeding almost three million people
around Darfur.
But the harsh reality about it,
is at the moment...
...the food resource is not available
in the way in which it should.
People that don't eat
will try to find it some way.
We get riots, we'll get violence.
Eventually, if the food is not available
anywhere else...
...these people will start dying.
I come from a family
of development workers.
We've always talked about the fact that
we need to all try to improve the planet.
For me, it's pretty much of a motivation.
It wasn't so much when I was very young.
I used to like racing motorcycles.
We have a lot of assessments to plan
where the priorities are going to be.
We need to think about it.
For me, the first one
would be this area here.
And basically we never went there.
All of this area has not received food.
And there's a drought going on here.
And if we do not help them,
they will migrate down with their cattle.
We don't want those people to come down.
Just no way.
We need to actually put the food there,
get them to stay in the area...
...and do whatever, in order to improve
the condition of those that are poor.
This is wheat and cereal.
- Mixed together.
- Very nice.
It certainly provides you with a very
strong sense of doing something...
...in a situation which the world
has to solve.
Because one cannot
just think that you can...
That we can just continue to see
burned villages and dead people.
It's the JJs.
Try not to let you see
too much pointing at them.
Keep your camera aimed forward.
Governments around the world
have always used proxy fighters...
...to fight wars that have
political implications for them.
The Janjaweeds
are basically an Arab militia.
Some people say that
they are a proxy force...
...but it's not just Janjaweeds. There's
an enormous amount of tribal violence...
...which is getting the situation
increasingly worse.
It's the responsibility of the government,
of having opened this Pandora box...
...that I don't think now
they have the capacity to close...
...in order to bring peace to this area.
In the international media,
we are told that the conflict in Darfur...
...it is between Arabs and Africans.
But this is absolutely not true.
It is not about religion,
it is not about ethnicity...
...but it happens that certain communities
have a nomadic lifestyle...
...and others are agriculturalists.
It is a classic case of a conflict...
...whose root cause is over resources.
Again, it's a backdrop of prolonged years
of drought in that part of the Sudan.
We are proud to be an Afro-Arab country...
...based on tolerance,
based on understanding.
We are African.
As you've seen it from our skin.
And we are Muslim,
but doesn't mean we are Arab.
We have our culture. Just...
We just use Arab
when we are doing our worship, yes.
But in our whole life, in our normal life,
we use our full language.
We hate Arab, and we don't like Arab...
...because you don't know what Arabs
happened to did to us.
You had asked that we give you a chart...
- Yeah.
...of those who are most responsible.
- Yes. And arming and funding of Janjaweed.
- Okay.
You have the armed forces
and the police units.
Together with the Janjaweeds,
they committed these crimes.
But all these units in some way
report to Harun.
Harun's position is central
to everything that happened in Darfur.
- He was a judge.
This photograph
that a witness provided us...
...shows a meeting that was held...
...with the government officials
and members of the Janjaweed.
There is one interesting piece of evidence
in Geneina...
...where he told the people that he had the
power to kill whoever he wished in Darfur...
...for the sake of peace...
...and that he can kill three-quarters
of the population...
...for just one-quarter
of the population to live.
So that just shows
the amount of power that he had.
- Hey. Hello.
- Hello. Hello, man.
The question is, where does Sudan get
all this money to fund the genocide?
And it's through foreign oil companies...
...who provide the Sudanese government
with billions of dollars in revenue.
And it turns out that these companies
themselves then rely on investors...
...like a state pension fund,
to continue their operations in Sudan.
The airport, Terminal 5.
And now we're asking the State of
California to say to those companies:
"You need to get out.
And if you don't do that, California's going
to sell its investments in your company."
So we're gonna use the weight...
...of billions and billions of dollars
of state pension fund money...
...as financial leverage
on the Sudanese government.
To make it happen, we have to get
the legislation we wrote...
...through the state legislature
and then signed by the governor.
You hear anything about the vote?
I'm not as worried as I was a little while
ago, but there's still a concern.
I'm from the Sudan
Divestment Task Force.
Since oil extraction began in Sudan...
...the money that's coming in from these
companies is going straight to the military.
You guys have been tireless on this issue,
that's for sure.
Prior to this, the only thing I'd organized
was bus trips down to Tijuana.
I was barely voting in elections. I mean,
what did I know about making laws?
Ten dollars for the T-shirt.
Assembly Bill 2941
is gonna set us on the path...
...to finally ending this genocide.
But this bill is under
an enormously important vote...
...and if it does not pass out of the
Senate, Assembly Bill 2941 is dead.
I can give you two things...
Daddy.
Ayana, can you get the door for John?
My friend, John Prendergast...
...for 22 years has been dealing
with conflicts in Africa.
When that trip to Darfur came up, he was
the first person to pop into my head.
Would you do me the favor?
If it's bad, I don't know.
It's good?
- Great.
- Yes!
Your fortune cookie says,
"Your sensitivity is an asset."
- Asset.
- What's an asset?
It's a boon. It's something good.
It's one of my good sides, it helps me out.
- Chapter one is now the preface.
- The preface.
Chapter two...
When we came back from Darfur,
I think we both thought:
"Well, that could be a book."
This section, it's your construction,
this idea of the path out of apathy.
Which I think is what
is the whole point of the book.
Is you can go about your life, but
you can... But you can get it done.
You can do... You don't just have
to be sitting there going...
...with your hands in the air,
"I don't know what to do."
And that was me. And that was you.
You know?
And then we started figuring it out.
I looked at myself and said,
"Well, what can you do?"
I thought, " Well, the best asset
really that I have right now is that...
...for the moment, I am a celebrity."
People stick a mike in front of me and say,
"What's going on?" You know?
And while I'm talking about, you know,
George Clooney and Brad Pitt...
...I can also talk about Darfur.
Going to Capitol Hill, we know
that the wheels of bureaucracy...
...and politics move very slowly.
But one of these people may be the
new leader of the so-called free world...
...and this is an opportunity
to make them state their position.
- Mr. Cheadle, how are you?
- Good to meet you.
- I've seen your film. The Hotel Rwanda.
- Oh, great.
I get a lot of questions too,
personally to me:
"What can I do?" And, you know,
I have all this passion now...
...but I don't know where to direct it,
you know?
We just gotta get people there.
And what I think is, when they see
particularly a humanitarian situation...
...and they think, "I wanna do something."
- Yeah.
And that's been...
That's one of my objectives now...
...is to try to get more people of means
to go to these difficult places.
Because I think they will then
take it upon themselves.
I'm gonna do what I can, and actually
what I can do is something substantial.
Because your soul's gonna be touched.
Once you see this,
you're not gonna be the same.
That's right.
We do have problems in terms of security.
There's been a lot of attacks
on humanitarian convoys.
We're running out of time, trying to finalize
the deliveries for the north, aren't we?
You will be able to open,
and we just... We just move.
This is the tracking sheet
that the convoy will be using.
Every seventh WFP truck, there's a one
piece of A.U., and that's how it goes.
It's for protection.
All drivers get in.
These jobs take an enormous amount
of risks, being shot at...
...being burned.
They've been attacked with bazookas.
The African Union protection force
has its limitations.
They cannot support deliveries with WFP...
...and at the same time,
provide protection to their camps.
I'd put a couple prominent
Republicans up front.
Okay.
Like, you can put this on a second line.
"Senators."
Go up, up.
I always felt that if I
passed out a few more flyers...
...convinced a few more people
that divestment's a good idea...
...that we'd get it to a level where
the experts... I didn't know who.
I just assumed there was divestment
experts, Sudan experts. You know...
...big NGOs that would, you know,
basically come in, shake my hand and say:
"Good job, we'll take it from here."
And I quickly learned that
that's not the case...
...and that you have to
become your own expert.
- Mr. Sweeney, hi.
- Good to see you, man. How's it going?
- This is Jason Miller.
- Hey, Jason.
He's my... The codirector, partner in crime.
He's my other half.
Well, we always have to
have a coconspirator.
We made thousands of these postcards.
People are signing them
and sending them back to us...
...and then wanted to bring 2941 of them
for Assembly Bill 2941...
...to the governor's office,
and wanted to get your thoughts on that.
- Did you print them in-state?
- Yeah.
You're in a state that is union-oriented.
And this piece has no union bug.
We care about an issue,
but we don't understand the whole...
- Game.
- The political context.
That's why
we're obviously seeking advice.
You don't want folks to say, " This is
a bunch of inexperienced white boys...
...who don't know how to deal
with the unions and people of color"...
...when this is a people-of-color issue.
- Right.
- Okay.
- So...
So who published this?
- Us.
- Okay, but...
- Pocket money.
- Pocket money?
Yeah, we're... I wait tables.
No. No, come on, man. Be serious.
- I'm serious. Yeah.
- You serious?
- Okay, well...
- We got a good deal.
Is this a union or nonunion printer?
It's a union printer.
I'll have them put the sticker...
Well, man, tell them to put
the damn sticker on here, man.
Are you satisfied with
what you have your hand on so far?
Must have names of people
you think...
Not the list of the...
But just your own list that you're...
Mr. Prosecutor, you know
to look straight at the camera.
I speak worse in Spanish.
Because I speak very fast,
no one can understand me.
Vanessa?
Can you help me to correct my English?
- How?
- I will read and then you will say no.
"I welcome the opportunity
to update the Council...
...on the activities undertaken by my office
since my last report in December."
- It's okay? Yeah?
- Yeah, that's good. Yeah.
"My office is collecting all available
information from outside Darfur."
- Available.
- Available. Available.
Like "Vanessa."
- Av... Available?
- Available.
Available. It's okay? Available?
It's boring, my goodness.
It's long and boring.
At this meeting
the Security Council will hear...
...a briefing by Mr. Luis Moreno-Ocampo...
...prosecutor of the
International Criminal Court.
There being no objection, so decided.
- You have the floor, sir.
- Thank you, Madam President.
I welcome the opportunity
to update the Council...
...on the activities undertaken by my office
since my last report in December.
I have stressed the need for cooperation...
...in order to ensure accountability.
Our justice effort should contribute...
...to the protection
and to the prevention of further crimes.
We need more information on groups
that continue to attack them...
...or impede them.
As my office moves toward
the presentation of evidence...
...it sends a signal
to those who are considering...
...committing further crimes...
...that they cannot do so with impunity.
Thank you very much, Madam President.
Of course it is needless
for me to reemphasize again...
...that the referral by the Security Council
of this issue to the ICC...
...has been very much politically motivated.
The judiciary in Sudan is very well-known
for its integrity and competence...
...and we think that it is within
the competence of our system...
...that we will prosecute
whoever is committing crimes in Darfur.
How many names are you gonna
present in your submission?
The Sudanese government won't turn over
these individuals for prosecution.
Will you offer Khartoum the list
of the people that you suspect?
Perhaps it's time to ignore
Sudanese sovereignty.
No, no, no.
Thank you very much. Bye-bye.
For people who are covering this story,
I think there's an emotional impatience.
People who would like the people
in Darfur to have an end to their suffering.
And they've been waiting and watching,
and it's like genocide in slow motion.
Yeah.
Hey, Vanessa, can you check
your BlackBerry and see...?
Yeah.
I didn't...
My BlackBerry is...
There's been reports that if
humanitarian aid was completely cut off...
...which it's gotten close to
or is getting close to...
...that the death toll would skyrocket.
So, what do you gauge success against?
People say, "You're doing a great job."
But it's still... The ultimate goal
isn't divesting from Sudan...
...it's ending the genocide in Darfur.
Part of it is guilt.
I don't wanna look back in 10 years
and say I didn't do everything I could.
It's frustrating you don't see...
...the goal in sight or the light
at the end of the tunnel...
...but putting things into perspective,
give yourself credit.
I'm not just saying that
because I'm your dad, but...
Give yourself credit.
You've come a long way.
It's hard. I'm scared because I don't see
the light at the end of the tunnel.
And it's easy... You know,
I have other things that I'm doing...
...and I can kind of, you know, I guess
even... Just if that's... I don't know.
All right. Hey, you know, it helps.
- Thanks, buddy.
- Thank you, man.
I'm proud of you. I love you.
Yes, good morning, base.
Any update on the convoy?
Did they start moving?
Coming to comp location? Over.
Zero-eight-five-seven.
About 17 kilometers away from location.
Oscar-Kilo, over.
Okay, so let's wait for your call
once the convoy is about to arrive. Over.
Daddy, come here. Daddy, come here.
Daddy, come here.
- Hey.
- Wait a second.
Why are you taping us?
I got an e-mail from George Clooney...
...explaining that he was going
to be going on a trip to China...
...and then on to Egypt...
...to meet with some heads of state
to discuss the situation in Darfur.
But given the lack of time,
we couldn't get a crew together...
...so I took it upon myself
to be the interim sound guy...
...DP, all of that.
It's never gonna work.
That was...
I don't know who that was.
Ladies and gentlemen, we have just landed
at Beijing Capital International Airport.
Hi, how are you doing?
They have huge economic ties to Sudan...
...and don't wanna do anything
to threaten that relationship.
There's been a real reticence
to even acknowledge...
...that there is a humanitarian crisis
in Sudan.
We're here to simply say:
How can we move forward from here
so that these people don't die?
And you guys have the relations.
And you...
We can't do this without you.
We need you.
- The bottom line is protection for civilians...
- Right.
...who are not soldiers,
who are not combatants...
...but who are innocents
literally in the way, in between.
- Have you ever been to Shanghai?
- Yeah.
We met with a foreign minister, A.F.A.
And it was a good meeting.
I guess as good as can be expected.
We weren't really imagining...
...we were gonna walk out of there
with anything very substantive...
...as far as him agreeing to do anything.
We are in Cairo.
We just had a meeting
with Gamal Mubarak...
...the president's son and the heir apparent.
He spoke about how to work
with the government of Sudan...
...and not force solutions down their throat.
There's not a lot of time left.
We wonder what these diplomatic
discussions are going to do.
We're the highest level delegation to
go to Egypt to discuss the crisis in Darfur.
That shouldn't be.
That's embarrassing.
They got six shots with their club play,
but they got five shots with the club players.
Then in the second half, they took them all
out and they only made one shot.
China does the largest amount of trade
with Sudan, mostly in oil...
...and has a great amount
of economic influence.
Egypt has a long history
with the Sudan.
Both countries believe
they have a role to play...
...and must do more to get
all the parties on the table in time.
It's just not enough.
We think there has been
a deafening silence.
Very recently, there were aid workers that
were attacked. A convoy was overcome...
...and supplies burned
that were strictly for humanitarian aid.
We need to press that these stories
not be small paragraphs on page 17.
We need these stories out.
Our call today is that priorities be linked
to human survival, not political processes.
Because someday this will end.
And the question then will be asked:
Where did the nations
of these United Nations stand?
The situation in Darfur
is very much overdramatized.
The United States is the only country
in the world that has labeled...
...what's going on in Darfur as a genocide.
Our view is that the United States uses...
...for its own public use, domestic use...
...especially during
previous election campaigns...
...to win the black voters...
...or other lobbies in the United States.
Any war is catastrophic.
There is no merciful war.
But it is not a genocide.
Channel Six, this is Gulf Service.
Police vehicles are at Juliet-five-five...
...has announced that kilo-one-com
situation is won.
- Sir?
- Yes.
I got some...
You might want to check this.
This point.
That's all we needed.
God almighty, man.
Listen, I just got the message
about the hijacking.
No one got hurt, I hope.
Yeah, that's the most important thing.
Yes.
We must diminish the number of convoys
that we're sending.
It is getting to be such a nightmare anyway.
Just recently there was a shootout,
one vehicle from the NGOs.
The passenger side of the car
received 12 bullets.
And only one of the people there
got hit on the leg.
Just luck! They could've been all killed.
How is your brother? How is he feeling?
Just give him lots of support tomorrow,
yeah?
Yeah, he needs to actually do well
on that exam. Yeah?
I'll call tomorrow. You know, just to
see how he did on the exam, yeah?
Okay. Ciao, my love.
Love you. Bye-bye. Ciao.
I miss... I miss my wife.
My little girl, she's...
We miss each other quite a lot.
With Manuel, I like his...
Now he's very protective of me.
Amazing. He's taller, big guy.
Puts his arms around me and he says,
"Don't worry, Dad, I'll take care of you."
I feel great.
Yeah, I miss all that.
This is the area. The rebels have
their camps in the higher ground.
And in the lower ground,
you have the villages.
So typically, the rebels would use
the villages to get supplies, food.
And the reaction of the government
and the Janjaweed...
...is to destroy the environment
around the hills...
...to make the life impossible
for the rebels.
This was their counterinsurgency policy.
Go to the village...
...remove all possible support
for the rebels.
And therefore,
the rebels would be exposed.
The suspect Kushayb was
the main militia commander, and Harun...
...he was the coordinator of the government
of Sudan's activities in Darfur.
And you can see a direct relationship...
...between the two of them acting together
to produce the crimes.
Ali Kushayb's name comes up consistently
amongst witnesses...
...in Bindisi, in Mukjar, in Kurumand,
in Arwalla.
Before the victims were raped, they were
paraded naked in front of Kushayb.
We're after criminals...
...and we have identified those two guys
as being responsible for atrocities.
So I consider that, yes,
the government of Sudan...
...which is a member
of the United Nations...
...which knows very well its obligations
in an international role...
...has to surrender those two individuals
to The Hague.
In two months, in six months,
in two years, they have to do it.
The irony of the situation is that
the ICC has never visited Darfur.
The evidence was gathered
from people outside Sudan.
So we question the credibility of ICC.
As far as Harun and Kushayb
are concerned...
...we are in no way going to hand over
any of our citizens to the ICC.
In this situation when you are fighting
rebels, you have to be very tough on that.
The government has a monopoly
of the use of force.
And the government exercises its authority
to protect its own citizens.
Today's the Senate vote.
Are you sure it's this way?
This way, I think.
Our goal until this afternoon is
to kind of rally up additional support.
Hello.
It doesn't matter how far
you've gotten in the legislature...
...once you lose, it's game over.
Assembly Bill 2941, by Assembly member
Koretz, act relating to investments.
Secretary, call the roll.
Aanestad? No. Ackerman?
Alarcón? Aye. Alquist?
- Ashburn? No.
- No.
Battin? No. Bowen? Aye.
Harman? Aye. Hollingsworth? No.
Kehoe? Aye. Lowenthal?
Aye. Machado?
Aye. Maldonado?
Aye. Margett?
McClintock? Migden? Aye. Morrow? Murray?
Aye. Soto?
Aye. Vincent?
Oh, my God.
Oh, man.
I almost... I needed a diaper.
I was gonna pee my pants.
So it's done with the state legislature...
...now it's on to the governor.
I bet you they strike out here.
Think they had trouble spelling it?
Adam, it's Don.
- How you doing?
- I'm good. How are you?
I'm all right. So I'm just going over
this little speech I'm gonna make.
I've been asked to say a few words today...
...but only a very few,
because quite frankly...
...the time for words
has drawn to a close...
...and action desperately needs
to take its place.
We ask today that Governor
Schwarzenegger sign AB 2941...
...and send a message loud and clear
that it is our responsibility...
...to prevent such tragedies, such
travesties, from ever happening again.
All right, ready? Let's go.
We'll take the thousands
of postcards we've collected...
...and walk down to the governor's office
to deliver the postcards.
- So how's the book coming?
- Tomorrow's the deadline.
But when you find something that...
...has such a purpose as this, it's kind of,
how do you drop it?
They'll take us into a conference room,
where we're gonna give them these.
So if this thing's vetoed,
it's gonna kill the movement.
And if he signs it, it will be law,
or it will be...
It'll be law, absolutely.
- How are your arms? You all right?
- Yeah, we're good.
Right here's our building.
- We follow you.
- Yeah.
We met with the deputy director.
They couldn't give the position
of the governor yet...
...but we told them that whether
he signs it or not, we'll know...
...and we'll be loud either way.
- We're trying to speak in a loud voice...
...so that people cannot say,
"I was unaware."
They can only say,
"I either acted or I stood by."
What is the most valuable action...
...to enroll people, other people
in our generation, to take action?
You'll figure out ways...
Because you're with like-minded
individuals... . to build and say:
"What are you doing, Carlos,
what's going on in your community?"
"What's going on? Where are you
connected? Can we get our groups together?"
You just have to start making those inroads,
and I think the answers will come to you.
You guys, we really do see you
as the instruments of change...
...what is going to take this grassroots,
collective movement...
...and create enough noise
and create enough pressure...
...that we finally push our leaders
to do what we want them to do.
That's what they're there to do.
Let them know that.
What do you want us to do?
The most important thing is to go directly
to the president. There is no question.
If we can bottle the same enthusiasm...
...and interest that people have to call into
American Idol, we can, you know, this...
We can knock this out pretty fast.
John and I authored a book together...
...to try and talk about our experiences
and how people could get involved.
I'm told that I should hold it up.
- Okay, I did it.
- And I'm going even further.
- I know my representatives.
- There you go. There you go. Get them.
- I'm gonna do whatever I can.
- Oh, man. I love hearing that.
A lot of people want to know how to
inject themselves into this process.
And even if it's tilting at windmills,
I think it's better to fight it...
...than to go, "What can I do?"
I don't know. But more than nothing.
A lot more than nothing.
- Thank you.
- Let me see your shirt.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, 10, 11.
I will nunchuck you very good.
Oh, you speak good English.
Chuck you very good.
- Ciao, guys.
- Okay.
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye.
The Sudanese people are such
sweet people, I'm telling you.
That's why it's so incredible
to hear about such violence around.
It's completely shocking,
and on the other side...
...you just basically realize that that
has actually been the story of the world...
...forever. Sixty years ago in Europe...
...we did the same thing
to millions of people in ovens.
So, you know, sometimes you
actually just try to put it also...
...in the balance of power, greed, and...
Just, for me, makes my engagement...
...to try and help...
...to change that whilst I am here.
And I just don't mean here in Sudan,
but in the world.
It's part of my responsibility
as a human being.
Okay.
Do you have the new questions?
Yes, you have them in the back.
They will have the responsibility
to implement the judge's decision.
Immediately following this briefing,
for the television reporters...
...the prosecutor will take a couple of
questions from you in the lounge area...
...where the red chairs are.
Good afternoon.
Thank you for your presence here.
I still think you could even say this slower,
this line here. This is really the whole point.
You start it off with a strong...
"To the people of Darfur." Pause.
"To the people of California."
What's up, man? How you doing?
Hi, guys. I'm Adam.
- Congratulations. Big day.
- Thank you.
We got legislation lined up
in 15 other states in January.
- Is it similar? It's the same pattern.
- Almost exactly.
Hello, how are you? Hello, everybody.
- Hey, how are you?
- Good.
Good to see you again.
How have you been?
Very good.
All decked out.
I've never seen you like this.
- I knew you were coming, so I had to come.
- Of course, you had to come.
You can hear the noise of the trucks
already, somewhere around.
It goes in that way.
All right, gentlemen, get ready.
Follow the governor.
Hello, everybody. How are you?
Thank you very much, everyone,
for being here today.
Today, I'm signing two bills
that will send a very clear message...
...that California does not stand for
murder and genocide.
It is an action that says we will not
cooperate with the horrors of Darfur.
We will not pay for it. We will not
support it, and we will not enable it.
See? It crossed quite easily, huh?
Welcome back!
It's such a great feeling
to see these guys back.
Yeah! Well done! Nice!
What are you going to do to prevent
these two men from going on the run?
Is it just to send a signal
or is it just the beginning?
Do you see the possibility of further names?
Can you make well-founded
judicial investigation...
...into a country that you can't visit?
Our greatest asset will be our ability
as a race, the human race...
...to reach within ourselves to find the
courage to move toward peace and balance.
To the Sudanese government:
We are coming after you.
Your genocide will not occur
on our watch...
...and it will not occur on our dime.
Yeah, we've done it once more!
Nobody got shot.
We delivered. We delivered.
That's the issue, you know.
We managed to give people...
...the food they need in a place like this.
Now I know why I'm here.
Now it makes me proud.
I'll talk to my family
and say to my kids:
"Guys, look.
This is what Daddy is doing."
I'm
honored.