First, there was darkness.
Then came the Strangers.
They were a race
as old as time itself.
They had mastered
the ultimate technology--
the ability to alter
physical reality by will alone.
They called this ability
"Tuning."
But they were dying.
Their civilization was
in decline,
and so they abandoned
their world,
seeking a cure
for their own mortality.
Their endless journey brought
them to a small, blue world...
in the farthest corner
of the galaxy.
Our world.
Here, they thought
they had finally found...
what they had been
searching for.
My name is
Dr. Daniel Poe Schreber.
I am just a man.
I help the Strangers
conduct their experiments.
I have betrayed my own kind.
You are confused, aren't you?
Frightened. That's all right.
I can help you.
-Who is this?
-I'm a doctor.
You must listen to me.
You have lost your memory.
There was an experiment.
Something went wrong.
Your memory was erased.
Do you understand me?
No, I don't understand.
What's going on here?
There are people coming for you
as we speak.
Don't let them find you.
Leave now.
Hello? Are you there?
Hey, Mr. Murdoch,
the Automat called.
Said you left your wallet there.
I suggest you retrieve it, since
you only paid for three weeks,
and they was up 10 minutes ago.
I've been here three weeks?
It's right there
in black and white, Mr. Murdoch.
Day and date.
We make our books like we make
our beds, all neat and tidy.
-I'll take care of it later.
-See that you do.
Only thing makes you a guest
in this joint...
is cash on the barrelhead!
House rules.
Three weeks is three weeks.
No days off for good behavior.
Mr. Murdoch, yes?
Where is he?
He just left
not five minutes ago.
Sleep now.
When the rumba rhythm
start to play
Dance with me
Make me sway
Like a lazy ocean hugs the shore
Hold me close
Sway me more
Like a flower bending
in the breeze
Bend with me
Sway with ease
When we dance,
you have a way with me
Stay with me
Sway with me
Hey, sweetie, he said he was
your husband's doctor.
He wanted to speak with you.
Excuse me.
-Doctor...
-Schreber.
Please, won't you come in?
You must be Emma Murdoch.
Thank you for coming to see me
on such short notice.
What is this?
A rather crude experiment
designed to further my studies.
I don't understand. You say
you're my husband's doctor,
but he never
mentioned you to me.
The truth is, John has been
coming to see me...
for quite some time.
He had been grappling
with feelings of betrayal...
stemming from
your marital difficulties.
-John told you what happened.
-Yes.
When was the last time
that you saw him?
Three weeks ago.
He packed a suitcase.
He was very angry at me.
I understand how difficult
this must be for you,
but for John's sake,
I would like you to think of me
as your friend, Emma.
It appears that John
has suffered a psychotic break.
-Complete memory loss.
-You can't be serious.
Oh, but I am.
He may be delusional.
Even violent.
If he were to contact you,
you must call me immediately.
Wherever your husband is,
he is searching...
For himself.
Good evening, Mr. Murdoch.
It is Mr. Murdoch, isn't it?
Mr. "J" something Murdoch?
J. Murdoch. What's your name?
Justin? Jerry?
My name's Jason Murdoch.
John Murdoch.
Jake Murdoch. How's it going?
Hi. Jack Murdoch.
Got to get a grip on myself.
I told the guy,
cash on the barrelhead.
I said, "Listen,
three weeks is three weeks."
-Where's our lucky winner?
-Upstairs, sir. Room 614.
The call girl.
-Evening, Husselbeck.
-Inspector Bumstead.
Your lace is untied.
Sorry.
Am I glad you're here, sir.
They say Detective Walenski's
got the heebie-jeebies.
Just take what they give me,
Husselbeck.
-Thanks a lot.
-Excuse me.
-Hello?
-Oh, it's you.
-You left your wallet here.
-When did I do that?
-When you was last here.
-When was that?
When you left your wallet.
Expect me to remember?
-Excuse me!
-No, no, seriously.
-Where you headed, chief?
-Home.
And where's home?
Haven't you mugs got
anything better to do?
I'm just doing my job, May.
There's a killer out there.
Look for him
instead of cooling your heels.
Go on. Get out of here.
Come on.
What's that make so far?
Six hookers in all?
-I believe so, sir.
-Give the man an "A" for effort.
So, Husselbeck,
what kind of killer do you think
stops to save a dying fish?
-Got me, sir.
-Bumstead.
What took you? This killer's
been running circles around us,
thanks to Walenski.
With all due respect,
Chief lnspector,
I've known Eddie a long time,
and he's a good cop.
Whatever kind of cop
Walenski once was...
he let drift a long time ago.
Let me talk to Bumstead!
Come on! Hold on!
Frank!
-Get his arm !
-They're watching us!
-On your feet!
-There's no way out!
God, can't you see?
Let me go!
I'm not going to hurt you.
-What was that?
-Walenski.
I'm being punished
for my sins, right?
What did I ever do to inherit
this? Where do you begin?
Well, everything Detective
Walenski committed to paper...
should be here, so--
The only thing that should be
committed is Walenski.
Nothing like
a little healthy paranoia.
I came here to file a missing
persons report for my husband.
-Take it to the front desk.
-They told me to come see you.
His name's John Murdoch.
Do these names mean
anything to you?
Who are these women?
Why are you looking
for my husband?
Are you going to accuse him
of something?
-Maybe. Maybe murder.
-Whose murder?
-Which one?
-All of them.
Mrs. Murdoch, I am sorry.
I didn't mean to alarm you.
I'm sorry that I came.
I just made a mistake.
If you'd please just give me
half a second to explain.
We met before?
If we did,
I hope you're still breathing.
What's your name, honey?
Well, that's
an appropriate name.
I was just thinking.
What you do...
It seems kind of dangerous...
right now.
How do you know
I'm not the killer?
You don't seem like
the killer type. Why?
You feeling any urges
I should know about?
Shoot.
So it seems you've discovered
your unpleasant nature.
-Who are you?
-We might ask the same question.
Sleep...now.
He can Tune!
What is to be done?
This man is dangerous.
-It is said he is able to Tune.
-Impossible!
We have seen it
with our own eyes.
On occasion, the imprinting
does not take.
They behave erratically
when they awaken.
We find them wandering
like lost children.
But this one was different, yes?
-What has the doctor to say?
-He has failed to report in.
-And Mr. Quick?
-No more Mr. Quick.
Mr. Quick...dead, yes.
Poor, poor Mr. Quick.
Mr. Book...does he know?
Should we not know, Mr. Hand?
We had hoped to learn more
before sharing with you.
We can know nothing
until we possess him.
We must have this man.
My brand, I hope.
I've been worried about you.
Are you punishing me?
If disappearing is
your way of punishing me,
I don't appreciate it.
What are you talking about?
I found these keys in my pocket,
so I assume I live here.
-You supposed to be my wife?
-"Supposed to be"?
You really...don't know
who I am, do you.
Your doctor called me. He was
worried that this might happen.
My doctor?
He gave me his card.
He's desperate to find you.
Feel like I'm living out
someone else's nightmare.
What happened to me?
Why was I seeing a doctor?
I had an affair.
You were angry at me.
Closing time.
The pool is now closed.
Most unfortunate it is...
that we were forced
to seek you out here.
You know how uncomfortable
we find all this moisture.
-I'm sorry. I--
-Failed to report in, yes?
I was frightened.
I have a weak heart, you know.
Your weakness is not, we think,
an affair of the heart.
We found this in his hotel room.
Must we reproduce
Mr. Murdoch's memories again?
I tried to reprint him,
but he woke up.
He knocked the syringe
right out of my hand.
-He has no memories, then?
-Only fragments.
The procedure,
it was interrupted.
I guess it's only a matter
of rounding him up.
You have had strays
before, right?
This is no stray, Doctor.
This one can Tune.
But that's impossible.
Only you have that ability.
You will process
another template...
of the subject's memories, yes?
Of course.
I'll imprint him again.
We require them
for a quite different purpose.
It's almost midnight,
Dr. Schreber.
We'll talk again
after tonight's Tuning,
but no more delays, yes?
No more inconsistencies
in your behavior.
The police were looking for you.
I know. I saw the papers.
"Killer stalks
city street-walkers."
I was with one of those women.
-Before I came here tonight.
-I don't understand.
I met her outside an Automat.
I guess I wanted to test myself.
I wanted to know if I had it
in me to do those things.
Maybe I have lost my mind,
but whoever I am, I'm still me,
and I'm not a killer.
I believe you.
You do?
-What?
-The car outside.
The one you arrived in.
It's a cop.
He dropped me off here.
I didn't know he was still here.
Hold it right there, mister!
-Wait. You have the wrong man.
-Stand aside, will you, please?
I didn't kill anyone.
Right now,
all you are is a suspect.
Turn yourself in. I'll listen
to whatever you have to say.
You won't believe
what I have to say.
-Try me.
-There's someone after me.
It's this group of men.
They want me dead.
And I don't even know if...
they're not even--
Yeah, who's going to listen
to a madman?
-Stand aside, Mrs. Murdoch.
-Run!
No one ever listens to me.
Murdoch, stop!
-How much further?
-We're almost there, buddy.
You happen to know
the way to Shell Beach?
You're kidding! Me and the wife
spent our honeymoon there.
All you do is
take Main Street West to...
Or is it the Cross...
Now, that's funny.
I can't seem to remember
if it's Main Street West...
or the Crosstown.
I'm sorry, lnspector,
I cannot be of more assistance,
but I am running late
for an appointment.
Well, I appreciate you
taking the time.
There's just one thing
that puzzles me.
I've met quite a few murderers
in the course of my work.
Murdoch doesn't
strike me as one.
Perhaps you are not accustomed
to digging deep enough.
Well, I do know when
someone is lying to me, Doctor.
Inspector, judging personalities
happens to be my business.
Maybe you can give me
a few pointers.
Certainly.
Let's take you, for instance.
You are a fastidious man.
Driven.
Consumed by details.
I would say
your life is rather lonely.
Good evening, lnspector.
I really must be going.
Come in.
-How is he?
-The same.
Walenski? It's me, Frank.
Come in, Frank.
Close the door.
I've been looking through
some of your old reports.
It's an interesting case.
Kind that make a man's career.
-Or break it.
-Yeah. I was on that case.
And then what?
What happened then, Eddie?
Nothing happened, Frank.
I've just been spending time
in the subway,
riding in circles.
Thinking in circles.
There's no way out.
I've been over this entire city.
You're scaring your wife
to death, Eddie.
She's not my wife.
I don't know who she is
or who any of us are.
-What makes you say that?
-You think about the past much?
As much as the next guy.
See, I've been trying
to remember things--
clearly remember things
from my past.
But the more
I try to think back,
the more it all starts
to unravel.
None of it seems real.
It's like I've just
been dreaming this life,
and when I finally wake up,
I'll be somebody else,
somebody totally different.
You saw something,
didn't you, Eddie.
Something to do with the case.
There is no case!
There never was!
It's all just a big joke!
It's a joke!
Tonight's requirements are...
12 family photo albums,
nine personal diaries,
17 love letters,
assorted childhood photographs,
requisite false l.D.s
and social security cards.
These do bring back memories.
This one is still warm.
What is it?
The recollections of
a great lover?
A catalogue of conquests?
We will soon find out.
You wouldn't
appreciate that,
would you,
Mr. Whatever-your-name is?
Not the sort of conquest
you would ever understand.
Let's see.
A touch of
unhappy childhood...
A dash of
teenage rebellion...
And last but not least...
a tragic death
in the family.
Mr. Book.
Why does Murdoch not sleep
during the Tuning?
Maybe he's a step up
the evolutionary ladder.
A freak of nature.
He's adapting to survive.
What do you expect?
Weren't you looking for
the human soul?
Isn't that the purpose
of your little zoo?
That's why you change people
and things every night.
Maybe you have finally
found what you are looking for,
and it's going to bite you
on your--
It requires several
of your lifetimes...
to master our gifts.
The idea that
a simple man...
could develop the ability
to Tune is--
Absurd, I know.
What other explanation is there?
It is time.
Shut it down.
Fredrickson says he'll take me
off the night shift.
It's about time, dear.
Hello?
Wake up.
Wake up!
Can anyone hear me?
Let the Tuning commence.
The Goodwins.
Charlie, Sylvia,
Jane, and little Matthew.
Jane and little Matthew.
The rich get richer.
Probably have
maid's quarters...
before the night
is through.
Dr. Schreber, I presume.
It's you.
Hey, come on.
That's no way to greet
a patient, Doctor,
if that's what you are.
Please, l--
Why is everyone asleep?
Please keep your voice down.
I can't remember anything.
What have you done?
Nothing. I want to help you.
We cannot talk here.
If they see us together--
I don't care.
I want some answers. Now!
Who are they?
Why are they trying to kill me?
Answer me!
My God.
-You really can do it.
-I did that?
Listen to me.
You have their power.
You can make things happen
by will alone.
They call it "Tuning."
That is how they change
the buildings.
Just now you acted
out of self-defense,
but I can teach you
to control your power.
We can stop them.
We can take the city back.
My glasses.
He made a terrible impression
for the firm,
Iollygagging around
as he did.
So I told Fredrickson
I was letting him go.
Well you should have, darling.
He attacked me.
I don't know where he's gone.
Come, Dr. Schreber.
We have much to do.
-Yes?
-Yes.
They say that
you're a runaround lover
Though you say it isn't so
But if you put me down
for another
I'll know, believe me, I'll know
Tonight's experiment will
take place in these locations.
The first subject
shall be imprinted on Avenue M.
Mr. Book, there is a problem.
There is no Avenue M.
We were unable
to complete it.
During the last Tuning,
we detected a lack of control.
An opposing influence
on the machines?
This man Murdoch is
more powerful than we thought.
He is becoming like us.
So we must become like him.
The doctor has done as we asked?
The life and times
of John Murdoch, volume two.
We must not do this.
Murdoch does not possess
these memories, yes?
How will his imprint
allow us to find him?
Everywhere he goes,
everyone he seeks out...
will be known to us.
And as he follows the clues,
so shall we follow the memories.
But to imprint one of us?
Failure has always resulted.
What Mr. Hand proposes
is our only option.
Imprint.
This may sting a bit.
Is it done?
Oh, yes, Mr. Book.
I have John Murdoch in mind.
"Johnny...
"Found this postcard
among your mother's things.
"Brings back memories,
doesn't it?
"Stop by sometime.
"We'll see if we can't
hook ourselves another mermaid.
"Love to Emma. Karl."
Karl.
Karl Harris.
Harris.
Excuse me.
Which way is Avenue C?
Try the subway.
You got a problem, pal?
Been working here long?
25 years.
No days off for good behavior.
We're looking for John Murdoch.
She knows nothing,
Mr. Hand.
A dead end, Mr. Wall.
We thought his imprint
would let us track him.
But instead
we have been brought here.
-This is irrational.
-Instincts are irrational.
We must follow
where they lead, yes?
Mr. Sleep suggests he may go
to places familiar.
His job.
He does not care about our job.
Indulge us, Mr. Hand.
If you were Murdoch, yes?
If I were Murdoch...
I would remember how
my wife had hurt me...
by sleeping with another man.
And then...
I would look for a way
to hurt her in return.
Leave me alone with her.
There's work to be done.
All change,
platform three.
All change?
Excuse me, how do I get
to the end of the line?
You want the Express.
How come the train didn't stop?
That's the Express.
There's no way out.
You can't get out of the city.
I've tried.
You're Murdoch, aren't you?
The one
they've been looking for.
You're not a killer.
They set you up with
a fake identity,
Iike everyone else here.
-Who are you?
-I was a cop.
At least in this life I was.
They steal peoples' memories.
Then they swap them around
between us.
I seen them do it,
back and forth...
till no one knows
who they are anymore.
How do you know all this?
Once in a while one of us
wakes up...
while they're changing things.
It's not supposed to happen,
but it does.
It happened to me.
They'll come looking for you.
Just like they'll come
looking for me.
But that's OK.
I figured a way out.
They were here.
Last night.
This was to be his home.
That was when we loved her.
This is all well and good,
but we require
a more practical link...
to his present whereabouts.
And I know where to find her.
We're very lucky,
when you think about it.
I'm sorry?
To be able to revisit
those places...
which meant
so very much to us.
I thought we were haunted
by them.
Perhaps.
There used to be a ferry
when I was a boy.
Biggest thing you ever saw.
Lit up like
a floating birthday cake.
That's just what my husband
once said to me.
On this very spot.
Where is your husband now?
I wish I knew.
What brings you here?
I met my wife at this place.
It's where I met my husband.
Small world.
Hello?
What are you doing here?
I've been following you.
Hold it right there!
Johnny?
It's been so damn long,
I thought you'd forgotten
your Uncle Karl.
You son of a gun!
Uncle Karl...
Wait.
-Is that me?
-Yeah.
Shell Beach is where
I grew up?
That's what I said.
Shell Beach.
-Your home town.
-I need to get there.
How do I get there?
I don't know.
I haven't been there in years.
You must remember.
You must have some idea.
Sorry, Johnny.
The old cracker barrel
ain't what it used to be.
-It was so bright there.
-Brighter times, I guess.
You were always scribbling
in that damn book.
That's me and your Pa.
What a couple of
handsome fools.
What happened to my parents?
Where are they now?
They're dead, Johnny.
They died when the house
burned down.
I looked after you.
You don't remember that,
really?
What's that? What is that?
It's a scar.
You burned your arm pretty bad
in the fire.
What does it mean?
It means these are all lies!
My husband told me
he'd been here.
He told me he wanted
to test himself.
See if he was...
capable of...
I wanted to talk to her.
I thought she could
help me find him.
I'm going to call the station.
It's beautiful.
It was a gift from my mother.
She died recently.
I keep it with me
to remind me of her.
I'm sorry.
It's a funny thing, though.
I can't remember
when she gave it to me.
How do you think I could
forget a thing like that?
What's happening, lnspector?
I'm not sure I know anymore.
I left your old room
like it was.
You can sleep here tonight.
Glad to have you back, Johnny.
-Even if it is for just a night.
-Karl.
-Is that the right time?
-Why, sure.
That clock's kept perfect time
since I bought it.
A.M. or P.M.?
-What do you think?
-I don't understand.
How can it be night already?
What happened to the day?
You're tired.
Anything's possible.
Get some sleep.
We'll straighten all this out
tomorrow.
Come on...
He's here.
He's acting peculiar.
I know. He's not himself.
Keep him there,
and I'll be right over.
-I'll try.
-Thanks. Bye.
I can't promise anything.
We'll play it as it comes.
We just wanted to help.
Karl. Uncle Karl.
If you're in trouble,
maybe we can do something.
Haven't seen you in so long.
Mr. Murdoch, you've been
the cause of much distress.
-Start talking.
-There's no need for this.
There's no escape.
The city's ours. We made it.
What are you talking about?
We fashioned this city
on stolen memories.
Different eras, different pasts,
all rolled into one.
Each night we revise it,
refine it, in order to learn.
-Learn what?
-About you.
You and your fellow inhabitants.
What makes you human.
-Why?
-We need to be like you.
I understand you now.
I remember that which you do
not, what you've been missing.
The ocean, yes? Running along
the waves as a child.
Meeting Emma at the river,
that first kiss that followed.
-What are you?
-You've seen what we are.
We use your dead as vessels.
Get in!
-What about her? Ring a bell?
-She was alive when I left her.
-What about this?
-This is nothing.
It must mean something--
all those pictures.
What pictures?
-I don't understand this.
-Stop playing games with me.
-Stop telling me lies.
-I am not telling lies!
Help me out.
Make me understand.
I have this jigsaw puzzle in
my face, and it makes no sense.
You think it makes sense to me?
I'm as confused as you are.
Let me ask you a question.
Have you heard of Shell Beach?
-Sure.
-You know how to get there?
-Yeah.
-Tell me.
-Right. You just go to the...
-Where? Where do you go?
Give me a second, will you?
You can't remember, can you?
Thinking that's kind of odd?
Wait. I got a better one.
When was the last time you
did something during the day?
-What do you mean?
-I just mean during the day.
Daylight. When was the last
time you remember seeing it?
I'm not talking about a distant,
half-forgotten childhood memory.
I mean, like, yesterday.
Last week? When?
Do you have a single memory?
You don't, do you?
I don't think the sun
even exists in this place.
'Cause I've been up for hours
and hours, and night never ends.
-That's crazy.
-You're damn right it's crazy.
But listen to me, Bumstead.
It's not just me.
It's all of us. They're doing
something to all of us.
Shut up.
I've heard enough.
-Please listen--
-Shut up!
There has to be an explanation.
Explain this.
I'm so sorry.
I never meant to hurt you.
I don't know why I did.
I wish I could take it back.
You didn't do it.
This affair of yours,
whatever you think you've done,
you didn't do it.
I don't believe it happened.
-What do you mean?
-This will sound crazy.
What if we never knew
each other before now?
What if the first time we met
was last night in our apartment?
And everything you remember,
and everything I'm supposed to
remember never really happened.
Someone just wants us
to think it did.
But how can that be true?
I so vividly remember
meeting you.
I remember falling in love
with you.
-I remember losing you.
-Time's up.
No, wait, please.
Just one more minute.
I love you, John.
You can't fake something
like that.
No, you can't.
Inspector? Sir?
Detective Walenski
killed himself last night.
I thought you should know.
The chief wanted to see you.
Sir?
I knew you'd track
the killer down.
Shoelace.
-How can we help you, sir?
-You can sleep.
Sleep. Sleep.
Evening.
I wanted to be the first to
congratulate you about the case.
Take us to Murdoch.
Sleep.
I knew you'd come eventually.
Isn't it time
you gave me some answers?
Yes, of course.
Won't you please sit down?
I come here often.
It's one of the few places
I'm allowed some peace.
You see, they have
an aversion to water.
One could almost call it
a phobia.
Who are they?
What do they want from me?
Right.
For now, let's say you're
the subject of their experiment.
We all are.
I'm sorry, but I have no time
to do this the right way.
Everything you need to know
is in this syringe.
I need you to inject yourself.
It's the only way to understand.
-You're kidding, right?
-We're running out of time!
-You have to do this now.
-Give me the gun.
He's more disturbed
than we thought.
I may not be the judge
of personality you are,
but you're the one
who looks disturbed.
You don't know what
you're doing.
What exactly is in this, Doctor?
All the answers you've been
looking for, I swear to you.
Guess I'll hold on to it for
safekeeping, if you don't mind.
Let's go, Doctor.
Go? Where are we going?
Shell Beach.
That's where you wanted to go,
isn't it, the ocean?
Won't find anything there.
I've been there--
Then you can show us the way.
I won't. I refuse.
You can't make me go there.
Don't you understand?
They'll be waiting for us.
I don't understand.
There used to be a bridge here.
Try that again, and your friends
will find you in the canal.
Don't hurt me.
I'll tell you everything.
It doesn't matter anymore
anyway.
What?
Who are you people?
Must go to the end
of the canal.
We will give you some more
pretty things soon...
-Anna.
-I'm not Anna.
You will be soon, yes.
I have another use
for her first.
I call them Strangers.
They abducted us
and brought us here.
This city, everyone in it...
is their experiment.
They mix and match our memories
as they see fit,
trying to divine
what makes us unique.
One day, a man might be
an inspector.
The next,
someone entirely different.
When they want to study
a murderer, for instance,
they simply imprint one of their
citizens with a new personality.
Arrange a family for him,
friends, an entire history...
even a lost wallet.
Then they observe the results.
Will a man, given the history of
a killer, continue in that vein?
Or are we, in fact, more than
the sum of our memories?
This business of you being
a killer was a sad coincidence.
You have had dozens of lives
before now.
You happened to wake up...
while I was imprinting you
with this one.
Why are they doing all this?
It is our capacity for
individuality, our souls...
that makes us different
from them.
They think they'll find
the human soul...
if they understand
how our memories work.
They have collective memories.
They share one group mind.
They're dying. Their race is
on the brink of extinction.
-They think we can save them.
-Where do I fit in?
You're different. You resisted
my attempt to imprint you.
Somehow, you have developed
their ability to Tune.
That is how they change things,
how they built this city.
They have machines buried
beneath the surface...
that allow them to focus
their telepathic energies.
They control everything here,
even the sun.
That's why it's always dark.
They can't stand the light.
Why do they need you?
When they first brought us here,
they extracted what was in us
and stored the information,
remixed it like paint...
and gave us back
new memories of their choosing.
But they still needed an artist
to help them.
I understood the human mind
better than they ever could,
so they allowed me to keep
my skills as a scientist...
because they needed them.
They made me delete
everything else.
Can you imagine what it's like
to erase your own past?
What about my past?
What about my childhood?
Shell Beach. Uncle Karl.
What about this?
This was blank when I found it.
You still don't understand.
You were never a boy.
Not in this place.
Your history is an illusion,
a fabrication,
as it is with all of us.
You made those drawings happen
with your gift.
You say they brought us here.
From where?
I'm sorry. I don't remember.
None of us remember that...
what we once were...
what we might have been...
somewhere else.
I've taken you this far.
You don't need me anymore.
Let's go.
There is no ocean, John.
There's nothing beyond the city.
The only place home exists...
is in your head.
Stop!
Please!
Now you know the truth.
You'll allow yourself
to surrender...
or it will result in
this one's death.
What do I care?
She's not my real wife.
She's nothing to me.
But you do still care,
don't you, Mr. Murdoch?
I have become the monster
you were intended to be.
Shall I end her life now,
as you would have?
-Don't hurt her, please.
-Then surrender.
Sleep.
Now.
Kill him.
Kill him !
He is powerful, yes, dangerous.
But he can also lead us
to what we seek...
what the doctor calls the soul.
It is time for our experiment
to move into a final phase.
We no longer need
the other subjects.
The time for study is over.
It is time to be one
with John Murdoch.
It is time, Doctor. Imprint.
Shut it down!
Shut it down forever.
What are you doing?
They want to imprint you with
their own collective memories.
They want to make you
one of them...
so they can share your soul.
But I've got other plans.
Imprint, Doctor.
No more disobedience.
I'm sorry. The pain will
only last a moment.
Remember, John.
You'll rise to greater heights
than that.
One day when you're older,
you'll understand.
Remember.
That's it, John.
Practice makes perfect.
Now, remember what I told you.
Never talk to strangers.
John, remember.
You're probably wondering why I
keep appearing in your memories.
It's because I have
inserted myself in them.
They were fabricated to
teach you about the Strangers.
Give you a lifetime of knowledge
in a single syringe.
You will survive, John. You'll
find strength within yourself.
And you will prevail.
Remember.
-Hi, Uncle Karl.
-Johnny!
Getting the hang of it, John.
Maybe one day I'll work for you.
Here's the machine the Strangers
use to amplify their thoughts,
the machine that changes
their world.
You must take control of it.
You must make the machine yours.
I know you can beat them,
but you must concentrate.
Something's wrong.
There is no time for romance.
The world can be
what you make it.
What have you done?
You have the power
to make anything happen...
but you must act now.
I knew you could do it, John.
You have their power now.
-You control their machines.
-Where's Emma?
She's not Emma anymore.
She has been reimprinted.
-So give her back her memories.
-I can't.
The facility where they stored
the memories has been destroyed.
I'm sorry.
What are you going to do now?
I'm gonna fix things.
You told me I had the power,
didn't you?
I can make these machines
do anything I want.
Make this world
anything I want it to be.
Just so long as I concentrate
hard enough.
Where are you going?
Shell Beach.
-What's the fare?
-A quarter.
-Please.
-Oh, no, sit.
Thank you.
Been waiting for you, yes?
-What are you doing?
-I'm just making a few changes.
-We're sure that's what we want?
-I'll take my chances.
I'm dying, John. Your imprint
is not agreeable with my kind.
But I wanted to know
what it was like.
How you feel.
You know how I was
supposed to feel.
That person isn't me.
Never was.
You wanted to know what it was
that makes us human.
Well, you're not going to
find it in here.
You went looking
in the wrong place.
It's so beautiful here.
So bright.
Do you know if Shell Beach
is around here?
I think that's it over there.
I'm headed that way myself.
Would you like to join me?
Sure.
I'm Anna, by the way.
What's your name?