"The silence of nature knows many sounds"
Henriette Roland Holst(1869-1952)
The light brings on a new spring.
Underwater, the cycle of life begins anew
In the land that we have conquered from the sea...
we forgot a small piece:
the Oostvaarderplassen (Netherlands)
Here only the laws of nature rule.
This is about the rights of the strongest,
about cooperation and vitality...
about living and to let live.
In this context we are shown the
unprecedented power of nature.
For four seasons we stand eye to eye
with the animals that are our neighbours.
This is our land as we have never seen it.
THE NEW WILDERNESS
Here in the grasslands the wild horses
reign supreme.
Almost a thousand Queen's horses
form hundreds of families.
A black mare has been born.
That seldom happens.
Foals are usually white as is
her cousin.
The black foal is a little shy.
She is hiding behind her mother...
and wants to spend the whole day
drinking her warm milk.
Her cousin is curious and playfull.
During the winter the Queen's horses
loose a lot of weight.
Now that the grass is tender and nutritious
everyone must graze...
to put on weight and strength.
One stallion is the leader.
He protects the family...
while the leading mare
has the "brains".
She know exactly where to find
the tastiest grass.
The world of the Queen's horses is
a world of scents.
Now that it is spring
and the mares are fertile...
they smell stronger than normal.
The young stallions are becoming
terribly excited...
by all the seductive fragrances.
They want to break the
head stallion's might.
They have to constantly keep an
eye on their rivals.
In the first 20 minutes after
the birth...
the two foals have two huge challenges:
walking and drinking.
The herd will not wait and
there is no room for weak animals.
They will be left behind.
The legs are as long as those of his mother.
Instinct know faultlessly what has to happen...
although it is easier said than done.
From the moment you arrive on this world
you have to fight to survive.
Your brother, already a year old,
wants to snack off mother.
You want to as well,
but how do you do it?
All you know is that you have
to be by a dark place...
somewhere about eye level.
In the swamp, building is in full swing.
The birds fly to and from their nests
with building materials
Design and implementation, material choices
and construction...
are processed with great precision.
But the most important question
for spring is...
who will be your new partner.
This choice is not random.
Some birds swap partners every year...
others live their whole lives
together.
The cormorants and grebes get to know each other
with their mating dance.
Such courtship shows the strength
and beauty of the future parents...
and is carried out with great care.
The act of mating affirms the partnership.
And the beginning of a new adventure.
There are thousands of grey goslings born
and they need to graze.
They want to get to the grasslands
as quickly as possible
That is a journey full
of danger
The Mute Swan doesn't appreciate those dumb geese
with their young...
barging straight through his territory.
Two large geese hold the swan busy
while the group escapes.
The geese play a major role in the
management of the swamp area
By eating the reeds the geese
give variation to the swamp.
which allows many other bird
species to flourish
Under the ground, spring has also started
After months of darkness
the colletes bee awakens.
On the first warm spring day,
exactly a half day after the males...
the females come out of
the ground en masse...
all together as if a giant alarm clock
has sounded
The feast of light is once
more enhanced...
by all the males flying in joyful
anticipation of the females
All day the bees are very busy
with each other.
The eggs are laid in little
underground holes...
and need until the next spring
to grow into bees.
No where in Europe do so many Queen's horses
live together in the wild.
This makes the special social structure
of the herd easily visible.
The families work together...
they use a complicated language
of sounds.
Body postures, gestures and odours.
It is warm on this spring day and the
horses are seeking to cool down.
For the mares this is an ideal moment to let
the foals get used to the water.
But the water is cold and one foal has
lost its enthusiasm
It has become too cold
The breeze has picked up and it is
rapidly becoming colder.
The mares are beginning to worry.
The foal is lying down too long.
It must get moving quickly.
otherwise it will die from hypothermia.
Family council.
Only the reddy-brown, childless mare is only too happy to help.
The head stallion soon lets it be known that
unrequested help is frowned upon.
Mother's love is big,
but permits no weakness.
The foal is severely dealt with,
it must get up and walk to survive.
Life is demanding and
this foal is fragile...
but it looks like it might survive.
In a peaceful corner of the swampland
by a toppled willow tree...
Kingfishers.
The Kingfisher male waits patiently
until the female has finished...
with the inspection of the nesting hole.
The root bulb seems to him an
exquisite place to nest.
The question is if she also agrees
with this.
Males have a black lower beak,
females an orange one.
To remove her last doubt,
he has a present for her.
That fish was a good idea.
The goslings need a lot of healthy grass.
Preferable, for safety sake,
they should be close to the water.
But there isn't enough grass.
There is no other choice
than to take a risk.
The parents are on their utmost gaurd.
They know danger looms not far from
the water's edge
The fox has more prisoners
than he can eat today.
He doesn't kill for pleasure.
What he has in excess, he buries for later.
Nothing is wasted.
It is an honorable burial.
Young foxes also need to eat.
To sharpen their reflexes and to
learn to deal out their cache fairly...
the young spend all day at loggerheads.
They must, because
the strongest hunter will survive.
They do not yet need to hunt,
that will come later.
Mother supplies the food, but they
must prepare it themselves.
Today we are eating geese, the same as yesterday
and presumably tomorrow.
Tasty, but you do get a dry mouth
from all those feathers.
Spring is already coming to
an end for the bees.
They are quickly gathering
the last of the food inside.
The Earth Bumblebee has
only just begun.
The workers comb a large
area for food...
and find the path to the nest again...
by memorising many points
in the landscape.
The nest is now full of
working females.
Everything revolves around the queen.
She is elected by her hive
and thereafter heavily fed.
She gets fertilized once
and she survives just one winter.
The queen must now live up to the task of
producing masses of eggs...
so that next year there
will be new queens...
that will supply new hive members.
The kingfisher has the beaver as
the closest neighbour.
In the spring they immediately begin
the repair of winter's damage...
to their nests.
The marriage that started with a fish
has in the meantime produced young birds.
The male must wait a while
with his shopping...
because there is faeces in the way.
That's what you get with kids!
He know well what he has started,
he has to work his butt off.
At least 40 times a day he
flies to and fro with fish.
After the cleaning the female takes
a bath and makes herself pretty.
That at least shows the male
why he is doing all this.
Almost no-one knows that this
is a nightingale.
It sings, of course, mostly overnight.
Full-on spring!
In the swamp the new day is
being welcomed...
by the symphony of the cormorant...
reed bunting...
Bluethroat...
Sedge warbler...
and Savi's warbler.
and breakfast...
comes along by itself.
In the grasslands the stallions
begin a special showdown.
The horses fight with
self-control.
It is about the ritual, about the
order of the group.
Scents are as important to these horses
as words are to us.
The dung tells the stallions about
the position that they occupy in the herd.
The rank order constantly changes .
Ambition or the lack thereof,
strength, masculinity...
it appears to be all written
in the waste products.
Everyone profits from each other.
In the dung of the queen's horses
a new world is created...
That of the dung flies
The males fight about
the best spots.
This dung heap is great for mating
and laying eggs.
As soon as a female comes past...
they jump en masse into the air
to grab her.
They are over the moon about it.
They themselves are so busy
they almost forget the females.
All that buzzing and flying
attracts yellow wagtails
In this bursting fly-in restaurant
they enjoy a welcome snack...
on their migration to
the north.
When the dungfly male has
taken the female...
he protects her until she
lays the eggs.
The eggs are equipped with a sort of armband...
so that they don't sink
too deep into the dung.
Flies, horses and birds.
Three different worlds...
but inextricably joined to each other.
In the cormorant colony the young
are growing like a weed.
They always want to eat more.
The coming of a strong north-westerly wind
makes it difficult for the parents
They must sometimes fly for tens of kilometers
to find the best fish.
Not only does the strong wind cost more time,
but also much more energy.
With this bad weather the young need
more food to keep warm.
The cormorants store their catch
in their crop.
They fly as low as possible
to take advantage of the air cushion...
that because of their wing beat
exist just above the water.
Just like cyclists they fly in formation
to save energy.
After a long arduous flight, landing in this
strong wind is a tricky art.
Having gone to so much trouble,
their crop is nearly empty.
The food that was intended for the young...
was food that the fisher itself
needed for fuel.
There is no other choice:
They need to immediately resume fishing
even though they are so tired.
Something is in the air
There is bad weather is on the way.
Cold and warm air layers collide
The recipe for a perfect
summer storm
When you experience your first thunder and
lightning storm it's very frightening.
Even Queen's horses know not to shelter
under a tree during a thunderstorm.
The whole herd escape to the safe boundaries
of the area.
Some animals are happy with the thunderstorm.
So, during the night, the lust of the
Natterjack toads awakens
Due to the heavy shower the pools
wherein they have propagated...
have filled with fresh rain water
With loud raised voices
the males roar to their females.
the vocal lure can be heard for kilometers.
The whole region profits from
the rainwater.
Now millions of tadpoles
appear.
And even more waterfleas.
Thus, because so much food is available...
there appears a patient enemy,
the Rod bug.
With one hefty storm the whole
system has come into motion.
Seldom does he let himself be seen:
the Bittern
Here he has found a place
where he feels safe.
That doesn't count for the brown frog.
He's on the bittern's menu.
Because of the high water level
and temperature...
the Carp have become active.
The carp must spawn in shallow water.
The long journey makes them vulnerable,
foxes also eat fish.
The males scour their flanks along
the belly of the females...
to stimulate the release
of the spawn.
During this process the carp have not noticed
that the water has again dropped.
It is now too shallow.
The wind has dropped.
But not in time for the cormorants.
For far too long it has blown fiercely...
and in all that time they have
not been able provide enough fish.
The young are hungry and are begging
their distraught parents.
They try to regurgitate something,
but their crop is empty.
The youth wants to really fish himself,
but he can't fly yet.
And when mother returns from her last
fishing trip, the chick has died.
In good years, the cormorants bring
up two young per nest.
This is an exceptionally
bad year.
On average less than one young
per nest grows up to be an adult.
Nothing is for nothing. Everyone carries their burden,
fights for their kind...
and feels instinctively that they cannot do
without the others, in life and in death.
The carp marriage ends in a sad tone,
but the wedding feast is for the brown rat.
The blowflies lay their eggs
in the dead fish.
They become maggots and attract other
guests to come .
The sadly beached carp are exactly
what this waterway needs.
With this she can give her chicks
a good start to life.
The young get cleanly rinsed maggots.
It is high summer. The wheel of life
is turning at full speed.
There is food in surplus.
In the rough vegetation the
field thistles are being sucked dry...
by masses of aphids.
Their excretions is called honey dew
and that is a sweet waste.
Ants find it delightful.
In their turn the ants
milk the aphids.
The aphid enjoy working with them,
but do want something in return.
The ant must stop his greatest enemy, the larvea
of the ladybird bug.
And that is something you don't
have to tell an ant twice.
It is now warm enough for the green-veined
white and small cabbage white butterflies.
Finally they can fly.
The caterpillars from the cabbage white
feed on the leaf...
of the exuberant yellow flowering
black mustand.
As soon as they have become butterflies,
they fly to the field thistles.
For the nectar
Having eaten, it is naturally
time for propagation.
The males don't shrink from
interrupting each other's lovemaking.
They are small and vulnerable,
but the mutual ties are strong.
Thus the strength and vitality of the whole
system is guaranteed
Every creature knows:
Alone I will never survive.
The ladies and the gentlemen deer
live apart.
Only when it is time to mate
will they seek each other out.
The last get-together was very
productive.
Hundreds of deer calves have been born.
They wait while the mothers
graze elsewhere with the herd.
They are not too good on
their hooves the first few days.
The ground begins to tremble. The calf
chooses the sure from the unsure.
and seeks a safe refuge
in the tall grass.
The Queen's horses are having the spring sillies...
and they are trotting in stampede.
Why? Maybe just because it is fun.
The horses are looking on in surprise.
They are used to their foal,who
immediately after birth...
Will attach themselves to the herd.
While deer and horses normally
shun each other...
it appears here that the mother instinct is stronger.
They try to force the deer calf
into action.
But the calf is keeping well down.
The young foxes are beginning to get
interested in the outside world.
Soon this will be their hunting terrain,
so the sooner they learn the better.
At the end of the day the does
come to gather their calves.
The mothers find them by calling out,
and then listening very carefully.
The calves make unique sounds
that the mother can recognise.
No calf is left behind. Without effort
mother and child are reunited.
A group of spoonbills
has come together...
to profit from the
water teeming with life.
With their long beak
they search for insects and small fish.
For the cormorant chicks
it is time to leave the nest.
They might be as large
as their parents...
They still can't do anything for themselves.
They must now fish by themselves.
Although this still means figuring out
what is fish and what is not
A kingfisher must be very
stress resistant.
Everything goes fast in their world.
The chicks are not five
minutes out of the nest...
and father expects them to fend for themselves.
Mother has already had enough of the young fry.
They have to go.
The parents want to start a new path
as soon as possible.
They show them how to fish a couple of times
and then it's up to them.
Nicely caught, but unfortunately, not a fish.
But still, within four days, the young kingfishers
will be independant...
and will leave the parents territory.
Now as the summer is progressing
the nights are getting colder.
At this time the Queen's horses come
together in one large herd.
All the families have merged.
Including the family with the black foal.
It is a peaceful scene,
but that is from an outward appearance.
But there is serious unrest.
Groups of single young stallions
live in the herd.
There, swirling testosterone is
overflowing in their veins.
They want to be the alpha male,
they want to mate, they want power.
The young stallions place the leaders
under severe strain.
The alpha males must protect their families
from these attacks.
The prize of leadership is high.
A dominant alpha stallion often
has many scars from earlier fights.
A young challenger suspects weakness
and starts the attack.
Another light coloured stallion
appears on the scene.
He has a wholly different strategy.
He doesn't attack the leader, but chases the
challenger away because he realises:
if you show a little bit of cooperation,
you can achieve a whole lot more.
The old stallion is well aware of it.
It costs him a lot less energy
to keep his family together
The challenger is contemplating a new assault...
but he realises that something has changed.
This is the deal between the
young and the old stallion:
If you help,
you can maybe be my successor.
But the lead stallion
is a tough teacher.
The white stallion must constantly show
that he is taking the task seriously.
The young one is now servant
and plays an important role in the family.
That gives him respect
and a higher place in the pecking order.
The challenger gives up.
the assaults on the position of the
lead stallion will keep coming...
But, for the time being, peace has returned.
You do not achieve success
by using brute force.
You achieve it with carefully forged
cooperatives...
wherein the balance between giving and taking
is continually renegotiated.
For today the poleaxe
will be buried.
The herd relax and enjoy
the late afternoon sun.
During these last summer days does it seem
that there is an enormous, humming...
Singing, neighing, quacking,
lowing organism has been created.
On such a day it is hard to imagine...
that a new season is lurking ahead.
Autumn...
and the air is pregnant with hormones.
Now the animals are gorging themselves
on fruits and seeds to make themselves...
as strong as possible to go into winter,
and the days are getting shorter...
the thicket seems to explodes
with a ferocious roar.
It is the time for the
red deer rut.
But first for some sparring.
And flinging some grass in the air
also makes a good impression.
The old deer wants to be involved
one more time.
He has to pump himself up
to tackle his rivals.
By peeing on himself, he underlines
his status and manliness.
The smell also makes sure
that the females know...
that they have to be with him
if they want to be protected.
It is all about the females.
the deer must gather and fertilize
the greatest possible harem.
The luck of the draw
turns out bad for the leader.
His first opponent is the biggest
and strongest in the herd
They size each other up.
The fight is short.
The challenger achieves a convincing
win in his first fight.
Unfortunately the ladies are less than
impressed with this manly conduct.
How difficult it may seem
you must not be too hasty.
It will be another two weeks to
the peak of the rutting season...
when the real decisions will be made.
Hidden between the field thistles...
the old deer keeps a eye on his opponents.
The most tropical bird in the Netherlands,
the goldfinch...
keeps him company.
It's a feast.
A fast expanding swarm of starlings
have discovered an overladen elderberry tree.
Dinner is in full swing.
In appreciation of the lift the sparrows leave
a track of elderberry poo behind.
It appears the Queens don't care at all
that they are becoming like purple zebras.
In the horse dung the starlings are
looking for insects.
They have developed strong beak muscles...
To make digging easier.
The black foal is doing her best...
To gorge herself for the coming winter.
But she does not find it really tasty.
Friends of her age have grown rapidly.
And the young stallions are constantly
busy with mock fights.
The mare foal likes nothing better
than to be close to her mother.
Compared to her cousin,
she is lean and scraggy.
This is a nasty situation.
The large grazing animals must now build up
their fat reserves for the winter.
They become some 70 kilos heavier.
In times of scarcity you must
build up this layer of fat...
otherwise there is a chance that
you will come short of spring.
The rut is at its peak.
The strongest deer have formed harems.
The most important issue, copulation,
is not decided by macho behaviour.
Tenderness play a role just as important.
The deer can put on a sturdy effort...
but it is up to the does;
they decide by whom they are fertilized.
The memories of his previous might and glory...
forces the old deer to have a go
one more time.
He doesn't have a chance. His pride is broken
as he leaves his last defeat.
Nearby the red deer rut
things are getting harsh.
More then by injuries, the weaker
animals are giving up due to exhaustion.
The ongoing fights demand the utmost...
and that costs them their resistance.
The  first to discover this are the ravens.
And thereafter the foxes.
Death is just as important as life,
as nothing is wasted.
Out of death, life begins again.
After a month only the bones are left...
and has provided a tasty food
for tens of creatures.
The wilderness of the Oostvaarderplassen
clothes itself...
deep in autumn, in a dense fog.
As pale angels the great silver herons
stand in the shallow water
End October brings on the first
barnacle geese.
After a flight more than 3000 Km
from their brooding places...
on Nova Sembla and in east Russia
More than 30,000 geese come here
to hibernate.
When they land, the frost will soon begin.
The foals see snow for the first time.
Again, every member of the herd has to get
used to the hard water.
A northeasterly wind carries in cold air.
The temperature drops rapidly.
The queens know that together
they can withstand much more.
They stand close together and
turn their backsides into the wind.
The youngest and weakest horses
get to stand in the warmest places...
in the middle of the group.
But the black foal
steps out of this shelter.
She is hungry and is looking for food.
This is a dangerous sign.
There is now almost nothing to eat.
The horses now rely on their fat reserves.
She has eaten too little,
hence not enough reserves.
Therefore it will become extremely difficult
to survive the winter
The hunting grounds are becoming
scarce for everyone.
The fox and the buzzard
are forces to search longer and longer.
There is no doubt that some field mice
are hiding under the snow.
But they are no easy prey.
It is freezing.
Eating is hardly possible while drinking
is now more and more dificult.
The queen's horses abandon the open plain.
Grass has become unreachable
under the layer of snow and ice.
They now search for their preservation
under the shelter of trees and bushes.
Death is lying in wait everywhere.
Water is freezing rapidly and is dangerous.
The leg is frozen and nothing can be done.
Connecting with the herd
is no longer possible
Without the protection of the group,
the chances of survival are slim.
The winter is ruthless.
It's freezing, it's blowing a polar wind,
it's snowing.
Everyone is sorely tested.
All the animals have moved away
from the plains.
Only the mute swans won't give up their spot.
The clouds pull away.
The earth radiates out its last warmth.
It is the harbinger of a period of Siberian cold.
Some animals can't handle the hardship
of this hard winter.
With the great wisdom of
their instinct...
they feel they may not see in
the coming spring...
and find a place to die.
However sad the loss of a life is...
the group, the most important unit, survives
On the spot where life is celebrated
so intensely...
is the death just as important.
Bearded reedling roam the reedbeds
in large groups.
They've eaten insects during the whole summer.
They switch their digestive system over
and pounce on reed seeds
Very different, but also tasty.
The other swamp birds
are not such easy eaters.
They want fish, and that's that.
But they swim relaxed, unreachable,
under the thick layer of ice.
The kingfisher male has decided
to spend the winter here.
This is to make sure that next year
he will still own this territory.
His partner and all the others have already
flown south beyond the frost line.
He had not counted on such a cold winter.
But it is too late as his last fishing
spot has frozen over.
The kingfisher must eat every hour.
A few hours without and he starves.
The cold then rapidly gets him
in its deathly grip.
A redbreast and the black foal
keep each other company.
The little foal digs the reed roots
and that brings out insects...
that the redbreast eats with gratitude.
They have become allies.
The foal has used up all of her fat stores...
and has no more reserves.
The little grebes have found the last
piece of water.
They just beat the bittern to it.
The hungry bittern decides to attempt
to catch one of them.
but they are on to him.
And then it appears there is much
easier prey amongst the reeds.
The horse with the frozen leg
didn't make it.
That is the chance the foxes and ravens
have been waiting for.
For them the heavy winter regularly
reserves a rich menu.
Although You can now eat what you want,
the nutritional value is minimal...
and you use more fat than
you produce.
What you have added on in summer,
determines what you can lose in winter.
Mother's milk is finished.
With the coming of a clear bitterly cold night
the end is also approaching.
The family mourns the loss of their young.
They travel further, because only the
strongest will survive.
And a little friend brings a last greeting.
There is always a new beginning.
Always there is the next sunrise...
the next spring...
the next generation.
The light returns and
warms the chilled earth.
After a long, severe winter...
the circle of life begins to turn
again at full speed.
In the land the people have
captured from the sea...
in a time when nature is under
pressure from everywhere...
here it is displaying an unprecedented
strength and richness.
A foal has been born.
a foal that lives in freedom amongst
hundreds of thousands of people...
in the densely populated land of Europe...
In the New Wilderness.
The see eagle is breeding again in the Netherlands
for the first time since the middle ages
Nowhere in Europe do so many red deer live together.
The fox hunts in The New Wilderness during the day.
That's something you almost never see anywhere else.
In 1978 the silver heron found a brooding site here
and this has in the meantime...
grown into one of the largest
colonies in north-west Europe.
The biggest wild horse herd in Europe
lives in the Oostvaarderplassen.
Narrated by
Harry Piekema
Music Composition
Bob Zimmerman
Captions by Hans Sanders ©
South Australia