Alright let's
finish packing
and get the hell outta here.
What the hell is that?
A gun.
Are you serious?
Ben...
will be out soon.
He'll try to find me.
He always does.
He has no idea where
you're going.
What if he finds out?
Alice, I don't like
you having a gun. You don't
even have a license for it.
I don't understand. Why
can't you just stay here and
work while I'm in New York.
I don't want to be
alone in the apartment.
I don't feel safe here.
Besides, I'm already
behind on my deadline.
You're putting yourself
under too much pressure.
It's too soon.
If I don't go to work
I will go crazy.
You look
really great on film.
You're a real
voyeur ain'tcha?
Filmmaker.
Oh, like there's
a difference?
There's other
things to film.
You're ruining my shots.
So how much are you
paying for this
place anyway?
Free.
Free?
Uh-huh.
This is the slimy producer
who's been trying to get
in your pants
for the last
year, correct?
He's not slimy. He's rich.
And he's helping out
a struggling writer.
Yeah. Right.
You know
what I was thinking?
Maybe you should write
about your own life?
It might be therapeutic.
I have no interest
in writing a horror film.
Oh my God
we've found it.
You think it's
big enough for me?
It's big enough
for a football team.
Oh my Goodness.
You are gonna be
so lonely here.
That's exactly
what I want.
It's perfect.
Well alright then!
It's huge.
Oh my Goodness.
Ohhhh.
Come on,
let's go upstairs.
Oh.
Bedroom?
Yes.
Look at that balcony.
I could definitely
get used to this.
Okay.
Old houses
are like people.
They grumble
and moan and cry
like they're in pain.
And keep you
awake at night.
I'm gonna miss you.
Are you?
Yes.
Even your sarcasm.
Ben was stupid to do
what he did to you.
I hate it
when you're sad, Alice.
It makes me sad too.
Come on.
Come on, let's check
out the rest of the house
before you have to leave.
Alice?
Where are ya?
Hey.
How odd.
I wonder
who owned this place before
the producer guy bought it.
I have no idea.
A family, I guess.
Alice.
Don't... Don't
torture yourself.
Come on. Come.
Come on.
Let's go.
Are you
sure you want me
to take the car?
Yes.
You'll be stranded
here without it.
That's the whole point,
so I can focus and work.
Why don't you just let me
take a cab to the airport,
it's not a big deal.
Becky, I don't want the car.
I'm never gonna use it.
Okay. If you're sure.
This is everything.
Where's my laptop?
Up stairs
in the bedroom
with your suitcase.
Is this enough
food for one week?
Plenty. I don't eat
much when I'm working.
I'll unpack the rest.
Come on,
let's go before
you miss your flight.
You'd better
call me.
Oh, of course I will.
Don't forget
to brush your teeth.
Thanks, Mom.
Don't forget
to drive carefully.
Hello.
Hello?
Becca? Hi.
Ally. I have something
to tell you. Promise me
you won't freak out.
Ben turned up
at the apartment looking
for you. He's out of prison.
Since when?
Last night.
Last night?
And you didn't
call me to warn me?
Calm down, please.
He has no idea
were you are.
No, I'm not calming down.
Ben knows he's going
to go back to prison if
he comes within a mile of you.
Rebecca, Ben doesn't
care about the law
and you know that!
Shit!
Need a hand Scooch?
I got it.
Play with your toy.
Hey, show me the ring.
Haven't you seen it
enough already?
Well Mrs. Woods,
I would like to see
how the lens does on closeups.
Tsk.
Wish I could've
afforded the other one.
David.
Don't say that. Alright?
I adore this ring.
And I adore you.
So what time
is your mom coming?
Seven.
Is she planning
on spending the night again?
It's her house.
She just gets
lonely by herself.
Alright. I'll talk to her.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Well
dinner's almost done
I think you could put
that thing away.
David!
Alright!
You look so cute
in your sexy glasses.
Come on turn it off.
Don't tell me
you weren't a
runway model one day.
Flattery will
get you nowhere.
Okay. Why don't
you pretend you're
somebody famous then.
No, Ally, I'm reading!
Give me the damn camera!
No, I don't think so.
Oh oh oh, she thinks
she's stronger than me!
I can't leave
the film like that!
It's still rolling!
So how long
are you going
to keep me a secret?
You're not a secret.
Nobody knows about me.
I haven't met
any of your friends.
Are you ashamed of me?
Oh, that's not true.
Then what
are you afraid of?
I'm afraid that
if Ben finds out
how close we are
he's gonna get
the wrong idea.
Wrong idea about what?
It doesn't matter.
Ally, nothing
is going to happen to you.
I had this dream once
where he killed me.
It's just a dream.
He's getting out soon.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hello?
Oh, it's me.
Alice, it's 4:00
o'clock in the morning.
I though someone had died.
I just. I needed
to hear your voice.
Is something wrong?
I'm not sure.
What does that mean?
I
I don't know,
I think, uh,
I think there's
someone in the house.
Have you called
the police?
No, it's not like that.
Call the damn
police or I will.
It's not normal.
Tell me what's
going on. You're
not making any sense.
I think someone died here.
Call the damn
police or I will.
I can feel it.
I can feel
the sadness, the energy.
Did you hear
what I just said?
Yes.
Well?
I think you watch
too many movies.
This house is creepy.
It's an old house, Ally.
Of course it's creepy.
Someone used my laptop.
And I keep
hearing these voices.
Someone crying
like they're
in so much pain.
Ally?
Yes?
Have you been taking
your medication?
You don't believe me.
It's 4:00 o'clock
in the morning and
you're talking about a ghost.
I shouldn't have called you.
No. Don't say that, please.
I'm glad you called.
Look, why don't you get
a taxi back to the city,
you'll be
here in a few hours.
I'm not leaving.
I came here to work.
You are putting yourself
under too much pressure.
You'll make yourself
sick again. Alice?
Alice?
Are you there?
Hello?
Yes. Alright.
I'll take my pills.
Sorry I called you.
Inspire me, Lucy.
My muse.
You are so beautiful.
Thank you.
Can you please
stop filming? You know,
it kinda makes me nervous
What time
do you think
you'll be home?
Not too late.
What's your friend's
name again?
Marie.
She single?
No.
She's a,
she's married
to Luke, remember?
Luke was at the wedding.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Was Marie at the wedding?
She's one
of my best friends.
I haven't really seen her
that much since I've been
with you, you know.
She is gonna freak
when I tell her
that I'm pregnant.
Ever since
we were little
we were always saying
we'd get
pregnant together.
You didn't tell her?
I've been saving it.
I wanna see her face
when I say ' I'm pregnant! '
you know?
I want the surprise.
You know, how do
I even know you're
seeing this girl. Huh?
You could be...
going to see some guy
David?
We're having a baby together?
How could you say that?
I guess I'm scared.
Scared of what?
Scared that you'll
meet someone else.
Scared that I'll lose you.
But I belong
to you. Remember?
You're just so
young and beautiful.
What man wouldn't
want to be with you?
Hey!
You came to help.
Oh, my god... Oh, honey.
Oh this place looks.
Our son is going to be
so proud of his beautiful
and talented mother.
Or maybe our daughter.
Then I'll have two
amazing women in my life.
David.
Can you stop playing
for a minute and
please help?
I'm documenting. All
of it. Everything
we're doing.
For our kid.
You're documenting?
Yeah, it's important.
Oh! What?
That is
completely unnecessary.
Ugh it's documentable.
Yeah, get it.
Oh, okay, I will.
Ughhhh, you killed me!
Nooo!
That's ridiculous!
Here here here.
Wait wait wait.
There, I'm helping.
No, yes, very helpful.
I'm crazy about you,
you know that?
You're my world.
David. What
brought this on?
I'm just being
nice to my wife
because she deserves it.
Well, thank you,
but I'm working.
You're distracting me.
Yeah?
You don't want to be
distracted right now?
No, not right now.
Why not?
Hm.
David, come on.
I'm serious.
Your smell Schoochy.
David. David!
What? Honey?
Just. You know. Jesus.
I just want
to be close
to you, honey, don't.
What?
Baby don't walk
away, I'm sorry.
What happened
to you, Lucy?
I'd like to see you.
Maybe I'll go back
to school in a few years.
Psychology?
You're right.
I never
thought about it
that way but it's true.
I'm going to,
uh, call you back.
Who you talking to?
Who were
you talking to?
Did you hear
what I said? Huh?
Who were you talking to?
This is getting ridiculous.
I, I can't
handle this any more.
Well then
just answer.
Answer what?
It's, I don't
have to answer.
It's a simple question.
Yeah you do! Who were
you talking to?
Your mother!
Alright? I- I was
talking to your mother!
What's happening to you?
Every day you're
like a different person.
I'm going to bed.
I would be more
comfortable if you
slept in the spare room.
Hello?
Lucy. Is that you?
You look like
an angel when you sleep.
Hello? Who is this?
Who is this?
David. David!
I told you
to stop filming me!
Where are you going?
David. Uh, I'm
just gonna take
a couple of days,
you know, take a break.
You're
you're smothering me!
Come on, close the door.
You're not leaving.
Close the door.
Just gimme the car keys.
No.
Just.
No!
I knew it.
You are not leaving
me for another man.
What?
Lucy, I've heard
you on the phone with him!
Talking.
Laughing. Flirting.
You, you
think I'm stupid!
David. Maybe,
maybe, you know,
we could talk to someone.
We could get some help.
Oh, really.
Oh, come on. No!
Help me.
Tell me what to do.
I'll do anything.
He thinks it's
someone else's baby.
It's cold.
Where's David?
What happened
to him, Lucy?
Lucy?
Show me.
Hey, I haven't heard
from you in days.
Something bad
happened here.
Look,
maybe you're
going through some kind
of delayed shock here,
you never really dealt
with what Ben did to you.
What are
you talking about?
A few months ago
Ben broke into the apartment
he went crazy,
saying the baby
belonged to someone else.
I don't remember that.
He tried to drown
you in the bath, Alice.
You miscarried the next day.
You had a breakdown.
You have to stop
denying this.
The missing tape.
You know if I had
the missing tape. If I
could find the missing tape.
What are
you talking about?
What missing tape?
He was always filming.
Always. There was an
empty tape box. Then
there's obviously another tape.
Listen, I need you
to do me a favor.
If you could get
on the Internet.
Just find out,
look up everything
on the name David Woods.
David Woods. Okay.
Who is David Woods?
Can you not ask
questions! Just
do it, please?
I'm still at
the hospital with my Mom.
I'll have to do it later.
This is important.
Do you promise me
you're going to do it?
I said I would.
Thank you.
The woman in the mirror lies.
Hello.
Ally, I checked on line
like you asked me to.
What did you find out?
David and Lucy Woods
were reported missing
May 5th 2006.
I knew it.
Who reported them missing?
David's mother. A few
days before he disappeared
he told his mother
that Lucy left him
for another man
and went back to Chicago.
They were only married
six months.
She was pregnant,
it says he had a history
of depression
and tried to kill
himself the year before
when Lucy
tried to call
off the engagement.
Alice, do you really
think he killed her?
I don't know.
What do you think
happened to David?
I'll call you back.
David.
David, come on.
This this
is hurting my arms.
I know you
slept with him.
Admit it.
Say it!
David, you gotta
stop and think.
Think about
this. Jesus.
I swear to God.
I swear to God baby.
You just
tell me the truth,
from the beginning
and this will be over.
This is ridiculous.
You called him
because you were lonely.
Because I neglected
you. And, right?
David?
It was Luke, wasn't it?
Do you...? Luke?
Just say it.
Marie was out of town,
and Luke was lonely too,
so you called him up and
Oh, my God.
You seduced him.
Oh my God.
David, we're having a baby!
That thing's not my child.
Oh, no.
Say it.
Just tell me
the truth, Lucy.
It's all I want,
it's just...
He, he, he,
I'll still love you.
Gosh!
I, uh...
Tsk. I seduced him.
Come on, David.
Come on.
Say it.
We made love and.
I only saw you, though.
Oh, oh.
Oh, shit.
David!
David.
David! David.
No. No!
Phew.
Ugh.
Oh, Lucy.
Hello? Who's this?
It's Ben.
Don't hang up, please.
What do you want?
Forgiveness.
For what?
While I was in prison
I thought about you a lot.
What I put you through.
The things
I said to you.
The baby.
You're in the house.
You've been
in the house all along.
It's been you, watching me.
No, I'm in Boston
with my mother.
You're a liar.
Please let me talk.
Look. I just need
to tell you that I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. And I know,
I know the baby was mine.
And I know that,
I know that I killed it!
I'm sorry. I promise that
I'll never hurt you again.
I'm going to let
you go Alice. You're free.
Lucy.
We're free now.
David!
David. What are you doing?
You damn idiot!
You damn fool!
David.
Are you all right?
Lucy.
Lucy?
Alice? Where
have you been?
The gun. Where
did you put the gun?
What?
He's in the house.
He's going to kill me!
What?
David.
Who is David?
Becky, we talked about
this. I told you about this.
Alice, I haven't heard
from you all week. I've
been worried sick about you.
Are you still there?
Why? Why did
you take the gun? Why?
I couldn't leave
you with a gun.
No one's going
to hurt you, Alice.
No! No!
No!
David.
Ah!
Alice!
Oh, my God.
Alice?
Ugh.
Alice, what happened?
Come on, I've got you.
Oh.
Let me help you.
No! No!
I don't want
to go in that bed!
Let me give you
some pills baby.
They're gonna
help you sleep.
Drink. Drink.
I'm sorry, baby.
Da... uh, uh,
Da- Da- Da-
David's mother knew
that he killed Lucy.
So she told the police
that they both went
missing to protect them.
And when she died
he moved back into the house
and he's been
here ever since.
No, he...
He was here.
He was in the house.
He's been watching me.
Shhhh. You have to rest.
Just listen to what
I'm saying. Please,
I think someone died here.
Just tell me the truth.
David! We're having a baby!
David.
Ugh.
I am so sorry
I left you alone.
I promise you
I will never leave
you alone again ever.
Okay?
You look like
an angel when you sleep.