English Subitles
Our planet is a blue planet,
deep blue water dwarfing
the patches of land we call earth.
Deep Blue - the source of life itself.
Here, half a million albatross jostle for space to breed
on a tiny island in the Southern Ocean.
After thousand of miles of searching,
at last the deep blue offers it's bounty.
The Ocean sustains far more life
than all of the land,
but it is unevenly spread
hiding and shifting in blue space.
Gathering seabirds betray a discovery.
The fish shoals have broken their cover.
This is a world of constant jeopardy,
an endless cycle of birth death and renewal.
For a new generation of sea lions,
life begins at the coast.
A place of safety to which
their mothers return only to give birth.
The unfamiliar land becomes
a gentle nursery,
a place where the young pups gather strength
as they grow in readyness for a harsher life at sea.
Killer whales have only a few days
to take advantage of the naive young pups.
Soon the sea lions will learn to avoid
the shallows of high tide.
Meanwhile, the whales risk being stranded
on the shore as they take their prey.
It's a dangerous business and the young
killers must be taught to hunt in open water
before they can risk the shore.
At the coastline, the earth and sea meet
to form a borderland,
a world of tension
where moods shift with the tides.
Away from the coastline in the bright warm water,
a tiny portion of the ocean holds its greatest riches.
The coral reefs, a narrow band of sun fed life
only found in the shallows of tropical seas.
This is a fragile world
built upon the smallest of organisms,
the coral polyps whose skeletons form the reef,
colonies that may strech for hundred of miles.
A gentle whale shark,
the largest fish in the sea,
visits the reef during the green of a plankton bloom,
sifting the water through its gills.
The moon has a powerful force upon the deep.
Her ghostly realm is a different world,
when new rules apply.
Rooted to the spot, even the coral
must fight a wall for territoty,
shooting out deadly stinging cells to paralyse
and then eat their neighbours alive.
The darkness brings it's own mood,
A change of rhythm where the creatures of
the light must find a hiding place.
A crevice under a coral head,
will provide shelter for the night,
but no certainty that you will see the dawn.
For others,
the darkness is feeding time.
The night feeders have no need of light
Special sensors allow them to
detect the slightest movement.
Even the smallest electrical twitch
of muscle brings them close...
...ready to choose their victim.
Storm and rain and wind and cloud
churn the seas with their own power.
The violent mixing of the waters brings life awakened
and fueled by light from the sun.
Underwater currents mix and blend
the liquid world,
Whipping up the nourishing swarms of tiny
organisms on which so many other animals feed.
The boneless creatures
have their place too,
trailing their tentacles behind their pulsing forms,
capturing their own prey as they drift.
At the ends of the earth,
north and south,
the frozen oceans wait
for the return of the sun,
the force that draws life
from the still waters.
Polar bears, no longer safe on firm ice,
are forced to take to the water.
In the far south, Emperor penguins gather
in vast numbers at the ice edge.
They are sleek and fast, ready to face
the harshest weather conditions on earth.
As the Antarctic summer ends,
almost all life heads to the north,
away from the freezing waters,
but still the Emperor penguins remain.
They face a long and arduous journey south,
100 Miles across the frozen
wasteland, to breed.
For three months, the male birds will starve
enduring temperatures of -70 degrees
and 100 mile an hour winds.
In the arctic, winter turns liquid sea
into solid ground,
and for the first time since
summer melted the ice,
the polar bears can move across
the ocean with ease.
After months of near starvation,
the bears are on a desperate search for food,
and a new generation must learn to hunt.
They scour their frozen world for signs
of nesting seals hidden in ice caves.
The freezing sea brings danger
as well as opportunity.
Locked under a sheet of winter ice,
these Beluga whales are trapped.
It will be many weeks before the ice opens up
and they can swim to clear water.
For now, they are forced to share
this tiny breathing space,
surfacing to snatch air and
battling to keep the ice away.
This time the bear fails,
but the Belugas will keep
the scars of the hunters claws on their
arching, streamlined backs.
Those that survive their icy prison will eventually
return to the freedom of the open seas.
The warming sun once again
chases away the ice,
and gray whales travel 6000 miles
to gorge in the polar seas.
This three month old baby is
new to the open sea,
and the mother grey whale must swim slowly
as she guides it to the feeding grounds.
Wary of the 30 ton mother,
who is twice their size,
the hunters target the vulnerable calf.
After hours of harrying by the killers,
the baby whale is exhausted.
Now the hunters try to push
him away from his mother.
They try to drown him.
The calf is dead.
Six hours after the chase began,
the killers finally have their prize.
The mother, bereft of the baby she carried
in her womb for 30 months,
must continue her journey alone.
The killers have taken only the tongue
and lower jaw of the baby whale.
Away from all land,
the open ocean,
an endless expanse of blue,
a vast watery desert.
Here, wandering giants travel thousands of miles
on the oceanic currents in search of food.
A lonely traveller in liquid space.
In just a few secret places in the blue,
normally solitary wanderers come together
in great gatherings.
Amid the fury, a 30 ton
giant rises from the blue,
leaves the narrow strip of rich sunlit waters
of the ocean surface,
and journeys downwards into perpetual night.
With each sinking meter pressure builds,
the temperature falls,
all light from the surface fades.
More men have been into space
than have visited the depest riches
of this alien world.
Go deeper and life under pressure adapts, changes,
ready to play a deadly game
of hide and seek.
Down here, the only light comes from
the inhabitants of the deep themselves.
Some use it as a lure to attract prey.
For others the light is a decoy,
flashes which dazzle and confuse their hunters.
The deep ocean floor is by far
the largest habitat on earth,
covering more than a half of all the sea bed.
Here, the pressure is 500 times
greater than at the surface.
It is mostly flat, but here and there
it is scarred by massive wounds.
The oceans' deepest reach,
the Marianas trench,
plummets seven miles down
towards the earths core.
The mid-ocean ridges are the largest
geological structures on earth.
They stretch 30,000 miles.
Water, hot as molted lead, gushes from chimneys
as high as 16 storey buildings.
The Black Smokers...
...highly poisonous hydrogen sulphide billows
into the water creating biological hell.
And yet, even here, there is life
in enormous quantities.
These chimneys are some of the most
densely inhabited spots on earth,
pillars of life where animals exist
without energy from the sun.
Every single night, life without number
emerges from the deep.
They come to feed in the rich surface water,
A daily ritual which is the greatest
biological migration on the planet.
We have sought out the stars and our moon
without getting to know the deep.
Yet it is the ocean
that continues to surprise us.
So far, we have explored only
a tiny fraction of the deep,
home to the largest creature
that has ever existed.
There were once 300,000 blue whales
in our oceans,
Now just 1% of these glorious animals remain,
and yet we continue to plunder their secret world.