628 Tremont.
6-2-8, three Dead.
- Not here.
- The fuckin' usual.
So no big deal these days, right?
Some guy, what's his name?
- Uh, I don't know.
- Who knows, who cares.
Who cares.
Fuckin'.
Shoots his wife and kid,
and eats the fuckin' licorice.
Sticks it in his mouth
and blows his fuckin' brains out.
This guy has no ID,
no fuckin' papers.
He probably squirreled over
the goddamn border.
Hey guys.
Channel 13.
Listen up, you're kind of blocking the shot,
can I get you to move forward a bit?
- Yeah sure.
- Thanks.
- You Ready?
- Yeah, almost.
Two minutes.
and we'll roll.
- Can't get close enough for an Emmy.
- Screw the Emmy!
- Settle for a fuckin' paycheck.
- Story of my life.
We downloaded this video off the internet
sometime over the last three days,
I can't remember
exactly when.
Look at this guy.
Look at this fuckin' guy!
Chowing down while his buddies are
shoving a corpse in the back of the van.
Some of this footage
was never broadcast.
It was secretly uploaded by
the cameraman who shot it.
It was his way of trying to tell the truth
about what was happening.
Bree Reno, reporting live
from Homestead,
where tragedy be-felled
an immigrant family.
An unidentified man has shot his
wife and 16 year old son to death
before turning the
gun on himself.
- Jesus!
- What?
- I don't believe this!
Is there something wrong with
the camera, just fix it!
She's still moving!
For Christ sake, Willy,
I'm right in the middle of...
- What?
- Jesus fuckin' Christ!
For god's sake!
- I thought they were dead.
- They're supposed to be, they are!
I don't know, she's moving on
the freakin' gurney man!
- Get out of the way, come on.
- I need some backup here.
Get off of him!
- Are you all right?
- Jesus, what the fuck was that?
- Keep still.
- The other ones moving!
Another one coming up too.
Take them out!
He's not going down.
He's not going down!
Holy shit!
Freeze!
You must shoot
them in the head!
No! No!
This can't be happening!
This can't be fuckin' happening!
We downloaded a lot of what we found
off on television, on the net, off blogs.
Images and commentaries
over those first few days.
Most of it was bullshit.
None of it was useful.
This is what we were getting
from the news networks.
None of us can
claim to know exactly
what has caused the chaos,
that we've stand from experience.
A natural calamity or sort of
a massive or monstrous hoax?
I'm old enough to
remember Orson Wells'
'War of the World's,' possibly the
greatest hoax ever perpetrated.
That was just radio.
Now, it’s 24/7.
This is some kind of...
we are led to believe
almost anything...
We made a film,
the one I'm going to show you now.
Actually, Jason was the
one who wanted to make it.
Like that camera man
from Channel 13,
He wanted to upload it so that people,
you, could be told the truth.
The film was shot with a
Panasonic HDX-900-and a HVX-200.
I did the final cut
on Jason's laptop.
I've added music occasionally
for effects, hoping to scare you.
You see, in addition to
trying to tell you the truth
I am hoping to scare you,
so that maybe
you'll wake up.
Maybe you won't make any of
the same mistakes that we made.
Anyway, here it is:
Jason Creed: The Death of Death.
No!
Cut! Cut!
How many times have I told you
that these things don't move fast?
You're a corpse,
for Christ sake!
If you run that fast,
your ankles are gonna snap off.
She's going fast, I have to go fast,
otherwise how am I supposed to catch her?
You're supposed to catch her later.
This is the beginning of the fuckin' movie.
You catch her now,
it's all over.
All you're supposed to do
is grab her dress, till...
...till my tits fall out?
Ain't gonna happen!
You know, can somebody
please explain to me
why girls in scary movies always have to
fall down and lose their shoes and shit?
It's totally lame.
And why do we do have to get
our dresses torn off?
Actually, I'm looking
forward to that part.
- Flashing!
- I swear...
Thanks.
Ah shit man, look at this,
your makeup is all unglued.
Give me a break!
Yeah, maybe you can see now,
because you're in way too tight.
All you're supposed to do
is run into the fuckin' shot.
No, not run...
shamble.
The script says the mummy
shambles into the frame and stops
for a second...
for one second.
You're telling me in one second you can see...
- The camera can see
and what the camera sees,
the audience will see.
What fuckin' audience?
There's always an audience for horror,
believable horror.
But who's gonna believe a mummy
if his makeup is all unglued?
Who's gonna believe a
mummy in the first place?
Here's a thought, genius.
Try zooming out, maybe
your fuckin' shot will work.
I know what I want here, Tony,
and I know what I'm doing.
That's right, you do,
don't ya?
We're only what, four days over
a three day shooting schedule?
Great, you're doing fine.
I hope we'll get fuckin' credits.
- You'll all be in the credits.
- Talking about college credits.
Leave those to me.
- Did we get the shot yet?
- No, we're still dickin' around.
Five credits for the each of you,
that's a pledge.
Mr. Creed has a vision.
Hey, I'm just trying to
make a scary movie here.
Yes, you are,
Mr. Creed.
Jason always wanted to
be a documentary filmmaker,
but for his senior class project,
he decided to try to make
a horror film instead.
In fact, that's what he was
shooting on that first night.
The night, when...
everything changed.
Stupid fuckin'
horror movie.
With an underlying
thread of social satire.
Jason, can I
take a minute?
- I have to pee.
- Oh shit. Alright.
- Jason...
- What?
I have to pee, too.
Jesus Christ, this whole
thing is falling apart.
Hey guys, uh, there's something
on the news. It's pretty...
well, I mean...
you might want to check this out.
...but it does seem to happening.
Two news agencies in two separate
counties in the tri-state area
are reporting accounts
of the dead returning to life.
In one of the cases, the one
in Summerset, the dead man,
identified as a
50 year old white male,
the victim of a drive-by
shooting yesterday,
sat up on the autopsy table and actually
attacked Somerset medical examiners...
- Horseshit.
- Shut up, Tony, it's on the fuckin' news.
The news is always horseshit. Always makes
things sound worse than they really are.
That's how they
sell soap.
And the next morning what happens?
"Oh sorry, our mistake. "
and when they say that, who's gonna
believe this shit, two dead people...
There are now
five dead people and...
here's another.
They're coming in from everywhere.
A corpse at Hope Memorial,
has apparently survived.
That’s six separate reports.
Six?
How could there be six mistakes?
For Christ’s sake, we hear
those sort of thing every day.
Yeah, the hurricane,
the planet gettin' too hot,
and the terrorist that was gonna dump a dirty
bomb on the Whitehouse or your house.
Somebody gonna put some germs
in your water or your mailbox.
and that letter from
Publisher's Clearing House, huh?
The good news is you
won a million bucks,
bad news is you'll gonna
wake up dead tomorrow morning.
Better believe what
we've just heard,
the problem doesn't seem to be
that people are waking up dead.
But that dead people
are waking up.
Listen!
- What's that?
- What was that?
A lot of people
are in on it.
Right.
If I'm gonna wake up dead,
it's gonna be in my own bedroom.
You can all come.
Eliot has the address,
he knows where is it.
Yeah, nice place too.
Cozy, takes up about half of Philadelphia.
Yeah, it's a fuckin' fortress.
I can't get in unless I'm invited.
Sorry Jason, you're
worried about your movie.
I don't mean to hang you
up or anything, but...
I'm gettin' the fuck out of here.
Like I said,
you can all come.
I mean it.
It's an invitation.
I'm in.
- Anyone else?
- Better be not.
Bye guys.
Fuckin' pommy gets all the girls.
So...
What are we going to do?
- How do you explain, that...
- I have no explanation.
OK, what I'm
going to do.
I'm going to the dorm,
Deb's there.
Whatever's happening,
I don't want her to be alone.
Transmit electrical
impulses
strong enough,
to animate what little
remains of the body's
muscle tissues.
OK.
OK, this is the women's dorm.
Jesus.
It's been 25 minutes
since we've heard the news,
and it looks like
everybody's gone.
Hello, who's
in there?
Fuck.
What the fuck are
you doing here?
- What the fuck you're doing here?
- I'm stealing shit.
What about you...?
What's a guy with a video
camera doing in the women's dorm?
Security!
Fuck.
Oh god.
Oh shit.
OK, OK, this is
Deb's room.
- Wait! It's OK. It's me.
- Jesus, fuck..
Are you still
shooting?
- What're you shooting?
- I'm just...
Oh my god!
- God, I'm so afraid.
- It's OK, Deb.
I'm here.
I've been trying to call them,
for like an hour...
Shit!
Shit! Same fuckin' thing,
no answer!
Gotta get out there,
we'll see everything.
- Babe!
- What?
There's no answer at my house.
My mom, my dad, Billie...
- They're supposed to be there!
- Maybe they're up at the cabin.
No, I already tried there.
Everything's out.
The circuits are busy, your folks probably
can't get through to you either.
It was all over the news,
all over the web.
But no one knew what
was really happening.
I wanna get out of here.
J!
I want to go home.
I think that's what
started the panic,
not knowing the truth.
What's been happening?
I don't know,
the prospects
truly are terrifying.
All my friends left before
we could even say goodbye.
It's funny. You spend some much
time resenting your parents,
separating yourself,
building your own life,
but when the shit hits the fan,
the only place you want to go is
home.
We're in Mary's
Winnebago,
trying to stick together.
- What is this about, Jason?
- I don't know, I just...
if this turns out to be a big thing,
I just want to record it, OK?
Come on everybody, when it
comes to you, say your names.
This is ridiculous.
- Mary. Mary Dexter.
- What are you doing here, Mary?
I'm going home...
trying to go home.
Can you just not film me
while I'm driving, please?...
so I can focus.
Say your name.
Jason, if you don't know
my name by now
then you can get your clothes
out of my closet, OK?
Come on, babe,
it's part of history.
Debra Moynahan.
And I'm trying to get home too, OK?
Like Mary.
And I'm wondering why my boyfriend
has a camera plastered to his face.
Scranton. OK?
Scranton. Pennsylvania.
That's my home.
It's my parent's home.
And my little brother's.
- Where are you coming from?
- College.
We're all at Pitt together.
University of Pittsburgh.
- Why are we on the road?
- Christ.
Yeah, Christ, Jason.
Lay the fuck off!
See this guy?
He won't say who he is, so I will.
He's Tony Ravello. He's from...
- Where is he from? Brooklyn or the Bronx?
- Queens.
He does makeup
that comes unglued.
You know what?
I'm a directing major, just like you.
- I wasn't supposed to do makeup.
- No, I was.
Sorry, babe.
You know what happens
when we try to work together.
I hear that.
Why are we here
on the road?
- Just trying to get out of Dodge right now.
- Why?
What do you want
me to say, Jason?
No, it's not what I want you want to say,
it’s what you want to say. Tell us...
Why does everyone wanna
get the hell out of Dodge?
Cause of this thing, this crazy
thing that's happenin'.
It is crazy.
- Where are you going, Tony?
- Nowhere. No place to go.
Except to hang with you, Jason,
until I can't take any more of your shit.
Hey, guys!
Can you explain why the department
of Homeland Security suddenly
raised its alert level to orange
earlier this evening
even though there are no
indications of a terrorist attack?
Your right, there's no
indication of any terrorism.
We believe these are
simply isolated and
unrelated phenomenon, and we expect
things to return to normal very soon.
See? They've already started
playing this shit down.
...maybe due to a
previous unknown viral strain
that leads, to a kind
of mass psychosis.
- Psychosis, who's going to believe that?
- Psychotic?
The President continues to monitor
the situation from his ranch and
he's asked the American
people to remain vigilant.
- Say who you are, Eliot.
- You just did, I'm Eliot.
Tell us more.
Eliot Stone, Harrisburgh PA.
I'm here with you fine people
because, I don't know
I'd like to get home, too.
It's on the way, I'm hoping you'll
be so kind as to drop me off.
Seems like everybody
wants to get home.
I know what you're trying
to do, Jason. I get it.
Gordo Thorsen.
Denver, Pennsylvania.
Tracy Thurman.
We're a...
together.
- Forever.
We'll see.
What's that?
Oh... this is
my camera.
Smile.
Thurman and Gordo.
Gimme a kiss.
Oh, I'm from San Antone,
that's Texas.
Don't mess with Texas.
Holy shit.
Look at this guy!
Christ!
He's gotta be doing like
a buck twenty.
Professor?
Ah-ha, you finally come to me,
I was beginning to feel rejected.
- It's just that...
- So far away, I know.
In storage...
sitting on a toilet seat
with everyone's dirty laundry.
Andrew Maxwell,
analyst.
Nowhere to go,
nothing to do.
and I'm not
with anybody.
Like Mr. Ravello, I'm just
popping along for the ride.
I'm not with
anyone either.
I'm... just...
here all alone...
just me and Saint Chris.
We'll probably be calling on ol' Saint Chris
before this night's over.
Oh my god!
Look!
We'll never get past that. Turn around.
We should go back to the dorms.
- Look!
- It's a cop.
- He's a State Trooper
- How do you know that?
- His hat is... because his hat.
- He looks hurt.
- He's all burned up.
- Not just burned, he's fuckin' fried!
Oh my...
He's dead!
I'm telling you, he can't be
anything else but dead.
Oh my god!
I think he wants more than
your license and registration!
Go! Go!
Oh fuck!
Fuck!
Wait, wait, wait!
What's that?
What'll we do?
- What time is it?
- Almost three.
I think we should pull over.
How do you feel?
Mary?
How do you feel about
what just happened?
- I killed six of them...
- They were already dead, OK?
You didn't anything
wrong.
Listen to me.
Jesus fuckin' Christ... you don't stand up
and walk around when you're dead!
Will you shut up?
We just killed three
people back there.
Three living, breathing
people like us.
No we didn't.
I did.
Shit.
We've stopped somewhere...
off the road.
God knows where.
You gonna say
something?
No, I don't know. Just give
her some time, you know.
I'm running low.
If I can make it to the State store
before they all shut their doors forever...
god, that's a
terrible thought.
The world where a gentleman
can't buy a bottle of bourbon.
Mary?
- Oh god, Mary!
- Mary
What did she do?
- What the fuck did she do?
- Any anyone know she had a gun?
- Why would she do this?
Because of what happened?
Those people back there?
It's our fault.
We're panicking,
we're turning this into...
Into what?
Some that's not.
Some more than this is.
This is all just bullshit!
You keep calling this bullshit,
someone else is
gonna kill them self!
You heard the TV,
Mary heard the TV.
We all should have
stayed at school
instead of driving around
in the middle of nowhere.
knocking down fuckin'
people like bowling pins.
- She's still alive.
- What?!
She's got a pulse!
- Mary!
- Pressure! Pressure!
- Looks like everyone's left.
- Yeah, up in a hurry.
This is a hospital,
where else is she supposed to go?
Just because we can't see anybody,
doesn't mean no one’s here.
- Maybe they're hiding?
- Yeah, maybe they're hiding because they think we're dead.
- Hello, we aren't dead!
- Cut it out, Tony.
Wait, wait, wait,
where are we going?
You guys look for a doctor,
we're gonna find the ER.
Hello!
Is anyone here?
Wait, wait.
I think I heard somebody.
It's down here,
come on.
It's just the radio.
Hello?
Is anyone...
What?
We're prisoners here.
So far as we can't move.
Stand by!
It's complete chaos.
We got them!
I can't do it.
- Get that son of a bitch!
- We got five of them here!
Where are you, sir?
- Got to get them in the head.
- Get everyone out of here!
- You've got to get them in the head!
I hope this isn't some
sort of mistake?
This is a hospital,
there's nobody here.
Is this for real?
What about Mary?
What if...
she dies?
We're not gonna be able to by just
standing around here.
- Fuck! Losing juice.
- Let’s see if we can find some batteries.
- There's somebody!
- Excuse me!
Excuse me.
We've an emergency.
Our friend is hurt and we need help.
Oh my god, what's
wrong with him?
He's dead. That's what
wrong with him..
- Get the gun.
- Debby, gun!
- Try the head! Try the head!
- Yeah, shoot him in the head!
Shoot him in the head!
- Fuck, the battery's almost dead.
- Yeah, that's not all?
What do you mean?
- What is going on?
- Jesus, the nurse.
Dead doctor, dead nurse,
makes sense, doesn't it?
Fuckin' hurry up!
Gordo!
It's jammed!
- OK, I'm gonna try something.
- What?!
Get her attention,
just to try to get her attention!
Come over here!
Hey, come after me!
Careful, Debra.
Careful.
Jesus H!
Jesus Christ.
Whoa, whoa, those are hot!
Put it back where you've found them.
We've got to get
her a doctor.
Yeah, a live one.
I got it.
Let's go.
Don't leave
without me.
What?
You're not coming with us?
- I can't, I gotta plug in.
- Leave it, let it charge.
I can't, I can't leave
without the camera.
The camera's the
whole thing.
Getting help is
the whole thing.
I should be
with them.
Maybe I can help.
I can't.
Because...
I'm fuckin'
locked in.
Some shit, huh?
What's wrong with these
fuckin' dead guys.
I'm sorry, Mary.
If anything that Tony said,
or I said, or Ted, made you...
People you killed were dead.
These people are dead.
At least they
look dead.
The way,
things are...
who the fuck knows.
Mary?
Shit.
Guys?
Guys, what's happening?
Fuck!
God damn it!
Hello?
Hello!
I found this in
one of the other rooms.
Tell us your name.
Say it!
- Deb, come on.
- Say it!
Gimme a break.
Jason Creed.
See how it feels to have a camera
shoved in your face?
to have to answer stupid questions
when people are dying all around you.
You see how it feels?
Deb, just put the thing down
and tell me what happened.
Well, you missed it.
If it didn't happen on camera,
it’s like it didn't happen, right?
There was a patient
in one of the other rooms.
He looked nice, you know,
not dead.
But...
he was...
he was on top of me
before I saw him.
It was Gordo who shot him.
Jesus! Did you...
I mean..
Hurt me?
No.
So who was screaming?
Me.
You want me to
show you how?
For the camera?
For history?
That's enough, Deb.
I got it...
Oh god!
I just shot
another man.
I've killed three men and a woman
in the last half hour.
You can't be certain they're dead.
I remember the war.
In war time,
killing comes easy.
Especially when you don't
have to do any of it.
There will be always
be people like you.
Wanting to document, wanting
to record, some sort of diary.
Me? You're the one who
put the camera in my hands.
You're the one who made
me want to do this.
Not this.
This is a diary recording.
In war times only the enemy can be marked,
like this son of a bitch...
...or that son of a bitch.
Then cruelty...
becomes justified.
God! Oh my god,
look at Mary!
- She's... She's dead.
- She's turning.
Oh god.
This is much
too much!
Too much.
God, I don't know...
Give it to me.
You can't do this,
give me the gun.
Oh man!
Oh my god! Oh my god!
Your stuttering, Mr. Creed.
Don't try to speak,
just shoot.
Shoot your picture, shoot for as
long as your hard drive runs out.
As long as
you're found.
Take this.
It's too easy to use.
Let's get
out of here.
It's interesting how quickly we'll
find out what we're capable of becoming.
Up until that night,
we had lived predictable lives.
Now, we will never be able
to predict what might happen next.
God has changed
the rules on us.
And surprisingly,
we were
playing along.
What the?
Jesus, Gordo!
Look out!
What?
What happened?
You got that,
huh, Tony?
After I stab them through the
heart, with this freakin' IV pole.
Why don't you
fuckin' die, huh?
Fuckin' die.
You got that, Tony, Huh?
You'll probably at least fuckin' understand?
- What happened?
- It hurts. The bite.
It hurts.
Take this.
It's too easy to use.
Come on Debby, you can
shot better than me.
Yeah that's what I thought,
I don't want to become you.
There are currently more than 200 million
video cameras in people's hands worldwide.
blogs, video windows,
extremely video...
A good job in
journalism...
Does the media put ourselves
ahead of what we see happening?
Millions of members out here,
driven, compelled, to broadcast their...
particular views.
Compelled, like the man said.
Jason was compelled.
I've never seen
him like that before.
What is it? What gets into our heads,
when we see something horrible?
A horrible accident
on the highway.
Some things just keep us
from just driving on.
Some things holds us.
We don't stop to help,
we stop to look.
First morning since
we've hit the road.
We're here to say goodbye.
I don't understand
why he died.
It was just a bite. How can someone
die from one little bite?
Maybe it's some kind of
poison or something.
Maybe it is a virus.
Anyone that gets sick
comes back as one of them.
No, anyone who dies
Thurman and Gordo.
No! No!
Gotta bury him, right?
How would you feel,
waking up in six feet of dirt?
Can't we just wait?
Can't we, at least just wait and see?
Maybe it won't
happen to him.
Please, can we
just wait?
- Hey guys, we gotta get going. I gotta...
- Get home?
Yeah.
Although after this,
I'm not sure what we're gonna find.
Your folks will be fine, Deb.
They're smart people, like you.
Oh shit.
Look!
Poor Gordo.
He just
crapped out.
that tree will give
no shelter, to say Amen.
these are the
end of times,
and for the sinners there will be no end.
Only the dead that will not die...
and the hunger that
will not be satisfied.
Get on your knees.
Get on your
fuckin' knees!
Here's a Channel
11 News update.
It wasn't until we
uploaded this footage,
that we saw how
bad everything was.
- What are we doing to help?
- ... sort of failure like...
Don't try to come
into major cities.
There are report of violence,
looting, killings...
Small towns kinda like ghost towns.
Most people have fled for their lives.
They're anticipating some
sort of Armageddon?
Using country roads
we hadn't run into riots or looting.
But we were about to
run into something else.
What a piece of shit!
It's alright,
It's alright.
I think it’s the fuel line.
If that's what it is,
I can fix it.
- Oh yeah
- Yeah.
I know what I'm doing.
Daddy used to pit crew for Gill Gilbert.
- Rumpert?
- Gilbert.
Who the hell
is Gill Gilbert?
We can't stay
out here guys.
We have to wait
inside that barn.
I'm going to see
where the others went.
You might now want to do that.
There might be...
Oh shit!
Whoa, whoa, stop, stop!
I don't think he's dead.
He might not
be dead!.
- "Who are you?".
- He's asking who we are.
"CAN'T HEAR"
Our car broke down,
we need help.
"AMISH
NO CAR"
We don't need a car,
we just need just to fix ours.
We need to use your barn.
"HURRY"?
Why?
Oh shit!
- They must have been following us!
- Oh my god.
- Tony, how many bullets you got left?
- Where did he go?
Jesus Christ!
I thought the Amish
were friendly folks!
"I'M SAMUEL
HELLO"
Yep, cap line's
leaking.
I'm gonna cut the line below the tear
and get it hooked back up to the post.
Thanks.
What is that?
Guys, what's all the screaming?
Birthday party.
Where did you
find this?
It was in the camera
Deb found in the hospital.
That's the guy, the one
in the orange shirt.
That's the guy from the hospital,
the one I thought looked nice.
The one Gordo shot.
What's that?
Guys, What that?
They're in the back.
At the back wall.
They're out front as well.
What the hell is going on out there?
Jesus Christ.
Oh god, there's
plenty of them.
"BACK DOOR"
Simply sorry for,
for all the trouble.
Hurry in, I wanna
get out of here.
Not to apply unnecessary pressure,
but we are all relying on you, darling.
Oh god,
the doors open.
I hear something.
Maybe one of them got in already.
Maybe more than one.
- Guys, what's happening?
- We're alright!
We're alright.
Almost there.
Certainly hope so, darling,
as much as I'd love staying, I wanna go home.
Tracy,
I love you!
- Alright, open the door!
- Open up, Tony, let's go!
See how many, there are?
Look how many.
Come on,
come on.
Excuse me gentlemen,
hurry!
Oh my god!
We're alright,
we're alright!
- Nothing we can do,
let's go.
They're all going to be all over us.
Let's go
It's estimated that if something
doesn't stop the slaughter
in three or four days,
our death rates will quadruple.
within 10 days, it will
have risen by 100 percent.
Before, there were, I don't know,
how many people died every minute...
8? 10? 20?
Now there are 5 times as many,
10 times, a 100 times.
Dead, but...
walking.
There weren't enough bullets
to stop them all.
They're monsters.
Monsters who prey on the flesh of the living.
We needed supplies...
Gas.
Without gas, we weren't
going anywhere.
There might be more
of them around.
- Think we can make it?
- We gotta try.
Get in, fill up, get out fast.
Yes, but what if...
Put the gun down!
- Who the hell are you?
- Don't matter who I am.
All that matters
is what I got.
What he's got is better than
ours, Tony, way better.
Damn right.
This is an M16 semi-automatic,
with the safety turned off.
and I'm just trying to decide,
do I pump two bullets at
your brain, or just one.
Alright.
Cool.
Good choice.
Now who the hell are you all?
Some kind of news people?
No, students.
University of Pittsburgh.
Damn, now the whole town
is going crazy.
Come on!
- Come on, where?
- Any place is better than this.
Come on! Before we
get our asses shot off!
What are you talking about?
Write their names, kick them out,
lock the door, and throw away the keys?
We've become hysterical about people
crossing the border into our country.
That's not the problem anymore.
The problem now is, all those strangers
crossing the borders, who can...
What the hell's with
that camera anyway?
Home movies.
Who's gonna be
left to watch?
So, what's up with you all?
What the hell you're
doing in my town?
We're trying to get to Stranton.
We need fuel.
We were at the pump,
back there at the gas station.
Them pumps are dry.
I've saved up all the gas.
Can we buy some
of what you took?
Buy? If this is keeps up,
money ain't gonna be worth nothing.
I'm talking about gas.
Yeah, I'll let you have some.
- Enough to get where you're going.
- What's with you all?
- How come you've stuck around?
- Cause we got the power.
For the first time in our lives.
We got the power.
Cause everybody else left.
All of us folks have suntans.
They'll be back, right?
The National Guards.
Somebody's gotta put all
this shit back together.
What National Guard?
Kid, I'm in the National Guard.
I know what's coming up,
with nothing together.
That's why I
got all this shit.
Anything worth anything
all under one roof.
It's called looting.
No, ma'am, it's called doing
what you've got to do.
Can I get online?
Back there.
Excuse me.
It's alright,
let them through.
Let 'em through!
A reporter was
on the scene,
Here's Homestead's
Chief of Police, Arthur Tacks.
This attack was carried out by
a bunch of illegal immigrants.
The only time they were dead
was when the white guy shot him.
They changed it.
They've re-cut it.
The media
was lying to us.
Or the government
was lying to them.
They were trying to make it seem
like everything was going to be alright.
- What are you doing?
- I just want to shoot us...
- while we're editing..
- I want to cover everything.
Now I can understand, why Jason
was so anxious to upload his own footage.
At the time,
I didn't get it.
now look at the angle
from your camera.
Put the gun down!
- Who the hell are you?
- Don't matter who I am.
All that matters
is what I got.
- And after that, we drove here.
- Yeah.
Sure, it'll be nice to have the surveillance
camera and go from where we drove in.
Figured that much,
here!
The recording of the security cameras.
Put the 7/11 in here.
- I got it all queued up for you.
- You're fuckin' brilliant man.
Why thank you.
What'd you do. Did you
get up there to record it?
It's a wireless system,
pretty sophisticated.
So sophisticated that I was easily able
to rip it off right out of the air.
Beautiful.
This is Excellent.
So what are
you guys doing?
- Editing.
- Editing what?
The stuff we shot.
When you said you
wanted to get online
I thought, you wanna get in contact
with your dad or something.
No, I just wanted
to upload our shoot.
Look!
72 thousand hits.
In 8 minutes.
Hey Eliot, can we
have a moment please?
Yeah.
Is the camera on?
If we're gonna have a conversation,
I'm sure you'd like to have it on tape.
If it’s not on camera,
it’s like it never happened, right?
OK J,
listen to me.
I'm trying to get home
to my family, OK?
I'm out there
trying to get home.
and you're in here,
dicking around on your computer..
It was a pretty
one-sided conversation...
72 thousand hits.
They're coming in,
from all over the world.
They're not getting the
truth from anybody else.
All that shit on the news,
is a pack of lies.
72 thousand hits in 8 minutes,
that's unbelievable!
- Congratulations, you're famous
- That's not what it's about.
Would you rather have people not
knowing whats going on in the world?
We might even be able to save
somebody's fuckin' life here.
72 thousand hits.
In another hour, it will be probably be
a million, by tomorrow, who knows..
All over the world,
people learning how to survive,
by seeing how we've
managed to survive.
You always know how to
make a good argument, J.
Oh my god! Text message
from my little brother.
Well, what's it say?
All this time, I've been imagining
the dead in our house
and they're not even home.
They went camping four days ago.
"Driving home, we're
OK, I hope you are too. "
Sent last night: "driving home".
That means, they'll probably meet us there.
- I told you they were safe.
- They're on the road, maybe not.
They're not safe,
but they're still alive.
Pack your shit,
I'm gonna check on my gas.
Yo! Dude!
Where are you, man?
Ridley, yo back
at ya here.
I'm in the middle of fuckin'
nowhere, out here.
How's Deb?
She's OK.
You know, coping.
Look here, if you need anything,
like a place to chill or whatever!
Get your ass
down here man!
We're having
a blast!
Hi J, love you.
- What's up?
- I don't know.
Something’s going on.
One of my men had a
bad heart. He died.
The thing is, we don't
know where he went.
Oh shit.
Finish the,
and lock the door.
- I'm gonna get Jason.
- Stay, I'll go.
Wait, that thing could
be inside there.
That thing could
be anywhere...
Fuck!
$100,000 education, and I can't find
my way out of a fuckin' warehouse!
Exit.
What was that?
Fuck!
Where the hell
have you been?
There's a dead guy
walking around. Let's go.
Wait! Say it that again?
I didn't get it.
There is a dead guy walking around.
Now, let's go.
It's all clear.
Turn that TV off!
Alright.
Everyone with a heartbeat,
Freeze and shut up!
Son of a bitch!
Where are we?
Fuck.
Fuck me!
OK, never again.
That's the door.
Let's go!
Let's go,
careful, OK?
Shut the fuck up!
I see him!
I see him over there!
Over here!
Come on, we've got him!
- We've got him!
- Over here!
- Oh shit!
- It's not him.
Son of a bitch!
Fuck off!
Don't shoot!
Those barrels are full of gas!
What the hell
is that stuff?
That's enough.
I need to fill the tank.
Stranton is only
65 miles away.
- We need to bring in some weapons.
- Food, canned goods, water.
- And lip gloss?
- The lip gloss, you can have.
- The rest of the shit is ours.
- All of it?
Every last can of peas.
But, what if we say we're not
leaving till we get what we need?
What would you do?
Kill us?
I'd think about it.
But I don't think
you'd do it though.
It's easiest just to give us
what we need, isn't it?
Cause otherwise, guess what?
You'll gonna have to kill us.
- Deb.
- Shut up, J.
You've gonna have
to kill us, because
we're not leaving until
we get what we need!
OK.
Fill her up.
Give them
what they want.
Come and get 'em.
- Is that enough for you?
- Come and get 'em!
That will do.
Gotta defend yourselves,
you've got to.
Because if this
keeps up...
people start to running
out of food, water, gas,
they're gonna start
shooting at each other.
No, think I've had enough
of this kind of thing.
This I'll like.
Now, this I prefer.
seems..
friendlier,
somehow.
Hey!
I think you're a lot like me.
Good luck.
Good luck to
you too.
What is that?
Where's it
coming from?
I found her on a message
board on YouTube.
Someone listen,
We Tokyo.
Very bad here.
Very bad Tokyo.
Tokyo. Can you
believe it?
There's hundreds of posts like this
all over the world.
It's got technology.
Don't bury dead,
better shoot in head!
- Damn it!
- Well, plug it in!
I just charged it!
It's not the phone,
it's the service
The fuckin' service,
is going out!
Nothing?
How can there be nothing?
The towers, the relay towers
must be out. Jesus, all of them?
Technology is terrific, Eliot.
Except, when it doesn't work!
Great.
It won't be long before nothing
works, starting nothing at all.
The mainstream has vanished,
with all its power and money.
Now it was just us,
bloggers, hackers, kids.
The more voices there are,
the more spin there is.
The truth becomes that
much harder to find.
In the end,
it's all just... noise.
We're in Stranton.
This is Deb's house.
- Thought they'd be here by now.
- They're what? Camping, right?
And they what?
They used to go to
some place in Virginia.
West-Virginia.
You probably beat them here.
Maybe they hit traffic, or something.
We didn't hit any traffic,
there is no traffic.
West-Virginia is only
100 miles away.
- Yeah, if that’s where they went.
- Yeah.
I'm gonna
wait inside.
You guys should head
back on the road.
What?... and just
leave you here?
This where I grew up,
this is where I want to be.
You guys all got homes too.
You should get going, get out of here.
Thanks for
bringing me here.
everything.
- I guess I'll try to call you.
- I'll try to come back for you.
Sorry, J.
Don't be an asshole.
Can't just let her wait here alone.
Hey, do you mind, if maybe
I hang out for a while too?
Yeah. OK.
Me too? I need to pee again.
I can't sit in
here anymore.
I wanna meet your little brother,
maybe he has a Playstation.
I'd like to meet your father,
maybe he has a bar.
We always hide a key.
Shit.
Fuck, I don't remember,
if it's 102 or 201.
It's probably wiring in
the single circuit.
- Where's the breaker box?
- In the garage.
How you're doing?
They're here?
Mom?
Dad!
Billie!
Maybe they dropped off their stuff
and went to the neighbors, or something.
Maybe there was an evacuation,
like a mandatory evacuation..
- They would have taken their car?
- No, there's buses, right?
Where they evacuate places,
they bring in, like buses and...
Fuck!
Deb?
What is it?
OK, they must have, like had
an accident or something, right?
Maybe. Maybe they're
at the hospital?
I just hope its not a hospital
like we went to...
OK.
My dad would have been
driving, and...
That means my mom would
be in the passenger seat, so...
that's my mom's blood.
Yeah..
and Billie would be in the back,
so that means, Billie is probably OK.
- Debra.
- No, I'm sure Billie must be OK.
- Deb!
- What?
OK. Listen to me,
You gotta know that this might be bad.
I know. No, I do, I know OK.
Really, let's go inside, come on!
OK, but don't think
about your parents.
Don't think about
your little brother.
Wanna go in, I want you to
try to find something, OK?
- Something like an old dog.
- Yeah, OK, an old dog.
OK, What's her name?
- It's not a her, it's a him.
- A him. OK. You got a guy dog.
Yes, like Ken.
Like Ken and Barbie.
OK, like Ken, but not Ken.
What is his name?
Michael.
Like the Archangel.
OK, so we're gonna go in there,
and look for Michael.
OK.
I thought long and hard about
whether to leave this footage in the film.
I decided, in the end,
to show you exactly what happened.
No! Billie!
Out of the way.
Let me through!
Deb!
No!
Daddy?
Mommy?
Mommy.
I think it’s time
we left this place.
By now, we've become part of it,
part of 24/7.
It's strange how,
looking at things,
seeing things through a lens,
a glass.
Rose colored or
shaded black.
You become immune.
You're supposed to be affected,
but you're not.
I used to think it was just you out there,
the viewers, but it's not.
It's us as well.
The shooters.
We've become immune too, inoculated.
So whatever happens around us,
no matter how horrible it is,
we just wind up
taking it all in stride.
Just another day.
Just another death.
It's gonna be OK, babe.
Everything will be OK.
Hey, do you want
to swap places?
I could take the camera
for a while, and you could...
Leave him alone,
Tracey.
He's right where
he wants to be.
Hey, where did you
learn to use that thing?
Archery squad.
Targets of course,
that's all we do.
Life and death.
I had such
steady hands.
You still do.
Thank you.
Where's your home, professor?
Where was it?
Oxford..
That's where it was, such as it was.
Not really a home,
just a place.
I've never seen
or imagined a home
that I would want to own.
- Sorry
- Not at all.
I'm a...
wandering spirit.
Yeah, he wanders to wherever
there's a bottle of spirits.
Unless...
- Where're we going Eliot?
- We're going to the right place.
- We talked to Ridley.
- When?
- At the warehouse online.
- Is he OK?
Yeah, he really sounded great,
he invited us to come.
Philadelphia.
We can make it there before dawn.
Hey, hey, hey!
Look at this!
It's the guards.
It's the fuckin' Guards!
Call me crazy, but those guys
don't look dead.
You see? Told you
they'd show up.
Hi there.
- It's so nice to see you guys.
- Good.
- What's with the camera?
- Just making a movie.
Is that so?
Where did you get all the stuff?
Friends.
You know, seems to be
a whole lot of folks
getting a whole lot of stuff
from a whole lot of friends.
Can we be friends?
You wanna turn that off, son?
Turn the fucker off!
Now!
There’s your fuckin'
National Guard, Tony.
- They stole everything we got.
- Not everything, they left us our weapons..
- Yeah, they have their own...
- They're military men.
With the world
been what it is
they know we wouldn't
survive without weapons.
They're not murderers,
just thieves.
With the world being what it is.
I agree with that.
From now on...
Everyone who dies,
is gonna come back.
I mean, think about that.
Everyone who dies,
unless they get a bullet in the head,
is gonna come back,
and try to kill somebody else.
And on, and on, and on.
Forever.
Get your helmet
cams on.
See anyone alive,
pull them out.
Hey, is anyone
in there?
Anybody home?
- Hey, hold it!
- Don't go in there!
- Hold it, hold it!
- Are you all right, mister?
- Take her with you.
- What are you hiding, old man?
No, please!
Nobody in here.
I don't see anything..
Son of a bitch!
Over there, behind you!
You fuckin' dick!
How'd you fuckin' get
to be in here?!
Look what
happened!
- They were family!
- Kill them!
- Kill the prick!
No, don't shoot!
Don't shoot them
in the head.
Shoot them
in the heart.
Let them fuckin'
wake up dead.
They used to be...
us against us.
Now, it's us
against them..
He was right,
us against them.
Except they
are us.
We're here!
Here is it!
Wake up, Guys!
Come on, wake up!
Oh man, it's huge!
Looks like what god
might have built.
Only if he
had the money.
Ridley made this place
so much like a fortress.
I've never been to a fortress before,
but don't they usually keep the doors locked?
- I told you, he said everything was cool.
- Well, that was yesterday.
Plenty of security.
There got to be monitors
around here, somewhere.
Monitors don't do us any good,
while somebody's watching.
Somebody might be watching us.
Right now.
OK, let’s go in.
No, wait, wait, go back.
Step back.
I wanna cover everything.
OK, ready, come in.
I can't do this anymore.
Every time we walk in somewhere,
somebody dies.
Or somebody already died.
It's gonna be the same
wherever we go.
Shut the door.
Ridley?
Ridley!
Francine?
Hello!
Hey Max!
Ridley?
This is where the party was.
Good lord!
Treasures.
Absolute treasures.
"A Tale of Two Cities. "
First edition.
You have any ideas
how much this is worth?
It was the best of times,
it was the worst of times.
Ridley! You scared us
half to dead!
You came! This is great, this is so
fuckin' great to have all you guys here!
- Where’s Francine?
- Where are your parents?
Why was the front
door open?
Oh, what that?
I was outside, just came back in.
Must not have shut it behind me.
Stupid. You know me,
I'm stupid.
What's in there?
Panic room.
Wow, what's going on,
why were you in there?
Just checking the generator,
that's all, everything's fine.
Even better now,
that you're here.
Guys! Hell, it's such so great
to have you guys here!
You must be
totally burned.
What can I get for you?
Something to eat? Drink?
- A cocktail would be lovely.
- The bar is up right over there.
I'll love to get this damn
corset off me now, please.
You know,
what I like?
A long, hot bath.
Take a bathroom. We've got six.
Clean towels, shampoo, soap.
Whatever you'll need.
Whatever.
So, nobody's tried to
break in or anything?
Nobody around
to break in.
We're pretty
isolated out here.
Country Club is closer than
the next house, but...
not too many people are interested
in golf or tennis these days.
Where's your stuff?
You must have brought
some stuff with you.
Dirty clothes.
Bags of them.
Well, bring it in!
Bring it all in!
Something tells me, you're
going to be here for a while.
I'm going to
the Winni.
I'll come with you, I'd like to grab
that out of the camera.
X-1's never enough.
Here, you take
this one.
I don't know. I don't wanna
make this kind of movie.
I don't want to movie this kind of
movie either, but I can't change the script!
- Here, see if you can resist.
- I don't want to do this.
Jason! I don't
want to do this!
My father shot a rabbit!
I thought it was in here.
Tony, you're filming.
I guess Jason was right,
you can't resist.
I'm filming you Ridley, because
you're acting a little weird.
All that shit, that
has been going on.
I know.
I know what's
going on.
I just feel a
little bit tired and...
felt a little drunk,
That's all.
- Forget the rabbits.
- Ridley.
Father shot two of them. They are
downstairs in one of those big freezers.
Ridley, can we look for
Francine now?
She's out back.
With my family
and the staff.
Right, you said that.
Why don't we go see her?
I don't think we
should do that.
- Why?
- Well...
To begin with...
Father's dead.
He was the first one to die, then he did
mother, and then they did the staff.
Brannigan, Brenda, Cook.
Really liked Cook.
Maybe she ate the rabbit?
Did somebody
eat Francine?
No.
Well..
Not exactly,
Brannigan bit her on the face.
I think. I don't know,
it all happened so fast.
- I think we should get out of here.
- Wait, wait, Ridley!
- Your saying they're all dead?
- Yes.
I had to bury them.
Is no one else hungry?
I didn't bury them in the garden,
I'd never dig up mother's roses.
That's OK, come on
I had to chop off Cook's hand,
that's why there's so much blood.
Francine.
Come on!
- Maybe we should get out of here.
- No, I got to see this.
Guys!
It's a little hard to see.
Here, I'll turn on the lights.
This is where I've
buried them.
Sweet Jesus.
- He's gone.
- There was blood on his arms.
I wonder if he
got bitten?
Guys?
- Jason! A little help here.
- I'm shooting.
Oh, Ridley. Can you
give me hand?
Jesus!
Oh shit.
He's fuckin' dead!
Oh fuck!
- Jason! A little help here?
- Run! Run, Tracey!
See? I told you these
things move slow.
Where the fuck
did they go?
Tracey?
Tracey!
Oh shit!
I can’t fuckin'
believe this!
This is like a goddamn
mummy movie!
Jason, put down that stupid
camera and come help me!
Get that Jason?
I hope you're happy, you son of a bitch!
Cut! Cut!
- This isn't a movie, Jason, its real!
- I'm trying to distract it. Cut! Cut!
Tell him,
I'm from Texas.
Tracey!
I'm leaving you, Jason.
You do the house, I'll do the car.
Francine!
- I don't believe this!
- What, is she nuts?
- Where does she thinks she's going?
- Well, she's not going for Chinese!.
You know what? It's OK..
We still got Ridley's car
there's other cars in the garage,
we can still get out of here.
No, bad idea.
Look, Ridley's mother and others are
moping around somewhere, dead or alive.
And there are human
goldfish in the fuckin' pool.
We just spent the last two days on the road.
Did you have a good time?
- No, but...
- Out there, we're lunch.
In here, there's a steel reinforced panic room,
where we could sit and play Nintendo.
Until this whole
thing blows over.
- It's me.
- Jesus.
- Where's Ridley? Have you seen him?
- Yeah, he's not Ridley anymore.
He's something else.
Eliot is something
else too, I'm afraid.
What?!
All gone.
He died in a tub of water,
with Ridley in his arms.
How do you
know all this?
I saw it on TV, darling. I took my bourbon
and I went in to watch the monitors.
I went into that
panic room, which
I suggest is the good place
for us all go right now.
Always wanted my
own swashbuckler.
- Your drunk, Professor?
- Indeed I am.
The drunkenness
have oddly.
Regretfully, never twisted my perception
of things I'd rather run with.
Tracey's phone.
- Let's go.
- No.
Jason!
We can't just lock ourselves
in the fuckin' room.
- We'll be locking ourselves out the world.
- That's the whole point.
We lock ourselves out the world,
before the world bites us on the ass.
We've got weapons.
We can take care of whatever comes.
We can't go
in there, Deb.
I'll miss...
I'll miss everything.
God damn it, Jason,
will you stop this?!
Come with us.
Be safe.
Settle, like I'm
trying to do.
- Settle, for...
- What?
For life.
For survival.
Survival? Who the fuck wants
to survive in a world like this?
All that's left, is to record
what's happening for
whoever remains
when it's over.
Please.
I don't wanna go in
there without you.
Alright.
I can't.
What was that?
Where the hell is he?
Oh no!
Oh god, No!
J...
Kill me.
No.
Michael...
the Archangel.
Hi, my name is J.
Jason Creed.
and I have been given the
opportunity, given the gift
to be able to document the events,
that has suddenly, landed on my lap.
and I just wanted to let you guys
know, the audience know, that...
I'm gonna do my best, to capture
the truth, with me and my friends.
Which gonna be no fakeyness,
I'm gonna go after everything...
really raw, really real,
and I'm going to do the best job I can...
and I'm really excited,
to be given this opportunity,
and I'm not
gonna fuck it up.
Yeah..
Debby?
Debra!
Deb?
I'm gonna
finish his movie.
The movie's off.
No.
There's gonna
be more.
There's gotta
Morning approaches.
Things always look
better in the morning.
Not to me.
Mornings bring light,
I prefer the darkness.
It's easier to
hide in the dark.
You know professor,
they actually get the...
mornings, they show you for what you are,
instead of what you think you are.
In-elegantly phrased, Mr. Ravello,
but accurately put.
Mornings.
And mirrors.
I despise them.
Mornings and mirrors
only serve to terrify old men.
Hey!
Can you say
that again?
I didn't get that.
The truth,
darling.
Look at this!
Close the door!
Jason once said he
thought he could help.
Maybe even
save some lives.
This is the last thing he
downloaded before he died.
A couple of hometown Joes,
who were out shooting targets.
That day, they
used people.
Dead people.
You know,
just for fun.
There was one target
different from the rest.
A woman, tied by her
hair to the branch of a tree.
The boys had this one setup
just for kicks.
They got out their
favorite 12 gauge and...
Are we worth saving?
You tell me.