Dae Shik!
Dae Shik, are you okay?
Hey, Dae Shik!
Dae Shik! Snap out of it!
What are you doing?
Please send an ambulance immediately.
Snap out of it!
Wait a moment. The address is-
Dae Shik! Hey!
What happened to you?
The address is the city of Seoul, Seo-cho, 18-19.
Hold on. The ambulance will be here soon.
It's going to be okay. It's going to be okay.
Dae Shik?
Dae Shik!
Wake up! Dae Shik!
Wake up!
Dae Shik!
A tarot card you drew was found at a crime scene.
I think the person who sent the tarot card knows you very well.
It feels like he is giving you clues to solve the mystery.
That in turn also means that you know the answer.
I don't believe in coincidence.
Stop the bullshit and tell me the truth!
Episode 5
Please, have some.
Thank you.
Should I get you a newspaper?
No, that's okay. I'm fine. Don't pay any attention to me.
Yes, sir.
What happened?
Something's happened.
Did Senior Kang head butt Seong Jun Pyo?
What are you talking about?
I'm not quite sure what's going on myself.
Anyway, Senior Kang says it's related to the tarot card case.
Where are you?
Hold on a sec.
Sorry. Did you wait long?
Got it.
No.
I'm sorry to interrupt, but another case came up.
A case?
Is this where you live?
Yes.
You really are a smart Dorothy, Sora.
*a famous children's song called "The Island House Child"*
"When Mother goes to pick oysters"
"in the shadows of the island. "
*a famous children's song called "The Island House Child"*
What are you doing?
Patient Yoon Dae Shik has passed away at 8:30 in the evening.
"Hearing the lullaby"
"sung by the ocean waves"
"The baby gently"
"falls asleep. "
What are you saying?
His heart had already stopped before reaching the hospital.
That's impossible. Impossible!
Why are you just standing there? Do something. Aren't you a doctor?
Dae Shik!
Try to stay with me. Try a bit harder, Dae Shik.
Dae Shik, can you hear me?
Do something!
I'm sorry. There's nothing more we can do.
He wouldn't just die like that.
I tell you, he wouldn't!
Listen to me!
Senior Kang!
Do something!
Calm down!
Please don't do this. Snap out of it.
You're the only one who worries about me.
After I've collected all the small debts, I'm considering opening an o-deng bar.
Dae Shik.
Your mother will be here soon.
Mom's always late because she has to earn money.
Do you want a surprise?
Now, which hand?
This one.
Tada!
An airway closure?
Since the patient had asthma, there's a possibility that an airway closed up due to the asthma.
Then are you saying the cause of death was asthma?
It's merely a conjecture.
Only an autopsy will tell you the true cause of death.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Give me the car keys.
Where are you going?
Give me the keys!
Mom!
Sora!
Sora! Are you okay? Huh?
Mister Wizard brought me home.
Over there.
I'm not certain, but it seems that card arrived by Quikservice.
With this doll.
I'm not sure how to thank you.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Don't mention it.
I'm not quite in the right mind now, but if you leave me your contact information, I will say my thanks properly later.
Don't worry about it.
But-
I had a lot of fun with Sora.
Next time don't follow strangers, okay?
You don't want to lose your way again. Understand?
Please go in.
Thank you so much.
Mom?
Here.
The Wizard of Oz gave it to me.
He did?
And...
This, too.
Oh Seung Ha Law Offices
Mister Wizard said to call him if I ever don't know where I am again.
I see.
This isn't right, Senior.
He's psycho. We can't leave him be.
You're jumping into this situation blindly!
The guy killed Dae Shik.
It could have been because of the asthma.
It was definitely murder.
We don't have any evidence.
We don't need any more evidence to deal with a psycho.
Let's come back after we've found the evidence.
Seong Jun Pyo.
Senior Kang!
Seong Jun Pyo, come out!
Why are you acting like this?
Hear me? Seong Jun Pyo!
Come out!
You need to pull yourself together.
Fine. Let's assume it was murder.
All the more reason to find the evidence first.
If we're not prepared, we're going to lose to him.
Do you want to defile the death of your friend?
Why in the world...
Why Dae Shik?
He was just starting to get his life together.
So why in the world...
So let's find the evidence.
Let's get the evidence and put the psycho behind bars.
Okay, Senior?
What are you two doing?
Didn't you hear me ask you what you're doing in front of my house?
We're police officers.
I know.
What I want to know is, what the police is doing in front of my house-
Where are you coming from?
Why do you ask?
Why do I have to tell you where I'm coming from?
*Jun Pyo drops formal polite speech between strangers or when speaking to someone older or of higher status.*
Why are you speaking ban-mal* to me?
(*informal speech)
What did you say?
We just have something we want to confirm.
Don't you realize this is a violation of my civil rights?
I'll apologize if that's how you felt.
If you have something to confirm, present the proper grounds,
follow through with the proper procedure,
and then come back to see me.
Don't go anywhere far.
I'll follow the proper procedure and be back real soon.
He told me you'd come to pick me up if I waited in front of the police station.
Do you know who the man was?
Mister Wizard?
No, the man who took you to the zoo and told you to wait at the police station.
Was it the man who came to our house last time?
You know, the one you said was scary.
Nope. It was the nice man who gave me this doll.
The man who gave you the doll?
Yup.
I've already looked. There's not much to find.
Why isn't the forensics team here?
The thing is, the situation hasn't been officially declared a case.
It's a murder case!
There's nothing here.
Move it.
Did you contact the immediate family?
Hey, hand me the flashlight.
It's a woman's.
I saw a little girl.
Around the age of five.
A little girl.
What?
I cannot stop myself
There's nothing I can do now
Oh Soo?
You know I really like you, right?
Fine, let's just date!
Please leave like the wind
Before we fall in love
I have things I must find
The lost dreams and truths
I was in so much pain
I could not hold onto your hand
I love you, I love you
I've hidden behind you and confessed countless times
I ask of you, please avoid me
I cannot make you happy right now
Did something happen?
Don't wait for me
Don't turn around
Please don't love this undeserving man
I was... just in the area...
How did you know I was here?
I woke up because of the rain and saw you outside.
Did something bad happen?
Don't love me
Go on in. You might catch a cold.
I have no right to receive your love
Just leave after seeing only the good things
Before there is sadness in the end
There is another world
Even with the same sky, the same land
The world does not recognize
My pained heart
I ask of you, please avoid me
I cannot make you happy right now
Don't wait for me
Don't turn around
Please don't love this undeserving man
Oh my goodness!
You surprised me, Mom.
I'm the surprised one here.
Do you know what time it is?
The sound of the rain was just so nice.
You're quite good at lying.
Who is he, the guy that was just outside?
Do you have a boyfriend?
I would've introduced him to you already if I did.
Why did he come to see you so late then?
What does he do for a living?
I'd better go back to sleep. After all, I have work tomorrow.
Mom, you should go back to bed, too.
Everyone has a secret they want to hide.
I'm disappointed in you.
Mom?
I'll tell you all about it later.
I will.
Are you mad at me?
Oh Soo?
Where's Soon Ki?
In the bedroom. Why?
Hey.
Today-
no, yesterday did you go to Dae Shik's office?
No.
You were supposed to meet him.
What's going on?
Tell me the truth. Did you meet with him?
What happened was
I did go to meet him, but-
But?
There was a police car up front, so I just came home.
What?
Dae Shik's been arrested by the police, right?
I saw this coming a mile away.
He's always ripping off the weak-
Shut up. Shut the hell up!
Oh Soo, what are you doing?
You told me the truth, right? You didn't go to his office?
I told you, I didn't go.
What in the world is going on?
Oh Soo?
Dae Shik is...
dead.
What the hell did he just say?
Sorry about yesterday.
Don't worry about it.
What was it you wanted to talk to me about?
I'll tell you in person next time.
When are you free?
I have no idea. Another case just came up.
Then please give me a call when you're free.
Will do.
Chief!
The immediate family has agreed to allow the autopsy.
Are you certain this is a murder case?
What do you mean?
I'm sorry about what happened to your friend
but we have to consider the doctor's opinion.
But-
Hear me out.
We can't assume it's a murder case on the
mere fact that a tarot card was sent.
I'm sure it was murder.
It's not just the package. Yesterday, when I went into his office, there was a strange smoky gas smell.
A gas smell?
Yes.
I can't tell you what smell it was exactly, but I'm certain it had something to do with Dae Shik's death.
Found it!
You went through a lot of trouble last night, right?
I had fun with that intelligent child.
So how did the mother manage to lose her child like that?
I forgot to ask.
Oh, has the date been set for Jo Dong Sub's first public hearing?
Not yet.
By the way, how did you happen to meet Jo Dong Sub?
Just... coincidentally.
I see.
Why do you ask?
Something about Lawyer Kwon's case disturbs me.
Which is?
It's entirely of personal interest, so I shouldn't even bother you with it.
That makes me even more curious.
Shadowed Journey
Listen. To the call of the trumpets of judgment.
Look. For a new world will come after the darkness is cleared.
The tarot cards are placed in the order they were sent to Senior Kang
and the content fits perfectly.
This guy really is a psycho.
After the Justice card, there's no mention of any other cards-
Wait up.
I figured out what the sculpture was.
It's something called the Gates of Hell.
It's this guy, without a doubt.
Contact the information team and find out who's the blog owner, his real name,
how many times he logged in, the
location from where he logged in, all of it.
Yes, sir.
I was meaning to come to see you earlier. I'm sorry I came so late.
Ah, here.
Here you go.
What is this?
I didn't thank you properly.
It's not much. Please accept it.
I've already received a recompense.
Please just take it.
And I heard you paid the tab at the bar.
I assume your friends are doing well?
Not really.
Do you remember Dae Shik from that night?
Of course.
He died last night.
How did that happen?
I'm not sure myself.
The funeral's been postponed because of the autopsy...
What a dreadfully unlucky guy.
I'm not sure what I can say in consolation.
I knew a person's life couldn't be controlled
but he wasn't even thirty yet.
What a pitifully young age.
That's what I'm saying.
Please inform me when the funeral date is set.
Why? Are you going to come?
Of course I will.
We have some connections, after all.
You don't have to bother.
Detective Kang?
The daffodil has brightly bloomed.
Huh?
The plant you gave to me as a present before.
That flower was a daffodil.
It's even more radiant today than usual.
I didn't even know what kind of flower it was.
I hope you got home all right last night.
My friend died.
The Justice tarot card that came to me was also sent to his office.
Then...
My friend was the next sacrifice that the card gave notice for.
Though I don't know the motive yet
it has become absolutely certain that the murderer is somehow connected to me.
So...
Dae Shik died.
Because of me.
He died because of me.
Here.
This is the doll you saw in the afterimage, right?
Yes.
Was this sent with the tarot card?
A knife was sent to Lawyer Kwon, and that became the murder weapon.
This time it's this doll, but I can't figure out why it was sent.
Was the cause of death a gunshot wound?
No, but an autopsy is scheduled, so we should find out soon.
Have you ever seen this man in your afterimages?
No.
Is that so?
Excuse me.
Yeah?
We found out the blog owner's identity.
Who is it?
Him, Seong Jun Pyo.
Got it.
I have to get going.
The tarot card found at the crime scene is also in here. The other evidence is being held right now at the station.
Please help us out.
Of course.
Thank you.
Detective Kang?
It's not your fault.
Whatever the reason, what's right is right, and what's wrong is wrong.
There are no exceptions to that rule.
Whatever the reason, the bad person is the criminal who took the victims' lives.
It's definitely not you.
So please do not blame yourself like that.
I'm sure your friend wouldn't want to see you do that.
What is it this time?
It's a search warrant.
What?
Wait, what's the charge?
Aiding and abetting murder.
I expect full cooperation.
Journalist Seong Jun Pyo.
Aiding and abetting murder?
That's right.
This is preposterous.
Being under suspicion means that there's some sort of reason behind it.
Go ahead and search.
The talking can come later.
I think it's a very meticulous person.
The scissor’s handles were wrapped in red string.
Senior Kang?
These look like the shoes on the security camera tapes.
I'm certain they are.
I watched that scene over 20 times.
I don't know who sent me the package.
Why were you holding onto items sent by a stranger?
Since it was from a stranger, I couldn't return it, could I?
What happened to the box it was sent in?
I put it into the recycling bin during separate garbage collection.
Yet you kept the items that were sent in that box?
How many times do I have to repeat myself?
And this is a matter of simple common sense.
If I had evidence from a crime scene
why would I leave it at my home?
You couldn't throw them away.
You needed them for your next crime.
What a bunch of crock.
Then why do you suppose a package was sent to you when you have nothing to do with all this?
For what possible reason?
That's exactly what I wanted to ask.
You wrote this stuff on your web-blog, right?
Nope.
The blog was created in your name.
I have no clue about that.
Do you think it makes sense that you have no clue when you created the blog?
You think that's the only thing that doesn't make sense here?
The fact that you have me here, questioning me about this, doesn't make any sense to begin with. And-
can you prove that just because it was made in my name, I'm the one to actually make it?
Why did you write that article sympathizing with Jo Dong Sub?
Does a journalist need a reason to write an article?
You want me to tell you the reason?
A few years ago, you wrote an article exposing the
corruption of Congressman Kang Dong Hyeon
and ended up getting sued for libel.
In addition to that, you were fired from the editor's position and divorced by your wife.
And so you bore a grudge against Congressman Kang and Lawyer Kwon
and decided to eliminate the people around Congressman
Kang, one by one, using a third party.
Your first target was Lawyer Kwon.
That'll make quite an interesting article.
It's the truth.
After murdering Lawyer Kwon, you wrote that article,
almost as if you had been waiting for the moment.
The article sympathizing with Jo Dong Sub.
It actually does make logical sense
but if it were me, I would have started with
Kang Dong Hyeon, not Kwon Hyeon Tae.
Or perhaps Kang Dong Hyeon's son.
Doesn't that make more sense?
You little-
Detective Kang!
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree, does it?
Where were you between 7:00 and 8:30 last night?
I had dinner with the editor of "Issue & Issue. "
And let me get one thing straight.
I'm not reckless enough to do something foolish out of personal spite.
I have enough self-control to sit back
and watch a rotten and corrupt politician
swagger around shamelessly.
I checked the IP address of the blog entries
and unlike Seong Jun Pyo's other entries
*Shin-chon is a popular area in Seoul, especially
since it's where Yonsei University is located
it was posted from a PC room in Shin-chon.
*Shin-chon is a popular area in Seoul, especially
since it's where Yonsei University is located
and it's a great place to hang out for young people*
it was posted from a PC room in Shin-chon.
Please look at the picture carefully.
Is this the man who asked you to send the package?
I don't think it is.
Take a closer look. Maybe try imagining that
he was wearing a wig and sunglasses.
Is it him?
No.
Take a closer look!
This man...
is not the guy.
It was verified that Seong Jun Pyo did receive a package.
And his alibi's airtight.
But there are so many dissatisfactory points.
My instinct tells me he's hiding something.
I don't think he's lying.
How can you be sure?
I can tell by his eyes.
His eyes were completely calm and pulled together.
But that's still just your opinion.
Let's organize our thoughts.
If Seong Jun Pyo did use Jo Dong Sub to murder Kwon Hyeon Tae
it does make sense.
His motive would be revenge against Congressman Kang Dong Hyeon.
But he has no motive to kill Yoon Dae Shik.
Then maybe the criminal used Seong Jun Pyo
just like Lee Bong Gyu was used.
That's a different case.
How so?
If Lee Bong Gyu was chosen at random,
Seong Jun Pyo was intentionally picked.
That's why the letter to Jo Dong Sub was sent in the name of Pyo Jun Seong.
And the afterimage of the row house-
Afterimage?
Let's talk outside.
Chief!
I already know.
Senior Kang didn't tell me. I found out by accident.
About what?
What are we talking about?
I'll explain later.
Let's finish listening to Detective Kang.
What are you guys talking about?
He already said he'd explain later.
Continue with your thoughts, Senior.
If Seong Jun Pyo has nothing to do with this case
there's no way the afterimage of the row house
would be embedded in the letter sent to Jo Dong Sub.
You're saying that even if Seong Jun Pyo isn't
the criminal, he's connected to the case somehow.
Right.
If Seong Jun Pyo was used simply to create
confusion in the case, then the row house afterimage-
What is it?
We need to speak privately outside.
What if...
someone intentionally put the afterimage
of the row house into the letter to Jo Dong Sub?
What does that imply?
It implies that the criminal wanted us to find Seong Jun Pyo.
And we moved according to his plan.
More importantly, it means that the criminal
knew about Hae In's ability from the start.
If that's possible, then...
We can't entirely trust any of the afterimages
that Hae In reads out of things.
Then kill me.
If you have the self-confidence, then do it. Don't just stand there.
Please take a step back.
Then kill me. Kill me.
Hae In?
What are you doing here?
My office is in this area.
Is there an emergency or something?
No.
You're sweating quite a bit.
I'm fine.
Use this.
Please get in.
I'm fine.
Is it your habit to say "I'm fine"?
Yes.
Please do get in even if you are fine by yourself.
You're headed to Galanthus, right?
*Galanthus is the name of the cafe that Hae In's friend
Ju Hee owns as well as the tarot cards that Hae In drew. *
My place is also in that direction.
Thank you.
Why were you running a race so late in the evening?
I had my reasons.
Did you eat yet?
Not yet.
I didn't eat either.
Want to eat together?
Let's eat dinner together.
I have an appointment at the cafe.
I see.
Thank you.
Go on in.
When did you get here?
Just now.
I heard about your friend.
Today, Kim Soon Ki came by my office.
He was a friend who seemed unusually close with you.
Your sadness must be great.
Thank you for your concern.
Then, goodbye.
Let's have dinner sometime.
Sure.
Aren't you going in?
Do you have something to say to me?
No. Let's go in.
I've got it.
Who-
Who is it?
I'm not sure.
Open the gate.
Who is it?
Oh Soo's friend.
I have to take care of him before Father shows up, so open the gate.
Why don't you go out and send him away?
He won't leave just because I tell him to.
You go out to him.
I don't like strangers coming into our home.
Che, what's going on?
You were home?
What brings you all the way here?
I was just so upset by what happened to Dae Shik.
I wanted to have a drink with you.
I would but I have an early meeting tomorrow morning.
And my wife isn't feeling very well, either.
Is that so? Then I'd better go say hello.
I never even got to see her face
since I was always at "school."
"school" is a euphemism for prison*
You can say hello some other time.
Take this.
What are you doing?
I didn't come here for this.
Take it.
Man, you shouldn't do this kind of thing.
Welcome home, Father.
Yeah.
Have you been well, Father?
*In Korean culture, you call close friends' parents "Father" and "Mother. "*
I'm out like this, thanks to you.
Where's Oh Soo?
He's terribly busy these days with Dae Shik's case.
I was planning to stop by sometime and discuss some matters with you.
You're the only source of strength I have, after all.
No matter how I try to lead a decent life,
society just won't allow it.
What did you say your name was?
Who are you speaking about?
Oh, right.
It was something like Kim Soon Ki, right?
Yes.
In my opinion, a man who knows his proper
place in life is the wisest kind of man.
The law of the world doesn't allow men to try to act
above one's lot in life. That just calls for disaster.
I'm not sure what you mean.
A person who makes the hairs on the back of my
neck stand despite the fact that I helped them,
I don't particularly like that kind of person.
Come to my office sometime.
Let's talk then.
Yes, sir.
You followed him? Have you no fear?
You're not Angelina Jolie.
Who knows what the horrible man might have done to you!
Did you see the man's face?
No. I only saw him from behind.
Did he have any distinctive features?
He looked like a common man.
He was average height and was wearing a suit.
Which subway station was it?
Kyo-dae Station.
*station where the Seoul National University of Education is located*
Oh, and this.
It was found in Dae Shik's office.
That's enough for today.
If all of this makes Hae In sick, are you
going to take responsibility for that?
Ju Hee.
Do you know how nervous you make me?
I'm afraid you'll become ill again.
Hae In once said that she wouldn't ever do this kind of thing again.
It's that difficult.
Aren't you overworking her?
I'm fine.
It's not fine!
I'm sorry. I was so anxious I didn't think that far ahead.
I want to know as well.
Why he's using the tarot cards I drew
to give an advance notice of murder,
how this is all related to me,
I want to know all that.
And I have to find out.
(She's in a jjim-jil-bang: steam room you go to with your clothes on. Popular hangout place to chat in Korea, Some even go here instead of motels when they need somewhere to spend the night)
What have you done with Sora, you bastard?
Where's my daughter? Where is she? Where is Sora?
What do you plan to do?
Sora.
She was looking for a child named Sora.
Who was?
I think it was the mother.
And she pulled the trigger.
Are you talking about a gun?
Yes.
She pulled the trigger several times.
But he didn't die by gunshot wounds.
Hello?
Um...
Isn't this Yoon Dae Shik's cell phone?
It is.
Can I please speak with Yoon Dae Shik?
He can't come to the phone right now. Who is this?
Is he okay?
If you tell me who you are-
Hello?
She hung up.
Who was it?
Seeing how she asked if the victim was
okay, she knows about his accident.
But she doesn't know about his death.
Trace that number immediately.
Yes, sir!
When is Yoon Dae Shik's autopsy?
Tomorrow, sir.
Yeah?
A gas gun?
It's highly probable.
There was a smoky smell in Dae Shik's office
and the fact that Hae In saw a gun can be explained if it's a gas gun.
I'm heading in now.
Detective Kang?
Please be careful.
I saw you and your friend in the afterimages of the crime
evidence, and that means the criminal is watching you.
Don't worry.
By any chance, is there anyone else who knows about your ability?
Why do you ask?
I'll explain later.
And go home early. Staying out late is dangerous.
You definitely don't have to worry about me.
Sorry. Did you wait long?
Don't worry about it.
What's the new case about?
Something that's a total pain.
What did you want to talk to me about?
I heard there's a Detective Kang Oh Soo on your team?
There is. What about him?
Is his father by any chance Congressman Kang Dong Hyeon?
That's right.
Is this about Oh Soo?
Hae In. There's a package for you.
A package?
It's virtually impossible to find the person with only the name Sora.
The kid's not even old enough to have a registration card.
*All Koreans receive their cards at age 19, Korean age. *
We haven't found Dae Shik's employees yet?
Yeah.
I think we have to release Seong Jun Pyo for now.
We don't have enough evidence to hold onto him any longer.
We traced the call made to Yoon Dae Shik's phone. It was made from a jjim-jil-bang.
*jjim-jil-bang = steam sauna*
Where's it located?
Package delivery.