It is not the horror of landmines
that is making a headline back home.
Reports of the Princess' romance with
Dodi Fayed...
Speculations fueled by the arrival last night...
Diana, Princess of Wales, has been formally separated from her husband,
Prince Charles for nearly three years.
Diana!
-Diana!
Di!
Diana, this way!
-Over here!
Over here, Di!
Looks like the check's in the post.
This way, Princess.
Over here!
Di!
Are you getting a divorce?
Di, are you getting a divorce?
Thanks.
It's been a long week,
you must all be very tired.
Go home.
And thank you.
Where would you like to supper,
Your Royal Highness?
I don't want anything, everyone can go home.
Thank you.
So yes i...
I did infict on myself.
I didn't like myself.
I was ashamed that i couldn't cope
with the pressures.
So, i just hurt my arms.
So i just hurt my arms
and my legs.
There were 3 of us in this marriage.
So it's a bit crowded.
The most persistent critism
is that as the marriage broke down...
You were unfaithful
to your wife.
That's a persistent critism, is it?
And open your eyes.
Would you like a pin?
Hmm...
It keeps coming back.
That dream i told you about.
Falling into darkness?
It's not falling.
It's being dropped.
Someone's doing it to me.
And take a breath.
I think perhaps you're afraid
of letting go.
No.
I hang on to things,
like my marriage.
You're a cancerian.
You hang on to the idea of love.
Cause you're so good
at giving love.
So you keep on giving.
The hard part is receiving love.
But if i can't receive it,
i'm back where it started.
And where is that?
On the doorstep.
A little girl waiting for her mother to return.
Perhaps that little girl should finally stand up
and walk into the garden.
It's been 30 years.
In your dream,
who's pushing you?
It's not the point, Oonagh.
The point is...
Will anyone catch me?
Just use the same...
Right then.
I suppose it's too late
to back out now.
It's fine, Wills.
Just take care not to shoot any carcass.
I'll see you next weekend.
The one after.
If that's what the palace
have decided...
No, it's fine with me.
As long as you're happy.
I miss you too.
I'm at the opera.
Having a great time.
I love you.
Bye, darling.
There's something coming up.
A nuclear submarine
needs to be named.
I've indicated to the palace
you might be willing to do it.
Perhaps you can indicate to the palace
that i'd like to see my children.
More than once
every 5 weeks.
The submarine, i think in the current situation
it'll be sensible.
A nuclear submarine?
I want to help people.
It's still possible
you might be queen one day.
Like it or not, you're going to have
an army and navy who will be helping people...
By...
-Shut up!
Sorry, Patrick.
Your Royal Highness,
there's a call from Oonagh.
She said it's urgent.
Excuse me, intensive care?
Second floor on the right.
-Thank you.
He had a hemorrhage.
It sometimes happens
with bypass operations.
Mrs. Toffollo.
Doctor.
This is Diana.
Joseph's condition is still
very serious.
I need your permission to take him back
this afternoon.
Of course.
Do please look after him.
He is very precious.
He's going to be alright.
Yes.
That man knows what he's doing,
don't you think?
Are you going down?
-Yes.
Thanks, i was...
Just think Joseph's so much better.
Mr Toffollo is not on that floor.
Right.
Yes, i got lost and...
You know, went a bit wrong.
Actually, i didn't get lost.
I was snooping.
Hospitals fascinate me.
Are you being serious?
Yes.
When i visit hospitals,
i get excited.
I feel like i can make
a contribution.
Perhaps i can show you around.
I would adore that.
I don't know
how to contact you.
Well, i'm like most people.
I've got a mobile.
Actually, i'm not like most people.
I have 4.
One number would do.
And 11.00 an audience with His Grace,
The Archbishop of Canterbury.
13.00...
-Paul!
Lunch with Clyde James.
15.00 briefing here at KP
with doctors from Broadmol.
On patient therapy.
Thank you, Paul.
And one last thing, ma'am.
There's been a rumor,
you've done an interview with BBC.
Yes, don't worry about that, Patrick.
Everything will be alright.
This is the Reginald Wilson Ward,
retains private rooms.
The NHS is on this side.
Basically we're about 50/50.
Is your father a doctor?
No, he runs the family business.
He plants bottles.
But i do have an uncle
who's a heart surgeon.
So you followed him.
I follow no one.
But yes, i admit.
My uncle did help
to set me on my path.
Family can be useful.
And bloody irritating.
Perhaps i've been luckier with my family
than you have.
I don't know.
I've got two families.
How lucky is that?
This is pretty much
state of the art.
How long a heart operation
go on?
Sometimes 8 to 9 hours.
God, how do you keep going?
You reach a place inside youself
where time has no meaning.
You don't perform the operation...
The operation performs you.
I'd love to feel that.
And when it's over...
Reality is a bit flat.
And you're very tired.
I bet.
This is the on-call accomodation.
You just crash here?
What do you eat?
There's a canteen on teh ground floor,
but it's not open late.
You can always pop around the corner
for supper with me.
I'm serious.
The palace, we stay open very late.
Sonya, are you sure this is the right stuff?
He's a heart surgeon, right?
He'd be a healthy eater.
I've got this.
Aren't they harder to cook?
You boil and drain,
8 minutes.
I'll do everything else,
you just stuff it in the microwave.
Are you sure he's not married
or something?
No, i've checked him out.
So what is it that you like
about this man?
He doesn't treat me
like a princess.
It's almost as if
he doesn't know who i am.
Maybe he doesn't.
He might be very badly informed.
Can we be of an assistance, sir?
Yes.
Cheers.
Are you working tomorrow?
Not at the hospital.
I'm writing a paper from Monday morning,
it's part of my thesis.
I have to be home by midnight.
How do you relax?
Doing such a stressful job?
I listen to jazz.
I'm not sure
i like jazz.
You should go to Ronny Scott's.
I can't just go places,
you know.
It's not the same
listening to records.
Jazz is in the moment.
You have to be there, it's improvise.
Just like life.
My life is completely
regimented.
You mean you're told where to go
and who to shake hands with?
Exactly.
But within that framework,
you improvise.
You look at someone for a clue
as how to start a conversation.
And you let it flow
from there.
You improvise all the time.
And if you can improvise...
You like jazz.
I've got to check
on the supper.
Pretty hot stuff, eh?
-What?
You in the kitchen.
Yes, hot stuff.
You can say that.
Hot stuff...
So hearts can't actually
be broken?
A heart can receive a shock so violence
it never recovers.
Yes, but can they actually break?
My colleagues might disagree...
But i believe for instance that Maria Carlos
died of a broken heart.
You don't like my food.
No.
No, it's lovely.
You're obviously very good.
Come on.
What kind of food
do you really like?
You couldn't make me
a hamburger, could you?
I'm not sure you can actually make hamburgers.
Oh dear.
I could send out for one.
Very good.
Yes, i can see.
Do you mind?
No.
I bet you give your patients lectures
about that.
About what?
-Smoking.
Of course.
But you don't lecture yourself.
I'm not the patient,
i'm the doctor.
You still have to look after yourself.
Tonight you turned down a healthy supper
for fast food.
You've drunk a fair amount of wine
and now you're smoking.
Is there anymore wine?
Or have we run out?
This is a palace,
we don't run out.
I didn't think you'd have a television.
Of course, i love telly.
What do you watch?
Everything.
Series and stuff.
My favorite is Casualty.
It was on tonight, so i videod it.
What?
They're defending too deep.
really?
Come on, push up!
Push up!
See, that's what happens.
You can't give Liverpool that much space to plan,
they'll walk right through you.
Who are the blue ones?
I don't think i should drive home.
Well, the tube is still running.
But if i leave my car here,
it'll be sold for scrap.
I was joking.
I already called
for a driver.
The service here
is rather good.
We should really have horsedrawn carriages
at the ready.
The full Windsor experience.
I'm used to horsedrawn carriages.
I were driven to school in them.
Pakistan?
-Yes.
Freezing cold,
huddled under blankets.
My friends and i, we would breathe the cold air out
and pretend we were smoking.
That's where the bad habits started.
I don't have any bad habits.
How do i get out?
The paratroopers are waiting
for you outside.
They drag you to the tower of London.
Where the Prince of Wales will personally
interogate you.
WIth his favorite set up of midevial
torturing lines.
Yes.
Yes, i was going to ask
about him.
Don't you read the papers?
Not those bits, sorry.
I'm glad somebody doesn't.
Charles and i
live separate lives.
So it's alright me coming here?
More than alright.
I'll call you soon,
if you like.
Yes.
Yes, i would like that.
Good night.
Wonderful cooking.
There's no one theme called jazz, right?
So when he says he likes jazz...
That's like saying, i like food.
People who like different kinds of jazz
come to blows.
It's very weird, from an intense young man.
He's so young.
Right, so.
Choose something, anything.
Good, yeah.
Stick it on.
You have to sit and listen.
You can't chatter through it,
they're very hard on that.
Sit.
Sit and listen.
Diana.
Surprise.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't sleep.
I thought i'd come to see
if i could help.
It's wonderful to see you,
but i don't think that's a good idea.
Right.
So bugger off, basically.
In the nicest possible way.
That's alright,
i'm good at that.
Had a lot of practice.
It's been mad in here.
I was actually going to call you tomorrow.
Stop it.
Diana, just...
You can't do this to me.
Just one more, seriously.
I know you.
News of the World.
You've got a good memory.
Yes, i remember the ones
i don't like.
And i don't do them many favors.
Clive, I'll call you back.
Clive, it's Diana.
This is out of order.
I come here to visit the terminally ill...
People who need to someone
to sit with them through the night.
Yes, and i'm allow to do this
in privacy.
No there isn't going to be a divorce.
Will you please follow the rules?
Good.
It's official, no more pictures.
Good night.
Shit.
I do a job that requires me
to be very focus.
It's not going to be possible
for you and i to go out together.
To a restaurant anywhere,
there would be millions of people swarming all over us.
That maybe your life,
but it can't be mine.
That's pretty clear, then.
I'm sorry, i think you're wonderful.
If there was a way.
I'd take it.
Yes?
Do i know you?
I'm the girl you're gonna ask on a date.
Beautiful.
Gorgeous.
You should have been here last week.
Somebody should have been here
last week.
We had bouncers on the door
throwing people in.
The boy turned up with 25 people,
We offered him a partnership.
Is the fucking mike on?
Thank you, madam.
It's always nice to meet someone who's been allowed out of the dark for the first time.
But, now i'm delighted to introduce
a young act...
That's been making a big impression
on the London scene.
The Dwayne Johnson Quartet.
Hello?
Where are you?
Don't apologize.
Saving lives is a bit
more important.
You know how to show a girl
a good time.
Listen, Hasnat.
I'd love to do that, but...
The next few days are going to be a little bit tricky.
No, i cant...
Just, watch your TV.
Thank you, sir.
Cheers.
Yes, i did inflict upon myself.
I didn't like myself.
I was ashamed that i couldn't
cope with the pressures.
What did you actually do?
I just hurt my arms
and my legs.
Do you think Mrs Parker Bowles
was a factor in the break down of your marriage?
Well, there were 3 of us in this marriage.
So it's a bit crowded.
What evidence that you have that...
Their relationship
is continuing?
Although you were married?
By the change in behavioral pattern
in my husband...
For all sort of reasons that a woman's instinct produces.
You just know.
Do you think
you will ever be queen?
I'd like to be queen of people's hearts.
In people's hearts.
And i don't see myself as being queen of this country.
I don't think many people
want me to be queen.
Because they've decided that...
I'm a non starter.
Why do you think they've decided that?
Because i do things differently.
Cause i don't go by rule book.
Cause i lead from the heart...
Not the head, and all be it,
that's what got me into trouble in my work.
I understand that, but...
Someone's gotta go out there
and love people and show it.
I sit here with hope
cause there's a future i heard.
A future for my husband,
a future for myself.
And the future for the monarchy.
Your Royal Highness, thank you.
That's not good, right?
I suppose it does.
So, what have we got?
These are the transcripts of the
LBC early morning phone-in.
The women are very strong for you.
The men about 50/50.
Yes, i've analyzed the TV pundets,
and that transcara...
Please.
Good morning, Patrick.
I suggest you show the tape to a lawyer.
I offered to open up a formal dialogue,
with Buck house.
I begged you to give me a preview so we could build some firewall
before the shelling began.
You keep telling me everything's going to be alright.
But it's not alright,
it's all wrong.
I've been trying to reopen doors
and you've shut them.
Personally, i have been place in an invidious position.
I have no alternative but
to offer my resignation.
And since i haven't the faintest idea
how to manage this that you have created...
I would like that resignation to have
an immediate effect.
Well Patrick, you've been a rock.
What will you do?
Get a new rock.
Hello?
Yes, tell me what you thought.
I see.
Sonya, so what do you think?
I'll call you back later.
Everyone thinks i screwed up.
I had to hit back.
Hitting back is a short term tactic,
what was your strategy?
I don't think i do strategy.
If your intention was to avoid a divorce,
you've achieved the opposite.
My parents divorced.
I made a vow to myself never put my children
throught the same thing.
So why would you do something
so drastic?
My boys need to see me happy.
It's time.
I have to move on.
So you didn't screw up.
Because now you'll be free.
Here, cover yourself with this blanket.
And lie down in the back.
That way the security guards
don't know more about my life than i do.
You've done this before?
Mind your own business.
Suspension's very low.
Explosive device?
Nah, too bulky.
Looking about 8 kilos there.
That'll be a Pakistani heart surgeon then.
I think we fooled them.
Were you alright in there?
Breathing was impossible.
Come on, that's just a detail.
I love feeling your hand there.
That day when i fist saw you.
So powerful.
Don't think i've been so strucked
by someone.
What do you mean?
It's like...
Nothing could distract you.
You're just doing your job
without any sense of self.
I'm a doctor.
Yes, i know but...
I can see how much love
you put into it.
Love is a garden.
If you can't smell the fragrance,
don't come into the garden of love.
Who said that?
-Rumi.
Persian poet.
13th century.
Garden of love.
I like that.
One year later.
What happened here?
She stepped on a mine.
She was pregnant.
Did she lose the baby?
Yes.
Cause of that problem.
She's Alena.
How old is she?
Seven.
She went out to fetch water
and stood on a landmine.
Her intestines were blown out
of her body.
Ma'am...
A government minister at home reported you a loose cannon,
for supporting this campaign.
Do you have any reaction?
I'm merely trying to highlight a problem
that's going on all around the world.
It's been said though that you're aligning yourself with labor party policy.
Do you think that's wise?
Labor? I don't know what...
I don't know what you're talking about.
This is a humanitarian mission.
It's enough to make me burst into tears that...
Who said i'm a loose cannon?
Mr Wonderful, come in.
Mr Wonderful, this is Diana calling.
My darling, they're attacking you.
Somebody in the house
is calling you...
A loose cannon, yes i know.
But did they print the pictures of the kids
with all their arms and legs blown off?
No, they're making it looked like a routine
hospital visit.
Bastards.
What shall i do?
Use your power.
You're the most famous woman in the world.
You don't have to follow Royal Family Rules anymore.
You're divorced.
So think differently,
improvise.
Alright.
Improvise.
Clear.
I have to do this by myself.
If i go with you, it gives them a chance to belittle me.
Okay, keep to the path,
no veering left or right.
Yeah?
Alright.
Good luck.
What's all the fuss?
They did this field already.
An family worker was killed
three months ago.
Three weeks ago...
That walk would've been impossible.
I'd been blown up many times over.
Soon, all this land
can be farmed again.
And children play in the fields.
But clearance is a lengthly
and hazzardous process.
Humanity's only defense
against landmines.
Is to stop manufacturing...
Thank you.
Something's coming, fellas.
Is it?
Thank you Charlie.
God, i miss you so much.
My beautiful...
I'm so proud of you.
You did it.
It's all down to you.
No.
Why do smokers always smoke
after sex?
After the greatest pleasure in life...
It's only natural to reach out
for the second greatest.
You should give up,
you of all people should know that.
Some people are exempt.
Bollocks.
-Some people lead a charmed life, and i'm one of them.
Walter Walt 22 carrats bollocks.
And i lead a charmed life.
No, i'm an expert
and you're not.
I'm an expert
on everything.
I know about fashion, polo, criminal psychology,
the internal combustion engine...
Rubbish.
It's all part of my job.
embroidery...
Nuclear submarines...
Not an A level to my name,
and i'm... What's that word...
I'm an om... omnipast?
omniscient?
Yes, i even knew that.
I've seen and done everything,
much more than you.
You're just a specialist,
and i'm...
What's that word?
Shut up.
Multiple choice,
is it dilettante, polymath...
Or ectomorph?
You're laughing at me.
You can't even speak proper English.
I don't have to,
i'm not English.
You're so smug.
All you know about is football
and jazz.
And...
Saving people's lives.
Saving lives.
That wasn't on your list, Miss polymath.
I knew it was polymath.
Saving people's lives.
Just delight to see that?
D-Vib tabules.
Charge.
Shoot.
Alright, everyone.
Close them up.
Thank you.
Once again we are champions.
Your patient today.
How bad was he?
He would've died tomorrow.
Or maybe the day after.
Now he'll have another 10 years.
You have power over death.
A doctor's triumphs are only temporary.
I learn that from Victor Chang.
The man you studied under
in Sidney?
Yes.
He treated the whole patient, and without any ego
with love, as you said.
So what happened to him?
6 years ago he was ambushed for money
on his way to work.
He refused to pay, so the guy shot Victor twice in the head.
Where you are, death will find you.
Even if you're in a house built up
strong and whole.
That's from the Qur-an.
I studied Islam
a few years ago.
When i was preparing for a trip
to Pakistan.
See? I was getting ready for you
before i even knew you.
Whose car is this?
My butler's.
What's your butler driving?
-My Audi.
Lucky butler.
WHere are we going?
To the very edge
of the kingdom.
Come on.
Look at this.
Now, be careful.
You brought me to the end
of the world.
I'm going to Australia.
Why are you running away from me?
Victor Chang Institute is doing a fund raiser.
I'm making the keynote speech.
You're doing this for me.
For us.
The world is ours,
this world and the world beyond.
I never think about
the world beyond.
You sleep with a Qur-an
at your bed side.
Habit, hardly ever read it.
I know you do.
Islam is very important to me.
To me it means, the constant rafimation
of one's character.
I believe in that.
I've been reforming my character
since i was seven.
It's finally getting me somewhere.
Your divorce has put things
on a different footing.
You mean with your family?
Yes, a barrier has come down.
Well, barriers coming down is good.
Last one back to the car
is a squash tomato.
- Look.
- What?
It has been said...
That for evil to triumpht...
Good men must do nothing.
Tonight, we give heartfelt thanks...
At a good man.
Dr Victor Chang.
Did a great deal.
And of that...
We can all be thankful.
As we look forward...
To the future.
Nice one.
What are we gonna do?
Our objective is to protect Hasnat.
So we rubbish the story.
But they'll find out eventually.
Well, we're buying time.
That's what we need, isn't it?
Talk about putting 2 and 2 together,
and making 5.
Not a word, not a word of truth.
Officially, i'm furious.
It's upseting for Wills and Harry.
Unofficially?
Well, to be honest.
Richard, we're laughing ourselves silly over this.
For God sake.
What do i look like?
One minute everyone's pointing at me
because i'm sleeping with the Princess of Wales.
Next thing she denies it,
and i'm the hospital joke.
I was just trying to protect you.
Protect?
I knew you'd be upset,
that's why we rubbish the story.
Rubbish?
Yes, good choice of words.
That's exactly what i felt like.
You can't object to being on
the front pages and then...
Complain when i protect you from looking like Cassanova.
You've blown our cover.
It can be dealt with,
i'm good at handling the press.
Oh, manigficent.
Now i'm clear on what you want.
How could it not had been clear?
I am a surgeon!
I can't work with paparazzi sticking their cameras in my face.
If you had to put up
what i have to put up with...
Exactly, i don't have to put up with it.
And i don't want to put up with it.
So what are you saying?
I'm saying there's no future.
The way your life is,
the way my life is.
It's pointless.
Hallo, Dr Khan?
How did you get this number?
We would like to visit you
at the office tomorrow.
How did you get this number?
Can you give me some...
Sonya, it's me.
I'm sorry, i know it's 3.30 in the morning, but...
Can you talk?
I'll never be happy again.
It's the end,
i just know it is.
I know it isn't.
You haven't gone this far
for nothing.
Nobody goes this far
Come...
Good morning, may i speak
to Hasnat Khan please?
He's in the Cardiac Surgical Unit.
Please hold.
Yes I'll hold.
I'm sorry, Dr Khan's not available.
He's not available?
What do you mean
he's not in?
He's in but not available?
Morning, love.
Can i have a word with Dr. Hasnat Khan, please?
He's in the Surgical Unit.
He's very busy now.
Yes, but it's rather urgent.
My name's Rita.
Rita Johnson.
Hasnat, it's me.
Hasnat!
I want to say this.
Yes, i've been a mad bitch.
Yes, i've been a stalker,
and yes most of all...
I put on a crummy Liverpool accent
just to get your attention.
But, i was provoked.
I don't know what to say if i upset you,
that was because...
I don't know,
i was trying to celebrate you...
And protect you at the same time.
Those two things got confused.
But...
I think i have a right to be confuse
when i'm up against a gorgeous creature like you.
Plus...
I'm a Princess.
And i get what i want.
The poeple have spoken.
I like the way Blair walks,
like he's crossing a bridge.
He's what this country needs.
Yes it is.
But i think we need to
think about beyond this country.
My work is here.
Well, all you need to do
is finish your PhD and then...
We could pretty much live anywhere.
People...
-People have hearts everywhere.
Yes, they do.
-Hearts that need repairing?
Exactly.
America...
Australia.
See my point?
If i could just get the boys away from here
for some of the time...
Somewhere warm.
There's been a communication
from my family.
Saying what?
Saying "you are 36, this is beyond the age when you're expected to marry".
Haven't you escaped all that?
The press coverage stirs things up.
The Phatan men is expected to marry a woman who will run an extended household.
A woman who will live with her husband's mother and family.
Someone from within the clan.
And what about you?
What are your feelings?
I want to save people's lives.
Hasnat, i asked about your feelings.
I love you.
But do you want us
to be together inspite all of our problems?
Do you want to make this work?
Yes.
I do.
Then it's time
i meet your family.
Are you serious?
Uh um...
I think i should go there, and they can get
a good look of how i really am.
Okay, then we'll go out there together.
Hasnat, we can't go together.
We'll be on the front page of every newspaper
in the world.
I'll go alone.
Doesn't matter how much you've charmed
the rest of his family...
But mother is the only one that counts.
She's the key.
Tough nut to crack.
She's an educated woman.
From a generation where such a thing is rare.
I would say two things.
Don't try to impress her.
And don't imply you're as close to her son
as you're obviously are.
Diana, i'd like to introduce you to Hasnat's father, Rashid.
Welcome, my dear.
-Hello.
Now then, Diana...
How good are you with names?
Diana, this is Hasnat's mother, Naheed.
Lovely to meet you.
Thank you.
Sir Cyril Radcliffe.
An Englishman by that name?
Is given 5 weeks to decide the fate of
90 million people.
And who advices it?
Mountbatten.
Your former husband's favorite uncle.
Muslims go one way,
Hindus the other.
6 billion people crossed
the new border.
Inevitably, there are crashes
and massacres.
One million people die.
I was 16.
And i can't forget that.
I'm sorry.
Yes, the English always say sorry
so beautifully.
It's a power cut.
Come on Diana...
Ready?
That was fun.
Diana, i want you to meet Hasnat's grandmother, Nanny Appa.
Hello.
She says that you are
a young lioness.
You must forgive me.
I can't help saying my piece
about the British.
Now everyone please,
try very hard to relax.
Say cheese.
Cheese!
God, it was magical. It was like a dream
of how life should really be, children and...
Grown up and grandparents living together,
one big family.
You know what your grandmother
called me?
A young lioness.
She's right,
as always.
Perhaps that's the future.
Being lions?
No.
Living abroad.
But that's impossible.
My work,
your boys.
Yes i know, my boys.
But...
Anything's possible,
isn't it?
We just have to mak it possible.
Yes.
Yes?
All of us,
if we're lucky, grow old.
But in the future, old people will make
a much larger percentage of the population.
The old, and that will include me,
will be weak.
But we won't be ware.
This will be the final battles of our lives.
And we must fight them, by establishing a habit of respect
for the older generation.
And by keeping our own skills fresh,
so that when we're in our 90s...
We can still be active contributing members
of our communities and families.
Thank you.
Bravo.
Bravo...
Professor.
-Please, call me Christian.
Christian.
Diana.
I want to tell you something
confidential.
I'm very good at keeping secret
except my own.
I'm in love with a heart surgeon.
He's still finishing
his PhD, but...
I believe he's a man of genius.
What's his training?
He was a favorite pupil
of Victor Chang.
He's now with Professor Yaku.
That's some reference.
I want to marry him.
But, he's a very private man.
We can't cope with England, so...
I'm thinking seriously
about living abroad.
You want me to find him a job.
Yes.
It was my son, William...
Who suggested i should clear a load of
clothes out of my closet.
And give the proceeds to the AIDS
Crisis Trust Charity.
I hope you've all remembered your check books
for the garage sale.
Sorry, auction.
And maybe some big laundry bags.
So you can carry your clothes home.
Now, i'm not gonna stay and watch here
and embarrased you.
But please, be generous.
Because there are so many people
who need you...
To be generous.
Thank you.
Hello?
This is Diana,
we've just landed.
So tell me,
how did it go?
What?
$5,5 million?
Yes!
A written request for my CV from the world's most famous heart surgeon.
To go with my job application.
There's been a slight mistake.
Did i apply for a job
in Boston?
Funny i don't remember it.
Things have got ahead
of themselves.
Funnier still, i actually seemed to
have got the job.
We talked about living abroad.
But we weren't really talking
about living abroad.
You're a wonderful doctor...
I was simply using
my connection.
I don't want anything from you.
I've worked long and hard
to get myself a life...
Don't go and reorganize it
without asking.
I was trying to find a way for us
to be together...
Someone has to do something.
If you don't understand
how i feel about my work...
How can we be together?
Yes?
Boss, i don't know if you want this.
But...
They're not so bad,
your security.
At least they've stopped making jokes
about my car.
Thank you, Paul.
The big one supports Queen's parkranger,
i never met anyone...
Who genuinly supported it.
Hasnat!
I can't seem to live
without you.
And yet the complications of trying to find some way of actually living with you...
Is just beyond me.
But that's nothing.
You were trying to find your way.
I'm so sorry.
Good afternoon, Queen's park rangers.
Sir...
Hasnat, asslamualaikum.
Walaikumsalam.
Hasnat, we're all very proud of your achievement.
You're a brilliant doctor.
Shining light.
What did the family think
of Diana?
The family loves Diana.
But it's a big question.
Should the most famous woman in the world
become part of our family?
And what's the answer?
Hasnat, you've been blessed
twice by God.
You have your calling as a doctor.
And a wonderful girlfriend.
But is it possible to have both?
I've known you since you were a child.
You're a private person.
Do you really tink you can work as a doctor
when you are so much in the public eye?
On the other hand,
if you were to marry Diana...
It'll be a great thing for Pakistan,
the whole Muslim world.
What did my mother think?
Your mother would never give her approval.
Diana is a divorced woman
and a Christian.
In a long journey of life, from time to time,
we come to a fork in the book.
Hasnat, it is time for you
to choose.
You're making it sound so simple,.
Life is simple.
I love her so much.
See you in 4 weeks!
Bye mom!
This must be the only park
we haven't visited in London.
We've done all the others.
Well, clockwise
or anti-clockwise?
I don't mind.
Long day.
It was hard in the hospital.
It gets dangerous.
Dodging the food trolleys trying to finish their rounds before the ice cream melts.
There's just one thing.
I know we could find a way.
So my trip to Lahore was a failure,
i didn't wint them over.
It's not to do with winning them over,
you can win anyone over.
But your family don't want me to be your wife.
That's no surprise.
I've never once been accepted by a family,
not my own, the one i married into...
When i think of the word,
i shudder.
My family haven't said that.
But your mother won't give us
her blessing.
That dream that you had,
sitting in a compound in a hall.
Surrounded by children
is impossible.
Why?
Because if i marry you...
I have to marry the whole word aswell.
We can't simply be
a man and a woman.
But you must have known that
from the start.
When you fall in love,
you just keep going despite the warning lights.
So now you've had the best of what's on offer,
you're just gonna clear off.
That's not true.
I've struggled to see how i could marry
the most famous woman in the world.
But i'll be giving up the very thing
that defines me.
I want to make it work.
I can't stop loving you.
They always say that
when they're saying goodbye.
I'm not saying goodbye.
Expect Charles,
i give him that.
Don't bring him into it.
Why not?
You belong with him now.
You're on the list, labelled
"the past".
Aren't you?
I don't want to see it
like that.
Then why call me in the middle of the night,
to this...
God forsaken park...
To get me my marching orders?
It's a bit dramatic.
Dramatic?
Dramatic? My whole life has been dramatic.
It's been full of the sound of people
shutting doors on me.
You say you love me,
you'll always love me...
There's about 5 billion people on this planet
who can say that.
But is there one...
Who can stay with me?
Is this fucking mike on?
I'm not saying it's over.
Yes you are,
you just can't say it.
I'm not saying it's the end.
Have the courage,
go on say it!
I'm not saying it's the end.
Yes, it is!
Okay, i'll say it.
It's over!
Don't follow me!
Diana!
Boss, this won't take long.
People aren't happy with the way things have been going over the last few weeks.
Members of your staffs feel
they've been exposed...
To situations that carry with them
element of danger.
We'd like you to consider strategy.
There's a feeling there's no clear direction...
You should...
Also you've received an offer from Dodi Fayed.
To join him again.
This time just you.
Say yes.
So where are we going?
Sardinia.
Cala the Vulpe.
Fox Creek.
Very fond of foxes.
Why so?
They're like me.
We've all escaped from the Windsors.
Hello...
Jason Fraser, what's happening?
Where are you?
Here.
Where is here?
You know where are the foxes.
Work out, handsome.
Pronto.
I've got something big.
Can you be somewhere this moment?
- Morning.
You sleep well?
What's the matter?
What is she up to?
There's no time to get the Americans involved.
Oslo is the last conference,
before they ought to retreat.
But America's signing will be huge.
There are too many sticking point.
There's basically only 3.
Exemption for the border
between north and south Korea.
A delay in the treaty implementation,
and the whole smart mines issue.
Smart mines?
They blow themselves up within 7 years
so the land are safe.
It meand redefining what a landmine is.
Stop the bus.
Your son?
Please kindly leave the message
after the beep.
Hasnat it's me.
Hi it's me.
I really want you to call me.
I mean really really.
Call me.
Hello...
Dodi.
The falling dream I still get it.
But it's different these days.
How is the dream different?
Well, I don't know.
I suppose...
I suppose it's...
Something I enjoy now.
I don't feel the need to be caught anymore.
So maybe it's not falling.
Maybe it's more like flying.
When you first came to me,
you told me your quest was a spiritual one.
Well, we danced with it
a few years.
Now the road is clear.
Your life is ahead of you.
With your talent and power...
You can do anything.
Does it feel right for you to be going on this trip?
Now that you feel differently.
I gotta have a bit of fun,
don't i?
And the boys are away so...
You're not going cause you feel lonely.
Oonagh...
Now that I've been loved...
I don't feel lonely anymore.
Yeah.
Hello, Hunter.
Where are you?
Looking right at you.
Did you get some more shots?
Oh yeah, plenty.
Good.
Well that's enough now.
I'll see you back in London.
Hi it's me.
I really want you to call me.
I mean really really.
Hi it's me.
I really want you to call me.
I mean really really...
Be ready...
Hello, Paul?
Yes, is he around?
Are you sure?
This is Diana, I can't take your call right now please leave a message.
Yes.
We don't know if Lady D was dead or not...
And we just know she's there...
In the old tunnel Place de l'Alma in Paris.
From the poet Rumi...
Somewhere beyond right and wrong
there is a garden...
I will meet you there.
Somewhere beyond right and wrong
there is a garden...
I will meet you there.
-rRr-