That's me, Jaak.
I am 8 years old in this photo
I live in Tallinn, in a newly-built
residential area called Oismae...
that is always expanding
My life is wonderful,
because I can watch Finnish TV
My father taught me
how to take photographs
Now I take photos of everything
that matters to me
The first photos I take are of...
commercials and films
shown on Finnish TV
Here, our relatives from
Southern Estonia are visiting us
They can't see Finnish TV there
It's Friday evening.
We're watching "Dallas", as always
But our relatives see "Dallas"
for the very first time
And they see a completely different "Dallas"
It is a captivating, spiritual seance...
and my mother is the medium
She interprets everything about
the strange characters...
their love affairs and relationships
But for the first time in their lives,
our relatives see...
people drinking whisky on the
rocks and working in skyscrapers
Men with perfect teeth and
beautiful, yet unhappy, women
And they are all millionaires
Then I promised Urve, my niece,
to write her every week...
about what is happening in "Dallas",
so she wouldn't lose her connection...
to that "real world"
she met at our home in Tallinn
In the beginning, there was
Miss Ellie and old Jock...
Bobby came too...
The police was there...
Everyone suspected Sue Ellen...
A film by Jaak Kilmi and Kiur Aarma
DISCO AND ATOMIC WAR
POEM: "The holidays aren't for slumbering,
get up and spread the joy"
"I wake up early and wash up,
I wash my little brother too"
"We run to the window,
a parade is passing"
"Oh, why are there so few
of these great holidays?"
We grew up during the Cold War
Estonia was occupied
and a part of the Soviet Union
Long live May 1st!
The International Day of Solidarity!
Long live the Soviet Union!
There was an iron curtain
between us and the free world
But radio waves seeped through it
And they sounded as if they weren't
coming from across the ocean...
but from the bottom of it
1,400 jamming stations in the USSR
transmitted static and whistling...
in between the wavelengths
of Western stations
Back then, radio was Estonia's
only connection to the free world
In the 1950s, the world
enters an era of television
In Tallinn, Soviet Estonian TV
(ETV) begins its broadcasts
Good evening, comrades.
Estonian Television begins its broadcasting
From us, in Tallinn, TV waves are
also spreading 80 km northward...
where Helsinki, the capital
of Finland, happens to be
But the Finns don't have their own
national TV channel yet
The same year, Soviet Estonian TV launches
its Finnish-language programming...
where you can see happy
Soviet workers talking
...then, the workers
are happy about it
The workers are happy
about automating the process
Today, more and more production
is expected from everyone...
...so automating the process
is natural
It's clear that this
propaganda channel was...
directed at Finland to spread
their red ideology here
We're amidst the Cold War and
Finland is no-man's-land
An outwardly Western country where...
nothing happens without
permission from Moscow
There are Soviet military bases
in Finland
The are rumours that the Russians
are setting up TV transmitters...
in their bases to drown Finland
in Communist propaganda
The Western secret services
are afraid of...
completely losing Finland
to the Russians
The fight took place mostly
in countries like Finland
The fight for souls
American diplomats in Finland realise...
that it is time to fight back
The secret telegrams from
the U.S. embassy to Washington...
demand an immediate response...
for launching Finnish TV
with Western support
And so it goes. Two years
after Soviet Estonia...
the Finns launch their own TV channel
At first, it is predictably
mild and cautious...
Welcome to our Christmas programme...
Then occurred the Prague Spring...
Czechoslovakia's uprising
against the Communist regime
Soviet Estonian media doesn't
cover the uprising...
as if nothing had happened
Soviet TV shows the
following images:
Here, the Czech people
welcome their Soviet guests
Here, you can see a lady chanting:
"Friendship! Friendship!"
80 km north of us, the Finns
see the following report:
Czechoslovakia has been
occupied for five days now
Large foreign troops are on the
move, especially in Slovakia
New units are brought in
This morning, the official
government of Czechoslovakia...
denied the Soviet news agency
TASS announcement...
which claimed there are armed
cars moving through Prague
Quite the opposite, the Soviet occupiers
are shooting ordinary people for no reason
The next day, an anti-Soviet demonstration
rages in Helsinki, the first since the war
It was very upsetting.
And a big disappointment...
for those who believed in the possibility
of a humane socialism
Here, the policemen
in white gloves...
remove some of the loudest
students from the Soviet embassy
But the Russians are still very upset
At the same time,
the Finnish TV director's car...
enters the embassy
through the back gate
The TV station is held responsible.
The director is ordered to explain...
why Finnish TV is spreading
lies and hysteria...
and ruining their friendly relationship
with the Soviet Union
It upset them very much.
But they couldn't do anything
The show had already aired.
And we didn't regret it either
In Tallinn, we watch the Finnish coverage
of Prague with interest and concern
By then, there are TV sets in most
Soviet Estonian homes
Then a new transmitter starts
construction near Helsinki
However, the specialists
notice at once...
that there's something very
strange going on
The Espoo transmitter wasn't directed
only at the Finnish mainland...
it had a circular diagram
At least half of the transmitter's
coverage was directed southward...
towards the Gulf of Finland
Are the practical-minded Finns
heating the Gulf just for fun?
Edward Lucas has done extensive
research on the Cold War
Western countries probably knew
that Finnish TV broadcasts...
reached Tallinn and
Northern Estonia as well
Naturally, the Soviet media thinks
Americans are behind this
They report that the mast was built
by an American company
Even more, they have built it
high enough...
for ideological waves
to reach Estonia
A newspaper rages:
"The Capitalist government of
Finland and the U.S. propagandists..."
"mean to dehumanise the Soviet people,
especially the youth..."
"with violence, cruelty
and sexual looseness"
They wrote that Finland wanted to
dehumanise the Estonian youth
That we were transmitting shows
to Estonia on purpose
It was complete nonsense!
Naturally, a forest of antennas
emerges on the rooftops of Tallinn...
its branches stretching
towards Finland
But you can't watch Finnish TV
with a Soviet TV set
The technical standard is different
You could see the black and white
images on Finnish TV...
but there was no sound
This is me, Joosep. And the weight
of our family's big secret...
is reflected in my eyes
When I was 9, our entire family
was involved in illegal business
Me, my father and mother
I knew that you could end up
in prison for things like that
So we had a strict procedure
concerning the telephone
It had to ring eight times
Then the caller hung up
and redialled immediately
Only then could we pick up
the phone
That was how my father's
clients called him
My father was an electronics engineer
at Tallinn Polytechnic
But he earned much more for
building Finnish TV converters
He built them at home, in his room
with heavy brown curtains drawn
I think all of father's colleagues
were building these blocks
The ideological virus spreading fast
from the West worries Moscow
The evil hand of the CIA
is seen behind every move
"TUPLA chocolate bar -
enough for two"
Soviet propaganda
fires back fiercely
In the State House of Political Education...
a room for the methods of
counterpropaganda is established
There, every propagandist can
quickly get a clear and...
in-depth overview of the methods
of counterpropaganda
In the Soviet films of our childhood...
the American secret services cruelly
hunt innocent Soviet people
The KGB gets a new leader,
Yuri Andropov, who is...
the man behind the bloody
suppression of the Prague Spring
He is a tough leader...
in control of the biggest
secret service in the world...
with thousands of agents
in hundreds of countries
Somewhere here,
in the KGB headquarters...
there is a special task force
for fighting the Western influence
They are responsible for what
goes on in our heads
Moscow sends a high KGB officer to head
a special committee inspecting Estonia
Secretly, a group of Estonian sociologists
are assigned to the committee
They are led by Hagi Shein, who,
as fate would have it...
later becomes the head of Estonian TV
It was a secret study designed to...
observe the Estonian viewers'
attitude towards Finnish TV
Especially young people's attitude
Finnish TV had become the most
watched channel in Estonia
The results were definitely worrisome
for the ideologists in Moscow
It bothered them,
it called for counteraction
Moscow sends orders to drown out
the Finnish TV signal
More and more TV masts
are built in Estonia...
bombing the waves with
Soviet programming
Our home coast, the southern
coast of the Gulf of Finland...
one of the most beautiful
places in the world...
has become the front line
of the Cold War!
But the American response
is clever
They are ready to bring out their new,
invisible weapon
Behind it, there was a skilled,
even genius, tactical plan...
for breaking up the Communist Bloc
Georgi Potcheptsov is a renowned
expert on ideological warfare
He has thoroughly researched
the methods of the Americans
Americans did a lot of work
with deflectors and tourists
You're a Soviet spy?
- No!
They were trying to understand
the nature of the Soviet person
Their minds were studied and
analysed to find a way inside
And it was found!
I have met people who have met
the head of CIA
Their plans were very precise...
regarding the means to use
in conquering the viewer
The chosen battlefield was what is now
known as "soft power"'
It was television, popular culture
There's the hard, forceful
power, like a tank...
and there's soft, entertaining
power, like a film
Finnish TV shows "Ninotchka"...
a feature film starring
the marvellous Greta Garbo
It is a story about
a female Soviet commissary...
who falls in love with
an American...
and betrays
the Communist ideals
For Moscow, showing that film
is a direct anti-Soviet act
So much so that the heads
of Finnish TV...
are called to Moscow
for a very serious talk
The Soviet Estonian party leaders
have their own suggestion...
a device should be developed...
to create captions for
Finnish broadcasts...
to overthrow the false
information! For example:
Disinformation! Champagne has been
produced in the USSR since 1928
That plan is found to be "at present,
impossible to carry out"
Or, to put it more simply,
nonsense
But the threat of the Russians
jamming the TV waves remains
By that time, Finnish TV has become
one of the main cracks...
for soft power to seep into
the Soviet Union unhindered
In Estonia, the underground
production of Finnish TV guides...
is a growing business
- At 7:40...
My grandfather had a friend
from wartime, Endel...
who worked in the district committee
(Endel) Did you get that?
My grandfather was
a school headmaster...
and he had a typing machine
in his office
So Endel gave the TV guide
to my grandfather...
and my mother got
a typed copy from him
Mother worked in a hospital
In the evenings, I helped her to
copy the Finnish TV guides
My mother sold them at work
for one rouble a piece...
I got 10 kopecks for each copy
Because of these TV guides,
I was a made man at school
At one point, we pulled a prank
with a couple of friends
I typed into the TV guides...
"Sex film at 2 AM"
I don't know if it's true...
but there were rumours of
many lit windows that night
The fight for the souls of our
generation begins in 1975
Although many of us
aren't born yet
The western countries make
a clever deal with the Russians
Today, the Soviet delegation
arrives in the Finnish capital...
to participate in the final stage...
of the Conference on Security
and Cooperation in Europe
The delegation is led by
comrade Leonid Brezhnev...
the Secretary General
of the Communist Party of USSR
The other members
of the delegation are...
Here, Brezhnev is signing
the Helsinki Agreement
The areas of influence of the sides
of the Cold War are laid out
The Western countries promise...
not to meddle with the Soviet
sphere of influence
In return, the USSR promises
not to jam the TV waves
The hook has been swallowed!
The Soviet Union probably thought
that the borders were now sealed
But, instead, they started to crack -
with more freedom of speech...
and other citizens' rights
Disco has become very popular
among the young people
But adults find this
dance move difficult
And then, one night, they showed
these moves on Finnish TV
One, two, three, four.
Let's lift our knees
And now, let's... disco!
Now, disco was everywhere,
including our school
These songs were stuck
in our heads...
and they were about love and
relationships
The news about the western dance
disease spreading in Estonia...
quickly reached Moscow
But this time,
nothing was done about it
Honour to our Leninist Party!
Andropov's cunning plan is launched
It is obvious that Brezhnev
is fading fast
Long live peace!
Behind Brezhnev's back, there's
a fierce struggle for power
Trouble on the ideological front...
is a trump card in the hands
of Andropov's KGB men
The horrified leader of Soviet Estonia
is scared for his own skin
He dashes to Moscow to assure...
that he will take control
of the situation himself
The men in power have a very
clear plan
The disco epidemic must be tamed
The racoon must become a poodle!
We have many neologisms
from the word "disco"
They've already become rooted...
just like a tree planted by a DJ
In every corner of the country...
activists from the Soviet
youth group Komsomol...
are told to master
the enemy's moves
A sexy form, but filled with
Soviet content
So, what are the problems
with disco dancing?
First of all, we are
reinventing the wheel here
Disco is danced all over the world,
but we didn't hear of it...
nor see what the others were doing
Alas, these moves are too late!
The rhythm of the times
is completely different
The Soviet Union attacks Afghanistan
Their relationship with the West
becomes very strained
In order to reinforce the home front...
the puppet rulers of the small
Soviet Republics are replaced
Moscow appoints a new
Party Secretary for Estonia
His name is Karl Vaino.
An old railroad man
He has to direct the local life
back onto the iron rails
And so, here's our generation
marching in front of the cameras
With paper flowers
and Estonian folk costumes
We are waving to Karl Vaino
and he is waving back
Instead of disco, the TV shows
a completely different dance
But somewhere far away,
there is a war raging
Karl Vaino makes his first visit
to Finland
An enormous bronze Lenin
is erected there
Everyone has a sour smile
on their face
Soviet Union is marking
its area of influence
But above that area,
through houses and cities...
over land and sea, the TV waves
float - uncaught!
At the beginning...
not all the villagers understood
what I was talking about
But in about one month...
they started asking questions
in the shop queue, like:
"So, what's new in 'Dallas'?"
When it snowed during winter...
I ran from house to house
with Jaak's letters...
and everywhere, my visit was
long awaited
Everyone wanted to know
what had happened in "Dallas"
And so I told them
Those, who were worthy
J.R. wants to prove to the judges that
Sue Ellen is an alcoholic
The sun is shining
and people are happy
A football game takes place,
followed by a rock concert
And then,
a proper youth riot...
against life in the ridiculous
Soviet Union...
something that Karl Vaino
has come to symbolise
The militia beats the rioters apart
The culprits are looked for
and found
Naturally, it is all the
punk rockers' fault
But how do the young people
in Soviet Estonia know...
how to be a punk rocker?
They've seen it on Finnish TV!
And whose fault is it that young
people watch Finnish...
rather than Soviet Estonian TV?
Naturally, the management
of Estonian Television
Here they are
They are ordered to come up
with measures against Finnish TV
The Programme Director,
Voldemar Lindstrom...
is called to Party headquarters...
and for starters, he gets
a harsh talking-to
Finnish TV was naturally
a headache for Party leaders
Estonian media was blamed for not fighting
against it with necessary means...
and for not spreading
different information
Now, "the necessary means"'
have to be found
The Party officials' plan
is this:
Estonian TV is watched
both here and in Finland...
so our channel should make
everyone believe...
how wonderful the life
in Soviet Estonia really is
It should take centre stage
in its full glory
The school uniform consists
of a skirt and a jacket...
And indeed, Estonian shows do
become popular in Finland...
but in an unexpected way
It becomes source material for
several Finnish humour shows
(mocking jabber imitating a Soviet
official speaking Estonian)
Karl Vaino decides that such
mockery must end
A full-scale campaign against
Finnish TV begins
Vaino fires the first shots
of this war in Moscow...
at the Congress of the
Communist Party:
Due to its geographical situation...
Estonia is in the front line
of the ideological battle
In a place, where the fire of
anti-Soviet propaganda is fierce
Lately, the acts of the
ideological enemy...
have turned especially cruel and
mean!
It's psychological warfare!
Spring. The last episode of the
season. J.R. is alone in his office
Someone enters
Two shots!
J.R. falls down
End credits.
Who shot J.R.?
I posted a letter to Urve...
and promised to continue writing
in the autumn
Then I went to Young Pioneer camp,
like every summer
I got Jaak's last letter.
He wrote that J.R. has been shot
He grabbed his heart and fell.
There was blood...
But I couldn't tell the villagers
that...
nothing's going to happen
before the autumn
Everyone was so eager to
hear about it
And so I made up my own version
of what happened
Specialists confirm that...
the primary targets were the minds
of Soviet Estonian children
There are very interesting
CIA documents...
about the work to be done
with the youth
One very important thing
they considered was that...
that in 1985, a new generation
will enter the stage
Here, our generation runs to the stage
with flowers for Karl Vaino
We have no idea that...
a cunning plan is being hatched
at Party headquarters
The secret order signed by Vaino
mentions...
"the measures for neutralising the
influence of bourgeois television..."
"on the inhabitants of the Republic"
In this document, they shoot at
Finnish TV without aiming
The city and district committees
of the Communist Party...
as well as the other
central offices...
should make it their main task
to battle the...
politically hostile influence of
bourgeois TV
Strict orders and prohibitions
pour onto us from Vaino's offices...
like ice cold rain
When I was in the third grade...
my grandfather was taken to
the hospital with a floating kidney
My business went downhill
My grandfather was treated
at Karl Marx hospital, where...
the Finnish converters
were removed from TV sets
The same was probably done
in all state facilities
Grandfather said that's why
his kidney stopped floating...
it got so boring at the hospital
he just had to get back home
The countermeasures became
quite strange
For example, the Party's
attempts to remove...
antennas directed at Finland
from Tallinn's rooftops
This seemingly ordinary man,
Nikolai...
is one of the first victims
of the evil campaign
One fine morning, there are
some comrades with a saw...
on the roof of his home
They left one antenna standing
and took away the rest
They had been ordered to
"just take them all down"
We didn't have much to watch here
The Estonian films or
war movies from Russian TV
How long can you watch those?
I wanted to see what was
happening abroad
Finnish TV brought the
rest of the world to us
Important men, somewhere high up,
had no idea that...
they have acquired a
rather dangerous enemy
Nikolai happens to be
a passionate inventor
Soon, a counter-plan is born
in a kitchen
But we will get there...
Long meetings are held
and reports written...
about the battle
against Finnish TV
Especially in the regions where
Finnish TV can't be seen
Where it can be seen,
the meetings are shorter...
in order to make it to home
to watch Finnish TV
Brezhnev's Soviet Union has already
split into parallel realities
The devastating news about
the great loss to our country...
and to the Communist Party
hit the collective farmers very hard
For us, agricultural workers,
it was a particularly painful loss
Let us not forget that
it was Leonid Brezhnev...
under whose leadership
and direction...
the objectives for the agricultural
industry were devised...
It is 12:45 and...
...the coffin was lowered
into the grave
After the demise of Brezhnev...
the way to power is
finally open for Andropov
Dear comrades! Let me thank you
from the bottom of my heart...
The Soviet Union rediscovers
an old truth...
things aren't advancing because
people are stupid and lazy
An era of fervent campaigning begins
As a result of one of these
campaigns...
a People's Militia is compiled
of ordinary people
They patrol the streets at night
for aimless wanderers, drunks...
or thieves of public property
Dear members of the People's Militia
The patrol's mission for
today is this: we've planned...
Nikolai and thousands of
others have started...
building TV antennas
from junkyard scraps
I built my first antenna
for my own TV
Just find an iron pipe, I already
had a welding machine
I did have to steal
some pieces of pipe
That's how it all started
First, you needed a copper pipe
It was an interesting time,
an era of 'do it yourself'
First, I made one for myself.
Then, one for a friend
Then for a friend of a friend,
and so it went on
There were plenty of orders
After a while, I was mass producing
antennas
This is me, Toomas. Here's
me at home and here, at school
Those are the two places,
where I spend most of my time
After school, the children
whose parents worked late...
were taken to the grass field
by the school...
and told to form football teams
Usually, I was a reserve player
My mother was part of
the People's Militia
They were entitled to buy things
from the factory cafeteria...
that were not available in stores:
canned peas, frankfurters
and tangerines
In the evenings,
mother patrolled on the streets...
I was allowed to watch TV
until quarter to ten...
then I had to wash my teeth
and go to sleep
Sometimes, I watched a bit longer
I couldn't fall sleep anyway
before my mother came back
Across the gulf, in Helsinki...
electronics shops are being
bought out of one item:
microcircuits
What are people using
them for?
The time of colour television
has come...
and some enterprising Finns have
discovered a prosperous business
The chips, hidden in clothes or body cavities,
are smuggled to Estonia
Here, they are sold to scalpers
for a substantial profit
And they resell them to engineers
who use them for colour decoders
The chip was small, you could
fit 50 in one cigarette box...
and the currency rate between
Finnish marks and roubles...
was better with microchips
than with jeans
The Soviet customs officials
have to toughen up...
and start catching
the chip smugglers
"What are our Finnish guests up to?"
asks this propaganda film
Tallinn is the fourth most popular
destination in the USSR...
for tourists from capitalist
countries
Not all of them come here...
for their sincere interest
towards our way of life
A propagandist should never
forget this...
as he comes into contact with
foreigners every day
There is vileness, amorality and
an empty soul behind...
their superficial kindness.
That's the face of capitalism
Calling all law enforcement
officers!
Underground microchip sales
are prospering
An intensive campaign begins
to catch the speculators
- Hello
One autumn evening in the early 1980's,
my father took me for a ride
He didn't say a word. We drove
somewhere in Mustamae district
I remember him constantly
glancing in the mirror
He parked the car away
from the entrance
I was to go in, take the elevator
to the 4th floor and...
ring the bell at
door number 45
That was how my father got
the chips to build new blocks
The man in a bathrobe
was a dealer
It was a strictly forbidden job
But that evening was
very important for me
Now, I was part of the same
secret society as my father
I wasn't allowed to talk about it
at school. And I didn't!
Hands on the table! Mouths shut!
Backs straight!
And what are you doing?
I took the no 7 trolley and
the no 26 bus home from school
But the other commuters
didn't know my true identity
In the autumn of 1984, Finnish TV
started showing "Knight Rider"
Just a few months later, it had
become an integral part of my life
It was about a car
With the push of a button, it
could jump over other cars
Michael Knight taught me to use
my watch to talk to cars
And I did talk...
to all 14 foreign cars I knew of
in Tallinn in those days
Dear members of the People's Militia
Three groups are heading
to residential areas
Pay attention to cars and underage
persons gathering around them
There was a foreign car
in our yard too
A sailor had bought a Renault
It was the only car
that mattered
But one day, I saw a boy
from building no 37...
using his watch to talk
to MY car
I think I was quite upset
But soon enough,
everyone was doing it
All you needed was a digital watch
On February 9th, 1984, the Secretary
General of the Communist Party...
Yuri Vladimirovich Andropov,
passed away
The fervent campaigns end
just as suddenly as they started
Life goes back to normal
But the Americans are preparing
the final blow
First, as if by coincidence,
Finnish TV shows "Star Wars"
Of course, we, Estonian children,
are completely blown away
Flying saucers appear in
our asphalt drawings
This rare shot of a school play
shows...
the Soviet Estonian version of
Jedi Knights
There are hundreds of satellites
beeping above us in space
The superpowers have
their own star wars
Americans have challenged
the Russians
They launch satellites to destroy
the Soviet nuclear missiles
In return, the Russians want
to build missiles...
that penetrate the American
protective shield
But these missiles
are very expensive
The project had no connection
to reality. It was a daydream
The Soviet Union took the bait and
never caught up with America
I saw on TV that Michael Knight
visited Finland
It was the closest meeting we ever had
Estonians knew that soon,
there would be an atomic war
In the school hall, they showed
us films about atomic bombs...
and carried out bomb threat drills
Should an atomic bomb
fall on Tallinn...
we are to put on gas masks and
go to the school cloakroom
It doubled as our bomb shelter
Soon enough, a few of us
discover that...
if you push the filter of a
gas mask to your mouth...
you can make the sound of
Michael Knight's car, KITT
From then on, atomic war
seemed pretty cool to us
At the same time, the Soviet economy's
only focus is the military production
It is wise to hit the shops early
if you expect to get any goods
There's never enough of anything
Only canned squid and baranki
(dry bagels) are left
That's when we meet Vaiski -
the face of Finnish food ads
Meat counter ready for inspection
- Well, this is not an inspection
We're just looking at it
through the client's eyes
Oh, what a beautiful veal,
pork and lamb!
Vaiski and the army of
cutlets and steaks...
arrive on the front lines of the
Cold War during the hottest battle
For Estonians standing
in long queues...
Vaiski becomes nothing less
than a fairy tale hero
The message of the ad is an
effective propaganda weapon
"What good things will Vaiski
think up next?"
"A delicious roast. From a
particularly good fillet..."
The Estonian officials announce that...
the delicacies in the ads
are just plastic fakes and...
the Finns couldn't
afford them anyway
"The delightful sauce will
make your mouth water..."
And Mr Vaiski must be on the payroll
of the American secret service!
General Dreyfus of American
military intelligence has said:
"In the ideological battle
with Communists..."
"we do not need the truth,
we need subversion."
In addition to our good influence,
the influence of the Party...
there is another,
hostile influence...
continuously affecting
the Soviet people
We all know that they are
trying very hard to do this
The Finns were harshly criticised
for their "Americanness"
And we didn't know it was because
the Soviets felt genuinely threatened
LUNCH BREAK
The village talked of nothing
but "Dallas"
Even the band of the
collective farm sang about "Dallas"
But in the autumn,
the people of our village...
sent a joint letter to
Estonian Television and...
Party Central Committee,
stating that they have...
a collective farm with
record-breaking results...
a winner of the
Socialist Competition...
and wouldn't it be possible
to show "Dallas"...
on an Estonian
or Leningrad channel
It all led to very big trouble
A commission from the District
Committee came to investigate
People were questioned,
a meeting held, fingers pointed...
and it was explained to the people...
that this was not proper
entertainment for Soviet people
The head of the village board and...
the Pioneer leader
of the school were replaced
So we heard nothing more
about Dallas
I still waited for Jaak's letters,
but he had taken up football...
and didn't have time
to write anymore
I still have some of his old letters
An anonymous engineer writes
a letter to a newspaper
He recommends building
a gigantic metallic net...
in the gulf between
Estonia and Finland...
that would catch
the Finnish TV waves
Vaino likes the idea very much
The management of Estonian TV is
called to Party headquarters
As always, the meeting starts
with a harsh talking-to
They were very stern
and direct
We thought that they will shoot us
on the spot
Vaino was clear that
a system has to be built...
to prevent hostile channels
from spreading in Estonia
The TV management tries
to convince Vaino that...
such a net would be complicated,
expensive and still useless
Engineers suggested building the
net on an island in the Gulf...
to make it hundreds of meters tall,
so it could block the Finnish TV signal
An overall anxiety spreads
Among others,
Nikolai prepares for resistance
It is time to build a simple
but efficient invention:
A mercury antenna!
You had to cut off the tip
of a thermometer...
insert a hairline thread into the
tube of mercury
You push it into the mercury
and pull back a bit
Then you connect the thread
to your TV set
It receives the signal much better
than an ordinary antenna
But it jams the reception of other
receivers in a 3-5 km radius
Next to us, there was a missile
base with two nuclear warheads
It was inspected and
guarded very well
As soon as the antenna
starts to jam the waves...
they will try to locate
the source. And they'll find it
Then you had to quickly
unplug the antenna
The thermometer fever
spreads fast
The pharmacies of Tallinn are
emptied of their thermometer stocks
65 kopecks a piece
The authorities claim it is
due to a flu outburst...
but in fact, it was
a different kind of epidemic
Even more, the virus from Estonia...
spreads quickly
all over the Soviet Union
In many cities, videotapes with
Finnish subtitles are discovered
The narrator with the nasal voice
becomes famous
He sits in a basement
somewhere in Leningrad...
and dubs these films
into Russian
Hollywood movies reach
Estonia via Finnish TV
and from Estonia they spread
all over the Soviet Union...
from Lithuania to Turkmenistan
It would have been easy
to arrest The Nasal Man
But he remained free, so we know
that wasn't the authorities' plan
True enough, the real plan was
far bigger
Later studies claim that
for decades...
Soviet Estonia had been a
secret laboratory of the KGB
They researched what will
happen to a Soviet citizen...
when flooded with
hostile propaganda
In some areas, detailed
experiments were carried out
How else could they research
the impact of this sort of thing?
This explains the regular
TV audience surveys...
that were forbidden elsewhere
in the Soviet Union
These surveys can be compared to
obtaining intelligence data from...
a social environment in order
to create new weapons
Karl Vaino, who knew nothing
about the secret laboratory...
has been led to complain, to weep...
and conduct powerless campaigns
against Finnish TV
Soviet authorities did possess the
technology to block Finnish TV signals
Radio-technologically, the Soviet Union
was a very powerful country
The jamming transmitters would have
been produced in military plants...
and installed without any involvement
from Estonian technicians
We, Estonian children, have been
the KGB's lab rats for years
They've been preparing us
with the help of Finnish TV
We are meant to be the new
generation of Soviet spies...
raised amidst the influence of
western popular culture
But the deadly virus has
broken out of the lab
By the mid-1980s,
the KGB realises that...
the "soft power" of pop culture
is overpowering the regime
Furthermore, the empire is
falling apart at the seams
The price of oil dropped below
prime cost. Soviet Union earns less
The Space Race ate resources.
The result was an economic collapse
The memory of Konstantin
Chemenko will last forever
On the verge of collapsing,
the USSR starts...
to warm relations
with the Americans
The new leader of the
bankrupt country, Gorbachev...
must save the little
that's left to save
Meanwhile, the ever deluded
Karl Vaino relies on an old trick:
when the end is near,
act like everything is fine
We, the veterans of the
army and the Party...
are convinced that you,
our young friends...
will carry on the flag of peace,
good will and Communism
Instead of folk costumes,
the lab rats are now...
wearing parachute satchels
and we're marching
But there is an air of spring
and decay around us
That spring I decided...
I will not wear blue socks
and brown sandals
I will not!
The teacher sent me home
because of my sneakers
But I don't care
It's May. School's almost
out and summer will begin
But not just any summer,
THE summer
In 52 days, Finnish TV
will show "Emmanuelle"
It is a famous erotic movie
Fresh out of the hospital...
my grandfather sent
a cake box to his friends
Guess what was inside?
Yes, a Finnish TV block
made by my father
Meanwhile, Gorbachev is
on a world tour, like a pop star
His perestroika movement
has to demolish...
the harsh image of the Soviet Union
In Finland, Misha is welcomed
like an old friend
The nightmare is fading
A lot of time has passed since the last
Soviet leader visited Finland
There's a feeling of change
in the air
Then, Gorbachev
flies to Tallinn
The meeting begins with
a harsh talking-to
My friend Karl Vaino tells me that
everything is fine in Estonia
But I know better. The leaders
have lost touch with the people
They are cooped up in their offices
and that leads to mistakes
They want to control everything
Even the customary kisses
now seem cold
Maybe this is when Gorbachev
whispers to Vaino...
that the expensive net in
the Gulf is a definite no-go
The visit is carried out
with bitter smiles
This is me, Jaak. It's summer and I'm
at Young Pioneer camp again
In the mornings, they woke
us with a blaring fanfare
You had to dress very quickly
Nobody knew why we
had to hurry...
because afterwards we
just lazed around
But even in my sleepy haze,
I knew: it's June 24
The day has arrived!
That evening, Finnish TV
will show "Emmanuelle"
Our relatives in
Southern Estonia...
start driving to Tallinn
early in the morning
By lunchtime, only children and
old ladies were left in the South
The rest headed to Tallinn
in their cars
Because in Tallinn you see
Finnish TV
By 4:15 PM, there are
112 cars parked...
on the football ground
next to our school
The sum of the licence plate
numbers is even for 63 cars...
and odd for 49 cars. There are
no foreign cars, only Russian
The Polish Fiat doesn't count
Mother says that there must be...
a big party or song festival
somewhere
Today, we are making
nest boxes for starlings
The sides have to be sawed
into neat pieces...
and a hole drilled into
the front board
We are supervised by
our teacher
But when we look at each
other, we start giggling...
Dear members of the People's Militia
The patrol's mission for
today is this...
In the evening,
the streets are empty
Just a few pigeons... and
my mom patrolling somewhere
KVASS (bread drink)
"But everyone is watching it," I say.
"Not everyone," says my mom
"For instance, you will not
watch it"
I got even by not brushing
my teeth that night
At 10 o'clock, everyone goes to
brush their teeth
Half past 10,
it's bed call
Usually, we tell jokes
and giggle. But not today
On the other side of the wall,
in the teacher's lounge...
a TV is on.
Everyone is waiting
Suddenly, I realised
how this world works
There are those who only get
a few coins for a TV guide...
and then those who get the
crisp banknotes
Those who fetch the cake box
from the dealer...
and then those who sell its
content for 400 roubles
And I didn't want to be
the loser any more
The TV signal was so weak that...
I decided to try out the
mercury antenna
It worked for me, but messed
up the neighbours' TV
As soon as I plugged it in,
they lost reception
I could watch for 30 min before a
jeep from the missile base arrived
So I unplugged the antenna
When the jeep left, I
plugged the antenna back in
Of course I kept watching
They said that if we
jam their radars...
they may accidentally
launch something...
and when that baby is out,
who knows what will happen
The atomic war doesn't
break out just then
Luckily enough, the erotic movie
ends before that
For some reason, I woke up
at 12:42 PM
It was light outside
I thought that war had broken out
and my mom's on the frontlines
But then I saw it - hundreds
of cigarettes glowing...
like fireflies on every balcony
of the opposing houses
A kind of bomb had been dropped
on Estonia and it ended the Cold War
The bliss of freedom soon
spreads all over the country
The Soviet Union surrenders
quickly and entirely
Only the men in fur hats
wave from the sinking ship
But not all of them go
down with the sinking ship
Some of them have
their life boats ready
There are theories about the
KGB destroying the system...
just to be able to rebuild it again
Today's actions were actually
planned way back then
Loyal Vaino is not one of
the chosen few
He gives up his post
in the summer of 1988
He immediately heads to Moscow
where he's still happily retired
He has never visited Estonia
during these 20 years and...
has given only one interview,
to a German TV journalist
"When did you realise that Estonia
would become independent...
and this process couldn't
be overturned?"
I believe that it's connected to
Finnish TV
People saw that life was
more free elsewhere...
that others had more
opportunities...
their standard of life
was higher than in Estonia
They asked, "How can that be?"
"How can they have all that
in a rotting capitalism?"
That got people thinking
Despite being forbidden, there
were antennas on every balcony
Banning them made no difference
Long live the workers of
the Soviet Union! Hurray!
And so we marched
to a song festival...
holding paper flowers and
wearing folk costumes
But we weren't waving to Karl
Vaino and he wasn't waving back
We were waving to ourselves,
in a completely different era
Urve, Joosep, Jaak and Toomas are
now leading completely ordinary lives
9 months after Finnish TV showed
"Emmanuelle", the birth rate in Estonia
soared to a high
There have been 37 sequels
to "Emmanuelle"
Nikolai works on a ship travelling
between Estonia and Finland
He has yet to patent his
mercury antenna
J.R. was shot by his mistress,
but he survived
The final episode of "Dallas"
aired in 1991 - the same year
the Soviet Union disappeared
The Cold War resumed after
a short break