King's Dream
I am going to obey the will of the heavens to save the people of the Three Kingdoms.
I will take Pyeongyang and receive king Bojang's surrender.
I will end the tyranny of the treacherous subjects of Goguryeo and
[June, 668]
save the people of Goguryeo.
Loyal servants of Silla!
I will unite your loyalty to conquer Goguryeo.
I will achieve the cause of unification which I inherited from the former king.
I, Kim Yusin, and the officials will support your great cause.
I am appointing you as the supreme commander.
Lead our soldiers in conquering Goguryeo.
I swear to conquer Goguryeo and unify the Three Kingdoms.
We swear loyalty to the cause.
In lunar June, 668, king Munmu appointed Kim Yusin as the commander and
ordered an attack on Goguryeo with 37 court officials as commanders.
Your Majesty...
If Goguryeo falls,
the Three Kingdoms will become colonies of Tang.
You must fight the Silla-Tang army and protect the Three Kingdoms.
I will remember what you said.
Namsaeng...
You three brothers must unite and protect His Majesty and the court.
Unite and defeat the Silla-Tang army.
Make Goguryeo the center of the world.
I give you my word.
Heavens...
Take my life and protect Goguryeo instead.
Mangniji!
- Father!
- Mangniji!
Father!
- Father!
Mangniji!
Yeongae Somun raised a coup and assassinated king Yeongryu.
He took the position of mangniji and controlled the court for 24 years.
He died 2 years before the attack in May, 666.
He left a will for his three sons to unite and lead the court,
but that wasn't the reality.
Namsaeng took over Yeongae Somun's position,
but Namgeon and Namsan weren't happy that he had all the power.
While Namsaeng was patrolling the border area, they drove him out.
Namsaeng barely escaped Goguryeo and wanted to regain his power.
He surrendered to emperor Gaozong and asked for reinforcements.
Despite the struggle for power by the three brothers, King Bojang was
still a king who was like a scarecrow.
Goguryeo was showing signs of falling.
Goguryeo is in trouble because of the fight by the three brothers.
The oldest son surrendered to me.
This is a perfect chance to conquer Goguryeo.
I am appointing the duke of Ying as the supreme commander.
Conquer Goguryeo and achieve our long-cherished ambitions.
I attacked Goguryeo with the former emperor.
It was a great regret for me that we weren't able to conquer Goguryeo then.
I am honored to have another chance.
Has the king of Silla replied to my request to rush an attack?
He appointed Kim Yusin as the commander of the army.
He is going to Hanseongju with 200,000 soldiers.
He will advance to Pyeongyang with the soldiers in Ungjin.
Kim Yusin is in command...
If Silla gains control of the army again, my cause to conquer Goguryeo will be ruined.
I will not let Kim Yusin take command, so don't worry.
I will believe in you.
Conquer Goguryeo and make our wish finally come true.
Tang camp near Hanseongju
The emperor is sending the duke of Ying as the supreme commander.
We should advance to Pyeongyang around the same time.
The Silla army wil advance under the command of the daegakgan.
The emperor was concerned about Yusin being the commander.
He is the greatest general of Silla. Why should he be concerned?
I have respect for Yusin.
But the duke of Ying led in the attack on Liaodong before.
If they fight over command of the Silla-Tang army,
we will end up fighting amongst ourselves and there will be trouble.
What?
Are you saying the daegakgan shouldn't be in command?
I will not give such an order.
I don't care how high a reputation the duke of Ying has.
The daegakgan is the only person who can conquer Goguryeo.
If Yusin insists on command of the Silla-Tang army,
the emperor ordered that we attack Goguryeo by ourselves.
What?
He gave such an order?
Your Majesty, it makes some sense.
If the Silla and Tang armies fight over command,
there could be more trouble like before.
You should consider that.
Yusin, did you hear?
According to a vision in Goguryeo, an 80-year-old general will cause
the fall of Goguryeo 900 years after it is founded.
The is the 900th year.
You will be eighty soon. It looks like the prophecy will come true.
Since Yeongae Somun gained control,
the court and nobility were busy trying to please him.
They tried hard to stay on his good side.
He united public opinion and the country seemed strong.
But royal authority was lost and
the custom of giving advice for the country disappeared.
After Yeongae Somun died, public opinion was divided and
the three sons fought over power.
Namsaeng asked the emperor of Tang for help to regain power.
He is going to help Tang make an attack on Goguryeo.
If royal authority is lost and treacherous subjects take power,
a country will fall just like that no matter how powerful it is.
Will Li Shiji concede command of the allied forces?
The daegakgan has to be in command for a victory.
Nobody could command the army better.
Li Shiji has a high reputation.
He will not concede command easily.
If he doesn't, we will just gain command with power
like we did with Su Dingfang.
What are you worried about. Right?
I will take the lead and dampen their spirits.
His Majesty isn't letting it show,
but I heard he is concerned there might be trouble over this matter.
Your Majesty, the daegakgan is here to see you.
I wanted to talk to you.
I heard you are concerned over the command of the Silla-Tang army.
Don't worry.
Nobody can conquer Goguryeo except for you.
No matter what the emperor of Tang says,
you are the only person who can lead the army.
I would like to step down from the position of commander.
Why are you saying that?
Goguryeo might be divided now and public sentiments might have turned,
but it is a country that was powerful for centuries.
If I fight over command with Li Shiji at this point in time,
the fight amongst ourselves could annihilate the Silla-Tang army.
I will return to Seorabeol and pray for a victory.
Please consider my wishes.
You made a difficult decision to lessen my burden.
I don't know how to repay your great loyalty.
Thank you.
I'm taking a step back now,
but after Goguryeo is conquered and we have to fight the Tang army,
I will take the lead.
I will order you even if you refuse.
We know you gave up command for a victory.
We will respect your intentions and be sure to conquer Goguryeo.
Loyal generals of Silla.
I beg you not to fight to achieve merit.
Fight without fear to achieve the cause of unification.
I do not doubt your loyalty.
Your names and merits will be engraved on the foundation of unification.
The Tang army has advanced to Yeongnyusan with Namsaeng in the lead.
The Silla army will join the Tang army in Pyeongyang.
What will we do?
Your Majesty, don't worry.
Li Shiji is a weak 80-year-old man and
the Silla army is like a tiger without teeth without Kim Yusin.
If we attack the Silla-Tang army first, we should be able to defeat them.
I will take your advice.
Namsan, lead the elite soldiers.
Go to Sacheonseong and defeat the Silla army.
You must not let them join the Tang army.
I will obey your command.
Do not retreat!
Noe Eumsin!
I will kill you and get revenge for the innocent people of Bukhansanseong.
Shoot arrows!
Attack!
Namsan is fleeing! After him!
You should have fought with your soldiers. Why did you return by yourself?
The Silla army was too strong.
Quiet!
You should have fought to your death.
Why did you return defeated? You are disgracing father and me.
That's enough.
There are victories and defeats in every battle. Don't blame him too much.
We need a plan to defend against the Silla-Tang army.
Return to your quarters and reflect.
If we can keep the gate closed for 3 months before winter,
they won't be able to withstand the cold.
I will not let the Silla-Tang army take our capital.
Tang camp at Yeongnyusan
I heard the Silla army defeated Namsan's soldiers at Sacheon.
Today's victory should have dampened their spirits a bit.
We should use the energy of this victory and
take the Goguryeo palace right away.
The Silla army will take the lead and break down the gate.
When I tried to conquer Liaodong
I attacked Ansiseong because our army was greater in number.
We were defeated and I still can't forget the humiliation.
The fortresses of Goguryeo are impregnable and can't be take just with more soldiers.
Pyeongyangseong will be difficult to take even with 1 million soldiers.
Is there another way to take Pyeongyang?
He is going to continue to surround Pyeongyangseong and
wait for them to get exhausted and surrender.
It will be winter in 3 months.
We will run out of military rations.
We should attack swiftly.
He is right.
There is plenty of water in the capital and they have rations for a year.
They will not come out of the fortress to fight.
What?
Did you forget that I am in command?
I made my decision. Just follow my orders!
Why do you look worried?
Are you upset that you didn't go to Goguryeo?
I might be here in Seorabeol, but if the soldiers I trained conquer Goguryeo,
it will be a victory for me, too.
Then what is wrong?
I am concerned that Li Shiji won't attack swiftly and
fail by using a strategy of surrounding Pyeongyang.
If the battle lasts long, the people will suffer from providing military rations and
the people of Goguryeo will suffer because of the battle.
It will just be the people who suffer.
The duke of Ying fought many battles. I'm sure he will fight wisely.
He suffered a huge defeat when he recklessly tried to attack Ansiseong.
He will be careful this time.
Then our attack will go to waste.
Father.
Come in.
Did you want to see me?
Yes.
Wonsul, take this letter to your uncle in Pyeongyang.
It is urgent, so go quickly.
Yes, father.
Silla camp near Pyeongyangseong
Yusin said we had to attack swiftly.
That old man is being stubborn. What will we do?
How about attacking on our own?
The Tang army is in command.
If we attack, we will be punished for disobeying military law.
The Silla commanders will be dismissed
and the soldiers will becomes shields for the Tang soldiers.
He is right.
It won't do us any good to upset the duke of Ying.
Uncle!
Uncle.
Wonsul, what brings you here?
Father said to give you this letter.
I am giving an order as the commander of the Silla army.
You must take Goguryeo before winter comes.
If Li Shiji uses a long-term strategy of surrounding Pyeongyang,
collude with someone in the Goguryeo palace.
Have them open the gate and attack.
May Buddha have mercy.
Buddhist priest.
You're...
Sh.
You want me to advise His Majesty to surrender?
The Silla-Tang army will not retreat until he surrenders.
Even if winter comes, Silla will continue to send military rations.
The Silla-Tang army will not retreat.
What will you do?
Are you going to watch Pyeongyang turn into ashes and
let the people of Goguryeo be slaughtered by the Silla-Tang army?
Or will you advise the king to surrender to prevent unnecessary sacrifices?
Even if His Majesty wanted to surrender, the mangniji won't let him.
If you open the gate for us when the Silla-Tang army attacks,
we will kill the mangniji.
Please do this to save innocent lives.
You want me to surrender to prevent innocent people from dying?
If you make a decision, Namsan will relay your wishes to the Silla-Tang army.
Kung Chumo founded Goguryeo. Am I to ruin Goguryeo after 900 years?
If the gate opens, our death squad will charge through.
We will head right to the palace and kill the treacherous subjects.
You should lead the army in defeating the Goguryeo army.
Will the king of Goguryeo surrender?
We don't know, but Buddhist priest Sinseong promised to
communicate secretly with us.
The gate will definitely open.
Supreme commander!
Namsan is surrendering.
Namsan, what brings you here?
I am here with His Majesty's order to surrender.
The king of Goguryeo decided to surrender?
Yes.
He sent me to tell you.
I'm glad you came.
This happened to Goguryeo because of you!
If you didn't surrender to the emperor of Tang and ask for his help,
this wouldn't have happened!
What?
This happened because you and Namgeon committed treason and tried to kill me.
Why are you blaming me?
Stop it!
This happened because brothers fought over power and
caused division in court and public sentiments turned.
Why don't you know that yet? You're still trying to blame each other?
Take them both away.
Yes, sir.
It has been confirmed that the king of Goguryeo is going to surrender.
We should let the Silla army take the lead and advance to the palace.
Is it true that you sent Namsan to surrender?
Yes.
I ordered him to go.
How can a king give an order that would lead to the fall of the country?
Ever since I took the throne, I was the puppet for the mangniji for 2 years.
Even after he died, I'm being controlled by his sons.
How can I call myself the king?
Rather than being controlled by treacherous subjects,
I decided to prevent the deaths of innocent people.
What?
Go ahead and kill me.
Kill me and take the throne.
Your position is higher than the throne anyway.
You can't do this.
You tried to sell our country to the Silla-Tang army.
You are no longer the king of this country.
I will discuss with the court what to do with you.
Keep him confined and watch him.
Yes, sir.
The mangniji ordered me to pray at a temple.
Open the gate.
I didn't receive such an order.
Are you doubting a Buddhist priest?
Open the gate right now.
I will confirm with the mangniji first. Wait here.
Open the gate!
They are Silla spies!
Let's go.
It's the enemy!
Let Heumsun and his soldiers fight here. You have to advance to the palace.
Okay.
I will signal Heumsun. Yangdo, advance to the palace.
Advance to the palace!
The death squad opened the gate.
Give the order to attack.
Attack!
What?
The Silla-Tang army invaded the palace?
The south gate is open.
I'll kill them all.
You!
Do not retreat!
That is the mangniji, Namgeon.
Capture the traitor alive!
Heavens...
Are you really abandoning Goguryeo?
Why are you trying to take your life?
You cannot die until His Majesty has questioned you for your crime.
Hurray!
Your Majesty, the Silla-Tang army has taken Pyeongyangseong and
the mangniji, Namgeon, has been captured alive.
Is this true?
You should hurry to Pyeongyang and receive the king of Goguryeo's surrender.
I will go to Pyeongyang to receive his surrender.
Goguryeo palace
I, Bojang, surrender the royal seal of Goguryeo to the king of Silla and
the emperor of Tang.
Please be generous and accept my surrender.
Bojang, you weren't able to eliminate treacherous subjects and
made the people suffer because of battle.
It is a crime that can't be washed away.
But you made it known you wanted to surrender and
prevented the deaths of innocent people.
I will accept your surrender and pardon you of your crimes.
I am truly grateful for your benevolence.
I will pray that you have a peaceful reign.
In September, 668, king Bojang, the last king of Goguryeo,
surrendered to the Silla-Tang army and Goguryeo fell.
Goguryeo fought the powerful countries of the Central Plain for centuries and
even defended itself against the powerful Tang empire,
but after Yeongae Somun died and his sons fought for power,
the court was divided and public sentiments turned.
In the end, Pyeongyang was taken by the Silla-Tang army and Goguryeo fell.
Silla palace
We were able to conquer Goguryeo because the daegakgan humbled himself
for the cause of the Silla-Tang alliance.
I am promoting his title to daedaegakgan.
I am giving him a special privilege. He will not have to bow to me.
I am honored that you are rewarding an old man for his efforts.
I will reward the commanders and soldiers with new titles and awards
depending on their merits.
I will pardon people and cancel the debts of the people.
The court will help me in achieving a peaceful reign.
You gave Yusin the special privilege of not having to bow to you.
Are you discriminating against your uncles? It's making me jealous.
I could give him the throne and have no regrets.
Now I know what my father meant when he said
he would rather lose the throne than lose uncle.
Crown prince, when you take the throne, remember the daedaegakgan's advice.
Yes, father.
It would be nice if the former king was alive to see this.
I am sure he will be very proud.
Yes, he will.
You achieved a great accomplishment.
Your Majesty, only the foundation for unification is set now.
The Three Kingdoms have to stand up to the emperor of Tang together.
Only when we do that and Silla embraces the Three Kingdoms will
the cause the former king sought be truly achieved.
I will not surrender to the emperor of Tang.
That is the wish of the former king and the true cause of unification.
The king of Baekje surrendered and so did the king of Goguryeo.
All I need now is surrender from the king of Silla and
I can declare the Three Kingdoms as colonies of Tang.
From my experience with the Silla army, the generals and soldiers are very loyal.
If you go to battle to conquer Silla,
the Goguryeo and Baekje rebels will also join them.
You should establish a governing office in Pyeongyang and annihilate
the Goguryeo rebels first before conquering Silla.
I think you are right.
Xue Rengui, I will give you 20,000 soldiers. Go to Pyeongyang and rule Goguryeo.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Duke of Ying!
Why is the emperor betraying the cause of the alliance to let
the Three Kingdoms carry out their own politics?
Why is establishing a governing office Pyeongyang?
The only way for Silla to survive is to serve up the Three Kingdoms.
What are you talking about?
If the king of Silla insists on the cause of the alliance
and wants to keep the Three Kingdoms,
the emperor will have to order his army to conquer Silla.
You should decide whether you want to be a servant of Tang or Silla.
The emperor of Tang established a governing office in Pyeongyang and
had 20,000 soldiers stationed there.
According to the letter sent by Inmun, after he suppresses the Goguryeo rebels,
he will attack Silla.
If I declare war against Tang, would that be betraying father's will?
The emperor of Tang is showing his true intentions to
make the Three Kingdoms colonies of Tang.
Even the former king would have declared war against Tang.
I am declaring the cause of the Silla-Tang army again.
The politics of the Three Kingdoms are for the people of the Three Kingdoms.
As the ruler of the Three Kingdoms,
I am going to embrace the land and people of Goguryeo and Baekje.
I will break off the alliance with Tang.
I will station soldiers in Sabi and Pyeongyang and
drive out the Tang army from the Three Kingdoms.
I will not let anyone or anything endanger the Three Kingdoms.
In order to protect the people of the Three Kingdoms,
I declare war against Tang.
We will obey your command and fight the Tang army.
Glory to a righteous battle for unification of the Three Kingdoms!
Glory!