Sean, let's go.
Sean, come downstairs.
Hi there.
- How long has this been here?
- Tuesday.
10-23 over on 10th and Montgomery.
Yeah. Detective. we got
a possible 1 87 out on Route 59...
south of Washington Township.
Detective Breslin.
Right this way.
- Has anybody moved the body?
- No.
- But-
- You got a cause of death?
Well, officially...
we haven't determined death...
sir.
What the fuck is that?
We thought we should call you
because of your background...
in the oral-
Forensic Odontology.
- That's someone's real bad day.
- Yeah. No kidding.
The victim is male.
Early to mid-30s.
Moderate smoker. Less moderate drinker.
Upper middle to upper class.
Lives in the city.
- And definitely not a vegetarian.
- You're sure of all that?
Well, the root transparency
and the enamel wear...
put the age at about 32,
plus or minus four.
Acid racemization will be more precise.
I'm waiting on the results of that.
But you see this right here?
That is lateral striated trauma.
It's where the pliers slipped.
The victim,
he was struggling during the extraction.
He could still be alive?
Yeah.
Be on a liquid diet, but yeah.
''Come and see.''
It was written on four trees
around the pond.
North, south, east and west.
Any idea what it means?
It means they brought a compass.
How are the kids holdin' up?
Fine.
Imagine it's been a tough week for 'em...
Karen's birthday and all.
Yeah.
It's late, Bres.
Why don't we get out of here?
I'm almost done here, so-
Come on. I'll walk with you.
Earthling. no one can help you now.
- What do you want from me?
- Not much.
Merely your help in arranging-
If you cooperate. I may let you live.
I'll die before helping you.!
Brave words indeed.
But we shall see.
''What is my strength that I should hope?
Is my strength the strength of stones...
or is my flesh of brass?
Wherefore then hast thou
brought me forth out of the womb?
O, that I had given up the ghost
to know I had seen me.
I should've been as though
I had not been.
I should've been carried
from the womb...
to the grave.
Are not my days few?
A land of darkness, as darkness itself...
and to the shadow of death...
without any order...
and where light is as darkness.
God hath delivered me...
to the ungodly...
and turned me over
into the hands of the wicked.''
Jesus Christ.
- Is that blood?
- No, it's paint.
She's been dead about 12 hours.
Don't know how long
she was hangin' up there alive.
How'd she get in that thing?
- Drug injection, probably-
- No, that's not what I mean.
It takes more than one person to do this.
Make sure we get a report
from Footprint Morphology.
Then there's this.
Looks like they stood right here
and watched.
That's a tripod.
They videoed the entire thing.
- How many kids does she have?
- Three, and they're downstairs.
Let me do it.
I'll do it.
Who found her?
The daughter.
- Which one?
- The oldest one.
You're gonna have all the support
that you need.
She's adopted.
He'll be here any minute.
Thanks for the hot tip.
Hello.
I'm Detective Breslin.
- I'm gonna be heading up the investigation.
- Get out of my way!
- And I just wanted you girls to know that-
- Where are they?
Daddy!
- Daddy!
It's gonna be all right.
You need to double-check that
before we do anything with it.
Yeah, will do.
What's up?
They took something.
They took what?
They took something from inside of her.
She was pregnant.
Detective?
I didn't mean to interrupt you.
No, no. It's all right.
Is there anything
that I can do for you?
Are you going to catch
the person that did this?
I'm going to try.
Kristin.
If you need anything...
if you need to talk...
or if you have any questions at all...
just call that number.
Anything at all.
Thank you.
What have you got for me?
Heavy gauge fishing hooks.
Ankles, backs of knees.
She had two in the back of each thigh...
one behind each elbow,
three up each side of the back.
And then there's this.
She was stabbed in the chest
with an unidentified...
very sharp, very long foreign object.
Punctured her lung.
The object lacerated one of
the bronchial arteries and the bronchus...
which is one of the major
air passages into the lungs.
So blood starts flowing out
of the severed artery...
into the severed air passage,
the lungs fill.
You ever accidentally
drank water down your air pipe?
Imagine doing it continuously
for an hour.
So are we looking at a torture kill here?
Well, if it was done intentionally, yeah,
we would call it torture.
But it wasn't. I mean, to skewer both
of those spots in just the right way...
that's basically impossible
to do deliberately.
They probably just wanted
to bleed her out.
- What is that?
- Etomidate injection.
- She was drugged?
- Yeah.
So she could be hung up by the fishhooks.
I understand things I see
less every year, buddy.
Shit.
Roger that. 14. Confirmed.
There's the Metropolitan Theater.
That's where I met your mother.
I know. You tell me that
every single time you pass it.
Yeah. Yeah, right.
Do you maybe wanna go to the game tonight?
What game?
Well, it's just that a friend of mine
has these season tickets...
and I thought you might wanna go,
so I gave him some money for 'em.
Where'd you get that kind of money, Alex?
It was from you...
every time you ditch us.
Oh, yeah.
Right.
What game is this?
The Red Wings.
Red Wings.
- If you can't go, if you got work-
- No, no, no. Let's go.
Why not?
- Sean!
- Yeah?
- Guess who's in town tonight.
- Who?
- The Red Wings.
- Cool.
- We're gonna go to the game.
- Yes!
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
- All right!
Come on! Hi, Rose.
- Hi, Mr. Breslin.
- Yes!
- Have fun, guys.
- All right. Go get ready.
The Wings havejust been a
dominant team not only at home...
but certainly on the road as well-
- Yeah!
- Show Dad. Show Dad.
Dad, Dad, look!
You guys look like twins.
- Yeah.
- Bres. it's Stingray.
- They found another dead body.
- Where?
18th and Broadway.
We got an anonymous call.
We need you down here right now.
I'll be right there.
Steven Silva, 33, single.
Teaches the second grade.
- Seems to be missin' all his teeth.
- No, thanks.
- Got any prints?
- Fingerprints? No.
Footprints? Four sets.
Three watching, one doing.
And the tripod,
just like before, except for the windows.
That's ripe.
Let me have some of that.
Is that paint again?
Yeah.
What'd you find out about these rigs?
These rigs aren't cheap.
Heavy-duty fishin' hooks.
Steel-reinforced lines.
Custom jobs tailor-made
for the suspension connoisseur.
Connoisseur?
Suspension is a subculture based on
ancient rituals found in several religions.
It's the next step of evolution
from tattoos and piercings.
All right. That's where we start.
Pay a visit to every tattoo parlor
in the city.
We're already on it.
What?
Look at him.
A second grade teacher.
Who's ever doin' this, it's inhuman.
Tuck, get the paramedics up here!
How the fuck did we miss this?
Sloppy fuckin' police work.
Come on! Let's go!
He's a good tenant.
He pays the rent. He keeps-
Just play that, will you?
What happened-
What happened to the picture?
What- Hold on. What time was that?
4:00 a.m. exactly.
Fuck.Just fast-forward again, will ya?
Okay. All right. What time was that?
7:00 a.m. exactly.
What time of death do you have on Silva?
Estimated time of death
between 5:00 and 6:00.
And we got an address
on that tattoo parlor.
- It's on the corner of Main and 10th.
- All right.
Hi there. Can I help you?
Yeah. I'm looking for something.
Suspension?
- Yeah, we do that.
- Really?
Hey, Banksy!
- What's up?
- You know who made this?
Yeah. I did.
- And when was that?
- Month, month and a half ago.
So he called you?
You never saw him?
Called me. Told me what he wanted.
Faxed me the schematics from a Kinko's.
Did it seem strange to you?
Come on, man.
We got doctors, lawyers, businessmen
come in here gettin' stuff done.
Scarification, dermal implants,
cock stretching, whatever.
Doesn't mean they want you
to know about it.
- How many did you make?
- What?
How many of the suspension rigs
did you make?
Bro, it's fuckin' midnight,
and I'm still at work helpin' you out...
when I wanna be at home
catchin' a jack to Belladonna.
So maybe you oughta cut me some slack
if you want my cooperation, capisce?
- Yeah, maybe I should.
- Yeah.
Or maybe I should just take you outside...
and search you and your car
for controlled substances.
How about that?
Four. I made four rigs.
Thank you.
Stingray, wake up.
I need you to listen to me.
He made four rigs,
and we got two victims.
Shit. So there's two more.
What'd you find out
about the girl in the closet?
Well, her name's WhitneyJacobs.
She's pretty dehydrated.
She's still in and out of consciousness.
They drugged her up pretty bad.
What I found most interesting about her
while checking her out...
was her recent divorced ex-husband-
Garrison Jacobs.
They share custody of two kids, currently
spending the weekend with the grandparents.
Two kids? Let me guess.
Garrison's got a kid
in the second grade, right?
Yep. Garrison Jacobs
must have figured out...
his wife was having one too many
parent-teacher conferences.
- And Garrison Jacobs is currently-
- Unaccounted for.
Let's find him.
- ''Come and see.''
- Hey.
You shouldn't be looking at those.
Come and see what?
Well, I don't know.
Come and see.
Sean, get away from my stuff.
Revelations 6.
You have got to be kidding.
It was ceremonial.
The serving tray, the teeth.
They're announcing themselves.
They want us to know that they're here.
Who?
Revelations 6.
''And I saw, and behold, a white horse.
And he that sat on him had a bow:
and a crown was given unto him...
and he went forth conquering.
And when he had opened the second seal,
I heard the second beast say...
Come and see.
And there went out
another horse that was red.
Power was given to him
to take peace from the Earth...
and there was given unto him
a giant sword.''
- Remember this?
- Shit.
''And when he had opened the third seal,
I heard the third beast say, Come and see.
And I beheld a black horse,
and he that sat on it...
had a pair of balances in his hand.''
They're labeling them.
The fourth is the pale horse.
''And his name that sat on him was Death,
and hell followed with him.''
It's the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse.
The book of Revelation
is a vision of the apostleJohn.
A vision of the end of times
as revealed to him byJesus.
The Horsemen are the first four...
of seven prophetic elements
of the Apocalypse.
Okay.
There's Death, who rides the pale horse.
Which, in fact, is green.
Pestilence rides the black horse.
- And the red horse is-
- War.
Yeah. What is the difference
between Death and War?
Think of War as more of a concept.
Not as man killing man, but as strife.
Death is a physicality.
War is a state of mind.
And the rider of the white horse-
The rider of the white horse
is the leader.
Some believe that
he is the Antichrist.
Others thinks he is Jesus Christ himself.
Aidan, these people...
chose the Horsemen
as their model for a reason.
If they truly understand
the symbolism of the Horsemen...
and it sounds like they do...
you should expect things
to get much worse.
We're looking for a four-person team.
Their intent is to produce two more victims.
I intend to stop them.
Suspect one is the smallest.
Between 100-115 pounds.
The other three kept clear...
while this one tortured Mary Anne Spitz.
The suspect spent quite a bit of time
around her head.
They must have had quite a conversation.
The second suspect is Garrison Jacobs.
His whereabouts are unknown at this time.
Suspect three delivered
the killing blow in both cases.
I think that he's the pale horse.
- Death.
- Why?
Because the fourth suspect
is the only one...
in both locations who never moved.
Not an inch.
The fourth suspect is the one
that we should be the most worried about.
He's the ringleader.
We find him, and this thing ends.
We got another dead body
at the Bell Hotel.
What do you got for me?
Hello, Garrison.
Remember when I told you
about Spitz's puncture wound...
and the chances of it being intentional?
- Yeah. You said it was impossible.
- I take it back.
Yeah. It's the same.
Almost to the millimeter.
That means we're looking
for someone with medical training.
No, we're looking for a medical savant.
It is all the same.
Except no rig.
Checked in Monday with a single suitcase.
Told registration he's staying indefinitely.
Nobody lives in a hotel unless they're
homeless or they're hiding from somebody.
He knew that they were
coming for him next.
And the only person who knew
how he knew that is in a vinyl bag.
Excuse me.
The only person with a motive's in a vinyl bag.
Every lead we had is in a vinyl bag!
- What?
- Sean told me that he helped you today.
He was really excited.
Yeah. Right.
Maybe next time you shouldn't be showing
a seven-year-old photographs of a murder.
Alex, I did not show them to him.
- He found them. I took them away from him.
- Whatever.
Hey, Alex.
Look.
Thanks for taking such good care of Sean.
You've been really great with him.
You have parent-teacher
conferences tonight.
- I reminded you last week.
- What time?
Like, five minutes ago.
Shit. Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
Shit!
Alex has so much potential...
which is why it's so frustrating.
- He's not doing well?
- Well, he does great when he's here.
That's just not very often.
Alex is what we call a maximum result,
minimum effort student.
He doesn't have to try very hard
to do well.
So he doesn't.
Well, that's...
kind of my fault.
I don't really get to spend as much time
with him as I would like.
His group therapist used to say-
On the other hand, if I can be frank-
I think it's a good sign
that Alex is trying at all.
Well, it's not often the case
with children who have lost a parent.
Yeah.
I'm sure.
Spit.
I'm done.
All right. Go get in bed.
Hey. I was thinking maybe Sean and I
can take you to school tomorrow.
Make sure you actually go.
That's good.
Good night.
- Thank you for seeing me this morning.
- Of course.
But, Kristin, I'm not sure that I'm
the person you should be talking to.
I'm not trained, and-
I just wanna talk to a normal person...
not a man in a crisp suit
with a tape recorder.
Okay.
Well, I should also tell you that...
I'm not very good with children.
I'm not a child.
No, of course you're not.
- Do you have any kids?
- I have two sons.
What kinds of things do you all do together?
We don't really do a lot of stuff together.
Why not?
Well, it's a lot of things.
Sean, he's young,
and I'm just figuring him out.
And Alex-
I was so focused on my job for so long...
that I sort of missed his childhood.
My parents did that.
They thought my mom was infertile.
They were going to pick a baby.
But then, my mom found out
about the orphanages...
about us- the older ones.
I remember the first time I saw her...
when she came in.
I was eight.
I wanted her to take me with her so bad.
I couldn't tell her...
but she did anyway.
I came here to the States.
They were my parents,
and I was their daughter.
It was just like
I always dreamed it would be.
The next year, Teresa was born.
Doctors said it was a miracle.
That must have been hard.
Why do people do the things they do?
I don't know.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry?
What do you have to be sorry about?
I didn't know... this was inside her.
Why do people do the things they do?
I didn't know that-
Why are you wasting our time?
I know what you're going to ask me
five minutes before you do.
Detective Breslin.
If you'd like to come in here...
I will tell you things.
I wonder, Aidan, what you think of me.
You thought I was just this sweet girl
who had been wronged by the world.
What do you think now?
I still think that.
Really?
The moment I met you...
I knew we would have
a special relationship.
So why your mother?
- Because I hate my father.
- Why not him?
Would you rather be dead...
or live the rest of your life
without your soul mate?
- I'd rather be dead.
- You just might be. Do you realize that?
Why'd you turn yourself in to me?
I was craving some good conversation.
You're not Death.
Do you know the difference
between Death and War, Detective?
Yes. Death is a physicality.
War is a state of mind.
You're right.
Death is what happens at the end.
War's everything else.
What is everything else?
You mean...
you haven't found them yet?
Some books, trophies...
creepy-ass clown dolls.
Let's see. We got some clothes.
Some cartoons.
Cartoons?
Yeah.
- She's a little old for cartoons.
- Here.
Here's another one.
''Garrison Jacobs.''
''Mary Anne Spitz.''
- Why are you doing this?
- What does it feel like?
Does it feel like you are weightless?
You should feel like you don't exist.
Do you feel expendable yet?
Does your heart tell you that
it's your time to come and see the end?
Yes.!
Oh. my God.!
Yes. Oh. God.!
Now you feel like I do-
at war for the last 10 years of my life...
fighting against the things he does
and the way you forget.
No.! I'm so sorry.! I'm so sorry.!
I'm your daughter.
and you allowed me to hurt.
Now you die.
The war's inside you now.
War. and then death.
You're going to drown now. Mom.
Oh. my God.! Oh. my God.!
Stingray! Where the fuck are you?
I didn't know you guys were here.
- I thought you were one of them.
- I know what you did.
What the fuck-
Did you come here tonight
looking for these?
She's getting under your skin, Detective...
manipulating you to believe whatever
she wants you to believe, Detective.
Stingray...
why don't you go call Child Services
and tell them to pick up the Spitz daughters.
Mr. Spitz is going to jail.
Will do.
Let me tell you something.
She's a fuckin' monster.
Your room is very red.
Come on, Aidan.
I know you understand what we're doing.
- No, I don't.
- Don't lie. You do.
You saw the pictures.
You know what he did to me.
Then you know just as well as I do-
taking her wouldn't have been enough.
He needs to know that she hurt inside...
like I did.
Twelve hours in exchange for 1 0 years.
I think that's a pretty favorable trade.
What about the rest, Kristin?
Garrison Jacobs, Steven Silva-
What did they do to you?
There's going to be more, isn't there?
Three people does not make an apocalypse.
How many more, Kristin?
Four Horsemen.
Four offerings.
No more.
You are not going to find them.
You forgot?
No, I didn't forget.
I would never forget that.
It's just that-
Alex, we can't keep doing this every year.
You know, it's just-
Hey! I don't know how many times
I have to explain myself!.
Just because I don't show it
doesn't mean I don't miss her.
- You don't know what she went through.
- I was there!
I was there for every biopsy,
every chemotherapy!
You weren't there when it mattered!
That case you were working on
when Mom was dying?
Was it worth it?
The Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse...
by Albrecht Durer.
Wood carving, 1498.
- Beautiful, right?
- Yeah.
We got this
from Garrison Jacobs's stomach.
I think they made him eat it.
''Exodus 9:15.''
The computer this chip came out of-
I need to know where it is.
Can you trace it?
If his system was inventoried on line,
we can connect the chip to the IP address.
- And that'll tell you where it is?
- Pretty much.
If the IP was assigned by the CO,
we can geo-locate down to a street address.
Do it.
- Computer guy's got a location on the chip.
- Let's go.
Get out of the way!
Halt!
Damn it!
He went down the fire escape!
Bring them down.
He's out in front
and heading down the alley!
Everybody out! Come on!
Clear the room! Clear the room!
Come on! Move it!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Bres! Come on!
- Fuck!
- Let it go, Bres! Let's go!
- It's evidence!
- Bres, let it go! Let's go! Come on!
Fuck!
Very interesting.
Bres, the suspect got away.
We're settin' up a perimeter.
Well, we got lucky about one thing.
Tell 'im, Terrence.
They wound magnesium ribbons
through the drives, around the RAM.
Burns at 4,000 degrees.
It's pretty smart, but the magnesium
didn't catch in this one.
It gives me a good place to start.
I saw a Web page on this monitor.
''We are the nothing.''
If that was on this,
would you be able to find it?
- Give me some time.
- Do it quick.
Black, black, black.
Red, red.
Green. Green. The Four Horsemen.
The Four Horsemen.
Order up, Cheryl.
I ordered you a coffee.
Black, with two packets of sugar-
So-
What do you want?
Mom and Dad support me, you know?
I don't understand why you can't.
Mom and Dad support you?
Mom and Dad don't understand this.
They don't understand why you're doing this.
I don't understand it.
It doesn't even affect them or you.
Doesn't affect us? Hey, fuck you, pal!
It doesn't fuckin' affect us?
Fuck you. You have no fuckin' idea.
Do you know what it's like to walk
down the street, havin' people say...
''There goes Taylor Kurth.
His little brother's a faggot!''
Having to suffer the indignity of people
talkin' shit about your own fuckin' blood?
And knowin' that they are right?
Fuck you!
What the fuck are you doing?
Stop fucking crying.
Fuckin' stop it!
I will fuckin' walk out of here-
What the fuck are you looking at?
Go fucking clean something.
Knock this shit off.
Right? Be a fucking man.
Jesus Christ.
For once in your fucking life-
This isn't how I wanted tonight to go.
What did you expect, Cor?
That I was gonna change my mind?
Tell you how happy I am
that my little brother takes it up the ass?
Come on. Fuckin'Jesus, man.
I just... didn't want it to have to come-
Seriously,just shut the fuck up. Okay?
I'm fucking exhausted.
Just drive me home.
Drive me home.
I just wanna go home, go to bed.
Jesus.
You all right?
Don't touch me!
- Is that you?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Everything in your pockets,
and do it fast.
Hey. You take another step back,
and I'll cut you like a fuckin' pig.
- Hell follows with-
- What's that?
I said, ''Hell follows with me.''
Owen Rundell, 35, seven priors-
breaking and entering, petty theft,
assault with intent to rob.
Amateur shit across the board.
Tonight Mr. Rundell here
tried to mug the wrong cat.
Victim fought back,
put a nice little hole in his side.
- And?
- Tell him.
He told me not to worry 'cause he
purposely avoided hitting my organs.
- Did you see his face?
- Yeah.
- Could you describe him to a sketch artist?
Okay. Great. Get our best artist on this.
I want this done fast, as in right now.
Fax it to every medical facility
in a 200-mile radius.
Check it against employees,
residents, candy stripers, whoever.
- Find him!
- I'm on it.
Hold on for him.
- Hello. This is Detective Breslin.
- Hi. This is Lee Shoemaker.
I'm a registered nurse
at the University Hospital.
I know Corey.
Do you have his last name?
Thank you.
Kurth. Corey Kurth. K-U-R-T-H.
This is Dispatch.
Can we have an address on Corey Kurth?
555 Canal Street.
Backup is on the way.
We found Green,
but we have no Horseman.
I feel fuckin' weird.
Jesus, this is- Christ!
Holy fucking Christ.
Oh, no. Somebody help me. Somebody-
Get me the fuck out of here.
I wanna get out. What?
Corey?
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck's going on?
Oh, shit. Corey. Corey!
Oh, my God! Fuck!
Somebody get me out of this fucking thing!
Help. Oh, my God.
Oh, fuck. Is that you?
Is that- Oh,Jesus Ch- Corey.
Oh,Jesus, thank you.
Get me out of this fucking thing.
Oh, my God. What are you-
Corey. Oh, Corey.
Get me out of this fucking thing.
There's fucking hooks in my-
What the fuck are you doing?
Come on. Let me out of this thing.
Get me out of this fucking thing, will you?
Jesus fucking Christ, man!
What are you doing?
What is this? I don't understand
what you're doing to me.
Yes, you do.
Oh, God!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I was wrong!
I didn't mean any of those things I said.
I didn't mean any of what I said to you.
I'm sorry. I was being stupid. I'm your brother.
Come on. What are you doing?
We can't both live like this anymore.
Having an older brother
who can't support me...
and be happy for me like I am for him?
I looked up to you so much!
Let's talk about it. Come on. I'm sorry.
No. No more talking.
What the fuck are you doing?
- The pain needs to go away.
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry.
I didn't-
The pain is going to go away tonight.
Corey, let me out
of this fucking thing right now!
Corey, let me out of this fucking thing!
I swear to God!
You fucking let me out of this thing!
What are you-
What are you- Oh, no!
Corey, stop it! Corey!
What the fuck are you doing?
Don't do it!
God, no! God, don't!
My name is Detective Breslin.
I'm afraid I have to ask you
a few questions.
Taylor, can you hear me?
- Taylor-
- I can hear you.
Can you tell me what happened?
Which part do you wanna hear?
The part where my brother hung me up?
Or the part where he made me watch-
watch-
Taylor, I need you to help me
understand why he did it.
'Cause he's a fuckin' faggot!
He's a fuckin' faggot!
You're a fuckin' faggot!
- Can you guys get these hooks out of him?
- Got it.
Excuse me.
How did he do that to himself?
- PCP?
- Enough to kill a small mule.
It's the closest I've seen someone come...
to cutting out their own heart.
So, you found Corey.
- Yes.
- Tell me about it.
He's dead.
Corey was a remarkable person.
No, I don't doubt that.
You and Corey are from different worlds.
How did two people
like you and Corey meet?
You want to know how people like us
can meet each other?
We are the nothing.
How can we not meet each other?
The world lives in my bedroom, Aidan,
and in Corey's.
And in anyone else's
who's looking for something or someone...
they can't find at home.
So, did Taylor hurt?
Oh, yeah. He's really fucked up.
- Does that make you happy?
- Is that what you think?
We do what we do,
and all of a sudden we are happy?
You don't know the first thing about hurt.
But you're paying attention now,
aren't you?
Yes, I'm paying attention now, Kristin.
I have four victims.
I only have two Horsemen.
I can save you a lot of time
and energy right now.
You're not going to catch
Pestilence... ever.
And the rider of the white horse...
you don't find someone like that.
Someone like that finds you.
Oh, really? Is that how it happened?
The rider of the white horse
found all of you...
put this all together?
Created a forum to show the world?
Yes. That's what a leader does.
You could learn a lot from him.
Don't be like that.
Where's Sean?
I let him go
to a friend's house for dinner.
I really didn't expect you back.
Yeah.
Can we talk?
This place is great.
Who do you come here with, friends?
Yeah, sometimes I come with friends.
Recently though, I've just been,
you know, by myself.
Sometimes I'll come after school
or whatever.
When Sean's with a friend
or you're working through dinner.
Well, we should start
coming here together.
Like, once a week we'll come,
like, on the same day.
We could make this one of our things.
Right.
Dad, Sean is starting
to ask a lot of questions.
Like why you're not around
and things like that.
And I can answer those...
but he's gonna start asking about Mom.
Alex, I want you to know that-
I mean,
I'm so sorry that you had to have...
that moment with your mom...
alone.
But do you know what I would give...
to have had that moment with her...
instead of you?
It's not that
you weren't there that night.
It's that you never came back.
Well...
the whole deal with your mom, it was-
it was hard on everybody.
But I'm coming back now, okay?
This is me telling you that I am back.
Alex, I just-
This case that I've been working on,
it's bad.
I mean, it's really bad.
But it's almost over.
And after this case,
it's all gonna be different.
Everything is gonna be different?
Promise.
Western Division has a case they need you on.
Attempted rape.
Apparently, he's a heck of a biter.
Briefing's this afternoon.
- Hey, Krupa. Wait a minute. Wait a minute!
- Yeah?
I don't have time for this.
There's still two Horsemen out there.
They told us to expect four victims.
- We have four victims.
- No, we don't. They're not finished.
Let me explain something to you.
They chose the Four Horsemen
of the Apocalypse for a reason.
Did you know that the word ''apocalypse''
does not even mean ''the end of the world''?
The literal translation of it
is ''the lifting of the veil.''
This whole time they've been trying
to show us something.
They're leaving clues.
It all ties in together.
Look at-This is the Web site that
the computer was connected to.
It's a forum.
There are thousands of members on it.
See that date? That's new. That wasn't there.
When I first saw that,
that was a place to type in a password.
Now, that's tomorrow.
This whole time, they've been trying
to lead us to something.
- They're building to something. Don't you see?
- Building to what?
I don't know!
But it's going to happen tomorrow.
Now, we know two of them.
If we can find out what connected them,
maybe that will lead us to find the other two.
- I need more time to find this out.
- You need to let this go.
- We don't have more time.
- I don't have time for this right-
Just drop it!
The Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse...
were sent here to initiate
hell on Earth...
and it's happening tomorrow.
Fine. You've got 2 4 hours.
They've been leaving bread crumbs for us.
Yeah, well, I guess we missed
a couple of those crumbs...
'cause-
Four ''Come and sees.''
One in each direction.
Mary Anne Spitz.
One, two, three, four.
Silva's apartment.
Garrison Jacobs's hotel room.
- There's only three.
- Yeah.
That's why there's no rig, no ceremony...
no paint, no necklace.
Nothing taken from the body.
That's why the veil hasn't been lifted yet.
Garrison Jacobs is not the third victim.
What was he?
Garrison Jacobs is Pestilence.
I was trying to get my beauty sleep.
Garrison Jacobs tricked us
into punishing the innocent.
What did he tell you?
- He told us Silva molested his son.
- He lied to you.
- He was-
- Heartbroken and lying.
So we bled him.
You could afford to kill him. You didn't need
Pestilence like you needed the others.
He just operated the computers.
It would have been nice to have carried
the Pestilence theme throughout.
Three Horsemen
just doesn't have the same ring.
That means there's one less Horseman...
which means there's going
to be another victim.
Does it eat at you, Detective Breslin?
That three of the four of us
are off the streets...
and you had nothing to do with it?
We would have caught you.
Really.
Good-bye, Kristin.
''The great day of his wrath has come:
and who shall be able to stand?''
Who shall be able to stand?
Maybe that's why they used the rigs.
Find something?
- They were both in group therapy.
- Who were the doctors?
Annette Richardson and...
Annette Richardson.
Well, we'll look her up and pay her a visit.
Oh, God.
We thought we should call you
because of your background in-
Forensic Odontology.
Bres, what's the matter?
Kristin has acted like she's known me
ever since the day she turned herself in.
That's because she does.
The teeth were placed on that pond...
to guarantee that I would be
assigned to the case.
They're after me and my family.
Stingray, I want you to do me a favor.
I want you to go to my house
and take care of Alex.
- I'm gonna pick up Sean.
- What's going on, Bres?
When Karen died,
Alex was in group therapy.
Same doctor.
This is Aidan Breslin.
I'm driving there now. I'm his father!
I just need someone to tell me
if he's in his classroom!
- Stingray?
- It's me. at the house.
- What the fuck?
- Stingray!
Stingray!
Shit!
Stingray?
Ray?
Police Emergency. How can I help you?
This is Detective Aidan Breslin,
1 4th Precinct.
I have an officer badly injured,
28th and Nanty Street.
You don't find someone like that.
Someone like that finds you.
Well, he does great when he's here.
That's just not very often.
Alex?
Alex! Answer me!
- Dad?
- It's gonna be all right, Alex.
I'm gonna get you down! Hold on!
It's gonna be okay, Alex!
It's gonna be all right!
I'm bleeding.
I'm supposed to drown, not bleed.
- No, you're not!
- Yes, I am!
You have to know!
- This won't end with us.
- Please, God.
There is no Four Horsemen.
There's millions of them.
They're born into this fucked-up world...
by parents who are unwilling
to even try to understand them!
I understand.
And it won't end until every parent
in this fucked-up society...
realizes that it does apply to them!
They're watching us right now.
They're waiting...
for the last Horseman
to make the final sacrifice!
Waiting for the sign-
my death-
to begin the apocalypse.
The veil will be lifted,
and the people will finally see.
Please tell me you didn't do these things.
Tell me you didn't do this to yourself.
Why? Because I'm your son?
You haven't been in my room
in three years.
All you had to do was go in my room.
I told you it would be different.
It can still be different.
Open your eyes!
Open your eyes! Look at me!
Dad. Dad?
You were right. You were right.
After your mom died, I never came back.
I never came back.
I wasn't there for you and Sean.
Please.
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me. Please forgive me.
Give me a chance to be a father to you.
We're gonna be all right.
Whatever happens,
I'm never gonna leave you again.
You're gonna be all right.
I'm not gonna let you die.
Sean?
Daddy?
Yeah.
I had a bad dream.
You did?
I'm here now.
Where's Alex?
Don't you worry about Alex.
Alex is gonna be okay.
I love you, Sean.
I love you too, Daddy.