Subtitle Created By : MUBDEE AL SADIK
You wanna play, you wanna stay, you wanna have it all
You started messing with
My head until I hit a wall
Maybe I should've known
That you would walk
You would walk out the door,hey!
Said we were done, then met someone and rubbed it in my face
Cut to the part, she broke your heart, and then she ran away
I guess you should've known
That I would talk, I would talk
But even if the stars and moon collide
I never want you back into my life
You can take your words and all your lies
Oh oh oh I really don't care
Even if the stars and moon collide
I never want you back into my life
You can take your words and all your lies
Oh oh oh I really don't care
I can't believe I ever stayed up writing songs about you
You don't deserve to know the way
I used to think about you
Oh no not anymore, oh no not anymore
You had your shot, had your shot, but you let go
Now if we meet out on the street
I won't be running scared
I'll walk right up to you and put one finger in the air
And make you understand
You had your chance, had your chance
But even if the stars and moon collide
I never want you back into my life
You can take your words and all your lies
Oh oh oh I really don't care
Even if the stars and moon collide
I never want you back into my life
You can take your words and all your lies
Oh oh oh I really don't care
Yeah, listen up
Hey, hey, never look back
Dumb struck boy, ego intact
Look boy, why you so mad
Second guessin
But should've hit that
Hey Demi
You picked the wrong lover
Should've picked that one
He's cuter than the other
I just wanna laugh
Cause you're tryna be a hipster
Kick it to the curb,
Take a Polaroid picture
But even if the stars and moon collide
I never want you back into my life
You can take your words and all your lies
Oh oh oh I really don't care
Even if the stars and moon collide
I never want you back into my life
You can take your words and all your lies
Oh oh oh I really don't care