You poor, poor young thing.
Running out of gasoline
on such a hot day.
Yeah, that's my own fault, ma'am.
How's that?
Well, I got a little
wasted last night.
I did a stupid thing.
Well, I got shit-faced.
I stole that truck.
Went on a little joyride.
A drunk and a thief?
Now, Father.
Let he who is without sin ,,,
You need ...
... a guiding hand.
You need a family.
You need ...
... a thing called love.
I need a snapshot.
Oh, for chrissake.
No.
Scotty?
Scotty, come out here.
Bring your camera.
Oh, God.
You leave Scotty alone.
Come on, baby, up.
They didn't mean it.
Oh, my baby.
You don't mind, do you?
Well, actually, if ...
A memento.
Filthy.
Say cheese.
Hey, settle down, boys.
Don't you yell at me.
- Sons--
- Don't yell at me.
Where's your mother at?
Oh, fuck.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
- Oh, God. Honey, honey, help me.
- You son of a ...
- You filthy sinner.
- Help. Help.
- Help, honey. Help.
- You filthy sinner.
Oh, yeah. Get him.
You defiled my soul mate.
Give it to him, baby!
Yes.
- Fornicator.
- Yes, yes, yes!
Oh, baby, do it for Jesus.
Please forgive me, Jesus.
Oh, baby, tell him.
We're just doing his will.
The Lord Jesus wants us
to cleanse you.
To cast out the demons that
have tainted your immortal soul.
You son of ...
Sweet lamb of God!
And if thy hand causeth thee
to fall into sin ...
... cut it off.
Yes, Jesus!
And if thine eye causeth thee
to fall into sin ...
... cut it out.
Smile for the camera.
- I'm feeling the spirit, Scotty.
- So sweet.
Come on, boys.
Oh, come on, boys.
Here we go, boys.
Come on, pick it up.
Smile.
What ...?
Oh, my God.
Check him out.
I love a man in a uniform.
You didn't come back from the fucking
war to party with your parents, did you?
You know, I used to help him
with his homework.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
I don't know.
A lot can happen in 18 months.
Tommy, I know I keep saying this ...
- Go ahead.
- ... but we're proud of you.
Thanks, Dad. Mom.
Don't worry, little brother.
I'll find you.
That's crazy. All right,
I'll check you later, man.
This is sweet and shit,
but none of this would be there--
People don't have a sense
of history anymore.
Oh, hey. You take this.
Yo, Tom.
Welcome home,
Captain Shock-And-Awe.
- Well, thanks, man.
- Yeah.
So how was it?
Now, come on. No, tell me.
What? Did you get shot at?
You kill somebody,
eat their heart?
- What?
- All the above.
Yeah.
So you and Marilyn ...
... together again?
Of course.
Jared, you don't know anything,
do you?
About my little brother?
Oh, no, no. I mean, I know
what everybody else does. Right?
Like, Jesse and Nicole ...
... took off for Hollywood a year ago,
and they haven't been heard from since.
If you don't get me
out of here right now ...
... I'm gonna go Columbine.
I'm going tomorrow.
What? Where?
California.
I got 10 days' R and R. Time enough
to get to Hollywood and back.
Tom ...
... baby, they're dead.
We don't know that.
Nicole was my best friend.
She would've called me.
And your brother,
he would've called you, right?
Think you're gonna find them?
Cops couldn't, their parents couldn't.
They're not me.
Listen, Jesse is my little brother.
I always looked out for him.
If I wasn't overseas, I--
I'd have gone after him
the minute I heard.
I want you to go with me.
I found him. Come on, guys.
Jeez, dude. I haven't been up
this early since high school.
Well, it's good for you.
Anyway, I wanna make El Paso today,
maybe even Las Cruces.
Yes, sir.
Oh, no.
Please. No, no, no.
No, Tom.
He's so not coming with us.
I heard that.
Tom is my best friend
and I just wanna help out.
You are not his best friend.
No, no. I said he's my best friend.
I can't control who Tom likes.
- Like you, for instance.
- I don't mind.
We got a lot of ground to cover.
We could use another vehicle,
but that piece of shit?
She's gonna hear you.
Come on. She can make it.
I know that she can.
If she dies,
you are not riding in this truck.
If she dies along the way,
you can bury me with her.
Deal. Let's get out of here.
I talked to my cousin, Jake.
He lives in L.A.
I think he was the last
to hear from Jesse.
-Well, what'd he say?
-Not much.
Jess was looking to crash
at his place.
Told him he was on something
called the Old Highway.
I looked on the map.
There's nothing called
the Old Highway.
It's weird.
What the hell are you doing?
Enjoying myself.
What are you doing?
Jesus Christ, Marilyn,
we'll get pulled over.
Don't be a dork.
I'm a corporal in the U.S. Army,
sweetheart.
You know what could happen to me
if I got arrested?
Why don't you wanna be over here
with the other dinosaurs?
I don't like it with the other
dinosaurs. I don't like it at all.
I'm gonna eat him
if he's over here with me.
That's what I'm gonna do.
He's asleep.
It's about damn time.
The kid hasn't shut up
since high school.
Oh, it's nice of him to help.
You know why he's
really here, right?
Why?
Jared's had a hard-on for Nicole
since, like, second grade.
He thinks if he finds her,
he'll finally get laid.
- Oh, good goddamn luck.
- I'm not kidding.
Marilyn ...
... are you glad I'm back?
What do you think?
It must have been hell for you.
Must have been so lonely.
You know, I'd understand if you
partied some while I was gone.
I want you to know that.
Don't worry.
I was a good girl.
I went to this store in Dallas
and bought a dildo.
I wrote your name on it
with a marker.
- You didn't.
- I did.
You wanna see it?
I packed it.
- Who is this guy?
- I don't know.
- What was that about?
But you get your ass back in bed.
That's an order.
Hey, Nicole.
Big daddy's coming to rescue you.
Yeah.
Hey, guys, it's me.
I'm burning oil like Marilyn
through a case of beer.
Fuck you, you dweeb.
Oh, whenever you're done with Tom.
Hello?
All right, there's a gas station
up ahead. We'll pull over.
It was just a joke.
l didn't think it was funny.
He didn't mean anything.
I'm not some kind of fucking drunk.
He didn't say that.
What do you think?
l don't even wanna
have this conversation.
Zip it up, boys.
Zip it up.
Hey, how you doing?
l don't know.
Listen, we're on our way
to California.
My buddy here needs some oil.
Suppose we could use a fill-up too.
It's self-serve.
l never touch the pumps
unless l have to.
Causes cancer in the testicles.
Thirty-weight, over there.
Bathroom's in the back.
Try our snack bar.
Something tasty for everybody's taste.
-Sh--?
-I'll pay for it.
Listen, we're looking for somebody.
Might have come through here
about a year ago.
They were in a blue convertible,
headed for Hollywood.
One of them was my brother.
l was hoping you might remember.
Come on, Tommy.
Let's get out of here.
Yeah.
Yeah, l remember.
l remember them all.
Young dreamers, young lovers.
Heading for the coast,
heading for a new future.
But them.
Them, l remember.
They're stuck in my memory
like gum under my chair.
Young.
So young.
But, hey ...
... for 22.95 ...
... I'll tell you everything.
Oh, for God's sake.
Tom, can we please
get out of here now?
Just tell me what the fuck you know.
They were lost.
Babes in the woods.
Lambs to the slaughter.
l tried.
l tried to steer them away.
l did.
l really did, l swear.
What did you tell them?
l told them I'd seen a lot of shit,
and they'd better watch their asses ...
... or they'd end up shit
under somebody's shoe.
And what did Jesse say to that?
My brother, what did he say?
He told me to have sexual
relations with myself.
That's not a bad idea.
This is hers.
l swear. This ...
This is Nicole's.
l remember when she won this
for riding.
We were, like, 1 1 .
You remember?
Yeah, l remember.
Dude, you're such a joke.
Where did you get this?
l don't know.
Where?
Where did you get it?
You know what? l do remember.
l know, yeah.
l--
About a year ago,
l found it on the Old Highway.
What Old Highway?
There's no Old Highway on the map.
You gotta know where it is.
Will you show me?
Sure.
It's about a mile up that way.
You can't miss it.
How much?
It's on the house.
Thanks.
Tom, come on.
Who's the most awesome guy?
Jared's the most awesome guy.
Hey, yo, it's me. l gotta pull over.
Fuck, Jared. Not more oil.
No, l have to go to fudge town.
A little too much information, dude.
Oh, sorry.
Oh, it's terrible.
We're close to a rest stop.
l just saw a sign.
It can't wait.
Breakfast gave me the McShitties.
I'll catch up with you.
My gosh. Shit.
Shit.
The next services
are miles up the road.
I'm betting they at least
made a pit stop here.
Yeah, well, if l know Nicole,
she sure wouldn't pee in the dirt.
-Hey, Tom?
-Yeah.
Nothing.
Shit.
Literally.
Klingons, perfect.
The fuck?
What the fuck? Fuck, dude.
Sir?
It's occupied.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck.
Damn it.
Jesus Christ.
It's occupied. It's occupied.
I'm almost done. I'm almost done.
l swear it.
As soon as Jared gets here,
you think we could find a motel?
l could use a little minibar action.
All right.
I guess I'll use the facilities.
Tommy?
Hey, are you okay?
Jesse.
I'm so sorry, Jesse.
I'm so sorry.
Did l hear you say Jesse?
Nicole?
What the fuck?
''KZL-303. ''
''Nicole''? Oh, my God.
What the fuck?
Tom?
Tom.
l don't like this.
What the fuck?
Oh, come on. Come on.
Just stellar.
Guys, it's Jared.
Can you hear me?
It's Jared. Please come in.
Thanks for the ride.
Oh, my ...
Nicole.
What happened to you?
It's been, like, a year.
Nobody's heard anything.
Oh, you look like shit.
What happened?
Yellow truck.
The driver ...
He took me to the bus.
Who the hell are you?
You're getting yourself
into a shitload of trouble.
You know that?
You hear me?
You hear me?!
Look at me, you fuck!
What do you think you're doing, huh?
What do you think this is?
Did you do something
to my brother, you fuck?
Say something to me,
you sack of shit!
l said, say something!
What the ...?
All right.
Here we go.
Let me take a look.
''KZL 303. ''
-What the hell is that supposed to mean?
-l missed you.
Really?
l missed you too.
I've always missed you.
Ever since the sixth grade ...
... when you sat next to me ...
... I've always kind of liked you.
l thought you loved me.
Of course. l just never thought,
in, like, a million years ...
... that you and l
would ever have a chance.
Oh, Jess.
He was a good guy.
ls. ls a good guy.
l mean, Tom and Marilyn,
they're out looking for him right now.
But l came because of you.
And whoever did this to you
is one sick fuck.
Pardon my French.
I'll kill him.
The driver, we'll kill him
for what he did to you.
The bathroom thing?
No, no. That's, like, nothing
compared to what he did to you.
We'll kill him.
First, we gotta get you to a hospital.
-Then we're gonna go to the cops.
-No, no, no.
l tried the cops. l tried everything.
Don't you see?
Ends here.
Ends here, ends here.
Nicole. Nicole.
Hey, easy, easy, easy.
Come on, come on.
I'll protect you.
Jesse.
You know what we have to do?
We have to go. We have to go.
Tom and Marilyn,
they're looking for us.
They're at the rest stop.
Hey.
Asshole.
Listen to me.
I'm a corporal in the U.S. Army.
They're gonna be looking for me ...
... and they're gonna find you ...
... and you're gonna be fucked.
You understand?
So you better let me go right now!
Hey, I'm talking to you.
My brother was here, wasn't he?
Jesse, my little brother.
You hurt him, didn't you?
Just tell me, you fucker!
Did you kill my brother?
Tell me!
Then you better kill me, fucker.
Don't you fucking dare!
You hear me?
No.
No, no, no.
I'll kill you-- No!
Fuck! Fucker!
l will fucking kill you!
Jesse.
It's Jared.
Oh, Jesse.
Nicole.
Jesse.
Oh, my God.
He's got Tom too.
He's got Tom in the bus.
What?
Ends here.
Ends here, ends here, ends here.
Nicole.
Oh, Jesus.
Jesus! Jesus!
Nicole?
Nicole? Wh--?
Okay.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Goddamn it.
You're letting me down, bitch!
So far, this trip sucks.
Hey, hey. Hey, please, please, please.
Thank you.
My car just, like, died back there.
The smell, I'm so sorry.
l fell ...
This guy, like, tried to kill me. l ...
-Popsicle?
-No, no, thank you.
Such a hot day.
Be nice to have something cool
to suck on.
Better take it, son.
Sure.
Scotty, Popsicle.
Thanks, Scotty.
There, isn't that nice?
You said someone
tried to facilitate your demise?
Yeah.
This dude in, like,
a big yellow truck and--
Yellow truck?
Did you see
who was behind the wheel?
- Did you see?
- No, not really.
It was some Dukes of Hazard reject.
Then you must be a sinner, boy.
Otherwise he wouldn't be on your ass.
- He was one too.
- What?
The one behind the wheel, the driver?
He was a sinner once, like you.
A fornicator.
His soul as black as coal.
-We cleansed him.
-He got what he deserved.
And then he gave us
what we deserved.
Look, all that l know is that
some asshole tried to kill me, okay?
Hey, l think we're really close
to the rest stop now.
You can just let me out,
I'll go find my friends.
He's gonna like you, boy.
You're a dirty boy, aren't you?
Dirty boys must be cleansed.
It only hurts for an instant.
What only hurts?
What are you talking about?
Show him, my sons.
And if thine eye causeth thee
to fall into sin, cut it out.
Thanks for the ride, you freaks.
Jared, what are you doing?
That's our ride.
No, l don't think so.
It's a bunch of wackos.
I don't care. I just wanna
get the hell out of here.
- Where is Tom?
- He's gone.
What do you mean, gone?
I went into the bathroom,
and when I came out ...
... Tom, the car, just vanished.
- Well, that's fucking weird.
- Yeah.
And that's not the only thing.
I can't go in there.
It's the girls' room.
You're not gonna suddenly
sprout tits, all right, Jared?
You know, I didn't know
that girls could be this yucky.
All right, listen to me, okay?
I don't think that this is how it is.
I think that this is how it was.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Look, the first time that l came in here,
it was nice and clean and new.
And l thought l saw Nicole, okay?
l thought l saw her tag this stall.
Look at it.
Jared, look at it.
What do you think,
I'm drunk off my ass and seeing shit?
No, l don't.
l saw her too.
Fuck.
Fuck!
What the fuck?
What the fuck? We're seeing ghosts.
-Why is that so hard to believe?
-Yeah, like, a ghost bathroom?
Jared, all l can do
is believe what l saw.
Okay? This bathroom is as real
as Nicole was.
And she was so real,
you could reach out and touch her.
You know what I'm talking about.
Are you fucking blushing,
you little weenie?
Oh, my God, you are.
What did you do with her, dude?
It's nobody's business.
Wow, you finally get laid,
only the chick's dead.
l don't wanna talk about it.
It's personal.
Wait, she told you
Tom was on the bus?
-What does that mean?
-l don't know.
Well, she wrote
that some psycho took Jesse.
The driver.
-Maybe the bus is his little playpen.
-Could be.
But she didn't say where it was?
''Ends here.''
That's what she said, ''Ends here.''
We gotta find that bus.
We gotta save Tom.
No, wait, wait, wait.
We're gonna wait right here ...
... until somebody comes along
and call the police.
That gas station, remember?
With that crazy old guy.
- We can walk there.
- No, that's, like, 60 miles from here ...
Come on, it's just over here.
The road goes around these hills,
but it's really just over there.
Tell me you're not thinking
about hiking.
It's the middle of the night.
Don't be a fucking pussy.
I'm not being a pussy,
there are snakes.
There are tarantulas.
There are inbred zombie cannibals.
God knows what else is out there.
Fuck it.
Marilyn, there could be
another explanation for all this.
-Like what?
-Here, here.
Maybe it's, like,
some kind of mass psychosis.
You and me got, like,
a mind meld going.
Read my mind, Jared.
Shut the fuck up.
l can do that. Sure.
-Jared, Jesus.
-Sorry.
Holy shit.
That's the fucking truck.
-What the hell is that?
-l took it out of Tom's, come on.
So, what are you gonna do?
You're gonna, like, shoot the driver?
Yes, if we have to.
There's nobody in there.
Maybe he ran off.
No, maybe he's in there. Come here.
Jesus, he killed him.
-What?
-Jesus.
Goddamn it. You just scared
the shit out of me, you asshole.
You're the asshole.
-You fucked my nap.
-All right, sorry, sorry, sorry.
Cash register's open.
Take everything.
Just don't hurt me, okay?
We're not here to rob you. We wanna
know where that customer is outside.
Customer? l got a customer?
-Where is he?
-That's what we wanna know.
-l think he took my boyfriend.
-He tried to kill me on the toilet.
-You're shitting me.
-No, he's not.
So he didn't come in here?
You haven't seen him anywhere?
You're the only one to disturb
my slumber and my supper.
Fuck your supper.
He's gotta be here somewhere, right?
l mean, do you have a bathroom?
-Locked, out back.
-Do you have a phone?
Our cells are dead.
Yeah, got a pay phone.
In the garage.
Hello. Hello.
-Hello?
-Yeah, is this 91 1 ?
-ls this 91 1 ?
-91 1.
-Great. Okay, my name is Jared Schnoz.
-Schnoz.
We're at a gas station,
right near the California border.
My friends and l think that our friend
might have been kidnapped.
Friend? Kidnapped?
Yes, his name is Tom.
- Tom Hilts.
- Tom.
Is this really 911?
- Who the hell is this?
- Tom.
Tom.
- Listen, fucker.
- Do you know something about this?
- Fucker?
Yeah? Well, fuck you.
Where's Tom?
What did you do with him?
Fuck you.
Jess?
- Jesse.
- No!
It's me. It's me. Jesse, Jesse.
It's Tommy. It's big bother.
It's Tommy.
It's me.
I found you, you little shit.
I knew you weren't dead.
I wouldn't let you be dead.
Tommy? Is that ...?
- Is that you, Tommy?
- Jess.
Are you Tommy? Is that you?
What did he do?
- What are you hoping to find?
- I don't fucking know.
This fucker's license, registration,
maybe the address for that fucking bus.
- I wouldn't do that if I was you.
- Yeah.
What if he comes back?
What if he finds you messing around
in that truck? What if he gets mad?
That's what this is for.
He gets mad, you blow
his fucking balls off.
Please, please.
That's private property.
Put it back. Right now.
Put it back.
Son of a bitch. He took Jesse.
He took Nicole,
and now he's got Tom.
Marilyn.
- What?
- Check it out.
There's blood.
-Oh, my God.
-What?
-Jared, show me.
l saw this on Court TV
about serial killers.
They take trophies. They're fetishistic.
This is like some sexual thing.
You're right. He probably
just spanked all over that stuff.
Gross.
Oh, Lord. Oh, Lord.
Oh, the eyes.
-The eyes.
-What?
What are you talking about?
What about the eyeballs?
Nothing, l don't know nothing.
He said that l was a sinner.
The driver?
No, the preacher.
Preacher? Who the hell is he?
l don't know. He seemed to work
for the driver, l guess.
So I'd wake up and there they'd be.
The preacher, his wife ...
... and their kids.
He brought his family ...
... to fuck you up?
They'd always stand around and pray.
They said they were helping me.
Helping you what?
Get to heaven.
And how the fuck
were they gonna do that?
l never knew when they were coming,
and then you'd hear the Winnebago.
- Winnebago?
- The family's.
And then he'd bring me casseroles.
l fucking hate casseroles.
- And then ...
- Fuck.
The driver would
drag me out of here ...
... and the preacher would start
praying, and then the fun would begin.
Don't bullshit me.
You know something,
something about the eyeballs.
Try our snack bar. Tasty.
For everybody's taste.
You know everything
that goes on on this road.
I'll bet you know all about this driver--
Where he is, what he wants.
--and you're gonna tell me.
No, l swear.
Tell me everything.
Everything you know,
or l will shoot your fucking ass.
Do you understand?
I try to warn them. I try.
But he hears.
He knows.
I gotta be careful.
I gotta be very careful.
- Who the hell is he?
- It's not who.
It's what.
There's an old Indian legend.
If you're buried
without your eyeballs ...
... your spirit is cursed
to wander the earth.
Restless, lost, in pain forever.
You're saying that
the driver's a ghost?
And that someone
took his eyeballs too?
That's exactly what I'm saying.
You know, I tried to find them
one day, his baby blues.
I wanted to find them.
I wanted to put him to rest.
Put him to rest?
Burn the eyeballs.
The smoke will rise to heaven.
His spirit will follow.
All right, we gotta find Tom, find this
bus. Do you have a car that works?
Yeah.
- Tow truck.
- Get it.
Take us to the next town,
we gotta get the cops up here.
I hate to say it, but I told you so.
Get the tow truck.
- Where the fuck is the truck?
- I don't know, Jared.
There's not even any tire tracks.
Ghost driver, ghost truck.
Whatever. We're gonna get the fuck
out of here, right? Doesn't matter.
Oh, shit.
Wait, wait, wait.
If it is a ghost,
do you think a gun ...?
Come on, Scooby-Doo,
let's find the mystery bus.
I think it was a van.
Hey, mister?
Hello?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, shit.
He's here somewhere. All right.
There, there, there! There he is!
Did you get him?
No, it's not him.
It's the gas-station guy.
Then who's this?
Jared?
You all right?
That's yours.
That's your truck.
- Come on, let's go.
- Shit.
I got you.
Oh, no.
Oh, God.
Okay. Good.
He wants you to understand.
- Understand what?
- Your duties.
Look, please, just please
don't let him hurt me.
No. No, don't you get it?
No, he doesn't wanna hurt you.
He ...
He
He wants you to hurt her.
No.
What?
He thinks she's a sinner.
- And he wants you to cleanse her.
- No.
No. No way. No fucking way.
He knows she was unfaithful, okay?
When her soldier boy
was off at war ...
... she took solace in drink ...
... and in the company of men.
I won't hurt her.
I was afraid you'd say that.
No, please.
I wish the goddamn
cell phone worked.
I can't wait to call Mom.
It's been really hard on her,
you know.
I thought about
you every day, man.
Once, I could have sworn I saw you.
We were running a checkpoint
in Buhriz.
It's just outside of Baghdad.
A car goes through. I see you
sitting in the back seat.
You don't think moments like that.
What the fuck
would you be doing in Iraq?
It was just a kid.
Had a jacket like yours.
You know, the red one?
You should have saved me.
You're my brother.
I did save you, shithead.
What are you talking about?
You're not gonna, Jared.
You're just not gonna do it.
Oh, my God.
Jared, you're not going to.
You're just not gonna.
Oh, my God.
Jared, please. Jared, please.
You don't have to do this.
- You don't have to do this.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Leave him alone!
Jared, don't you fucking dare do it.
Jared, don't you dare.
Jared, don't you dare!
- I'm sorry.
- Jared, no!
- No, Jared.
I can't. I can't.
- I can't.
- Fuck you!
Jared, no, no.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
All right!
You all right?
I prayed for you ...
... to save me.
- You never came.
- What the fuck are you talking about?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Jess.
Jess. Jess, hold on.
- I'll get you to a hospital.
- You should have saved me.
What?
Jesse!
Marilyn?
-Marilyn?
-Tommy.
-I'm here, baby. I'm here.
- You were on the bus?
- Yeah.
- Is there any sign of your brother?
- My brother's dead.
So is Nicole.
And they took Jared. I'm sorry.
We gotta get you some help.
I'm gonna be fine.
Let's just get home, okay?
- Oh, my God.
- What is it?
Oh, my God.
This is it. That's what Nicole
was trying to tell Jared.
Ends here.
- This is it. This is where we should look.
- Marilyn.
- They must be here somewhere.
- What?
- His eyes.
- The fuck you talking about?
The driver. Burn his eyes
and we can put him down.
- I got this guy.
- Tom.
Tom.
Jared?
Jared, what happened to you?
The family made me dinner.
It's casserole.
Okay, listen to me, okay? Jared.
Jared, listen.
The driver's eyes...
Look at me!
... they're here somewhere.
Okay, we have to find them
and burn them.
Jared, you check out here.
Oh, shit. I think I might have it.
I think I might ...
Oh, God.
- You find anything?
- Nothing.
Me either.
How do you burn
somebody's eyes, anyway?
That'll do.
Wait, how am I gonna light that?
- Wait.
- Jared, just find them.
Fuck.
What the fuck?
- He's gone. He's just fucking gone.
- Tom!
- What?
- They're there. Here's a picture of them.
The twins.
The twins have the eyes.
Tom, look out!
Open up.
Thanks for the fucking ride.
Tom.
Tom. Baby, it's over.
Come on.
What the ...?
Goddamn it.
Maybe he went on ahead.
It's just not like him.
And that car of his ...
I drove practically the
whole way back. It's weird.
Marilyn.
I know this has been hell for you.
We did the right thing.
We stopped the bad guy ...
... even if this whole thing
was completely fucking crazy.
Marilyn, please stop crying.
You should have saved me.
The fuck?
I don't fucking believe it.
Tom, help me.
Marilyn.
Marilyn!