Subtitles brought to you by I Dare You Team @Viki
I came from the future.
I am you. Na Mi Rae, Na Mi Rae.
To help you meet a good husband...
I like good looking men, height about this tall,
Please let him be younger than me~
What about his profession? This has been Kim Shin's Morning Show, I'm Kim Shin.
Is that bastard's tongue long or short?
That type of bastard instead of me,
It's starting from now.
To change your life. For now,
you have to avoid that fellow.
Why?
The person you love dies.
Because of that jerk.
Episode 2
[1. You kill the person that I love = YBS]
You're really YBS... -That's right, I'm a YBS person.
So, what do you want?!
Why are you yelling and causing a ruckus?
Because this car has no family insurance registered, you cannot receive any insurance.
[1. Isn't insured]
If you cause one scratch while riding around in my car I will kill you. [1. Isn't insured]
[1. My brother is going to kill me.]
Cost of Fixing Foreign Cars is Rising.  [The price of the foreign car 3B is rising.]
In most cases, even if it's a simple event, the repair costs  are almost $4,000...
[1. Repair Cost $4,000.]
I have a slipped disc, I think it's completely broken.
Aiyoo, what do I do?
You were fine until a minute ago.
That's because there was an accident.
Oh, what do I do? I really don't think that I can move.
The hospital. I think I'll have to go to the hospital.
I reported on disc patients' emergency procedures,
and a real disc patient can't straighten their back like this.
I'm hurting even more because of you right now.
Do I have to live forever like this?
With my back twisted like this?
Aigoo, really **** I got caught by the wrong **** person.
Curse. Did you just curse at me, Announcer?
What? You shouldn't curse at me.
How can an announcer curse like that?
Omo, really, how can you... Aigoo, really.
I wanted to just do it nicely through the insurance. But this woman, we can't do it.
Let's go to the police station.  -Wait one minute.
That's fine.
I'll let you go.
Oh, let's just treat it like it never happened.
If you give me only $2,000 to repair my car.  -I can't.
If only for the good of society, a wench like you has to go to jail.
Give me your drivers license and go first to the police station.
I'll follow from behind you. -How can you even use violence?
Oh, let go of me. HOLD ONTO THE STEERING WHEEL!
Give me your driver's license and start the engine.
You're a broadcast writer?
If something like you comes into a broadcast station, the broadcast will all be ruined.
Ok, depart.
I was wondering who would drive so recklessly,
you were a beginner!
That's what I thought too, 'Who's that driving so recklessly?"
You were driving without a license.
What driving without a license?
The expiration date has passed.
Way over one year.
Here, shall we try to go up against each other earnestly?
My waist has gotten better.
For ten minutes now, back and forth.
We're not even at the zoo.
Aiyoo, my car's repair costs $2,000. If you give me that then it's fine.
Kim Shin, you really have no sense.
Do you really not understand the atmosphere right now?
Fine, fine.
I'll give you a big discount, $1,900.
And on top of that, that an announcer cursed,
using my disc as an excuse to hug me from behind,
all kinds of violence, and most importantly not having a license,
I will forget everything, ok?
Ok.
Then, the money...
I'll turn myself in.
Turn yourself in?!
Why? Are you crazy?
You're studying to be a broadcast writer, aren't you?
Watch carefully.
While you're doing broadcast work, this type of moment,
"Should I tell the truth or take the lie?" There's a lot of places to get hung up,
then we have to choose the truth, the facts.
Aiyoo, your position is very admirable, but
I already decided to forgive you and make it as if it never happened. Why...
There's you, the viewer.
I'm really ok.-A lie isn't ok.
So, let's go in together.
Aiyoo, why me?
Driving with no license and a car accident are two different things.
You need to pay for the damage.
Oh no, wait, wait.
I want to see it!
I saw your last news broadcast.
You said that you would return to the anchor position,
but I felt it so abruptly.
In truth, I'm a fan of yours.
The news, every day, I only watched yours.
5 o'clock. Isn't that right?
I, as a fan, really respect this kind of form,
but I want to see you return quickly and read the news again.
And the driving without a license, it's not really that.
Since you're busy, wouldn't it be because you forgot? Isn't that right?
But still, I'm an anchor.
As a person who publicly criticizes others, I myself must have no stain in my record--One year later.
One year later, after returning to the anchor's spot, you can explain it then.
Your viewers aren't foolish.
If they just feel your sincerity, they'll understand your heart definitely.
That's fine.
Then after one year definitely.  -Definitely.
I'll reveal it.
From that meaning, your phone number.
Yes?- I have to receive my car's repair fee, $4,000.
You don't have to repay it immediately, so your number.
I'll tell you after I see my cellphone.
You can't memorize that? Your number?
Oh, is there any reason for anyone to call me?
Also, I changed my phone number a little while ago.
Why start the engine.-To turn on the light.
It's so dark that I can't see where my cellphone is.
Oh, hey! Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
Oh, there was an accident.
It's urgent right now, so let's talk after I get home.
How can she think of running away in that situation?
Is she really crazy?
I'm sorry that I ran away.
Right now, I really have no money.
But one day, I will definitely repay you.
I'm really sorry. -She's really laughable.
Then why did you hide your number?
Just wait till you get caught by me...
Mi Rae! You, what kind of accident happened to you?
Were you hurt a lot?
I have to sit down.
Why?
Oh... -Hello.
It's my brother. -Who are you?
Oh, she's my friend. My very close friend, Hae Rim. Hae Rim's closest ahjumma,
something happened with their lease on deposit and I told her to stay here for two months.
Did you buy this house?
Why didn't you ask if you were going to bring someone in?
I did it because I owed her a personal debt of gratitude.
Since the second floor is empty, couldn't we tell her to stay there?
Debt of gratitude? Did you commit a sin?
Oppa!
Oh. You look a lot like a person she knows so when I showed her a picture of you earlier, she cried so much.
Oppa. Oppa. Oppa.
What's with that Oppa. She called me Oppa.
Isn't there something mentally wrong with that Ahjumma?
No, she's fine.
It's just because she has a lot of emotions.
At the broadcast station, is there any extra work?
Aiyoo, there's a lot of extra work. The problem is that there's no one who knows how to do it properly.
Hey, that's right. Among your friends is there anyone who knows how to preview?
Forget it.
Would your friends be any different? When you're like that.
That P...What is it? Can't I do it?
Why? If you teach me, I can do it well.
In high school I took broadcasting classes, and I won an award in the film contest!
Do you think the broadcast is some sort of high school symposium?
Who hasn't won an award at a film contest?
And also, writers are all people who participated in the newspaper writing contest.
How can you? You weren't even good at studying.
Who says I'm taking a PD entrance exam?
I just wanted to go to the broadcast station and learn to do some part-time work.
Just in case, if I hear that you're doing broadcast work at another broadcast station, I'm going to turn it upside down.
Why?! Why when it's somewhere else?
Because it's obvious that you won't be able to do it.
Then just by being your brother, I'll be disgraced.
Instead of going to the broadcast station, get married, get married, get married, married...
Why do you keep bothering me?
I'm going to go out. -Give me the car keys.
Why the car keys?-I have to go to work tomorrrow.
That's right. Even if the transportation costs come out to a lot, I'm going to take it to the office from now on.
I can't bear to see you going around using my car. Give me the key.
Oppa...
You know the saying that good luck comes to the one that endures.
May you receive a lot of good luck.
Aiyoo, what do I do about that person? When it becomes tomorrow there's going to be such a commotion.
Ahjumma, could it be that the person who's going to die is my brother?
It would be good if it was him.
I'm just kidding. A joke.
Even if he's bad tempered, he's the one and only family I have so of course he can't die.
It would be big trouble, right?
But Ahjumma, why did you cry earlier?
I can understand you being happy to see him after such a long time,
don't you think crying is a bit overboard?
Okay, fine.
Oh, dust...
Ahjumma, to let the dust out we have to leave that open...
Don't open it. Leave it.
You...
should..
promise me... that you'll not go to
the broadcasting station. Okay?
It will be okay if I avoid YBS...-If you don't do as I say,
I will just go back now. All the prizes you would get in the future
includes a refrigerator, television, apartment, and a car, but..
I will not go there.
Really?-Yes.
Instead, please give me some time.
I absolutely can't become a public servant so help me find what else I might be good at.
I will think about it a little bit more because I'm curious.
Organize it within three days. I don't have the time.
What do you mean that you don't have time? You even went with me to have fun at Jeju.
I told you, right?
I came here risking my life.
To me, one day is like one month.
I'm getting older.
When I turned thirty, time started to go so fast.
They say it goes as fast as the age. When you're 30, 30km/hr, when you're 40, 40km/hr, for ahjumma...
It does seem fast.
But still drive safely. Ok?
Ah, pillow! I didn't bring a pillow. I'll be back.
Aigoo, really.
I'll be right back.
Subtitles brought to you by The I Dare You Team @ Viki
Aiyo...
It would be a waste, but
he's already gone down the river.
Oppa... I'm sorry... I love you...
That's right. You just turn yourself in.
Don't be affected by a weird girl's lies. By using my own principles, whenever, confidently...
Aren't you an announcer?
What are you doing here this early in the morning?
This... I...
Actually, I...'Caught without a license'
Yes..
Hello?
Is this Mr. Kim?
Yes, that's right.
This is the police station.
Since everything has been found out, you better come here right now.
Mr. Kim Shin...
Whatever it is, I...
It's me, Detective Kang.
Lee Chae Soo.
Now, why are you trembling so much?
Could it be that you've really done something wrong?
I came out for the kids without a license, for the shooting.
The Police aren't cooperating.
The police's wife is a big fan of you, Sunbae Kim.
Can't you send him an autograph through fax?
Hey, you...
I don't want to.
Also, to a young person, what do you mean a shoot?
He's famous! Starting at 1 am,
he's number one on the search list.
And the things we prepared, they're going to completely take out and they're going to go with the unlicensed storyline.
Go to the office. I'm telling you it's been chaotic.
Well, for what reason are you...
Ah, yes. I...
I came to see if you are active in Ilsung.
Then...
Hello.
Hello!
Hello (formally).
Oh, here's the opening. We changed it to be about unlicensed drivers.
Okay, we're starting.
I'm thinking if we should really be doing this.
It's a totally hot issue.
You have a license, right?
Why?
I left it at home.
Aiyoo, it's more effective if the MC take his own driver's license there directly.
Okay, 30 seconds. This is the last warning.
We'll go. 5 seconds.
4 seconds.
3 seconds.
Cue.
Hello. I am Kim Shin on Kim Shin's Morning Show.
Today at dawn, a famous idol group's leader was caught driving without a license.
He's said he was so busy,
he didn't know that his driver's license had expired, and that it was a simple mistake,
but the public's response is cold.
Please explain![Famous idol group's leader Chang Gong, caught driving without a license]
I'm sorry to my fans and to all the citizens.Chang Gong (22)
A driver's license doesn't just apply to oneself,
it is something that can affect the life or death of another citizen.
The fact that someone has prevented this,
is that a person doesn't even have the least consideration for others.
Good. Admonish more strongly.
I...
would like to say to him, who disregarded the basic responsibilities of a public figure, or even an average citizen,
I want to call him this.
A criminal of the roadway.
That he was a speeding
murder weapon.
This morning, the announcer who harshly criticized the non-license driving of an idol group leader,
Kim Shin, was revealed to have been found driving without a license as well, creating shock in the public.
I'm sorry for running away. I really don't have money right now but I will pay you back. I'm really sorry.
I still have to turn myself in.
This is so dirty that I really...
At YBS, at the same time we fired Kim Shin,
Broadcasting Board of Ethics
will block him from being in any broadcasting stations.
And he will be replaced by
me.
What's this?
Pretending to stop me from turning myself in,
but actually waiting for a similar incident to appear on the news to ruin me-
I have to catch that girl. Na Mi Rae.
Who are you?
I wanted to monitor (observe) your class.
All these people here have paid to hear this lecture, how can I let you just monitor (observe)?
Ah, I...
Because I'm your fan. The Burning Friday, The Family is Going, I've seen them all.
Can't I do it just this time?
Will you be okay with that?
Yes.
Thank you!
Thank you.
Then, again.
Hello?
Are you by chance, Na Mi Rae?
Yes, with a white foreign car with long hair, dressed like a broadcast writer.
You drive a truck?
I understand.
Hello? Are you Na Mi Rae?
I rewrote the closing that you spoke about. If you could look at it one time...
You're a man?
But your name is...
I understand.
Kim Announcer, I need to search for a preview intern, too... I'm really busy right now!
Hello? Are you Na Mi Rae?
Yes, that's right.
Do you drive a white foreign car and have curly hair tied back and study broadcast writing?
Who are you?
Hey, 'Hit-and-run.'
Its 40,000,000 won.
I'm also busy so I'll just read it right now.
A bit later.
The best way to face an enemy is to place him/her next to you and observe that person.
Hey-!
Wha- What?
Observe. If that person becomes my side, everything will get better.
Good. Very good.
Okay? Cool.
This is too much.
I'm sorry.
I tried to study by myself,
Maybe it's because I'm stupid but it wouldn't register in my brain!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Ah seriously, I have to change my number or something...
This is my third time sending you a text,
you want to be a broadcasting writer right?
I'll let you do it, so come to the YBS lobby right now and call me.
Ahjussi do you go to YBS?
Yes I do. He said yes... what do I do?
Are you getting on or not?
Should I go or not?
It seems like a trap right?
I really want to become a writer
Seriously...
Oh-
Wait a minute, Miss Bo Ra is coming through!
Bo Ra is coming through!
Move aside.
Don't stand in Bo Ra's way. Move!
Please move. Move!
Don't take photos, she has too much makeup on.
Hey!
Darlings, do I have to really be irritated for you to come to your senses?
Carefully, carefully. . .
Miss Mi Rae,
Hello.
Sorry, I can't really say that to you.
17,000 won, I'll definitely pay the rest.
Every month 30,000 won. . .  Never mind that.
Give me your resume.
Why?
You read the text and came here.
I told you I'll let you work here.
But why me?
Because you ran away.
How can somebody who wants to be in broadcasting have that kind of attitude?
So I told you to come so I can teach you myself.
Show you that this is real broadcasting.
Then am I the morning show team?
Of course. I'm the MC.
And if you
tell other people that you're a part time worker at the broadcast station,
I'll go crazy.
Oh no but...
Think about it quietly.
What you really want to be and what you're good at.
I'll do it.
Please use me.
Your resume is so simple,
very chic.
Right?
Your major is... regional emotion? This kind of major exists?
It's like analyzing the emotions of different regions.
YBS is a nationwide broadcast right?
I know the different analysis for each region so I'm perfect for this job!
And on top of that -
Enough,
just promise me this.
In one year, you give me the opportunity to turn myself in for unlicensed driving.
Oh... so simply speaking, don't go report it you before then?
I'm not that interested in other people's lives.
I'm busy eating and living.
Okay then.
You know how to do the preview right?
Yes, I heard about it from my bro-
No I don't know.
What's that? Is it hard?
As hard as region emotions?
You basics...
I'll get them done!
If preview is the broadcasts basics I'll learn it.
I won't do just what you tell me to do. I'll find things on my own.
If you tell me to do ten things, I'll do twenty.
If you tell me to dig 10m, I'll dig 100m, 1000m further and think about it.
Because the real basics is that.
Experience.
She's just your type and she knows the basics.
So, you don't know how to do the preview?
If you teach me I'll try my best.
Over here everyone tries their best, the problem is doing well.
Do you go out with Kim Shin?
No.
That's not it. . .
This is the preview USB.
You can sit here and do it or put in in a laptop and
do it somewhere else.
But what is the preview?
The PD records on the tape.
Yeah,
then someone has to edit it.
But since they just do film anything you don't know where is what.
Na Mi Rae, you're supposed to organize it.
To make it so we know what is where.
Yes.
It's urgent, so please hurry.
Ah wait!
Where is the bathroom for the Morning Team?
Over there.
There?
Na Mi Rae,
Yes?
I'm not giving you work because I like you.
Your daughter's age is 32 and her older brother is a broadcasting PD.
Your daughter's current job is... Unemployed.
But before that, she worked at Hong Electronics.
But if we sign the contract. . .
We'll see from Section D.
Start from A.
A is a special section,
Let's first see it.
Then, just check what level she is.
If she's professional enough,
Look, look.
She did drugs.
He gambled,
He was captured because of abusing his wife,
This is just a jail list.
Give me B.
B is doctors, lawyers and people like them.
Oh then I don't even need to see it.
Then, should I show you D?
Give me E.
Their levels are very low.
Their families aren't so well, or their jobs aren't good.
Give it to me.
You must not know well because you're from long ago,
Oh my, oh my, oh my.
All the people I'm looking for are in here.
Here, here, this person.
This person is a very famous photographer.
Oh my, and this guy is a movie director.
He went all the way to Hollywood.
Oh my.
He was in this generation.
Please give me a copy of this list,
and please let me meet them.
Also, within these people,
anyone who's involved in broadcasting, take them out.
Announcer Kim Shin
Should I tell you honestly why you can't be the main anchor, Mr. Kim Shin?
It's because you're old.
What people want nowadays is not news.
The News, everywhere you look it's the news and what do they know.
But still, the reason why people still watch the news is the anchor.
Anchor's visual, voice, style!
Are my visuals, style, and voice, that bad?
Of course, you're great.
But a better guy came in so what can I do? You should step down.
In what way is he better than me?
His pronunciation is not good, he can't make the vital points, has repeated mistakes...
He's young.
How very youthful he is makes you want to watch.
Even though he makes mistakes, since he's young, he's cute.
Because of his pronunciation do you not know that more people are watching our news?
This time, we ranked number 1.-News is
Journalism isn't something like that.
That is exactly the problem in our broadcasting systems these days! Enlightened sex!
That's why abroad, older anchors are more...
Of course, there are older anchors but there are also girls who do it wearing bikinis.
The President of YBS is me.
So prove to me Kim Shin's ability.
If you get at least a 15% rating on your morning show then
I will make you the main anchor for the 5 o'clock, no, the 9 o'clock news.
Oh, are you here to visit Miss Seo Yoo Kyeong?
Here everyday, you're so devoted.
While you're doing this, might there suddenly be a report about the two of you getting married?
Ah, no.
Since I hit her with my car, at least while she's in the hospital I have to take responsibility.
But what should I do? Miss Seo Yoo Kyeong went for a check up.
Sunbae!
YBS, Editing Desk.
Others,
many are gathered.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5
7 people ran out,
Aigoo, why does this keep steaming up?
What should I call...
Ah, I really don't know.
What should I say?YBS Editing Room
Without one word...
If you're always going to do this, we can't have it.
WHAT?!
I'm sorry!
Just a minute, just a minute.
Ah! Oh! Sorry!
Where do I go? I'm not here. Make it so I'm not here.
Who are you?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Just this one time.
Oh, that...
A girl came in here right?
Who?
An idiot with round eyes and scattered hair.
Is she pretty?
If that's the case then introduce me to her.
I'm sure it was Na Mi Rae.
This is the last one though.
Just watch if she really came here, I'm going to wrap her stuff and throw her out,
and take her off our family registry.
Excuse me...
She sees me as water, that's what it is. Does she think I'm a fool?
I thought I was going to die.
If I'm caught it's my death. I'm sorry.
Your name is Na Mi Rae?
Yes.
Oh! You're that man!
Do you remember me?
Yes!
Why does this keep steaming up?
The video of the grandfather.
You kept cleaning the lens.
Oh.
You're previewing it? I shot it.
Really? That's amazing!
Earlier I saw that and came.
As I looked at it, the same thing came out. It was really amazing.
I am amazed too. I thought I'm not going to see you again.
But now I'm looking at you like this.
But why is the Team Leader like that?
Ah, that...
Na Mi Rae fighting!
Even if that wench weren't here, just...
Let's give up. Just give up.
Instead of the quail it's a chicken.
Yes?
Ahjumma, do you know where Mi Rae is?
I'm not sure.
Office...-I already know that she's at the office.
Could it be that she went to the broadcasting station?
Why?-Just now
I saw someone who looked exactly like Mi Rae.
Looked the same?
So much that you'd recognize her at once?
What is this?
Is she really working at the broadcast station?
No, she should be studying for the civil servant exam, level 7.
What?
This time she's really made up her mind strongly so try believing in her.
There's no way she went to the broadcasting center so don't worry.
Yes.
This girl, really...
Ah, does Team Leader really look down on his own sister?
Aiyoo, I took out my brother's car and completely destroyed it.
That's a bit...
Anyway, if you go there you should be able to preview it quietly.
I'm not sure. I just need to check if she's here or not.
I would just look at the visitors log...
No, no...
Hey! You!
Ahjumma!
Why did you lie? The broadcasting station...
I told you especially that YBS wasn't ok.
Wait, wait a moment.
Who are you?
Me? I'm her mother.
Ah...
Do you know me?
Park Se Ju!
Ah, I...
When your parents went abroad,
I lived next door.
I lived in the house next door.
Ah...
Your baby face is still there exactly.
Then Korea,
you've completely come back in? Then now...
I'm a VJ on Kim Shin's Morning Show Team 3.
I was a VJ for a while.
Since I had to takeover the Broadcast Station later, from the standpoint of learning from the ground up.
I did mislead some people.
He fooled me too. Completely.
That person then...
Do you have someone you're dating?
No.
What are you doing?
Then someone you fell for at first sight?
You have one.
Is she pretty?
No. I'm serious.
Are you for sure? You're definitely not a reporter?
Please!
I'm sorry, I asked you so much for the first time.
Then you're with this person Morning team?
Yes. Why?
That's good.
Good?
Can I talk to Mi Rae for a bit?
Yes.
Ahjumma, what have you been eating to be this strong?
You, what's your relationship with him?
Relationship? What? I just met him today.
Ahjumma, I'm really sorry for deceiving you.
It's fine, you did good. I mean you didn't do good on deceiving me.
But why doesn't he know Seo Yoo Kyung?
Is he lying?
The person he fell for at first sight,
And in Solo he's in the same team as you.
But the problem is that guy is in here too.
What are you doing?
I'm building your life for you!
It's also my life, but.
Okay,
Yeah, VJ.
No. He's not a VJ.
He's a conglomerate.
Soon here, no,
Why would such a person work here?
Ahjumma is he that person?
The person who's going to kill the person I love?
Listen carefully. He is
a person you need to marry.
And the person you almost had an accident with, you need to avoid.
But the problem is that person is also in the Morning Show team.
That guy is in our team? Who is he?
Did I say Morning Show?
Since I'm old, all my words are being twisted.
Not Morning Show, , , morning drama.
So its not the writer, then oppa, , ,
You!
Lied and the broadcast. .
I told you to avoid YBS but what is this?
You, if you're going to be like this
I'm going to just leave.
I'm not going to tell you and just leave.
Is something going to happen to me?
If you want to know then do whatever I say.
For now you, whatever it takes
seduce Park Sae Joo.
Seduce?
Yes.
Right now and in the future it only happens in dramas.
All except one.
He said he fell at first sight in Jeju island,
but he said he's single right now.
It means that our future days is starting to change.
A chance has come to you.
Trust me.
Park Sae Joo,
is the last best Cinderella ticket.
We need to get it.
You have to seduce Park Se Joo, no matter what.
Go and seduce him. Quickly.
Quickly, quickly quickly.
I'm sorry honey.
But,
I don't think I can
live like that again.
Did your Mother leave well?
She's not my mother,
she's just a far relative.
This must be a music storage room. It's nice.
What if my brother finds me?
Team leader won't come all the way here.
We made it so that they can just download it in the office.
Also I saw the preview that you've done,
It's not called big screen, but a full shot.
Full shot.
And this is called the title shot.
This is so interesting.
I didn't know what to call it so I just wrote whatever,
The English in the broadcasting system is simpler than I thought.
Actually the English isn't very important.
But, what's full shot 130 screen?
Have you counted them all?
Yes.
Wow, that's a lot.
Then what about the highlight marks?
They seemed important, and the numbers
Why?
It seemed very hard,
I thought it would be better if we did it like this. . .
I'm so sorry! You've worked so hard and I
No, I like it.
It's fun.
You're right, the most important thing in broadcast is that.
Really? Thank God.
It was so cool seeing the things that weren't edited. I would imagine 'what would it be like if it were like this'
Have you thought of what music to play?
Yes.
This one.
Daebak. Really this?
By any chance, is it track #3?
Want to listen together?
Yes.
Does that make sense? Although he's good looking. . .
But still, he seems like a good person.
It's so good.
Writer Bae.
Nam Mi Rae isn't answering her phone? Why?
I thought it was weird because an announcer recommended her.
Why did you change the third line of the ment?
Where?
That, it seemed hard in reality.
Why?
Why are you talking about that now?
Bye.
No wonder, she came so quietly with one text,
Excuse me driver, turn the car to the broadcasting station.
Yes.
Have you found her?
No. I called her about 3,852 times
but still.
I'm Nam Mi Rae's mother,
but her cell phone isn't working
If you're nearby,
Can you tell her to come to the lobby?
I'm not sure,
I also can't find Nam Mi Rae whom you're looking for.
Nam Mi Rae? Who is it? Who's looking for Nam Mi Rae?
She's making a mess here and there.
She says she's her mother, but her words are weird.
Are they planning something?
Yes Mother?
Hello? You're Nam Mi Rae's mother?
Yes. Who are you?
Where are you?
In the lobby. . .
I'll go down.
This way, please.
You're the mother of Ms. Nam-Mi-Rae, aren't you.
Excuse me to say this at start, but I had issue with your daughter.
She just took off even without telling me way to contact her.
Few days ago, problem happened with her.
I was bit suspicious on her, but since she's younger than me,
Trying to help her, I introduced her on broadcasting job.
For her 1st day on new job, she should be very responsive on my call.
But, I can't even contact her.
This is rather serious issue.
What issue?
Real issue is yourself.
People may be fooled by your deception, they'll know soon.
How ignorant you are!
How egotistical you are!
Thinking of becoming 9:00 news anchorman, you're full of motivation, aren't you?
Well, not so fast. This may be your peak.
Anchorman? Don't be ridiculous.
Only way for you is going down the hill.
Is that what you've heard from your daughter?
It's conspiracy, isn't it.
So, when are you going to expose this?
Why did you kill her?
You want to say it's accident. But, it's not.
You did it on purpose. You're getting paid.
Although you're being paid, you just let it happen...
How can you just leave her dying like that?
Miss NamIlHay
Is that what she said?
She almost got run over by car to death?
You killed her.
Do we need to go to editing room to see that?
What if I see him on the way?
He may be in writers' meeting.
So, as we watch the ones we saw earlier ..
Writer Bae want to see me.
How come I have these many calls!
Maybe, they're complaining at you.
What do I do?
Let's hurry.
Hey, Writer Bae, I'm Shin. Sound the emergency alarm; have everyone find Ms. lNam Mi Rae, make it quick!
How did you know her, and seduced her?
Seducing her? It's all your plan anyway, isn't it?
You laid out all the plan, didn't you.
My assistant manager
You figured out in secret. Waited until I drive to work to collide on my car.
Pretending to moderate the accident; she's fantasizing whether to sue or blackmail me
Did she really hit your car?
Why are you doing this?
Mother and daughter is very close relationship, ma'am.
It was another car accident?
She's enjoying it? She's real sickening.
I think same way you do.
I'll accuse her of threatening. Why don't you continue your dubious acting all the way to courtroom?
If you want to accuse of threatening, you accuse me for that.
Don't ever get near her, and don't mess her around!
Don't worry. She'll be kicked out instantly for you.
My preview was not the cause of problem, was it?
Maybe tape messed up, or machine broke down or something.
Perhaps. What should I do.
Hey, What the hell you've been doing?
Oppa, I'm very sorry on that one.
And, I have small part-time job
Oppa?
Are you brother and sister? Didn't I tell you if you mess up, I'll kick you out.
You did, you did.
Sir, she's doing good job on preview.
You shut up, and go to editing room. You come out.
Come out!
You got caught today.
Come over here!
You're hurting me.
It hurts.
Aren't you going to confess?
How did you get into this company?
I got into here using front gate.
What happened?Kim AnNa is showing up.
Kim...?
How did you know that guy, Kim Shin?
I just came to know him.
That's enough.
Are you dating him?
Thou ought to stop saying that non-sense.
You're the oldest daughter of your family, aren't you.
Pack your stuff in here. We'll talk in your home
After she finishes her preview, sir.
Preview writing is good. She seems to have skill.
If you going to push her out, you need to bring someone for previewing.
Hey, writer Bae. She's my sister.
Because of work here, I couldn't even attend my son's anniversary party.
You may think same way I do.
For us, work comes 1st before family stuff, right?
You said preview didn't even have good terminology.
Terms you can learn in 1 day isn't important.
Integrity is 1st for us, isn't it?
You showed hard work on preview, ma'am.
Thanks.
Team leader,
I'm in hurry, sir.
Ok for now.
However, if your work is done here,
Why don't you leave home, please.
Such a hard ass!
You must be depending on him.
Hey, why you're not calling her instantly?
She'll be here soon.
She's with team leader.
That's why you need to call her now.
She's scammer.That's your idea, sir.
For me, she's one of my team member.
It's correct that she need to see team leader 1st.
What?
Not even appears to be correct to see him 1st?
It appears to be correct as you said.
What do you think you are?
You're just 28 years old, and just new assistant manager.
You're lecturing what's correct to department manager?
Now, you're even trying to take me over?
You think you're chairman here?
Are you a relative of Miranda?
Are you a spy?
I'm sorry, sir. I didn't know.
You like vanilla drinks, don't you?
I'll buy it for you.
Thanks so much.
Only up to your preview, ma'am.
I know you work hard for this.
Hiding that team leader is your brother, and Kim AnNa issue. I don't like it.
That's not what I was trying to hide.Most of all, you're...
You're 32 years old.
You're too old.
I'm main writer; I'm 30 years old.
Pushing new writer into hard working environment, I don't like to do.
You can push me hard, too.
I may be just old, but...I feel uncomfortable.
Why don't you quit.
This time, you leave home, please.
Why don't you quit, now.
Still, I received some recognition on broadcasting.
Is this the only broadcasting station?
Well, I tried to avoid YBS station anyway.
I can work some other stations. Let's go.
Sorry for being late.
Are you awakened now?
Should I use ice cold water instead?
So, how far advanced in your plan?
You may have told this to team leader I dislike, already.
What do you want, money?
Or official writer status?
I'm going to expose all your plan.
It includes your threatening accusation.
I like to know something.
Did you have traffic accident on night before Aug 15th?
How did you know this?
It happened on slow lane of on-ramp to bridge.
You're the one, jack ass.
You said that I'm going to kill the person I have loved.
You think it would be better for you to kill me?
What I love most in this world is myself.
Well... you see.
I'll no longer pretend to be okay or happy.
Eye for an eye, tooth for tooth.
I'll get what I want, no matter what it takes to get it.
But, then you're killing me?
I barely manage to recover a little, then you're killing me again?
Stop your bloody non-sense.
I'll survive no matter what.
My own brother who's looking down on me, and my friends
I'll show to everyone I can be successful, you damn bastards.
Miss, did you see Mr. Kim?
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
No.
I'm not okay.
I'll no longer pretend to be okay.
(Choice for future)
Did you fire her? She's too old.
Should I help you. I have some resources.
You speak up for yourself.
You said you have full of stories you want to tell.
What's your relationship?Did you sleep together?
Person Mr.Kim wanted to hit was Miss Seo?
Hello?
While visiting for his recovery, they became close.
Rumor says they may even get married.
You seem to have acquired program this way, I'm sorry.
I was just assistant manager
They seem to be giving her whole package deal.
I saw something, you know.