Re edit & Sync From: kyr
~CPh0bia~
This somebody' sidea of a joke?
Not mine.
And the rest of these.What are
they, replacements for steel wool?
You wanna keep working here?
Substandard.
Damn it.
All right, you heard the boss, back to work.
What about that meeting?
It's important, jake.
You deal with it.
I'm outta here.
Evening, jakey.
Shanna's in room 12.
Shanna?
You in here?
Ah, so good to see you.
You stink.
Like rotting flesh.
Fur trader.
It's, you know, my work.
But someday... someday it's gonna
make mea very rich man.
And you'd like that,
wouldn't you, shanna?
Someday, someday, someday.
If I had a dollar for every
"someday" I heard in this dump,
I could've bought myself a
job as a supermodel by now.
That's not allowed.
Come on, gimme.
No.
Come on, come on.
I paid ya.
Not for whatyou wanna do.
You know the rules, you pig.
If you don't stop it,
I'll call security.
Get out. Out.
Get out. Get out.
You bastard.
Okay, I'm goin', I'm goin,
but one day, you'll give it to me.
I don't like it this far out here, pa.
What if we get caught?
The only way we're gonna
get caught, larry,
- is if you keep yappin',
- Yeah, so shut up.
This is mother mayter'sland, ain't it, pa?
And?
And we're not supposed to
go out there, are we?
I mean, maybe there's a reason people
don't go this deep into the woods.
What if something gets us?
I went in yesterday to
set the traps, didn't I?
And I came out okay, didn't I?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, but. Go on.
Mother mayter has done a good job
spreading stories for generations.
To scare people off the land.
It's a bunch of crap.
Those stories don't scare me,
cause I know bullshit when I hear it.
What are all these structures?
What are you gonna do? Pee yourself?
They're nothin'.
They said they was
ruins from some old.
Some old city.
Well, that is amazing.
Enough. And be quiet, you hear?
Bingo.
Hey, there's raccoons in all
the traps you set down there.
I told you it will be all right.
You remember how I told you it's done?
Yeah, I crush their throats.
First you turn
the mover on their backs.
Then you put your
hee lon their windpipe.
And you stomp down real hard.
If you do it right, you'll
hear a good crunch.
That'll be their windpipe shattering.
Oh, well.
The heel ain't gonna
work with them.
They still got some
pepper left in 'em.
It ain't?
That's what the bat's for.
You give 'em a bunch of good whacks.
I've seen it take
up to 50 swings once,
so you just keep swingin' until
you crush their fuckin' skulls.
Okay.
We've go to ur selves some.
Some traps to clear.
Hey, pa.
Look at this.
Come look.
Well, I'll be damned.
What do you think happened?
That critter must've chewed
its own paw off.
You really gotta wanna get
free to do something like that.
We got almost a dozen
beauties here, son.
In all my years, I ain't
never seen pelts this pretty.
I can hardly believe they're coon.
We're gonna have money to burn
when we sell them to feldman.
Shit.
It's mother mayter.
Let's get the hellout of here.
Thick as can be.
And not a bald sporto a scar.
Primes, larry.
Yeah, dad.
They sure are beauty, pa.
And you know, the amazing thing
is that they're all identical.
As if all those coons came
from the same big family.
Give me, uh, kind of a funny
feeling, you know?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Make me feel all warm inside.
Yeah, and all that money that
feld man is gonna pay for 'em,
that gives me a good, warm feeling.
Listen.
I- I'm gonna hit the
sack after I phone feldman.
So you stay here and
clean up. Understand?
Yes, sir.
This better be good.
How about pelts.
Of such an out standing quality that
you'd be willing to pay 10 times
the going price just to have 'em.
And out of the kindness of my heart,
I'll give you first crack at 'em.
Jameson, the only reason
you'd give me first crack is
because there is not another chump east of the pacific
ocean who will even take your fuckin' phone call.
You keep makin' jokes, feldman,
the loss is gonna be all yours.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hold on.
What's your stock, jameson?
Coon.
But trust me, feldman.
You've never seen pelts like these before.
They're gonna make you a rich man.
They're gonna give you.
Whatever it is that your heart desires.
You better not be bullshittin' me.
Jameson, I do not have the time to head out into the
fuckin' boonies on some wild fuckin' goose chase.
You just get here before I change my mind.
You better not be bullshittin' me.
They're just so damn beautiful.
Hey, wake up.
What is it? What?
What do you want?
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
That's where the bat comes in.
I seen it take upwards of 50 swings once.
Fuckin' hillbilly bastard.
Jameson.
It's feldman.
Go on in, lo...
Hello?
You see anything?
No.
Jameson?
No matter how many times I smell it,
I'll never get used to the
stench of dried blood.
My god.
Jameson was not bullshittin' me.
How long we beenin the for business, lou?
15? 20?
You ever seen anything
like these pelts?
Nothin', boss.
Absolutely nothin'.
Pelts like these.
The sky's the limit.
We can have anything our hearts desire.
What the fuck was that?
Jameson.
Is that you?
Fuckin' hell.
Jesus christ, jake.
He fell face first into it.
Where's jameson?
What the hell happened here, jake?
Can you believe those pelts though?
You gotta be kidding me.
No.
Can you imagine.
The coat that we can make with those pelts?
We might finally have something
to make a little noise next month.
Cirio?
The world's biggest international for show.
It doesn't get any bigger than that.
When we gonna call the cops, jake?
Yeah. Yeah.
We'll call them from the highway.
Anonymously.
Come on.
All right. Let's get this.
Let's go.
Come on, lady.
Let's go. Get 'em inside.
What's got them, boss?
Probably had some bad fuckin' egg
rolls for lunch, lo...
Who the fuck cares? Come on.
Get them inside and let's go.
By this time next week, lou,
we're gonna have one of the
world's most extraordinary for coats.
After cirio, sky's the limit.
Sky is the limit.
We're gonna need the right
model though, you know?
Somebody worthy of the coat,
otherwiseit's all for nothing.
Lou, I already got somebody in mind.
No, don't stop.
Damn it.
Go away.
Shit.
- Who is it?
- Don't stop.
- Damn it.
- No.
I'm so sick of this shit.
Chill out. Okay?
Yeah?
Somebody's here to see you, shanna.
He says it's important.
Tell him I'm busy.
Shanna.
It's me.
Jake feldman.
It's okay. Let him in.
He smells like a god damn
slaughter house.
He's hopeless.
I got a business proposition for you.
I've heard your propositions before.
Man, how many times do
I have to tell you?
I'm not in to that.
I'll never let you have that.
Not for all the money in the world.
This is a straight,
down-the-line business deal.
I'm making a coat and I want
you to wear it next month.
At cirio.
Cirio?
It's been a while since I've
done a legitimate fashion show.
Shanna, I wanna do this show,
and I don't wanna do anything.
Once you see the coat
that I'm makin' for you.
These pelts.
Are unbelievable.
Well.
We'll see. Okay?
No.
The coat will be finished next week.
I'll bring it to your place.
I know what you like.
We'll see.
No.
Cutting is an art, sergio.
Fuck that up again.
And I'll cut your nuts off my self.
Capisce?
Can you imaginean endless
supply of those pelts, boss?
Yeah.
I'll take us to the coons from
wherever jameson trapped 'em.
To the coons.
A breeding pair.
Where you going?
Where'd you trap those pelts, jameson?
Oh, yeah.
Hello there, ma'am.
You must be mother mayter.
My name is jake feldman, and I, uh.
I brought you.
A bottle of moonshine.
I... I just need to ask
you a few questions.
Do you mind if I come up there?
Come.
I've been expecting you.
You wanted to see me?
Yeah.
About the animals.
The one son your land.
The pine lights, you mean?
Pine lights.
Many years ago,
a whole nest of the pine lights gathered deep
in the woods in the clearing just beyond here.
They became.
Sentinels of the lost city.
So.
Pine lights.
Clearings. Sentinels. Lost city.
No disrespect, but.
What has that got to do with anything?
It's why I walled off my land.
It's why I warn people about trespassing.
---------
---------------
To protect them?
Is, uh.
Is that them?
Are they the pine lights?
Yeah
I was wonderin'
if you'd be willing to give
me a couple of the, uh.
Raccoons?
Now, obviously, I'd be
willin' to pay you for them.
It was you the other night, wasn't it?
- You killed them.
- No, ma'am. Of course not.
You were the reason they died.
- To satisfy your vanity.
- No, ma'am.
- Your callousness.
- No!
*******
***********
They have not had their final say.
They have not finished with you yet.
What's the matter, lou?
Sue chin yao.
What the hell happened?
She suffocated.
What?
We had to pull an all nighter
to make sure the coat was ready.
Apparently she sent the other seam stresses
home around 4:00 in the morning.
Said she could finish it herself.
She was the only one
here when this happened.
You tellin' me she did this to herself?
Did you call the police yet?
No, I was waitin' for you.
Okay. Good.
Go ahead and call 'em.
But keep things as
quiet as possible.
- Hey, jake.
- The last thing.
That we need.
Is a lot of bad publicity.
Lot of bad shit's been happening around here
ever since we started working on this coat.
It's like it's cursedor something.
I don't believe in curses, lo...
You shouldn't have come here, jake.
I just wanted to show you the coat.
You wanna see it, right?
Okay okay. You wait.
You wait till you see this.
Wait.
Are you ready?
Look at this.
Look at this, shanna.
Yes. Oh, my god.
You're right, jake.
It's... it's beautiful.
- Can I.
- Let's try it oninside.
The light's better.
Fuck wearing the coatin some show.
I just wanna have it.
You have a very good chance.
I might just give it to you.
Good chance?
Well, we've got it out to a
couple of other models.
We've gotta give the
ma chance to audition.
I don't want anyone
wearing this coat but me.
We'll see.
Really?
Believe me, baby, this is the
only audition you'll need.
Stop.
Too god damn big.
Where's your bathroom?
It's down there.
I gotta... gotta find something sharp.
What?
I gotta freshen up.
I've done a lot worse for a lot less.
Shanna. Shanna.
Hey, is everything okay?
Your... your skin is gone.
I made it for you.
My work of art.
I did this to impress you.
Help me.
Oh, my god.
Shanna.
Get away from me.
He was my friend.
You know this guy?
Let's get somebody over here.
Yeah, you.You.Come here.
Get a statement.