(Loud bang)
(Alarm beeps)
(Groaning)
Great.
("Beauty Killer"
by Jeffree Star)
* So self-obsessed with
my mascara and mistakes
* Vanity's like a funeral
and everyone's at my wake
* Before I run out of air
there's more makeup to apply
* Doll eyes stare into
Valium-colored skies
* I've got a sweet tooth
and strawberry youth
* You wanna be my licorice
and misguided youth
* And right now
I'll show you how
* I'm a beauty killer
* Rhinestone my eyes closed
and please fix my hair
* This concealer can't
hide all my pink nightmares
* Before I run out of air
there's more makeup to apply
* Doll eyes stare into
Valium-colored skies
* I almost died
but it felt great
* Faking perfection
wasn't worth the wait
* I may be easy, easy to hate
* But you're so fucking
easy, easy to break
* I've got a sweet tooth
and strawberry youth
* You wanna be my licorice
and misguided truth
* And right now
I'll show you how
* I'm a beauty killer
* Doll eyes stare into
Valium-colored skies
* I'm a beauty killer
* Gorgeous killer
* Hot pink killer
* Fierce killer
* I'm a beauty killer
* I'll fucking kill you
Hello Novella.
Oh, hey Tracy.
What happened to your agent?
What's that?
Oh, I saw that you're
not with Teller & Davis
On the sign-in sheet.
Oh yeah, I've been
thinking about moving on
For a while now.
Really, hmm.
Olivia Thompson said
they let you go.
No, I moved on.
Did you ever get
a call back for that
Budweiser commercial?
Sure didn't.
Oh really?
Well, I got the part.
We're lensing next week.
Oh.
That's great.
Who's the producer on that?
Kurt Hansen.
I thought he was gay.
What does that matter?
Because he's
obviously hiring you
So you could blow him.
Everyone does.
What would a gay
guy get out of that?
Fuck off.
I mean I guess it
doesn't really matter,
Getting your dick
sucked by a girl
Probably feels
the same as a guy.
Besides, it's not like
he's butt-fucking you,
Although I'm sure you
offered that, too.
You can say whatever
you want to, darling.
But the truth is,
you're terrible.
That's why you
don't get the parts.
Oh yeah?
Yeah, what are you, like 40?
I'm barely 30, idiot.
Okay, let's see here.
Oh, Tracy.
Hey baby, come on in.
Um, ma'am?
We were here first.
Sorry sweetie, but the
producer specifically
Requested her for this one.
I'm sure they did.
Yeah, sorry sweetie.
Eat your heart out.
What a bitch.
I know right?
(Car alarm unlock tweets)
(Shrill static)
Shit.
(Knocking)
Eesha.
Novi!
Hi, Eesha.
How are you, I just
saw you coming in.
I'm good, how is Jethro doing?
Oh, he's doing fine,
he just has started
Picking on his privates so I
had to put the cone back on.
It must be strange to
have your privates cut off
Like that, you know?
Poor little guy.
Yeah, so did you have
any auditions or callbacks?
Yeah, I had some
auditions today.
How did they go?
Good, you know, we'll see.
I just wanted to know
how your month was going,
It's almost the end of
the month, you know?
Mmm-hmm, yeah,
time sure flies by.
It sure does, yeah,
it just seems like
Last month just ended.
Sure does.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
Well um, have a good night.
You too, bye Jethro.
Say bye-bye Jethro,
come on, say bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Oh, bye-bye, he's
saying bye-bye.
Okay.
Oh, bye-bye, oh bye-bye.
(Phone vibrates)
Hello?
Oh hey, what's up?
Yeah.
Sure.
I'll see you there in 20.
Eh, I'll tell you
about it later.
Okay, yeah, sounds good.
Cool.
See you then, bye.
Whatever.
So then the casting
director comes out,
Doesn't even look at
the sign-in sheet,
And lets Tracy audition.
She didn't even
look at the list.
Is she the bitch that got
the commercial over you?
Not just the
commercial, but like,
The last four or five
roles I've tried out for.
I hate her.
Was she that good?
I don't know, I haven't
seen any of her shit.
Well, is she really
hot or something?
No.
I mean she's cute, but not like
Out-of-this-world beautiful.
Right.
And she's got like
this snaggletooth.
Oh, gross.
She's younger, that's
mostly the reason.
Well how young?
I don't know, early 20s.
Whatever it says on my headshot.
Look Novi, I know that
this has been really tough
For you, okay?
But you're a really good
actress, and I think
That you just need
to tough this out.
Candice, I haven't
gotten a part
In the last three years.
Nothing, not even
a corporate video.
Well you're not trying to
do a corporate video, Novi.
I mean you're trying
to become a movie star
So that you can fuck
Michael Fasbecker.
Candice I can't get anything.
So what, are you
gonna quit, just because
You're going through
a rough patch?
A rough patch is three
weeks or three months,
Not three years.
I think that you should
give it a couple more weeks.
I mean, it's always
darkest right before
The sun comes up.
It's before the dawn.
What?
Nothing.
So, you girls wanna
dance or something?
It's Candice and Novella, right?
Why don't you go
grab me another drink?
Another one?
You haven't said two
words to me all night.
Well, I'm sorry
baby, but you know,
We've just been
talking about some
Really serious shit
over here, you know?
Yeah, sounds like it.
You know what?
If you go get me another
drink I'll make it up to you,
I promise, I'm just
starting to get my buzz on.
Yeah, great.
Look, I have a gun
right here in my purse,
And I'm not afraid to
shoot your dick off
Right now on this couch.
But if you go get
me and my girlfriend
Another drink, I'll be
happy to make it up to you
With a handjob in the bathroom.
So now which one of those
scenarios would you prefer?
Hmm?
Baby girl, do you
want another drink?
Yep.
Hey, Louis CK, yeah, you.
You wanna get my girl
a vodka and soda?
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Shit, you know
what, I've gotta pee,
I'll be like two seconds, okay?
Can't you wait,
we're on our way out.
Novi, I've already
like, broken the seal,
I mean that dipshit just
bought me like, four beers.
I'll be right back.
Well hurry up,
I don't feel good.
Okay, I'll be right
back, but just watch out
For Ren and Stimpy, okay?
How's it goin'?
What's your name?
Novella.
Are you an actress?
Why do you ask?
You have a movie star name.
Thanks.
What's your last name?
McClure.
Really?
That's an incredible name.
What do you do?
I'm an actress.
Seriously?
I knew it, you're
beautiful and skinny,
You have an amazing name.
Don't worry I'm not
gonna friend you
On Facebook or anything.
Oh, good.
So uh, what's your
name and occupation?
Me?
Um, my name is
Simon, I am a doctor.
Call me Dr. Simon if you want.
That's what I call myself, so.
Are you really a doctor?
I am.
So, do you save
people's lives and stuff?
I do, if you
consider saving lives
Talking to rich people
about how bored they are.
Mmm, not so much.
Yeah, me neither.
I usually just tell
people I'm a surgeon,
But, I don't know, you
bring out the truth in me.
I have that effect on people.
Maybe you should just
change your name to Polly.
What?
Like a polygraph test?
Okay.
Yeah, it's a lie
detector test, yeah.
I was really going 'til
that last one, huh?
Yeah, it kinda came
out of left field.
Uh, speaking of which,
looks like I'm up to bat, so.
You have a boyfriend
or something?
Hey, let's go.
Come on.
Nice to meet you, Dr. Simon.
You too.
Novella McClure.
(Loud bang)
Ugh.
Oh, my god this is so stupid.
Shit.
Oh, fuck, that's right.
Hi there.
What's your name?
Novella McClure.
Miss McClure, I was
hoping you'd make it out.
Oh, really?
Are you a casting agent?
Oh no, I'm just
helping out today.
Oh, well thanks,
I'm happy to be here.
Ha ha, I'm sorry,
what I meant was,
I've seen you before, and
you have a great look.
Do you do any modeling?
Of course I do modeling,
are you looking for models?
A friend of mine
has a company, and is
Looking for some new faces.
He's really talented.
Oh, well what's the
name of the company?
Oh, well I'm
not sure, but he's
A really great photographer
and film maker.
Where's it based out of?
I think he said San Fernando.
Look sweetie, I'm not stupid.
No thanks.
I'm sorry, did I
say something wrong?
I don't do porn.
What?
This is not my first
audition, I've been
Doing this for a while now.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Any modeling company
that doesn't tell you
The name of the company
is a porn company.
No it's not.
Then what's the name of it?
Well, I don't remember.
Have you seen his work?
Well, no but I've
been dating the guy
For a few weeks,
and I think that...
Ah, see there you go.
He knows that you're
interning here
And asked you to collect
headshots and shit, right?
Yeah, but it's
not a porn company.
Has he asked you to audition?
Yeah, but that'd...
You see, there you go.
Stop it, he doesn't
do porn, okay?
Besides, you're the
one with the porn name.
What the hell does that mean?
Well maybe the reason
people keep trying
To cast you in their
porn movies is because
Of your stupid name.
It's not stupid.
What, was Laura Lust
taken or something?
A porn name is your
pet's name, and the street
You grew up on.
Do you really think I'd
name my cat Novella?
Oh fuck me, are you serious?
Be sure to grab her
headshot, she'd love to
Fuck your boyfriend on camera.
Excuse me?
Fuck off, Tracy.
Uh!
Hi, I'm Tracy Armstrong.
Did you need me to sign in?
Oh shit!
Fuck!
Dammit.
(Novella breathed raggedly)
(Knocking)
God dammit!
Oh, hi Novi, how are you?
Eesha can you come back
another time, this isn't
Really a good time.
Well, I just don't know
how to tell you this.
What is it?
Oh shit.
Novi, I have been
trying to tell you this
For three months to pay your
rent but you haven't paid.
I know Eesha, it's not
your fault, it's mine.
I'm sorry, look, I'll
get you a check, okay?
I'm up for a big role
and I'm pretty sure
I'm gonna get the part.
Novi, you have been
saying that since February,
And so far you haven't
paid your rent, you know
I hate doing this.
I know it, I just...
Oh Novi, no look,
don't start crying.
What happened?!
I was in a car accident.
And I had to get a,
a car, a rental car
Just to, I had to get a
rental car to come home
And then go to my audition,
and now I'm being evicted
And I don't have any
money, and I just
Don't have any place to stay.
Okay wait, don't,
don't cry, listen,
Don't worry, look,
look, just sit here
And we'll take care
of your hand, okay?
I'll go get some cleaner.
(Ominous background noise)
(Heart monitor beeping)
Good morning, how
are you feeling?
You've been out all night.
The medication should make you
feel pretty groggy right now.
How are you feeling?
Groggy.
Okay.
I'll go grab the doctor
and I'll send her right in.
No, that's not necessary.
I'll just grab my stuff
and go home, I'm okay.
Oh, no no, you've
had quite the night.
No please, I'm not
a fan of doctors.
I don't trust them.
No offense, you're not a
doctor, so you're cool.
Okay, just sit back and
relax, and I'll send her in.
Fuck.
This is gonna be expensive.
(Knocking)
Hello, Novella,
how are you feeling?
Groggy.
That's probably
the medication.
That's what I hear.
My name is Dr. Morgan Walker.
I'm the psychiatrist
here at the hospital.
Excuse me?
I came to talk to
you about your wrist.
Psychiatrist?
Your friend Eesha
brought you in.
She told me you might
be going through
A tough financial situation.
So I have Eesha
to thank for this?
She saved your life.
Right.
Look Dr. Walker,
I'm not suicidal.
In fact, it's a
really weird story.
Really?
Yeah, would you like
me to tell you about it?
Please.
Okay well, yesterday
when Eesha left,
Well I got nervous, and
whenever I get nervous,
I get hungry.
Does this happen often?
Yeah.
So, well, and I got
a can of peaches out.
Peaches?
Yes, peaches, to eat.
Because I was hungry,
and, well, I love peaches.
And when I was opening
up the can of p-peaches,
I s-s-sliced and slipped on...
Yeah.
Okay, Novella.
I'm going to put you on
24-hour suicide watch.
Do you have any friends or
family who can stay with you?
I don't know.
Miss, I mean Dr. Walker, I'm not
suicidal, I just told you, I...
Miss McClure, the wound
on your hand is a bite mark.
The first responders
thought it might be
From an animal, but the
blood caked on your face,
And pieces of flesh in your
teeth, proved otherwise.
You must have a friend or
family member stay with you.
If not, you'll be
required to stay here.
And I also want
to give you this.
It's for the psychiatric
facility up the street.
You must meet with
a psychiatrist there
Two times a week until
further evaluation.
Is this clear?
Novella.
We're trying to help you.
You don't need to lie to us.
Now I'm gonna send the
nurse in and get you
All cleaned up and ready to go.
Fuck!
So then I go and check
out, and it's gonna cost me
2200 dollars for
one night's stay.
Why did she say it
looked like an animal bite?
She's a lying bitch.
All doctors are.
I was opening up a can
and slipped and now
I have to go see
a god damn shrink
In an insane asylum.
Don't worry about
it so much baby girl,
I'll stay the night
at your place tonight.
We'll make the most out of it,
I actually think
it'll be kind of fun.
Candice, I don't have a place.
I'm being evicted.
Are you kidding me?
Just tell your landlady that
you tried to kill yourself
Because of her.
You've got her wrapped
around your finger.
My apartment is
attached to her house.
I don't think she's gonna
let me live there for free.
Well she has been for
the past three months,
I think you should
just trust me on this.
I don't know, I feel bad.
I get off work at seven,
I think you just need
To talk to your
landlady and everything
Will work itself out.
Okay?
Hey!
Suicide watch, come
on it'll be fun!
Buck up!
(Stomach growling)
Dammit.
(Phone dialing tones)
Thank you for
calling Sun City Bank.
Please enter your password.
(Phone dialing tones)
You have negative 642
dollars and 13 cents.
To access your account
please press one,
Or stay on the line...
(Phone vibrating)
Hello?
Is this Novella?
Yes it is.
Hi, my name's Brad Hatcher.
I'm a film maker
here in Los Angeles
And I was calling
because my girlfriend
Gave me your head shot today.
Oh, cool, who's
your girlfriend?
Uh, the one you
yelled at yesterday.
Oh wow, umm, I'm surprised
she gave it to you,
I was pretty nasty to her.
Me too, actually, but we
all have shitty days, right?
Tell me about it.
Well, my producers and
I are putting together
A small scene and we
all think you have
The perfect look for it.
We'd really like to
talk with you in person,
Um, would you be interested
in coming in to audition?
You know, honestly Brad,
I really appreciate it,
But I've been thinking
about taking some time off
For a while now.
I don't know if she mentioned
this, but it's a paying role.
Oh really, how much?
It's 1500 dollars
for a four-hour scene.
Did you just say 1500 dollars?
I did, will that work for you?
Yeah, uh, when and
where is the audition?
It's at our production
studio in the Valley.
I can text you the
address if you want.
Okay, great,
I'll see you there.
Great, thanks Novella.
Oh, uh, real quick, is this
your current email address
On the back of your headshot?
Uh, yes it is.
Okay cool, I'm gonna send
you some more information
About our films and uh,
any reference materials
You may need, otherwise,
we will see you tomorrow.
Okay, thanks Brad.
Hmm.
(Airy piano music)
(Knocking)
Ow, fuck.
Oh, um, hi Novi.
How are you?
Hey, Eesha, I'm fine.
Sweetie, what happened?
Oh, they let me go from
the hospital this morning,
And I'm just waiting
for my friend Candice.
She should be here soon.
(Jethro barks)
No no no, I mean, why did
you do this to yourself?
(Jethro whining)
I don't know, I, I
just have a lot of things
Going on right now.
You know Novi, don't
worry about your rent.
Oh no, Eesha, I'll
pay you the rent.
You are very special
to me and I don't know
What I will do if
anything happened to you.
Thanks, Eesha.
You are very talented.
And one day you will
be a big movie star.
You don't need this
stress in your life.
(Jethro barks)
What's going on, what
are you wanting there?
Awww!
Oh my god, you are so cute!
Little baby!
Uh, Eesha, this is
my friend Candice.
Candice this is my
landlady, Eesha.
Hi.
Oh, hi.
He likes you, oh
otherwise he turns into
A little ball of barb wire.
Oh he's precious.
Well, you can keep
him if you want to.
Ever since he got his
testicles chopped off,
He's been quite a handful.
Oh, yeah, I don't know,
I think he's pretty sweet.
Oh well I'll leave
you two by yourselves.
Take care, Novi.
Thanks Eesha.
Mmm-hmm.
It was really
nice to meet you.
Oh, nice to meet you too.
And you too, handsome
little man, you say bye-bye?
Say bye.
Oh my god, so precious,
have a good day.
You too.
Bye.
Adorable, oh my god.
So cute.
So what do you
want to do tonight?
Ugh, I need a drink.
Sounds good to me.
Wait a second.
Should we be going
out after you just
Tried to kill
yourself or whatever?
Are you kidding me,
that's exactly why
We should go out.
That's my girl.
I'm gonna go get ready.
Wait, do you have a
dress that I can borrow?
(Club music)
So are we gonna
dance at all tonight?
Baby, I was just dancing.
Yeah, but not with me.
What, you don't like to watch?
I bet you like to
watch, don't you?
You wanna get out of here?
I live really close.
I think that cast
on your arm is hot.
I kinda wanna lick it.
Um, I could use a drink.
Yeah.
I could use another drink, too.
Why don't you boys go get
us another round, okay?
Yeah yeah, but you know
I'm not gonna do this
All night for free,
you know what I mean,
Not for your health, baby.
Yeah, that's really charming.
You know what,
make mine a double.
These guys are
especially douchey.
I think we should
just get another drink
And then we should roll out.
Are you okay?
I have my last
audition tomorrow.
What?
I'm quitting acting.
God, not this again,
I mean can't we just
Get drunk and have some fun?
Candice, I'm serious,
if I get it, I'll get
1500 dollars, and
I'll stick with it.
If not, I'm done.
Really?
What are you gonna do?
I can cut hair with you.
At my shop?
Yeah.
Why would you want to work
there, I hate that place.
Because you make
money and I don't.
I think that you're
doing just fine.
I mean look how nice
your apartment is.
Candice, I got evicted.
No you didn't.
Now you can just keep
doing what you love.
Candice, I don't love it.
I don't love sitting in a
room full of pretty girls,
Girls who would literally
kill me just so they
Could have the part.
You're just paying your dues.
Paying my dues?
It's all dues, it's only dues.
I've been paying my dues
for the last 10 years.
Baby girl, you're
like my blood, okay?
I just don't have
your back on this.
I just can't let you
give up on your dream.
My dream is to be happy.
And I haven't been
happy in a long time.
Especially lately.
You know, I sit in
that shop all day long
Cutting hair while everyone
else is out in the world.
And that's why I've
always loved you
And respected you, Novi.
Because you didn't give
up like I did, I mean,
You fight and you claw
and you struggle every day
So that you can keep
living your dream.
Meanwhile, I sit in
a fucking box all day
Cutting the hair of people
who are total assholes
And making them look pretty.
Here's your double,
you'll like that one.
Oh, thanks.
Uh, gimma peck
on the cheek first.
Are you serious?
Hey what the fuck?!
Get off me!
Cheers!
Okay, sorry.
You know what,
um, I've gotta pee.
Yup, me too.
Excuse me.
Don't be gone too long.
You'll make me sad.
Are um, are you good?
Yeah, I hate that bathroom.
Okay, I'll b-r-b.
Hey.
Oh, hey Dr. Simon.
How are you, Novella?
You remembered my name.
Of course, how could I
forget the one and only
Novella McClure?
By the way, I don't actually
have to go to the bathroom,
I just, I saw you over here.
Alright.
Last time, I had to
go to the bathroom,
But now we're standing
here, how are you?
[Awkward laugh]
I'm okay.
Great.
What happened to your hand?
Oh, car accident.
How bad?
This bad.
Wow, yeah.
Uh, hey so, before your
scary girlfriend comes back,
I wanted to ask you out.
Oh, wow, you just kinda
came out and said it.
Yeah, I sure did, didn't I?
I'm about as shocked as you are.
Um, what do you think?
Go get a cup of coffee,
or eat food together
Or something.
Um, sure, I'm kind
of drunk right now,
So it might not
be the best time.
Oh yeah yeah, of course.
I didn't mean tonight,
I actually have
A new patient in
the morning, so.
I will give you my number.
That way you don't have to
call if you don't want to.
It's a win-win situation
for you, you know?
Well I appreciate the
option, but I will call.
Great.
So what, you're boyfriend's...
Oh god no, they're
just a tab for the night.
Really?
That's probably not the
safest way to get a drink.
It's the cheapest though.
(Laughing)
Just so you know,
if we do go out,
You can have whatever you want.
You don't have to slip out
back afterwards, either.
Sounds like a good plan to me.
Okay, well I'm going to
quit while I'm still ahead.
I will call you
soon, Dr. Simon.
Talk to you then.
Novella McClure.
(Muffled voice from bathroom)
Yeah, and now you can
go, just like I said.
[Bathroom girl] It
took you long enough,
Did you get it all?
You wanna take
it outside, bitch?
[Bathroom girl]
Fuck off, bitch!
That's what I thought.
Fucking bitch.
Everything okay?
Yeah, it's fine,
there's just some hipster
Bitch in the bathroom
starting shit.
Let's just go, come on.
Uh, do you remember what...
I know where the
car is, come here.
It's this way.
Oh.
Those guys were
like stupid douchey.
Well they were assholes.
Dude, I feel pretty
drunk right now.
Are you okay to drive?
Yeah I just, well I
don't know, I feel kind of
Fucked up, but just
give me the key.
Shit.
Me too.
Oh, shit.
(Muffled background noise)
Something's wrong.
There you are!
Ha ha ha ha!
I told you not to run
away from me, Stumpy.
Candice, shit, we
have to get out of here!
We've been buying
you little girls drinks
All night long.
And here you are,
trying to run out on us.
Ron kind of figured
you were gonna do that.
I thought you might
need a little something,
Extra, to get you in the mood.
Extra, extra!
It'll be okay baby girl, okay?
So remember when I said
I wanted to lick you?
Well now you are gonna lick me.
Rub along those teeth like
that, just brushin' 'em...
Do what he says, okay?
What?!
I like this one.
Fuck yeah!
Oh, god I can't
wait to fuck you.
It'll be fun, just
do what he says.
Yeah, come on, just do it.
Listen to your friend, come
on, come on just suck it.
Suck it, slut!
Here, allow me.
Aaaahhhh!
Novi, get in the car.
(Novi screaming)
Why did you do that?!
I don't know, they
were fucking rapists,
What the fuck was
I supposed to do?
Could you at least tell me?
It was kind of a
last-minute decision, Novella!
Candice, we're
gonna get arrested!
We're not gonna get
arrested, we're gonna go home!
(Screaming)
Oh my god!
(Tires squealing)
(Men moaning and screaming)
(Faint police sirens)
I still feel kinda woozy.
Is it okay if I crash
in your bed tonight?
You're supposed to, remember?
Are you okay?
You look kinda sick.
What the fuck was that?
You know that I carry a gun.
Yeah but you never use it.
Well I do when two assholes
are about to rape us!
You know what?
I really don't feel great.
I'm just...
I'm gonna go lay down.
You're welcome?
By the way.
Yeah, thanks.
Oh, ow.
Ow.
Candice!
Candice, I need your help.
What's wrong?
I feel like I'm starving.
Well go get something to eat.
No, I think it's
worse than that.
I need you to take
me to the hospital.
Ugh, we'll go first
thing in the morning
And we'll get burgers and stuff.
No...
Candice, wake up.
God dammit!
Wake up.
(Novi sobbing and
breathing raggedly)
Ow, ow!
Ow!
(Novi moaning and screaming)
(Shrill static)
Novi, be back at seven,
hope you're feeling better,
Good luck at your audition.
Audition?
Fuck!
(Ragged breathing)
Novella?
We, have been looking
forward to meeting you.
Thanks, I've been looking
forward to this as well.
Uh, I hope you don't
mind my asking, but uh,
What happened to your hand?
Oh, I was in a car
accident a few days ago.
Jeez, is everything okay?
Yeah, I just hurt
my arm and my foot.
It's no big deal.
Did it hurt your eyes?
Oh, sorry.
So, I explained a
little bit about this
In the email, but
we're still looking
For our lead actress and we
think you have the perfect look.
Awesome.
You did get the email, right?
Sorry, I haven't read it yet.
Oh, that's okay, it had
a couple sides in there
For you to read, but you have
something prepared, right?
Yeah, I have a
monologue I did for a play
A few years back.
Sounds awesome.
(Novi sighs)
They look at me
as if I'm not there.
They listen to me
as if I don't speak.
As I walk through the
darkness of my life,
All I can hope for
is to find the light.
No one knows who I
am, or what I can be.
What I can become, only I do.
And I fight, and
I climb, and I try
With every ounce of
strength in my body
To break down these walls.
But it's never enough.
My heart hammers at my chest,
Begging to escape,
pounding so hard it hurts.
It hurts unlike any pain
I've ever felt before.
And I have felt a lot.
One day I will show
the world who I am,
Not the person they see,
but the person I am.
I will find the light.
They will see me.
They will hear me.
(Laughing)
That was amazing,
seriously, did Steve
Put you up to this?
Who's Steve?
Oh, Novella honey, you
didn't get the email, did you?
No, why?
We're making Anal Alien 7,
not fucking Hamlet, sweetheart.
I was a little excited
there for a second
I was like, monologue
from a play?
Fuck yeah, I love porno plays!
Yeah, Novella.
Do you do anal?
(Sad music)
Hi Novella.
Hey Simon, what are you...
Oh my god.
It's okay, come on in.
Jesus, I didn't
even think about this.
It'll be alright, I promise.
Step in my office, please.
Fuck.
Dr. Simon.
Oh, shit.
Can I get you
something to drink?
No.
Anything that would make
you feel more comfortable?
I'm pretty sure nothing can
make this more comfortable.
Fair enough.
Okay, um, where to start?
Simon, seriously,
I wasn't too thrilled
About this whole
thing to begin with,
And I know that I'm required
to talk with a shrink,
But this isn't gonna work.
Besides, I've had
the shittiest day...
Okay, I know.
I know.
Look, I take suicide
patients from the hospital
So rarely, but they
offer them to me, okay?
They give me a list of
files, they ask if I want
To take any of them on pro Bono.
And I saw your name on the
list, I thought I could help.
Well this isn't what I had
in mind for a first date.
Me neither.
Look I like you.
I don't even know
you, and I like you.
But when I saw that you
tried to kill yourself...
I didn't try to kill myself.
Right.
Can of peaches try to take
a bite out of your arm?
Novella, you're a
beautiful woman, alright?
And I know we've only
talked a few times,
But you're an incredible person.
I help people, every day,
people who don't deserve it.
You need help, alright
not because you're crazy
Or suicidal, or
anything like that.
I wanted to help you because
you should have never
Felt like you needed
to leave this world.
It's better with you in it.
I rent this room
from the facility,
It's not even
mine, that diploma,
No idea whose that is.
Are you hungry?
Are you serious?
Let's go grab some lunch.
Just don't tell anyone.
You like tacos?
I love tacos.
How much, though?
Go grab some.
So where do you live?
I actually have a place
a few miles from here.
It's an apartment attached
to my landlady's house.
Live alone?
Yeah, but my friend Candice
is staying with me right now.
She's my suicide watch dog.
Yeah, your scary
friend from the club.
She's not scary.
Are you kidding
me, she's terrifying!
She's got bigger arms
than I do, and I work out.
Sometimes.
She's a sweetheart.
Actually, she did shoot
two guys last night.
What?!
So Candice always carries
this gun in her purse,
Just in case.
Do you remember those guys we
were dancing with last night?
Yeah.
Well, they tried to rape
us in the parking lot,
So Candice blew off their dicks.
Oh my god!
Oh, that's awful.
But you can't say
anything, right, that whole
Confidentiality thing?
Oh, totally.
Just eating tacos, anyway.
Seriously, that's
fucked up, are you okay?
Yeah, I mean Candice
always has my back.
In fact buddy, better watch out.
I got it!
I was gonna offer
to talk to her, but
I think I want to avoid her now.
Yeah, that's
probably a good idea.
So, this isn't so bad, right?
Feel like you can talk
to me about things?
It's better than
listening to some douchebag
Talk all night just so I
can score a free drink.
I bet.
Wanna tell me what
happened to your arm?
I've just been going
through a lot lately.
Yeah, like what?
I haven't landed a
role in over three years.
How are you able to
pay for everything?
I've had some
inheritance money saved up,
And that well is
pretty much dry now.
So, oh, and I got
in a car accident.
Oh you really did
get in a car wreck?
Yeah, that's what
happened to my foot.
And when I got home,
my landlady told me
I was gonna be evicted.
So I don't know I just,
I just snapped, you know?
I just bit my wrist
as hard as I could.
You know, when things
start to pile up,
It's good if you have
something you can count on
To make you happy.
A place you can go, a family
member you can talk to,
Even a television show
you like to watch.
Do you have anything like that?
I don't know.
Come on.
How about acting?
You know, a few years
ago I'd have probably
Said yes, but I just...
When I was younger, and
stupid shit would happen
It didn't bother me because
I was young and stupid.
But now that I'm older, it's
just not me anymore you know?
Times change.
Exactly.
It's just not me.
Maybe it's time
you start being you.
I've been thinking that
a lot lately, actually.
Speaking of which, I like you.
Isn't that breaking some
sort of rule or something?
I don't know, probably.
No, definitely.
It's true though, I like you.
I talk to people all
day, I don't like them.
You, I like.
That's very sweet.
What are you doing tonight?
Tonight?
Mmm-hmm.
You gonna go to the club,
castrate a few more guys?
I guess I could always
do that this weekend.
Great!
(Novi laughs)
Have dinner with me, then.
Actually, that sounds great.
Hey there.
Jeez!
You scared me.
Sorry.
You're home early.
Yeah, I just, I wanted to
talk to you about last night.
Are you okay?
Yeah, it was just
intense, I've never seen
Anyone shot before, let alone
right in front of my face.
I was talking about you
being sick last night.
Fuck those guys.
Me being sick?
Last night?
In the bathroom, you were sick?
And then this morning I
tried to open the door
And you locked yourself
in there, I mean
Are you okay?
Yeah it was just the ruffi.
I'm sorry I didn't
take you to the hospital,
I just got so fucked up
that I passed out, you know?
It's cool.
I mean those guys had
it coming, you know?
I mean if anybody tries
to fuck with you or me
Then I'll fuck 'em up.
Clearly.
Well yeah, clearly.
I'm sorry, um, but do
you think that those guys
Are ever going to fuck
with any girl ever again?
Candice, I'm more worried
about being a wanted fugitive.
I would love to hear that.
Um, uh, these girls
tried to rob us, uh,
In an alley, and we
didn't know what to do,
So we just ran away with our
tails between our legs, uh...
Okay, but if we get
busted, you're on your own.
Novi, can we just forget
about this whole gun thing?
It's not that big of a deal!
Jesus.
What happened to your foot?
From the car accident.
You didn't tell me about that.
I didn't?
No, you didn't tell
me about your foot.
Don't you think you
should see a doctor?
Candice, do you not understand
the concept of being broke?
I have enough medical
bills to pay for.
I don't know, Novi, your
foot looks kinda gangrene.
I'll clean it later.
Eww.
Gross.
Are you going on a date?
Yep.
No shit, with who?
Dr. Simon.
Who the fuck is Dr. Simon?
The guy from the
club the other night.
Hmm.
I don't remember him.
And if you're going on
a date, you should not
Wear that dress, it makes your
sides flip out like a muffin.
Well get this.
He's actually my doctor.
Your doctor.
You hate doctors.
Not my doctor
doctor, my shrink.
Huh.
Is that like illegal
or something?
I don't care.
I didn't want to do that
therapy shit anyway.
And he's sweet, he cares
about me, and I like
Talking to him.
I like that dress.
You look really
hot in that dress.
It's not weird, really.
And, he thinks I should
quit acting, too.
What?!
Yeah.
He agrees with me, it's
just not me anymore.
So, are you just gonna
do whatever Simon says?
I'm sorry, that's just
really bold of him to say
Considering that he
barely even knows you.
Well, maybe you
don't really know me.
What the fuck is
that supposed to mean?
Candice, I've been going
through a lot lately,
And you don't really
seem to support me.
Are you fucking kidding me?
No, I'm not!
Fucking amazing!
I mean, really!
You know what?
Let me compose a list for you.
When you tried to kill yourself,
who was there for you, me.
And when you needed
someone to stay with you
Every night this week,
who was there for you, me.
And when two fucking
assholes tried to rape you
In a back alley, who
was there for you, me!
I know, Jesus, Candice!
I've just gone through a
lot lately and I really
Need you to support
me and you're not!
I just need some space!
Gimme some fucking room
to breathe, you're always
Fucking smothering me!
You know what?
You can have your fucking space.
Unbelievable.
God dammit!
(Ominous background noise)
I'm sorry, I have
absolutely zero manners.
It's fine, really.
I prefer it to
the salad-pickers.
Yeah, I've always been an
eater, the more meat the better.
Mmm, you from Texas?
Bakersfield.
I am so sorry.
I know, right?
How could you have ever left?
Tell me about it.
It wasn't too bad though.
It was just boring.
So, where's your family?
Well, my mom left
when I was really young.
Mmm-hmm.
And my dad died a
few years after that.
He was getting a minor
operation and the doctors
Screwed up and killed him.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Is that where you
got your inheritance?
It was a cash
settlement, actually.
It's lasted me all these
years, but, you know
I'd give it all away just
so I could have him back.
Absolutely.
After that, I lived
with my aunt and uncle,
It was pretty awful.
What?
You know, the usual stuff.
An abusive uncle.
Something that will give
us plenty to talk about
In a session someday.
Good, I'll look
forward to it then.
So what'd you do today?
Mmm, I had another
patient for an hour
And then I went home.
You?
I went home, I actually
got in a fight with Candice.
About what?
I don't know, she
can kinda be annoying.
How long you two been friends?
Since that creepy uncle.
She helped me run away from him.
Sounds like she's
a real friend.
Yeah.
She's pretty badass.
She always has my back.
How do you feel about dessert?
Just, scale of one to 10.
I'd love to.
Yeah?
It's actually, it's not here.
I'm sure it's wonderful here.
Do you trust me?
What is it?
Life-changing is what it is.
(Novi laughs)
Sure.
Viola!
Oh my god.
I told you, they're
worth waiting for.
Will I appreciate
these even though
I'm kind of drunk?
Novella, darling, the dead
can appreciate these cookies.
Here.
Woo!
Still a little hot, careful.
Thank you.
Hold on!
Together.
Mmm!
Mmm.
(Wistful music)
Oh my god.
What?
(Shrill static)
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You okay?
Yeah, I just had a bad dream.
Good.
We can talk about it
in our session today.
You still want me to come in?
Sure, why not?
I have a few appointments
in the morning,
But then maybe we can
spend the day together.
Okay, sounds great.
Novi, baby, how are you?
Hey Eesha, how are you?
Oh, I'm fine.
Did you have a long night?
I did.
Were you with a boy?
I was, I was indeed.
Is he handsome?
Oh, very.
So, what does he do?
He's a psychiatrist.
A doctor!
Oh my Novi, I am
so happy for you.
Thanks, I really like him.
I bet you are, and it's
about time that we had
Some little grandbabies
running around here.
I think so, too.
Have you ever
decorated a baby?
It's so much fun.
What's wrong with
you, you little shit?
He gets really jealous when
I talk about grandchildren.
I bet he does.
Well, I need to go but,
if boyfriend comes over,
Be sure to introduce him to me.
I must approve.
I will.
Bye, Eesha.
Bye, Novi.
Come on, come on.
Well well, look who's
doing the walk of shame.
Hey, don't hate
the playa baby.
I came home last
night and you were gone
And I got kind of worried.
Seriously?
Yeah.
You made me realize that
sometimes I can just kind of
Freak out about stuff, you know?
Uh, yeah, I know.
I don't know, I just...
I don't know, sometimes
I just feel like I...
You know what, I don't know.
I know.
I'll try to lay off.
Thanks.
Do you like him?
He's amazing.
And he bakes cookies.
Really?
Are they any good?
Life-changing.
Well, if you like
him then I like him.
So I was talking to Sara
at the shop the other day.
And I told her that
you like to do my hair,
You know what she said?
What?
That you can come by the
shop whenever you want to
And take a look around.
Are you serious?
Yeah, totally serious.
Thank you so much.
What are you doing home?
I have off work.
I thought I'd go on
a hike or go shopping
Or some shit like
that in a little bit.
Do you wanna go?
Well I do, but Simon and I
are gonna go grab some lunch.
Right.
You guys are totally
still in your
Honeymoon phase, aren't you?
Yeah, I guess we are.
I'm happy for you.
Thanks, I am happy.
But seriously, if
he breaks your heart
I'll fucking kill him.
(Novi laughs)
I will!
I'm serious!
I know you would.
Are you following me?
What the hell
are you doing here?
I'm meeting someone.
Who?
Simon?
Yeah.
Like, for an appointment?
Sort of.
We're kind of seeing each other.
(Tracy laughs)
Why are you laughing?
You're kidding me, right?
No, I'm not.
Then what are you doing here?
I have an appointment
in an hour, and I had
Nothing else to do so I
thought I'd come here early.
Did you try to kill yourself?
No, I didn't.
Why would you do that?
I didn't!
Yes, you did.
Why?
Tracy, I didn't
try to kill myself,
Why do you think I
tried to kill myself?
Because I...
I tried to kill myself.
Last year.
That's when I
started seeing Simon.
Why would you try
to kill yourself?
I asked you first.
Because my life sucks.
So does mine.
Your life is amazing.
You get all the roles,
and you're beautiful.
God, I wish I had half as
much success as you do.
And you're 10 years
younger than me.
I haven't gotten a
part since I moved here.
What are you talking about?
I haven't.
I just say I do.
It makes me feel better.
So then why do all the
casting directors and producers
Request you, why do
you have an agent?
Because.
I do everything you say I do.
What?
I uh, I sleep with them.
And they always say
they'll give me the part,
And they never do.
They just use me.
Ugh, I'm disgusting.
No you're not, don't say that.
Yes, I am, I disgust myself.
And that's probably why I try
to cut you down all the time,
Because you're so much
stronger than I am.
No I'm not, trust me.
Yes, you are.
But I never would
have thought you would
Give in to Simon.
What do you mean?
His game.
What are you talking about?
Oh no, oh no.
- What...
- I'm sorry.
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
Tracy, tell me!
Simon does this all the time.
Does what?
Okay, he calls the
hospital, he asks for
Suicidal girls.
Then he pretends
he's Prince Charming,
And he sleeps with them.
I heard him telling
his friends about it.
No, that's not true.
Simon and I knew
each other way before
I ever started coming here.
Then that's probably
why he picked you.
No Tracy, he didn't pick me.
This is different!
Novella, I'm not
trying to be mean.
I'm sorry.
Then why do you
keep coming here?
Because, he
makes me feel good.
All the other guys
don't even talk to me.
At least he pretends I'm
there when we're having sex.
Oh my god.
This isn't happening.
Novella, I'm so sorry.
Shut up, Tracy!
If it makes you feel...
Shut the fuck up
you fucking slut!
You're fucking lying to me!
Fuck you!
What the hell is going on?
Why are you crying?
(Ominous background music)
(Novella screams and sobs)
(Retching)
What the fuck is
wrong with you?!
(Indistinct yelling)
Is this a dream?
This is a dream.
What the fuck did you do to me?
What the fuck did you do to me?!
What did I do to you?
Are you kidding me?
Let me go!
Let me go now!
Novi, just stop,
okay, just stop.
No you just stop!
You're not my fucking
mother, you're not
My fucking sister,
you're fucking nobody!
Why don't you just
go cut someone's hair
Or fucking shoot
someone, you psycho!
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
(Novi sobs)
Shhh, shhh it's okay.
It's okay.
Candice.
I'm so fucked up.
Candice, I'm a fucking lunatic.
I can't live like this
anymore, I just can't.
Why did you do
this to yourself?
Dr. Simon.
What happened?
He used me, just like
everyone else does.
What do you mean?
He fucked me because
that's what he does
With every girl he meets.
Just like every
director or producer,
Or any guy with a fucking
dick between his legs!
Novi?
I'll be right back, okay?
No, Candice don't leave
me, I'm gonna fucking
Bleed to death.
Just, here.
If you need to call someone
or anything, the phone's
Right there okay,
I'll be right back.
Candice!
No, don't leave me!
Novi, I'm gonna take
care of everything, okay?
Don't worry,
everything will be...
It'll be fine.
Okay?
Candice, no!
(Phone vibrating)
Hello?
Novella?
Simon, I need your help.
What happened
today, where were you?
I know everything.
You're using me.
What?
I know you were just
using me to fuck me.
I know you don't
even care about me,
You probably don't even like me.
Tracy told me everything.
Oh god, Novella, listen.
Tracy has been a patient
of mine for two years.
She's a pathological liar.
No, I'm done with
your bullshit, Simon.
Novella, just listen!
She tells her friends that
she's this popular actress,
She tells people she
tried to kill herself.
She also tells people that
we've been involved, sexually.
It's all lies.
I'll show you my client
list Novella, there's you,
Tracy, and umm, a
woman in her 50s.
Other than you three, I
have five male patients.
Oh shit.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry!
Simon, I need your
help, I'm in big t...
Hold on, god dammit,
hang on sweetie, there's
Some kind of breakdown
at the ward here.
No Simon, please!
Just two seconds, I'll
call you right back.
No Simon, please!
Please, no Simon!
Don't, oh shit!
No!
Fuck!
Oh, shit!
Simon...
(Novi sobs)
Where did you go?
What are you doing?
There you go, baby girl.
I got it all taken
care of for ya.
Oh don't worry about it.
Candice, what is that?
(Candice grunting)
Now you have
something to eat, huh?
(Novi screaming)
What the fuck did you do,
Candice, what did you do?!
You killed him, I loved him!
Well I thought you ate people!
I'm not a cannibal!
Well then what
the fuck are you?!
(Knocking)
Oh, ow!
Candice, right?
Yeah.
Yep.
Is everything okay here,
I heard a terrible scream.
You know, everything's fine.
Thank you.
Where's Novi?
Everything's fine, it's
cool, okay she's fine.
Where is she?
I'm in here Eesha, I'm okay.
Is everything okay, Novi?
I'm coming in!
You're not coming
in here, lady.
Get out of my way, bitch!
Bitch.
Fuck.
Novi, what happened to you?
Oh, please.
(Gunshot)
(Novi screaming)
(Sad music)
She was, going
to call the police.
You do this to me.
Why do you do this to me?
I just...
I just want to protect you.
I just want to keep you safe.
I love you.
I've always loved you.
I love you, Novi.
(Gunshot)
(Sad music)
*
[Breathing heavily]
[Flesh ripping]
(Sad music continues)
*
[Choking]
[Flesh ripping]
(Sad music continues)
*
[Heart beating]
[Chewing]
(Sad music continues)
*
[Chewing]