Ta-da!
(Episode 24)
Guys, look at this.
What is it?
My goodness. Isn't he very famous?
"Cha Pasta. I've been looking
for it for two days in a row."
"I really want to try it."
- My gosh!
- Goodness.
- Isn't it amazing?
- Indeed.
That's so cool.
I can't believe it.
(Cha Pasta. I've been looking
for it for two days in a row.)
(Steak Pasta)
Gosh, what's this?
- Oh, my.
- It looks amazing.
- It's mouthwatering.
- It looks so good.
Gosh, what's this?
- I want to try this.
- What is it?
It's sold on a food truck?
It looks so delicious.
(Find this truck for me. I
need to go there right now!)
Oh, my.
- I really want to try it.
- Me too.
(I want to go there right now.)
(Where is this place? I'm salivating.)
(My gosh, I want a bite of that too.)
Shall we do it here today?
Okay.
It's so quiet though.
Do you think we picked a wrong spot again?
How many servings do you think we'll sell?
I'm not sure. About 17 servings?
- Oh, gosh!
- This is amazing!
- My gosh.
- This is so cool.
- I'm so excited.
- It's Cha Pasta.
- What's the matter?
- Amazing.
- It's Cha Pasta!
Score. I found it!
Oh, it's Cha Pasta.
You're right.
- Thank you.
- I already paid.
- Yes, thank you.
- It looks delicious.
Thank you.
It took me so long to find you guys.
Thank you for the food.
No problem. Enjoy it.
Two Oil Pasta, please.
- Two Oil Pasta.
- Sure.
Thank you. The wait won't be long.
Next customers, what
would you like to order?
Look at that. They're quite impressive.
Ms. Kang, go and get the
best thing on the menu.
Yes, ma'am. I'll be right back.
(Cha Pasta Food Truck)
They said pasta with
steak is most delicious.
Is that right? Let's try it, then.
What do you think?
Both of them are handsome.
Not those guys. I'm asking about the pasta.
How does it taste?
Which one do you like better?
I'm torn.
I'm torn too.
(Cha Pasta Food Truck)
Next, please. What would you like to order?
- Hello!
- Yes, hi.
The contest results must be out by now.
I'm so nervous.
Please...
(CN Group Contest Administrations Office)
(CN Group Character Contest)
Yes, this is CN Group Character
Contest Administrations Office.
I'm calling about the results.
Please give me your name
and contestant number.
My name is Jung Jung Won,
and my contestant number is 569.
Thank you. Just a second, please.
I'm sorry, Ms. Jung. You're not
on the list of the prize winners.
I see. Have a good day.
We have customers.
Yes, I'm going now!
Hello. For how many people?
- For two, please.
- You can take this table.
Great, thank you.
(Cha Pasta Food Truck)
I'm dying to try their pasta.
My gosh, they're so busy.
Thank you.
- You said two, right?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
Mr. Cha. I can step out
for a minute, right?
Yes, go ahead.
You guys are busy.
We've been so busy all day.
It'd be quiet like this, then
customers swarm at the same time.
I didn't make it.
I didn't win the contest.
Gosh, that's too bad.
I totally thought you'd win.
I had such a great dream.
To tell you the truth, I
didn't really think I'd win,
so I'm okay.
You've matured up.
I'm happy to see the business doing well.
I wish I were able to tell you good news.
Don't think that way.
All right. Here's to Hae Sung's success!
- Cheers!
What are you doing?
I didn't win the contest.
- Goodness.
- What a downer.
Raise your glass properly.
Guys, let's do it again.
Raise your glass high, okay?
- Raise it high.
- Okay, 1, 2, 3.
To our success!
- To our success!
To our success.
- Gosh.
- Goodness, Jung Won.
- Seriously.
- What's with you?
Hae Sung. I tried your food,
and it is really good.
It doesn't taste like street food.
Of course it doesn't. The chef
used to own a big restaurant.
Jung Won, why are you eating
what fell on the floor?
I failed the contest, you know.
That's why I should eat it off the floor.
- Come on.
- What's wrong withy you?
That's enough.
Jung Won, stop that right now.
She's right. Don't feel so bad.
Let's not mention any kind of
failure in front of Jung Won, okay?
- Let's not bring it up. Okay?
- Okay.
Tae Hoon, can you drop some of
the snacks, so I can eat them?
- Hey, that's enough. Stop it.
- You little...
- What are you doing?
- Stop it.
Hey, let's change the subject.
Let's talk about something else.
We will talk about something else now.
Moon Sik, work must be slowing down
for you since summer is almost over.
When the water drips from
the AC and I get the order,
I have to go. This manager
who is a complete failure,
makes a big deal out of nothing.
- What's wrong?
- You.
- What? What is it?
- Hey.
- How many times did we tell you?
- Goodness.
You never get it. You never do.
- You are not considerate at all.
- Why are you doing this to me?
I can't believe I even fell off the bed.
Jung Won!
Jung Won! Jung Won!
Why is he knocking on
my door in the morning?
Hurry and open up. Jung Won!
Jung Won!
Hey, get dressed quickly.
Hey, I even fell off the
bed sleeping last night.
Goodness, stop feeling sorry for yourself.
Come on. Get changed right away.
You and I have to be at somewhere.
I was going to stay home today.
No, get ready. We have to leave now.
What are you going to wear?
Which one? Is it this one? Or this?
Okay, fine.
I have to wash up first
for me to get changed.
Okay.
Get out.
But promise you'll hurry. Okay?
What do you think? Isn't it nice?
It is nice.
Hey, how did you find this place?
I stayed here last week.
Really?
Ma'am!
Hae Sung!
- Do you know her?
- She's the owner of the farm.
Hae Sung!
Ma'am!
- Hello.
- Hi.
Goodness, I almost forgot. I
forgot to unload the corns.
- I'll bring them to you.
- Can you do that for me?
I heard my cousin stayed here for a week.
Thank you.
You can tell me that he's your boyfriend.
Sorry?
You're Jung Jung Won, aren't you?
I heard everything from Hae Sung.
Pardon?
My husband came back to this world
three years after his death.
Really?
You and I are in the same boat.
I see.
Why did you steam so many corns?
I told Jung Won everything.
I see.
Then...
where is your husband?
Him?
He's back home in Seoul.
I see.
I have to go now. I have a
poker game to attend to.
You should eat these corns...
- and clean up the cattle sheds.
- Okay.
Win big!
Hey, we have to work?
This is a place where you come and
work without having any thoughts.
Let's eat these up. Come on.
Goodness.
This is a place where you let go of
your frustration and just work hard.
What's so bad about spilling them?
You can pick them up just as easily.
You're right. I'm not
thinking about anything.
This is a place where you let go of
your frustration and just work hard.
Fine.
Or not! Come here.
Come back here!
No!
I'm tired and hungry.
Aren't we going to eat?
This is a place...
- where we work without any thought.
- Where we work without any thought.
Jung Won and Hae Sung from Seoul,
come to the community hall and cook.
Come to the community hall and cook.
That'd be all.
She's not going to feed us?
We have to cook?
This is how things are in this town.
Let's go.
But why am I so happy though?
I guess you like when I touch you.
Forget it.
I feel like I failed that contest ages ago.
But where is she? Shouldn't
we say goodbye before we go?
She went back to Seoul in the afternoon.
She went back to see her husband.
Yes.
Jung Won.
Your hair pin.
Oh, no. I had it on in the afternoon.
I must have lost it in the farm.
Really? Let's hurry then.
Come already. You might
miss the last bus to Seoul.
We're coming.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
But if we miss the bus, you can't
work on the food truck tomorrow.
What should we do?
Mr. Cha can't work by himself.
Gosh, what should we do?
Mister, we'll be quick.
Give us just 10 minutes.
We are already late. We
have to get going now.
Hae Sung, let's leave for now.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Let's go.
(Eunha Farm)
What's the matter with him?
Hey, I poured the hot water
in it, so I could eat that.
You can make another one then.
That was the only one left.
That was the last one.
Fine. I'm sorry.
Why are you lashing out on me?
Did something happen?
Jung Won lost the hair pin.
The pin? The hairpin you
bought 12 years ago?
Yes.
Goodness. She got herself in big trouble.
I asked him to have udon before
coming home, but he just left.
He got all angry at me just
because I lost that hairpin.
He's so small-minded.
I didn't know Hae Sung could hold a grudge.
Of course, I do feel sorry
about the fact that...
I lost something he got for me.
But he was angry at me for three
hours throughout our ride back home.
Don't you think that's a bit too much?
I don't think it's that big of
a deal, so let's just hang up.
I'm sleepy.
Don't hang up.
I need to badmouth him a little
more to be able to fall asleep.
Jung Won, what's that behind your back?
What?
My gosh, Jin Joo.
(Cha Pasta Food Truck)
Please enjoy.
(Hong Jin Joo)
My gosh.
Hey, Jin Joo.
Ho Bang, why are Jung Won and
Hae Sung still fighting?
It's getting on my nerves.
What? I thought you wanted
me to stop calling you.
Jung Won, I think you should
apologize to Hae Sung.
What are you suddenly talking about?
You know that hairpin you lost?
It's not just any hairpin.
What do you mean?
I just heard about it from Ho Bang.
Hae Sung...
apparently bought that hairpin
for you 12 years ago.
He just never got to give it to you.
He bought that for me 12 years ago?
He couldn't give it to you because
he had gotten into an accident,
but he recently got lucky and found it.
That's how he was able to give it to you.
What?
Jung Won.
Jin Joo, I think I need
to go find that hairpin.
- I'll hang up now.
- Jung Won.
Move over, you guys.
What should I do?
I can't find it anywhere. What should I do?
You're going to go with
me to the US, right?
I've given it some thought...
If I build my career there...
I'm sorry, Young Jun.
To be honest, going to the US
is a bit too sudden for me.
I've started to enjoy working at
the magazine publishing company.
Seo Won.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity for me.
You're already competent enough.
You don't need to go.
Okay.
I won't go without you.
I'm sorry.
Instead, let's get married
as soon as possible.
Hi, Young Jun. I'm sorry
for making you wait.
- No, it's okay.
- Okay.
Did you prepare all the required documents?
- Sir.
- Tell me...
if you need anything else.
I'll take care of everything.
I'm investing in your future.
Don't feel pressured.
Well, I'm grateful for your kind offer,
but I've decided not to go to the US.
What did you say?
I may not come from a great background,
but I'd like my competence
to be acknowledged.
It's not an opportunity that
will come to you often.
You're making a mistake by
letting that opportunity go.
I'm sorry, sir. I came to tell you this.
When I kindly offer you
something, you need to take it.
You're not in any position to decide.
Sir.
I understand.
You may leave now.
- Dad.
- Hi.
- You're home.
- Yes.
You're home.
Is something bothering you these days?
No. You don't need to worry.
I met Chairman Shin's wife at
the massage spa this afternoon.
And apparently, her youngest son's wife...
treats her really nicely.
Oh, really?
"Oh, really" is not what you
should be saying right now.
When are you going to introduce
us your future wife?
When it's time.
My gosh, does that mean you're
going to introduce her to us soon?
Honey, you need to help me out here.
My gosh, just cut it out.
He'll take care of it on his own.
Why are you trying to rush things?
I want a daughter-in-law too.
You men don't know anything.
I'm the only one who's suffering.
Gosh, it's so late. Where
in the world is she?
My gosh.
My goodness.
Hae Sung, why did you come home so late?
Did you wait a long time?
Here. I brought you some
steak from the food truck.
That's not important right now.
Jung Won...
Jung Won? What about her?
Well, she went to the
farm all by herself...
- to find that hairpin.
- What?
Did you tell her?
Yes, of course. I didn't know
that you guys had fought.
My gosh, she could've just
talked to me about it.
Ho Bang, I'll see you later.
Hey, how are you going to
find that in the dark though?
Where could it be?
Please.
Please show up.
What?
I found it.
Gosh, I found it.
I should hurry up and go now.
I'm not scared.
I'm not scared at all. No, that's not true.
Gosh, I'm so scared.
My gosh.
Hae Sung, how did you know I was here?
I found this.
How could you come here
alone without telling me?
Why didn't you tell me?
I heard you bought this for me...
12 years ago on the day of the accident.
That's right.
I didn't know that.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to let it slide
because you're pretty.
I promise I'll never lose it again.
What time is it?
We'll miss the bus. Let's hurry up and go.
We already missed it.
Then what are we going to do?
I don't know.
Usually when a couple misses the last bus,
they can't help but spend
the night together.
And usually, there's only one room left.
Aren't I right?
What?
I was just kidding.
The farm owner said he'd give us a
ride as he's going to Seoul too.
They said they'd give us a
ton of corn and potatoes.
Let's get going.
Let's go.
- Finding this was so hard.
- It must've been.
- You found it though. Good job.
- Yes, I'm so glad.
What's all this?
This is corn, and there
are potatoes in this.
What shall we eat first? Tell
us what you want, Ho Bang.
Then shall we start with corn?
- Okay.
- Okay!
- Where's the big pot?
- It's here.
There are so many of them.
My gosh, they look so fresh.
Hello?
This is Detective Shin Ho
Bang at Mapo Police Station.
You're the one who put up the
banner in Chungho, right?
The banner in Chungho?
Yes, that's right. It was me.
I have some information for you.
Did you witness the accident
that happened 12 years ago?
Hello?
Hello? I'm listening.
On the day of the accident 12 years ago,
a murder took place inside the school.
That's right. Please go on.
I want to give you some information...
about that murder case.
(SE O's "Kiss Me" is available
on major music websites.)