Download Korean Drama at DramaLoad
I'll help.
Marry me and have three children, too.
Then divorce and you can go.
- What?
- I said, I'll help you.
A life that you can only live once, don't you think it's unfair?
I don't know who it is, but because she told you to come back after you've been married,
it doesn't seem like it's the first time for her.
Although that shouldn't be a problem,
but what she said is correct.
As long as we're living, we should
do everything that's possible to do.
That way we won't have any lingering attachments or regrets.
Just because everyone else is doing it, should I do it too?
I should do what I want to do. That is...
really live the life I want.
Right now,
are you rejecting my confession to you?
Is there heavy traffic?
Mother.
Yes.
- Should I help you?
- Oh, no.
It's alright. Go and rest.
Ok.
Then...
- I'll wash up first.
- Alright.
Ok.
Yes?
Where?
Why isn't she answering?
Yoo Ji Ho
Who is it at this hour?
Hey, maybe it's the owner of this apartment.
The rent for this month is paid.
Oh, okay.
Who is it?
Da.. Da In.
Da In.
Why are you here?
Let's go outside. I'll tell you everything once we're outside.
Tell me here!
Who you are, and who is the person that's hiding!
Let's go out. Let's talk outside.
Jeong Hee Joo!
Go after hearing me out.
Let go.
Jeong Hee Joo.
That's right, you were Jeong Hee Joo.
- Da In, please.
- Let go.
I told you to let go. Let go!
Da In, please, give me a chance to explain.
I don't want to hear it! Let go!
Let her go and talk.
What is it? What's going on?
Liar!
It was planned from the start, right?
Everything you've said up to now, your behavior,
everything was a lie, right?!
What exactly was your deception?
Why is Da In like this?
I just...
wanted to be by your side.
I liked you.
- Da In.
- This jerk!
Who likes who?!
Don't bother with him.
Don't you ever show up in front of me again.
I didn't like you from the start.
Instead being like this here, let's go to my house.
In Woo probably hasn't eaten yet.
Where is the soup?
Da Jeong.
Leave it!
What are you doing? Hurry and clean it up.
Yes.
What was that noise?
That's why I told you to go home.
A girl, whose hands have never even
touched a drop of water,
what kind of work are you saying
you're going to do?
I can do it.
Mother, So Lee and I will clean this up.
Please go out.
So Lee.
You should know too, since you heard the story.
Following after your household,
I almost got my throat ripped out.
Here. Give that to me,
released your attachment, and go.
I told you that I left my home. I have no place to go.
If you stay at our house like this,
then we're the only one who will be cursed at.
You know very well that your mother is exceptional.
Mother.
Da Jeong, you too, don't let this girl into your house.
I really don't have any place to go. I'll do well.
- Mother
- What is it?
- What are you going to do about So Lee?
- I was kicked out.
That's why it makes me more mad!
Why is dating In Woo something to be
kicked out of your house over?!
- Don't.
- Why?
What are you guys doing?
Father.
What?
Aiyoo, you should do things properly.
Oh man, I don't what I should do.
In a situation like this, it's best to keep one leg out.
Women's problems should be left for them to resolve.
If you pointlessly butt in, the matter will only grow bigger.
Then you're saying for me to look the other way?
You saw what I did, right?
When I protected Da Jeong, Mom got more angry.
For now, pretend you don't know.
Are you passing on your know-how
since you are the older brother?
Aiyoo, don't worry. I won't protest in a tent like Hyung did.
So what are you thinking to do?
I think I'll get married.
Hey, if you're going to get married, you should.
What is with this "I think I'll get married?"
Be certain.
Marriage and Baduk (Korean board game)moves
are things you can't take back.
Seeing as how she packed her things and left her house,
it looks like So Lee's house is against it.
Aiyoo, well, it's because I was indecisive before.
If you give your permission, I will try to convince them.
So...
is it a sure thing this time?
Don't say anything different later.
You're scarier than Father.
Oh boy.
Honey.
Try dissuading So Lee.
She says that she doesn't need to marry
and that she'll just live in our house.
Then, tell her to live here.
If this big scale wedding didn't work out,
I was going to tell you to give it all up.
Well... the false bravado is gone and it's good.
How are we going to get them married like that?
There's no reason to waste your energy over the children.
If we've raised them up to this point, they're
supposed to live their own lives as they see fit.
Honey.
I just...
What I did to Da Jeong . . .
I feel like In Woo is getting
it back exactly the same way.
Don't you know by looking at our parents?
As children, what is there for us to do for them?
In the end, there's only the married couple left.
You be good to me.
But what's wrong with our In Woo that
he should go so quickly and quietly?!
Team Leader Im.
Writer Han.
What is all this?
Who did you drink with? Did you drink alone?
I'm not alone.
Oh, he left.
He ran away.
Who did you drink with?
Nam Goong Yeong.
The CEO?
I confessed that I liked him.
He left.
Aiyoo, it's so embarrassing.
Get up. Where is your house?
Writer Han.
The CEO says that there's a woman he likes.
You were so bad (to tell me to date him).
So bad.
She's gone out.
At this time?
To meet whom?
I don't know.
But why are you calling at this hour...?
I was supposed to call for just a minute,
but she's not answering her cell phone...
So, I was just wondering if there was something wrong.
Don't worry about my mother,
since I'm here.
If you have something to tell Mother, let me know.
I will relay it to her.
Oh... well, it's nothing much, but
I wanted to discuss with her... regarding the book.
He has to ask so pointedly in such detail...
When was it the book came out
(that he's trying to use that as an excuse)?
What are you doing, Honey?
Honey, I figured it out.
In Mother's book, the hero of "I can't love."
Who is it?
Oh, they fooled us so completely.
It seems like it's already progressed quite far.
What?
I'm your senior when it comes to parental opposition.
If you cry, you'll just lose strength.
Don't cry.
Da Jeong,
How did it end up like this?
I understand Mother-in-law's heart,
but I'm disappointed and upset.
Didn't you see me do it? You need to endure this much.
When Mother-in-law only loved you,
I was so jealous and upset.
I'm sorry.
I didn't say that to make you apologize.
Go to your house and relieve your parents' hearts.
If you're going to do it, do it properly.
Properly.
Mom and Dad aren't even looking for me.
They aren't calling either.
But don't push them too much at the moment
because they aren't happy.
Take a step back and start again.
I know that Grandma isn't well.
Grandma loved me so much, but I didn't
realize and was just jealous.
Jealous?
Recently In Woo only knows the home and the hospital.
I've already sorted that out.
Now, I know what is the sincerity that
In Woo Oppa talked about.
Help me stay beside him, Sister-in-law.
See, So Lee isn't a bad kid.
Just know that you were lucky enough
to meet a good Sister-in-law.
She still accepted it all even though she has flu-like symptoms.
I'm not going to live like you when I get married.
Don't be so sure about future matters.
Your sister-in-law has to rest, so,
take So Lee and go to the house next door.
Don't be like that and let So Lee and Da Jeong
sleep together today.
Tell them to sleep together and you can sleep with me.
Wake up, you.
Da Jeong, let's go up.
I have a fever and I'm cold.
It seems like the flu. My whole body aches and I'm cold.
Where? Where?
Can I ask you something?
What?
Why are you so good to me?
No, maybe it's because I've never received
this kind of treatment before.
It's nice, but sometimes it's awkward and weird.
We're going to live together forever.
I need to take care of you or who else would?
They say that around the 3rd year of marriage,
things wane and dry up.
Don't believe in those things. My grandfather and
my dad lived without knowing those kind of things.
One more . . .
Why did my dad like somebody apart from my mom?
I mean, my mom is pretty,
and is ten thousand times better than my dad.
That's why Father-in-law must be regretting
it a lot even though he can't go back now.
If you liked some other girl besides me,
I think I'll just go and die.
What?
That's a bad thing to say. Take it back.
After I got married, I think about my mother a lot.
My mom's heart must have hurt a lot.
"I can't love again,"
I think I know how she felt.
Jeong Da Jeong, has it been one month
or a year since we married?
What do you think you know so much about?
Mom went on a date with Uncle.
Really?
My mom was so pretty.
Omo, Mom, what do we do?
I told you that I'd marry and divorce you, do it all.
What is she talking about?
Let's leave. When someone's drunk, sleep is medicine.
Really.
Where are you going?
It's so embarrassing, really.
Mother,
Oh, you surprised me.
Weren't you sleeping?
There was a call from CEO.
Really?
But why are you whispering?
Because I felt that I had to. After all, who am I?
I'm this house's Son-in-law and head of
the household. I'm the son, Mother.
Well...
Don't think about it weirdly and misunderstand.
He called me about the book.
Go up and sleep.
Misunderstanding? What misunderstanding?
Would it be a misunderstanding?
What misunderstanding?
You're the daebak king of being jealous.
Are you even being jealous over
Mom and Uncle's relationship?
Just saying, what if CEO becomes our father-in-law...
There's not even that much of an age difference . . .
That's because My Honey is so very old.
Da Ae,
should I see if honey's heart is thumping?
Listen to it, listen to it. My heart is thumping.
Then, Hee Joo is your oppa?
Brother? What brother? He's someone
that has nothing to do with me.
No, he's someone that I never want to
meet again in my lifetime.
You also should never again act like you know him.
So shameless, how dare he show up here.
So, that's why he was so good
to you and your family.
Good? How was he good?
Liar!
If we nitpick about it, then Hee Joo never lied.
"My mother's dead. I'm lonely, give me some food."
That's all he said.
If my mother finds out...
I brought him home saying that he was my friend.
But, are we of the type of relationship to be
feeding him and even packing side dishes for him?
He says he's going to the army soon.
Then you won't be able to see him anyway.
I'm so angry. That terrible bastard.
Let go of your anger. Truthfully, Hee Joo is quite pitiful.
What?!
His father two-timing isn't Hee Joo's fault.
Hee Joo is also a victim.
A victim?
How can you say that?
You go too! I don't need anyone.
- Da-in.
- Go!
Hey, I told you to go. Go, go, go!
I told you to go!
Look here,
why did he hit you in the face out of all places?
For a punk that looks all thin and weak, his fist is quite strong.
By now, the whole family will know, right?
What about the family?
That's why I told you not to meet with them.
Where is a man going to use such weakness, being so affectionate.
Here.
Hey, it'll scar. Apply this before you sleep.
Hee Joo.
Oh, I must be crazy.
Why am I here?
You were drunk so my mother brought you here.
I spouted rubbish, right? I was in a bad mood yesterday.
I shouldn't drink at times like that.
No, you just slept.
But where's Writer Han?
How can you leave a drunken person like that?
In front of the cafe, we separated to go home.
- She drank?
- She's at my house right now.
She slept there?
When I asked her address she was so drunk
and carrying on and making a fuss. What was I to do?
Then you should have told me.
I didn't know, so I was worried all night
because you didn't pick up your phone.
Did you not sleep?
I kept waking up.
Did Team Leader not say anything?
No, not really.
Let's meet for now.
Now? Team Leader Im is still sleeping.
Team Leader Im isn't a young child. Just come out.
- Oh, but-
- Mom, why are you here?
- Yes.
Yes, why?
Team Teader Im is awake.
Oh, okay.
My mom must really be dating
It's so refreshing.
Seeing as how I have this terrible headache,
I must have overdid it yesterday.
Should I buy you medicine?
No, no. If I just have some hangover soup
and sleep deeply, I'll be perfectly fine.
By any chance, did I make any mistakes?
No.
That's a relief. I blacked out so I was a little worried.
Should I go to the sauna and sweat it out?
Do you want to go together?
I have something that I need to do.
You're always busy.
Oh, my head.
If it's okay, even if I'm not here, do you
want to take a nap before you go?
Really? Thank you, thank you.
Don't worry about me. Do whatever
you need to do and come back.
Yes.
- Mother
- Yes, are you going out to exercise?
No, I'm going to the pharmacy.
Da Jeong has flu-like symptoms.
Is she really sick?
You don't need to worry about her; she'll be better after taking some medicine.
Don't feed her medicine carelessly, since she may get pregnant.
A baby?
-Uncle?
-Yes.
Oh, he's had something to discuss with me regarding the book.
Yes, I'm just popping in because of the book.
Yes. Yes. I'm just popping in to see Da Jeong too.
Then, discuss please.
Why did you have to come now of all times?
Get in quickly before we meet any more of your family.
Aiyoo, I was in such a bad spot.
Team Leader Im asked me to marry her, have kids with her, and even divorce her.
So what?
What's "So what?"
No, she's an okay woman. She's young too.
Does that make sense, Writer Han?
Hello.
You're going home?
We were talking about the book some.
Have you read the book?
What are you saying when he's a high school senior test taker.
When your examinations are over make sure to read it.
Yes!
Please speak.
Okay.
I can't do this because my heart is racing. I'll get going.
What do you mean you'll get going?
I haven't finished talking.
Where are you going?
How can I leave you and go to the army?
Han Da In, use this camera to take lots of nice pictures.
Terrible bastard.
Da In!
Why did you come?
In case you were feeling down.
Chocolate!
I came here instead of the library to study together.
It's delicious, right?
But, is there no contact from Hee Joo?
Don't talk about him!
- Shh.
On the way here, I saw your mom.
She was in Hotel uncle's car going on a date.
Why would Hotel Uncle and my mom have a date?
Here.
You said you had something to say, why come here?
Near the house, the kids keep appearing. We're safe here.
This seems to be the best one to see.
But I can't figure out what's what at all.
Aigoo.
It's a headache to have such a big family.
Oh, man. Let's go inside.
It's been years since I've been to a movie.
Aiyoo, here. Eat this.
Writer Han, it's a long time for you too, right?
It's been a few years.
I may get a pair of those.
- Why?
The subtitles look blurry.
Give them to me.
They don't seem to be magnifiers.
When you get to our age we need ones for looking far and near.
Wow, you can see it well.
Excuse me, can you be quiet?
- Sorry
- Sorry...
It's them, right?
Yeong slipped all the way over here.
You don't think that they saw us, right?
So what if they see us.
- Hurry up and give them to me.
- Just a minute.
I'll read you the subtitles.
"It's only that I want to spend a wonderful time together. That's right come here."
Be quiet!
Now he says to come into the room.
She says that she's of an age where she doesn't need her father but me.
Tada. Try them.
Are you all done now?
It's much softer and more delicious than last time.
Hey, it dissolves so nicely.
Thank you.
Are you done?
Jae Woo, try one. I made it out of rice.
Oh, it's delicious.
It melts in your mouth.
Now we can go, right?
Hey, why do you want to go so much?
I'll tell you when I get back.
For now, I don't see the baby's house yet (amniotic sac).
See, I told you. That's not it.
I think I see it though.
The blood test results show that you're 3 weeks pregnant.
I told you! I could see it!
Are you sure it's a baby?
Yes, in 2 to 3 weeks we'll be able to see the baby's house (amniotic sac).
You can even hear the heartbeat.
The heartbeat...
Jae Woo.
Da Jeong.
Are you crying?
Jae Woo.
He's not normally like this.
Since it's the beginning of pregnancy you have to be careful.
Yes.
Mother?
- Isn't that your phone?
- Mine?
I'm sorry. Aigoo. I'm sorry.
Hello? Huh?
- Da Jeong is pregnant!?
-A Child?
Excuse me
- We're sorry.
- What do we do?
Of course we have to go!
Quickly! Quickly!
Aigoo, what are they doing?
Pregnant?
Hey, Da Jeong. You did well. You worked hard.
Father, now I also will become a father.
Aigoo, good for you, you punk!
Aigoo, really.
Aigoo, aigoo. Our father likes it so much that he can't breathe properly.
Here you go, Mother!
Aigoo, seriously.
- Such an embarrassing thing...
- It looks delicious.
- Aiyoo, hey. If there's something you want to eat tell me. I'll make it for you.
-Yes.
Aigoo, it's only 3 weeks now. What's with all this fuss?
They say that there are people who get morning sickness early.
Of course, of course.
Grandmother, you have to keep making us lots of delicious stuff.
Of course, of course!
Aigoo, that's right. Thinking back now I think my morning sickness was a little fast.
That's something Da Jeong takes after her mother-in-law.
If you're 3 weeks pregnant it's a honeymoon baby, right? It's so romantic.
He's coyly fast at the decisive times.
Aigoo.
Hey, hey, hey. Stop laughing like that. You look like an old man.
- Hey, the stew will cool. Let's hurry up and eat.
- Yes.
Because of you I think Mother-in-law is in a better mood.
Thank you. I'll latch on some.
Eat this. Mom, eat this.
Do well to sister-in-law!
How can I do better from here?
Da Jeong.
Mom!
Our Da Jeong, congratulations.
- You came?
- Sit down.
We had to come when they said that our great grandchild was made.
Jae Woo slipped right properly.
Jae Woo! Aigoo.
You came!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
How did you know to come, Uncle?
Me?
I... I... I... well, um...
Jae Woo. I heard from Jae Woo. Right, Jae Woo?
Me? It wasn't me though.
That person jokes so well.
Ah, it's refreshing! Right, son?
Teacher Jeong told me to buy bean sprouts.
Let's go back.
Yes we're going to buy the bean sprouts.
-Buy some flowers too.
-Eh? Flowers?
Da Jeong is pregnant.
Really?
Wow, Brother-in-law must be happy as a clam.
Why?
Auntie Da Jeong is pregnant!
Yah, you have a dongsaeng now!
Da Ae, why don't we have any children news? We were married first.
What? Eun Chan is...
Yes, I'll go quickly.
Hey, Eun Chan.
Dad, you're really happy.
Of course! Why? Do you not want a younger sibling?
It's good if I have one.
What type of flowers do we buy?
It's so nice being out here in the front yard.
So that Grandmother can comfortably enjoy it, Jae Woo brought it out here.
Thank you, my Puppy.
You have to come often.
Mother, use the massage chair. It's good for blood circulation.
Ah, I'm using that really well. You don't have to worry about it.
How are you? Everyone is gathered here.
You were still in there?
How did you know that I was here?
There is nothing Yeong doesn't know.
Drink some tea.
Yes.
Team Leader Im, did you know? Our Jae Woo is going to be a daddy soon.
- Congratulations.
-Thank you very much.
Team Leader Im, come and have some fruit.
Yes. Thank you.
Have a seat.
Father, don't you think that Jae Woo is going to carry this baby to work with him after it's born.
I can't stand watching because it's eye blinding.
If you're that jealous then you should also hurry to get married and have a baby.
How can I have a child at this age?
What does that matter?
Men can have children in their 60-70's, right?
Isn't that so, Mom?
I think it's more important for him to find someone he loves before children.
Seriously, Mom, but still
he needs to have one child so that he has someone to pass the hotel on to.
Sister-in-law, why did I become the subject of this conversation when we were talking about Jae Woo?
Oh seriously,
I'm just saying that because you are the only one left.
You even caught the bouquet. Hurry up and get married.
I think he would do better than Jae Woo if he got married and had a baby.
She's not here either.
Where's So Lee. Has anyone seen her?
Oh, your posture is good just like this.
See, how you are looking at the ground at 45 degrees?
Oh, you look feminine and pure. You are exactly my style.
Oppa,
What?
Do you want to see your mother?
No.
It's nice being with your family.
Then are you jealous of Da Jeong?
Because she has everyone's attention because she's pregnant?
That's not it.
If that's not it then why are you so serious?
You have me.
It's true.
I feel like I'm going to fly now that I've seen you.
Should I really make you fly?
Alright.
I'm scared!
Stop acting timid. That doesn't work with me.
Let me down.
Isn't this fun?
It's scary.
I told you to go home but I'm going to let you have it since you're not listening.
Stop it...
Da Jeong made this.
Yes.
It tastes like castella cake.
It's soft and nice. It's good. It's delicious.
Thank you.
What did you use to make this?
It was made with rice.
Nobody was asking you.
I thought Yeong was here. Where did he go?
Why are you sitting here by yourself?
Why are you here?
You should have stayed with the elders.
What's the matter? Are you sick?
Go back to the other side.
I need to look over Eun Chan's homework.
Eun Chan?
Why is she acting like that again?
Let's go already. I think you over did it today.
Go home and bring me some clothes and my medication.
Let's stay a few days since Da Jeong has so many food cravings.
You're so fickle.
Did I put sesame oil or not?
- Do you have some extra energy?
- Days like today I could run around everywhere.
You're going to start running soon.
If In Woo and So Lee gets married, you'll end up seeing lines of grandchildren.
Maybe because it's been so long since we had a baby. Just the thought of one makes me happy.
Grandma, Da Jeong has indigestion. Can she take some medicine for it?
No! There would be big trouble.
Does walking make you feel a little better?
Yes.
Grandma, you need to exercise everyday regardless of how difficult it it.
That way you can raise our baby.
I'll have to.
Make sure you have a baby who looks like Jae Woo. If you do, the baby won't be bothersome to you.
Was he good when he was a baby?
Of course. Even if he cried,
he would fall asleep as soon as I put him on my back.
He was a late talker and walker.
I was so worried because he was still crawling on his first birthday.
Jae Woo is a little on the slow side.
Yet he considers himself to be quite fast.
He seems to think so.
He's gotten so talkative lately.
He has learned how to finally talk in his 30's.
That's true. He's totally late.
What is she so happy about to be laughing like that?
You said that when there is sadness there is also happiness and if someone is angry there is someone to make them laugh, right?
Da Jeong and I will be the ones to make you laugh.
How are things going with your mother-in-law and Uncle Yeong?
They came to the movie theater today.
It does seem that they like each other, but
I can't get involved since it's my mother-in-law's business.
I'm in the process of watching.
Of course. You feel cautious about it.
It's such a waster to see your mother-in-law who is alone.
Also when I see Yeong
I can't tell him to "get married and go." Isn't he still young?
Do you feel like it's a waste for Uncle?
Hm? Who would say it's wasteful.
If I thought of him as a son, I can't tell him to get married soon.
Jae Woo, I'm tired.
Let's rest a little.
Grandma must be feeling tired.
You married well.
Ti-tak, dong!
Honey!
By any chance, has good news arrived for us too?
No, it's because the Kimchi smell was too strong.
Sister-in-law thought she had a cold but it turned out to be pregnancy.
Let's go to the hospital.
I said I'm not.
By any chance,
are you looking down on me
because I'm too old?
No, you could be pregnant. Why are you insisting you're not?
Hurting my self-esteem.
-It's not that
-Then, go to the hospital.
Let's go.
No,
I take (birth control) pills.
What?
Why do you take pills without even discussing it with me?
Eun Chan will hear us. Let's talk later.
Eun Chan,
what are you doing here?
Eun Chan said he wants a younger sibling.
Then would he say no if you ask him?
Don't say anything to me. It's something I decided before the wedding.
CEO Nam Goong Yeong
All right then.
Then I'll meet you in the front.
- I don't have an afternoon appointment, right?
-Even if there is, we should move it.
Your eavesdropping. I'm going going to let it slide today.
What's wrong with that guy?
Jeong In Sung!
Did you commit a crime?
Why are you surprised to see me?
Is there something wrong at Da Ae's Mom's house?
What problem?
Since Da Ae's mother's book is selling well so I was just wondering.
-This doesn't seem to be about that?
- CEO!
What is it?
I'll be leav...yes.
Who is that person?
- Hotel employee.
- He doesn't seem to be just an employee.
Isn't Da Ae's mom Writer Han?
That's really impressive.
What is?
What would make you take the ex-husband
and give him a job?
- Do you by chance have wings?
- Was this because of my wings?
I thought it was my allergy to bad luck that had me so itchy.
What is it?
I'm going to say one thing because I know it's not me
How can a man be like that?
What did I do?
If you like her you should just go for it.
If I do that I'll get slapped.
Writer Han's hands sting. In her youth
she played volleyball.
For someone who took in her ex-husband,
are you afraid of a slap?
Didn't you see Writer Han's expression yesterday?
How can you date if you're so dense?
What am I suppose to do?
How long are you going to stay here?
I don't know either.
I'm not feeling great lately either.
I want to be alone!
Yet you can't feel worse than me.
Do you still have something you want to say?
What are we going to do if you keep opposing this?
Wasn't this in order to set a wedding date for the kids?
That's something we should discuss slowly.
Send out daughter back home.
My thoughts exactly.
It's difficult for us also.
She won't leave even when we tell her to.
It's because you're taking her in.
Then should I put her out on the streets?
Would you like that?
They're saying that they like each other that much,
what can we do about that?
While they are going forward with the marriage even if there is an unsatisfactory situation,
please be understanding-
- Climb one mountain then there is another, they say.
Even In Woo's grandmother is ill, I heard.
Ah, yes.
Don't take it the wrong way.
Aren't all the parents' hearts the same?
That's not right.
You should have told us about something like that in advance.
And the matter about the dowry!
I paid that back already!
I came here because So Lee liked us but why do we have to listen to this?
Did we have the engagement because So Lee alone wanted it?
If you think that way, we should end it even more so!
You, stop it already.
I wish things would settle well.
The parents' will is important in marriage matters.
However, we are not the ones who are getting married.
Do you think you can break your only daughter's stubborn will?
She says she doesn't need any dowry.
She knows about the Grandmother's illness yet she wants to become our family member.
At this point, I don't have any means to stop her.
If you are still against it,
I will consider her as my own daughter. Will that be all right?
Honey.
These days, it seems like I am dreaming everyday.
Is it because of the books are selling well?
Some of it is because of that.
It's embarrassing but
at some point I became curious about you.
And I started to feel jealous.
When we date like this,
my heart fluttered.
When we did the interview with the reporters,
I really thought you were Prince Charming.
Well,
as much as Prince Charming?
It was a good dream.
Even when I woke up, I felt good...
CEO, you said I made you comfortable, right?
So, I will tell you everything.
My Da Ae, says that she won't have a baby.
Because of Eun Chan.
I am so frustrated.
I don't know why she would give up having a baby when she can.
So, I am going to try convincing her not to.
So, you're going to
tell me to get married, have a baby and come?
Is that what you're trying to say?
That...
I'm not just saying that out of anger, but what I really feel.
I know it makes no sense, but
if that could happen,
I wish it really would happen.
Then every time we meet,
I wouldn't feel sorry.
What is the problem when I'm saying it's fine?
It's me.
Chairman, don't you want to do everything for me?
I feel the same.
However,
no matter how much I think about it, there's nothing I can do for you.
Writer Han!
It was really hard raising Da Ae, Da Jeong and Da In.
Even so, I was really happy.
I would really like for you to experience that happiness.
You should have been a little less good to me.
Then I might have held onto you.
At this age where would I meet Prince Charming?
Even if I step closer like this,
My heart beats fast,
As time flows by,
My heart is falling deeper and deeper,
Do you not know, this heart,
Your other half that heaven has decided,
Although I may be a bit late, slowly, more slowly,
Do you want to open your empty space,
I love you just like this,
Will it be okay even if I'm not there?
Are you still worried when I said that I'd go instead?
Only I know the secret tips to the rice cake.
That's true.
Fine, rest well and you have to make sure to come later in the morning.
Yes!
See, without me the ddeok (rice cake) shop won't function properly.
- Still...
- All right.
- Go and return.
- Okay.
- Okay. Great.
Let's go inside.
That car, isn't it Uncle's?
Oh, you're right.
Uncle!
- What are you doing?
- Something terrible will happen if you sleep here.
I was close by and
I was sleepy and told myself I'd just rest for a bit...
I dozed off.
You should go inside the house.
- Get off.
-No.
I slept well. I'm going.
Well...
I don't like it.
Why?
Sister-In-Law, you like Uncle Yeong.
I do like him but if she gets married to him, family structure will get more confused.
What will get confused?
Father's last name is Jeong. My last name is Han. And the new Father's last name will be Nam Goong. Isn't that confusing?
Da In. It's not like Mom wants to get married right away.
Let's cheer on Mom and Uncle.
Of course. We are on board.
And, getting married is not that easy a thing to decide.
I know you are having a hard time but do you want Mom to live alone for the rest of her life?
All of you agree, right? Then, you don't have to ask me.
Come on, Sister-In-law.
Why are you acting like that?
I don't know. These days, I don't like anything.
Sister-In-Law.
-Da In.
She's sensitive. Is there something going on?
It's hard to accept the matter of a parent's remarriage.
But how did you get the sense about Mom and Uncle?
I'm pretty quick on the uptake.
There is a thing called woman's intuition.
How should we help out?
The lamp post and the wooden bench...
liked each other.
Eun Chan.
Yes?
What are you thinking about?
Nothing. Can you read it to me again?
Do you have secrets that you are keeping from your Grandmother?
Grandmother.
Is it nice to have a younger sibling?
Of course.
You will be getting the best friend of your life.
How is that a friend?
- Da In.
-Mom, just what are you doing these days?
You have no concern about what I am thinking about, right?
Da In. Where are you going, Da In?
Da Ae, why is she like this these days? Is there some sort of a problem?
I don't know. She's been strange lately.
Who is it?
Hey. Who is it?
Hey. Where are you going?
Da In was here.
Da In...
I don't think it should end this way.
Hey, Hee Joo. Hee Joo.
So Lee, you really want to become our family member, right?
Yes.
In Woo, you want to marry So Lee.
Right?
Yes.
So Lee, you are going to have to brace yourself. Your Father-In-Law wants to make you his daughter.
What?
- Dad!
-Yesterday, I met with So Lee's parents.
If you two want, I will let you have the wedding.
Da In.
Da In!
Open the door. Talk to your mom, okay?
Da In.
Da In. Da In?
Han Song Jeong. Da Ae. Da Jeong.
Da In...
Ji Ho is not answering.
I think he has it on vibration mode.
Did she fight with Ji Ho?
Mother, don't you have the keys to the room? Let's just open the door and go in.
Let her be. We can can hear her cry.
Do you know Hee Joo's phone number? Hee Joo must know why she is like that.
- Hee Joo?
-That's right.
Hee Joo said he was going to the military service. Is she saddened by that?
I know his number.
I will try to get in touch with him.
Oh, wait...
Oh, he's here.
= Hee Joo.
-Hee Joo.
Hee Joo, did something happen to Da In?
I'm sorry.
Hee Joo.
What is this?
What I did was wrong.
Why are you doing that?
Hee Joo, what did you do wrong?
My name is Jeong Hee Joo.
Jeong Hee Joo, you shouldn't come here. Do you know where this is?
I don't want to see you. Get out of here immediately!
Da In.
I have something to give you, Writer Han.
What is this?
My Mother...before she passed away.
It's her will.
But why are you giving this to me?
What I did was wrong.
What is this guy trying to do all by himself?
If I go in, it's going to be a battlefield.
Why is Hee Joo giving his Mother's will to you?
Hee Joo. Are you perhaps...
Perhaps...you're not, right?
Get up, you punk.
Why are you kneeling?
What did you do wrong?
Hey, you punk.
Besides the fact that you are my son, what did you do so wrong?
I am the one who did wrong.
I lived the wrong way.
Father.
I'm sorry.
I did wrong.
Get up.
Here, Writer Han...
Don't show yourself in front of the children this way and get up!
Don't you know?
This heart of mine. The one that Heaven decided.
Preview
If you had a Father, what did you want to do the most?
Hey, just help me.
Let's marry off Song Jeong. Yeong likes her.
How did you seduce Uncle so that...
What do you mean seduce? He says he likes me even if I am just there.
And do I have to live alone for the rest of my life?!
Who are you that you come into my yard all of a sudden?
Grandmother, you don't know who he is?