Back from the strange world
underwater, scientists study the samples.
One of the foremost scholars in the world
in his field, Dr. Pawlowski,
studies the DNA sequences of foraminifera.
What looks esoteric is in fact one of the
fundamental questions about life on Earth.
In the same way that cosmologists search
for the origins of the universe,
the scientists here are tracing back
the evolution of life to its earliest stages.
Sometimes the building blocks
of the sequences all seem to fit.
Jan, what have you found today so far
on the sample that we found?
- Three new species.
Three new species on the dish.
That's fantastic.
- This is from the ROMEO site.
- Yeah, from the ROMEO site.
It's one small silver and two elongated ones.
I don't know what it is.
We have to do the DNA, too.
We don't know...
Is this a great moment?
- Yeah, yeah, this is.
- Yeah, any time you increase
the known diversity of these types
of creatures, it's pretty exciting.
Yeah. That is very special.
Apologies to rock musicians everywhere.
Once the importance
of the discovery has sunk in,
Sam Bowser and his group plan to celebrate
the event in their own way.
They are rehearsing for
a late-night outdoor concert.
After the helicopter had dropped us off
back at McMurdo,
nobody was around. The sundial showed
that it was close to 1:00 a.m.
It did not feel like night,
so we had a look around.
This unobtrusive building
had raised my curiosity for quite a while.
Here amongst unripe tomatoes,
we ran into this young man.
How did he end up in this place?
Oh, yeah, well, you know, I like to say,
if you take everybody who's not tied down,
they all sort of
fall down to the bottom of the planet, so,
you know, I haven't been...
That's how we got here, you know.
We're all at loose ends
and here we are together.
I remember
when I first got down here I sort of
enjoyed the sensation of recognizing people
with my tribal markings.
You know, I was like,
"Hey, these are my people."
PhDs washing dishes and, you know,
linguists on a continent with no languages
and that sort of thing, yeah. It's great.
Yeah, specifically I was in
a graduate program, and we had lined up
to do some work with
one of the people who was
identified as a native speaker
and a competent native speaker of
one of the languages
of the Winnebago people, the Ho-Chunk,
I think is how they pronounced it, and...
To make a complicated story short,
he ran into New Age ideologues who made
insipid claims about black and white magic
embedded in the grammar of this language.
Some of the oral tradition
that had been passed along...
Hence, in this stupid trend of academia,
it would be better to let the language die
than preserve it.
...you know, I could document a language...
He had to destroy his entire PhD research.
So just imagine, you know, 90%
of languages will be extinct
probably in my lifetime.
It's a catastrophic impact
to an ecosystem to talk
about that kind of extinction.
Culturally, we're talking
about the same thing. I mean,
you know, what if you lost all of
Russian literature, or something like that,
or Russian, you know? If you took all of the
Slavic languages and just they went
away, you know, and no more Tolstoy.
It occurred to me that in the time
we spent with him in the greenhouse,
possibly three or four languages had died.
In our efforts to preserve
endangered species,
we seem to overlook something
equally important.
To me,
it is a sign of a deeply disturbed civilization
where tree huggers and whale huggers
in their weirdness are acceptable,
while no one embraces
the last speakers of a language.
McMurdo is full of characters
like our linguist.
The bleak Motel 6-drabness of
the corridors is misleading.
Behind every door there is someone
with a special story to tell.
Back in the '80s, I took a garbage
truck across Africa from London to Nairobi.
That was a trip. Four months in
a garbage truck. It was horrible.
On numerous occasions we came pretty
close to, I don't know about dying,
but pretty close
to being in some straits where
we didn't know if we were gonna get back
out of it, you know.
We got taken over by the military in Uganda,
and we were kidnapped, basically.
Truck was turned around
and we were going back to Entebbe.
We got out of that one.
We were trying to wait for
this ferry in Wadi Halfa,
the one that blew up and 800 people died.
Well, we didn't get on that one.
We took off across a desert,
and we got stuck. We got stuck for five days
of absolute agony, of clawing
this truck with... We were using plates,
just the dinner plates that we were using
for dinner, clawing at the tires.
We had no water.
He had used all the water tanks for gasoline,
so basically we had a cup of water a day
or two cups.
Her story goes on forever.
She dealt with a bout of malaria,
with a herd of angry elephants pursuing her
through tsetse fly-invested swamps.
Got caught in a civil war,
spent a night in a bombed-out airport,
with rebels fighting and shooting
in a barroom brawl,
and was finally rescued
by drunk Russian pilots,
slaloming around crater holes
in the runway.
This is how you get yourself
to any place in Antarctica.
At the so-called Freak Train event
at one of McMurdo's bars,
Karen is, not surprisingly,
one of the most popular performers.
This is her famous
"Travel as hand luggage" act.
Yeah, take her home.
- Thought of another one.
- Yeah.
I traveled from Ecuador to Lima, Peru
in a sewer pipe.
Forgot to mention that.
I hitchhiked once from Denver to Bolivia
and back up,
and we got a ride from a truck in...
It was a flatbed truck with three huge sewer
pipes on the back, so I spent... It was days
in the back of this truck, in a sewer pipe,
watching the world go by just like that.
That's all you could see.
Travel for those who have been
deprived of freedom means even more.
These are the ones you'll find in Antarctica.
Libor Zicha works as a utility mechanic.
He lived like a prisoner
behind the Iron curtain.
You escaped.
And how big a drama was that?
Oh, it was, wasn't a drama, but...
The tragic events surrounding his escape
haunt him to this day.
If we can...
- You do not have to talk about it.
- Okay. Thank you.
For me, the best description of
hunger is a description of bread.
A poet said that once, I think,
and for me the best description of freedom
is what you have in front of you.
You are traveling a lot.
- That's right, yeah.
- Show us.
That's my freedom,
and I will be glad to show you.
He keeps a rucksack packed
and ready to go at all times.
Inside is everything he needs
to set out in a moment's notice:
a sleeping bag, a tent, clothes,
cooking utensils.
How much weight is this all?
It's... I usually don't go over 20 kilos.
That's my limit,
and it's a limit also for airlines.
Some of the contents of his backpack
are quite surprising.
That's about the size of the raft.
- How quickly can you leave?
- Oh, I am always ready.
My bag is always prepared,
and I am always ready for adventure
and exploring new horizons.
Back in the days of Amundsen,
Scott and Shackleton,
scientific exploration of Antarctica began,
and this opening of the unknown continent
is their great achievement.
But one thing about the early explorers
does not feel right.
The obsession to be the first one
to set his foot on the South Pole.
It was for personal fame
and the glory of the British Empire.
This is Shackleton's original hut,
preserved unchanged for 100 years.
But, in a way, from the South Pole onwards
there was no further expansion possible,
and the Empire started to fade
into the abyss of history.
It all looks now like an extinct supermarket.
On a cultural level,
it meant the end of adventure.
Exposing the last unknown spots
of this Earth was irreversible,
but it feels sad
that the South Pole or Mount Everest
were not left in peace in their dignity.
It may be a futile wish
to keep a few white spots on our maps,
but human adventure, in its original sense,
lost its meaning,
became an issue for the
Guinness Book of World Records.
Scott and Amundsen
were clearly early protagonists,
and from there on
it degenerated into absurd quests.
A Frenchman crossed the Sahara Desert
in his car set in reverse gear,
and I am waiting for the first barefoot runner
on the summit of Everest
or the first one hopping into the South Pole
on a pogo stick.
Well, I had this idea of breaking
a Guinness record in every continent,
and Antarctica would be the sixth,
so, now I'm trying to think of a way
to get to Antarctica.
Ashrita Furman did not want
to travel this way,
because he already holds a
Guinness record in this discipline.
And also in this one.
So, he decided upon the more prosaic
approach and took an airplane.
We flew down to Antarctica.
Anyway, it was thrilling
because I'm in Antarctica,
and I'm trying to break a Guinness record.
Being in Antarctica
is like being on the moon.
It's so... I mean, it's so peaceful.
It's so pure.
It's so desolate.
I mean, it's just a great place.
Antarctica is not the moon,
even though sometimes it feels like it.
Yet, on this planet,
McMurdo comes closest to what
a future space settlement would look like.
We left McMurdo for the penguin colony
at cape Royds.
Everyone spoke about penguins,
however, the questions I had
were not so easily answered.
I was referred to a penguin expert out there
who had studied them for almost 20 years.
I was told that he was a taciturn man,
who, in his solitude, was not much into
conversation with humans anymore.
But Dr. Ainley gave his best effort.
Well, here we are at Cape Royds.
This is 2006,
and it's just about the 100th anniversary
of the first penguin study
that was ever done,
which was done here at Cape Royds by
a person that was part
of the Shackleton expedition.
They all had a good winter,
and they're very fat.
They've
claimed their territories and eggs have
been laid and females have left,
and now there's just males
that are sitting on eggs,
using their fat reserves
and waiting for females to return
to relieve them and then go to sea.
I tried to keep the conversation going.
Dr. Ainley, I read somewhere
that there are gay penguins.
What are your observations?
I've never...
Or strange sexual behavior.
Can you talk about...
Yeah, there has been... I've seen
triangular relationships where there's
one female and two males,
and the female lays the egg,
or eggs, and the males and the female
trade off over the season.
There are mis-identities, initially,
of the sex of penguins.
Somebody recently described
what they call prostitution where
a female, who is out
collecting rocks for her nest,
and, of course, some penguins are...
The only way they collect rocks
is to steal them from others.
So, in order to do that,
they have to be very submissive
in order to get close to a male,
who's maybe advertising for a mate,
and so she'll come in, sit in his nest,
and sometimes they'll copulate.
But, really, her idea is to get a rock,
and so, as soon as she can,
she escapes with a rock.
Dr. Ainley, is there such thing
as insanity among penguins?
I try to avoid the definition of insanity
or derangement.
I don't mean that a penguin
might believe he or she is Lenin
or Napoleon Bonaparte,
but could they just go crazy
because they've had enough of
their colony?
Well, I've never seen a penguin
bashing its head against a rock.
They do get disoriented.
They end up in places they shouldn't be,
a long way from the ocean.
These penguins are all heading
to the open water to the right.
But one of them caught our eye,
the one in the center.
He would neither go towards the feeding
grounds at the edge of the ice,
nor return to the colony.
Shortly afterwards, we saw him heading
straight towards the mountains,
some 70 kilometers away.
Dr. Ainley explained
that even if he caught him
and brought him back to the colony,
he would immediately head right back
for the mountains.
But why?
One of these disoriented,
or deranged, penguins
showed up at the New Harbor diving camp,
already some 80 kilometers away
from where it should be.
The rules for the humans
are do not disturb or hold up the penguin.
Stand still and let him go on his way.
And here, he's heading off into the interior
of the vast continent.
With 5, 000 kilometers ahead of him,
he's heading towards certain death.
The last field camp we visited
was at Mount Erebus.
This active volcano is 12, 500 feet high.
It is of particular importance, as inside
the crater the magma of the inner earth
is directly exposed.
There are only two other such volcanoes
in the world,
one in the congo and the other in Ethiopia.
Because of political strife in those places,
it is actually easier to conduct field studies
here in Antarctica.
First thing, we were instructed in
the etiquette of dealing with this volcano.
One very important thing to keep in mind
when you're on the crater
is that the lava lake
could explode at any time,
and if it does, it's vital to keep
your attention faced toward the lava lake
and watch for bombs
that are tracking up into the air
and try to pick out the ones that might be
coming toward you and step out of the way.
The last thing you wanna do is turn away
from the crater or run or crouch down.
Keep your attention toward the lava lake,
look up and move out of the way.
We were fortunate that the lava
lake was not enshrouded in mist this day.
This here is the new observation camera.
William Mclntosh is the leader
of the team of volcanologists here.
This camera is designed for prison riots
or to be explosion proof,
and it's coated with this thick
Teflon housing.
Here's the lens here. This is a camera.
The camera inside is made by a small
company in Canada, Extreme CCTV.
The inside housing is specifically
designed for explosion...
...to be explosion-proof.
There's a bang from the lava lake
right now. No bombs, though.
This is the magma lake
filmed 30 years ago.
At that time, there was a bold attempt
to descend into the crater.
Halfway down there is a plateau.
From there, it is a gaping hole straight down
into the magma.
They were in for near disaster.
The magma exploded, striking one of the
climbers, who got away with minor injuries.
Today, the lava is monitored
by Dr. Mclntosh's camera.
Dr. clive Oppenheimer, a true Englishman
from cambridge University,
surprised us with his tweed outfit, which
he wears as a tribute to the explorers of old.
He analyzes gas emissions
from volcanoes all over the world.
If this were one of those active
volcanoes in lndonesia,
I'd be far more circumspect
about standing on the crater rim.
This is a very benign form of volcanism,
and even the eruptions we've seen in the
historic period are relatively minor affairs.
If we go back into the geological record,
we see that there are huge
volcanic eruptions,
massive, explosive eruptions that produced
thousands of cubic miles of pumice,
showering large parts of the Earth
with fine ash,
and these have been demonstrated
to have had a strong impact on climate,
and one of the biggest of these events,
74,000 years ago,
has been argued even to have affected
our human ancestors
and may have played an important role in
the origins and dispersal of early humans.
So these events will recur, and I think
the more we understand about them,
the better we can prepare for
their eventuality.
For this and many other reasons,
our presence on this planet
does not seem to be sustainable.
Our technological civilization makes us
particularly vulnerable.
There is talk all over the scientific
community about climate change.
Many of them agree the end of human life
on this Earth is assured.
Human life is part of
an endless chain of catastrophes,
the demise of the dinosaurs being just
one of these events.
We seem to be next.
And when we are gone, what will happen
thousands of years from now in the future?
Will there be alien archeologists
from another planet
trying to find out what we were doing
at the South Pole?
They will descend into the tunnels
that we had dug deep under the pole.
It is still minus 70 degrees here,
and that's why this place has outlived
all the large cities in the world.
They walk on and on.
And then this.
As if we had wanted to leave one remnant
of our presence on this planet,
they would find a frozen sturgeon,
mysteriously hidden away
beneath the mathematically precise
true South Pole.
They stash it back away
into its frozen shrine for another eternity.
And then they find more,
memories of a world once green.
As if the human race wanted to preserve
at least some lost beauty of this Earth,
they left this,
framed in a garland of frozen popcorn.
Back at the base camp of Mount Erebus,
due to the considerable altitude,
once in a while the volcanologists
need medical care.
But soon we find them back at work.
My face is frozen.
Quite cold up here today.
Just by having that fantastic lava lake
down there with all that energy,
we still have to bring old petrol generators
up to the crater rim.
Man versus Machine, Chapter 53.
Professor Clive Oppenheimer on Erebus.
Hands in pockets,
waiting for it to start spontaneously.
He could be waiting a long time.
Have you ever seen two men kiss
on the top of Erebus before?
Pushing back the frontiers.
It's R-18, okay?
I like working with Harry.
Along the slopes of the volcano
there are vents where steam creates
so-called fumaroles, bizarre chimneys of ice,
sometimes reaching two stories in height.
It is possible to descend into some of them.
You only have to be careful
to avoid the ones containing toxic gasses.
At the foot of Erebus, out on the sea ice,
the two tallest buildings on this continent
are located.
In these hangars,
scientific payloads are being readied
for their balloon launch
into the stratosphere.
We were interested in
the neutrino detection project.
Scientists are planning
to lift an observation instrument
40 kilometers up into the stratosphere
in search of almost
undetectable subatomic particles.
As it rises, this small-looking bubble
of helium will expand
to fill the entire skin,
which here still looks like a white rope.
It will eventually form a gigantic globe
more than 300 feet in diameter.
When it reaches the stratosphere,
the detector will scan
thousands of square miles of ice
without encountering electrical
disturbances from the inhabited world.
Prior to the launch,
we were inside the hangar.
The neutrino project is led by
Dr. Gorham of the University of Hawaii.
So, what we're trying to do
with this instrument is to be the first
scientific group to detect the highest
energy neutrinos in the universe, we hope.
Yeah, but, Dr. Gorham,
what exactly is a neutrino?
The neutrino is... It's the most ridiculous
particle you could imagine.
A billion neutrinos went through my nose
as we were talking.
A trillion, a trillion of them
went through my nose just now,
and they did nothing to me.
They pass through all of the matter
around us continuously,
in a huge, huge blast of particles
that does nothing at all.
They're like...
They almost exist in a separate universe,
but we know, as physicists,
we can measure them,
we can make precision predictions
and measurements. They exist,
but we can't get our hands on them,
because they seem to just exist
in another place,
and yet without neutrinos, the beginning
of the universe would not have worked.
We would not have the matter
that we have today,
because you couldn't create
the elements without the neutrinos.
In the very, very earliest few seconds
of the big bang,
the neutrinos were the dominant particle,
and they actually determined
much of the kinetics of the production
of the elements we know.
So, the universe can't exist the way it is
without the neutrinos,
but they seem
to be in their own separate universe,
and we're trying to actually
make contact with that
otherworldly universe of neutrinos.
And as a physicist, even though
I understand it mathematically
and I understand it intellectually,
it still hits me in the gut
that there is something here around
surrounding me almost like
some kind of spirit or god
that I can't touch,
but I can measure it.
I can make a measurement.
It's like measuring the spirit world
or something like that.
You can go out and touch these things.
Not surprisingly, we found
this incantation in Hawaiian language
on the side of his detector.
It was as if spirits had to be invoked.
What would we see if we could film
the impact of a neutrino?
What you would see is, you would see
a lightning bolt about 10 meters long,
about that thick,
and it would blast at the speed of light
over this 10 meter distance,
and you would see the most beautiful
blue light your eyes have ever seen.
It happens in about...
The entire impulse of radio waves
is up and down in probably
one one-hundred billionth of a second.
It just goes bang and it's gone,
and that's what we're looking for.
There is a beautiful saying by an American,
a philosopher, Alan Watts,
and he used to say that through our eyes,
the universe is perceiving itself,
and through our ears, the universe
is listening to its cosmic harmonies,
and we are the witness
through which the universe
becomes conscious of its glory,
of its magnificence.