East and West do not
mistrust each other because we're armed.
We're armed because
we mistrust each other.
Mr. Gorbachev,
tear down this wall.
James fucking Gasciogne.
How did you find me?
Maybe you're not as good at
this spy shit as you think.
It was Satchel, wasn't it?
Satchel gave me up.
I always thought
if I got tagged,
it would be by the best.
But you're not the best,
are you, Bakhtin?
You're the biggest
fucking cunt in the KGB.
Sticks and stones, Jimmy.
That's a nasty black eye.
Where's C?
Given the scale
of recent world events,
C will not be joining us.
Yes, of course.
The voices on record
are the following.
Myself, senior directorate
officer Eric Gray,
our American guest,
Emmett Kurzfeld,
of the U.S.
Central Intelligence Agency,
and returning British operational
officer Lorraine Broughton.
Before we begin, sir,
may I formally request
that Mr. Kurzfeld be removed
from the debriefing.
Request denied.
What I have to tell you, sir,
is not for the CIA to hear.
Lorraine, you are the subject
of this debriefing.
Not its controller.
I understand that.
I was there, in Berlin.
And I'm here with the full
executive authority of Langley.
Would it make you
more comfortable?
I could stand behind the
mirror with everybody else.
But it's a little
crowded back there.
Cocksucker.
What did you say?
I didn't say anything.
I'm sorry. Did you say
something, Lorraine?
Did you hear me
say something?
I thought you
said something.
What did she say?
What?
Well...
Do you want to play
the tape back?
Well, then.
Shall we begin?
Berlin.
What happened?
Yeah.
Berlin.
Fuck.
Ah... Lorraine.
Sorry to bring you in
on such short notice.
You know C.
Lorraine; Yes.
We were just
going over your file.
I see your Russian
is excellent.
An expert in
escape and evasion.
Proficient in intelligence
collection and hand-to-hand combat.
It's an impressive
set of skills.
And knowing
the reds as I do,
she'll need to use
every damn one of them.
I'll get
straight to the point.
How well do you
know James Gasciogne?
Enough to say hello.
We worked together
in Istanbul in '85.
He's dead.
Gasciogne was killed last
night on a mission in Berlin.
The west German police fished his
body out of the Spree this morning.
And a coroner extracted
a 7.62 Tokarev round
from the base of his skull.
Soviets.
Yesterday, Gasciogne met with a
Stasi officer, code-named Spyglass.
We promised
Spyglass immunity
in exchange for a document on
microfilm, code-named The List.
Hidden in
a Swiss watch, no less.
The list contains every
active clandestine officer,
all their shady deals.
It's an atomic bomb
of information
that could extend the cold
war for another 40 years.
And we believe the man that
killed Gasciogne now has it.
Our sources point
to Yuri Bakhtin,
a KGB hatchet man with more
than a dozen confirmed kills.
So you want me
in Moscow?
No.
Bakhtin never
got on the flight.
So he's still in Berlin
along with The List.
Everyone's
hunting for it.
The yanks, the frogs,
Soviets of course.
And our man,
Percival.
Who's Percival?
David Percival. He's our
number one in Berlin.
He's your point
of contact there.
Straight from
the tit of the Virgin Mary.
The Jordache wasn't easy.
It's for my wife's birthday.
That's really nice. Now,
where's that fucking list?
I gave the microfilm
to Gasciogne last night.
James didn't show up.
I did my part.
I gave him The List.
You have to get me
and my family across.
It's not safe
for us anymore here.
The Russians are onto me.
No List, no deal.
I risked everything.
You listen to me, Spyglass.
Without that list, why
shouldn't I take you outside
and shoot you
in the fucking head?
You are going to kill
a Stasi officer?
One that's about to defect
to the west? Yeah.
Without an embassy
to look after him,
Percival has gone
somewhat native.
Gone fucking feral.
Berlin is the wild west.
And if that bloody wall
comes crashing down,
we don't want
to be under it.
If the Russians get that list,
we're all buggered sideways.
You're Elizabeth Lloyd,
a Cambridge-educated lawyer
sent by James
Gasciogne's family
to retrieve
the body and effects
of their
recently deceased son.
Your mission is
to connect with Percival
and do whatever it takes
to get that list home.
And remember, Lorraine,
this is highly sensitive.
Trust no one.
Follow me!
Come, come, come!
Quickly! This way!
Tell me you made a copy.
I memorized it.
Memorized it?
Every single agent
on that list?
Every Wednesday, you visit
the Penny Lane Brothel.
Your favorite girl is Margot.
Her real name is Maria.
Maria?
All right,
I'll get you across.
You're a good man,
Percival.
Fuck off.
I just want The List.
Once I... oh, fuck!
I will be in touch.
Uh...
Ooh!
I'm so fucking late.
Miss Broughton, Mr.
Percival was running late.
He sent me
to pick you up.
Checked bags?
No, they've been sent.
Please, follow me.
Docking in front
of the terminal
is not permitted.
Passengers loading
and unloading only.
So...
Is this your
first time in Berlin?
Yes.
Well, it's a remarkable
time to be here.
Wonderful music, superb
nightlife, marvelous restaurants.
You must try the central
café for a drink.
You'll need it later.
You remember Mr.
Bremovych, don't you?
Of course, you do.
Well, he's very curious what
you're doing here in Berlin.
What the fuck
are you doing?
Welcome to Berlin.
I'm David...
Where the fuck were you?
Don't shoot.
I've got your shoe.
Let me help you
with your bags.
Come on.
For fuck's sake.
Russians are
fucking heavy.
Five minutes on the
ground and I'm already made.
You're not made. I hope.
They knew my name.
That's troubling.
And yours.
That's hardly surprising.
Great fucking
start, Percival.
So what was
your first impression?
Of David?  - Well...
He was handsome. Late 30s.
Disastrous
Sinéad O'Connor hair.
Irish singer.
Hmm.
I asked him what the deal
was with that, and he said,
"lt's to blend in."
You want to touch it?
It's to blend in
in the east.
That was the Brandenburg Gate,
by the way.
I mean, how the fuck
do the suits think
that you're going to be able
to help me find that list?
As soon as you pick up
Gasciogne's body,
they'll null
and void your visa
and you'll be on
the first flight back home.
I'll figure it out.
That's
Checkpoint Charlie.
My office
is just back there.
I'm not here to collect
postcards, Percival.
Just drop me at my hotel.
It's around the corner.
I thought you said you'd
never been to Berlin before.
I can read a fucking map.
This will
just take a minute.
What are you doing?
Sending
a message to a fascist pig.
Say hello to comrade
Bremovych for me.
Bremovych.
Tensions are
high in east Berlin tonight,
as civil disobedience
continues to build momentum.
East Berlin's youth leaders
shout out their protests
through tear gas
and water cannons.
And there are
numerous reports
of police beating peaceful
demonstrators with batons.
I've been sent to arrange
the return of a British subject.
The body was
identified by your attaché.
Yes, I believe so.
This was not a question.
It was a statement.
He was your colleague?
Different department.
Which department?
A different one.
You have the transfer papers?
Do you know those movies where
the picture just starts to slow down,
and melt,
then catch fire?
Well...
That's Berlin.
The passport
number is incorrect.
I will not release this body
without the correct information.
It's a simple mistake.
Ms. Lloyd, in Germany, we
don't make simple mistakes.
I'm not going to lie,
I'm impressed.
You've got some balls
breaking in here.
You should see my balls, then
you'd be really impressed.
Hmm... I'll take
your word for it.
I see you found
a way to stay.
You wrote "16" when it
should have said "76."
That's right,
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm here for at least
another week.
Lucky fucking me.
They won't release the body now
until they've investigated
that red tape nightmare.
How the fuck
did you get in here?
You know, I've been
in Berlin a long time,
and I think I know
every doorman of
every decent shithouse,
borderline decent flophouse,
both sides of the wall.
Well, then you must
know Spyglass.
Never met the fellow.
He was James's.
What do you know
about this woman
who's been following me
since Tempelhof?
I'd say that
you're an attractive woman,
and you should do the math.
You know, if I was to follow
you, I mean, properly,
you'd never fucking know.
There's a knack
to it, isn't there?
It's like walking a tightrope
or playing bagpipes.
You can either do it,
or you can't.
Knock yourself out.
I'd like to purchase
a watch.
I need access
to a network in east Berlin.
Come back tomorrow
before closing.
East Berlin is on
a short fuse again tonight
as communist party officials
struggle to maintain order.
Gray- How well do you
know James Gasciogne?
He's dead.
You need to be careful.
...7.62 Tokarev round
from the base of his skull.
Soviets.
Gray- We know who Satchel is.
You need to run.
You expected to find the
list in Gasciogne's apartment.
You realize you were
late to the party.
Percival, the Russians,
everybody must've already
ransacked the place.
Lorraine; Yes.
But The List
wasn't our only problem.
Before I left,
he told me one last thing.
This is exactly why
I didn't want the CIA present.
Spyglass revealed
that this list
would expose a double agent
by the name of Satchel.
I want Satchel,
dead or alive.
This traitor has been a Thorn
in our side for years.
He's a black eye
to the crown.
And the single biggest
intelligence leak in MI6 history.
You expose this bastard,
Satchel,
and we'll hang him
for treason.
You might find yourself taking
tea at Buckingham Palace.
So no, I wasn't just looking for
The List in Gasciogne's apartment.
Percival and I seem to have a
different definition for collaboration.
Gray- What's that
supposed to mean?
He was the only one who knew
I was going to Gasciogne's apartment.
And if I knew he was
going to call the police,
I would have worn
a different outfit.
"Different outfit"?
Hey!
Halt!
With repeated calls
for change on the streets
and the protestors growing
ever more confident,
time is running out for
the east German government.
Popular opinion has it
that the communists' claim to
leadership can't be upheld much longer.
And if rapid change
is not forthcoming,
today's relatively calm
protests could be seen
as the calm before the storm.
It's not just new faces
that are called for,
but perhaps a complete
demolition of the wall.
Hmm?
Let me take your coat.
Make yourself at home.
Fucking hell.
Do you want a pair of
jeans? Help yourself.
Hmm.
Your library
includes Larry flynt?
Champion of free speech.
Hmm.
What have you found
on Bakhtin?
Look, if Bakhtin wanted the
Russians to have that list,
he would have given it to them by now.
We just have to wait for him
to make his move.
We can't afford to wait.
This is your city,
Percival.
Or do you only know
doormen and bellhops?
So what did you find
in Gasciogne's apartment?
Some deutsche marks, empty
passports, travel visas.
And a picture of the two of you
together a few years back.
Did I not mention
that we were friends?
No.
No?
I must have forgot to.
Get your coat, love.
We're going for a walk.
Look, we're all
exposed by that list.
Saving the world
is cool and all that,
but my main objective
is staying alive.
I've been head of Berlin
station for 10 years.
You've got to know that I'm
the only man in this town
that can help you
get that list.
Yes, I've read your file.
I've also read
your dog file.
So let's cut the crap,
shall we?
This whole hungover,
show-up-late,
don't-know-which-way-is-up
act?
I'm not buying it.
I trust you about
as far as I can throw you.
"It's a double pleasure
to deceive the deceiver."
Niccolò  Machiavelli.
It was on your shelf.
Oh, my god. I think
I fucking love you.
That's too bad.
If Percival was telling
the truth about Bakhtin,
I needed to figure out
what the Russians knew.
Stoli on ice.
I'm not speaking
German tonight.
So, you're British?
Very impressive.
This can't be
your only talent.
Talents can be overrated.
A dedication, a loyalty
is very rare these days.
Everyone here is
searching for something.
What are you
looking for?
Well, when all's
said and done,
wouldn't you say deep down, we're all
just searching for the same thing?
I leave you alone
for only a moment
and already you are
attracting admirers.
Monsieur, three is not always
a crowd, but tonight it is.
French women.
What about the British?
Maybe we can make
some sort of arrangement.
We haven't seen each other
in a long time.
And we really
need to catch up.
Alone.
Ladies, Berlin
is a small place.
I'm sure our paths
will cross again.
Sorry.
You looked like
you needed saving.
Well, I appreciate
the gesture, miss...
Lasalle.
Delphine Lasalle.
Pleased to meet you.
So, what do you do,
Delphine?
I'm a part-time translator who
really wants to be a poet.
Maybe a rock star.
My friend owns a club nearby.
Want to come check it out?
Now?
Sure.
I can't.
Well, I'll give you
the address anyway.
Come meet me there
tomorrow night?
Will you come?
Maybe?
You're relentless.
Oui.
David Hasselhoff's in town.
Lucky us.
Berlin is truly doomed.
Your watch is ready.
It's on the counter
in that plain envelope.
I think you'll find
my contact very useful.
Your watch is ready.
It's on the counter
in that plain envelope.
I think you'll find
my contact very useful.
East Berliners stormed
the west German embassies
in Czechoslovakia
earlier this week,
as the Czech government has
begun to waive the refugees
through checkpoints
with few questions.
One has to ask how long the east
Berlin government can hold on
as the tide of loaded Trabants
continues to flow out.
Bakhtin and The List had
not yet surfaced in the west.
I needed to meet
my new contact
and see what I was
up against in the east.
You should have applied
for a visitor's permit.
What kind of work
do you do?
Legal affairs.
If you do not
return before 6:00,
you will be arrested.
Do you understand?
I understand.
Right now, I'm not feeling very
confident about this story of yours.
Why not use Percival's
connections in the east?
He told me
to trust no one.
Hello?
You are late.
And you were followed.
I'm late
because I was followed.
I lost them 20 minutes ago
near the Palast der Republik.
You're as good
as your reputation.
Are you sure this
is the best place to meet?
Keep your enemies close.
I'm a permanent
fixture for them now.
The watchmaker says there has
been great interest in this list
on the black market
the last few days.
Any sign of Bakhtin?
No.
This Satchel character has people
worried on both sides of the wall.
Yeah.
What kind of network
have you assembled?
There's a lot of dissatisfied
youth on this side of the wall.
They're like a tinderbox.
If you find the right spark...
Keep talking.
I am interested
in selling a watch.
What are you selling?
It is extremely valuable.
The finest quality
and filled with secrets.
Would you mind if I inspect
the merchandise?
Fuck yes, I mind.
Just tell potential buyers
Bakhtin is open for business.
Ladies,
Berlin is a small place.
I'm sure our paths
will cross again.
Sorry.
You looked like
you needed saving.
My friend owns a club nearby.
Want to come check it out?
I didn't think
that you would show.
Stoli on the rocks'?
You pay attention.
I look for pleasure
in the details.
Speaking of which, I've been
dying to ask you a question.
Let's go someplace quiet.
Why the gun, Delphine?
You're not as well disguised
as you may think.
I know who you are.
You're Lorraine Broughton,
MI6.
And you're here because
of the death of Gasciogne.
What do you know
about Gasciogne?
Nothing.
But if someone is killing allied
officers, shouldn't we all care?
Whatever is in that list has
people willing to kill for it.
This is my first assignment
with the French intelligence.
I've only been here
a year.
I'm scared, okay?
I got into this
because it was exciting.
But it's never been
like this in Berlin.
You should have
become a poet.
Or a rock star.
So you made contact
with the French operative?
Obviously.
Why?
I believed she had information
I could exploit.
Nothing more.
Kurzfeld- And did she?
Did she have
any information, Lorraine?
There is something
I need to tell you.
It has to do with your friend,
Percival. He's...
Lorraine?
Did she have
any information, Lorraine?
Did she
give you information?
She gave me nothing.
David fucking Percival.
Are you following me?
Maybe you're not as good
at this spy shit as you think.
That was for James,
you fucking prick!
Now give me
that fucking list!
Gray- We needed to get you
a message, Lorraine.
We're several days into a
mission without a single lead.
And plenty of distractions.
You have to be reminded
of the course at hand.
Oh, I received your message.
That's quite a view.
70 miles of barbed wire, 31 of guard
towers, 65 anti-vehicle trenches,
40,000 Soviet-trained,
heavily-armed frontier troops.
All that,
and 5,000 GDR citizens still
had the brass balls to escape.
You've got the MI6 so worried they
called the CIA to talk sense into you.
Eric Gray called me.
Of course he did.
I don't have to remind you of
how fast the clock is ticking.
If this thing gets out,
a lot of good,
hard-working folks,
brave men and women
are gonna show up dead.
You and I included.
I swear to god,
the last few weeks,
I dread even waking up
in the morning.
I understand the severity
of the situation, sir.
And the time imperative.
Listen, I didn't
climb all the way up here
just to give you
some rousing pep talk.
So I'll cut to the chase.
Last night you met a woman.
Delphine Lasalle
is out of her depth.
Given the climate, I'd hate
to see an executive order
come down the line that
falls in her disinterest.
"Her disinterest"?
What do you mean,
"her disinterest"?
Don't insult my
intelligence, Lorraine.
You know exactly
what I fucking mean.
I hope you get a snapshot.
Next week, this will be
a whole different picture.
Satchel has been compromised.
Meet me at the rough
trade bar at Oranienstrasse.
We need to talk.
Look at all these hedonists.
It's like a beautiful woman
gone wrong.
I fucking love it.
Word is Bakhtin
has resurfaced.
Cops found him
with a homemade lobotomy.
Either way, we have
to deal with Spyglass.
Thinking it through, he doesn't
have much time over there.
Our priority is The List.
We can't make mistakes.
Come on!
He's hardly the most trustworthy
person I've ever met.
Or the fucking brightest.
Wait. You said
you hadn't met him.
I lied.
And he claims to have
memorized the entire List.
He's ready
to make the jump.
You believe he committed
the entire thing to memory?
Everything.
Had I known earlier, I would
have prioritized Spyglass.
His knowledge made him
as valuable as The List.
I could have grabbed him
at any moment.
Instead, Percival
kept it a secret,
putting us in
a precarious position.
Look,
the KGB are gonna have some
very angry bastards out there
looking for Spyglass.
We can't trust any
of the old routes or methods.
It's not that difficult to drive
across the border these days.
It is when you're
wanted like Spyglass is.
We have to walk him
across personally
to ensure his safety
in plain sight.
We'll use the demonstration
tomorrow at Alexanderplatz...
That's insane.
All those protesters
will make a great distraction.
Spyglass is my guy.
We're going to do it my way.
Fine.
But we use my contact to get
all our papers in order.
All right.
Do we have a deal?
I'll take that as a yes.
Hmm.
You see,
I received a call from David
Percival that evening, Lorraine.
He said he had The List.
I'll need
a little time to wrap it up.
And he knew
the identity of Satchel.
Oh, I'm very close
to Satchel.
And no one thought to tell me?
Hmm?
Fuck.
You brought
a lot of friends.
I heard Bakhtin
had a little accident.
I heard he slipped
and fell on an ice pick.
Berlin's a cruel mistress.
Especially for traitors
like Bakhtin.
Don't be such
a fucking communist.
You've got a problem.
Yeah, I know.
You have the fucking list.
We've been in the trenches
long enough to know
that at times like this, Berlin
has its own set of rules.
I can give you information
that will keep the balance.
Now, are you in or out?
Percival's trying
to set me up.
Are you surprised?
Not really.
These relationships
aren't real.
They're just
a means to an end.
When you tell the truth,
you look different.
Your eyes change.
Thanks for the warning.
What do you mean?
I mean,
I better not do it again.
Why?
'Cause it's going
to get me killed one day.
Well, lam impressed.
I thought Merkel here
was just a good bartender.
You smell like
a Stasi officer.
Shave off that mustache.
Use that soap and cologne.
It's from the west.
You can't take anything
from the east.
Merkel will give you
some clothes.
Right this way,
Mr. Spyglass.
It should have been easy.
The plan was sound.
Whatever went wrong did so
because someone wanted it to.
Someone from the inside.
You were betrayed
by a fellow agent?
You mean Satchel?
Would that be unheard of?
Per your request.
You won't be
needing that.
It will be worse
if they find it on you.
Everything else ready?
Yes. Everything
you requested.
I'm ready.
What do you think
of his shirt?
I wouldn't be
caught dead in it.
But for him,
it's perfect.
Stand over here.
Now look like a free man.
East Berlin youth leaders have
organized a demonstration this week
at Alexanderplatz.
Did he tell you I
memorized the whole list?
Yes.
I realize I may not be
valuable to some people,
and some people
may even want me dead,
but what choice do I have?
You're no good to me dead. And
I've never lost a package.
I know.
Hey! Hey!
It's his family.
This was not
part of the plan.
Part of mine.
Please?
I'll take the wife and kid.
You just have
to deal with Spyglass.
I don't know if I have
enough passports.
Percival.
Your golden boy.
We have to go.
See you in the west.
Good luck.
This was never
part of the plan.
It was part of mine.
No.
Stay low.
In here.
I need to deal with this now,
or we'll never get across.
I don't want to die.
You're not going to die.
Stay here.
Fuck.
Two more. There's two more.
Go!
We need to stop
that bleeding.
Search for anything.
Alcohol, rags.
Am I a bitch, now?
Get in.
Get in!
You need
to work on your German.
It's horrible.
What in hell?
Fasten your seatbelt.
You all right?
Yeah.
We have to go...
It's so cold!
Open your door!
My foot is stuck!
Just breathe!
- You need a break?
- No.
So...
Yes, I think I
understand everything.
You made your plan.
And you failed to get the high value
asset safely across to the west.
You sent me into
a fucking hornet's nest.
I was made by the KGB
from the moment
my feet touched the ground.
Maybe even before.
But then you knew that,
didn't you?
You had your doubts
about Percival.
And you used me
to shake him down.
Ready when you are.
Hey, hey. Whoa,
whoa, whoa...
It's me! It's me!
He's dead.
Spyglass is dead.
And you are alive.
They're all listening to me.
They knew.
The KGB knew everything.
I need to get across.
Well, I expected more out
of the Brits than a royal goat fuck.
I know. We're sorry.
No, wait.
You lot don't have your own
private Stasi agent, do you?
Not one with
a photographic memory.
We need to get with
Broughton and get on the same page.
We need that list.
Now more than ever.
Broughton?
She made it out.
Right.
You know, a beautiful
Italian girl once said to me,
"David,
"you can't unfuck
what has been fucked."
Women are always getting in the
way of progress, aren't they?
What no one in Germany
believed possible has happened tonight.
The wall is coming down.
The wall is down.
(On TV'; People here have
lived with the wall since 1961.
And I think now it's time to
break the wall down, you know?
The wall is crumbling.
The sledgehammers in the hands
of men not born when it went up,
tear into it.
Behind it, the east German
soldiers tried to stop the tide.
Water cannons
were brought out.
But the west Berliners
were determined.
One west Berliner
sprayed champagne back.
You know, if I was to
follow you, I mean, properly,
you'd never fucking know.
It is the moment Berliners
have waited 28 years for.
Even the east Germans
seem exhilarated.
A symbolic breach
in the structure
that cost hundreds of lives, and
separated friends, families,
and lovers for decades.
I found
a French UHF device
in my coat
after Spyglass died.
I now believe it was
Percival who planted it.
Made it look like Lasalle.
Why are you here?
You need to leave Berlin.
When I didn't hear
from you, I got worried.
How naive can you be?
We chose this life,
Delphine.
This only ends one way.
What are you talking about?
He set us both up.
You have to leave
while you can.
Yes?
Don't underestimate
me, Percival.
Oh, Lasalle, listen
to me very carefully.
You have no idea
who you're dealing with.
You set me up.
Come on, love.
This is the game.
I know your secrets, David,
and I can play this game
better than you think.
Percival's trying to set me up.
Are you surprised?
Not really.
These relationships
aren't real.
They're just
a means to an end.
When you tell the
truth, you look different.
Your eyes change.
Thanks for the warning.
What do you mean?
I mean,
I better not do it again.
Lasallei why?
'Cause it's going
to get me killed one day.
There is something
that I need to tell you.
It has to do with
your friend, Percival. He's...
Shh.
I'm sorry, darling.
This is the game.
Fuck!
Celebrations
continue in the streets tonight.
From the moment
the first wave of east Germans
crossed into Berlin,
they have been
showered with champagne
and cheered by
a crowd of thousands.
It is clear
this will be one of Berlin's
most dramatic days.
East Berliners are overcome
as they cross the border
that has been closed
to them for 28 years.
West Berliners are
chipping away at the wall
that scarred their city
and scaling it.
There is no more
interference from the police.
Unified, Berliners lay
symbols of peace.
Thousands of them looking east
and chanting,
"down with the wall."
There's only one question
left to ask.
Who won?
And what was
the fucking game anyway?
And I was thinking
the wall will never fall.
Germany's peaceful revolution is
probably the political and cultural story
of 1989.
We're gonna
take a quick break,
but we'll be back
with an in-depth look
at the number-one musical
controversy of the year. Sampling.
Is it art or is it
just plagiarism?
Don't go away.
Percival to win,
first, you have to know
whose side you're on.
In our line of work,
that's right up there with black
holes or "to be or not to be."
You fight the good fight, and then
one day, you wake up and you realize
that all you were
was Satan's little helper.
Ironic.
The news will tell them
there will be no more secrets.
But you and I,
we both know that's not true.
The world is run on secrets.
Oh...
Whoever has that list
has power.
And without it, you're just
another fucking target.
So what have I learned
after all this time?
After all those
sleepless nights,
lying to friends,
lovers, myself.
Playing this crooked game
in this crooked town
filled with backstabbers
and four-faced liars.
I'll tell you
what I've learned.
One thing
and one thing only.
I fucking love Berlin!
You didn't have to kill her.
You suddenly decided
to develop a conscience
after all you've done?
Have you noticed
how everyone you get close to
ends up fucking dead?
You gave Bremovych
the details of the plan.
You went to the KGB
to take me out.
You were too fucking scared
to do it yourself.
Too smart, more like.
If those KGB pricks
had done their part,
I'd be on my way to a hand job
with the queen by now.
I've read that list.
Lorraine.
Phew.
And you feature heavily.
It turns out, you've been
a very naughty girl.
Spyglass was a liability
to us all.
I couldn't risk
leaving him with you.
Where's The List, David?
I don't have it.
It's en route to MI6
where it belongs.
No!
Are you going to lie
till the very end?
Truth and lies.
People like us
don't know the difference.
No, we know
the difference, David.
We choose to ignore it.
Isn't that right,
comrade Satchel?
So that's how
you'll make it work.
"It's a double pleasure
to deceive the deceiver."
Well played.
You killed David Percival?
All the paperwork is in order
for the bodies of James Gasciogne
and David Percival.
You killed our head of station,
an officer of the crown.
You'd better have hard proof
and a damn good explanation.
Who are you
to judge my actions?
I'm your superior.
My superior.
This was never about
stopping the war.
It was about
saving your ass.
You couldn't bear the
embarrassment of the sins
that we committed
in the cold war.
And I was stupid enough
to give my life for it.
Yes, well, that's
your job, isn't it?
I did my job.
Despite your best efforts
and your incompetence,
l succeeded
where you failed.
I uncovered your traitor,
Satchel.
Brought him the only justice
he deserved.
A bullet.
Percival meeting
with Bremovych
the day before
Spyglass was killed.
Maybe we
can make some sort of arrangement.
You've got to
know that I'm the only man in this town
that can help
you get that list.
Very impressive.
A dedication, a loyalty
is a rare thing these days.
"It's a double pleasure
to deceive the deceiver. "
We have a deal?
What about the British?
Do you trust Gray?
Percival no.
What about C?
C is an arrogant lap dog who
understands precisely fuck all
beyond the edge of his desk.
Percival was Satchel.
Where's The List?
Where's The List, Lorraine?
I don't know.
Oh, bollocks.
The prime minister is going to
have a difficult time with this.
We're choosing to bury
this one, Broughton.
Your mission
never took place.
This conversation
never happened.
I'm putting you on leave,
effective immediately.
We'll start the next decade
well-rested.
C?
What should I wear
for my tea with the queen?
Hmm?
Did you really think I
was going to give you that list?
Before you die,
I want to get this through
your thick, primitive skull.
I never worked for you.
You worked for me.
Every false intel I gave you,
a rip in the iron curtain.
Every piece of intel you gave
me, a bullet in my fucking gun.
I want my life back.
Safe travels.
Estimated flight time
to Langley, 11 hours and 37 minutes.
Cleared for takeoff.
Let's go home.
That sounds good.
Cocksucker?
Really?
I'm glad
it was convincing.