- Ah who's this?
- You're cute.
Just look at him.
Go on inside.
Oh dear.
This guy doesn't seem to get it.
Bow!
Where are you trying to sit
without properly greeting us?
That's what he's trying to
get at right now.
How do I get initiated here?
Shall I sing?
Or...
should I get hit a few times?
Oh boy...
Hey.
I hear you're in here
for attempted murder.
You crazy nut.
Don't waste your strength because
I went through a lot to get you in here.
First, I'm going to explain the situation
to you, so listen up.
The man you messed with in jail...
He's our Boss.
He's on a completely different level
from scum like you.
That man bled from his nose
because of you, Attempted Murder.
The news about it
has already spread everywhere.
Even within this prison, there are
a dozen gangs who know you've come.
Hey.
We can't show them that
you can walk with both legs.
Our Boss has a reputation to uphold.
Is that so or not?
Will it do if I just apologize?
If I go to the Boss and...
Hey, you!
Ah, you mannerless bastard.
Hey, get up.
Who's your Boss?
Let's talk about it.
I'll do what you say.
If we just talk...
Get up.
Bastard.
Hey, does it hurt?
Do you see the sweat on
the sole of my foot? The sweat?
I sweated... to make sure
that you were in this room.
- How long have you got?
- 3 years and 6 months, sir.
I still have 8 years left.
We've got plenty of time.
Oh boy, oh boy.
Oh boy...
Someone come help!
Call them.
Officer, that prisoner is hurting himself.
He keeps banging his head on the wall
and saying he's going to die.
Officers, thank you very much.
He only came in here
to inflict harm on himself.
He should be given something refreshing.
Welcome!
Why did he call you out?
Is he going to give us something?
- Welcome!
- Yeah.
Danny!
Danny, you're mean!
You didn't call for me last time, right?
- You were too expensive.
- Danny, stay the night tonight.
I'm so tired, huh?
Isn't it written on my face?
That I'm a sucker?
- Suck me dry.
- Danny.
Do Woo, this girl wants me
to stay the night.
You have Yeon Hee.
How many are coming today?
Five.
Then should I send in nine more?
Yes. Have this girl and that girl
with Director Oh...
Executive Director Chae.
Are you by chance gay?
This and this.
No matter how much my girls flirt with you,
I hear that you don't even look at them.
Don't try to take them away
in the middle of our meeting.
You want me to pretend
that I don't know anything?
I like to gossip...
If you're afraid, you can prove it to me.
Please take extra care
of our room tonight.
We have important matters to discuss,
so ask the band to come in an hour later.
- Did you see it last time?
- I saw a little.
I heard that Do Woo's treating tonight.
What's the occasion?
Did that old man give you money?
Would that old man give him money?
It's probably money he earned
from a part-time job.
Stop trying to tiptoe around it
and tell us.
It's something that
we're going to be reluctant about, right?
I need some money.
Money?
You need some too, right?
Yeah.
A lot.
Why is my life like this? There are
only guys like this guy around me.
You in trouble?
How much?
For now...
I need five.
- He said five.
- Five billion won is a lot.
Hey, even if we drank five billion won
in this room every year...
It would take ten years.
And we could have ten ladies with us.
We could have five companies
that went bankrupt.
Doesn't your father
have a lot of cash, Do Woo?
His father?
A measly few hundred in annual revenue?
If a construction company revenued
a few hundred a year...
Can it build about two apartment buildings?
What a pathetic kid.
Hey, Yeon Hee.
- Yeah, Danny.
- Pour me a drink.
Okay.
Chae Do Woo.
Might as well come out with it.
I heard a rumor that
you messed with Byukjaewon.
- It's about that, right?
- What's Byukjaewon?
You don't know? It's that company
that sells tofu and dumplings.
Because of the dumpling scandal,
their stock price fell.
I heard there was someone who shook it up.
Was it you, Do Woo?
What's with this childish act?
Tofu and dumplings?
It's pretty big.
Its revenue is in the tens of billions.
Everything's been planned out.
I just need to hit it a couple more times.
You bastard.
So you're going to take over a company...
and you were thinking of
giving us the interest?
Since it's risky,
I'll take in the risk first...
Drink.
- How many shots is this?
- Thirteen.
These thirteen...
drink them all.
If he drinks all thirteen,
he'll die.
My taste for liquor is disappearing
because of this bastard.
You're not going to drink it?
I need the 5 billion Won by next Friday.
Hearing your voice annoys me.
So drink...
and shut up.
Do Woo might be annoying
but his IQ is 180.
We should listen to his plan first.
Baby, that 180-IQ Man's glass is empty.
What are you doing?
This has been planned for three months
and I'm this close to pulling it off.
The minimum profit is 10 billion Won,
the maximum is up to 30 billion Won.
- Do Woo.
- Yeah.
Drink.
Do Woo.
I'll drink it.
That kind of favor...
is something you ask of your own Daddy.
Should I be your Daddy?
Huh?
Call me that.
Dad... dy.
Daddy!
Ah, seriously...
If I tell you to call me by that, you do.
Ah I'm not drunk.
Let's have another beer!
Hey son!
Your car already left!
Did you not pay your driver?
- Director Oh!
- Yeah.
- Take care of my son...
- Okay, I'll take care of it. Go home.
Bye!
You're conscious, right?
I've... known you since
our Imperial College days.
Are you someone who gets drunk?
About Byukjaewon.
How much money did you already invest?
Three billion Won.
I'm missing seven billion Won.
In total 10 billion Won.
You put in quite a lot.
You that confident?
That account you took from Jae In with 2
billion Won. It's still as is, right?
Trying putting in half of that.
You... scary bastard.
How did you know about that?
One month from Friday.
Doesn't matter when it goes out.
I won't take a cent
of what you invested.
You'll give us 100 to 300 percent
in profit margin?
If you liquidate your safety deposit boxes,
it'll be about 2 billion Won.
Today it was 15,200 Won,
so the profit margin rose 76 percent.
If you sell at opening, it should be
a little more than 2 billion Won.
What?
I had something like that?
The inheritance you got two years ago
pays off tomorrow.
You slick bastard.
How do you know about the stock
I didn't even know I had?
I'm the slick bastard who's doing it.
Want in?
Okay. I'm in.
To be honest, Danny only knows
how to spend money.
I'll invest in you.
Because you only know how to earn money.
Me?
Someone who's able to tell
who makes money?
How many?
Two.
Three.
Take him away.
He's well.
Ahh.
Ah, ah.
2924.
Let's go.
- Please put me in another room.
- What?
If I go back, I'm going to die in that
room. So please place me in another room.
If I die, you have to write
a written explanation.
So... please put me in a different room.
Come inside.
Hey, you.
You there.
You're not with those gangsters, right?
But how come they don't hit you?
Those bastards just leave you be.
Has it been long since you've been here?
So is that why...
you know some tricks?
Look here.
Teach me.
What do I have to do
to those bastards?
No... I just want to change rooms.
How do I do that?
What do I have to do?
Why am I asking a crazy gangster...
Ah man, I'm going nuts.
Money.
Money kept in custody...
they've asked me to put in a lot.
Money.
And food.
Along with brand name training clothes.
Of many different sizes.
They ask me to put in a lot.
When people come to visit, they say it.
To put in a lot for them.
That's all you need.
Money...
Money.
Don't come.
You mustn't come.
You know the money at home?
Take that and leave for someplace far away.
Don't even tell me where you're going!
These guys are ten times worse
than the gangsters last time...
If they find out about you Myung Sun...
they might even harass your family.
Shin... but...
From now on...
I'm not the kids' uncle.
Don't even write me a letter.
Do you understand?
Then who will
send you supplies, Shin?
After Kyung Ah heard what happened to you,
she severed off all ties...
I said don't do it!
Don't mention Kyung Ah's name,
don't call me 'Uncle'...
And from now on,
don't even think about me either.
Just do as I tell you!
It's been over a week since they've moved.
They basically sold off
their furniture or whatever...
At dawn, they rented a moving van,
packed their things and left.
Aren't you Shin's fiancee?
How could you not have known?
Do you know where they went to?
It's because I can't reach them
by their cell phones.
I'm worried since I can't contact them
all of a sudden.
Do you not know?
I heard that you have a good relationship
with the residents here.
We do have a good relationship.
I even count the number of spoons
and chopsticks in each home.
But they left without telling you either?
But I heard that Shin got put in jail... and
you severed off all ties with the family.
That's how I heard it.
I hear a lot of things.
That's right. I cut ties off with them
but now I want to repair them.
Are you going to send me away
just like that?
Yes, Mr. President.
A girl came to look for them.
It seems like she heard something
from the security guard.
Yes, I understand.
Uh Boss... are you going
to let that guy go?
Don't make too much noise.
We're not an amateur baseball team.
Don't worry.
Just teach him a lesson.
We'll take care of him
exactly to your liking, Boss.
Ah, why does it keep falling?
Over here!
Food's here!
Hey.
If the food's arrived,
you should say so!
- The bathroom door's open. It's cold.
- Yes sir.
Scoop the soup, you bastard!
Give it.
- Let's eat.
- Yes, enjoy your meal!
Oh my...
It spilled.
Hey.
Save me!
These guys are going to kill me!
Guard!
- What's he doing?
- We're watching an act, sir.
Guard!
I'm going to die.
- 2924.
- These guys are trying to kill me.
I said these guys are trying to kill me!
You have a visitor.
What?
I've been put in the wrong room.
This room isn't right.
I don't know this person.
And I...
don't have anyone who would visit me.
- Kim Shin?
- Who are you?
My name is Chae Eun Soo and...
And what?
I came here to apologize.
What is she?
I'm Chae Eun Soo, the daughter of
Chae Dong Woo of Chae Dong Group.
On behalf of the company, we extend our deepest
apologies for the damage we've caused...
I will do my best to do whatever I can to provide
compensation and comfort for your losses.
If there's anything you need,
please let me know.
Clothes, blankets,
anything to eat...
- You there.
- Yes?
I think you've made a mistake...
You're Kim Shin, right?
- That's right but...
- Your brother is Kim Wook, correct?
I heard that he committed suicide.
Because of his business.
You.
What are you?
That's because...
it's our company's fault.
I would like to do whatever I can to...
Even if it's small...
What is this nonsense?
What about it is because of your company?
I'm not sure of the details.
I only know...
how to apologize.
I'm sorry.
You really have poor manners.
You should stand and bow, kid.
Say that you've returned...
And when the Boss gives you permission
can you sit.
Hey.
Jeez, I ought to just...
There.
And there.
Jeez...
Hey, Attempted Murder.
You should be making a ruckus and
pressing that emergency bell over there.
Hey.
Stand while I still ask nicely, huh?
Here we go...
One...
Two...
About me.
I wasn't going to make a peep
and then get out of here...
Has this jerk gone crazy?
I suddenly have something to think about.
So don't mess with me.
So I can think.
Oh!
Why don't you stop it!
What's he saying?
I said stop it.
My nickname in the army was
'Crazy Dog'...
You want to know...
the behind-the-story to it?
Over there!
He's... the younger brother
of the president of the dumpling company.
[Broadcasting Company Disturbance...]
The one who committed suicide...
Does the Chairman know about this too?
It's likely that he's
been briefed about it...
Eun Soo goes to visit this guy
and brings him food.
How did she find out about this?
Is it likely that we have a spy?
How does a girl who stays at home
find out about this and find him in prison?
Look into where the leak is.
- Yes sir.
- What else?
This is the list of people
the Chairman will meet with this week.
This was sent from the prison.
Because the recipient has refused to accept
the items that you have sent to the prison...
you will receive the equivalent
of the amount for the food.
Sender: Kim Shin.
It looks like he sent it himself.
Should I read this to you as well?
I was really...
about to get hit.
If that pane of glass
weren't blocking us...
that person, Kim Shin,
could have hit me.
He's a man who's in for attempted murder.
What do you expect?
But...
But what?
But strangely, he wasn't scary.
Isn't that quite strange?
He got angry and was yelling...
He didn't seem scary but...
could I say... he looked sad?
- What?
- He's good looking, isn't he?
- That guy.
- Mr. Do...
You want to read it yourself?
The letter that sad man sent.
Please read it for me.
If you're going to report to my
father anyway, you have to read it.
All right.
Mr. Do.
This is Kim Shin.
The younger brother of the man
who committed suicide, like you said.
I have something to ask you.
I hope you can come to visit me again.
Let's go.
The Chairman is waiting for us.
The people of this country
who speak so bluntly...
That's the beginnings of a nonstarter
in the character of the people.
You have to lead with an appropriate amount
of autocracy and charisma.
That's what the people want.
In that sense, if President Park led
this country for another twenty years...
the GNP would be double what it is today.
- Right?
- Yes.
What this country needs is a monarchy.
An autocratic monarchy.
Even if President Park were still alive...
that would be difficult in our present day.
There is so much discussion
with the world of the Internet...
My, my, how frustrating!
What's so hard about it?
You buy a few Internet companies...
Those slackers who don't do anything
because they don't want to work.
You get a few hundred of them
and pull them in.
What's that? A part-time job.
Put them to work.
Hard?
That's easy.
That's why I told you.
That we need to conduct business
like Chairman Chae.
But running for congressman
isn't that expensive.
Why won't you go for it?
Stop trying to coax me.
Take a look at this man's answer, huh?
He's interested in it!
He's interested!
These people whom I have invited
cannot leave empty-handed.
Oh dear, she's pretty.
She's pretty, huh?
Of course she's pretty!
She's got a pretty face
but she's not very smart.
University is pointless.
At first, I thought about sending her
to study abroad...
But if you send a girl overseas, the only
thing that will happen is that she gets hurt.
That's why I keep her here.
What are you doing?
Present your greetings.
Oh, she's a beauty.
A beauty!
She's my only daughter...
And when I die, I'm thinking of
giving her more than my son.
So look around for a decent match.
Chairman, will you notice a son from
just anyone's family?
I don't want an average
second-generation rich man.
And I hate those who
took drugs in New York.
I'd like a man who's able
to earn his own money...
knows a few things
and has mastery over them.
Would there be a man like that?
This old man has become more greedy
as he gets older!
2924.
Stay still!
2486! Stay put!
You know how many demerits you get every
time you're put in solitary confinement?
It's not like you can enjoy yourself
with the accumulated amount anyway.
Let's be careful.
Just... think that
you were bitten by a crazy dog.
Boss, this isn't a situation
you should involve yourself with.
If you get involved,
your demerits will increase...
And if your demerits increase,
it will affect your parole.
Boss.
No matter what, you have to make parole
and get of here early.
That way we can stay in business.
So Boss, please do not get
flushed by that kid's...
Am I like toilet water
to be flushed?
For now, I told the kids to lay off of him.
- Oh, that's not bad.
- The others will be shocked when they see.
Just give us an order.
We'll take care of him
without anyone catching on.
There are plenty of fellows
who are lining up to join our group.
If we can get a useful one to...
A few days later, a few days later...
What is there to take care of?
Just leave him be.
Seriously, Boss.
Us, South Faction, aren't
the only ones here.
All the factions of the country, at least
one or two of them of each are in here.
'Boss is getting hit by a nobody.'
Do you want this kind of rumor
to float around the country?
Our Yong Shik.
You sure have grown a lot in here.
Now you're teaching me a thing or two.
Huh?
Let me go!
Grab him!
Stay still!
Let go!
- Stay right there!
- Break it up!
- Grandma!
- Me?
I came to find a friend
who moved here from Seoul.
- Do you know where she lives?
- Seoul?
Uh, she's a mother with two kids.
Two daughters.
Yu Ri and Nu Ri.
It's probably been about a week
since they've moved in.
Is it that house over there?
I'll give you food.
I'll make you a lot of tasty food.
Yu Ri, your mom's coming.
- Yu Ri.
- Kyung Ah's here! Kyung Ah!
Yu Ri!
Have you been well?
Go on inside.
It looks like Shin used a loan shark
to repay Wook's debt.
That makes it our debt.
So instead of us,
he's taken a loan upon himself.
Instead of myself and the kids.
Wook left us after that incident...
If the insurance money came out right, then
we could have at least sold the apartment...
and we could have repaid that debt.
Because those people
don't want to give us the money...
they make false claims
about the dead...
What would you like to drink?
We don't have coffee.
You're cold, right?
The boiler must be old,
it's not very warm.
- How much is that debt?
- I don't know.
Shin won't tell me.
I know.
That portrait won't talk.
That he will cause trouble
before thinking about his actions.
To be in debt to pay off a debt.
And because he wouldn't be able to pay,
he voluntarily went into prison.
But he didn't say anything that made sense.
To me. Not even one thing.
He just said words that disgusted me.
Myung Sun, I was really disgusted,
by that man.
Shin tried to cut me off too.
You're more precious to him than I am.
So he probably had to
push you away further.
But why did you come?
You might as well have misunderstood
and left without looking back.
Just...
Kyung Ah.
Shin and our situation...
is so bad.
I missed you all.
Yu Ri and Nu Ri.
You too.
Stay the night and go back.
Go back and forget us.
That's what Shin would have wanted too.
- Should I?
- Yeah.
That doesn't seem to work very well.
That.
To forget.
I'm sorry.
Kyung Ah.
We're so sorry.
To Shin... and to you...
Here...
Kim Shin's older brother, Kim Wook.
That person's dead.
His wife, Oh Myung Sun.
Their daughters Kim Yu Ri, Kim Nu Ri.
Everyone's here.
What is this?
Who are these people?
Oh, it's cold.
Hello.
It took a lot of effort to find you.
Thanks to this young lady,
she guided us right here.
But who are you, young lady?
Are you Kim Shin's fiancee?
Hi.
- That was a set!
- Fine fine!
Okay, again.
Again.
You're Kim Shin, right?
Your brother is Kim Wook, correct?
I heard that he committed suicide.
- Because of the business...
- Who... are you?
That's because...
it's our company's fault.
I would like to do whatever I can to...
Even if it's small...
What is this nonsense?
What about it is because of your company?
Is it true that no one came to visit me?
That's strange.
I asked her to come.
When was it that you said
that you would never take visitors?
Excuse me.
The woman who visited me last time...
is there a way I can get her phone number?
Can you look into it for me?
- There we go.
- Oh my.
It's freezing cold out there.
Grandma, I'm going to sit here
for a bit and then leave.
That's better.
Who are you calling?
Lady, shut that baby up!
I can't talk.
Nu Ri.
Hello.
This is the police, right?
We have some gangsters in our house
and they're bullying us.
Myung Sun, what's the address here?
Thank you for your hard work.
I'm a representative for Chae Kwon Dwa.
I'm here to collect a debt.
This woman borrowed my savings and promised
to pay me back in a few days but she didn't.
In this harsh winter, it looks like
my family will soon be out on the streets.
She called me a gangster?
Oh dear me...
Officer, is lending money a crime?
Yes, I understand.
Of course I want to settle it politely.
Yes, yes.
Have a good day.
- Hey.
- Yes, sir.
I was going to keep my words civil,
but she called me a gangster.
A gangster... we're going to
have to show her what that means.
What's going on?
- Let's go eat.
- Come here.
- Gather around!
- Hurry hurry!
Hurry up and gather around!
Everyone is gathering together.
Okay, your name!
Next!
Seriously!
This arrogant jerk!
- You bastard!
- Stop right there!
Come here you bastard!
Come here!
- Stop it!
You aren't complying?
- Let me go!
- Seriously!
You bastard.
Bastard!
This isn't even enough
for one month's interest.
You come crawling to a faraway place,
with gas and travel expenses.
What is this paltry amount!
Anyway, let's see each other again
next month, Lady.
And next time, give us a reasonable amount.
What is this?
We destroyed the children's
toys for nothing.
Hey.
Keep a close eye on this lady
so that she doesn't escape again.
Yes, I understand.
I'm hungry.
What do you boys want to eat?
Something with broth?
That money...
was the last bit we had.
After we moved out of our apartment
and gave our workers' their wages...
that was what was left.
My children have nothing now.
- Have a drink.
- Yes, sir.
Mister.
Punch in your number.
Hello.
That number is mine so contact me
about Kim Shin's debt issue.
I'm better than a woman with children
who only knows how to do housework.
- What did this young lady say just now?
- That she'll repay the debt herself.
So there are women like this
in the world now, huh?
How much is it?
Kim Shin's debt?
Ah, I'm touched.
A lover should act like this...
People these days...
That's wrong.
It's not like that.
You said that you're going to
repay the debt.
A woman who hasn't
registered a marriage to him.
That means you're his lover.
That jerk and I...
aren't lovers.
If you want money from me,
don't call me that.
Do you hear me Mister?
Do you not want to live?
You know those guys are
part of the South Faction gang, yes?
If you knew, then going straight
for their leader...
means that you want them to kill you.
What I've said is off the record.
I just threw it out there
so we'll move on.
2924.
Starting today, we've assigned you
to a new room.
We even changed the guard...
Once you are there, behave yourself.
Ah.
Your fellow cellmate, 4687,
will be joining you.
Make sure to thank him
when you see him.
Because if it weren't for him,
you would have really died.
Was I... wrong?
At first...
I just wanted to extend
my jail time a little longer...
Because if I get out of here early,
nothing good will come of it.
So if I keep fighting and get beaten...
Then I could stay in here
for 10 more years, I guess.
That's what I thought.
Do you know that?
If I do that, then I could become
the best fighter in here.
But...
It became more and more tiresome.
Be it in here or in the world...
There's nothing that I can do.
There's nothing...
that I can do.
Therefore...
should I just die?
I thought like that.
We must be brothers.
Wook.
You were like that too, right?
Last night, Daddy...
in his doting affectionate way...
held in his hand, crayons...
he bought and brought for me.
All night... in dreamland...
An elephant was dancing...
Crayon soldiers...
rode the other leaves and played.
I'm going to earn money.
I'm going to turn into a dirty and
awful girl and repay your debt.
Think of it as my entrance fee
to another world.
What did they do to you?
- We can't see each other anymore.
- Are you okay?
Because you and I...
are going to live in different worlds.
Let's try the Byukjaewon project again.
Let's try to spread some rumors slowly.
The road's been covered already,
so let's light the fire.
Those without money will probably say this.
Why would you do that for some money?
You fall short and
you grumble everywhere else.
Blaming others for your whole life.
Don't you feel ashamed?
What did you say your name was?
Chae. Do. Woo.