You bastard.
You should've protected her.
How could you kill her, you bastard?
Look here.
Do you think I killed Ae-gyeong?
Do you really?
I said I would bring her back.
I never said I would kill her.
I'm a businessman.
I'm not a gangster anymore.
A businessman does not commit murder.
We do business.
Let's see what's going on in the hearing.
Ae-gyeong Kim, please come forward.
You do know the hearing is today, right?
-Do you like this too?
-Wow. Thank you.
What a good kid.
When is Mommy coming?
Please stand and take your oath.
Well...
I swear
to tell the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth.
It's Mommy. Mommy's on TV.
Please ask her your questions in order.
Ae-gyeong Kim,
Mayor Sang-do Bae received a bribe
and helped Chairman Yeong-guk Jo, correct?
When someone is above the law...
he doesn't fall into the gutter.
Do you understand whom you just took on?
No, he did not.
Wait a little while.
I'll make the same things happen
as three years ago.
There is circumstantial evidence
that you were present
when Yeong-guk Jo bribed
Mayor Sang-do Bae.
Do you still deny it?
It is not true.
Stop perjuring yourself.
I am not.
We heard you know Mayor Sang-do Bae
and Yeong-guk Jo well.
I've never met Mayor Sang-do Bae.
The people are watching.
Why do you think you're here?
I do not know.
Je-mun, you punk.
People had been discussing
the possible reason
for Ae-gyeong Kim
not appearing to testify.
Therefore, her appearing
at the hearing now
has a huge implication.
Won't this hurt
the prosecution's position?
It was their assertion
that Yeong-guk Jo
was intentionally hiding her.
But she appeared to testify.
She testified that
no illegal connections were used
to win the bid
for the Inseo redevelopment.
-In that case...
-Yes, that's correct.
You can tell by looking
at the change in numbers.
Ever since Ae-gyeong Kim testified,
Mayor Bae's approval rating
went up by six percent.
Hyeonseung Group's stock also went up
about 23% today to...
Seong-cheol.
Yes?
You're taking that often lately. You okay?
Why wouldn't I be?
Take a break once this is over.
A break? What for?
Don't worry. I have Pil-sun.
She takes good care of me.
-Yes?
-What will you do now?
How will you get
Ae-gyeong Kim's testimony?
Do you have a plan?
I'm thinking it over.
So, you have no plan.
Why did you lose her?
Why did you lose her to Yeong-guk Jo?
If things go wrong, we're all dead.
Do you realize that?
Let's go classic. What we do best.
AE-GYEONG KIM ACCOUNTING OFFICE
We're with the Prosecutors' Office.
Hey. Search it all.
Ae-gyeong Kim!
-What is it?
-We're with the Prosecutors' Office.
We're executing
the search and seizure warrant.
Grab the laptops.
-Let's corner her before we die ourselves.
-Move quickly!
Someone who dealt with dirty money
must've gotten her hands dirty.
We'll dig into that woman's finances
and find every detail
of every transaction she made.
Ma'am.
Check the drawers.
-Dig deep,
-Min-su.
-bring me anyone who received
-Mommy.
-It's okay.
-a dime from her.
Be careful!
Get them to come voluntarily
or arrest them.
Just bring them to me by tomorrow.
So...
-Hello?
-Ae-gyeong.
People suddenly barged in here,
supposedly from the Prosecutors' Office.
They say the money I got from you
was a gang's laundered money.
I'm coming.
Min-su, stay at your nanny's, okay?
I know it's dirty, but we have no choice.
Just do it!
-Please.
-The police may fall,
but we cannot.
Conglomerates may fall, but we cannot.
The government may fall, but we cannot.
-Dad.
-Ae-gyeong.
Why did you come here?
Dad. Everything will be fine,
so don't worry.
-Mom...
-Let's go.
-Dad.
-Mr. Kim.
In Korea, we are the authority.
We are the truth.
We are justice.
If we fall,
our nation falls.
Ae-gyeong.
I don't understand what's going on.
-Hello?
-The vendors are calling,
saying the prosecutors
are raiding their offices.
They're being asked about
what their relationship is with you,
and about the money that was exchanged.
What should I tell them?
Hello?
Must we do that to people
who have nothing to do with Yeong-guk Jo?
We're trying to get Yeong-guk Jo,
not Ae-gyeong Kim.
It'll be a problem later.
If you worry about later,
you'll regret it later.
Which prosecutor issued the warrant?
If we lose Yeong-guk Jo again,
we won't have another chance.
Do you want to get screwed over again
like three years ago?
You said you got tough.
You said you could do anything
if you could catch him.
Then show me
how well you sharpened your knife
over the past three years.
I didn't do anything...
I followed the policies...
We'll investigate. So please be quiet.
What did I do wrong?
You must've brought me in
because I did something wrong.
-Please sit down.
-Is it a crime to be rich?
-Please...
-I followed the policies...
Why did you drag me down here
all day long?
-I never did anything wrong.
-Tell me!
I never washed money...
Mr. Woo.
It's okay. You don't have to say it.
I know.
This...
This isn't your idea, is it?
Keep up the good work.
Where should I go?
This way.
One sundaeguk and soju please.
I don't have any sundaeguk. I'm all out.
Then give me anything I can eat.
How long has he been here?
About two hours.
What are you doing here, Je-mun?
You're not the only regular here.
Why do you look like that?
Where's your wig?
I lost it while working.
I'll buy a new one tomorrow.
Being a human rights lawyer
is good and all,
but think of your own rights too.
Whose rights was it about this time?
I'm representing the residents of Inseo
being displaced by the redevelopment.
I got a few punches in too.
I've always been a good fighter.
Seriously. Good for you.
Fight in the courtroom, will you?
Don't get beaten up on the streets.
Think of your well-being.
We need to get to the courtroom
to fight there.
When I was a prosecutor, I was there
more than I was in my own home.
That's how the court is.
Why did its walls get so high
once I retired?
Why do you live like that?
Live like the other guys.
Pick up some divorce cases and make money,
and buy a nice wig. Please.
Is this why you took the bar exam?
This isn't living.
Then what? What is "living well"?
Teach me, so I can live like that.
Je-mun. You know,
I wish Seowon, our town
would be like this.
Where common sense trumps senselessness.
I wish following the law
would trump cheating.
I wish coexistence would trump
survival instincts.
I wish warm hearts would trump
cold hearts.
I wish nonviolence would trump violence.
If our town is to be like that...
If our town has to become
where people don't get sick
and don't get hurt
as much as possible,
this is the only way.
Lose every day, get beaten up every day,
and cry every day.
I don't know anything about it.
I've never seen it before.
Do you know Gwang-seon Oh?
No, I don't.
In 2016...
Even if people mock me,
saying I'm stupid, stubborn, and clueless,
living like this...
Living like this and changing it...
That's what I must do
to be proud of myself.
Every town needs an idiot like me.
A few more would be nicer.
Yes, Mr. Woo.
Let those people go.
Let's start over.
Let's not harass innocent people.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
Let them all go.
I said to send them home.
Thank you for today.
We'll be in touch, so go home for today.
We'll treat you properly
like prosecutors next time.
Jun-hyeok, was it your idea to have
Ae-gyeong Kim
testify at the hearing?
Why are you hanging out
with Yeong-guk Jo and Sang-do Bae?
You weren't like that.
Don't you know what they're like?
Of course, I do.
I know very well.
Then why are you mingling with them?
Mayor Bae was voted by the people.
We should respect
the people's judgment and decision.
And what if the people judged incorrectly?
Why should we judge that?
Because we're prosecutors.
You think prosecutors can do anything?
Did you become a prosecutor
to gain authority?
Jun-hyeok.
Do you remember when we were
on the National Council
of Student Representatives?
You were so cool back then.
When you spoke on the platform
in front of hundreds of underclassmen,
you were so cool.
Do you know what I thought
when I saw you up there?
"That is authority.
That guy Jun-hyeok Ban has the authority."
That's what I thought.
What are you trying to say?
Where people are, is authority.
And if I don't grab it, someone else will.
That's how authority is.
You may deny it all you want,
but we prosecutors are authoritative,
and we prosecutors have authority.
That's why the government created us.
Stop mingling with them.
It'll look bad
if it gets out that he had a prosecutor
in his back pocket.
Do you understand?
I'm not sure.
We'll have to wait and see
which way things turn.
You don't seem to have
any more hands to play.
You've been cornered.
Many people suspect you too.
Think about it.
What if the knife
you were pointing at those people
suddenly targets you?
And what if everything
you wanted to hide so badly
all came to light?
Which way do you think things will go?
Jun-hyeok.
Are you threatening him?
It's okay.
Jun-hyeok.
Do you want to succeed that badly?
Enough to stab your own family?
There are
many people who are
in a different category than you.
You should know by now, don't you think?
So?
Where's Je-mun now?
Je-mun.
The chief prosecutor didn't look happy.
Did something happen?
Why did you let them go?
Holding her family hostage and forcing her
to say what we tell her to
is too degrading.
That's not what a prosecutor should do.
If it isn't, what should a prosecutor do?
I would like to keep professional
boundaries when we work.
We're not gangsters.
What are we doing,
detaining innocent people?
Do you think you're the only good,
true prosecutor?
That's why you'll never make it,
you moron.
Do you know why you aren't promoted,
while junior prosecutors surpass you?
You know that line you refuse to cross?
The others crossed it already.
Then what?
Should we torture Ae-gyeong Kim?
Should we bring her child as well
as her parents and lock them up?
Is that what I should do?
Yeong-guk Jo said last time
not to use someone I cherish
and want to keep close to me
for a long time to hold the dagger,
since he may die.
Do you know what I did?
You. I called you
to point the dagger at him.
Call them back in.
Call them back, and torture them.
Who knows?
I may not call you next time
for something like that.
I can't do that.
I can do anything to Yeong-guk Jo
and the East Gang.
I'll do anything you ask.
But let's not bring in innocent people
and show off our strength.
We're prosecutors after all.
Then kill him.
Go and kill Yeong-guk Jo.
You said you would do anything I ask.
What? You can't do it?
You have no guts whatsoever.
That's your problem.
That's why your wife left you, loser.
Hello, Mr. Chairman.
Hi, Ms. Kim. I heard you were called
into the Prosecutors' Office.
Good work. Did anything happen?
No, sir. Nothing happened.
Really? Nothing happened?
Ms. Kim.
You're not hiding
something from me, are you?
Of course, not. I am not hiding anything.
Okay.
I believe you.
Stop by when you have time.
Let's have dinner or something.
It's been a while.
Yes, sir. Good night, sir.
Okay.
Tie up loose ends now, Sang-mo.
That feels refreshing.
You took a while.
You haven't eaten yet, right?
You didn't tell my mom, right?
-About what?
-About what happened before.
If she finds out, I'm dead.
Exactly.
If you're worried about your mom,
don't go to places like that.
I'm not worried about my mom.
I'm worried about myself.
I'm the one who will die.
Anyway, keep your promise.
I won't forgive you if you tell my mom.
Kids these days.
Eat up before it gets cold.
It's good.
Sorry.
You should just eat first.
I wanted to live.
That's why I did it.
If you can't take it anymore,
if it's too hard to endure,
you should leave.
That's all.
So that I can end up like you?
Lose everything I have, get hurt,
and run a restaurant in a place like this?
I can't live like that.
No.
I won't make Min-su live like that.
I just need to endure it.
As long as I hold it in and endure it,
my son Min-su...
I just need to endure it.
Then everyone will be happy.
You asked last time, right?
Whether we're living in the right times.
I suddenly feel like
it's right for you,
but not for me.
This damned life.
Did we get a new doctor?
Excuse me.
There was nothing injected.
Her condition hasn't changed.
-Ju-myeong.
-Yes?
Put some boys here that we can trust.
Okay.
It was Yeong-guk Jo.
That bastard ordered it.
No. We don't know for sure yet, so...
Drop the bullshit.
We're not sure about what?
Who else would try to kill my sister?
He's taking out the trash.
Now that things are over,
he's trying to kill my sister again,
since he failed the first time.
There's no way
to catch those bastards now, right?
Say something!
Let's go before my sister gets back.
Shouldn't we stop him? He seems dangerous.
You're kidding, right?
Gang-ju may kill Yeong-guk Jo.
You know that as well.
Just leave him. Let him do whatever.
To be honest, I don't know...
I don't know
what kind of a person you are.
Earlier, you said to let those people go,
and now...
I mean...
Aiding and abetting a murder is a crime.
Hey. You think people
are either black or white, right?
But they're not.
Everyone in this world is gray.
You should know by now.
Even still...
What are you trying to do?
I'm saying we shouldn't do anything.
Whether or not Gang-ju kills Yeong-guk Jo,
you cover your eyes and ears,
and stay quiet. Is that so hard?
Sir.
Hey.
Jin-pyeong.
You can't understand why I'm dying
to get Yeong-guk Jo so badly, can you?
It was their assertion
that Yeong-guk Jo was intentionally
hiding her.
But she appeared to testify.
She testified...
Find out Yeong-guk Jo's schedule.
Hi, it's me.
Starting tomorrow...
can you track Gang-ju, please?
It's still quiet so far.
What is this about?
Why did you ask me
to track Gang-ju out of the blue?
It's nothing big.
Well...
The thing is...
Depending on the situation,
it may become big.
What are you talking about?
Did Mr. Woo order this...
No, he did not.
I'm doing this on my own.
So...
I would prefer that
Mr. Woo doesn't find out about this.
Do you understand?
I'll take the blame
and any responsibility for this,
so please just let me know
wherever Gang-ju goes.
I'll make sure you aren't hurt by this.
You can do that much, right?
Just tell me this.
No one will get hurt
because of this, right?
It's to live...
I'm doing this so that we can all live.
Please trust me on this one.
Okay.
I'll let you know
if Gang-ju goes anywhere.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay.
Hold on.
Hey, Gang-ju!
You punk. What are you trying to do?
Is that a knife in your hand?
Hey, Gang-ju!
You punk. What are you trying to do?
Is that a knife in your hand?
Gang-ju ran.
He took a weapon with him.
I don't know where he went.
What's going on right now?
Wow. There are a lot of you.
Hello, I'm Yeong-guk Jo of Hyeonseung.
My employees
will explain the details slowly,
and in easy-to-understand terms shortly.
To be honest,
I don't understand it either.
There are too many big words.
Shit.
There is only one thing
I can tell all of you
gathered here today.
"Inseo is a town
where people who have nothing
gather and live!
They are leeches
who eat up our tax money!
Those Inseo bastards!"
Many people are saying that.
How close are the Inseo bastards?
They're almost here.
You're here today
-because you're trying to survive too.
-Damn it.
Those annoying bastards.
Should we call the boys?
-It may be ugly now, but it won't be
-Call over the chairman's bodyguards.
once it is redeveloped.
Bundang started with shacks,
Seocho was farmland
and there's nothing but water at Haeundae.
But look how they are living now.
They're doing well and are proud now.
Why do you think that is so?
People!
It's because the people changed.
Once the people changed,
the surroundings changed.
Once the surroundings changed...
My gosh. The land price changed.
INSEO REDEVELOPMENT PRESENTATION
The Inseo that I envision
will be the same.
A town where if you say,
"I live in Inseo,"
everyone will envy you.
I'll turn it into a town like that.
You know I do
anything I set my mind to, right?
Yes!
Should we block the entrance?
Send the boys back to the chairman.
-Sorry?
-Send them back!
I ended up talking for too long.
Listen to the presentation now.
Thank you.
We oppose the Inseo redevelopment!
We oppose!
Lock up Yeong-guk Jo!
Lock him up!
Best in the country? That's garbage!
Garbage!
Mr. Chairman, we want to talk!
Let's not go that far.
That bastard!
Let go!
Die!
Damn it!
Kill that bastard!
Kill him!
Chairman Jo!
Hey. Jin-pyeong.
You can't understand why I'm dying
to get Yeong-guk Jo so badly, do you?
That bastard manipulates people.
"I have authority and money,
and you don't.
Those with, are on my side.
Those without, are enemies.
Those without are trying to take from us,
so fight with me."
That's how he starts a fight
between people,
and hides behind them.
Isn't he an evil bastard?
That's life.
If you don't have anything,
you can't succeed in anything.
When that happens,
you get nervous,
which leads to resentment.
Resentment leads to misery.
That's why murders occur.
The killer and the killed
both become miserable.
Hey. Must we live like that?
Must we keep fighting?
If you have money, you should help.
If you don't, ask for help.
Isn't that human decency?
Isn't that how we should live?
Yes.
I understand what you mean, but...
You're toying with Gang-ju too.
Then what makes you any different
from Yeong-guk Jo?
-What was that?
-What the heck?
This...
This isn't right.
Gang-ju was there today?
Yes, sir.
My instincts told me to stop him,
so I was able to this time...
But those rats will try again.
How could civil servants
do something like that?
Those bastards
must've been there to kill me, right?
Yes, I believe so.
Okay.
If that's what you think, it must be true.
What do you think we should do?
How do you think we should punish them?
Tell me your opinion.
To be honest,
I didn't think you would go there.
What do you mean?
I thought you would leave Gang-ju alone
to cause trouble.
Hey, I'm still a prosecutor.
Exactly.
I realized for the first time
that you were a prosecutor.
You punk. Don't start with me.
I'm just happy, that's why.
You're a prosecutor,
and I'm an investigator.
When people like us do something,
it's by governmental authority.
Governmental authority
can't ignore the law
and kill people directly and stuff.
People like us
shouldn't like using a knife.
It should stink.
We should think the law is the best thing
in the world. Don't you agree?
I think Sang-mo Ha
saw Gang-ju's face earlier.
Protect him well, Ju-myeong.
He may retaliate.
Yes, sir. Of course.
Of course, we must.
Why are you in such a good mood today?
Did something good happen?
Did your wife go to her parents?
Why did you tell me, when you promised
Jin-pyeong you would keep it a secret?
Out of loyalty?
No. Allegiance.
I know I've been all over,
like some peddler,
but I'm your investigator.
Forever. I'm yours.
You punk. Listen to you.
You're like this to other people too,
aren't you?
It's a trade secret.
I need to pee.
I must be incontinent.
I keep having to pee lately.
Yes?
Yes, I'm fine.
Due to raised suspicions,
a public hearing is in progress.
The conflict between the people
regarding the Inseo redevelopment
is intensifying.
In Seowon...
Is it bad?
I'm fine.
I'll go get it.
Hey.
Go to the hospital.
What will you do without me?
You'll really die at that rate.
What are you babbling about?
Don't worry about me, and go.
You should go to the hospital
if you're not well.
Not like they would...
What the heck...
Let's talk when I get back.
Shit.
Damn it.
A brawl broke out among the people
regarding the Inseo redevelopment.
This morning,
at the Inseo Redevelopment Presentation,
both people for and against
the redevelopment appeared,
and five people were injured.
Some of the oppositionists
crashed the presentation and threw eggs
-at Chairman Jo.
-Hello.
-It's a valued project
-Kimchi stew please.
of Seowon and Hyeonseung Group.
-The redevelopment is expected
-Okay.
to face difficulties.
What do you think about it?
Well, the presentation
held in Inseo in Seowon City
came to an abrupt end.
Those who oppose the redevelopment
and attendants of the presentation
created mayhem at the venue.
The attendants...
So cold.
What?
Why won't this work?
Hi.
My child has a fever.
I have to take her to the doctor,
but I have no car.
Could you give us a ride?
Why is it so small suddenly?
Well, I only get what they give me, so...
Then you should ask for more, you bastard.
What's wrong? What is it?
-Pardon?
-You're sweating. Are you sick?
No. That... That's not it.
I don't... I don't have a choice
about this either.
What are you talking about?
No choice about what?
You're high, aren't you?
What's taking her so long?
Damn it!
Shit. This punk.
You're not skimming, are you?
No. I didn't do that.
I... I'm sorry.
I'm so... so sorry.
Stop stuttering, and talk properly.
Sorry.
About what?
What?
Okay, good night.
Here you go.
Who are you?
You little...
-Ju-myeong.
-Mr. Woo...
Let go!
Damn it, let go!
What are you doing?
Don't come here.
Pil-sun!
Damn, you bastard!
Hey.
Every town needs an idiot like me.
A few more would be nicer.
Look.
I'm sorry to say this,
but that's nonsense.
If common sense trumped senselessness,
it wouldn't be like this.
If following the law trumped cheating,
we wouldn't be here.
This wouldn't have happened to you.
They asked me to just call you over.
Pil-sun.
Look at you. What is that?
Our town
won't end up how you wish it to be.
If it could, it would've already.
Just keep living with that attitude.
I'll continue cleaning up dirty shit.
So? What do you want to tell me?
-I have a favor to ask.
-What?
I don't care if they're detectives
or our guys.
Send me 20.
Then I'll bring you that bastard
Yeong-guk Jo's head.
You want an all-out war?
There will be consequences.
I don't care.
I'll quit if they want me to.
I'll go to jail if they want me to.
Just let me kill Yeong-guk Jo.
That's all I ask.
Hello, Commissioner.
Can you send me ten guys?
Hold on. Hello?
I want ten of my men and ten of yours
to do something.
What kind of guys do you want?
You want young guys who fight well, right?
It doesn't matter.
Just scumbags.
Scumbags will do.
Yes. No.
I can talk. Go ahead.
What? Go ahead.
Yes.
Yes, sir. I'll go now.
Hear that? Send me ten scumbags.
Shit. Do you have wet wipes in the car?
-Yes.
-You do?
-We have to go. We've been called.
By whom?
-Je-mun Woo.
-Je-mun Woo?
Did you pack the stuff?
-Yes. Here it is.
-Good.
-Did you check it?
-Yes, I did.
-Satisfied?
-Hurry up!
Now, go get Yeong-guk Jo.
Catch him and kill him.
Remember this. If you fall,
Korea falls.
Je-mun Woo. How much does he know?
Should we kill Yeong-guk Jo?
That doesn't sound so bad,
if that would end it.
I'll also fight dirty now.
Don't even think of leaving
until we kill Yeong-guk Jo.
Kill before you get killed.
How did we end up here?
In the Seowon that I envision,
there's no place for Chairman Jo.
Where's Yeong-guk Jo?
Who hired you? Who was it?
You still don't get
what's happening, do you?
Shut up, you bastard.