- It's headed
right for the pin.
- Oh, man.
- Why can't I hit a ball
like that?
- I could answer that,
Or you could just look
in the mirror.
- All right,
what did I miss?
- The swedish guy
is starting to choke.
- Swedish guy?
Who taught him how to swing,
heidi?
- Actually,
heidi was swiss.
- Get out of my chair.
- Hey, robert, can you
move over a little bit, please?
- No. Take the middle.
- I don't want the middle.
Gianni, you move over
to the middle.
I'll go on the end.
- Just sit down.
- All right, you're gonna
feel a little man thigh.
How does that feel?
You like that?
- Come on!
Cool it already.
- People, shut up,
all of you guys.
- What?
What's wrong?
- Nothing. It's...
Debra's not feeling well
bio...Hormonally.
- Oh...Got it.
The enemy within.
- So...Do me a favor.
Just don't do--
don't give her a reason--
Be cool. Be cool. Be cool.
- Hey, ray.
These were on top
of the hamper.
Are they dirty,
or are they clean?
- Uh, yeah,
those are dirty.
- Oh, they're dir--
okay, well, then, ray,
Let me enlighten you
as to how a hamper works, okay?
There's a lid on it,
and that lid lifts up.
Now, you take your clothes--
not your clean clothes,
Not the clothes you're
wearing right now,
But your dirty clothes--
You lift that lid,
you insert the clothes,
And you shut that lid.
- Yeah. Got it. Got it.
- This is very nice, ray.
Yeah. This is very nice.
Pretzel crumbs
all over the place.
- Yeah, I'm gonna clean
those up.
- Okay, see what
I'm talking about?
Frickin' mood swings.
They find me chopped up
in the freezer,
Don't believe
the suicide note.
- That's a beautiful shot.
- Boy,
it's a rough time of the month.
You know a lot of criminals
turn themselves in
When their wives are like this?
- Look,
just do me a favor.
Don't be, like, animals,
all right?
I don't need--
- iceberg dead ahead.
- Coaster.
Robert, coaster.
- What?
- Need help?
Need any help?
- No. I'm going to the bank,
all right?
Listen,
when the buzzer goes off,
Could you maybe take the clothes
out of the dryer?
- Yeah. No problem.
How long you gonna be?
- Why?
- Oh, nothing.
No. Take your time.
Or hurry back if you want to.
It's your choice.
ah...
I thought
she'd never leave.
- Is debra aware of how
she's coming off to others?
- No, she--she doesn't
hear herself.
And if I bring it up to her,
she gets all nuts and denies it.
That's the sickness.
- You should get her on tape
and make her listen to it.
- You want to wear a wire?
I'll shave you down
and hook you up.
- Why doesn't she just
take something for this?
- What's she gonna take?
- Raymond, have you ever been
in a drugstore, huh?
There's a whole wing
dedicated to this problem.
- Yeah, all right,
what am I gonna do?
What am I gonna do,
buy her something?
Besides, I wouldn't
even know what to get.
- Get 'em all.
- Yeah, all right.
Just don't worry about me,
all right?
I'll just ride it out.
- You dumb bastard.
- What?
- Ride it out?
You put a stop
to this now.
- All right, dad.
All right.
- Let me ask you,
she's in a bad mood what,
Two, three days tops?
Not so tough now, right?
She's gonna get a mood
that lasts five days...
Then it's a week.
And before you know it,
What used to be
a bad mood now takes over
And becomes her only mood.
And then...
Well, then you become
like me...
Where not a day goes by
That I don't wish
there was a comet
Screaming towards earth
to bring me sweet relief.
- What's so funny?
- Dumb bastard.
He's a dumb bastard.
- Hey, banjopants.
Hope you're in the mood
for some delicious italian,
And I don't mean just me.
Big bag of nemo's takeout.
- Oh...
- What? I--I went by,
And I stopped,
and I picked up some dinner.
I also picked up
some after-dinner mints...
Which for your sake,
I've already dipped into.
- But I have already
started dinner, ray.
Why didn't you call me
ahead of time?
- Who knows?
But look, surprise.
Garlic bread.
- Well, I've made a salad,
and I've cooked the rice,
But...
Forget it.
We'll eat your food.
- You all right?
- Yeah...Fine.
I'm sorry.
Thanks for the dinner.
- Don't worry about it.
Look, I know a lot
of stuff's going on...
Feminine-ally...
You know.
I know it's--
it's not your fault.
I understand that.
It's, uh...
You know, it's like
a jekyll-and-hyde thing...
Only more...Hyde...
If he's the bad one.
It was hyde, right?
Whatever. Whatever.
That's yelling at my friends
for making a mess
Or getting all crazy
about clothes on the hamper.
I know that
that's not you.
That's hyde...
If he was
the bad one.
But you know what?
While--while I was out today,
I got you something.
I--I really...
I want to help you
feel better, you know,
And...And--and this should
take care of all your...
Symptoms.
- Except for bitchy,
right, ray?
- I mean, there's nothing
in here for bitchy.
- Probably need a prescription
for bitchy.
- Boy, this is
just like you, ray.
Just when I think that you can't
be any more insensitive,
You rise to the occasion.
- Hi, are the kids home yet?
I've got cookies.
- Oh, mama, mom--mom,
please, just go home.
It's not a good time--
- It's okay.
She can stay if she wants.
I'm not afraid
if she hears this.
- Jekyll would be.
- Tell you what,
I cannot...
Take this anymore, okay?
You make a huge mess,
you don't help me at all,
You invite
your friends over
To drive me crazy
all day,
And all you can think of is,
"oh, she must have pms.
Let's just load her up
with drugs."
- No. It's got
st. John's warts in it.
- I can't believe you.
If there's ever
anything wrong, it's pms, huh?
Sometimes--I just--
I don't know what to do.
Sometimes I just want
to smack you.
- Debra's right, raymond.
- You smacked me.
- I know I did. I'm sorry.
- Well, what--uh--
what you do that for?
- It's just that it sounds
like you're becoming
Just like your father.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
It's just that...
He was so awful during my...
Ladies' days.
Anytime I happened
to make a comment
About his usual
disgusting behavior,
He would just
blame it on that.
- That's what ray does.
- That's what they all do.
- What are you talking about?
Look, I'm just
trying to help.
- You should be quiet.
- Yes.
Yes. Oh, no.
He is trying to help.
Look what he bought me.
Magic pills, huh?
Maybe I should try some.
mmm. Oh, look.
Ray's clothes
just flew off the bed
And into the hamper.
These really work.
- Oh. Let me have one.
Ohh...Frank's toenails
Just crawled right
into the garbage can.
- What are you doing, mom?
It's me. Raymie.
- Raymond, you know
that I always let you two
Fight your own battles,
but I can't let you go on
With this cycle of
your father's imbecility.
- I'm out of here.
- Oh, come on.
Where you going?
- I'm leaving too.
I'm gonna talk to your father.
- Oh, please, come on.
Debra, debra, please.
- Raymond, don't you
say one more word,
Or I'm gonna send
your mother right back in here
To smack the crap
out of you.
- The three-game series is even
at one apiece.
- Hi.
- Oh, you're home.
Did you have a good time?
- Yeah.
- What'd you do?
- I told you.
I went shopping with amy.
- Shopping? For 5 hours?
Where are your shopping bags?
- I didn't buy anything.
Then we went back to amy's and,
you know, just sat around,
Talking, relaxing.
- Oh, sitting around,
talking, relaxing, yeah.
You want to hear my evening?
Peanut butter and jelly.
Then I gave 'em a bath,
'cause they were covered
In peanut butter and jelly.
Then I'm mean, because I won't
let them sleep in a tree house,
And then they went to bed
yelling and screaming.
So that was my evening.
Thank you very much.
- Well, that's my evening
every night, so--
- Oh, don't even.
You just wanted me
to suffer tonight.
- What?
- Yes. It's not fair.
You get to walk out
and do whatever you want,
And--and--
let's just say it--
Use your "ladies' days"
as an excuse
To treat me rotten
every month.
- My needing to get out of here
once in a while
Has nothing to do
with my "ladies' days."
- Bull-loney.
- What?
- Baloney.
You want to see?
'cause I don't care, okay?
I tried to be nice,
and that doesn't work.
Here. Look at this.
You see this date?
That's today.
Now, this is last month.
What a coincidence
that on the same day last month,
I found my golf clubs
upside down in the garbage can.
I'm telling you,
I'm sick of this, all right?
Every month the--
the same wacko screaming at me
For no reason,
having meltdowns and crying,
Crying over nothing.
And god forbid I should mention
what might be the problem.
You know what I think?
I think that you
enjoy your ladies' days,
Because you think I deserve
to be treated like this.
"oh, look what day it is.
Oh, come here, ray."
Pow. Pow. Pow. Pow.
"oh, oh, I've been
saving that up."
And then after
a couple days of that,
You're like, "oh, sorry, ray.
I was just a little bit,
heh, you know."
And by the way, the next time
I used those clubs,
I shot a 110, so don't think
I don't know
You didn't put a curse on them.
- You are out of your mind.
- No, you are...
Once a month.
How come you don't treat me
like this on all the other days?
- I treat you just fine, ray.
You're just mad,
'cause you had to spend
One lousy night
with the kids.
- Oh, so you don't get crazy
this time of month?
- No.
- You remain perfectly calm,
Don't overreact,
don't treat me meanly,
Or yell at me
like a screaming, raving maniac.
- No, I do not.
4:38 today...
Right when
the guys went home.
- I've told you 8 million times
when you empty the dryer,
You clean the lint screen.
Look at all this lint.
What, do you like lint, ray?
Maybe I'll get you some
for your birthday.
Happy birthday, ray.
Here's your lint.
- I just thought you'd,
you know,
Want to hear
what you sound like
When you're like this.
Okay?
- You are a gigantic ass.
10:32, "gigantic ass."
Listen, I'm sorry.
I know what it's like
to hear yourself on tape.
I remember when I heard
my first radio interview.
First of all, I sounded
like snuffleupagus.
I said, "do I really sound
like that?" and andy said--
- Oh, would you stop it.
I'm not crying
because of what I sound like.
I'm crying because I'm married
to an insensitive durfwad
Who instead of trying to make
life better for his wife,
Tape-records her so he has proof
that she's a terrible person.
- What's a durfwad?
- What, was that tape
for the guys, huh?
You gonna play it
for the guys?
"hey, come on, fellas,
step right up
And listen to the witch
who killed my good time."
- No. No.
It's just for us.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Where's my tape recorder, ray?
When I was in labor
with the twins for 36 hours,
And you were asking the nurse
if the tv gets espn?
- Well, I mean, 36 hours,
that's not a short time.
- Yeah. Guess what.
It's even longer
when you're trying to push
Two human beings
out of your body
"does this hospital
have fudgesicles?"
Yeah, where's
my tape recorder, huh?
Or when you ask me
why I get so upset
Because I find your
underpants in the kitchen, huh?
Or when you started snoring
at my grandmother's funeral?
Or when you taped
a football game
Over our wedding video?
- Do you--do you really need
a tape recorder?
You seem to remember everything.
- Yeah.
That's right, ray.
I remember everything.
And I'm not gonna forget,
either.
- Honey, I think you make
some excellent points here,
But I can't help
wondering that, you know,
Maybe part of the reason
you're so upset right now
Might possibly
be pms-related.
- Would somebody get me
a tape recorder,
- Look, I don't know what to do.
I just don't know what to do.
- Yeah. Yeah.
No kidding.
Listen, if I had pms--
and I'm not saying that I have--
Is that how you help me?
By taping me,
by telling me I have pms?
That doesn't help me, ray.
That doesn't help me.
- Well, what do
you want me to do?
I don't know what to do.
Show me what to do.
Just draw it out for me.
- Have you ever thought
about giving me a hug?
- A hug.
Did you ever think
of hugging me, you jerk?
- Well, it's pretty hard
to hug someone
Who's trying to kill you.
- Yeah, well, it never
occurred to you.
You've never even
tried it before.
- Well, look.
This is not huggable.
This--this is not debra.
This is the woman
who shows up once a month
To rip into me like a monkey
on a cupcake.
All right, that's it.
That's the reason
I taped you:
And maybe admit
that there might be a problem
That isn't just me
being a dorkwang or whatever.
- Hello?
Hi, amy.
Yeah. Yeah.
You went back
for that dress?
How much was it?
Oh. You are so bad.
Yeah. Right. Right. Right.
Oh, god. I know.
Me too. Me too.
Oh, my god.
Okay, well, listen.
I'll call you tomorrow, okay?
Okay. All right. Bye-bye.
- Feeling better?
- She's so funny.
- Yeah, she is.
Could we put her number
on speed dial?
- Listen, ray.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I guess I am a little,
you know.
- Well, I didn't want
to say anything.
- Listen, I...
I--I don't mean to--
to lay into you like that.
- I know. I know. I know.
- Come on. Sit.
- No. It's okay.
- Ray.
Honey, listen.
I need a little understanding,
just a little caring.
I need to know that,
you know,
If I'm going through
a rough time,
That--that
you're there for me,
And that you want to,
you know,
Just take care of me.
- I do want to.
You're my girl.
- I love you, ray.
- Oh, god, you're a mess.
- I know.
- Listen, you want to just try
those pills that I got you?
'cause I really just want you
to feel better.
- Yeah, I know, but I just
want you to know that,
You know, no pill
is gonna solve everything.
- I mean, do you have any idea
what goes on in here?
- Yeah. Let me just get 'em.
- I know, but--
You know, yes,
there's all these emotions--
Believe me. Listen.
I'm very into all of that.
Let me get the pills.
- Here we go.
Hmm?
Here we go.
It's okay. It's okay.
Look, it's, "for bloating--
For bloating, cramps,"
and, oh, right there,
"irritability
associated with pms."
We have a winner.
Goes great
with ginger ale.
Okay, here we go.
Here we go.
What? Hey. Come on.
- Why don't you just
lock me in the attic
For a few days?
- What?
You, you're the one
who said, "hug me."
The hug was your idea.
Come on, comet.
- So you think I'm just rude
and insensitive,
That I'm so tough
to live with,
And you're the queen of sheba?
Did you ever
hear yourself?
Well, in case you haven't,
Here's a little trick
that my boy raymond taught me.
I said, "where's my eggs?"
Wait a minute.
Here, here. Wait a minute.
Here, here it is.
What?. It's just my feet.
They're not dirty.
Aw, crap.
You scared you're gonna hear
something you don't like?
If I scratch it,
it's because it itches.