Victor?
There's a goddamn palm frond
floating in the--
Jesus Christ.
Ike...
♪ Now when I was a little boy ♪
faye! Where the hell's Danny?
♪ At the age of 5 ♪
Ike... we got it.
We're handling it. Don't go out there.
♪ I had somethin' in my pocket ♪
Fair pay! Fair work! Fair pay!
Fair work! ♪ keep a lot of folks alive ♪
You!
♪ now I'm a man ♪
Tell Mike Strauss
I wanna see him.
Hoffmans. 10 a.m.
Tell him Fluffy says "Hi."
Uhh!
♪ You know, baby ♪
Come on!
♪ I'm a man ♪
You can't do this!
Unionize! Unionize!
Unionize! Unionize! Unionize!
Get Vee another white poodle
now, before she wakes up.
Vic...
Make sure it's a girl dog.
Where's Stevie?
Sleeping. You check his room?
Find your idiot brother.
The union won't cross
the picket line
to deliver my booze,
and I got 1,500 thirsty people
coming to see Sinatra tonight.
Get Stevie.
Okay.
Unionize! Unionize! Unionize!
Unionize!
Unionize! Unionize!
You. New kid. Come here.
What's your name?
Uh, Ray. Ray Mathis.
Ray-Ray, put your hand here.
Right here.
What do you feel?
Feel? Nothing.
Exactly. Perfumed air
is supposed to blow
out of that nozzle
24 hours a day.
Perfumed?
What does it smell like?
Smells like the ocean
and new money.
You get Cecil the engineer, okay?
Absolutely.
Hey.
You ever wonder why we keep
it so cold in here? No, sir.
Goddamn meat locker, right?
It's so the ladies
can wear their furs.
That's our job, Ray-Ray.
We sell the dream.
Yes, sir. And-- and, sir...
It's just Ray.
Not anymore.
♪ I know a cat
named way out Willie ♪
♪ he got a cool little chick
named Rockin' Millie ♪
♪ he can walk and stroll
and suzy Q ♪
♪ and do that crazy
hand jive too ♪
♪ papa told Willie
you'll ruin my home ♪
Stevie, slow down.
I will if you will.
♪ Willie said, mama,
don't put me down ♪
♪ they're doing that hand jive
all over town ♪
♪ hand jive ♪
♪ Mama, mama,
look at Uncle Joe ♪
My car! Stevie!
What about my car?
It's-- it's fine.
What?
It's just holding its breath.
Stevie! Stevie!
There you go.
Sounded good out there, pop.
Ahh.
See you, Arthur!
That Inez has
got some rack on her.
Arturo!
Lovely.
Do you know Inez gives me
a shower every morning?
Sits me on a stool, right?
She soaps me up everywhere.
Even my privates.
I know.
Listen, smart-ass,
heard you're having
dog problems.
Good news travels fast.
Still got a few friends.
I know.
That's why I'm here.
I was wondering and thinking
that maybe you could
talk to Al Strauss for me.
I know he's retired,
but his son Mikey
is a union lawyer now.
I think Mike would listen
to Al.
Mikey's a pisser
like the old man.
They're both of them
stubborn as hell.
He won't back down.
Can you just talk to Al for me?
I've gotta go
meet Mike at Hoffmans.
You handle it.
You.
Don't even think
about going to your partners.
Don't... don't start, pop.
I don't have partners.
The Miramar is mine.
I see.
And Benny Diamond is what,
your new bellboy?
And what brought him down
from Chicago all of a sudden?
He likes Sinatra.
How the hell do I know?
You know.
Don't expect any help from him.
Those ganefs
only help themselves, Isaac.
I'll see you later, pop.
Isaac...
Happy new year.
Yeah.
Happy new year, pop.
Dad?
♪ For your love ♪
♪ oh, I would do anything ♪
♪ I would do anything ♪
♪ for your love ♪
♪ for your kiss ♪
Who is it?
♪ Anywhere ♪
It's Stevie.
Is my dad here?
At Hoffmans.
Some breakfast meeting.
Spare a cigarette?
Sure.
It's our secret.
Ike thinks I quit.
That's your business.
He calls, let him know
I'm down at the Atlantis.
Stevie?
Is everything all right?
You know, with the strike
and tonight?
Well, what'd he say?
He says yes.
Then it is.
♪ That's why I... ♪
♪ for your love ♪
Housekeeping.
Hey.
You're in a great mood.
Yeah, well,
I have to work tonight.
On new year's?
Sinatra's playing downstairs.
One of us owns the place,
and the other one is the maid.
You're a maid
like I'm a cabana boy.
Your dad--
Works for your dad.
I'll see you later.
Be my date tonight.
A date?
Like your date, date?
Yeah.
No. No.
I don't know.
Just come with me.
What's the big deal?
We're friends, right?
Friends go do things.
Right?
Yeah. Absolutely.
I can't go anyhow.
I told you--
Oh, I'll get Stevie
to change your shift.
What?
I don't have anything to wear.
I'll see you at 8:00.
You're the biggest.
You go, the whole strip will go.
And I will go.
But we had two goddamn
hurricanes this fall
that cost me the high holidays.
I blew Christmas thanks to you.
Now if I don't make good
on Frank's new year's run,
it's over.
You shut me down, Mike,
then what?
Then maybe the next guy
runs an open shop, Ike.
My people are happy, all right?
I pay them better
than any hotel on the beach.
They don't want it,
and I don't want it.
I killed myself getting
my own place,
and now I'm gonna
make you--
Make the union my partner?
Let you tell me
what I'm supposed to pay?
How to run my hotel?
I'll be out of business
by summer.
So who do you like
in the orange bowl?
We are talking about
my goddamn survival, Mike.
My hotel. My family.
I will do whatever
I have to do to stay alive.
Do you hear me?
You know what? Fine. Fine.
I'll pull my guys
off the line till midnight,
- okay? That gives you the day.
- Okay?
That's the best I can do.
Midnight?
It's goddamn
new year's eve, Mike.
Sinatra starts
his second show at midnight.
What the fuck am I
supposed to do in a day?
Unionize.
This could get ugly, Mike.
It will get ugly.
Give Vera a squeeze for me.
Victor.
Get Ricki. Have her do
something with the cabanas--
A fashion show, bikini contest.
Comp 'em the shit champagne,
screwdrivers.
Let's keep the lobby clear
in case our friends come back.
Wait a minute. The strike--
They're coming back?
No. I don't know.
Stevie?
You look like shit.
Well, as grandpa always said...
"You only go around
once in life,
and sometimes,
not even then."
You do know that
your grandfather's insane?
You starting new year's
a little early?
I always hated new year's.
Even as a kid.
Seemed like the only people
having a good time
were the tourists.
Just couldn't
compete with that.
I guess I had my nose
to the glass.
They're back on at midnight.
Can we stall?
Tell 'em we'll vote
in the new year?
It may get us through the night.
Mike's too smart.
He wants to hit us.
Make an example.
The whole town's
watching the Miramar tonight.
He wants to shut us down.
How 'bout this--
How 'bout no fucking way?
Not tonight.
Not in my joint.
You know who's upstairs
in my goddamn hotel?
Mr. Frank Sinatra.
Francis Albert Sinatra,
in my presidential suite.
And tonight he's walking out
onto my stage,
in my hotel,
and he's ringing in
my goddamn new year.
That sounds like a lot of fun.
It sounds like a hell
of a lot of fun.
So basically, you got
a warehouse full of booze
sitting in Fort Lauderdale
and no way to get it in here.
Not until now.
How you gonna find guys
crazy enough
to fuck with the union?
Not crazy. Hungry.
Champ.
Thunder and lightning.
Grady, tell my boy here
what you told me.
Some of the fellas...
You know, the boxers
at the Sir John...
If I ask them,
they'll drive for y'all.
It could get messy.
You pay cash...
These guys will park
your whiskey in the lot.
I'll be waiting for you.
All right. Let's go, champ.
Stevie...
Mm?
Miramar doesn't hire
dopers or felons.
I'll do my best.
It's your fault, kid.
Sounds good.
The card room?
Yeah, right off the lobby,
but we got a $1,000 limit
on that game.
Bel? It's Ike.
Sure, but if you got
the juice you say,
there's the cabana game tonight.
Cabana one,
next to the ice machine.
Yeah. All night.
That game's no limit.
Sure. Right. Okay, fine.
You let me know.
If that mobster's got
two nickels to rub together,
I'm a rockette.
Hey. Ike. I'm dying here.
It's like a morgue.
I had to let Iggy go.
Dead. No action. And it's
the season, for Christ sakes.
I got ponies, dogs, jai alai.
I got bubkes.
What would you like me
to do, Belvin?
You know what you gotta do.
You gotta talk to our friend.
You gotta cut
the head off this thing.
You can't ask Francis Albert
to walk through
that circus tonight.
Somebody's gonna get hurt.
I heard they killed Vera's pup.
Come on, now.
That's just wrong.
Ugly.
All right. Where is he?
Now you're thinking.
He just got back
from his honeymoon.
Ben divorced Doris?
Well, kind of.
She died in childbirth.
Didn't... didn't Ben's first
wife die in childbirth, too?
Yeah. What are the odds?
This new kid's
a real beauty. Whoo.
Legs to here,
like Cyd Charisse.
Benny's smiling. Now's the time to get him.
Good luck, kid.
Thanks, Bel.
Sea breeze lingerie.
Fat Tony!
It's a goddamn fruit salad.
How can it take 40 minutes?
This meat loaf is ice cold.
Please.
Give me that.
What's going on?
I don't know.
What the fresh hell is this?
Honey, honey,
all of the help is gone.
Please do something.
Oye, people! What the hell?
Che has taken Santa Clara.
Havana will be next.
Maria is there.
My Maria is there.
Batista will never
let Havana fall.
It'll never happen.
We'll get Maria
on a plane tomorrow.
I promise.
We'll get her home.
Victor, I need your help
out here. Come on.
Mr. James.
It's grady James.
Hey, champ!
Grady James! Can I get
your autograph, please?
Here you go.
Can you sign this for me
right here? Yeah.
Hey, Stevie,
why don't you look around?
Give me five minutes
with the fellas, okay?
Just follow me
right through here.
♪ the evening breeze ♪
♪ caressed the trees ♪
♪ tenderly ♪
♪ the trembling trees ♪
♪ embraced the breeze ♪
♪ tenderly ♪
♪ then you and I ♪
♪ came wandering by ♪
♪ and lost ♪
♪ in a sigh were we ♪
♪ the shore was kissed ♪
♪ by sea and mist ♪
♪ tenderly ♪
♪ I can't forget ♪
♪ how two hearts met ♪
♪ breathlessly ♪
♪ your arms opened wide ♪
♪ and closed me inside ♪
♪ you took my lips ♪
♪ you took my love ♪
♪ so tenderly ♪
Thank work for you, doll?
Not bad, Miss E.
For a first pass.
I'm Stevie.
Stevie Evans.
Lily.
So...
What's a rich white boy
doing in overtown
on new year's eve day?
You waiting for
the ball to drop?
Yeah.
Exactly.
And?
Has it?
Four...
Three...
Two...
One.
Hey, did you guys see a really,
really pretty white girl
come through here?
Not since Elizabeth Taylor
was doggin' Nat King Cole.
Forget about the girl, junior.
You just
tell us where and when.
The cavalry has arrived.
You can't have
the McGuire sisters
sitting all together.
All right, fine,
then put Phyllis
between Danny Kaye
and Jack Carter.
Daddy, I want Frankie Avalon.
Who doesn't, kid?
Jodi Segal had Frankie Avalon
for her bat mitzvah.
Lauren, honey,
let's leave daddy alone.
He's working.
Forget it.
You know, just forget
the whole thing.
I hate you.
You know, I don't even want
a damn bat mitzvah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What'd you just say?
Hey! Hey,
did she just fucking curse?
Get back here
and apologize to your mother!
She's not my mother!
Lauren!
Honey, it's okay.
It's okay.
She's just anxious.
Oh, she's anxious?
Well, they pick up
on our stress.
Stress...
Lose Jack Kennedy
and the Lawfords.
Why? They'll love
sitting with Kim Novak.
Lose Novak, too.
What? That's a great table.
It took us two weeks to get a--
They canceled.
All right? The strike's
all over the news.
We're bleeding here.
Ugh!
We'll be fine.
Yeah, you say so.
I do. I'm not worried
about one night,
about some party.
Six years ago, this was
all just sand and mosquitoes.
Now it's the Miramar Playa.
You did that.
Marry me.
We're already married.
Right. Okay.
Again.
We'll see how tonight goes.
Shit. I gotta go.
What-- what about lunch?
I'll grab something.
Hey, who do you want
at your table tonight?
Um, Cary Grant
and Sal Mineo.
You get Georgie Jessel.
Jerk.
Beauty.
Look at her, honey.
She's acting so weird.
Won't come out when I call her.
They pick up on our stress.
Everything all right?
Yeah. Why?
Why? You on the beach?
Is Bel's cabana game
set for tonight?
Yeah, I'm seeing him
at 4:00.
Good.
Ugh. Sand.
A necklace of bubbies.
That's what mom used to call 'em.
Yep.
When you met mom,
saw her for the first time,
did you...
I mean, was it--
was it like that thing,
you know, like in the movies,
when you just know--
Bang-- she's the one?
No.
That came after.
But it did happen.
Your mother-- Stevie,
she was the love of my life,
but not like that.
Not that way.
What you're talking about...
That only happened with Vera.
You know, the first time
I saw Vee...
I actually forgot
how to breathe.
You know that feeling?
Congratulations.
You poor son of a bitch.
Hey, Stevie...
Vera's everything to me.
Look, it's been crazy--
Make it work with her.
After we get through tonight,
everything will be cool.
Call me if you talk to Cuda.
Will do.
Okay, here's the drill--
On stage-- No flowers,
no perfume.
Jack and water on the piano.
Shecky does a tight 15 to open,
not a second more.
Stick all the blondes
in the front.
Keep the air on high.
He likes it cold. Done.
Send him something light
for dinner--
Spaghetti marinara, no meat,
like around 6:00, okay?
And I'll, uh, send somebody up
with our list in about an hour.
Okay.
Are we okay tonight?
Okay? We are... magic.
Pure magic.
'Cause if he sees any empties,
one empty seat, he walks.
Square business, Ike.
Frank is gone,
and you are done.
You tell Frank
there are no empties.
We are standing room only.
You'd better be.
Thanks, Jilly.
Get Mike Strauss for me. Now.
Mike.
So did you come to your senses?
You have to call off your strike
till after Sinatra's run.
Oh, I have to?
I will revisit
the union vote in a week.
One week. I promise.
You guys come back
at midnight tonight,
and I am finished.
That's the whole point, Ike.
We strike
when it hurts the most.
I will lose everything.
You know me, Mike.
I'm not gonna let that happen.
I will not let you do this.
You know, that sounds
distinctly like a threat.
It's the truth.
Well, then, my friend,
I guess we both do what
our conscience tells us to do.
Thank you.
Sorry. I soaked your shoes.
Cooled me off.
Ike Evans.
Lily Augustine... Diamond.
It's a pleasure, Mrs. Diamond.
Mr. Evans.
Of course. From the Miramar.
You have a son, right?
Two, actually--
Danny and Stevie.
I hope I'll be seeing you
at our Sinatra show tonight.
Absolutely.
Wouldn't miss it.
Put your eyes
back in your head.
Come here.
Ben.
Ike. Sit down.
Catch a few rays.
Relax.
So, Ben, I was sorry
to hear about Doris.
I'm still in mourning.
Remember the day that you, me,
and do went out to the glades?
Out to your quarry?
And she looked into that hole
where you were digging out
all that coral...
Limestone.
Limestone, right.
Yeah, for your hotel lobby.
And she asked you how deep
the water was,
and you said...
Bottomless.
Parked a lot of cars
down there, kid.
Limestone, coral, marble...
You spent a lot
on that palace of yours, huh?
What's-- what's your monthly nut
over there?
What do you owe?
You know what I owe, Ben.
Humor me.
$65,000.
A month? Every month?
And you come up with that?
How about this month?
How about right now?
Have you got 65 G's
on you right now?
I'm back two days,
and already I hear
you've got union problems.
I need your help tonight.
I'd like you to talk
to Mike Strauss.
I'm not in the fucking union.
So what do you want from me?
Right.
What'll it take?
What do you want?
The rest.
I got half.
I want the rest.
No.
What did you say?
I said no.
The Miramar is--
Mine!
Mine.
Fine.
You take it.
You know what the Miramar is
worth without me running it?
It's a pile of sand,
silverware, and towels.
You'd get half of what
you put in,
but you take it.
You fucking choke on it.
Hey.
Come here.
You cut yourself.
Jesus.
You're very, very
highly strung these days.
You ought to relax.
I'm serious.
Why don't you go home?
Kiss that pretty shiksa wife
of yours for me.
Have a drink.
I'll see you later.
Isaac!
You ever hear the story
about the frog and the scorpion?
No, Ben.
The scorpion begs the frog
to carry it across the river.
The frog says, "No. No.
If I carry you,
y-you'll sting me to death."
And the scorpion says,
"Oh, come on, froggy.
If I sting you,
we'll both drown."
So the frog lets the scorpion
hop on its back.
Halfway across the river,
the scorpion whips his stinger
into the frog's ass.
Now while the frog is sinking,
and they're both gonna drown,
the frog says,
"But why? Why?"
You know
what the scorpion says?
What?
"It's in my nature."
In the end, Ike,
we are who we are,
and I want more.
That's what I've always wanted.
I've always wanted... more.
Think about that
as we swim across
the river of life together.
Hi, Stevie.
Ladies.
Welcome to the Miramar.
Thank you.
Hi.
You ready to meet the richest,
best-looking,
most famous guys in the world?
- Yes.
- Oh, yeah.
You ready to meet
millionaires and movie stars?
Yeah.
You ladies are beauty.
You're sex.
You're every man's dream.
And you're the Miramar Playa's
gift to 1959.
You make us proud, girls.
Yes, sir.
- All right.
- Definitely.
Oh. Make us rich.
Bye, Stevie.
Look what the cash dragged in.
Granny.
Judi. Babe.
Mmm.
"Oh, Judi. Babe."
Behave, or you're working
at fun fair.
Miss silver, you kill me.
Mm. Prove it, lover.
"Never ride the working stock,"
Ike Evans.
Oh, yes.
Cuda.
Get Miss Silver a very dry,
very cold gin Martini
with two pearl onions.
He remembers.
Stevie?
I'm gonna need you
for the night.
I've been waiting my whole life
to hear you say that.
How is everything?
Are we okay?
Mrs. Evans...
We are beautiful.
Por favor.
Mm.
Ugh. Cut it out.
Can somebody get Fluffy
off my sweater?
She's getting it all--
Fluffy?
I'm not kidding.
She keeps growling at me.
Now she's really acting weird,
honey. Come, babe.
Hey, Lauren.
If you're gonna keep
wearing skirts that short,
you'd better start
shaving your legs.
Dad!
Do you like that?
Aah! Don't!
Don't! No! No, get it off me!
Aah! Can somebody help?!
No! No! Aah!
No! Aah! No!
Aah! Can somebody help?!
Aah! No!
Fact or fiction?
Somebody once told me
that whatever you're doing
at the stroke of midnight
on new year's eve
tells you what your whole year
will be like.
It's just 10:00.
Well, it's midnight somewhere.
Who are you?
The wrong woman.
Now you tell me.
Are we good?
Oh, yeah.
Rousted a few local pickpockets
and a couple of working girls
from the causeway.
Our, uh, friends
from the justice department
are here to count heads.
Speaking of which...
I'll be around.
Thank you, Vincent.
Big night.
Don't mention it.
Where's the missus?
Oh, um, um, powdering her nose.
Jack, we're at table 18!
Dad, you know Mercedes.
Since birth.
You look beautiful, honey.
Thank you.
So what are you doing with this yutz?
Huh?
Hey, dad.
Hey, kid.
Where's Stevie?
He'll show.
- Relax.
- You did it.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome to Ike Evans'
world-famous
Miramar Playa hotel--
Mr. Frank Sinatra!
♪ I've got the world
on a string ♪
♪ sittin' on a rainbow ♪
♪ got the string ♪
♪ around my finger ♪
♪ what a world ♪
♪ what a life, I'm in love ♪
♪ I got a song that I sing ♪
♪ I can make the rain go ♪
♪ any time I move my finger ♪
♪ lucky me ♪
♪ can't you see? I'm in love ♪
♪ life is a beautiful thing ♪
♪ as long as I hold the string ♪
♪ I'd be a silly so-and-so ♪
♪ if I should ever let it go ♪
♪ I got the world on a string ♪
♪ sittin' on a rainbow ♪
♪ got the string
around my finger ♪
♪ what a world, what a life ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ life is a beautiful thing ♪
♪ as long as I hold the string ♪
♪ I'd be a silly so-and-so ♪
♪ if I should ever let it go ♪
Yeah. It's me-- Mike.
Call it off.
Call off the strike now.
Yeah, pull all our guys.
It's over.
Yeah.
Five, four,
three, two, one...
...With the flight
of dictator Fulgencio Batista
and the entry into Havana
of rebel forces
to be acclaimed by the city.
His departure touched off
wild rejoicing in the capitol.
Then the temper of the throng
changed,
and an ugly mob
reigns the streets,
its prime targets, the symbols
of the overthrown regime.
Couldn't sleep.
Sleep's overrated.
We made it.
Yes, we did.
♪ Moon over Miami ♪
♪ shine on my love and me ♪
Happy new year.
♪ So we can stroll ♪
♪ beside the roll ♪
♪ of the rollin' sea ♪
♪ moon over Miami ♪
♪ shine on as we begin ♪
♪ a dream or two ♪
♪ that may come true ♪
♪ as the tide ♪
♪ that comes in ♪
♪ hark to the song ♪
♪ of a smiling troubadour ♪
♪ hark to the throbbing guitar ♪
♪ hear how the waves ♪
♪ offer thunderous applause ♪
♪ after each song ♪
♪ to the stars ♪
♪ I say, moon over Miami ♪
♪ you know we're waiting for ♪
♪ a little love ♪
♪ a little kiss ♪
♪ on Miami shore ♪