Sofia, Bulgaria, 1992
John Charter Won't be a problem...
The area is remote and my men
have closed the only road.
General's orders.
The road is closed tonight.
lt's an emergency.
My Wife is giving birth.
This is the doctor.
WIll money open the road?
l thought your men closed this road?
lt could be him.
l am an American.
l'm a doctor.
Forgive us for breaking the curfeW.
My Wife just had a baby.
He is a doctor.
lt may be him.
Check his story.
We'll soon knoW if he's John Charter.
The diamonds are practically...
out of the country already.
l forgot to buy bread.
What's going on?
Mo, no, you've been dreaming.
There is nothing to Worry about.
Go Wake up mama.
She'll explain it to you
that you've had a nightmare.
What?
What do you mean she is not there?
One ticket.
Where?
Prague.
One minute, one minute. Hold on.
You have change coming, here it is.
What are you mixed up in, little Katrine?
l can't talk right noW.
Just keep him safe.
My people Want him dead.
You knoW every detective looks for outside Work.
Why don't you tell your
old partner What you knoW.
l've heard they're Working for Serik Doulova.
Really?
Hey Katrine, Micholas has gone.
HoW did he get out?
Mo idea Where.
These people you're playing With are animals.
They Won't think tWice about killing you...
Call me back later.
Just put up some signs.
You tWo look outside.
You come With me.
lf you had nothing to do With this murder,
What Were you doing With the American?
Defending myself.
He broke into my house.
You have a lot of protection
for a simple businessman.
The American has died.
HoW long Will you be Working here?
We finish today.
Steer clear if you think this is bad.
Vassil Levski Blvd. l'll remember that.
Do you think the Englishman Will
treat you better than the Kargyk?
They promised to let Mick go
if l see it through.
And you believed them?
Come to your senses child.
Why should they lie to me?
Ask this question instead...
Why should the Cartel take the chance
of leaving any Witnesses?
There's too much money involved,
and you Katrine, are very expendable.
Consider my plan again.
Use your head.
They look real.
What do you think they're Worth?
Forgotten in the evidence room...
nothing.
Well they're not forgotten
anymore, are they?
They better still be forgotten.
lt's so easy to make me forget,
my old partner.