A one, two, three.
"O, pardon me,
thou bleeding piece of earth,
"that I am meek and gentle ..."
Quiet! Quiet down, please!
You got big dreams.
You want fame?
Well, fame costs.
And right here is where
you start paying, in sweat.
♪ Remember, remember, remember ♪
♪ Remember, remember,
remember, remember ♪
♪ Fame! ♪
Sorry!
Excuse me!
Sorry.
Oh! Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Hey, good luck, Victor.
Thanks, Papa.
♪ You'll see my face on the cover
of a magazine one day ♪
♪ You'll hear my voice blaring
out your car radio ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma, I'ma,
I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma, I'ma,
I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma, I'ma,
I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma do big things ♪
♪ Big, big, big,
big, big things ♪
♪ Hey! I'ma, I'ma, I'ma,
I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma do big things ♪
Malik, is that you?
♪ I'ma do big things ♪
Group Six, you're up.
Where do you train?
Cedar Falls, lowa.
My mom has a studio there.
You're a long way
from home.
Well, I'm hoping to get
into a professional
ballet company.
We don't have a school
like this there, so my
mom put me on a plane.
Well, don't worry.
You might be back in lowa
sooner than you think.
All right, thank you.
That's enough.
♪ I'ma, I'ma, I'ma,
I'ma do big things ♪
♪ I'ma, I'ma do big things ♪
All right. Group Eight, let's go.
Right away.
♪ You cataracts and hurricanes ♪
♪ spout till you have drench'd
our steeples, drown'd the cocks! ♪
"Chickity China
the Chinese chicken ...
You have a drumstick
and your brain stops tickin' ...
Chickity China the Chinese chicken ...
You have a drumstick and your brain ..."
Okay. I'm sorry.
Actually, one more second.
"Chickity China the Chinese chicken
Chickity China the ..." Okay.
You talking to me?
There's nobody else here.
Who the hell do you think
you're talking to?
Oh, yeah? Okay. Okay.
Uh-huh. Mmm-hmm.
Boom! And cut real wide,
like a, you know,
a Scorsese wide shot.
I'm really, really angry.
Like, really angry.
And scene.
Well, Neil, I take it
that filmmaking is your
number one passion.
Now, you wanna tell me why
you want to study acting?
Well, you know,
I'm a method director.
And I believe that actors
are the heart of any film.
And in order to speak
the language of an actor,
I must become an actor.
You'll do well.
Next group of
musicians, please.
That's enough.
I can play better.
I just need to ...
I doubt it.
That was superb.
Next!
Five, six, seven, eight!
Okay, that was good.
Group Two on the floor, please.
My God, I can't stand
any more of this!
First, you spurned me
for Eddie.
Then you throw him off
like an old overcoat
for Rocky!
You chew people up
and then you
spit them out again!
I loved you.
Do you hear me?
I loved you! And
what did it get me?
Yeah, I'll tell you.
A big nothing!
You're like a sponge.
You take, take, take!
♪ Come on, babe
why don't we paint the town ♪
♪ And all that jazz ♪
♪ I'm gonna rouge my knees
And roll my stockings down ♪
♪ And all that jazz ♪
♪ Start the car
I know a whoopee spot ♪
You've got to choose
between me or Rocky,
so named because of
the rocks in his head!
♪ Where there's a nightly brawl ...
and all ♪
♪ that ♪
♪ jazz ♪
♪ That jazz ♪
Wow. You're fearless, aren't you?
Some say "annoying."
Well, you know,
it's possible to be both.
And you composed
this track as well?
Yep. I didn't get a chance to add the
guitar stuff yet, though. Let me show you ...
No. No.
You've got talent.
Let's see what we can do with it.
Nice.
Do you know where Room 310 is?
If you have already auditioned ...
- Thanks.
- and have been cut,
please leave immediately.
we have a lot of people
to see today.
- You lost?
- Thank you.
Uh, yeah, actually. I'm looking for
Room 310. Mr. Dowd's class. Acting?
Yeah. Actually,
I think they're that way.
I saw somebody
with a wig and cape
going down the hall.
Okay. Thanks.
Yeah.
Good luck!
Hope you get in.
Yeah. Thanks. You, too.
My theory is ...
Um ...
Parents are given a ...
Jenny, Jenny, it's okay.
It's okay.
There are a lot of things
in this world to be
nervous and afraid of.
And this isn't one of them.
So just relax, take a deep breath,
and then when you're ready,
I want you to talk to us ...
and not at us.
- Okay?
- Yes, sir.
My theory is that
when parents get divorced,
they're given some kind of
a handout.
When my parents told me
that they were splitting,
they told me three things.
One, "It's not your fault."
Two, "It's not your fault."
And three,
"It's not your fault."
Problem is, I don't buy it.
No kid does.
I've seen the pictures
of when you got married.
When you were good-looking,
and you smiled at each other.
Hell, when you even
just looked at each other.
So what happened
between then and now?
Me.
I ... I came along,
and I made you tired
and cranky and anxious
and I made you lose your hair
and gain 20 extra pounds and ...
Somewhere in all of that,
I ... You stopped loving each other.
So I have my own idea
for a handout.
Next time tell me,
"One, happiness is hard."
"Two, don't make the
same mistakes we did."
"And three, okay, so maybe it is
your fault a little."
You want me to be honest?
You go first.
"Death, destruction
around every corner"
"Another dead body
and you wanna keep running"
♪ I know I misbehaved
And you made your mistakes ♪
♪ And we both still
got room left to grow ♪
"And all you could do
is stay alert,
and try to stay out
of the searchlight"
♪ And we'll make this thing work ♪
♪ But I think we should take it slow ♪
"No prison, nobody make bail"
♪ We don't know which way to go ♪
"Everybody gotta go, but see ..."
♪ 'Cause we're ordinary people ♪
"... it ain't no jail"
"Think about death taking your
last breath Heart beating like a ..."
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold it. Hold it.
♪ And this time we'll take it slow ♪
This is the theater, Malik.
Not the street.
The theater.
Sacred.
This is not a place of anger.
Oh, yeah, you get to
play angry characters.
But there are no angry actors.
And do you know
the difference between the two?
All righty.
- Marco.
- Yeah.
Uh, where have you trained?
Um, I sing at my dad's restaurant
every once in a while.
That's pretty much about it.
Really?
Well, that's pretty impressive.
Thank you.
So, did I get in?
Welcome.
This year we received
over 10,000 applications ...
for the 200 openings from students all
across New York City.
And you got in.
Congratulations!
For the next four years,
you have the unique opportunity ...
to immerse yourselves in the arts.
You can be spontaneous,
original, maybe even a little outrageous.
You got it made, right?
Wrong!
You're gonna have it twice
as hard as everybody else.
In the mornings, you're gonna
have all your arts classes.
After lunch, you will cram in
a full day of academics.
Drop below a "C" average
and you're out. No exceptions.
Now, let me make this very clear.
We don't care about your headshot.
Or your dress size.
Or your dreams of being
in OK! Magazine,
on talk shows, on the red carpet.
Here, you will learn a discipline.
Here, you will come to understand ...
what being a performing
artist really means.
Here, you will dedicate
yourself to your craft.
Now, if you're looking for shortcuts,
if you want fame,
if you want easy rewards,
I highly recommend
that you get up and leave now.
There are many very
talented young people ...
who would be thrilled
to take your place.
So, have a great year.
Five, six, seven, eight, go!
Extend that leg. Travel!
Rosie, you're getting dizzy
because you're not spotting. Now, spot!
- I'm trying.
- Yeah, not hard enough.
Shoulders down.
Press them down.
Stay with her, Kevin.
No, no. Stop. Stop.
Stop. Stop. Stop.
Kevin, you're a mess. Look.
She does passé fifth position.
Let her get a real good plié,
so you both have a good
preparation for the pas de chat.
On her next lift, you've got to use
your stomach and your back.
Stay strong.
You have to support her.
All right, take a minute.
Jeremy and Alice.
Kevin, you're not gonna
be a professional ballet dancer ...
unless you learn how to partner.
And ...
Kevin, watch Jeremy.
See that?
Lovely.
Beautiful, Alice.
All right. I don't want
you to think about it.
Get out of your head
and let it be spontaneous.
This exercise is about honing in
on your natural instincts.
Free your inhibitions and
physically inhabit your own body.
Otherwise, you'll never be in touch
with any characters you're playing.
Here we go.
Zip-Zip! Zip-Zip!
Whoom! Whoom!
Pow! Pow!
Be! Be!
Booga-Booga! Booga-Booga!
Bam! Bam!
Che-whe-wow! Che-whe-wha!
Jenny, Jenny, Jenny,
get out of your brain!
You got to learn to loosen up ...
and go with the first thing
that pops in your head.
Okay, everybody follow me.
Come on. Shake it out.
Shake it out. Shake it out.
Come on, shake, shake, shake!
Come on, it's the
only body you got!
You gotta be loose!
Loose, loose!
Jenny, is that loose?
You gotta learn not to be embarrassed
and you better do it now.
All right, loose, folks!
Loose. Loosen your bodies up.
Keep your eyes on
the sheet music.
If you holdin'
my money then pay me.
Just another day
in the life of the queen MC.
Can't stop, won't stop
until I cop a Bentley.
No, no, throw the dice.
Where you been, man?
I had to get this out
of the storage room.
We gotta get rollin'.
- Yo, plug this in.
- Are you serious?
Rosie, plug it in.
Come on. Right now?
Your action is "to give love."
Or "to seduce."
Let's try "to seduce."
All right, what does that look like?
What does that look like?
Okay. No, that was awful.
Can I sit down?
Sure.
Thanks.
I just met these agents,
like, a month and a half ago,
and they've been sending me out,
and I guess these casting directors
are really excited to see me for this pilot.
You didn't like the shaking?
See, I didn't see that as fun.
It was more of a hassle.
It doesn't really have
anything to do with acting.
I can maybe introduce you guys
to the agents if you want. You know?
But it loosens you.
Okay, what happens
if your character's, like, really tense?
Joe, does it work?
Today?
No.
I keep telling her to just relax.
It's nothing big.
But I have too much work
to do after school.
I have vocal exercises
and memorizing monologues,
and that's all before
I even start on my normal homework.
You actually do all that stuff?
Huh?
There's a drum set over there.
I dare you to go on it.
How many years
have you been rapping?
She won in the last round.
You are retarded.
Your brain is not working right.
Yeah? Is that so?
- Hi.
- This is Marco.
- How you doing?
You know I'm gonna
eat you up in front of everybody.
You can never ...
Whoa!
Oh, yeah!
♪ You need toget your life
straight for Christ's sake ♪
♪ Because your mind state
ain't moving as fast as my pace ♪
♪ You're spending cheese
every other day on new kicks ♪
♪ It's useless,
sometimes I wonder if you're stupid ♪
♪ Yo, I'm a real boss chick
You better believe it ♪
♪ I buy what I want
whenever I need it ♪
♪ A girl like me don't worry
about haters and all that light stuff ♪
♪ I'll worry about it later ♪
♪ You're acting like a dummy and I'm mad. ♪
- Mad?
♪ You think we don't know
you get your money from your dad ♪
- What?
♪ It's obvious ♪
♪ You never even had a job before ♪
♪ Step to this
you'll be highly sore what up? ♪
Shut up. Yo, Jamie,
drop out at the next bar!
♪ Now when I say we gonna
y'all say rock it ♪
♪ we gonna rock it! ♪
♪ When I say we gonna ...
Y'all say rock it ♪
♪ We gonna rock it! ♪
♪ When I say we won't
y'all say stop ♪
♪ We won't stop! ♪
♪ When I say we won't y'all say stop ♪
♪ This is my life ♪
♪ I got to get it, baby say yeah ♪
♪ Say yeah. This is my life ♪
♪ I got to get it, baby. Say yeah ♪
♪ Yeah. Say yeah ♪
- Hey.
Not your thing?
Not really.
My parents would die
if they saw that.
They think it's a conservatory.
Everyone practicing cello all day.
Hey, I'm Denise.
Malik.
Mind if I sit down?
You know, if it makes
you feel any better,
my mom doesn't
even know I go here.
Seriously?
She thinks I'm down
at the public high school.
She works three jobs.
She's never gonna check.
Why don't you just tell her?
She doesn't want me to be
an actor or a rapper.
Look, what about you?
I mean, I see you playing the piano
like you're Beethoven and everything.
Is that your thing?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
Well, actually, I don't know.
I mean, I guess, I think it ...
Okay, truth is,
I've never tried anything else.
Oh.
What's up, man?
What you looking at?
I'm just watching
this girl dance.
Yeah, I've seen her.
But she thinks she's, like,
the most talented kid in the school.
Maybe she is.
Well, I gotta go. You want to
keep staring, go right ahead, man.
See you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
♪ But I will wait
for you to figure it out ♪
♪ Soon you'll be chasing me
through the out door into the street ♪
♪ I will be kneeling on the ground ♪
Can I help you?
You know,
you can really dance.
Thanks for the newsflash.
But I think you could dance a little better,
though, if your music wasn't so wack.
I'm just saying.
Excuse me?
Yeah. I mean,
if you really wanna dance,
you need something
way better than that.
And you know just what that is.
Yeah.
Here, listen.
That's just a demo, too.
I mean, I'm adding, like,
a lot more bass and effects.
The second, the second bar,
that's not even
the final part, let me tell you.
- I got more stuff that I can show you.
- Not bad.
I got more tracks.
I'm sure you do.
♪ There's a somebody
I'm longing to see ♪
♪ I hope that he ♪
♪ Turns out to be ♪
♪ Someone who'll watch ♪
♪ Over me ♪
♪ I'm a little lamb
who's lost in the wood ♪
♪ I know I could ♪
♪ Always be good ♪
♪ To one who'll watch ♪
♪ Over me ♪
Okay. Very good, Jenny.
Thank you.
Except for the fact that you
have no idea what you're singing about.
Well, it's about a girl who gets her heart
broken and is looking for another guy.
Yeah. I was not feeling
that from you.
That is technically what the song is about.
Okay, this is very important.
Jenny, for your homework tonight,
I want you to go home and
write out all the lyrics to that song ...
and then work on them like
they're an acting monologue. Okay?
Because there's really
no point in singing a song ...
if you don't understand
what it is you're saying.
Okay, go sit down. Thanks.
It was pretty. I just wasn't getting
a lot out of it. All right?
- Okay.
Life will go on.
Okay, next.
Uh ...
Let's see. Marco.
That's right.
I want you to sing the same song,
but I want us to all really understand ...
what the song is about.
Do you know it?
Yeah. A little bit.
A little bit?
All right, well, this should be
interesting. Come on.
Hurry up. Grass isn't
getting any greener.
Could you change it to E-flat?
♪ There's a somebody
I'm longing to see ♪
♪ I hope that she ♪
♪ Turns out to be ♪
♪ Someone who'll watch ♪
♪ Over me ♪
♪ I'm a little lamb
who's lost in the wood ♪
♪ I know I could ♪
♪ Always be good ♪
♪ To one who'll watch ♪
♪ Over me ♪
Yes. That's what I was
talking about, everybody.
Very good, Marco.
Thank you.
- So you live in Long Island, right?
- Yep.
And stay with my dad enough days
to meet the residency requirement.
I'd like to stay
with my mom more, but ...
Yeah. Is it worth it?
Of course.
It's what I want. Always wanted.
You understand.
I mean, not everyone
is like you, Jenny.
You know, as committed and focused
as you are. All the damn time.
Yeah, but you're
the best singer in our class.
With that kind of a talent,
you have a responsibility.
I mean, the only thing
I gotta do is be happy.
What?
Do you always take
things this lightly?
I would give anything in order
to stand up in front of class ...
and sing a song and
be completely in tune.
Or whiz through a monologue ...
and have everybody laughing.
- Jenny ...
And there are so many kids in this city
that would love to be going to this school.
You wouldn't understand.
See you in class, Marco.
These are not diaries.
They're journals.
I'm not interested
in what you had for breakfast,
or what you think of
your stepmom's boob job.
Not even your latest breakup.
I wanna know about
the world you inhabit.
The people around you.
Who are they?
How do they behave?
Language and behavior,
that's all the actor's got to work with.
So keep your eyes open.
Observe. Record.
Mr. Bazinska, this is disgraceful.
It's unhealthy, it's unsanitary.
No, it's fine. It's clean.
No, it's not unsanitary. It's ...
The only thing missing from it ...
is a finger on the scale.
Your finger on the scale. You're the worst.
How is emotion
expressed through action?
Gesture?
That's disgusting. What can I say.
Look, it's clean.
So they got all the ...
Now what are you doing?
- Taking my pictures without asking!
- Sorry. Homework.
You're supposed to get me
to write off something before you do that.
I could sue you,
and I could sue you.
Dad, you home?
Understand other people.
And you'll begin to understand yourself.
Bye, Mr. Cranston.
Ms. Dupree.
Yes?
You practice more than
any other student here at P.A.
You are a very talented
classical pianist.
Thank you, Mr. Cranston.
I happen to be looking
for an accompanist ...
for our spring production
of Chicago.
It might serve you well
to branch out a bit.
Expand your horizon.
Okay, so what does this entail?
It's just a couple rehearsals.
It might go a little late ...
Okay, what's "late"?
Midnight.
- Midnight?
- Only on the nights it performs.
That's what Mr. Cranston said.
Daddy, it's a big honor for a freshman
to be asked to play for one of the musicals.
And it's Chicago!
Do you realize ...
You are training to be
a classical pianist.
Can you tell me how
playing honky-tonk songs ...
till all hours of the night
is gonna help with that?
It won't, but it
would be fun. Fun!
Something new! Daddy, I want to
do something different for a change.
"Something different"
was never part of the deal, Denise.
You will be saying "no" or I will be
pulling you out of that school. Period.
I'm sorry.
Ma, I was gonna tell you.
Performing Arts?
Do you have any idea
how risky that is?
As a career?
Of course I do.
Malik, you're trying to do
something everyone wants to do.
Every teenager on this block thinks
they can make it as the next rapper ...
Look, Ma. You have to let me stay there.
It's everything I have now.
I just don't know about this.
Look, they're good grades!
Did you even look at it?
Look, Ma.
I'm talented.
If somebody's gotta make it
out there, why can't it be me?
And who in the world
told you you were so special?
You did.
I just can't deal with this
right now. I'm late for work.
All right. Bobby.
Okay. Kevin!
Look out!
- Yeah?
- Master Tavares,
you play with élan,
brio, gusto, panache
and a host of foreign adjectives
that indicate excessive style.
What you neglect to do is
play the music as written.
And though your interpretation
may be entertaining,
it is of no value in my class.
May I suggest that the only thing of
value you could possibly bring to Bach ...
is your respect.
And unless you devote
yourself to study,
drill and mastery of technique,
you will be of little or no value
to anyone. Including yourself.
Now let's try this again, as written.
Parenthetically,
study, drill and technique
do not stifle talent.
They free it. Once more.
Mr. Cranston.
This music, it's boring.
It's just not my thing.
No, it's Bach's thing.
Stubby little German guy.
Wore a wig.
Yeah, and he died 1,000 years ago.
His teachers told him to stop
playing music his way. He said no.
Really?
Well, if his teachers told
him that, then they were wrong.
And should your music ...
survive for the next 350 years,
please allow me to
apologize in advance.
Proceed. We will suffer
through it with you.
She was eight years old.
Her name was Ayanna.
Means "beautiful flower."
She was always
on the street, playing,
jumping rope.
Happiest girl you ever saw.
She didn't see the man in the car ...
or the man running past,
until the bullets flew.
The day after she was buried,
I got this.
I was only 13 at the time.
I thought my mom would whup my ass.
But she didn't.
Said I should remember
every single day ...
what happened to my little sister.
How did her death affect you?
I mean, you've given us the facts.
And you waited till the end to let
us know that Ayanna was your sister,
which was very dramatic.
But I want to know how you felt.
And I think you need
to know how you felt.
How do you think I felt?
Well, I have no idea.
Why don't you tell us?
You know what? Screw this.
I ain't gonna cry for you.
I gave you the truth.
Is that what happened?
Did you cry the night she died?
Did you blame yourself? Do you
think you could have prevented it?
Listen, I'm gonna be famous.
And I don't need you
or your therapy bullshit!
So screw this and
screw this class!
The theater is not a place
for cowards, Malik.
♪ Sometimes I wonder ♪
♪ Where I've been ♪
♪ Who I am ♪
♪ Do I fit in? ♪
♪ Make believin' ♪
♪ Is hard alone ♪
♪ Out here on my own ♪
♪ We're always provin' ♪
♪ Who we are ♪
♪ Always reachin' ♪
♪ For that risin' star ♪
♪ To guide me far ♪
♪ And shine me home ♪
♪ Out here on my own ♪
♪ When I'm down ♪
♪ And feelin' blue ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ So I can be with you ♪
♪ Oh, baby, be strong for me ♪
♪ Baby, belong to me ♪
♪ Help me through ♪
♪ Help me need you ♪
♪ Until the morning sun appears ♪
♪ Making light of all my fears ♪
♪ I dry the tears I've never shown ♪
♪ Out here on my own ♪
♪ But when I'm down and feelin' blue ♪
♪ I close my eyes so I can be with you ♪
♪ Oh, baby, be strong for me ♪
♪ Baby, belong to me ♪
♪ Help me through ♪
♪ Help me need you ♪
♪ Sometimes I wonder ♪
♪ Where I've been ♪
♪ Who I am ♪
♪ Do I fit in? ♪
♪ I may not win ♪
♪ But I can't be thrown ♪
♪ Out here ♪
♪ On my own ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Out here ♪
♪ On my own ♪
Attention, students.
After-school rehearsal will be canceled
due to the dance performance class.
Tomorrow, regular scheduled
rehearsals will resume as normal.
Those of you who would
like to see the show,
tickets will be on sale in the
main office starting Thursday.
Yeah?
I know your secret.
What are you talking about?
Why didn't you tell me
you could sing like that?
Wait, you were in there?
Yeah. And I heard you.
Look, look, just come with me.
I got an idea. Okay?
Hold on, hold on,
calm down. I have class.
Look, just trust me.
Come with me.
All right? It won't
take long. Come on.
- Excuse me.
- Sorry.
Where are we going?
Me and my man, Victor, is working
on this record that's gonna be huge.
I'm talking about beats you
wouldn't even believe. All right?
Yo. Yo!
- What's up?
- Listen.
If you think the girls
we've been trying out are good ...
Ten times better.
I didn't know you could sing.
Dogs, this girl is amazing.
Wait. Hold on. You guys produce?
Yeah, we produce.
I'm actually working on a track
right now. We still need a singer.
So, what's good?
Will you do it?
I can't.
Come on. Why not?
My dad. He doesn't like me
to get distracted.
And why, exactly,
would he have to know?
♪ Go ahead, you know you want it ♪
♪ You'll have no other way.
You just want to take us down ♪
♪ Go ahead ♪
♪ Go ahead, I'll be your junkie ♪
♪ I'll be deplete you can
heap all rubbish here ♪
♪ Go ahead, now dump it on me ♪
♪ If I go quiet will the itch
go down with me ♪
♪ Oh, you got to get it ♪
♪ Never mind that it was
never there nowhere ♪
♪ But, oh, no, not for a minute ♪
♪ For now you'll make your bed.
And it will wait, I swear ♪
♪ No way not me what you got,
it's not for me ♪
♪ But you'll find a way ♪
♪ No way not me what you got,
it's not for me ♪
♪ Don't reach too far.
You will fall over ♪
♪ Don't be surprised what you discover ♪
♪ Don't fear your call ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ ... what you got It's not
for me, but you'll find a way ♪
♪ No way not me what you got,
it's not for me ♪
♪ Don't reach too far.
You will fall over ♪
♪ Don't be surprised ... ♪
Yo, Malik. I just
finished it last night.
Pop it in, man.
Let's see what they think.
Malik, what are you doing?
Why are you playing our song?
What's the problem? Victor said
he finished it last night.
I just wanted to put it in and
see what people thought about it.
But you know this is our secret.
My parents don't know
about this. I don't ...
Just relax.
Your parents aren't even here.
And besides, they like it. Look.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Yo, give it up for a track
produced by my boy, Victor!
Yeah!
You made that?
And of course, yours truly.
Let's go!
Let's give it up, y'all!
And on vocals, give it up for —
Anonymous.
And she's drinking.
All right, hurry up before
someone steals my camera.
Are you wasted yet?
I don't know.
I've never been drunk.
What's it feel like?
It feels like that.
Yo, check it out.
This is for my homies.
No, don't waste it.
Check it out.
Mike check, one-two.
Turn my headphones up.
- Ooh!
♪ Cruisin' down
the street in my six-fo ♪
♪ Jockin' the bitches.
Slappin' the hoes ♪
♪ Went to the park to get the scoop ♪
♪ Knuckleheads out there
cold shootin' some hoops ♪
♪ A car pulls up, who can it be ♪
♪ A fresh El Camino rollin' Kilo G ♪
♪ He rolls down his window
and he started to say ♪
♪ It's all about makin' that GTA ♪
♪ 'Cause the boys in the hood
are always hard ♪
♪ You come talkin' that trash
we gonna pull your card ♪
♪ Knowin' nothin' in
life but to be legit ♪
♪ Don't quote me, boy,
'cause I ain't said ... ♪
Shit.
Well, first of all,
I loved the presentation.
Why, thank you. I mean, it's, you
know ... It's totally not ready yet.
But, I mean, it's ...
The drunkenness, however ...
I was trying to expand
my life experience.
I've never been wasted before.
Trust me. I'm not gonna do it again.
Hey, hey, Jenny, hold up.
Just a dinner. At my dad's
restaurant. I promise.
If you don't have a good time,
I'll stop asking.
I don't understand.
You keep asking me out
and I keep telling you no.
Why do you keep trying?
I don't know.
I feel like if I keep asking,
maybe one of these times,
you'll actually say yes.
Text me the address.
- Really?
- Yeah, I'll come.
Okay. I'll see you later then.
- Okay. See you later.
- Okay, bye.
So, how's school?
Do you think you'll
get what you need?
Will it be enough to get you
into a professional company?
How am I supposed to know?
You know, Alice,
Dr. Malamed thinks
that your aloofness ...
is a sign of sub-clinical
depression.
So, are you depressed?
No, Dad. I'm bored
like I always am.
Alice!
- Excuse me, sir.
- Huh? Oh, I'm with them.
May I take your hat?
No, no ...
Are you sure I
can't take your hat?
Who is that?
The opposite of boring.
Hey, baby. How are you?
What's up?
These your parents?
I know, I know, it's just that ...
I've never had to work this hard
in my entire life.
And they don't really tell you
what it's gonna be like.
I don't know why I'm
telling you all of this.
Everything seems to come
so easily to you.
No, that's not true.
I've just ... I've been
performing my whole life.
I mean, as soon as I could,
I was out there singing.
I will tell you this,
no one makes as much in tips
as a first grader.
So, you play the piano, too?
A little. Yeah.
Okay, I want to hear.
I mean, you see me sing all the
time at school. There's no need to ...
Yeah, I want to hear something
different. Come on, Marco.
No. Just 'cause
the piano's there ...
Just me, you, and the restaurant.
You're playing for me.
Jenny ...
I told you,
you've already seen this.
No! Go on.
Well, what do you want me to play?
Uh, anything you want.
And we'll see if I'm willing
to give you a tip at the end.
Okay.
Seriously?
How about this one?
♪ If I walk, would you run? ♪
♪ If I stop, would you come? ♪
♪ If I say you're the one ♪
♪ would you believe me? ♪
♪ If I ask you to stay ♪
♪ would you show me the way? ♪
♪ Tell me what to say ♪
♪ So you don't leave me ♪
♪ The world is catching up to you ♪
♪ while you're running away ♪
♪ To chase your dreams ♪
♪ It's time for us to make a move ♪
♪ 'Cause we are asking
one another to change ♪
♪ And maybe I'm not ready ♪
♪ But I'll try for your love ♪
♪ I can hide up above ♪
♪ I will try for your love ♪
♪ we've been hiding enough ♪
♪ I can hide up above ♪
♪ If I walk, would you run? ♪
♪ If I stop, would you come? ♪
♪ If I say you're the one ♪
♪ would you believe me? ♪
So I'm guessing you liked it?
You could say that.
Okay, that was good, but let's take
it again from bar four-twenty. Okay?
Denise!
We got in with the label.
They want us to come in
and talk about our stuff.
Can you go?
Tomorrow, after school.
I'm supposed to have extra piano ...
No, no, cancel it.
No, no. Cancel it, cancel it.
Meet me out front at 3:00, all right?
Sorry. This is it, Denise.
Our big break. I can feel it!
Okay. Sorry, let's ... Sorry.
♪ What a mighty God we serve ♪
♪ Angels bow before him
Heaven and earth adore him ♪
♪ What a mighty God.
What a mighty God ♪
♪ What a mighty God we serve ♪
♪ He's mighty. He's mighty ♪
♪ He's a mighty God.
He's a mighty God ♪
♪ He's mighty. He's mighty ♪
♪ He's a mighty God.
He's a mighty God ♪
♪ What a mighty God.
What a mighty God ♪
♪ What a mighty God we serve ♪
So, I have an audition later today,
but I don't think I'll go
because I'll never get it.
But you're working with
a casting director. That's huge.
See, that's what I thought, too.
And they do get me some auditions,
but I'm up against the same 15 girls.
And they always get the part.
Yeah, maybe, but they're not Joy.
Yeah, well, me, I've got a lot of good
shit happening off of my YouTube page.
In fact, I'm meeting
with a producer today ...
about putting together
an independent film.
What?
Yeah. Uh ...
I have an idea for a short.
It's about a legendary director ...
who suddenly dies
while filming his movie.
So his inadequate son decides to
honor his father by finishing the film,
but the only help he has is
this misfit cast of characters,
like, straight out
of a Wes Anderson.
It's The Life Aquatic meets
The Bad and the Beautiful.
Sounds really artistic, Neil.
Well, I think so.
Hopefully, Sundance agrees.
- Small place.
- Yeah.
You want some coffee or some water?
I'm all right.
You don't want to see me on coffee.
Wired enough as is.
Take a seat.
The script is good.
Thank you. Um ...
It's, you know, a labor of love of
mine and it's not quite there yet.
I would be honored to take it on.
We don't often do shorts, but,
in your case, we'll make an exception.
Eddie, that's ...
That's amazing!
Now ... Now,
let's talk about the budget.
Yeah, let's talk about it.
Let's talk about the budget.
How are you gonna raise the money?
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity here.
I don't understand. Shouldn't
he be giving you the money?
Isn't that what producers do?
He's not the financier. He's the
producer. And there's a difference.
All I need you to do is kick in,
like, five grand.
And I know. I'm aware.
I'm aware that's a lot of money.
I really get it. I get it.
But, you know, Eddie says
we could even, you know ...
We could sell it to television
and make a profit.
You gotta trust me on this one, Dad.
I'd be shooting on a real film
and everything.
I mean, Dad ...
I mean, this is the real deal, Dad.
The real deal, huh?
You think so?
Come on, Dad.
Help a brother out.
So this is what it's like
to have a social life?
Yeah, well, it beats memorizing
Shakespeare, doesn't it?
Yeah.
How long do we
have to stay here?
I don't know. Come on,
let's just have fun.
We haven't been out in a while.
Okay.
- I'll get us some drinks.
- Okay.
Well, look who it is.
- Andy! Hey!
- Hey! Um ...
- Jenny.
- Jenny. That's right. Of course.
I remember you from last year.
You did the show with
the monologue from ...
From Proof, right?
Yeah!
Yeah, you were really good.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
So how is P.A.? I kind of miss it.
It's the same-old, same-old.
But I've been watching you
on your show.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
Well, thanks.
Yeah, it's going pretty well.
I got a big storyline
right now, so ...
- Andy.
- It's kind of blowing up.
- We're slamming shots, bro.
- Yeah. Shots.
Give me one second.
I'm talking to Jenny. Um ...
You want to take shots?
I'm good, thanks.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. - Okay.
You know, they're looking
for day players on the show.
Would that be something
you might be interested in?
- Seriously? - Yeah. I mean,
I could put in a good word.
Yeah! That would be perfect.
Thank you.
Okay. So how should we do this?
Do you want to give me your number?
Yeah, I don't think
I have a pen or a ...
No, no, don't worry about it.
Just put it right in here.
Okay.
Um ...
I think that's it.
Yeah, I can do this.
Yeah, I don't ... Yeah, okay.
Perfect. Well, it's so good
to see you. You look great.
Thanks. You, too.
All right. I'll see you later.
Okay.
- Bye.
- See you.
See you.
Shots up. Ready to go.
One, two, three!
- One, two, three!
All we were doing
was talking, okay?
He saw my monologue from P.A.
That's all we were talking about.
He wants to help me.
God, could you possibly
be that naive?
He's trying to hook up
with you, Jenny.
That's ridiculous.
He's a big-time actor.
He can hook up
with whoever he wants.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, he loves
your talent. That's what he loves.
So it's that preposterous that somebody
might actually like me for my talent?
No, of course not.
Look, no one believes in you more
than I do, and you know that.
Honestly, it's just
the way he was looking at you.
Fine.
If it means that much to you, I won't
talk to him ever again. Promise.
Now let's get out of here.
We can go to my dad's apartment.
- What, now?
- Mmm-hmm.
He's on a date.
He won't be back until later.
There's definitely something there.
Something that could be interesting.
Check it out.
We've got an A&R meeting next week.
What I'd like to do
is play it for the team,
see what kind of feedback we get,
and I'll get back to you.
Nice.
Yo, yo, did you see him
bobbing his head?
He was bobbing his head to himself.
He was bobbing ...
Guys, guys.
He didn't say he wanted us.
Did you not hear what he said?
He said, "Interesting."
- Interesting!
- Man, we are so in.
Yo, I'm gonna give my moms a house
in the Hamptons on the beach.
- Guys?
- It's gonna be crazy.
You're not even trying, Rosie.
Ballet is a requirement for every
student dancer in this school.
But, Ms. Kraft,
I'm good at hip-hop!
My job isn't to cast music videos.
It's to train serious dancers.
P.A. isn't about just
doing whatever you want.
It's about becoming
a complete performer.
I ... I don't know
where you fit in here.
Fit in here?
What's that supposed to mean?
It means you're gonna keep
flailing around and you're not gonna ...
This isn't about me, is it?
You don't like my body.
Admit it!
Don't be ridiculous. Modern companies
are full of girls who don't have the ...
Oh, really? Then how come this department
is filled with skinny little girls ...
with no titties and tight little butts,
walking around drinking Diet Coke?
I ain't never gonna be
like them. And I don't wanna be.
You want girls who've
been starving themselves,
and look like they're 11
and have so little body fat ...
they can't even get a period
to dance parts for real women.
And that sucks!
You're part of a machinery of
oppression, Ms. Kraft. Just admit it.
Hey! First of all,
don't speak to me like that.
Don't speak to any teacher like that.
It's very rude.
It's also very ugly.
And second of all,
you know that's not true.
I want my dancers to be healthy,
and I talk to you
all about that all the time.
You don't have a good technique,
and you're not working
toward a technique.
And yet, I wanna keep you here.
Shit.
Jenny! Guess what.
What?
I got a job.
You're kidding!
I've been trying to find you to tell
you that it's the best show ever,
and I'm only semi-regular at first,
but then they said
I could get a lead,
and it's so amazing
you won't believe it.
Yay! Okay.
So what show is it?
Sesame Street.
Holy shit. That show's still on?
I'm gonna get paid to act.
That's incredible!
You bitch.
I wonder if they need any hot,
young, new, macho director types.
I mean, I know they're always
looking for new talent on that show.
I don't think so.
But if you're really nice
and give me back rubs,
I might let you be
part of my entourage.
Ooh, back rubs.
You mean like ...
Oh, I'm sorry, did that hurt?
I'm sorry.
Yeah. You know what?
Singing in front of all of
your friends in the classroom ...
is one thing, but now we're here.
And you guys are gonna sing ...
in front of this lovely group of
total strangers,
who actually are sort of hoping
that you'll be really bad.
It's gonna be great.
Also, try to have fun,
because it's part of your grade.
♪ I get knocked down
But I get up again
♪ You're never gonna keep me down ♪
♪ I get knocked down
But I get up again ♪
♪ You're never gonna keep me down ♪
♪ Pissing the night away ♪
♪ I have a tendency to wear
my mind on my sleeve ♪
♪ I have a history
of losing my shirt ♪
♪ It's been one week
since you looked at me ♪
♪ Cocked your head to the side
and said, "I'm sorry" ♪
♪ Five days since you laughed at me ♪
♪ Three days since the living room ♪
♪ It'll still be two days
till we say we're sorry ♪
♪ Two days till ... Sorry ♪
All right! wow. Thank you.
You guys are awesome.
So tonight, I would love to
donate my time.
I'm gonna do a little
something special.
I'm gonna give my time over to
someone very important to us.
Our teacher and hero ...
No.
... Ms. Fran Rowan!
No!
Yes! It's all you.
You brought us here.
That's our teacher!
Yeah, thank you.
Shake it.
Oh, God.
How did this happen?
Okay, you're expelled.
Hope it was worth it.
Oh, no. All right,
I don't even know ...
Do you have: "You Took Advantage
of Me" by Rodgers and Hart?
Say no. Please say no.
- Yep. we have it!
They have it!
Good. Perfect!
Yeah, Rodgers and Hart.
♪ A mental deficient ♪
♪ You will grade me ♪
♪ I've given you plenty of data ♪
♪ You came, you saw, you slayed me ♪
♪ And that-a is that-a! ♪
♪ I'm a sentimental sap,
that's all ♪
♪ What's the use of
trying not to fall? ♪
♪ I have no will ♪
♪ You've made your kill ♪
♪ 'Cause you took advantage of me ♪
She's amazing!
Of course she is.
♪ I'm so hot and bothered,
that I don't know ♪
♪ My elbow from my ear ♪
♪ I suffer something awful
every time you go ♪
♪ It's worse when you're near ♪
♪ Here am I with all
my bridges burned ♪
♪ Just a babe in arms
where you're concerned ♪
♪ So lock the doors ♪
♪ Lock that door! ♪
♪ And call me yours ♪
♪ Because you took ♪
♪ You took advantage of me ♪
Oh, my God, that was amazing!
Why are you guys
so boring in class ...
and so great at karaoke tonight?
Why didn't you ever bring us
there before? That was so much fun.
I know. I should've done it before.
You know, that was so great,
because it's not about you.
It's about the audience, and I
really saw that. It was great.
- I know.
- You know what else is great?
- That girl gave me her number.
- That was a guy, Neil.
Irregardless, I was flattered.
Joy, you were on fire.
- It was unbelievable. - Thank you.
I mean, it was so cute and good.
And completely ambushed by Kevin.
Hat's off. Wait, one thing.
How come you never sang
in front of us until tonight?
Oh, my God. Because
I'm the teacher. Seriously.
You should more often,
because you were stellar, man.
I mean, I'm inspired.
Speaking of ...
So do you ever perform,
ever? Like ...
Do I what?
Recently, any of these days,
do you ever perform?
- No, no. No, no, no.
- You should.
- Yeah.
- Gosh.
- Especially for your students.
- Well, why ...
No, no. Too much.
Can't ...
- Why did you quit?
- Huh?
Why did you quit?
It's ... Why did I ... Um ...
She's like, "What ..."
It's not a good ... It's a boring
story. It's long and boring.
No, really. Why did you quit?
Um ... Well, let's see.
You know, I went to college and I was
a little, happy theater major ...
and all bright and
shiny and everything.
And graduated from college
and moved to the big city ...
and started getting out there and
auditioning, and I did the whole thing.
You know, I did all the cattle
calls and the whole nine yards.
I don't know, after a while I just
kind of started feeling like ...
it really wasn't meant to be.
But, you know, I mean,
sometimes when I go see
a Broadway musical,
I just kind of
sit there and think,
"You know, I could've done that."
"I totally could've done that."
I think. I think.
I think I could've.
Now, look, man, you said there was
something interesting about it, though.
Yes. There is.
Her.
Look, you don't come across
a voice like that every day.
Hold up, man.
She didn't even want to sing!
Look, you need to find
different producers.
You know? Work with Pharrell,
Ronson, Timbaland.
No, look, I'm the producer, man.
I make the tracks, right? Me.
And I found her. She wouldn't
even be here if it wasn't for me.
Look, guys, I'm sorry. That's just
the way this business works.
Look, you're young.
All right, you're
just getting started,
but right now
this is her time to shine.
Look. Give me an opportunity
to do this for you.
We're doing 360 deals
that will blow your mind.
We just joint ventured
with Live Nation.
Clear Channel's giving us 1,000
spins of anybody that we want.
Listen, I worked on
Alicia Keys' record.
I worked on Lauryn Hill's record.
I know what to do for you. But you
gotta trust me. Let's do this.
Come on, let's go.
This is bullshit. And you know it.
Wait, wait. Hold, hold on.
Now, you were born to do this.
You know that.
You know what, thank you,
but I can't. I just can't ...
I know they're your friends.
But what I'm trying to do
for you could make you a star.
Look. Just take my card
and think about it, all right?
Denise! You coming?
So, this is all I've been able to
come up with for the moment,
'cause my financiers
were slightly shallow ...
Don't worry about the money.
I mean, we'll shoot some scenes.
Okay. We'll cut a mini-trailer.
We'll use that to get more money.
I'm feeling it. I mean, I've already
got this storyboard thing going with ...
I've got some visuals here.
- I thought I could run this by you.
- Right, right. Yeah!
I have a shot list in my bag somewhere
if you'd like to see it now.
- You just get into your process.
- Sure.
I've already talked to
my friends at Sundance.
This is exactly what
they're looking for.
That's incredible. Let's make
a movie. Let's make a movie.
Excuse me.
Hi, I'm looking for
Andy Matthews' trailer.
Is he expecting you?
Yeah.
Right this way.
So what's going on?
Um ...
We were gonna go see your
casting director, right?
At least that's what
you said on the phone.
Right. Yes. No, no, no. Totally.
She's actually out today.
She has a flu.
Wow. I'm so sorry. Well, then I
should come back another time ...
No, no, no, no. She said that we
could put a scene on tape for her.
Yeah. No, that's fine.
That's great.
Okay. Perfect.
So, I have a scene coming up this
afternoon if you want to run that one.
Yeah, sure, that'd be good.
Okay.
Um ...
- It's ...
- Yeah, it's a scene where ...
we're coming back from a party
and we're just at my apartment.
Just relax. Here.
You're gonna be great.
Thanks.
So I told her a lot of stuff
about you, you know.
I told her you're the prettiest
girl at Performing Arts.
- Thanks.
- It's true.
So, what we're gonna do here,
we're just gonna slate.
- Okay.
Okay. It's like name and age, and
then we'll get going with the scene.
Okay.
And go.
Hi, I'm Jenny Garrison
and I'm 17 years old.
Perfect.
And action.
"The music was so loud,
I had to get out of there."
"Well, Maddy, I'm so glad
you brought me with you."
"You know how I feel about you."
"Or at least I hope you do."
- Andy, you actually have
still another line. - Right.
Yeah, that line. I like to
improvise. It's kind of my thing.
You know? I'm sorry.
No. It's okay.
Just don't stop the scene again.
- Okay.
- You want to be an actress, right?
Right, of course.
You gotta be ready for whatever
they throw at you.
I mean, our job, as actors,
is to make the audience believe
what's really going on.
- Right.
- I remember learning that at P.A.
- Am I wrong? - No, not at all.
That's exactly ... Yeah.
- No, that's it. Perfect.
- Okay.
Let's try it again?
Yep. Let's do it.
Okay.
And action.
The music was so loud,
I had to get out of there.
Maddy, I'm so glad
you brought me with you.
I mean, you know
how I feel about you.
Or at least I hope you do.
- Andy.
- Jesus, Jenny.
Look, I don't understand it.
You're not getting it.
I mean, do you know how many girls
would die for this opportunity with me?
Yeah. And I'm sure you've had
every one of them in this trailer.
No, probably not every one of them.
Look, is this even an audition or do
you have a collection of these tapes?
I might have a few.
Look, Jenny.
No. You came here.
Okay, what did you think
was gonna happen?
We were gonna talk about our craft?
I don't do that.
- Okay, you don't, but I do.
- Right.
No, look.
Stop it, okay!
- Can you just leave me alone?
- Jenny.
Just leave me alone!
Wait. Andy?
What about Andy?
Andy invited me to set
to meet a casting director.
And we went into
his trailer. And ...
- Well, I ...
- Jenny.
Well, did he try something on you?
Kind of.
I knew it! I knew
this was gonna happen.
- Marco!
- I told you
about this asshole
from the beginning.
But you still went behind my back.
I know. And I'm sorry,
but I ...
Look, I thought that maybe if he did
want to flirt, just a little bit,
that it would be fine if I ...
What, if you got the job?
You know what, Jenny?
If becoming famous
is so important to you,
then go for it. I'm done with this.
- Marco, I ...
- Hey, you know what?
I hope you really get
the role. I really do.
What do you mean,
I can't have my camera equipment?
You see, I already gave
the check to my producer.
So, this is a matter of ...
Sir, there's no ...
- You are not registered
on the computer. - Right.
- Neither you nor your
producer are here. - Okay.
I cannot do that.
At the same time,
this film is fully funded.
- I don't care. It may be.
- He just called me.
He goes, "Earl's gonna help you out."
You're not helping me out, Earl.
I would love to help you out, but
there's nothing I can do. I cannot ...
You know what, let's check
the name again.
I've checked the name
already three times ...
Please just check the name again.
Let's do it again. Come on.
B-A-C-Z-Y-N-S-K-Y.
I know how to spell it.
I tried it three times.
Earl, please help me here.
I would love to help you, but it's
not there. There's nothing I can do.
Eddie, it's Neil.
You remember how you asked me to write
you that letter of recommendation?
Of course.
Well ...
I'm sorry, but I can't
write you that letter.
Sometimes we get students
who are promising,
but they never progress
past that early promise.
♪ If the fish swam out of the ocean ♪
I know you want to
be a ballet dancer,
but I don't believe that's
going to happen for you.
Not on a professional level.
♪ And the stars fell out of the sky ♪
♪ And my tears rolled into the ... ♪
I work harder than anyone else.
I'm sorry, Kevin.
You're just not
a strong enough dancer.
♪ ... set my world into motion ♪
♪ 'Cause if you're not really here ♪
You will never, in my opinion,
be able to support
yourself as a dancer.
It's my responsibility
to tell you that.
♪ Black and gold ♪
♪ Black and gold. Black and gold ♪
♪ 'Cause if you're not really here ♪
You should continue
your year here at P.A.
But you need to be prepared.
♪ Black and gold. Black and gold ♪
Kevin, there are students who are
going to get picked up ...
by Ailey, City Ballet,
Complexions.
And there are other students who are
going to have to pursue other options.
Like,
you might make a wonderful teacher.
- Maybe you're right.
- I know, I'm so proud of you.
It's Sesame Street. Okay,
who doesn't know Sesame Street?
- Everybody grew up with it at
some point. - Cookie Monster!
Okay, okay ...
♪ You made me want you ♪
And all the time,
♪ I guess you always knew ♪
♪ You made me happy sometimes ♪
♪ You made me glad ♪
- No.
- No?
See, there are some people
that like crispy cookies ...
and some people that like gooey ...
I don't like ...
And so, if I could create my perfect
Sesame Street cast ...
No, see, you see, if I could make
my ideal Sesame Street cast ...
The puppets ...
Kevin!
Did he call you again?
Yeah, he called me again.
So does he want you to record
an album or something?
Yeah. He wanted me to work with Damon
and Poyser, whoever those people are.
What'd you say?
I told him no.
Because of your pops?
No.
What? Because of us?
Yes, because of us.
It's you, me and Malik.
That's it. Package deal.
Denise, look, I ... I don't wanna
keep you from your dreams, all right?
That man's right,
you were born to sing.
Jesus, Victor!
Enough already.
Before you and Malik,
I didn't even realize
I could sing that music.
That I loved that music.
I didn't even know who I was.
You guys believed in me,
so I'm not gonna sell you out.
And that's that.
Now, can we get back to practice?
Yeah.
I've been calling you
and texting you.
Left a few messages
and you don't even respond.
And I didn't see you
at school. What's up with that?
I'm sorry. It's been crazy. I've
been so busy getting ready and stuff.
Busy? Doing what?
I got into Complexions.
Complexions? What's that?
Only the greatest modern
dance company in the world.
They want me for a world tour.
What?
Wait, are you serious?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
That's what I'm talking about.
What did I tell you?
It's gonna be a lot of work.
I bet. What's it like?
Give me details.
Twenty-two cities.
We start rehearsing next week.
Next week? What about school?
I'm dropping out.
Your parents will let you?
Are you kidding? They've put me
in dance class since I was five.
They're thrilled.
Oh.
That's great.
I know I should have told you
sooner, Victor. I'm sorry.
We'll still, like ...
We'll still see each other, right?
When you come back to
visit your parents. Right?
Alice, baby, come on.
Victor, listen.
It's not just us.
A lot of my friends
say that after P.A.,
you just go on your separate ways.
It's just the way
the world works, Victor.
That's just how it works?
Hey, Malik.
What happened to your dad?
What?
Your dad. Where is he?
Mrs. Simms?
Joy. Come in.
Have a seat, dear.
Come here.
Come and have a seat.
I want to talk to you.
I think we both know
why I asked to see you.
Your grades.
I'm your teacher, Malik.
And I want an answer.
The oldest story in the book,
all right? He left.
After Ayanna was born. Didn't
even come back for her funeral.
Was there anyone there
to take his place?
I tried to make it work for
as long as I possibly could.
I know.
You know how I feel about P.A.
But I'm working on the show
all the time now.
And I ... I just ...
I don't know what to do.
Everything you're ashamed of,
all the parts of yourself
that you keep secret,
everything you want to
change about yourself,
it's who you are.
That's your power.
Deny it and you're nothing.
And you'll never be
much of an actor.
This school is here to
develop you as an artist.
And when you're ready, send you
out there to go to work.
Are you ready?
Now, you're good, Malik.
But you've got to start
breaking down those walls ...
and accept your circumstances.
Just tell the truth.
Nobody cares about that shit.
Yeah, maybe so.
But I do.
You all right?
Why the hell are you so nervous?
Cool. You invited them.
No, not exactly.
What does that mean?
I told them some kids
from school were performing
who were, I don't know,
musically gifted.
Wait, so they don't know
you're singing tonight?
No.
But do they know it's hip hop?
I told them, "Classical jazz."
Oh, it's gonna be good tonight.
Oh, yeah.
You sure you don't want
anything to drink?
I'd love one, but I'm gonna be
paying my dad back till I'm 30.
I can't afford a drink.
You don't mind if I have a sip
of yours, though, right?
Look who it is. Look who it is.
Mr. Dowd.
Yeah, sorry, guys,
I gotta go.
How've you been?
I've been okay.
That's good.
I've been thinking
a lot about you.
Yeah, I have, too.
I think about how I hurt you ...
and it kills me. I'm so sorry.
I went there for all the wrong
reasons and I know that now.
Things will probably never be
the same between us, but ...
Mike check, one-two, one-two.
Do you think you'll ever
be able to forgive me?
Hey, guys, the show's
about to start.
Coming.
Listen.
Let's just talk about this later.
Okay?
All right.
Yo, what up, everyone?
How y'all feeling tonight?
Come on, let me hear y'all.
Yeah!
Come on, y'all can
do better than that.
Look, look, look. we got a
special group for y'all tonight,
straight out of the
Performing Arts High School.
How y'all feel about that?
I got a question for y'all.
How many people here have gone
to the Performing Arts?
Okay, raise your hands.
Let me see. Let me see.
I see you. Okay, one, two, ten.
Okay, good, good.
So look, look, tonight is their
first performance ever ...
- Good luck, girl.
so try not to be too mean, all right?
Just give it up, people.
Give it up.
♪ You want to know my life? ♪
♪ well let me give you a backdrop ♪
♪ I was born in
the era of the flattop ♪
♪ Low-cut Air Jordans
with the black socks ♪
♪ When Run-DMC was
chilling with Ad-Rock ♪
♪ Mom was broke and
Dad did crack rock ♪
♪ So I hit the streets to keep
the padlock off our apartment door ♪
♪ Me and my mans holding the 'four ♪
♪ Standing in front of the stash spot ♪
♪ Until one day
my little sister got popped ♪
♪ It took away my
whole life in a snapshot ♪
♪ And it might sound gory,
but that's the unfortunate story ♪
♪ Between the "haves"
and the "have-nots" ♪
♪ Between the "gots"
and the "ain't-gots" ♪
♪ I was tired of not
getting so I got on the go ♪
♪ Everybody worldwide
got to get it for sure ♪
♪ Get on your job, get on your
grind. Get on the flo' ♪
♪ Now let's go ♪
♪ Yeah, come on ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor
Come and shake it with me ♪
♪ So high we're not coming down ♪
♪ we ain't coming down
Baby, get on the floor ♪
♪ 'Cause I know you believe, Yeah ♪
♪ We've come too far to turn
back now Tell them, baby ♪
♪ Don't want to think
about yesterday ♪
♪ Or the time that slipped away ♪
♪ Or the things that people say ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm just living my life.
Living my life ♪
♪ And I can have anything
if I choose it ♪
♪ And I'm ready and willing to prove
it I like the way you move it ♪
♪ I like the way you do it, yeah.
So let's get down tonight ♪
♪ It's time to show me what you
got. Show me what you got ♪
♪ Keep it moving,
please don't stop. Don't stop ♪
♪ Don't want to
wait until tomorrow ♪
♪ All we got is here and now.
All we got is here and now ♪
♪ No need to let
these moments go by ♪
♪ we got one night. One night ♪
♪ One life. One life ♪
♪ So come take this chance with me.
Yeah ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor.
Get on the floor ♪
♪ Come and shake it with me.
Just shake it ♪
♪ So high we're not coming down ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor.
Get on the floor ♪
♪ 'Cause I know you believe. Yeah ♪
♪ We've come too far to turn back
now. Don't turn back now ♪
♪ Too far, too, too,
too far. Too far ♪
♪ Too far Come on ♪
Yeah, what's up, everybody?
Give it up for the band!
Yeah!
Thank you for coming out.
I'm Malik. That's my
boy Victor on the keys.
And on vocals ...
what's up, y'all?
It's your girl, Denise!
♪ I say everybody Everybody ♪
♪ Keep moving to the beat.
Move to the beat, y'all ♪
♪ If the feeling that
you're feeling is true ♪
♪ It's true, baby. It's true, baby ♪
♪ I say everybody. Everybody ♪
♪ I want to see you on your feet.
On your feet ♪
♪ 'Cause the music's got me
feeling brand new ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor ♪
♪ Get on the floor, y'all ♪
♪ Shake it with me ♪
♪ Just shake it ♪
♪ we're not coming down ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor ♪
♪ 'Cause I know you believe ♪
♪ Too far to turn back now ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor
I know you like it, baby ♪
♪ So high we're not coming down
we're not coming down ♪
♪ Baby, get on the floor
'Cause I know you believe ♪
♪ We've come too far ♪
♪ We've come too far
to turn back now ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
- Daddy ...
- Denise, I can't believe ...
you tricked us into
coming here tonight.
I thought it was a school event.
I had to. There was
no other choice.
And who were those boys
you were up there with?
They're my friends. I ...
And when the hell
did you start singing?
I just want you to know that
this is completely unacceptable.
You know what? If you can't accept
this, then you can't accept me.
Because this is who I am.
Playing piano isn't enough for
me anymore, Daddy.
Sitting in an orchestra,
invisible. I hate it!
That's it! I'm pulling you out
of that school.
I don't care if there's
three months left.
- But ... What?
- No.
I have been watching Denise play the
piano all her life and she is good.
And she practices and she's done
everything we asked her to do.
But she doesn't love it.
She went to school to be ...
You will stay at that school and
we will support you no matter what.
Now, wait ...
There will be no more discussion.
There are some things
success is not.
It's not fame.
It's not money or power.
Success is waking up
in the morning ...
so excited about
what you have to do ...
that you literally
fly out the door.
It's getting to work
with people you love.
Success is connecting with the
world and making people feel.
It's finding a way to
bind together people ...
who have nothing in
common but a dream.
It's falling asleep at night knowing
you did the best job you could.
Success is joy and
freedom and friendship.
And success is love.
What are you doing here?
You're not graduating.
True, but my best friend is.
I bought you a present.
Oh, my God!
Where did you find this?
I thought the Gucci print might be a
little too much, but I thought you'd like it.
No, it's perfect.
What happened to all your stuff?
It all went home already.
What do you mean?
I'm going back to lowa.
But I thought we talked
about you staying here,
doing dance class and Broadway ...
Joy, Joy, Joy.
I'm lucky. I have a place to go.
I'm gonna take over
my mom's dance studio.
And I'm gonna be the best goddamn
dance teacher there ever was.
Four years of ups and downs,
of wonderment and disappointment,
of ennui and joy.
It was everything
I'd ever hoped for.
And scene.
- Congratulations!
- Can I take a picture?
Over here.
- Hi.
Welcome, everyone, to the
New York High School of Performing Arts ...
graduation and performance.
I got us seats right here.
we ask that you now turn off
all your cell phones ...
and please refrain from
any flash photography ...
during the performance.
Thank you very much
and enjoy the show.
♪ Countless hours of learning more ♪
♪ Countless hours of knowing less ♪
♪ Can't look behind you ♪
♪ You have to look ahead ♪
♪ So many doubts
running through your mind ♪
♪ All the excuses.
Don't have the time ♪
♪ All the rejection you
have to leave behind ♪
♪ Leave it all behind.
Leave it all behind ♪
♪ Hold your dreams ♪
♪ Don't ever let it go ♪
♪ Be yourself ♪
♪ And let the world take notice ♪
♪ You'll find strength ♪
♪ when people bring you down ♪
♪ They will see ♪
♪ If you would only ♪
♪ Only believe ♪
♪ Someway, somehow.
Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Don't give up now.
Don't give up ♪
♪ Don't be afraid ♪
♪ To succeed. To succeed ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Someway, somehow.
Come on, everybody ♪
♪ The time is right now.
It's our time, yeah ♪
♪ Don't be afraid ♪
♪ To succeed. To succeed ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Hold your dreams ♪
♪ Don't ever let it go ♪
♪ Be yourself ♪
♪ And let the world take notice ♪
♪ You'll find strength ♪
♪ when people bring you down ♪
♪ They will see ♪
♪ If you would only ♪
♪ Only believe ♪
♪ Remember, remember ♪
♪ Baby, look at me
and tell me what you see ♪
♪ You ain't seen the best of me yet ♪
♪ Give me time I'll make you
forget the rest ♪
♪ I got more to me ♪
♪ And you can set it free ♪
♪ I can catch the moon
in my hand ♪
♪ Don't you know who I am? ♪
♪ Remember my name. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ I'm gonna learn how to fly. High ♪
♪ I feel it coming together ♪
♪ People will see me and cry. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna make it to heaven ♪
♪ Light up the sky like a flame.
Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ Baby, remember my name ♪
♪ Remember, remember,
remember, remember ♪
♪ Remember, remember ♪
♪ Baby, hold me tight ♪
♪ 'Cause you can make it right ♪
♪ You can shoot me
straight to the top ♪
♪ Give me love and take all
I've got to give ♪
♪ Baby, I return ♪
♪ Too much is not enough ♪
♪ I can ride your heart
till it breaks ♪
♪ Ooh, I've got what it takes ♪
♪ Remember my name. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ I'm gonna learn how to fly. High ♪
♪ I feel it coming together ♪
♪ People will see me and cry. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna make it to heaven ♪
♪ Light up the sky like a flame. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ Baby, remember my name ♪
♪ Remember, remember,
remember, remember ♪
♪ Remember my name
Remember, remember ♪
♪ Remember, remember,
remember, remember ♪
♪ Remember my name. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ I'm gonna learn how to fly. High ♪
♪ I feel it coming together ♪
♪ People see me and cry. Fame ♪
♪ I'm gonna make it to heaven ♪
♪ Light up the sky like a flame. Fame ♪
I'm gonna live forever ♪
♪ Baby, remember my name.
My name ♪
♪ Remember my name ♪
♪ Nowhere to run. Nowhere to hide ♪
No time for games. Time to decide ♪
♪ The pressure's on ♪
♪ It's got to be right ♪
♪ Won't be detoured by foolish pride ♪
♪ Gotta work just a little ♪
♪ Just a peek
for something committal ♪
♪ Got to find
somewhere in the middle ♪
♪ So confusing with my feelings ♪
♪ I'm just lost in the fever ♪
♪ It takes time for true feelings ♪
♪ But I can't seem to fight it ♪
♪ No matter how I try ♪
♪ You can't run from love ♪
♪ You can't push and shove ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter what
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You try your best to speed up ♪
♪ But you don't measure up ♪
♪ There's nowhere to hide
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You can't run from love ♪
♪ You can't push and shove ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter what
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You can't hide from love
Can't hide from love ♪
♪ Can't hide. Love will always ♪
♪ How do I feel? ♪
♪ what do I say? ♪
♪ I'm on the spot. Today's the day ♪
♪ Decision time What should I do? ♪
♪ Should I deny or give in to? ♪
♪ Gotta work just a little ♪
♪ Just a peek for something committal ♪
♪ Got to find somewhere in the middle ♪
♪ So confusing with my feelings ♪
♪ I'm just lost in the fever ♪
♪ It takes time for true feelings ♪
♪ But I can't seem to fight it ♪
♪ No matter how I try ♪
♪ You can't run from love ♪
♪ You can't push and shove ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter what
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You try your best to speed up ♪
♪ But you don't measure up ♪
♪ There's nowhere to hide
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You can't run from love ♪
♪ You can't push and shove ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter what
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ Can't hide from love. Yeah ♪
♪ Can't hide from love. Come on ♪
♪ Can't hide. Love will always ♪
♪ Through all my shades
you shine so bright ♪
♪ Move, you do it. You do it like ♪
♪ Nobody. It's plain to see ♪
♪ Your TNT is dynamite ♪
♪ Your fuse I'd gladly ignite ♪
♪ For your bomb madly recite ♪
♪ Stadium status
'cause you're the baddest ♪
♪ midnight train since Gladys Knight ♪
♪ Girl, you know
we got a problem, right? ♪
♪ I salute you
like stars and stripes ♪
♪ Introduce you to all these sights ♪
♪ 'Cause that's what you've been
waiting for all your life ♪
♪ I know you like that fancy stuff ♪
♪ Make a nigga wanna
take advantage of ♪
♪ Yes, I'm calling,
'cause I'm falling ♪
♪ For you and cannot be hurt.
Let's go ♪
♪ You can't run from love ♪
♪ You can't push and shove ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter what
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You try your best to speed up ♪
♪ But you don't measure up ♪
♪ There's nowhere to hide.
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ You can't run from love.
You can't run ♪
♪ You can't push and shove ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter what.
Love will always catch you ♪
♪ Can't hide from love.
Can't hide from love ♪
Can't hide ♪