Hello.
I have a new body for you.
Seven days?
No problem. I'll store it for you.
But you have to give me a deposit.
I'll meet you at the same time,
same place.
7 DAYS LATER
Let me go before I tell everyone...
...that you make money
from dead bodies!
Make money from dead bodies!
Doctor! Doctor!
Quick. Inject her.
No!
I've already told you
that practice makes perfect.
It's fish maw soup.
Here, let me get you some.
Hello. It's me.
Why haven't you picked it up yet?
You have to wait.
I am not ready yet.
Not ready?
But it's been seven days.
There could be a problem with the body.
You sell the bodies.
You must know what needs to be done.
There were never any problems before.
Our customers were always content.
But there could be a problem
with your order.
Calm down. I've already paid for it.
Just wait for me at the usual place.
Let's get married.
Love Tahwaan
Doctor Tar.
Let's take a look at some wedding rings.
Excuse me.
This is Nook, my sister.
You can go now.
Don't even think about her.
Next we will be presenting the award
for doctor of the year.
Please welcome Doctor Tar
to the stage...
...who will receive his bouquet
from Professor Yo.
Doctor Tar is not only
doctor of the year...
...but is also deeply loved
by the staff of this hospital.
Are you going to the ceremony?
Look at all that makeup.
What's wrong with
a little makeup for work?
So this is what 100,000 Baht tastes like.
How many days has it been?
Has what been?
How many days has she been dead?
Today is the seventh day.
Why do you want to know?
Did you know the dead always return to
the one they love on the seventh day?
If she knew that you wanted
to take Doctor Tar from her...
...she would come for you
tonight for sure.
Are you out of your mind?
Anyway, what could she do?
It's almost midnight.
And even if she did try something,
with this little time...
...I'm sure she would
come for you first, Aeh.
You'll know soon enough.
Why get married?
What do you get in return?
Will you get married
And become a servant
Or will you just tend to his garden?
Low class scum
should stay where they belong.
You...
Do you know you're the most
beautiful girl in the world?
No, you're the most beautiful.
No, it's you.
You're the most beautiful.
You are.
Close your eyes.
That hurts.
Now it's my turn. Close your eyes.
- Let's play ghosts under the covers.
- Come on.
Let's play it.
I'm under the covers already.
Stop acting so sweet, the pair of you.
It's time for work.
What are you laughing at?
- I won.
- The loser must pay a forfeit.
What kind of forfeit?
- I’ve given you my heart.
- You missed me and grazed my head.
- Now you give me yours.
- Here.
Quickly. One more time.
Here.
- It went over there.
- You're all crazy.
If you don't love us then don't look.
- But if you do look you will love us.
Patty cake, patty cake, baker's man
Bake me a cake as fast as you can.
Fifty-five.
Fifty-six.
Fifty-seven.
Fifty-eight.
Fifty-nine.
Sixty.
So sexy!
Go away!
Whatever.
You cannot eat yet.
Do you want to become a fat pig?
I'll keep an eye on your weight
for you. Get out of here.
Shit.
Hey. Hey. Let me go.
Thanks, Tuwangwit.
You know people who are born
under Virgo shouldn't work in hospitals.
Why not?
It's a kind of conflict.
What conflict?
What do you mean?
You have to stay virgins.
- Oh, I see.
- Get it?
Can I borrow your telephone
for a moment, ma'am?
- Of course you can. Here.
- Thank you.
Just a second.
Hello.
You old fart. You just can't
control yourself around young girls.
- Hello.
- You insane bitch.
Why did you do that?
You're out of order.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Who are you? Who are you?
Your damn husband.
I'm afraid my husband died
five years ago. Who are you?
Excuse me, ma'am.
Ms. Samornsri, please forgive me.
I dialed the wrong number.
Damn it.
What do those two emblems mean?
Everything has a cycle.
It symbolizes eternity. Do you like it?
It's cool.
One, two. Pose.
One more. One more time.
Me too.
All of me.
Look this way. Yes, just like that.
Nook. Help us, Nook.
Nook. Please help us, Nook.
Nook. Help us.
Nook. Nook. Nook. Help us, please.
Nook. Nook. Nook.
Aeh.
Aeh?
No, doctor. This isn't the right place.
If the dead want to be jealous,
that's up to them.
How could you do that to me?
You're my sister. My sister!
Are you going to
stay away from my doctor?
Answer me.
I told you to answer me.
You like this, don't you?
Is this what you want?
You like it, don't you?
I'm carrying the doctor's child.
You!
Why do you
care about him so much?
He'll never marry you anyway.
Let me go. I'm gonna get her.
This is none of your business.
Let me go. Let me go. Doctor!
Doctor. Doctor. Doctor, help me.
Doctor!
Doctor, you have to marry me!
You promised.
You promised me!
You've lost your chance, Tahwaan.
Let me go.
Let me go!
Let me go...
...before I tell everyone
that you make money from dead bodies.
You make money from dead bodies!
Doctor... Doctor...
What is it, my love?
Doctor... Doctor... Tah... Tah...
Tah. What are you talking about, Nook?
Tah... Tah...
Tah. Come as quick as you can.
I have a surprise for you.
You have something special
for me today?
- You're being very secretive.
- Just come back quickly.
Okay. I'm on my way.
- This way.
- No, this way.
Am. Am. Come on. Am. Am.
Am, quickly.
Am.
Am?
Am.Am.
Where are you, Am?
Where are you?
Is it with you?
Or is it with you?
Wait. Hold on.
- Orn, be careful.
- What is it?
Behind you. Behind you!
Orn!
Orn! Orn!
Off]!
Orn!
Orn.
Help me!
Let go of me!
Help me! Somebody help me!
Help me! Help me!
No.
Aeh?
Am...
Don't, Am.
Orn.
Hold on.
I have to find a way to get this off first.
Nook.
It'll come off after I pull this free.
Nook... Nook. Don't do it.
Nook...
- Nook.
- Just one more to go, Aeh.
Nook.
Wait for me.
No more.
Don't do this to us anymore, Tahwaan.
We didn't mean to.
Let us go.
I'm sorry.
You bitch!
No!
- Quick. Inject her.
- Let me go!
Orn. She's a person,
not just some dead body.
Tell them, Nook. Tell them to stop.
What should we bet on next?
I'm bored of doing it for whiskey.
How about if the winner can ask
anything of the loser?
Are you up for it?
No worries.
Damn it.
I've lost again.
What do you want?
You have to promise you'll do it first.
Okay.
Let's get married.
You're crazy. I can't marry a man.
Please don't do this to me.
For the sake of a child, please.
Have mercy on me.
Compassion
Will support the world
I'm scared.
Go get the needle.
Orn.
You are so cute.
What are you waiting for?
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Doctor, doctor, doctor!
Don't bite me!
You are so perfect.
I'm going to teach you a lesson.
Doctor, doctor, doctor!
See, I am a woman now.
You have to marry me now.
What do those two emblems mean?
Everything has a cycle.
It symbolizes eternity.
Tuwangwit.
Call me Tahwaan.
Let's get married.
Tuwangwit.
Marry me.
Nook.
Don't!
I know Tahwaan is about to report us...
...but I don't see why we have to do this.
Nook... Nook...
Nook... What's wrong with you, Nook?
Nook. Someone stop them.
Nook...
Don't, Nook. Don't.
Let's get married.
Come on.
Let's get out of here, Nook.
Marry me.