Listen, Baxter!
You can have them now if you like!
Since dead men can't talk!
It seems they didn't like my joke.
We'll let them go home in a while.
This bad boy will be our guest only until
Baxter leaves San Miguel for the frontier.
Put him in the cellar.
Esteban, good work!
With Antonio as our prisoner,
the Baxters will have to give in to us.
Now we can make any kind of demand!
Don Miguel! Don Miguel!
What has happened? Talk, will you!
I don't know who,
but somebody shot at me.
Marisol!
Marisol! Where are you, Marisol?!
Strange... how you always manage
to be in the right place at the right time.
It's nothing serious,
a headache that will pass. She'll sleep.
Keep your eyes open. She's not to move
from that room, you hear?
I wouldn't mention I brought her here.
I wouldn't want the Rojos to think
I was on your side.
Don't be worried. I'm rich enough
to appreciate the men
that my money can buy.
I've been to talk to the Rojos.
They'll give back Antonio
in exchange for Marisol in the morning.
Very soon, you're going to be rich.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's not gonna break my heart.
Where is she?
You said I'd see her! Where is she?
I want to see her!
Come back here, Jesus. Come here.
Why can't I look at her? I want to see her!
Go. Go to him, Marisol.
Mama!
- Mama!
- Jesus!
Mama!
- Mama! Mama!
Julio.
Marisol.
Get Julio.
You were warned to get outta town.
Now I'm gonna make you pay
once and for all.
Let him be.
You better get goin'. Ramon's waitin'.
And you, get that kid home
where he belongs.
A pig, that Ramon!
Tell me, what's Ramon
got to do with them?
You weren't told, eh?
In these parts, the story is very old.
A happy little family until trouble
comes along. Trouble is Ramon.
Claiming the husband cheated at cards,
which wasn't true,
he gets the wife
to live with him as hostage.
The husband?
Him, there's nothing for him to do.
The Rojos threatened to kill his boy,
Jesus. He was forced to accept things.
That Ramon is smart.
Where are you going?
To the Rojos, to look for a job.
Poo!
I'm glad we have the Americano with us.
It's the best thing to happen to us.
If either government starts an enquiry,
we'll need every man we can get.
To be at war with the Baxters now is
worse than sitting on a case of dynamite.
- Where should we put this?
- Put it over there.
Come on, everybody. Drink up!
Good shooting. Very good shooting.
To kill a man, you shoot for his heart,
and a Winchester is the best weapon.
That's very nice, but I'll stick with my .45.
When a man with a .45
meets a man with a rifle,
the man with the pistol
will be a dead man.
That's an old Mexican proverb,
and it's true.
You believe that?
Paquito, take five men
and escort Marisol to the small house.
- Everything is prepared.
- Do not worry. I will return tomorrow.
The wagons are ready. We can leave.
Everyone!
Enjoy yourselves during my absence!
You heard Ramon,
let's have a good time.
He weighs over a ton.
Of course, with all he poured into himself.
Papa,
did you not tell me
no-one could go see Mama?
That's right.
Then, why does that man see her
when I cannot?
- I want Mama!
- Come away from the door. Quiet.
We cannot show ourselves.
You must stay away.
Hello.
There's somebody shooting
at the small house.
Saddle the horses immediately!
Come on, let's go!
Look out!
Take this money. It's enough to live on
for a while. Now, get across the border.
Get as far away from San Miguel
as possible.
How may we thank you
for what you are doing?
Don't try. Just get goin'
before the Rojos get here.
Why do you do this for us?
Why? I knew someone like you once.
No-one was there to help. Get movin'.
Get movin'.
Get outta here!
What do you see, Chico?
They're all dead. They massacred them.
- They kidnapped Marisol!
- This looks like the work of the Baxters.
Quick! Let's get back before
they attack our house in the town.
Chico, give out the ammunition.
Esteban, spread your men
around the house. Keep your eyes open.
Miguel, Paco, behind the house.
Manolo and Alvaro, come with me.
Stay alert!
The way they killed those men,
there must be a lot of them.
It's a warm evening.
One of our wagons lost a wheel
so we had to turn back here to get help.
One of the men tells me...
the Baxters attacked the small house.
Do you know about it?
Tell me what you know.
Oh!
Well?
Where did you hide Marisol?
Rubio.
Bring him over here.
You are a stubborn idiot. Tell us
where Marisol is and it'll all be ended.
In a week, you'll be back in shape,
and you can go wherever you want.
That's enough for today.
Sooner or later he'll talk.
It's just a matter of time.
He mustn't escape or die.
Otherwise, do as you like.
Wait till he comes to.
This way he hardly feels anything.
I have a poker hand waiting for me.
Now I am stuck here! I can't get back to it!
This is more amusing than cards.
Just be sure he does not die,
and also make sure
he regrets the day he was born.
The gringo is asleep, I imagine.
That's all right. I'll enjoy waking him up.
Esteban, what was that noise?
I do not know.
I heard a yell and then a crash.
It's useless to hide!
You are finished playing the smart boy.
Go up and look in the loft!
And take a look behind the barrels!
Let's get out of here!
Hurry! Hurry!
- Come on!
- You, come along with me!
Surround the town! Block the streets
leading out! Find him for me!
- Esteban, search the whole town!
- Follow me!
Get him back right now!
You've got to at any cost!
Look in the stables, in every corral,
in the store!
Look for him in the church!
Go in there! Search every inch of it!
Search everywhere! Rubio, in here!
If somebody is hiding him,
burn their house down and kill them!
You, come here!
Look for him near the Baxters',
but take him alive. I want him alive!
Alive!
Rubio,... in the bar.
He says he knows nothing.
He's being smart.
Bring him here to me.
I swear I'm telling the truth.
Well,... you know nothing, huh?
Nothing! I have not seen him!
Rubio, you take care of him!
Where have you hidden him?
I... didn't... hide...
You are the right friend
for that filthy Americano.
You'll end up the same way.
We looked everywhere.
In his cellar, in the attic, on the roof,
but there is no trace.
I couldn't find anybody in the back room.
He has taken refuge with the Baxters.
The Americano isn't stupid.
He knows that's the best place to hide.
The Baxters, eh?
Then better go and get him.
Curse them!
Piripero!
Eh?
- Piripero!
- Hm?
- Come here.
- I can't see anybody.
- Dios mio!
What are you doing in there?
Never mind. Get me outta here.
But you're not dead yet.
I will be, if you don't get me
outta here quick. Get the lid down.
Rubio.
I see some signs of life.
Let's be ready
when they decide to come out.
Don't shoot!
We surrender! Don't shoot!
Don't shoot! We're coming out!
I surrender! Hold back your fire!
Don't shoot! We're surrendering!
Stop. I wanna take a look at this.
Ramon! Don't shoot!
We're comin' out.
We surrender!
Listen, you've won! It's enough!
I'll get outta town!
I'll do whatever you like!
- You promise that?
- I swear it, Ramon!
You won't try any tricks?
None. No, no tricks. I said before,
I give you my word, we'll leave!
Are you sure? You had better
ask permission of your wife.
Maybe she won't be too happy!
Antonio! John!
Murderers.
They had no guns!
Murderers! I hope you rot in hell!
May you all die spitting blood!
Curse you for this!
Murderers!
Let's go. The show's over anyway.
Keep looking for him!
Search among those bodies!
The filthy Americano
has to be somewhere.
Silvanito?
Where's Silvanito?
Any news today?
I have to tell you some bad news.
I hate to tell you this, Joe, but...
Where is Silvanito?
He was captured this morning
by those men of Ramon's.
They grabbed him on his way here.
He was bringing in some provisions.
He is being tortured, but he won't talk.
He's stubborn.
Whatever they do, he won't say a word,
even if it means his life.
Listen to me.
They'll never be able to force him.
Now, old fool, loosen up your tongue.
No.
Rubio!
Get back to your shop.
You're liable to have business there.
Very good! That's what I wanted to hear.
I brought a little surprise for you.
I know how much you will need it.
It was hard to get my hands on it.
I got it by using my head.
No-one can resist two bottles of wine.
I thought you might need that pistol.
And I brought another present.
It's dynamite.
I stole it from the Rojos.
The moment's come
for you to light the fuse
and send it back to them.
Still lots of light.
Rubio, here.
I shouldn't like to ruin the rifle.
I could never find another like this one.
Later, Ramon.
Let's try it with this one now.
Gringo!
I heard you wanted to see me.
The Americano's dead.
Cut the old man down.
What's wrong, Ramon?
You losing your touch?
Are you afraid, Ramon?
The heart, Ramon. Don't forget the heart.
Aim for the heart or you'll never stop me.
When a man with a .45
meets a man with a rifle,
you said the man with the pistol's
a dead man.
Let's see if that's true.
Go ahead. Load up and shoot.
Hey. Hey, listen, Joe.
Listen, Joe, l... I...
Oh, Joe... Joe...
I guess your government'll be glad
to see that gold back.
And you? You don't want to be here
when they get it, eh?
You mean,
the Mexican government on one side,
maybe the Americans on the other,
and me, right smack in the middle?
Uh-uh. Too dangerous.
So long.
Adios.