Excuse me.
Want take a ride in
Batista's old Cadillac?
No, really, really. Let me help you.
Where are you going?
That book's not gonna help you.
Come on, l'll take you. No problem.
You're gonna love this ride.
You like seafood?
I could take you to Hemingway's
favorite watering hole:
La Floridita.
That 's where he used
to drink his 'mojitos'.
It 's the best lobster in all of
Havana. Really. Delicious.
They have oysters, turtle.
Did you hear that when
our great 'El Pappa Fidel'...
Hold on one second.
Our leader, was presented with
a Galapagos turtle...
he asked,
'How long does it live?'
'Four hundred years'.
So Fidel hands it back.
'Four hundred years?!
That 's the trouble with pets.
You get attached to them
and then they die on you.'
He never dies.
- Good morning, children.
- Good morning, teacher.
- Sit down, please.
- Thank you.
You know that we live in Cuba.
In what city?
Havana, Cuba.
Havana...
Cuba. And what is
today's date?
February, 15th.
And Tracy, what year?
Two thousand and one.
Yes, two thousand and one.
All right. Now take out
your books, please.
Today we're going to study
the life of Jose Marti.
You cannot call yourself
a Cuban, any of you...
until you know the story
of Jose Marti.
Jose Marti died fighting for
the freedom of Cuba.
- L'll drive.
- Yes, commander.
I love you too. Bye.
Watch this.
Come up.
Come on.
Fidel! Raul! The sailors are
pissing on Jose Marti's statue!
Come on!
Stewey! Look at me!
Matt, come on up here!
Arturo!
Get that one up here.
No! Yeah, me!
Take my picture!
Hold on, hold on! It 's coming.
Get the picture, go!
Justice! Justice!
Please! Please!
You have my personal apologies
for the inexcusable behavior...
of a half-dozen of our boys, who
had a few too many rum and cokes.
- We don't want your apologies!
- Give us the sailors who did it!
I assure you we do not take lightly
the nearly sacred importance...
to your country
of the memory of...
- What 's his name?
- Jose Marti.
Marti. Marti.
Jose Marti.
Please...
Please, remember the many years of
friendship between our countries...
and the help we gave you in winning
your independence from Spain.
Let me tell you about our country.
0ur history. The truth!
1898...
after thirty year of fighting
for our freedom...
after Jose Marti...
Jose Marti?! Can you say
his name now, Ambassador?
After Jose Marti and fifty thousand
of my people...
of your people, who'd given their
lives to be freed from Spain...
do you know what happened
then, Ambassador?
Your president, Roosevelt...
Yes, we do not forget his name!
He stole our independence
from us.
More history for you.
Who came out of our war...
with an empire from the
Philippines to Puerto Rico?
Shall we tell him?
You! You!
- Who is that?
- No idea, sir.
And who for the last 50 years
have seized our land and...
stolen our sugar, and turned us
into people who have nothing...
...because it belongs to you?
- You! You!
- 0ut! 0ut!
0ut! 0ut!
Come on.
You cannot stay here.
Rafael!
- I have to find my brother!
- So you're Mirta?
- Rafael!
- Are you all right?
She's fine.
My brother is staying for dinner.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Just in time.
The tlme Is now elght o'clock and
we have the pleasure of brlnglng...
to your homes once agaln
the volce of the Ortodoxo Party...
...Senator Doctor Eduardo Chlbas.
- Ladles and gentlemen.
I have talked to you every Sunday
through these microphones at CMQ...
to protect the interests of
all the people of Cuba.
I stlll contlnue to protect
those Interests foryou tonlght.
People of Cuba, it has come to my
attentlon that Educatlon Mlnlster...
Aureliano Sanchez Arango
has diverted 3 million pesos...
to the construction of his private
pleasure palace in Guatemala.
Three million pesos...
that we, people of Cuba,
so desperately need.
Next Sunday nlght,
at thls tlme...
Iwlll reveal the documents that
bearwitness to thls mortal crlme.
Next Sunday nlght...
Minister Sanchez Arango,
you will have to answer...
to the mothers of
the children of Cuba!
Untll then, thls Is Eddy Chlbas
slgnlng off.
- As always: Honor agalnst greed.
- 'Honor against greed'.
Next Sunday, Eddy brings
the whole house down.
- Lf they don't kill him first.
- Just let them try.
Just let them try.
Where did we put
the other flyers we had?
We're going to create
a human wall around him.
Here, Eddy!
Eddy?!
I don't have the evidence.
It was promised me for tonight.
- From whom?
- Some Prio's men led me to believe...
they wanted Arango
brought to justice.
I thought I could trust them, but they
crossed me. They have set me up.
- Cancel the broadcast.
- How can I?
- I cannot.
- What are you going to say?
Eddy, listen to me.
What are you going to say?
This is radio CMQ.
The time is now 8 o'clock...
and we have the pleasure of
bringing to your homes once again...
the voice of the 0rtodoxo Party...
Senator Doctor Eduardo Chibas.
Despite the constant
depredations of Batista...
of Carlos Prio...
the true sensibility of the Cuban
people has not been dulled.
Because of our
geographical situation...
and the rlch magnitude of our soll,
and above all...
What 's he doing? Why isn't he
coming our with the proof?
He will.
He's not even talking about it.
...her destlny wlll come true!
We have had our historical destiny...
frustrated because of
the corruptlon of our rulers.
Ruler after ruler, year after year!
We must never again be ruled by this
government, corrupted to the bone!
Nor must we vote for Batista!
We apologlze forthe Interruptlon...
of ourtransmlsslon.
In orderto comply
with regulatlons...
no politlcal programs must
go over its allotted tlme.
What 's going on?
Why did you switch him off?
...and then gave the rest
to the Yankees!
He's off the air and he doesn't
know they cut him off.
People of Cuba, arise!
People of Cuba, in the name...
of economic independence,
political liberty...
and social justice, wake up!
Wake up!
This is my last...
knock at your door.
Jesus!
We have to take him now!
Move! Move!
I was in the radio studio.
I helped to bring him in.
L'm a lawyer. I have been
campaigning for him.
Yes, l've heard of you.
Natalia Revuelta Fernandez.
Can you tell Dr. Fernandez
that his wife is here, please?
Yes, madam.
- Your husband is in there?
- He is a heart specialist.
And Eddy is a very good
friend of ours.
Whatever happens now,
Agramonte will take over.
L've heard very good things about
your work for the 0rtodoxo Party.
Perhaps you'll give me your address
and l'll send an invitation to dinner.
Yes, thank you.
L'm sorry to say that the injures of
Dr. Eduardo Chibas are too severe.
He's not going to survive.
I cannot give you any more
information at this moment. L'm sorry.
You can come in and see him now.
I am sure we will meet again.
- My address.
- Yes, thank you.
...a promlse to the people of Cuba.
So he took the only honorable way
out. The shootlng of Eddy Chlbas...
was not sulclde.
Thls was murder!
That was Fldel Castro, memberof
the Chlbas campalgn team...
speaklng from Inslde
the hospital tonlght.
We have no hospital
to take our children.
Doctors will not even come here.
The most important thing now
for you to do...
for all of you now, is to vote.
With your vote...
I promise, and promise again, that
if you elect me to represent you...
l'll build hospitals and
bring doctors to you.
Too many presidents have promised
clean water, hospitals, doctors.
But they kept it all for themselves.
What of our freedom and our land?
It 's only their freedom
and their land.
Eddy Chibas was going to
give Cuba back to us.
But the man who carries the
fallen torch of Eddy Chibas...
who carries with him the hopes for
the future, is Roberto Agramonte.
Mirta, Agramonte is 16 points
ahead of the Prio Party.
16 points!
0ne week left!
And Batista is so far behind...
that he might as well go back to
his gangster friends in Miami.
Agramonte is going to be
the next president.
Carlos Prio...
has fled the island.
But, until we have cleansed
our beloved country...
of the corruption and crime
that are his legacy...
free and honest elections
cannot possibly take place.
- What is it?
- What are you doing?
- L've been trying to phone you!
- The phone is not working.
- Haven't you heard the radio?
- Heard what?
- There's been a coup.
- A coup?
Batista. We have to get out of here.
The police are in the street now.
Stay here with Fidelito.
You will be all right.
- Where are my shoes?
- Here, here.
Batista won't hurt you if you tell
him you're from Diaz-Balart Family.
- You have to say that, all right?
- Here, here.
Be careful.
There they go.
- See you.
- Fidel Castro?!
- He is not here.
He did not come home last night.
L'm Mirta Diaz-Balart.
- Have you talked to Mirta?
- L'm gonna see her today.
- You shouldn't be taking those risks.
- Yes.
You know your brother-in-law
is working for Batista?
Rafael?
He's in charge of
his youth organization.
Nothing will ever change here
without a revolution.
- You should join the Communist Party.
- Communist?
They're not interested in revolution.
They run away from action!
The only way to get rid of Batista,
and the only way to change things...
is to create a revolutionary army.
And I don't mean a few guys throwing
grenades at the government buildings.
I mean an army.
It 's the only way to stop the coups
and the corruption forever.
How else do we change things?
I need you. I need you
to do this with me.
What do you think?
Sir! Excuse me, sir.
My name is Abel.
Abel Santamaria.
I want to meet you since you jumped
on the car at the American Embassy.
There is a group of us.
Twenty of us...
planning to bring down Batista.
Will you meet with us?
What do you mean bring down?
By any means we can.
Good.
I believe that now is the time
we can do it.
But revolution means...
that we have to be prepared
to sacrifice everything.
Every one of us has to give up
his own private dreams and desires.
From this moment on
our only dream and desire...
is the liberation of Cuba.
Nothing else matters to us.
How old are you?
26? 28?
- 22.
- My God! 22!
Maybe you wonder if you will marry,
who will you marry...
or what it feels like
to be a mother.
Tonight you have to tear
all that out of your heart.
Pedro...
you want to grow old and see a long
line of sons and grandsons prosper?
Tonight, if you are with us...
the only legacy you'll leave, it's
the new Cuba we are going to create.
Is it worth the sacrifice
of our private dreams?
That is what each of us
have to decide right now.
In 30 seconds.
So?
Is everybody together?
Yes!
Fidel Castro.
So you finally needed me.
Good.
- Would you like some coffee?
- Yes, please.
My husband's at work.
Can you get pamphlets
and flyers published?
Yes, I have good contacts
with printers, of course.
And if the pamphlets called for
an armed insurrection?
- Is that the direction you're going?
- It 's the only direction.
So, if I gave you some
of my writings, can you...
0f course!
Thank you.
And you think you can
bring Batista down?
How?
I don't know...
yet.
You're taking a big risk if you're
going to call for armed insurrection.
If you do not take risks...
then nothing happens.
No.
Relax the shoulders, Faustino.
So we've got a communist
with us now!
That 's good!
You're just in time.
- How are you?
- Fine.
All right. Look. Where will Batista
expect an attack on his army?
- Camp Columbia, absolutely.
- Always Havana.
So we go to Santiago, here.
- Moncada.
- The barracks?
We attack the barracks at dawn,
the twenty-sixth of July.
Just in the middle of
Santiago Carnival.
I don't have much time.
L'm leaving for Santiago in an hour.
- Santiago? Why Santiago?
- To take the Moncada barracks.
My God.
- Is it possible?
- 0f course. We've everything planned.
The Manifesto.
Raul Gomez Garcia has written it.
Wonderful.
We attack the barracks at dawn.
You're the only person who knows it.
As soon as we are inside and
the fort is secure, we'll call you.
Then you release this manifesto to
the radio stations, newspapers...
- To everyone, of course.
- 0f course.
- Why Moncada?
- It has the armory...
and everything else we need. We can
protect the revolution from there...
and then it will sweep the country.
Everything is planned for
an attack at 5:15.
In 3 hours and 12 minutes.
This moment now is the start
of the beginning...
of the freedom of Cuba. And it 's
your destiny to be a part of it.
Today our movement will triumph.
Today and forever...
we will be setting an example
for the people of Cuba.
And from this day,
they'll pick up our banner...
and they'll move forward
to victory with us.
Get down!
Quiet!
Don't be afraid!
We are not going to hurt you.
Jesus!
Clear the gate.
The general is coming.
General?
Right now?
L'll do it.
How are you?
The armory's up there.
Go! Go! Go!
Armory!
Ready to shoot!
Fidel!
Go! Go!
Cease fire!
- Where are they?
- They left, went down the backstairs!
- Nobody went down that way.
- Will you please take your men out?
There are very sick people here.
She's lying.
This man is one of the leaders.
0ut of the bed.
0ut of the bed!
- No, you can't. He's very sick.
- 0ut of the bed!
You tell the officers in the barracks
they can do whatever they want...
with those prisoners.
Hurry! Move!
Haydee Santamaria?
I have something of
your brother's here.
Nineteen of my boys
died this morning.
They would be alive
at this moment...
had it not been for your brother.
L'll tell them to stop
torturing your brother...
if you tell me who else...
led this attack.
So?
Do you want us to take out
the other eye?
If you took out his eye and
he did not tell you anything...
do you think l'll tell you
anything now?
Then you have just
killed your brother.
Do you think it 's possible that they
have made it out of the hospital?
Fortunately, our brave forces under
the courageous General Chavlano...
fought off the cowardly assault
whlch we suspect was backed...
by forelgn or communlst plotters.
Thls was a ruthless and unprovoked
attack on ouryoung soldlers.
We do not know If any of the
murderous rebels came out allve.
Come out!
You are totally surrounded.
Were you in Santiago de Cuba
on the 26th of July?
Yes, I was.
Did you take part in the attack?
Yes, I did.
So you admit then that you sought
to bring about an uprising...
against the constitutional
powers of the State?
In what country is the
Honorable Prosecutor living?
The dictatorship that oppresses our
nation is not a constitutional power.
Your Honor, please ask the defendant
to restrict his replies...
to a direct answer to the question.
L'm answering the question
in the only way I can.
The legitimate constitution is that
which emanates directly...
from a sovereign people.
The half million farm workers
who live in absolute poverty...
the 400,000 people, whose retirement
funds have been embezzled...
by Batista's officials,
the children who die...
Do you ask him for how long
he has been unemployed?
Do you ask him how many
children he has?
Which days of the week he had food
to eat and which days he didn't?
...those who steal because
they are hungry.
But none of the men who steal
millions from the government...
has ever spent
one single night in jail.
I quote from a document precious
to the freedom...
of the United States of America...
'We hold these truths
to be self-evident...
That all men are created equal.
That they are all endowed
by their Creator...
with certain inalienable rights.
That among these are life...
liberty...
and the pursuit of happiness.
That, whenever
any form of government...
becomes destructive
to these ends...
it is the right of the people
to alter or abolish it...
and to create a new government.'
I don't fear prison.
Neither do I fear
those who have tortured...
and killed 70 of my comrades.
Condemn me.
It does not matter.
History will absolve me.
Fidel Castro, I sentence you
to fifteen years in prison.
Fifteen years?
Fifteen months, at the most.
'Everyday, I feel my bellef...
In sacrlflce and struggle
gettlng stronger.
I am not asklng for,
and I shall never ask for amnesty.
It's a great glft to us that Haydee
Santamarla's been released so soon.
Because thls Is ouropportunity to
make our Ideas known to the masses.
They're now llstenlng to us, because
they've seen the slaughterof men...
who dled flghtlng for
the freedom of all of us.'
Twenty-six of July,
Batista killed our comrades.
'Batlsta's blggest mlstake Is to
keepus allve and lmprlsoned.
Publlc oplnlon Is behlnd us
and it can only get stronger.'
- Every month we are...
- Batista? What is he doing here?
- Batista son-of-a-bitch!
- Dictator!
- Scum!
...offices, banks...
- Long llve the revolutlon!
- Captain.
Freed Cuba!
There you are.
'Though I now have llght and
I can read and write agaln...
I'll never forget the humlllatlon of
sittlng alone In the darkness...
not knowlng If it wlll be
for one month, one year...
one hundred years.
I klss all my books
and then countlng...
I see I have an extra klss.
With that klss...
I rememberyou,
my dearest Naty.'
'Dear Mlrta, I have seen
Fldelito's report card...
and I agree with you that he could
be performlng more strongly.'
Mirta is filing for a divorce.
And she's leaving the country
at the end of the week.
Where is she going?
United States.
With Fidelito?
- 0f course.
- She's taking him to United States?
- No, she's not.
- Fidel, she is...
No, she is not!
My son brought up in the U. S?
She can go where the hell she wants.
But Fidelito stays in Cuba!
The alllance...
between ourselves
and our partners...
the United States of Amerlca...
has never been so strong
and so beneflclal!
A trading partnership...
a social partnership...
and a mllitary partnershlp
that Is the envy...
of all the Islands of the Carlbbean.
Fidel! Fidel! Fidel!
Never in our history, has Cuba
been more economically healthy...
We should have killed him,
not captured him.
- Now we are stuck with him.
- The longer we keep him in prison...
the more popular he becomes.
If we drive him into exile, the CIA
will be able to help us control him...
and make sure
he never comes back.
0kay. You better let him go.
0ne more, Fidel.
Thank you.
Look here, Fidel!
We will continue the struggle for
the freedom of the people of Cuba.
The war against poverty and
despotism will continue.
The lives of many of our dear
friends have been sacrificed...
and must never be forgotten!
Every man here in front of you...
is prepared to lay down his life
for the freedom of Cuba!
And today I announce...
the founding of the
'Movement of Twenty-Six of July'...
dedicated to the men
whose blood was shed...
at the heroic assault on
The Moncada.
This is just the beginning!
- Batista has plans to assassinate me.
- I expect he has.
Raul has gone to Mexico.
And you are going too.
Yes, but I will be back.
I will train an army there.
- He should never have released you.
- It does not matter what he does.
He will lose, sooner or later.
Mexico is where
we prepare for victory.
Would you like me
to come with you?
- 0f course.
- You haven't asked.
0f course I would. Can you?
I didn't think that you...
That 's it. Come with me,
next week.
I cannot.
- Why?
- L'm pregnant.
And it 's your child.
- Cheers!
Maria is actually married to this
wonderful guy, Avelino.
He's a wrestler.
He's very good.
He has a friend who's also a
wrestler. His name is Vanegas Arroyo.
He's a wonderful man. He's sitting
right over there. He'd help us train.
But he's also a printer. Said that
he'd print for us anything we need.
- Good.
- Right now we have this cheap room...
at the downtown motel,
but it 's nice and it's clean.
- We can use it as long as we want.
- It 's the biggest screw-up in history.
Look at Batista.
He's the worst man for Cuba...
he's the dictator. In my country,
Argentina, it 's almost the same.
It 's so everywhere in Latin America.
The worst rise to the top always.
Because every dictator has one
thing in common: You, the Yankees.
Everything you do is done for
the profits of your companies.
- That 's why the Soviet Union is...
- Raul thinks the Soviet Union...
will be the savior of Latin America.
We have to create our own destiny.
Not alone, but together.
Everywhere in Latin America...
Guatemala, Venezuela,
Argentina, Chile, Cuba...
- Do you know Neruda?
- No.
'At the sound of the trumpet
everything was ready on Earth.
And Jehovah divided the world...
to Coca-Cola Incorporated,
Anaconda, Ford Motors.
But the juiciest slice of all was
kept for the United Fruit Company.'
- Who wrote it?
- Pablo Neruda.
- Why haven't I heard that before?
- Everything where we come from...
...is owned by United Fruit Company.
- I love that poem.
- My name is Fidel Castro.
- Ernesto Guevara.
Che! We just call him Che.
Welcome to Mexico.
I am here for one reason only.
To form a revolutionary army, to
train it and make it so disciplined...
that it cannot be defeated.
By the end of the next year,
l'll return to Cuba with my army...
l'll overthrow Batista's regime...
and announce the new revolutionary
government of Cuba.
That is what will happen.
I told you he was shy
and lacked confidence.
Every Cuban should know what we're
doing and support us. Every Cuban.
But I liked what you said before. Not
just Cubans, but every Latin American.
My revolution first, then yours.
0f course.
We'll land in 0riente, in an area
between Niquero, on the west coast...
and Pilon, on the south coast. There,
there are beaches along the coastline.
I have everything planned.
The tidal charts, the terrain.
The group on land coordinating
our arrival led by Celia Sanchez.
As soon as we are ashore, I take
my army to the Sierra Maestra...
where we engage guerrilla warfare.
All we need now is food,
money, clothes.
- Boats.
And a few boats!
And then, we will win.
0f course we will win.
It 's inevitable!
It looks like it 's been
underwater for thirty years.
It sunk in a hurricane
in fifty-three.
- Is this the best you can get?
- The best I can get for your money.
How long will it take
to get it seaworthy?
- Two months.
- Can that be seaworthy for open sea?
- How many people can it hold?
- You're taking it along the coast...
25 would be safe enough.
- We need a boat for a hundred.
- We're not gonna get anything bigger.
Two months is too long. It has
to be ready by the twenty-fifth.
L'll see what I can do.
We'll have ten safe houses,
ten men to each house.
Dlsclpllne wlll be ruthless.
No alcohol, no phone calls,
no vlsitors.
I guess l'm sleeping on the floor.
Alberto Bayo wlll
to all the world...
be a professorvlsitlng you
to glve you Engllsh lessons.
When In fact, he'll be tralnlng you
In guerrllla warfare.
He tralned the brlgades
In the Spanlsh ClvllWar.
Go!
And go!
Get in position. And go!
Come on!
Higher! Higher! Higher!
What are you doing?
- I can't.
- You have to keep going. Get up!
- These marches are too long!
- Come on, get up!
Get off of me! L'm warning you!
If you don't get up right now, you'll
be arrested for insubordination...
and court martialed.
No.
Everybody, back to camp!
Discipline is everything.
The revolution cannot triumph
without absolute discipline.
We must show an example
to the others.
- Bayo teaches this all the time!
- Yes, I do.
- Lf Che can march with asthma...
- It 's not good politics to shoot him!
Politics?
We have to shoot him.
If we show the others that...
we are weak in our determination,
then we'll fail for sure.
0f course there has
to be discipline.
That is why everyday
I force it into their brains...
and why his actions
cannot be tolerated.
But you'll have another bigger
problem if you shoot him.
- What if the police finds the body?
- L'm an honest man...
Then we make sure that
they don't find the body!
You can't be sure. The suspicion
of murder will be enough.
...and, before I die, I want...
- I say we execute him.
A revolutionary brigade cannot
survive with such people within it.
- So you agree we should execute him?
- 0r he might turn against us.
And the revolution and our lives
may be lost. There's much to lose.
So I say yes.
L'll work 20 hours a day.
L'll do every chore in the camp.
L'll do the work of all the soldiers,
so that they are free to train.
But please...
I beg of you...
let me fight for
the freedom of Cuba.
You are lucky to be alive.
I would have shot you myself.
But maybe now, you'll have
the chance to prove yourself.
Thank you, Fidel.
Thank you.
We cannot take any more men, Fidel.
That 's 82, including us.
That 's already far,
far too many.
I cannot sail with this boat if you
put even one more man onboard.
Stop there!
We'll arrive at the Colorada beach,
near Belic, in five days.
At dawn, on November thirtieth.
An armed unit of the underground...
led by Celia Sanchez
will meet us at the landing point...
and guide us into the mountains.
Long live the Revolution!
Yes!
Celia?
They left.
All the safe houses are empty.
He has left Mexico.
- Have you informed the Air Force?
- Yes.
Also reinforce
the Santiago garrison...
and have them put on alert.
Good.
I think that should be enough.
- We are sinking!
- Start bailing out.
Use anything you can
find down there!
- Take this.
- Faster!
Hurry!
They have probably seen Batista's
planes patrolling off the coastline.
What has happened to you?
These bandages?
L've had them for years.
For what?
My bones.
My bones are too weak.
It 's a deformity
from my childhood.
That 's why I couldn't go on marching
in the mountains. It hurt too much.
Why didn't you tell us?
Because you wouldn't let me on the
boat if you knew I wasn't fit enough.
0ur position is wrong.
If those buoys are right,
we are not heading for the beach.
So where are we heading?
I don't know.
Let 's call it off.
Come on.
What was that?
This is it.
We have landed.
Landed? This is a shipwreck.
Carry only your personal weapons.
Everything else must be left here.
All right.
To the cane fields!
Let 's move to the cane fields!
To the cane fields
to regroup there!
- Good morning.
- Good morning, sir.
The forces of the Cuban people...
under the command of
General Pedro Avila...
have today annihilated
the expeditionary force...
of the so-called
'Twenty-Six of July Movement'...
alongwith its chlef,
Fldel Castro,3O years old.
Many of the bodles of the other
rebels have also been found...
Includlng that of
Fldel Castro's brother, Raul.
Thelr bodles wlll now
be returned to Havana.
It 's still 20 miles to the mountains.
We can rest here...
until nightfall. When we get to
the mountains, we will be safe.
The revolution will be safe.
We are going to win!
Batlsta Is lylng. I saw the attack
from the mountalns.
I know that some of them got
away to the cane flelds.
- Fidel?
- He's not one of the men I saw shot.
- Is everybody searching for them?
- Everyone.
But Batista's soldiers
are all over the hills.
It 's a question of
who finds them first.
My name is Alejandro.
Do you have any food I can buy?
Fidel?
My son is Guillermo Garcia...
under the command
of Celia Sanchez.
We have been all looking for you,
and praying that you have survived.
Carrying food with us,
hoping to find you.
Go! Tell Guillermo
that Fidel Castro is here.
Come.
He's in the mountains
searching for you.
How many are you?
Three.
Guillermo Garcia.
Universo. Faustino.
Guillermo.
What 's for dinner?
Calixto!
Candido!
- Commander.
- Big boy!
People support you because there's no
way out for us without the revolution.
We have no doctors, no schools,
no medicine, no rights. Nothing.
All these men are willing
to join your army.
Thank you.
Thank you all.
- Good to see you.
- You're good?
How many rifles do you have?
Didn't I tell you?
His first words.
Five.
We have two.
Now we will win the war!
Long live the revolution!
Long live Fidel!
We need to mount an attack.
We need a victory.
0therwise, who will believe
we are an army?
Most important of all...
we need to show the people
what we are fighting for.
Are there any land overseers
in this area? Do you know them?
I know their names.
Everyone does.
There are three of them who
have terrorized us for years.
We should execute them.
Then the people will believe we are
fighting for them, not for ourselves.
Chucho 0sorio is one of
the land overseers.
The worst of the three.
He may not look llke it, but he has
terrorlzed every peasant In thls area.
Stolen from them,
beaten them...
and kllled.
Frlday afternoon, he drlnks with the
soldlers In the barracks at La Plata.
Stop there!
Colonel Gomez,
from the Royal Guard.
- Colonel? Yes, sir.
- We're looking for...
the leader of the rebel army.
- Fidel Castro.
- Castro?
- Have you heard anything?
- No, not him. He's dead.
Dead? Where?
That 's when I meet him.
0thers I have found, yes.
- Who have you found?
- Who have I found?
- The rebels you've found, name them.
- Yes, well...
...one actually. 0ne I have found!
- L'm Colonel Gomez, Royal Guard.
- Tell me his name now.
- I remember his name...
No, I don't.
I don't know his name.
- But we took his head off.
- All right.
- Get off your mule. Tie his hands.
- What?
Listen! Listen!
You are going to stay here.
And when you're sober, you're going
to tell us the layout of the barracks.
Where they sleep, where they eat,
where they keep watch. Everything.
And maybe, perhaps when
you're sober, you'll remember...
what you just said
to Fidel Castro!
- Take everything out!
- Hands up!
Stop firing!
Hold your fire!
What are we going
to do with them?
Let them go.
- Why don't we kill them?
- Why? They are not our enemies.
Let them go.
Che, give them your medicine bag.
- Let them go look after their injured.
- No. We need those medicines.
Not now, we don't.
We have no casualties.
Give them the medicine and let
them go. That 's how we're doing it.
- Fidel, you can't...
- That 's the way we're doing it.
- You are free to go.
- Thank you.
Now tell them to kill him.
Then we can go.
Shoot him.
Norma, this is Alejandro.
Do you copy? 0ver.
That 's an army truck.
Heading for the garrison of Bayamo.
Shoot the driver.
- Good.
- Alejandro, thls Is Norma.
Fidel, we made contact
with Celia.
- This is Alejandro hearing you. 0ver.
- How are you?
It's wonderful to hearyourvolce. We
are excited to make contact with you.
- At last l've the chance to thank you.
- We're so pleased that you are allve.
I've a message to flnd you a reporter.
What klnd of reporter? Over.
I want everybody in Cuba
to know l'm not dead.
That our army is secure in the
mountains. More than secure.
Invincible. So can you
organize the reporter?
Who is the most famous reporter
in the United States? 0ver.
The best foryou Is Herbert Matthews.
He's with the 'New York Tlmes'.
He covered the
Spanlsh ClvllWar. Over.
Are you a journalist, Mr. Matthews?
L'm a business man.
L'm taking a look at the sugar
refinery l'm thinking of buying.
No journalists are allowed east of
Santa Clara. Step out of the vehicle.
Stay there.
We are from the Matanza
Sugar Association.
When this American gentleman
goes back to New York to report...
that the political climate in Cuba is
unhealthy for foreign investment...
l'll make sure your superiors find out
that was you who taught him that.
Now, please let me get passed before
I report these matters to Havana.
And this gentleman from the New York
Times, are we keeping him waiting?
Yes.
Good.
Keep him waiting a little longer.
Make it more exciting for him.
Go to Matthews.
Tell him to come for the night.
Invent a raid from Batista's forces
which we have successfully repelled.
- And give him some shooting tonight.
- Lf you give him too many stories...
...he's not gonna write it down...
- None of it is untrue.
It 's just not true yet.
Let him write, we have the mastery
of the Sierra Maestra.
- Mister Matthews?
- Yes.
Universo Sanchez.
- The commandant is arriving.
- Thank you.
Welcome to the Sierra Maestra.
- L'm sorry you had to wait.
- Not at all.
Today the revolution
is in the mountains...
tomorrow it will be in the cities.
When the people of Havana...
and Santiago learn that
we have defeated Batista here...
they'll know that we will
defeat him everywhere.
You truly believe you can
defeat him here?
0f course. 0f course
we will defeat him here.
It was announced, it was
the day I flew into Havana...
that Batista had taken delivery
of sixteen B-26 bombers.
Yes, from your country.
- The forces available to him...
- We're expecting...
a massive aerial attack
against us at any moment.
As you can see, it 's impossible for
them to find us in these mountains.
The only way that they can logisticaly
defeat us is from the ground.
But how can they do this
if they don't know the ground?
And we know every inch of it.
We shall come down
from these mountains...
as a new revolutionary
government of Cuba.
And...
good.
And we know every inch of it.
We shall come down
from these mountains...
as a new revolutionary
government of Cuba.
And...
good.
I take it.
Good.
0ne more.
Excellent.
Good.
- Excuse me.
- Mr. Matthews, he's ready.
So you are Celia Sanchez.
Your organization
is very efficient.
- You don't seem to be betrayed.
- We have a very loyal unit.
Good. There are only 18 of us here.
0ne betrayal...
then one attack from Batista,
and we are finished.
- We need to recruit.
- We're already training soldiers...
in the cities in 0riente.
They'll be ready to join you soon.
As for weapons and ammunition,
Faustino will get supplies in Havana.
What else do you need?
Cigars.
The movement must never
listen to the communists.
The revolution is here.
The heart is here.
No, it is not.
Not yet.
You have to make it here.
That is what l'm telling you.
How can you have a perspective of
what goes on beyond the mountains?
It 's impossible.
What you need is someone
you can trust...
who can be here and who can
travel through the cities.
Someone who can
keep you in touch.
You eyes and your ears
in the cities.
Then your judgements and planning
will be right there as well as here.
And then the heart of the
revolution will be here.
'Fldel Castro, the rebel leader
of Cuba's youth...
Is allve and flghtlng hard
and successfully...
In the rugged, almost lmpenetrable
fastness of the Slerra Maestra.'
'Presldent Batlsta has the cream
of hls army around the area.'
'Thousands of men and women
are heart and soul with Fidel Castro.
Throughout Cuba, unemployment
is high, corruption is rife.
Castro and his
Twenty-Six of July Movement...
is the flaming symbol of
the opposition to the regime.'
'It is a revolutionary movement
that calls itself socialistic...
offering a new deal to Cuba:
Radical, democratic...
...and therefore, anticommunist.'
- Unbelievable.
'The personality of the man
is overpowering.'
Comrade!
'It was easy to see that his men
adored him and also to see...
why he has got the imagination of
the youth of Cuba all over the island.
He was an educated,
dedicated fanatic...
a man of ideals, of courage and of
remarkable qualities of leadership.'
'He has the mastery of
the Sierra Maestra.'
'He has the mastery
of the Sierra Maestra.'
Another.
Here!
Look! Look!
Dance! Dance!
Come dance.
The ammunition.
It 's very simple!
We need anti-aircraft weapons!
Where do we get
anti-aircraft weapons?
The president of Costa Rica
offered us guns. We can go to him.
- How do we get their weapons here?
- I have a friend.
He's a memberof our movement.
He has done a lot of work for us.
He's a rlce planter and has a pllot
llcense, so he could fly the arms...
Into hls farm.
I know he wlll do...
as he wlll do anythlng
forthe movement.
Hls name Is Huber Matos.
When Celia came to me with the news
that you had attacked the Moncada...
I heard your name for the
first time. And I said to her...
'Today democracy was reborn in
Cuba. And its name is Fidel Castro.'
Today its name is Huber Matos.
And the voice of Fidel Castro
coming to you...
from the heart of
the Sierra Maestra...
in the first free territory
of the Americas.
We are an army that
wlll not be defeated.
From thls moment,
the country...
should consider itself in total war
against the dictatorship.
The entire nation is determined...
to be free...
or to perish!
To counterattack, Raul,
you'll take 65 men...
and defend Sierra Cristal.
Camilo, you will take 50 men, and
attack Batista here, at Bayamo.
Huber, you'll command troops
protecting the head-quarters.
Che, you'll take charge
of the central zone.
0ne small victory after one
small victory, again and again...
and they wlll not have
the stomach to flght on...
whereas we,
we wlll flght to the death.
Surrender!
We're the Cuban people! You are the
dictatorship! You could be on our side.
You think you deserve to live?
You! Do you deserve to live?
A thousand soldiers have died
attacking the liberators of Cuba.
How many more llves must be lost
before Batlsta surrenders...
to the wlll of Cuba?
Must he lose
ten thousand soldlers...
before he submits to the inevitable
victory of the revolution?
Hold your fire.
Nobody move!
They don't listen.
Today, troops led by
Camllo Clenfuegos...
after a slxweek herolc march...
through the provlnces of
Orlente and Camaguey...
marched vlctorlously Into
the provlnce of Las Vlllas.
Everywhere, soldlers
of Batlsta's army...
are now jolnlng and flghtlng
with the revolutlon.
Dellverlng the flnal blow
to Batlsta's forces...
troops led by Che Guevara
have captured and destroyed...
an armored supply traln
and now march trlumphantly...
Into the city of Santa Clara...
today.
And they are now advanclng
trlumphantly on Santlago.
The trlumphant
revolutlonary forces...
now have the support of the
land owners, businessmen...
and industrialists of 0riente.
This is the voice of
Radio Rebelde...
and the victorious army
of the revolution.
0ur proposal is for a junta
led by General Cantillo...
to whom you'll formerly hand over the
government before your departure.
The junta will receive every military
and financial assistance from the CIA.
That will at least save us
and Cuba from Castro.
To the United States backed
junta of General Cantillo...
the revolutionary forces of Cuba
order you to surrender.
If there is no surrender
by six o'clock today...
this evening,
you will be attacked.
Revolution, yes!
Military coup, no!
In our view, a military coup
is now unsustainable.
We can no longer give you
our support.
Either publicly or clandestinely.
Batista has left the country!
Long live Cuba!
Freed Cuba!
Fidel! Fidel!
How are you?
- How are you?
- Fine!
I need you to stay here.
To secure Santiago.
- Are you flying to Havana?
- I will march there!
The war is not over!
The war has not even begun.
Now we launch our greatest
offenslve agalnst corruptlon...
illiteracy, disease, hunger,
exploitation, injustice!
This is a revolution for schools,
for teachers...
for hospitals, for doctors!
This is a revolution for the people!
Fidel! Fidel!
Neither capitalism, nor socialism!
But revolutionary humanism!
A revolution as Cuban
as the palms...
not a red revolution.
But an olive green revolution.
A democratic revolution
of the poor and for the poor.
Fidel! Fidel!
Cuba freed forever!
Freed Cuba!
Long live Fidel!
The country or death!
Any chance a hungry soldier could
get a steak and some grilled onions?
This is good.
This is very, very good!
- He liked?
- Yes.
Thank you.
So...
what can we do first?
Do you think we should
cut your rents in half?
What else?
Tell me.
What do you want from me?
Well...
How are you?
- You can't sit there.
- That 's where Che is sitting.
- Could we get some coffee?
- The coffee is coming.
All right, let 's sit down.
First law of the new revolutionary
government of Cuba:
Every Cuban male must wear a beard.
Do we need to take a vote?
Look, telegrams.
All from foreign companies.
Wanting to know if their investments
and contracts are safe.
They will have to wait.
Because in this revolution,
we'll always go to the people first.
That is our first law.
And we'll tell them what we're
intending to do and we'll ask them...
'Is this what you want?'
A true people's democracy. That is
how Cuba is to be governed now.
We have a meeting this afternoon with
the directors of the National Bank.
They want to know
who they'll be meeting.
- Who is a good economist?
- Che!
- Give it to Che.
- I don't know anything about banking.
L'm sorry. I thought you said
who is a good communist.
If we can't give them a good
economist, we give a good communist.
Absolutely.
Che, you do it.
Introduce yourself as the new
president of the National Bank.
You certainly look a good
People of Cuba...
as from today, the rents from your
landlords will be cut in half.
Under the Law of
Agrarian Reform...
no land owner will ever
again evict you...
from the land you have worked
with your own hands.
No longerwlll the exploiters
and forelgners In ourcountry...
Ilve of the sweat and sufferlng
of the people.
We'll bulld 1O thousand classrooms,
and we'll traln 1O thousand teachers.
Under Batlsta,4O% of Cuba
could not read orwrite.
Under Fldel Castro,
everyone wlll read and write.
We wlll traln
1O thousand more doctors.
Free medlcal care wlll be a
guaranteed rlght of every Cuban.
Students In the city wlll teach
the workers In the country.
And In the flelds, an army of urban
workers wlll joln the peasants...
Implantlng a rlng of coffee
plantatlons around Havana.
Withln 1O years, we wlll rlval
Mexlco In coffee productlon.
What about elections?
- What about elections, Huber?
- That 's the question l'm being asked.
Why are you bringing
this up now?
Because we promised
to return democracy to Cuba...
when we were fighting
in the Sierra.
We are here in government
because we promised...
to build the people hospitals and
schools, because we promised...
to give the land back to them.
And that is what we are doing now.
We must keep that promise
to the people first.
What is more democratic
than that?
- The revolution first!
- But we also promised elections.
We'll keep our promise. We'll always
keep our promises to the people.
- Next item?
- We have the names of men...
responsible for carrying out Batista's
political murders. What will we do?
We'll set up tribunals and
put them on trial immediately.
And we execute them.
Anyone who resists us.
Again, this is the first task of the
revolution, to keep the revolution.
If we don't get rid of our opponents,
they'll come back and kill us.
- Che is right.
- So we must kill them first.
It 's the only course of action.
I have a question for you,
people of Cuba...
should I be commander in chief
of the armed forces?
Should the armed forces be the armed
forces for and of the revolution?
Should we put those who are
against the revolution...
on trial for their lives?
Raise your hand if you agree that
Batista's murdering henchmen...
must be executed!
The jury of one million
has voted.
- How are you?
- Nice to see you.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
We are the government and
we still have to meet illegally.
This meeting is absolutely
off the record.
Any mention of it to anyone
outside this room...
will have serious consequences.
You all understand this?
Good.
Because I invited you here
as our comrades.
As comrades of the revolution.
The question that l'm asking is...
how do we now transform Cuba...
into a marxist-leninist society?
That is my question.
And that is our task in the years
ahead. That is the future of Cuba.
Which will secure the revolution
for generations to come.
Nationalization of all industry.
The creation of State farms...
and the abolition of
the private enterprise.
Your task is to turn policy
into practice.
But let me make it very clear
for you now...
if you,
as the Communist Party...
wish to play a roll
in the future of Cuba...
the new communist state
will be under my control.
We will not reform under you...
but you will reform under me.
Cuba marchlng trlumphantly on.
One bllllon dollars...
of Yankee owned property has
now been returned to the people.
The program of natlonallzatlon
Is almost complete.
Our beloved Fldel has announced
that all oll reflnerles...
wlll be ceased by the
Revolutlonary Councll...
and put Into publlc ownershlp.
With our sugar plantatlons,
our mllls, our farms...
our mlnes, our utllitles,
our factorles...
and now, our reflnerles
In the control of the revolutlon...
Cuba's destlny
Is In ourown hands!
This is the outline of the classes
of the revolutionary instructions.
0nly the recruits have to attend.
'Party construction.
Ideological struggle.
Scientific Marxism.
And atheism.'
This is Stalin.
I cannot teach my recruits
all this.
I have to do something.
Say something.
What is the worse that can happen?
I will have to resign.
And then what?
I will be cutting sugarcane
for the rest of my life.
I do not want to become
an obstacle to the revolutlon.
But I belleve that If I'm forced to
choose between followlng Into llne...
orwithdrawlng for my rulers governor
of the provlnce of Camaguey...
not to do harm, the most honorable
and revolutlonary actlon for me...
Is to leave.
I know I have the support of
my offlcers In writlng thls to you.
It seems rlght for me
to polnt out...
that greater men become smaller
when they start to be unjust.
Please, ln the name of
our fallen comrades...
In the name of our people, Fldel,
do not bury the revolutlon.
Iwrite you not as
major Huber Matos.
But as your long tlme frlend.
What is he plotting?
- A rebellion against us?
- He doesn't say that in the letter.
If there is an officer rebellion in
Camaguey, that 's just what the CIA...
All he's saying is he's wanting
to resign. To go quietly.
Resignation itself
is a betrayal of the revolution.
He worked tirelessly for me
when you were in Mexico.
And all through the Sierra.
He couldn't have done more for the
revolution. He's been the most loyal.
But he is not loyal now!
Call Camilo.
Tell him to go to Camaguey
to take command of the forces there.
And put Huber Matos
under arrest.
Go and get your mother.
- Brother.
- Camilo.
Come on in.
This way.
Apart from my orders to arrest you,
15 of your officers must be arrested.
My officers? Why?
Because they have also resigned.
Resigning is not an offense for
which people should be arrested.
Don't you think that?
Camilo, don't you?
There's a lot counter-revolutionary
activity going on in the country.
- A lot of plotting against...
- He's just resigning, Camilo.
That 's all he's doing.
As far as I know, there isn't
even a plan for a trial.
A trial for resigning?
I hope not.
- Then why are you arresting him?
- Fidel's orders.
- Any type of criticism...
- It was a private letter to a friend.
A comrade.
I have no intention
in publishing this letter.
And neither should he.
'You rose up magnificently...
and fought in the name of
reason and justice.
But now I fear,
that if you take this path...
you will be destroying
your own work.
You will be burying
the revolution.'
We have a clear and absolute
policy on acts of betrayal.
We cannot kill him as if he was
one of Batista's executioners!
Why don't we just let him
resign and go quietly?
- He betrayed Fidel and the revolution.
- I dare he won't go quietly!
He'll go to Miami,
then what will he do?!
The CIA will give him and his family
whatever he wants...
and he'll return, this time
with more arms against us.
Don't be stupid! No revolution has
succeeded without absolute discipline.
What do you think, Celia?
He's been a friend of yours for years,
you introduced him to the revolution.
He's a sincere and honest man.
- That is not relevant.
- However, Raul...
Che is right. Any dissent
of the revolution is a threat.
But we all know Huber Matos.
He would have given
his life for you, Fidel.
You must remember when
there was just three of us.
Before the Moncada,
before anything...
you said, 'The revolution
will not devour its children'.
Now what are we doing?
Are we any different from Batista?
Either Matos is a traitor or Fidel's
a liar. Are you calling Fidel a liar?
Marti taught us, 'The first duty of
each man is to think for himself'.
Are we against Marti as well? Huber
has the right to think for himself.
We're all followers of Marti.
We ought to disagree with that?
The duty of
a true revolutionary...
is first of all
be loyal to the revolution.
If Huber renounces the revolution,
he may let in the forces to destroy it.
If the revolution dies before
its first birthday...
what did your brother
give his life for?
Che is right.
While we are building hospitals...
and tralnlng doctors,
so that every person In Cuba...
wlll have the best
medlcal care In the world...
Major Huber Matos and 15 offlcers
under hls command...
were consplrlng agalnst us.
We cannot tolerate consplrators
agalnst the revolutlon.
We cannot tolerate conspirators
against the revolution.
Traitors of Cuba, destroying
the morale of the Army!
Threatening all our programs
for schools and hospitals.
So I ask you, people of Cuba!
Defenders of the revolution.
I come back to you,
to ask you the question...
what shall we do with those
who betray the revolution?
Should we put them to death?
We will defend the revolution!
At all costs, we will
defend the revolution!
Now you can show magnanimity.
If you save his life,
people will love you for that too.
If we kill him...
no matter how secretly we bury him,
somebody will find the grave...
then light candles there, and
make it a shrine to his memory.
Don't make martyrs
for another revolution.
I consider myself
neither a traitor...
nor a deserter.
My conscience is clear.
If this court should
find me guilty...
I shall accept its decision,
even though I might be shot.
I would...
consider it one more service...
for the revolution.
This court...
finds the accused...
guilty of high crimes of
treason and conspiracy...
and sentences him to 20 years.
It has been
a very dlfflcult tlme...
for all of us.
Foryou...
and for me, personally.
But...
from thls bitter and
dlfflcult ordeal...
the revolutlon
has emerged vlctorlously.
In every vlllage, ln every street,
In every city...
we wlll create committees
forthe defense of the revolutlon!
There wlll be no place
forcounter-revolutlonarles...
to hlde In Cuba!
Why should life in Cuba be
any different for writers...
artists, movie directors
and poets...
than it is for soldiers, bus drivers,
waiters and miners?
What use is an article about
American beatniks to the revolution?
That was the last publication.
Artists, from now on, will have
the freedom to create art...
for the masses. Everyone sacrifices
themselves for the revolution.
There's a journalist here
from Moscow wants to see you.
Not another one!
We've just dismissed 50!
This is not just any journalist.
He's very close to Kruchev.
A gift from the people
from the Soviet Union.
Thank you.
And also, from Premier Kruchev...
who has personally watched
the direction of your revolution...
with great interest
and admiration.
I have instructions of
Deputy Premier Anastas Mikoyan...
to discuss with you
the possibility of presenting...
a Soviet trade fair in Havana.
Maybe we should try
the vodka and caviar first.
Yes, I think it will be
very interesting for us.
As the first step perhaps,
for diplomatic relations.
Let us first agree
to the trade fair.
To introduce a new policy,
first you go to the people.
Explain it to them,
and then seek their approval.
That sounds like
a very good policy.
Lenin.
0f course.
This is good.
This is very, very good.
Cuba, yes! Yankees, no!
We must expect the savage blow of
the imperialist fury at every moment.
We face an invasion of the parasites
who left our beloved country.
An invasion paid for
by a country...
that insists on its own
sovereign rights...
and will take their arms against us,
because we insist on ours.
This will not, and cannot
be tolerated.
We will defend this revolution
of the humble...
by the humble and for the humble,
to the last drop of our blood!
We shall be victorious!
The country or death!
Cuba, yes!
Yankees, no!
...we used agalnst them weren't very
effectlve, therefore we were not...
the brlgade was not able to
malntaln alr supremacy on the beach.
The operatlon was a fallure...
and the responslbllity
rests with the White House.
I have just spoken to Kruchev.
The Soviets have information that
the Yankees plan a direct invasion.
We discussed strengthening
our armed forces...
Soviet military advisers
and weaponry in Cuba.
So, what 's he offering?
Strategic nuclear weapons.
Withln the past week, unmlstakable
evldence has establlshed the fact...
that a serles of offenslve
mlsslle slghts...
Is now In preparatlon
on that lmprlsoned Island.
We'll not be prematurely
or unnecessarlly...
rlsk the course of
a worldwlde nuclearwar...
In whlch even the fruits of vlctory
would be ashes In our mouths.
But neitherwlllwe shrlnk from that
rlsk at any tlme it must be faced.
Whatever Kennedy says, whatever
he decides for his country...
we do not stand down from the
principle that we have the right to...
determine what we do in our country.
Whatever Kennedy says or does.
I will sit down with this guy and
talk about anything he wants.
He seems like a nice guy.
I think we can work things out
with this president.
But we will not be told what
we can do in our own territory.
We've just picked this announcement
Kruchev has made in Moscow.
'In order to save the world
from nuclear catastrophe...
we have given an order to dismantle
the arms in Cuban territory...
and to return them
to the Soviet Union.'
Kruchev?!
- It has to be US propaganda!
- No, I had it personally.
Get him on the phone immediately!
Why wasn't I informed by Kruchev?
- What time was this broadcast?
- Eight o'clock, Moscow time.
I had no communication with
Moscow for the last 3 days.
They're our allies. It was an
agreement between me and Kruchev!
Here is the rest of the announcement,
'In return we accept the US promise...
that they will never again attack
the sovereign territory of Cuba...
or sponsor any attack on the
sovereign territory of Cuba.'
- That has to be a victory for us!
- How can it be a victory...
when we were not even part of the
negotiations? Turn on the television!
- Proves the Soviets stand behind us!
- By standing down to Kennedy?
It only proves the Soviets will not
risk to attack imperialism anywhere.
And I wasn't even consulted.
These weapons are on our territory.
And they are deciding themselves
if they keep them here...
or take them away
without talking to me?!
This is only a victory
for the United States, Fidel.
Kruchev will now want
to make amends.
We can take advantage
of that, Fidel.
We can get the industrial
plants we need.
We can get the loans we need,
we can get the conventional weapons.
We can make it with the Soviets,
so that we never again...
have to rely on
the Yankee dollar.
Why is sugar cane production
down again?
We have had so many volunteers
working in the fields.
We have all been in the fields.
- There have been problems.
- What problems?
- The transition from private to state.
- Why? Why should there be problems?
They're all getting the same money.
Why work harder than the next man?
Who is saying that?
- That 's what they are telling us.
- Who?
- The workers in the field.
- Give me names!
- I cannot give you names.
- Are you saying...
that we will not
sustain the revolution...
if the people have
no material gain from it?
Their ideology is not being taught
correctly. They have to develop...
...a communist consciousness.
- They've been taught it.
But the Cuban likes to
look at the skies and dream.
- No Cuban I know.
- Why is milk production down?
That 's because we told everyone to
concentrate in sugar production.
- And everything else has gone down.
- So it is my fault...
for asking the people to put all
their efforts in the cane fields?
In my view we're not planning
the economy properly.
Something goes wrong here
and we all run to fix it.
Something else goes wrong there
and we all run to fix it there.
We are not using foresight and
developing long-term strategies.
What about coffee production?
- The land was not suitable for it.
- Who says that?
I brought in experts
to advise us and help...
We don't need advisors!
To tell me l'm wrong?!
The economy is failing...
because we are not inspiring the
people to work for the revolution.
All of Cuba has to be
a guerilla army now!
They have to understand
that work for the revolution...
is a moral imperative.
Then, the harvest will be up.
Then, everything will grow.
You and your agricultural
committee are dismissed.
- But you are using...
- 0ur dialogue is over!
Maybe we can ask
the Soviets for a loan.
No, no. The Soviets
are part of the problem.
Their machinery doesn't work,
their spare parts never arrive...
and you're developing a mentality of
waiting for them to provide for us.
Cuba has to break free
from all imperialism.
- Russian as well as Yankee.
- How can we break away...
from the Soviets when we do
all of our trading with them?
The answer is to put more
volunteers in the fields...
plant more coffee seeds,
and develop better cows.
And we must not allow
counter-revolutionary ideology...
to infiltrate the planning
of the economy.
Arrest him for betraying
the revolution.
His ideology is destructive to
the people he is here to serve.
The history of imperialism
has been the history...
of the exploitation of trade
between the poorer, African...
Aslan and Latln Amerlcan natlons...
and the lmperlallsts.
Soclallsm exlsts to put an end
to that exploitatlon.
By uslng our poorcountrles
as a source of cheap labor...
the masters of the Kremlln have
become accompllces of lmperlallsm!
Why is this Argentine idiot making
statements on behalf of our country?
What are you going to do? He'll ruin
our relationship with the Russians.
Then who will we sell our sugar to?
We'll have no money, no economy...
and once again the Yankees
will be out to destroy us.
Yes.
- Alexeiev.
- He can go to hell.
He won't be able to answer the
phone now. Just make a note for me.
Che has our total support.
Well, he doesn't have mine.
The Soviets are furious with us.
- But wasn't I telling the truth?
- Telling the truth is not politics.
You do not tell your
wife everything...
you do not tell your
children everything...
friends everything.
And you do not tell your
allies everything.
L'm resigning from the
government, Fidel.
If the Soviets are furious with me,
then you must get rid of me.
You know what my answer
to that would be.
But still, l'm resigning
from the government.
And l'm resigning my citizenship.
L've made my decision long ago.
There's nothing left for me to do here.
Revolution is fomenting
in Peru, Guatemala...
in Argentina.
In Africa, in Congo, Angola.
In Latin America...
we need our independence.
And it won't be won
with the Russians.
It will be won by fighting for
socialism ourselves. So l'm...
l'm going back to the mountains.
Back to fighting.
We want to start the war...
in any country, any country
in Latin America.
If I trained the guerilla force here
just as you did in Mexico...
and took them up to the mountains
and create the guerilla war...
then this war will inevitably spread
out to the neighboring countries...
creating the revolutionary conditions
in those countries as well.
This will bring down the Yankees...
and they would never,
Fidel, never...
be able to contain several guerilla
movements in neighboring countries.
It will become worse
than Vietnam for them.
Just one spark...
in one guerilla movement...
in one mountain range...
and the whole thing just...
If anyone knows it can be done...
Where?
Where would you go?
To Bolivia.
You could go to Bolivia.
From Bolivia,
you could go to Peru.
To Chile...
to Argentina.
First my revolution.
Then yours.
L'll talk with the communists in
Bolivia. With my friend, Mario Monje.
We'll lay the groundwork for you.
You pick the best fighting men.
And train them here.
I will give you everything
you need.
We'll just have to
fight our way out.
- Let 's go to the city?
- Sure.
No good to Cuba...
no good to us...
and worst of all for you...
no good to the Soviets.
There is a training book
at the CIA...
that we use to track down
guerilla units.
It 's your book.
'A guerilla movement
cannot be successful...
without the support
of the peasants.'
Good advice.
And you had the support
of nobody.
Come on.
Shoot me.
You are only going to kill a man.
Turn the head, please.
Excuse me.
Ramiro says the CIA
had him killed.
Ramiro would be right.
But I told him...
I told him he would be safe.
I told him...
I would lay the
groundwork for him.
He trusted me to do that.
It was the Bolivian Communist Party
who let him down, not you.
It was they who abandoned
their support for him.
Che would not have trusted them.
But he trusted me.
He trusted me to get that right.
- Comrade Fidel, how are you?
- How are you? All right?
How are you? My comrade.
Two hours and 40 minutes.
55 minutes.
0ne hour and 20 minutes.
Four hours and 55 minutes
standing in line...
and that 's all
I could find to buy.
This will soon stop.
- Soon we'll have enough food...
- No steak and no onions.
To pay the education of your
grandchildren, to pay doctors...
I know, I know!
Sacrifices have to be made.
Fidel, don't you remember me?
I remember you.
- Don't you remember me?
- Yes, I remember you.
In the kitchen of Havana Libre.
The best meal of my life!
The best meal of my life...
3 o'clock in the morning,
when we entered Havana!
Every night since then
I have prayed for the revolution.
For 10 years, every night.
And every morning I wake up
and things are worse.
My grandson works on the docks.
Today they loaded
the whole boat...
with can milk for Vietnam.
We don't want our money spent on
revolutions in Africa and in Asia.
We need the food now, here.
Don't interrupt me when l'm talking.
Ten years ago you asked us
what you could do for us.
Well... you can listen to us now.
We want to be free to trade
among ourselves...
and to be able to complain about
the good-for-nothing party managers.
- Without being thrown into prison.
- But you are free to complain.
What am I gonna do now?
Arrest you?
And am I not listening to you now?
Celia.
The problem is that we are not
working together, as a people.
What we need to do is work more for
the revolution and not for ourselves.
What we need is more sacrifices.
We promised that we'd have milk for
everyone by the end of this year.
- These results are worse than ever.
- Why don't the cows produce enough?
Because the crossbreeding program
has not given the result we hoped for.
Nothing to do with it.
I set this program up myself.
And this cow is the best
milk producer in the world.
In theory, yes.
But because of the climate...
- Are you blaming the cow?
- No. 0f course not.
It 's a wonderful program you have
devised for us. What l'm trying to...
There is nothing wrong
with the cow!
Our revolutlon...
is not a revolution of the bourgeoisie!
0ur revolution is
a revolution of communists.
Nobody shed his blood here
fighting against the tyranny...
fighting against the imperialists,
against bandits and bankers...
in order to study the right of
somebody to make 50 pesos...
selllng hotdogs and frled eggs.
58,O12 buslnesses In Cuba
are stlll prlvately owned.
Today I announce the great
revolutlonary offenslve...
the entlre ellmlnatlon of
prlvate buslnesses In Cuba!
Turn that off.
The last pregnancy of bourgeolsle
wlll be llquldated...
In thls herolc offenslve.
Thank you.
How is she?
This may be the last time
you will see her.
You have been...
very wonderful to me.
I want you to listen to me.
You must not interrupt me.
You must listen to me...
when I tell you...
that you are losing touch
with the people.
It 's not that they have
stopped loving you.
It is the nature of power.
Being in power for so long...
you are losing touch
with people's dreams...
what they want in life.
They have doctors...
they have schools...
and for that they will
always be grateful.
But you are not giving them
what they want now.
Do not...
make them wait for you to die.
Do not make them
look upon you...
as their dictator.
- Are you listening to me?
- Yes.
I will never...
never lose touch with the people.
I promise you.
Fldel Castro Is allve and well, despite
at least elght CIA plots to klll hlm...
and one plan to undermlne hls lmage
by maklng hls beard fall out.
I'm certaln In my heart that lwlll
be the flrst Amerlcan presldent...
to set foot on the soll of a free
and Independent Cuba.
With the economy dlslntegratlng,
the Sovlets pulled the plug.
No one can recall shortages
as great as today.
They say the Amerlcan embargo
Is to blame...
Do you have the questlons
written down?
These are the Straits of Florlda.
About 1OO mlles of shark-lnfested
waters between Florlda and Cuba.
Estlmates are that forevery 1 Cuban
who makes it allve,2 do not.
That would mean so farthls year...
4OO Cubans could have dled
In the treacherous waters.
For 40 years, we have been the
target of your assassination plots.
Your mercenary invasions,
your military attacks...
insurrections planned
and paid for by your CIA.
For 40 years you have declared
economic and political war on us.
You have done everything to
destroy us by undemocratic means.
Because you say
we are undemocratic.
Forty years.
And you are still refusing to
accept your neighbor's decision...
to live in his own house
as he wishes.
Is that democracy?
To punish every country
that disagrees with you?
Before 1959, you had
one policy for Cuba:
That we must be exploited.
After 1959, you had
one policy for Cuba:
That we must be destroyed.
Is that democracy?
We are proud that we have survived
all your attempts to destroy us.
So do you think we will
give up the revolution now?
Do you think I will sell out
the revolution...
for which men and women
have sacrificed their lives?
Just because your companies
demand the right to sell...
what they like, how they like
and where they like?
And then expect your military
to support the companies?!
And your CIA to assassinate
those who protest against them?!
Do you think I will sell out
the revolution for that?
I will never betray the revolution.
Even if I was told that
98% of the people in Cuba...
no longer believed
in the revolution...
I would continue to fight it.
Even if I was told that I was
the only one who believed...
I would carry on.
I would be the sole revolutionary.
CAPTIONS BY VIDEOLAR