See you later.
Excuse me. You know
where 42nd Street is?
Hey! What are
you doing?
Stop him,
he took my briefcase!
I got you,
don't worry about it!
Hold on a second, ma'am,
there, I'll get it.
Thank you.
Hey!
Hey, you're holding people up here!
How you doing today?
Not so good.
Through the
turnstile, please.
Yo, we got it! Piano Man, Piano
Man. Billy Joel. Uptown Girl.
Hello, beautiful. Anybody selling
tickets to Piano Man? Box seats.
Piano Man!
Les Misérables, sir.
Les Misérables.
Come on. Billy Joel,
Uptown Girl.
Anybody selling ticket
for Piano Man?
Uptown Girl!
We Built This City on Rock and
Roll. You know that's it, come on.
Hey, Janet,
how you doing?
You okay today?
You be careful today,
there's cops everywhere.
Anybody selling
tickets for Piano Man?
IPods! Harry Potter books!
IPods, $20.
Uptown Girl. We Built This City
on Rock and Roll. You know...
How you doing, ma'am?
IPods, $20.
I like that oriental
jacket you got on.
That's $20 each, ma'am.
Two for $20!
No, no, you got...
That's $20 right
here, ma'am.
You got to give me
another $20.
Ma'am, you got two
of them right there.
How you doing,
young lady?
How much is this
Harry Potter book?
$20. Kids love them things,
that Harry Potter stuff.
You got kids,
they gonna love that.
Yo, move your shit, man.
What's that?
IPods, $20!
Move your shit, man.
How much is your book?
I'm just trying to
make some money, man.
Harry Potter Versus
the Hipopotamus?
This is misspelled.
No, that's how
you spell it.
Where do you
put the tape?
No, it's not a Walkman,
it's an iPod, sir.
Move all this shit, man.
Move all this shit.
Excuse me, can I have
my money back?
I want my money back.
Hey, hey!
What are you doing?
Get off me!
Come on, stop!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Drop this, man!
Get off me, I said!
Don't run, bitch!
Watch yourself!
Get off me, man!
Look, I'm sorry. I'm
not trying anything.
Grab that.
Grab that. Grab that.
Hey, hey, hey.
Come here. Come here.
Hey, what are you doing?
Just watch yourself.
Give me
back my money!
Somebody ought
to call the cops on you.
Walk this way, walk.
Pay your fare!
Hey, Mr. Sou.
How you doing, Mr. Sou?
Good? You know that
Radio Music Hall up there?
Man, I'll tell you, they
tried to kill me up there, man.
I bought some stuff
from downtown.
It was a fake book. I don't
even know how you do a fake book.
I'm gonna get some umbrellas
from you, is that okay?
Can I get some umbrellas from you? Yeah?
You said $100
last time, right?
I got in a fight, lost all my
money. This is all I got left.
Is that okay?
That's $100 right there. I
got one $20 left, all right?
Man, I had my stuff at
Radio City Music Hall.
I ain't gonna go down
there no more, though.
They're a bunch of crooks down
there. I'll see you later, Mr. Sou.
It's that kid from before,
Harvey. He's coming in here.
Can I help you?
Come on, look, I want
my money back, okay?
What money are you
talking about?
You know what I'm talking
about. Look, I don't mean no...
Come on.
He took it.
No, he did not... Okay,
I want it back right now.
He took your money? Okay.
Same shirt and everything.
This is Z and
as you can tell,
he's a little retarded
sometimes, okay?
Harvey.
Look, listen.
How much are we talking about
here? Don't give him shit.
No, no, listen. I've
got this. How much...
Hey, that's not nice.
That's not nice.
Here, thank you very much.
I should call the police on
you, you know? You should.
That's exactly what you should do.
I'll wait here for you if you want.
You know, you shouldn't be
robbing people, you know that?
And especially ones that
can come and find you.
Why don't you sit down and
talk to me for a second?
I just want to have
a conversation with you.
I was talking
about you earlier.
Look, try some of these bread
things, they're terrible.
You're going to
go after this kid?
Hey, wait up a second.
Where you going?
You know, that was some show
you put on out there today.
In the streets, you
know, the fisticuff thing.
Can I ask you one
question, though?
I'd much rather you
just stop following me.
I'm not following you, I'm
walking down the street.
But look, if you
want to make money...
You know...
Sorry, buddy.
There ain't
no friends here.
Think sitting behind a desk,
sucking ass all day, is making money.
Look, I'm Harvey Boarden,
all right?
Let me introduce myself,
I'm Harvey Boarden.
Shawn MacArthur.
Good to meet you.
You like to fight?
If I have to.
I can make you $5,000.
Got you interested, huh?
You see that store
right there?
You ever wonder how little
places like that stay in business?
BMW parked in front of it.
People dressed nicely.
They like people
that like to fight.
You want to make
some money at it?
Huh?
Yes or no?
You don't want to make no
money, you don't have to go.
You can go on
with your life.
I can make $5,000 with
you on one fight alone.
You can stay there
and go home if you like
or you can come
and get $5,000.
Wait, hey.
You ain't got no place to
go, go where you're going.
You better give me $5,000
if I walk across the street.
Come on, break out
one of them umbrellas.
It ain't raining.
You're right.
You know these guys, you
ever seen these guys before?
I'm like an agent for them,
I get them talent and stuff.
Hey, Christopher,
Jack.
Hey, Harvey.
Hey, Claudette, Martinez.
Chinese guy
named Martinez.
What?
Go figure.
That guy was Chinese?
Yeah, his mother
or something.
But those guys, they run every
bet place in this whole city.
And that's what matters
'cause that's how you get paid.
Hey, Mr. Wilson. Mr. Wilson. Mr. Wilson.
Harvey, I have to thank you so
much for those Billy Joel tickets.
I'm so glad you enjoyed it.
You look lovely tonight, ma'am.
Did he do my favorite song,
the "Downtown Alexa" thing?
Okay. Hey!
What are you doing,
Harvey? No way.
No way. I gotta go to 38th
Street to get some juice.
It's about to rain.
Get in the car, drive.
Get in the car, Z.
I got an umbrella for you
anyway. Come on, get in.
Get rid of the box, you
don't need that anymore.
Where are we going?
We're in a $100,000 Mercedes.
That's where we're going.
Okay, so what
happened to the $5,000?
Hey, here's your boy.
Good morning.
Thanks for showing.
I got your text,
so here I am.
You need a soda or anything?
No, I'm cool.
Do me a favor. Go get me
a orange soda or something.
So what goes on here?
Well, we're going to get you an
opportunity. You want to fight, right?
I want to make money.
Okay, first thing, we got
to make you presentable.
Put this on. I don't
want to wear your jacket.
Presentation is everything. Come on.
It's about making money. I'm
going to give you an opportunity.
Real nice smile.
This thing
don't even fit me.
Where's my change?
It was $3.
You know, I can get that
for $1 across the street.
Yeah, and you could have gotten
it for 50 cents at the supermarket.
Comedians.
Come on.
I don't...
We're going to
make some money?
Yeah.
I feel stupid.
If they invite you over,
tell them you can fight,
'cause you can,
you know?
Better yet, don't even say nothing
to them, let me do the talking
and I'll take care
of everything.
Yo, Harvey,
you want a stove?
Hey, Christopher, you guys are
still doing the fight stuff, right?
I've got a guy right here.
Hey, Z, bring him over here!
This kid right here is
an incredible fighter.
Oh, yeah?
Jack. Jack.
Tell me, when was the last
time that you had a white guy
that looked like this
in one of your fights?
And you did college
and everything, right?
You went to college?
That is remarkable.
He's the real thing.
A white kid who went to
college, that's amazing.
How come I never
heard of you?
Well, he's from...
No offense, but I've
never heard of you either.
Look, I'm sorry, you know,
sometimes he's a wiseass.
But he's...
I'm not joking here.
I'll give him a peep.
Yeah,
White boy who
went to college.
Thanks, Jack.
Can I get my jacket back, please?
Why'd you go
talking to him?
He asked me a question.
You got to let me do the talking
from now on, okay? Please.
Okay.
Please.
You know, I'll beep you
if he calls me. Come on.
Beep me?
Well, I'll page you,
text you, whatever.
Where are y'all going?
What, you lonely,
you need a friend?
We got things to do.
We'll text you.
Now there's these junk stores and
these vendors and these big signs and
overhead construction
cranes and all this...
Lady! What are you
yelling about?
You know, they used to
sell drugs in that building.
Well, that's okay,
but now they've got
men riding elevators
to wash the windows...
Well, let them...
Move on, it's okay.
And you take your life in your
hands just crossing the street,
there's so much demolition
stuff all around. Look at it...
After you.
Hey, Giovanni, you got
a refrigerator in there?
Last one, baby,
get it while it's hot.
Baby, come and get one,
buy one, get one free.
Come on over.
They had money on you
not making it.
So this thing's
for real?
Yes, it's very real.
Very real.
$5,000?
Yes, but minus costs.
Hey, be careful with
those shoes there.
Minus what?
Costs. This is Alexander.
Ray, Alexander.
Ray, Shawn.
You roughed them up
the other day,
so they're gonna ride
in the front and drive
and you're going to be
in the back with me.
No, no, I'm driving,
this is my car.
And it's
a very nice car.
You know, if your boy
wants to go, we can go.
Wait a second.
Come on, man, look,
I wasn't interested in no trouble
with you, so you need to relax, okay?
Where's this
hostility coming from?
Text me again, and I swear
to God I'm gonna hurt you.
He keeps sending me these
stupid little things, you know.
Just costing me money.
Come on, Harvey.
Why am I sitting in the
car and it ain't moving?
Come on, these little texts
that you keep sending me
are costing me $1 a minute.
So, what, I'm going to fight
this guy, then what happens?
Well, we go in,
you win, you get $5,000.
You lose, you get nothing.
So we get
paid tonight?
Yes,
we will get paid.
You keep asking me
the same question.
All right, Harvey.
So what, they got rules or something?
They don't like scared,
okay. There's the church.
Yeah, if you kick him
in the nuts, you win.
Right.
There's Sydney up there.
Gouge the eyes,
everything.
Come on. Come on, Z.
This is Brooklyn, huh?
Yeah,
as you can see.
Hey, there, Sydney.
How you doing?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're late.
We have to have this place cleaned
up by the morning, so hurry up.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Here you go, do what you got to do.
Scratch, bite.
Thank you.
Yo, smells like farts and
ass in here, you smell that?
Smell like pure vodka.
The place is a
playground, but, like, bad.
Filled with bad people.
Fighter.
You ready?
Go make some money.
Hey, Jack.
Harvey, you running on
Caucasian people time, huh?
I'm running. I'm running.
You're running?
Yeah.
Yeah,
you keep running.
Na zdorovie, brother.
Let's see what
you got, Shawn!
Let's see it, Shawn!
Go, go, go, go!
Ow!
Yeah.
Excuse me,
excuse me, excuse me.
Hey, come here.
It's over, it's over.
Come on, have a seat.
Don't smile at nobody.
Just sit down.
Watch yourselves.
You got some tissue in your
pocket? Anybody got tissue?
Give him some tissue.
He can fight, right?
On the water fountain.
Told you
he could fight.
So you both should come to the
club. He's going to need a jacket.
I got to get out of here.
Give him your jacket.
I can't stand Brooklyn.
You tell Jack I know
what I'm doing.
Yeah.
No, we're special guests of Mr. Dancing.
Could you just
see for me?
I'm telling you,
we're on the list.
Will you let Renee know
I'm on the list, please?
Let them through.
Two of you.
Now, come on, Harvey.
Harvey!
I feel like a bum.
No, you look great.
Cordell!
Cordell, Harvey Boarden.
We're VIP.
We're VIP. Hi.
We got VIP.
That's reserved for us. Right
here. They ain't gonna tell us.
Try to ink out. Come here, have a drink.
You gonna introduce me to your friend?
Shawn, this is
Shevonne Dubai.
Am I pronouncing
that right?
Mmm-hmm.
Have a seat.
Yo, yo, yo!
Come here,
where you going?
Yo, man. I heard you were great
out there in Brooklyn today, man!
He's a winner,
he's a real winner.
Yeah, look, I meant
to say hi to you
the other day on the
street, but with Harvey,
you never know when anybody's
anybody, you know what I'm saying?
Yeah, I think
I saw you out there.
Yeah, yeah, you guys are just coming
from dinner, right, something like that?
Right?
No.
Yeah, listen, man, you ever want
to dine, I'll take you to a place
where you don't have to sit at a
counter, you know what I'm saying?
Shawn, right?
Yeah, that's his name.
Listen.
It seems we're going to be
working together, okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You know,
I heard he'd already lined up
to fight big boy
over there.
Yeah, yeah, well, I was
talking to him about that.
What is this, Harvey,
$10,000?
Since when are you into
this kind of stakes?
Can he just rest for a
minute? He just had a fight.
You want some water?
Yeah, yeah.
Can I get you some
water? Poor Harvey, man.
Let me ask you something.
You think you could beat
big boy over there?
Do we think
he can win?
Harvey,
I wasn't asking you.
I was asking your friend here in
the nice blazer, with the blonde.
Can I do that?
Can you all pardon
me for a second?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Hey, Harvey, you're gonna
lose that real quick. Watch.
Excuse me,
Harry Potter book.
You got to be kidding.
Okay.
I knew I was going
to see you again.
Look, I feel bad
about that book.
Look, you remember me?
You remember me,
don't you?
I remember you.
We spoke, you...
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah?
Hey, look, I just wanted to
take you to dinner or something.
I'm good, thank you.
No, I was thinking
maybe sometime
something without
a counter. That's all.
That's good. I like that,
without a counter.
I just heard somebody
say that upstairs.
You heard somebody
say that. Okay.
No, look, I just feel
bad about the book,
kind of want to, I don't
know, make it up to you. Hey.
Hey. Thank you. Looking
beautiful as usual.
I'm Shawn.
Zulay.
That's pretty.
Thank you.
I believe in fate, so...
I don't.
Oh, no.
What do you think?
If I see you again,
then we'll call it fate.
Okay. One more time.
Okay.
Goodbye.
Counting on it. All right.
Okay.
Zulay.
Bunch of losers
in here, man!
Someone tell that idiot the
whole place is filled with losers.
Right, Harvey?
Hey, so we got
another fight, huh?
Yeah, we are, but we're gonna
talk about it in a second.
I'm going to meet you
over there.
So what did you say,
$10,000, right?
$10,000, that's like
a hundred $100s.
There he is.
Shawn, this is Jerry.
Jerry.
Nice to meet you.
This is Jim.
And that's Joel right there,
and these are their dates.
Look, I'm going to
meet you over there
and we're going to
talk about everything.
Shawn.
You know, we lost a lot of money
betting on your ass to get beat tonight.
Well, maybe you'll bet
the right way next time.
And what's the
right way to bet?
'Cause, you know, I wipe
my ass with a hundred $100s.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hey, hey. Just have a seat.
I'll be over
there in a second.
Come on, Jerry.
Excuse me,
we're sitting here.
You're Evan Hailey,
right?
Yeah, and you're
wearing contacts.
Holy shit.
Shawn MacArthur.
I'm sorry,
man, is this your girl?
No. Uh-uh.
So what brings you
to New York, man?
Well, just...
Martinez.
How you doing, man?
Hi, bud, I know who you are. But
you have to excuse me for a second,
I'm just... I'm bugging
out a little bit right now.
You all two
know each other?
I know who you are.
Yeah. Yeah,
we know each other.
I used to wrestle for Shawn's
father back in Birmingham, Alabama.
So how is your father?
Yeah? I'm sure he's fine.
Mmm-hmm.
You know, I'm going to let you
all have a good night, okay?
I'm gonna go ahead
and get out of here.
Hey, come on, man.
Relax, man,
come on, sit down.
Hey. Don't touch me.
"Don't touch. "
You know what...
You worried about your jacket?
Huh? That's the problem?
I'll buy you a new one,
how's that?
I don't need your jacket. No?
Hey, is everything
okay over here?
Harvey.
These two guys are
old friends, man.
Evan just was offering
to buy him a new jacket.
I said I didn't
need a jacket.
Come on, Shawn, look.
You guys.
I'm Harvey Boarden.
Harvey Boarden,
go wash my car, man.
You know, somebody
might hurt you
for doing something
like that.
That somebody
going to be you?
Come on, let's go.
You should go, Harvey.
You're bad, man.
Yeah, Harvey,
you can go now.
Neolithic-looking idiot.
Always saying my damn name.
My daddy used to tell me, "Nothing
good happens after 10:00 p. M."
It's got to be damn
near 2:00 now.
Right?
Yeah.
You knew that guy, huh?
Yeah, he used to wrestle
for my dad's team.
Really?
You know,
I'm gonna go, okay?
Well, where you going?
What, you need
a friend now?
What?
I'm just gonna
go for a walk.
Okay.
Good night, Zulay.
Good night.
Zulay. Like July?
Yeah, that's right.
I say that right?
You did.
I figured I'd take fate
into my own hands, you know.
And you did.
I have to go. I...
Nice seeing you, Shawn.
Oh, you called me
Shawn. That's cool.
Hey, you make sure
she gets home okay.
Okay. Thank you.
All right?
Thank you, Shawn.
Uh-oh! Don't use it again.
My name. That's good.
Good night.
Hey, King Arthur,
it's Merlin.
Hey, man.
What you doing here?
That's what I was
gonna ask you.
What time is it?
You fell asleep
on the bench.
You look like a crackhead.
I just sat down
for a second. And...
Wow.
I can't believe you just
saw me sleeping on the...
I just sat down,
just for a minute
and I don't know, I just
kind of went to sleep.
I can't believe it.
I've got an extra room at
my place. You can stay there.
Hey, hey, hey.
Look, I'm okay.
If you like.
No, you're not okay.
I was just about to
go to a hotel, man.
Yeah, 7:00 in
the morning.
They don't even check
you in until 1:00.
You don't have to
stay at a hotel,
I've got a place
right around the corner.
But you can stay there
until you find another place.
All right, look,
I'm gonna pay you.
Yeah, you're going to
pay me back for sure.
Come on,
grab your stuff.
If somebody saw you sleeping out
here, you know what they'd think?
We wouldn't make
no more money.
Nothing's free
in this world.
I just was there
for a minute or two.
Well, you're in deep
with Harvey Boarden now.
So we're going
to work it out.
Make sure you wipe your feet
on that carpet right there.
I'll shut the door.
Okay, so here we are.
Fresh paint job, new lamps.
It's all right for now.
Yeah?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
You know, for now, at least.
But anyway, here's your area.
That's a Sealy ostropedic.
I got that new.
You like Broadway? You know? Yeah.
'Cause I got tickets, you know,
like Legally Blonde and Wicked.
Wicked's a very good one.
I don't go too often,
but when I do,
I go and see that one.
Is that you?
Yeah, don't mind those,
that's me, Jack and
Martinez, you know, and...
Well, we were going to be
these moguls, you know?
We used to sell tickets
at the Garden.
It was when
we first got here.
So you ain't
from here, either?
Are you kidding me? I'm from
a place with some culture.
Chicago, you know?
But I guess you've got
your own story, too, right?
You left your suitcase
out here.
What, you got
gold in there?
My father used to always say, "Stay
business, ready for business. "
Well, you got to...
So you got a plan
or something?
You know, like a big plan
with this fight stuff?
Yeah, I didn't travel all the way
to New York just to be some hustler.
I figured I'd save up some cash,
play some professional ball.
Open up a IHOP. You know,
with an office in it
and my name on the door.
What, like an International
House of Pancakes?
Turns out all I ever was
was a two-bit hustler.
Well. Guess that's not
so bad though, right?
Well, by definition, that's just
somebody who can't win, that wins.
We just won.
I'm just saying.
You know, if that's...
Get you some rest,
Shawn MacArthur.
Go to sleep. We got
a big fight coming up.
$10,000, right?
Yup.
Jerome. This
is Jerome, right?
Looks like
we're here.
Yeah. Look at this tough.
I bet they won't complain about somebody
putting up new buildings
around here.
Come on, you guys,
get in.
It took you
long enough, man.
That guy's
waiting on you.
Shawn, ready to
get your ass busted?
This is where you take me,
Harvey? That's for suckers, man.
Hello, ladies. This is
what I'm talking about.
What's up, girls? Yeah.
How you doing?
She's cute, yo.
I like that.
You're cute, why you got a mad face?
Put a smile on your
face. Not my fault.
I wonder why I don't come
to the Bronx that often.
You know this
kid, right?
Yeah, man,
he's a big dude.
Don't get too close.
Yeah, thanks for that.
There you go,
there comes the king.
Yeah. Get a good
look at that, all.
Bring out the cash, papa.
Bring out the cash.
Do it.
Whoop his ass.
Come on.
Come on, Shawn.
Move, Shawn! Move, Shawn!
Stick and move!
Work it! That's what
I'm talking about!
Ah! My throat!
Come on, Shawn.
Shawn! Shawn!
No, no! No, Shawn! Shawn!
What are you doing?
He knocked my shit over!
My ear!
Hey, what are you doing?
We don't want no trouble!
Hey, come on, move!
I don't want no trouble!
I swear to God,
Come on, open the door!
Push gas!
Yo, my ear, man!
He's okay, right?
Yeah, his ear's a little
messed up, but he's all right.
He didn't... Did he
say it was a dog?
You know, he didn't fill out
no police report or nothing?
A dog?
Yeah, a dog.
Can you call him?
Yeah. Nobody's
getting paid.
I'm going inside.
You should put some ice on that hand.
Gotcha.
It was a good
fight, man.
Thanks, man.
Hey.
All right.
We really ain't
getting paid?
We ain't getting
nothing
'cause of them damn
maniacs in the Bronx.
I really need money,
you know.
Really.
Look, I'm gonna work
something out, okay?
Okay.
I'm late every day
for work.
It doesn't matter.
Go, do your job.
I will, and the last
time, it wasn't done.
Please, let me do the job. Okay.
Lila, you're going to be good,
okay? Remember what I told you.
Abuela, I know,
I'm just telling you.
I'm telling you,
I'm reminding you
because you forget a lot
of things, you know?
Take it easy, young lady.
Let me go.
Out? Okay, out.
You relax.
Are you sure you know
how to get home safely?
You make me excited.
I know how to drive
better than you,
you know that.
Okay. Bye.
You know better.
Oh, my goodness,
what kind of lady?
Be good, Lila.
Oh, my God.
Huh?
It's a funny thing, us
keeping meeting like this.
Are you going
into work now?
Yeah. What are
you doing here?
I was just walking by, for the past
two hours, hoping you'd show up.
Oh, stalking? Okay.
No, I just wanted to see
if you wanted to come
get something
to eat with me.
I have to work.
I have 20 minutes.
Just like...
Twenty minutes? You're the
first one here anyway, come on.
Remember, I've been here for
a while. So you want to go?
Yeah? I have to be back, though,
'cause I work here. I'll
get you back, come on.
Twenty minutes.
Like, you don't have to
go if you don't want to go.
Twenty minutes.
Okay, let's go.
If my boss calls me,
I have to go.
Okay, let's go.
Thank you.
Here, let me get that for you. Oh, okay.
I'll get you some sparkling water, okay?
Okay, thanks.
Is that good?
Yeah, yeah.
No, that's good.
So, is this
okay for you?
No, this is good, this
is good. This is...
It's good? Okay.
I'm trying to figure out
what I'm gonna eat.
I think I'm just gonna
have a calamari.
Okay.
By: BackFire
You know,
I ain't that hungry.
All right.
You're not hungry?
No, not really. Thank
you, though. I'm good.
So, that little girl in the
car, that was your daughter?
Yeah.
She seems sweet. I saw the
way she was looking at you.
Yeah, she's sweet.
What? I'm sorry.
There's a big pink thing
coming down the road.
Yes.
That's pink bunny man.
You think that's funny?
Wow. That's a lot of
bunnies right there.
You want one of them things? No.
You know, I'm gonna go get
you one, hold on a sec.
No. He's really
gonna go get one.
Excuse me, sir.
Can I get one
of these bunnies?
Yeah, right on, my man.
How much are they?
$5.
$5? Here you go. Thank
you very much, sir.
You have a good day, okay?
You too.
Excuse me.
Pink bunny.
Thank you.
You didn't want
that thing, did you?
My daughter's
going to love this.
She thinks the guy's from
outer space or something.
So what's her name?
Lila.
Lila?
That's a good name.
Oh!
That must be my boss.
I can't stay. I can't be
late for work again, so...
Well, you just ordered.
Yeah, I'm sorry, I'm
just late. No, no, no, no.
This is our date.
Don't even worry about it,
I'll wait for the check.
Date?
Yeah, it's a date.
Date, okay.
All right, well...
Yeah, get out of here.
Don't be late.
See you later.
Okay. You're in
a rush always.
Sorry, I know.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Harv.
What the hell is
wrong with you?
What is this?
What happened to the
whole, I don't know,
"be ready for business,
business ready" thing, huh?
When I'm not being chased
out of the damn Bronx
trying to hustle up you some
money, I'll be a little more alert.
That ain't my fault.
In fact, they actually want you
for another fight this Friday.
Are you up for that?
Yeah. How'd you do that?
Well, I told you, I got
my connections, you know.
It wasn't easy either.
How much this time?
Well, that's what I want
to talk to you about,
but give me a second, I
need to put my clothes on.
It's about this guy you're
about to go up against.
You know, I know you're a
tough guy and everything, Shawn,
but you're not
going to beat him.
But he's gonna... Come
on, I can handle myself.
I know you can, that's why,
when he puts you
in the choke move,
you're gonna go to
sleep, it's that easy.
What are you saying?
I think you know
what I'm saying.
No, I don't know what
you're saying.
Sounds like you're saying
you want me to throw it.
Well, whatever you want
to call it, you know?
We're gonna make some money,
not like up in the Bronx.
You're complaining about
that whole thing, right?
No, I'm not losing.
I know you're
not gonna lose,
you're gonna do what
I'm telling you to do.
I appreciate everything
you did for me.
But, you know, the only way I'm
going to lose is if somebody beats me.
Okay, then, whatever,
let him beat you.
I'm serious.
Martinez came up
to me, he said,
"You know, hey, if you go around
with me, that's fine, man. "
I don't know.
What?
You and Martinez what?
What do you mean, "what"?
I want to hear why, you
know, you said, "Martinez... "
I didn't say I was
gonna do anything.
No, I want to know what
you're gonna do, 'cause...
I mean, here I'm trying to talk
to you about making you some money,
and, you know, nobody made
anything up in the Bronx, right?
You know that.
I know that. I understand. I know.
And you're gonna threaten me now, right?
What? I'm not
threatening you.
You're not threatening me? I
take you off of a park bench,
and you're going to
threaten me in my house?
Harvey, I ain't
threatening you.
No, I know you're
not threatening me,
'cause you know why?
'Cause you're gonna get
out of my house now, Shawn.
Look, hold on.
I'm sorry, okay?
No.
No, no.
Get out of my house.
Grab your garbage
and go. Okay?
Okay.
Hey, there,
Ms. Florence.
Dog's got a demon in it.
Demons.
You know, I gave you
a place to stay, Shawn,
'cause that's
what you needed.
It was a place to stay, it didn't
have any of this other stuff.
I understand that.
You saw that picture I showed
you of Martinez and Jack and me?
I didn't say I was
gonna go with him.
I had a whole
lot then, Shawn.
He broke my leg for $100.
That's crazy, right?
$100.
All I was saying is,
I wanted to win.
That's it,
that's all I wanted.
It's funny, you lose
one step in this game
and everybody leaves you.
At one point, there was
a whole lot of people
that would put a whole
lot of money on me.
You really think you
can beat this kid, huh?
I hear he's fierce,
you know?
'Cause if you lose,
you get nothing.
You win, you get...
You get $30,000.
Hmm.
Okay.
Okay, we'll do it.
Hi.
Hey, sweetie.
How are you?
So what are you
doing here?
Waiting for you
the whole time.
That's a man, bro.
You're a man?
Hell, no.
Sit.
Thank you.
I'll be right back.
Z, fold this up.
Harvey, you know you got no
business in a place like this, right?
Come on, Shawn.
Shit!
Holy shit!
Yeah! Yeah!
Get out of there!
Get out!
Pick his ass up!
Come on! Get up!
Yeah! Yeah!
There it is!
Yeah!
Yo, Shawn, get up.
We won!
Yeah, baby! We won!
Get up, get up, yeah!
No more deliveries tonight, man. You!
Your man
got knocked out!
What, baby! That's us!
What! You saw that!
You saw that! That's us!
Yeah, baby!
Well, looks like
Harvey's got a winner.
That's us, baby,
all the way!
Get out of the car...
No, no.
I'm proud of you.
You put the works on
Bruce Lee, though, man!
I got to give
it to you.
Get out of my car.
Come on, Harv. Let me out.
Come on,
Harvey, let's go.
Let's get a drink,
Harvey.
Aren't you going
to have one?
No, I don't want to. Go, it's
your night, have a good night.
Man, it's raining,
come on.
I'm going to go home and
count my money. Leave me alone.
All right, grandpa.
Don't get in no trouble.
I'm serious, though.
Come on, serious.
Come in, just have one.
I ain't got nothing, go.
Thanks for tonight.
Thanks, Renee,
I appreciate it.
Yes, sir.
Please tell me you're not still
putting money in your sock.
What'd your father
used to call that?
Niggerish, that's what
it was, right?
So this is who you hanging
out with these days, Shawn?
These your boys?
Saw you step out your fancy
stretch limousine there.
What, did you all pass
around a hat to get that?
Take up a collection?
You know, the only enjoyment
I got back in college, Shawn,
was watching
your asshole father
humiliate your shit
all over the place.
Really?
Until your bitch-ass cold-clocked
him in front of the whole gym.
Come on!
I'm right here!
Do something!
Shawn! Look at me!
Like your bitch-ass daddy.
Shawn, Shawn,
what are you doing?
I ain't your father.
You can't go to
a club and have fun.
That's right. I'm cool.
I'll see you around.
Let's get out of here.
It's ridiculous. I don't
even... I can't stand him.
I just... It's not late.
This guy's always putting
these notes on people's doors.
It's not late,
though. Sorry.
It's okay.
I hit you with
the door. So...
This is my living room.
I have to go and check
on Lila, so have a seat.
It's nice, right?
It's really nice.
Thank you.
Big TV.
It is, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Shawn.
I'm Zulay's friend.
She brought
me over to...
Zulay. Zulay.
What happened?
This is...
I'm sorry, this is...
This is Shawn.
Shawn, this is...
I don't care
who is he.
I care why you bring anybody
at this time to the house.
He look like
a criminal.
I know...
You're not supposed to bring
nobody at this time to the house.
I'm sorry... Don't be sorry.
Don't do that to me no more.
Okay?
Please,
don't say "por favor. "
I don't want to hear nobody
in the house at this time.
Hi. What are you
doing up this late?
What's that?
My pink bunny.
Sorry. What are
you doing up?
My grandma thinks
you killed someone.
He didn't kill somebody.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Why are you up, baby?
I want to see
the scary man.
I hear that I'm gonna
cook for you.
I'm gonna do it, but as soon as
you eat, please, you got to go.
Okay?
Yes, ma'am. I'm sorry.
Look at the way you are.
Look at you.
Please, it's okay.
I'm sorry, actually, you
know what? Look at you. Look!
You know what?
I need some thread.
What a shirt.
I'm going to
fix it for him.
I'm gonna take a needle and do some job.
That way he don't
gotta stay like that.
You don't feel bad?
I do.
What kind of men look
like that on the street?
Thank you so
much for the...
Come on, no. Back.
Back, let's go back.
I don't want
to go to bed.
Let's go back,
back to sleep.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh-huh?
Shawn has something
he wants to tell you.
What?
I don't understand what you
talk. Talk English, Spanish?
Okay.
She's wide awake.
This is going good.
I don't know, so... Hey, that
notice that was on your door,
everything all right?
Like, if you...
You know,
if you need anything.
Just let me know.
So...
That guy, Evan, from
the club, you know him?
Yeah. I mean,
yeah, I know him.
How do you know him?
Well, I don't, I just...
People were talking about
him at the club all night.
I guess he's a pro or something?
What, does he fight? A boxer?
Yeah, I mean,
a couple, you know,
the guys at the club
or whatever,
we just came back
from this...
You know, it's not a
professional thing, but...
Out in, like, you know,
Korea land,
we just came
from a fight, too.
You know,
it went pretty well.
So you're a fighter?
No, I mean, yeah.
But not professional. Just,
you know... I don't know...
I got this guy, he's an
agent/coach sort of thing.
I mean, it's been going
pretty good, though.
What?
I don't know.
So how do you know all
those guys at the club?
I don't. I...
I don't even know
your name, really.
What's your name?
Your last name?
MacArthur.
Shawn MacArthur. Like
a knight. I like it.
What are you
thinking about?
So...
Simple as that.
I can fix this for you.
Hmm?
I want to fix
this for you.
It's not so bad.
You want to fix it?
Mmm-hmm.
I want to kiss you.
Come on...
Why are you shaking?
Because I lied about
being able to sew.
It looks like
you're doing a good job.
Look at that mess.
Wow, I am shaking.
Wait, come here for a second.
Give me your finger.
Make a wish.
I got mine,
you got yours?
Mmm-hmm.
I do.
Excuse me! You got to go.
I'm sorry. I know.
Enough is enough.
Please go.
Yes, ma'am.
I believe it's enough
for today.
You can meet
later today.
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
Just a second to say bye.
No second. Come in.
You come in.
Thank you so much, Mrs.
Valez, I appreciate it.
I'm no Mrs. Valez,
I'm Mrs. Guzman. Okay?
And you got to go. Go.
Give me one second
to say bye, please.
Oh, my goodness, you give
me so much trouble today.
I'm sorry.
She could have come a little
bit later, that's for sure.
That would have
been nice.
Totally. I know.
Okay, so...
Okay.
Good night, yeah...
So I'm going to
see you again?
Yeah.
Yeah. When?
You sleeping?
Who can sleep with all
that banging up there?
Told you we'd win, huh?
Did you get our money?
Right at it, huh?
Yes, sir.
Look, I know we already had a
fight, but any word on another one?
I just want to make sure
we're capitalizing
on everything we got
going on here.
I told you, if you like,
anything I got,
the tickets, the hats,
the sneakers,
you can sell those until
I get you another fight,
if that's what
you want to do.
Go ahead,
turn around.
Huh?
You wanna get paid,
right?
Go ahead, man, get it,
I ain't gonna rob you.
I know you're not
gonna rob me,
'cause you're gonna
turn around.
After tonight,
you don't trust me?
Okay, fine.
I've turned around.
This is me,
all right?
I've turned around,
go ahead.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
I've turned around, go.
I was with this girl
from the club tonight.
Keep looking and you're
going to be with her now.
You can turn around now.
Man, she got a daughter.
She's kind of having a little
trouble with the rent, I think.
I kinda wanted
to help her.
Stop smiling at me, I know
what you're going to say.
Yeah, I bet...
Why wouldn't I
help her, then?
Beyond the kid and
the need for money...
Why you gotta break
everything down?
That's your problem, man,
you don't trust nobody.
Here you go.
I'm never trusting you,
you and your suitcase.
My suitcase?
Yeah, your suitcase
don't trust nobody either.
There's $10,000 right here.
Yeah. Nice, isn't it?
I was right, wasn't I?
Look, I just...
We shouldn't be selling
tickets and sneakers no more.
I tell you, we gotta... This
is what we're doing right now.
So...
This girl. She works
over at the Marquee?
Yeah, Zulay.
Zulay. She's nice, man.
Zulay.
Yeah.
Okay.
You get some rest,
all right?
There's $10,000
right here.
Yeah. Get some rest,
all right?
Hey, you know
where Zulay is?
What do you want
to talk about?
Isn't there something
you should be telling me?
What are you talking
about, Harvey?
You're gonna
make me say it?
Why didn't you tell me that
you were sleeping with him?
Why couldn't
you tell me that?
'Cause I don't have to tell
you everything. That's why.
Now you want him
paying your bills?
I did not ask him
to pay my bills.
Are you kidding me?
You're bringing him around your
daughter, you like him like that?
What, you think he's
better than me, right?
No. That's...
You think you're
better than me,
that's why you fill his
head with all this garbage.
About riding off
into the sunset,
like this is a movie
or something, huh?
No, no, come here I'm talking
to you. Don't touch me.
I'm talking to you.
Don't touch me.
Stop it.
If he decides to up
and leave you tomorrow,
you think you're
part of his plans?
You think
your daughter is?
Maybe. What about your grandmother?
You're always so paranoid.
Yeah, that's what I am,
I'm paranoid. I'm paranoid.
You still believe
in fairy tales.
But you think
I'm paranoid, okay.
Does he know
how we met?
You in the back seat,
sleeping in your car,
with your daughter
in the front seat?
Is that something
to be paranoid about?
Okay.
You think that little thing
right here between your legs
is gonna make everything
okay, don't you?
That's what you think.
It isn't.
You use that on him.
Don't put no more
garbage in his head.
Yo, check this out, yo.
Check what out, this
dirty-ass crib you got?
There are bare wires
laying around, man.
Clean this shit up.
When was the last time
you cleaned this shit?
Shut up, bro, I'm about to kick you out.
Evan Hailey KO's Richards.
It's your man from the club.
This dude's corny.
No, check it. A dude like this
man, you got to take serious, man.
Yeah, look
how he punches.
He look like he's punching like a
girl, but those punches hurt, man.
It's your man, Shawn.
Who is that?
That's that dude
from the club, bro.
No, man, he's the real deal.
Yo, Shawn, no disrespect, man,
he's fighting for real
money in real venues.
Shawn over here
bullshitting with us.
Look at you, Harvey.
You know, you've been doing
that for some time now.
It's called bi-polar
or manic depressive.
What? What?
Oh, my God.
Harvey, come in. Come
in, sit down. Come in.
We were just talking about
you. Come in, come in.
Special occasion, you
got the suit broke out.
Nice suit.
Jacket, at least.
That's nice.
Beautiful,
you're looking good.
Not bad, Harvey.
Listen, I didn't
come here, you know,
to take up a whole
lot of your time.
I'm just here
to tell you
that if you've got
something for Shawn...
Look at little Harvey,
he's like a little kid.
He's very excited, like he
has a secret to share with us.
What's the secret,
Harvey?
I'm just saying, if you...
If you got something for us,
we're ready to go, you know.
He's the biggest draw
in this town,
and if you're ready for
something, we're ready for it.
Wow.
It must be very hard for you
to come in here and grovel
in front of all of us
here. Especially Martinez.
You know, Jack, I don't have to
stay here and take this from you.
Guess what, Harvey?
We were talking about
you and we said that
maybe we should put your
man in one of our fights.
A big fight. $100,000
to the winner, Harvey.
Harvey's excited, huh, Harvey?
You excited, Harvey?
$100,000.
Evan Hailey's going to
rock your boy's world.
Time out. He couldn't
wait to tell you that one.
See, this is the way
it's going to be.
Evan Hailey versus
Shawn MacArthur.
And we're going to play
up this whole thing
about how they went
to the same school,
you know,
the education rivalry.
Rivalry for education.
Okay.
I know.
As soon as we
get the word out,
the phone's just going
to ring off the hook.
We'll let both
of you know.
Harvey, you sure you're
ready for this, Harvey?
Can't help but keep
calling my name, huh?
I don't know, Harvey,
maybe I'm stupid, you know?
But I'm not stupid enough to think
that Shawn's going to win this.
That's stupid, Harvey.
Yeah, really.
Really?
You just don't know how
good he is, you know?
Yeah, I do.
That's why I got Evan.
And the loser gets shit,
Harvey. And you still get shit.
Hey, man.
We need to take a walk
and talk for a second.
Okay.
So you gonna tell me?
Well, I got you
another fight.
Yeah? How much?
$100,000.
What?
Yeah.
They want us to fight
Evan Hailey.
He's your opponent.
Great.
I'm taking all my money and
I'm placing it against us.
You ain't got no money.
You have any idea
how much money
I can raise for
something like this?
Then raise it and
put it on us to win.
People like a guarantee,
Shawn.
Then guarantee it.
You saw Jerry,
those Wall Street guys,
even Martinez would
get in on this.
We're talking
real money.
No, you're talking
about money.
No, come on, Shawn.
What do you think, there's a
trophy involved in all of this?
Nobody cares about it.
And if we lose, you know we get
nothing. You get that, right?
What? Come on, Shawn.
Look, all right, look...
You think I don't
understand that I'm nothing?
I'm nothing, I get it.
I ain't worth nothing.
Nobody said anything like
that. I mean, come on.
All I'm saying is that
I don't want to lose.
That's all I'm saying
is I don't want to lose.
I'm telling you, Shawn...
Look, I know it sounds
stupid to you.
It's stupid.
But that's what I...
I don't want to do it,
so I won't. Okay?
Cut all that stuff,
man, listen to me.
I mean it.
Listen, listen.
I'm talking to you.
Harvey.
What, you gonna hit me?
No, I'm not gonna
hit you... I'm sorry.
You think I'm your
father?
You're going to slap me around
like I'm your father, huh?
Okay, okay, I get it.
You think I don't know
who you are, Shawn.
What?
I know all about you.
I said, can the moral
garbage with me, Shawn.
It don't work here.
Harvey, you don't ever
talk about my father, okay?
You gonna hit me?
You don't ever
talk about my father.
Hey.
So you came back.
You know me, the stalker.
You caught me
taking a shower.
So, what are you
doing here?
Nothing, I was just... I don't
know, just kinda wanted to see you.
Okay, well, come in.
My grandmother has
Lila, so, come in.
I know it's really
hot in here, so,
if you want, just grab a
seat and I'll be right back.
Hey, listen.
Look, I made some money
and I kinda wanted to help
you with the notice that I saw
on the door the other day.
That's really... No...
That's sweet, but...
No. For Lila.
No, I don't need it.
Listen, hold on, hold on.
Just for Lila.
Hold on a second. Just,
please, just listen.
I don't know what
I'm trying to say...
The last thing I want
to do is upset you.
All I want...
You came in here
offering me money.
Just don't...
It's no big deal, okay?
I don't know how to...
What?
Your hair smells good.
Thank you.
You know, when you wash
your hair in the sink,
they call it
a Puerto Rican shower.
My grandfather used to hate
when people called it that.
Of course, he can say it.
I like this,
this is nice.
I know what
happened with your dad.
Oh.
Is that okay?
I read... Me and Lila
were on the computer,
and we just kinda
stumbled across...
Wow...
I'm sorry...
No... Checking up on me?
That's all right.
It's okay?
Yeah.
So you think
I'm crazy now?
No.
Well, I mean...
You'd be right.
I mean, I did. I went
a little crazy, so...
You know that guy Evan,
the other night,
at the club, you know,
after the whole thing?
Yeah.
We were on the same team
and my dad coached us.
Man, he loved Evan.
I was a freshman, and they
always used to mess with me.
And I just couldn't take it
no more. I kind of lost it.
And me and Evan went at it.
And my dad got between us
and I didn't even
see him, you know.
I just kinda...
I hit him.
I hit my father.
And I just didn't stop.
You know?
I just couldn't stop.
My father never forgave
me. 'Cause he shouldn't.
I got to go get that.
Okay, I have
to get going
because I have to go do something
at the club, I realized. I'm sorry.
I have to go and do
something at the club
that I completely
forgot about. So...
Okay...
Please hurry up.
I'll walk you.
I'm hurrying.
We do have to go.
I'm sorry, I just...
Okay. I heard you the first
time, I'm going, I'm going.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I just forgot I had to
go get this stuff done.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine, why?
Just wondering.
You're good?
Yeah.
Hey, Harvey.
Wait. What?
What's going on here?
Um...
I was going to tell
you, I know Harvey.
Wait, hold on. You all know each other?
Yeah, I know her.
I know her.
Listen...
Wait, how do you know...
I mean, how do you
know each other?
What's going on, 'cause, are
you together or something?
No.
Listen, Shawn...
No, no, no...
I'm talking to her...
I'm talking...
No, no, let me... I just
want to hear it from her.
Let me talk
to you, okay?
What did I say? I said
I'm talking... What now?
Shawn...
I want to talk to her.
I'm talking to you.
I want to talk to her!
Get your hands off me!
Shut up!
Get your hands off of
me! Get out of my head!
Look, everything
isn't what you think.
You're not the only one
that worked with me.
She works with me, too.
It's what I was explaining
at the apartment.
Nobody knows we know each
other. She places bets for me.
Okay, that's
what it is.
I was going to
tell you, Shawn.
You asked about my...
You asked about my father.
Shawn...
Why would you do that?
You better learn
to answer your phone.
Why didn't you answer?
That's all you had to do.
Why did you call?
Why didn't you text me
and say something?
Listen, Harvey and I have been
friends for a really long time.
Listen to me. I should
have told you, I know that.
I don't know what I
might say to you, okay.
Wait. Just listen
to me, okay?
Look, I make $11
an hour, okay?
Is that what you
want to know?
I make $11 an hour,
I'm broke.
I pick up glasses from people
that I hate all night long,
and I'm not really supposed
to be doing this right now.
Why didn't you
just tell me that?
Because.
Harvey... We're just friends.
He just gives me this money,
and I just go place bets for him
and that's all there is to it.
Nobody even knows that
we know each other.
Then why couldn't you
just say that to me?
Is this thing still on?
Listen, man...
Yeah, I understand.
Throw it. No one will
ever know the better.
And you're going to tell me
you're okay with that, huh?
Yeah.
Whatever you raise,
I want half.
We ain't talking about
anything here, you know.
No, forget it, then.
Okay.
Just like that,
though, huh?
Yeah. Just like that.
All right.
Then, you know once
you get out there,
all those eyes are
going to be on you.
And if there's even a hint that
you're throwing this thing...
And that's
both of us dead.
You understand
how much money they...
They don't scare me, Harvey.
This city doesn't scare me.
I'm gonna do what you want. And
you're never going to see me again.
None of you.
This isn't tickets,
Harvey.
You understand there's
$250,000 in this bag.
And, Harvey, don't make
us come looking for you.
Nice office, Harvey.
Glad you could
make it.
Yeah, you should
get a receptionist.
Is he going to listen
to you, Harvey?
If you don't believe me, he's right
out there, you can ask him yourself.
I'm asking you,
Harvey.
There's $250,000
in here.
And if he decides
he don't like losing,
and by some miracle he wins,
I still want my money, Harvey.
I don't get my money,
Harvey, I'll kill you.
Lot of money.
Come on in.
Zulay, did you have
another dream?
It's a lot of money,
Jack.
Oh, yeah?
How much are we
talking about?
Half a million dollars.
Hmm?
So what are you doing
walking around the street
with half a million dollars
in your bag?
I have investors.
Investors.
If it's too much
money, I can...
Too much?
Listen to that.
She's cleaning up the
dumpster, now she's in the club.
Tell your rich-ass and your
drunk-ass investor friends
that I will be happy
to pay them off.
And happier not to.
Count it.
The man
is here. Outside.
We need to get everybody out on
the terrace so we can do this thing.
People, the show's
going to start. Outside.
You have a nice place here. Of course.
City Hall, I've got
the Woolworth Building.
My meditation room.
Let's go, people.
Look, I'll meet you out.
Let me talk to you
for a second.
You know what we're
dealing with here, right?
Let's just go.
Let's get it over with.
Look at this, Harvey.
Now you see how far
you've come?
Hey, everybody,
Jerry invited us all
up here so we could
catch a glimpse of
his bank account.
That's nice, huh?
Here's to Jerry.
But what
the thing is...
I mean, the real shit
of this thing is,
is what's going on
right here.
So, Jerry, right now,
you should step off.
And gentlemen,
you should step up.
Let's go baby, let's go!
We're going
to sit down, people.
And these two gentlemen are going
to go toe to toe, blow to blow.
Whatever goes on
up here, whatever.
Whatever you do to
each other, whatever.
Whatever you say to
In the words of the late,
great, American poet,
Mr. Marvin Gaye,
"Let's get it on!"
Let's go, baby,
let's go! Yeah!
You froze? Huh?
It's a stare-down.
Oh.
It's the evil eye.
Is that what you gave
your old man? Huh?
Knock that smile
off his face, let's go!
Yeah, baby!
All right. Let's play.
Let's play, Shawn.
Show him what
you got! Do it!
Do it, baby!
Go on, Shawn! Yeah!
Get him, Shawn!
Get him! Get him!
Right here, Shawn.
He's talking shit!
You can't stay there,
Shawn!
Oh, shit!
Hey, hey,
that's it! That's it!
That's it! That's it!
That's enough! Call it!
Go on, Shawn!
Get up! Get up, bro!
Get up! Get up!
Get out of it! Get out of it! Get out!
Come on, Shawn!
You got to fight!
Come on! Get out of it!
Fight!
Come on, Shawn! Yeah!
No! No!
Harvey, what's
going on, Harvey?
No!
Come on! Yeah!
Holy shit!
No!
Yeah, boy!
Yeah, Shawn!
You got it, Shawn.
Let's start moving, boys.
Yeah!
What up now, bitch?
Harvey, I'd like to
shake your hand, man.
You're a dead man.
You're a dead man,
Harvey. Dead man.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
What up now, bitch?
Yeah, baby!
I'll need a drink
after that, man, right!
Thank you, Evan,
you fight like a bitch.
Harvey, we're going out,
VIP Harvey, we out of here.
Whoa, there he is!
You're the shit, man.
Yeah, last night was
great, man. Thanks a lot.
Thanks for the ride.
Thanks for
being there.
Yo, we're going to the club
tonight, kid. You wanna come?
VIP all night,
drinks all night.
Come on. Let's go.
No, I'm beat up.
VIP, Harvey. VIP.
VIP, you all
be careful.
Well, tonight,
show your butt off.
You know, I'd be lying if I didn't
say, secretly I wanted you to win.
That's crazy, right?
If I wasn't a dead man,
I'd be happy, you know.
But you killed me
with that, Shawn.
You know, you do what
you do, you know.
Look, Shawn,
in a couple of minutes
there's going to be some men
that's going to come here,
and you can't be here
when they get here, okay?
Me and Zulay,
we put it on us to win.
Yeah.
We knew you'd
never go for it,
so we didn't say
nothing, but...
There's $1 million
in there.
Business ready
for business, huh?
Business ready.
You taught me that.
Okay.
That's a lot of
money in there.
Mmm-hmm.
No, I'm not kidding, Shawn.
That's a lot of money.
That's a lot of IHOPs.
We're going to Birmingham.
Okay...
You know, we're going
to go and see my family.
See what's left of it.
You know what I mean?
Maybe stop by Chicago,
or something.
On your way to
Birmingham, Chicago.
Right. Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Why don't you come?
So Birmingham is
where you're thinking?
Yeah.
It's where I'm from.
Okay, what we
should do, then...
Hear me out.
I think we should go past
Birmingham to some place warm.
If you're going all the way to Chicago,
through Birmingham,
whatever...
Take it to California.
You know, they've got a whole lot
of great opportunities out there.
I've been doing
a lot of reading,
I'm not giving those
people this money.
I don't give...
Unless...
We shouldn't give nobody none
of this. We should just go.
"'I believe in love,'
said Grandma,
"I'm going to go to Africa
because my boyfriend is there.
"And then I change my mind,
maybe. Because love is beautiful. "
Oh, my God.
It's amazing, Alabama.
Alabama. Alabama. All the
time, Alabama, Alabama, Alabama.
Would you
all shut up already?
You're driving me crazy.
You're making
my ears bleed in here.
Edited:Cgha