There was once in venice
a moor Othello who for
his merits in the affairs of war
was held in great esteem.
It happened that he fell in love
with a young and noble lady
called desdemona,
who drawn by his virtue,
became equally enamoured of him.
So it was that since her father
was much opposed to the union
of desdemona with a moor,
she fled her house at night.
In secret haste
they were married.
Now there was in Othello's
company, an ensign named lago,
a very amiable outward appearance
but his character was
extremely treacherous.
I have told often and
I retell it again and again.
I hate the moore.
I'll poison his delight.
How? How, lago?
Proclaim him in the streets,
incense her kinsmen,
and though he in fertile climate
dwell, plague him with flies.
No, they come.
What will I do?
Why, go to bed and sleep.
- I'll incontinently drown myself.
Oh, bitterness.
What should I do?
Put money in thy purse.
Ere I would say I would drown
myself for love of a guinea
hen, I would change my
humanity with a baboon!
Come, be a man.
Drown thyself?
Drown cats and blind puppies.
It cannot be that desdemona
should long continue her love
to the moor or he his to her.
It was a violent commencement.
And thou shalt see an answerable
sequestration,
put buy money in thy purse.
When she is sated with his body
she'll fine the error
of her choice.
She must change, she must,
for youth.
Your daughter!
- Look, your house!
- Your house!
- Your daughter!
Senior, is all your family
within?
Why, wherefore ask you this?
Lf't be your pleasure for your
dull watch o' th' night,
transported, with no worse nor
better guard but with a knave
of common hire, a gondolier,
to the gross clasps of a
lascivious moor.
This thou shalt answer!
Straight satisfy yourself, if she
be in your chamber or your house,
lago, can I depend on the issue?
Thou are sure of me.
Go, make money.
It is too true an evil.
Gone she is.
Is there not charms by which
the property of youth
and maidhood may be abused?
Call up all my people!
Raise my kindred!
Where is the moor?
Keep up your bright swords
for the dew'll rust them.
Oh, thou foul thief!
Where hast thou stowed
my daughter?
Hold your hands! Good signor,
where will you that I go to
answer this your charge?
To prison till fit time of law
and course of direct session
call thee to answer.
Now at the same hour, there
came messengers in haste
to the senate for there was
news that the turkish armies
were moving against the
venetian garrison in cyprus.
The senators, already raised
the net, elected the moor to the
commander of their troops.
And officers were searching
the town to apprise Othello
of this honor
when lo, desdemona's old
father himself brings the moor
at sword's point to the council
chamber upon a charge of
working from desdemona with
unlawful enchant.
She was abused,
stolen from me and, ay,
corrupted by magic spells.
I'm very sorry for't.
If she in chains of magic were not
bound, whether a maid so tender,
fair and happy would ever have
to incur her general mock,
run from her father
to the sooty bosom of such a
fierce bat!
Damned as thou art,
thou hast enchanted her!
Othello, what in your own part
can you say to this?
Nothing but this is so!
Did you by indirect and forced
courses subdue and poison
this young maid of affection?
Most potent grave and
reverend signors,
my very noble and approved
good masters,
that I've taken away this old
man's daughter it's most true.
True I have married her.
The very head and front of my
offending has this extent,
no more.
Rude in my speech,
and little blessed with the soft
phrase of peace,
since these arms of mine had
seven years' pith till now some
nine moon wasted they
have used their dearest action
in the tented field and little
little of this great world can i
speak more than pertains
to feats of broil and battle.
And therefore little shall I grace
my cause in speaking of myself.
Yet by your gracious patience
i will round unvarnished tale
deliver of my whole course of love,
what drugs, what charms,
what conjuration and what
mighty magic, for such
proceedings am I charged withal
that I won his daughter.
Her father loved me, oft
invited me, still questioned me
the story of my life.
I ran it through even from my
boyish days wherein I speak of
the most disastrous chances
of moving accidents by flood
and fields of hair-breadth
scapes for the imminent
deadly breach.
Of being taken by insolent foe,
and sold to slavery,
of my redemption thence and
potency my travels history
wherein a venturous vast and
desert idle, rough quarries,
rocks and tills whose heads
touch heaven.
It was my head to speak.
Rest to hear, but desdemona
seriously inclined.
But still the house affairs would
draw her thence, which ever as
she could with haste dispatch,
come again and with a greedy
ear devour up my discourse.
I found good means to draw
from her a prayer of earnest
heart that I would all my
pilgrimage dilate, and often
did beguile her of her tears
when I did speak of some
distressed stroke of my use of it.
She gave me for my pains,
a world of sighs.
She swore, in faith: 'twas
strange, 'twas passing strange.
Twas pitiful, 'twas wondrous
pitiful.
She wished she had not heard
it, yet she wished that
heaven made her such a man.
She thanked me, and bade me
if I had a friend that loved her
i should but teach him how to
tell my story
and that would woo her.
Upon this hint I spake,
she loved my for the dangers
I had passed,
and I loved her that she
did pity them.
This only is the witchcraft
I have used.
I think this tale would win
my daughter, too.
Come hither, desdemona.
Do you perceive in all this
noble company
where most owe you obedience?
My noble father, I do perceive
here a divided duty.
To you I am bound for life
and education.
My life and education both do
learn me how to respect you.
You are the lord of duty.
I am hitherto your daughter.
But here's my husband.
And so much duty as my
mother showed to you
preferring you before her father
so much I challenge that I
may profess,
due to the moor, my lord.
God be with you. I have done.
When remedies are past
the griefs are ended.
Please it your grace on to
the state affairs.
The turk with a most mighty
preparation makes for cyprus.
Othello, the fortitude of the
place is vast known to you.
You must away this morning.
With all my heart.
When we consider the importance
of cyprus to the turk, we must
not think the turk is so
unskillful to leave that latest
which concerns them first,
neglecting an attempt of ease and
gain to wake and wage a danger.
Look to her, moor
if thou hast eyes to see.
She has deceived her father
and may thee.
My life upon her faith!
Mark me with what violence
she first loved the moor
but for bragging and dealing
a fantastical lie.
Will she love him still for prating?
Ah, let not thy discreet heart
think it.
- Lieutenant cassio.
- Largo
what a cannon.
I know my price.
I'm worth no worse a place.
But he, sir, had the election.
And what's he? This michael
cassio, this florentine,
that never set a squadron in the
field nor the division of a battle
knows more than a spinster.
Yet cassio must his lieutenant
be, by god bless the mark of
the fellow's ancient!
Well, I would not follow him that.
Oh, sir, content you.
I follow him to serve my turn
upon him.
Lago? Lago!
Honest lago!
I wake up on your lordship.
My desdemona must I leave
with thee.
I pray bring her after good time
to cyprus.
Well, me good lord, I'll do it.
The moor's of a free and
open nature, that thinks men
honest that seem to be so,
and will as tenderly be led by
th' nose as asses are.
We cannot all be masters.
Nor all masters cannot by
truly followed.
You shall mark many a duteous
and knee-crooking knave who
doting on his own obsequious
bondage wears out his time,
much like his master's ass, for
naught but provender; and when,
he's old, cashiered.
Whip me such honest knaves!
Others there are who, trimmed
in forms and visages of duty,
keep yet their hearts attending
on themselves,
and throwing but shows of
services on their lords,
do well thrive by them, and when
they have lined their coats
do themselves homage.
These fellows have some soul,
and such a one do I profess
myself for, sir, it is as sure
as you're roderigo, were
I the moor, I would not be lago.
In following him I follow
but myself.
When my outward action doth
demonstrate the native act and
figure of my heart in compliment
extern, 'tis not long after but
I will wear my heart upon my
sleeve, for daws to peck at.
I am not what I am.
I have but an hour of love
to spend with thee.
We must obey the time.
Oh, lago, what tidings can
you tell of my lord?
He's not yet arrived, but the
turkish fleets be not enshelterd
they are drowned.
It is there! I know
Othello's trumpet!
News, lads! News! The desperate
tempest hath so banged the turks
that their designment halts.
Our wars are done!
He takes her by the palm.
Well said. An excellent courtship.
With as little a web as this will I
ensnare as great a fly as cassio.
It gives me wonder great as my
content to see you here before me.
Oh, my soul's joy!
If after every tempest come such
calms, may the winds blow
till they have wakened death.
- My dear Othello!
- Oh, my fair warrior!
I prattle out of fashion, and
I dote in my own comforts.
- Worthy montano, your pardon
- sir
good michael, look you
to the guard tonight.
Come, my dear love.
Once more well met at cyprus.
It is Othello's pleasure that
upon certain tidings now arrived
importing the destruction of
the turkish fleet, every man
put himself into triumph.
Each man what sport and revels
his addiction lead him.
For, besides these beneficial news,
it is the celebration of
our general's nuptial.
Heaven bless the isle of cyprus
and our noble general Othello!
First, I must tell thee this.
Desdemona is directly
in love with him.
With cassio?
Why, 'tis not possible.
Her eyes must be fed.
And what delight shall she
have to look on the devil?
Very nature will compel her
to the second choice.
Now sir, this granted,
who stands so eminent in the degree
of this fortune as cassio does?
Why, none! Why, none!
A slipper and subtle knave,
a devilish knave!
- He is handsome.
- Cassio?
He has all the requisites in him
that folly and green minds
look after.
Oh, a pestilent complete knave
and the woman hath found
him already.
I cannot believe that in
desdemona.
Did you not see her paddle
with the palm of his hand?
Did not mark that?
Yes, that I did, but that was
but a courtesy.
Courtesy? Lechery. An index
and obscure prologue to the
history of lust and foul thoughts.
They met so near with their lips
that their breaths embraced together.
Villainous thoughts, roderigo.
But, sir, be you ruled by me.
Listen, listen to cassio tonight.
Watch him on the court of god.
Cassio knows you not.
I'll not be far from you.
Do you find some occasion
to anger him from what
other course you please.
Well
sir, he's rash and very sudden
in choler, and haply may
strike at you.
Provoke him that he may,
for even out of that will I
cause these of cyprus to mutiny
and the displanting of cassio.
Lieutenant cassio!
Lago, I'll say, you like me
well, lago?
In the sincerity of
love and friendship.
Come, lieutenant, a stoup of
wine!
Here a brace of gallants that
fain have a measure to the
health of black Othello.
Not tonight, good lago.
I have very poor and unhappy
brains for drinking.
Oh, just one cup.
I must to the watch.
Not this hour, lieutenant,
'tis not yet ten o' th' clock.
Our general cast us thus early
for the love of his desdemona.
He hath not yet made wanton
the night with her
and she is sport for jove.
She's a most exquisite lady.
And full of game, I'll warrant.
What an eye she has
to provocation.
I object, I think right modest.
Well, happiness to their sheets.
Another cup, I'll drink for you.
I have drunk two cups and
I don't dare not to task
my weakness with any more.
My man, 'tis a night of revels.
I'll do't, but it dislikes me.
If it were now to die, 'twere
now to be most happy,
for I fear my soul hath her content
so absolute that not another
comfort like to this
succeeds in unknown fate.
Ah, brothers on call tonight!
God, an excellent song!
I learned it in england, where
indeed they are most potent
in potting.
Your dane, your german,
and your swag-bellied hollander
- drink, ho! -
are nothing to your english.
Is your englishman so exquisite
in his drinking?
He drinks you with facility
you dane dead drunk,
he sweats not to overthrow
your almain,
he gives your hollander a vomit
ere the next pottle can be filled.
To the health of our general!
I am for it, lieutenant, and
I'll do you justice.
Good faith, a little one,
not past a pint, as I'm a soldier.
Well, god above all
and there be souls must be saved,
and there be souls must not
be saved.
It's true, good lieutenant.
For mine own part, no offense
to the general, nor any man
of quality, I hope to be saved.
Ay, but, by your leave,
not before me.
Do not think, gentlemen,
I am drunk.
This is my ancient, my right
hand, this is my left.
I am not drunk now. I can
stand well enough, and
i speak well enough.
Excellent well!
Very well. You must not think
then that I am drunk.
Zounds, you rogue, you rascal!
What noise is this?
A knave teach me my duty?
What's the matter, lieutenant?
I'll beat the knave into
a twiggen bottle.
Away, I say.
Go out and cry a mutiny!
Mutiny! Mutiny! Mutiny!
Stop, lieutenant!
Hold this shame forever!
Have you forgot all place of
sense and duty?
Hold the rage!
Hold, gentlemen!
You're ordered above.
Yeah, move, come on!
Why, sir, the generals!
Silence that dreadful bell!
Who began this? Lago.
I do not know.
Friends all, but now, even now,
in quarter and terms like
bride and groom devesting
them for bed,
but now swords out and tilting
one at other's breasts.
Worthy montano, what's the matter
that you unlace your
reputation thus and spend your
rich opinion for the name
of a night-brawler?
Your officer, lago, can
inform you.
Fortunate. Town of war to manage
private and domestic quarrel?
In night, and on the court
and guard of safety?
Lago, who began't?
Thou dost deliver more or less
than truth, thou art no soldier.
I had rather have this tongue
cut from my mouth than it should
do offense to michael cassio.
Sir, men in rage strike those
that wish them best,
yet surely cassio I believe
received from him that fled
some strange dignity, which
patience could not pass.
I know, lago, the honesty
and love doth mince this matter,
making it light to cassio.
Cassio, I love thee,
but never more be officer of mine.
Look if my gentle love be not
raised up.
I'll make thee an example.
What, are you hurt, lieutenant?
Ay, past all surgery.
Marry, heaven forbid!
Reputation, reputation,
reputation!
O, I have lost my reputation!
I have lost the immortal part
of myself,
and what remains is bestial.
My reputation, lago,
my reputation.
Reputation oft got without
merit and lost without deserving.
I tell you what you shall do.
Our general's wife is
now the general.
Confess yourself freely to her.
Desdemona is of so free, so
kind, so blessed a disposition
she holds it a vice in her
goodness not to do more than
she is requested.
Farewell, lieutenant.
Roderigo.
My money is almost spent,
i have been tonight exceedingly
well cudgeled.
And I think the issue will be,
i shall have so much experience
for my pains, and so, with
no money at all, and a little
more wit, return again to venice.
How poor are they that
have not patience!
Does not go well?
Cassio has beaten thee, and
thou by that small hurt hath
cashiered cassio.
Content thyself awhile.
For whiles this honest fool
plies desdemona to repair
his fortune, and she for him
pleads strongly to the moor.
Io, by how much she strives
to do him good, she shall
undo her credit with the moor.
So will I turn her virtue into pitch,
and out of her own
goodness make the net
that shall enmesh them all.
Do not doubt, cassio.
I'll have my lord and you again
as friendly as you were.
Madam, whatever shall become
of michael cassio, he's never
anything but your true servant.
Ha! I like not that.
What dost thou say?
Nothing, my lord, or if,
I know not what.
How now, my lord?
I have been talking with
a suitor here.
A man that languishes in
your displeasure.
Who is't you mean?
Why, your lieutenant cassio.
Went he hence now?
I' sooth so humbled that he hath
left part of his grief with me
to suffer with him.
Good love, call him back.
Some other time.
- Shall't be shortly?
- The sooner, sweet, for you.
- Shall't be tonight at supper?
- No, not tonight.
Tomorrow dinner then?
I shall not dine at home.
I meet the captains
at the citadel.
Why then, tomorrow night.
I prithee name the time.
No more. Let him come
when he will.
I will deny thee nothing.
Whereon I do beseech thee
grant me this to leave me
but a little to myself.
Shall I deny you? No.
Farewell, my lord.
- My noble lord.
- What dost thou say, lago?
Did michael cassio, when you
wooed my lady,
know of your love?
He did, from first to last.
Why dost thou ask?
But for a satisfaction of my
thought, no further harm.
Why of thy thought, lago?
I did not think he had been
acquainted with her.
O, yes, and went between us
very oft.
- Indeed?
- Indeed? Ay, indeed.
Discern'st thou aught in that?
Is he not honest?
- Honest, my lord?
- Honest? Ay, honest!
My lord, for aught I know.
What dost thou think?
Think, my lord?
Think. Thou dost mean something.
I heard thee say even now,
thou lik'st not that,
when cassio left my wife.
If thou dost love me
show me thou thought.
My lord, you know I love you.
I think thou dost.
For michael cassio, I dare
be sworn, I think he is honest.
I think so, too.
Men should be what they seem.
Certain, men should be
what they seem.
Why then, I think cassio's
an honest man.
Nay, yet there's more in this?
I prithee speak to me as
to thy thinkings.
Good name in man and woman,
dear my lord, is the immediate
jewel of their souls.
Who steals my purse steals
trash; 'this something, nothing.
Twas mine, 'tis his, and has
been slave to thousands.
But he that flinches from me
my good name robs me of
that which not enriches him
and makes me poor indeed.
By heaven, I'll know
thy thoughts.
Beware, my lord, of jealousy!
It is the green-eyed monster,
which doth mock the meat
it feeds on.
That cuckold lives in bliss
who, certain of his fate,
loves not his wronger.
But o, what damned minutes
tells he over who dotes,
yet doubts, suspects,
yet fondly loves!
Why? Why is this?
Think'st thou I'd make a life of
jealousy to follow still the
changes of the moon with
fresh suspicions?
No, lago, I'll see before I doubt.
When I doubt, prove.
I speak not yet of proof.
Look to your wife.
Observe her well with cassio.
I know our country disposition
well.
In venice they do let heaven
see the pranks they dare not
show their husbands.
Their best conscience is not to
leave't undone but kept unknown.
Dost thou say so?
She did deceive her father,
marrying you.
And when she seemed to shake
and fear your looks,
she loved them most.
And so she did.
Why, go to then! She that so
young could give out such a
seeming to seel her father's
eyes up close as oak.
He thought 'twas witchcraft.
But I am much to blame.
I humbly do beseech you of my
pardon for too much loving you.
I'm bound to thee forever.
I see this hath a little
dashed your spirit.
Not a jot, not a jot.
Trust me, I fear it has.
I hope you will consider what
is spoke comes from my love.
Cassio's my worthy friend.
My lord, I see you're moved!
No, not much moved.
I do not think but
desdemona's honest.
Long live she so.
And long live you to think so.
And yet, how nature erring
from itself
ay, there's the point, as to
be bold with you, not to
affect many proposed matches
of her own clime, complexion,
and degree.
One may smell in such a will
most rank, foul disproportions,
thought unnatural.
My lord, I would I might entreat
your honor to scan this thing
no further. Leave it to time.
Farewell.
Leave me, lago.
How now, my dear Othello?
My lord, I take my leave.
Are you not well?
I have a pain upon my
forehead here.
Why, that's with watching.
It will away again.
Let me but bind it hard, within
hours it will be well.
Your napkin is too little.
Let it alone!
I have a thing for you.
You have a thing for me?
It is a common thing to
have a foolish wife.
O, is that all? What will you
give me now for that
same handkerchief?
What handkerchief?
That which so often you
did bid me to steal.
Give it me.
If it be not for some purpose
of import, give't me again.
Poor lady, she'll run mad.
I have use for it. Leave me.
How now, general?
I swear 'tis better to be much
abused than but to
know't a little.
- My lord!
- Is my lord angry?
He went hence but now, and
certainly in strange unquietness.
- I will go seek him.
- I prithee do so.
There's matter in't indeed
if he be angry.
Villain, be sure thou prove
my love a whore, be sure of it!
Give me the ocular proof,
or, by the worth of mine eternal
soul, thou hadst been better
have been born a dog than
answer my waked wrath!
Is't come to this?
Make me to see't, or at the
least so prove it that
the probation bear no hinge
nor loop to hang a doubt on
or woe upon thy life!
Never pray more,
abandon all remorse.
For nothing canst thou to
damnation add greater than that.
O monstrous world!
Take note, take note, o world!
To be direct and honest
is not safe.
By the world I think my wife
be honest, and think she is not.
I think that thou art just, and
think thou art not.
I'll have some proof. Her name,
that was as fresh as dian's
visage, is now begrimed and
black as mine own face.
Would I were satisfied!
How satisfied, my lord?
Would you, the supervisor,
grossly gape on?
Behold her topped?
It is impossible you should
see this.
Were they as prime as goats,
as hot as monkey?
Give me a living reason
she's disloyal!
I lay with cassio lately, and
being trouble with a raging
tooth, I could not sleep.
There are a kind of men so loose
or should that in their sleeps
will mutter their affairs.
One of this kind is cassio.
In sleep I heard him say,
sweet desdemona, let us
be wary, let us hid our loves.
And then, sir, would he gripe
and wring my hand, cry
o sweet creature! Then kiss
me hard as if he plucked up
kisses by the roots that grew
upon my lips, laid his leg o'er
my thigh, and sigh, and kiss
and then cry, cursed fate
that gave thee to the moor!
I'll tear her all to pieces!
Tell me but this. Have you not
sometimes seen a handkerchief
spotted with strawberries in
your wife's hand?
I gave her such a one.
Such a handkerchief, I'm sure
it was your wife's, did I today
see cassio wipe his face.
If it be that
if it be that, or any that was
hers, it speaks against her
with the other proofs.
Now do I see 'tis true.
O, that the slave had
forty thousand lives!
One is too poor, too week
for my revenge!
- Yet be content!
- Blood, blood, blood!
Patience, I say.
Your mind may change.
Never, lago. Like to the pontiac
sea, whose icy current and
compulsive course nev'r keeps
retiring ebb, but keeps due on
to the propontic and the
hellespont.
Even so my bloody thoughts,
with violent pace, shall nev'r
look back, nev'r ebb to humble
love, till that a capable and
wide revenge swallow them up.
Witness that here lago doth
give up the execution of
his wit, hands, heart to
wronged Othello's service.
Within these three days let me
here thee say that
cassio's not alive.
My friend is dead. 'tis done
at your request.
But let her live.
Damn her, lewd minx!
O, damn her!
Now art thou my lieutenant.
I am your own forever.
Cassio! Cassio!
Give me your hand.
This hand is moist, my lady.
It hath felt no age nor
known no sorrow.
This argues fruitfulness and
liberal heart. Hot, hot and most.
'Tis a good hand, a frank one.
You may, indeed, say so
for 'twas that hand that
gave away my heart.
A liberal hand.
Come now, your promise.
- What promise, chuck?
- Let cassio be received again.
Lend me thy handkerchief.
I have it not about me.
- Not?
- No, indeed, my lord.
That's a fault. That handkerchief
did an egyptian to my mother
give.
The worms were hallowed that
did breed the silk.
Then would to god that
I had never seen't.
Is't lost? Is't gone?
Speak, is it out of the way?
It is not lost.
But what an if it were?
How?
I say it is not lost.
Fetch't, let me see it!
Why, so I can, but I will
not now.
This is a trick to put me
from my suit.
Pray you let cassio
be received again.
- The handkerchief!
- I pray talking of cassio
the handkerchief!
A man that all his time hath founded
his good fortunes on your love,
- shares dangers with you
- the handkerchief!
Come, come, you'll never
meet a more sufficient man.
Away. Away!
Away!
Cassio, this handkerchief.
Whose is it?
I found it here.
I like the work well.
'Tis very good!
Shall I see you soon at night?
I will see you soon, bianca.
- Come, lieutenant.
- Cassio, handkerchief.
Take it. Have it copied
thee made for it.
Tell you yet once more,
importune desdemona to
put you in your place again.
Sure there's some wonder
in this handkerchief.
'Tis a year or two shows
us a man.
They're all but stomachs,
and we all but food. Cassio!
They eat us hungerly, and
when they're full, they belch us.
How now, good cassio?
What's the news with you?
What trumpet is that same?
Something from venice.
My noble lord, whilest you
were here, overwhelmed with
your grief, cassio came hither.
I shifted him aways, bade him
anon return, and
here speak with me.
Mark the fleers, the gibes,
and notable scorns that dwell
in every region of his face.
For I will make him tell
the tale anew,
where, how, how oft, how
long ago, and when he hath
and is again to cope your wife.
I say, but mark his gesture.
Marry patience, or I shall say
you're all in all in spleen,
and nothing of a man.
Dost thou hear, lago?
I will be found most cunning
in my patience.
But - dost thou hear? -
most bloody.
- How do you know, lieutenant?
- Lago.
Now, if this suit lay in bianca's
power,
how quickly should you speed!
Alas, poor caitiff!
I never knew woman love
man so.
She gives it out that
you shall marry her.
Ay!
I was talking on the sea bank,
and the bauble falls me thus
about my neck
so hangs, and lolls, and
weeps upon me,
so shakes and pulls me!
- Cassio!
- I must leave her company.
What did you mean by that same
handkerchief you gave me even now?
A likely piece of work that
you should find it in your
chamber and know not who
left I t there!
This is some minx's token.
I'll take out no work on't.
Now now, my sweet bianca?
How now?
After her! After her!
Did you see how he laughed
at his vice?
O lago.
Did you see the handkerchief?
Was that mine?
Desdemona gave it him, and
he hath giv'n it his whore.
I had been happy if the general
camp, pioners and all, had
tasted her sweet body.
So I had nothing known.
What sense had I of her
stolen hours of lust?
I saw it not, it harmed me not.
I slept the next night well,
was free and merry!
I found not cassio's kisses
on her lips.
A fine woman, a fair woman,
a sweet woman.
Nay, you must forget that.
Ay, let her rot and perish,
and be damned.
No, my heart is turned to stone.
I strike it and it hurts my hand.
O, the world hath not a
sweeter creature!
She might lie by an emperor's
side and command him tasks.
Nay, that's not your way.
Hang her! I do but say
what she is.
So delicate with her needle.
An admirable musician.
O, she will sing the savageness
out of a bear.
Of so high and plenteous
wit and invention
she's the worse for all this.
O, a thousand, a thousand
times.
Of so gentle a condition?
Ay, too gentle.
Nay, that's certain.
Yet the pity of it, lago.
O lago, the pity of it, lago.
I will chop her into messes!
Cuckold me!
- Will you think so?
- Think so, lago?
- What, to kiss in private?
- An unauthorized kiss?
Or to be naked with her
friend in bed an hour or more
not meaning any harm.
Naked in bed?
But if I give my wife
a handkerchief
what then?
Why, then 'tis hers, my lord,
and being hers shy may,
i think, bestow't on any man.
By heaven, I would most
gladly have forgot it!
He had my handkerchief!
- Ay, what of that?
- That's not so good now.
What if I had said I had seen
him do you wrong?
- Or heard him say
- hath he said anything?
He hath, my lord, but
no more than
what hath he said?
That he did I know not what he did
what? What?
Lie.
Lie with her?
With her, on her, what you will.
Damnation!
My lord, I say, Othello!
Dost thou mock me?
I mock you not, by heaven.
O now for ever farewell
the tranquil mind.
Farewell content.
Farewell the plumed troops,
and the big wars that make
ambition virtue. O farewell!
Farewell the neighing steed and
the shrill trump,
the spirit-stirring drum,
th'ear-piercing fife, the royal
banner, and all quality,
pride, pomp, and circumstance,
of glorious war.
And o you mortal engines
whose rude throats the immortal
jove's dread clamors
counterfeit.
Farewell! Othello's occupation's
gone!
- God save you, worthy general.
- Pray you.
The duke and the senators
of venice greet you.
I kiss the instrument of
their pleasures.
Is there division 'twixt my lord
and cassio?
A most unhappy one, I would
do much t' atome them,
for the love I bear to cassio.
My lord?
May be th' letter moved him,
for, I think, they do command
him home, deputing cassio
in his government.
- Trust me, I am glad on it.
- Indeed?
- Why, sweet Othello
- devil! Out of my way!
I will not stay to offend you.
Truly an obedient lady.
I do beseech your lordship
call her back.
- Mistress!
- My lord!
What would you do with her, sir?
Who? I, my lord?
You did wish that I would make
her turn.
Sir, she can turn, and turn,
and yet go on and turn again,
and she can weep, sir, weep.
And she's obedient, as you say,
obedient. Very obedient.
Proceed you in your tears.
Concerning this, sir
o well-painted passion!
I am commanded home.
Get you away, I'll send
for you anon.
Sir, I obey the mandate and
will return to venice.
Cassio shall have my place.
You are welcome, sir,
to cyprus.
Goats and monkeys!
Is he not light of brain?
He's that he is.
Let me see your eyes.
Look in my face.
Why, what art thou?
Your wife, my lord.
Your true and loyal wife.
Had it pleased heaven to try me
with affliction, had they rained
all kinds of sores and shames
on my bare head, steeped me
in poverty to the very lips,
given to captivity me and
my utmost hopes.
I should have found in some
place of my soul a drop of patinece
but, alas, to make me the fixed
figure for the time of scorn
to point his slow and moving
finger at.
Yet could I bear that too, well,
very well.
But there where I have garnered
up my heart, where either
i must live or bear no life,
the fountain from the which my
current runs or else dries up,
to be discarded thence, or
keep it as a cistern for foul
toads to knot and gender in.
I hope my noble lord
esteems me honest.
O, ay, as summer flies are
in the shambles, that quicken
even with blowing.
O, thou weed, who art so
lovely fair, and smell'st so
sweet, that the sense aches
at thee, would thou hadst
never been born!
Alas, what ignorant sin
have I committed?
Committed? A thou public
commoner, I should make very
forges of my cheeks that would
to cinders burn up modestly.
Did I but speak thy deeds.
What committed?
Heaven stops the nose at it,
and the moon winks,
the bawdy wind that kisses all
it meets is hushed within the
hollow mine of earth and
will not hear't. What committed?
- Are not you a strumpet?
- By heaven you do me wrong!
- No, as I am a christian!
- Is't possible?
- O heaven forgive us!
I cry you mercy then.
I took you for that cunning
whore of venice that married with Othello
how do you, madam?
How do you, my good lady?
Faith, half asleep.
Good madam, what's the
matter with my lord?
With who?
Why, with my lord, madam.
Who is thy lord?
He that is yours, sweet lady.
I have none. Do not talk
to me, emilia.
I cannot weep, nor answers have
I none, but what should go by water
prithee tonight lay on my
wedding sheets, remember.
Get me some poison, lago,
this night.
I'll not expostulate with her,
lest her body and beauty
unprovide my mind again.
Do it not with poison.
Strangle her in her bed, even
the bed she hath contaminated.
Good, good! The justice of
it pleases.
And for cassio, let me be
his undertaker.
Excellent good!
You shall hear more by midnight.
A halter pardon him!
And hell gnaw his ones!
Who should he call her whore?
Who keeps her company?
What time? What place?
What form? What likelihood?
The moor's abused by some
most villainous knave,
some base notorious knave,
some scurvy fellow!
Speak within doors.
Some such squire he was
that turned your wit the steamy
side without and made you to
suspect me with the moor.
Desdemona.
Get you to bed.
Dismiss your attendant there.
Look't be done.
I do not find that thou deal'st
justly with me.
What in the contrary?
Every day thou daff'st me
with some device, lago.
I have wasted myself out of
my means.
The jewels you have had from
me to deliver desdemona would
half have corrupted a votarist.
You have tole me she hath
received them, and returned
me expectations and comforts
of sudden respect and
acquaintance, but I find none.
Very well. Go to.
I cannot go to, man,
nor 'tis not very well.
I will make myself known
to desdemona.
She will return me my jewels.
If not, I will seek satisfaction
of you.
Now I see there's a mettle
in thee, and even from this
instant do build on thee a
better opinion than ever before.
Give me thy hand, roderigo.
I protest I have dealt
mostly directly in thy affair.
It hath not appeared.
I grant thee it hath not appeared,
and your suspicion is not
without wit and judgment.
If thou hast that in thee indeed
which I have greater reason
to believe now than ever,
i mean purpose, courage, and
valor, this night prove it.
If thou the next night following
enjoy not desdemona,
take me from this world
with treachery.
There is especial commission
come from venice to depute
cassio in Othello's place.
Why, then Othello and desdemona
return again to venice.
Unless his abode be lingered
here by some accident, wherein
none can be so determinate
as the removing of cassio.
How do you mean, removing him?
Why, by making him uncapable
of Othello's place.
Knocking him out his brains.
And that you would have
me to do?
I will be near to second your attempt,
and he shall fall between us.
I have no great devotion
to the deed.
It makes us, or it mars us.
Think on that.
Lago.
Hark! Who is it that knocks?
It is the wind.
I called my love false love.
But what said he then?
O, these men, these men
dost thou in conscience think,
tell me emilia, that there be
women do abuse their husbands
in such gross kind?
There be some such,
no question.
Wouldst thou do such a deed
for all the world?
Why, would not you?
No, by this heavenly light!
Nor I neither by this
heavenly light.
I might do it as well as
in the dark.
Wouldst thou do such a deed
for all the world?
The world's a huge place.
It is a great price for a small vice.
In troth, I think thou
wouldst not.
In troth, I think I should.
Marry, I would not do such a
thing for a joint-ring, nor for
measures of lawn, nor for
gowns, petticoats, nor caps,
nor any petty exhibition, but
for all the whole world?
I do not think there is
any such woman.
Yes, a dozen, but I do think
it is their husbands' faults
if wives do fall.
Say that they slack their duties
and pour our treasures into
foreign laps, or else break out
in peevish jealousies, throwing
restraint upon us,
or say they strike us.
We have galls, and though
we have some grace.
Yet have we some revenge.
Let husbands know their wives
have sense like them.
They see, and smell.
And have their palates both for
sweet and sour, as husbands have.
What is it that they do when
they change us for others?
Is it sport? I think it is.
And doth affection breed it?
I think it doth.
Is't frailty that thus errs?
It is so too.
And have we not affections?
Desires for sport? And frailty?
As men have?
Then let them use us well,
else let them know, the ills
we do, their ills instructs us so.
Good night. Good night.
It is the cause, it is the cause,
my soul.
Let me not name it for you,
you chaste stars.
It is the cause. Yet I'll not
shed her blood.
Nor scar that whiter skin of
hers than snow, and smooth
as monumental alabaster.
Yet she must die, else she'll
betray more men.
Put out the light, and then
put out the light.
If I quench thee, thou flaming
minister, I can again they
former light restore, should
I repent me.
But once put out thy light,
those cunning'st pattern of
excelling nature, I know not
where is that promethean heat
than can thy light relume.
- Othello.
- Ay, desdemona.
Will you come to bed, my lord?
Have you prayed tonight,
desdemona?
Ay, my lord.
If you bethink yourself of any
crime unreconciled as yet to
heaven and grace,
solicit for it straight.
Alas, my lord, what may you
mean by that?
Well, do it, and be brief.
I would not kill thy
unprepared spirit.
No, heaven forfend!
I would not kill thy soul.
Talk you of killing?
Ay, I do.
Then heaven have mercy on me.
Amen, with all my heart.
If you say so, I hope
you will not kill me.
Peace! And be still.
I will so, and yet I fear you.
Why I should fear I know not,
since guiltiness I know not.
But yet I feel I fear.
That handkerchief!
That handkerchief which I so
loved and gave thee,
thou gave it to cassio.
No, by my life and soul!
Send for the man and ask him.
Sweet soul, take heed.
Take heed of perjury,
thou art on thy deathbed.
- Lord have mercy on me.
- I say amen.
And have your mercy too.
I never loved cassion in my life.
I saw the handkerchief.
He found it then,
i never gave it to him.
Send for him, let him
confess the truth.
He hath confessed.
What, my lord?
That he hath used thee.
How? Unlawfully?
Ay.
He will not say so.
No, his mouth is stopped.
Honest lago hath taken
order for it.
What, is he dead?
Had all his hairs been lives,
my great revenge had
stomach for them all.
Out, strumpet! Weep'st thou
for him to my face?
O, banish me, my lord,
but kill me not!
Down, strumpet!
Kill me tomorrow, let me
live tonight!
It is too late.
Now how dost thou look now?
Cold, cold, my girl,
even like thy chastity!
O cursed, cursed slave!
Whip me, ye devils, from the
possession of this heavenly sight!
Blow me about in winds!
Roast me in sulphur!
Wash me in steep-down gulfs
of liquid fire!
O desdemon! Dead desdemon!
Dead, o! O!
My lord! My lord!
What, ho, my lord! My lord!
I do beseech you that
I may speak with you, my lord.
What, ho, my lord!
I had forgot thee.
O my good lord, yonder...,
alas, what cry is that?
Yonder's murders done.
It is the very error of the moon.
She comes more nearer earth
than she was wont
and that makes men mad.
Alas! That was my lady's voice.
O! Sweet desdemona!
Who hath done this deed?
Nobody, I myself.
Commend me to my kind lord.
You heard her say herself.
It was not i.
She said so. I must needs
report the truth.
She's like a liar gone
to burning hell!
It was I that killed her.
She turned to folly, and
she was a whore!
Liar!
Cassio did top her.
Ask thy husband else!
That she was false to wedlock?
Ay, with cassio.
Had she been true, if heaven
would make me such another
world of one entire and perfect
chrysolite,
i'd not have sold her for it.
My husband say she was false?
Ay, it was he that told me
on her first.
An honest man he is, and hates
the slime that sticks
on filthy deeds.
She was too fond of her
most filthy bargain.
Peace.
- Do thy worst.
- Peace.
This deed of thine is no more
worthy heaven than
thou wast worthy her.
Peace, you were best.
O gull! O dolt! As ignorant
as dirt!
I'll make thee known though
I lost twenty lives.
Help! Help, ho, help!
Murder! Help, ho!
Disprove this villain, if thou
be'st a man.
He says thou told'st him that
his wife was false.
I know thou didst not.
Speak, for my heart is full.
I told him what I thought, and
told no more than what he
found himself was apt and true.
But did you ever tell him
she was false?
I did.
You told a lie, upon my
soul, a lie! A wicked lie!
Did you say with cassio?
With cassio, mistress.
Go to, charm your tongue.
I will not charm my tongue.
I am bound to speak.
My mistress here lies
murdered in her bed.
Heaven forfend!
Nay, stare not, masters.
It is true indeed.
Villainy, villainy, villainy!
I think upon it, I think I smell it.
O villainy! I thought so then.
I'll kill myself for grief.
What, are you mad?
Good gentlemen!
I'll charge you get your home.
Let me have leave to speak.
It is proper I obey him,
but not now.
Perchance, lago, I will
never go home.
Nay, lay thee down and roar,
for thou hast killed the sweetest
innocent that ever
did lift up eye.
O, she was foul!
Lago knows that she with
cassio hath the act of shame
a thousand times committed.
O heaven!
Cassio confessed it, and she
did gratify his amorous works
with that handkerchief!
Handkerchief!
- 'Twill out, 'twill out!
- Hold your peace.
I peace? No! I will speak as
liberal as the north!
Be wise.
Heaven! A man, devil did
them all, all, all!
I shame against me,
yet I'll speak.
Oh, thou dull moor, that
handkerchief thou speaks of
i found by fortune, and did
give my husband
she was chaste, she loved thee.
She loved thee.
Othello, did you and he
consent in cassio's death?
Ay.
Dear general, I never gave
you cause.
Othello, your power and
your command is taken off,
and cassio rules in cyprus.
Be not afraid though you do
see me weaponed.
Here is my journey's end.
Here is my butt, the very
seamark of my utmost sail.
Will you, I pray, demand that
demi-devil why he hath thus
ensnared my soul and body?
Demand me nothing.
What you know, you know.
Are there no stones in heaven
but what serves for the thunder?
I pray you, when you shall
these unlucky deeds relate,
speak of me as I am.
Nothing extenuate, nor set
down aught in malice.
Then must you speak of one that
loved not wisely, but too well.
Of one not easily jealous,
but being wrought,
perplexed in the extreme,
of one whose hand like the
base indian, threw a pearl
away richer than all his tribe.
Set you down this.