Discovery of Love
Episode 3
Whenever I see you, I still get mad.
I only remember the difficult times I went through because of you.
I only remember the good memories.
So what?
Han Yeo Reum,
you...
If I ask you if you can break up with that man and come to me, would you?
If you come back...I will never make you cry again.
I...
never forgot anything about you from beginning to end.
From when we started at Jinju Station until we ended at Jinju Station.
10 Years Ago
It was nice to meet you. I'm Kang Tae Ha.
I'm Han Yeo Reum.
Han Yeo Reum... That's a pretty name.
Let's meet again. - Okay, again.
You go first.
Don't do anything stupid.
You even followed me to the bathroom...
Did you look for train tickets to go back to Seoul?
Oppa!
Why is she like this now?
There is a really pretty island around here. Did you hear about Yeonhwa-do?
What 'do'(island)?
Why? - Oppa, you have money, right?
I don't have money!
You get lots of allowance!
I don't have any!
What the..?
Let's go.
I'm not going.
Don't say anything and just follow me.
I don't want to go!
You should smile. Is this a funeral?
I'm not going to go!
Let go of me!
I will let you go when we get to Yeonhwa-do.
It's an island, anyways, so you can't go anywhere.
Hurry up.
Let's go!
Hey, I'm going first.
Hey, hey! Han Yeo Reum!
You two can go! Can't I just visit Soonam in the military?
No! If you go there, you will be called a crazy b*tch.
Please! Why do you interfere so much with my life?
Really! You are getting yourself more in trouble.
Let's go! Let's go!
Is she crazy? Hey!
Oh, Han Yeo Reum!
She doesn't have any money!
Hey!
Oh! What a coincidence.
Oh!
Are you going to Yeonhwa-do?
I told you before, that I'm going to Yeonhwa-do.
Oh, did you?
I didn't hear.
That is a strange coincidence.
Don't you call things like this, "fate"?
We call it a coincidence.
In the beginning, most fates begin with a coincidence.
Well, it depends on how you look at it.
Then, let's say that it's "fate".
I'm about to go crazy. They didn't get on!
You should go now.
Why? Are you waiting for someone?
No...
You were alone the whole time.
You should climb up. If you go up right now, you might see the setting sun at Yeonhwa Mountain.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry to say this when we just met, but can you lend me some money?
Follow me.
Excuse me, I'm not relieved.
That's the last boat, but I don't have any money for a place to stay.
I can sleep anywhere, but I just need a transportation fee to go back to Seoul.
Do you really have no money?
Then when you said that you fell in love with me at first sight on the train, were you serious?
Yes! - You didn't want to just get money?
Look here! What do you take me for?
You didn't follow me here because of money, either?
You have to go to the mental hospital if you are this suspicious.
Do you really, really have no money?
I can't believe you.
They are my friend and a close oppa.
Who?
Oh, the rude couple that were talking on the train?
They didn't get on! I thought they did.
They have all the money, and I only have this bag.
You really have no money.
Please lend me some. I will pay you back in Seoul.
If I lend you money, will you not follow me around?
Of course. I won't bother you.
I thought that you fell in love with me.
I will promise you that I won't bother you.
Then, I can't lend you money.
That man, really.
I don't have anybody I know here,
and you are the only person that I know.
Let's not be like this. Can you look at this world in a more optimistic, beautiful light?
How old are you?
I'm scared. Why do you want to know that?
How are you asking me for money without revealing your personal information?
Your name is Han Yeo Reum. How old are you?
I'm twenty-two.
You said your major was Woodworking and Furniture Design... What school do you go to?
Korea University. - Did you make that ring yourself?
Yes!
Oh, then. Do you want this and lend me money?
A wooden ring?
It's fine.
Aish! He is really evil!
Kang Tae Ha!
Don't! I'm scared!
Stop!
Wow, look at that.
I learned an important lesson in my life today.
I can't trust a man that I fell in love with at first sight.
Why don't you keep those thoughts to yourself? It wouldn't be beneficial to me if I know that.
Since we observed the scenery, can you lend me money now?
I don't have money either. I have to go back down and get some from the bank.
Then you should have done that for me before!
Did you just yell at me?
No.
Let's go back down. It's getting dark.
Let me take some more pictures.
I hope you have a happy trip!
Broken
Is this a dream or reality?
It's reality, reality.
Did you not hear that woman?
She can fix it when the ship comes back! Tomrrow at 2 o'clock in the afternoon.
Where are you going?
Why do you care?
Excuse me!
It's 60 cents.
I'm 10 cents short.
Was that your entire money in your bank?
Only ten cents?
Aren't you hungry?
If you don't want to eat it, then never mind.- Did I say that I didn't want to eat it?
We're in big trouble. Where do we sleep?
Well, I can sleep right here.
No way. It gets really cold at night!
Excuse me!
By chance, is there a community center, school or church nearby? There should be at least one of the three, right?
How do you even know about these things?
If you grow under a mom who often kicks you out for no reason, you learn these tips.
I didn't think they would let us borrow blankets as well.
I'm on this side, and you are over there.
Don't roll over onto my blanket while you're sleeping.
I'm the one who should be saying that.
I've taken care of the money for food and lodging,
so when you get money from the bank at 2 o'clock tomorrow, promise that you'll lend me fare money.
How are we going to eat breakfast and lunch before 2 o'clock?
There is a way.
I'm a woman that could survive being dropped in the middle of the desert.
I think there's a mouse.
What do I do?! I think there's more than one! What do I do?
I thought there was nothing you were afraid of, but you're scared of mice?
I really don't like gray animals, like salamanders.
Do you think it's here, too?
Well, there could be.
Umm, Kang Tae Ha. Yes?
Can't we sleep closer together?
Let's just sleep close together.
I won't do anything.
I'm really innocent.
I'll just sleep really calmly next to you.
Then I'm putting the blankets together.
I'm a bit relieved now.
You're not afriad of men, are you?
What's so scary about men, they are human, too.
It's probably better than mice, we can at least communicate.
Are you sure?
I'm telling you in advance,
I'm very good at Taekwondo, I'm a black belt.
Oh wow, you're an amazing person.
She was an amazing person.
I'm not scared of you at all.
If you can risk your life, then try coming over.
What do I do?? The mice... really...
Please hold my hand.
Let's sleep just holding hands.
Please?
Don't let go. Just hold it and sleep.
♫ In the silent night sky ♫
♫ The beautiful starlights ♫
♫ are far away♫
Hey.
♫ and on the windows ♫
Don't you feel anything weird?
What kind of feeling?
Like something ticklish?
Like something... tingling, too.
And something...
warm and mushy...
Something blooming, too.
I think the ramen from earlier was a bit weird.
It's not the ramen.
It's probably the feeling of something new starting.
What's starting?
Ordinary women seem to call that love.
♫ In the deep night, in that beautiful time♫
♫ You find me like this, and give me your heart♫
♫ This dream of an everlasting summer ♫
♫ I remember it ♫
Hold it and sleep.
Because I like it, too.
♫ With the sound of the soft song ♫
♫ My heart, like a child ♫
♫ To the memories, of the winds and the beach♫
♫ I am running towards it♫
♫ In the deeping night, that beautiful time ♫
♫ Comes find me like this, and gives me their heart♫
♫ Dreaming of an endless summer♫
I... only have memories of the good, soft and sweet times.
How honest you were,
how easily you smiled,
how cute you were,
all that is still very clear in my head.
Even how your lips felt.
You didn't get flustered by what I just said, right?
You have no intentions of going back with me.
Of course, isn't that obvious?!
Then there is no reason for you to not work with us.
You have a boyfriend and have no reason to be shaken by me.
I'll tell you this for sure, I have no intention to start over with you nor any other intentions.
I just found this work place while looking for the perfect work partner.
I hope you don't interfere business with your personal feelings.
Think about it and call me.
What in the world.
So there's a bar over here and on the other side is a wine rack,then how many tables are there supposed to be? Wow.
Yes, CEO.
Can you come to the car within ten minutes, I don't think I can wait long.
We have a GK Apartment meeting at 2 o'clock.
I really can't tell what's on his mind.
He was like that before. It's not like he's playing around with me, but...
he hides his true feelings and plays with people. He did that ten years ago too!
Oh! Money!
Kang Tae Ha, didn't you say you were going to lend me money yesterday?
Hey, what are you doing?
You're really strange.
A promise is a promise.
You had a place to sleep last night thanks to me, and it's not proper if you repay me like this.
You will get out of the island in that ship if I lend you money, right?
Of course.
That's why I'm not lending you money.
Hey, you crazy jerk!
What kind of jerk is he?
I'm a business man. Put simply, a merchant.I need her now.
Also, I have an animal sense to know how to get what I want.
Right now there's only one way to get a hold of Han Yeo Reum.
By pricking her pride.
Her... she'll come over soon.
Like ten years ago.
Ahjumma, one more bawl of water sashimi, please.
Yes.
You ate ramen off of me yesterday, right?
You buy this.
The ship left. So I, with no money, couldn't get on. And it's raining.
I know that.
You're the first jerk that I've ever met in my life.
You could have given it to me ten minutes ago!
Why do you live like this?  - I do what I want.
You're a complete nut job.
Spend just one more day with me.
I don't want to part with you like this.
♫ Could this be love?♫
♫ This strange feeling. And the confusing whispers ♫
♫ There are so many other women in this world ♫
♫Say goodbye oh, I love you. Like fate. A new type of destiny ♫
♫ Like a monsoon on a summer day ♫
I take back the crazy man part.
Oh, also the psycho part. I don't usually say rough things like that.
I must have gone crazy for a second.
Is it spicy?
♫Should we hold hands and walk down the street? It's a nice day♫
♫ I'll even sing songs to you♫
♫We're singing lullaby. How great, how deep, how big is your love?♫
You know, I heard if a person tells a lie here, the boat will shake.
Yeah, right. There's no such thing. Do I look like a fool?You're just making things up.
I'm serious. Do you want to test it?
You like me now, don't you?
You got an ax disease*? I don't! (*delusion that someone's in love with him/her)
Are you okay?
What did I tell you?
You fell in love with me on the train, you followed me to the island, and you completely fell for me last night.
♫ You don't know. My heart beats for you making me confused ♫
♫ This complicated relationship of you and me, is this called love? ♫
♫ What do I do ♫Why'd you get up? Hold onto my hand.
♫ Our complicated relationship. Oh, is this love now? ♫
But... I'm holding your hand.
I was holding your hand since a while ago.
- So you really like me, huh?- Yeah!
What is it?
Wow. It's a heart.
When did you get this?
Earlier in the morning when I was taking a walk.
It's a duck!
Lies.
What is this? There's nothing.
Are you going to keep lying?
I really saw one.
So cute.
So this is is the joined trees.
- Is this your first time seeing it?  - Yes. It's amazing.
There really are branches attached to it.
How much do they have to like each other to become one like that?
See. We're also joined trees now.
I know, right?
Trees are always there, in the same place.
Not harming anyone, they stay still in the same place.
I like it. It makes people feel comfortable.
If I make furniture, I won't let trees go to waste and treat them properly.
If you're a carpentry major, then do you want to open a woodshop store later?
I already have a name made. Summer & Pine Tree.My friend's name is Sol(pine).
I once went to Heuksan-do before I went to the army.
There's joined zelkova trees there and the size is amazingly big.
Do you want to see it with me later?
It's raining.
It must be sudden showers.
Let's go.
It will go the way I want. I'm sure of it.
She will probably call me tomorrow.
She's a person with a lot of pride.
She will want to prove that she doesn't have any feelings for me.
CEO!
I'm just five minutes late.
But seriously... Oh, so hot.
So who told you to run? I gave you 10 minutes.
Don't chew anything hard and...
call me if the problem worsens.
Yes.
I think you're right. It was Ahn Ah Rim that you've been looking for.
But she still hasn't finished college yet.
She's on leave working three part-time jobs to pay for school tuition.
Including this.
What's your relationship with her that you had to search so desperately for her?
Is she someone you knew when you were little?
Excuse me, but are you the doctor that can turn even the most unfortunate face into a goddess?
But is this face possible to work with?
I'm sorry but it will be impossible in this hospital.
Please go to another hospital.
How would you like me to change it?
To Kim Tae Hee.
Kim Tae Hee. Hey, go to another one. Another one.
Hey, she's not much to look at. You're much prettier.
I feel like throwing up.
I'm leaving.
Hold on.
Take this.
Thank you, Kim Tae Hee.
What brings you here, what about your workshop?
I was nearby doing work.
Should we kiss for a bit in the other room?
Do you know how pretty you are when you do that?
Where did you learn to say those cheesy words?
From my mother's dramas.
Wow.
Han Yeo Reum, listen to me carefully.
You work hard all day and come home,
but a friend that knows you very well and is very close with you is waiting for you. It must be nice, right?
Yeah.
But this friend won't go home even if it's very late.
You can play with him all night.
Even if you spend the night cuddling with him in one bed, no one says anything and even mother takes it for granted.
They sleep together everyday and go together everywhere, too.
Even if the two stick together all the time, people don't say anything and actually, they get quite jealous.
I think of that as marriage.
Give me your hand.
Which hand?
It's a bit late because I was thinking of a graceful way to do this.
But I couldn't really think of anything.
Let's get married.
I'll come next time.
Oh- wait, wait!
Hey- wait, catch her!
What's the matter?
You didn't leave yet?
I... just got... proposed to.
Already?
But I still didn't hear an answer.
It must be a rejection.
It's not that.
It's not a rejection.
It's just that I can't right now.
It's a rejection alright.
Ah, I'm so full.
Yeo Reum,
you can just start right now without your mother's help at Ha Jin's place.
Frankly speaking, what do they not have in that house?
I don't want to. It hurts my self esteem.
Ha Jin's mother won't be still either.
Ha Jin is her only child.
And especially... a doctor son.
Hey. You must think that we marry and use our occupation to marry, but these are only a few.
Yoon Sol, what do you think about this?
I miss Choi Eun Kyu so much.
All the men that pass by look like Choi Eun Kyu.
Even in my ramen, Choi Eun Kyu's face bobs around.
Really... I wish I can have a proper conversation with her.
That's what I mean.
What should I do? It's mom.
Was there no money in my bank account?
I took out cash.
Rock, papers, scissors!
Arrgh!
I lose every time!
Clean up, hurry.
Then as of today, Jun Ho is $0, Sol is $1,100, and Yeo Reum is $2,650.
Including what you borrowed when you set up the workshop.
How is it that the debt doesn't shrink no matter how much I pay?
Let me see this.
You count the cost of appendectomy I had when I was 24 as debt too?
It's your body, you should have paid for the surgery.
If you're like this, then I can't be responsible for you when you get old.
Just take responsibility of your own life. I'll take care of mine until I die.
Don't you think this is too much to your daughter?
No one knows what will happen when you get older, Mother.
I like you very much, Mother.
Hey.
Where else would we find a house like this for a room-and-board fee of $500?
When my parents emigrated, my future looked dark,
but I am very satisfied right now, Mother.
You said well.
Imagine if I collect monthly rent after I move out of this house.
It's $1500 for you three combined now, and I'll probably ask for more, right?
Of course.
Aren't you even thankful to me?
It's a relief that I don't do drugs.
That's the truth, Mother.
These days, people over thirty stay home getting supported by parents with the excuse of studying.
I heard you sleep outside often these days.
Mother, do you have CCTV installed here somewhere?
Do you sleep at Ha Jin's?
You should scold her on that, Mother.
You need to live a more sound life.
You're on birth control, right?
Is that all, Mother? When she's sleeping in her boyfriend's house?
Even if you wear a wedding dress pregnant, or even divorce, it's all your life but since I'm your mother, I will warn you this.
Make sure you're on birth control.
You, too.
As expected, our Mother.
You are very cool, Mother!
I respect you, Mother!
So, the world these days is where only the official virgins get the short end of the stick.
Where do I need to go to get my virginity praised?
Mom.
Ha Jin asked me to marry him.
And?
I don't have any money.
Did he tell you to buy the house?
It's not that.
Just do it in range with what you have. Is marriage a big deal?
All you have to do is sign papers.
Don't muster up useless pride and just tell him you don't have any money.
Mom, why are you like this to me?
This is too much.
Am I a daughter Dad brought from outside?
What a load of bullsh*t.
Darn it. Even my teary acting didn't work.
Even though they came out in the perfect timing this time.
What did Mother say?
Can't you tell from her expression?
She probably said "It's your life so you do whatever you want".
The only answer is Kang Tae Ha.
What do you mean, Kang Tae Ha?
He came to our store, asking to work together.
Was I the only one that didn't know that important fact?
Hey! Tell me!
That's not what's important.
If you work with Kang Tae Ha, you can pay off your debt in one shot.
It's not like you still have feelings for him, right?
It's not!
Why do you say it twice, making me suspicious?
It's because Ha Jin worries me.
Trust me.
Ok, listen well.
This could be a very nice way to do revenge.
On the day you finish the job and get paid, you tell Kang Tae Ha,
"With the money you paid me, I'm getting married!"
Isn't it so cool and beautiful and amazing?
Isn't it such a happy ending for you? Isn't it?
Wow, women are so cruel.
I actually do want to give that jerk a taste of his own medicine.
Just feed it to him, feed it to him.
Let's feed it to him.
Let me think about it again.
Ugh.
You're difficult, Han Yeo Reum.
I sent Chief Yoon, so go take a look at the site.
Prepare a design soon and get ready for a presentaton.
What are you going to do?
I'm not doing it. If you want to do it, do it alone.
This is a huge one.
It's a 330 sq. meter (3500 sq.ft) wine bar.
We're just checking out the place for now.
This is the equivalent of 5 sets of wedding furniture.
Are you in the luxury of rejecting work when you can't even get married because you're broke?
Stop poking my painful spots!
Excuse me?
Are you hurt somewhere?
No.
It's nice, right?
The main construction is over and we just need the final touch. Take a quick look around.
We might die while working.
We didn't agree on this deal yet.
Just do it. Let's do it.
Han Yeo Reum.
Stop it.
A fun work came in.
An construction company wants us to do interior carpentry work for a wine bar.
That's nice.
You said that you wanted to expand to interior design once your workshop does well.
Can I do it?
I think it will be fun. I will get to experience how the interior works out.
You'll do it even if I tell you not to.
That's not true. If you tell me not to, then I won't.
Do it. Do everything that you want.
Instead of just looking at me. Kiss.
If you work more, then your hands will be more chapped.
It's okay. You put the hand cream on me every day.
Alright. Let's sleep.
Hold on. I'll check on my mom's situation.
She will probably stay in the office the whole night.
What have you done to me?
It's childish.
What have you done to me to make me like this?
Bullsh*t.
What's wrong with you that you'd say that, Chief?   - Idiot, you don't even know that?
You're all I think of the whole day.  - What?
I'm saying you're all I think of all day!  - Chief.
Such a fool.
Teacher!
You were the one who wrote it...
That's why it's irritating. That I'm writing that sort of stuff.
Yoon Hee. I'm here.
I pity him. He is bereaving without much sleep after his loss.
In this scenario, should I have them kiss again?
Ahn Jin Soo
Oppa, I'm hungry.
Hang on. It's been two days,
so we should be able to get down tomorrow morning.
If we go down today, then you won't have to go with that ahjussi and ahjumma.
Then I can stay with you.
When we go down, we will eat
and oppa will wash you too.
Ah Rim. Ah Rim!
I'm fine, oppa. Put me down. I can walk.
No, oppa will carry-
Ah Rim! Ah Rim!
Ah Rim. Ah Rim. Ah Rim.
Wake up. Ah Rim!
Ah Rim!
Ah Rim! Wake up! Open your eyes!
At first, we thought they hid somewhere inside the nursery.
So we searched everywhere including storage rooms.
Over there. It's Jin Soo and Ah Rim!
Where did you go? Where have you been?
My God. Please call an ambulance!
What do we do. She's badly hurt.
What are you doing? Please call an ambulance!
We'll take care of her.  - Put her down.
No!
What are you doing? We have to take care of Ah Rim's wound.
Don't! I don't want to! I said, no!
If I put her down, you're going to send her away for adoption.
I'm not going!
I want to be with oppa!
Please don't send her away for adoption.
Let's bring her to the hospital first.
Ah Rim. No. No.
Oppa! - No!
Ah Rim!  - Oppa!
Let go! Let go!
Ah Rim, no!  - Oppa!
Ah Rim.  - Oppa!
Ah Rim! Ah Rim! Ah Rim!  - Oppa!
Oppa!  - Ah Rim!
Don't go! Ah Rim.
No...
Did you have a nightmare again?
You're sweating so much. Should I go prepare you a bath? Or should we go take a walk?
Take a walk.
What kind of nightmare are you having that makes you go this way?
Hold on, let me bring a wet towel.
I'm fine.
Please press here for me.
Your heart hurts again?
Stay here to sleep. I will come back later.
I don't want to. I'm coming with you.
You woke up because of me. You are going to be tired tomorrow.
I will not leave you to suffer alone. We are going to through this together.
I love you, Han Yeo Reum.
I told you to drink Camomile tea before bed every night.
It works for insomnia.
Get up.
One, two! ♫Take a chance♫
♫Your heart can be the dance♫
Let's go! ♫If you're afraid to fall, you'll keep missing all the romance♫
One, two, three!
♫All about you♫
♫Even when we're far apart, you can hold my heart forever. It's all about you.♫
♫You know, it's all about you♫
♫Even when we're far apart, you can hold my heart forever.♫
♫Forever♫
♫It's all about you♫
This feels nice.  - It's nice.
It's great we came out. Thanks.
Can I ask you something?
What your nightmare is about?
You get it at least once a month;
those times you wake up from sleep and just sit there.
At least we came out here because I saw you tonight.
If I did not, then you would have come out to the living room and just sat there.
And I would have been sleeping without knowing anything.
It's nothing.
It's nothing, really.
You would have told me if it was nothing. It's not just nothing since you're not telling me.
Like right now, you won't tell me.
It suddenly came up to me.
The secret I can never tell Ha Jin.
I had forgotten I had such a secret as well.
It's okay. You don't have to tell me.
When I was young,
I did something wrong to someone.
I keep seeing the kid in my dreams.
Before, I read in a book,
that someone who has frequent nightmares is an innocent person.
It says that those people have nightmares to atone for even the littlest evil thoughts.
Next time, I will tell you when I'm ready.
I hope you can open up quickly.
You're telling me to run into your arms now?- Yeah!
Just try coming over here.
I love you, Nam Ha Jin.
Wait, it's not the right way.
Look at you sleeping outside often so skillfully.
I hear you check out your mother's schedule with Writer Jang.
I'll make breakfast.
Hey. Pay some attention to Sol.
I thought she was okay for a while,
but she got so drunk yesterday and cried her eyes out. It was no joke, I thought I was going to die.
She went crazy again, didn't she?  - What did I do wrong to deserve this?
Looking after you guys all the time.
I had to hold back the thought of beating up Choi Eun Kyu, yesterday.
Should I just go punch him?
You know they didn't sleep together. Don't you know Sol?
She just looks fine on the outside but she is no better than a fool.
Good morning.
Guess your love life is going well.You're staying out overnight quite frequently now.
Yeah...
The world has become very kind.
Even though a single man and woman sleep together openly,
a so-called mother doesn't even care. Right?
♫ A girl who is warm and humane during the day.(lyrics from Gangnam Style)
♫ A classy girl who knows how to enjoy the freedom of a cup of coffee.
♫ A girl whose heart gets hotter when night comes.
♫ Where is that kind of woman?
Do Joon Ho,
as a man, what do you think?
Men don't have a conscience.
Right, right? - Yes. They are bastards.
I'll be out. - Where are you going?
I'm going to exercise.
We're in big trouble.
How are you? I'm doing well.
I'm riding the bicycle in the Han River. The world looks beautiful.
I'm doing the things I used to do with you alone.
No matter what I do, it's not fun.
Choi Eun Kyu, it's fine if we are friends, so let's meet and hang out.
I miss him.
Why do you miss that kind of rascal?
Where is your pride?
Right, I have to regain my pride.
Yes! You are valuable, Sol.
What are you going to do now...
I thought about why Choi Eun Kyu didn't sleep with me.
It's because I have small boobs.
How big does it have to be from that?
So I'm going to get surgery.
Where? Your boobs?
Yes, I will do it for you.
I will get you water drop shaped breast implants for free.
It's fine. I'm not going to ask you to do it.
Who else would you ask?
Doctor Nam.
So dirty!
Isn't it okay? - No! You can't.
Hey! I'm the professional at breasts.
It's too small. Can you make it this big?
You might not be able to walk.
It's okay.
We're the only ones like this, the competition is no joke.
They're saying they'll work on the renovation no matter what-- So you're going to work for them?
You don't have to put it that way- - Did you check the planning fee?
No, other companies don't have such an item.
And considering the work and view, tell them to go do it somewhere else.
Then we should at least do consultations. Just in case...- Did you see doctors give free consultations to lawyers?
Tell them to pay for the consultation! Then I will be more than happy to do it.
Hey!
I'm still older than you! How can you interrupt all of my sentences!
I didn't this time.
When is Summer & Pine Tree's design coming out?
Next week.
Is she sleeping again?
How are you here?
Let's have a drink.
Why would I drink with you?
Do you think that I would spend money for somebody else's girl? I just want to check out a place.
You really talk meanly.
There is a bar that we can refer to.
Where is that?
This is not really a wine bar, but more like a pub.
The designs and concepts are completely different, but the point in which people can freely hang out is similar.
♬  What should I do? I keep looking at you. ♬
♬ It is too early to call it love, but it seems like it will become love. ♬
Thank you. ♫What's up with me? I don't know if I'll start this love♫
Here, this is the thing that you guys looked forward to the most.
You guys will sing. But you can't sing
just because you practiced. "I'm really bad at singing,
I don't want to."
Even if you are like that, you have to sing if you are pointed at. Do you guys agree?
Yes!
Good. Today, I will point at people on my own.
Between people who are sitting on the standing seats, a woman who is wearing a t-shirt.
Me?
The person next to her that is wearing a peach-colored dress will sing.
Me? - Come to the stage!
I have to sing? - Try it.
You think that I will back out on things like this, right?
Why are you like that? I'm Han Yeo Reum, the hottest woman in this world.
You are pretty! - Fighting!
You're beautiful!
What song do you want to sing today? - Doctor Nam!
Oh, Sol. Are you with Yeo Reum? She isn't answering her phone.
Where are you? Are you outside?
Oh, we're at a bar.
Oh, that song is quite hard to sing, will you be fine?
Where are you that you won't tell me?
You know I have a GPS finder app with Yeo Reum, right?
Han Yeo Reum's boyfriend is coming.
And he's near, too.
Is it ok?-It's a secret that you dated Yeo Reum a long time ago.
How about the band people?
Do Joon says it's best to keep a woman's past a secret. You'll cooperate, right?
I'm going to the bathroom.
♫ If this life that repeats everyday gets boring, tell me ♫
♫ I'll try to become a little bit of strength to your heart that is always tired.♫
♫ When you want to see movies that are trending these days, tell me ♫
♫ Even your smallest desires are happiness to me too ♫
♫ On a Sunday afternoon with no plans made ♫
♫ When you wake up late from a nap and feel sad for no reason ♫
♫ Next to you, is someone that understands you more than anyone else is this world♫
♫ There's a woman who thinks of you first than myself♫
♫ I've watch you for a long time♫
♫ You can come in my embrace and rest all you want♫I found the reason why I wasn't able to forget her for a long time.
It was because she was Han Yeo Reum. Just...since Han Yeo Reum is Han Yeo Reum.
This man has Yeo Reum.
It's not jealousy. Well, if you call it jealousy, I can't say anything.
It's just, I was curious whether this man knows
how great of a woman he has.
♫ Even your smallest acts of frustration is happiness to me♫
This man knows how precious the thing he has.
I felt it. The glaring pride.
I apologize for the inconvenience.
My phone got switched with the man I saw at the hoteland when I went to get my phone back,
I ended up sleeping at his house.
♫ I watched over you for a long time ♫
♫ Come in now and rest comfortably ♫
♫ Go back in time, if we can meet again♫
♫ If we can love again, I can give up everything else♫
♫ Go back in time ♫
Discovery of Love
Preview
Explain to me. How you ended up working with that man, too.
The two of them, they have too many coincidences.
Doctor Nam found out that Kang Tae Ha and Yeo Reum dated for five years.
That guys are all cool about a woman's past, that's all a lie.
Did you guys sleep? You slept together, for 5 years!!
What's wrong with that? He must have been surprised.
You sleep so well anywhere.
How can a human not sleep?Do you have some tonic hidden and eat it alone?
- I only sleep when I see my girlfriend.- That's why you always get dumped.
I never got dumped before.
Think again. There should be one.
I hope you won't let me misunderstand things on my own.
You can hold my hands if you want.
I keep losing you.
Do you have any plans to fix that scar?
What kind of guy is your boyfriend?
Why are you suddenly curious about my boyfriend?
- Why do you see that punk?- Why do you call him punk?
Is your eyes for men that bad?
What are you to act like you know another person's love life?
You must have a woman?
You like Han Yeo Reum, don't you?
Why? I can't like her?