Jesus!
Stonebridge?
- I'm going in!
- No. Fall Back. Repeat. Fall Back!
It's Connolly.
Are you fucking kidding me?
It was just a bit of fun.
We had the charge set to explode
away from your body.
Not that you knew that.
Which was the fun part.
Oh.
No calls? You didn't even go
for your phone.
You strapped a fucking bomb to my chest.
Who am I gonna call?
My mom?
Ask her to defuse the fucking thing?
You sick fuck!
Scott's alive.
Repeat, Scott's alive.
- Well, you passed.
- Oh?
And now it's time to claim your prize.
Just the one, mind.
Show him. Come on.
Colonel.
Look, Kate, one day you're gonna be
where I am
and you're gonna have to make
these decisions for yourself.
I knew Connolly would vet Scott
in the most extreme manner.
I told Scott that he
was not to flinch in any way.
Not to make a play,
not to call for help.
Even if he thought he was going to die.
Did you order him to go in?
I gave him an informed choice.
He volunteered, knowing exactly how
dangerous Daniel Connolly is.
Do you have previous with Connolly?
Northern Ireland was my first posting.
I'd been there three days when
Connolly broke into the home of
a delivery guy.
He delivered groceries to the barracks.
Connolly tied up the man's family
in the front room and told the guy
that if he didn't drive a lorry full of
Semtex into the barracks
that he would kill his family
in front of him.
But if he did what he was told,
Connolly promised to spare the lives of
his wife and children.
The explosion killed five soldiers and
maimed dozens.
I was first on the scene.
And the man's family?
Daniel Connolly is not a man to keep
his promises.
They've moved to the compound.
- Bank job?
- You don't need to know.
You just need to do your job.
Yeah, which would be what, exactly?
To override the security.
Do I get to see this place beforehand?
Fuck.
What about there?
Not your concern.
Cracking the access codes for here,
that is.
You okay with that?
Yeah, well, as far as a future-proof and
impenetrable encryption
data storage unit goes, looks fine.
I'll need to run some checks
at my place.
What's this?
Hugo, the guy before you.
They're the codes he was working on.
Hey. You can take the shiny stuff
and nothing else.
I want you back at the bar in two.
Stonebridge.
Do you have a visual on Scott yet?
- Affirmative.
- Is he okay?
I think he'll come through.
Fuck!
Kate.
I've been looking into it
like you asked.
Read this.
You look like shit.
Yeah, they fucking blew me up, dickhead!
Sorry I don't look fucking better.
You know, I've met some
sick motherfuckers in my time,
but Daniel Connolly...
I'm fine by the way, thanks for asking.
Sorry about that, mate.
How are you feeling, you all right?
- Fuck you.
- I saw what happened back there.
Oh, you saw that, did you?
Did you learn anything?
- You're reckless, Scott.
- Excuse me?
She's a fucking terrorist.
You know fucking shit. Don't worry
about me, buddy, I'll do my job.
Really? You're gonna put a
bullet in her?
Yeah, if I have to, she's the bad guy.
You're the one that's banging one
on the home team.
Look, I told you, Kate and me
is none of your fucking business.
It fucking is if it's gonna get
me killed out there!
Sort your shit out, Michael.
For your sake.
For Kate's, especially for Kerry's.
Your wife? Remember her?
You say Scott did this
from memory?
And he only had eyes
on them for seconds.
Looks like it relates to the same site.
- One appears to overlay the other.
- Mmm.
If this is an ATAT facility,
there'll be anti-ram barriers,
acoustic infrared sensors.
Ballistic-resistant entry points.
You name it.
Not to mention more guards
than even Connolly could kill.
This looks like some sort of
tunnel system running underneath.
Scott said the maps looked much older
so this structure could have been
there for years,
decommissioned, forgotten about.
Well, whatever and wherever this is,
Connolly's going in by the back door.
Try again.
All right.
Route at 10,
dot, 105,
dot, 0,
dot, 57.
M-K
D-I-R, dot.
No. That's not right.
Argh!
Try again.
All right, uh...
These documents date back
to 2003. Now, take a look at this.
- Excuse me, sir.
- No, not right now.
Mahmood. Pakistani weapons scientist.
We know what length Latif went to
capture and interrogate her.
Now, it turns out that up until 2003
she's on ATAT's payroll.
Mahmood and Bratton. Baghdad in 2003.
Days before Porter got him out of there.
Now, what if, right,
Bratton and ATAT had intended on
planting a chemical weapons stock
in Iraq,
giving the Pentagon hawks
what they wanted
and making a killing
when the war started?
Shit.
If what you're saying is right,
there's been a huge conspiracy here.
Where some very influential people
go a long way
to make sure none of this
ever comes out.
Where are we?
Scott saw the code that
Connolly's hacker used.
Right, do we know what it was?
Well, we have the data
and we have the device
but we also need the
initialisation protocol
that they used to hack into
ATAT's security system.
Can we use it to hack?
Only if we get the exact code.
One wrong character,
it's completely useless.
Oh, come on,
having a photographic memory
and trying to remember all this shit's
really fucking hard
with all you people talking.
Shut the fuck up.
The guy before you, he was working on...
Try this.
D-I-R,
slash, root at 10,
dot, 105,
dot, 0,
dot, 57.
- We're in.
- Well done.
Fuck, yeah.
Did you see that?
I've implanted a worm
on this hard drive.
Scott needs to open the system
with the drive and the code,
the worm will then allow me to remotely
bypass the proprietary firewall
and work on the system from here.
Right, only one problem, dude,
I don't speak geek.
You just remember the code.
Leave the rest to me.
- But you will need to buy me some time.
- Yeah, how much?
A few seconds.
Shouldn't be a problem for Damien Scott,
world-class bullshitter.
So that opens the vault?
No, hacking into the system will bypass
the base site security
and avoid triggering the alarm.
Right.
All right. How do we get in the vault?
Hmm, most likely a biometric key.
Retinal scan, fingerprint match...
From a high-ranking executive like...
- Bratton.
- ...Kenneth Bratton.
All right, I'm out of here.
- Hello?
- It's Ken Bratton. I need to see you.
I can't speak over the phone.
We have to meet somewhere safe.
- Looking forward to that drink together?
- What drink?
She's here, got to go.
- Hey.
Where's everyone else?
Busy.
All right.
What are you worried about?
- I'm on orders to keep you relaxed.
- Hmm.
Bratton's scared. He wants to meet in
a public place.
- You think he's telling the truth?
- I do, yeah.
This is about his children.
You know Colonel,
if we're right and bring Bratton in,
this puts an end to Connolly's plan.
You could pull Scott out.
Captain, nothing would give
me greater pleasure
than chopping Connolly off at the knees.
But his plan needs to succeed if he's
to lead us to Latif.
Connolly could be coming for
Bratton at any time.
I want you to extract him
quickly and quietly
so we can brief him and put him back to
work with Connolly
under our protection.
All right, you're his contact.
You're running point.
- Yeah.
- Okay?
Copy that.
Kate, let me get in close.
You run point.
- He asked for me.
- Yeah, I know he did but...
But what?
Scott told me about Connolly.
If something goes wrong
or it's a trap...
Michael, I don't need you protecting me.
Look, I know you don't need me
protecting you.
But I care about you.
I know.
Lovely family, Ken.
I can't speak over the phone,
we have to meet.
I just want to know that
my family are going to be safe.
You wanted to see me, Ken?
Darin, there's certain things
I need to tell you.
Oh! Fuck me!
Please, please, please will
you just stop, stop, stop,
Oh, my God.
Oh.
Wow.
That was amazing.
You really know what you're doing, huh?
I trained for two years.
Pleasure and pain. That's me.
You know, if you're that good
at something...
Nobody wants to pay for a massage,
not since the credit crunch.
So, uh, you just become some
terrorist groupie, hmm?
You don't know Daniel.
You don't see what he stands for,
what he believes in.
Anyway, live fast, die young.
So what happens if you don't die?
Who'd you rather see in the mirror
in 20 years' time?
A happy masseuse with a couple of kids?
Or just some cold-hearted soulless
bitch with black holes for eyes? Hmm?
Fuck you.
Hey.
So how many people have you killed?
Where the fuck are they?
Visual on principal.
Visual clear. Moving to transport.
Copy that, initiating contact.
Yeah?
Walk to the end of the street,
take a right at the coffee shop.
Wait for me at the windows outside.
- Mr Bratton.
- Am I being followed?
Relax, we're going to get out of here.
- What about my family?
- They're fine. You need to come with me.
Yeah, I have to know,
I have to know that they're safe.
They'll be safe. We're 50 yards from
making that happen.
- You just need to come with me.
- No!
I need to know
that they are safe!
Kenneth, I need to get
you into the car.
Christ, how the hell
did I get into this?
Is the principal secured?
Negative, walking away.
We'll talk about that,
come with me, get into the car.
No! You have no idea the pressure
we were under.
They wanted, no, God knows, they
needed to find chemical weapons in Iraq.
Listen to me.
It was never, never supposed to be.
- Get into the car, Ken.
- Kate, bring him back.
That's why, that's why I hid it.
Principal is not secure.
Repeat, principal is not secure.
When I found out what this damn thing
could do to millions of people
- with just a few drops...
- Okay, I'm listening.
You're talking Sarin?
You're talking VX?
- Yes, and you must understand...
- What the hell is going on?
- Move!
Move! Get down!
Shit!
Neve, we're moving now.
It's true what they say. You can take
the girl out of Ireland...
Connolly is after a chemical weapon
for Latif?
Yes, Sarin VX. That's what Kate said.
We have to get our hands on it first.
Kate?
We do not deflect from this mission.
All right. We still have Scott
on the inside.
And we have no way of knowing
where Kate is.
That's not entirely true, Colonel.
Maintaining lock on Scott's phone.
Heading east.
Signal is slowing.
You're not fucking serious. Come on...
Oh, very fucking sneaky. Nice.
Why'd you change the schedule?
Are you getting cold feet?
We've lost Scott's phone.
I don't remember giving you an order
to put a tracking device on
Captain Marshall.
Give them the tracking reference and
then get out in the field and find Kate.
Yes, ma'am.
So what is this place?
Patience.
How are you holding up, Ken?
I have a surprise for you.
They've got my family!
Now, come on, Ken.
Remember Ramadi.
Remember the lies I told for you.
I put my neck on the block for you.
And just because you've lost your balls
doesn't mean you're gonna
take me down with you.
We've got Marshall's signal.
It's the same location as Scott.
So, as we discussed.
Ken's not leaving?
Nobody's leaving.
Now, I've got to ask.
What's a nice girl like you
doing working for the colonial enemy?
Spare me the prehistoric shite.
You see, I'm thinking it's a
childhood thing
that you've uh, never...
Well, you know, playing soldiers
in the back garden
with your brother... No, brothers.
Always wanting to be one of the lads.
Enough about me.
Did you always want to
be a cold-blooded butcher?
No,
it wasn't my first calling.
Don't tell me,
you want to become a priest.
No. As a matter of fact,
you know I've never told anyone
this before
but I always wanted to be a jockey.
On the level.
When I was 15, I jumped school
and hopped on a bus to Fermanagh
to work at a stable out there.
You know, mucking out, grooming.
I even got to ride a couple of times.
It was the greatest week of my life.
And then, on the Saturday,
the head lad calls me in and says
we have to let you go.
Why was that?
I frightened the horses.
They 're on the move.
Sending new co-ordinates.
So basically, we're just gambling that
Marshall will be with Connolly.
If she's still alive, it's because
Connolly has a use for her.
We're getting transmission interference.
Her signal's down.
I'm patching through last co-ordinates.
Roger that, on my way.
According to Captain Marshall's last
known position,
I think the tunnel's under
this facility.
All right, what is it?
It's a factory making fertilisers,
agricultural chemicals.
A shell company for ATAT?
A hiding place.
You're on.
Mind giving me a bit of space?
Please?
D-I-R, breaker at 10, dot,
105, dot, 0,
dot, 50.
Okay.
Scott's online. Okay. Here we go.
The worm's not loading.
All right. Doors,
access...
Voilà...
- What's the problem, Major?
- I don't understand it.
Come on!
Fuck.
Fuck, it's not loading!
Uh, I don't know what's going on.
Activated! Okay, okay.
The worm is uploading.
Come on!
Denied?
Not denied. Not recognised.
Come on, come on. Work, damn it. Work!
Have we a problem?
Come on!
Damn it!
The worm! It works! Okay.
ID, password. Please.
We're in.
I've never doubted you.
Watch him.
It's a bit late to find your spine, Ken.
This is nice.
Open it.
Do you have any idea what this is?
I have no fucking clue. Pack it!
What are you gonna do?
You gonna kill me?
If that's what he tells me to do.
I'm on his side, remember?
He's got no side. All right?
It's just him against everyone else.
He's killing everyone else.
Think about it.
Come on. As soon as I'm done here,
he's gonna kill me.
Shut up. Shut the fuck up!
That's it.
Soon as you're done,
he's gonna kill you.
Who are you?
Who the fuck are you?
What about my family?
You'll never know.
They've detected the worm.
No!
Fuck me.
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Grenade! Get down!
Another grenade. Move!
Connolly, drop your weapon!
Come on, Scott!
Capture, Michael.
Do not fucking kill him!
He's up, he's up, come on!
Connolly, stop! Don't move!
Put the weapon down, Connolly!
Put it down!
- Put the fucking weapon down.
- Put it down!
Gently.
- Now, get on the ground.
- On the ground.
Connolly, get on your fucking knees!
Get the fuck on the ground!
Typical fucking British,
always giving orders.
Get on the ground.
I think you should look
in the van, lads,
can't have too much insurance,
you know what I mean?
You watch him.
No, Michael, Michael!
Shit.
Kate...
It's all right.
Okay.
You like that?
You fucking piece of shit!
I should have shot you when
I had the fucking chance.
Some of my best work.
Shut the fuck up! Shut up!
We have an anti-handling device here.
- There's a tilt switch, yeah?
- Yeah, that's right.
That mercury moves, it will detonate.
You have to stay still.
These charges are shaped to blow right
towards you. You feel anything else?
Yeah, there's something, um...
Cold, uh...
There's metals digging into my stomach.
No, I can still cut through
this cable here...
- No, it's wired to the bomb.
- No, it's all right,
I can get this off of you, I just need
to see what's behind the cable.
Besides we both know
there isn't any time.
Switch it off,
switch the fucking thing off!
Yeah, I can switch it off,
but you'll have to let me go.
No fucking way!
You've won. You got your
fucking apocalypse back.
Now, what I'm saying is,
I can disable that timer remotely.
That is bullshit!
But I'll need a10-yard start!
No, no, Michael!
You think I haven't done this sort of
thing before?
You fuck!
Yeah, go ahead, shoot me!
Go on! He will not fucking do it!
Scott, we have to give her
a chance, mate.
There is no fucking chance and
he's playing you!
Come on, soldier.
What other choice do you have?
- Or maybe she's not worth it!
- Fuck!
Michael, Michael!
Michael, he's a fucking liar!
Tick-tock, lads.
I can't let her die.
- Tick-tock!
- He's not gonna do it.
Michael!
100 yards.
It's all I need.
- Michael, he won't fucking do it.
- Shut up, Scott!
- Michael, he's fucking lying!
- Michael, no!
- He'll not get the bomb off her!
- Shut up, Scott!
Promise.
Shit.
Fuck!
- We got the weapon.
- What have you done?
- It's fine, we got the weapon.
He promised!
He promised.
- What have you done?
- He promised.
Bitch!
Time to go.
Michael, look at me.
Do you love me?
Sergeant, you will obey this order!
- I'm sorry, Kate.
- Michael, get the fuck out.
You always had my back.
Come on! Move!
- I'm sorry... Kate!
- Move it!
Come on!
Kate!
Kate! Kate!
Yes?
My friend, a thousand apologies.
Until now he had proved very reliable.
The reputation of a man like Connolly
relies on results.
Let him know I am
extremely disappointed.
Of course. But I assure you this is
only a temporary setback.
Crawford's contact is still in place.
I know where the remaining stock
can be found.
Fellas.
What took you so long?
It didn't seem like you were
going anywhere.
You're right.
I figured between you and Latif,
I got tired of running.
Sorry about your friend,
but you know how it is.
I had a dream about you, Eleanor.
So I did.
I'd like it to be you.
Soldier to Soldier.
You were never a soldier!