WOMAN: Thank you so much,
Mr. Clark.
I really appreciate it. Thank you.
GIRL: What are you reading?
The Hulk vs. Wolverine.
I'm Ava.
I think I've seen you around school.
You're in Ms. Blanchard's class,
right?
BOY: Almost ready, Ava?
This is my brother, Nicholas.
- Hi.
- Oh.
Come on. Let's go.
You wanna come hang out?
Oh... Sure.
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
Where the hell do you think
you're going? (SNEEZES)
- (SNIFFLES) Open up your bag.
- What?
Don't think I didn't see you rob me.
Open your bag.
I didn't take anything.
(SIGHS)
And a liar too.
That's why you were talking to me.
So your brother
could put that stuff in there.
Henry, I'm shocked.
And you two...
Just who do you think you are?
(CRACKING)
(SIGHS AND SNIFFLES)
A fine specimen.
The wood it provides will keep
our family's hearth warm this winter.
- Can't I have an ax?
- Huh?
You did say you wanted me here
so I could help.
That I did. So here is your task.
Take the cart. Go fill it with
kindling. The drier the better.
Okay.
And have your brother accompany you.
Okay. Come on.
Wait.
(PANTING)
Take this.
Your compass?
So you don't get lost.
A family always needs to be able
to find one another.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Go.
- Thank you.
Be safe.
(OWL HOOTS)
It's getting late. We should go.
(ROCK THUDS)
Hey! Give it back.
Come on, Gretel. Give it back.
No, Hansel.
We need to get back to Father.
Fine.
Follow me.
This is where we left him.
So why isn't he here?
- Father!
(MAN GRUNTS)
Father!
- Father!
- (HOOVES CLOPPING)
- (GASPS)
- (HORSE WHINNIES)
(SNORTING)
Get up.
(GRUNTING)
What are you doing in my forest?
I'm sorry, Madam Mayor,
but your son was shoplifting.
Were you?
Well, look for yourself.
My son doesn't eat candy.
And he knows better than to steal.
It was obviously those two.
We're going.
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
Henry? What happened?
Ms. Swan. Must I remind you
that genetics mean nothing.
You're not his mother.
And it's all taken care of.
I'm here because I'm the sheriff.
REGINA: Oh, that's right.
Go on, do your job.
Take care of those miscreants.
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
Did you call their parents?
The number they gave me
was disconnected.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Did you guys give
Mr. Clark a fake number?
Then why is it disconnected?
'Cause our parents
couldn't pay the bill.
You guys are just trying
to help out, huh?
Please. Please don't arrest us.
It'll just make things worse
for our parents.
Please forgive us.
We didn't mean to bother you.
We just...
Well, we just lost our father.
Two helpless children,
lost and alone.
A family torn asunder.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
Such a sad and moving story.
Guards,
seize them.
Hansel, run!
(WHOOSHING)
- (CLANKS)
- (GASPS)
(HORSE WHINNIES)
- (WHOOSHING)
- (LAUGHS)
Running from me is foolish.
(LAUGHS)
- (CROW CAWS)
- (ROOTS CRACKING)
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS) Foolish,
but also brave.
(GRUNTS)
And that bravery
may just have saved you
and your family's lives.
You're letting us go?
Oh, I'm doing so much more than that.
I'm going to find your father.
You are?
Why?
Because you two
are going to do something for me.
And then you'll take us home?
This it?
Please. No.
If our parents see you,
they'll be so embarrassed.
Did Henry tell you
about my super power?
We just met him.
I have the ability to tell
when anyone is lying.
So tell me the truth.
Money problems aside,
is everything okay at home?
Yeah. We're great.
Can we go?
All right.
(ENGINE STARTS)
She's gone. We're good.
(GRUNTING)
(CLATTERING)
EMMA: Why did you guys lie to me?
(BOTH GASP)
Where are your parents?
We don't have any.
Do you know them?
Do they go to your school?
I've seen them, but I had no idea.
None of us did.
Ava and Nicholas Zimmer.
They said their mother
was a woman named Dorrie Zimmer.
She died a few years ago.
No one seems to know her
or remember her.
And the father?
There isn't one.
At least not one that they know.
What does...
What does Social Services say?
You didn't report them.
I report them, I can't help them.
They go into the system.
The system that's supposed to help.
Yeah, says the woman
who wasn't in it for 16 years.
Do you know what happens?
They get thrown into homes where
they are a meal ticket. Nothing more.
These families get paid
for these kids.
And as soon as they're too much work,
they get tossed out
and it all starts over again.
They're not all like that.
All the ones I was in.
What? We're just gonna adopt them?
I wanna look for their father.
They don't know him.
He may not know they exist.
And you think if he knows
he'll want them?
I don't know.
But what I do know,
is it's hard enough finding foster
families to take one kid that isn't theirs.
Let alone two.
It's their best shot or...
(CRYING) We're gonna be separated?
No. That's not gonna happen.
AVA: Please.
Please don't let it.
Excuse me,
(MISPRONOUNCES)
Mr. Krzyszkowski?
It's "Krzyszkowski."
Everyone calls me "K."
Mr. K, I am Sheriff Swan.
I'm hoping to look
at the birth certificates
of Ava and Nicholas Zimmer.
All right, just fill out this form
in triplicate.
Okay.
I'm so sorry.
Those documents
have been recently removed.
By who?
Don't worry, Ms. Swan, you can relax.
I've contacted Social Services.
It turns out these kids
are on their own.
They need help.
Which is exactly what I'm trying to
do. I'm trying to find their father.
Well,
he doesn't exist.
He has to.
Of course, biologically, he exists
but there is no record of him.
Which means we have no choice.
These children need a home. So they
will be put into the foster system.
Storybrooke has a foster system?
No. But I've contacted the state.
Maine's group homes,
unfortunately, are filled,
but they put us in touch
with two homes in Boston.
A boys' home and a girls'.
They're separating them?
I don't like it either.
But we've got no choice.
You need to have them
in Boston tonight.
Me?
Well, you wanted to be sheriff.
This is what sheriffs do.
Yes, you're taking them.
No. I promised them
they wouldn't be separated.
Well, then perhaps you should stop
making promises you can't keep.
These children need a home.
I'm just trying to find the best one.
What is that?
My father's compass.
He gave it to me so I could find him.
But now it's broken.
When are you gonna tell us
where we're going?
This is close enough.
Close enough to what?
The home of the Blind Witch.
That doesn't sound good.
She has something of mine.
And I need you to get it back.
What is it?
Something I need to defeat a very
wicked and powerful enemy.
It's kept in a black leather satchel
inside her house.
Why don't you get it yourself?
How come you need us?
Because the house
is protected by magic.
I can't enter.
But luckily the spell
doesn't work on children.
You'll have to wait here
until nightfall.
And then, once the witch is asleep,
you can sneak in.
And if we do this,
you promise you'll find our father?
Oh, indeed I will.
But there's one more thing.
The witch's house is
unique.
And because of this, you have to take
special precaution once you're inside.
Like what?
No matter what you do,
no matter how you're tempted,
don't eat anything.
Any luck?
No.
I know who they are.
A brother and sister. Lost.
No parents.
Hansel and Gretel.
Anything in there about the dad?
Just that he abandoned them.
- Great.
- (CLOSES BOOK)
Sounds like a familiar story.
Whoever this guy is,
he could be in Laos by now.
No, he's here.
(SCOFFS) And just
how do you know that?
'Cause no one leaves Storybrooke.
No one comes here.
No one goes. It's just the way it is.
I came here.
Because you're special.
You're the first stranger here, ever.
Right. I forgot.
Well, if he's around here anywhere,
I'm gonna find him.
Can you tell me about him?
I don't know anything yet.
Not their father. Mine.
I told you about your parents,
now you're even living with your mom.
Mary Margaret isn't...
She's...
Never mind.
Please.
I was pretty young.
I had just gotten out
of the foster system.
And the only job I could get was at
this 24-hour diner just off the interstate.
And your dad
was training to be a fireman.
He always got the worst shifts.
So he'd come in
and order coffee and pie,
and sit at the counter,
and always complain
that we didn't sell pumpkin pie.
But he always came back
the next night anyway.
Did you get married?
(CHUCKLES) Oh, no, nothing like that.
We just... We hung out a few times
outside of work.
And life happened.
His got better and mine got worse,
and I got in some trouble.
When you went to jail?
(INHALES) Yeah.
Before I went, I found out
I was pregnant with you.
And I tried to contact him.
And I found out
that he died saving a family
from a burning apartment building.
So, you think I'm a savior, Henry?
He was.
Your father was a real hero.
Do you have anything of his?
Something you can remember him by?
Something I could see?
I...
I don't.
Henry. I'm sorry. I gotta go.
I may know how to find this guy.
I want to show you guys something.
What's that?
It's my baby blanket.
It's something
I've held on to my whole life.
It's the only thing that I have
from my parents.
I spent a lot of time with
a lot of kids in your situation,
and all of them,
all of us,
we held on to stuff.
I want to find your father,
but I need your help.
Is there anything of his
you've held on to?
I might have something.
But if I give it to you,
you'll make sure
we stay together, right?
Right.
A compass?
Our mom kept it.
She said it was our dad's.
Thank you.
Did you find them?
Who?
Your parents.
Not yet. But I'm gonna find yours.
(MOUTHING) No.
Shh.
(WHISPERING) How can you
be sure she's sleeping?
I can't.
And remember what the Queen said.
Not even a lick.
(SNORING)
You were right. Look.
And there's the satchel.
What do you think is inside it?
Doesn't matter.
All that matters is getting it to
the Queen so she can find Father.
- (RATTLES)
- (SNORTS)
(CONTINUES SNORING)
No.
(MOUTHING) No.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SNIFFS)
(SIGHS)
(BOTH GASP)
I smell dinner.
(SIGHS) Mmm!
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Emma. How lovely to see you.
I'm flattered you'd take time off
your busy schedule for me.
What can I do for you, Sheriff?
I'm looking for information
on this old compass.
Any idea where
it could have come from?
Well, well.
Look at the detail.
You know, this is crystal.
This jeweled setting.
And despite
the rather unfortunate shape it's in,
this is actually
a very unusual piece.
The person who owned this
obviously had great taste.
And where would someone
like that buy it?
Right here, of course.
You know it?
Indeed. A piece like this
is difficult to forget.
Do you happen to remember
who bought it?
(CHUCKLES)
Well, I'm good with names, Ms. Swan,
but maybe not that good.
However, as luck would have it,
I do keep quite extensive records.
And yes. Here we are.
What's your price?
Forgiveness.
How about tolerance?
Well, that's a start.
The compass was purchased
by a Mr. Michael Tillman.
Anything else?
Just a name.
But I generally find
that's all one needs.
Good luck with your investigation.
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
Not possible.
Actually, it is.
Well, I'm sorry.
Look, Dorrie, she wasn't my...
It was just once.
Sometimes that's all it takes.
I met her when I was camping.
And we...
No. It's not possible.
I don't have twins.
Yes, you do.
You have twins that have been
homeless ever since
their mother passed away.
You have twins who've been living
in an abandoned house
because they don't wanna be separated
from each other.
Your twins are about
to be shipped off to Boston
unless you step up
and take responsibility for them.
Look, I can barely manage this
garage. I can't manage two kids.
And why are you so sure they're mine?
Besides the timing?
Have you ever seen this?
I lost this.
Let me guess,
12 years and nine months ago?
I know it's a lot.
Believe me, I know.
A month ago, a kid showed up
on my doorstep I gave up for adoption
asking for help with something.
And I ended up moving here. For him.
I heard about that.
It's the mayor's son.
But staying in town is a lot
different than taking him in.
I don't have my kid
because I don't have a choice.
You do.
Those kids did not ask
to be brought into this world.
You brought them into this world.
You and their mother.
And they need you.
And if you choose not to take them,
you are gonna have to answer
for that every day of your life.
And sooner or later, when they find you,
because believe me, they will find you,
you're gonna have to answer to them.
I'm really sorry. I am.
(COMPASS RATTLES)
I don't know anything
about being a dad.
If it's a good home
you're looking for, it's not with me.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
Hey, it's me. I need you
to come outside right away.
Is everything okay?
Don't say anything in front of
the kids, but no, it's not.
(GIGGLING)
He doesn't want the kids.
And you don't want to tell them.
I can't.
Because all I'll be telling them
is that the false hope I gave them
was exactly that.
The truth can be painful, Emma,
but it can also be cathartic.
I agree on the painful part.
Hey, look. You told Henry the truth,
that his father is dead,
and he's handling it great.
I didn't tell him the truth.
What?
Henry's father was no hero.
And trust me, he does not need
to know the real story.
Maybe we can hide the kids.
Just until we can find a family for
them, someone to take care of them.
Yes, hiding the 12-year-olds
is a good plan.
You have a better idea?
Maybe there isn't an idea.
Maybe you just have to...
Sheriff?
Shouldn't you be on the Interstate?
What are you doing here?
Seeing to it that you do your job.
You know you don't have to check up
on me. I know what I have to do.
Really? Because those kids are
supposed to be in Boston tonight.
(SLAMS)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(SING-SONG) Where are you?
(CHUCKLING) Oh!
Yes! Nice and tender.
A succulent roast you'll make.
(SIGHS)
(CREAKS)
(WHISPERING)
Gretel, she's gonna cook me.
We gotta do something, quick!
Stay calm. When she opens the cage
to get you, don't try to fight.
Then while she's
carrying you to the oven,
grab the key that's in her pocket
and toss it to me through the bars.
(GASPS)
Hmm.
She's coming. She's coming.
I can't do it. I'm gonna die!
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
Gravy or butter?
What shall it be?
- Ow!
- (GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(SING-SONG) Come with me, little boy.
(CHUCKLES)
(HUMS)
(CLANGS)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(GRETEL GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
Gravy or butter?
How shall I baste you?
(WHIMPERS)
Butter it is.
Time to cook.
(GRUNTING)
Oh! (GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
- Quick, Gretel, lock her in!
- (LOCK CLICKS)
BLIND WITCH: Let me out!
Let me out! You come back right now!
Let me out!
You'll pay for this!
(SCREAMING)
I would've gone gravy.
(FOOTSTEPS)
My dear children.
Were you successful in your task?
Yes, Your Majesty. Though we were
almost made into dinner.
Oh, how barbaric.
Now, if I could have my satchel.
I've waited
a very long time for this.
Let's hope you didn't let me down.
(GASPS)
You did it.
Yeah, we did.
You've got a strong heart, girl.
You remind me of myself at your age.
We did all that for an apple?
Trust me, dear boy,
this is not just an apple.
It's a weapon.
A weapon for a very particular
and devious enemy.
One who's still under the illusion
that she's safe.
Whatever your plan is,
we did what you asked.
Now you have to keep your promise
and find our father.
Of course.
To reunite your family.
So you can live happily ever after.
You were left alone in the woods.
You deserve better than a father
who would abandon you.
(VOICE BREAKS) But he's all we have.
Perhaps he doesn't have to be.
What do you mean?
You and your brother
have impressed me.
You aren't the first boy or girl
that I've sent into
that sticky sweet house.
But you are the first to emerge.
And as a reward,
I've decided to invite the two of you
to live with me
here.
You mean we get to live in a castle?
(LAUGHS) Yes.
You would have your own rooms,
of course.
Personal carriages, and valets, too.
All of your dreams could come true.
No.
We want our father back.
He would never abandon us.
And even if he did,
we would never want to live
with someone as terrible as you.
Is that so?
Yes. We're going to find him,
with or without your help.
And when we do,
we're going to prove you wrong.
We'll see about that.
(WHOOSHING)
Gretel? What's happening?
EMMA: Come on.
It's gonna be...
Here.
I'm sorry. But we gotta go.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
Let's go, Henry.
No. You can't take them.
They can't leave Storybrooke, Emma.
They can't.
Something bad will happen.
Something bad has already happened.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(ENGINE STOPS)
Are you kidding me?
What happened? What's wrong?
Engine stalled.
(BEEPING)
- Who are you calling?
- Help.
QUEEN: Now she's cavorting
with dwarves?
When did that happen?
Your Majesty,
the prisoner you requested is here.
Bring him in.
(CHAINS CLINKING)
I demand to be released.
My children are in that forest
that you took me from, alone.
They could be in great danger.
Yes. I know all about your children.
That compass
you gave sweet little Gretel...
Well, I'm afraid it didn't help her
find you, though, now, did it?
What have you done with them?
Tell me where they are!
Gone. I told them you abandoned them,
leaving nothing
but a compass to find their way.
But I didn't bring you here
to answer your questions.
You're here to answer mine.
I offered your children everything,
whatever their hearts desired.
And they still chose uncertainty
because of their blind faith in you.
Tell me why. Hmm?
Why did your children refuse me?
Because we're a family.
And family always finds one another.
No.
Release him.
You're letting me go?
You can all be together,
as a family,
as soon as you all find one another.
(OWL HOOTS)
Hansel, wake up. Hansel.
(ANIMAL HOWLS)
She let us go.
I'm scared.
Don't be. Everything will be fine.
Nicholas, look.
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
(TRUCK DOOR CLOSES)
Those are them?
Those are them.
And your car? It's fine.
I just wanted you to see them.
Just once.
I didn't think I could do it either.
I gave up Henry 'cause I wanted
to give him his best shot.
And when I saw that he didn't
have it, I couldn't leave.
I was just as scared. More, probably.
But once I saw him,
I got to know him,
I couldn't go back.
And you're taking them? To Boston?
I don't have to.
No. You don't.
(DOOR CLOSES)
- Hey. What happened?
- (SIGHS)
Their dad.
He showed up. Changed his mind.
Changed his mind.
Just like that?
He might have had a little nudge.
They found their father.
That's great.
I wonder what that would be like.
Maybe you'll find out.
You can't give up.
I don't know.
I kind of think giving up
might be the best plan.
I think I need to let go.
No, you don't.
Really?
If they wanted to know me, they
wouldn't make it so hard to look.
Maybe.
But maybe there's other reasons.
Maybe there is an explanation.
(SIGHS) If there is, it's something crazy.
Something even crazier
than Henry's theory.
- Yeah, what's Henry's theory?
- Well,
that my parents put me
in a magical wardrobe
and sent me to this world
to save them.
(CHUCKLES) Oh!
And who does he think they are?
- (CHUCKLES)
- Well, for one,
you.
Me.
Well, Snow White.
Snow White has a kid.
Apparently that book you gave him,
not exactly the stories
in the most traditional sense.
(CHUCKLES)
I have a kid.
You'd think I'd remember that.
Yeah, you'd think.
You do kind of have my chin.
(CHUCKLES)
I think I need to go get some air.
I'm gonna go think.
If you're gonna be back late,
I can wait to eat with you.
No, don't do that.
I'll leave you leftovers.
What a pretty blanket.
Thanks.
Good night.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SNIFFS)
(EXHALES)
What's that?
Just an old file. What's up?
Pumpkin pie.
I thought you'd like some.
It was pumpkin, right?
Right.
(SIGHS) Henry, about your father...
Yeah?
I'm glad I told you.
Me too.
(SIGHS)
Give me that.
What you did, with Ava and Nicholas.
You really are changing things.
(ENGINE ROARING)
Hey.
Is this Storybrooke?
Yeah.
Any place to get a room around here?
You're staying?
That's the plan.
Just looking for a bed.
Granny's Bed & Breakfast is just
up the road. Another two blocks.
Thank you.
Hey, I didn't catch your name.
That's cause I didn't give it.
(ENGINE STARTS)
I thought you said strangers
don't come to Storybrooke.
They don't.