[ Narrator Reading ]
[ Pilot On Radio ]
I'm offbase, bound for Arctic North.
We'll be out scouting.
[ Man On Radio ]
There's plenty out here.
It's just a matter of finding the right one.
[ Pilot ]
If we can find a base up here somewhere
that looks like it'll be workable,
I'll go ahead
and set down on the top.
[ Man ]
7601. This is one of
the highest peaks out here.
Let's go see if we can get in up there.
[ Pilot ]
That sticks up above everything.
Oh, it's gonna be "nukin''"up there.
[ Man ]
I could see somebody doing that,
if the conditions are right.
It'd be one of the hairier lines,
I can guarantee that.
[ Pilot ]
Gotta play a really fine line
getting in and getting back out.
[ Heart Beating ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Crowd Cheering Fades Away ]
[ Cheering Resumes ]
Feels good to be back in A.K.
Alaska's so good
because of the long runs
and really steep runs.
And it has tons of terrain.
It's just a mecca for
free-riding snowboarding.
I didn't know it was going to
be, like, bam, bam, bam, all around.
It's freakin'amazing.
[ Teter ]
I'm just looking to have
an awesome time and learn a lot...
and hopefully gain
some new skills.
I think everyday is going to be,
like, the best day of my life.
You know?
This is really where
all the gnarliest stuff I've ever done
happened, you know,
where I really pinned it to the wall
and, like- and threw down.
When you're
sitting down in the lodge
or at your house thinking about it,
you have a lot of
delusions of grandeur.
And then, the closer you get
to the top of that mountain,
a lot of that stuff melts away...
and you're just
trying to survive.
Look at that track.
Look at that track right there.
It's really strange to start out
as a beginner again at a new thing.
I know nothing
about the mountain.
And the scariest part about it is,
you can'tjust, like, go on pure luck in Alaska.
'Cause that doesn't really work.
[ White Laughs ]
Oh, man,
this is gonna be so much fun.
Can't wait to hook up
with the Farm.
Can't wait to hang out with Terje,
and meeting Shawn and Hannah.
You know, I've seen them on TV
and in the mags and movies and stuff,
and I'm stoked to
actually get up there and ride,
take them to my backyard.
Anytime you can get four generations
of talent and knowledge
and ability together,
it's gonna be explosive.
just to be back here with all these guys,
you know, especially Farm
back on our home terrain,
it's special-it's one of those
once in a lifetime reunion trips
that you only dream about.
And with Terje here,
somebody that,you know,
I hold in the highest regards-
He's the best snowboarder
in the world, really.
Terje has been like the guy
I've always looked up to...
because he was the best
in the pipe and in the park.
He was always
backcountry riding.
[ Farmer ]
He's a pretty reserved
and pretty low-key dude.
Once you get him out there,
I mean, he's just like a cat. He flies.
[ Perata ] Shaun and Hannah
being here for their finrst time,
and their,you know, freestyle ability level-
it's a once-in-a-lifetime deal.
There's a big gap here.
We're talking 20 years.
I think that all goes away,
really, once you get up here
and start riding together.
It's great for me.
It just makes me feel young,
even though I'm old.
Nick and Farmer is one of
the pioneers from Alaska.
They've been here
for a lot in the past.
And it helps a lot
having that experience here.
[ Perata ]
Back in the old days,
it was free and wild,you know.
It really was.
It was carefree, and everything
was the finrst descent.
You know where you were going,
there was no other person
ever has ridden.
[ Farmer ]
Nick just was all about Alaska.
Hejust knew
that's what he wanted to do.
Now he's been guiding
for 1 3 years.
He didn't even ride a resort ever.
Hejust rode-pow.! Rode choppers.
I'm stoked just to see...
that the top freestyle performers
are willing to come up here...
and risk their lives just to ride
and get better that way.
[ Farmer ]
If you just take it from a money aspect
or your investment,
and you look at this Shaun White dude
and he's, like, worth all this dough,
and I'm thinking, I can't believe they're
even gonna let him come up here,
'cause we all know
that people have been taken out
by mountains like this.
; Back in A.K.
Beautiful day ;
Remember what happened last time
we stayed in this cabin, Farmer.
What happened?
Wow.
Look at this view.
Holy schizzel.
Pop-a-whizzle.
Yeah, Nick!
Yeah, Farm.
Back again.
Which do you like more, Hannah?
*NSYNC or Boys II Men?
[ Laughing ]
I would have to say Boys II Men.
[ Teter]
Oh, yeah!
[ Perata ]
Something like this
with,you know,
all these generations of snowboarders,
is definitely historical.
It's priceless.
It really is.
[ Narrator ]
In the 1 970's, snowboarding emerged
from the backwoods of America.
It was an unknown sport with roots
based on freedom, flow, self expression...
and a lifestyle that offered
a truly unique feeling that defied description.
During its brief,
but chaotic history,
snowboarding would battle the establishment,
overcome prejudice and fght to keep its soul.
And in just 25 years
it would spread around the world...
and change the face of sports
as we know it today.
Snowboarding is so young,
and it came about so quickly,
that there wasn't really a chance...
for the history to lay itself down
and be concrete.
Any town you go in in the U.S.,
there's always some old-timer
that comes up with a story like,
""Oh, I was the first guy
to ever snowboard.
I took a water ski and I cut the back off
and I put a rope on there.
I invented snowboarding. '"
I'm one of those guys
that's, like, I'm not the inventor.
I'll never say I'm the inventor.
I'll never say I'm the first.
There's always been somebody before you
that's had the same idea or something similar.
To me,
it was more of an evolution.
Snowboarding has been around
longer than any of us even know,
maybe over a hundred years.
[ Richards ]
I believe that snowboarding's
more about the pioneers that started it.
jake influenced the growth
of snowboarding on the East Coast.
Tom Sims and Chuck Barfoot influenced
the growth of snowboarding on the West Coast.
And then a sport was born.
[ Man ]
He was a strange breed.
"Individualist'"
would be an understatement.
jake Burton was definitely
one of the visionaries,
if not the main one
to put the sport over the top.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
[ Burton ]
I got exposed to the whole concept
of snowboarding through the Snurfer.
The Snurfer was a product
that was made in the '60s.
It had no bindings,
and the early ones had no fins.
So it was just almost rodeo style.
But there was something there.
[ Ranquet ]
Tom was coming from a surfg
and skateboarding background.
He went about it a different way.
I wanted to be able
to surf the board.
Well, surfing in those days
was all about nose riding.
So, I didn't think of
having a big kick on the front.
I just wanted to be able to hang fve
and ride across the hill.
Looking back, it's kind of amazing
I didn'tjust grab a water ski out of our garage...
and go ride it down the snow.
'Cause it would have saved
many years of development for me.
It was a process of developing
product that could stop
and turn right and turn left.
Definitely a lot of creativity
and a lot of failure.
;[ Ends ]
[ Narrator ]
By the end of the '70s,
the pioneers had finrmly laid down the roots.
But snowboarding's future
and its survival remained uncertain.
[ Farmer ]
People didn't even know what it was.
There was no instructors, no lessons.
There was no set way to do it.
There was no book.
[ Barfoot ]
There was so much variation
in where it was going.
'Cause snowboarding
wasn't really a sport yet.
It was only a few of us doing it.
Ah.! Digger.! Yeah.!
[ People Cheering ]
[ Burton ]
It was a pretty tight fraternity,
and we were all passionate about the sport.
But there wasn't this feeling of sort of,
hey, we're building something.
We were just riding and, unknowingly,
progressing the sport at an incredible rate.
This is a map
of the Chugach Range here.
The Chugach is just one of
many, many mountain ranges in Alaska.
Whatever you want's out there.
If you want cornices, they're out there.
If you want wind lips, it's out there.
And the whole thing is,
just make sure
you find the one that you want.
Back in the early days,
when everything was untouched,
you could just go
right across the street
and get an untouched mountain.
This is a good example
of most of the runs up here.
Steep, gnarly at the top.
You cannot see
your first four or five turns.
But once you get over that edge,
everything comes into place.
Looks pretty steep,
that one mountain right there.
It's always going to look steeper to your eye
when you're flying in a helicopter
or when you're looking at a photo.
It's still going to be steep,
but not as steep as-
To me it works opposite.
Really?
I get into it,
but, damn, this is steep.
This is steeper than I thought.
That's what I'm concerned with-
going off,like, a wind lip
or something and then just-
'Cause I've never really
landed in powder that often.
Like, landing and then rolling.
[ Perata ] Go at your own pace.
You want to come back here.
You want to ride here again next year.
This place is gonna show you
where your limits might be.
just ride to your ability level.
Which, you're all
the best riders in the world
in the freestyle genre.
And you can be the best riders in the world
in this free-riding genre too.
I don't know-
I've never really been in
a controlled environment...
where I had to watch out
for upcoming stuff...
and look forward and be, like,
""I gotta think about this before I do it''
instead of just go for it.
Gotta actually visualize
and map it out inside my head.
If you can see the bottom,
follow Farm.
- If you can't see the bottom, don't follow Farm.
- [ White ] Don't follow Farm.
Alaska, to me, to my friends,
is the pinnacle of snowboarding.
There's nothing
as big and vast and grand.
Once we got here,
we knew that's where we wanted to be.
It was like, God, this is rad.
Pretty much everything you can ask for,
like a big mountain rider-
somebody who wants to have
a really good time on a snowboard.
[ Perata ] There's so many
undiscovered mountains out there still
that no one's even seen.
It's just unfathomable
how many mountains are out there.
[ Farmer ]
Once you ride powder,you never forget it.
It's like a drug. It brings you back every time.
I'm a little scared.
At first, I was really scared.
Like, man,
I've never done this stuffbefore.!
It's just such a different mind-set out here.
You get a respect for how big everything is.
Avalanches
are our biggest concerns.
Crevasses. It's always scary.
You never know what to expect.
You just have to know your outs,
know where your safe zones are.
[ Farmer ]
You have to be aware
that something can go wrong.
And when it does,
it's usually catastrophic.
[ Perata ]
You'll never be totally
comfortable up here. Never.
And if you are,you shouldn't be here,
because all around you the mountains are alive.
Unless you're fully prepared to be
in a situation oflife or death,
you shouldn't be up here.
[ Farmer ] You can't get lulled
into a sense of anything being routine
up here, because it's not.
When you're flying and you're
getting on top of these mountains,
you better pay attention
to what the hell is going on.
Because one mistake is going to cost you
your life or your friend's life.
[ Perata ]
Biggest thing that would bum me out
is if somebody got hurt or killed up here...
in my backyard, in the place
that I've been riding for 1 5 years.
It's always been my thing.
I feel like the mother hen out here,
and, you know, I would feel responsible.
It always crossed my mind that I'd end up
coming out here when I was a lot older.
I always thought that I'd master everything
and then take over on this thing.
I think it'd be a good time for me
now, though, to get some experience.
If something spectacular happens
or it's obviouslyjust got to be that way,
then I'm ready to throw down like that.
But at the same time,
I'm not going to try to kill myself, really.
At least until towards
the end of the project.
[ Bottle Drops, Shatters ]
[ Man ]
You're out of control.
Oh, man.
[ Farmer ]
Big mountain riding
is definitely in my blood.
He likes to come back here,
but he'll never really ever live here.
Because he's got to either have
the mountains or the ocean, I think.
If I didn't get to
come back home to my parents,
I'd probably- I'd be in a box.
A cardboard box by the Dumpster.
[ Laughs ]
Shawn's favorite sign in the whole world
is the store that has- What, Shawn?
[ Shawn ]
Guns, liquor, ammo.!
Pull.!
[ Gunshots ]
You won't get that.
I knew you wouldn't get that.
I thought we were going this way!
We're going to.
Pull!
There it goes.
[ Gunshot ]
Hey!
Going back to Alaska for me is-
I wouldn't call it a comeback 'cause I've
been here the whole time,you know.
But it's gonna be
an excellent opportunity.
I'm excited just to get up there
and do some chopper time.
[ Gunshots ]
Yeah, I want to show everybody
that I've still got some skills.
And for sure up there, I know I can-
you know, I can get with anybody
up on a big mountain.
Pull!
[ Gunshots ]
I knew you'd miss.
Oh, you got it on the second one.
Nothing wrong with that.
How do you like me now?
Shawn had this
antiestablishment thing.
And that's what appealed
to all the young people.
He gave them a sense
of a free-riding spirit...
that did what he and they thought
was the right way...
to do and express yourself.
The bad downside to that
would be,
you have to live up to some
pre-concept that people have.
So everywhere you go, they expect you
to, like, break bottles over your head
or something,you know?
Orjust do something crazy.
That was the hard part to deal with.
And I think that's
one of the reasons why...
among the-
what I want to call the subculture-
I'll say the snowboard culture-
that's why he's been able to
retain the following that he has.
[ Farmer ]
I came out in a movie
called Totally Board One.
I think when that movie came out,
it really did rock the industry.
I ended up doing
that Mount Baker Road Gap,
which was a mythical beast.
Maybe some people had done it,
but, mostly, people just talked about it.
And that's when I realized
that was for me.
I just became
a big mountain rider.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
I ended up getting some money,
starting getting paid to snowboard.
I couldn't believe it,you know?
I'm getting checks year round, you know.
I'm getting checks in the summer.
Even before that,
I was already a little bit out there.
And then now,
this was like gas on the fire.
;[ Rap Metal ]
;; [ Rapping ]
[ Don Farmer ]
I always told him,
you know,you can'tjust go out here
and do what you want to do.
When you're in the corporate world,
that doesn't always work.
And it cost him dearly.
I never had a plan.
I didn't even care about money.
I just wanted to have a good time.
And my good time ended.
If your, like, fairy tale goes wrong,
then you have to have a backup plan,
and I really didn't.
[ Saw Buzzing ]
[ Man ]
We actually bought
our finrst snowboards together.
I think joe bought
both of them, actually.
Well, I'd just wrecked his car.
I backed it into a telephone pole.
But I'd already wrecked his car
way before.
[ Ford ]
So his mom was paying me
some money,
and we went and bought
snowboards with it
instead of fixing his car.
[ Don Farmer ]
Shawn has never quit
pursuing what he liked.
He has stayed right there.
He's done it and done it.
And I used to think, well,
he'll finally say, "That's it, '"
and throw up his hands.
He never has.
And as far as I'm concerned now,
as old as he is and what he's been doing,
he never will.
[ Farmer ]
The early days of snowboarding...
were definitely something
that can never be duplicated.
It's like rock and roll in the '50s
or something,you know?
People didn't even really know
quite what it was.
And I'm just fortunate to have
lived through it and been part of it.
[ Narrator ] The next wave of snowboarders
was inspired by the hard-charging
skate and punk movements of the '80s.
These antiestablishment influences
would fuel a clash of cultures
that would last for over a decade.
Snowboarding was a direct
descendant of skateboarding.
Definitely surfing had its place
in influencing what snowboarding did.
But as soon as people fgured out
how it would actually ride on snow,
they wanted to do skate tricks.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
It was all about slashing
and finding walls...
and trying those skate maneuvers
on my snowboard.
I think it was a pretty rowdy crowd
at the beginning.
Snowboarding was basically,
you know,just punk rock kids
just wanting to go out and thrash,
be aggressive
andjust try to express themselves.
They're, like, a lot ofkids
with a lot energy.
The music we were listening to
told us to, you know, thrash, have fun.
Fuck authority.
Freeze!
Not that funny.
[ Richards ]
This whole, like,
anti-authority movement...
definitely pushed the sport
in the direction of free thinking-
you'd go and do what you wanted to do.
The sport was yours to mold.
We were stoked to be a part
of something that felt like our own.
It wasn't welcome at all from the skiers.
[ Man ]
Is that good enough?
I think so.
I think when
snowboarding came along...
and the skier establishment
saw this new thing that they
really didn't understand,
they couldn't help
but reject it and try to ban it.
I remember the first day
we went snowboarding.
We weren't allowed on the ski lifts.
So we hiked up
along the side of the run.
And I remember getting heckled
from the skiers, and that look, like,
what are they riding on?
There was less than half a dozen
ski areas...
that allowed snowboarding
on planet Earth in 1 982 and 1 983.
The ski industry
thought that this was a fad-
"We want nothing to do with this. '"
I'd get letters from ski companies saying,
""Stop making these things.''
[ Burton ] We knew we were entitled to it.
I think there was this feeling
that it was going to happen.
But,yeah,
when big resorts caved in
you'd get a phone call-
""Hey, we can get on Vail.''
And it was, like, ""No way!''
It was such cool news at the time.
All of the sudden there was
these weird people on their hill,
and they didn't follow a tradition in skiing.
[ Man ] We were taking creative lines
down the mountain
that skiers weren't taking.
They thought we were going to
injure ourselves or injure some other people.
Which was not really the case.
Was there a prejudice from
skiers towards snowboarders?
I think absolutely.
Snowboarders seem to be
a little wilder and take up more room.
We were standing in line
and three of them cut in front of us.
Wejust didn't want to bug with them
because we thought they
might have guns or something.
And I think, as I look back in my career,
when it was really a bad boy image,
snowboarders, I must admit,
deserved some of the criticism
they were getting.
They're looking down at you,
and you like that, though,
when you're a kid.
""Yeah, I'm a scumbag.
I'm riding a snowboard.''
What it did is gave you
that angst and that energy
to go out and prove them wrong.
You know, prove to them
that you could go out and enjoy it
just as much or more than they could.
There was some behavior
and attitude problems.
There was a lot of language
from both sides.
I hope you get hit in the face.
You're an asshole to everyone
who goes by here.
[ Barfoot ]
You got a kid with
a lot of freedom in his mind...
and someone turning around,
telling him,you know, "I hate snowboarders. '"
So, he turns around and is, like,
"I'm going to do what I want. '"
And then it turned into,
like, almost a mental war.
Theyjust weren't ready to let go of their skis
and get on a snowboard.
Even though
I'm a little bit of a geezer,
I've been snowboarding myself
full-time for six years.
I've never been back on skis.
I took it up when I was 60
andjust ride with
all the young guys around here.
It's great.
I've been totally hooked for six years,
and I just don't ski anymore.
Usually, I don't ride with people
in these mountains...
unless they're really good
at using all the safety equipment-
probe pole, beacon, harness.
You need to know who's in your group
and what kind of skills they have
with this type of gear,
because it could be my life
that they're trying to save.
Seven-four!
Seven-one!
Me and Farm
dug them both out in four minutes.
That's survivable time with no
brain damage or anything like that.
Maybe some hypothermia.
So if they beat four minutes,
then I'm gonna say, ""Yeah,
they were listening real good.''
If they don't beat four minutes
and it comes to seven, to eight,
now, potentially,
we have a body recovery instead of,
you know, saving your friend.
All right, this way.
So, we'll see.
Are we getting so close?
I'm finding it.
[ Beeping ]
Okay. There you go.
Here it is- point-six.
Dig it.
I hit something.
Is it squishy?
Oh, yes.
It's right there, baby!
Time!
[ Woman ]
Did you get it?
Yeah!
Every time I've been told about
the backcountry, they'rejust
like, "Listen,you know,
even though your friend's buried,
you still have to take your time
and just find him.''
I mean,
there's no use in just panicking
and going like this everywhere.
It just doesn't do anything.
They found the beacon in two minutes.
They found it quicker than me and Nick.
So I'm sure they can handle it.
[ Teter ] A while ago, Shaun and I
were talking about, like, whoa,
we've never done this before.
Like, we don't wanna die up there.
Not bugging out about it,
but being, like, I don't know-
feelin'a little stressed on it.
You know, I want to be safe,
but I still want to learn a lot.
I want to learn about backcountry riding.
And I want to progress,you know.
[ Perata ]
This is called Kiwijunior.
It's a good little run.
It's not too much exposure, but there are
places where you can get hurt, definitely.
It's probably some of
the best snow that we've found.
So, there's four or fve lines
in here that we can rip.
And it's just kind of a little warm-up
for the finrst shot of the day.
Once you drop in, the slough's
going to be on either side of it.
So you gotta get on the middle.
If you don't get on the middle,
you're gonna get pulled off either side.
There's a little
chocolate chip to the left.
See it?
We land the helicopter,
and you look at this big mountain face
and you're, like, ""Okay, pick your line.''
And I'm trying to look
at the mountain that way,
but I don't see it.
There's just so much going on.
It's hard to focus.
[ Perata ]
They are so out of their element up here.
It's a gut-wrenching feeling
when you know they can do it,
but are they gonna
be able to do it?
[ Man On Radio ]
Three, two, one.
[ White ]
It's just different being up here...
because it's no longer
just, like, little runs.
It's like every run's its own mountain.
I'm not used to it at all.
That cliff at the bottom was huge!
[ Laughing ]
It was just a flat-
I'm, like, shaking.
That was a big one.
I came off therejust, like, oh, no.!
[ Imitates Scream ]
And it's so much bigger
than it looks.
I'm getting into it though.
It's so much fun.
Let's do it again.
It was probably one of the
coolest rides I've ever done in my life
'cause it was just so new to me.
I don't know, afterwards,
I felt like I'd accomplished this huge feat.
Even though it was, like,
one of the mellow runs of Alaska.
I just felt, still, that it was
just such a big thing for me.
So many things
could have gone wrong,
but they didn't.
[ Nick On Radio ]
There's a great line for Hannah.
just tell her to almost follow my tracks.
Keep them on her skier's left side.
Andjust-
tell herjust to trust it.
Tell her to trust me
andjust stay on that ridge
andjust slowly work her way down it.
Yeah, Hannah!
[ Teter ]
Nick's always given me tips, no matter what,
even if I don't ask for them.
He'll just finll me
with some good information.
And he's just making sure
I'm safe.
I really appreciate
having someone behind my back,
even though I just met him.
Oh, yeah, guys. Yeah, Nick.
Thanks for radioing up
and reassuring me. That was cool.
I was all, like,
""Yeah! He said it's good!''
Good job.
[ Perata ]
Me and Farm,just for us
to come back up here...
to where our eyes
got opened-
We told ourselves back in '89
that this is it-
we will always come back here.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
just to be able to hang with him
in these mountains,
where we both got our start...
and our end of our career,
it's-it's awesome.
He's just one of a kind, man.
He's a one-of-a-kind character.
If you ever wanna go ride
a snowboard with somebody,
he's one of
the funnest guys to ride with.
;[ Continues ]
[ Haakonson ]
Yeah, the finrst day, me and Shawn
went up for this afternoon run.
It's kind of cool to go with Shawn.
He's got such good skills.
So, I was not, like, afraid he was
gonna not make it or adapt to it.
I think that was the least problem.
I was kind of stoked
I'd probably get to go first.
[ Laughs ]
;[ Continues ]
[ White ]
The worst was, standing up
at the top with Terje...
and then I'm just
thinking over in my head,
like, my mom and dad, like-
I'd gotten, like,
four sit-down talks with them-
""Okay, I know Terje is gonna go with you.
Don't let him take you up anywhere.''
I was just standing up there like, wow,
I'm just doing the total opposite
of what everybody's told me.
It's just kind of getting over that fear
of what everybody's telling me...
and just kind of
taking my own look at it.
;[ Ends ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ White ]
I'll be honest-
I had a little shake going.
I was, like-
Like right before you drop in,
like, the X-Games pipe,
you got a little bit of a shake going.
And that's exactly what it was.
I was just like, okay, well, if it slides,
you're just gonna fly that way.
Oh! It was fun.
It's just such
a different mind-set out here.
I'm such a far ways away from
where I was just a couple weeks ago.
[ Man ]
Grand marshal.
You're an honored guest here
of Mountain Dew...
at the final
Mountain Dew Southern 500.
And you'll give the command to
start the 43 engines this afternoon.
Yeah, the
""start your engines!''
Jeff, real quick.
Shaun White, our grand marshal.
What's going on? Nice to meet you.
Good to have you here.
Hey, thanks.
You're awesome,
what you do on that stuff.
[ Laughs ]
Actually, my snowboarding boots
are your boots.
Oh, really?
That's awesome!
Yeah! Did you hear that?
That was awesome!
Oh, dude, Gordon's
gettin' a snowboard in the mail.
[ All Laughing ]
[ P.A. Announcer ]
And now, race fans, will you please
welcome back Shaun White.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please join me in saluting...
the running of the final
Mountain Dew Southern 500.!
[ Cheering, Applauding ]
Gentlemen,
start your engines!
Whoo!
[ Engines Revving ]
[ White ] I never would have thought
being grand marshal at NASCAR.
You know what I mean?
There's just so many opportunities
within snowboarding
that I'm starting to realize now.
He is a mainstream celebrity,
whether he likes it or not.
He's on TV. Kids know his name.
They know that he's one of the
best snowboarders of all time.
He's also one of the most amazing
skateboarders we've ever seen.
;[ Rock, Fades ]
[ White ]
I did japan for, like, 1 0 days.
I got home from that
for, like, a day or tw0-
straight to NASCAR.
And then after NASCAR,
here we are- Hollywood.
Oh, no.
[ Sighs ]
The only thing that wears me out
is just, like, the time zones,
because, like, you get home
and you want to sleep
and then you got to stay up.
[ Groans ]
There's the back.
I hate looking
at the whole calendar...
'cause it's just, like,
you look at this whole calendar...
and the whole thing's just covered
in red ink and you're, like,
"Oh, I have to do all that. '"
I just try to take
the one month at a time.
[ Director ]
Stand by.
I feel that when the mainstream
comes into snowboarding,
it's really good, I feel.
Because the more money
that gets in the sport, it ends up
bringing more things back home.
The week has been crazy.
The mountains are taking
half their budget to make a sick park,
so kids will show up and ride.
And I think that's one of
the coolest parts about the mainstream
coming into our sport.
[ Announcer ] Shaun White,
two-time defending gold medalist.
The man is focused.
He told me at the beginning of the week,
"I am hungry for competition. '"
We will see ifhe can get it done
and get his third gold.
[ White ]
For me, the X-Games is just something
for me to look forward to.
It's always the biggest event
of the year.
There's so many people
that come out to it.
It's full-on live television.
[ Cheering ]
It's where snowboarding
really came to light.
People started to watch the X-Games on TV
and started noticing faces and people.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
Snowboarding is
the heart and soul of the Winter X-Games,
and it was from the very beginning.
A lot of mainstream sports critics
said these aren't real athletes,
these aren't real sports.
But the kids, they're the ones
who have the same regard
for professional snowboarders...
that they have for
any other professional athlete.
;[ Continues ]
When you're on a medium
like ABC's Wide World of Sports...
and it's your run being beamed out
to 1 50 million people,
let's face it-if you put it down,
it's going to change your life.
If you throw down the hottest run,
you're going to be on SportsCenter.
- SportsCenter.
- [ Cheering Continues ]
You getting nervous or what?
I'm sweating it.
[ White ]
It's pretty intense.
I train most the yearjust to
be able to go there and do my thing...
and do the best that I can
at that event.
It's the one that
I think about the most.
You talk to anybody
from mainstream America
who wants a piece of snowboarding,
the finrst question is,
What was your place in the X-Games?
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
That's pretty much
what it comes down to.
;[ Continues ]
[ Man ] Shaun is setting the bar
in every event he does.
[ Cheering ]
It doesn't matter
if it's slopestyle or rail jam,
if it's half-pipe.
[ Cheering Continues ]
[ Announcer On P.A., Indistinct ]
I hate to use
the MichaelJordan reference.
We'll say LeBron James.
He's like LeBron james
on a snowboard.
Shaun, we love you!
[ Masekela ]
I don't think we even have any idea
how big his star's going to be.
[ Announcer On P.A.]
Anybody know his name?
Shaun White coming home with the gold.
[ Cheering Continues ]
Ifhe thought he was famous now,
just wait till the Olympics.
[ Narrator ]
Despite growing acceptance,
snowboarding was still underground.
In the mid-'80s, early contests
brought together snowboarders
from all over the world,
triggering the sport's
rapid evolution.
;[ Man Singing Funk Rock ]
The U.S. Open was huge for us
on the East Coast.
That's where we went to watch
the other guys that were top in the sport
show us what they had.
And it was our chance
to show them what we had.
I started snowboarding
up in Tahoe.
And not until the finrst time I went to
my finrst world championships contest
in Breckenridge...
did I realize that snowboarding
existed anywhere except Tahoe.
There's European snowboarders
and there's the East Coast Burton guys.
And there's now
bigger hard-core guys.
It was just a bunch of people
stoked to see that there were
other people out there doing it.
[ Narrator ]
As contests evolved, freestyle
and free-riding became the focus.
These creative, more expressive
styles of riding would become
the driving forces...
that would
shape snowboarding's future.
The whole birth of
freestyle snowboarding came from us
being able to ride half-pipes.
Back in the day,
it was dominated by racing.
Racing became so serious
and you didn't like the people
you were racing against,
and there was all these rivalries.
;[ Rock ]
[ Richards ]
Half-pipe gave it a chance
for kids tojust be kids.
[ Farmer ] The tallest half-pipe
was probably-if it was six feet tall,
that was a pretty damn big half-pipe.
And it was really just a mess.
It was really just,
you know, kind of a mess.
[ Man ] Now you go onto these pipes
and they're, like, 20-foot walls,
perfectly cut by a pipe dragon.
And kids these days get to
ride that kind of stuff everyday.
;[ Continues ]
A key element of contests in general
was the fact that you got media out there...
and those photographers would
open the eyes of millions of people.
Every single kid would look
at those magazines and go,
"Oh, my God, I want to do that. '"
[ Richards ] Magazines were
a way to show progression.
It was a way to show trends.
It was a way to touch
everyone all over the world about
what was happening in our sport.
But then, with the advent of
the snowboard video, we were like,
Whoa, snowboarding's
way different than the way we do it.
Let's do it that way.
[ Rippey ] When I finrst started snowboarding,
the stars of the sport, to me,
were the guys that were in the videos.
You know, Damian Sanders,
Craig Kelly, guys like that.
I mean, I would
watch a video 25 times, easy.
Film is the biggest influence
on snowboarding.
Maybe more so than contests.
[ Tina ]
All of the sudden, there was
this whole generation of snowboarders...
that didn't have to go
and win contests to be sponsored.
We could go free-ride
and go ride powder and experience
more of snowboarding...
than just traveling around
doing the contests.
You're on fire!
[ Laughing ]
[ Richards ]
Videos helped to look inside
and see what else what was going on...
besides when the snowboarders
were on the hill...
andjust more about, like,
their personalities.
And that's what grabbed you-
like, these guys are cool.
;[ Man Singing Punk Rock ]
[ Farmer ]
You can snowboard all day
andjust go haywire at night.
And I mean haywire.
[ Leines ]
The videos were more
geared towards partying...
and the Whiskey movies
and stuff where it's just mayhem.
- ;[ Continues ]
- [ Motorcycle Engine Revving ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Bottle Shatters ]
[ Man ]
They had a different idea of
what apres-ski activities might be.
Yeah!
Basicallyjust being Jackass
before Jackass was even cool.
[ White ] I knew snowboarding was crazy,
but when you watch those videos
you really know how nuts it was.
And deep down, I think,
I really wanted to be a part of that.
[ Farmer Rapping ]
;Farm ain't playing
He's just gonna be finlleting faces
;After they drop him off at the top
and he rips it through
the bottom of the bases
; But that's the way he does it
every day of the week ;
; 'Cause he's a powder-ridin'
longboard freak, hey ;;
;[ Man Singing Alternative Folk ]
[ Perata ]
You know, morale goes down a little bit
when the whiteout comes.
We had other things planned to do
and now we can't do them,
so it's just another Chugach notch.
Another down day.
What's up, Farm?
What do you think, bro?
What are we gonna do?
[ Mumbles ]
Huh?
[ Perata ]
You're gonna get a huge storm.
You're gonna get a couple,
three, four days of clearing.
Then you're gonna get some wind.
That's the cycle
of these mountains.
You have to be patient,
because when it does break
it's going to be the best that you've ever had.
You got to find things to do around here,
or you're gonna go nuts.
As soon as Farm hears the rotors flying,
he'll be the finrst one dressed and ready to go.
Huh, Farm?
That's right.
See?
Hopefully, it's dumping up top, up high.
I'm sure it probably is.
I didn't know Travis was coming.
He kind ofjust showed up.
I'm, like, "Yeah.!'"
[ White ] He's a good friend of mine,
and he's an awesome rider.
I'd heard he might have been coming,
but it's just awesome to have him here.
[ Rice ]
It's a good crew coming up here-
Perata, Farmer, Hannah,
having Terje up here
with, like, Shaun White.
All right, let's do it.
[ White ]
He'll ride anything.
He's all about the backcountry.
He can do a half-pipe contest
and slope south.
Alaska is a place where Travis
can separate himself from other riders.
He knows it's the best
for backcountry free-riding.
;[ Folk Rock ]
[ Teter ]
First couple days we got blue sky, finally,
after the rainy, like, cloudy storminess.
I was so happy, you know,
just knowing that we were going up.
Yeah! We're going up!
[ Perata ]
Now that we've had new snow,
it's made everything unstable.
It's good 'cause we get a fresh coat,
but it's also bad 'cause it now
makes everything more dangerous.
;[ Continues ]
[ Teter ] Yeah, I heard
that it's kind of avalanchey up top.
So today we'rejust gonna,
I guess, plan a jump.
[ Farmer ]
How do I feel about building a kicker
in the Alaskan backcountry?
Well, I think
it's a bunch of bullshit myself.
But I live by the motto,
don't sweat the petty.
Pet the sweaty.
He's got a point.
[ Laughs ]
[ Farmer ]
This is probably the most popular part
of snowboarding videos and everything.
Kids go out
and build thesejumps,you know?
Dudes like Shawn
and Travis Rice here.
Terje won't have a problem either.
I'm sure Hannah will do fine.
We'll see.
I don't know,you know.
I could throw out something.
I'm a little scared, actually.
I've never really done
this kind of stuff before.
Oh, God, no!
Do a couple of those,
you'll be all stretched out.
[ Laughs ] Yeah.
I thought we'djust be
coming up here, we'd build
a little one foot-high, single track jump.
I mean, when did it come to this?
Why do you have to fly a hundred feet?
I don't understand it.
Farmer was a little nervous because
he's never really had a jump like this.
And the jump was huge.
It was a really big jump.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
It was just something
that was bringing the whole new wave
of snowboarding right to him,
and I don't know
whether he was ready for it or not.
Hannah had never been out
in the backcountry to hit a jump like this,
and to start out with that was
just insane 'cause it was- I was scared.
;[ Continues ]
;[ Ends ]
[ Hannah Teter ] Whenever I'm
put in front of a challenge,
I want to do it.
I want to conquer it
and come out of it feeling this sense
of satisfaction that I went for it.
[ White ]
It was a really big jump
that any other girl that was up here...
would most definitely
back out of.
I give her so much credit
for even going for it.
It was really scary.
I was, like,
""Well, Farm went.
I guess I'll go for it.''
Let's give you
a quick head-to-toe.
Take a deep breath for me.
[ Man ]
Careful now.
Does it feel like
a broken rib at all?
Big mountain skills
or hospital bills.
That's the story up here,
you know?
Hematoma.
[ Perata ]
A hematoma. No big deal.
That your bone sticking out?
In the wrong spot?
I don't know.
All the way up.
Yeah, you're gonna have
some bruisin'.
A little swelling
right in here right now.
[ Perata ]
Ice him down.
[ Farmer ]
You know, it's been a little bit
of a reality check for me too...
'cause at my age I can get there
and I have experience...
and I can get down stuff
that a lot of people
wouldn't even consider.
And then, on the other hand,
it's like,you know,
maybe it's time
to just relax and chill out.
Which- I'm torn.
Dude, that's gnarly.
[ Clears Throat ] Gnarly.
[ Perata ] Those guys are
all stomping it though, huh?
No problem.
;[ Rock ]
;[ Man Singing ]
[ White ]
You just start to feel it
right after that finrst 360.
I was feeling it.
Did another three even bigger,
and then I was, "Oh, I'm gonna
seven it. I gotta do it. '"
;[ Singing Continues ]
It was definitely
one of the biggest 7 20s
I've ever done.
;[ Singing Continues ]
[ Chuckling ]
It's just, like, ""What?''
It's just mind-boggling, man.
Really, I mean, I was, like,
""He just greased it, you know?''
[ Rice ]
That was a fun
little session.
Got quick couple bumps
with the heli
and splitjust in time.
Yeah, it worked out probably
better than we had hoped.
[ Farmer ]
A little bit
over my head right now.
But, yeah, these guys
killed it, man.
You have to accept where
you're at in this whole game,
so that's hard for me,
but that's what I'm doing, you know.
We'll see.
You never know.
[ Hannah Teter ]
It kind ofhurt my pride
a little bit,you know.
Like, when I was
tumbling down that hill,
you just feel it.
You know,
a fall I had never taken before.
Just kind of bruised my little ego.
Yeah, I grew up
with four older brothers just
charging around, doing stuff.
And to come here
and kind of get a sense
of that, like,
""Wait up! I want to come!''
You know.
So it was a nice,
like, atmosphere for me.
I was born, raised-
I've lived here my whole life-
Belmont, Vermont.
It's just so peaceful up here.
I love coming home
afterjust being on the road.
Do I have pride?
I'm not changing my last name
when I get married.
Keep it Teter forever.
It was nice to have
four older influences to kind
of guide me along,you know?
Are you going to show me
how to ride a rail today?
[ Hannah ]
Amen. I've been traveling
with him a lot lately actually.
I'm Hannah's manager and agent,
as well as Abe and Eliijah's.
So we've got the Teter family
snowboarding business going on.
[ Announcer ]
Abe Teter.!
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Yeah.!
We all rode
the same first snowboard.
We all learned on it.
There it is.
This is the old man
right here.
That thing is awesome.
Look at the size
of that puppy!
Look at the dust on it.
That's amazing.
I mean, four older brothers,
and the only sister.
It's made her pretty
rough and tough.
Keeping up with them
all those years,
she was always determined
to be right there with them.
Don't hit me with that.
I think Hannah
exemplifies competitive.
She is so competitive,
almost to a fault
in certain ways.
I mean, she's so competitive
in her head...
and so driven to win
and be the best
at what she's doing...
that sometimes it takes away
from how much fun she's having.
[ Announcer ]
Hannah Teter.!
- Come on, Sissy.
- Come on, Hannah!
It helps me
to have a little support
at the bottom.
No matter what happens,
it's just that positive
energy type...
that I can get from my family
and no one else,you know?
He's a skeezer.
Kill it, man.
This is the first time
the backyard in the Teter family
has ever seen rails.
[ Hannah Giggles ]
Liden,you are so skeezy.
I think theyjust
kick-started me,you know?
Like, I started snowboarding
because they were.
And then I kind
of sprouted off.
[ Amen ]
Over the last couple of years,
Hannah's, like,
taken it where we started it
and where those guys started it...
and then taken it
to that next level.
As her brother,
I just find myselfbeing
just so overwhelmed sometimes.
Like, holy shit, dude!
She is killing it!
Like, my little sister's
one of the best snowboarders
in the world,
and that's nuts.
[ Narrator ]
As the decade changed,
so did snowboarding.
Increased exposure,
a no-limits attitude
and continued progression...
would push the sport to a level
that few had ever imagined.
[ Burton ]
It seemed like overnight
we went from being a threat...
to being, like, the saviors
of the ski industry.
We were bringing kids back on
to the mountain, and lift ticket sales
started going back up.
It seemed like
when something flipped,
it just flipped very quickly.
[ Tina Basich ]
Snowboarding was growing so fast,
and ski resorts started to realize
that they're gonna miss out...
if they don't allow snowboarding and they
don't start catering to snowboarders.
[ Seoane ]
They started advertising on the radio,
"'And we don't allow snowboarders. '"
The year after they were, like,
"'And we have a great half-pipe. '"
And they were, like, completely
kissing ass to snowboarders.
[ Grunts ]
I hate it when they do that.
Because all it comes down to
is them making money.
The bus was leaving.
You're either gonna be on the bus
or off the bus, financially, on this thing.
Then you saw the exponential growth
of snowboarding,
with double-digit increases
every single year.
And who wants to miss that boat,
from a business point of view?
And after all,
we're running a business here.
Snowboarding just kind of started
going mainstream a little bit.
There was bigger contests.
There was more prize money.
It was such an accelerated path
from sleeping in the cars...
and clipping lift tickets...
to be able to get up and ride
to this huge insurgence of money
into the industry.
Before I knew it,
we were traveling the world
and forgot how we got there.
'Cause itjust
kind ofhappened overnight.
All of a sudden you started seeing
snowboarding commercials on TV.
Why do I use the card?
I spent my whole life
doing things my own way.
American Express
never questioned it.
[ Richards ]
Then you started to see snowboarding
more and more and more,
and it was, like, "Oh, shit.
People are into this sport.
Snowboarding's cool.!'"
There's a lot of good things that come from it,
but there's also a lot ofbad things.
All these companies
are throwing money at us,
and all of a sudden it's, like,
"You'll have all these opportunities, '"
which is all cool and everything.
But then sometimes
you'd sit back and you're, like,
"'Am I selling myself out?
Am I selling out the soul
of snowboarding?''
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
It definitely makes you feel
like you got robbed, in a sense.
But now we've reached
this worldly exposure,
where it's actually kind of neat.
You know, like,
you have kids all over the world
who respect you for what you do...
and admire you.
[ Narrator ]
What had once been an underground
American subculture...
soon spread to Europe and japan
and became a global phenomenon.
Europe was more focused on racing,
and we were more focused
on the freestyle aspect of it.
[ Burton ] They rode fast.
They rode some serious big mountains,
a lot of powder.
And I think that those riders
brought a lot to the development
of the whole thing.
In general, the Europeans embraced it,
I think, a lot quicker than the Americans.
[ Richards ] Thejapanese people
are amazing, and they're amazingly
fanatical about things that they love.
And they found snowboarding,
and they embraced it,
and they turned us into rock stars.
We had never felt like that
before in the U.S.
[ Cheering ]
When you got tojapan,
it was these people-
- They knew your names,
and they were showing up at airports.
- I love you!
And, like, asking you
for autographs everywhere.!
There's dudes there
that buy six boards a year.
They werejust so obsessive.
That definitely fueled that
billion-dollar industry for sure.
[ Cheering ]
[ Announcer Shouts In japanese ]
I don't know.
This isn't really snowboarding.
But, uh, it's a show.
It's an event. It's how it goes.
[ Announcer ]
Please welcome...
Extremejump in Tokyo Dome.!
[ Loud Cheering ]
[ Rice ]
You know, in the U.S.,
snowboarding is kind ofbig,
but over here,
it's kind of taken to the next level.
And, of course,
it's sold out once again.
That's why
it is the best contest.
They have pyrotechnics
and smash a big old gong.
And, like,
Who Wants To Be A Millionaire
lighting going.
;; [ Imitating Musical Sting ]
Four, three, two, one, start.!
;[ Man Rapping ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Explosion ]
When you get to the top
of the dropping deck...
and you look out over,
you know, a sea...
of 40,000 japanese
who arejust chanting,
uh, it's definitely
a humbling, humbling view.
[ Announcer ]
Travis Rice from Wyoming, U.S.A..!
[ Cheering ]
What has snowboarding
come to?
You definitely feed off the crowd.
You know,you get out there,
and there's that many fans.
So, of course,you know,you're gonna go
a little bit bigger, a little faster,
try a little harder.
[ Cheering Continues ]
It's crazy that snowboarding's
brought me to, like, a place like this...
where that many people are that hyped
on what we're doing.
[ Perata ] Most of the heebie-jeebies
of finrst coming here and seeing
these big ol'mountains...
are pretty much over.
It's nice that we can get out
and get some runs under our belt.
Shaun and Hannah are getting
more and more comfortable
each day they're here.
You know, obviously they don't
have the big mountain experience
the rest of the group has.
But from what I've seen so far,you know,
the potential is definitely there.
You know,
having Travis here and Terje,
I'll tell you what-
It's pretty awesomejust to see
how much it's progressed.
It's definitely amazing, you know.
Nobody would have ever thought
that the sport would have gone this far.
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
[ Man On Walkie-Talkie ]
Well, all right. How was that?
That was really good.
Uh, the snow is super good.
The sunny sides
are a little sunbaked,
but other than that,
it's like some wet Tahoe powder.
[ Haakonsen ] Riding with Travis
was so good because he was so motivated,
you know,just to be up there.
And then,you know,
he's so top of the game right now.
You know, that helped a lot,
having him just motivating me.
;[ Singing Continues ]
[ Rice ]
You snowboard long enough,
and you get an eye for trying
to fgure out the line.
And shredding with Terje-
He's been looking for the line
ever since he was, like, 1 5.
[ Haakonsen ]
You always pick the lines
where it's hard to get to.
Or it seems like those are the lines
that are really good.
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
[ Rice On Walkie-Talkie ]
All right, my line is, I'm dropping
on the, uh, next ridge over...
from what Terje did
on top of that last feature.
I'm gonna air off that
into that landing-
that landing that's getting
shaded right now.
[ Ice Cracking ]
You all right?
Yeah.
Feel good?
Good? If you care,
I've got the power shot.
Yeah?
Yeah. Nice one.
Whew!Just got to, uh,
keep fighting for those ones.
That thing cracked, and I just had-
I knew I had to get to the side.
So, uh, I was able to weasel out.
just, uh- You gotta be persistent,
hold that edge, keep cutting out of it.
[ Haakonsen ]
You're pretty good at weasling.
That was right
where I was trying to go.
Yeah. It was perfect.
Then I just saw everything crack,
and it was, like- [ Screaming ]
The crack was huge. Oh,yeah.
Yeah.
[ Haakonsen ] It's a big avalanche
to wake up in the morning with,
and it's not gonna stop us.
We already knew that
before we came up here-
that there's gonna be avalanches.
We've both seen them before,
and let's keep rolling.
That's what A.K. is all about.
I was telling them that we were
gonna bump up and do another one.
[ Haakonsen ] Yeah, perfect.
Yeah.
[ Rice ]
So much of snowboarding is-
all you have is what nature gives you
as far as features.
Like, 90% of what we do
is exploration,
trying to find,you know,
the perfect feature.
[ Haakonsen ]
Some of the progression, I think, too,
is, like, how good are you to play?
Travis is a really good example.
He can play with any kind of terrain.
That's what makes him such
a well-rounded snowboarder.
[ Farmer ]
If you were tojust,you know, say,
"Hey, let's justjump onto the corners, '"
everything would've
been okay yesterday.
When?
Yesterday.
Well, you went first, dude.
I was waiting for you to do that
so I could follow your lead.
And you just jumped
the whole thing.
[ Hannah ]
It was a relief to know I was just
gonna make some turns.
They were like, "Okay, we're gonna
go take a couple runs. '"
And I was, like, "Whew.!'"
You know, no big jumps today.
Scores.!
;[ Man Singing Rock Ballad ]
[ Farmer ]
She's really not afraid,you know.
She throws down, and she's strong.
And it's just a matter ofher
getting a little experience
on this type of terrain.
But she's a superstrong rider.
;[ Singing Continues ]
[ Hannah ]
Shaun White and I
are kind oflike classmates,
and then, like, Farmer and Nick
are kind of the teacher.
You know, we're in their class.
And I didn't expect that coming up here.
I thought I'djust be hanging out
with a bunch of dudes.
A trip to Alaska is special for me.
And what I expect,you know,
is just to get the best runs of my life.
The runs I did here 1 0 years ag0-
like, I still remember those runs.
Sometimes you just pick a line
that was maybe over your head
or not what you expected.
You kind of got to
pick lines like that if you want to be
in the limelight of snowboarding.
And that's about pushing limits...
and trying to avoid,you know,
an uncomfortable situation.
Okay, there's no going back now,
that's for sure.
Be actually hard
to unstrap my bindings...
where it's jammed
in the little snow coulier.
It was definitely a lot of rush
going through my head and my body,
and I was, like,
breathing pretty heavy, I'm sure.
[ Grunts ]
You want to put yourself
in a situation like that,
but also, again, not to be
in a situation like that.
It's that fine line again.
Getting the chance to come up
and shred with Terje is, like-
you know, I couldn't ask
for anything more.
It's ideal.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Haakonsen ]
I'm, uh, really glad I got
to grow up in Norway.
I think it's a beautiful country
and a good country.
Coming from someplace where,
you know, as soon as you're born,
you're throwing on a pair of skis
and pushed out onto the snow-
It's something that developed
really naturally for him.
Terje is really-
I mean, he's revered there.
He's a real icon.
Terje was the finrst guy
to break the barrier...
and turn into, like, the full-blown
snowboard rock star.
Terje Haakonsen became
a household name.
And for a name like Terje to fall off the lips
of some people in middle America,
that's saying something, for sure.
[ Lynn ] The platform that he's built
for himself, to see him take it
and to start a contest like this-
and to see him try to make
a difference with it-
makes the event that much
more enjoyable to experience.
Listen up, guys.
[ Burton ] It's funny 'cause Terje
was always a guy that sat back...
and kind of reacted
to the powers that be.
For him to be in that position
is definitely a change.
[ Haakonsen ]
I like to have the control of what's
going on for us riders,you know.
I'm still riding in it.
[ Burton ]
He's had this vision
for where the sport should go.
A lot of younger riders probably
aren't aware of the fact
that it was that event...
and Terje making that event happen...
that brought this scale...
of snowboarding features
and snowboarding competitions
to that level.
[ Kass ] That's what Terje likes.
He's really, like, pushing
quarter-pipe riding,
and he has to pretty much
almost the limit and beyond.
[ Announcer, Indistinct ]
Andy Finch.!
Whoa.!
Oh, my God.!
[ Finch ]
I wish there was more quarters like this
'cause it's so much damn fun.
Glad to be walking away.
[ Chuckling ]
Congratulations.
Thanks.
I'm super stoked that we got,
finally, to ride, you know.
[ Haakonsen ]
Well, I'm looking really
to the surfg part.
The plan is to,you know, fly in,
hold all the events...
and then get on the boat
and go out to this island
and enjoy some surfg.
When we had to announce
that we didn't have a half-pipe contest,
it was just, like, ""Yeah. Cool.''
It's not that important for them,
you know, to compete all the time.
I think we get more stoked
riding that way.
I really enjoy that sport.
It's great to me.
I wish I could do that in every contest.
I want tojust go for surf.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Narrator ]
Because of its rapid rise in popularity,
the Olympics soon set it sights
on snowboarding.
In 1 998 snowboarding reluctantly
stepped on to the Olympic stage,
dividing the tight-knit
snowboarding community.
[ Rice ] Coming up to the Olympics,
there was all this hype about how Terje
wasn't gonna be there.
And at that point,
Terje was pretty much considered...
the best half-pipe rider
and the person to beat.
And ifhe wasn't there,
it wasn't a real contest.
And I totally agreed with that.
I think it's really wrong
and not really good for the sport.
They're trying to pick countries
that are up against countries.
It's not so much
what snowboarding's about.
[ Tina ]
It was important that he was there
to make that decision...
because there was both sides of it,
and he represented that side of it.
[ Richards ]
As the Olympic team
going into Nagano,
we had a lot of faith in people
that weren't up to the task...
of making snowboarding
look really cool to the world.
The athlete Rebagliati, Ross,
member of the Canadian delegation,
is disqualified and excluded
from the 1 8th Olympic Winter Games.
It was unfortunate,you know,
to have the whole scandal...
with Ross testing positive
for marijuana.
They wanted to strip his medal, and then
they finally allowed him to have it...
Because that wasn't one
of the banned substances.
So because
that whole thing happened,
they cut 80% of the coverage
of snowboarding...
to the American public.
[ Richards ] If anything,
he should get a bonus medal...
for actually being able to get
a gold medal while stoned.
[ Mike ] Wejust felt like
they needed us to get over with,
get on the plane and get home.
It sucked.
I'd say that's a good kick-off
for the Olympics for snowboarding.
I wouldn't choose
to have it any other way.
[ Narrator ]
Four years later
the Salt Lake City games...
would show snowboarding
in a much different light...
and forever change the mainstream's
perception of the sport.
Kelly Clark won the finrst gold
for the United States
during that Olympics,
and that was a huge deal.
It really got the attention
of the American public.
They actually gave it
the coverage that it deserved,
and America finally got to see
snowboarding competition,
how it could be.
People freaked out.
Forty-seven years
after the last time the Americans
swept anything in the Olympics,
we get the U.S. snowboard team
come in, and they do it.
And they were the perfect package.
You had the pretty boy,j.J. Thomas.
You had the consummate
professional, Ross Powers,
and the dirtbag, Danny Kass.
I think it was, like, kind of like
a morale booster for the States.
I was just more pumped
that my family was there.
A lot of them came out.
So that's where the pride
really kicked in.
It was, like, made my mom proud.
I think she cried. It was awesome.
[ Mock Crying ]
Oh, God. Cut!
[ Tina ]
With the guys in 2002,
all of a sudden
snowboarders are our heroes.
And they're hopeful for getting
more gold medals at the Olympics
for years to come.
;[ Man Vocalizing ]
- Whoo.!
- Yeah!
;[ Man Singing Alternative Dance Rock ]
[ Farmer ]
It's kind of turned down the volume
on my program a little bit.
The conditions are tough,
and I jacked myself a little bit.
When you throw down and kill one,
a really sweet line,
it's an awesome feeling,you know.
I can still get down some stuff
and throw down a decent line, I think.
Yeah.! Farm.!
[ White ]
Every day I've gone up, it's just been
some weird new experience.
And this is the only place
I've really felt out of control.
I haven't felt like I was on top of my game,
like I could do anything.
It's tough when you feel like that,
especially after so many years of me
just feeling like I could do anything.
And I don't know- Itjust kind of
changed my whole perspective
on everything.
Hopefully this is,you know,
the culmination of it all.
And this fire can chase
the demons out of everybody...
and whatever they have left in 'em,
as far as looking forward
to our final goal here.
[ Rapping ]
; 'Cause that financial growth
is about to happen ;
; When the world finds out
about this rappin' ;
; Not the money and fame, yo ;
; I don't give a damn
'cause this song remains the same ;
; No matter where I am ;;
[ Cheering ]
[ Man On Radio ]
Thompson Pass area traffc,
Helicopter 8 1 4, Echo Hotel lifting.
Tsaina Lodge, westbound.
[ Perata ]
Oh, we like this ride, don't we?
Oh, pretty day.
Follow our favorite river.
[ Perata ]
Well,you know,
as we leave our backyard here,
we venture into the Arctic North,
which is kind of the last zone
where nobody's been yet.
That's where the highest
mountains are in this area,
so there's got to be some rad lines
in there someplace.
You know what they say-
There's always a better line
over the next ridge.
Pretty much this is all
undiscovered terrain out here now.
It's getting
more and more vertical
as we get back here farther.
You know, one of things that we're
gonna be running up against, Drew,
is finding a zone
that can please everyone.
We don't want to scare anybody
to the point...
of wanting to be helicoptered off
the top of the mountain.
There's plenty out here.
It's just a matter of taking our time
and finding the right one.
[ Drew ]
Let me call back to base, and we'll
get the troops headed this way.
Sounds good.
[ Hannah ]
My last day of riding.
I'm gonna miss it.
This schedule
has been so fun-finlled,
and I'm going to miss all these guys
so much, you know.
We werejust being,
like, a nice team.
[ Drew ]
If we can find a base up here somewhere
that looks like it might be workable,
I'll go ahead and try
and set down on the top.
And, uh, we'll go with that.
[ Perata ]
Sounds good.
760 1- this is one of
the highest peaks out here.
Let's just go see
if we can get in up there.
Okay. The winds are pretty strong today.
I may have to
make a couple of attempts at it.
This'll be one of the hairier lines,
I can guarantee that.
[ Perata ]
Being on the top of that thing,
with the winds blowing, I was scared.
I didn't think.
I'm, like, "There's no way
we're going down this. '"
The true fact is, I was scared of it.
I can say, ""Oh, I didn't trust
this, this and that.''
But I was scared
to fall down that mountain.
[ Hannah ]
You know, when I'm scared, I know that
it's not right, for me, at least at that time.
It was gnarly. [ Laughing ]
It was super gnarly.
The wind
was just hammering so much.
And I didn't even think the helicopter
was going to come back.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Perata ]
Well, conditions got to bejust right
to do a mountain like 760 1.
You know, there's no doubt that there's
plenty of peaks out there to ride,
but we were kind of
coming up short on time,
and we still wanted to get
that one big run in before we all left.
[ Farmer ]
The hardest thing for me is
to actually come down to Earth...
andjust be, like,
"Okay, here's something I can't do. '"
'Cause I always look-
I want to do the superhero lines.
How big
do you think that was?
Middle cliff band is huge.
I don't know, dude.
Probably, huh?
Looks like it's gonna be pow.
I think it's gonna be killer
coming down.
There's a lot of ridge
on the way down.
See all those things?
So, I think this is us
right here on this cornice.
If you came in like that,
that would be skier's ride
a little bit...
to get around the rock bend
and to get out where you can
look at it.
[ White ]
I learn something every day
when I'm on the mountain.
The one I talk to the most
would probably be Farmer.
You know, hejust puts it in such a way
that it's easy to understand.
Now,just don't cut.
If there's a huge river of snow
or whatever there, don't get in it.
As long as you stay on that wall,
you'll be all right.
When it really comes down to it,
you know, it's pretty much
the best thing ever.
It's way better than competition.
I know that, you know.
Or, like,you don't expect
anything of yourself.
You know, "I'm just gonna go out
and make a few turns today. '"
[ Perata ]
You know, she had a special sparkle
in her eye for this place. She did.
She got confdent. She knows
that there's no limits up here.
I just respect somebody that charges,
that is not afraid-
apprehensive, but not afraid-
to actually bust out
when the time comes.
It's got a little pow,
but it's decent snow.
It'll be safe.
[ White ]
I talked to Farm, and he said,
"Slow down.just take it under control. '"
And I went out there,
and I just took my normal speed...
andjust pulled it back just a notch.
Yeah.! Yeah.!
That's killer.
[ White ]
I found more cliffs.
I found more little things tojump.
I found the line
I wanted to do way easier...
than if I was just blazing
through there.
It's been kind of a revelation for me.
Right now, I'm not in a lot of pain,
but, man, in the morning,
I swear to God, for the finrst
three or four hours, man,
I can't raise my head off the pillow.
So, I'm jacked pretty good,
but it's nothing permanent.
I'm glad it wasn't serious,
but I'm cool with it.
His line is sketchy.
I honestly don't think he knows where
he's gonna go until he's in it.
There's this huge open powder face
or there's this sketchy, rocky gorge.
He's all, ""Hmm, I'll take the gorge.''
I had one good line in this whole trip.
One good line.
[ Perata ]
Oh, man, by the time we'd finished,
you know, the wind had died down,
and Terje wanted to go back
and have a look at 760 1.
You know,
he had that mountain on his mind
the whole time, I could tell.
Yeah, Terje's gonna have a real good look
at 760 1 and probably ride it.
So, we would like the second group
to come out right now
and come over to "F'"top.
[ Man On Radio ]
Copy that. Second group
coming out to "F'"top.
Yeah, Terje, that looks sick.
Terje's, like, ""I'm going back
to that one. I'm doing it.''
Me and Farm are, like, ""What?''
[ Haakonsen ]
The conditions were right.
There was a big line.
just got tojump on it when you can.
Definitely needed a long run
before I could leave Alaska.
[ White ]
When nobody's ever done something,
and it's a descent...
or you don't know whether it's gonna
avalanche or not, it's really sketchy.
If you mess up, it's, like,
big consequences,you know.
[ Perata ]
Whenever you're doing the grand finale,
the biggest peak or the gnarliest line,
you have to have mental toughness.
And one of the mental toughest
snowboarders I know is Terje.
Terje Haakonsen's on top
of that peak right there.
It's called 760 1.
I think that's how high it is-
7,000.
It's gonna be a finrst descent.
[ Perata ]
It's really gnarly up there.
I mean,
it's looking 60 degrees at the top
just to get on the chute.
I know he was gripped.
You have to be gripped on top of that.
[ Man ] Five, four, three,
He's gonna rip it, man.
He's a good snowboarder.
two, one.!
;[ Rock ]
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
[ Farmer ]
Oh, my God.! He's hauling ass.!
[ Perata ]
He's totally raging
down the face right now.
[ Farmer ] Damn.!
[ Perata ] Hard.
[ Perata ]
Gnarly. Absolutely amazing.
;[ Singing Continues ]
Killing it.
You know, I was so impressed.
[ Farmer ]
When you overcome that doubt and fear
at the same time and you pull it,
you'rejust, like,jacked, man.
Jacked for sure.
It was awesome.
It was awesome to witness.
I feel privilegedjust to even see that.
It's history. Truly history.
[ Haakonsen ]
It gives you a great rush, that's for sure.
And a lot ofbutterflies,
you know, a couple hours later.
You know, I could've packed up
and called it a day.
Think I did, actually.
[ Perata ]
He overcame all his fears,
which is the hardest thing
for a human being to do.
It's tough, man. I can't do it.
Terje can. Farm can.
Sometimes.
Once in a while.
[ Haakonsen ] Coming up here
and, like, looking for finrst ascents
and clay mountains-
the name's on them-
you know, it's not important.
The thing to d0-
I think, it's morejust-
You have to satisfy yourself,
doing what you like to accomplish.
You know, I got it all in this trip.
I'm stoked with it.
I can live with it.
[ White ]
He's, like, probably one of the most
amazing snowboarders I've ever met.
[ Farmer ] He's so fluid,
and he's a true master ofhis sport.
And I don't think there's anything that
that guy can't do on a snowboard.
That was killer, man.
Sick.
You won't forget that one
for a while.
Yup.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Perata ]
This place enlightens you.
You know, it puts you in a good mood.
It-It humbles you.
It hits you with so many
different emotions...
just sitting right here,
looking out there...
that you can't help leave here...
and not be a bigger and better person.
That's what this place does to you.
It makes you strong.
[ Hannah ]
Alaska's really touched my heart
in an amazing way,
and it's influenced me so much
that,yeah, I'm gonna come back.
just 'cause I've had so much fun
and found so much joy here
and learned so much.
You know,
how could I not come back?
;[ Man Singing Rock ]
I feel like,you know,
if I was a warrior,
I would've got- I got a badge here.
;[ Singing Continues ]
[ White ]
I have such mixed feelings
while I'm out here.
I think this place
is amazing,
but, for me, I just think I need to focus
a bit more on some other stuff...
before I come back here.
It's just opening up this whole new book
when I haven't even closed this other one.
I still have some more chapters to fill.
just being in the Alaskan mountain,
it's like a competition itself,you know,
but for yourself.
Taking that next step
to the backcountry free riding.
This is what
snowboarding's all about.
Every time I think I don't care anymore,
you know, I go out and I do it,
and I have, like, the best time.
In fact,
that's almost the best time...
is when you just lay it down for a while
and then pick it back up.
I'll do it for as long as I can,
which is probably forever.
;[ Singing Continues ]
[ Narrator ]
For snowboarding, the diverse culture
and free-thinking attitude...
that has been there
from the beginning...
will always shape the sport.
And the future
will be determined by the riders...
who will continue to push limits
and change the way mountains are ridden.
[ Perata ]
I would say snowboarding's future
has always looked bright.
[ Burton ]
What's gonna happen
1 0 years from now?
What, are they gonna be
getting 40 feet out of the pipe
or 1 0 rotations in the air?
Nobody can tell you where
snowboarding's going to be in 1 0 years
or what riders are gonna be doing,
but, for sure, it's gonna progress.
It's changed in size.
People go way bigger now
'cause thejumps are bigger.
People go fatter in the pipe
'cause the pipe's fatter,you know.
But, really, it all comes down
to visualization...
and what you can think of
in your mind.
I look at a mountain completely different
than a person that mightjust be
a recreational skier does.
I see the mountain
as a gigantic terrain park.
Everything's rideable,
everything's doable
in some way or another.
Your mind always got to be working,
and that's how you learn tricks.
That's how you progress the sport.
That's everything. Your mind's gotta be open.
I think the next level in snowboarding
is starting to happen now.
I mean, all of us have learned
all these freestyle tricks.
So, we're all starting to take that
into the backcountry where
the elements are unpredictable,
and you can't necessarily see over
the next thing where you're gonna land.
[ Mike ]
Freestyle in the backcountry...
is the ultimate part
of snowboarding for me.
And I'd tell anybody, you know,
if you haven't done that, then go do it.
Or be careful
because you will get hooked.
It's something that I want to do
till I can't do it anymore.
[ Kass ] It's kind of comforting to know
that something that was such a struggle
is so easy now.
It was a hell of a ride.
It started for the all
the right reasons,
and it started with a group of people
that were so 'core and so in love,
so passionate about snowboarding,
that nobody will ever be able
to take that away.
;[ Rock ]
;[ Man Singing Rock Ballad ]
;[ Continues ]
[ Whispering ]
;[ Steady Drumbeat ]
;[ Singing Continues ]
;[ Singing Continues, Tempo Speeds Up ]
;[ Ends ]