(Finch) You are being watched.
The government
has a secret system--
a machine that spies on you
every hour of every day.
I designed the machine
to detect acts of terror,
but it sees everything...
Violent crimes
involving ordinary people.
The government considers
these people irrelevant.
We don't.
Hunted by the authorities,
we work in secret.
You will never find us.
But victim or perpetrator,
if your number's up,
we'll find you.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
(Quinn)
The politicians come and go,
but we'll be here forever.
(Simmons)
Beecher's looking for answers.
(Quinn) I always told
Cal to be careful.
Being a cop's a dangerous job.
(Carter)
HR rebuilt itself from ashes,
'cause we didn't cut off
the head.
If we had,
Cal might still be alive.
I'm playing
by different rules now,
until I can bring down
the boss.
Who do you
and Simmons report to?
Who calls the shots?
(Man) Those bastards think
they can steal from me?
Then they're gonna reap
what they sow.
Finch, you doing
a little spring cleaning?
I wish I was.
I received numbers
this morning.
38 of them, to be precise.
Maybe the machine blew a belt
or something.
It's not a lawn mower,
Mr. Reese.
It's also never wrong.
While I haven't decoded
all the numbers,
there does appear
to be a common thread.
(Reese) They're all cops.
Four of them
are known members of HR,
leaving a high probability
that the rest may be as well.
3 dozen members of HR,
all about to commit
a violent crime?
Or they've been targeted,
and HR is under siege.
Things are about to get chaotic,
Mr. Reese.
I've already contacted Ms. Shaw
to enlist her assistance.
I'll see if Fusco's heard
any rumblings around the Eighth
of an HR conflict.
If we could locate
the source of the threat,
perhaps we could
defuse the situation
before it escalates.
Perhaps.
Meantime, you might
want to get Bear here
fitted for a vest.
Vest?
Not like yours, Finch.
K-9 ballistic.
For when things get chaotic.
[Bear whining]
(Reese) Heard anything, Lionel?
(Fusco) If you're
looking for info on HR,
I got something you wanna see.
[Man speaking Russian]
Everything okay here?
- Detective Fusco.
- I'm Detective Stills.
Can we be of any assistance?
Not unless you speak Russian.
Best I can tell,
he was driving along,
and he came upon a burning car.
Then-- if I got this right--
someone knocked him out
and stole his truck.
Zdravstvuyte, my friend.
What kind of truck
were you driving?
[Speaking Russian]
Office supply truck?
A delivery truck?
Da.
I think you can take it
from here, Officer.
Nice badge.
You wanna give me a warning
next time you do
something like that?
But that would ruin
the surprise.
So what does all this
have to do with HR?
Know who has
an office supply company?
Peter Yogorov.
He uses it to smuggle drugs
into the city.
Under the HR alliance,
the cops are supposed to provide
safe passage.
Now you wanted to know
why HR might be in trouble?
How about the Russians losing
a truck full of contraband
on their watch?
(Reese) Think you can get us
a look at that camera feed?
Yeah, I love using
all my favors for you guys.
What do you think, Finch?
I'm inclined to agree
with Detective Fusco.
So Yogorov blames HR
for his missing shipment.
Decides to sever ties.
And targets 38 members
of HR's rank.
This situation is
a powder keg, Mr. Reese.
It's about to explode.
So who lit the fuse?
(Quinn)
Whole department's reeling.
Not too sure of how many more
funerals the NYPD can endure.
Do you have any idea
what happened
between Detective Terney
and Officer Laskey?
I wasn't aware of any conflict.
Didn't even know
they knew each other.
Well, there's some speculation
that it's HR-related.
Mayor's concerned
about a resurgence
in organized crime.
Last time we talked,
you seemed to indicate
that HR might have been
behind my godson's murder.
Maybe.
I-I don't know.
All I know is taking on HR...
it's like fighting
a battle that can't be won.
One step forward,
three steps back.
And now, losing my partner...
I need to close the book
on Cal's murder.
I have to move on.
I wanted to tell you that
in person.
Joss...
you're one of the most
dedicated cops I know,
and the city could use
more like you.
Cal would be very proud
of everything you did.
And don't worry.
We will find who's responsible
for his death.
Thanks, Alonzo.
Anytime.
I've got a big briefing
with the Mayor.
I'll take care of this.
I'll see you soon.
I look forward to it.
[Device beeps]
(Quinn)
Spoke to Carter this morning.
Says she's stepping down
on the Beecher case.
You believe her?
Even if I did, we can't have
any more bodies
dropping right now.
Keep an eye on her
just in case.
Will do.
- Did Yogorov accept our new terms?
- Not yet.
He wants to meet
at a grain depot in Red Hook.
(Quinn) Meet him in
Siberia if he wants.
Just get him
to agree to the new price.
(Yogorov) Who's the new guy?
(Simmons) This is Mitchell.
He'll be running point
on tomorrow night's shipment.
So we still on schedule?
Just in time
to restock the shelves.
My guy will call you
when he hits Laurel Hill.
(Simmons)
We'll escort the trucks,
provide safe passage
through town.
But it's gonna cost
an extra 10%.
Why?
Cost of doing business.
If I'm going to pay more,
I ought to get more.
- Don't you think?
- Like what?
My brother's still
in Rikers, for one.
You were supposed to get us
both out.
Well, these things take time.
It's in progress.
I'm starting to feel
less like your partner
and more like your errand boy.
We launder your money,
sell your drugs,
even take out your trash.
Like that narco cop you were
too afraid to knock off.
(Simmons) I didn't come to
hear you bitch, Yogorov.
You kicking in
the extra 10% or what?
I don't think so.
You don't pay, we don't provide
safe passage for the drugs.
Anything happens, it's on you.
I'll take my chances.
What do you wanna do?
Let me worry about that.
I need you on a new assignment.
[Keys hit tabletop]
Tell me you didn't use
the front door.
I never do.
Where's Taylor?
Somewhere safe.
Any reason
he wouldn't be safe here?
Like your off-the-books
pursuit of HR?
Everyone needs a hobby.
Most hobbies don't involve
dirty cops staked
outside your apartment.
If you want,
I can take care of him for you.
I'd appreciate it
if you left him alone.
Respectfully, I'd appreciate it
if you left me alone
for a while too.
Now's not the time
to fly solo, Carter.
Don't get me wrong, John.
I appreciate everything
you've done for me
and the city.
But in the eyes of the law,
you're still a criminal.
And HR already knows
we work together.
And if they could prove it...
No, I'm sorry.
I gotta finish this alone.
All right.
Do what you need to do.
But HR won't go down
without a fight.
If you get in over your head,
give me a call.
With the way you guys
keep tabs on me,
how much trouble can I get in?
Watch your back, Joss.
[Door closes]
[Sighs]
[Tense music]
♪
(Vogel) Read your file, Carter.
Top of your class
at the academy,
high marks across the board--
that's great.
Now, throw it all out.
None of it's worth a damn
out here on the street.
[Laughs]
Excuse me for one second.
I'll be right back.
'Sup, Joss?
What are you doing here, Paul?
Just got back into town.
Friend hooked me up
with a construction crew.
I see you traded in
one uniform for another.
Guess you, uh,
always had a thing
for hunting bad guys.
None of that
answers my question.
Wanted to see how you were
getting along, you know?
See how our son was doing.
You think you can just show up
after two years
and ask to see Taylor?
Look, Joss, things are
better now, okay?
I'm better.
So that means
you went to the VA?
The VA?
Nah, I don't need some
head shrinker analyzing me.
All right, Joss?
I just needed some time
to just clear my head.
It's not that simple, Paul.
I saw the toll
combat took on you.
You still think
I'm a danger, don't you?
- Joss, I never laid a hand
on either one of y'all. - No!
I'd just find you asleep
on the kitchen floor
cradling a gun, with our son
in the next room.
Well, that's not
gonna happen again.
You're right.
It won't.
Because if you don't get help,
you'll never have a relationship
with your son.
And until then,
I think it's best
you stay away from both of us.
(Carter)
I got your messages, Fusco.
All ten of 'em.
I heard
what happened to Laskey.
How you holding up?
It's never an easy thing,
losing a partner.
Kinda makes you wonder
what really went down
between those two that night.
Not sure I wanna know.
You know what I think?
I think someone else was there.
I think someone shot them both
and staged the scene.
The only question is, who?
I don't know, Fusco.
But whatever happened,
I don't want any part of it.
Terney was the one who told you
HR had your boyfriend killed.
Now he's dead along
with your rookie partner?
I mean, don't you
wanna know why?
Something I realized...
It's not always worth the risk
to know why.
I guess not.
It'll be all right, Fusco.
Just lay low for a while.
Yeah.
Hey, listen, I gotta get back.
[Sighs]
Don't stay a stranger,
all right?
[Phone beeps]
[Dialing]
Hey, it's me.
I need you
to pay someone a visit.
(Nikolai) Just got word.
Our shipment's crossed
state lines.
So far, no signs of trouble.
Makes me wonder why
we ever needed cops for this
in the first place.
[Spits]
What the hell?
[Guns cock]
You know what crime
you're most guilty of, Peter?
Letting this man cook for you.
[Guns cock]
Those look heavy.
Relax.
If I wanted you dead,
I'd be a little more
creative than this.
I'm surprised
you're still in town.
Figured you be
on a beach somewhere,
sipping mai tais
and licking your wounds.
I just can't leave yet.
Not with front-row seats
to this little drama
playing out between you and HR.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
The wheels of history
are turning again, Peter.
Take my word for it.
If the cops can't control you,
they'll betray you.
Just like they did me.
But unlike me,
you still have a chance
to do something about this.
Words of wisdom from the man
who killed my father.
Tell me why
I should listen to you.
Enemy of my enemy.
I just can't pass up
a chance to watch HR suffer.
What's this?
A gift.
Mmm.
[Smacks lips]
Let that simmer for 15 minutes,
then stir with vinegar.
[Dialing, line ringing]
[Cell phone rings]
Well?
Yogorov got the package.
Whether he received the message
is another story.
He'll understand soon enough.
Save everyone a lot of trouble
if you'd let me kill him.
(Carter)
That won't be necessary.
In fact, you might want to keep
a low profile
for the next couple days.
Already planning on it.
And whatever
you're up to, Officer,
I wish you the best of luck.
I have a feeling
you're gonna need it.
Hmm.
[Phone beeps]
Who was on the phone?
Someone who owes me a favor.
It's all there?
Everything but the kitchen sink.
Tried it, didn't fit.
I appreciate you not telling
the guys about this.
Boys can't have all the toys.
You're fixing to have quite
a party with all this stuff.
You sure you don't need
an assist?
The 37 mil can be tricky.
Thanks.
But I can take it from here.
_
[Speaking Russian]
[Coughs]
Honestly, Mr. Reese,
this looks like something
you would do.
Gotta admit,
I wish I was invited.
After digging into 30
out of the 38 HR numbers,
not a single man possesses
the talents displayed
in that footage.
I'm not so sure it was a man.
Come take a look at this.
Height, build--
I think our assailant
might be a woman.
A woman sets a car on fire
and attacks a drug shipment
wearing a gas mask?
Who does that
remind you of, Mr. Reese?
(Shaw)
What are you guys looking at?
[Bear whines]
All right, you're being weird.
This your handiwork?
I guess she does know her way
around a 37 mil.
Ms. Shaw, you know
something about this?
I know
someone needed firepower.
Reese had plenty,
so I made a donation
on his behalf.
Wait.
That's my grenade launcher?
Oh, my God, that's
Detective Carter, isn't it?
Your social circle
isn't terribly wide.
She told me she didn't
want you guys involved.
Because we would have tried
to talk her out of it.
Until now,
her investigation into HR
has fallen
on the legal side of things.
But this...
Pitting them
against the Russians?
You two get eyes
on every one of those numbers.
And how exactly can we be
40 places at once?
[Gun cocks]
I don't care.
If they find out
Carter's behind this,
only one number's coming up--
hers.
[Cell phone rings]
[Phone beeps]
Yes?
Good morning, Alonzo.
How did you get this number?
Found it.
On the burner phone
your man dropped
when he made off
with my supply truck last night.
I was sorry to hear about
what happened to your shipment,
but I'm not exactly sure
what you're implying.
You ripped me off, old man.
Taking your toys
and going home.
Except they weren't
your toys to take.
(Quinn) I'm going to pretend
you're having
a momentary lapse in judgment.
You got robbed, and now
you're not thinking straight.
Well, then let me be
extra clear right now.
I'm looking
at names and pictures
of top-level HR members.
Return my drugs,
or your men
don't make it home for dinner.
[Phones beep]
Joss?
[Tense music]
♪
[Gun uncocks]
Finch, I haven't found Carter,
but I think I know
who the head of HR is.
And I believe I know as well.
I just decoded the last number.
Alonzo Quinn.
Makes sense.
The Mayor's Chief of Staff
would be in a prime position
to lead HR from the shadows.
(Reese) He's also the man who
ordered Beecher's death.
This is more personal for Carter
than we thought.
Then you'd better do everything
in your power to find her.
[Line beeps]
[Phone beeps]
(Carter)
I see you're looking for me.
Joss?
Where are you?
I can't tell you that.
But I know
exactly where you are.
[Clicks tongue]
Thought you promised
to keep your distance.
That was before I knew
you were starting a war.
We know about Quinn
and what he did to Cal.
Then you know
why he can't get away with it.
Take it from me.
Revenge isn't the answer.
Tell me where you are.
Please just let me help you.
You once asked me to trust you
to do what needed to be done.
Now I'm asking the same of you.
[Phone beeps]
[Line rings]
(Quinn) Talk to me.
No one knows
who hit the Russian truck.
Video footage from the RTCC
is conveniently missing.
This has "Man In The Suit"
written all over it.
Frankly, I don't care
who stole Yogorov's cargo.
If he's considering
an end to our alliance,
he's a major liability.
He's threatening our people.
I'd say the alliance
is finished.
Peter Yogorov
doesn't have the stones
to come after us.
[Grunts]
Boss, what the hell
just happened?
Someone just took a shot
at me in my office.
Yogorov.
He wants to bite the hand
that feeds, he can starve.
Round up his top ranks and take
them on out to Red Hook.
Kill 'em and bury 'em.
But bring Yogorov to me.
I'll deal
with that son of a bitch myself.
[Phone beeps]
(Finch) While you were looking
for Detective Carter,
I received more numbers.
It appears that HR has responded
to the Russian threat in kind.
Guess it was only
a matter of time
until this escalated
into an all-out war.
If you'll forgive
my gallows humor,
I'll put my money on HR.
Why do you say that?
Because they have something
on their side
that the Russians don't,
Mr. Reese.
The law.
(Simmons) Grab Yogorov's men.
Keep it quiet.
No blood on the streets.
Hands where I can see them.
Get out of the car.
[Indistinct chatter]
[Grunts]
(Yogorov) Nikolai, where
the hell are you?
Watch your back.
HR's moving against us.
[Pounding on door]
[Phone beeps]
[Gun cocks]
First five guys
through that door
get early retirement!
(Carter)
That come with a pension?
I remember you.
Good, we can skip
the introduction.
HR already rounded up
all your boys.
You're the last little Indian.
And right now,
they're on their way here
to kill you.
So if you wanna live,
you're coming with me.
Last time I went with you,
you arrested me.
Guess old habits die hard.
Taylor!
Taylor?
You okay?
We're great.
Aren't we, little man, hmm?
I'm sorry.
He just showed up.
It's all right,
thanks for calling.
Paul, can I talk to you
outside?
Why not here?
I mean, the boy's old enough
to hear what you have to say.
Take my son into his room.
Sure.
Come on, Taylor.
[Footfall on stairs]
[Sighs]
The hell are you doing,
besides giving me a good reason
to lock you up?
Look, Joss.
A boy needs a father
in his life.
A father who's willing to admit
when he needs help.
You know what?
You didn't see combat
like I did.
You spent your time
back on a base,
chatting up terrorists.
And then when you came home,
[Chuckles]
you were fine.
You think
it was that easy for me?
I had problems too.
But I found ways
to handle them.
Look, just because
I did it by myself
doesn't mean you have to.
Okay, so let me guess.
I should go...
talk to the VA, right?
[Scoffs]
I told you,
I'm not gonna do that.
That's right, because you run
from your problems.
I'm not running!
You gonna shoot me now, Joss?
Get out of my house.
Joss--
[Door closes]
[Sighs]
[Indistinct chatter]
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
[Door closes]
I'm sorry you had to hear that.
What's wrong with daddy?
Sometimes he gets mad.
And he doesn't know why.
Will he get better?
I don't know, baby.
But hey...
as long as we got each other,
you and I are gonna be fine.
Okay?
Come here.
This your idea of protection?
A sheriff station in Bedford?
I booked you as a DUI
under the name Joe Manco.
Should keep you alive
for a few hours, at least.
The best I could do for the guy
who took a shot
at the head of HR.
I didn't take a shot at anyone.
Thing about dirty cops,
Peter...
they're not big on evidence.
Do you recognize this man?
That cop got shot
a few months back.
His name's Cal Beecher.
He was Alonzo Quinn's godson.
Remind me to send flowers.
Peter, I know
Quinn's the head of HR.
And I know he ordered your men
to carry out
the hit on Beecher.
Even if that were true...
never be able to prove it.
Maybe not.
But then again...
I've been following HR
and the Russians for months.
I've gathered enough evidence
to put almost everybody away.
Including you.
So then why are we talking?
Because it's your lucky day.
I want Quinn's head
more than I want yours.
[Chuckles]
Sorry.
I'd rather rot in prison
than be labeled a rat.
Every room I go in,
I always look for the exits.
I was a soldier.
Can't turn it off.
So trust me when I tell you
you only have one way
out of this.
And that's Quinn going down.
He stays out there,
doesn't matter
who else I arrest,
he'll be coming
for you eventually.
I can take care of myself.
I respect that.
I really do.
But can you say the same
for your brother?
You ever wonder
why HR's kept him in Rikers?
Leverage.
There are about half a dozen
corrupt cops awaiting trial
on the same cell block
as your brother right now.
You sign this statement...
I could get Laszlo moved
to safer facilities
within the next few hours.
So what's it gonna be?
[Paper slides across desk]
Just show me
the damn statement.
[Writes on paper]
Now what?
I get an arrest warrant
for Quinn.
You sure you got a judge
you can trust with that?
Quinn liked to spread
that money around.
We made him a lot of it.
Spent the last few days
vetting judges.
Narrowed it down to a couple.
My statement,
the evidence you got,
and this whole thing
comes down to blind luck.
Do me a favor, Officer.
Choose wisely.
Because if you don't,
then you, me, and my brother...
are all dead.
[Door closes]
Scared me
half to death, Carter.
I'm sorry.
Can't take any chances.
Yeah, Wonder Boy told me
what you're up to.
This your idea of laying low?
I had to make a bit of a mess.
That's why I needed to see you.
Yeah?
I'm not sure why.
I couldn't figure out at first
why you didn't read me
into this thing.
Why you cut me out.
Then I realized
you still don't trust me.
I get it.
I guess there's a certain stink
you really can't wash off.
That's not it, Fusco.
But I know how hard it was
for you to get out
from underneath HR.
Anything goes wrong,
you're the first guy
they're gonna come for.
I was trying to protect you.
Protect me?
By keeping me in the dark?
I thought we were partners.
We are.
That's why I'm here now.
What's this?
It's to a safety deposit box
at the one state bank
in Hoboken.
Inside is everything
I collected on HR.
Recordings, money trails,
everything.
I'm about to get
an arrest warrant for Quinn.
Then what?
Then I'm gonna arrest him.
But if anything happens...
I need you to hold on to that.
- No.
- "No" what?
No way you're gonna come here
with this "If anything
happens to me" crap.
Lionel, you're the only person
in the world
I trust with this.
Plus...
you're the best partner
I ever had.
If you think I'm gonna let you
take down Quinn by yourself
after coming here
and saying something like that,
you got another thing coming.
Okay.
We'll take your car,
but I'm driving.
[Keys jingle]
Oh, you might want
to get your vest.
- Let me grab it.
- You know what?
Grab your 12-gauge too.
All right.
[Door closes]
Sorry, Fusco.
But I gotta do this one alone.
[Keys hit ground]
All this could have been avoided
if your boss
hadn't tried to kill mine.
Carter's so determined
to get Quinn,
she's forgotten
about collateral damage.
You ready, Shaw?
One question--
once we save the bad Russians
from the bad cops,
what exactly are we gonna do
with them?
Let's finish this.
[Sirens wail]
FBI!
Who's in charge here?
Detective Stan Mitchell.
We got a tip the Russians
were making a deal out here.
We came to bust it up.
Carter.
(Barnes)
You know, we got a tip as well.
Bunch of corrupt cops
were gonna kill some Russians
over a pile of missing drugs.
[Dog sniffs, barks]
Mind if we look in your trunk?
[Dog barking]
Hope you got
a good lawyer, Detective.
Guess our work here is done.
[Gun uncocks,
cell phone vibrates]
Did you find her, Lionel?
She found me.
But she, uh...
Let me guess.
She ditched you.
She's going alone on this one.
She doesn't want any help.
They'll kill her
if they figure out
what she's up to, John.
We'd better find her then.
Let's split up.
Spread out in case Finch
comes up with her location.
[Phone line rings]
[Phone rings, beeps]
Hello.
Judge Monahan?
It's Joss Carter.
I apologize for calling so late,
but I was hoping
you could grant me
an arrest warrant tonight.
It can't be done
in the morning?
I'm afraid not.
I have a sworn statement
implicating a prominent member
of city hall
in a major crime
and corruption ring.
Have you spoken
to the DA about this?
I will, first thing
in the morning.
But right now,
I need the warrant.
I understand.
Get here as soon as you can.
[Phone beeps]
[Dialing]
[Line rings]
Sir, this is
Judge Andrew Monahan.
I'm sorry to bother you
at home.
I just received a call
you might want to be aware of.
Do you know a police officer
by the name of Joss Carter?
You were right to contact me.
Tell me everything
she told you.
[Sighs]
Joss!
No uniform.
You made detective.
What you need, Paul?
I didn't come here
to ask you for anything.
I just...
Just wanted to show you this.
_
Good for you.
- You look better.
- I am.
I mean, not all the way,
but some.
The counseling's
kicking my ass.
Lot of stuff
I didn't wanna relive--
things I did,
- people I hurt.
- Yeah, uh, Paul, I--
No, no, no.
I know.
There's no going back.
I see that now.
But they keep telling me
I have to find a way forward,
a purpose.
That's what I'm working on now.
I just wanted you to know that.
If there's ever anything
I can do for Taylor,
for both of you,
here's my number.
Thanks for hearing me out,
Joss.
All right.
[Sighs]
[Dialing]
[Line rings]
[Phone rings, beeps]
Hello?
Paul, it's me.
Oh, hey, Joss.
Let me get him for you.
Actually, I needed
to tell you something.
What's up?
Thanks.
For taking care of him.
It's good he can rely on you.
That's how
it's supposed to be, Joss.
it always should have been.
All right?
Hold on, somebody wants
to talk to you.
Hey, mom.
Hey, baby.
How's it going over there?
Good. Dad tried
to make a casserole.
We ended up ordering pizza.
[Laughs]
Y'all are hopeless.
You okay?
Yeah! Fine.
Just driving and, uh...
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
For what?
To me...
you're still
my little dude, you know?
Sometimes I-I forget
you're practically
all grown up.
These last eight months,
I've been secretive,
keeping you in the dark.
You're protecting me.
I get it.
But whatever you're doing,
you know you don't have
to do it alone, right?
[Chuckles]
You got my back, don't you?
Always.
And not just me.
Lots of people care about you.
If you ever need any help,
all you have to do is ask.
You know that, right?
I love you, baby boy.
I'll call you tomorrow.
I love you too, mom.
Okay.
[Phone beeps]
[Tires screech]
[Knock on door]
Judge Monahan,
thank you so much for--
- Let's get this over with, shall we?
- Absolutely.
I wouldn't be here this late
if it wasn't important,
Your Honor.
See, this warrant
is the key to our--
He wasn't talking
about the warrant, Joss.
Heard you were looking for me.
Figured I'd save you
the trouble.
I'll spare you
the Shakespeare quote.
(Quinn) You know, I think
that's your problem.
You see yourself
as a protagonist
in some great tragedy.
Determined
to face the world alone.
Even if it gets you killed.
"To be or not to be," bitch.
Move.
For what it's worth,
I had hoped that we could have
avoided this day.
At least have the balls
to pull the trigger yourself.
Don't outsource me
like you did your own godson.
I don't relish
what happened to him,
but sometimes sacrifices are
necessary for the greater good.
My mistake was not having
you killed along with Cal.
Then neither of you
would have had to die alone.
You were right.
I was wrong.
I thought I could
take you down alone.
Always did have trust issues.
Tried to do it clean.
Photos,
recordings, sworn testimony.
But then I realized
you're just too dirty.
Everywhere I turned,
you had friends
ready to help you out.
And I was alone.
So...
I called some friends
of my own.
You get all that, fellas?
She's not wired.
(Carter)
It's a brave new world, boys.
Don't you read the papers?
Anyone can listen in
on your phone.
Even when it's turned off.
(Quinn) My mistake was
not having you killed
along with Cal.
Then neither of you
would have had to die alone.
Now, Mr. Reese.
Everybody, down!
[Gunfire]
[Grunting]
Get your ass up here, now!
- Thanks for the help.
- Thanks for the call.
- Where are we taking him?
- Fed building downtown.
The FBI may be
the only ones we can trust.
Lot of dirty cops
between here and there.
This will be the last mistake
you ever make.
[Tires screech]
NYPD!
Get your hands on your--
Where the hell are they?
Gone.
[Turns key]
It's dead.
He shot out the engine.
He didn't shoot your camera.
[Typing]
(Simmons)
Get this out on the wire.
Our people only.
Not just the ones in blue.
I want every criminal outfit
on the street
to have this picture.
The man in the suit
dies tonight.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net