Clear the stage,
please.
Ladies, gentlemen, please
vacate the stage.
I know you hear me.
I know you know what it means.
Clear the stage!
'' The ballet competitions
are the most effective
'' For a candidate
the dancer is seen
by elite dance schools
the world and other companies.''
'' Youth America Grand Prix
is the ballet competition
World's largest''
granted full scholarships
and employment contracts
dancers from 9-1 nine years.''
'' First'' position
Care, Hannah.
Hannah.
I started dancing
when she was four.
I love ballet.
I do not know.
I just like it so ...
It's hard to explain.
This is an air gun.
Maybe I should
shoot right now.
These are things
Ballet Training
and this is a foot extender.
It hurts a lot.
This one here,
you're supposed to do
whenever possible
and then five times
after flatly
no longer can do.
This is to help
to turn around.
That is right!
Yes!
My ballet teacher called
Denys Ganio.
He is French.
He is very strict,
but not in bad vibes.
Is strict cool.
It's funny.
When you do something right,
you really corrected.
Him ..
Well, sometimes it's painful.
When I work with Aran,
I'm not working
with a 1 1 years.
Pas de Bourree.
Plie.
If we have one or two as he
in our life, it is much.
I was lucky to accept
my son at 20
in Ballet
of the Paris Opera.
Now I have to Aran
and I am full.
Youth America Grand Prix
is coming
and have been training
very hard.
Hopefully that will deliver results.
It feels good to have
worked so hard
and have that mentality.
Then you feel like everything hurts
when you get home.
Children who are engaged
the ballet as a career
leave much of his childhood.
Do not go to parties or sleepovers
and nothing unravel
or those things.
Not possible.
Do not throw the camera.
There are two babies.
'' The family of Aran
currently lives
near a U.S. Naval Base
Naples, ltaly.''
Since we are
a military family,
we moved a lot.
Ryan finished working
Bethesda
and it was time to move
to another place where there was
ballet training.
So our only option
was to go to that place
and try to find ballet
somewhere
or six months did Ryan
in Kuwait.
Ryan chose to go to Kuwait
Six months
for Aran could continue
with their training.
Now we are in Naples
and drive two hours
north to Rome
to find
the best training.
So when you're ...
when you're in the Navy.
You can not ... You do not choose
where to live, so ...
It's a small price to pay.
Rock School'',
the best dance education''
Slowly.
I was born in Sierra Leone,
West Africa.
My name was Mabinty Bangura.
When I was adopted,
changed it to Michaela.
It is a miracle that I'm here.
P. .. I can not ...
I can not believe I'm here.
When I was younger,
I used to think I was dreaming.
'' Michaela was born during the boom
Civil War 1 2 years
in Sierra Leone''.
Wherever eye,
saw someone die.
There was not even a reason.
My parents were killed
by the rebels,
so my uncle brought me
the orphanage and ...
I lived there.
That was very good.
Yes.
Very well.
Do you know?
I think it is from the beginning
leg sometimes goes,
then you try,
and get up and later.
Do you understand the joke?
In other words ...
Yes, sorry ...
That, returns to passé
a second.
Resistance is also
at the last moment,
not just drop it.
- Punta.
- Yes!
- Yes, exactly.
- Oh, my God.
- Big difference.
- It's huge.
If I'm here judging,
that would be a big difference.
In truth, it's huge.
So we decided to make
with its variation
was to go beyond the limit,
because it has extreme power.
You can do many things.
It's very athletic.
Now I have to get her away
Eagle
and a little closer
to the swan.
This is me and she is Mia.
We adopted the same time.
I do not know how to describe it,
but it was ... it was very difficult
go to sleep
and the other children at the orphanage
were afraid that something bad
happen and escaped.
Michaela handled it all
very well, as ...
Once, I tried to save
my teacher,
but like I lost
knowledge
and cut off the arms
and legs,
and just left there.
Then we came to the United States
and all concerned
for us.
It was great.
Good night, Mom!
Good night, princesses.
Good night.
Elastic spend my night painting
for the braces.
This used underwear
under their tutus,
not come in dark brown.
Pinto this
for a brunette girl
because they are all what we call
flesh color.
Well, white.
Would you still like this
is dark brown?
Here?
This needs to become
in dark brown.
A mother once told me:
'' Everyone knows that girls
Black can not dance ballet.''
Do they speak well because she
is adopted
and imagine that they feel
the same for her
what they feel they
for their children?
Or so they say
because, in reality, are so
insensitive about race?
'' Love, Family''
We always wanted
a large family
and I said to my husband:
'' Why not adopt
'' An African country affected
by war?
No one deserves to be caught
in a war zone.''
We were in the process
to adopt Mia
and said:'' There's another girl
'' And can not find
a family for her
'' Because he has vitiligo,
'' Has pigmentation
'' And everyone is afraid
of adoption,
'' Because they thought it was
Devil girl
because of its spots.''
He said:'' Oh ...
Well, we can adopt it.''
I said,'' Yes, I thought so.''
That's how we had to Michaela.
I remember when I was six,
had her first recital
and he said:
'' Mom, you see my spots?''
I said:'' No, not at all.
No notice''.
She said:'' Oh, that's good.''
He said:'' I just wanted to make sure
'' Because if you can not see
from the audience
then I know that I can be
a professional dancer.''
At the orphanage,
I found a magazine
with a ballerina en pointe
in a pink tutu.
I kept it and I thought,
if I ever take,
I want to become something.
He looked so happy.
Being on tiptoe,
I thought it was great.
Is the only
I lived for,
become this person,
be exactly
as that dancer.
Getting a scholarship is something
very large.
It gives you the opportunity
to go to a place
where you never thought to go.
He takes pressure off your parents,
who you are paying everything.
The thing is that there are many
stereotypes
they say that if you
a ballerina black
have terrible feet,
have no extension.
You're too muscular.
Not have sufficient grace.
I would like to know as
the delicate black dancer
ballet dancing.
'' Every year, more than 5,000
Dancers (from September 9 to 1 years)
'' Enter the semifinals
of Youth America Grand Prix
held in most of 1 5
cities around the world.''
'' Only the most talented
advance to the finals
'' And compete for scholarships
and valuable contracts
from prestigious institutions
Dance around the world.''
You have to keep working,
follow, follow, follow
and the day will come.
A ballet competition
is controversial.
People do not realize
how important it is
fututo for a dancer.
They know exactly what
they want to do with your life.
They need to start
find work at 1 7 years.
Entering at least 5,000
competition
for the semifinals
and only a few hundred
reach the end
in New York.
You have five minutes
on stage
to prove why
you deserve this opportunity
and not someone else.
When I'm Back
the stage, I always tell
'' Good luck'' or'' good job''
and I look like I'm crazy.
Because people
is super competitive.
When I say'' good luck''
I see it as,
'' Who are you?
Why are you talking about?''
All evaluate each other
when they arrive.
You can see immediately
when you enter,
especially in the dressing room.
Five minutes to the show.
Five minutes.
From 263 to 270, please
out into the hallway.
We are about to begin.
The talent level here
is very high.
So it's a good place
for them,
because there directors
from different companies
worldwide
and disclosed.
My name is Joan Sebastian.
I'm from Colombia.
My dream
is to be a professional dancer.
This competition is very,
very important to me.
A scholarship can change my life.
Working for my family.
I remember all the time
my mom telling:
'' Keep going.
I know it will be wonderful,
the better.''
You're not jumping,
're flying, remember that.
Master, can play ...
and one, two, and three, and four?
Working this hard.
Sometimes you wake up
and your body is very tired.
Then you say:
'' Why am I doing this?''
It's like, no, I quit.
I want to go to Colombia.
I want to see my family,
but when you start
to take class
feel this magic thing
you have.
So it's like,
no, I want ...
I want to ...
I really want to do this.
How will you finish
your variation?
Well, I have to.
As a dancer,
I think he is very talented
and I think it was made
to dance.
This is when I was dancing
ABT.
Memories to jump
were without pain.
One, two, three.
Mine is better.
Joan, leaving his family
so young
and coming to another country
where you do not speak the language.
Everything is completely different
and you have to start from scratch.
I can give a
phone card, please.
Sometimes I ask:
'' How is everything?''
He says:
'' Well,'' I miss my mom.
It's tough.
He will be responsible for helping
his family,
so has
a great responsibility.
The food is almost ready.
We are, indeed, Latinos
and we love beans.
- And rice.
Almost every day,
eat the same.
Many dancers
would like to have a career,
but very, very, very few
succeed.
You must have the correct physical.
You must have the correct technique.
You must have a good
economic situation,
because the ballet is very,
very expensive.
Shoes, clothes, trips,
inscriptions, instructors,
tuition.
Maybe you could buy
two cars.
It can cost $ 1, 500
by choreography,
but winning advertising
to do well
competency
it might be a job
in a company.
All the money we have paid
in the last 1 0, 1 5 years
you've been dancing
be worth your university.
Hopefully now collect
the fruits, hopefully.
The daily income of the study ...
More private classes.
Each tutu, perhaps making
about 1 to 00 hours to,
depending on how many
layers of tulle.
It is very expensive to go
and buy them all the time.
A well-made tutu
can cost
between $ 1 500 and $ 2,000.
For me,
is like a wedding dress.
No ballet dress
1 for a girl four years.
Although we live in ltaly,
Aran has a manufacturer
Chicago favorite costumes.
These shoes premiered yesterday
and almost no use.
Sometimes, I try to find
stronger shoes,
to avoid having to spend
$ 80 daily.
Really, I love
see them dance.
I can see like five
or six hours a day
without getting bored at all.
Many kids my age,
January 00% are not sure
what they want to do.
I know I want to dance ballet
for the rest of my life.
Those people who say I'm
losing my childhood ...
I think I've had
enough childhood
and ballet sufficient
until now.
Let ...
Leave your head.
I think dancing in a company
with my brother
when we are bigger,
that is my big goal,
but it depends on him.
I mean, if he wants to achieve
that goal.
Yes, a high passé,
above, outside.
I think I'm better at ...
I think I'm better at emotion.
No emotion, but to smile.
I knew nothing,
nothing about ballet,
not even the first position
or nothing.
Before the start Miko
with ballet,
sulked
after his nap.
I took her to ballet.
Suddenly
was well animated.
It was, well, well happy.
So I started to study
to have more knowledge
about ballet.
If we were not a family
ballet,
perhaps would weigh
about 4 kilos more.
We would take more vacations,
would see more TV.
We would like
a normal family.
My ballet teacher, Viktor,
suggested it would be good idea
to study at home,
so that there were more hours
for ballet.
So I can improve
in less time.
I miss my friends,
because at home,
only my mom and my dog.
Miko, we gotta go.
Otherwise,
arrive late for rehearsal.
Okay, Miko.
Let's get ready.
Show us the wild child
the streets of Seville.
Forward.
Energy. Dynamic.
Yes.
Open shoulders.
Perfect.
Arms in first position.
Up, up, up!
Do not give up!
Be strong!
Miko is a student
exceptional.
Thank you.
Good job.
I do not see Jules
is the same case.
Can you plunge the stomach?
You bring a suit ballet
young.
Can you work hard?
Deal stomach.
Crush your breakfast.
I did not choose this variation.
I want to take the blame for everything
to Satoko.
Dream come true.
Your son is dancing now
Swan Lake .
A softer plie, Jules.
Plie softer.
Pie pointed.
I run!
Run, run, run, run.
Final position since.
Come on!
Big jump!
Even bigger now.
Top!
In fact, reverence
is the best part.
Well, the good thing is that
I'm not cool
and he loves it.
Do not tell anyone of my friends
school I dance ballet,
because in my old school,
I said,
but all began
to ridicule me.
Many men believe
that ballet is not what it is.
He is very athletic.
Women have tutus
and ballet flats.
Men do things male.
There is much energy and focus.
We heard stories
on children dancing
entering the secondary
and exit
by merciless teasing
and stereotypes.
Until now,
he is strong and understands
not worth listening to
to such people.
I must say,
I never imagined that my son
was a dancer.
I played baseball as a child
and assumed that my son was going to do
some baseball, basketball ...
But it could be
more proud.
'' European Semifinals
Youth American Grand Prix''
'' Israeli Aran and her friend, Gaya,
compete
in the youngest division,
of 9-1 1 years''.
One, two, three ...
'' Today the dancers dance
both variations of ballet,
contemporary and classic.''
I want you beautiful.
In the summer,
went to an adult class
and she was very scared
because all
They are very professional.
Suddenly, we saw a child
of age ...
An adorable toddler and wonderful.
Gaya became interested
in ballet after that,
I think it was for Aran.
He was handsome and strong.
Photo ...
Two flashes at a time.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Not anymore.
Number 1 4,
Aran Bell, January 1st years
variation Bayadere only .
I was lucky to land well
in the spins,
because the lights ...
It was all a blur.
Very well.
Bravo, bravo, bravo.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Gaya Bommer Yemini of lsrael
Broncos  presenting .
When she dances,
something in his face changed.
Two different people.
I see your age
changing ...
As age is changing.
Something in the expression
and concentration
is changing.
It becomes adult
when he dances.
I can not breathe.
It was wonderful.
She certainly
will go into the final round.
I hope so,
after what he did.
Yes, she will get something.
He's cute.
Then the bow.
Beautiful dancers.
Stuck!
When Gaya hurt his foot,
could not walk.
When he saw Aran running,
suddenly, with all the love,
ran after him
as if he had nothing.
See what makes love
people?
Love happy.
'' Night'' awards ceremony
And the winners are ...
'' Only three dancers
Aran Division
'' Win prizes
in European semifinals
and advance to the finals.''
Aran Bell.
Gaya Bommer Yemini.
'' They have five months to rehearse
before meeting
in the finals in New York''.
If you dance so well
and know what you are able,
Rebecca could certainly win.
284, Rebecca Houseknecht,
January 7 years
presenting a variation ...
- How was it?
- It was pretty bad.
Shut up.
You did good!
Neither saw him.
Stacy saw.
It was horrible.
Turn around.
Practices both
even then
one minutes on stage
and you're done, that's all.
No one sees all the work
you put.
Ballerina Princess''''
'' Princess''
I think I live a life
quite normal.
I go to a regular high school.
I have friends at school.
I have a boyfriend.
I have task as all
others in my school.
Management.
Also as.
As much.
I was a cheerleader last year.
What a shame.
This is me cheerleading.
Another attempt to normal.
I think that's flexible.
It's pretty disgusting.
Many people tell me
I'm disgusting
because I can do strange things
as these.
'' Parking princesses,
'' crane is used
'' Princess''
Street'' Princess''
My nickname at school
is Barbie,
I think because I can bend
in different directions
and I love the pink,
I have blond hair.
I started dancing
just for fun
but now it is much more than that.
I'm working to be
professional and is just ...
It is a way to express,
besides talk.
My friends tell me as:
'' Why can not miss
one day at a dance class?''
They do not understand the discipline
of the dancers.
Do not believe it is a race
or so I've been
working so hard
all your life.
Rebecca Houseknecht.
'' The second dance of Rebecca
demonstrated to the judges
that had the potential
to advance to the final round.''
I was fully prepared
for this competition,
was on stage and ...
For this variation
in particular
which is super easy
for her.
I said:'' This is not my Rebecca''.
However,
handled it pretty well.
I mean, not to cut down
veins.
He handled it pretty well,
which is a tribute
maturity.
It will do much better
in the finals in New York,
Is not it?
- Yes
I need to relax.
Yes.
You can see it in your face.
Exhale and relax.
That's it.
It's better.
Then comes the little pirouette
to the arabesque position.
Why can not do that
with music?
- Do not know.
- Do not you know?
Do it again.
It definitely helps to have
a beautiful body
for ballet ...
Long legs and cute,
small head,
beautifully arched feet,
proportionate body.
Tenacity is the main thing
you need a dancer.
I worry that Rebecca
is looking for work
at this particular time,
because companies
are laying off dancers,
are not engaging them.
It has everything and is ready.
You just need to trust her.
Michaela semifinal round''''
I have fear.
There were, like, really good ...
People really skinny.
Ya know.
Wish I was ...
That green leotard.
It was great.
Was it like super high?
Yes ..
lgual and go outside.
Outside?
Yes, because I can not stand
be here.
I'm starting to give heat.
Issue 1 1 4, Michaela??
Michaela DePrince, January 4 years.
Dryad  Will Change
of Don Quixote .
Bravo!
Been great!
It was the first time
I see you dancing,
my love.
You were enjoying it,
smiling and were
doing well.
No more than people
the show.
This is great.
You danced better than ever.
I was impressed.
You were great.
I hold my breath ...
until it ends.
Yes, sometimes,
hold your breath
almost all the time.
The dance was perfect today.
He was in total control.
So it was ...
Almost we break fingers
to hold on so strong.
This side and tip.
Competition in the world
is so great.
If a girl like her,
but with better feet
judges and directors would take it
her instead of Miko.
I always joke and say:
'' Miko, I'll break your foot
or I'll break your wrist.''
That's what it takes
because elsewhere
Children are working
non-stop, right?
With devotion and with the idea
you want to be
a great dancer
or a great dancer.
We moved two weeks ago
to be closer to the ballet.
Then my husband changed
his office,
so workers
also had to move
by Miko and Jules ballet.
My sons work
more hours than I
and work every day,
to Saturday and Sunday.
's Father because well I have not
the guilt''
the entrepreneur''
as my children, in fact,
work harder than me.
Good face, good foot.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
All right, all right, all right.
Oh, my back.
The other moms think I'm
too involved,
but I will not regret
have been able to do more
them.
So I think I try to do
best.
I love broccoli.
Dad, I bet I can
this put me in the mouth.
I bet you can.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
Andale, J. J.
Do it.
Metellus.
I have money wagered.
Say:'''' Fat Bunny.
Fat Bunny.
I want to eat broccoli,
spinach and carrots.
We cheese, but is 50%
less fat
and 30% fewer calories.
Nonfat yogurt
for Miko and Jules
and low-fat yogurt
for my husband and me.
I have very carefully
to stay fit
and do not get fat.
When we fight and my sister
I say fat,
I say anorexic.
But I'm not.
Well, I'm not.
Really, I am.
I love food.
Yes, she is not anorexic.
Some people say I'm
too skinny
and I should start to get fat,
but ...
But you have to be skinny
to dance ballet.
You must have a lot of energy
and for that, you need food.
In fact, I think
the dancers eat much.
Most, I think.
I do not know. We are.
I think we're just thin
because we burn all
calories.
If you did not eat,
could not dance.
Joan Sebastian Semifinal''''
My dream is to go to the Royal Ballet.
My inspiration is Carlos Acosta.
He changed everything
in the world of ballet,
it was the first dancer
black at the Royal Ballet.
For some reason,
I feel something like
to be Colombian.
'' Joan Sebastian
advances to the finals''
Semifinal Round''
Miko and Jules''
Punta.
Punta. Punta.
Higher, higher, higher.
Number 202, Miko Fogarty,
January 2 years.
Urban Flower .
I was thinking,
Why do you fall?
I screwed up both.
It's my fault.
No Miko's fault.
What goes wrong
on stage is my fault,
but to be good,
is for her.
'' After falling, Miko will
to prove to the judges
should still advance
to the finals.''
Miko Fogarty, January 2 years
spring moments July 1 .
He was as anxious all
as well ...
Like a bird in its cage
wanting to escape.
Then ...
Then, yes, I did well.
What I love about her,
fell.
Never seen before
that fall well
and got up and danced as
if he had not fallen.
It's tiny, but strong.
- Right?
- Yes
The strongest thing in the world.
I think I did very well.
I think Viktor will say:
'' You did better
because you had an audience
front of you.''
Or something negative that is supposed
must be positive.
You always do a good job
on stage
and that's important.
Are you happy?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Yes?
Well, well, well, well.
The way to bring their children
to New York
to make themselves known.
'' Both Miko and Jules
advance to the finals.''
'' Jules was the youngest child
in their division
and the judges gave
another chance.''
'' Joan Sebastian returns home
for the first time in over one year.''
Here we are.
It is a soup with chicken.
Every time we are together,
always do this.
This is as traditional.
Oh!
God.
The scholarship is about $ 50,000
and the minimum wage in Colombia
is $ 250 a month.
J. J. stopped taking classes
ballet.
He said:'' I have no passion
for the ballet''.
I think it's difficult for my mom
I quit seeing.
So she asks me:
'' Really, tell me the truth.
Like ballet or not?''.
And I say something like:'' No''.
Something like that.
I ...
I never imagined that when
leave him,
I would be so sad.
I like the ballet,
but I never loved
as my sister.
I miss him dance.
I saw a boy dancing
Swan Lake
which he danced
and music ...
I told his mom,
you can wear the costume of J. J.
So I could see.
Ay, J. J.
People do not realize
how difficult it is to make
as a dancer.
You have so many injuries
as professional athletes.
People always think
that football players
lacrosse, soccer
are those that are injured,
but ballet dancers
are injured every day
and must continue working.
The skin on the bottom
my foot is clear,
as you cut
and the top of my foot
scraped
friction with the floor.
The top of my foot
starts bleeding
and I get like scabs.
You're working your body
maximum
since we have
about five years.
They are beautiful
in ballet slippers,
but when you take them off,
are not as nice.
They have a torn ligament
or have a stress fracture
and may be out for a year.
Well, that can make
shatter a career.
Which causes further
working with injuries
when they should not.
You make your body do things
that is not supposed to do,
it is not.
But satisfactory.
- Not natural.
- It is not.
If you only stay there.
Feel the heat.
'' Waiting Room
CT scans''
When you return to dance,
you will feel like you never
happened.
'' Three days before the end''
I have tendinitis
in my Achilles tendon.
I started hurting really bad.
I'm doing half of what
others are doing.
It is very painful.
Never stops hurting.
It should not be competing,
but do not want to ruin
my career here, so ...
We are three days
competition
and we are working with her,
their eyes fill with tears
and says:'' I do not think
I can do it.''
If you can not,
Do not.
He also knows that if he does
and can not do well,
then what is right?
Michaela!
Stop. Stop.
Try to keep it warm.
Do not overdo it, not worth it.
Maybe I should stop dancing.
Maybe this is not for me.
Oh, it is super cold.
Okay.
Right now is just bloated
and it hurts a lot.
I can not do anything about it.
Miko, can you check everything
what we have?
Where did you put on makeup?
Makeup goes here.
Can you put makeup there?
It looks good.
It's cute, right?
A crown.
How fitting.
Yes.
Yes, that ...
Seems to be
perfect blue tutu.
Will we be so lucky?
I like it very much.
Me too.
Really,
I want to see everyone dancing,
especially
to younger girls.
I want to see if any of them
is super good.
Oh, my foot,
now it hurts.
'' Over the next week,
300 soloists
worldwide will
the stage.''
'' On the last day,
30 judges representing''
elite institutions ballet
'' Will award scholarships
contracts and medals
the dancers
'' promising.
'' City Center in New York.
Final Round''
'' International Competition
ballet students.
I try to think of the thing
scariest
I've done in my life
to maintain calm
and think:'' This is not so bad
like that.''
However, I can not right now
think of anything.
Then we went to eat ...
Open the stage.
Come on, please.
Let's see, Miko, smile, smile.
Great smile, okay?
Do not say anything that has
to do.
Teachers will.
If you want to smile,
should smile.
If you want, you should not.
Be strong, be strong,
Be strong, be strong.
Strive fully.
Strive.
Do not feel anything ...
No, no, no.
Open up, open.
Stay, stay.
Where should you stay?
Opens.
Strive.
Feel, feel.
Dancers, leaving the
scenario, please.
We are about to begin.
Please take your seats,
please.
Is your number?
Are you 446?
Are you 444?
Okay.
444, Aran Bell, January 1st years
presenting  La Chauve-souris .
It was great.
Thank you.
It's really amazing.
I came from lsrael to New
York for this competition.
My heart is beating right
strong, I'm super excited.
I'm so stressed,
but need to calm down
and get into my character.
I felt much as Coppélia.
It was so emotional.
They both did very well.
It was fantastic.
- Thank you.
- Beautiful.
Oh, my God.
I loved it.
She could not see your number
because ...
But it is safe
you were perfect.
Did you enjoy it?
Sorry.
New York is stressful.
All are wonderful.
Everyone has potential.
Everyone wants to go
the same companies.
These children are so hard
themselves
that if they make a small mistake,
is difficult to deal
with them after
because they're perfectionists.
Amber, look at me.
Just tell me it was horrible.
It was beautiful.
Only that ... only the second
bourrée pas.
It's a live performance.
Whatever happens,
happens, you know?
You can not do this.
You should enjoy this moment.
See, you're hard on yourself.
Vente.
Let's go.
Amber. Amber.
Amber??
The finals
are the best of the best.
The greatest of the great,
so for many who
much is at stake.
She is very talented
and is beautiful.
If you put it all together in
this lovely package,
has everything going for it.
The difficult thing for a dancer
right now
is the fact that there
very little employment.
With this in mind,
just follow your dream.
It felt good.
Some girls,
how they work,
really are pointed.
Present your foot.
They turn
and are very accurate.
Many of them have
a facility,
a body, feet
and wonderful legs.
You see them and say:
'' She does have that something.
She's going to win.''
Everyone is looking
combinations body
training, passion
and personality.
It is very rare.
It is one in a million.
It is assumed that I have to see me
as Spanish.
lmagino in Spain
have curly hair,
so,
yes, I'm getting these.
I'm half.
Half?
Yes.
Well, I feel butterflies.
Sometimes I have to go
to pee, but okay.
Right now no.
Good Luck.
Number January 1, Miko Fogarty,
January 2 years
United States of America.
Don Quixote variation  .
Excuse me, sorry.
We spent hours last night
putting cream on her leg,
soaking,
Fingers crossed,
waiting today
feel better.
Is Johann or John?
- Joan.
350, Philipe Lens, January 6 years
Belgium,
present a variation
La fille mal gardée .
Everyone is watching.
You feel nervous.
It's like:'' Oh, my God,
I'm here.
I have to. I do''.
You start feeling
exciting thing
and then just dance.
351, Joan Sebastian Zamora,
January 6 years
present a variation
Don Quixote .
In fact, this
could stunt my tendon
and ruin the rest
of my career.
My teachers know
I'm not going to stop.
Even when injured,
still in pain,
even when sick,
continue dancing.
Issue 1 1 4,
Michaela DePrince, USA,
Fall  fast .
It hurt so much.
Seriously, I thought it was not going
be able to do any of this.
I just had to remove
all bounds.
I was so nervous,
not even I realized
I had an injury.
I forgot.
I held my breath
all times.
Did you like it?
God.
It was great.
After all,
was struggling to breathe.
Deliberation room'' judges''
87,350.
306 Kayley? Winfield?
3 ...
84.3.
What I seek is that glow
eyes,
love to dance.
View student potential,
not what I see in the moment
where they are on stage,
but what I can see in five
or ten years.
Technical, proportion,
expertise, musicality
and personality.
They are some of the things
I'm looking for
and hunger
and the need to dance.
In this competition today,
There are children who will
to be big stars.
Come on.
It is Manny.
Ladies and gentlemen,
is a pleasure to
welcome
the presentation of awards
competition
of Youth America Grand Prix.
At age division,
which is for dancers
of 9-1 1 years ...
'' Medals.
Aran Division Gaya''
In the women's category,
the bronze medal ...
Gaya Bommer Yemin
of lsrael.
In the men's category,
bronze medal,
Reo Morikawa.
The silver medal,
Juan Miguel Fernandez Vera.
And the gold medal ...
Sunu Lim of Korea.
There is another prize.
It is for the dancer
which potential
has been estimated
as the highest
in the age division.
Best overall performance.
The award goes to ...
Aran Bell.
Neither knew she had won
third.
I was like:
'' Yes, won third place!''.
She was like:'' What?''.
Oh, my God.
Until now understood
what happened!
All this time she did not know.
I am very proud of you.
You sores everywhere.
In the junior division,
including dancers
1 2 to 1 4 years ...
'' Medals.
Miko and Michaela Division''
In the women's category ...
I'm not sure
hearing
a girl 2 years 1 win.
I'm not expecting much.
The bronze medal,
Miko Fogarty.
That is small.
Yes, hard work rewarded.
Hard work rewarded.
I'm super happy
and it's amazing.
I think I heard a scream Viktor
in the public
when they said my name.
I can not believe.
I do not know.
Really,
I can not believe.
Here are our winners
junior division.
Expect much this time
and have an expectation
as high
it can change your career.
Today we are creating the future.
Some of the dancers
receive
professional practice or
work
with some ballet companies
represented here.
What Rebecca is looking
is the opportunity for a
position in a company.
Let's give them a round of applause
to all our winners.
Rebecca'' did not receive an offer
'' contract.
The most important
to win scholarships.
Most young people come to
become known in the future,
but higher come
because they want to win these scholarships
for large schools
International.
For the American Ballet Theatre
school
Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis,
Scholarship winners are ...
Michaela DePrince.
I always think of the little
girl who was so ill,
I did not think he was going to
bring home alive.
ABT I want now.
I am so grateful.
For the Royal Ballet School
UK ...
Joan Sebastian Zamora.
Finally, it is my dream.
My life will change.
'' First'' position
Send me a message to arrive.
I love you.
Also I love you.
Goodbye.
God.
Look at my parking lot.
Yes.
'' After the competition,
Rebecca graduated from high school.''
'' Two months later, a judge
Washington Ballet called.''
'''' Was hired.
'' Miko has new coach
stretching
and is working harder
'' ever.
Lower your shoulders.
Yes, well.
Requires stretching classes
extreme special.
It is so sore that
is difficult to put my knees
together in first position.
My mom says that if you have
a knack
as ballet or something,
the only way to enter the Ivy
League schools such as Harvard
or M.l.T.
is being really ready.
So I got all these
workbooks.
Michaela'' accepted his scholarship
and moved to New York
with his family.''
'' His foot has healed.''
Once it is
a professional dancer,
I want to return to Sierra Leone
and open a dance school
so that other children have
the experience I had.
Gaya'' has been practicing,
Cartoon girl,
a modern piece with
choreographed by her mother.''
'' He hopes to win a scholarship
this year.''
'' Aran still living in ltaly
'' And learned
a new contemporary dance
The mad hatter  called ''.
Strong arms.
Keep the second position.
I'm in London now
at the Royal Ballet.
I can complete my dream.
I want to be the main
or solo in a company.
Passé.
Now, walk into your elbow.
'' Joan Sebastian is the first
Colombian student
attending school
Royal Ballet''.
Resync'ed from DVD version by SourGrass :-))