[ Final Episode ]
Just like Soo and Bin's biological mother
I can be possibly become like her?
Is that why?
When I die, are you going
to take care of my kids?
What?
When I die you have to raise all five
kids, what are you going to do now?
It will be back breaking, Honey.
I won't be able to die because I
would be so worried about that.
Don't say things like that. I don't
like it even if it was a joke.
Why are you being like this when
the test results not even out yet?
I'm sure that there will
be nothing wrong with me.
I'm just scared because I'm reminded of
what happened a long time ago that's all.
I know, I can understand
you're worried Honey
but I will be fine, really. You know why?
I have a long life line ever
since I was born you know.
Take a look honey, ta-da! Look at this.
This is my life line here,
it's super long, look at it.
I'm going to be living for a long time.
A long time ago there was this famous old grandpa that was a
palm reader in my neighborhood and that's what he told me.
I will be living way longer than
you, Honey so don't worry. Okay?
Oh Grandmother, you're awake.
But Son-in-law,
What are you doing so early in the morning?
I'm making some porridge
for the children's mother.
She went through an endoscope examination yesterday so I
want to feed her some porridge first thing in the morning.
The doctor said that she should avoid eating food
that's a little too stimulating for the time being.
Hey, Son-in-law is making you
porridge right now, dear.
He said that you should eat porridge since
you went through an examination yesterday.
Really?
My goodness, he cares for you horrendously.
My husband is that kind of man, Grandma.
I really married well, didn't I?
You did, sweetheart. You're such a lucky
girl to meet such a husband like that.
When is the test result
going to come out anyway?
In about a few days or so. I also did have a
corrosive esophagitis in the past too, Grandma.
I was told that this kind of sickness is common for modern people
because they drink coffee constantly and go to sleep and stuff.
It's nothing really so don't
worry about it, Grandma.
How can there be a sickness that's not a big deal? Even
something small can turn into a big illness you know.
So that's why Son-in-law is so
concerned like that, you know.
But it's nothing really though.
He is so sensitive about
me getting sick grandma.
I think it's because of
his former wife too.
He cried yesterday grandma.
Huh? The son in law cried?
Is it because of you getting
checked out at the hospital?
Isn't that funny grandma? I
thought I was gonna die laughing.
I think he is super scared because he
thinks that I'm gonna die or something.
Don't laugh sweetheart. He
went through that once before
so whenever something like this happens I'm
sure he gets scared and feels uneasy too.
I really feel sorry for that guy.
Last night at 2:00am in the morning
I woke from my asleep
but then you weren't there
when I looked next to me.
Maybe you opened up your eyes
briefly when I in the restroom sir.
That's strange.
I also opened up my eyes briefly around 4 o'clock in the
morning but your sister wasn't there next to me either.
Where were you at that time miss?
I went to the restroom first and I couldn't go
to sleep so I walked around the neighborhood.
Can you anything that
early in the morning huh?
- Does that make sense?
- Of course it doesn't.
The air is really fresh here you know.
You went for a walk at
that hour didn't you?
Yeah, he's right, it's really
nice over here you know.
It's kinda dangerous though.
So from what we know so far, starting from
2-4 am in the morning, the two of you
weren't in the rooms that
you're supposed to be in right?
More than anything, they
disappeared early on
and showed up a lot later too.
Should I get some more bread?
There are fruits available too.
Wait for me, let's go together.
Do whatever you want.
What are we gonna do? I don't
think either of them were asleep.
They're just saying that.
Yeon Doo, I'm sure you haven't got much sleep
but why are you still so pretty today?
What are you saying?
- Let's just go back to Seoul.
- Why?
You should let them spend some time together
with the rest of the time they have left oppa.
You said that you have some
filming left to do anyways.
Stop messing with your sister already.
Okay. Let me eat the rest of this.
He can't go workout? Why?
My new mother went to the hospital yesterday and went through
an examination pr something like that because she is sick.
So when's the result coming out?
Didn't that take about two
to three days back then?
Did it?
Is your new mother awake?
How is she feeling?
- She's feeling good and she said she is fine.
- Is that right?
- I'm gonna go back upstairs now.
- Oh, okay.
- Alright.
- Bye.
I bet our son in law is going through
a lot emotional pain right now dear.
Yesterday I asked him if the
children's mother is sick
and the moment he heard that
his face become so pale.
Why wouldn't he be?
When you see experienced something traumatic you would
be shocked when similar things happen you know.
When son in law heard about that it reminded
him of Jin Young just like it did for us.
I told you not to say stuff like that honey.
What are you constantly being like that for?
Do all the people that go to the hospital and go through
an endoscope exam all die of cancer huh? Geesh.
Did I say that it was the case?
But the situation is exactly the same as our Jin
Young no matter how much I think about it..
I told you to stop that. One time is enough
with talking about unlucky things okay?
Hey, Jin Joo
hurry up and change into your
exercise clothes immediately.
- Why?
- Teacher Kim will be coming here for his morning exercise you know.
Nobody from the third floor is gonna be
going out to exercise today anyways.
Are you gonna make Teacher Kim wait by himself
outside huh? He's probably waiting for us by now.
You can go out there by yourself dad.
Would Teacher Kim come here for me?
He is coming here for you silly.
You silly little thing.
Don't say anymore and just change into
your workout clothes already. Alright?
Hurry up girl!
This silly boy.
Are you aware that teacher Kim your son
comes over to our house every morning?
Pardon?
He works out with me every morning folks.
Honey, I think Taemin went over
to that house to exercise again.
What should we do dear?
What else can we do honey? All you have to
do is approve of their relationship honey.
Honey.
You know very well how Taemin is honey.
When he acts like that there is nobody
that will be able to stop him you know.
Just let him have his way dear.
That's the only thing that we can do.
First of all, we should take care of Sang Min's wedding
then you should think about it carefully honey.
I wonder if something's going on.
Have you been well?
You lost a lot of weight. You
should try to eat better.
Same goes for you too.
Why do you keep on coming over here
to exercise in this hot weather?
Don't do that.
Are you worried about me now?
It's a lot of fun.
Running every morning with your
father, Soo's father and the boys.
It would be difficult to do
when the new semester starts
but I still want to take the time out during
the weekend and go exercise with your dad.
You said that you wanted to end it with
me but I do not want to do that Jin Joo.
I'm a man that breaks the
heart of a woman he loves
so I'm aware of the fact that I'm
a foolish man. I do know that.
Taemin.
Jin Joo.
Just this once. Do you think you can
put your trust in me this once?
I will try to do better.
You won't have to be hurting
again nor be disappointed.
And I will work a lot more harder
to be able to do that. Okay?
How much better can you do than this? How much
more do you have to work harder than this?
You are already more than
enough to me Taemin.
You never even disappointed me.
Sorry, Taemin for giving
you such a hard time.
Jin Joo.
How about if we take it slow this time?
- Slowly?
- Yep.
You can do all you can with your nail
art work which you like so much.
I can do all I can with my work too and
we can just take it slow like that.
I've been thinking about a lot of things because
of what I've been going through with you.
I thought that marriage
wouldn't be so difficult as long as our
feelings towards each other was strong.
But I realized that it wasn't.
I don't have anything that I can call my own since
I'm not financially stable like my brother.
I won't be able to get married
without the help of my parents too.
And maybe I thought of getting married
to be something to easy to achieve.
I should have thought about it more carefully, and I think
that we have come this far because I didn't do that.
Why do you keep on thinking
that it's just your fault?
I am more at fault here.
So this time
lets hold each others hands like this
without rushing and just go at it slowly.
My parents and your parents feelings
could be changed bit by bit if we work on
understanding where they're coming from.
Actually
I learned a lot by seeing you working
really hard to be accepted by my parents.
I was hurt for being disapproved but
she's still your mother after all.
I should've tried harder.
Instead of trying to overcome it by
myself, I should've discussed it with you
so we could come up with
a solution together.
I thought about all that.
It's still not too late.
We can both try really hard like that
and when we are able to get married with our own strength, then
we should get married with both of our parents blessing us.
When would that be?
About three years at the most.
But what if your mom still
isn't happy with me then?
Then we should just get married on our own.
We would be able to save up
some money within three years.
And we would be able to get
married on our own by then.
Would you be able to buy a
house within three years?
Of course not.
You want to live in a big house Jin Joo?
No, no. I'm okay living in a room for
rent as long as I can marry you.
Me too.
As long as I can be with you I'm
fine living in a rooftop house.
Let's not forget about how we feel
we should just trust each other
and go at it slowly Jin Joo.
Okay.
Let's try this out and go at it slowly.
I will try really hard.
I found out that he didn't
really break up with Jin Joo.
Yes, well..
We can't really talk about anything in detail
here but here is a gift for you. Please take it.
Why did they have to give me this?
It makes me feel so burdensome.
They bought a quality product.
Alright, our marketing team did it again.
You all worked really hard.
- Cheers.
- Thank you for the good work!
Sorry guys, Assistant An hasn't
been feeling well lately.
Look at you, you are totally
devoted to your wife.
You saw that right? You should also learn everything
you need to know before you get married Hye Sung.
Yes, ma'am.
You are taking your vacation late because there
have been so many events, isn't that right?
But I think this is way better since you are able to go on
your vacation with a lot of free time and a leisurely manner.
You've all worked really hard so you should get
plenty of rest while you are on your vacations.
Okay!
How are you gonna spend your time while you're
on your vacation? Where you guys gonna be going?
I'm gonna use up the vacation time I haven't used
and I'm planning on going to Spain and Portugal.
Really? You're so lucky. I heard that there
are a lot of good looking men in Spain.
That's why I'm going there you know.
Are you going anywhere Yeon Jae?
I'm going to Jeju Islands with my friends.
What about you Hye Sung sunbae?
I bought a ticket three months in advanced
so I can go to Okinawa with my family.
By the way, you should go on a
family vacation too Team Leader.
While I'm on vacation I will be spending
my time being with Assistant An perhaps?
Oh geez.
Here look.
My goodness, you are really too much!
I wanted to at least go to the mountains
with the kids while we are on vacation.
Should we go after we hear
the test result tomorrow?
I'm sure the test results will come out
to be positive. Don't you think so?
We can't do that.
No matter what your test result come
out to be, you still have to rest.
The kids will be disappointed though.
This won't be the only
summer we'll have you know.
But still.
I have a plan for that.
One. Two.Three.
♪ One and two. Two and three.
Three and four and five. ♪
♪ Hey yo.♪ ♪ Hey yo.♪♪
Watch out for fire. ♪
♪ Hey yo. Hey yo. Watch out for fire. ♪
Oh yeah!
[Phone ringing]
What happened? Why haven't you called?
I've been so curious.
I haven't heard the test results yet
because they are backed up with patients.
Are the children having fun playing?
Alright, I'll give you a call when
the test result comes out. Okay.
- Was that your grandma?
- It was.
She said that the kids are playing
really hard. Your idea is good.
- Ms. An Mi Jung.
- Yes!/Yes!
Your test results has come out.
You are diagnosed with mild stomach cancer.
Mild stomach cancer?
To explain this simply, mild stomach cancer
is cells growing into a tumor in the stomach.
And usually this can lead
to a full blown cancer
but Ms. An, you were able
to discover it early on
and the cancer cells are weak so it's possible
to get rid of it with just a simple operation.
Oh, thank you doctor.
So, how would the operation proceed?
And the operation will proceed using
a double path spectrometer device.
Also the duration time for the operation
will be about four hours at the most.
You will be staying at the hospital
for about five days at the least.
Should I set up a date for
the operation right away?
Yes, doctor. It would be great if I can get the operation done
as quickly as possible since we are on vacation as of today.
It would be great if I can get the
operation done while I'm on break.
Sure thing, we will try to set up an operation
date revolving around your schedule.
How long is your vacation by the way?
Come out already!
Get out kids. Hold on to Bin.
Like that kiddo.
I told you honey, they
said it's nothing big.
You were getting scared for nothing
and it got me all scared too.
You have to get an operation, how
can that be something small?
I do feel a little scared
to be honest with you.
But still, we should be thankful
that it's nothing a deadly disease.
I think the kids are done playing.
Come on in father in law. What's all this?
What are you two doing here?
What did the doctor say at the hospital?
You said that you'll call us as
soon as the test results come out.
Here we are.
I brought some pickled vegetables.
Let's see here.
And this is grilled yellow corvina from Beop
Seong that is given to us by our friend Mr Kang.
So take this out of the freezer
everytime you want to have some, okay?
And this is salted seafood from Mokpo
and this is perfect for you to have when
you don't have any appetite you know.
And the rest is just regular side dishes.
Oh okay. Thank you very much,
we will enjoy it for sure.
We didn't bring any kimchi on purpuse since your
mother in law is making it for you, isn't that right?
Oh my, this is so much. If you bring all
this then what are you going to eat?
We have a small family you know.
And our maid lady is such a good cook
so we eat three delicious meal a day so
you won't have to worry about a thing.
I guess I won't have to worry
about side dishes for awhile.
Why are you standing there like that?
Have a seat. Just have a seat.
Alright, alright. Woo Young's mom.
Oh, okay. Son in law, I know that the
grandma here is helping around the house
and Woo Young's mom is tired too
so our maid lady should come here twice a week and you can
also get the side dishes from our house too. Can we do that?
Just do that. I heard from Soo that
the grandma here looks very tired.
And I also heard that you do all
the housework even after work.
I appreciate your thought but...
Of course I know how you feel my dear son in
law. That's why you refused last time you know.
But son in law things are a bit
different now than before.
We live like one family even though we live in a different apartment so why
would it be such a big deal for our maid lady come by every now and then?
Don't you think so?
Then I will receive your help while
I'm recovering from my surgery.
That's a good idea.
Just continue to use our help after that so you
won't have to jump up and down because of the kids.
Let's just do that honey. Your grandma
is having a hard time too you know.
Then I will do that. Thank you very much.
I was flustered when both of you moved
over here at first to be honest with you.
Of course you were.
We felt the same way. I did misunderstand you and felt
suspicious about you at first to be honest with you.
It's natural for us to be in that
position at the time you know.
And after living so close to you I realized
it's hard to fine someone like you.
Now I can understand why my son in law
was so stubborn about marrying you.
I think the kids are really here now.
Oh my.
You guys had a pool party
up on the rooftop?
Yes, sir. We really had a lot of fun.
Woori, did you have fun too?
Woojoo, you're not cold? Your
lips are all blue now kiddo.
Mommy, I want some warm water.
- Oh, okay sweetie.
- Come here sweetie. Go on in my dear.
What happened to mother at the hospital?
Woori!
This is so difficult.
Woori, let's talk with grandpa for a bit.
Woori, let's talk this out sweetie, okay?
Grandpa really has something to tell you.
Grandpa thought about something.
In order for My Woori to be
chosen from the next audition
I was wondering what this manager
of yours should be doing.
Woori, do you want a
private piano lesson? Huh?
There could be a piano
playing scene in a drama
and if you are really good at playing the
piano then that would be a good thing, right?
You don't want to?
Then what should I do for you?
Woori, you should talk so I would
know what you want my dear.
There is no way of knowing what this grandpa
should do because you are saying anything Woori.
It seems like you don't
know anything grandpa.
What do you mean?
If you want to make me feel better you shouldn't keep
on saying that you're gonna do something for me.
But you should first appologize
to me first instead.
Grandpa, you said that you're only gonna bring me
to this place but you brought Bin over here too.
So that's what it was all along?
Woori, grandpa will truly and
sincerely apologize to you.
That day Bin was in a really bad
mood that day to be honest with you
and I brought her here to cheer her up.
But before that you were really the first child that I
brought over to this shaved ice place. And I mean that.
So, if you don't want a private piano lesson
then how about a private English lesson then?
But my new dad is doing that for me though.
I like that way more because
its so much more fun.
Then let's get you enrolled into an
academy. The very best acting school.
But the acting school is far away from home so I
won't be able to go there by myself you know.
I will take you. You have a manager right here
and you shouldn't let that go to waste kid.
Really?! So you'll be taking me to the acting
school and also bring me back grandpa?!
Of course my dear!
I'm your manager after all Woori. Then it's a deal,
you're gonna be attending the acting school, okay?
I love it! Then pinky swear.
Promise.
You can't break your promise this time.
Of course I won't.
So don't you worry.
It's gonna melt so let's eat up.
There you go.
The shaved ice here is
really delicious grandpa.
Of course it is. Your manager here will
buy you plenty of it in the future, okay?
So, eat up my dear. Yes, mix
it up nicely like that too.
- Father. - Yes, son.
- What are you gonna do about Woojoo now?
Do you know how Woojoo was after
coming back from the playground?
Woojoo, what's wrong?
My Woojin.
Woojin, I miss you! My dear Woojin!
- My dear Woojin!
- It's okay, baby.
It's okay baby.
Is it that bad?
What are you gonna do now father?
My goodness.
This is worse than I thought.
Mr.Pro Kim, you are so gorgeous,
please give me an autograph.
This popularity of mine for goodness sake.
All that you're doing will be useless now.
If you keep on doing this..
What's going on here? How did
you find out that I was here?
I contacted Manager Do of course.
What's going on here? Did you guys plan
something together to surprise me huh?
Is that what this is?
I'm off now.
- Don't be too hard on her.
- Bye hyung.
Goodbye.
We were supposed to meet up in the evening.
I made reservation at a nice restaurant.
I have someone that I don't want to wait till
dinner time because I miss him so much you know.
Who would that be?
There his guy name Kim Sang Min
who is my personal golf teacher.
Then shall we go on with
the special lesson?
You should teach me properly this time. You
were just fooling around last time you know.
Okay, come here silly.
- Put your left glove on. - Yes.
- Hold on a minute. Instead of this
This one here.
Bend your waist like that and put your
left hand on the golf club like that.
And smoothly like that.
You're here.
What happened my boy? You should've
at least told me about this?
How could you tell me about this so
suddenly early in the morning son?
I didn't want to worry you guys.
We should all worry together.
It's fortunate enough to be not
so big of an operation right?
Did the doctor say that she will be
perfectly healed after the operation?
Yes, mother. He said she'll be fine.
Oh my, thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Even when I heard about the surgery I
feel like I lost ten years of my life.
Just by hearing about the surgery
it made my heart drop my boy.
I'm sorry for making you worry.
What are you talking about? I feel this way
so I'm sure you're feeling
a lot worse right now.
I bet you had all kinds
of strange thoughts son.
Being sick from time to
time is normal in life.
But bad things don't happen all the
time because of sickness either.
Don't be so anxious about it. All you have to do
now is to love her and care for her even more.
Just think of this as a challenge that comes your
way from time to time so you can be more loving.
Yes, father.
Eureka! Okay!
How many times have we been going
around in circles? I'm so tired honey.
No, you can't. They say that you have
to exercise in order for you to fart.
This is so tiring.
You're being such a crybaby.
Howcome you can't even lay a fart properly? You
were so good at doing that on a normal day.
I also want to fart too honey, I really do!
I am so hungry. I want to eat too honey.
Why don't you go around the hospital by yourself one more
time then. I'm gonna go to the bathroom for a bit, okay?
My goodness! You did good.
Be careful.
Woojoo, look at this.
There a lot of potential brothers
that you can choose from here Woojoo.
Choose the one that you
like here the most okay?
Look, this guy over here is pretty too.
That one there looks nice too.
This guy over here too. There we are.
What do you think about this one here?
You don't like this one either?
This one is is nice looking
and so is this one too.
But it doesn't look like Woojin though.
But take a good look at it, you never know if you can
find one that's even nicer looking than Woo Jin.
There isn't any. It has to
be Woo Jin no matter what.
Is that right? But try to take
a look at it more carefully.
Alright then. I guess Woo Jin was very
nice looking and precious to you.
Woojoo, let's go since your grandma
is probably waiting for you by now.
Let's look for it next time, okay?
Thank you.
- Come again.
- I will.
How do you feel eating real food after just eating
nothing but porridge for the last few days?
I think I'm able to live now.
I had a more difficult time holding in my hunger
than having the surgery to be honest with you.
Eat everything that's here equally.
And your mother in law sent
this over for you to eat.
Make sure to eat all of this too, okay?
Yes, I will.
Oh yea, you said that you'll be discharged
today right? When are you guys leaving?
Your grandma must be waiting
for you right now big time
because we're so late right? Woojoo my dear
Woojin!
Hey, Woojoo! What's going on?!
Grandpa, please hurry up and come
over here. Woojin is over here.
Huh?! Are you sure this is Woojin?
I'm sure of it! This is my little brother Yoon
Woojin. Woojin, what have you been doing here?
I know right?
Our dear little Woojoo here has been looking all over for you
WooJin, why were you here so far away? You've been a bad boy.
Grandpa, if you get mad a little much my
dear little Woojin will be scared of you.
Yeah, that must be so right?
Woojoo, should we hurry up and take Woojin
before someone comes and snatches it away?
Woojin, I'm so glad to see you again.
Let's not separate ever again.
You got that?
Woojoo, let's go.
Hello everyone!
Congratulations.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you very much.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Congratulations.
You're here.
It's so hectic huh?
I'm fine. Let's go this way.
Thanks for coming
Congratulations.
We can't miss out on such
a good day like this.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much. I'm so glad you're here.
You're here.
Oh my goodness, you look so
beautiful in that hanbok.
Do I really?
Of course you do. Have you ever heard me saying anything
I don't mean? You look beautiful because I said so.
Why does the ribbon look
so cricket like that?
Director Lee. Oh my goodness.
You've been working so hard,
keep up the good work.
Thank you for coming.
Mother, father. Jin Joo is here.
Hello, father and mother.
Welcome.
Yes, thank you. Have you been well mother?
- I've been well. Have you also been doing well?
- Oh my goodness!
This couple looks so
good together you know.
- You're here.
- Yes, you are such a sweetheart.
I sincerely congratulate your oldest
son's marriage with all my heart madam.
It's nice to see you again sir.
You looks so gorgeous madam. You probably
look even prettier than the bride herself.
No wonder you were able to give birth to such good
looking sons, it's because you are such a beauty madam.
- Let's go honey.
- It was nice seeing you again.
Alrighty then.
See you later.
Thank you ladies.
Don't smile at me.
Don't smile yet Yeon Doo.
My heart hasn't calmed down yet.
You're overreacting again.
I'm not overreacting, okay? Oh my goodness.
You are really pretty today,
you are super beautiful!
Oh man, I thought you were
a goddess or something.
Hey there Jin Joo!
Hey, girl!
You look really pretty, this is so awesome!
Don't you agree Taemin?
Oh yeah, Jin Joo, this is your
first time meeting Sang Min right?
Huh? Hyung is what? You
were here all along bro?
Yeah dude.
Really? This is your first
time seeing each other huh?
Ah yes, hello there.
Yes, hello.
The woman you liked so much that you even used a childish
strategy to trigger a jealous behavior out of her was
Yeon Tae huh?
Don't look at me like someone that you already know.
This is our first time seeing each other okay?
You must feel good right now
since you're able to finally get married
to the girl that you really like.
Hey, I will be your older
brother in law pretty soon.
I know, let's get along in the future okay?
My future brother in law..
What is it? What's going on you two?
Huh? Oh, it's nothing.
Should the four of us
take a picture together?
Okay, shall we?
Sure!
Let's go.
Come over this way.
Over this way.
Thank you.
You're so pretty.
♪ When I quietly think about you. ♪
Finally, this will be the most
important moment of today's wedding.
This lady is the prettiest
of all, at least for today.
The bride will be entering the room!
♪ The heaven that I looked
up to so quietly. ♪
♪ Your name that appears
in my blank mind. ♪
♪ Cos I love you. ♪
♪ I want to know you. ♪
♪ Day by day I'm becoming
more like you each day. ♪
♪ Love is like a spring sunshine and
is pouring down my heart so warmly. ♪
♪ And it's embracing me. ♪
♪ Just by your name it
fills me up with love. ♪
♪ And it makes me smile all the more. ♪
♪ You hold me and make me laugh. ♪
♪ You really do. ♪
♪ You are the one that changes me. ♪
♪ You're the one that's able to do that. ♪
♪ You always make me dream. ♪
♪ Whenever I think of you,
I'm here just smiling. ♪
Be careful what you eat okay?
You do not have to worry
about father and mother.
I will treat my Yeon Tae like a
princess and bring back safely.
Brother in law, there is something that
you need to keep in mind for the future.
What would that be?
That fact that our Yeon Tae
has two older brothers.
Not one but two and that means
whatever you do to our Yeon Tae
will make you go through double the
punishment for what you did buddy.
You must understand very well
what I'm saying here right?
Yes, of course sir! I
will treat her well sirs!
Stop giving him a hard time and let him
go already boys. They will be late.
He's right dear. You should get going miss.
We'll be back safe and sound everyone.
You do that son.
We'll be back safely everyone.
Have a good trip!
Mother, it must be heavy carrying all that
to the car so I can help you carry them.
You don't have to do that.
I will carry those mom.
Taemin, let's go.
What are you doing these days?
- Me?
- Yeah.
Mother, I've been continuously
working at the nail shop.
I'm very good at it now.
I will be taking an exam for an official
licence and I'm very confident about that too.
- Really?
- Yes.
They won't be able to
oppose for too long right?
The kids are working so hard
to make it happen like that
so how would they be able to continuously
go against it honey? My goodness.
If they dare to continously oppose then I will just have to take
teacher Kim away from them and bring him to our home to live wit us.
You made up the decision
to go down to Kyungjoo?
It's because my aunt works down there.
What are we gonna tell Woori then?
It can't be helped if that's what you
have to do. I will tell Woori about it.
Please take good care of the kids.
We will raise the kids well,
so don't worry about that.
Write to the kids when you get there.
Even if Woo Young said that he didn't want to see you, he didn't mean
that. He just did that because he was angry with you that's all.
So please write okay? Make sure to do that.
I will do that, I promise.
Ho Tae, thanks for the good work.
Yeah, I really should be appreciated
for all the good work I did.
I did nothing but make movies which are just one part so I really
was exhausted doing a daily TV series that's 120 episodes you know.
But something good came out of you working so
hard. You even got high ratings for the show too.
Now its time for us to make
a new contract, right?
Hey, I should get back to making movies now since I made
some money. What's up with signing another contract?
Do you know how miserable I was there guy?
What do you mean you were miserable? It
looked like you were having fun to me.
I was exhausted mentally.
Mentally, you know.
My dream is way over there but my physical
body is right over here in this reality.
Do you know what that feels like guy? You would never understand
that feeling dude. Hey, you should take this back and..
- Wait a minute, this is..The money for this contract, is it for real?
- Yep.
It's real. No more B team for you man, now
you should come into become a real director.
Does this even make any sense? Are you seriously
gonna pay me this much? Are you serious about this?
Saehwa give your hand. Open up your hand.
What are you doing?
This is a flower from the garden.
Liquid from the flower?
Yeah, it's to dye your fingers red.
Hey, it's me Ho Tae.
I will sign the contract.
But you remember the movie that I didn't finish making? Let's
sign the contract once I'm done finish making that film.
That's the term for signing that contract. I must
finish making that film no matter what. Okay?
It has been a year since I have
become a father of five children.
Mother and father, congratulations
for your 1 year anniversary!
Congratulations!
We will blow out the candle after
we count two two okay? One and Two!
Mommy and daddy, did you make a wish?
Why would they have to make a wish? People
only make a wish on birthdays silly.
Why? Don't you make a wish
whenever you blow out the candle?
Whatever, you can do that if you want.
Mom and dad, did you make a wish?
I thought that it would be great if we
can eat out like this next year too.
I did too.
I wanted it to do my best
to make everyone happy.
And I wanted to be a good parent but
the kids didn't open up as easily.
It's here!
Daddy, this place is really good.
- Eat to your hearts content and let me know if you need more okay?
- Okay.
- You too Bin.
A year has already passed but
we are still clumsy parents.
The kids fight from time to time
and fall out every now and then
but we there are more happier times that make them
laugh and we are slowly building up time together.
[Team Leader An Mi Jung]
Hye Sung, there is a meeting for working
on the pattern for Pro Yoon right?
Yes, ma'am. There is a meeting with the
design team at 3:00 pm this afternoon.
The hand drawn portrait of Pro Yoon that he draw
himself which I got to see last time was outstanding.
The individuality of the athlete is
important because of the high profile name
so please make sure to take care of the athlete in
detail whenever you are working on the pattern.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Oh and Assistant Chun
Assistant Chun.
Oh about this year's FW season, is
the photobook for that out yet?
Not yet. The agency has sent us a planned visual of the project but
it came out to be a mess so I'm reorganizing everything right now.
I think I can submitted it by
tomorrow morning sometime.
Oh yeah?
Oh and Assistant Chun.
Could it be that, You are not dissatisfied by losing
the team leader spot to me or anything right?
No, I'm not okay? How could you
think up something like that?
I was just joking.
Young Jae, you have handed over the summer sale
POP and the poster to the sales team right?
Yes, ma'am. I have handed all
over earlier this morning.
You should help out Assistant Chun since
she's having a hard time right now.
Yes, ma'am.
I will be back, I'm gonna go to the directors
office a for a little bit everyone.
What should I help with?
I will do it myself.
Mr. director sir. Are you
really busy right now?
Yes, I am super busy. Why, what's up?
This is regarding Pro Kim's signing his contract
again. I have a headache because of this.
The term for the contract that Miracle company is
offering right now is totally shocking you know.
They told him that they will pay him twice as much as what we are offering here at Crystal
fashion, which includes the contract fee, incentive, and the training expenses too.
Would that even be possible? What we are
paying him isn't a small amount either.
They are desperate since the athletes that
they are sponsoring have poor results.
They are trying to get a hold of Pro Kim no matter what since
he has good results with a good fashion sense to boot.
Considering our budget we won't be ale to give him anything
more than what we originally offered him you know.
What are we gonna do, Mr. director?
What else can we do? We should try to get a hold of him somehow.
If Pro Kim leaves then we would be at a great loss too.
How are you gonna grab him?
I won't be able to get any answers if I
just sit here and worry all day long.
We should be calm and talk it out whenever we are going
through something like this you know. My goodness.
Hey, Brother in law.
Yes, hyungnim. What do you need sir?
I'm sure You are getting a lot of offers right now so I
was wondering if you are carefully taking a look at them.
Yes, I am here at the office of
the agency taking a look at...
You are not gonna make a decision
all on your own are you?
Of course not, I would have to
discuss with the agency as well.
You should also discuss with Yeon Tae too.
- Pardon?
- You don't discuss that kind of stuff with Yeon Tae or something?
The contract for a sponsorship is a very important matter you
know. A married couple should discuss it with each other, right?
A married couple with a good relationship shouldn't have any secrets
and it's all about sharing everything together, okay brother in law?
Do you even know what
I'm talking about here?
Yes, I do sir. But hyungnim
you couldn't be pressuring me to resign the contract with
Crystal fashion subtly by bringing up Yeon Tae right?
What are you talking about guy? You
are the one that should decided that.
How could I be able to make it happen
by pressuring for goodness sake?
Look at this, you look so much better
with the clothes from here you know.
The clothes from this brand is match
made in heaven for you Sang Min!
Do not try to persuade me girl. Private and
business matters are two different things okay?
Yes, this is Pro Kim Sang Min.
He is the model for this brand.
- Doesn't this look super good on him?
- Yes, he does.
You can go now.
Honey, be honest with me.
Would you like it if things go
better for us or your brother?
If things go well for my brother it
would be good for us too you know.
And also the brand that you were telling me about does give you a lot of money but you're the
one that told me that the quality of sponsorship for training is still pretty low there.
You're the one who acknowledged the fact that my
brother's company is the best when it comes to quality.
Yeon Doo my dear. That's not the kind
of answer that I wanted by the way.
I wasn't talking about anything that sounds so work
related. What is it that you really want Yeon Doo?
Me? I would be happy for you
to succeed the most of course.
Right? I'm always your first priority
to you. And I'm your number one right?
Of course, I would you ask something
so obvious like that for?
You should make sure to confirm all
that everytime you are reminded of it.
Then you'll be working again for
my brother's company right?
Alright girlie.
Let's go sign that contract.
So, you'll be opening up
your own shop Jin Joo?
My director wants me to stay and work as
a manager but I have a dream too okay?
Look at this.
After seeing this I decided to look into it and I
realized that I can run a business of my own too.
You have a lot of regulars and you have the chops
so you'll be able to go for something like this.
I know right? You have to
cheer me on okay Taemin?
My mom and dad are against it. They don't think
that I'm capable of running my own business.
Should I invest in your business?
How much are you gonna
invest in it anyways?
How much do you need? 30,000 won?
50,000 won?
What the hell?
[Laughing]
I told you to come out and eat
and you're still sleeping?!
Mom, let me sleep for ten minutes more!
Just five more minutes!
Hurry up and come out to eat or else
I'm gonna clear the table then.
Lee Bin! If you eat you're the one that gets
full and not me! Hurry up and come out to eat.
- Hurry up.
- I hate you mom!
What?
You hate me now? You come over here right
now girlie. Come over here right now.
Get up, you're not gonna get up?
You're not gonna get up?
Come over here. I'm gonna
have to carry you out now.
Mother and father. We are here.
- Welcome.
- Hello.
Our sweet little Joon is here.
Come to grandma.
Look at this pretty little thing.
I took him to get a shot but it was so hot
outside so I decided to stop by briefly.
It was hot right my babyboy?
You went through all that hardship
to go get a shot my little baby.
He didn't cry when he got
injected by the vaccine shot?
He cried for about 30 seconds.
He stopped crying really fast.
I think our little Joon here takes
after you for being so gentle.
I think so too. Ho Tae was so sensitive
that he started to cry the
moment we got to the hospital.
And I went through a lot of hardship taking him around
to places because he embarrassed me wherever we went.
Is that right mother?
Joon, your daddy was a cry baby.
He was a cry baby but you are not.
When you come home you should wash your hands
and change clothes, didn't I tell you that?
You play video games the moment you come home. Am I making you wash
up because it's good for your daddy here? Woo Young, you tell me.
Am I making you wash up because
it's good for your daddy here?
No, sir.
Both of you raise your arms up straight.
You're not gonna raise your arms up straight?
Honey, come here and some fruits.
Raise your hands up high.
I'm asking you to read for me sis.
Later on. Let me do this first. And
you could just read it by yourself.
But there are some words I cannot read yet
though. You always want to do it later sis.
That's what I'm saying. You'll be starting school next year so how can
you still not know the Korean alphabet completely? You are so silly.
Yoon Woori, howcome you are using such ugly
words to talk to your little sister like that?
I'm tired too mom.
I barely finished my homework and
I finally am able to rest too.
Are you bragging about the fact
that you did your homework huh?
Mom, you don't know anything.
That's your homework, not mine.
Woojoo, you should study hard too kiddo.
I really hate studying.
It's my oppa!
[Asia Film Festival, Directors award.
Lee Ho Tae]
First and foremost I would love to
thank you for giving me this award.
I had many hardships and
crucial moments in my life.
I gave up making movies temporarily and I
also even peeked into other areas as well.
During the most difficult part of my life I
started out with just one line of inspiration.
Even my son Ho Tae gets a chance to receive
an award like this for goodness sake.
But what should I do? I can think
of only one name right now.
My forever love, and the
only woman of my life.
The woman that became my first and
last audience, my wife Mo Soon Young
My life is complete and I was also able to finish
making this movie because she was by my side.
Soon Young, I love you dear! I
love you my son who is my rock!
Thank you!
Father, mother did you hear my name?
Oh my goodness, what am I gonna do?
Joon, your father received an award.
You feel very happy too, right Joon?
Congratulations dear. You went through
a lot of hardship too my dear.
He's right. You endured a lot of
hardship by being by his side.
No mother, I really was
no help to him anyways.
I thought Ho Tae was also gonna
mention our name at least once.
That punk. I even gave him money so he
can make that movie for goodness sake.
There's nothing that comes
out of raising a kid I say.
You finally realized such an
immortal saying like that?
You know that so well but why you
do you look so disappointed dear?
Dad, this is our first time going on a trip as a
whole family ever since you got a new car right?
I'm super happy that we're
able to fit in this car.
Oh yea? I am happy too. There's nothing we
left out right? We'll put it below there.
Alright, get in the car now.
Let's go!/ Yes!
Let's go guys!
- Get in the car.
- Let's go.
- Woo Young help me with this.
- Okay.
- Alright everybody, get in the car.
- Be careful.
What? What did you forget to bring?
We didn't get to do this properly last time so
I brought it so we can do it better this time.
Alright honey, hurry up
and get in the car now.
♪ Hey lovely boy, here's my love song. ♪
Are you kids all set?
Put on your seatbelts too.
♪ Just, just play the music. ♪
♪ I want to take you with me boy. ♪
♪ I want to get things started, oh love. ♪
♪ Bring it on, Bring it on, Bring it on. ♪
♪ Just drop it. ♪
♪ I'm so happy when I'm with you. It makes♪
me feel so good.♪♪ What am I supposed to do?
♪ What's wrong with my heart? ♪
♪ It's you, It's you. ♪
We went through many trial and error for a whole
year and we finally came to a realization.
We should embrace each other a lot more.
Also spending a lot more time together and
loving each other. That's the only way.
♪ You're the only one I can see. ♪
♪ You are so pretty no
matter who sees you. ♪
♪ Let's go forward together. ♪
♪ I met you like a character in a movie. ♪
Mom.
Mom, please come over here
and take a look at this.
Oh, okay.
A parent is someone that exists and stays at a
place whenever the children calls for them.
A place that you can be to rest comfortably and a person
that'll be there to embrace me whenever I need them.
Hey kids, lets eat some noodles!
Hurry over here kids!
♪ What should I do? ♪
Noodles, let's hurry up and eat!
It looks super delicious.
♪ It's you, It's you. ♪
♪ I love you boy, I send you my song. ♪
♪ Just the two of us
underneath the blue sky. ♪
♪ The happiness to know that we can breathe together.♪
♪ All I want to do is feel that with you. ♪
♪ Oh baby. ♪
♪ It's you, It's you. ♪
♪ I love you boy. ♪
This is for your mom.
Here you go my dear.
Thank you.
This is your grandfather's noodles?
Hows this grandpa's noodles dad?
He's right, you're the
one that made this dad.
Whenever your daddy here was going through a hard
time I would go over to your grandpa's house
and your grandfather made a bowl
of noodles like this for me.
And everytime I had a bowl of
noodles that your grandfather made
me forget about all of the
difficult and hard times I had.
You have no idea what I'm
talking about here right?
You'll find once you become
an adult later in life.
Alright, let's eat.
Wow, this looks so delicious. You should
thank your dad for the food kids.
Thank you for the food dad!
Yum!
Dad, this is so tasty.
This is super tasty.
I will make it for you at
home in the future too.
We are becoming a family like
this bit by bit every single day.
Honey, look at the family over there.
They have five children.
I know right? That's a lot of kids.
I know right?
They probably go through a lot of headache.
[We truly thank you for watching and tuning
into this weekend drama Five Children.]
♪ Our love that is like fate. ♪
♪ You are my one and only love. ♪
♪ Even if you complain to me you're
still my one and only love. ♪
♪ Today' is another day
for love with you. ♪
♪ A love that came to me like
a dream, just like this. ♪
♪ I'm happy as long as I can be with you. ♪
Hey, how can you two be brothers?
Your last names are different.
We have different last names but
we are still brothers okay?
Brothers can't have
different last names huh?
Can that be possible?
♪ Be there for you. ♪
♪ You're always holding my hand. ♪
There you go ma'am.
Daddy, I will be learning how
to swim starting from tomorrow?
Of course, Our Woojoo will
be a seal from now on.
I don't mean to ask you this
but are you really her father?
Yes, I am.
But the last name is..
I have a different last name but I'm still her dad. Is
it wrong for me to have a different last name as her?
I also have a different last name
as my mom too, isn't that amazing?
♪ I can't forget it. ♪
♪ I'm happy as long as I can be with you. ♪