My God.
Brother, what have you done?
Yet again we arrive to witness
this monster's aftermath.
I will not tolerate this
any longer, Marcus.
Your brother must be stopped.
It ends tonight.
We must move quickly,
before they turn.
Is he still here?
Yes.
Viktor, he must not be harmed.
I gave you my word, did I not?
But William must be controlled.
Burn the bodies.
Search the outbuildings.
Form two groups.
You, douse them with fuel.
- Yes, sir.
- Marcus.
Stay with me.
Give me the torch.
They're turning!
- Retreat to the woods.
- I'll stay and fight. You need my help.
I need you alive.
If you die, we all die.
Now, go.
Go!
- We found him.
- And?
- We need more men.
- Find Amelia.
Amelia, we found William.
Surround him!
Take him down.
No.
Leave him be.
Stop this, you're killing him.
More!
William.
Marcus!
He was not to be harmed.
Place him in my charge
as we agreed...
...or you will pay for your deceit.
And you will learn your place.
Your sympathy for this beast
is foolish.
Your brother is entirely
beyond control.
It will be done my way.
You know well the consequences
if you murder me...
...or William.
If you so much as speak
his name again...
...you will have chosen
that future for him.
What is thy will, my lord?
Imprisonment for all time.
Far from you.
For six centuries I was a loyal soldier
of the Vampire clan.
But I was betrayed.
The war was not as it had seemed.
In one night, the lies that had united
our kind had been exposed.
Kraven, our second-in-command...
... had formed a secret alliance
with Lucian...
... ruler of the Werewolf clan...
... to overthrow Viktor, our leader.
But Kraven's lust for power
and domination had failed.
Viktor was not the savior
I had been led to believe.
He had betrayed us all.
Soon the hunt will be on
for his killer.
I have but one ally left:
Michael...
... the human descendant
of Corvinus.
Neither Vampire nor Lycan...
... but a hybrid.
It's only a matter of time
before we're found.
My only hope now
is to awaken Marcus...
... our last remaining elder...
... and expose the truth...
... before Kraven tries to murder him
while he's still in hibernation.
Kraven knows
he's no match for him awake.
Perfect.
This thing's been dead for weeks.
I thought Lycans went back
to their human form when they die.
They do. It's been given
a serum to stop regression...
...so it can be studied.
How can you tell?
Not quite your department, I guess.
I just killed them. I didn't pay
much attention to their anatomy.
- How long can we stay here?
- Not long.
These safe houses are
linked together on one mainframe...
...with motion sensors revealing
which ones are active.
Someone could have
picked us up already.
There's only about an hour
till daylight.
Can you make it back
to the mansion before sunrise?
- Just.
- Okay, let's get what we need and go.
No.
I'm going alone.
Open it.
Marcus?
The blood memories
of this wretched creature...
...have shown me that your treachery
knows no bounds.
My lord, I can explain.
Why would I listen to your lies...
...when the journey to the truth...
...is so much sweeter?
I kept his secrets,
cleaned up the mess.
You'll go before Viktor...
...and tell him
exactly what I tell you to!
You just concentrate on your part.
Please.
I can assist you.
Oh, you already have.
If I can plead my case...
...there's a chance
you'll be granted sanctuary.
Right now, you'll be killed on sight.
I'm not prepared to risk it.
What am I supposed to do, wait?
Kraven may still have men with him.
You're not going alone.
You're not as strong
as you might think.
- What?
- Michael, you're unique.
There's never been a hybrid before.
However ambivalent you feel about it,
your powers could be limitless.
But you depend on blood.
You need to feed.
Without it, you'll be growing weaker
by the second. Use the time for that.
Jesus Christ.
And what if I don't?
What if I can't?
Normal food could be lethal.
If you don't anticipate your cravings,
you will attack humans.
And believe me, you don't want that
on your conscience.
There really is
no going back, Michael.
I'm sorry.
Look, I understand what you did.
I'm grateful.
You saved my life.
I wasn't ready to die.
I don't know.
Everything's changed.
I probably need a minute
to make it all fit in my head.
It's a lot to process all at once.
Look, go. I'll be here.
You just make sure you come back.
Sir.
The innocent who witnessed...
...they've been silenced?
But otherwise unharmed,
as ordered.
- Show me what you have.
- Yes, sir.
Two Death Dealers were killed.
We found no Lycan bodies.
Apparently they were using
a new kind of ammunition...
...some sort of UV round.
Amelia?
No one survived.
It seems Kraven's men
might have been present...
...but they did nothing to prevent it.
And Viktor?
And no trace of Marcus
amongst the ashes?
It seems he destroyed
his own coven, sir.
It was never his coven.
We need to go.
Give me a moment.
There you are.
How you doing?
Thank you.
You've got to get away from me.
Get away from me!
Hello?
There.
Michael Corvin.
Get the men up there. Now.
Get the fuck away from me.
Stop. Stop.
Shit.
Michael. Oh, shit.
- Here. Take it.
- No.
Michael, you'll die.
Shit.
Can you move?
We need to go.
Marcus.
I know what you've done, Selene.
Viktor deserved his fate
and Kraven was no better.
Kraven has already reaped
the rewards of his own misdeeds.
And Viktor...
Viktor deserved his fate...
...many times over.
A terrible business...
...the slaying of your family.
Yet so much effort was spent...
...to conceal this matter from me.
What do you suppose
Viktor had to hide?
Or perhaps it is you, Selene...
...as the last
of your wretched family...
...who has something to hide.
Go!
Get in.
Dead or alive,
you will give me what I want.
You okay?
- He's a hybrid, isn't he?
- Yes.
He wanted this. Why?
I don't know.
But we have another problem.
Turn off up here.
Shit. All right, get down.
Keep your foot on the gas,
but stay down.
Hold on.
Stay down.
Come on.
Give me your hand.
Jesus Christ.
There's really no need.
I'll be right back.
All right, let me see.
See?
No need.
Area secure, sir.
Sun's setting.
What's wrong?
The supplies were taken.
Used weapons were left behind.
The tavern events occurred before
dawn, so they couldn't have got far.
Remain airborne for the moment.
I'm sure they'll reappear...
- ... in good time.
- Yes, sir.
I've seen this before,
when I was a child.
I've held it.
When it was open, like this.
How is that possible?
I don't know.
But I know someone that might.
Andreas Tanis.
He was the official historian
of the covens.
He fell from favor after documenting
what Viktor considered malicious lies.
Of course, as it turns out,
he was probably telling the truth.
What happened to him?
He was exiled over 300 years ago.
Three hundred years?
What makes you think
we'll find him now?
I was the one who exiled him.
Looks like a monastery.
It used to be.
More like a prison now.
Tanis has been hiding there
since Viktor's order.
We'll be the first people
he's seen in centuries.
- That's odd.
- What?
I don't remember this gate
being here before.
Take this.
Shit.
Go back!
Gotcha.
Fuck.
I knew it was you, Selene.
The stench of Viktor's blood
still lingers in your veins.
Tanis.
I see your aim hasn't improved.
You haven't changed.
You don't scare me, Selene.
Well, we're gonna
have to work on that.
We need to talk.
Your exile seems a bit more
comfortable than I remember.
How does a Vampire
have Lycan bodyguards?
A gift.
From a most persuasive client.
Lucian.
Why would Lucian
wanna protect you?
Because he was trading with them.
UV rounds.
How long have you been
in the business of killing your own?
I've done what's necessary
to survive.
My decision was made easy the day
your precious Viktor betrayed me.
Betrayal was something
he did very well.
Viktor's dead. I killed him.
You?
Kill Viktor?
No, I think not.
Oh, unless you've learned the truth.
So your eyes are finally open.
Isn't it interesting how the truth...
...is even harder to absorb
than light?
You know, I tried to stop him,
of course.
A travesty,
committing such a horrible crime.
And then turning you.
That was too much to take.
My protests are why he put me here.
Careful with that, dear.
Makes a terrible bang.
Open the blades and they're active.
Good to know.
Viktor put you here for a reason,
but I doubt it was...
...because you had moral qualms.
- What do you know?
- Very little of anything, I'm afraid.
Well, then, perhaps I'm mistaken
and there's no use for you at all.
Marcus was after this. Why?
Some history is based on truth...
...and others on deception.
Viktor was not the first of our kind,
as you were led to believe.
He was once human...
...the ruler of these lands.
Marcus...
... he's the one.
The source.
The first true Vampire.
So the legend is true.
Toward the end of his ruthless life...
... when the next breath meant more
to Viktor than silver or gold...
... Marcus came with an offer...
... a reprieve from sickness
and death.
Immortality.
And in return, Viktor was to use
his army-turned-immortal to help him.
To do what?
To defeat
the very first Werewolves...
...a dangerous
and infectious breed...
...created by Marcus' own
flesh and blood:
His twin brother, William.
But these weren't
the Lycans we know.
Disgusting though
your brethren may be...
...they at least are evolved.
No, these were raging monsters.
Never able to take
human form again.
It was only later generations
that learned to channel their rage.
And William's appetite for destruction
and rampage was insatiable.
He had to be stopped.
And so once Viktor's army
was turned...
...the legions of Vampires
under his control...
...tracked down
and destroyed the animals...
...then captured William...
...and locked him away.
Viktor's prisoner for all time.
Why let him live?
For the very same reason that Viktor
never conspired against Marcus: Fear.
He was warned that,
should Marcus be killed...
...all those in his bloodline
would follow him to the grave.
So in Viktor's mind...
...William's death would mean
the end for all Lycans...
...his slaves.
Yes.
Yes, a clever deception...
...but one Viktor was hardly willing
to put to the test.
And so Marcus was protected...
...at all costs.
Yes, here we are.
- Vampires?
- Mortals.
Men loyal to Alexander Corvinus.
The father of us all.
What's this?
You should know.
It's William's prison.
The prison your father
was commissioned to build.
So you've been the one keeping
a watch over this for me, have you?
I've been searching everywhere
for this, my darling.
What is it?
What's wrong?
She now understands
why her family was killed.
But that was many years later.
The winter of Lucian's escape.
Your father knew too much.
Or too much for Viktor to risk...
...especially when Lucian...
...had the key to William's cell.
And I'm the map.
Yes.
The only one still living
who has seen its location.
Oh, Viktor realized you'd be too young
to remember explicitly...
...but Marcus knows
that the memory...
...and therefore the exact location
of William's prison...
...is hidden away in your blood.
Why is Marcus looking
for him now...
...after all this time?
That I cannot answer.
But I do know someone...
...who could stop him.
Perhaps I could arrange a meeting.
In exchange for your discretion,
of course.
Of course.
Tanis. You seem anxious.
Why do you flee
the very sight of me?
Please...
...sit.
There's no need
for this to be unpleasant.
I've always rather enjoyed
your company.
Now you're being rude.
Sorry.
Viktor struck two keys.
What do you know of them?
Keys?
I don't know of any keys.
Oh, yes.
Yes, those keys.
- Yes?
- Well, one was...
One was kept in plain sight...
...draped around
his daughter's neck...
...right there for you to see.
- And the other?
- Kept with Viktor at all times.
- Where?
Within him.
Beneath the flesh.
Please. Please.
I beg you. Please.
Please, I beg you.
- Who could stop him.
Perhaps I could arrange a meeting.
Go to pier 17.
Ask for Lorenz Macaro.
How do we know Tanis
isn't setting us up?
He's not brave enough
to set me up.
You can go.
You're familiar with this, then?
Intimately.
You're Alexander Corvinus.
There was a time
that I was known by that name.
By any name,
I am still your forefather.
How have you stayed hidden
all these years?
For centuries I've stood by
and watched the havoc...
...my sons have wrought upon
each other and upon humanity.
Not the legacy I prayed for...
...the morning I watched them
enter this world.
And a tiresome duty...
...keeping the war contained,
cleaning up the mess...
...hiding my family's
unfortunate history.
- Couldn't you have stopped it?
- Yes.
Could you kill your own sons?
You know what Marcus will do.
If he finds me,
he finds William's prison.
You need to help us stop him.
You are asking me
to help you kill my son?
You?
A Death Dealer?
How many innocents did you kill...
...in the six-century quest
to avenge your family?
Spare me
your self-righteous declarations.
You are no different from Marcus
and even less noble than William.
At least he cannot control
his savagery.
Anything I've done
can be laid at your feet.
Hundreds of thousands have died
because of your inability to accept...
...that your sons are monsters,
that they create monsters.
You could've stopped all of this.
Do not come groveling to me...
...simply because you are weaker
than your adversary.
You know the devastation William
caused before he was captured.
He cannot be set free.
Wa... No, wait.
You're no match for him.
Soon, brother.
No.
Father.
They've gone.
There, there, my child.
You are safe now.
No. Michael.
Look at me.
Michael.
Shit.
Please.
Come on.
Fuck.
Hello, Father.
You are unwelcome in my presence.
The predictable heart
that never thaws.
Pity it beats within such a fool.
The eldest of the immortals...
...yet you have made no attempt
to seize your destiny.
We are oddities of nature, you and I.
Nothing more.
This is a world for humanity.
And that petty sentiment explains
why you rejected your sons?
Why you stood by
for over half a millennium...
...as William suffered alone
in darkness?
No, Father.
I have no respect
for your petty sentiment.
Viktor's key. Where is it?
Whatever plan you have
for William is futile.
- You cannot control your brother.
- Oh, I am stronger now.
And our bond is greater than you
have ever wanted to acknowledge.
You're wrong.
Soon you'll be drowning in Lycans,
just like before.
Oh, not Lycans, Father...
...or Vampires.
A new race, created in
the image of their maker...
...their new god:
Me.
And a true god...
...has no father.
You will fail.
- Get the kit.
- No.
Please, sir, let us help you.
The time has come, my friend.
Find the girl.
Bring her to me.
No, wait. Wait.
If you want Marcus,
you'll need Alexander's help.
Don't leave him here.
- Did he get the pendant?
- Yes.
He's too powerful for you alone.
You are the only one
older than he is...
...the only one stronger.
You could have killed him yourself.
No matter what he's become...
...he is my son.
You are the last hope left.
There is only one way
to defeat him.
Quickly, now...
...before there is no more legacy
left in my veins.
What will I become?
The future.
Go now.
We're getting close.
Head back around
towards the river.
I don't see a way inside.
There used to be
a river entrance just there.
It must be submerged now.
Looks like we're getting wet.
Closer.
Selene.
William.
Wait.
No, William. Stop.
Be still, brother.
It's me.
I'd no sooner harm you than myself.
Which way?
Is this it?
He's already here.
What is that?
Nothing. Let's go.
We're too late.
- After him.
- Get behind him.
Impressive.
Michael, you're unique.
There's never been
a hybrid before.
Your powers could be limitless.
Hold it! Oh, fuck.
- Where is he?
- He went right through there.
All we have are UV rounds.
They won't take him down.
No, but they'll slow him down.
Let's go.
You all right?
Jesus Christ!
But these weren't
the Lycans we know.
No, these were raging monsters.
Unable to take human form
ever again.
What are you waiting for?
Shoot them.
I can't. Not without taking her out.
I can't get a shot.
Michael.
Take her down.
Cut us loose!
We're going down!
William!
I knew Viktor made a mistake
by keeping you as a pet.
He should have killed you
with the rest of your family.
An unknown chapter lies ahead.
The lines that had divided the clans
have now been blurred.
Chaos and infighting are inevitable.
All that is certain is that darkness
is still ahead.
But for now, for the first time...
... I look into the light with new hope.
subtitled by ren