Listen.
I am standing at the door, knocking.
And if you hear my voice
and open the door,
I will come into you
and eat with you,
and you with me.
Oh, my God.
John.
Write
to the church in Ephesus,
that anyone who has an ear,
listen to what the Spirit is saying.
I, Ceasar Augustus Titus Flavius Domitianus,
glory of the Empire,
do hereby proclaim myself
divine.
This is the dawn of a new day.
The whole universe will recall it
as the day of new birth.
The advent of the reign
of the god
Domitian.
Pretending to be a god,
when he is still alive,
it's unheard of!
Quintus.
My lord and god.
These Christians continue to profane
my honour and glory.
Especially those in Asia Minor.
You assured me, general,
that the last of the apostles
was dead.
Yet, his very name
is still on their lips.
I am certain, my lord,
John is dead.
I know you.
You said "dead".
But the myth
lives on.
The god Domitian will not
tolerate this.
You will give these
Christians an ultimatum.
They have 28 days
to acknowledge me publicly
as their god.
Their only god.
Should they resist,
you
put them to death.
Valerius.
Irene.
Let's go.
You know the situation.
One month's time.
We must betray our faith,
proclaim Domitian as our god,
or die.
What are we waiting for?
Let's get out of here!
Brothers!
The Romans are out there now,
seizing every Christian they can find.
But no one is gonna force me out.
I can't believe a Christian
doesn't have a right
to defend his own life.
Defend his life! Ha!
What about the women and children?
What about the old?
The Lord is closer to us now
than you think.
This is from John.
The Lord has returned to speak to us
through his apostle, John.
John is still alive.
Every church has started to receive letters.
But we have to be sure
they're truly from him.
Why isn't he here?
Because he has to hide from our enemies.
Like we do. More than we do.
Don't you see that?
- Irene, I wanted to tell you...
- I saw John once.
Did you know that?
I was only a girl at the time,
but I remember it so clearly.
My mother went to listen to him
and brought me along.
He came over to me. To me!
And he took me in his arms
and he kissed me on the cheek.
And whispered something in my ear.
What did he say?
'My child, you have the eyes of a doe'.
Now lok at me.
I run like a doe, carrying his
letters to the brothers.
Do you remember the first time we met?
You couldn't believe that I'd loved
the same things as you...
- I'm afraid, Valerius,
- You?
Everything is at stake now.
Our lives are about to change,
they have to or we will die!
And nothing will ever be the same.
Listen to me.
I'm leaving Ephesus.
You're leaving? Now?
"Escaping" is what you mean to say?
No.
I'll miss you, Valerius.
General.
At last!
What news do you bring to god Domitian?
A spy, my lord.
He's just this minute arrived from Ephesus.
I raised him myself.
He's like a son to me.
A son who's a spy?
Well, speak!
Your lord and god
are ready to hear.
Bring him to me!
My lord.
There are rumours in Ephesus.
It seems that John the apostle...
is still alive.
It appears that an old man
by the name of Theophilus,
another Christian, is in touch with him.
-Strange letters have been...
- Silence!
Legends, my lord, legends.
They take a while to die out.
It's to be expected.
- Somebody pretending to be their apostle...
- This is your dream, general.
My supreme patience has run out.
I'm sending you to take over
as governor of Ephesus.
Crush the vermin who perpetuates these lies!
I want you, I implore you...
eliminate every trace
of this impostor.
And Quintus,
My lord.
You will also cut off your
spy's head...
But my lord!
...if what he has spoken
reveals itself to be...
untrue.
I should have told him myself.
Do you know where
the old man is at least?
He's a prisoner
on the island of Patmos.
It puts him under
the jurisdiction of Ephesus.
You'll have to get yourself arrested
and sent off to Patmos.
No.
You raised me to be a soldier.
To face my enemies in the battlefield,
not to go around lying
to everyone all the time.
I turned you into one of the finest
officers in the empire.
And I have no intention
of repeating myself.
You have your orders.
And if I refuse?
Refuse?
You can't refuse.
You can't even think about refusing.
You are obliged to me.
Look what you are today.
Your real parents weren't just slaves.
They were criminals,
traitors to the empire.
What were they?
Christians?
Were my parents Christians?
I'm sorry.
But you are not free to choose.
You're a soldier.
We have to keep you alive... for now.
Come on, scribes,
even you need to eat.
That's for you, Theophilus.
John.
I'm afraid of even calling you by name now.
Jesus saved us.
He brought you, his last apostle,
here into this pit.
Why?
Give me that bowl!
This is enough for you, old man.
And consider it a gift,
for what little you get done in the mine.
You only earn yourself
more enemies like that.
Is that a sin, Demetrius?
I wish I had your strength.
My strength...
My strength does not come from me.
It comes from the Lord.
Gaius, no one has seen John,
except Theophilus.
Who is that?
He's the one John gave the letters to.
The one who passed the letters
onto Ionicus, my brother.
He travels there with supplies for the prison.
Where is this Theophilus?
He's a prisoner in the mines on Patmos.
All I know is that he's a very old man.
I see...
John is not only alive,
he speaks with a prisoner
on an inaccessible island.
Listen to me.
The letters are too important.
Irene, convince your brother
to take it to Patmos.
I want you to speak
to Theophilus yourself.
Only you can do it.
Father,
hallowed be your name,
your kingdom come,
give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our sins
as we forgive everyone
who is indebted to us.
And lead us not into temptation,
Amen.
John,
tell me more about Jesus,
how he died.
Blood was running from his hands,
his feet and his side.
And his breathing so suffered
I could not bear to listen to it.
It was very cold,
a strange wind came up.
And his mother took a veil
to shield herself,
but she stayed.
She would have stayed
until the end of time.
And then before Jesus died,
he opened his eyes
and looked at her
and said, 'Mother,
do not cry'.
And then
he said to her,
'Mother,
this is your son'.
And he looked at me.
John...
What you see, write in the Book
and send it to the churches of Asia.
Lord...
Do not fear, I am Alpha and Omega.
The first and the last.
And he that lives.
I was dead, but now
I am alive for evermore.
And have power over death and hell.
Write the things I will show you.
They are messages for all churches.
Come, I will show you things
which must be hereafter.
I entered the door of Heaven.
There were 24 old men
dressed in white robes,
with golden crowns on their heads,
and four living beings.
Bless the Lord fire and heat.
Bless the Lord all waters.
Let the earth bless the Lord.
Bless the Lord every wind.
You are worthy, o Lord, to receive glory,
for You created all things.
There was a sea of glass like crystal.
Behold the throne
that was set in heaven.
And on the throne there was a scroll
that was written on back and front,
and was sealed with seven seals.
Seven seals...
Yes. To guard the story of man
- the past, the present, the end, the truth.
Who is worthy to open the scroll
and break its seals?
Who can reveal the true meaning
of the things God has prepared?
No one in heaven,
nor on earth, or under the earth,
can open the scroll and read it.
No one is worthy.
No.
Oh my God.
I beseech you.
Someone must break the seal.
It is our only hope.
Our only hope.
John.
Master.
John, what did you see?
Tell me.
Please. Tell me.
I saw Heaven.
And the secret of all things
protected in God's hands.
Wait.
Open the gates!
New prisoners from Ephesus.
There are ten of them.
First five inside for registration!
Don't you understand, Irene?
Maybe I'll help some friends to escape,
but I don't want to risk anyone's life.
- Be careful.
- Ionicus, please.
Not a word when we land on Patmos.
I'll do the talking.
They already know you came
to help with supplies.
You don't have to explain anything.
How can I get to Theophilus, brother?
Demetrius will introduce you to him.
After all the letters
he's given me for your Christians
we've become acquaintances.
There it is - Patmos.
Ionicus, is the mine
as bad as they say?
It's my idea of hell.
Next.
Your name?
Valerius
From Ephesus.
If you need another scribe,
I can also read and write.
A Christian.
We're not the ones to decide.
You know what you've come here for.
You may go.
Come on, let's go.
- Demetrius.
- Ionicus.
And you're Irene?
I'm Demetrius
and here's Theophilus.
Since you are new to us,
let me show you
the warehouse straight away.
Come with me.
Irene, come with me.
This is what you asked me for.
This is from John.
Guard it with your life.
Trust me.
When can I speak with Theophilus?
Well, I don't...
He's the only one who knows
where John is hiding.
I have to convince
John to come to us.
And if the Romans find him?
You know what that would mean.
He's the only one who can save us.
What's going on in here, eh?
Hurry up, sister.
We have to get back
to Ephesus before dark.
Open the gate.
I believe something
very important for all of us
is written on that scroll, son.
Visions!
Tell them to our brothers,
who are hiding in their houses.
Tell them to our brothers
in the Roman prisons.
If John doesn't come here,
if he doesn't show us that he's alive,
will they find the courage
to keep their faith?
We must wait until
his letters show us God's will.
The Romans won't wait.
I see you have made
yourself at home, general?
There's no time for formalities, Corvus.
The situation here
has slipped out of control.
I'm talking about Christians.
And the lies they spread.
You've done nothing to stop them.
What lies are you referring to?
Of the apostle called John.
He's still alive.
Ah, that one.
Yes, they've been saying that
for a hundred years now.
You know that these
Christians love old wives tales.
But the emperor doesn't.
You are removed from your
responsibilities as governor.
I am in charge of Ephesus, starting now.
This hardly comes as a surprise, general.
There's something you can do for me
while you set your affairs
before your departure.
Stay out of my sight!
I see.
Well, if that is all, governor,
I shall be on Patmos.
One more thing.
Have any more prisoners
been taken to the island of Patmos?
More Christians?
There's hardly room for another one.
And they accuse me of being lenient.
We shall make plenty of space
when the ultimatum expires.
We?
"We" won't do anything at all. I will.
If I so decide.
You won't take a single
initiative, is that clear?
Valerius.
Thank you.
You!
Get down in the mines
and help the others.
Did you get the map from Ionicus?
Did he get the boat?
Look, we have an ultimatum over our heads.
Which means they are going to kill us.
Just see to that we have the boat.
The tunnel does not lead to Ephesus.
We're just as anxious to get
out of here as the rest of you.
We still have to convice Theophilus.
We're not moving without him.
Be all ready! Because I won't wait for
anyone when the time comes.
Where do you think you're going?
Where is it going?
Stick your nose where it doesn't belong
and you'll end up losing it.
You die in here. Bit by bit.
You've been here for a while.
Do you know everybody here?
More or less.
Must be hard at your age.
For you and the other one.
Theophilus, right?
He's the only human being
you find down here.
Hey!
You haven't done a lick of work all day.
And now you are wasting his time too.
Now!
Get up if you wanna earn your meal.
I said get up!
Get up now or you'll be sorry for...
Don't ever touch that old man!
Guards! Guards!...
You'll see what's in store for you.
And don't say you didn't deserve it.
He'll die.
Stop!
Be quick.
Why did you do this?
You said you're a Christian.
You should know.
What I know is we are going to die soon.
You are afraid to be in a cage.
Because you have known
the value of liberty.
No.
I thought I was free.
But I'm a slave.
I'll always be a slave.
Your servitude does not
depend on Rome.
No Roman can ever free you.
What do you know about me?
Your chains are in your heart.
You drag them around
with you wherever you go.
You must free yourself.
Who are you?
That's enough.
Why do you lie to your brothers?
You write the letters.
John is dead!
My Lord!
I am the last of your apostles alive.
Yet, you keep me here
as if it were my tomb.
Lord,
you revealed your truth to me.
Truth that can free us all.
Yet...
you hold me here
where liberty is denied.
Did you not call me to lead
my brothers to your kingdom?
Why do they think that
I have abandoned them?
They are lost. Lord, forgive them.
They are only human.
And I am only human.
Forgive us all.
Oh, God,
lift the shadow from my heart.
Make me worthy of your call.
Make me worthy of the Light.
Do not weep.
Look. The Messiah has triumphed.
And he will open the scroll and its seven seals.
Come.
Come triumphant.
To triumph once more.
Here is the power of the risen Christ.
The rider who wins over death.
Come, take away peace from earth.
Who was that?
It was war. He's the one who
sets people killing each other.
How can he have such power?
So they know where the paths of hate lead.
Come.
A crust of bread for a worker's wages.
To spread hunger and misery
throughout the world.
And injustice - the fruits of selfishness.
Come.
Now the worst scourge of them all.
What is its power?
The most terrifying power there is.
The power of death.
To remind the world that
only in God there is life.
So that men may turn to Him
again and praise Him.
Who can stop all of this?
Only the love of Him
who gave His life for us.
Death will not have the last word.
He who believes
shall have eternal life.
God is love.
And whosoever lives in love
lives in God.
And God in him.
If we bear all pain and
suffering with faith and love,
we will find true joy in the Lord.
We've decided to leave Ephesus
before it's too late.
May God protect us all.
Let's go.
Come on.
What does "apostle" mean, father?
It means that John
is a very special person.
Like an angel?
No. He's a person like you and me.
It's his life that is special.
Jesus chose John when
he was still a boy.
And John was Jesus'
favourite disciple.
He never left Jesus' side.
Even if He was on the cross.
And all the others had fled
because they were afraid.
I wouldn't be afraid
to stay by Jesus' side.
I know.
Irene,
go back to Patmos.
Find Theophilus.
Find John.
Unload the supplies.
This map guides you
to the boat landing.
We're going to the island
after tomorrow.
Demetrius.
Theophilus has left the
list of supplies at the back.
- He's not well today.
- What happened to Valerius?
Come with me.
I'll watch out for the guards.
Valerius tried to defend another prisoner.
They put him in isolation for four days.
Oh my God.
-John's had another vision?
- Yes.
And he gave it to you in person?
No..., he passed it onto Theophilus.
How does he do it?
I have to see John.
He has to come to us.
I told you that.
How does Theophilus do it? Tell me!
It's through a friend, a guard, I think.
- A guard?
- Yes.
He... he's a convert...
he comes from Laodicea and...
Ionicus told me the guards
are all from Rome.
It's not a guard.
There's no one.
No one at all.
You two invented it all
to keep his name alive.
- But John is dead.
- No. John is alive.
He's as alive as you and me. Trust me.
Then explain to me how we...
My child,
you still have the eyes of a doe.
John.
Master.
Thank God I've found you.
We need you so badly.
You are the only witness
to the resurrection of our Lord.
They will listen to you.
- You'll save us.
- Oh, no.
Don't cry, my child, don't cry.
Only the Lord can save us.
But now He wants me here.
To deny my own name
and testify to His.
If you stay here, you will be killed.
Listen, there's a plan to escape.
Come with us.
Tell our brothers and sisters
what God wants from us.
There's no other way.
We cannot escape
from the will of the Lord.
But I will continue
to send you His messages
until the final mystery is revealed.
Please.
Please, share my secret with me.
Corvus... Just what we need.
- We have the boat. It's for tonight.
- Where's the map?
Hold on. We still have to
convince Theophilus.
I'm not gonna rot in here.
Give me the map!
Put it on your head.
It'll keep you from drying.
I don't wanna see you die.
I'm gonna need you now.
Look, those other Christians
don't have any brains.
When they take you to the cell tonight,
get your hands
on the map they're hiding.
Enough!
Why do you tend him?
He will soon cut your throat.
You stubborn fool.
Take this old man
and put him in the cage!
Let the other one go.
Back to work!
It is claimed that in Laodicea they
speak of no one but John the immortal.
Thence by decree of Domitian,
divine emperor of Rome,
the said province shall be purged by fire.
Not a single blade
of grass be left standing.
He can't blot out the entire land!
An ultimatum one day, a decree the next!
This is sheer madness.
What do I tell the emperor?
Tell him that his orders
will be carried out.
The map of the coast!
Where did it come from?
No one knows about it.
Foolish of you!
Cut the rations.
Back to work!
Attack every Christian
village in the area.
Kill all the Christians.
They're orders from
the emperor Domitian himself.
And I want them carried out.
Company!
Centurions!
Mum, look! It's Romans!
Oh my God, it's Roman soldiers!
The children! We must get the children!
Quickly!
Come on!
No!
No, God...
Is this your will, Lord?
John!
(CROWD CHANTING: Miserere nobis)
Sostenes...
When, my Lord,
will innocent blood
no longer be spilt?
Be patient a little longer,
until the number of your
brothers is complete.
Now share my victory over death.
Get up! Time to work!
Let's go!
Sostenes, come on, old man.
You'll make it.
Come on.
Sostenes...
Sostenes is dead!
John! John!
Did you hear?
Sostenes is dead.
No, no.
He is alive.
He is standing
in the presence of God.
This is our chance.
Old Sostenes has given us
the keys to freedom.
Come on. It's now or never.
Come on!
When we get to the port,
we'll try to seize the boat. Let's go!
They've found out!
The knew all the time.
Let's get ot of here! Come on!
Oh my God, no!
Hold it!
How stupid of them to think
they catch me unprepared.
You can go back to your friends now.
If anyone else attempts to escape,
I'll sacrify others along with him.
As it is, the ultimatum
expires in a couple of days.
And we will be forced to kill
everyone of you who still refuses
to give up the Christian God.
You have two days!
What a waste of breath.
What a waste of manpower.
John,
give me your blessing.
And prepare me for death.
I am not afraid any more.
May the Lord forgive me
for my sins.
I have known you,
His friend.
I bow to His will.
Master,
John,
Blessed are you, poor,
for yours is the Kingdom of God.
Blessed are you that hunger now,
for you shall be satisfied.
Blessed are you that weep now,
for you shall laugh.
The wicked will not stand
firm at the judgement,
nor sinners in the
gathering of the righteous.
The path of the wicked is doomed
- chaff blown around by the wind.
Who are these people?
Where have they come from?
They have been saved.
These are the people who have
been through a great trial.
They've washed their robes white again
in the blood of the Lamb.
They will never hunger or thirst again,
because the Lamb will be their shepperd
and guide them to the springs of life.
And God will wipe away
all tears from their eyes.
There, look.
The Lamb, the Messiah,
is breaking the seventh seal.
John,
answer me, John.
The Lamb,
has broken the seventh seal.
and there was silence.
Silence,
in Heaven.
I must be mad. We'll never make it.
We have to make it.
You, come here. Now listen...
Valerius.
Irene.
We have to go now.
John,
John, come with us.
I...
I have to stay.
You can't. If you stay
here, it means death.
I have to stay here.
Please, come with us.
The Lord has spoken to me.
The seventh seal...
Perhaps it is my life
for the Romans to take.
John, God doesn't
want you to die now.
He's freeing us.
We've got to hurry.
We're in your hands.
Save us. I beg you.
I beg you in the name of Jesus.
Please, John.
God help me,
if I am making a mistake.
- Come.
- Yes.
Stop.
Stay where you are.
There are fewer guards on that side
and they removed the sentries from the gate.
Now, move!
Guards!
Prisoners are escaping!
That's enough centurion,
kill them all!
Pull up! Form two groups!
Cut them up before they
get to the port!
This way!
They've found our trail.
Leave me here.
I'm not gonna
make it any further.
I'll delay them. Please.
It's our only chance.
In the name of Jesus,
your sins are forgiven.
Amen.
Go with God.
John will never keep up.
I'll stay with him.
The rest of you go ahead
to the boat.
We'll meet you there.
- Valerius is right.
- No. We should stay together.
I'm not leaving John.
Yes, you are. This time
listen to me, sister. Let's go!
Let her do what her heart commands.
Hurry, they're almost here. Let's go!
Seize him!
Get round behind him!
Where are the others?
Answer me!
That way!
Quick! Let's go.
There.
Over there.
Lord, Lord,
forgive me.
I thought You had no more voice left for me.
Salvation has been won by our God
and all the authority for His Christ.
For all evil has been defeated
for evermore.
They must be somewhere.
They are here.
Do not be afraid of the truth,
if you don't want to remain a slave.
The truth could kill you.
Only the truth will free you.
Valerius...
The soldiers of Rome,
Corvus is a traitor and thief.
I am here by order of the
new governor from Ephesus,
Quintus Maximus, to unmask
the real enemies of the empire.
And I order you to arrest him
in the name of the emperor Domitian...
Seize him!
If you do so, you will answer
to Quintus personally.
Look! A ship flying
the emperial colours.
Quintus...
I said seize him!
That's an order!
Kill him! Kill him!
Arrest them all!
Quintus will judge them
in the name of the emperor.
What has been going on here?
Who are they?
These are the prisoners
who tried to escape.
One of them claims he knows you.
If they have to die, I choose
to die along with them.
I am a Christian.
The son of Christians.
I will accept your
sentence under the laws of Rome.
Remove the chains.
What? They must die. That's
the order of the emperor.
Domitian has been assassinated.
Nerva is the emperor now.
He has declared an amnesty
for all prisoners.
And an end to the persecution
of Christians and Jews.
Move the chains!
You are free man now.
Your father admires your courage, son.
Now you know the truth.
I lied to you.
I didn't understand.
I didn't understand myself.
But now my eyes are open.
I love you, Irene.
I love you.
Can you forgive me?
Irene.
Jesus told me once
that God forgives the most
those who love the most.
I've always loved you, Valerius.
Your suffering is over.
You're free to go, old man.
My name is John.
God will always win, friends.
His victory over evil
is the root of our faith.
The words of Jesus
come true before our eyes every day
and will continue to come true
to the end of time.
Blessed is he who obeys His
commandment to love one another
and make a better world.
May the grace of the
Lord Jesus be with you.
Amen.
And then I saw a new Heaven
and a new Earth.
I saw the holy city
the new Jerusalem
come down out of Heaven from God,
prepared as a bride for her husband.
Here God lives with human beings
and He will make
His home among them.
They will be His people
and He will be their God.
God with them.
And He will wipe away
the tears from their eyes.
And there will be no more death,
no more mourning,
no sadness or pain,
the world of the past is gone.
The Spirit and the bride say:
"Come, let all who are thirsty, come.
And all who want it may
have the water of life.
And have it free".
Amen.
Come, Lord Jesus.