Clear.
Akcm, this one's a feeble piece of shit, too.
Boyfriend not the killing machine
you hoped for?
...but you built a great punching bag.
Maybe we can skip right to the fine?
Do you know what's wrong
with Mother Russia?
Too goddamn hot.
As you wish.
I used to be in charge of all this shit.
And now...
Great jacket! Where can I get one?
You! Come here!
You got a light?
The fuck you think I have arms for?
You're free to go now.
You want a puff?
-Yeah.
Ella.
Ella, you whore!
Take him to Jimmy.
Is this Jimmy?
I'm not going back in there!
That thing's destroyer-class!
What's wrong with his hand?
Who is he? Is he a robot?
He's cute.
I know how to make him feel better.
No, I know a better way.
Lift him.
No, the lower one.
Bye-bye.
I'm not with them!
Jimmy, you asshole!
You want Akan? Here's your Akan.
And here's your Akan.
We can go now.
I don't hear a "no."
Gentlemen, please go
check that shit out.
Freeze!
Baby, the gag reflex is psychological.
It's all in your head.
Leave.