- okay.
- I'm ready.
- jacquiese, stand up.
Jacquiese whelchel is not
guilty of false imprisonment,
attempted false imprisonment,
terroristic threats,
or battery.
Sit down.
The judge is gonna tell you
that if the state fails
to prove their case,
it is your duty;
you must acquit.
That's the beauty
of this system.
It's set up to give people
the presumption of innocence,
to give them an opportunity
to not just be heard
but hold the state accountable.
You want to take my liberty,
you got to do it right,
and if you don't, acquit.
The fifth amendment to
the united states constitution
guarantees it.
As I've made my objections
throughout this trial,
it's to make sure that this kid
gets a fair trial.
It's not a big case,
is what they say.
They are saying that they have--
they have the gall to say
that this is not a big case.
There are huge consequences.
This boy will become
a convicted felon.
That's the reality of it.
That's what
this case represents.
Thank you.
♪
- I'm scared man
- I know it
- keep your head up. Don't look
down.
- it's almost over
- I've been advised that you've
reached a verdict in the case.
- yes, ma'am.
- madam clerk, if you'll please
publish the verdict.
- yes, ma'am.
In the superior court
of hall county,
state of georgia versus
jacquiese m'shawn whelchel,
we, the jury,
find the defendant not guilty
this second day
of november 2011,
count one, jury foreperson.
- my goal is
to fill this wall up,
and then once
I fill this wall up,
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Hopefully, like,
my whole office
will just be covered
in acquittals.
I decided,
since the wins go on the wall,
the losses have to go somewhere,
and I'ma tattoo--
uh, I don't have any tattoos,
so I'm gonna get the last name
of every case I've lost
tattooed on my back.
Right now it's only five,
and hopefully it won't get--
hopefully I won't fill
my back up.
That's the goal.
But since the wins
go on the wall,
I decided the losses
have to go somewhere,
and they'll go on my back,
'cause they're gonna be
with me forever.
- when you work
as a public defender,
you say to somebody,
"oh, I'm a public defender,"
and then they're like,
"well, what does that mean?"
"i defend people who are charged
with committing crimes,"
and then they'll say,
"how can you defend
those people?"
I tell them the truth,
and the truth is,
it's about the sanctity
of human liberty
and the cost of it
if you want to take it.
- hi.
- I'm well.
How are you?
Trying cases
is an adrenaline rush,
and when you win,
there's a high.
But that is not the average day
of a public defender.
this is great!
A client got approved
for the pretrial
diversion program.
I am so excited for him.
Ah, if only we can get him out.
If we can't get him out,
it's pointless
if his mom can't buy him out.
Hi, may I speak
with miss howard?
Miss howard,
how are
This is brandy alexander
over at the public defender's
office in clayton county.
I got a letter
from the d.a.'s office today
indicating that they have
referred him
to the pretrial
diversion program.
Are you familiar
with that at all?
It will allow him
to have his charges dismissed.
Now, in order to get him in
the pretrial diversion program,
he's gonna have
to get out of jail.
You think you'll be able
to do that?
I know it's a lot,
miss howard.
I know.
The average person
cannot come up with $3,000
in a month
or in less than a month.
Is there any amount
that you can afford?
Okay.
Your mom has 500.
How much do you have?
You don't have anything.
Is his--
all right.
I'll talk to you soon.
Bye-bye.
♪
He's gonna have to choose
between a trial and a plea.
- being a public defender,
you realize very quickly
the reality is,
90% of the people
or 95% of the people
who get charged
with something
plead guilty
to something, right?
Because the system is designed
to force them to plead guilty,
and it punishes
their failure to comply.
This is the way it really works.
You go to jail.
You're charged with an offense
based upon what a police officer
thinks you did.
They set a bond,
and if you're poor
and you can't make the bond,
you don't get out.
so you sit
and you sit
and you sit.
You may have lost your house.
Your kids may be
needing sustenance.
You may have been
taken out of high school--
all the things that could happen
if you were summarily plucked
from your life.
You have so much tremendous
pressure to plead guilty.
It's all about
lessening the penalty.
That's what we do.
- this is the kingdom.
Um...
These are crime scenes,
aerial depictions
of burglaries and robberies
that I've collected.
This guy was charged with, like,
38 counts of burglary,
and it took--it took forever
to close the case,
and I just kept
the blowups from it.
There's really nothing
to see in the house.
It's next door to the office.
That's my favorite thing
about it.
It's next door to the office.
All I do is this.
I don't do anything else.
I don't have a wife and kids.
I do this.
I do this for a living.
You know,
in a given case,
if I don't do
all I need to do,
somebody's gonna become
a convicted felon,
and they go to prison.
They can't vote.
They can't get a job.
Like, I think about that
every case.
the job is just emergencies.
Everybody's
in an emergency state.
Everybody's in jail
or charged
with child molestation
or getting beat up
or something crazy is going on.
It's just--it's just chaos.
- judge, this is
case number 2011cr252-c,
the state of georgia
versus branden lee mullin.
On the incident date,
the defendant was
with cody campbell,
and they discussed
ordering a pizza.
They did discuss
robbing the pizza man.
Cody campbell made the call,
and the car was approached
by mr. mullin,
who put the knife
to mr. wrengle's throat
and told him to freeze
and to give him the money.
The investigation
progressed from there.
- when I get a case,
I'm more like an investigator
than a lawyer.
I really consider myself
a lot more like matlock
than f. lee bailey.
- uh, just--just a statement.
Yeah, slightly incriminating.
You know, "i was there.
I saw this guy jump out.
I didn't know
what was going on."
- no. no.
I believe
he just happened to be
at the wrong place
at the wrong time
hanging with
a bunch of dummies.
But it ain't lookin' good.
But, oh, man,
it'll break my heart
if this kid gets convicted.
Ten-year mandatory minimum,
day for day.
- yeah, 19.
- and our kid
is a cute little white guy.
He's gonna have a rough time
at the big boy prison,
'cause that's where they're
gonna send armed robbers.
He's gonna have a rough time.
He probably won't live
to see the ten years.
If he does, when he gets out,
I would hate to see him.
For 96 bucks.
All this shit over $96.
♪
- all rise.
- mr. mardell,
you were charged with driving
after being declared
an habitual violator.
Upton, you were charged
with aggravated assault,
with terroristic threats,
and battery.
Mr. rawlings, you were charged
with violation of the georgia
controlled substances act.
This plea form has a written
statement that indicates
that you wish to plead guilty.
How do you wish to plead
to these charges?
Not guilty or guilty?
- guilty.
- how do you wish to plead
to these charges?
Not guilty or guilty?
- guilty.
- so is there anything further
from the state?
- no, your honor.
- anything further
from the defense?
- no, your honor.
And that's all I had.
May I be excused?
- yes, ma'am.
- these are the new clients
that you need to see.
Here's the file
that I was just asking about.
- oh.
thanks. okay.
- miss wright,
how are you doing?
Um, I talked to the prosecutor.
She'd be willing to go up
on the bond, $10,000,
and then give him a curfew.
But I want to make sure
that it's not gonna, like,
increase your amount that you
have to pay every two weeks
by more than $100.
Okay.
You're welcome.
I'll talk to you soon.
She's behind
on all of her bills,
and they're about
to take her car.
This kid is in high school.
He's so smart,
so incredibly smart.
That's him.
He's 17.
He was arrested
for armed robbery.
This is--i can't even believe
that they arrested him for it.
I really don't believe it.
And it's a ten-year minimum
mandatory sentence.
And win, lose, or draw,
tears will fall,
because this kid is--
I don't think he's guilty.
I don't.
I think he's innocent.
- when they arrested me,
I was scared.
I didn't know what was going on.
- why don't come on in
and help me get decorated?
There's some meatloaf and
cabbages in the refrigerator.
Throw that trash out.
- it was december 9, 2010.
Me and my family was sitting
in the living room watching tv,
cooking, you know,
just a normal family night.
All of a sudden,
we hear a big knock on the door.
So my mom go to the door
and open up.
They say
it's the college park police.
- I unlocked the door,
twist the knob,
and didn't even get a chance
to open the door all the way.
As soon as it cracked--
I guess they heard me
twist the knob--
they just pushed the door in,
pushed me back,
they spinned me around,
pushed me on the floor,
rushed in,
pushed my daughter on the floor.
They all had guns and
flashlights to all our heads
on the floor.
They rushed in the living room,
yanked my son off the sofa,
throw him on the floor,
put the handcuffs on him,
and just took him outside.
I cried.
It's a unexplainable feeling,
situation,
for someone to come in
to your home,
whether it's been
the police or whomever,
and take your child away.
Demontes was a very good baby.
This is when he became
kind of challenging.
He would take his toys apart
and put 'em back together,
and I bought him
one of those razor motorcycles.
You would never believe it.
He took that thing apart
and re-rigged it up
to run faster.
- when they arrested me,
I was 16.
Then they--they held me
at a juvenile detention center
until I turned 17,
and then they took me
to the county,
which is adult jail.
I was scared,
but I knew I couldn't--
I couldn't really
let it get to me,
'cause I knew
I had to be strong,
'cause at the time,
I was gonna be there
to be there,
so I couldn't really
stress myself.
It'd make the situation worse.
I already knew
I couldn't afford a lawyer,
so I was expecting
a public defender.
I was just praying
on a good one,
and god answered my prayer.
- armed robbery
is a maximum life penalty.
A judge could sentence you
to life for it.
You understand what that means?
- yeah.
- it's hard to understand
a life sentence when you're 17.
But those are things
that you have to think about.
I know a man.
He was sentenced
to life in prison
for a crime
he did not commit.
You have to think about that.
I know that you're young,
and it's easy to want to run
the streets with your friends
and do what you see on tv
and get tattoos
and so on and so forth.
That's real cool,
and it's great,
and it's wonderful
while you're 16, 17 years old.
But when you're 25,
who's gonna hire you
with tats on your neck
and all down your hand?
That make sense?
- yeah.
♪
- so welcome back to birmingham.
all right.
I--i don't know
if everyone knows,
but--but, um, just this month
we had three more lawyers
leave their offices,
three more s.p.d.t.c. lawyers
leave their offices.
It's not a surprise, right?
I mean, you guys are doing
the most difficult work
in the most difficult places.
But as I've talked
to some of you
who haven't left but maybe
have been considering it,
I know one issue
is certainly money.
But another issue is
that it's just too hard.
"i feel defeated."
I think that that's what
this community is about.
- I closed
over 500 felonies last year,
and I have 165 pending cases
right now that are all felonies,
and i--i cannot be
an effective attorney
at those numbers.
- without this group,
I would've quit a long time ago,
because, as you said,
it's a hard job,
and when you've got nobody
that's helping you,
and when you've got
everybody telling you,
you know, "you work too much.
You should"--
that are actually ordering me
out the door
and ordering me not
to work the hours that I work.
- the summer after I graduated,
a young lady by the name
of alice stamps was like,
"june, you've got to come work
for the hinds county
public defender's office."
I was like, "no.
"y'all got to pay me.
"i got six figures
in educational debt.
What are you say"--
"june, all of that's
gonna work out, baby.
Don't even trip on it."
- there was a case.
It was a sex case,
and the client
was accused of, like,
raping his 12-year-old daughter.
So I go to talk to him,
and I'm expecting him
to tell me
why he didn't do it
and, you know,
help me to establish
a defense for him,
and he starts to tell me
how he raped his daughter,
and he's proud of it.
And I literally had to, like,
stop myself from vomiting.
Something clicked in me
that said,
"some people
are just bad people.
Some people just do
evil things."
That, to me, is not what
a public defender should--
like, I don't feel like
I should think those things
about my clients.
And I feel like I'm doing them
an injustice
because I think those things
about a lot of them.
And I feel like people
like travis
who I respect
very, very highly--
I look up to travis--
and I feel like
I'm letting travis down
in being this person
that I've become.
Real talk.
You can't--
you can't really look
for the same thing
to motivate you
per client.
Like, some people are just--
everybody has--every case
has a redeeming quality to it--
not every person necessarily.
Don't necessarily focus on
the folks sometimes, you know?
Like, it would make you
feel good to, like,
do right for people
when they right.
But, shit, I want to do right
for people when they wrong too.
- what I've seen from doing it
for 15, 16 years is,
the ones who last at this,
they do what travis
is talking about.
Sometimes it's just good
to fight the system
and just be a warrior
and just go to war,
and they find that balance
that helps them
get through the times
when one of those
isn't working for 'em.
- when you go back
to your offices,
you will forget
what you feel like right now,
and it's understandable,
'cause you're going
back to hell.
Some of you are
going to hell, right?
And you're gonna feel like
you just can't make it,
and work is too hard.
You all know people who chose
to go to firms
to make a lot of money.
They're gonna drive cars
nicer than you,
live in houses nicer than you.
But they're not gonna
make a difference.
Let me say this to you, though.
This will be a battle
that will be won,
and your children
will look back on this,
this struggle to save people
from this injust, cruel,
inhumane criminal justice
system,
and you all will be
the foot soldiers.
You will be the ones
who brought that about,
because that
civil rights movement,
it was young people
jumping on buses
from the south
and from all over the country.
And that's what this is,
and that's what you guys are.
♪
- we live, eat, breathe among
alleged criminals,
ex-offenders every day.
I'm not living in fear.
I don't feel threatened
by my clients.
It's an honor for me
to represent my clients.
I have 150 clients,
and they are all counting on me
to be there for them.
okay.
We'll start with the--
with the not indicted.
It's a boatload of these.
These guys I've had to do
preliminary hearings for.
These are some
of my indicted cases here.
And these cases,
these are from my guys
who are in, um,
like, drug court.
But these are the three
that I deal with
on a daily basis.
Of course, now,
super hands-on cases
are these and those.
In my experience--
take, for example,
statutory rape cases--
my clients
just don't seem to know
that consent is not
an essential element.
You have an 18-year-old
with a 14-year-old.
You know, she looks
very much like a woman,
um, and it may not cross
the young man's mind that,
you know, she may be playin'
with dolls at home.
Um, in those instances,
I'm like,
"okay, he was just ignorant of,
you know, the law perhaps."
But for those instances where
I've had a client who was drunk,
and he got
his stepdaughter pregnant,
I was just like,
"that is complete insanity.
That is complete
and utter insanity."
But I have to do my job,
and the state,
they need to do their job.
♪
- branden is
a typical 20-year-old.
He can be endearing.
He can be infuriating.
He can be hardheaded,
very charismatic,
and very sweet.
We met this young guy who,
at that point in time,
was homeless, had no job,
no family.
I hired him to do some work
for me
basically 'cause
I have a bad back,
and as we got to know him
over the course
of working with him,
we decided to offer him
a place to live.
- we developed a family unit.
It's not by any stretch
of the imagination
ward and june cleaver,
but for us, it works.
- I mean,
my dads are pretty cool.
I mean, they both love me.
I mean, I really don't know
what I would've done
without their help
with all this stuff.
I never really thought
I would have anyone like that.
My mom left me when I was 12.
I haven't seen her since.
I mean,
since I was 12 years old,
I was pretty much in foster
homes and stuff like that,
in group homes.
This is, like,
the most stabile environment
I've been in,
living with them.
I like travis a lot.
Compared to any other lawyer,
like, he's different.
You know,
he actually seems like he cares.
- this is tough work.
This is grueling work.
You're dealing with people
who society has forgot about,
society don't give a shit about.
But that's something
that I can relate to.
I was born in georgia.
My mother was--
had escaped from custody
here in georgia,
and she took on an alias name
in order to avoid detection,
and her alias name--
the last name was williams.
That was--one of her aliases
was jackie williams.
And so she gave birth to a child
under that alias name.
And that child was me.
She fled to florida,
and she just dropped me off
with my grandmother
and took off.
And so I don't know
who my father is.
♪
- I collapsed in court
last week.
My knees kind of gave out,
and the prosecutor
had to catch me.
I was so stressed.
I was having anxiety attacks
and getting really upset.
My hair was falling out.
So the doctor suggested
that I take a week off.
I had a client
charged with murder
who apparently
was planning my murder.
I had a couple
of other clients warn me
that he had been bragging
in the jail
that he was gonna end my life
if we lost at his trial,
that he had a "plan"
on how he was gonna do this
and that he had nothing to lose
because if he was convicted
of murder,
you know, he was gonna get life
without parole.
So from what I was told,
let's do it big.
Take out a lawyer
in open court.
Go down in history.
I worked my ass off
for this client.
I went to the jail
every time he called
and said he needed somebody
to come and see him.
He wanted to talk to me,
but I knew he didn't have
anything to tell me
that was new or helpful.
That he just wanted
to see somebody's face.
That was me.
I was going out there.
I was the person
staying up at night
because I didn't know
what was gonna happen to him
or if I was even good enough.
That was me,
and you're planning my murder?
It's a part of the job.
that's what I'm told.
I don't think it is.
I don't think
it's part of the job.
- yes.
- I remember the speech
at, like--i guess
it was maybe the last day
where you said, "some of you
are going back to hell."
because it's true.
I'm serious.
It's so true. it's so--
- what would it take
to have someone like you around
in ten years?
- you don't want somebody
like me around in ten years.
- I'm just very jaded now.
'cause now I'm like,
I can't save everybody,
and then I see these clients
coming back and back and back,
and I want to be able
to tell the story
about the client
that was saved
and how the police,
like, tricked him.
But a lot of the cases
are not that.
Most of 'em are not that.
- but, brandy, you can't--
I mean, if you define success
as victory in every case,
right, where in fact
the evidence is overwhelming,
it doesn't matter
where you practice.
You're gonna feel defeated.
The fact that you recognize
that this is a job
that causes you
to sort of lose your humanity
and your sensitivity,
the fact that you recognize that
means you still have the ability
to sort of correct it
and push forward.
Right, like, you come home,
and you're like--
in the heat of the moment,
"i am insensitive,"
and you come home,
and you feel badly about that.
- I do.
I feel like--
- which sets you apart.
That sets you apart
from so many people
who do this work.
All right, that is why
we would want
someone like you around
in ten years.
But look, right?
I mean, if you're trying
to rescue people from hell,
you do have to go to hell
to do it, right?
- yeah.
- and if you don't,
you won't rescue anyone.
- you're wearing your hat.
- yep.
You know,
I wrote all the appeals
that I wrote that I won,
I wrote wearing this hat.
Not this hat,
but a marlins hat.
- yeah.
- rachel is a girl
I met a few months ago,
and we've been dating
for most of that time period.
- how much longer
are you gonna be?
- just a few more minutes.
Obviously, my work habits
are not helpful
to a relationship.
So we're trying to come up with
certain rules for us to follow,
a contract of sorts
that I'm gonna draw up
and we're both gonna sign.
- do you want me
to really draw up a contract?
- yeah, we really are
gonna draw one up.
Maybe tonight.
We need to actually
put this in writing,
because I've got an issue
with the contract.
- this is the thing.
We have a contract
that on nights
when I don't have my son,
he's supposed
to leave the office when I do.
And as you can see,
I'm off of work,
and he's still going for it.
- no, no, I'm down with that.
I'm not saying I'm against that.
- but you're just--
you just told me
you needed to make
an amendment.
- no, I mean--i do.
I do.
And that's the real issue.
I need to make an amendment.
- I'm all ears.
- why don't I just
come back later?
Let me go home and get
some stuff done, and can i--
I'll just come back later.
Is that good?
- okay.
- that works.
♪
- thank you, everyone,
for coming.
I want to thank
certainly
congressman lewis
who organized freedom summer.
I thought about a quote
that says,
"our lives are not our own.
They belong to those
who need us desperately."
Congressman lewis,
you've lived that quote.
- I'm delighted to be here.
You know,
I got arrested a few times.
I went to jail 40 time
during the '60s.
And it was lawyers,
unbelievably courageous men
and women of the bar
that came to my rescue.
They defended us.
They filed briefs.
And if it hadn't been
for the lawyers
during that period,
I don't know where we will be
as a nation and as a people.
So I want to thank
this wonderful organization
for getting in the way,
for defending those that have
been left out and left behind.
Thank you.
- life in clayton county--
I dare not speak for all of the
public defenders in georgia--
but life
in clayton county, georgia,
is a different beast.
The average bond
in clayton county
on a theft by shoplifting
is $40,000.
- wow.
- my clients
cannot afford that bond.
So they sit
for four to eight months
waiting to be indicted.
I've wanted to leave
so many times.
I think I've lost count
at this point.
And I know lots
of other people
who have wanted to leave
as well.
It's only s.p.d.t.c.,
and particularly
jonathan rapping,
that keep me here.
So I hope
that I've given you all
a small glimpse of my world
in clayton county.
It is not fun at all.
But it's a necessary evil.
Thanks.
speaking in front
of the congressman,
that was really surreal.
It won't hit me until, like,
two months from now.
When I met him, he said,
"thank you for your service."
I was like, "oh.
"really, congressman john lewis?
"you're thanking me?
I feel special."
I felt very special.
- it's important, I think,
for the clients to see us,
and kind of keep their morale up
and know that we have,
you know,
their best interests at heart.
I know in particular with me
how I interrelate
with my clients.
I see them as cousins
or brothers,
some uncles,
just because it--
the face
of the black community is,
so many of them are locked up,
and of course,
I'm having to work against
their initial impression
of public defenders
because their first
public defender
somewhat screwed them.
Hi, miss lewis.
Good.
Maybe if you could
sit over here.
How are you?
- I'm doing fine.
- good. good. good.
Good to see you.
- you too.
- two days in a row.
It's freezing outside.
- it really is.
So you know why I'm here.
I'm here to...
- yeah.
- kind of get
a better understanding
of what took place
when you were arrested.
But let's kind of
go through some of
your biographical information.
What do you do?
- I'm a certified mechanic.
- you're kidding me.
- no kidding.
- okay. certified mechanic.
Wow.
How long
have you been a mechanic?
- about 15 years.
- okay.
So once you're released
and you go back to your norm,
you'll go back
to working on cars and such?
- I'ma try,
'cause since I've been in here,
I've lost my house.
They've broken in
and stole all my tools.
- oh.
- so I'ma have to, like--
- start from scratch.
I'm have to--i'ma leave here
and go into a shelter
and start from scratch.
- okay.
- but after my landlord
found out I was incarcerated,
he filed eviction notices
against me.
- my mom said she went
to go get it the other day,
but he had the lock on the door,
'cause I had court
that he put an eviction notice
on my door,
and I had court,
and I told three guards here
that I was supposed
to be in court.
Okay, nobody took me to court.
So the court, they ruled
in the landlord's favor.
- wow.
It's default judgment.
Mm-hmm.
- yeah, so that caused me to be
really evicted from my house,
but she said she called
the court to let 'em know
that I was incarcerated.
- mm-hmm.
- but she said that
they haven't really did
the eviction yet,
so he just, like,
holding my stuff.
- okay, wow.
Thank you
for letting me know that.
So you were convicted of cocaine
possession back in 2004.
- yeah, I admitted to it.
Yes, I did.
I really pled
to get out of jail,
'cause I had never
been in jail before.
It was just my public defender,
and me and her had problems.
And she told me
when I took that plea--
she told me that I wouldn't be
considered a convicted felon.
I've been screwed around
the first time
by a public defender,
and when they told me
I had another one,
I figured my life
was completely over.
- your sentence
was two years suspended,
two years on probation,
and you're right.
Since you were
a first-time offender,
you should've been eligible
for a nonadjudication.
I'm not sure what happened,
and I apologize that--
- I don't either.
- that that took place.
But it's not
the end of the world.
It's not the end of the world.
We can definitely fix it.
- it's the end of my world,
'cause that messed up
a lot of stuff for me.
- but we can--we can come--
we can rebound from it.
I'm sure we can.
I'm gonna, you know,
ask about
the different eyewitnesses.
Where were they standing?
Were any of them
under the influence?
I mean,
'cause it could've been anything
that clouded maybe their vision
or their vantage point,
their perception
of what took place.
All right?
So I will see you on monday.
Thank you so much.
- thank you.
- you're welcome.
You're welcome.
- branden's trial date
is coming up.
So far, neither side has come up
with any conclusive evidence.
The person who committed
the robbery was disguised,
so the victim
can't accurately i.d. anyone.
I was looking through
branden's file a few days ago,
and that's when I remembered
the fingerprints.
- the driver drives in.
He's looking for essentially
that apartment, I believe.
I believe he's looking
for that apartment.
Somebody comes out
and puts a knife towards him.
Now, what happened is,
the robber, no gloves,
put his hand
certain places on the car.
The state lifted prints
from the hood,
but they never tested them.
I wanted to test the prints,
but unfortunately
we don't have the resources
to make that happen.
So I have to trick the d.a.
Into doing it.
So I filed a motion in court
saying that I wanted to ban
all fingerprint evidence
from the trial.
This made the d.a. think
that I was scared
of the fingerprint evidence,
and they tested it.
We got the results back,
and they didn't match
branden or cody.
This backs up what branden's
been saying the whole time.
Neither of them
committed the crime,
so we're going to trial.
- branden mullin.
- waiting for
the state's announcement.
- um, I'm--i'm--
I guess we'll be ready
subject to a plea.
We're, um--
- well, a plea
was a possibility,
but that's not gonna happen.
We're ready for trial.
- all right.
We'll mark it as ready.
- and, sir,
just out of curiosity,
where will that case be
on the trial calendar?
- it looks like it's number two.
- and so we would be number two
on the january 9th calendar?
- number two
on the january 9th calendar,
probably number one--
Yes, sir.
- okay, we're gonna go
over the evidence
that the prosecutors have.
Officer brennan says
that on december 3rd,
he responded
to an armed robbery.
A black in color
automatic handgun was used.
They handed over
around $300 worth of cash.
They said
that they know the person
as being a frequent customer
in the pizza shop.
"i, officer brennan,
initiated an arrest warrant.
"upon officer searching
the room of the offender,
"they found a yellow
in color cardboard box
with 13 winchester .25
auto bullets."
According to you, they are--
they match a revolver, right?
- yeah, a .22.
- I mean, it can be.
They got .22 automatic,
and they got .22 revolvers.
- okay.
So would bullets to a .22
match the same bullets
to a 9
- oh, not at all.
.22 bullet like this small.
9-millimeter, they medium-sized.
- okay.
All they have is testimony.
They don't have
any fingerprints,
any pictures, 'cause they
didn't have a camera in there.
I wish I could say that we were
gonna go in and win this case.
I just don't know,
and that's
the god's honest truth.
I can tell you that I will give
everything that I have
to getting you
out of these charges.
I've maintained that throughout
my representation of you.
But at the end of the day,
you just never, ever know
what a jury is gonna do.
Ever.
So--and the stakes
are really, really high,
because if we lose,
it's day for day
at least ten years,
day for day,
no parole.
If you're found guilty,
they're gonna take you
into custody that day.
So even if we put sentencing off
until a later time,
they're not gonna let you leave.
Anything else?
- do you have another copy
of the discovery packet?
- yeah.
- what'd you do
with the one I sent you?
- I still got it,
but it got wet.
I had got tea on it.
- I'll make you a copy.
- I don't know.
I don't know either.
You ain't got no questions?
You got to have
some kind of questions.
- I have huge student loan debt.
After I pay
my student loans and my rent,
I have probably $300 a month
to pay extra bills
like gas and the car,
all that kind of stuff,
groceries.
But I don't see
how you can do this work
for any period of time
and not begin to love it.
If you don't, then it'll just
drive you insane.
Either you--either this
is your cause, or this ain't.
- student loans.
Bank of america telling me
that I overdrew.
student loans.
Seriously, most of these
are student loan bills.
And that is why I'd prefer
not to look at them.
It's depressing.
this is all the money
I have in the world right now.
My gas light is on.
And so I'm getting $3 in gas,
and hopefully that will
take me home
and back to work
in the morning
and then back home
in the afternoon,
because I don't get paid
until friday.
- money pressure
is like any other pressure.
It takes something out of you
to deal with it,
and this job takes
a lot out of you
just to do the job.
That can be a significant burden
on a person.
But it's just something
you have to come to live with.
It's something
you have to accept.
- in the last year,
three public defenders
left the office.
It's rough financially.
So it takes--it takes
a certain kind of person maybe
to continue to, you know,
work under the circumstances.
- I'll probably leave here
about 2:00, so...
- yeah.
- let's go upstairs.
- all right.
- I am gonna make you
some homemade alfredo sauce.
- when I met travis,
he told me he originally moved
to georgia to find his dad
but hadn't found his dad yet,
and then he finally got
the courage
to ask his birth mother,
you know, for a name and stuff.
And now he's about to go
meet this guy.
we're on our way to meet up
with my biological--
potentially
my biological father.
Had a conversation
with him the other night,
and he seems to think
that I'm his son.
Said he always wanted a son.
I never wanted a father.
In fact, I don't want one now.
I just want to close
this chapter in my life.
♪
Well, we sat down, and I hit him
with a few questions,
just, you know,
"do you think I'm your son?
"how do you know
my biological mother?
What was y'all
relationship like?"
You know, and he kind of
answered the question
as to why he never tried
to make contact,
that he had no way
to get in contact with her,
which was true.
Which was true.
But I don't know.
As a person that never takes no
for an answer,
I was just--
that wouldn't have been enough
for me.
I don't know.
I guess I was just hoping
that somebody wanted me.
- today is my 30th birthday.
Whoo-hoo!
I'm so glad you made it!
- my dad came up from florida.
I've been in atlanta
for about 2 1/2 years,
and he's never come.
So it's amazing.
Okay, that's good.
Danielle, I need one
with me and my daddy.
Okay, go.
- turn it the long ways.
You got to get
my figure, danielle.
Come on.
- all right, one, two, three.
- at any point you get nervous,
and you feel like you want
to hold on to something,
grab your harness right here.
- right here.
- yeah,
just don't grab my hands.
- okay. 'cause then
we can't pull the parachute.
- 'cause--yeah,
then I can't open the parachute.
- don't you worry.
I won't grab your hands.
you gonna scream, daddy?
- yeah.
- now I'm nervous--
excited but nervous.
- oh, yeah.
My hope for my daughter
is to be happy.
I look up to her
because she believe
in helping people.
And when you got a person
that believe in helping people,
you cannot fail.
I don't care how much
you feel like you fail.
Failure is when
you stop dreaming.
She never stopped dreaming.
- I found out yesterday
that branden's friend cody,
the one he got arrested with,
has become a witness
for the prosecution.
He is gonna say that he
committed the crime with branden
in exchange
for a lesser prison sentence.
This is probably
the most damaging evidence
the state could have.
Even with
the fingerprint evidence,
it's gonna be hard to walk
branden out of that courtroom.
Me and the prosecutor
have agreed
that the charge of armed robbery
is gonna be dismissed.
Branden will plead
a robbery by intimidation
with a cap of five years,
so he can't get any more than
five years to serve in prison.
I think him pleading guilty
is the right decision
only because the risk is great.
You can get life in prison
for armed robbery
in the state of georgia.
We had a chance at prevailing,
but if the jury believes
that it was--believes cody,
we--our chance of winning
goes to zero.
- cody was like a brother,
you know?
I've known him
since I was ten years old.
Life's not fair.
I could either
take the chance
of going to trial
and losing
and having to serve
the whole time,
or I could take this deal
which is less time
and maybe still get, you know--
get out
and do what I got to do.
There's--there's nothing--
there's no way around it.
There's no running from it.
It's just something
you got to handle.
You got to--you just
got to take care of it.
- when you're a public defender
with clients, you know,
it's--it's--
it's a very close relationship.
It's you and this other person,
and you're having
a legalized war,
you know, with the state,
and you're, you know,
planning together,
and you're working together,
and you meet their family,
you know.
So losing a case
with a friend
and having that friend cuffed,
and you might've been able
to do something about it,
and maybe you didn't do it.
Maybe you missed something.
And those are the things
that keep rolling around
in your head,
really, forever.
That's what it's like.
It's awful.
- today is branden's plea day
and sentencing.
Even though
we aren't having a trial,
we're still going to be able
to make an argument
that branden
should get less time.
In this case, the amount
of time is very important.
If he gets two years,
which is what we're asking for,
he will likely go
to a medium security prison
or hopefully
a boot camp program.
If he gets five years,
he'll probably go
to a maximum security prison
where people get sexually
attacked and assaulted.
You know, it's anal rape prison.
It's the real deal.
It's not a game.
It's not a joke.
Branden,
how are you doing today, man?
- good.
- we have to go over
the plea petition
and all the rights
that you give up.
It's branden lee, right?
- yes, sir.
20?
How far did you go in school?
- um, sophomore.
- you've seen the discovery
and everything.
You understand what
you're charged with, correct?
- yes, sir.
- all right.
The sentence you'll get
is solely a matter
for the judge to decide,
especially in our situation.
Do you understand?
- yes.
- and did you commit
the acts as
- um, I mean,
I was there.
- so when the judge asks you--
the judge is gonna ask you,
"did you commit the offenses
as charged--
commit the offense as charged?"
And that'll be either yes or no.
it is something
I got to say yeah to, huh?
- it's not something
you have to say yeah to.
I can have us answer the plea
to say that
"although
I'm not admitting guilt,
"i do recognize
that the evidence is sufficient
to authorize a conviction."
- yes.
Something like that.
- all right.
Now, you give up
some important rights
when you plead guilty.
I'ma go over those rights.
If you don't understand
any of 'em,
just stop me
and I'll explain 'em.
You waive
your fourth amendment rights
against illegal
search and seizure.
By waiving those rights,
you can be searched
by law enforcement
or your probation officer
at any given time
for no reason at all.
You give up the right
to plead not guilty.
to have a trial.
You give up the right to make
the state prove your guilt
beyond a reasonable doubt,
and you give up the right
to appeal your conviction.
Your conviction
may negatively impact
your ability to obtain
or maintain a driver's license,
obtain or maintain employment,
vote,
and there may be
other consequences
which you cannot anticipate.
You understand those rights?
- mm-hmm.
- and do you still want
to plead guilty?
Yes?
- yes.
- all right, today is the...
9th day of april 2012.
Sign right here.
♪
- dick mecum running for
hall county commission chair.
Appreciate your vote.
- right down there.
- judge deal is doing
jury orientation right now.
Okay.
- um, cody is here.
Um, I was
- mm-hmm.
- no.
- judge, this is case number
2011cr252-c,
the state of georgia versus
branden lee mullin.
The defendant
is entering a plea
to the offense
of robbery by intimidation.
- all right, mr. williams,
any evidence
you wish to present?
Any comments you have
about the sentence?
- yes, sir.
What we would ask
for this court
to sentence mr. mullin to
is a ten-year sentence
with two years to serve
at the prison work camp.
Our contention at trial would be
that he was not the robber,
and there were several people
at the house--at least four.
The robber was disguised.
We contend that that person
was one of the other guys
that was at the house.
Also branden has taken this time
since this incident
to improve himself greatly.
Branden is lucky enough to have
encountered people lately
that care
a great deal about him,
that are interested
in his well-being
and have a vested interest
in his success.
That's not something
he's ever had before in life.
Branden has had
a tough go-around.
Branden has had people
that are supposed to care
the most about you not care.
Personally,
I can empathize with that,
and it hurts my heart
to understand that this kid,
this child, is potentially gonna
be thrown to the wolves.
And so we would just ask
the court for grace
in the sentence
that the court renders.
- all right.
Mr. mullin,
you got to understand
sort of where this all sits.
I have heard
about your history,
and I empathize with you
about that.
It sounds like you've had
a rough go of it here,
and perhaps points out some
of the failings of the system
regarding our children
that are in foster care
and that sort of thing.
But you also have to understand
that somewhere along the lines
when you start putting
other folks at risk,
then the scales
start to change,
and holding a knife
to someone's throat,
that just can't be tolerated
by our society.
Our society has to be protected
from folks who would do
those things.
And I do believe
that you have potential.
I mean, you appear to be
a smart kid, smart guy.
You got folks
that are supporting you,
and they have built trust in you
and given you opportunities,
and you've proved yourself
worthy of those opportunities.
So I hope you understand
this is not a condemnation
of you personally,
but it's a condemnation
of your actions.
It appears that the state has
given you a tremendous break,
because the mandatory minimum
sentence for armed robbery
is ten years in prison,
and the evidence would point
towards supporting
an armed robbery charge.
But they've reduced it
to robbery by intimidation
and essentially cut
the sentence in half,
and so the sentence
on count one
is gonna be ten years with
five years to serve in custody,
the remainder to be served
on probation.
But I'm gonna remand you
to custody this year.
- thank you.
- love you.
♪
- he is eligible for parole.
- yeah.
- that's not five years
to serve.
- it's--it's five years
to serve,
but he's parole eligible.
He is parole eligible.
- and the violent crime
that he's gonna serve,
how much of it?
- probably 65% to 90%.
Probably.
- the whole time
it never felt real to me.
I grew up with him.
He was my best friend.
You know what I mean?
Branden may not care
about anybody in the world,
but he loved me.
I still love him
with all my heart.
And I wanna just...
I can't.
- that's enough.
Come on.
- I got to do another
guilty plea in a few minutes.
Ain't no different
than what I see
every other day, so...
It all takes a toll on me.
It's not easy.
I'll never get used
to people going to prison.
I'll never get used to that.
- this case is different from
most others that I've tried,
because I don't have
any witness statements.
So I don't know what these
people are gonna testify to.
I have no idea,
because we're in georgia,
and I don't have the pleasure
of taking depositions,
because money is not at stake,
because somebody's liberty
is at stake.
So I don't get a deposition.
And because of that,
it's really kind of difficult
to come up with a solid defense,
'cause it--they could spin it.
Based on
what the police have said,
my defense is going to be that
the person that they identified
was not mr. wright.
It was just a mistake
in identity.
Young mr. wright had braces
at the time of this incident.
There is no mention
by the police
of the victims telling them
that the person had braces.
They say that they know
for a fact
that it was young mr. wright,
because they're familiar
with young mr. wright
because he frequents
the pizza parlor.
So they should know
that he was wearing braces,
and they should know
that he has tattoos
from here down
and from here down to his hands.
Like, he has tattoos
on his hands.
I'm hoping that those braces
are our savior.
I'm hoping.
I have his orthodontist
under subpoena,
and even though
he does not want to come,
so help me god,
I will drag him into court
kicking and screaming
in handcuffs
because he is our out
as far as I can tell.
Now, again,
they may flip it on me
and say that the person
had braces all of a sudden,
and then I'm kind of screwed.
I mean, I don't know what
I would argue at that point.
Hopefully,
they leave that out.
♪
- all right, you got your ball.
Bottled water is in the car.
Got your shin guards.
I left
the public defender office.
The main reason was the pay.
I was struggling to take care
of raha and myself.
All right.
Have a good game.
I can remember
writing a check for groceries
knowing that I didn't have
enough money
in my checking account.
More and more,
I was just disgusted.
How dare this system
treat public defenders
like this?
We matter this much,
that after I get paid
once a month,
I have $20 left to my name?
I am still in jackson.
I'm still doing, in my mind,
public defender work.
I still get
court-appointed cases.
I'm still representing
indigent clients.
So though I'm not in a full-time
public defender capacity,
I will forever be
a public defender,
and it's an honor.
- we always deal with people
in our profession
who like to bitch and moan about
how tough they had it
getting through law school
and this and that,
but they had it easy.
Things were handed to 'em.
Things were there for them.
Travis had none of that.
Travis came up hard.
Travis grew up without a father.
He grew up without a mother
that he could rely upon.
Nothing was handed
to this young man.
He struggled his entire life.
He's a fighter.
One of the highlights
of travis' career so far
has been the trial
of a man accused of
all sorts of felony obstruction
at the jail.
In that case,
what happened was,
the client ended up
being convicted
of a misdemeanor affray charge.
That's a win.
We all know that's a win.
But he didn't stop there.
Travis appealed
the misdemeanor affray charge
and reversed it on appeal
and walked his client scot-free.
That's a public defender,
folks.
So because you are
such a good example,
because you are such
an outstanding illustration
of what it means
to be a public defender,
we decided that,
travis williams,
you, this year, are
the assistant public defender
of the year.
Come up here and get your award.
- thank you, mr. dunn.
Thank you.
So much of our job goes unsung,
and to have any sort
of recognition
is a true honor.
Just this week, a young client
of mine went away to prison,
and so this award, in some ways,
is bittersweet.
Every day, my goal is to be
a better man
and a better public defender,
so thank you.
- the stakes are as high
as they could possibly be.
I mean, we have cases
that haunt us.
This case will haunt me.
If we--if we lose,
it'll haunt me.
He is a kid,
and he's facing a lot of time.
If he's found guilty,
it will break him.
Mentally and emotionally,
he'll be broken.
I can't fathom--
I cannot fathom
turning around to his mother
after a jury has said guilty,
and I've told her he's gonna get
ten years at least, at minimum.
She says he's done, like,
a complete 180.
He has a job.
He's working on his g.e.d.
Apparently he has
this girlfriend, so...
I think that
he's been scared straight,
assuming he gets
a not guilty verdict
and is allowed
to live his life.
And here's hoping
that that's the end result.
And we don't see
happily-ever-afters very much
in this profession,
but hopefully we get us
a happily-ever-after.
♪
- all rise.
The superior court of clayton
county is now in session,
the honorable matthew simmons
presiding.
- good morning.
Please be seated.
Let's bring the jury in.
All right, members
of the jury, good morning.
At this time,
we'll hear opening statements,
and, uh, miss owens,
the state may proceed.
- ladies and gentlemen,
you're here today
because on december 3, 2010,
this defendant decided to dress
in dark clothing,
enter into a pizza shop that
he'd visited many times before
with a gun--
the testimony will show
that it's an automatic weapon--
and took the money
out of the cash register.
We'll ask that you find
this man, demontes wright,
guilty of all the crimes
alleged in the indictment
which include
aggravated assault,
armed robbery,
and possession of a weapon
during the commission
of a crime.
Thank you.
- on december 3, 2010,
young mr. wright
was 16 years old.
16.
He was not a man.
He was a boy.
And on that day,
super crown pizza was robbed.
We don't disagree with that
at all.
It was not young mr. wright
that robbed that store.
Now, let me be very clear.
We don't have to prove
anything in this case.
We have no burden.
It's the prosecutor's burden.
They have to prove beyond
and to the exclusion
of every reasonable doubt
that that boy
committed the crimes
that they've charged him with.
It's a high burden.
Hold them to that burden.
- the state may call
its first witness.
- the state calls assim sadik.
Can you tell us
what exactly happened?
- "i was cooking in the back,
"and then I heard some noise,
"so I came in front.
"one man came,
and he was holding a gun."
- what was he doing
with the gun?
- "he was--he had pointed it
to my brother.
He asked for money."
- are you certain the person
that you saw that night
is the same person
you see here today?
- 100%.
- "yes, yes, 100%."
He is always around our store,
so we always see him.
- thank you.
No further questions.
- you said that young mr. wright
comes into your pizza parlor
regularly.
yes.
- we just see his face.
We don't see admitting in detail
what he has or not.
- okay.
Have you ever seen his arms?
take off the jacket.
- I don't look at people
in that detail.
- you don't look at--you don't
see details with people.
- it's rude to look at people
if we look at them
in detail like that.
- okay.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't sure I heard you.
So I'm just gonna
repeat it to make sure.
You said that it's rude
to look directly at people--
- it is rude to look at people
in detail like this.
- okay.
Having seen young mr. wright
so many times,
even though
you don't see detail,
can you say whether or not
at any time he wore braces?
- "no, I don't remember."
- no further questions,
your honor.
- the witness may step down.
Members of the jury,
we'll take morning recess now.
Take a 15-minute break,
then we'll resume.
- I just don't think
it's going very well,
'cause the--the problem is
that they were just so sure
that it was him
even though they're like,
"we don't pay attention
to detail,
"and we don't know
what he looked like,
"if he had the tooth,
'cause we don't pay attention
to that."
jesus, mary, and joseph.
I think it's a good thing
that they don't pay attention
to detail,
but we better pray
that your doctor's gonna say
that you had those tattoos.
and if he doesn't remember
whether or not you had 'em,
that's gonna hurt us,
because it'll be like, "oh,
the doctor doesn't remember.
"then they can't hold
the witnesses to any standard
if they don't remember."
Hey, where is your investigator?
She has her phone
going straight to voice mail,
and I'm in the middle of trial.
Can you please get ahold of her
and tell her I need the dentist
to send--to bring along
the picture
that he took of demontes wright
after he took his braces off?
I've got to run back into court.
- did you ever learn what type
of weapon was used in this case?
- yes, ma'am,
a semiautomatic weapon.
- okay.
Can you tell us what exactly
is located in that box?
- it's a .25 auto 50 grain
fmj winchester box.
There's currently 13 bullets
full metal jacket
inside the box.
- you found those bullets,
you say,
under young mr. wright's bed,
correct?
- that's correct.
- but you don't know
how they got there.
You don't know
who put 'em there.
- no, ma'am.
- all automatic weapons
don't take the same bullets,
do they?
- no, ma'am.
- so you can't say
if those bullets
go to the gun that was used
in the robbery
at crown plaza pizza?
- I do not have
an exact make and model
of the weapon that was used.
All I have
is a brief description.
- correct.
- okay, you indicated
that you didn't take
any fingerprints
in the store.
- at the time,
there was nothing touched
that the victims had told me.
And I assumed
that there was gloves used
at that time.
- you assumed
that there were gloves used.
So when you wrote in your report
that gloves were used,
that wasn't something
someone told you;
that was something you assumed.
- that there was
gloves used, yes.
- okay.
Do you often assume things
and put them
in your police report?
- no.
- so this was just
a onetime thing.
Do you usually put things
in your police report--
- no, ma'am.
- no further questions,
your honor.
- state actually rests
at this time.
- you may call
your next witness.
- the defense would call
dr. barry clower.
Are you familiar
with demontes wright?
- uh, yes, ma'am, I am.
- he was a patient of mine
for 3 1/2 years.
- I sure did.
- and can you tell me the exact
date that you did that?
- his treatment started
in may of 2007
and concluded
in december of 2010.
- when you put braces on people,
do you take a before picture?
- yes, ma'am.
- do you take pictures
of your patients
after you've removed
their braces?
- absolutely.
- is this the picture
that you took
prior to putting
the braces on?
- yes, ma'am, it sure is.
- and does young mr. wright
have a tattoo in that picture?
- uh, yes, ma'am,
both sides of his neck.
- and is this the picture
that you took after
you removed the braces
on december 6, 2010?
- yes, ma'am, it is.
- and does he have tattoos
in that picture?
- yes, ma'am.
- okay.
I have no further questions,
your honor.
- no questions from the state.
- all right, we'll hear closing
arguments at this time.
The state has the right
to open and conclude.
- thank you, your honor.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the defense
would like you to believe
this is more complicated
than it is.
This is an open-and-shut case.
Atif and assim knew who entered
into their store.
They know him.
It's this man,
demontes wright.
There was a lot of fuss about,
"oh, these guys don't remember
this, that, and the other."
Well, let's talk about
what they do remember.
They remember that this man
entered into their store,
that throughout
the whole entire incident,
this man had a automatic handgun
in their face,
terrifying them.
They sat here today
and said, a whole year later
and a new look,
"that man, demontes wright,
"is the one who entered my store
on december 3rd,
"stole money from me,
"put a gun to my head,
"and waved a gun at my brother
and took my money."
Ladies and gentlemen,
I submit to you
that we have in fact
proved our case
beyond a reasonable doubt,
and I ask you to find
this defendant,
demontes wright,
guilty of all the crimes
in the indictment:
two counts of armed robbery,
two counts
of aggravated assault,
and two counts
of possession of a weapon
during the commission
of a crime.
Thank you.
- I want you to think of
the criminal justice system
as a really long road, okay?
And at the beginning
of that road is a charge,
where they charge someone
with a crime.
At the end of that road
is a conviction.
Now, before the state can get
to the end of that road,
before the prosecutors can get
to that conviction,
they have a big brick wall
in front of 'em.
That brick wall
is called reasonable doubt.
Atif sadik
said a number of things.
But it's what he didn't say
that I want you to focus on.
It's what he didn't remember
What I found really interesting
is that he said
that young mr. wright
comes in his store
three to four times a week
for the last two years.
I was an english major.
My math is terrible.
But from what I gathered,
that's about 342 times
over the course of two years.
But he didn't remember
whether or not
he had braces.
And he didn't remember
whether or not he had tattoos.
I had braces.
They were terribly embarrassing
because every time
you open your mouth,
the very first thing
that people see
are those braces.
And when he's coming in
three times a week,
three to four times a week,
for two years,
you would know
that he was wearing braces.
And since they say
he didn't always come in
with long sleeves,
they knew that he had tattoos.
But the person that
they described to the police
did not have braces,
and he did not have tattoos.
Reasonable doubt.
We would ask
that you find
the only just verdict
of not guilty.
- members of the jury,
you may now go to the jury room,
but do not begin
your deliberations
until you've received
the indictment,
the evidence,
and the verdict form.
Thank you.
- remain seated.
Come to order.
- would you bring
the jury in, please?
Members of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
- yes, we did.
- will you read
that verdict to us, please?
- in the superior court
of clayton county,
state of georgia,
the state of georgia
versus the defendant,
demontes regary wright,
case number 2011cr636-8,
verdict, count number one:
we, the jury,
find the defendant
not guilty of the offense
of aggravated assault.
Count number two:
we, the jury,
find the defendant
not guilty of the offense
of armed robbery.
Count number three:
we, the jury,
find the defendant
not guilty...
[your hand in mineby
explosions in the sky playing]
♪
- ♪ Woke up this morning early
♪ Blinded by light
♪ A way of insight
♪ New perception in life
♪ For true believers
♪ Every day is a fight
♪ Yeah, give me my whites
♪ And I'm ready to take flight
♪ There's so much fake
in this world ♪
♪ Something's got to be real
♪ Working every moment
♪ Need a hour to chill
♪ Especially when
the stakes higher ♪
♪ Than the cow on the hill
♪ Give you my shoes
to climb it ♪
♪ And ask you how does it feel
♪ My belief in freedom's
♪ The only way to escape
♪ Going against the odds
♪ While reconstructing
our fate ♪
♪ Decisions we make today
♪ Tomorrow affect the seeds
♪ The world can learn too
♪ But first you got to believe
so please ♪
- ♪ A promise you
ought to make ♪
- ♪ True believers
♪ True believers
- ♪ I give you all you need
- ♪ True believers
♪ True believers, yeah
- ♪ I'll make the world
believe ♪
- ♪ True believers,
true believers ♪
- ♪ You just got to be here
- ♪ True believers
♪ Sell them records,
sell them records, sell them ♪
- ♪ Don't quit on you
♪ And I won't quit on me
- ♪ Visualize the future
♪ See it in hindsight
♪ Nothing's a guarantee
♪ They live
for telling this mic ♪
♪ With shackles cuffed nice
♪ Rope tied tight
♪ Until I turn to houdini
♪ And disappear in the night
♪ I can't think with thoughts
♪ That's built
for hurting your brain ♪
♪ You can't love a soul
with a heart full of pain ♪
♪ Channel your energies
♪ Stay on track in the train
♪ Loyalty's more important
♪ Than your personal gain
♪ So no
♪ Don't quit on you
♪ No, don't quit on you
♪ I got to channel love
♪ And I can send it through
♪ What we do today
♪ Tomorrow affect our seeds
♪ The world can learn too
♪ But first you got to believe
so please ♪
- ♪ A promise you
ought to make ♪
- ♪ True believers,
true believers ♪
- ♪ I give you all you need
- ♪ True believers
♪ True believers, yeah
- ♪ I'll make the world
believe ♪
- ♪ True believers,
true believers ♪
- ♪ You just got to be here
- ♪ True believers
♪ Sell them records,
sell them records, sell them ♪
- ♪ Don't quit on you
♪ And I won't quit on me