Episode 49
Welcome.
Did you confirm it?
I'm sure you saw what would have really
happened to the real Hong Myeong Ho.
010-447-437
Moon Seon Ho, this is Jin Hyeong Woo.
Wait a minute. Don't hang
up, listen carefully.
Don't trick me. You're tracing my
location with the police, aren't you?
That's not it. I'm alone now.
Give me just a minute. Nobody
can get you in that time.
What do you want?
I know you're in a bad position.
You are wanted nationwide. Even if you want to go
abroad, you are banned from leaving the country.
Moon Seon Ho, if you want to get away,
your only choice is as a stowaway.
However, it's not easy to stow away, either
because Kwon Soo Myeong is
trying to get rid of you.
Haven't you figured how Kwon Soo
Myeong really takes care of someone
who knows too many of his secrets?
So? Just get to the point.
Where are you going to stow away?
Hey, am I stupid? Aren't you trying
to sucker me and then capture me?
You don't have many alternatives right now.
Either trust me, or die by
Kwon Soo Myeong's hands,
you have less than a minute. You decide.
Hong Myeong Ho?
Who are you?
I'm Moon Seon Ho.
Are you sure you're Moon Seon Ho?
Yes, yes.
Hey, guys!
Take him away.
Ah, yes. I caught him.
Did you bring a homeless Hong Myeong Ho?
Why did you go that far to help me?
Kwon Soo Myeong's ₩300 billion
that you sent to Brazil...
- I have it.- What did you say?
I followed the method you
always used and hacked it.
You jerk. You trap me and then rescue me?
What is your motive?
To divide you and Kwon Soo Myeong.
Moon Seon Ho, you have nowhere else to go.
My motive is to catch Kwon Soo Myeong.
It's not because I have
any grudge against you.
Help me catch him.
Then I'll help you to get away.
How should I trust you?
You know I came here alone.
If I wanted to arrest you, I
would have brought the police.
Moon Seon Ho,
there was definitely a time
when you loved Eun Soo.
There isn't much time before Eun Soo will
be on trial for instigating a murder.
Please help.
Are you saying that Kwon Soo Myeong had money
sent to Dr. Im in the Eun Gang Foundation's name?
Yes, they are going to try to make me clearly
into an instigator of murder before the trial.
So did you have the money sent?
Yes, but I didn't send it in the Eun
Gang Foundation's or the Madame's name.
I sent it in the name of the bank that
Kwon Soo Myeong withdrew the money from.
Manager Jo, I think we may be able
to catch Kwon Soo Myeong using this.
Because it wasn't sent in his
name, he'll try to get out of it.
I'll testify. Regarding everything
Kwon Soo Myeong ordered me to do.
But he'll still slip out.
We have to find direct evidence that Kwon
Soo Myeong and Dr. lm were connected.
Manager Jo, is it possible we can
wiretap him committing a crime?
Even until before you appeared,
Eun Soo had faith in you.
Even after I revealed your true identity,
she said you wouldn't do that
and believed in you to the end.
You want to send that kind
of woman to jail again?
So why are you doing that for Shin Eun Soo?
That woman let you go and married
an old ex-Prime Minister.
Why are you hanging yourself over
a woman who's been married twice?
She was my first love.
If I hadn't let her go back then,
Eun Soo's life wouldn't have
gone through so much difficulty.
I've lived regretting
it forever since then.
Now it's your turn.
Do you want to live regretting it, too?
It's an amazing love.
I'm different from you, so you two
should take care of it yourselves.
Are you going to keep this up to the end?
What kind of grudge do you
have against Eun Soo?
It wasn't enough that Kwon
Soo Myeong used Eun Soo.
It wasn't enough you sent an innocent
woman to jail and kept ₩2 billion.
You show up again in front
of that poor woman.
The one who manipulated the Eun
Gang Foundation money was you, too.
Why in the world are you doing this?
I don't know a thing.
What don't you know?
You're the same as Kwon Soo Myeong.
You are a dog-man that waves its
tail while being fed scraps by him.
If I hadn't done that, Shin Eun Soo
would've died seven years ago!
Don't try to break a boulder with an egg.
You don't know Kwon Soo Myeong's power.
By doing this, you're only putting
Shin Eun Soo in more danger.
I was taken. I got taken by him again.
My money. How did I steal ₩300
billion from the Prime Minister?
What brings Mrs. In-Law...
Kwon Soo Myeong, I reported you for
instigating the murder of the Prime Minister.
Here's the complaint.
What kind of threat is this
using a sheet of paper?
Kim Gyeong Min confessed
that you told him to send money to Dr.
Im in my name.
Is this still only a threat?
This proves you falsely
accused me, doesn't it?
And I will catch that murderer
in Singapore as well.
I will make sure that you
won't sleep until then.
Negotiations between Ruling and Opposition Parties
Break DownOver Personal Cell Phone Tapping Bill
Hello?
I sent the money, but you
can't take it out yet.
- What are you saying?- Shin
Eun Soo's side got wind of it.
I'll find another route, but in return,
you can't show up at the bank.
Did you send all ₩20 billion of it?
What are you talking about?
I promised ₩10 billion...
Don't you remember?
When I called you five days ago,
I definitely said ₩20 billion.
If you don't send all of that money, I'll
reveal that it was you who pulled the strings.
Can you restore the date erased?
Yes. If you give me 2-3
days, it's possible.
This doesn't work as conclusory evidence
that my father really went to that hospital.
Then?
I'll have to investigate the
pictures from a long time before.
I like that kind of stuff.
Alright. Good work. Keep watching him.
Is thephone tapping successful?
No, he only spoke with the secretary.
Perhaps, haven't they noticed?
I don't know.
Don't get too disappointed.
Someday, we'll catch him tripping.
President Kwon
If you have an ounce of conscience,
testify about Kwon Soo Myeong in court.
Tell them what he did to my life.
Why should I endanger myself like that?
Because you're Mi Rae's dad.
At the very least, I don't want her to
think her dad was like Kwon Soo Myeong.
I'm sorry.
You're here and I thoughtlessly
touched Prime Minister's things.
He used it for a long time.
Could this have been your present to him?
Yes.
Team Leader Go.
I spent more than half my
life with the Prime Minister.
I still feel like he wants
the newspaper every morning.
So I bring the newspaper, but...
But...
You're putting me to shame.
But you single-mindedly stayed
with the Prime Minister.
No, Madam.
Because of you, the Prime
Minister was very happy.
I'm thankful to you for that.
Madame. I think you need to come out.
Honey.
The step.
No. Why did this set that left
the house come back again?
Agasshi.
Please! How could you be like this?
How can you hit such a rock bottom?
What happened?
Yeah, with what you took, you could have played
around for years on what you got for it.
My husband... tried to do
business here and there.
We got conned.
- Excuse me. Give me another bowl.
- Yes.
You're eating that!?
Really! Seriously! How
can you be like that?
Il Ran, still, he can't starve.
You do whatever you want, it's your money.
Of course, I should report them.
Hey, Il Ran.
When it comes to money,
there's no blood or tears.
However, I'll leave this
matter to my wise husband.
Excuse me? Me?
Haven't you wanted to see
Mi Rae at least once?
At the very least, I don't want to let her
think her father was like Kwon Soo Myeong.
Here. Here.
Here.
You can't take this off here, or
else the balloon will fly away.
Wow. When are we going
to go to New Zealand?
New Zealand?
When you're better, we have to go.
I'm all better.
Yeah.
When you can run and play.
Let's go then.
You're cold, aren't you?
I'll go bring you a blanket.
When more time passes and
when everything ends,
let's talk again. I will
mark time until then.
Mi Rae. I'm going to go take a call.
Hello?
It's a pretty balloon.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
I got hurt.
Why?
To protect something precious.
It must hurt a lot.
You called for me?
I have something to ask you, Manager Jo.
Seven years ago, on the day when we
learned that Mi Rae's dad had died,
we went to the amusement park.
At that time, why did you and
the Prime Minister go there?
Did you see us?
Yes.
Because of that, my husband ran away
in a rush. Why did you do that?
Honestly, I also received a report
about a week ago before that incident.
It said that someone was looking for the
Prime Minister's Swiss bank account,
and when I looked into
it, it was Moon Seon Ho.
So I escorted the Prime Minister and went to catch
him, but he beat up all my subordinates and ran away.
We were also flustered when we
heard that he died the next day.
So Kwon Soo Myeong has been targeting the
Prime Minister's slush fund since then.
That's probably the case.
I couldn't tell you beforehand
for fear you would be hurt.
- I apologize.- It's fine.
Now, the mystery is solved.
Now, you're even upsetting me?
Why won't you open the door?
Why are you doing this? Let's
talk, you know I abhor violence!
You tried to get rid of me first.
Hey, that's because you took my money!
There's something called ethics, how
could you just steal it like that?
I didn't take it. Jin Hyeong
Woo intercepted it en route.
- What?- What about my payment?
Hey, then you should get it from Jin
Hyeong Woo. Why would you come to me...
I got it, I'll give it to you.
I'll give it to you.
Wake him up right now and
bring it to me in cash.
Ugh, I said I got it.
Don't think of ever searching for me again.
Don't even call me.
If there's even an hint of you tracking me, I'm going
to tell the prosecutors everything you've done.
Look here, you'll need my help
if you want to stow away.
I can do just fine on my own as well, because I
want to end this tiresome relationship with you.
You...
Aigoo, why do you live in a place like
this when you have so much money?
If you have ₩300 billion, shouldn't you at
least have a house the size of a gymnasium?
- It seems you met Moon Seon Ho.-
Look here, Lawyer Jin. Let's make up.
I also have things I agreed to with your mother
in the past. Let's just split that equally
and let's stop bothering each other now.
We'll only shed blood if we
start a war with each other.
I'll make sure Shin Eun Soo is
found innocent at her trial,
so let's make a peace treaty.
I told you I don't trust your strategy that you are taking
whatever you can get while hiding behind a weak façade.
You've stabbed me in the back
more than once or twice.
I'm sorry, but the government
will confiscate that money.
What has the government done?
Lawyer Jin, are you crazy?
Are you a patriotic separatist?
Why are you really doing this?
Honestly, you have nothing against me.
As you said,
let's just say I did something to my in-law.
Then shouldn't you be grateful to me?
Why are you bothering me?
Please take ₩150 billion and go to New Zealand with
Shin Eun Soo together as you originally planned.
Then everyone will be happy.
Why the hell are you doing this to me?
- Because of justice.- Justice?
What's that?
Yeah,
when I was young, I thought that
something like that existed
but does the world revolve around justice?
In this society, power and
money rule the world.
Don't you know that? Is that why you're
complaining about justice like a little child?
If the world is like that,
we should try to change it.
- That's what I learned from my father.-
What's the result? Your father just died.
Yes,
my father proved justice through his death.
The same goes for me. Even if I die,
even if I'm attempting to break a stone with
eggs, I'm going to fight until the end.
That's how you and I are different.
At least Kang Seok Hyeon reflected
before he died. You're just a monster.
I know how many people
that monster will kill,
so I'm going to fight until the end.
Yeah, he wants to have a go?
Something that my dead in-law
couldn't do, he dares to...
- What is this?- I'm Prosecutor Jeong
Ji Yeong from the Seoul District.
Since Shin Eun Soo reported you on charges of instigating
the former Prime Minister Kang Seok Hyeon's death
and threatening her personally, we're
planning to investigate. Please cooperate.
Aigoo... what is this world coming to?
A goby is jumping, and a small
octopus is jumping as well.
Call my lawyer.
Yeah, let's go.
Did you say you are Prosecutor Jeong?
Do you think it makes sense that
I instigated my in-law's murder?
Didn't you give money to Kim Gyeong Min
and send it to Singapore under the
pretense that it was from Shin Eun Soo?
President...
Look here, I don't know
who Kim Gyeong Min is,
and I sent money to Singapore to invest
in the construction of a building.
The recipient's account is also
from the construction company.
Did that murderer, Im Dong
Jun, take that money?
Did he?!
Excuse me. I'm going to make
you confront each other.
Kim Gyeong Min, is everything
you testified to true?
Yes, everything is true.
I said I didn't know who that person is.
What do you do?
I have evidence.
President, I took about three
voices and did a test.
Find the coordinate book.
Once you pick among these
three, I'll use that voice.
In-Law, where is my voice in that file?
Coordinate book or whatever, is there a
reason for me to be studying math at my age?
The phone number Gyeong
Min called is your number
- and he also visited your office multiple times.-
I receive around 20 spam phone calls a day.
I've never met that person in my life.
I'm Kwon Soo Myeong.
- Why would I associate myself with that scammer?-
I even sent money to Singapore under your orders.
- Are you going even to deny
it?- I have nothing to say.
The right to remain silent. Do you know
what the right to remain silent is?
Father-in-Law was arrested
by the prosecutors?
Yes, that woman Shin Eun Soo reported him.
There's nothing to worry about. My father
has the prosecutors in his pocket.
He won't be imprisoned just
because of a woman's complaint.
But you also think that your father
instigated my father's murder.
Yeah, of course.
You need to have this
much evidence like me.
Tada! Do you want to see?
Isn't this the hospital
Father-in-Law used to go to?
So are you going to turn this
over to the prosecutors?
Are you crazy? Why would
I persecute my father?
Then why did you obtain this?
As insurance for you.
I can use this to force my father to
retire and take his President's seat.
What is this?
Prosecution Service
I'm Shin Eun Soo's
attorney, Jin Hyeong Woo.
I've brought supporting evidence that Kwon Soo
Myeong instigated the murder of the Prime Minister.
Hey. Jin Hyeong Woo.
Prosecutor, would you step
outside for a moment?
Chief Prosecutor.
We'll investigate you without detention.
Without detention? You haven't
even interrogated him properly.
Then, I just have to go?
No! You killed the Prime Minister.
Since as far back as nine years ago, you've
used me to get the Prime Minister's money.
You even threatened me that you
were going to kill my child.
Look here, Lawyer Lee, can you also
charge this woman for defamation?
I tried to leave her alone because of
Eun Gang's face but I can't do it.
Didn't I tell you that I have other
evidence? You have to at least look at it.
Submit it as a written reference.
How can you do this?
Investigate it properly!
We have evidence, why
are you releasing him?
Even though it's without
detention, I'll indict him.
He'll be judged at trial.
Why do I have to do this?
Oh, my. You can't do it like that.
You have to wring the water completely
out of the rag first before wiping it.
You're the one who most hated having
water on the table while eating.
Right now, who is supposed to do this and
who is standing idly giving instructions?
What are you doing it
not wiping it yourself?
Why would I do that?
Team Leader Go clearly said that in the future
we are to leave the housecleaning to you.
Look here.
Hey!
Why? Is she goofing off?
Agasshi, this isn't right. How
could I do what the maids...
Shut up!
Do you want to go to the police then? Must you
make me do things that aren't good for the baby?
No, who said I wasn't going to?
I'm doing it now, see? So clean!
What... what is this?
I didn't do it, your employee did.
But In-Law Ma, honestly,
isn't this too much?
Even still, can you work
me like a dog like this?
I'm higher ranking than you in the house.
But at work, didn't I
tell you to call me Boss?
And everyone here is working so diligently.
Will it do or not for you
to work so nonchalantly?
And the life of our restaurant is a smile.
Did I or did I not tell you that?
With an already tough-looking face,
if you scowl like that, would
customers want to come in?
How can I help if I look like this? Do you
want me to get plastic surgery like Il Ran?
I don't know. I'm not doing it. I can't.
Fine.
Ah, hello?
Hello, this is 111, right?
I want to report a thief.
Ah, fine, fine. I'll just do it... Sir.
Smile.
It doesn't seem to help.
The shop work is good enough, but
if you go out, the lobsters,
can you count how many are left, and if
there aren't enough, place an order.
Here's the number.
Fine... Sir.
Ah. Really.
Oh, no, my hand slipped!
What, what happened now?
How did it fall in there?
My hands have always been fern hands.
I'm so sorry, what can I do, Boss?
You'll have to buy a new one.
How can you drop someone
else's phone into the water?
Sheesh, seriously.
Hey, guys. Were you not hurt? Are you okay?
You did it deliberately, didn't you?
You're so immature, I can't take it.
Stop doing stupid things and
go inside and wash the dishes.
It's piled up like a mountain.
What is this?
I heard about you, Father-in-Law.
You've had a hard time, haven't you?
Yeah. I have just been to visit a neighbor
for a short time. How about Moo Hyeok?
He went to work.
That's good.
Have a seat.
What is it?
Give that here and go.
Yes.
You are really hopeless.
The memory chip was changed.
Where is the original one?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I'm sure you don't.
This is my cell phone log.
Even though it was deleted on
the cellphone, it's still here.
You called Dr. Im, didn't you?
Father-in-Law, you instigated
my father's murder.
Let's say I did. So what are
you going to do about it?
Just having spoken to him isn't evidence.
But you're different.
There's a witness that
you pushed the child.
And the child herself could
open her mouth and talk.
Il Joo, I really like you.
We're of the same breed.
But if you put a knife to my
neck, what will I do with you?
Power is uniquely such a thing.
It is like a very high castle wall that the
ordinary people like us can never jump over,
no matter how hard we struggle.
It's not over yet.
He's looking down at us
from that high castle.
How can we bring them outside?
How can we prove Il Joo did it?
The breaching of the castle wall has
already started, so please be patient.
Il Joo, bring that child to me.
That's the only way you can live.
I'm not trying to harm the child.
I want to negotiate with Shin Eun Soo.
Soo In, the doctor is looking for you!
Yes!
Mi Rae, stay here for a moment.
Mi Rae.
I'm sorry.
Do you... remember me?
That's right. Our daughter-in-law
finally did something I like.
I got it.
In-Law,
what fault does the child have?
How could she get into such an accident
after being born to the wrong mother?
It's still not too late.
Just plead guilty at the trial.
The child is making small sounds.
Isn't it all right for
your mother to raise her?
As I've told you, the
Prosecution's sole evidence
is a single letter by the
murderer, Im Dong Jun.
My client
is certain that he received
an order from someone else
and sent that letter.
Unless Im Dong Jun personally comes
to this trial and confesses,
my client is innocent.
Prosecution, do you have more questions?
Defendant. You love your daughter, right?
Then, even if it's just for
your daughter, confess proudly.
If you have no more questions, we'll
adjourn here. The next session will...
Just a moment, Your Honor.
I request a witness.
Please summon President Kwon Soo Myeong, who has
made a false accusation against the defendant.
Look here! This is Shin Eun Soo's trial.
Why should we call him here?!
As of now, President Kwon Soo Myeong
is under indictment for blackmailing
and threatening Shin Eun Soo.
Your Honor, to establish
Shin Eun Soo's innocence,
we must have his testimony.
You said Chief of Staff Lee Eun
Seok was the Blue Beauty, right?
Call him and tell him
exactly what I tell you.
What do I have to say?
"You have those documents, don't you?"
"Return them to my wife."
She's a vicious woman.
Even though I told her that I had her
child, she's still not confessing.
Since the situation has come to this,
you should reveal this at the trial.
Let's make her look completely shameless.
Are you going to go as a witness?
If I avoid it even after they called
me, then I wouldn't be a man.
What would they do to me?
As long as the attending physician
doesn't show up, no one can imprison me.
Taepyeong News
Was Former Prime Minister
Kang Seok Hyeon Murdered?
You were discovered by Kang Seok Hyeon
while going through the Swiss bank?
Listen closely. If you get caught,
I'll be in danger as well.
It'll be better to
disguise yourself as dead.
Then I'll send you abroad.
It's better for you to take
that ₩2 billion with you.
Do I have to go that far?
It could just be a coincidence.
Kang Seok Hyeon appeared in front of the
amusement park. Is that a coincidence?
If you don't follow my orders, the
problem isn't you going to jail.
You have to save your wife
and the child in her belly.
♪ A flame concealed in my heart ♪
♪ burns and consumes me. ♪
♪ I can't see a thing.
♪ I am just hurting now ♪
♪ There is a flame (a flame)
in my heart (my heart) ♪
♪ The flame in my heart is burning me ♪
♪ If I can last tonight
will it be different? ♪
♪ When the moon sets and the sun rises ♪
♪ Dazzling like the morning ♪
♪ Like a moment comes to
which I am entitled ♪
♪ Please stay here with me ♪
Eun Soo...
Eun Soo!!!
Hello?
You know the boat will leave
in four hours, right?
I know.
Witness.
During the time the defendant was arrested on charges
of instigating the murder of Kang Seok Hyeon,
you used Brian Moon.
Through a computer expert
named Moon Seon Ho,
you fabricated evidence to give the impression that money from the
Eun Gang Foundation was transferred to Im Dong Jun's wife, correct?
Brian Moon? Is he a Korean residing abroad?
Ah, this is quite the situation.
I don't even have dementia. Even if I look back over my entire
70 years of life, there is no name like that in my memory.
The witness, using the same method,
attempted to transfer a huge amount of money to
Im Dong Jun under Shin Eun Soo's name once again
through Kim Gyeong Min.
Objection! The prosecutors who
investigated the President
have already concluded
that that was not true.
What?! Kim Gyeong Min, you bastard,
you were that man's subordinate?
Oppa! Oppa, do that later.
Look at that shameless face.
Aigoo... I'm sorry, Your Honor.
As I am sitting in front of the
person who killed my lifelong friend,
my heart is breaking apart.
Why did you do that, In-Law?
You should stop now.
Please stop, it was you.
You killed the Prime Minister!
Right! It's not Mother! No matter how I look at it, it's
you, you piece of trash that's not even worth a used rag!
Be quiet! I'll have you removed.
Why? As a pregnant woman, I have a free pass. I
have the right to sit down anywhere I want to.
Why? What's wrong? What did I do?!
Aigoo, it's a mess. Anyway,
you're quite pitiful as well.
A mother should protect her child. How
could you waste time in a place like this?
Your Honor, we have other evidence that the
defendant murdered Prime Minister Kang.
I call the former Prime Minister's daughter,
Assemblywoman Kang Il Joo, as a witness.
Witness
T-that... that...
You have evidence that you
submitted yourself, correct?
Yes. Please turn it on.
This video from the black box installed
in President Kwon Soo Myeong's car
was filmed the night before my
father visited the hospital.
What are you doing right now?
Gallery! Silence.
There is one more remaining video.
Coincidentally, Doctor Im Dong Jun's car was
parked next to President Kwon Soo Myeong's car.
He abandoned his car in his
rush to escape to Singapore.
The next video is the black
box recording from that car.
Oh my, what to do?
- What are they doing? Huh?-
Goodness, what to do?
No...
Your Honor!
Kang Il Joo is a criminal who
pushed a seven-year-old child down.
She's the very woman who tried
to kill Shin Eun Soo's child.
On top of that, she even
kidnapped that child.
How could this type of culprit be a
witness at Shin Eun Soo's trial?
That's true. I pushed the child.
Wait, she pushed the child?
Goodness, goodness, goodness.
Why on earth...
In this seat, I'll reveal that
truth and accept my punishment.
However, President Kwon Soo Myeong was the
one who ordered me to kidnap the child.
- What?- Goodness...
Where's Father?
He was summoned as a witness
in Shin Eun Soo's trial today.
I see.
What? Who's she?
Pardon? Ah, that's...
Who is she?! Why is she in my father's
office when my father isn't here?!
The thing is... she's
Shin Eun Soo's daughter.
Mi Rae? Why is she in this office?
This isn't Mi Rae.
My father brought her here
thinking she was Mi Rae?
Who are you?
Who brought her here?
That's... Assemblywoman
Kang brought her here.
Il Joo did?
♪ Jorong Jorong on the web a golden germ.
♪ Darong Darong all the blades of grass.
♪ Every flower, every leaf with a smile.
Aigoo, you're doing so well. Once you get
all better, you should become a singer.
You can talk and you can sing, now it'll
be perfect if you can just walk. Perfect!
More importantly, I hope your
mother comes out safely.
Mi Rae, I'm sorry.
You remember me, right?
I didn't come here to shock you.
You remember
what happened that night, don't you?
Do you remember that I pushed you?
No.
It wasn't you.
That's right, Mi Rae. It isn't this woman.
She's my friend, there's no way
she would have done that to you.
Just as I told you last time,
you just had a bad dream.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want her to remember
that someone had pushed her.
This is the world my daughter will live in.
I didn't want her to learn so early
that an adult couldn't protect a child.
She feels terror every time she sees you.
Living her entire life with
that trauma is too distasteful.
My Mi Rae, she's already
had such a hard time.
I said that I was going to forgive you.
I only want one thing from you,
I hope you realize who made your
father, the Prime Minister, die.
- Father...- What do we do now? How
could you do that to my father? How?
I'll submit another piece of evidence.
This contains President Kwon Soo
Myeong threatening the defendant.
In-Law, what fault does the child have?
How could she get into such an accident after being
born to the wrong mother? It's still not too late.
Just confess your crimes at the trial.
The child is making small sounds. Wouldn't it
be all right for your mother to raise her?
- How could he do this, how?!-
How could he use a child?
- What did he do to the child?
- What do we do about Mi Rae?!
What kind of situation is this?
Once again, I'll report
President Kwon Soo Myeong.
He put the defendant into the former Prime Minister Kang's
house forcefully, blackmailed and threatened by all means.
And ordered to kidnap the child, stole the
former Prime Minister Kang's slush fund,
and instigated the murder of former Prime Minister Kang
Seok Hyeon. On those charges I am reporting against you.
The defendant is you now.