CHEERING
MUSIC STARTS
This programme contains
strong language from the start
and scenes which some viewers
may find disturbing.
OZZY WHISTLES
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
OZZY DOES VOCAL WARM-UPS
INTRO MUSIC: "CARMINA BURANA"
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
# People look to me and say
# Is the end near?
When is the final day? #
Rock'n'roll's
definitive crazy person.
# What's the future of mankind?
# How do I know?
I got left behind. #
Ozzy Osbourne, who is known for
biting the heads off of bats...
Hey, he's twisted
but he's all right, man.
Another scientific mystery
that's stumping scientists.
How is Ozzy Osbourne still alive
after decades of drugs and alcohol?
# Everyone goes through changes
# Looking to find the truth
# Don't look at me for answers
# Don't ask me
I don't know. #
What was that?
APPLAUSE AND CHEERS
Happy birthday!
Well, we made it, Bill.
Good to see you, good to see you.
Nice to see you too.
It's good to see you, man.
It's fucking amazing.
I never thought that.
You look great.
I do.
Nice smile.
Come on, Ozzy - smile,
it's your birthday!
I don't feel like fucking smiling.
Shut the fuck up.
Come on, smile, it's your birthday.
There you go.
'Looking back, I should have died
a thousand times, but I never did.
'I never thought I'd make it to
fucking 40.'
By 12 o'clock in the old days
I'd have powder up my nose,
fucking shit in my veins
and all kinds of stuff.
One, two, three.
Nice smile, ladies,
come with your brother.
There's like one or two ways
to get in this world,
but there are so many
fucked-up ways to go out.
Once you're dead, you're gone.
I'm just a very fortunate man
to be still here
talking to you about my life.
One, two, three.
Louis, smile!
I am smiling!
'I've had a crazy life,'
and it ain't over yet.
# Happy birthday to you
# Happy birthday, dear Ozzy
# Happy birthday to you. #
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
OZZY BLOWS
CHEERS
'I was born John Michael Osbourne,
'December 3rd, 1948.'
'I was raised in Aston,
'a working-class suburb
of Birmingham, England.'
'A lot of the city was destroyed
by the Germans in World War II.'
I used to play on
a bombed building site,
thinking it was the name
of a place that you go and play,
not realising it was a building
that had been bombed in the war.
That's my grandma, my mother,
and Gillian, my sister.
My three sisters.
My sister Jean, my sister Iris
and my sister Gillian.
We're a working-class family.
There wasn't a lot of money about.
We lived in a small terraced house.
Six children had to share
the same bedroom.
We were the poorest kids in the
street, there was no doubt about it.
'I didn't come from fucking royalty.
I didn't come from'
a middle-class
or upper-class background.
Where I came from was like...
the very bottom end of the scale,
you know?
'We were all from the same area
in Birmingham in England.'
It was very much a working-class
area, uh,
I don't think any of us had,
like, hot water
or indoor toilets or...
things like that.
My mother and father.
He was a good guy.
He was, um, you know, he was a...
He worked hard all his life,
you know?
Would never miss a day from work.
If he ever missed a day off
you knew he was fucked.
He used to work nights at a factory.
'John used to go out'
and have a drink, get in fights
and that was it.
From what I saw, Johnny
was always in and out of trouble,
Dad was always telling him off.
And one day, Dad says he'll either
get killed or, you know...
He'll die one way or the other,
you know what I mean?
A lot of the kids turned to crime,
and I did for a time,
but I wasn't really good at it.
I didn't want to do it, really.
"John Michael Osbourne,
aged 18.
"Break and enter
the shop of Clara Sharpe
"and steal therein two coats,
20 pairs of stockings."
Fined 20 quid.
Cut a long story short,
the police come around
and says to Mr Osbourne,
"Does John Osbourne live here?"
And our dad says,
"There he is - take him."
I got locked up in Winston Green
Prison for about six weeks.
When I eventually got out of prison,
life still felt hopeless for me.
I'd let my family down
for being arrested.
I had no idea what I wanted to do.
Really there were about three or
four choices when we were teenagers.
One was... We would either
probably go to prison,
or go in the factories
or go in the army.
'I remember being in a factory'
and one bloke I said to, "How long
have you been working here?"
And he goes "Oh, 35 years this year,
"and I'm retiring -
I'll get a gold watch."
I thought, a fucking gold watch?
35 years of your life
have been in this fucking factory.
And I just couldn't handle it,
you know.
I had job after job after job.
I could never hold a job down,
I didn't want to.
I couldn't, I couldn't...
I used to think, "Fuck this.
"Is this me
for the rest of my life?"
John wanted things
which he couldn't have.
Something inside him
wanted to get out.
Nothing really happened to me in
my life until the Beatles happened.
And then it was like someone
had turned the world on for me.
They played She Loves You
on the radio
and I remember thinking to myself,
"Fucking hell, this is incredible."
From that moment on, when
I first heard She Loves You,
I knew I wanted to be a rock star
for the rest of my life.
Come on!
MUSIC: "Paranoid"
You are number one!
# And so as you hear these words
# Telling you now of my state
# I tell you to enjoy life
I wish I could
# But it's too late... #
Hey!
Thank you, goodnight!
God bless you all! Stay safe!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Adrenaline from the gig.
Hello, is Sharon about?
Just tell her
the gig was phenomenal.
The crowd was fucking unbelievable.
It's fucking...undescribable.
It's like a divine experience,
you know?
All right, I'll call back.
Speak to you later. Bye.
'I'm lucky - I'm 60 years of age,
'I'm still travelling
all over the world.'
I'm still having gigs, doing gigs
and people still want to see me.
CHANTING: Ozzy! Ozzy! Ozzy! Ozzy!
It's Ozzy night, man.
It's the night of the living dead.
I've been fucking listening to him
since I was nine, ten.
Yeah, man, I got those ones.
I got that one
and then I got that one.
A big Black Sabbath cross on my leg.
Number one Ozzy fan.
Since Black Sabbath days.
Check this out.
Fucking love it, man.
CHEERING
Crouch down.
I remember
when I was a fan of the Beatles,
and I always had my fantasies.
if it's going to make somebody's
day a little bit better to say,
"Wow, I met Ozzy Osbourne today,"
I mean, that's my job, you know?
Can you get this, please?
Sure.
Just right down, right down there.
Sharon goes to me,
"You get back there
and sign that fucking autograph."
I, I go, "What do you mean,
my darling?"
And she says, "Well, one day
you're going to be...
"If they don't ask
for your autograph
"that's when we got a problem."
Check out my shirt.
You can't fuck it up
no more than President Bush.
I have something for you.
Here's your own.
Thank you!
'I go down the road
and if I get recognised,'
I get pissed off. But if I don't
get recognised, I get pissed off.
People have recognised me
for a lot of years
and for a lot of different reasons.
I just want my audience to know
that I have not abandoned them
to become a fucking weatherman.
Wonder how many signatures
you've signed.
LAUGHTER
MUSIC: "War Pigs"
# Generals gathered in their masses
# Just like witches at black masses
# In the field the bodies burning
# As the war machine keeps turning
# Evil minds that plot destruction
# Sorcerer of death's construction
# It's the same wherever you go
# To the war pigs people know
# Oh, Lord, yeah... #
Sabbath was monumental.
A huge influence on Metallica.
'Black Sabbath
was a big deal for me.'
Man, we worshipped those records.
'They were like pioneers
on so many levels, you know,'
doing new things with rhythm
and with musical interaction.
'I mean, listening to it now,'
it doesn't sound that crazy at all,
you know?
But then it was quite sort of...
off the wall.
'My very first memory
of Black Sabbath,'
I just remember hearing...
COUGHS
BEATBOXES HEAVY DRUMMING
I was like, "Oh my God,
this is insane!"
Thank you very much.
Before Black Sabbath, I was in
a band
with Tony Iommi and Geezer.
What we...
What was next needed really
was a singer.
So, uh, we went to this music shop
in Birmingham
where all the musicians
used to hang out.
'Ozzy had put
this little calling card
'in a music shop called
Jones & Crossland'
and he had written,
"Ozzy Zig needs a gig."
The first time I ever met Ozzy
was at school.
He, he, he was like... For want
of a better word, a nuisance.
And so when Bill and I
walked up to Ozzy's door
I saw him in the back room walking
in, and I said to Bill, "Forget it."
I just thought,
"This is going be a joke."
Ozzy wrote the magic words,
"has his own PA",
because nobody could afford PAs
back then.
If you sang and had a PA,
you got the job.
We didn't even have to hear him.
Although money was very scarce
in the household,
I asked my father to buy me
a PA system.
It was the best gift I ever had,
because had he not got
that PA for me
I don't think I would ever have
got a gig.
The first time we got,
we got together it went down great.
And, uh... No, it was good.
In the early days it was just
fucking guys having a blast,
you know.
You know, if we had never have made
anything of ourself
it was a good time for me
just to be around a bunch of guys
with fuck all to lose and everything
to gain. It was great.
We used to rehearse across
the street from a movie theatre.
And, um, I think it was Tony
who said, "Ain't it weird
"that people go, go to movies
to get scared?
"Why don't we start doing
scary music?"
THUNDER ROLLS
MUSIC: "Black Sabbath"
# What is this
that stands before me?
# Figure in black
which points at me... #
And that's how the beginnings
of Sabbath started.
# Oh, no! #
'And when we used to play that song
live in the early days,'
kids would just fucking scream
and run out.
# People running
cos they're scared... #
'And we started getting invites
to fucking black masses
'in fucking Highgate
fucking cemetery'
at fucking 12 o'clock. And we're
like, "is this for real?", you know.
We never thought it was real.
In life we know about the dark side
and the light side,
the good side and the bad side.
I think that's the attraction,
it hadn't been dealt with
till Black Sabbath
started dealing with it
and people go,
"Oh yeah, this is great."
You know, "Well cool." It's like the
attraction of Dracula and vampires.
It's, uh, it's a rich source
for exploration, I would think.
'What happened with Sabbath...'
For instance, Black Sabbath 1,
the first album,
we recorded that in 12 hours,
believe it or not.
The whole thing was done in 12 hours
on an eight-track machine
in a little backstreet studio
in London
and cost, like, ten bucks to make.
It was one of the biggest-selling
albums I ever did.
'And the manager comes up to me
and he goes,'
"Your album is going in the chart
next week at number 17."
I says, "Fuck off, you're joking,
you're winding me up." "No."
When I got my first record
royalty advance in money
I got £105, which is about 220.
I went out and bought myself
some shoes and some socks,
some trousers,
and a bottle of Brut cologne
which I liked the smell.
I've always liked to smell nice.
I used to stink.
Coming from having nothing,
literally fucking zero,
no socks on my feet,
walking around in fucking
open sandals in the winter.
From that to
a pair of fucking socks and shoes.
Big time, you know?
Then the next one, Paranoid,
comes out.
The song Paranoid
went up the English charts.
The album went straight in
at number one in England.
It was like, "Fucking hell, what?"
That was our second album
we got our number one album.
We were like "Fucking hell, man."
The real rock star vibe,
you know, hit us.
This is the first one I ever got.
Gold disc from...
It's fucking spelled my name
O-S-S-I-E, which is fucking great.
But those early days
were fucking fantastic.
We all had a laugh,
we'd fuck around, we'd fucking
smoke dope, drink beer, you know.
Going around with him
was a total adventure -
we never knew
what was going to happen.
Ozzy would often
walk into a room naked.
In the early days
he was absolute bedlam.
Me and Oz were kind of like
a wrecking crew in the hotel room.
So we'd dismantle the bathroom
completely.
Just have big sledgehammers,
and toilet, sink, all gone, put it
outside, everything goes outside.
I remember I got a picture early on
of him setting fire
to Bill Ward's beard.
And Ozzy'd be laughing
and Bill would just sit there.
'Growing up,
Ozzy was a real prankster,'
but especially in his twenties
with Sabbath,
he was like the band clown.
He always, like,
got everyone going, laughing.
He did that
because that was his shield.
That protected his insecurities.
Ozzy had low self-worth.
He always considered himself
"less than".
That's how, you know,
he survived everything,
was just being the prankster.
And what do you do to relax?
Smoke marijuana.
LAUGHTER
You were joking when you said that,
of course? Yeah, right.
'With the success of the albums
came more money,
'which enabled us to buy
a better class of drug, basically,'
which is basically what we were all
doing it for at the time.
Cocaine and acid
and stuff like that.
This is a good old cocaine shot.
We were all fucked up on this.
Look at the face.
When you took cocaine you just lose
all expression in your face.
'We did the album Volume 4,
and we'd been in Los Angeles'
recording that
for about three months.
We used to have it in...cereal boxes
of cocaine delivered to the house.
We'd just tip it into this big bowl
and sort of...
A bit like Scarface,
kind of thing.
For a while we used LSD
before we played.
And so we would go on stage,
you know, tripping.
Come on!
Let's party!
Oh, yeah!
MUSIC: "Children of the Grave"
SCREAMS AND CHEERS
# Revolution in their mind
# Children start to march
# They hate the world
in which they have to live
# Oh, the hate that's
in their hearts
# They're tired of being
pushed around
# And told just what to do
# They'll fight the world
until they've won
# And love comes
flowing through, yeah... #
'I was young, had money, I had cars,
I had a fucking house.'
I was fucking king of the world
at fucking 23.
Thank you VERY much!
We'll see you again soon.
'Shortly after I became successful'
with Black Sabbath,
I met Thelma in a nightclub.
Then we got married and we had
two children, Jessica and Louis.
And this is a picture of my parents.
That was actually
at the Hilton Hotel in Las Vegas.
There are some lovely ones.
Him looking very young and handsome
and sultry.
This is a nice...
These are nice ones -
before we had our house decorated,
so this must have been
very early 1972.
Got a Black Sabbath sticker
on the telephone.
'My recollection from my childhood
with Dad is that he'd be away for'
very long periods of time.
Um, and there would always be
a period of adjustment
when he came home.
And then it would get to normality
and then he'd go again.
So it was a very erratic childhood
with Dad.
This is Dad, Dad got into
the local newspaper
for prize green beans
that he had grown.
Nice picture of the house
and our vegetable garden.
'He was always
a very big social drinker'
so the pubs in the villages
where we all grew up
were a very big part of the social
scene. So he would go to the pub.
The only thing in the English
countryside really back then
was pubs. So I'd, I'd go,
"Oh, there's a pub there,
"the house is
just down the road. Ideal.
"I haven't got a driving license.
"If I want to, I can walk to the pub
and back."
My idea of going for a drink
was to go to a pub,
get as much poured down my neck
as I could, and stumble out.
That was my idea of a drink.
When he was around and he wasn't
pissed, he was a great father.
But, you know, that was
kind of seldom, really.
I just have a lot of memories of him
being drunk.
Fucking just random shit.
Fucking driving cars across fields
and crashing them in the middle of
the night and stuff.
It's just... It's not good
for family life, really, you know.
When you drink alcohol and someone
goes, "Dad, help me do this math,"
you go, "What the fuck are you even
bothering me for?" you know.
It just gets a big ugly scene, but
that's the way your life becomes.
I don't remember being
put to bed or bathed,
or that kind of thing by Dad.
Um, I wouldn't say he was there
for us, no - never on a sports day
or school trip, a parents' evening,
he wasn't, he wasn't like that, no.
It just pissed me off that Dad
never remembered my birthday.
Just a fucking phone call to say,
"Happy birthday, Lou."
That was all I wanted,
but he couldn't remember that.
When was Jessica born?
Sorry?
When was Jess born?
I think it was '71, '72.
Before... maybe before...
I don't... I don't really know.
I can find out for you.
Do you, do you think
he was a good parent?
No.
'I did the best I could
in that situation.
'I was fucking twenty fucking two'
and I had the...
I mean, people knew who I was.
I could drive the fucking Mercedes,
fly on Concorde to New York
fucking first class.
Stay at a nice hotel.
You know, I mean, I was a rock star.
When you become
a successful rock star
they don't give you a handbook and
say, "You should learn these rules,
"here's what you gotta stick by."
It's the fucking world.
You know, you're young,
you got money, you're successful,
chicks want to be seen with you.
You know it's, it's...
What more can you say, you know?
It's just probably stress
or anxiety.
I don't know.
I'm not anxious, I feel OK.
Well, you don't...
You've told me before
that you get wound up at gigs.
No, but the last I was great.
I mean, I just went out
and did it, you know.
I'm not wound up at all.
TAPE: OK there, Ozzy, here we go.
Now give me muhm, muhm, muhm,
M-U-H-M.
# Muhm-muhm-muhm muhm-muhm-muhm-muhm
muhm-muhm-muhm... #
Now we're going to give it the
"gee, gee, gee," slightly hooty.
End with the long one and say...
# Gee, gee, gee, gee, gee, gee,
gee, gee, gee, gee, gee... #
Now, Oz, give me a plain old "ooo"
and the same thing. Say...
# Ooo ooo ooo ooo ooo ooo ooo ooo
ooo ooo ooo ooo ooo ooo. #
# Na na na na na na... #
OK, we're going to give you a chance
to rest for a little bit
and then we'll start again.
'I love my job, you know.'
I'm very fucking passionate
about it.
When I can't give a good show
I get pissed off about it, you know.
When I can't do my job I'm, I'm...
I suffer from
terminal perfectionism.
I'm going to flip-flop Bark at
the Moon with Suicide Delusion.
Um, Crazy Train,
and leave it as the old set.
Yeah. I mean, if you want
to get your pipes in shape
we can do Fire in the Sky
because that's low for you to sing,
you know what I mean?
Yeah, but... I'll know when I get
there, you know, if I can sing.
Exactly, you know.
But I'm not going to fucking
do all this shit. Ironman.
I mean, we're going to
go over everything.
We'll be here until fucking midnight
going over all this shit.
We've gotta have a little while.
Just keep going
until we get it right. All right.
# The light in the window
is a crack in the sky
# A stairway to darkness
in the blink of an eye
# A levee of tears to learn
she'll never be coming back
# The man in the dark
will bring another attack... #
Not every night I'm great,
and not every night I'm half-great.
Sometimes I'm terrible - my voice
goes out like everybody else's.
But the show goes on.
DISTORTED VOCALS
People can't get...
Fucking, I'm deaf. Next year
I'll be like fucking Braille, man.
TURNS TV ON
Here you are.
You're so tired, that's why.
'I first met Ozzy
when Black Sabbath'
asked if my father was
interested in managing them.
Black Sabbath was a phenomenon.
It just instantly happened.
And for guys that just came
from a poor background
to suddenly money everywhere
being thrown at them,
they were really out of
their comfort zone,
those guys, they really were.
When you think, you know, they were
all so young - terribly young.
Towards the late '70s
we were very high, high, high.
There was a lot of cocaine.
I know was I using cocaine
regularly, on a daily basis.
We were doing it every day,
like 24 hours a day practically.
So I didn't realise at the time
all the management was interested
was ripping as much money off of us
as they possibly could.
I mean, Sabbath was royally fucking
ripped off, royally ripped off.
I mean, we didn't know anything
about royalties or...
I didn't even know you GOT royalties
for, for writing the music.
Circa about 1976,
I produced this report,
quite a long report,
basically saying how their money
wasn't quite as they thought it was.
For example, they all had houses,
but they didn't own them.
We had all these million
platinum-selling albums
and everything and, um,
and nothing to show for it.
No money, we were all
out of our brains on dope.
Um, so the band was
just, like, split anyway.
Uh, it had been broken, really.
Hello. Welcome to Top of the Pops,
and right now here is a rundown
of the brand new Top 30.
Right now, Never Say Die.
That's the brand new one
from Black Sabbath.
# People going nowhere
Taken for a ride
# Looking for the answers
that they know inside
# Searching for a reason
Looking for a rhyme
# Snow White's mirror said
Partners in crime... #
'The last album I did with Sabbath
was Never Say Die.'
And it was the worst piece of work
that I've ever had anything
to do with.
I'm ashamed of that album.
I think it was disgusting.
APPLAUSE
He puts everything he's got into it.
That's Black Sabbath right there.
John Travolta and Olivia Newton-John
have gone straight in at number 23
this week...
'When his dad passed away,'
it really, really, really,
really knocked the shit out of him.
It nearly destroyed him.
We were all devastated.
We all loved Jack.
It was Jack, uh,
that had given us the crosses.
This is the original, original,
original Sabbath cross.
My father made that
when he was at work.
And then when he,
when he come back with it,
everyone in the band wanted one,
and he made another.
Bill Ward wore his right up
to relatively recently.
I always wanted a man-to-man
conversation with my father
but I was too into drugs
and alcohol before he died.
I miss my father a lot, you know.
Uh, but I was young,
I was, you know, I was doing...
I was riding the fame game
for a long time.
'Oz was in absolute turmoil'
and he, he put his self
right inside the bottle, you know.
He stayed there for a while.
And, uh, so we got on with
trying to make a another record.
And we all came over to LA to do
the album after Never Say Die
and Ozzy didn't turn up
for two weeks.
Two weeks later he, he just, like,
rolls through the door,
smashed out of his head.
He'd beaten somebody up on the plane
coming over from England
and Customs had arrested him
for beating this person up.
And by the time he got to the house
he was just, like, obliterated.
And we started, like, rehearsing.
He just wouldn't sing on anything.
"That's shit,
a load of crap, that is."
Ozzy just wasn't into it.
He really wasn't into it then.
Most of the time,
he'd be on the couch asleep.
Done some Quaaludes or whatever
it might have been at that time.
I mean, he wasn't happy.
He was doing too much of everything.
As we all were,
but some people can handle it
better than others, and he couldn't.
'The conversations began'
about the possibility of
looking at another singer.
He just didn't want to be there.
And we knew it was like
either the whole band split
or we get somebody else in.
It was me that actually says to him,
you know,
"Oz, we're going to move on,
we're going to move on without you."
Broke my heart.
We all cried our eyes out
for about a week
when Ozzy had gone because we...
I swear to God if he hadn't have...
If he hadn't have been
fired from the band
he'd have been dead, like, within...
within a month.
It was tough for Ozzy when he first
got let go from Sabbath.
He had no... Very low self-esteem.
He had no confidence whatsoever.
When I got fired from Sabbath
I didn't know what, what to do.
I didn't know where to go.
I thought, well, you know, it was...
I thought it was
the end of the dream, you know?
I never, I never ever dreamed
I would do it again on my own.
I was like, "This is it."
So what money I had, I just
got fucked up and bought drugs
and stayed in an apartment
for three months and got loaded.
You'd go into Ozzy's room
and he'd be curled up on the floor
covered in piss,
beer bottles all around him,
you know, drug paraphernalia
everywhere.
And what could be sadder,
what could be lower than that?
His dignity had well gone.
Ozzy did feel very alone,
lost and broke.
Suddenly he was out of the band and,
you know, would he get picked up
and who was interested in him
and was his career over?
For, for a guy like me
who's got self-esteem issues,
the idea of going solo
was very, very scary.
I knew he had great talent,
and I just felt in my gut
that he could make a huge comeback.
It was then that I became
his actual manager, properly.
And first thing,
we had to find that band.
We auditioned
hundreds of guitar players.
Literally we would turn up
at the rehearsal rooms
and there would be
lines around the block
of musicians waiting to see Ozzy.
It was a bit of a slow process
at first
until I met someone who put me
in touch with Randy Rhoads.
Randy had like a deepish voice
for a little guy, "wow", you know.
So he goes into the studio
and I'm fucking sitting there
in the studio window thing like that
looking out.
I'm fucking zonked and he goes,
"What do you want me to do?"
I says, "Play any fucking thing."
He said, "I have a solo,"
and he played his fucking solo
and I was like, "Am I that fucking
stoned or am I hallucinating?
"What the fuck is this?"
GUITAR SOLO
# Heirs of a cold war
# That's what we've become
# Inheriting troubles
# I'm mentally numb... #
So he was very lucky
to run into Randy Rhoads.
And the guitar sound
really reinvented Ozzy's voice.
# ..Driving me insane
# I'm going off the rails
on a crazy train. #
And he had a true writing partner
and a friend.
And they really clicked.
Everybody thought
maybe he'd be down and out
because of what happened
with Sabbath.
And he just shocked the world.
Especially with Randy Rhoads
and the,
the magnitude of
what this guy was doing.
I mean, this guy is giving Eddie
Van Halen a run for his money.
Everybody thought that
Eddie Van Halen was the king.
Well, I knew instinctively that
he was something extra-special.
He was like...a gift from God.
And having that fucking thing,
having a gift from a higher power...
Oh, I don't know
what the fucking deal was,
but this guy did something to me.
And one thing that he...
One thing that he gave to me
was hope.
He gave me a reason for carrying on.
Blizzard of Ozz, the first record,
was done in six weeks.
It was just, you know, instantly,
instantly blew up everywhere.
# Steal away the night... #
He went right on tour
through Europe with the band.
Then back into the studio
three months later to do
Diary of a Madman.
Less than a year after being fired
from Black Sabbath,
Ozzy was a rock star again.
CHEERING
HOWLS
Can't hear you!
Diary of a Madman Tour
was just massive.
It was the loudest show
I've ever been a part of.
Come on!
# Over the mountain
# Take me across the sky
# Something in my vision
# Something deep inside
# Where did I wander
# Where d'ya think I wander to?
# I've seen life's magic
# Astral plane I travel through
# I heard them tell me that
# This land of dreams was now
# I told them I had ridden
shooting stars
# And said I'd show them how. #
'That show was
just like a magical time.'
I think Randy and Ozzy
gelled together like,
like left and right hand.
It was just amazing.
Their friendship was...
It was just like two best mates
hanging out and laughing.
But yet, that passion for music...
I mean, everything was the albums
that they were writing and the gigs
and just music talk the whole time.
You know, Randy
was able to achieve a lot
in a very short period of time
and a lot of it was due to
Ozzy's mentorship.
Randy, on behalf of
the over half-million readers
of Guitar Player magazine in the US
and in 70 countries
throughout the world
I'd like to present you with
the 1981 Best New Talent Award.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Oooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
Give him a kiss, Ozzy.
'I've got a lot of work to do.'
It makes you realise this is
a lot of responsibility,
and this, this tour I want to
really get myself together
and work harder, you know,
cos I'm really proud and honoured.
And I don't want to stop here,
you know?
TV: Randy Rhoads,
the 25-year-old lead guitarist
for Ozzy Osbourne's group, was
killed in a plane crash this morning
along with two other people - Andrew
Aycock, the pilot of the plane,
also Rachel Youngblood,
the group's hairdresser.
Ozzy Osbourne himself was in the van
when one of the plane's wings
clipped it,
but Ozzy escaped injury,
we understand.
25-year-old Randy Rhoads
is dead today.
The morning that Randy was killed
I'll never forget.
I never forget... We...
When, when... You know, we had...
We were there for so many hours
because it took so long for...
for the authorities who came down,
the police and the fire department.
We finally went to a nearby hotel
and I just couldn't stay in my room
so I went down.
I went out in the street
and I found a church,
right down the street.
All I wanted to do was
just sit there and be...
and just, you know, make some sense
of what was going on.
And I didn't even look up.
And I'm sitting there
and I hear this sobbing
and this, and this crying and...
And I thought, "Wow, this,
this person has got to be
"in more pain than I am."
And I look up
and there's Ozzy sitting there.
The craziest day of my life
was the day that Randy Rhoads died.
I couldn't believe that one...
You gotta deal with that, you know.
People tend to forget people
in this business so quickly.
That guy was my brother, man,
that guy was like a part of my life,
you know, and he's dead.
Why don't people start talking to me
about the death of Randy Rhoads
instead of asking me the craziest
prank that I've ever done?
That was the craziest prank
that I've ever witnessed,
was seeing that guy burn, you know.
And the day that Randy Rhoads died,
it was a day a part of me died, man.
And Rachel Youngblood,
my, my seamstress.
I can't forget that, you know.
It just gets kind of weird.
OZZY DOES VOCAL EXERCISES
It's Friday... Saturday, yeah?
Today is Saturday, yes.
I don't know what country I'm in
half the time.
I don't know what fucking time
it is. Tell me about it.
CHANTING
# Mr Crowley
# What went on in your head?
# Oh, Mr Crowley
# Did you talk to the dead?
# Your lifestyle to me
seemed so tragic
# With the thrill of it all
# You fooled all the people
with magic
# You waited on Satan's call
# Mr Charming
# Did you think you were pure?
# Mr Alarming
# In nocturnal rapport
# Uncovering things that were sacred
# Manifest on this Earth
# Conceived in the eye of a secret
# And they scattered the afterbirth
# Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey... #
GUITAR SOLO
# Hey
# Mr Crowley
# Won't you ride my white horse?
# Oh, Mr Crowley... #
After the Diary of a Madman Tour,
I went to Barbados with my family.
My ex-wife told me on the plane
coming back, "I want a divorce."
But, you know,
that's very ugly for a while.
My children still wanted
their father, their dad, you know.
And that's a fucking dreadful
feeling that you have to go through.
I remember going to my house one day
and Louis, my son, was a little kid
and he, and he got me in a...
I can remember him
sticking his fingernails in
and tears were
streaming down his face
and he says, "Daddy, please
come home, we can work this out."
That one incident tore my heart out.
Tore my fucking heart out.
It's, it just fucked me up.
I don't know...
Anyway, it really devastated me.
Ozzy and I were friends.
We worked together and that was it.
But it wasn't until August of 1980
that we actually
had a relationship going.
We were at... The first night
that we were actually together
in Shepperton in 1980,
and then the next day I thought,
well, you know, it just happened.
Drunk, we were, you know,
in the moment, it will all be over.
And each night after the show...
It happened again.
It happened again and again
and again.
And then we'd be...
It was either we were in the pub,
in bed or on stage. That was it.
That's about it, isn't it? Yeah.
I didn't know they had
a relationship or anything,
and I'm shooting Ozzy in the bed
and then all of a sudden
Sharon, uh,
goes under the covers.
All of a sudden, Sharon
is down there like she's...
doing the deed, you know, like,
and Ozzy is just, like, freaking.
Ozzy and I got married
in 1982 in Maui.
And we wanted to start a family -
that's why we got married.
We both wanted our own family.
Dad was there for me when I was
growing up, and there were...
There were times, like chunks.
You know, but then again
there were loads of times
where he, you know, he wasn't
a great father
and he wasn't, you know, there,
you know, there when I needed him.
Meaning, you know, the fact that
he was messed up a lot of the time.
Well, when he was drunk,
he was mostly tearful.
Um, and sometimes
he'd get a bit angry
and a bit like, "I work hard,
I should be able to do what I want."
Um, but mostly tearful.
I don't honestly think that Ozzy
knew how to be a father.
The drinking, you know,
the huge success
that was going on in his life.
The turmoil of leaving one family
and starting another family -
he was just, you know,
he was like treading water.
And that caused the behaviour
to get even worse.
So his pranks that he used to play
would get bigger and larger
and crazier
and his whole behaviour
on and offstage was over the top.
And it was like, um,
insanity just going around
and around and around -
complete insanity.
TV: Rock star Ozzy Osbourne,
who is known for biting the heads
off of bats at his concerts...
Osbourne was arrested for
urinating on the Alamo.
Reunion Arena was filled
with the anticipation
of a cat slaughter tonight.
Rumour was that punk rocker
Ozzy Osbourne
was going to release
hundreds of cats here
and expected the audience
to kill them
before his appearance on stage.
The lyrics from one of his songs
encouraged a young man
to commit suicide.
His father claims John was listening
to Ozzy Osbourne music at the time.
You have a reputation for being rock
and roll's definitive crazy person.
Well, I suppose you could say that.
Can we talk about you being crazy?
I'm not crazy.
'In the '80s,'
I was the craziest guy
in rock and roll.
If you... If you wanted me to do
something, tell me not to.
That was about the order
of the fucking...
I was drunk and fucked up
on a daily basis.
So when you get drunk and fucked up,
you hardly expect to fucking
tiptoe through the tulips
or whatever the fuck.
And when you're loaded,
you do crazy things.
MANIACAL LAUGH
It was the first time
that Ozzy met the A&R staff,
promotional staff,
at CBS in Los Angeles.
And, um, you know,
Ozzy's deal was a cheap deal -
they didn't want Ozzy.
It was a favour
that they signed Ozzy.
It was just a favour.
You know, 65 grand
they paid for the album.
So he wasn't on their high list
of priorities, you know.
They had fucking Michael Jackson,
and it was like "OK, well,
they've got to remember you."
And so then we said, "Oh, the doves
of peace - that'll be nice,"
you know, go in and let the birds go
and then it'll be lovely
and, you know, they'll remember.
Maybe it'll shit on somebody's
desk and that'll be funny.
And then we leave.
She wanted me to go in there
with two doves -
a peace offering, you know.
She says, "You blow this
and we're completely fucked."
We go into the meeting and there's,
you know,
the big conference table
and there must have been,
I don't know,
20, 30 people in there.
And he's sat there
and he lets this bird go
and everybody is, "Ooh!" You know,
"Magic trick!" "Oh, is that real?"
I threw the one up in the air,
sat on this girl's lap
and snapped the other one
in my mouth and bit its head off.
There is a photo somewhere of me,
of the actual event happening.
He just picked it up,
and ripped its head off
and spat it out on the girl.
And she went absolutely
fucking insane.
They suddenly called the security
and we were, like,
yanked out of the conference room.
It was not a publicity stunt.
I was just out of my fucking face on
drugs and alcohol, you know.
What is the truth behind Ozzy
biting a head off of a bat?
The bat started because of the dove.
Kids kept hearing these stories
so they would bring him animals
to the gigs...
thinking that he
would want to eat them.
And somebody threw a bat...
To find someone who goes to
a concert with a bat in their...
a real bat. You always get
the joke ones, you know.
You get the rubber ones
you buy from the corner joke shop.
And I picked it up and
I thought, "This will be good."
Bit into this bat.
You bit it?!
Believe me, if I'd have known
it was a real live bat,
I would never have picked it up.
But I'll tell you what,
afterwards, the rabies shots
were horrendous.
Oh, God, yes.
It went out on the wire that Ozzy
had bitten the head off a bat
and had to have these rabies shots.
And then suddenly, Ozzy is this
larger than life character.
When we were on tour with Ozzy,
we'd always have
these crazy parties backstage.
He would come onto our bus
and say, "I'm riding with you guys
to the next city!"
And he'd fucking reach into his...
into his coat pocket or his pants
and pull out, like,
two huge bags of cocaine
and he goes,
"I've got bags of this shit!"
And we would, fucking...
All of us would go
to the back of the bus
and we would fucking snort cocaine
for fucking, you know,
ten-hour bus rides.
And we're walking into hotels
like the Four Seasons
or the Ritz-Carltons
where like, you know, mom and dad
were a happy family
or out by the pool and everybody
is like, "the little resort"
and here comes Motley Crue and Ozzy
just fucking blasted.
And it was like this,
"who can out-gross" contest
which Nikki kind of started,
and all of a sudden,
we're sitting out by
the pool having drinks
and Nikki pisses on the ground
and goes to lick up his own piss
to freak Ozzy out.
Well, Ozzy beats him to the punch
and starts licking up Nikki's piss.
And we're like, "Oh, fuck!"
"This is fucked up!
What is wrong with you two?!"
And the hotel is freaking out.
The security is kicking us
out of the pool.
This is like, they're doing the
out-gross contest, snorting ants,
fucking licking up piss.
I'm like, "Dude, let's just go
to the fucking room,
"let's just chill out, come on."
(MIMICS OZZY) "I'm in the fucking
right and fucking..."
I'm like, "Dude, please."
I fucking grabbed him like, "Come
on!" I take him to the elevator.
I find his room, put the key in.
I'm like, "OK, bud."
I, like, push the door open,
"OK, bud, you're in your room, bye!"
He's like,
"No, fucking come here, mate!"
And I'm like "Oh, fuck,
I almost got out of here."
And he pulls me
into his room, pulls his pants down
and just shits on the fucking floor.
A fucking big shit on the floor.
And I'm like...
HE RETCHES
"OK, dude, I've got to go."
(MIMICS OZZY)
"No, fucking come here!"
And he fucking drags me back in and
he picks up the shit in his hands
and he's just smearing
it all over the walls
of this fucking hotel room.
I'm like, "Dude,
I've got to go, this is fucked up."
And I just...
I just remember turning around
and I just saw his back
and he was just painting
with this shit on the walls.
And I just, fucking,
was like, "Now is my chance."
And I fucking pinned it
out of there, dude.
I was like, this is on some
other, next level shit.
Like, I'm not really ready
to compete at this level.
I'm cool with, you know,
taking a shit in the toilet.
HE LAUGHS
I think that Ozzy's behaviour
in the '80s...
I think it's a fact of...
Um, everything,
Ozzy had always lost.
You know, he'd lost Sabbath,
he lost his first wife,
he lost his first kids, he's...
you know,
everything would come and go.
So he was, like, fucking everything
that fucking had a pulse.
Sniffing everything he could sniff
because he thought that it
was all going to end so he was going
to go out on a high.
# Screams break the silence
# Waking from the dead of night... #
I hated this video.
It's so fucking lame.
I don't like it.
Fucking stu... Everybody was fucked
up and drunk and everything.
Look at it!
I don't even know what drugs
I was addicted
to at the fucking time.
# Buried in a nameless grave... #
So, next, come on.
# Well I know
# I could be just
another stranger... #
It's a cliched
fucking '80s video, that is.
# I guess I'm just another fool... #
I can't remember doing
this fucking thing.
I was a mess in the '80s.
I was doing fucking morphine,
um, Vicodin,
fucking booze... all kinds of shit.
I can't remember. I just can't
remember it at all.
Never happened.
# I'm breaking all the rules
Breaking all the rules... #
Next!
It's hokey.
# And that's the ultimate sin... #
"Whose idea was it?"
How the fuck do I know?!
This is boring.
You know, it's fucking hard
to go back there, you know
and a lot of it, I don't want to go
back there, you know.
# Anyway, I look into you
# The doors are closing
Cannot be opened... #
Where are you going?
I'm getting up and walking around.
I don't fucking want
to watch this shit.
# Your momma told you that
# You're not supposed
to talk to strangers
# Look in the mirror, tell me
# Do you think your life's
in danger here?
I can't fucking hear you!
# No more tears. #
APPLAUSE
Let's get on with this, then.
What does it feel like tonight?
You have a tour starting tomorrow.
Is it always like this
or this is an exception?
Yeah.
Yeah, it is. Come on, come on!
No, no, no, it's like...we do...
uh, what, 16 days ago,
we got over from Japan...
When Ozzy was drunk,
he was fucked up beyond belief.
I mean, to the point
where he would drink
until he couldn't drink anymore.
Where he would be unconscious.
That's the only thing
that would stop him drinking.
He'd be unconscious or asleep.
He was blacking out.
He was drinking
and going unconscious on the floor.
He couldn't move.
His eyes would be open but he would
be, like, unconscious. It was weird.
I passed out with a bottle
of fucking Vicodin in my mouth!
Mainly, I was concerned about him,
like, choking on his vomit,
falling asleep when he was drunk
and choking on his vomit.
This is me on my stag night.
I'm fucking blasted.
I think it was in Memphis,
Ozzy disappeared
and, you know, he got
found in the middle of a freeway.
You know, he crossed over half of
a freeway and stopped in the middle
and he was in the central
reservation and he was sleeping.
And he woke up
and he had to cross the other half.
I mean, how he didn't get
knocked over
because he was
absolutely shit-faced.
This is when I clocked
Sharon, I think. I think so.
We were always fucking fighting,
me and Sharon.
That's when I smacked her, Sharon,
in the eye...
for over what, I don't know.
It had been coming for a while.
Ozzy was on a bender, you know.
He was, he was really on a roll.
He'd been very bad
for the last couple of weeks
and we'd had a couple of fights
where we'd beaten each other
and, you know, it was nasty.
But you kind of get the, you know,
when anyone who knows, who lives
with an addict, that there are
times when it's worse than others.
And it was just building
to something,
you could just feel it in
the atmosphere between us.
And, um, my God, it did.
And he put...
I'd put the kids to bed.
You know, we were sat down,
I was reading and, um, he came in.
He'd been laying down.
He'd actually drunk himself
into one of those, you know,
like, comatose things on the bed.
He'd passed out and woke up,
came downstairs and
I knew when he came in that
he was, like, looking for trouble.
And Ozzy is very rarely calm,
very calm,
and his eyes, the kind of shutter
had gone down on his eyes.
You couldn't really... you know.
I had no idea who was sat across
from me on the sofa,
but it wasn't my husband.
Um, and then he just said
that he had made a...
"they" had come.
He said "they" had made a decision
that I had to die.
And I'm like, "They?"
"Yes, they've made the decision,
we've made the decision
"you're gonna have to die."
And then he just, um...
got up from the sofa
and just dived on me
and started to choke me.
Fabulous(!)
All I remember was waking up
in Amersham Jail.
And I asked the cop why I was there.
"Excuse me," I said,
"Why am I here?"
And he says, "You want me to
read your charge?"
So he read, "John Michael Osbourne,
arrested for
"attempted murder of his...
of Sharon Osbourne."
I'm like, "Is this a joke?"
He says, "I'm not joking.
"You're going to court in a minute."
That hit me like a... like a fucking
hammer between the eyes.
It was like, I was like...
I remember getting this,
this dull feeling in my heart,
which is like...
And I thought, I thought...
I didn't know
whether she was in hospital
or what I had done, you know.
Oh, I know where we are.
That's where we used to rehearse.
That's where we used
to rehearse, there.
That's the pub
I used to go to, right over there.
Just down there is Whitton Road.
I used to walk all the way up here
to get off at Lucas car factory
to go to work for my...
with my mum.
Fucking hell.
We're just coming up
to Lodge Road now.
Fucking hell, man.
It's so small, it's unbelievable.
I can't believe how small it is.
Fucking... Jesus Christ.
When I was a kid, it used
to be like the longest road in
the world, you know.
'When you're a young kid and
you get successful like I did,
'you get very arrogant
and your ego runs the world.
'You think it's you, you know.
You forget your upbringing.'
It took me till now to kind of
realize that, you know.
Wow.
Oh, this is...
Wow, this is unbelievable.
It's amazing.
Wow.
That was Mrs Clarke's shop
I broke into.
That was my rear bedroom up there.
As my sisters, as my family,
my sisters would get older
and get married,
you were allowed to go in the
back room and have it to yourself.
And this is right here,
I lived in here for a while and,
this is unbelievable.
I hated school.
I fucking hated it.
'I had dreadful,
dreadfully bad, uh, dyslexia.
'When I was at school, nobody knew
what it was about, you know.
'Somebody would go,
"Look, one plus one equals two."
'You look at him and you go, "Well,
what the fuck does one mean?"'
I couldn't retain any information.
My attention deficit was so bad.
It still is.
I go rambling on, you know,
it's like I don't know what
I'm talking about half the time,
I just talk.
'I was very low on self-esteem.'
I used to get picked on by bullies.
But I just... it just pushed me
further inside myself.
Where you came from... Yeah.
..did everyone drink?
Coming from the background
that I come from I thought
that was, um, what you do.
You get successful,
you get married, you have kids
and you get to go to the pub.
And I used to think everybody, as
they get older, gets fucking pissed.
The first time I got drunk
I was about 14.
I, I, I didn't stop.
I drank it and I got the feeling
and I drunk until I pissed my pants
in this fucking pub.
And that's where, from
the first drink, I wanted...
I didn't drink for a drink,
I drank for the effect.
How many rehabs?
I've been in a bunch.
Between detoxes and rehab
this will be about ten or 12.
Ozzy tried to get sober,
I would say between 40 to 50 times.
But he had been in and out
of rehabs about,
I can think of ten different rehabs
he went to over the period of time.
Well, see I used to go 90 days,
I'd go, "Fuck this, it's crap,"
and go out and get stocked up again.
One minute he'd be sitting here
sober,
the next minute you would see him
be fucked up, you know.
He'd disappear somewhere or
he would go to the fridge
and get a beer or he'd go for
a walk up the drive to the pub.
I just knew...
I just knew the cycle.
It would be like, my dad would
to treatment,
he'd stay sober for maybe 60 days
tops and then he'd start
messing around with pills and
then he would do that for a while.
And then he would
just go right to the drink
and it would get really bad.
Then he would go back to treatment.
I don't actually believe
that he was ever fully sober.
He was just drunk.
He was just not a dad.
He was drunk
and he was fucked up all the time.
I came home from school
every single day to see him
lying on a couch, drooling,
with a pill bottle on the floor
or a vodka bottle on the floor.
Or, you know...
opening up the oven to make
a cake with my friends
to find that that's
where my dad would hide...
hid the bottles of alcohol.
One thing about drugs and alcohol -
they make you lie.
You start lying and covering up
your tracks and hiding things
and fucking...
I used to have to wait for
the guy to drop my drugs off
and I'd be, like, running in and out
of the fucking house all day long,
thinking that nobody would suspect
I was waiting for dope
to be delivered, you know.
When The Osbournes first started,
he was probably at his worst
peak of drinking.
I mean, like, pretty much
going through the worst times.
..That you pick up the fucking phone
and call.
That was the worst thing I'd ever
do, I was never off the phone.
Sometimes, you know, he'd be popping
pills from numerous different
disgusting doctors that would
give him whatever he wanted and...
I don't know, sometimes he'd be
on downers,
sometimes he'd be on uppers.
So like, that obviously will make
anyone behave a little bit off
and, you know, scary sometimes.
Why do we have three brown fingers?
Three brown?
Oh, because I put brown dye
in my hair.
I think it was affecting...
Well, it was affecting his speech.
It was affecting the way he walked.
It was affecting the way he stood.
It was just everything.
Part of his fame came from how
he looked.
People thought it was funny,
thought it was cute.
What the fuck is this shit?
This is not allowed.
What's happened to it?
How do I get this fucking thing on?
What they thought was funny
was kind of sad because
he was actually destroying himself
and also destroying the family.
I mean, there is hours
and hours of footage of stuff
that just couldn't show.
It just... It was too, too...
It was too real.
You know, granted The Osbournes
was not scripted, but people don't
want to sit home on MTV and watch
alcoholism tear apart a family.
When we first started filming
The Osbournes,
it was no secret my dad did drugs,
he was an addict,
but he was kind of
a functioning addict.
But when my mum was diagnosed
with cancer, it very quickly...
He was out of control,
out of control.
He never came out of his room
that we called the Bunker.
He couldn't stand up straight,
he couldn't walk properly,
he couldn't hear, he shook,
he stuttered.
I mean, everything that
you could imagine.
I mean, he was a zombie.
I was taking drugs too during
that time when my mum had cancer.
I was using too.
I got through that experience
by hiding my emotions
through using drugs.
I'll go get you a bottle of water.
Just sip on water, Kelly.
I got that interview on the phone.
On the phone? She's holding on.
I had to hang up
because I was throwing up.
Let me get, let me get you
a bottle of water.
Jack and Kelly started using
and doing drugs and alcohol
and whatever at a very early age.
Things started
happening in my family.
I mean, it was my son, Jack,
who got sober first.
When I got sober, we were sat
at a table and he's like,
"Oh, you know, I threw away all
my pain medication the other day."
And I was like, "Well, why did you
have them in the first place?"
And this whole argument erupted
and he, you know,
the one excuse my dad always
went to when he was getting
messed up was, "You guys
never needed for anything.
"You never, you know,
whatever you wanted I gave you."
I said to him, "What the fuck are
you always pissed off at me for?
"You've never ever wanted
for a fucking thing from the day...
"the moment you took
your first breath."
And he went, "Oh yeah?
What about a father?"
And that hit me straight
between the eyes like
fucking David and Goliath,
and he's got that slingshot.
He just knocked me on my arse.
I just... "Oh, fucking hell."
I honestly think that the turning
point for Ozzy was Jack's sobriety.
Jack learned how to deal
with life sober.
And I think it shamed Ozzy
that he couldn't do it.
He could never get it.
And that's what was
his big turning point in life.
That was the start of the journey
of him being sober.
You know, the evidence
proves the fact
because he hasn't drunk or
abused for over five years now.
I'm clean, I'm sober.
I don't smoke, I don't do drugs,
I don't do alcohol anymore.
I haven't done for a long while.
But, uh, I like being sober,
I like being straight.
I don't want to smoke
tobacco anymore.
He blew us all away.
I mean, we didn't...
None of us ever really thought
that he'd maintain it
for as long as he has now.
It really seems like
he's come through the other side.
When you really, when you really
let go it's like somebody takes
that chain off you,
you know, and you just go.
And you don't...
When you're involved in it,
you don't realize
how much hard work it is to be
a fucking alcoholic.
But when you get fed up with
you behaving the way you do,
I mean, sometimes I go
this is what it's all about,
I want to get fucked up,
but I don't.
His face is alive and he stands up
straight and he walks tall
and with confidence and he's not
ashamed of himself anymore.
He has nothing to hide anymore and
he has nothing to lie about anymore,
which makes him...
I think he's really proud of
himself.
I think it's the first time
he's proud of himself.
Do you like it, being clean?
I like it, yeah.
With a bit of time, you, um,
you start to go, what did
I ever think about that was fun?
What was fucking fun about waking up
in a police station,
in the back of
a fucking police car?
I have a laugh now,
I mean naturally.
I mean, if I could...if I could
sprinkle this on the fucking world,
it would be a much better place.
I spent 19 years of my life praying
that I would wake up one day
and have the father I have today.
And most people can't turn around
and say that
that has happened for them
and it happened for me.
And I love...
I am so proud of him
because I know how hard it is.
It's fucking fantastic.
Our relationship has improved
over the last few years
since he's been sober.
I'm actually quite
amazed at how much...
how fit he is and how more astute
he is than he was.
He is changed a lot.
He's lost a lot of weight.
He's very health conscious.
He works out nearly every day.
Ozzy has grown up.
You know, it took him longer than
most people, but he's got there.
He's here.
He works really hard for
his sobriety and he deserves it.
'Sobriety has totally changed him
as a person.'
You know, he's just got...
He just seems like he's a lot
more at ease with himself.
Whereas before it was, he was
just kind of all over the place.
But now he'll just sit with his
headphones on quietly, just drawing.
It's not art. I do it
for therapeutic reasons.
I always find it stops my head of
hand grenades going off, you know.
It's, um, it slows my head down.
I've always worried.
Sometimes I worry cos
I've got nothing to worry about.
That's how bad it is sometimes.
I don't go to bed at night thinking,
I shouldn't have painted that
because people will get pissed off
at me and they ain't going
to buy another painting.
It's just something,
out of all this chaos
and all this anxiety that I live in
and all this fear,
stops everything in its tracks
and it's mine.
And so when you ask me a question
about it, I have no answer,
because I don't think of it
anything more than it's mine.
He really talked for years about
wanting to have his driving licence
and never thought
he could do it, you know.
Well, he wouldn't have
been able to do it
in his drinking days obviously.
But since he become sober,
he had talked about it quite a lot
about getting his driving licence.
I'm getting my licence
so I don't feel like
a fucking terminal prisoner,
meaning that when everybody leaves
the house I'm stuck, you know.
Um, I can't go anywhere.
I just want...
It's, it's a way of feeling free,
you know.
I don't depend on everybody to
drive me wherever I want to go.
That's the reason I want
a driving licence.
I'm not intoxicated
and I don't want people to...
I want a part of my life where
I can say, I'm in the car,
driving my car where I want to go
and not be sitting there
having an argument with
someone over some shit.
I just want to get the freedom
of being able to drive
in with my head, you know.
When I first got successful,
right, I bought the...
I bought the guns,
the fucking knives,
the fucking archery sets,
motorcycles.
All the things that
I felt that was... I didn't...
I couldn't afford to have when I was
younger, when I was younger.
So I got all that out of my system.
Now, I've always really wanted
to drive,
but I've been too fucked up
to get there.
So I'm done...
I'm fulfilling all the things that
I wanted to do.
I've had a one of a kind life,
you know.
I mean, I've had a lot of ups
and downs in my life.
But people say if I could change
any one thing, what would I change?
I don't know.
I think everything...everything
is there for a reason, you know.
And life is a learning process.
And I don't know what the fucking,
uh, what the secret of life is.
I don't know the thing.
It's just been...
I've had a good run, you know.
I love my wife, I love my family,
I love my, my...
I'm beginning to love me
a lot more than I ever used to.
It's the first person you should
always learn to love is yourself.
ALL ABOARD!
WILD CHEERING
MUSIC: "Crazy Train"
# Crazy
# But that's how it goes
# Millions of people
# Living as foes
# Maybe
# It's not too late
# To learn how to love
# And forget how to hate. #
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
E-mail subtitling@bbc.co.uk