Korean - Bahasa Indonesia by Yongyongmi22
Instagram; @yongi2201
Bahasa Indonesia - English by : @bbeellyy_  @candyssaem_ @foursky4 @MeeNoFear @tennetamong
QC & editor: @20for_
English Subtitle By Inner Circle
If you are so worried about him, then go and meet him.
- You just have to go and meet him.
- Ah seriously! What's wrong with you again?
Kim Jae Hyuk is okay, right? You have to always stay beside him, what if all those crazies bother him?
Is Kim Jae Hyuk still doing sports? Ah, but his shoulder shouldn't be injured.
Go and meet him by yourself, tell him you love him.
Go meet him, I will introduce you to him. He would definitely remember you.
- I don't want to.
- Why?
I'm shy.
Hello everybody. FM Morning Show. No Hong Chul.
Just one night, and the temperature dropped.
And please mind your outfits, everyone...
But my child, where are you going? To the office? To the shop?
Or to somewhere only you know?
Where is it? Is it the place that you could use to workout?
If that is so, it's really okay.
Everyone, don't get swear at, and don't swear. Enjoy this warm and fun day.
I will play the song 'Bravo' with enthusiasm.
Food!
What are you looking at?
Ah looking at the snow? You must like snow a lot.
- They said if you go hiking, you will meet...
- Because I love ice cream.
- I suddenly want ice cream when I see snow.
- Go to the supermarket, cook noodles, and then ice cream...
If you asked, you can go out and do it.
Jae Hyuk, before doing it, you have to pray first because there are so many psychos there.
But I don't believe in that kind of thing.
Uncles! Food!
Everything is the same in here.
Don't ever eat the seaweed soup...
And don't eat the eggs, too.
Even though you want it, don't ever crack it.
This bastard. Just because he wants to be alright, he is always lost in his own thoughts.
Hey, he was pulled out from here, why did you bring him back?
He doesn't fit in with people like us.
Wait, it's still an honor...
When else could we be together with a superstar?
Hey! Porter!
Hey, where is the half of the chicken soup? Where is it?
Uncle, it's the people in kitchen who did the thing, my role is just to distribute it.
This kid, who do you think you are lying to?
Hey! Do you know who is in this room?
There's a superstar in here! Superstar Kim Jae Hyuk.
Someone who got jailed just because of hitting someone...
Someone who, after beating someone, still managed to look fine.
Oh gosh! This unfair world.
No! Maybe God protects such people in order for them to keep staying in prison.
Oh?
Chicken neck. I'm blessed.
What a positive minded person. Watch and learn.
English Sub by : @bbeellyy_  @candyssaem_ @foursky4 @MeeNoFear @tennetamong
QC & editor: @20for_
Yeay, chicken leg!
Help me!
No!
Mister!
My chicken leg!
[Wise Prison Life]
- You've worked hard.
- Officer Lee must be happy because you are his fan. Congrats!
Don't forget.
- You've worked hard.
- Thank you.
Your wish came true Officer Lee. You got to meet Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk.
I didn't know that you really liked me.
- Shut it.
- Just say it...
- That we are friends.
- Nope.
I'm the one who is going to be tired in the end.
With everyone not knowing about this, I can take care of you more freely.
Cook the noodles.
People in here, though they already got out, they don't contact each other anymore...
That's why don't ever promise to meet up and give them your phone number...
Of course, you aren't that kind of person.
However, it's only a few days left, you have to be careful.
Especially with those people from the death row, they say they're the scariest.
- But before I go, there's a person that I want to greet...
- Who?
- But there's death row in here, too?
- Of course.
Although they used to be separated in the past, they're being put together now.
Those death row prisoners don't have a future. There's no hope, that's why they can do anything, so you have to be careful.
If you meet them, just avoid them, especially the white haired with star tattoo on his hand.
2300, Kim Jae Hyuk.
Turn around.
Right? Even though I came, you aren't happy at all.
I didn't come here because I want to, but because your mother told me to come so I couldn't do anything.
I saw a death row prisoner.
Jiho, I saw a death row prisoner earlier.
- How's the appearance? Must be really scary, right?
- No.
Looked pretty normal.
That's why it's really scary.
2300, Kim Jae Hyuk, turn around.
This place is really weird.
- Like a place for those evil people.
- That's the reason they got jailed, you fool.
A week left, hang in there for just one more week.
But you...
We have broken up, why do you keep coming back here?
Ah, your mother asked me to. I told you a minute ago.
You never pay attention to my words, indeed, it's always you who talks.
What you see, it's not everything.
Package delivery!
Don't trust anything and anyone.
Excuse me.
Drink this.
Oh my, it's okay.
Don't worry too much, this place is still a place for humans.
Only one week left...
Just live as a fool.
Like it used to be. Like usual.
I will check on this package.
Cola, orange juice, milk, citrus juice...
Chopsticks, sun cream, body lotion, and gloves.
Ah right. T-Money Card, this is for Uncle Seagull.
It's free as well today. Whose turn is it today?
I'm Song Se Min
Thank you Athlete Kim. It's an honor to meet you.
Hey, Porter!
Get out.
Hey! Hey!
[T/N: Kkal is a slang word for sword, knife]
'Kkal' is not allowed.
Even if you have 50,000 Won, I can get punished.
And even more.
It's your problem, whether you make it or steal it...
Bring it in tomorrow, understand?
Do you understand or not, you piece of shit?
Go.
- Just one bite.
- No.
This is my first ever package, If you want, I will give it for 7,000 won.
You have money? Didn't you have no money?
Ah, my sister gave me 300,000 won. I bought it with that money.
My donation money. Therefore you shouldn't ask for it too, Professor.
Dinosaur snack, cola, and orange juice, please keep it well.
Because you have to be here for a long time.
I don't need this kind of thing anymore. You can take it.
Why? Because I will get released next week.
No, seems like you can't get out of here..
Ah, you didn't know what happened to this person apparently.
This person is the famous White Money scammer
He counterfeited 50,000 won with a white paper.
He put in salt water into a small bottle and spread it to the white paper...
Then he put the white paper in cold water, and that white paper will turn into 50,000 won.
Yes, he is that great scammer.
What do you mean by scammer?
I'm a magician.
7 Free Stars, it was also a scam.
Kim Jae Hyuk.
Meet me for a minute.
Ah, there's no more of it. I will give all of these to our officers who are on duty.
Can I get one cup of coffee?
Ah, I can give 100 cups if you want.
He wants you to stay here for long...
But is it appropriate to say that?
Ah, Officer Lee said that. Let's meet again next time.
We can't say it these days.
Ah, do you happen to know Lee Joon Ho?
That person has always talked about Kim Jae Hyuk since then.
Not an ordinary fan.
Ah, he is too much.
Ah, seriously... He asked for everything.
Ah What's with him?
That.
- You think wisely.
- Everything is just the same.
T-Money Card works like ATM card here.
This is 100,000 won. But it works as money here.
You must have known about this. Even for one visit and one call only, it's very much impossible.
Because you're still not concerned about this, because you can't fight with just anyone outside
Therefore, even though T-Card is a useless thing outside here...
He can buy everything everyday.
Yes, exchange it with cigarette.
One T-Money Card a pack, means that it's equal to 10,000 to 50,000 won.
That time there was someone who owned a T-Money Card and he could ride the subway.
Doesn't work. Since a long time ago.
Then, what about that?
Got broken, last year.
Oh? It's still recording.
Is it?
Ah, it works fine. We can see it clearly.
What do you mean? I could only see one person.
Between the wall and 30cm from the chair, you couldn't see anything beyond that point anymore.
I got this information from one person 3 years ago, how could he know about it?
Really awesome. As expected, someone who is hard to beat.
I will check on something.
Everything could be seen.
- This is the reason why he is the chief.
- What Chief, he is just a gangster.
I'm leaving.
But Sir...
This place seems to be more and more out of reach. Want me to connect you with my journalist contacts?
Kim Jae Hyuk hit someone, but why is there not a single article?
Tell everyone that Superstar is scary.
Isn't that how it's supposed to be?
Hey, let's talk...
Just for a while.
I'll shut you up a little.
Do I look easy to you?
Hey, asshole. Pretentious garbage.
People's patience doesn't last forever.
That's why you should finish your fucking prison term well.
I'm leaving.
I used to have a religion when I was in school.
I went to the temple with you yesterday, remember?
I don't go there at random. I've only been there twice, and during those two, I pondered hardly before I went.
Especially sometimes the Catholics and Buddhists give milk bread and varieties of candies, if we come and visit.
The timing and venue are really more important than anything.
In church there's hymnal and it's perfect when I want to shout.
But, Jae Hyuk...
Excuse me, Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk.
Tennis ball. I'm embarrassed to give it earlier, so I held on to it first.
You can use it until your release.
Hey! Porter!
Give me the fucking knife. Knife.
Because of this, there is no reason for me not to hit you.
Hey, look directly into my eyes.
This is the last warning, work properly.
If you come emptyhanded again tomorrow, I will stab you with that knife. Understand?
Do you understand?
Hey! What's happening there?
Sports time's up!
- It's cold today, are you alright?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- Thanks for caring about me.
- Ah it's okay, this is the Chief's special order.
We're the one who feel guilty because we can't allow you to do sports more than 30 minutes.
Wanna change?
Screaming makes you feel better.
Hey Swindler, are you really going out?
I'll bid goodbye first -- in the future, you have to live your life better.
This place isn't a nice place for people to live in.
- You swindled a lot of people, how can you go out this soon?
- What do you mean by how?
If you can go in, you can go out too.
Athlete Kim will be out soon too. Is the date same with mine?
- Ah.
- Dong Ho .
Ah, now...
Ah, Kim Jae Hyuk's time is coming to a close.
Who would know the verdict later on.
Isn't it too quiet today?
It's like something huge is about to happen.
Chief, Chief! There is an emergency patient.
Send help, quick!
Room 7HA5, there's an emergency patient.
Hey, hang on. You can still breathe, can't you?
- Dong Ho! Dong Ho!
- There's an emergency patient here!
Ah what are you doing?! You didn't call for an ambulance?
Attention! Please dispatch...
Hang on. Dong Ho. You're going to be alright.
- What do you call 119 for?
- Ah you didn't call for an ambulance?
I said call an ambulance!
- Start counting. One.
- Chief!
What are you guys doing?
Chief.
Please call the ambulance.
Two...
Dong Ho.
Three...
- I'm fine.
- Really?
- It got better really quickly.
- Thank God.
Dolmaeng, your acting skills got better.
This time you almost got me.
Chief, how did you find out?
Only idiots think that the heart is on the right side.
Remember that, Officer Choi.
He wants to go out so bad. To smell the fresh air and see the ladies.
And drive huge cars.
- That was just acting?
- Yes, but Chief Jo can tell with just one look.
Because I panicked so much, I couldn't think straight.
In the military, there will always be people like that.
I'm not envious at all.
My brother came. I'll be back soon.
Ah, this kid, really...
- He will be freed, right?
- Of course he will.
- Should I use this?
- Quit it.
Should I take it off?
Have you eaten?
How was your sleep?
Father, I will really be freed, right?
Of course, just wait a bit.
You will use Lawyer Kim Hae Chan, right?
Don't worry, your mother is seeing him today.
- Thank God. The people here hit me...
- Oh?
Kim Jae Hyuk. That's athlete Kim Jae Hyuk.
Please, just act normally, please.
Seriously, I don't even know why he's wearing this.
What are you doing? Come on, greet him quickly, it's your idol.
Hello.
I am... Lee Joon Ho... My brother... My brother is Lee Joon Ho...
I am his younger brother, Lee Joon Dol.
You really look like a fool.
I think I saw you when I was in middle school.
In your house.
Right, that was with me. There was him too.
You're good looking.
Hey, he used to be fine, he became like this when he started liking you.
You're a university student now?
How can you call a kid like this a university student?
Tell him your actual work.
In order to create a brighter and more harmonious society...
- Forget it. My brother...
- Officer Lee.
The Chief said to return soon.
You two go ahead and talk.
My kindhearted brother, there are only several minutes left.
I don't know when else I can meet him, please add just a little bit more time.
He'll come out in two days, just meet him directly then, or go to a sauna together.
- You have time, right?
- Of course.
Ah, today we have a special event. You have to come.
You can shout all you want there. You know that, right?
Indeed, it's nice there...
But it's also loud.
What do you do?
- I'll be back soon.
- Where to?
- To the office, it's my turn to clean up today.
I'll be the one going. Please rest.
Today's activity is to teach you how to beg for salvation.
from hurting your friend's heart, or...
when you don't recognize God's grace and kindness.
It is hard to have a heart that easily forgives.
But Jesus,
- He is forgiving, even for repeating sinners.
- Jae Hyuk, there are a few days left now.
You just might receive an innocent verdict during the trial,
but there might also be a problem in court. If so, just plead guilty.
But, Jae Hyuk...
You've worked hard.
Huge problem.
Uncle...
- Uncle Seagull..
- What? You surprised me.
What?
This kid is quite good. No one saw you, right?
Let's sing!
Let's finish it.
How stupid.
Ah, why hasn't he arrived yet?
I was planning to make a nice scene...
Ah, you shouldn't have gone this far.
- You're my favorite person.
- Me too...
But since it's almost time to go home, you have to go back now.
Looks like our friend Porter won't be eating dinner.
In life, there will always be that kind of moment.
Where have you been, Athlete Kim? We don't really have that much time left together.
What are you doing? Why didn't you enter straightaway?
They say today's dinner is Donkatsu, I can finally taste such dish here.
Have I finally held this knife after so long?
Quick, sit down.
Search! Alley seven!
Search!
Search and make sure you don't miss anything!
You there! Out!
Check everything meticulously from the head to toe!
One won't know when it'll be conducted, this is an activity done since last year.
If they find you out, you'll receive punishment 30 times as hard. It's as if you wished for a death row.
Since you'll be out in two days, you'll surely get away with this.
Anyhow, what a perfect timing.
Isn't it as if someone tipped that Seagull has a knife with him?
That's impossible. The officers and other prisoners wouldn't have known.
That's just because Seagull has a very bad luck.
By the way, this Donkatsu... why are we always short of it?
Of course, no one would give me more even if I ask for more, right?
Uncles...
Do you want me to add more Donkatsu?
Thank you.
Don't mention it. Compared to you who saved me from getting fired, this is really nothing.
But how did you know?
Aside from the Chief, no one else knows that schedule.
I saw it in Officer Choi's calendar.
Excuse me, but, may I have just a cup of coffee?
I'd even give you a hundred if you ask. Please wait a moment.
[Inspection]
Wait a minute.
There's nothing else I can say. Thank you for helping me out.
- Because I...
- I didn't do it because of you.
Hey!
Hey, Kim Jae Hyuk!
2300, Kim Jae Hyuk.
Come out.
- I need to sleep.
- I told you to stop making a fuss, didn't I?
Finish one thing at a time. Don't you have any goals?
How did you know about the inspection ?
I saw it when I signed a paper in the officer's room.
Did Porter look sad?
You helped him because Seagull harassed him, didn't you?
Porter, that person is as sly as anybody else, he's honestly nothing different.
That is true. Why don't you know people's personality?
Please, just shut up. Why are you suddenly so bothered by other people's business?
I did. That's not because of him.
I wanted to be like that, too.
I want to live peacefully to the point that I don't have to say anything.
But how am I supposed to stay still and not saying anything?
- Why couldn't you?
- Because he is a rapist.
Seagull, he's a rapist.
How could I stay still? How am I supposed to stay still, goddamn it?!
If I think of my sister.
That kind of person...
I'll definitely kill him.
[Kal Dae Bong; Rape.]
One more day left.
Tomorrow...
is the most important day in my life.
Please bear with it just one more day.
Okay.
Officer, Porter! There's a dead body here!
- Officer!
- Hey, Please breathe! Dong Ho!
- Officer, over! There's a patient who stopped breathing here, over. - Dong Ho.
Attention, we request for help. There's an unconscious patient over here. We need help.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know what's happening too, but please don't call the ambulance yet.
One...
Two...
What's this? Is this kid for real?
Dong Ho, Wake up, Damn it!
Dong Ho! Damn it.
Hey, call the ambulance, and wait in the waiting room. Do it now!!
Hey, hey, Dong Ho, wake up!
What are you doing? Please open this, now.
Hey! Dong Ho!
Hey!
Hey, Damn it! Don't joke around! You have to wake up soon!
You crazy bastard!
What are you doing? Carry him, hurry!
Get out of my way!
Ah, I got goosebumps.
Half of the month passed by already..
Don't you guys feel like this month passed by too quickly?
No.
The days feel slow and long.
Have you done something good and met someone nice today?
I mean, What's the point of being nice person?
To each of his own, but I think the good side of being nice depends on ourselves..
Officer Lee isn't home yet.
Ah, I thought of going home now.
People's judgment isn't really important
Respect those you see every day and those who are always there for you.
Prejudice and stereotype,
These two words are among many that they hate the most.
The closing song today...
Toi song - Good Person.
Chief Jo, here.
Thank you, Officer Lee.
You've worked hard today.
We all worked hard.
I almost beat him while I'm on my duty.
He added so much unfortunate things in my life.
Officer Lee, remember this.
Don't avoid problems and don't trust people easily especially those you meet on duty.
Because all of those are just excuses.
Officer Lee, I always give the same advice to people I care for like my own brother.
Ah, the coffee is sweet.
Officer Lee, the more I see it, you seem like a nice person.
Oh? You worked overtime last night.
I have to work hard.
Of course.
Because today is Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk's last day, you must want to see him.
- Law Man is here, isn't he?
- Ah, he is.
He's there.
But whatever happens, you have to take care of this. Because you are not allowed to wear other outfits.
I will wash the clothes and prepare food for you, you can wear this.
Hey, Law Man.
You're free, go pack your stuffs.
- Are you doing something? Go follow me.
- But...
- May I ask for a little more time please?
- What bullshit is that? There's no time left, go follow me.
Hey!
That... But Jae Hyuk...
Thank... you.
Ah, Jae Hyuk... thank you very much.
My mother is still alive thanks to you.
Honestly I...
I am scared I could actually lose my mother.
If my mother ever leaves this world...
My life will fall apart.
I don't think I will ever have the desire to be alive as well.
Jae Hyuk, I really thank you.
I.. I really need to go this time, no...
I really want to go.
In my entire life...
I never said thank you for a long time.
And... in my entire life...
I have never received such help and support.
My heart is really breaking into pieces...
I don't know how to explain this feeling.
What I have said, I really feel sorry...
I will be with you forever from now on.
Hey!
Jae Hyuk...
You have to win...
You should join the Major League and succeed there.
Thank you.
I put something on the window.
That's my gift for you.
There are many concerns directed to the ongoing trial after the abuse case of Kim Jae Hyuk...
Tomorrow, at 11 am, there will be a second trial for Professional Baseball athlete Kim Jae Hyuk...
Last January, he was sentenced for one year in prison by the court, and caused some unending controversies.
In the second trial, we will see the progress that the court will be presenting...
Oh, Reporter Choi. Of course, I have completed all of it.
Only the insiders and court officers will be able to see this
That's why, send this tomorrow morning.
What?
Ah, What do you mean with that...
You've done your best. You've worked hard...
See you soon.
We finally see that tunnel, that means we're a bit closer.
It's cloudy, it looks like it's gonna rain.
People said that rain right before a trial is a bad sign. We really need to be careful when we arrive there.
- Thank you.
- Good Luck, Kim Jae Hyuk.
He's here!
Kim Jae Hyuk-ssi, do you accept all of those charges?
- Kim Jae Hyuk, do you have your own proof?
- What do you think about that, Mr. Kim Jae Hyuk?
Mr. Kim Jae Hyuk, your statement please.
- Please give us your statement.
- Mr. Kim Jae Hyuk.
Today at 11, Kim Jae Hyuk trial has started...
Are we going to see the same result today, after seeing the victim's condition?
Because Kim Jae Hyuk's lawyers are very confident, people are all waiting to hear what they have wished all this time.
Damn it, we still need to see the result?
I'm going to destroy their trial if they don't have the results.
- Why is it not out yet?
- I heard he couldn't sleep last night.
Don't you think he look the same?
Why wouldn't he enter the room already?
Everybody please stand up.
We are going to start the trial for suspect number 2017/187.
First, suspect Kim Jae Hyuk,
He ran for the person who raped his sister, then he beat that person defending both of him and his sister.
But he didn't stop at that, he kept chasing his victim.
The main issue here, he beat him with fatal means, which was a trophy.
And because of that, the victim is now in a critical condition...
He did intensive treatment but now he suffers from extreme brain death.
Because of Kim Jae Hyuk's severe rage and violence, the victim is requesting to do some evaluation and postpone the trial today.
In the end, this self defense is regarded exceeding the limit itself.
Because he is already doing his punishment, an appeal against his sentence would not be considered.
Meanwhile, the Korean Baseball committee announced that there will be an immediate meeting between KBO Baseball association and...
Fans are no different.
Kim Jae Hyuk's fans who plead him free of charge were all shocked.
Boston side were expressing their disappointment while waiting for the results of the trial and
Nexen Heroes is not even able to predict what's going to happen.
How can I meet Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk now?
But Professor Myung isn't going back, right?
Yes, You're right.
So what's actually the reason of this all?
People who did fraud to others for almost 7 million won can easily be freed from prison, but a person who literally saved her sister from a rapist couldn't.
I really don't know how this world works.
Only those who have power will be able to live peacefully.
Why is Officer Lee not back yet? I need to do the shift.
He has a separate room, until we're done with the prison cleaning, I have prepared a different room for you.
No worries, Officer. I don't want to make you busy, I am fine with the previous room I used to have.
Okay then, if you need something, please let me know.
So compared to other prisoners, don't you think we should treat Athlete Kim with special treatment?
If so...
- May I ask for help? I promise only this time..
- What's that? Sure.
- I haven't done my exercise today, can I do some exercise?
- Exercise?
Of course.
- Thank you.
- Ah but...
It's....
That kid, what is he doing now...
- I'm fine.
- I'm not fine.
Let's go.
- Change your clothes with mine and go out...
- And...
Killing a person?
After running away, who should I kill?
Shall I kill the judge?
Or shall I kill that brain-dead person?
My life is a mess now, who should I blame?
It's okay.
Finally I have time to rest in my life.
But is that published in the news?
All day long.
- The news about you was published all day long.
- Not my news.
Reporter Choi, why didn't you receive my call?
Ah damn...
His number is active...
Oh?
A private room.
Oh, you look so happy.
Nice.
I like it.
Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk that got sentenced in Seoul Western District Prison for attacking a man will be in trial today.
Even though suspicions raised up, his sentence has been upgraded to one year in prison.
Published all day, all day. Here and there.
Hey, don't turn it off!
Hey, don't turn it off! This man, news reports should be watched until end.
Why are you coming just now?
Sorry.
Moreover, just like his popularity, this prison is being the center of interest now.
Based on the officer, there are no special treatments for him, just like other prisoners.
Hey, Officer Lee. Come here and let's watch together. There's an interesting news coming out.
The continuation of the revealing case in public service...
The officer with a job that to serve prisoners, it was revealed that he is illegally giving them supplies.
Our KBC staff is preparing for further information.
This is the CCTV footage from Western Prison a while ago.
This video shows how he swaps cigarette with a T-Money card as their money in prison.
That's the T-Money card that we can buy easily.
That officer gives cigarette to the prisoners and in exchange, they have to give him a T-Money card.
Shouldn't that be the camera's blind spot? What happened?
Someone must have fixed it already.
Alright, take some rest! Will there be a ghost attaching your body if you don't work out?
Hey, I have this.
Hey, where did you get this from? If you bring this, you'll get in trouble.
- Give it to me!
- No! The situation is not good now!
Hold on for a little bit, I'll give it to you in two days.
Okay.
Alright, I'll throw it once. Just once.
Where will you throw it?
Outside? You'll just throw it carelessly?
Really?
So...
I'll let you see how my pitch used to be.
I failed.
Ah, what a crazy person.
The officer that's been caught on camera won't be able to avoid the penalty for three days, and this case has been sent to the court.
Meanwhile that officer was also caught doing the same thing to the prisoners' family.
Ah, it's okay.
Don't worry, this is a place for people to live, too.
I'll keep it well.
Even though I've thought to keep it well.
The salary for an officer here is certain already.
Even though your heart wanted to do something good, in fact you can't do anything.
Besides, it's almost winter. I want to give something. But still everything is all about money.
Ah, I forgot to bring cash.
- Excuse me, where's the place to take money?
- Over there.
Please take care of my child for a little bit.
Please don't worry, just go. I'll be waiting for you here.
Let go.
How could the reporters know about that?
I'm not sure...
Isn't he a prison guard?
The citizens are demanding countermeasures and prevention so this action will not happen again.
Lee Joon Dol from KBC reporting from South Detention Center.
Ah, what's your job?
I'm a reporter.
I'm a daily reporter.
Field reporter.
May I give you a present?
Jae Hyuk.
Don't worry.
You're gonna win the trial.
Because justice still exists.
One day, maybe if God gives His hand, and we'll met again coincidentally...
At that time, I'll buy you the most expensive ice cream.
For now, this is my only treasure.
I'm fine.
Please tell Mother and Je Hee, that I'll move away, so they don't need to come here.
Because probably it would be unavailing.
I've also thought about several things.
Maybe I couldn't come out from here...
...I also thought about that.
I am fine.
Seriously.
Really?
Are you sure that you're fine?
I said, are you sure that you're fine?
You can end up rotting in jail for one year, and if that's the case, will it be fine?
You already signed contract with the Major, is it still fine?
I said, are you sure that you're fine?
Ah, it sucks!
Ah it sucks, damn it!
I'm home.
Is my son doing okay?
- I'm sure his heart is aching.
- His face and expression was fine.
It's better than I thought.
You know what kind of person he is.
- You sure?
- Of course.
He is just like what I thought.
I think he's doing better now.
Then, please don't worry too much.
Don't go visit him too often. School will start soon.
It's okay, after all I'm happy to go there.
Mother, living in Seoul is not that bad right? Although there's not much good restaurants compared to Gwangju, but people still live well.
Living with Je Hee is also fine, so we can eat home made food everyday.
Ah please say something, I'm really worried.
I already told you, he's doing fine.
You know his personality, too.
He is really fine, he is just worried about you.
Ah really, just live with him then.
I also want to have a brother who can be trusted like that.
Ah that's not what I meant. Jae Hee, he is truly fine, he is okay.
Ah, I already said to you, he is like a bear, I bet he already forgot the incident.
Ah, Jae Hee.
In a time like this, it would be good to go outside, right?
I thought that he would lose hope and spirit. If I were him, I would be like that, but Kim Jae Hyuk is different for sure...
...he is just doing his usual daily things, he exercised and practiced.
If so, then just get prepared, eat and then shower, get ready to work.
You're sure he's alright?
- Absolutely. He's fine. Don't you know who Kim Jae Hyuk is?
- A man who never gives up.
In 2005...
He got into an accident and his shoulder got broken.
Other people will think that life, everything is already ending, but..
It was like he died and was brought back to life.
He truly is.. whether it is rain or snow that pours, he kept doing his exercise and treatments straightaway.
And after that, three years later in 2008...
Finally he joined the rest of the Heroes team...
It doesn't make sense, as if it was just like a war.
Although there were a lot a great athletes, and he was standing in the last position...
He won over more than those 10 great athletes...
And after that the world held back on him, but...
The most important thing is that between those failures and trials, he was never disappointed and blamed himself...
Although my life has several events which ached my heart, but my body never got hurt...
The man who always smiled with confidence even during difficulties, is Kim Jae Hyuk.
- Even if the country cursed on him, he'll stay fine. Like that?
- Kim Jae Hyuk is the wisest person ever, different from you, you're someone worthless.
Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk, today there's an event at the church. You won't come, will you?
- You can just stay in the room.
- But I'll go there.
Dear my beloved family...
Jesus will keep you in His blessing if you want to live with kindness.
- Amen.
Alright, and next...
We will sing our pride song, number 338, together.
Today, a band from University of Cheonwon will accompany us all.
You fucker!
Fuck!!!
You fucker! Are you fucking satisfied?!
You fucker!!!
Kim Jae Hyuk is really pitiful, what to do about this?
What else can we do? We can just visit him often.
But until when is he going to stay here?
- He must be going out soon, right?
- Hey, even us know nothing about our punishment, nor about his.
If only he was here right now, then we will know certainly.
Even the sudden inspection, he already knew that beforehand, and maybe things related to himself, he must know it already.
What do you mean?
The truth about why Seagull get punished...
Kim Jae Hyuk is the one who snitched about it.
He told me first, I matched the timing and successfully got away.
- Ah, damn, justice still exists.
- Really?
Wow, amazing. How did he know about it?
Athlete Kim Jae Hyuk...
Today one person will come...
Just rest.
Is your body okay?
You, die!
[Preview]
OST :
Kang Seungyoon & Song Minho (Prod by Zico) - Door