In the old times, when my
grandfather was alive,
our country was weak, and
we once lost our country...
to our neighbor, Japan.
At that time, there were people
who were trying to get it back.
And General Baek San was their leader.
At that time, there were also bad
people who stayed close to Japan...
and took all the national treasure.
- At that moment...
- At that moment,
General Baek San and his men
appeared in front of him,
took all those treasures back,
and hid them in a remote area...
deep in the woods.
General Baek San recorded
the location of...
those treasures in three different maps.
However, one betrayer,
who wanted to take...
those treasures for himself
killed General Baek San.
However, the maps weren't found,
and the treasures got hidden forever.
Hey! Open the door! It's the police!
Open it! Hey!
Hey! Open the door.
Where is the gold?
He ran away this way.
What?
Hey!
Stop!
- Gosh.
- Hey!
Oh no.
Go away.
- You jerk.
- I didn't do anything.
I didn't do anything. Let go of me.
- Let go of me!
- I got you.
Mr. Cheon In Moon.
I bet you've been through a lot.
Let me just ask you...
a few questions.
Make yourself comfortable.
Just relax.
Mr. Cheon In Moon.
I know that you were taking care of...
the gold Cheonmun defrauded.
Where is the gold now?
Did your colleagues run away with the gold?
- Who are they?
- I don't know.
I'd like to resolve things...
with a decent conversation.
It wouldn't be good for you to piss me off.
Look at my face. I'm not a nice person.
But I really don't know anything.
We didn't even exchange names.
I'm serious.
Then...
who were the men waiting outside the door?
- Oh, those men?
- Yes.
They hired us.
I don't know who they are.
You jerk, if I ask you
something, you should answer it.
Well, I just...
went there because I heard
I'd get paid a lot.
I'm serious.
You're late.
- Yes.
- Why would they let you work...
until late without paying you?
- Where are the kids?
- They are in Min Jae's room.
I guess Dol Mok has a slight cold.
He went to bed early.
You're studying.
He doesn't have a fever. I think he's okay.
Okay. That's a relief.
By the way, Dad, someone came
to our house earlier today.
Who was it?
He said he is the father
of Dol Mok's friend,
but he seemed a little strange.
He was trying to find out if
Dol Mok and I are brothers.
So what did you tell him?
Did you tell him the truth?
No. Why would I say that to a stranger?
And he asked me if I knew...
a man named Baek San.
Do you know who he is?
No.
I don't know him.
Dad, what's wrong?
I said I don't know.
What are you talking about?
I let you take care of it
as you sounded so sure.
Now that you lost the
person and the evidence,
there's no way to attack the tycoon.
Say no more.
Just find the evidence.
Otherwise, you'll be finished.
What are you doing, Seong Il?
Just confess the truth or you will be dead.
You are a cop. How can you do this to me?
- I'll sue you for assault.
- Assault?
All right. I'll show you
how it's done. Look.
Watch. Watch me.
This is assault.
Hey, you just hit me.
You're a suspect who hit a cop.
I just hit you in self-defense.
So tell me. Who took the gold? Say it!
Stop it.
You jerk, I need to find evidence.
I have to put Chairman Hong in prison.
Do you know what I've been
through in front of So Joo?
My daughter cried a lot.
- Stop it.
- I have to catch that scumbag.
I need the evidence. Who took it?
Who took the gold?
I really don't know anything.
You jerk! Tell me the truth!
You jerk!
My daughter cried a lot
because of that scumbag!
What's wrong with you?
What?
You keep tossing and turning
without falling asleep.
I'm trying to sleep.
(Chuncheon Police Station)
Is this an interrogation room or an inn?
I'm sorry. I was just
thinking about something.
So did you...
So Joo!
Go wash up and change your underwear.
It shows all over your face
that you're a widower.
Dol Mok, how's your head feeling?
I'm okay.
Min Jae, you should hurry.
You're on duty today.
I have enough time.
Well, can we move out?
I don't think I'll get
paid in this company.
I think I should find another job.
I guess things would be better in Seoul.
What are you talking about now?
What about their school?
They can move to another school.
Stop talking nonsense
and just eat your meal.
You've worked hard for more than
two months. You have to get paid.
We are not going anywhere.
Will you move out after I get paid?
You're being ridiculous.
Things have just settled for my tofu
business. Why would you say that?
Gosh.
I'm going to school.
Why don't you finish your meal?
Gosh.
Dol Mok, eat up.
What's so funny?
That's my food. Why is he eating my food?
Hey, just wait.
Please help yourself.
You must be tired and hungry...
as you were harassed by Dad all night.
Can I really eat this?
You should eat some food and
keep your energies high.
Okay.
What's wrong with you?
I have a daughter.
She's the apple of my eye just like you.
She must be staying with
her old grandmother.
I wonder if she's eating well.
I don't want to eat alone
when Dad doesn't come home.
My daughter is only four years old.
She must miss her dad so much.
I always hung around with Dad at her age.
Can't you just come clean...
and go home?
How can I do that?
They must have started the job...
just to feed their young children.
One of the guys I worked with has two sons,
but he didn't get paid for a few months.
His family is about to starve to death.
But why did you do that when you have...
the skills to make gold?
You mean goldsmith?
When I was in the prison,
I learned the skill,
so I can live well when I get out.
But who would hire...
ex-convicts like us?
Even normal people get sacked.
Eat some meat.
My dad made it, and he's
a really good cook.
You interrogated him all night
and failed to get anything.
And she managed to do it so easily.
She's so amazing.
Who do you think she got it from?
You go and get a list of people
who learned goldsmith...
in the prison.
And narrow the list down to
people with a newborn...
and people who have two sons.
Okay.
I should make her a prosecutor.
Or should I make her a judge?
Did you get into trouble again?
What are you talking about?
I know you.
You didn't sleep at all last night,
and you suddenly suggested that we move.
You've been sighing deeply like
a steamer releasing steam.
Fess up. What did you do?
It's nothing.
Did you steal again?
I didn't.
So just tell me what you did.
Don't you dare think about lying to me.
Tell me right now.
Wait for me.
I said, wait for me.
Why are you going to school so early?
You have to stay in the classroom alone.
But I want to go to school with you.
You should help mom.
I loved it when you held
my hand the other day.
Min Jae.
You rascal.
I really like you.
I really, really like you.
Catch me if you can.
I caught you.
So...
all of these happened...
because I told you to
file that application.
I started everything because I
wanted to raise Min Jae well.
While I was trying to protect Min Jae,
my friend died,
and his wife died as well.
It all happened because I exposed him.
My goodness.
Goodness gracious.
How can this be?
How could you...
keep that to yourself...
and not say a word about it all this time?
They threatened to kill...
everyone in our family if this gets out.
They killed the innocent history teacher...
and turned him into a drug offender.
I can't deal with them.
Even so, you should've told me earlier.
You should've told me.
What good would it have done if you knew?
It was better for me to
take all the burden.
Still, if you told me earlier,
I wouldn't have treated Dol Mok so badly.
His parents were sacrificed
instead of Min Jae.
Because of us,
he lost his father...
as well as his mother.
I owe my life to him.
What do I do?
The problem is...
that they seem to be suspecting me.
They recently visited the town.
Is that...
Is that why...
you suggested that we move?
Ha Kyung,
I...
I will give you a comfortable life.
Let's leave this place.
I have to protect Dol Mok.
Otherwise,
when I die,
I can't face my friend.
Poor Dol Mok.
I'm back.
Hey.
Did you find out anything?
There is only one prison
that teaches the goldwork.
Among the ones who got
discharged from that prison,
there is one man with a newborn daughter,
and there are 3 men with 2 sons.
Investigate that man with
a newborn daughter first.
Okay.
Ta-da. This is a reward for So Joo.
You like corn dogs, don't you?
Wow! You are the best!
- Enjoy it. Bye.
- Okay.
Let's see. Let's see who the suspect is.
Choi Bu Seo.
Lee Jong Yeol.
Jang Pan Soo.
(Family members)
Dol Mok? Dol Mok?
Dol Mok? Jang Dol Mok?
Can you see through papers now?
How did you know it was Jang Dol Mok?
Are you stupid? You saw him
at the hospital yesterday.
He's the one who went to
the gold mine with me.
Who is Jang Dol Mok?
It's him.
Who is Dol Mok?
It's me.
Dad, I think Dol Mok is...
the kid you were looking for a while ago.
What was his name?
Who are you talking about?
The boy I met in the hospital.
The boy who got gas poisoning.
- Soo Yeon.
- Right.
It's him for sure. I remember it clearly.
I once gave him a candy and a corn dog.
He said the same thing he told me then.
You can give it to me.
Are you Mr. Jang Pan Soo?
No.
You have to bring a power of
attorney if you're not him.
Didn't you get a call from
Prosecutor Yoon Joong Tae...
from Chuncheon District
Prosecutors' Office?
Oh, right.
So that's you. I am sorry.
Will you wait over there?
Where is it?
Where is it? Dobong-ri.
Dobong-ri.
Gosh!
What are you doing?
What is it again? What's wrong?
Didn't you see that this area is
strictly permitted to the staffs?
Stop it. Get out.
What do you want now?
Gosh...
I am sorry for making you wait long.
All the records will be computerized
by next year, and it will be faster.
- Give it to me.
- Here.
Settle down.
Dol Mok.
You don't need to take the
afternoon classes. Go home.
- Why?
- I don't know.
It seems like something
came up in your house.
Go.
He is registered as his son
in the family register.
Yes.
Soo Yeon, aren't you hungry?
I am not a bad person.
I will look into it.
Dad.
I remember that man.
He came to the hospital,
and he even came to our house.
Right?
Did he see you?
No.
He came for me, right?
Why is he following me?
He's trying to take you.
Why would he take me?
Who is he?
He is...
After your mother died,
I think your mom's side of the family...
came to take you away.
Right now,
I have your mom and your brother.
Do you want to go with him?
No, I'm scared of him.
I am going to live with you no matter what.
I'll live with my brother and mom too.
Really? Then...
you can't say your old name.
You were never Soo Yeon.
Your name is Jang Dol Mok no matter what.
Do you understand?
And if you ever meet him again,
you have to pretend that it's
your first time seeing him.
He only saw you when you were young.
He wouldn't be able to recognize you...
if he sees you all grown up like this.
If you look scared just like before,
he will realize you're Soo Yeon.
You understand what I'm saying, right?
Yes. But why are you at school?
My teacher told me to go home early today.
Did something happen at home?
Should we talk about that on our way home?
Okay.
All right.
I heard Jang Dol Mok is Min
Jae's younger brother.
- You didn't know?
- Oh, really?
Then was I mistaken?
I always thought Min Jae was an only child.
Well, it's been a long time
since I taught Min Jae.
I might have not remembered correctly.
(Certified copy of Jang Dol
Mok's family registry)
According to his family registry,
he is Jang Pan Soo's biological son.
Yes, he is.
But something doesn't feel right.
The school teacher seemed confused.
I went to his old neighborhood,
but some people thought Min
Jae was an only child.
Well, since it's such a remote area,
they didn't know about him in depth.
(Certified copy of Jang Dol
Mok's family registry)
Gosh, this is good.
What's up?
How important of a guy is he?
Even the prosecution contacted the office.
How can you ask me to get a copy...
of certified family registry
without any reference?
You know this...
This is illegal, Seong Il.
I put up with this job...
although the pay is so little...
because I want to get that
pension when I get old.
That's why.
If something goes wrong, I'll lose my job.
- What are you going to do?
- I know that.
Goodness. Is this how
you're going to play this?
You're not going to give me anything?
Hey, I'm buying you a meal...
- and I gave you some money before.
- That wasn't much.
Are you serious?
You're so petty.
I don't want you to get hurt.
I knew you would deflect my question.
(Date of birth: May 14, 1989
Date of registry: May 28, 1992)
Gosh.
Hey, Dol Mok!
Isn't that rice wine?
No. It was just overflowing.
Why are you here?
What do you mean, you dummy?
I'm here to see you.
Why?
I didn't get to thank
you for the other day.
You don't need to.
- Is Hwa Young well?
- Yes.
- You like Hwa Young, don't you?
- No, I don't.
Don't lie. You're getting red.
It's because I drank the rice wine.
There's no need to be embarrassed.
Every boy in our school
likes Hwa Young too.
She's pretty.
I don't like her. I'm going.
Hold on.
Wasn't your name Soo Yeon before?
What are you talking about?
Why did you roar like a tiger
when you gave me that corn dog?
I didn't want you to cry.
That's what my dad told
me when I was young.
You're talking nonsense.
Can I visit your house
some time in the future?
You won't be able to.
We are going to move anyway.
It was nice meeting you. Bye.
You're going to move?
Min Jae, you have luck with food.
Come in. Sit and have some meat.
What is all this?
We are having a party.
- A party?
- Yes. I got a job in Seoul.
We're going to move to Seoul.
Min Jae, we are moving to Seoul.
It's such a big city. There
are a lot of cars too.
Did you not understand me?
Stop investigating that case.
Sir, this isn't just an ordinary case.
Someone scammed the whole country.
This is a big case.
If this happens the right way,
your career will take off.
So is that why you beat up a
suspect without an evidence?
Well, that's history.
I'm so close to getting that evidence.
I can almost taste it.
Don't make a big deal out of this.
Stop investigating when I tell you.
Where is this coming from?
- They paid you off, didn't they?
- You jerk.
Do you think I'm like you?
Don't lose your job by
making a fuss out of this.
Don't start something you can't handle.
Understood?
I think Cheonmun Group must
have gotten a wind of this.
Where is the evidence?
We'll catch them soon since the
suspect has been narrowed to two.
You should only take care
of that, Detective Kang.
I will be in charge of
handling Cheonmun Group.
- Here.
- There you go.
This is so tasty. Hey.
Min Jae. Here.
You ought to learn how
to drink from your dad.
Drink it up.
Why are you looking at me?
It's from your dad.
What?
Hey!
- How does it taste?
- It's sweet and delicious.
It's even tastier with the meat.
It's been so long since we had meat.
Gosh, Dol Mok...
will be good at drinking now.
Min Jae.
All of us should drink it up.
Let's get this started!
Gosh.
Gosh, you're good at drinking too.
Now you are a man. Okay?
Hey, get up.
Get up and follow me.
Get up.
Hey.
We are going to have at it like a man.
Did you get that?
- Come at me.
- I won't go easy on you.
There's no point regretting it later.
Gosh.
Hey, do you call yourselves men?
How can men talk so much? You punks.
Come here.
This feels great.
Who.
- Would know - Would know.
- A man's - A man's.
- Crying heart?
- His pure love - His pure love.
- Is shaken - Is shaken.
- By the wind - By the wind.
- His love is like the reed.
Everyone is trying to collect
gold to save our country.
I also thought hard about this.
Darn it.
I thought our country comes first
even if I starve to death.
I went out with the wedding
ring your father gave me.
But this turned out to be fake.
Don't laugh, Dol Mok.
I lived my life for 15 years
believing that this was real gold.
Mom, I will buy you...
a better ring later.
So will I.
I will buy you a diamond ring.
Sure.
To me,
this gold-plated ring is more precious...
than any treasure in this world.
I know too well that...
your dad worked on the construction
site for days to buy this.
My memory for this ring is
the value of this ring.
You understand what I'm saying, right?
The material of the ring
isn't of importance.
Blood isn't of importance too.
You are...
my son whom I bore with my heart.
Understood?
Later,
when your dad and I no
longer live in this world,
your family will be only you and Dol Mok.
You two should take care
and cover for each other.
Okay?
What matters the most is...
that you two share the same memories.
Just like your father and
me living together...
and caring for each other
through thick and thin,
you also will build a strong bond.
This is...
a gift I give you guys.
You should keep what I said in
mind for the rest of your lives.
Okay?
Goodness.
My little sons.
You're my dear sons.
I would envy nobody!
My dear sons.
(Cheonmun Department Store)
What brings you here?
I'm Prosecutor Yoon Joong Tae from
Chuncheon Prosecutors' Office.
On the charges of embezzlement,
special larceny, and malpractice,
a search and seizure warrant for
your department was issued.
You may begin.
Have I...
ever made you upset?
What is this without notice?
This isn't a personal matter...
between me and you.
You committed a crime that
can never be forgiven.
Listen.
You know how harsh the
time is for companies.
All the large companies
have gone to the wall.
I had no choice...
in order to survive.
Is that why...
you siphoned off...
the wedding rings and baby rings
people donated for the country?
Didn't your conscience
feel the tiniest prick?
Don't be so naive.
Conscience feeds nobody.
People can prosper only
when companies prosper.
That's nonsense.
I know how greedy you are.
I'm sure you'll still fulfill
your selfish desires...
even if all the people in the nation die.
What you're doing is the exactly same...
as your father did during the
Japanese colonial period.
I think you've crossed the line.
Do you think you're flawless?
Kim Chan Gi case.
If people find out you framed an
innocent man as a drug offender,
you'll be doomed as well.
So you're trying to get nasty.
Then...
you'll have to explain why you
threatened him and his little kid...
in your villa and killed him in the end.
What are you talking about?
He killed himself!
It doesn't really matter.
It was your excessive
avarice that made him die.
You'll be gravely punished by the law...
and criticized by the public.
Then you will never be...
able to stand on your feet again.
So...
you want to get messy?
Do you really think you can beat me?
Let's see if I can beat you...
or not.
Dad!
Catch your breath first, Dol Mok.
I found it.
I found General Baek San's treasure.
It's here.
I came here to say goodbye to Grandfather.
And I happened to look into this.
I found something in here and opened it.
Come here, Dad.
Look. This is gold, isn't it?
This isn't General Baek San's treasure.
Then what is it?
It looks like gold.
I brought it here.
Where did you get this?
Dad,
did you steal it from others?
No way. I didn't steal it.
You've heard of gold
collection campaign, right?
Bad people smuggled it...
when it was being transported
to the government,
so I took it.
Still,
you stole it after all.
Right.
General Baek San also took
treasures from the bad people.
You can use this for good things.
Exactly.
You must not talk about this to anybody.
If people find this out, I'll
be arrested by the police.
Promise me.
Let's go.
Come. Good boy.
Why are you coming from there?
We came to see if we can find
anything we can still use.
Did you tell your teacher?
I did. She said I should...
report the district office
first for school transfer...
so that I can be assigned to a new school.
Really? Then we should do
that when we get there.
- Where is Mom?
- She went out to sell...
the leftover tofu.
Pan Soo, you stole the gold, right?
What are you talking about?
It is no good denying it.
We talked to the one who's in police
and the other one who ran away.
You were the last to leave.
Then it's you who took it.
Dad, what are they talking about?
That's not true. I have no idea
what they're talking about.
You jerk.
Do you have a death wish?
Give it to me right now.
What are you doing to my dad?
Get off, kid.
He's just a kid!
Give the gold back to me, you jerk!
I let you make a loan,
and you steal the gold from us?
Do you know who it belongs to?
He's out of our league.
He can easily get rid of you on the quiet.
Give me the gold!
- Where did you hide it?
- Hey, you are...
We've met at the warehouse.
You were there!
Hey!
Stop!
Hey,
do you know who I am?
I do. You're So Joo's dad.
You're very smart.
Those jerks.
Mr. Jang,
we need to talk.
- Who are you?
- Just come with me.
You stole the gold, right?
Sorry?
No... No, it wasn't me.
Mr. Jang,
I'm a police officer.
If I have my subordinates...
ransack your place,
I bet we can find it in an hour.
You already have two previous convictions.
Do you want to be put
behind the bars again?
By the way, what interests me...
isn't really the gold.
Well, it interests me a little,
but I'm more interested
in your son, Dol Mok.
No, his name isn't Dol Mok.
He's Soo Yeon.
He's the late Kim Chan Gi's son...
Kim Soo Yeon.
What's that nonsense? Dol Mok is my son.
(Family register, Jang Dol Mok)
It says you adopted Dol Mok...
six years ago in 1992,
doesn't it?
There's no need to be bewildered.
We have the same goal.
I have a grudge against Hong Il Gwon.
Who is that?
You don't know him?
Chairman Hong Il Gwon of Cheonmun Group.
Kim Chan Gi's body was
found near his villa.
Someone called me...
saying the kid was abducted back then.
Who was it?
I wasn't sure.
It was you, right?
It turned out...
Kim Chan Gi was one of your
middle school friends.
You don't need to get scared.
He's really something.
Mr. Jang.
I'm on your side.
Trust me.
Let's work together to get
rid of Chairman Hong.
To do so, I need you to tell me the truth.
About what happened that day.
Did you know about this?
Follow me.
Min Jae.
You lied to me again.
We were moving out as
you got a job in Seoul?
That's not it, Min Jae.
I won't believe a word you say now.
You've always tried to deceive me.
But I trusted Mom...
and felt bad for you.
Even when I got upset because of Dol Mok,
I tried to understand you
because you're my dad.
I just put up with it.
But I can't believe...
anything you say anymore.
You lied to me that you loved me.
Min Jae, I'm sorry.
- Listen to me.
- No!
I'm sick of hearing you're sorry.
You've never told me the truth.
You're a liar and a thief.
You're impossible!
Do you even know...
how hard I tried...
to forget that you're a thief?
But...
you just deceived me again.
Min Jae, he took it from bad people.
- What?
- He can take it from bad people...
and use it for good.
What's wrong with that?
Stop judging him.
- There are people worse than Dad.
- You punk!
Hey! What are you doing?
So what? Do you want to live like Dad?
Do you want to go to prison?
Do you want to be criticized by people...
and give Mom a hard time?
Do you know why you don't have friends?
That's because of Dad.
Do you know that?
Hey! I know you're mad, but
you didn't have to hit him.
It's my fault, not Dol Mok's.
All right. You must be happy...
to have a son who understands you.
I hope you two will live
happily ever after.
Why you...
Min Jae. Min Jae!
Don't cry.
- What do you think? Isn't it fun?
- Yes, it is.
That's very interesting.
Where did you hear that story?
I heard...
Dad. Grandpa is here.
You're here.
I was talking with Hwa Young.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Is that true?
Are you trying to put Dad behind bars?
Father committed the worst crime.
Didn't you know that he's
that kind of person?
Why are you taking care of it?
No one wants to do this, so I'm doing it.
It's my dad we are talking about.
You told me the other day.
That if you had to choose between
Father and me, you'd choose me.
Gosh, you planned this since then.
No.
I will never let you do that.
You know how he is.
It may seem like you're holding the cards,
but you never know what will happen later.
I wouldn't have started it
if I were afraid of that.
You can't do this!
- Shin Ae.
- Do you know...
why I've put up with this even
when I was humiliated by Mi Ae?
We won't get anything if we
turn our back on Dad now.
If you don't stop it
now, we will be doomed.
Even though I love you, I can't let you...
drag Hwa Young down to the bottom.
You got Shin Ae involved in this quarrel.
I don't have time to take every
little thing into consideration.
When you play go, you should
play all your cards just to win.
Joong Tae.
Let's make a deal.
We don't have to go down the tube together.
- Make a deal?
- Yes.
I'll turn...
20 percent of the company shares...
over to Shin Ae.
And I'll send you...
to the Supreme Prosecutors' Office.
If I break this promise,
you can break the scandal.
You're the one...
who's holding the cards.
Do you remember my dad?
My grandfather was an independence fighter.
But my dad lived as a petty
official for his entire life.
When I married Shin Ae,
he couldn't raise his head in front of you.
Distinguished family.
Great achievements of ancestors.
All things...
yielded to money.
So...
I'm telling you that I'll give you money.
No.
I want something bigger than that.
The country is in a mess.
The country is ruined by
the venal and the corrupt.
So even children are stepping
up to save the country.
I want to get things right.
I won't fail like my grandfather did.
To do so,
I have to stand on the highest peak.
Are you...
- thinking about...
- That's right.
I want to work in politics.
I don't think it will cause you any harm.
You've never told me the truth.
You're a liar and a thief.
You're impossible!
Do you even know...
how hard I tried...
to forget that you're a thief?
Mr. Jang.
I'll give you some time until 8pm.
Come visit me with the gold.
You can work together with me...
to avenge your friend's murder...
or live as a thief for
the rest of your life.
It's your choice.
Did you...
talk about Baek San to Hwa Young?
Why didn't you tell me
the whole thing before?
I don't understand what you mean.
Hwa Young says...
Baek San had three maps.
You didn't tell me that.
Haven't you let it go yet?
I told you to forget about it.
Unlike you,
I don't give up easily.
This isn't about money.
The quintessence of this country...
that my father worked on
all his life is there.
It's the heritage from my father.
I will find it no matter what.
Dol Mok.
Min Jae is right.
As I found it hard to live...
I made a mistake.
I'll bring this back.
I need to talk to the police for a while.
So you should go home, Dol Mok.
Don't be upset with your
brother that he hit you today.
You should tell him you're sorry.
I'll go later and talk to Min Jae.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay. Go now.
Detective Kang.
Dad!
Pan Soo.
- Hey!
- Dad!
You're under arrest for special larceny.
Why are you doing this? I
brought the gold as I promised.
Dad!
Dol Mok!
Stay still!
Don't worry, Dol Mok! I will come out soon.
Dad!
- Let go of me!
- Dad!
What are you doing right now?
Mom, didn't you know that dad lied about...
getting a job in Seoul?
We're in trouble, Mom. Dad was taken away.
What do you mean?
- Dad...
- When you steal,
you get arrested.
What are you talking about?
Dad stole again.
He stole the gold people
donated to save this country.
- What?
- He was trying to return it.
That's why he took it
to the police station.
And they arrested him.
Listen. You have to...
pay for what you've done.
It might be a mistake the
first time you do it.
But when you do it twice or three times...
Why don't you listen to me?
He was trying to return it.
That's what I am saying.
He did what he should never have done.
So he should pay for it.
What are you doing? Your
father got arrested.
Dol Mok, where is it?
Where did he get arrested?
Detective Kang.
Have a seat.
Why did you arrest me? This
is not what you promised.
- What promise?
- You said we will work together...
to take revenge on Chairman
Hong when I bring you the gold.
Did you have a dream?
Why would I work together with a thief?
And what are you saying
about Chairman Hong?
That's nonsense.
You said that while...
showing me Dol Mok's family register.
Did I?
So what about Dol Mok?
What does the family register mean?
Tell me. I'll go get people.
Tell me with your tongue.
Stop talking nonsense.
I got all the evidence.
So just admit the crime.
Let me write a report.
Did you steal the gold from
Cheonmun Department Store?
The department store reported a burglary.
What are you talking about?
I turned myself in because
I trusted your words.
The ones who took the gold
from the storage are...
the loan sharks.
You saw it too.
Hey, Pan Soo!
You thief, listen carefully.
You stayed in prison for five
years, so you must be quick-witted.
You stole the gold from
Cheonmun Department Store.
Only then you will be extenuated
for turning yourself in.
Do you understand?
I can't do that.
I can't go to prison again
and leave my children.
Why would I take responsibility
for something I didn't do?
Do you want me to tell you why?
It's for Dol Mok.
If you keep being stubborn like that,
I will go to Chairman Hong.
What do you think I will say to him?
I will tell him that Dol Mok is...
Soo Yeon, the son of Late Kim Chan Gi.
How's that?
Do you know that?
His underling even went
to the district office...
to find out about Dol Mok.
I stopped him from finding out.
What will happen if the
chairman finds out the truth?
There's no guarantee that Dol Mok
won't end up like his father.
It's not time yet.
This is crazy.
What nonsense are you saying?
It's not an ordinary crime.
These men stole the gold...
donated by little kids.
Detective Kang.
You weren't always righteous, were you?
I will give you what you want.
I will promote you to a
first-degree detective...
and be responsible for
your daughter's future.
I will make sure to keep my words.
It's clear that you are no better than me.
This deal will put the
chairman in a safe position,
and both of us will benefit from it.
Is that it?
I clearly said it's not the right time yet.
I am going to grow my power,
and when the right time comes,
I am going to catch him.
It's more fun if you wait until
the fish becomes bigger.
Let's stop it between us who has evidence.
Do you know who that man is?
He's the man who saved
your child, Jang Pan Soo.
Also, he is just a
simple-minded technician.
There are other people who
take care of this stolen gold.
When you unveil the managers,
the chairman might get exposed.
We have to stop at Jang Pan Soo.
We have to.
Sir.
I am no good man,
but I can't put the man...
who saved my daughter
behind bars like that.
Then you might end up behind bars.
- What?
- Do you think he doesn't know...
that you're in charge of the investigation?
It seems like he already has
a connection with your boss.
Whether you like it or not,
you already stepped into this filthy world.
Let's think about our future.
Think about the future of your son...
and about my future dream
of capturing Chairman Hong.
In order to pass through a big mountain,
you have to bear with small scratches.
We are on the hunt for a tiger.
Why do we have to worry
about cockroaches too?
- Dad.
- Goodness.
Goodness.
What are you doing?
You're going to smoke again, aren't you?
Please quit.
Okay. Why are you here?
I've come to see if you are eating well.
Are you not coming home again?
No.
Don't be a cop like me.
Why not? You catch bad people.
While trying to catch bad
guys, I will turn bad first.
What do you mean?
It's nothing. What do you want to eat?
Should we go eat tteokbokki?
Is this the right place?
Yes, I am sure.
Let's go.
It's him.
Dol Mok.
So Joo.
Mister.
You arrested my dad, didn't you?
Why did you arrest him when
he came to turn himself in?
Let my dad go.
What is he talking about?
Did you arrest Dol Mok's dad? Why?
His dad...
stole the gold from the
gold collection campaign.
Are you sure about that?
No.
It was other people who stole the gold.
You came to my place and saw them yourself.
And Dad only tried to take
those to the police station.
What do you know?
Your dad stole it.
Sir, then...
can I meet my husband?
I need to talk to him and
find out what happened.
Where is he right now?
According to Dol Mok,
he got caught around here.
Then he was arrested while trying
to return the gold, right?
Why would you interrogate him?
I can't tell you the reason now.
Anyway, you can't see him.
Let them meet, Dad.
I said no.
Why not?
Aren't you allowed to meet
your attorney and your family?
How would you know?
Do you think we're playing
and this is your playground?
- Let's go.
- Wait, sir.
Wait. Gosh.
What do we do?
What is it?
It's here.
- Mr. Jang.
- Mr. Jang!
Do you admit your charge?
- Please answer me.
- Did you do that alone?
Or is there anyone behind you?
Please make any comment.
I did it on my own.
I did it alone...
out of greed. I apologize.
- I am sorry.
- You're a filthy thief!
You pieces of trash!
Mr. Jang who suffered from poverty...
intruded into Cheonmun
Department Store's warehouse...
and robbed 20kg of...
It's not true. It's a lie.
He said he took it from there...
because bad people tried
to pocket the gold.
Okay.
There must be a misunderstanding.
You must know...
that your father isn't a bad person.
You must wake up.
He confessed his crime.
Gosh. Min Jae. Min Jae!
Give the gold back to me, you jerk!
I let you make a loan, and
you steal the gold from us?
Do you know who it belongs to?
He's out of our league.
He can easily get rid of you on the quiet.
Give me the gold!
Where did you hide it?
We've met at the warehouse.
You were there!
(Gangwon 36, Na 4785)
It was Gangwon 36, Na.
And 4785.
(The Good Thieves)
Dol Mok went to the villa?
I think I've been to that villa before.
I already laid the blame on
the guy named Jang Pan Soo.
Jang Pan Soo? The thief?
You know the real culprit?
What do you mean by that?
I came here because I
cannot trust the police.
I did steal the gold,
so don't act recklessly anymore.
Dol Mok isn't what matters now.
You will have to spend
your whole life in prison.
There's a good reason why your dad...
cares so much about Dol Mok.
I'm sick of Dad and Dol Mok.
This wouldn't have happened if
you hadn't come to our family.
Min Jae! Min Jae!