Previously on United
States of Tara...
I just woke up... again...
next to that woman
from the grocery store
Pammy's got just what you need.
Uh... I can't do this.
It's always the disease's
fault, isn't it?
Never someone just
being an asshole!
Marshall and Courtney...
game on.
Marshall says he's
straight now?
How is your beard, anyway?
You guys boning?
How am I doing?
Lynda P. Frazier.
Your check bounced.
You owe me money.
Princess Valhalla Hawkwind.
Damn, girl.
We should know our neighbors
a little better, right?
- Ted Mayo. This is my partner, Hany.
- Hi.
The Hubbard house
is officially ours!
Escrow just closed.
You need a real carpenter.
How much money did you
give him for materials?
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
You know what? I think you
have been sully-rigged.
Give me back my money.
Buck, I love you.
I love you.
All I've ever done
is be good to you.
That's all I've ever done...
just be good to you.
Open up the sky.
This mess is getting high.
It's windy, and our
family needs a ride.
I know we'll be just fine.
When we learn to
love the ride.
I know we'll be fine.
When we learn to
love the ride.
I know we'll be just fine.
When we learn to
love the ride.
The ants are back
in the kitchen.
What happened to your neck?
A door-to-door werewolf.
Give me that crowbar.
What the fuck happened last night?
Huh?
Who was that?
I don't know. I...
Oh, you know.
Her name is Pammy.
I saw that look on her face.
She's in love with you.
It's nothing.
It's... it's Buck.
It's not me.
That is not enough.
You know Buck.
You've known Buck forever,
the stuff that he...
No, it's you!
You were better.
You fucking told me you
were better... for months!
You said you weren't
transitioning.
I didn't know!
You fucking knew!
I guess...
I guess a part of me...
Yeah. That's why I'm mad.
'Cause you lied to me... not
Buck, not fucking Alice.
You fucking lied to me!
So...
What do we do?
We don't do anything.
You fucking get help.
Find a therapist.
Okay. I will.
Yeah.
You will.
Give me that.
Why?
'Cause I told you to.
No. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Not... not in here.
Not in this house.
Hey, Kate.
Tara.
No more "mom," huh?
Now I'm just "Tara"?
I don't know why you'd
be upset, Tara.
I've called you many names
over our time together.
Okay. Stupid ant!
I'm sure what happened last
night was confusing...
Not to me. I'm used to it.
Is there a name you'd rather
be called, Tara, than "Tara"?
That's fun, Kate. Good stuff.
Morning.
I'm off to work.
Someone around here needs
to be a responsible adult.
Also, you have grass
all over your back.
So, I found this killer wedding
dress by badgley mischka,
but it's really expensive.
But it's awesome!
But I need my
chocolate fountain.
I'm not getting married without
my chocolate fountain.
And I don't care what
Nick's family says...
We are dancing down the aisle,
and we are all
wearing sunglasses.
Well, that sounds like
every little girl's dream.
So...
Last night?
Huh?
You and Max work it out?
Charmy, I really don't
want to talk about it.
Oh, you know what I
realized this morning?
My bedroom window overlooks
the Hubbards' backyard.
That's quite a view.
A good therapist in
Overland Park? Please.
I can't even find a good latte.
That one place...
That café attached to
the Christmas store?
With that little queen
behind the counter?
Spiritual pride in a barista?
I won't brook it! I won't!
He won't brook it.
So, what's the problem?
Let's just say
I've been seriously
without help for a while,
and I've... I've...
I've been okay,
but I think I actually
need help again.
Just got some stuff
going on with me.
Or... Max.
With me and Max.
Well, you're not gonna
find anybody around here.
Ugh!
Hany and I went through
a rocky period
a few years back...
Erectile dysfunction.
Let's just say it...
it was me.
It was him.
We went to quack after
quack after quack.
It was a duck pond.
So, uh, shrinkwise, I'm fucked?
You may be.
But in the meantime...
Take this for a spin.
Written by my old therapist.
Oh, the much-lauded
Shoshana Schoenbaum, huh?
It's simple stuff, but
she's very down-to-earth.
Till you find the right doctor.
Yeah, I'll give it a look.
Just don't crack the spine.
He hates that.
I hate that.
Hey, buddy.
Just in time for a little
Billy Jack action.
"When I see this child."
"Who is so special to us."
I kind of have to
get to school.
"We call him God's
little ray of sunshine,"
"so demeaned by this
idiotic moment of yours..."
"I just go berserk!"
Oh, I fucked my back.
I thought Billy Jack
was about nonviolence.
I don't know.
So...
I guess Buck's out.
Yeah, Buck's out.
You and mom okay?
Yeah. We're dealing with it.
I thought you were
working with that guy.
Sully? No, not anymore.
Motherfucker tried
to rip me off.
So... You just... Let
the guy take our money?
No, I took care of it.
How?
I kind of kicked the
shit out of him.
Does, um...
Does mom know?
No.
Let's keep it that
way, okay, bro?
I was just out of art school
and realized that the crap I
was making wasn't selling.
Mm-hmm.
Little less talking,
little more painting.
- So I started making princess paintings.
- Oh, God.
My arm's fucking killing me!
Quit complaining.
I mean, at first,
I hated myself.
Starting to hate you!
But then I realized, you know,
at least my paintings
were selling.
And every now and then, I could
afford a whopper... with cheese.
Sword!
So, what are her superpowers?
Does she burn things
with her eyes?
Does she hear good?
Does she fly?
Oh, yeah. She flies.
What about sex?
Do I use my body like a weapon,
like Poison Ivy on Batman?
I mean, I'm pretty fuckable.
No. The princess don't fuck.
Because she won't?
Because she can't.
Got it.
Like Barbie... no holes.
Hey, Max, I was just...
I figure we could do it there.
Sure. Yeah. Makes sense.
I-I mean, we could...
No, it... this seems right.
Classic.
Yeah, it's, uh...
It's what you'd
expect, you know?
A bed.
What'd you tell Ms. Watkins
to get out of school?
I told her I had an ortho.
You?
I went with explosive diarrhea.
That's a lot of condoms.
Where did you get all that?
Planned parenthood.
My mom's nightstand.
My cousin Graham.
So, any of these
calling your name?
Um, that one.
No, I...
No.
Yeah, sure. That...
that's fine.
Yeah?
Yeah.
The... the... um,
the other way.
I think it's
supposed to be hard.
I bet if you wanted to,
you could make some pretty
good coin off this thing
and pay off your debt.
You know... mugs and
t-shirts and key chains.
Sure.
And hats and stickers.
And you could put
out a magazine
with pictures and a centerfold.
Oh, no. Not a centerfold.
She's a subject, not an object.
Mm-hmm.
But you know what?
You're right.
I mean, who the fuck is
gonna see the painting?
Let's make a movie.
"From birth,"
"each of us sets out to
discover who we really are."
"But when trauma occurs,
we create ways to survive."
"Often, we split into pieces"
"and abandon the most
vulnerable parts of ourselves,"
"boxing them up in tidy
packages and tossing them away."
"Later, we spend our lives
looking for these parcels,"
"hoping to meet someone
who can help us"
"find these lost splintered
pieces of ourself."
Charmaine, dear, shut
that door this instant!
All that rain will
Buckle the hardwood!
Tara, what in the name
of all that is Holy
have you done with your poncho?
I don't know, Mimi.
Don't play games with me.
That thing you did...
That was you c-coming, right?
Uh... Yeah.
Big-time.
Did you?
Yeah. Totally.
A lot.
So many times.
So...
I don't know if you're,
like, all worn out...
But I could go again.
Oh.
Okay, yeah.
Yeah, if... if you want to.
You're not in any... Pain
or anything, are you?
I don't think so.
We could go back to school.
I do have a chemistry test.
What?
I got help.
I found somebody.
Okay.
Remember that woman that Ted
was telling us about...
His therapist in New York?
Well, when I was there this morning,
he gave me one of her books.
I've been reading it all day.
It's so good.
And it says that people...
all people...
have ways of being
not integrated,
and that... and that we
jettison parts of ourselves
into these parcels.
Come on. Speak English.
It's a book. A
book is not help.
We need a new doctor.
Well, I got in touch with her.
Did you call her?
Yeah, I called her. She's
Ted's old therapist.
Max, she's fucking brilliant.
She has a mind like...
She loves my story.
She's in New York.
Well, she's happy to start
with phone therapy.
We might Skype.
Skype?
And she can travel. She's,
like, this famous author.
I don't trust these...
Small-town locals.
I'm too...
What?
What are you?
It's Kate.
Yep.
You got to be kidding me.
W-what's wrong with the car?
Oka... no, no, no, no.
Don't start it again.
You flooded it.
Where are you? We'll
come get you.
Where?
Wow. This is colorful.
Smells like pee.
Kate!
We're here! Let's go!
Bye! Bye-bye, Kate.
Goodbye, goodbye!
Oh. Hi.
What are you wearing?
It's my Princess
Valhalla costume.
You're not walking around like that.
Come here.
Ugh. That fucking car.
Stupid piece of American shit.
Yeah, that's who's at fault here...
Detroit.
Ugh.
That sign was the
only thing left
when I found this place.
They made copper plating,
doorknobs, drawer pulls.
How long have you lived here?
About a year.
But you don't want
to know that.
I don't?
I've noticed that when people
walk into a new place,
they get nervous,
so they start asking
questions about numbers.
What do you really
want to know?
Hey.
You, uh, you ready to go?
Yeah.
I'm gonna give this to you.
It's Kate's.
Look, we're not talking about it anymore.
End of discussion.
You can't ground me. I
was there for my job.
I've had it up to
here with you guys.
Who's the parent
around here, anyway?
No one.
Jesus God, girl.
Could you cut me some
fucking slack for once?
Maybe I'll move out.
Maybe I'll move in with Lynda.
How come you never
told us she was black?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Wake up, Fox News.
There's a new sheriff in town.
His name is Barack Obama.
I think it's a cool thing.
Oh, great. Now it's
cool that she's black.
That's even worse.
Okay, here's the deal...
You're done with the car. You're
done with going downtown.
You're done with that woman... having
nothing to do with her being black.
What do you guys
even do together?
Bottom line... you're grounded
until we say otherwise.
You know what, dad... if you are
so desperate to ground somebody,
you should be grounding mom!
She's the one that has been
pretending to be somebody else
with that crazy lady from the
ice-skating rink, doing God knows what!
Coming from the girl
in the winged hat
and the princess costume.
Stop! Okay?
Look, Kate, your
mom's getting help.
We found an expert in New
York who's gonna help her.
New York?
Yeah. They don't know what
they're doing around here.
Come on. Let's just give the
new doc a chance, all right?
Hey, kids!
So...
We've got some big news.
We're pregnant!
What the fuck, Nick?
I'm sorry.
You fucking ruined it!
Okay. You go.
No. What am I
supposed to say now?
I... it's gone. The
moment's gone.
Hey, guys...
Congratulations, Charmaine.
Thank you.
If that baby knows
what's good for it,
it'll tie the umbilical cord
around its neck and take a leap.
What the hell, Kate?
Anyway...
Uh, Max, I want to
talk to you sometime
maybe about... Maybe
buying this place.
For me and Charmaine and...
Our baby.
We're so excited to have
our own little family,
but Charmaine said she
can't imagine doing it
anywhere but here... right
next door to you guys.
Aw.
Hey! Ahhh...
All right. Great, great.
Good. Goddamn.
I guess I'm a little confused
about why you're
living with us.
I mean, aren't you supposed
to be "re-virginating"?
Well, it must have happened
before I moved out of Nick's.
I love the light in here!
This is gonna be
the baby's room.
Okay, obviously, this
junk has to go...
Oh, my God!
I know... a porch swing!
So then Nick and I can
rock the baby together.
Hey, Char?
Yeah?
You're gonna be a great mother.
Hey, dad, where's mom?
Oh, she's next door,
but don't bother her.
She's got a phone session
with her new therapist.
She found somebody we're
kind of excited about.
Cool.
Yeah.
Hey, I know, uh, I've
been kind of busy
and a little preoccupied,
but how's things going
with you and Courtney?
You know, uh...
We're...
It's...
I'm not prying, okay?
It's none of my business.
I'm gonna run down to grandstand
and grab some burgers.
You want anything?
I'm gay.
Good.
So, you want anything?
Yeah, um...
Maybe I'll just come
with you to grandstand.
Cool.
I think you should tell mom
about that guy you beat up.
How was your session?
Really, um... Intense.
Yeah?
Marshall came out
to me tonight.
Officially?
Oh, Marshmallow.
How'd you take I?
I don't know.
I-I guess it gave me...
Some hope.
I'm just glad you
found someone.
Me too.
Tara?
Yeah?
I did a bad thing.
Tara?
Excuse me? Do you mind? I'm
finishing up a session.
Hold on, Dolores.
Can I help you?
It must be something
psychological.