FLASH: Speed it up, will you?
You drive like my granny.
We're moving with the flow of traffic.
When do I get to drive?
-My car, so, never.
-(CELL PHONE CLICKING)
Ooh, I'm gonna sign up
for this thing called "Tweeter".
You put up what you're thinking like,
"I love pizza,"
or "I'm having pizza now,"
or even "Pizza is awesome."
All your thoughts don't have to be
pizza related.
Says who?
Hey, I could order a pizza,
while we're puttering along here.
Ooh, great idea.
"Gonna have pizza soon."
First twit sent.
What the heck is that?
(EXPLODING)
-Flash, go find out.
-On it.
-Report.
-You need to see for yourself.
I'm not totally sure.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Big week for us.
First, we stopped the Fearsome Five.
They were so pissed.
"You'll pay for interfering with us."
Blah, blah, blah.
SPEEDY: And now we get to
stop an alien brawl.
-(GROWLING)
-(GRUNTING)
SPEEDY: Which side do we join?
-Really?
-Looks can be deceiving.
(GROWLING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Titans, go!
And the fact that she's hot
has nothing to do with it.
(GRUNTS)
Buzz off, lizard lips!
(GROWLING) Coming through. Excuse me.
Pardonne—moi.
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(GROANS)
(SPEAKING IN TAMARANEAN)
I think Rapunzel is trying
to tell us something.
(BEEPING)
Speedy, you got something loud
to close that thing?
Got you covered, boss.
(EXPLODING)
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(ALIENS GROWLING)
-(GRUNTS)
-(SIGHS)
(EXCLAIMING)
(GROWLING)
Whoa!
(TRUMPETING)
(ALIEN GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALIEN GROANING)
(SPEAKING IN TAMARANEAN)
I did not see that coming.
Thank you.
I am Koriand'r of Tamaran.
Our kind can learn language
from the act of kissing.
Useful.
Are you all right?
My sister, Komand'r,
staged a coup and took the throne.
I had to flee.
But I will soon return.
Well, you can stay with us
until you figure it out.
Okay?
Yes, please.
I would ask sanctuary
for two or three days.
A week at the longest.
Let me introduce you to my friends.
Oh, by the way, I speak some Spanish,
if you wanna learn that.
-Second year high school French.
-(SIGHS)
Welcome to the Teen Titans.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAWING)
(COCKING GUN)
(THUDDING)
MAN: Careful, you fool.
This equipment is worth
more than your lives.
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
MAYHEM: What?
DEATHSTROKE: The Titans will be there
in less than a minute.
I see no signs of that.
Believe, don't believe, your choice.
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
-(THUDDING)
-(GROANS)
-(CLANKING)
They're ready.
They're slow.
I hardly had time to answer a post.
(HOOTING)
It's a tough climb,
especially in this moonlight.
-STARFIRE: Nightwing.
-They're bound to spot us.
-Nightwing.
-If we wait for those clouds...
-Dick!
-What?
Terra is taking us up there.
She is?
Yeah, I do all the dirty work around here.
(ROCKS RUMBLING)
Going up.
You've been gone a long time, cowboy.
Let's move.
(ROCKS RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
-(STRIDULATING)
-Quiet down.
The bug is nervous.
I'm not feeling too good
about this myself.
How come you're so calm?
You have never been a gopher.
(SIGHS)
(STRIDULATING)
Hey!
Scarab, stop.
Control that thing, Beetle,
or I'll control it for you.
You're going to have
a sword fight in here?
How about some place roomier,
like a broom closet?
Everyone, calm down.
The enemy is above us.
You have to channel
all your thoughts to that.
Remember, these opponents are different.
Uh, as Kori will tell you.
No, keep going.
I've been studying them
since I left the Titans.
They're zealots, extremists.
They'll sacrifice themselves
without hesitation to get to you.
So, the quicker we take them down,
the better.
That about cover it?
Very well said.
-(RUMBLING)
-(GRUNTS)
-(SIGHS)
-Terra, can you do this?
(SIGHS) Yes, if you'd all shut up.
(SIGHS) We're six inches under the floor.
(SIGHS) Who wants to knock?
(EXPLODING)
Titans, go!
(SCREECHING)
"Thanks for getting us into
the impenetrable H.I.V.E. base, Terra."
"Yeah, you're the best."
(GROANS)
This bad guy is yours, mama.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GROANING)
Terra, stay with us.
Like I couldn't take out
all these jokers by myself.
(SCREAMING)
We've been compromised.
Abandon the base.
(EMERGENCY SIREN BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
They prepared well.
Their reaction time is much better.
Robin, stop complimenting the bad guys.
But he's right. Be ready for anything.
These dudes must buy their
bad guy stuff in bulk.
How about we do that move
you taught me last weekend?
Now?
I admire your boldness,
but what will the team think?
What? No, not...
Okay, you got me.
The training move, please.
(GROANS)
(TRUMPETING)
(SCREAMING)
Get in the truck.
Your service has come to an end.
-(THUDDING)
-Bless you all.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Watch it, dude. Those are my friends.
At least act like you're trying to
keep your parasite in line, Beetle.
-(GROWLING)
-(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
That was unbearable.
(SCOFFS) Get it?
Seriously?
(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
(GROANS)
Could you not leave yourself
open like that?
-I worry.
-(CLICKING)
I'm sorry, babe.
I've been doing a lot of thinking lately.
About what?
I think we should take the next step
in our relationship.
To be continued.
(GROANING)
(SHRIEKING)
Say cheese,
and post.
Hey, how about a movie tonight?
Whoa! (SHRIEKING)
Keep moving, Magilla.
-(BEEPING)
-The base is ours.
(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
So, what were you saying
before we were interrupted?
I...
(SIGHS)
Okay, good a place as any.
I got an apartment in the city.
I hoped, maybe, we could share it,
you know,
together.
Oh, snap!
(CHUCKLING)
No rock?
That's so lame.
On Tamaran, everyone would gossip.
So it's a good thing we live here.
What I'm getting is that
they're too good to hang with us.
-Yeah, that's the takeaway.
-(PHONE BUZZING)
(BEEPING)
Hey, I'm over a million followers!
(SQUEAKING)
(ELECTRICAL BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
Call me jefe.
You need to get your head
in the game, Gar.
Or, maybe your head
is in a different game.
Who wouldn't want to date me? I'm awesome.
But everything I do pisses her off.
Want my advice?
Quit turning into a chimp
and stealing monkey kisses.
People think that's adorable.
Nope, no one thinks that.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Time out.
-(GROANS)
-Gotta make a call.
(METAL CLANKING)
(GRUNTING)
Terra.
Would you like to join me?
The staff helps clear the mind.
No thanks.
I'm just trying to avoid
Green Bean for a while.
I never cared much for the zoo.
If he's bothering you...
(CHUCKLES) He's just a jerk.
Is it true what they say about her,
that she has her father
trapped in that jewel on her head?
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Yes, his name is Trigon.
He's a demon.
(HESITANTLY) They have issues.
At least she knows where she can find him.
You should talk to her more.
You'll find that Raven can be quite
interesting.
No thanks. Too creepy for me.
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
Sounds like a good time, Milagro.
Did you get my gift?
Sure did. Gift cards to 17 Forever.
My favorite.
Mom and Dad wanna say hi. Love you.
There's my baby boy!
Are you getting enough to eat?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Yeah, how's it goin'?
(STRIDULATING)
-(GRUNTS)
-(WHIMPERING)
Still doesn't like me, huh?
It's getting better.
Let's not talk about that thing.
It's been two years.
I'm working on it, Dad.
But it's hard, you know.
It's got a mind of its own.
-And a temper.
-Aldo.
For God's sake.
He's with a bunch of super heroes.
ALDO: You think Superman
or someone could take that thing off him.
You're supposed to calm down.
We can't have every call
end this way, Aldo.
Jaime won't wanna talk to us.
(SIGHS)
Why is the cake coming out? It's not time!
Ah, your aunt Consuela, está loca.
Go, Mom, we can talk later.
I love you, Jaime.
Be good.
Consuela, give me that cake!
I better go too.
I'm sorry. It's just...
I miss my son.
(BEEPING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
COMPUTER: Accessing most recent footage
on Brother Blood.
BROTHER BLOOD: Lies.
My church is a holy place
and we strive only to do good.
Come now, Brother Blood.
Isn't your church just a gloriﬁed cult?
BROTHER BLOOD: Unlike you, Bryce,
I believe in an America
where all beliefs should be
treated with respect.
It's a shame the press doesn't.
I'm afraid that's all we're going to get
from Brother Blood.
I'm Bryce Peterson.
-Have a good night.
-(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
Grandfather would have been
impressed with Blood,
running a worldwide cult
as well as H.I.V.E.
They're the same thing.
He just makes them look separate.
Do you ever get out of that uniform?
Only when I bathe.
Might be time.
(SNIFFING)
I'm good.
Goin' out.
I hear you're gone a lot.
Where do you go?
You realize I'm not a child
who needs permission to go outside.
Correct?
Damian, I wasn't interrogating.
Just taking an interest.
Oh!
I go out on patrol.
By the way, I should offer congratulations
on your cohabitation, Grayson.
Starfire has proven herself
to be a decent leader.
I approve.
Thank you.
Have you found anything
in the H.I.V.E. files?
Nothing Earth-shaking,
but I'm still checking.
Sounds like you got squat.
I love endangering my life for nothing.
Which is why I've added the newest files
to the ones too damaged to read
from the previous raids.
I'm hoping the computer
will find a connection we missed.
It may take the program a day or two.
Not your worst idea.
What?
Ugh!
Hey, anyone seen Jaime?
Yeah, he's right there.
(JAIME EXCLAIMING)
Something is wrong.
Yeah, there is.
He's about to be crushed at foosball.
You wanna come see?
Buzz off.
(EXCLAIMING AND GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Maybe you should go.
Might be good to have
two of you down there.
And I say to you,
those who deny the chosen
have no place in the Eden
that shall be built.
Sinners and blasphemers
who do not share our values
need not apply,
brothers and sisters.
CROWD: Hail, Brother Blood!
Hail, hail!
Hail, Brother Blood.
BROTHER BLOOD: Ah, there you are, Mayhem.
Punctual as always.
MAYHEM: How can you be so calm?
That was the third base
the Titans have destroyed.
My plan is nine centuries in the making.
In every age,
there are always those who oppose me.
But as you can see,
I am always victorious.
Is that the reporter?
Yes.
Our friend won't be asking
impertinent questions anymore.
His heresy does not compare
to the Titans' threat.
We barely escaped them.
But you did,
because he warned you.
Our guardian angel.
Oh, stop your fretting, Mayhem.
He'll keep the Titans at bay.
I've foreseen it.
Plus, I pay the bastard enough.
BEAST BOY: Could you slow down, Jaime?
Go back to the Tower then.
Nobody asked you to come.
Oh, come on. We're here to support you.
I'm not.
What I mean is,
I respect Jaime not wanting to talk.
In fact, more people should learn
to shut their mouths.
Well, that's no fun.
Uh, okay, I give up.
The center.
My parents volunteer
for the one in my town.
And...
Maybe I should volunteer.
(SCOFFS) Yeah, right.
We're Titans.
We don't serve soup.
You don't have to move a mountain
to help people, Terra.
Besides, I gotta find a way
to make the bug
more comfortable around humans.
Can I help you?
Yes, um, Traci.
I was wondering who I could
speak to about volunteering.
That would be me.
And there it is.
Just because we have powers
doesn't mean we can't, you know,
have relationships.
Don't you think?
Hey, there's nothing wrong
with having a life, right?
Kill her!
Kill the demon!
(GASPS)
What's the matter?
Nothing.
This is lame. I'm out.
(DOOR CLOSES)
For nearly a millennium,
I have bathed in my enemy's blood,
and for some mysterious reason,
it has provided me immortality.
I have often wondered why.
Why me?
But now I know.
It was meant to bring me to this age,
this place, this moment,
where technology can at last
be made to serve my greatness.
Proceed.
(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
(ALL GROANING)
(PANTING)
(CLANKING)
(METAL SCREECHING)
You've done well.
Advance the preparations, Mayhem.
The time has come for us to move
from immortality to glory.
MAYHEM: Your service has come to an end.
Bless you, my son.
NIGHTWING: For a space princess,
you sure have a lot of stuff.
(CLINKING)
I've had this since I was a little girl.
It was the only thing I had time to take.
-(RUMBLING)
-Not again.
(GROANING)
ROBIN: Terra, are you okay?
She's going to bring the building down.
I can help.
(GROANING)
(GASPS) What are you doing?
Get off me!
You were shaking everything, Terra.
We came to check on you.
Are you all right?
It was a freaking nightmare.
(SIGHS) Just leave me alone.
I'm okay, so, get going.
You heard me. Get going.
You too, Greeny.
Does that happen a lot?
It happens enough.
-What did you see?
-Nothing.
And if I did see anything,
it wouldn't be your business.
Everything that goes on in the Tower
is my business.
Just like it should be for all of you.
The last I checked, Damian,
Kori was in charge, not you.
So good to see you again, my friends.
It's been too long.
Too long.
MAN: Don't make this weirder
than it already is, Blood.
Are you referring to the setting?
I myself take strength from it.
The cemetery isn't a place to be feared.
It's a place of renewal.
MAN: I have no problem meeting
anywhere you want,
but I get concerned
when my employer talks to himself.
I talk to the dead,
for no matter how rotted the corpse,
there's always a tiny wisp of life left.
Sometimes enough life to bring them back.
You of all people should know that.
What do you want, Blood?
I want to move everything up by a week.
I've waited long enough, Deathstroke.
That wasn't the deal.
I'll double your price.
Is that acceptable?
As before, I want all the Titans.
Can you do it?
To be ready for anything,
you must train for everything.
That was the most important lesson
instilled in me by the warlords of Okaara.
(IMPASSIVELY) Them again?
Dude...
And so it shall be instilled in you.
Let's pair off.
Those not fighting, watch and learn.
Nightwing.
Shall we dance, good sir?
But of course, my lady.
(METAL CLANKING)
(GRUNTING)
Guess we know who's taking out
the garbage at the new place.
(SIGHS) That was not a confidence booster.
You did very well.
You lasted far longer this time.
(SNICKERING)
I meant in training, of course.
He's very proficient when we have--
Kori!
Blue Beetle, Raven.
Sorry, Raven, the bug doesn't wanna lose.
And you do?
(GRUNTS)
-Huh?
-(STRIDULATING)
Dios mio! I'm so sorry. Are you okay?
-What the hell are you doing?
-(STRIDULATING)
Ah, I'm fine.
Though Dad feels I've disgraced myself.
So that's nice.
Beast Boy, Terra, you ready?
Right. Sorry.
I'll take it easy on you, Terra.
I'm gonna enjoy shutting you up.
Only if you catch me, mama.
(GROWLING)
(SHRIEKS)
Ah, mon cherie,
let Garfield give you a big hug.
Mmm, so soft.
I let you go for a little kiss.
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
MAN: Kill her!
Now, little witch,
you get what's coming to you!
Who you calling a witch?
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
Terra!
She's going to kill him!
Argh!
Terra, control yourself!
What?
What's going on?
(GROANING)
I'm sorry, it's not my fault.
-Let me calm your mind.
-No!
-Don't touch me.
-It's okay, Terra, we understand.
Take a breath.
We're here for you.
Yeah. I know you didn't mean to hurt me.
I took it too far.
What's wrong with you people?
I know what you're going to say.
Terra needs more training.
No, it's something else.
She knows.
Since we talked,
I have sensed something off about Terra.
She needs to be watched, Grayson.
She needs understanding, not surveillance.
Terra has her rough edges.
But Kori thinks she's worth it.
And I agree.
Making decisions with your heart
will get people killed.
It's not like I can't sense
the vibrations of someone following me.
Even if they are on a roof.
I know what it's like
not to fit in with the group.
What's wrong?
Aside from Monkey Boy making me melt down,
or Raven staring all the time,
Nightwing acting like a den mother,
Jaime and his freako bug,
Miss Smiles-A-Lot, and you,
my new stalker,
huh, nothing I guess.
If you need to talk,
let us help you.
Such an observant, considerate boy.
You would think he truly cares.
Slade? Look what hell just spit up.
Stay back.
Let me guess,
they got you to a Lazarus Pit
just in time.
Yes, I've been bathing in it
quite a bit lately.
You might say it's addictive.
Improves muscle tone too.
(GRUNTING)
Losing your edge.
Your friends have made you soft.
(GRUNTS)
Like I said, soft.
(GROANING)
Took you long enough.
You betrayed us. Why?
Betrayed?
That assumes I was ever on your side
in the first place.
(STRAINING)
There you go, Mr. Fernandez.
-Great to have your help. Thanks.
-No.
Thank you.
I kinda needed this.
This just reminds me of home.
-Ow! Huh, hot.
-Careful.
You don't wanna get burned.
(CHIRPING)
Do you hear that?
-I heard it before.
-Uh...
I hope there's not a short.
I think I heard it move over there.
-(CHIRPING)
-I know my pulse is racing.
But I'm in no danger. None.
Defensive measures are not needed.
Oh, boy, how do I explain this?
There's something humans call
sexual attraction.
-Ay, my life.
-(CHIRPING)
Uh, Jaime?
(CHUCKLES)
What are you doing?
I thought I'd get more comfortable.
Don't.
You can't run over here
at the first sign of trouble.
I was losing it. I had to see you.
Luckily, taking Robin out works.
Brat's a handful.
Best to get him out of the way.
He was suspicious.
Always is.
Didn't say he was stupid.
He damaged the camera lens.
Greeny was asking for it.
It's taken a year
to get the information I need
to defeat the Titans.
Could've ruined everything. Stay still.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
MAN: Kill her!
ALL: Kill the witch!
Kill the witch! She's a demon!
Kill her now!
(WHIMPERS)
(BLADE SWISHES)
(GASPS)
(THUDDING)
Leave or die. Your choice.
Terra Markov.
I heard you're a special girl.
Is that true?
My name is Slade.
Looks like I got it.
Not yet, you haven't.
But you could.
-We discussed this.
-I'm not a kid.
-You said we'd be together.
-Not yet.
The contract is everything.
We need total concentration for it.
You know it's taken
a lot of work to get here.
-Especially by you.
-I don't wanna go back.
The Titans are always acting
like they care so much.
(SIGHS) lt messes with my head.
Just a little longer, Terra.
With the money from Blood
we'll form our own league of assassins.
You and I.
Together in every way.
I didn't see you bringing
quite so many weapons to our new place.
-If you don't like them...
-No, no. They're great.
Is something up?
After the incident at the training field,
you met with members of the team
without me.
Yeah, we talked. But it wasn't a meeting.
Kori, you know I'd never
undermine you, right?
They went to you.
You were... Are a great leader.
So, they instinctively look to you,
now that you're back.
After all, I'm not even from your world.
Hey. Stop.
You were chosen by the team to lead them.
And have I told you how glad I am
that you've chosen to move in with me?
At least I was your first choice for that.
Yeah. Well, Gar's got his house
and Jaime couldn't afford the rent.
(SCOFFS) You brat.
(PHONE BEEPING)
Damian! Of course.
Perfect timing.
-Solo?
-He's working on something.
Have I mentioned he approves of us?
So do I.
Yeah? Problem?
Not yet.
(SCOFFS) Nice visit.
I know I'm not easy to get close to.
We have that in common, I think.
But I could teach you
some meditation techniques.
It might help you stay in control.
Maybe. Maybe so.
The other reason I'm here is to tell you
the team's assembling in the common room.
I need a minute. You go on ahead.
They know about Robin.
DEATHSTROKE: They don't.
Raven, being nice?
And there's nothing scheduled.
They know I'm working with you.
If they knew,
she wouldn't have come alone.
Unless they wanted to get my guard down.
I don't think I can take them all
if they're ready.
Calm yourself. The fools trust you.
Use that.
(HUFFS)
-(LOUD CLICKING, GASPS)
-ALL: Surprise!
Shit.
(SIGHS DEEPLY) You guys scared me.
We can see that.
-Are those for me?
-They sure are.
For your one year anniversary
as a member of the Titans.
-It was all Raven's idea.
-I...
No one has ever done
anything like this for me.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Dry those tears
and let's get this party started, mama!
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(BEEPING)
The computer's done.
-The one with Blood's files.
-Let's take a look.
COMPUTER: File reconstruction
and integration complete.
NIGHTWING: That scientist used
to work for H.I.V.E.
Body never recovered.
Seems his personal lab
is still being paid for
by one of Blood's holding companies.
STARFIRE: The Titans should
look into this.
Beast Boy's sending you
pictures of Terra's party.
Shame you're missing it.
You should go.
Playing with teenagers
is about your speed.
I'm not gonna let you bait me, kid.
Oh, what the hell.
(GRUNTS)
Big man.
Why not get me out of here
so I can defend myself properly?
-Unless you're afraid.
-Really?
You're down to hoping I'm gonna act
like the biggest stooge in a B-movie?
Your outfit said "Give it a shot."
(GRUNTS)
Grandson of the demon's head, you are not.
You're an entitled brat.
I rose from nothing
while you had everything handed to you.
You cost me my rightful place.
And the family you betrayed...
They turned on me by choosing you.
You took my old family, Damian.
So I'll take your new one.
(PHONE RINGING)
I should reply.
"I am well and will see you soon."
Hmm.
You're more of a dick.
"Undercover. Don't bother me."
It's a shame I don't have more time
to break you down.
Inside a month,
I'd have you bringing me my pipe
and calling me Papa.
TERRA: Slade!
Get your head out of your ass.
-You seeing this?
-And if we do find the scientist...
We want him alive at all costs.
We leave in five minutes.
Be a good boy.
(DOOR OPENING)
Careful. Watch your spacing.
(BEEPING)
BEAST BOY: Any idea what that gizmo is?
Nothing good.
He's deleting. I vote we stop that.
That makes two of us.
-(CHIRPING)
-Okay, three.
Step away from the computer.
You won't be hurt.
(ALARM BLARING)
(GRUNTS)
Go after him. I'll cover you.
(GASPING)
We should have stayed at the party.
Quit complaining.
Uh-oh!
(GRUNTS)
Oh, you wanna play?
That's it? Lame.
(GROANING)
What do you want to ask him first?
Bad luck for him.
At least it wasn't one of us.
Yes, bad luck.
That we couldn't speak with him
about these.
Maybe he was a fan?
STARFIRE: Is it really a surprise
they would study us?
We've been defeating them for months.
And you were after them even before that.
But this stuff is so in-depth.
Things on genetic makeup.
Theories on Raven's power.
Beast Boy's too.
And Beetle's suit.
What's it for?
We need to get Robin back here.
You know how stubborn he can be.
He's a Titan. He needs to be here.
Nothing like laser-spewing H.I.V.E. drones
to take you out of a party mood.
I'm beat and I'm making lunch
at the center tomorrow.
In more exciting news,
I've been invited to be
on Kevin Smith's podcast
at Metrocon tomorrow.
Hold up, Starfire's got something to say.
With what we discovered tonight,
we all need to be extra vigilant
and not take any chances.
Are you kidding me? It's Kevin Smith.
I didn't say don't do
what you have planned.
But keep your eyes and comm lines
open at all times.
I have a feeling
whatever Blood is planning,
tonight is just a prelude.
(CROAKING)
Sorry your party was interrupted.
That's the way it goes.
Don't let all that talk back there
shake you up.
You know I got your back.
It's other stuff.
Like what?
I'm all ears.
You have a pretty smile.
Do you know how I became an orphan?
Uh, your parents died?
No.
After I got powers, they freaked.
Thought I was possessed or something.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I don't need your pity.
It can be a bond, you know?
Everyone on the team's had it rough.
Yeah.
I can tell Princess Sparkle Thong
knows all about eating from a dumpster.
Kori is a refugee
being stalked by her homicidal sister.
Jaime has a family that loves him.
And, because of the bug, odds are
he's never seeing them face-to-face again.
I think pain is what makes a hero.
It's like a pressure that either
forms a diamond or grinds you into dust.
But what about you, Chuckles?
Aside from an unhealthy online presence,
you're normal.
Yeah, you're green.
You wouldn't change it if you could.
You like the attention.
Besides,
it looks okay on you.
Wow.
You didn't kill me.
This time.
Don't get used to it, jerk.
Yes! Yeah!
Whoo-hoo! Yeah, baby! Ha-ha!
(HOWLS)
Yeah! Oh, yeah!
Oh, yeah, baby!
Let's go!
(HUMMING HAPPILY)
-DEATHSTROKE: Nice play.
-(GASPS)
Almost bought it myself.
We move tomorrow.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
I'm tired, Gar.
Yeah, sure, totally get it.
See you tomorrow. And the next day.
Whoo!
Yeah, I got them all in.
Hey, I know I'm a noob, but I got this.
See you when you get here, Traci.
The guest of honor
with a million followers is...
Uh, here?
Hello?
Kevin? Other guy?
(WATCH ALARM BEEPS)
I think we should look over
the files again this afternoon.
Make sure we didn't miss anything.
Oh!
NIGHTWING: Sure thing.
And per your orders,
I'll check on Jaime and Gar.
(GASPS) You don't have to do that,
but thanks.
By the way...
The warlords of Okaara
didn't teach me much about cooking.
I think you should pick something up
on the way back.
See you soon, babe.
Hmm...
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
What's going on?
Not sure. It should be open.
We got a new guy.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(BEEPING)
Jaime?
Argh!
(GROANS)
Titans, Blue Beetle has been taken.
Gather at the Tower.
(PHONE RINGING)
-This is Kori...
-And Dick. We're not home now.
BOTH: So leave a message.
Starfire, pick up if you're there.
I'm going to get Beast Boy.
Get to the Tower now.
Argh!
(GROANS)
Oh, come on, Gar.
Kori, you here?
Kori.
Argh!
Bad day, Nightwing?
It's about to get worse.
What have you done
with Kori and the others?
Don't fret.
I'm here to take you to them.
Bring it, asshole.
(GRUNTING)
Aikido needs work.
Your spacing's for shit.
(GRUNTING)
You're overrated, kid.
Damn it.
(GRUNTS)
Argh!
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Argh!
Enough.
Screw this.
(GROANS)
You could have died by the blade
with honor, Grayson.
Loser.
DEATHSTROKE: Is it done?
Yeah, we're good.
Argh!
(LATCH OPENS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
He's lying to you.
About everything.
He had you pegged from the start.
That's how he does it.
Mixing truth with lies.
You're so freaking annoying.
You don't know anything about him.
He saved me.
Let me guess, he kept you isolated.
Dependent.
Told you everyone was your enemy.
Trained you, ruthlessly.
And promised you exactly what you wanted.
Believe me, I know.
(GRUNTS)
-(SCREAMS)
-I've always hated you.
-You and all the others.
-(GROANING)
The Titans treated you like family.
And you threw it all away.
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
Stop...
Argh.
Can't I leave you for two minutes?
I can see why you want him dead.
(BEEPS)
What's wrong?
In a few hours, we're gone.
It's as good as done.
TERRA: Just glad this is over.
You've been in deep cover for a year.
It's perfectly normal
to have feelings for them.
But after this we can be together.
Just like you wanted.
Concentrate on that.
Computer, track Terra Markov's phone.
COMPUTER: Discovered, subject is moving.
I'll bet she is.
BROTHER BLOOD: Brothers and sisters,
I have spoken many times
about false gods.
These so—called heroes
with no allegiance to our cause
are nothing but secular idols
and must be ended.
This is the true house of faith
and I am the one true God.
Hail, Brother Blood. Hail, hail!
Today, I am claiming
their powers for us all.
For we are the seeds
of the next generation.
We are the hive of humanity.
And nothing will stand in our way.
Praised be this holy day.
The day of blood.
CROWD: Hail, Brother Blood. Hail...
Place gives me the creeps.
I hear you.
Ugh...
Huh? Guys, Raven's not moving.
Something's keeping me
from using my powers to morph.
DEATHSTROKE: Yeah,
the machine's doing that.
But I'm the one who put you here.
Deathstroke.
What have you done to Robin?
I beat the crap out of him
for being mouthy.
Come on, you've all had the urge.
Once I get out,
I'm gonna break you into little bits.
It's good to have goals, ese.
Me, I'm having waffles after you're dead.
By the way,
can I introduce you to my assistant?
I think you've met.
Hey, team, how's things?
Terra, what did he do to you?
Nothing. And I've asked a bunch of times.
Terra was a key part of my plan.
A natural double agent.
That can't be true.
What can I tell you, Goldilocks?
You win some, you lose some.
We took you in.
Helped you.
Yeah, well, thanks.
Now you're gonna die.
Geez, not a lot of gray area there, huh?
Terra...
Place reminds me of my parents' church.
Bunch of crazies.
Insolent trash.
Who you calling trash?
Keep it together.
Let's be civil to our guests.
Our business is not yet complete.
Sure it is.
You wanted the Titans, and here they are.
Not all of them.
Not Nightwing.
lt ruins the machine's symmetry.
We agreed some deaths
might be unavoidable.
Things happen.
I accept that.
But I told you even in death
there is life to be drawn.
Where is the body?
Unless you have a body, you're one short.
Therefore, our contract is not complete.
Happily, there is still a path
to the salvation of our deal.
Don't you agree?
Excellent.
Mayhem.
Argh.
Terra!
(GROANING)
Ugh.
Oh...
I should have charged more.
With her powers,
you're getting an upgrade.
(BEEPING)
Amen.
Now, our business is complete.
Slade, help me.
Sorry, kid. But a contract is a contract.
You'll pay for this.
Oh, it's a shame you have to go,
sweet cheeks.
We would have been fantastic lovers.
You know, since we're both newly single.
(MACHINE RUNNING)
Let it begin!
(CROWD CHEERING)
You think yourself a holy man, Blood?
You're filth.
Take heart, sinner.
You are about to become
part of the greater good.
We're gonna show you the greater good.
By kicking your ass.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
No God is going to save you, Deathstroke.
Word to the wise, Blood,
whatever you're gonna do to them,
do it quickly.
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
(SCREAMING)
Not feeling so good.
I consider their pain
a retribution for their sins against me.
Right.
Have a nice day.
Oh, don't leave now, brother.
Everyone stays for this part.
What part is that, brother?
When their powers are transferred
and I ascend to god state.
Hail me, brethren,
for the moment of ascendency has arrived.
CROWD: Hail, Brother Blood. Hail, hail.
Hail, Brother Blood. Hail, hail.
Hail, Brother Blood. Hail...
Yes, my children, this vessel
shall now transform me...
And you are witness.
(CHANTING) Hail, Brother Blood.
Hail, hail.
I feel it.
Yes!
My godhood is nearly complete.
Praise him.
All hail Brother Blood.
(ALL CHANTING) Hail, hail.
Yes...
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
I knew you'd come.
(GROANING)
(CROWD SHOUTING)
Hey, Papa, here's your pipe.
Argh.
Save some for me.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
Slade!
Don't you know I am the chosen?
Don't you know I am divine--
(GRUNTING, GROANING)
TERRA: Slade!
I'm gonna kill you!
I was being studied, like all the rest,
wasn't I?
You planned this right from the start.
Calm down.
This is all a big misunderstanding, love.
NIGHTWING: Terra, no.
Oh, shit.
You heathen brats.
You've destroyed my holy temple!
Argh!
You've robbed me of my destiny.
You will die!
You cannot harm...
(BLEATING)
No, you stay away from me.
You demon filth!
They're not demons.
Let me show you one.
(CHANTING)
What the hell?
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
I planned so long.
I was destined, can't you see?
Please, I beseech you.
I am Blood.
I...
I am...
Saved.
I won't let them cage you, my love.
Come on.
(GASPS)
Argh!
So long, kid.
(SCREAMING)
Terra...
I'm sorry.
No, Terra...
(SCREAMING)
-No...
-We have to go.
The place is gonna collapse.
Terra!
So, let me ask you this, man,
how do you become a Titan exactly?
I mean, is there an audition?
Do you look at videos?
'Cause I've been working out, you know,
I want in.
BEAST BOY: Well, Kev, I guess
the most important thing to being a Titan
is to have a strong sense of family.
Some of us don't have our own,
so we support the ones that do.
Of course, an outgoing personality
doesn't hurt, but, you know,
you gotta have a power.
-Something cool.
-Something cool?
Listen, you turn into animals, man,
that's beyond cool.
Thanks.
But it's not just about
the cool super powers,
snazzy uniforms and daring adventures.
It's about us helping each other grow.
Be better people.
(WHINING)
KEVIN: Listen, I know you're not
supposed to talk about this,
but I just gotta ask.
There's a new girl, right?
BEAST BOY: All I can say is that
she's a wonderful addition to the team.
-Come on, Gar...
-Starﬁre would kill me.
KEVIN: There's no way Starﬁre is
listening to this, man,
she's brushing her hair.
Forget it. My lips are sealed.
Whoa, man, he just turned into
a seal, folks, I swear.
But really, Gar, is she gonna,
like, replace Terra?
Terra?
Yeah, you know,
there are lots of stories about her.
I know.
Ooh, too soon?
Yeah.
I mean, that's cool, honestly,
if you don't wanna--
But I'd like to say something.
There are a lot of people
who've been handed a rough life.
They never asked for it, but...
They do what they can.
Many of them can't rise above the hurt.
It's just too hard.
But in the end, when the chips were down,
and she finally showed her true self,
Terra Markov was like a diamond.
Most beautiful thing that I'd ever seen.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
BROTHER BLOOD: I talk to the dead,
for no matter how rotted the corpse,
there's always a tiny wisp of life left.