Subtitles by DramaFever
Soon Shin.
Teacher.
- Mi Ryung.
- Teacher.
What are you doing here?
Soon Shin, I need to talk to you.
What are you talking about?
- Get off.
- Can we talk please?
- Soon Shin...
- Let's go.
- We need to talk.
- Let's go, Mi Ryung.
- I'll go get a doctor.
- Okay.
What's wrong with you, Mi Ryung?
Get your head straight.
What were you going to say to her?
You said her name is Kyung Sook, right?
You didn't throw away that picture yet?
Since when did they know each other?
Why are you asking me that
this early in the morning?
You said she chased him.
Didn't they date each other?
How serious was the relationship?
What are you doing all of a sudden?
You said you weren't jealous
of her the other day.
I'm not jealous.
Mother, tell me the details.
Jeong Ae.
Have a seat there.
What is it?
Is Soon Shin's birth mother Kyung Sook?
She is.
No.
Why are you hiding it from me?
Just tell me.
She is, isn't she?
I said no.
I don't want you to
talk about this anymore.
I am okay now.
I don't care if that's
Kyung Sook or whoever now.
So don't be so curious about it.
- Jeong Ae.
- Mother, please.
I'm home.
Were you talking about important stuff?
No. It's nothing.
[Song Mi Ryung]
Soon Shin.
I guess she felt sorry for me.
What were you doing, Mr. Hwang?
Why didn't you pick her up early?
This could have been bad.
- I...
- What else were you doing?
She was carried to a hospital by Soon Shin.
Does that even make sense?
I'll keep my eye on her.
Thank you, Yeon Ah. You can leave now.
You must be busy.
No. Don't mention it.
I want to stay here tonight. I'm going to
go home when I see you're getting better.
It's okay. I'm all better now.
It was just stomach cramps.
Are you kidding me?
You still look pale.
I said I'm okay.
You can leave.
Why don't you go upstairs and rest?
I said I'm okay!
I want to be alone.
Please go home. Please.
Mom...
What are you doing today?
What? I'm not doing
anything special. Why?
Then come to the
mineral spring with me.
I haven't done any exercise
in a long time.
Don't say no to that. Let's go take
a walk and get some fresh air.
You also need some exercise.
Grandma, can I join you too? No.
How about we all go together?
Aunt Soon Shin, I have to go to class.
I'm sorry. I have to go work.
I have a lot to finish.
Yeah. I know you guys are busy.
Just take care of your stuff.
I only need Jeong Ae.
Grandma, let Soon Shin and me join you.
I'll make some Kimbob.
That sounds great.
You're okay with that, right?
You said you are going work.
Why are you so dressed up?
I'm not dressed up.
Bye.
Are you going somewhere?
I'm meeting my college colleague.
I see.
I was going to ask if you want
to go to the mall with me.
You need some summer jackets anyway.
Go with Chan Mi today.
You can also buy what you want with this.
I'm okay.
I don't need anything.
I have some money too.
Buy some clothes for you. I make money too.
You don't have to work as hard as before.
Go hang out.
The weather is nice.
Thank you. You're a good son.
You're the only one who makes me happy.
Don't drink too much with your friends.
Take care of your body.
Yes, Mom.
Why are you so late?
Is everything okay?
My family will come out soon.
They asked me to go on a
hike but I lied to them.
Let's go before anybody sees us.
Okay.
Mom, give me a cup of coffee too.
Sure.
You can have this.
Hey, did Mi Ryung
say something to you?
Like what?
I told you how she was being
so rude to me, right?
Didn't she apologize about that?
No.
How could she do that?
How could she not call me to apologize?
That's who she is.
Just let it go.
Yeah, maybe I should.
I'm going to work.
You work on Sunday too?
- Yeah.
- Did you get a haircut?
Hey, Soo Jeong.
Did you make it home safely that day?
That day?
Oh, that day...
Yes, I did make it home safely.
Mi Ryung.
How could you do this to me?
Don't you feel sorry for me?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I must've been very drunk that day.
But still.
You shouldn't have done that. Do you know
how much I was embarrassed and humiliated?
Doctor Park was too.
I know. I'm sorry.
Are you really sorry?
Then you should've
called to appologize.
How could you say I spoiled my
kid in front of everybody?
Of course, it's not like I don't understand.
This is why I keep telling you
to get married.
If you live alone for a long time,
your mind gets twisted.
You should get married
and have a baby.
That's providence of nature.
But if you don't follow that,
your mind gets twisted.
Are you done talking, Soo Jeong?
Don't be so upset about what I say.
I was really upset that day.
I'm sorry.
Just like you said,
my mind gets twisted.
You happy now?
Who was it, Mom?
What made her so change like this?
Honey, what's wrong with her?
It was Mrs. Song, wasn't it?
Oh my God.
Her mind is getting sicker.
You are so harsh on her.
What did I do?
I can't tell if you're making
fun of her or comforting her.
Oh my.
How could you say that?
Find out what I meant.
Hey, Yi Jung.
What does that mean?
I think he's taking her side.
What?
Oh my God,
you prepared food by yourself?
I'm going out for a walk.
Okay, ma'am.
Don't you feel great being outside,
Grandma?
Yeah.
This place reminds me of Dad.
I wish Dad was here with us now.
Yeah. Your dad came here with you a lot.
He took care of you more than anybody.
- I didn't understand why he did that but now..
- Mother...
Jeong Ae, Chang Hoon is a bad son.
How could he leave us like that?
We all miss him a lot.
Grandma...
She just misses Dad a lot.
Grandma, have some fruit.
I'm okay. You eat.
Long time no see, Chang Hoon.
Long time no see.
You live in this neighborhood?
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
I also live in this neighborhood.
I just moved here.
I see.
It's nice seeing you.
I'm out of breath.
Do you want to take a rest?
No. Let's keep going.
Have some water.
Sure.
Grandma, you've gotten so old now.
You went on hikes with us sometimes last year.
I'm healthier than other women my age.
You're right.
The air is so fresh here.
Teacher Song.
Who is she?
She's Teacher Song Mi Ryung.
An actress.
She taught me acting.
Are you feeling better?
Yes, I'm better.
Bye.
That's Song Mi Ryung?
Yeah. She lives in the upper town.
- Mom, let's go.
- Okay.
Let's go.
Mi Ryung.
Why are you so surprised?
Il Do, put this house up for sale.
What?
Put this house up for sale right now.
I'm moving out.
Why so sudden?
Did something happen?
Mom, are you okay?
Yeah.
I didn't know she lives
in this neighborhood.
What a small world.
Don't tell Grandma about this.
There's nothing for her to know.
Don't tell her.
Understand?
Give me a glass of water too.
Jeong Ae, the woman we saw...
Oh my God, I totally forgot to do the laundry.
What was I thinking?
I'll talk to you later.
Aren't you hungry?
Are you not going to eat?
What?
What are thinking about?
Nothing.
- Isn't this delicious?
- Yeah, it is.
- Yoo Shin.
- Yes?
Can we just tell our family about us?
Did you forget the rules? We break up
the moment our families find out about us.
I know,
but we can't avoid them forever.
And it's tiring to hide this from out families.
It will get more tiring if they know.
Yon know how it is
between your mom and I.
She's not going to stand it
if she finds out we're dating.
Mom isn't that bad.
If you two try to understand each other...
Do you know what she said to
me at your family restaurant?
Did something happen?
Never mind.
I would rather not tell you.
By the way, who did you meet that day?
- What?
- That day.
You didn't even answer my call.
My director invited me to his house.
Why did he invite you to his house?
We just had dinner.
Drink the coffee before it gets cold.
I'm home.
Hey, Mom.
How was the hike?
Was it okay?
Yeah.
Go take a rest.
Hey.
Did something happen while hiking?
Nothing happened except
we ran into Teacher Song.
Teacher Song?
You mean Song Mi Ryung?
Yeah, we ran into each other.
What does that matter to Mom
that she looks so depressed?
What's wrong with Mom?
She looks really depressed.
How is Song Mi Ryung?
Is she pretty?
She is.
I think she got depressed because
Song Mi Ryung is pretty.
That's not true.
Mom is so much prettier.
I know you love Mom.
But that's not true.
Mom aged a lot
after Dad passed away.
And you helped her get old to
by making Mom upset.
She is Kyung Sook.
I'm sure she is Kyung Sook.
I need to get over this.
I have to.
[Lee Soon Shin]
[Choi Yeon Ah]
Teacher, I made abalone porridge for you.
I heard you haven't eaten
anything since yesterday.
Please have one bite at least.
I said I'm okay.
Why did you make that?
Can't you tell me what's wrong?
Did something happen at the studio?
No.
I'm really sad when you do this sometimes.
When I get sad or tired,
I tell you everything.
What am I to you?
Don't say that.
I'm just tired.
- Is she that sick?
- She just had severe stomach cramps.
She's okay now.
- How did you know that anyway?
- I called him.
He's the head of her entertainment company.
I think he doesn't care about his actresses.
Don't you think you're
being careless with her?
So what happened?
Are there some problems with a
movie director or something?
A problem I don't know about?
It's not that.
Yeon Ah, you're making it a big deal.
You don't look so well though.
I skipped my exercise and was busy with
interviews and shootings. That's all.
I'm old, you know.
I didn't take care of my health.
I will from today.
Is that all?
What else would there be?
You must be busy.
You can leave.
But still...
You sure you canceled the
contract with the girl?
Who?
Lee Soon Shin?
Yeah.
Soon Shin.
You helped me do it.
Joon Ho.
Can we talk?
Thank you.
So what is it you want talk about?
You have changed, Joon Ho.
Why are you being so cold to me?
Am I?
Well... You've always been like this.
When we were dating,
you were like this.
'This guy really loves me
and only cares about me.'
I was sure about that.
But once you get mad,
you're like a different person.
You were so cold to me.
What do you want to say?
I'm really confused now.
Wasn't it me you wanted
a few weeks ago?
You made the bet just
because so you can have me.
That's what I believed.
I honestly wanted you to win the bet.
Was I wrong?
Yeon Ah.
Just like you left me
because you changed...
I changed too.
I'm not stupid enough
to believe in love anymore.
Is this because of Lee Soon Shin?
Do you like her?
- No.
- Then what is it?
Fine. I made the bet
because of my pride.
I was only thinking about winning
the bet and making you lose.
But wh?
What made you change?
Don't you feel sorry for her?
We used Soon Shin for our little game.
If you were her,
how would you feel?
I'm just cleaning up
the mess that I made.
I can at least do that for her.
I have to go.
Bye.
Is that true?
Did that really happen to you?
I was reading it for fun, you know.
- Soon Shin.
- Yes?
Are you still attached to that?
Attached to this?
No.
I got fooled more than enough.
I'm not attached to this at all.
Never ever.
I'm taking a shower.
No matter how hard I think,
this isn't right.
We promised that if
the business goes well
we're going to prepare for the GED so I can go to
college for me and you can finish high school.
I don't remember that.
Now you remember?
That hurts, man.
It's supposed to hurt.
Wait here.
You came to buy some books?
Yes.
You read this kind of book?
No. I'm reading it for translation.
- Translation?
- Yes.
You must be so good at English.
So you can read this book as
if you read a Korean book?
No, no.
I'm not that good.
You have to be good to translate this.
The English words I know are...
Thank you. I'm sorry. Big Bang. Top. Sister.
And mother, father, gentleman.
That's it.
[GED for College]
This isn't my book.
When I was in a jail... No, no, no.
- I meant the bakery...
- Hey, dude.
I'm leaving.
Good luck on the GED.
Fighting!
Fighting GED.
Actually...
I couldn't get into college.
Because my family was poor.
My parents passed away
when I was little.
And I was raised by my grandma.
Her one and only wish was
to see me go to college.
I couldn't fulfill her wish before she died.
Since my business is going well,
I just want to try.
Your grandmother will
be so happy in Heaven.
I'm...
I'm Seo Jin Wook.
Pardon?
Come to think of it, you don't
even know my name yet.
I'm Lee Hye Shin.
I see. Hye Shin.
Grandma, Jin Wook is starting to study.
I'm all grown up now.
You should've waited for me.
You left me too quickly.
I miss you.
Please welcome Son Mi Ryung
and Choi Yeon Ah.
What a brazen woman...
- How long have you been there?
- Go back to that chanel.
What?
I want to take a look at that woman.
Go back to that channel.
Mother...
You don't have to hide it from me.
Why are you trying to hide this from me?
What am I hiding from you?
I'm not hiding anything from you.
Yeah, I understand how you feel.
You don't have to tell me.
I understand.
Where are you going?
Where do you think I'm going?
I'm going to go water the garden.
Hello...
Mrs. Lee, what are you doing here?
Have a seat over there.
S-sure.
You shouldn't do this to me.
Pardon?
What are you talking about?
Soon Shin is Kyung Sook's daughter,
isn't she?
What?
What does Kyung Sook do for living?
Tell me where and what she does.
I know you know everything,
but you're hiding it from me.
Mrs. Lee...
Song Mi Ryung is Kyung Sook,
isn't she?
She is...
No, Mrs. Lee.
It's not that. It's...
The beacon does not shine on its own base.
I'm home.
Hey.
Hello.
Long time no see, Chan Mi.
What are you doing here?
Is everything okay?
She came to visit me.
That's all.
Mrs. Lee, would you like Sprite?
Are you making tea?
Make some ginger tea for Grandma.
She's not home.
Where did she go?
Hello?
Hi, Mrs. Lee.
It's Shin Joon Ho.
I have something to tell you.
What is it?
Have a seat, please.
How have you been?
Good.
Is Soon Shin doing well?
Yes, she's doing well.
I thought we were done talking about this.
Yes, you're right.
I'm sorry for making you worry
about your daughter.
I just want to ask you one last favor.
What favor?
Soon Shin was so happy when
she was learning acting.
I'm positive about that.
I think she shouldn't give up on what
she wants just because of me.
Mrs. Lee, please help her act again.
I admit that I wasn't trustworthy.
Help her go to a different agency
and keep learning how to act.
She will do just fine.
Mother, you must be hungry.
I'll go prepare dinner.
You! Why didn't you tell
me about this earlier?
Follow me.
I heard everything.
I've given it a lot of thought,
and I think it's Kyeong Sook.
Where did you hear that?
That was why she was so crazy
about being an actress?
Blood sure is thicker than water.
Now everything makes sense to me.
How did you go through this
by yourself?
You must've been so painful
to go through this.
Mother...
Please let's just pretend
none of this happened.
I have been through this already.
I'm okay now.
I even talked to that woman.
You met her?
You met Kyung Sook?
Yeah. We talked and it's all done.
She doesn't want Soon Shin back.
She told me to raise her.
What?
She really said that?
Yeah.
She's so shameless.
She's so spiteful.
You should've pulled out
her hair or something.
Wait. I'm going to go
talk to that bitch.
Please don't do that.
Don't do that?
Aren't you mad?
Aren't you upset?
I'm going to go talk
to her and scold her.
Mother, I told you it's all over.
If Soon Shin finds out about this,
things will be more complicated.
Mother, I really want to forget about this.
Chang Hoon...
You caused all these problems
and then left us?
- Hi.
- There you are.
- Boss.
- Yes?
I'm working only until this week.
I'm done training the new waitress.
I heard that.
Thank you for everything
you've done for me.
The weather is nice.
Do you want to get some coffee?
The weather is really nice.
Do you want to go to a park?
Sure.
So what's your plan for the future?
I don't know.
I'm going keep looking.
Then how about you keep working here
until you find what you want to do?
Actually, I want to do that too.
But if I keep coming here, I'll be attached
to this whole acting thing. I feel so small.
Why do you think like that?
Don't feel small.
You're the best, Boss.
You know what, Soon Shin?
I wish you could keep acting.
What?
You were so pretty while doing that.
When?
When you were preparing for the audition.
You looked so happy.
You were glowing and pretty.
Try to read your heart.
Think of what can really
make your heart beat.
I think there's only one way
to find the right answer.
It's your heart.
See if your heart is beating.
Cheer up! That's your strength. No matter
what you go through, you're always cheerful.
An iron will, Lee Soon Shin.
Thank you, Boss.
Let's go.
I don't care about her anymore.
It's all over now.
I did what I could do for her.
She smiles at everybody.
She laughs easily.
- Something bad happened.
- What is it again?
- It's about Song Mi Ryung.
- What is it?
You remember her rumor that
might have been an issue?
Rumor?
They're trying to make a big
issue out of that again.
They said her past is all
fake and she had a daughter.
What?
I thought the rumor faded away.
I think someone is writing
a follow-up story.
What should we do?
Where's Mr. Hwang?
What do you want, Reporter Park?
What do I want?
There's nothing I want.
Reporter Park, I'll do anything.
I'll do everything you want.
Just tell me.
Don't do this.
I don't work like this.
Then why are you so obsessed with this?
Why in the world are you doing this?
What's so good about ostracizing her?
You...
Give me one second, Reporter Park.
Hi, Mr. Shin.
Yes, yes.
I'm sorry.
I have another appointment.
Wait.
Reporter Park. Wait!
Here comes the chicken.
Enjoy.
Hello, Mrs. Lee?
Where's Song Mi Ryung's house?
What?
Tell me. Where is it?
Are you going to go see her?
Excuse me.
Let me ask you something.
Sure.
I heard Song Mi Ryung
lives around here.
Do you know where she lives?
Mother.
Where did she go?
Bok Man?
Is Mrs. Lee home?
No. She was home a second ago.
But she's not now.
This isn't good. I think she's
on her way to see Kyung Sook.
What?
You have a visitor.
- Who?
- She said she's Soon Shin's grandmother.
What?
Long time no see, Kyung Sook.
You live in a nice house.
It's such a nice house.
Have a seat.
- You can go home.
- Okay.
Kyung Sook,
you shouldn't have done that.
Don't call me like that.
I'm Song Mi Ryung.
Why are you to tell me to do that?
To me, you're Kyung Sook.
Kim Kyung Sook.
Where are you going at this late hour?
Hye Shin, you should come with me.
Where?
Your grandmother went to
see Song Mi Ryung.
What?
Let's go.
Is there anything you want
to say to me now?
What do you mean?
You haven't changed at all.
You're as brazen as before.
Are you even a human being?
How the hell could a human
do a thing like this?
What do you mean?
What did I do?
Do you know what problem
you caused my family?
Do you know what my daughter-in-law
had to go through because of you?
How am I supposed to know?
That was your daughter.
You left her with my family.
How could you even live with that?
Aren't you ashamed of showing yourself
in front of everybody as an actress?
Well... I guess you could do that
because you've lived such a lowly life.
You probably don't know
what's right and wrong.
Watch your mouth.
Tell me everything from the beginning.
I know Chang Hoon is not that type of person.
He didn't even blink his eyes at you.
What happened?
You still fall at his feet,
just like the old times.
Why do you always think
whatever you want?
Who was clinging to whom?
You don't know anything.
What?
You think it's unfair that your
family raised my daughter?
Then why didn't you approve of
me and Chang Hoon's marriage?
I have nothing to say to you.
I didn't tell him to raise my daughter.
That's what Chang Hoon and his wife decided.
I didn't tell him to do that.
If you came here just to ask you
that question, please leave.
How dare you come to my place without my
permission? Do you even know who I am?
Kyung Sook...
I'm not Kim Kyung Sook.
Didn't you hear from your daughter-in-law?
I told her to think that none of this happened.
- You're such a bitch.
- Don't swear to me! How dare you?
You said I live a lowly life. I don't think
you have the right to say that.
Il Do, show her the door.
I think this old bag lost her way.
What are you doing?
How could you do this to me?
Get off!
You're a bitch!
- Mother!
- Grandma!
I'm sorry, Jeong Ae.
I'm so sorry.
My son did what he wasn't supposed to.
I'm sorry.
She's such a bitch!
A bad bitch.
She didn't even say sorry.
Mother.
Why did you go there?
Stop drinking.
Il Do, that old bag thinks
I'm still Kim Kyung Sook.
How dare she treat me like this?
Calm down.
- Go upstairs and rest.
- Who told them to raise her?
Who told them to do that?
Get up.
If she's so upset about this,
should I take her back?
She's my daughter.
I can take her back.
- Are you crazy?
- Why not? You think I can't?
Don't even say that.
Don't even think about it.
Don't you know what situation you are in?
If this is exposed to the public,
what do you think it's going happen to you?
What's going to happen to me?
Mi Ryung.
Aren't you afraid of Soon Shin's father?
You think you can keep in touch
with her family?
What have I done wrong?
What did I do? Tell me.
People are going to find
out eventually anyway.
Even that old bag knows about this.
This isn't a secret anymore.
Wake up. You're going to lose
everything you have then.
I'm not going to lose anything.
I'm going to take her back from that family.
Don't stop me.
I'm going to take her back!
Subtitles by DramaFever