MARIJUANA:
THREAT
THREAT or MENACE?
- Marijuana, the dried leaves and flowers
of the Indian hemp weed,
- is used in the form
of a cigarette.
- Marijuana smoking,
experts point out,
- can make a helpless addict
of it's victim within weeks,
- causing physical and
moral ruin and death.
- Should you ever
be confronted,
- with the temptation of taking that
first puff of a marijuana cigarette,
- don't do it!
GRASS
Anything to get a kick,
Anything to get a blast,
Anything to palm his mind,
Potheads!
They think they can
go out and get high,
They think they can get
turned on with pot,
They can get loaded,
they can get stoned!
57% of the student
party was smoking pot,
Smoking pot, pot, pot,
It fascinates,
and then assassinates,
And then it kills!
A drug epidemic that's
sweeping our nation,
Anything to get a kick,
Anything to get a blast,
Anything to palm his mind,
Quit playing games with God!
English subtitles by Goblim
goblim@hotmail.com
The Official TRUTH
If you smoke it...
You Will Kill People
"HIGH ON THE RANGE" (1929)
"Chick gave 'em to me - a
new kind of cigarette."
"They're Marihuana weed, a devilish
narcotic; and if you smoke them,
you go bughouse, loco, and
want to raise h--- in general."
I'd like to try one just to see
what effect it would have on me.
When the day's work is done...
"There's to much Marihuana smoking
on this ranch and I'm going to stop it!"
"Why did you do it, Dave?"
La cucaracha
Although people around the world have been
smoking marijuana for thousands of years,
the custom only reach the United States
at the beginning of the 20th century,
LAREDO, TEXAS circa 1912
when it arrived in the south west,
with the wave of Mexicans
looking for work.
Porque le falta
Marijuana que fumar!
- Badge, please.
- Next!
To these
poor laborers,
smoking marijuana
was a way to relax,
after a long day of
working in the fields.
But white Americans
along the border,
didn't much like these foreigners
or their strange customs.
Marijuana, it was rumored, gave
the Mexicans super-human strength,
and turned them into
blood-thirsty murderers.
ALIEN WEED MAKES
MAN INTO KILLER
One evening in El Paso, some white
Texans where allegedly attacked,
by a Mexican that went
crazy on the killer weed.
Moving swiftly the El Paso city council
passed a law banning possession of marijuana.
Supposedly designed
to control marijuana,
they law quickly became a way
for the city to control Mexicans.
El Paso Ordinance 1914
PASSED
Unlike the people of El Paso,
most Americans had never
even heard of marijuana.
They were more concerned
about the rising addiction,
to opium, morphine, cocaine and heroin,
which were all serious public health issues.
But instead of treating drug addiction
as a public health problem,
TREASURY DEPARTMENT
Washington, D.C. circa 1930
the federal government put control of these
drugs in the hands of the Treasury Department,
who created the Federal
Bureau of Narcotics.
- Rolling!
HARRY J. ANSLINGER
Commissioner
Federal Bureau of Narcotics
- This is Harry J. Anslinger, commissioner
of the Federal Bureau of Narcotics.
- Sorry...
- The Treasury Department intends
to pursuit a relentless warfare,
- against the despicable dope-peddling vulture
who prays on the weakness of his fellow man,
- Hold!
Americas first drug czar
was Harry J. Anslinger.
A law and order evangelist, Anslinger
would shape Americas attitude,
toward marijuana for
generations to come.
FAMILY • TEMPERANCE • PLEDGE
GOD BLESS OUR HOME
Like many Americans, Anslinger
was a prohibitionist.
These morally correct citizens,
sincerely felt that progress
could only be achieved,
by controlling the depraved
impulses of the masses.
- Swordfish.
He believed that if the laws where tough
enough, America could be rid of alcohol.
Put enough people in jail,
and eventually the public
will learn to behave.
And he applied this same philosophy
on mounting the government's war on drugs.
Special treasury agent are
part of a massive force,
U.S. WARS ON DOPE
created solely to control
the traffic in narcotics.
U.S. WARS ON DOPE
- You got any merchandise
obtaining in Canada or abroad?
- Have you any liquor?
- No.
- Get out of the car and
let's take a look at it.
- Come on.
Move over, J. Edgar Hoover,
here come the agents of the
Federal Bureau of Narcotics!
Like J. Edgar Hoover,
Anslinger posed for the cameras,
creating the impression he was smashing
one major dope ring after another.
But he found it pretty quickly
that policing 48 states,
on a depression-strapped
budget was impossible.
His solution was to try to convince the
states to police local drug traffic themselves.
Campaigning tirelessly he *** each
state to sign a join agreement,
to commit state resources
to fighting drugs.
But only nine
states signed on.
The other 39 viewed it as federal
interference in their affairs.
It was a major defeat for
the young drug commissioner,
but he wasn't the
type to give up.
NEW ORLEANS, LOUISIANA circa 1919
Meanwhile marijuana, carried
by west Indian sailors,
arrived in port cities
like New Orleans.
Known as 'muggles',
'tea', or 'reefer',
it was popular with the jazz crowd
because it made music sound so good.
From here, musicians carried
it up the Mississippi,
to urban centers in the North.
Have you ever met
that funny reefer man?
Cab Calloway in
"INTERNATIONAL HOUSE" (1933)
If he says he swam to China
and wants to sell you South Carolina,
then you know you're
talking to that reefer man!
Have you ever met
that funny reefer man?
Oh that funny, funny
funny reefer man?
If he trades you dimes for nickels
he says watermelons are pickles,
then you know you're
talking to that reefer man!
Have you ever met
that funny reefer man?
Oh that funny, funny
funny reefer man?
He smokes a reefer, he gets
high then he flies to the sky,
that funny, funny
funny reefer man!
"Reefer" Parties
on South Side
"Muggles" Replaces
Liquor in Harlem
With marijuana showing
up in big cities,
JAZZ MUSICIANS
BLOW "TEA"
Anslinger realized it might
be the answer to his problem.
If he could persuade
white America,
that marijuana was
a deadly menace,
frightened voters might
push their state legislators,
to sign on his
Uniform Narcotics Act.
THE NEW OFFICIAL TRUTH
If you smoke it...
YOU WILL GO
INSANE
"REEFER MADNESS" (1936)
- Faster!
- Play faster!
- Faster...
- Play faster...
- Faster.
- I know what you want.
- You wanna kill me!
- In this case the state weighs
trial with defendant Ralph Wiley,
- it is convinced that he is
hopelessly and incurably insane,
- a condition cause by the drug
marijuana to which he was addicted.
- It is recommended your honor,
- that the defendant be placed in an institution for
the criminally insane for the rest of his natural life.
- I see no reason why the
request should not be granted.
Wrap your ***
*** distinct of tea
Blow this hay
and get high with me
Determined to get the act passed,
Anslinger unleashed a media campaign
to make the public believe,
that this little known plant growing
at the side of little roads,
was the biggest threat
America had ever faced.
Parents beware: your children
homeward bound from school,
are being introduced
to a new danger,
in the form of a drug cigarette:
Marijuana!
A Chicago mother watching her daughter
die as an indirect result of marijuana addiction,
text from Harry J. Anslinger Radio Address (1936)
told officers that at least 50 of the girls
young friends where slaves to the narcotic,
continuing addiction until
they deteriorate mentally,
become insane, and turn
to violent crime and murder.
MURDER!
INSANITY!
DEATH!
Extra, extra...
SCHOOLYARD
DOPE FIENDS!
Anslingers campaign was tailor
made for the lurid tabloid press,
and supported by an army of moralist
groups it captured the public's imagination.
Movietone News covering the
world to bring you the news!
He's a man that
smokes that jive,
that jive will take
you for a dive,
One slip you will arrive,
When you smoke that killing jive!
America is threatened
by a new drug menace:
FEDERAL T-MEN BARE
SECRETS OF NEW DRUG
America is threatened
by a new drug menace:
Street corner vendors whose stock-in-trade
is the deadly local weed marijuana,
pass it out in cigarette form.
From ingeniously
concealed containers,
the reefers go to the waiting
hands of deluded youngsters.
That feeling will arrive
When you smoke that killing jive!
A police find a city
backyard full of dope.
This innocent looking weed
is Mexican marijuana,
which when smoked produces
more nightmares than opium.
Captain Mooney of the narcotics squad
will tell us something about it:
- The constant use of these marijuana
cigarettes causes temporary insanity.
Yet you smoke
that killing jive!
- Let's go, Jack, I'm red-hot!
Our state voted for the
Uniform Narcotic Act,
and so should yours!
The propaganda campaign was successful
beyond Anslinger's wildest dreams.
One by one, state
after state signed on.
When you smoke that killing jive!
CAPITOL HILL
Washington D.C. circa 1937
- Gentlemen, take your seats.
But now, frightened out of their
minds, the American public,
demanded that the federal government
assed new laws to fight marijuana.
Terrified voters wanted action,
and their government responded.
Without any public debate, scientific
inquiry or political objection,
the Marijuana Tax Act was signed
into law by President Roosevelt.
JUNE 14, 1937
The act prohibited possession of
marijuana anywhere in the United States,
without a special tax stamp
from the Treasury Department,
and the Treasury Department
didn't give out any stamps,
effectively making marijuana illegal.
Over night a new class
of criminals was created.
MARIJUANA
TAX ACT of 1937
PASSED
- To the treasury agents of the Bureau
of Narcotics comes the job,
- of wiping out this traffic.
- And in 1937, we smashed
ten major narcotic rings.
- Only the cooperation of
an awakened public,
- Can make-would make...
- Ah, to hell with it!
The latest crave, the
country's rave is jive, jive, jive!
HUNDREDS ARRESTED
IN DRIVE ON DOPE
This modern treat
makes life complete,
Jive, jive, jive!
All the jive is gone
All the jive is gone,
I'm sorry, gate
but you got here late,
All the jive is gone!
All the jive is gone
So come on in
and drink some gin,
All the jive is gone!
The first person to be convicted
was Samuel R. Caldwell,
a 58 year old Denver man,
sentencing him to four years
hard labor at Leavenworth,
judge J. Foster Syme said:
"I consider marijuana the
worst of all narcotics."
"Under it's influence,
men become beasts."
"In the future, I will impose
the heaviest penalties."
"The government is going to enforce
this new law to the letter."
NEW YORK CITY circa 1937
- Prohibition cannot
be enforced,
- for the simple reason that the majority of
American people do not want it enforced,
FIORELLO LA GUARDIA
Mayor of New York
- and are resisting
it's enforcement.
- That being so,
the orderly thing to do,
- under our form
of government,
- is to abolish a law
which cannot be enforced,
- a law which the people of the
country do not want enforced!
New York’s prohibition fighting
mayor, Fiorello La Guardia,
was somewhat skeptical of
the government's claims,
that marijuana was causing murder,
rape, and destruction of Americas youth.
Wanting to get the facts,
he commissioned a study,
by a group of 31
impartial scientists.
After six years of medical and
sociological research,
the La Guardia
commission found:
Smoking marijuana did not lead to
violent or anti-social behavior;
Smoking marijuana did not cause
uncontrollable sexual urges;
Smoking marijuana did not alter a
persons basic personality structure.
Item by item, the commission’s report disproved,
every negative effect
claimed by Harry Anslinger.
THE MARIJUANA PROBLEM
IN THE CITY OF NEW YORK
Furious, Anslinger used
his influence with the press,
to have the
report discredited,
and destroyed every copy
he could get his hands on.
And by restricting the
supply of marijuana,
he put a stop to any
further research.
Not taking any chances,
Anslinger ordered his men
to dig up dirt on anyone,
who disagreed with him,
and going on the offensive, he targeted
the entertainment industry,
which he saw as a degenerate
moral influence.
Gene Krupa in
"DRUMMER MAN" (1947)
GENE KRUPA IS ARRESTED
Robert Mitchum in
"PURSUED" (1947)
- I told you I'd wait
until he was grown,
- but now he's grow
and he gets his legacy,
- only it's made
out of hemp.
MITCHUM NABBED IN
MARIJUANA RAID
Not wanting any trouble
with the government,
the Hollywood studios agreed to
give Anslinger personal control,
over all movie scripts
that mentioned drugs.
And movies he felt sent
the wrong message,
were just banned.
Canadian Film
Banned in the U.S.
WAR ON MARIJUANA
1937-1947
$220 MILLION
Official Replacement TRUTH
If you smoke it...
YOU WILL BECOME A
Heroin Addict!
Youth is a time for fun,
pranks and jokes,
"DRUG ADDICTION" (1951)
of ice cream cones
and chocolate sodas.
Youth is a time
for getting a job,
for finding one's
place in the world.
But sometimes, in
these troubled days,
the very thoughtlessness of youth
has led to a living nightmare:
Addiction to drugs.
- What's that?
- H.
- H? What's H?
- Shhh! Not so loud.
- It's heroin.
- Will it make me sick like the reefers did?
Marty's story is like
many of the others.
It started with
marijuana cigarettes.
- Come on, it's my turn next!
- Gee Duke, where did you get them?
- I... I know a guy.
- Three for a buck.
- Let me try.
He was determined to be one
of the gang, if it killed him.
And it almost did.
Several weeks later,
after smoking reefers,
Marty's befogged brain hit on a
clever way to open pop bottles.
Later Stan went to the hospital,
for swallowing broken glass.
Marty badly cut the inside of his mouth,
though he didn't even know it at the time.
Before long Marty
was hooked,
physically dependant on heroin.
Nothing mattered but the ever-
present craving for the drugs.
He had given up interest
in everything else.
I get no kick
from champagne
But the early 1950's,
concerned about marijuana,
was overshadowed
by a new media scare:
Rising heroin addiction
among teenagers who,
were drifting into crime
to support their habit.
"MY SON IS A
HEROIN ADDICT!"
TEEN JUNKIES
ON CRIME SPREE
- I want some
money old Sam.
- You're... you're crazy.
- The money!
- I know you. They put you in jail.
- Just get the money!
- No, no!
- Please, no!
This heroin scare gave
the aging Anslinger,
a new way to attack
marijuana and respond,
to anyone who might
doubt it's terrible danger.
Smoking marijuana,
he declared,
was a direct stepping
stone to heroin addiction.
Remember: Most "H" Users
Started On Marijuana
Satan is real
working in spirit,
You can see him, and hear him
in this world, every day
Satan is real
Working with power
He can tempt you
and lead you astray!
- An individual who tries
the drug just for fun,
"TEA, HORSE AND CRIME" (circa 1951)
- or experiments with it,
acts exactly like a person,
- who loads the gun,
puts a bullet in,
- puts it up to his head,
- very carefully, hopes for the
best, and pulls the trigger.
Please stand by.
Teenage narcotic addiction,
is there an answer?
CONFIDENTIAL FILE
- May I have your name, please.
- Robert M. Connolyn,
- Command of the detective bureau
Culver City police department, Culver City, California.
- Is there any general personality
traits that would apply to addicts?
- Well yes. Most of these
addicts are very sick,
- and they are a menace
and have to be arrested.
- I get a lot of self satisfaction
arresting those people.
- And what about teenage addiction,
how does that come about usually?
- They start out by using marijuana.
- And the most marijuana users,
- finally go on to hard stuff?
- Yes.
- What kind of changes could be made
to improve the narcotics situation,
- based on present
knowledge, Bob?
- Well Paul, the addict
is a sick guy.
- And anything that can be make through
legislation to make the penalty far greater,
- I'm sure would be appreciated by every
cop, on every beat throughout the country.
- Your name, please.
- Harry J. Anslinger.
SENATE CRIME HEARINGS 1951
- And your position and occupation?
- Federal Commissioner of Narcotics.
Appearing at the
Kefauver crime hearings,
Anslinger backed Senator
Hale Boggs proposal,
to increase penalties
for all drug offences.
Tougher penalties were needed he said,
because behind every narcotics peddler,
there was a communist, preparing
to overthrow our government.
COMMUNIST CHINA'S ROLE IN THE
INTERNATIONAL DRUG TRAFFIC
- According to all the documents
that we have been examining,
- today, the major
source is red China,
- And do you see a marked
increase in the amount of drugs,
- circulating this country which you believe come
from red China since China went communist in 1949?
- Oh, very much so.
- I think, under the nationalists they had
the situation pretty well under control.
- There were about a thousand
executions a year,
- under the nationalist
Chinese government,
- I haven't heard of anyone being
wounded under this regime.
Even though there was absolutely no proof
of a communist plot to dope up America,
the country was in the
grip of cold war hysteria,
and no politician could afford
to look soft on communism.
Taking Anslingers advice, President
Truman signed the Boggs Act,
which dramatically increased
penalties for possession,
and ordered mandatory
minimum sentences.
BOGGS ACT
BOGGS ACT 1951
PASSED
- There's a considerable amount
of heroin coming out of China,
DANIEL SUBCOMMITTEE HEARINGS 1955
- You mean red China?
- Red China, yes.
On a roll now, Anslinger agitated
for even tougher laws,
and got President Eisenhower
to push them through congress.
Narcotic Control Act
Narcotic Control Act 1956
PASSED
The Narcotic Control Act put marijuana
in the same category as heroin,
and made it subject
to the same penalty.
A first conviction
for possession,
was punished with a mandatory
prison term of 2 to 10 years.
In addition, a number of states
added their own penalties.
In Missouri, a second conviction
for possession could get you life.
- This is Lieutenant McGee,
Atlanta police...
the Atlanta police department.
- We got the stuff, right away before
the man had a chance to distribute it,
- Do you think this stopped
the entire operation?
- Yes sir,
- I'm sure of it.
- Have you ever seen anything like it before?
- No sir, not in my career I haven't,
- haven't seen that
much marijuana.
Ok I'm gonna get a
different lens on here...
UNITED NATIONS
New York circa 1961
Setting his sights higher,
Anslinger went to the UN,
and used Americas influence to
persuade over 100 countries,
to consolidate their various drug agreements
into a single, inflexible convention,
outlawing marijuana
around the world.
This was the ultimate achievement
in Anslinger's relentless crusade,
to criminalize
marijuana use.
SINGLE CONVENTIONS ON
NARCOTIC DRUGS 1961
SINGLE CONVENTIONS ON NARCOTIC DRUGS 1961
PASSED
- Quemando,
Quemando todo!
- To Harry Jacob Anslinger,
distinguished citizen,
- in your dedicated efforts
to combat the illegal traffic,
- in narcotic drugs, you have fashioned an
effective organization to pursuit this objective.
- your noteworthy
achievements in this field,
- have earned for you the
respect of the world community.
- Signed, John F. Kennedy.
In leaving the
bureau he'd built up,
under five
different presidents,
Anslinger warned
his successors,
of an impending
drug revolution,
which he felt would be nothing less than an
assault on the foundations of western civilization.
WAR on
MARIJUANA
WAR on MARIJUANA
1948-1963
WAR on MARIJUANA 1948-1963
$ 1.5 Billion
Official TRUTH for a New Generation
IF YOU SMOKE IT...
You will WITHDRAW
FROM SOCIETY
Lose All
Motivation
and
UNDERMINE NATIONAL SECURITY
The responsibility
only to oneself.
Life, liberty and the pursuit of pleasure.
"MONDO MOD" / "TEENAGE REVOLUTION" (1966)
The new declaration
of independence,
for the teenager
around the world.
Smoke a joint,
burn a little grass,
Pot party, roach party, mainliners,
skin pop. Shoot some crystal.
The language of the narcotic
and marijuana user.
The language of a large and ever
increasing number of teenagers.
Starting in high school on
benzedrine and dexedrine pet pills,
it is not long before many
soon graduate to marijuana.
For some it quickens
sexual desire.
For some it is the release
of sexual inhibitions.
But whatever it is
teenagers are going for it,
and maybe the forerunner
of a new drug society,
out of some science fiction
writer's imagination.
Will drugs pave the
road to destruction,
for the now generation?
UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA LOS ANGELES
circa 1966
Come on now honey,
You know you
really turn me on,
On campuses across the country, a whole
new generation discovered drugs.
Rebellious, and willing
to experiment,
they found their light,
altering their consciousness.
And when and
when you do...
- Do you smoke pot?
- Yes I do.
- Do you smoke marijuana?
- Yes.
- Do you smoke pot?
- I have been smoking pot for about a year.
- Have you found it addictive?
- Oh no...
- I go for months and months
without smoking it,
- and then I'll smoke a
lot maybe in a week.
- Well the argument is made that pot leads
to the addiction to heroin or other narcotics.
- Have you found this to be so
among the people you know?
- No, not at all.
- The people who use the stronger
drugs, the opiates etcetera,
- are not the people
who smoke marijuana,
- the people who smoke marijuana
do not use the other drugs.
MARIJUANA IS WHOLESOME
Gradually, the perception that marijuana
was dangerous began to change.
Many students saw smoking grass as
a rejection of establishment values,
a way of declaring
their independence.
SAN FRANCISCO 1967
Over bridge of sighs,
To rest my eyes
in shades of green,
Under dreaming spires,
GOLDEN GATE PARK BE-IN
to Itchycoo Park,
that's where I've been,
GOLDEN GATE PARK BE-IN
- What did you do there?
- I got high!
ALLEN GINSBERG, poet
- What did you feel there?
- Well I cried!
TIMOTHY LEARY, psychologist and author
- But why the tears there?
- Tell you why:
JERRY GARCIA, musician
It's all too beautiful!
I feel inclined
to blow my mind,
Get hung up feed
the ducks with a bun,
They all come out
to groove about,
Be nice and have
fun in the sun!
- At this point we are going
to leave Golden Gate Park,
- to go into the Haight Ashbury
district of San Francisco.
- The last 18 months has seen a tremendous
increase of the so-called 'hippies'.
- This is a protest against the middle and
upper class people of San Francisco,
- *** of the area.
- It is the belief of the people
who live within the area,
- that we, the middle class, have
done a very, very poor job,
- in running our government
and in our way of life.
This weekend Jefferson
Airplane on Friday,
Grateful Dead on Saturday,
at the Carousel Ballroom,
high above Market
and Van Ness.
- Anybody hungry?
- Hey how about we order some Chinese?
- Order some Chinese
to do what?
TREASURY DEPARTMENT
Washington, D.C. circa 1967
Federal Bureau of
Narcotics, please hold.
TREASURY DEPARTMENT
Washington, D.C. circa 1967
Federal Bureau of
Narcotics, please hold.
HENRY GIORDANO
Commissioner, Federal Bureau of Narcotics
The new head of the Federal
Bureau of Narcotics,
HENRY GIORDANO
Commissioner, Federal Bureau of Narcotics
Henry Giordano, began to
realize he had a problem.
To address it,
he developed a campaign he hoped would
be believable to the younger generation.
"If you smoke marijuana,
you will become an,
unmotivated,
dysfunctional looser."
Pammie's on
a bummer now,
And nobody knows
where she's at,
She could be
almost anywhere,
Maybe someday
she'll be back,
She started
smoking pot,
- If you become
a pothead,
SONNY BONO
entertainer
- you risk blowing the most
important time of your life:
SONNY BONO
entertainer
- Your teenage. That unrepeatable
time for you to grow up,
- and to prepare
for being an adult,
- that can handle problems and make
something meaningful out of life.
- Or, you have the choice to have
the courage, to see and deal,
- with the world for what it really is:
far, far from perfect,
- but for you, and for
me, the only one...
PALO ALTO, CALIFORNIA circa 1967
Because so many were trying
marijuana without any ill effects,
PALO ALTO, CALIFORNIA circa 1967
the public demanded
to know more.
And for the first time,
the federal government,
approved scientific testing.
- The plain fact is that none of us
know very much about this drug,
- in any verifiable way.
- Well Bill it's been about two hours since
you got the drug, how do you feel?
- Fantastic!
- "Defiant?"
- Not at all.
- "Businesslike?"
- "Friendly?"
- Extreme...
- This is so ridiculous.
- Would you be interested in taking
part in a study like this again,
- and having the same type of drug?
- Sure!
- It's been a very pleasant
experience for you?
- I'll do it anytime you want.
- Do you think it would be...
- Any time at all!
- Just call me any time at
the day or the night...
- We found out that the
drug makes people happy,
- it makes them intoxicated
and finally makes them sleepy.
- Which is about what marijuana users
were telling us happened all the time.
Last call folks,
drink it up!
It's nice to see you, Bob.
How's the wife, huh?
Kids are okay?
Good. That's fine.
Let's drink tomorrow!
Hell, let's drink tonight!
Hell, let's drink!
- It says right
here that
- alcohol does more harm
to your nervous system.
- Stop reading that underground trash and
pay more attention to your homework!
- All that drivel they talk...
We don't smoke
marijuana in Muskogee,
We don't take
our trips on LSD,
Whether the younger generation
was presented as drugged-out hippies,
or anti-war protestors,
conservative America
reacted with a fear,
and hatred that threatened
to pull the country apart.
And I'm proud to be an
Okie from Muskogee,
A place where even
squares can have a ball,
We still wave Old Glory...
This is fire support base Aeries,
50 miles northeast of Saigon.
Vito is a 20 year old
draftee from Philadelphia.
A photographer before
he entered the army,
Vito is now a squad leader,
responsible of the lives of a dozen men.
- Well, it's called the shotgun...
- What we basically use
it for on the LC,
- I guess even out in the fields
so if you wanna know,
- is that we use it to shotgun.
- From a bowl, you know you just
put the bowl in the chamber and all,
- Paul let me borrow that
that bowl from the...
- Here you go...
- Cool.
- This is probably all sins and we're
getting busted, but I don’t care.
- "Shotgun"...
What's happening here is also
happening to some extent,
at virtually every other American
installation in Vietnam.
Recent surveys estimate that well over 50%
of the soldiers in Vietnam use marijuana.
- You get really stoned.
- Then like, who cares
about the war?
- This war...
NIXON CAMPAIGN COMMERCIAL (1968)
It is time for an honest look at the
problem of order in the United States.
So I pledge to you, we shall
have order in the United States.
ANAHEIM, CALIFORNIA 1968
Manipulating the fears of what
he termed the silent majority,
Richard Nixon build his
campaign for the presidency,
around an emotionally
charged central issue:
Restoring law
and order,
and it worked.
As president, Nixon was
determined to be seen,
as the toughest
crime fighter ever.
But most crimes fell
under state jurisdiction,
so Nixon wasn't allowed
to get involved.
However there was one area where
the federal government did have power:
Drug crime.
Early in his first term,
Nixon launched Operation Intercept,
a military style exercise,
officially described as the
country's largest peace time,
search and
seizure operation.
In it, 2000 customs agents were
deployed along the Mexican border.
Their orders?
Stop the marijuana.
- This is the biggest mistake the
government of the United States has made,
- and the biggest offence they could
have done to the Mexican people.
- I think it's excellent,
- I think if it stops the marijuana
flow in Los Angeles,
- and the southern cities I think it's excellent,
if it doesn't, then I think our time is wasted.
Although more than five million
American and Mexican citizens,
passed through this dragnet,
practically no marijuana was intercepted.
After three weeks, Operation
Intercept was abandoned.
I have a couple of burritos, Over.
Have you brought the hot sauce? Over.
Yes, it is very tasty. Over.
Okay. Let's have a picnic.
I will see you at the picnic site.
Now, even more determined
to appear tough on crime,
Nixon poured federal money into
equipping, training and educating,
local police forces
across America.
In the day-to-day conduct
of your police duties,
no matter how or for what reason you're
called to investigate a situation in a residence,
POLICE TRAINING FILM (circa 1969)
use your eyes to detect
evidence of marijuana,
hashish, or
narcotic violation.
The evidence you're looking
for is here alright.
But it has to be located
before you can read it.
Use your eyes.
Ashtrays are logical places
to use your eyes,
for evidence of
marijuana violations.
There are some noticeable differences
between a marijuana or grass joint,
and the butt of an
ordinary cigarette,
fairly visible even at distance
to those you use their eyes.
This of course is
marijuana itself,
the best
evidence of all.
It has distinctive characteristics.
Learn them. Use your eyes.
It also has the
distinctive aroma,
so use your nose
as well as your eyes.
- Police officer,
open the door!
- Inside, inside,
come on...
- Look right here.
As arrests skyrocketed, the convictions
were no longer limited to minorities,
now most of the
people serving time,
were white, middle-
class American kids.
- Why do you
smoke marijuana?
- It's really
very simple.
- I smoke it because
I enjoy it.
- It doesn't worries you that
you're breaking the law?
- Sure it worries me!
- I mean it worries me because
I don't wanna get caught,
- I do not want to go to jail,
- for something that
I consider a pleasure,
- and harmless, to both
society and to myself.
- I'm not hurting anybody,
I'm not hurting myself.
- Why should I be
punished for it?
And you may see me tonight
with an illegal smile,
It don't cost very much
but it'll last a long while,
Won't you please tell the man
I didn't kill anyone,
No I'm just tryin'
to have me some fun.
When Don Crowe was
convicted of selling marijuana,
to undercover agent
there seemed reason for hope.
It was his first offence after all,
and the amount had been small,
less than one ounce.
But the jury saw it's duty.
Sentence?
50 years in prison.
For Crowe, 25 years old, newly
returned from Vietnam,
it was a bitter pill.
- I had the feeling that I was fighting
for my country, and for my fellow men.
- And it is kind of depressing to know that
I should come back and be given 50 years,
- for allegedly selling
some marijuana.
- This is a purple heart that he received
the first time he was wounded.
There is a mother's
pride as Ms. Crowl,
recounts Don's military record.
But it is
hard for her,
"He loved his country", she says.
"He was a good boy."
- Well we were naturally
so proud of him,
- when he was over there,
- and when he came back
and all this happened,
- of course I've just been heartbroken
and I think it is a little severe penalty.
POTpourri:
Many Views of Marijuana
- I don't think that a kid should have
their entire future career blinded,
- by having an arrest record for being
caught in a room where marijuana was kept,
- or of smoking a joint of marijuana when
they're a kid in college or a young kid,
- and that's exactly what happens,
- Everyone here seems
to emphasize the kids,
- How can you communicate with them
when they got flowers on their ears,
- so they can't hear and hair
down to their hip pockets,
- A young person, other
minority group members,
- have a much greater chance of
being arrested and are arrested,
- and if this continues, we're going to
decimate the youthful population of America.
- That's exactly what's
going to happen.
- If anyone of us has
a kid who's arrested,
- it's going to be an arrest for narcotic
violation in his record for the rest of his life.
- He can't go in the peace corps, he
can't teach school, he can't be a cop,
- What's the difference if he committed
murder he'd have an arrest record?
- Fine if he committed murder
he's harmed someone!
- Can any law be effective, especially
a law dealing with marijuana,
- when there is so much controversy
from so many eminent-
- No law can be effective that actually, that
tries to regulate or legislate private morality.
- You can't make homosexual
laws effective, you cant make,
- could you pass a law that
says it's a crime to masturbate?
- You couldn't enforce it!
- There's laws in the book that says "thou shalt not fornicate"
either, and you wouldn't go around arresting kids for fornicating,
- *** law I would.
- Don't you even know it's against the law? You're a hell of a cop!
- It is against the law a matter of fact... sex is illegal in most of America,
- Everything is illegal in America.
- *** illegal *** it's that simple.
- I think we've come to somewhat
of a conclusion here,
- in that the law is not very effective.
- No it's not, how can it be effective,
- when you have 10 thousand kids in one
city are being arrested in one year,
- the law is
not effective.
As middle class parents
began asking,
MARIHUANA: Time to Change The Law?
"Why is my kid in jail?"
More and more Americans began to
feel that the problem was not marijuana,
MARIHUANA: Time to Change The Law?
but marijuana laws.
Feeling's getting stronger,
WOODSTOCK MUSIC FESTIVAL
Music's getting
longer too,
Music is
flashin' me,
I want to,
I wanna take
you higher,
Support for reform of marijuana law
seemed to come from everywhere.
Even federal officials agreed that
harsh penalties were not working.
SENATE HEARING ON MARIJUANA LEGISLATION 1969
- A conservative estimate
of persons in the United States,
SENATE HEARING ON MARIJUANA LEGISLATION 1969
- both juvenile and adults who have
used marijuana at least once,
DR. STANLEY YOLLES
Director, National Institute of Mental Health
- is about 8 million and may
go as high as 12 million.
DR. STANLEY YOLLES
Director, National Institute of Mental Health
- Can you imagine what would
happen to the law enforcement,
- and correction system
of this country,
- if each of these 12 million people had been caught
by a policeman when smoking his first marijuana cigarette.
- The first place in which legal
reforms can be made,
- is in the removal of mandatory minimum
penalties in all cases of drug abuse.
Sensing the public's mood,
Congress passed the
Controlled Substances Act,
which eliminated mandatory
minimum sentences,
and reduced penalties
for possession.
Would take you
high, high, high...
WAR ON MARIJUANA
1964-1969
WAR ON MARIJUANA 1964-1969
$1 BILLION
$2 BILLION
WAR ON MARIJUANA 1964-1969
$3 BILLION
$4 BILLION
WAR ON MARIJUANA 1964-1969
$5 BILLION
$6 BILLION
WAR ON MARIJUANA 1964-1969
$7 BILLION
$8 BILLION
WAR ON MARIJUANA 1964-1969
$9 BILLION
OFFICIAL TRUTH FOR YOUR OWN GOOD
If you smoke it...
BAD THINGS
WILL HAPPEN
BUT WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THEY ARE
- Is she dead?
- Not yet.
- This picture was taken at 10 pm.
- The girl lived until midnight.
"DRAGNET" (circa 1970)
- Any questions?
- But I maintain the evidence
against marijuana isn't in yet.
- Well sir, will you conceive that it
might be as harmful as alcohol.
- Alright, but it's no worse.
- No sir, I hope not.
- Because according to
US government figures,
- between 5 and 6 million people in this country are physically
and mentally sick as a result of their use of alcohol.
- If marijuana possesses only
half the potential of alcohol,
- for violence, criminality,
- accidents and social degradation...
- Do we need pot?
Unwilling to let a bunch
of *** liberals to,
ruin his crime
fighting agenda,
Nixon enlisted TV-producers
and show business stars,
to send a strong
moral message,
"to every home, every school
and every church in America."
I've done a study
of drug abuse,
and I'm at the middle
of the whole thing,
where I can do the most good.
ELVIS PRESLEY
Special Assistant, Bureau of Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs
Some people say that in a matter
of months "Acapulco Gold",
PUBLIC SERVICE ANNOUNCEMENT (circa 1971)
will be available over the counter,
menthol and king size,
which is an indication of how little
people know about marijuana.
Today research scientists are
studying it's effects on the brain,
the nervous system, chromosomes,
various organs of the body,
maybe it will turn out there
is no reason for it to be illegal.
But nobody can be sure
until all the facts are in.
And until they are,
it's a pretty bum risk.
Repelled by the idea
of softening any laws,
Nixon maintain that until more was
known about marijuana's dangers,
the law should not change. To this end
he made millions of dollars available,
to find those dangers.
POT SMOKERS BEWARE
Scientists report bizarre side effects:
MEN GROW BREASTS!
- Many of us are concerned
that a large percentage,
- of our young people are breaking
the law by smoking marijuana.
- As you know here on White House
conference youth voted to legalize marijuana,
- I know you thought about
this problem and I wonder,
- if you could give us some of your thoughts on it.
- As you know,
- there is a commission that is supposed to make
recommendations to me about this subject,
- The recommendation of the
Commission in it's first report,
RAYMOND P. SHAFER
Chairman, National Commission on Marijuana and Drug Abuse
- is that we do not
feel that private use,
- or private possession
in one's own home,
- should have the stigma
of criminalization,
- that people who experiment,
- should not be criminalized for
that particular behavior.
The presidential commissions
report on marijuana found,
marijuana use in and of itself,
did not cause crime.
Current laws against grass
led to selective prosecution,
and the police were suspected of
using these laws to arrest people,
with objectionable hairstyles,
skin color, or politics.
The enormous cost of trying to
enforce laws against marijuana,
overwhelmingly outweighed any
deterrent value of these laws.
The commission had conducted the
most comprehensive highly publicized,
study of marijuana,
ever done.
THE OFFICIAL REPORT OF THE NATIONAL
COMMISSION OF MARIHUANA AND DRUG ABUSE
Furious, Nixon tossed it in the waste
basket, without ever reading it.
- Mr. President?
- Okay...
- Whenever you're ready.
- I shall continue to oppose
efforts to legalize marijuana.
Doing the exact opposite
of what was recommended,
Nixon declared an
all-out war on drugs.
His primary weapon, the DEA.
A new government agency,
that combined all of the government's
existing anti-drug agencies,
into a single, all-powerful
super-agency.
- You should keep
going forward until...
- until you're right there...
- Looks like you're right on top of it.
- Is that all there is?
- Yes.
- The last week we pulled 13 pounds of it from about 5
different patches and we got another 4 or 5 now,
- that are really small patches but we are
gonna go get in and pull them out today.
- What do you do with the, so you just come
in and destroy the patches, that the idea?
- We destroy the patch and
then we'll take it and burn it.
- Apparently there is somebody coming
back here and cultivating this?
- Definitely.
- These are all in nice little neat rows,
- it's kind of rotating crop,
some are smaller than others.
- How good is Georgia pot?
- I've never smoked it,
so I don't know.
One toke over the line
Sweet Jesus,
One toke over the line,
Sitting downtown
in a railway station,
One toke over the line!
Employing more than 4000
analysts and agents,
the DEA had the authority
to request wiretaps,
in their private homes without knocking,
and gather intelligence on ordinary citizens.
Brewer and Shipley still
"One Toke Over the Line",
and now Wadsworth Mansion,
smoking a little "Sweet Mary".
Sweet Mary sent
a letter to me,
She say to hurry home
I need you right away,
Meanwhile, in suburbia, smoking
pot had become the in-thing,
for middle-class adults.
Sort of like having a
martini at happy hour,
Sweet Mary I'm
coming home,
Coming home to
you, yeah, yeah,
Sweet Mary I'm
coming home now,
That's the
least I can do!
Fry over a low to medium
fire for about 5 minutes,
stirring to
avoid burning.
Let it cool a few minutes,
then, grind it into a powder.
Now you can do anything
you want with it:
will it be an ice cream,
butter, milkshakes, Jell-O,
or put it in honey an freeze
it into squares for later.
- Until recently the use of marijuana
was considered a youth phenomena,
- a thing of campus protest,
the counter-culture, longhair.
- Well, not so in the 70's.
- Meet some of the
"criminals" at large.
- I've spent a lot of time with
my daughter and her friends,
and they all smoked marijuana,
and so I had to try it!
BETTY STRAND, GRANDMOTHER, AGE 56
- I first used pot back in
the latter part of 1968,
- and used it since then with
some degree of regularity.
- I had some pot earlier today
before I went down to court.
- I smoke at home, smoke
at parties, many places.
- To me it's a question of
the rights to life, liberty,
- and the pursuit of happiness.
- You know, who owns me?
Sign up here!
You over there, come here!
As smoking marijuana became
increasingly mainstream,
pro pot activists began organizing
support for decriminalization.
- Last year in this country, there were
226.000 marijuana related arrests,
- and although the police sometimes tell us that they're
only interested in the pusher, the seller, as they say,
KEITH STROUP
Founder, National Organization for the Reform of Marijuana Laws
- the fact is that only 7% of those
arrests were against the seller.
- 93% of those arrests were
for possession and use.
- Now what that means is that there
were about 200.000 young people,
- in this country last year, who were
given an unnecessary criminal record,
- and all that involved for
the rest of their life,
- simply because they smoked grass, something
which is a relatively harmless thing to do.
- So we're not trying to encourage the use of
the drug, in fact we're trying to discourage it.
- But we're trying to get the country to understand that
there are other means to discourage the use of drugs,
- other than a criminal law,
and in this case,
- the use of the criminal law causes
more harm than the drug itself.
A political activist named John Sinclair
became a symbol for the movement.
He received a jail
sentence of "10 for 2",
10 years in prison for
possession of 2 joints.
- This song I wrote
for John Sinclair.
John Lennon and Yoko Ono in
"TEN FOR TWO" (1972)
It ain't fair,
John Sinclair,
In the stair
for breathing air,
Won't you care
for John Sinclair?
In the stair
for breathing air,
Let him be,
set him free,
Let him be
like you and me.
They give him
10 for 2!
What else can
judge Columba do?
We got to, got to, got to, got to,
got to, got to, got to, got to, got to,
got to, got to, got to, got to,
got to, got to, set him...
free!
FREE!
Takin' it to
the streets,
Consistent with the changing times,
the city of Ann Arbor, Michigan,
passed an ordinance taking marijuana
possession out of the criminal code.
and making it a minor offence,
the equivalent of a parking ticket.
Takin' it to the streets,
No more need for runnin',
Takin' it to the street...
Ann Arbor City Ordinance
GRASS
A year later, after a groundbreaking
vote in it's legislature,
Oregon became the first state to
completely decriminalize marijuana.
- Here is a state that is not
afraid to plow new ground,
- in an area where
there's a lot of hysteria.
- It's not gonna be very
widely understood,
TOM McCALL
Governor of Oregon
- but I think as you look back
over the handling of drugs,
TOM McCALL
Governor of Oregon
- if you can keep it in for a few years,
you'll see it was landmark legislation.
Takin' it to the streets,
Oregon Decriminalization Bill
Oregon Decriminalization Bill 1973
PASSED
In 1974, with legal problems of his own,
Richard Nixon resigned from the presidency.
Legalize it,
LEGALIZE MARIJUANA
Don't criticize it,
- We smoke pot!
Legalize it,
Yeah, yeah,
And I will
advertise it,
- We don't want any penalty
for the private possession,
- and use, and cultivation
of marijuana.
Legalize it...
A study in Oregon 4 years
after decriminalization,
showed no increase
in marijuana use,
and a substantial savings
of tax dollars,
formerly spent on
law enforcement.
By that time, 10 other states
had decriminalized marijuana.
Continuing Nixon's
war on drugs,
fill-in president
Gerald Ford ordered,
US forces to spray
Mexican marijuana fields,
with the military
defoliant Paraquat.
But in the upcoming presidential election, he found
himself running against an unexpected opponent.
- Appreciate your vote.
Jimmy CARTER
for President
- I do favor the decriminalization of marijuana.
CARTER PRESIDENTIAL CAMPAIGN 1975
Can our government
be competent?
Jimmy Carter
says yes,
Tonight on Headline NEWS:
President Carter proposes major
changes to federal drug laws.
- I support a change in law, and
in federal criminal penalties,
- for possession of up to
one ounce of marijuana,
- leaving the states
free to adopt,
- whatever laws they
wish concerning marijuana.
Doing part to advocacy by the
decriminalization movement,
the government was finally
preparing to abandon it's war,
on marijuana smokers.
WAR ON MARIJUANA * 1970-1977
COST $76 BILLION
Fundamental Official Truth
If you smoke it...
YOU WILL BE IN THE
GRIP OF SATAN
and The Godless
Sodomites That Run
HOLLYWOOD
- Is that a joint man?
"UP IN SMOKE" (1978)
- That looks like a
quarter pounder man,
- Led Zeppelin!
- Be careful with that shit man.
- Toke, toke it
out man.
- Kinda grabs you by the
boo-boo, don't it?
- What is in this man?
- Mostly Mauie Wowie man,
- Yeah?
- But it got some Labrador in it.
- What's Labrador?
- It's dog shit.
- What?
- Yeah my dog ate my stash man,
- So I had to farm with a little baggy
for three days before I got it back.
- That's some heavy
shit man...
- Hey man, I'm
I driving okay?
- I think we're
parked man.
Well alright you squares
it's time we smoked,
HOLLYWEED
Everybody get high,
Sing bustin’ out!
In the permissive 70's, marijuana
seemed to be everywhere,
through movies and television, it
had entered the popular culture.
- The FBI claims that a huge shipment of
grass which they are calling "Killer Dope",
- has been smuggled into New York City.
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" (circa 1978)
- The bureau urges, users not to smoke
the weed, which is greenish-brown in color,
- not particularly seedy, and
contains mostly cannabis buds.
- Warning symptoms are a mild euphoria
a slight rise in the pulse rate,
- some hallucination and death by
laughter within 15 minutes of ingestion.
- In an effort to aid the FBI in it's
investigation, Weekend Update,
- is undertaking it's own analysis of marijuana sent to
us anonymously by any viewers who may be worried.
- Simply place a small sample of the
suspected cannabis in an envelope,
- and send it immediately to:
Chevy Chase,
apartment 12, 827 West
New York City 10053.
But not everyone was laughing.
Worried about teenage
marijuana use,
a number of concerned parents
organized pressure groups,
to fight the new
drug culture.
- This is a dashboard pipe that fits
under the dashboard of your car,
- so that you can put pot in here,
and then the driver and his date,
SUSAN RUSCHE
Co-Founder, National Families in Action
- can get stoned as they're
touring down the freeway.
SUSAN RUSCHE
Co-Founder, National Families in Action
- This is designed to put some
pot in and then you smoke,
- the pot out of here.
- You can toss a smoke
to a friend if you want to.
- There are things like
"bongs", that's B-O-N-G.
- You put the pot
here, light it,
- and smoke travels
down here, collects,
- and then you get a concentrated
volume of smoke... by sucking in like this.
- And I think the label is instructed:
Bong, the only thing wasted is you".
- This too is a bong, it's called a power-hitter,
and it works by sticking a joint here,
- and then blasting it,
into your lungs, like this.
- It comes as a Star
Wars space gun also.
POSTER
HUT
CHAMBLEE, GEORGIA 1978
- Hello Gary?
- Just put the box in the
bag... we'll make the...
- Could you please leave?
- You're gonna have to leave, I'm sorry.
- And you are?
- Closed, officially closed as of now.
- Most of the afternoon was
spent trying to decide,
- what actually were headshops
and drug-related paraphernalia.
- Mangers and owners from headshops around the
area testified that the law is now so ambiguous,
- that possibly as much as 80% of their
inventory could now be considered illegal.
- One owner admitted he may be
out of work within the week...
- Okay.
- Most of the afternoon was
spent trying to decide,
- what actually were headshops
and drug-related paraphernalia, and...
- Okay.
- Most of the afternoon was
spent trying to...
- Okay.
- Most of the afternoon was
spent trying to decide,
- what were headshops and
drug-related paraphernalia.
- Owners and managers of headshops around...
- Toke, toke!
THE QUAALUDE AFFAIR
It the midst of this backlash,
Dr. Peter Bourne,
Carter's chief drug policy advisor,
was caught up in a scandal
involving alleged cocaine use.
As the press had a field day, the
president could no longer afford,
to appear soft on drugs.
His proposal to decriminalize
marijuana would die in congress.
She don’t lie, she don’t lie
she don’t lie, cocaine...
WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO DECRIMINALIZATION?
- I'm sick and tired of hearing
about all of the radicals,
- and the perverts,
and the liberals,
- and the lefties, and the communists
coming out of the closet,
- it's time for God's people to
come out of the closet,
- out of the churches and
change America! We must do it!
Driven by a sense of
righteous indignation,
the religious right mobilized
into a potent political force,
after a brief period of tolerance,
America was poised for a
major swing the other way.
VO†E
- Leading medical researchers, are coming
to the conclusion, that marijuana,
REAGAN PRESIDENTIAL CAMPAIGN 1980
- pot, grass, whatever
you wanna call it,
- is probably the most dangerous
drug in the United States,
- and we haven't begun to
find out all of the ill effects,
- but they are permanent ill effects,
the loss of memory for example.
This is your brain on drugs,
Any questions?
- Just say "no".
- Just say "no"!
In her crusade to address the America,
Mrs. Reagan let school children...
...are police officers in
schools to spy on...
...ordered mandatory drug testing for all federal
employees. He then calls for the nation's industries to...
The supreme court has given
school principles the right to,
strip-search any student
suspected of drug possession.
Signing a threat to
national security,
the president today, signed legislation,
ANTI-DRUG ABUSE ACT 1968
allowing law-enforcement agencies
to seize property from society...
ANTI-DRUG ABUSE ACT 1988
Under president George Bush's new zero
tolerance policy, marijuana smokers...
- Using illegal drugs
is against the law.
They'll stone ya when you're
tryin' to keep your seat.
- And when you're caught,
you will be punished.
They'll stone ya when
you're walkin' on the floor.
- Some think there won't
be room for them in jail...
They'll stone ya when you're
walkin' to the door,
- We'll make room.
- The rules have changed.
In his speech to the coastguard
today, George Bush said,
that drug trafficking should
be grounds for death penalties.
Everybody must get stoned!
- I'm proposing a quarter
of a billion dollar...
- billion dollar..
- 2.2 billion...
- 8 billion dollars.
- The largest increase in history.
But I would not
feel so all alone,
Everybody must get stoned...
WAR ON MARIJUANA
1980-1998
$214,7 BILLION
"DRUG WAR" MEANS
POLICE $TATE INC.
- We smoke pot!
WHO AM I HURTING?
Pot MAKES ME HAPPY
Since President Clinton took office,
NEW YORK CITY 1999
over 3 million people have been
arrested for possession of marijuana,
NEW YORK CITY 1999
more than under any
previous administration.
The United States government
continues to wage a war on grass that,
time, and time again, has proven
itself misguided, and completely ineffective.
That being so, the
orderly thing to do,
under our form
of government,
is to abolish a law which
cannot be enforced,
a law which the people of the
country do not want enforced!
- Soothe me with
your caress,
- Sweet marihuana,
- Marihuana!
- Help me in my distress
sweet marihuana,
- Please do!
- You alone can bring
my lover back to me,
- Even though I
know it's all a fantasy,
- And then
put me to sleep,
- Sweet marihuana,
- Marihuana!
English subtitles by Goblim
goblim@hotmail.com
- Potheads!
Anything to get a kick,
Anything to get a blast,
Anything to palm his mind,
They think they can
go out and get high,
get turned on with pot,
They can get loaded,
they can get stoned!
Get a bong, get a
bong, get a bong,
57% of the student
party was smoking pot,
Smoking pot, pot, pot,
It fascinates,
and then assassinates,
And then it kills!
A drug epidemic that's
sweeping our nation,
We need to legalize pot!
Man... I didn't dig that!
Smoking pot!
Cold turkey
withdrawal!
Smoking pot!
Anything to
palm his mind,
Smoking pot!
Anything to
get a blast,
Smoking pot!
Quit playing games with God!
Potheads!
- If what you see and
hear in this picture,
- will keep one of you, only one
person from taking that first step,
- our purpose has
been accomplished.