The Greatest Marriage
Episode 11
[3 Years Later]
Cue!
This is '24 Hours of Hope' and
I'm with the rescue team right now!
I'm Cha Ki Young, your reporter
starting today.
Right now, the rescue team is on its way
to save a person who fell while hiking.
The patient's life depends upon how fast
they will be able to get to the hospital.
Cut!
Let's get on the helicopter!
- You want me to ride in the helicopter?
- Of course!
No one told me that I had
to ride in the helicopter!
You have to be in the action
if you want the full story!
One of the rescue team members will help,
so don't worry and get in!
I don't think I can do it!
You don't have a choice!
We have to record this show!
Are you going to get in or not?
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Hello?
Yes, Director?
I'm not in a position
to talk on the phone right now!
Today?
- I'm going to be late again today.
- What are you doing?
Please take good care of Dan for me!
I'm sorry!
This is Channel Korea with your
nine o'clock news. My name is Jo Eun Cha...
and Kang Ha Ni.
Here is our first story.
The three most powerful men in North Korea
will be attending the closing ceremony
of the Asian Games.
Talks between the the North and South
are more active than ever.
Reporter Kim Hyung Joon has
the full story from the Blue House.
The possibility of peace between
North and South Korea...
What are we to do if reunification happens?
- You hate reunification?
- I totally hate it.
We'll have to live with
those poor North Koreans.
Also, why are North Korea and
South Korea considered one country?
Americans think we look the same
as the Japanese.
She's an anchor. Why is she so clueless?
She's studied in America
since she was young.
And she was singled out
to be an announcer.
She only looks Korean.
Internally, she's completely American.
My daughter is also studying abroad.
And I'm afraid she's going
to turn out like her.
Director, Eun Cha has changed.
In the past, he would've trampled
all over girls like Kang Ha Ni on the spot.
That punk. He's just playing nice because
the general elections are coming up.
You honestly think people can change?
Ma'am, I'm busy right now.
I'll call you later!
What the heck are you doing right now?
Move!
Seriously, I'm going nuts here!
Transfer him to the operating room!
Cut!
This sucks!
Why did you bring a woman along?
We'll refuse to cooperate
if you keep getting in our way like this!
You're not even remotely interested
in the patient's condition.
You're only concerned about your child!
I'm sorry.
The daycare closes at seven and
it's past nine o'clock right now.
The teacher kept calling to say
she was closing.
Then quit your job and
watch your kid instead, okay?
I hear this isn't the first time
you screwed over a recording!
Your words are a bit harsh.
You think my words are harsh?
What about your actions?
Let's just call it quits.
Throw away every recording
with Cha Ki Young in it
and let's start all over
by casting someone else.
Let's wrap it up.
Ma'am, I just finished wrapping up.
How is Dan doing?
We've headed over to commercial.
Hey, Gap Soo.
Kang Ha Ni?
A fashion show MC?
Why would a news anchor
host a fashion show? Hang up!
Why didn't you ask for my opinion first?
I didn't ask for your opinion
when you were placed next to me.
I'm not going to ask for your opinion
when you get fired, either.
You have a problem with that?
I'm so sorry!
He kept waiting for you at this spot
and he just fell asleep.
I'm so sorry. My work ended
much later than I expected.
I'll take him.
Does Dan have other family members?
His grandmother perhaps?
He doesn't have one.
It would be nice if he did.
Dan is a little different
from the other children.
In what way?
Boys like to get physical when they play.
But Dan's always playing quietly by himself.
He doesn't know how to approach people
and I'm wondering if it's because
he only spends time with you.
Those symptoms usually appear
in children that lack attention.
He's been a quiet child
ever since he was born.
There are children who are
outgoing by nature
but there are also children
who are introverts.
It's not like I'm going to raise him
to be a professional athlete.
I'm going to raise a child who
loves to read instead of a dumb jock.
All right then, list off
all the clans in our family.
Which generation should
I start from, Father?
Start with the 25th.
Jae Shin Kyu from the 25th generation,
Yong San Jong from the 26th generation...
Ho Soo Soon from the 27th generation,
Im Joo Sang from the 28th generation...
Yeol Yong Hee from the 29th generation,
Shi Joon from the 30th generation...
Ho Heum Goo from the 31st generation,
Hae Yoon Han from the 32nd generation...
Shik Geun Kwon from the 33rd generation,
Hon Eung from the 34th generation.
Good job.
Now, read these characters.
Park Eun Chil?
This is the name of Tae Yun's son.
Good.
Sons are precious in our family.
During my father's lifetime,
a monk told us
our lives would be shortened
if we used a family name.
That's why I didn't give
Tae Yun a common family name.
But I've decided to begin that tradition
again, starting with Tae Yun's son.
Thank you, Father.
Since the short lifespan was
taken care of with your miscarriage...
I'm sure we won't have another child
who will die early again.
Did something good happen?
Mother, Father came up with
a name for our future son.
What's the name?
Park Eun Chil.
Eun Chil?
That's a fine name.
She remembered every family name
when no else could.
We accepted a daughter-in-law
without a son to show for it.
In that sense, it's comfortable.
This the picture
he sent me last night, Mother.
Where is this now?
It's a small restaurant in Kyoto, Japan.
He was in Czechoslovakia two months ago.
He said he's going to study every cuisine
in the world before he returns.
You must keep this a secret
from your father-in-law.
For all he knows,
Tae Yun is still studying overseas.
Understood?
Yes, Mother.
When I open my eyes,
I find this small child next to me.
I still find it unfamiliar and fascinating.
I never relied on anyone
from the moment I was born.
But now, my whole life
revolves around this child.
- Hey, Mom.
- Is the child growing well?
- Yeah.
- How about work?
Well, it's coming along.
I know it's tough trying to work
while taking care of him.
There's no need to suffer like that.
I said I'd take care of him for you.
I left so we could live together.
That would be meaningless
if I left him in your care.
Also, I won't be able to work more
if I drop him off.
Don't worry, Mom.
Alright. Call me right away
if something happens, okay?
I will, Mom.
Hey, baby.
Baby.
It's time to wake up.
- I don't want to.
- You have to wake up now!
I don't want to.
Let's see here.
You didn't have an accident today!
Good boy, come here!
Mom.
- Yes?
- Can't you come and pick me up today?
Why?
My other friends have their
mom or dad come to pick them up
and I was the only that didn't.
In the past, baby bones were discovered
in many of the royal palaces.
When night came, the only man was the king.
The palace maids would compete fiercely
to put their baby on the throne.
They say this yongbong stew
gave energy to the king back then.
Here are the pictures
of the child you requested.
I've only been taking pictures
for the past three years.
When do you want me to take action?
Just wait and always be ready.
- You stupid bastard.
- Hey!
Did you come for a recording?
I hear you're running for election
to the National Assembly?
Please help me.
I promise to support you on your comeback
if I get elected to the National Assembly.
You won't get elected
no matter how hard you try.
You think anyone can be a politician?
You did it too.
Why are you speaking ill of me?
Didn't you feel anything when you saw me
get kicked out of the National Assembly?
You and I are alpha males to the core.
And we can't live our lives
hiding that fact.
Sixty percent of the voters are women.
How can sexist men like us be elected?
One wrong word makes
the both of us look bad.
Even so, you think we'll be able
to throw away that alpha mentality?
That's the very thing that
our fathers passed down.
'Men are the heavens
and women are the Earth.'
You may have failed
but I have a trump card that will
help me rack up all the female voters.
What is it?
I'm an alpha male disguised as a feminist.
Let's just say I'm a wolf posing
as an innocent sheep.
I only picked women with bad performance
evaluations who have children.
Cha Ki Young is ranked
number one on the list?
She's been ranked last for the past
three years with her evaluations.
Let me take a look.
Goodness, how did she come to be like this?
All the decent ones are gone,
and only the useless ones are left.
Who would stay when everyone's
salaries were cut by 30 percent?
Five of our ace reporters quit
just last month alone.
Do you have something in mind?
We have no choice if we want
to save the company.
Get rid of all the useless
people like Cha Ki Young
and give all the decent workers
their original wages back.
Is that the only solution?
I hear Cha Ki Young is struggling
to take care of her child.
The company is in danger
because you're so soft-hearted!
Ho Pyung, you need to toughen up!
Money has been tight ever since our
wages were cut by 30 percent.
I'm pretty much at zero after
I pay the monthly loan interest.
I thought your ex-husband
was helping you with that?
Nurse Jung is the office wife.
She has a tight hold on
the hospital's purse strings.
I'm even paying for all the
apartment maintenance fees on my own.
It pisses me off the more I think about it.
Hurry up and end it with him
while Ara is studying overseas.
It's been three years since we put our home
on the market and he still won't leave.
Have you ever heard of
a woman that still lives with
her ex-husband just because
their place hasn't been sold?
Raising a child is so expensive.
I realized that money is more important
than love when it comes to raising a child.
Hello?
Cha Ki Young, this is the news station.
We need to talk.
Right now?
It's important.
I need to go to the news station.
He says it's important.
He probably wants you
to fill in for a minor program again.
What are you going to do about Dan?
I can't drop him off anywhere
on this short of notice.
I guess I'll just have to take him with me.
Mom, where are we?
It's the news station I work for.
Let's go in.
Don't go anywhere and stay right here.
I'll be right back, okay?
Okay.
Hello.
- You're here.
- Yes.
Sit down.
Cha Ki Young.
You know I'm not good at
beating around the bush, right?
The is usually the Director's job to do.
But he's too soft-hearted,
so he handed it over to me.
[Reconstruction List]
Why is my name on the very top?
You've been ranked last for the past three
years with the worst employee evaluation.
You used to be so greedy for work.
How did you come to be like this?
You're always making mistakes
because of your child.
Forgive me.
All the producers held a meeting
and agreed not to cast you.
No one wants to cast you.
You're the number one person
everyone wants fired.
- Good job, everyone.
- What else can we give you to work on?
Sit down and continue what you were doing.
Eun Cha, you're here.
You should talk about
stuff like that on the roof.
What is this?
You're disturbing everyone.
I'll do what I can to find a position
for you in the next reorganization
if you leave of your own free will.
Turn in your letter of resignation
by next week.
Cha Ki Young, long time no see.
I thought you quit the station.
I haven't seen you at all.
Dan.
Excuse me, but have you seen
a little boy about this tall?
No, I haven't.
Dan!
There was a little tadpole
squirming in the river.
- It swam up the river.
- What is this?
Who are you?
Where's your mom?
I said where's your mom?
- Huh?
- And it became a frog.
Here's a phone number.
Someone call this number quickly.
So irresponsible.
How on earth did a child get in here?
Cha Dan? Is your name Dan?
Dan!
Hello?
Are you the mother of this boy, Cha Dan?
- Yes!
- This is the news studio.
Please come quickly and take your child.
Okay!
Hey, you can't climb on top of there!
Come down this instant!
Dan!
Come down!
- What is this?
- Dan!
Seriously, I have to report the news soon!
What are you doing?
You're not supposed to clean a silk skirt
with a cheap brand like that!
And how could you let
your child come in here?
Why did you have a child on your own
when you can't even manage it?
You're really a disgrace
to all the announcers!
I'm weak when it comes to women with
pretty faces and nice bodies like you.
But I won't stand for mutiny
against your seniors!
Anchor Cha deserves your utmost
respect and honor! Understood?
Go and change into
a shorter skirt right now.
The only reason you're even in
this position is those long legs of yours.
Get out this instant!
815, do you remember Daddy?
- Dad?
- That's right.
I cut your umbilical cord
when you were born.
And we almost lost you when
your mom tried to protect this position.
I was the one who saved you.
Dan, let's go.
- Dad!
- That's right, I'm your dad!
I'm your dad.
Call me anytime if anything happens to Dan!
It's only because
you're not requesting my help.
But as a surrogate father,
I'm ready to be Dan's dad.
Anytime.
Is that man really my dad?
No.
He looks like my dad.
I told you that I'm your mom and dad.
But you're a woman, though.
Do you want a dad that's a man?
Yes.
But male fathers will scold
and spank you all the time.
Still... I want one.
Dan.
Shall we run a kimbap business?
You love cooking.
You can be with me all day
if we run a kimbap business.
That sounds good, Mom.
Hello?
- Hi, this is the owner.
- Yes?
Your lease will be expiring soon.
Ah...
I'd like to extend the lease contract.
Ah... then you'll have to pay
an additional 50 million won.
50 million won?
Ask around in that area.
Everyone's rent has increased
by that much.
I'll call you later.
It's one obstacle after another.
[Jo Eun Cha]
What's going to happen to Cha Ki Young's
anchor position if you get elected?
Why? You want it?
If you back me, I promise to live
as your faithful servant.
I can't choose whoever I want
for the main anchor position.
We all know you're in charge of
the news and personnel appointments.
But, why are your hands so stiff?
It should be done my a woman
if you want a decent massage.
Kang Ha Ni, are you doing
a good job on my article?
Yes.
Make sure my article is better than yours.
What do women think about Cha Ki Young?
You saw what happened yesterday.
What about other women besides you?
Are there a lot of haters?
She has a lot of female fans
that don't know anything.
Still?
Even though she gets
the cold shoulder at work
she's considered a hero among feminists
and the general female population.
They say she's a pioneer
ahead of the times.
She's branded as the Korean Angelina Jolie.
I like the sound of that.
The Korean Angelina Jolie.
[Cha Ki Young]
I swear, she and I are always
on the same wavelength.
Hello?
It's me, Cha Ki Young.
And?
I need to talk to you.
What is it?
I'd like to talk to you face-to-face.
I'm busy.
- I'll call you some other time then.
- Today, between five and six o'clock...
I only have an hour to spare.
Well, the daycare ends at four o'clock.
Bring 815 with you.
Thank you.
The station isn't ideal.
I'll text you the address
so come to that place.
Aw, my son is here!
You got so big!
Sit, sit!
This is my campaign office.
It hasn't been long since it was set up.
You've gotten so handsome.
Here we go again. You're fidgeting
and can't look me in the eyes.
You came to ask for a favor, didn't you?
You get nervous and can't speak
if there's a favor to ask.
The thing is...
You have to be thick-skinned
if you're going to raise a child.
The same goes for favors as well.
My lease ends next month
and the owner wants
an additional 50 million won.
You want to borrow money from me?
I need to get a loan for the extra money.
But I won't be able to if I get laid off.
So?
- If you can...
- If I can what?
- If you can help me.
- How am I supposed to help you?
You're the first one
on the list to get laid off.
You're not even second. How am I supposed
to save the first person to go?
815, I'm going to cover your ears
for just a moment, okay?
Get on your knees in front of me.
Pardon?
I'll save you if you cry and beg
on your knees.
You can't do it, can you?
You don't even have the courage
to get down on your knees.
Then why did you spout
all that nonsense
about how you can raise
a child all on your own?
You don't have the means
to buy formula for your son
and yet you can't let go
of your pride, right?
Dan eats rice, not formula, okay?
Dan, let's go.
Hey, did you receive
Cha Ki Young's resignation?
Not yet.
Get it from her quickly!
She only listens when
she's backed into a corner.
Tell her to turn in her resignation
this instant!
Yes, Manager?
Why haven't you given me your resignation?
You have until tomorrow to turn it in.
She's coming, she's not coming.
She came!
Forget it.
Sign here instead.
You like contracts.
You're the queen of contracts.
Sign that contract and sing 'Pa Pa Pa.'
'Everyone all together now!'
It's like the contents of this contract
were written by an adolescent boy.
There's nothing wrong with it.
'One. Cha Ki Young will actively help
and participate in Jo Eun Cha's election.'
'Two. Cha Ki Young will
become Jo Eun Cha's wife'
'if he fails to get elected
to the National Assembly.'
'Three. She will take off his socks and
cook his meals for the rest of her life.'
'And sleep with him whenever he wants.'
Turn in your resignation
if you don't want to.
The company is covering
a fashion show special.
I want you to be the MC for that.
You need to show everyone
that you've still got it.
That's the only way to prevent you
from getting laid off.
Are you really going to become my wife
if I fail to get elected? Huh?
And sleep with me whenever I want?
Don't you have a woman?
Why do you ask?
Surprisingly, there are a lot of women
out there who like macho men like you.
How am I macho? Huh?
Do macho men recommend
single mothers for a job? Huh?
Do you honestly think I would be your wife,
even if you were the last man on Earth?
Then why did you sign the contract?
Son, let's go!
Daddy will buy you a toy.
- Yay!
There's a lot of nice toys here.
What do you want?
Go ahead and pick one.
Do want the fire truck or the fork lift?
- The fire truck!
- The fire truck it is!
Here you go!
Let's take a picture
since I bought this for you.
Look over here.
- Fire truck.
- Jo Eun Cha.
Dan looks exactly like
his father instead of you.
You know I'm a horrible liar.
He looks exactly like his father.
Park Tae...
- Hello Madam.
- Goodness, welcome.
Did you get it?
These are the sheets and blankets that
helped a woman to conceive her triplets.
Good job.
Use these sheets and blankets
when Tae Yun comes back.
Give her an adorable grandson to hold.
She wouldn't have asked this kind of favor
if she didn't want a grandson so badly.
Did the obstetrician give you
a clean bill of health?
We just have to wait and see.
It's going to be used once
Tae Yun enters the country.
Stand up for me.
Excuse me?
Turn around.
Pardon?
Turn around. Mrs. Oh can also tell
if a woman is able to bear children.
Please take a good look.
Her butt looks small
from both sides, but...
it's much deeper than I thought
from the front and back.
The uterus has to be wide and deep
so the sperm doesn't leak out.
Let me see here.
Goodness, her eyebrows
are dark and her lips are thick.
Madam, there's nothing to worry about.
Just wait for your son to arrive.
Seriously.
He looks exactly like Park Tae Yun.
It's game over for me
if his parents find out.
Do I kill Cha Ki Young
and the child together?
Or do I only kill the child?
No, should I just kill Cha Ki Young?
Hey, Ki Young.
Yun Hee, I need to borrow your clothes.
I have to host a fashion show
but I have nothing decent to wear.
I don't have clothes that are
appropriate for a fashion show.
I'll go home and dig around my closet.
- I'm counting on you.
- Okay.
Those steamed ribs look delicious.
Have a bite.
It's perfect.
Should I...
- sleep here tonight?
- No, my friends are coming over.
Friends?
- Like who?
- Ah, just some girlfriends.
Female friends.
Really?
I went to Ara's Facebook this afternoon,
and she seems to be doing well.
I noticed she made a lot
of American friends too.
Yeah.
Since Ara's not here,
can't you move into my place?
What about marriage?
You want to get married again?
You want to live together
when we're not even married?
That's comfortable for both of us.
You should live alone
if you want to be comfortable.
Why would you want to live with someone?
No, come a bit later.
I'm going to go.
Wait.
Take these steamed ribs
with you and eat them at home.
What about that?
These are for my friends.
Your female friends?
Yeah.
See you later.
Chairman Park.
We plan on firing Cha Ki Young with
the upcoming company reorganization.
And?
Please let go of your anger now.
I know you took your ads out
because of Cha Ki Young.
Please come back and
do business with us again.
That was a long time ago.
Our news station went into a deep financial
crisis after you took your ads out, Sir.
Frankly, we don't have the power
to hold on anymore.
It might be better if your company took
over our station. What do you think, Sir?
I'm a businessman. I'm only concerned
about selling my products.
I'm a not a news person!
Chairman Park.
Sir!
Are you really going to leave
your junior high and dry?
We'll go ahead and work with you
because Eun Cha kept pressuring us.
Honestly though, I'm really worried.
I mean, it's not the first time
you screwed up.
It's been quite a while
since you've been an MC.
I'm going to get fired if I don't
pull through with this program.
And my child and I will have to live
on the streets if that happens.
I promise to do well.
Please trust me.
Somehow, I feel like I can relate to you
from hearing your brutal honesty.
Okay, let's all do our best
with Cha Ki Young.
Please take care of us.
- I think it's going to turn out well.
- Please take care of me.
Fighting!
Hello.
Hello?
This is the writer for the fashion show.
Please give me your email address
so I can send you the script.
Sure. I'll text it to you.
Madam, hello!
- It's been a long time.
- Yes, it has.
Isn't the membership fee
for this place ridiculous?
Getting in is more difficult than the cost.
Not unless you're a royal family.
As always, a woman has to be smart catching
the right man instead of just being smart.
Smart women are too busy trying to build an
impressive resume and compete against men.
They can't buy a decent house
in Seoul even after a decade.
You... got everything in one shot.
You're the winner compared to
all those arrogant spinsters.
Give me some dating advice.
On how to marry a rich man.
Hello, Ma'am.
Oh my, aren't you
Chairman Park's daughter-in-law?
My mother-in-law and I were thinking
about going to your boutique.
I was really busy preparing
the fashion show.
I sent an invitation to your mother-in-law,
so make sure you both come, okay?
Yes Ma'am.
That was Designer Oh Shin Hee.
Don't you know who she is?
Of course I know who she is!
I totally love her clothes.
I only have one outfit of hers.
It's so expensive.
Make sure you take me with you
to the fashion show, okay?
Well... we'll see.
[Cubs Village Fathers' Day Visit!]
Chan!
I'm sorry! Did you wait too long?
My precious baby,
let me take a look at you.
Did you eat?
- Are you upset because I came late?
- Yes.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
We have a Fathers' Day visit tomorrow.
- What would you like to do about Dan?
- What is that?
It's a party where the fathers
come and play with their children.
I think it might be best if
Dan took the day off tomorrow.
I have an important matter to take care of
tomorrow so he has to be here.
I prick him with a needle
and there's not even a drop of blood.
I mentioned how we attended
the same high school
and Chairman Park
still wouldn't budge.
Ho Pyung, is the company
in that bad of a situation?
In just the first half of the year alone,
we had a deficit of 20 billion won.
It'll be a 50 billion won deficit if
we go into the second half of the year.
Just hang in there a little longer.
Once I get elected...
Are you adding fuel to fire right now?
Do you have to leave at this critical time?
I'm much more beneficial to you
as a politician than a news anchor.
Just wait until I get that
gold badge pinned on my suit.
You think I'll let the news station
fall into ruins like this?
It doesn't have to be Chairman Park.
I'll rake in every nickel and dime
from all those tycoons.
Don't worry.
All you have to do is give me
your full support with my campaign.
I ran into Cha Ki Young today
at the news station.
Is that so?
I saw a picture of her son.
I thought she would give birth
to a monster from her sperm donation.
But he looks exactly like us.
He was quite good-looking.
By the way, you're sure
Tae Yun is not the father?
Of course. She got pregnant
from a sperm donation.
Goodness, what is this?
It's yongbong stew, Father.
I learned it from the culinary school.
They say all the kings
used to eat this in the past.
I was told this is a good dish for elders
recovering their energy to eat.
Is that so?
Ah Mother, Madam Oh Shin Hee
is holding her fashion show tomorrow.
She sent me an invitation last week.
Isn't Oh Shin Hee the wife of
Assemblyman Kim Pal Soon?
Her clothes are ridiculously expensive.
Yes.
The elections are coming up soon and he's
using his wife's fashion show as an excuse.
He's trying to get political funds.
You two might as well buy her clothes
since I'm making a hefty donation.
Okay.
It's very good. Sit down and join us.
That's okay, Father.
I'll just take my time and eat later.
[Fathers' Day Visit!]
Where are the other children?
They all went out to prepare
for the fathers' day event.
What about Dan then?
He doesn't have a father. How...
So, today was a day that children without
fathers shouldn't have come, is that it?
It's not that...
Then you should have been
frank with me yesterday!
I didn't want to say this to you...
but you're really cruel!
When the other children are laughing
and playing with their fathers...
What is Dan supposed to do?
What are we to do when
Dan is sad and down...
Excuse me...
are you a member of Club Jaekwon?
Yes.
Ah yes, please have a seat.
Are you the person that
came for the blind date?
Of course!
If you don't mind me asking,
how old are you?
I'm not that old!
I'm only 50 years old!
50 years old.
Then it won't be too long until
you celebrate your 60th birthday.
I'm trying to find a partner I can share
the last remaining years of my life with.
Last... remaining years?
After my late wife died of
cancer three years ago...
I was really, truly lonely.
I thought it was time to open myself up
and share my life with someone again.
I have two sons.
One moved out after he got hired.
The other rascal married early
and I even have a grandchild now.
You won't have to lift
a finger if you marry me.
- Hold on, I need to go to the restroom.
- Sure.
The restroom is over there.
Seriously, I'm going crazy!
Let's go.
Aren't you busy?
Isn't the fashion show today?
Anchor Jo.
I can't do the fashion show.
I know this is a huge inconvenience but you
should find someone to replace me quickly.
What the heck are you saying right now?
I have to be with Dan
at that time somewhere.
Are you crazy?
The news station is your bread and butter.
And you're telling me you're going
to bail the show because of your son?
- I'm sorry.
- I'll keep it short.
Turn in your resignation right now if
you're not going to host the fashion show.
Do you think the news station
is a child welfare foundation?
You don't even work!
Why does the station have to pay
you to raise your kid?
Mom.
Please lower your voice!
Dan can hear you!
Just how long are you
going to live in hiding?
Where did that high and mighty
attitude of yours go to?
I'm sorry.
Cha Dan, I'm not angry.
A man's voice is always supposed
to be loud if he wants to succeed in life!
Convince your mom and send her
to the fashion show. Understood?
Hey, Bro!
I heard you replaced Kang Ha Ni with
Cha Ki Young for Oh Shin Hee's fashion show?
Yeah. Why?
You know her husband is
Assemblyman Kim Pal Soon, right?
Of course I know!
And I know that he's nominated unofficially
as the chairman for the ruling party.
Did you also know that Kim Pal Soon
is the president of the
'Men Are of the Heavens and
Women Are of the Earth' club?
Really?
You're having a single mother
host a fashion show
of the wife of the most macho man
in the National Assembly?
You're going to be a great politician
with that brain of yours, you idiot.
Kang Ha Ni, dress up and come
to the fashion show right now! Right now!
Seriously, I'm going to go nuts!
Will the models please enter.
Walk down the runway.
Please continue.
Cha Ki Young.
I got an urgent order
from the company just now.
We need to switch MCs.
- Excuse me?
- I'm so sorry.
Anchor Jo Eun Cha will explain
all the details to you.
I understand.
Wait.
Give me the script and
cue cards before you leave.
Thank you. Here you go, Miss Ha Ni.
I'm sorry, but let's start the rehearsal
over with Announcer Kang Ha Ni.
I understand. Okay, start the music over!
Cha Ki Young, I'm sorry.
It was the President's order. I'll find
a better program for you to take over.
The fashion show is just a one time deal.
That's okay. Just help me not to get fired.
Okay! I can do that!
Where are you going to go now?
- To Dan's daycare.
- At this hour?
All the fathers are invited to
come visit their children today.
I declined the fashion show
because of that reason.
It turned out well since I got the boot.
I'll talk to you later.
Jo Eun Cha. You really are a rotten jerk.
You convinced her to be the fashion show MC
and then replaced her with Kang Ha Ni.
You're a two-faced liar.
Nothing but complete trash.
Good for nothing trash!
Trash, trash, trash!
Daycare?
First, let's introduce each
father that came to visit.
- Please introduce yourselves.
- I'm Kim Yoo Ki's father.
The next person please.
Yes, I'm Bo Na's father.
I'm Mi Jae's dad.
- Dan!
- Mom.
Ms. Cha, you came!
Dan, let's go home.
- You want to do that?
- Yeah.
Really?
- Who's your dad again?
- Cha Ki Young! My dad is Cha Ki Young!
Let's go.
Cha Dan's mother has come instead.
Please give her a round of applause!
Everyone please stand up and
carry your child on your shoulders.
Let's go on daddy's shoulders.
We'll start now if everyone is ready.
One, two...
Dan! Dan! Dan, are you okay?
- Dan!
- Dan! Dan! It's okay! It's okay!
Are you okay?
You idiot, you got hurt more!
It's okay! Let's go to the hospital!
Let's go to the hospital!
Let's go!
Fortunately, you didn't
break a bone or anything.
Your muscle is just in shock.
We'll give you a shot. Just take it easy
for a few days. You'll be fine.
Mom, are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
Cha Ki Young.
You're not going to raise Dan
as a hidden child, right?
Why would Dan be a hidden child?
He becomes a hidden child if the mother
keeps hiding and running away!
If your back is against the wall...
Then you just have to push
your way through! That's life!
Starting now, you do exactly as I say!
No matter what! No matter what! Got it?
Kang Ha Ni, go home.
Cha Ki Young is going to
be the fashion show MC.
- Excuse me?
Anchor Jo, are you joking right now?
Don't mess with me,
I'm not playing right now.
I refuse to obey your order.
It's unfair, Sir.
Is that so? Then starting tomorrow,
you're no longer an anchor!
I'll post the personnel
appointment tomorrow morning.
I refuse to be the MC as well!
Then turn in your resignation tomorrow!
How am I going to host
the show when I look this?
We have less than 30 minutes
before the show starts!
You kept on reporting the news
while you were in labor, remember?
Your dress is all ripped, right?
Kang Ha Ni, take off your dress and give it
to Cha Ki Young when you go home. Quickly!
Mom, you look pretty.
The little rascal knows
his mommy is pretty.
I'll take good care of Dan,
so go and show them what you got.
- Dan, have a good time with Mr. Jo, okay?
- Mom, fighting!
Fighting!
Hey, Mom.
- When did you get here?
- A little while ago.
Hello, Ma'am.
Eun Cha, I brought what you asked for.
But, why did you call me?
Dong Shik.
Starting now, I'm going to gamble.
And I need you to keep record of it.
Gamble? What kind of gamble?
I told you raise your arms.
If I let Cha Ki Young
host the fashion show...
I might not get nominated.
But I'm still going to do it.
Do you know why?
Because even if Kim Pal Soon
gets nominated...
My macho image right now
won't get me elected.
And?
As Dan's surrogate father...
What's connected to it?
A single mother like Cha Ki Young and
women like her are powerless in society.
What do we call something like this?
Feminists?
As of now, I'm going to become the
leading feminist in the Republic of Korea!
Me too, me too, me too.
Hello, my name is Cha Ki Young.
Just a moment!
Now, we have two MCs today.
Announcer Cha Ki Young and her son Cha Dan!
Please give them a round of applause!
Designer Oh Shin Hee's
fashion show concept for today...
is a happy life for the working women.
And we can't leave out children
in that happy life now, can we?
But you try to work and
your child cries out for you.
So you take care of your child but
then your job cries out for you.
Today...
this fashion show is
a place to cheer and support
the weary lives of those career women.
Now, please bring a chair
for our little Chan. Quickly.
You brought out a pretty red chair for him.
Dan will be hosting next to his mother...
and Designer Oh Shin Hee will
personally set him down in this chair!
Ma'am, please come out.
Thank you.
Okay then...
I will hand over the mic to
Announcer Cha Ki Young now.
The Seoul Designer Association has died
and Channel Korea is
giving its full support.
Oh Shin Hee's fashion show will now start!
Pedro, why are you...
Unbelievable. I took a picture of him.
- Why are you...
- Hey, hey...
Mother, do you need something?
No.
Announcer Cha Ki Young who publicly
claimed to be a single mother
is getting much attention
for hosting the fashion show.
Anchor Jo Eun Cha is also
the focus of public attention
in volunteering to be the surrogate father.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Why are you here?
And what brings you to my house?
Are you even a human being?
Go away!
I'm sorry, Myung Yi.
I feel so sorry for myself.
Show me your face.
I missed you.
You must be crazy. I'm married
and I have two kids, okay?
I'm going to be responsible
for the choices I made.
- He is your child.
- How... just how...
What are we to do?
It's better to expose it
if you can't hide it!
This Cha Ki Young can turn a man into
the president if you sleep with her.
Seriously, I'm going to lose my mind!
- Announcer Cha, where are you going?
- I lost my son.
Give me back my son!