Unduh-movies.blogspot.com
I know she'll be here that Professor McGonagall
Good evening Professor Dumbledore
Do not know rumors are not true anymore?
I am also very worried professors à On the good and evil
- And the baby, why? Hagrid is bringing it to
Instruments that wise to trust Hagrid with something important like that?
My whole life is to trust Hagrid
Dear Professor Dumbledore Professor McGonagall
- No matter what I believe Hagrid instead? Well okay
Just having a little trouble only fly over Bristol
Do him the province.
It then.
How specific do you think it's safe to leave it with these people?
I think this whole thing has held true evil is so amazing
The family that the boy live
The boy would become famous. He will not forget what the name implies
Yes
He better let it grow up away from the thing ...
until it is ready
It's not goodbye, but
Good luck ...
... Harry Potter
Bloody
Right now
Get up guy cousin, we go the park
Birthdays come and boys. Happy birthday son Nhe
Why you do not get baked bread for breakfast and try not to burn anything there
I want everything to be perfect
Dudley's special day for Pets
- How Fast! Dua li tao coffee. Well Uncle sparse
They are great not hard ha?
All how many?
Last year was the 37th of that
- A number larger than this number of children a year. I do not care how big they
This is what parents will do
My parents would buy you two new outfits Nhe
Would have a beautiful day in the park. Mother excited too.
Now I warn you
if there is any action that weird
you will have to starve in a week
Of the following graph:
Make it away
moved
cows go. It is sleep that
Animals boring
Sorry. It was liking that.
... see the ugly face swim
You can hear the game I mean?
I never ever talk to both solid
Do you ...
... Or talk to people?
You come from Burma, right? Nice but where?
You lose family?
Tao also be full. I never saw their parents again
Dad, here. Dad will not believe the snake is doing what
Thank you !
Ko nothing
Snakes!
Mommy save me
How did you fall in there?
What was her child and that this creep? There are no snakes?
Department Pets okay! Mother take me instead of wet suits.
- What happened?
- I swear is not known which
The mirror has disappeared like magic it
There is nothing magic here is the kid
Laughter does.
Vernon, watching him watch. I can not believe it.
In another week the boy will attend Smeltings.
Release of Smeltonia. That is most proud of in our lifetime!
I have things to wear that?
- Why? Smeltings you to attend?
- Ha!
Do not be stupid. You will attend Stone Walling, where with you.
You will wear this stuff after I dyed it.
But it is Dudley's old uniform. I would like elephant skin loss disguised.
Will fit only you.
Go get the mail out, quick!
Marge sick from eating a snail's funny.
Harry is a letter.
- Return to me, that's me
Who wrote that for you baby?
Will not have any letters any more by the mailbox
Wishes him a happy working
Go
Beautiful Sunday
As we are the best of the week. Why Dudley Huh?
Because there will be no mail on Sundays? That's right Harry
Ko messages from all
Today will not be cursed letters
Ko is a letter to all hell
Ko letter ...
Make it stop it!
Well now!
What's the mother?
Give me the letter
Put me out
They are her letters, throw me out
We will go away from here
Away from here, where they can not find!
Does not he is insane?
For a treaty to which Harry
Someone?
Sorry
I want him to leave immediately. He is broken into my house there
Hey, im Offers listening, Mr. Dursley?
I have long not seen since she was a baby
She looks bigger than it sounds. especially in the song there
I ... Harry's not
A nephew.
- Well of course she then
This is what I ne
I just fear that has sat on it but not much flavor is fine.
I made cake, both written and all disabilities.
Thanks Uncle
Entering the 11 th birthday must not
Sorry. Uncle is?
Rubeus Hagrid. The lock and keep the food at Hogwarts
Of course I know a little about Hogwarts instead. Ko a
I do not want to know why my parents are learning here?
Ko to ache
You're a witch there
She is something of a? A Witch
and I need to be trained a little
Make Your wrong. Italian children, I can not ...
... As a witch is
I just ... Harry
was only Harry. I've done anything that upset yet?
anything that I can not explain why when I was angry or scared
Hm.
Dear grandson Potter we are here to inform me that
She has received education at Hogwarts school of magic and magic
It will not go there we'll stop this silly stuff
Uncle knew without telling me?
Of course I know. How do you not rather have?
Sister completeness of the tao.
I'm very proud parent when it received a letter like this
We're a witch in the family miracle baby?
Only you I see how it is
Monsters!
When it encounters a hand Potter and generate you ...
... I know you also like only. strange and unusual
And when it exploded four that I stuck with you.
Explode? The people who say her parents died in a car crash
A car crash that killed Lily and James Potter are u?
It is insulting and shameful
It will not go anywhere,
A fat like his Muggle name, but ask to speak back?
Muggle?
Who have no magic. He had the right since it was born
You will learn best in magic schools
operated by the principal talent never thayt at Hogwarts, Albus Dumbledore particular.
I WILL NOT PAY FOR LABOR penny idiot straight wire POTTER What are evil!
Never insult Albus Dumbledore tools ...
... Before me
Uncle would appreciate if you do not tell this to anyone at Hogwart
- We are not the magic,
- Yes
Your only task is to make
Of course if you do not want to stay here
First year students need three sets of robes to practice ...
... A wand. "
A few essential items that Harry.
"A pair of leather gloves dragon."
Hagrid, that they are really a dragon?
They have no intention penguins right? Ha
- Crikey, I like a dragon.
- Uncle like dragons?
Just as people do not understand the beast only, Harry.
Confused.
"All students must be equipped ...
... A cauldron a size 2 or maybe more if you like ...
... With an owl, cat or toad. "
we can find all U in London?
If you find the right place.
Ah, Hagrid! As usual, but still
No thanks Tom I'm performing for Hogwarts
Helping Harry to school supplies shopping.
Chai Oh! It was Harry Potter!
Welcome me back, Potter.
Doris Crockford. I can not believe I finally met.
It's hard to describe the joy of it, Harry Potter.
Hello professor, I do not see him here
Professor Quirrel teacher would be against the Dark Arts Room of the child.
Pleased to meet me
Feeling awful appeal
We have to get going Potter
There are many things to buy
Welcome him.
Son of the famous, that does not
- A famous child star?
All they do know who she is?
Your Uncle is not sure the right person to tell you about it
Welcome to the Xeo Alley.
Here you will earn echidnas and ink.
There are all sorts of distortions to describe magic pi.
Flying broom class.
Look it behold the new Nimbus 2000
it is the fastest flying broom
Uncle Hargid me how to pay for this? I do not have money
Kia is her money, bank Gringotts wizards
Unable to secure. Except Hogwarts.
What exactly are they that?
They are the goblins, but is not the most friendly creatures.
Follow any Uncle
Mr. Harry wants to withdraw assets.
So Mr. Harry Potter is the key graph:
Wait a minute do I get it
It took a little bit difficult
and also something more
Professor Dumbledore gave me this
Get a bag he know it's out of the cellar
Very good
Ham 687
Please lamp
The key
Think that parents do not leave her anything, right?
- Ham 713
- Something in which a
Can not tell me the service was top secret at Hogwarts to
Back to back
Do not mention this to anyone Nhe Harry
I'm still missing a wand again
Wand u? In stores Olivanders No place better
Why not me in there and wait, your a few other things to do
Hello?
I wonder when I see, Mr. Potter.
just like only yesterday ...
... Father and mother here to buy the wand of their first
It then
Let's try it waved
It seems not to
Sometimes ...
This ...
No definitely not no problem ...
I wonder
Weird.
Yes, very strange
Sorry but what is he a weird?
I remember carefully one by which we sold to them
Phoenix has feathers ...
make her wand, has a different feather.
for someone else
It is strange as I was pre-fixed with this wand
As his wand of it causing it to scar me
And who owns a wand that?
We really do not want to say his name out
Wands often take a witch
Not always clear why
But I think clearly
that we can expect great things when the baby
after all he has done
Great
Horrible
but great
Harry
Happy Birthday Nhe
You're right
It seems longer shy
He did not kill my parents a right? Who left me this this?
Uncle said that Hagrid would say I know Uncle
First, your understand this because it is very important
Not all wizards are good
One of them had degenerated
A few years ago a wizard has become extremely cruel. And of his name is ...
- His name is ...
- Your can write it
Your spells do not know where
Well ... Voldemort
Shh.
It was a dark period Harry
Voldemont review and set those who follow him
bring them to the Dark side
Anyone who is against both died
Parents to have to fight them
No one saw the murderer
None
Except for me both
I u? Voldemont tried ... I kill u?
And then he left a cut on her forehead
It is the result of an evil curse
What happened to him?
Some say he died
Your guess he is still out there
Too weak to continue
but one thing is of course completely
about things that I have challenged him in the evening
That is why her popularity. That's why everyone says that to me
She is the baby still alive
She looked about?
By now it u?
Your grandchildren must break up, there is more work assigned to Uncle Dumbledore
The train will depart in 10 minutes
Her ticket here. Hold a good time. It is important to Gil
"Ga 9 ¾"?
But Hagrid, make any mistakes. This is the platform 9 ¾ where
What is the platform that
here?
Excuse Notes
Why?
can pay for me to know the platform 9 ¾ where not a
The platform 9 ¾, you do not think it was a joke silly game?
MRS. Weasley: It's the same every year, packed with muggles.
Go to the platform 9 ¾ this way
Percy child before going
Fred continued to do
- It's not Fred, I here of that.
- In the only other time we recognize
Sorry George
Con only a joke, but I was Fred
Sorry Uncle
Uncle told me how ...
how in the station right? Where not hard
Ron gambler is it the first time to Hogwarts there
All I do is go through the wall of the station was between 9 and 10
- Just try to run if you do not worry.
- Good luck
Hello. Are you afraid ... All the seats were packed and
No problem
Oh by the way his name is Ron
I was Harry Potter
Oh so that's true then
I mean he really is ...
- What?
- Scar was
Oh, yeah.
It's cruel
- There is not anything like the love child?
- No thanks, I already have all gone
They will take me a lot
Whoa.
- Among them is something that
- It's hard to say, chocolate and mint, the name Betty Bott, and gum meet you, very much
These frogs do not have it right?
It is just magic
Besides, each packet has a picture of a famous magician
- There is no real frog?
- The time is the mantra. which require the card.
Each package has a witch or a famous magician. I then earned a 500.
Look
We did not catch them where their
- I have the tools ne Dumbleore.
- I have something like 6 then
Specifically it was gone!
How could he want them to be around forever in it right?
This is Scabbers, you have permission or do with it
Little bit.
First you can prop it charm and turn into yellow hair. Not want to see?
Has anyone seen a toad ko?
-There is a boy named Neville has lost it
-No
`Ah you're doing magic Let's see how
As sunshine and daisies, butter yellow bile and melon
Please turn yellow
Are you sure that real magic is not there. Not very effective, right?
I became familiar with the simple stuff like that then
But it all works out
For light enough
Argounous Repairo ("Fix")
Does not get better right?
He is Harry Potter?
I was Hermione Granger. And you are?
- Ron Weaseley.
- Very pleased
You should also change clothes to uniforms. Maybe we'll get there soon
Well you can add a stain on the nose. You know, this place
Right there.
In one go this way.
How do the most embarrassing years. How Fast.
- Hey, baby, Harry.
- Hello Hagrid.
Whoa.
Take it any way. The children follow me.
Wow.
Data too!
Welcome to Hogwarts games
Just a little more time they will walk through this door join the party with classmates
Before sitting down to his seat, they must be classified in the House
Having the Griffindor, Hufflepuff, ...
Ravenclaw and Slytherin ...
When the children here, the house will look like child's family is so
Achieve good results, they are awarded points
Any violation of what the rules are penalized
At the end of the school, which earned the most points will win the Cup
Trevor
Sorry
Sorting ceremony will take place only for a moment longer
That's true. What I said was on board
Harry Potter went to Hogwarts
Harry Potter?
This is Crabbe and Goyle
And I was Malfoy
Draco Malfoy
Interesting name you think I do? Do not forget to ask you
Red hair that may coat your hands? You must be under the Weasley
He will earn the family witch blocks rather than bags.
He did not want to be friends with those who like but
I can help
I think I may find yourself kind of person who does bad
We are ready and now all I think
The ceiling is actually a witch by the prop to make it look like the sky outside
I've read about the history of Hogwarts
They wait in rows along the slide
Before we begin
Professor Dumbledor want to say a few words
I have a few notes to inform
The first year as we know it ...
... Students were banned entirely in the Black Forest
and he also supervised his Flich reminds me to remind the game
Third floor corridor on the right
is limited to those who do not wish pain or death
Thank you !
When we call someone names, please step forward
I will put my hat on top of em Classification
and they will be assigned to the
Hermione Granger
Oh, oh leisure travel.
What is the shortest I told him there
Now only time is now
Griffindor
Draco Malfoy
Slytherin!
It is not the team that asked its hat into Slytherin and
Susan Bones.
Ah!
Harry what?
Ko stars, their fine
Let's see ...
Hufflepuff
Ronald Weasley
Another Weasley boys home. I know what to do with him
Griffindor
Harry Potter
Very difficult
Courage is redundant
not a trivial mind if do not want to talk about talent
and desire to assert itself
but put him where to now
Slytherin's not sure he has not?
You'll really want to know. It's all in his head
And Slytherin will make him great
U did not hesitate
If the better ...
... Gryffindor!
Note that
We started the party but only pediatric
Wow.
Á themselves as witches.
Father is a Muggle. She is the shaman
Bit of a nasty shock for him When he found out.
He asked me, I sat next to his teacher Professor Quirrel is Ireland?
It was Professor Snape Slytherin Chairman
He taught what a?
Potions, like four things that he knew it was his passion
Hi, how I
Hello children to Griffindor
It's the Bloody Baron!
A summer of fun but
Once again our request to join Ma-takes-first Assembly rejected
You know, he is the first Nick must be narrowly-lost-a ko?
I would rather call me than if I was not afraid Nicholas
Almost-lost-investing, how he almost lost the first?
This like this
Griffindors Followers
Ravenclaw, follow me. This way.
This is the path leads directly to living room
Keep an eye on the staircases. They like to change.
Keep up, please, and follow me. Quickly now, come on. Come on.
The picture is moving
RON: Look at đó one. HARRY: I think she fancies you.
GIRL 1: Look! GIRL 2: Who's that girl?
Welcome to Hogwarts
Someone?
Password
Marsh mallow
Wow.
They follow me. Follow up quickly
We gather here
Welcome you to the living room of Griffindor
Men upstairs room on the left and women on the other side
They will find their belongings on it
How Fast!
You can imagine her face when McGonagall into class late ko?
- It's terrible.
- Thanks for that assessment of the role, Weasley.
Perhaps it would be better if we turn into a Potter game and watches affordable?
- And then maybe the game will arrive on time more.
- We would get lost.
So be sure to bring a map. I believe the role of households do not need anyone to find your place again.
There are no foolish wand waving a magic or stupid in class.
Of course, we do not expect the game
understand and appreciate the science and art as well as the preparation of this poison bottle.
On the few who choose
Ownership of the special formula.
We can teach the game to spell on the mind
and feeling trapped.
You can tell the game to hear how the reputation, or gain glory
and even death to those who give our block.
And again some people just to Hogwarts
live in their belief that qualified and confident to be able to ...
... Not focus!
Potter games.
Another popular new character.
Tells us that if we will be crushed into powder Arsedel roots?
Games not know à? Let's try again.
Games will find games where if we ask for a piece of diamond?
I do not know sir.
The difference between the poppy and oak beams?
I do not know a.
Unfortunately.
Clearly, fame is not all ...
Potter ko ... right?
Sure, Hermione said.
It seems a shame to not ask her.
Silence.
Put your hands down, the little silly,
Information for the game, Potter ...
... And spread wormwood Nhat Quang create powerful sleeping drug ...
... Be known as: The pain of death is life.
There is a gravel crushing bezoar from the stomach goat ...
... Can explain most of the toxins.
Hats priests and a wolf ...
... Also known as aconite.
That's it ...
... They are now waiting for what is not recorded on the file go?
The Gryffindors ...
... Will be deducted five points ...
... Because of the sassy.
Rabbit eyes, stuck tight. Turn water into rum.
Rabbit eye ...
Gregory is doing with a glass of that?
Turned into rum. Actually, he had to do it yesterday before ...
This letter.
I want now? Thanks.
Look, Neville get the ball a small packages.
I've heard of it. When the smoke turns red, that is something you forget.
Only problem is, I can not remember what I forgot.
Someone broke ne Gringotts bank. Listen.
Suspect this is caused by a sorcerer or magician Dark made anonymous,
The goblins at Gringotts while admitting responsibility rules, also emphasized that not all things will be lost.
Basement of 713 was actually almost empty before.
That is where my basement and Hagrid arrived.
- Welcome the class.
- Hi Ms. Hook.
Hi Amanda.
Welcome them to fly first class.
Also waiting for? People step on the right hand side of the broom handle any
Any hurry. Right hand raised them above the broom. And said: "What Up."
"Up"!
Soaring
- Up.
Up. Up!
Feel.
Up!
- Up. Up.
Up! Oh!
Harry stopped going.
Now, when they had learned the broom and she wants you to ride on it
Hold tight to it. You will not want to slip off the first broomstick.
When she whistled, she wanted each of you foot down on the ground
Hold brooms in the air, hovering a few laps,
then practice flying in a straight line gently, and then landed.
According to the flute of light, 3, 2, 1.
I Longbottom.
Longbottom!
Studies with!
Ground quickly!
Games Longbottom!
Whoa!
Ow!
People get out of that!
Play it right?
Well, the broken wrist and then. What's go.
They stand at the push while I put games Longbottom went to the hospital wing.
Me yet? If she saw a broom on no ...
c, the person must, but leave Hogwarts before being expelled.
This guy is the face of it.
Maybe it will have caps out there. Who will not remember this stuff for hours baby.
Return it right, Malfoy.
No way. I think I'll hide it somewhere for Longbottom to find.
On the roof, why baby?
How so, Potter? Beyond the right?
Harry, do not wait. He heard her say it that hooch.
Besides, he was not even flying.
What an idiot.
Put it here if not I will kick you off flying broom there.
Really?
So then how do you?
Beautiful, Harry. Look, Harry!
Harry Potter!
Follow me.
The waiting game then.
Professor Quirrell, Sorry. Wood can I borrow at one time is not?
Oh, of course.
Potter, this is Oliver Wood. Wood, she has found for you a range manually.
She has heard of Harry Potter is the new range of Griffindor not?
I always knew that boy made good.
Why the U? But in the first year is often not selected for team players.
- He surely is the youngest Quidditch player in 100 years.
- According to her McGonagall.
Doing well, Harry. Locking Wood just told him.
Fred and George are also in the team. The recovery there.
The mission of four he was not sure I dropped off the broom.
Arduous sport, Quidditch.
Violence. But no one died over the years. A few people have an accident.
But they still come back after one or two months.
Come on, Harry. Quidditch is a great thing. He will be great.
What I have never played Quidditch all. What happens if I'm an idiot?
No, you will not mistake any where because it was ingrained in his blood then.
Whoa.
Harry, he never told his father he is also a range of game players?.
I do not know that.
I'm talking to him there, it's spooky. He knew more than what you know.
Why not?
What's happening?
The stairs are moving. Remember?
- Let's go this way.
- Before moving the ladder again.
Does anyone think that we should not here?
We do not intend to here that.
This is the third floor there. It is not allowed.
Come on.
- That he Filch's cat.
- Run.
Quick fast. Hide behind that door.
- It's locked then!
- Like that.
Stay away!
Alohomora.
Go inside.
Alohomora?
Basic Books Mantra, Chapter 7.
There is not anyone here?
Come on.
- Filch he left.
- So I think the door is locked.
- It was locked.
- For a good reason.
What schools are you doing? Keep things like that one in a store like that
À Do not pay attention? You do not see what it was standing above him?
I do not look at his feet. Then you're looking at first.
Can you not clear, it has three consecutive head!
It was standing on a trapdoor, that is not coincidence that it is there
- It's guarding something.
- Guard?
That's right. Now if you are no longer two anymore, I go to sleep.
Before the two he went to a wise idea that we almost lost their lives.
Or worse, stripped of magic.
He needs to reassess itself there.
Quidditch, easy enough to understand. Each team has seven players.
Visit the 3, 2 Tan players, a goalkeeper, and a systole. Chinh em there.
There are three different types of balls. This is called Quaffle.
The bird left the Quaffer Access and trying to throw it through three other golf circles.
Keeper, is he here, defending the stakes golf. No questions too?
I think so. What are a few other things?
You should try this.
Be careful, it is coming back.
Not bad, Potter. You may be the best attack there.
Uh-oh.
A. What is that?
Blugger ball.
But she is withholding.
The only thing that I want you to worry about is this.
Golden Snitch ball.
- I like it.
- Knowing that you like
But wait. It flew so fast and hard to see.
What are you doing with him?
I caught it before the Games the other teams do.
Did you get it, the game will end.
Did you get it, Potter, and we won.
Whoa.
The primary skills, magic spells of witches.
That spells Bay. They make objects fly.
They have feathers yet? That's good.
Do not forget the gentle smooth motion when we practice.
Just wave the wand and tap it. What the children.
Waving and tapping. Good.
- While waving your chopsticks they shouted: "Le-vio-sa wingardium"
- They do go.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Stop, stop. You're making people pay attention there.
Furthermore did you even read the wrong mantra. Pronounced "Le-vio-sa," not by "Le-vio-sar"
If you understand how then do it. See how.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Doing good. Do not you see? She is done already!
Excellent!
Very good.
I think we need a different feather sparse professor.
Must be "Le-vio-sa," not by "Le-vio-sar"!
She was a nightmare, really there. No wonder how it did not have friends.
I think he heard it there.
Hermione then what?
I hear a girl saying he was not out of the female toilets.
It says he's in there throughout the afternoon, and cried.
Monster rose from the cellar!
Everyone should know.
Any order!
The game is not lost.
Now ...
... The chief Huynh will lead them to living room
Teachers follow me to the basement.
Griffindors, held every entrance and alarm for each
How the hell is that place?
Monsters are often stupid. Sometimes these people are joking we should.
- What?
- Hermione, he knows not!
I think that monster out of the tunnel.
And going to female restrooms.
Hermione, run away!
Help!
Hey!
Studies with!
Whoa!
Ugh.
What to do instead!
- What?
- Whatever!
- Quick!
- Loans and tap!
Wingardium Le-vio-sa
Or much.
It's not dead baby?
I do not think so, sure it only fainted.
Dirty monster.
God. Explain to us to see. Both of em!
It is the fault of the children sparse Professor McGonagall.
Ms. Granger U?
I went looking for giant monsters, you already know about it. I thought I could catch it.
But I was wrong.
If Harry and Ron do not come and find me ...
... I would have died.
This was an extremely foolish act
She had hoped that a rational action of the children. I make her disappointed, Granger.
5 points will be deducted from the Griffindor ...
... By the lack of consideration of children.
Both of you, too ...
... She hopes they clearly see how lucky you
Not many first-year students could take down a monster so mature
and holding it until the last minute.
5 points ...
will be awarded for each child.
So good luck that weird.
They should go away. It can wake up there.
Fortunately, because we both have from the former Ministry of trouble.
I saved it that.
Small will not be saved if we are not locked up.
Friends to do what?
Making only a few bread crumbs.
You need to have good health today
I do not hunger that
Good luck Potter, Quidditch Morning
A game to prove himself, but is not the easy job
Especially against Slytherin
Tumor samples?
Listen, last night I guess Snape used the attack tactic
in fact for him to come to the dogs
but it was biting him again. That's why his legs go limp so
Why would anyone want to come near the dog that?
The day that you and Hagrid went to get it out of the basement material
Uncle said that it is duty of Hogwarts. Inscrutability
So you're going to say ...
That is what the dog is guarding the game. It's something Snape wants
- Do you own brushes à
- I never had a whole
They open it yourself
A broom
Not where ordinary brushes. It is a Nimbus 2000 broom effect propulsion
But who-?
- Fear not Harry?
- A little
He also has such a feeling before the first match
- What happened to a?
- I do not remember anymore
He wrapped a bandage on his forehead
and woke up in hospital a week later
Welcome to the first match of the season at Hogwarts
Slytherin match today against Griffindor
Gryffindor!
The players take their position ...
... To be able to start the game
and I want a nice game
from all children
The Bludger flew up, then the ball Snitch.
Remember the ball will bring 150 points Snitch
Why do players catch the Snitch ends the game
And the game starts
10 points for Griffindor
Very good
Good!
Slytherin back position
10 more points for the Griffindor
Give it to me!
You to side!
Whoa. Whoa!
What happened to Harry's broom that?
It was Snape. Lao had charms broom prop
- Peer charms U? We do?
- For it yourself
How quickly, Hermione!
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
Austria behold he fires
Go, go, go, go!
Looks like it was how he
He caught the Snitch
Harry Potter gained 150 points for home team
Griffindor win
Oh, no.
Yes!
How badly? Why the concept curse Snape to Harry's broom instead?
They know me. So why did he try to pass the three-headed dog in a Halloween night?
Who told the children about Fluffy?
- Thursday, including a name?
- Of course it has a name and it's Uncle
Uncle brought it on last year. After that doctor would allow it to Dumbledore to guard ...
Yes?
Do not ask any more questions anymore. That's a secret
But I have Fluffy matter what Snape is also trying to steal it
Professor Snape is a school teacher Howarts
The teacher or not. I have seen his magic and
He kept looking at him and focused on not blinking at all
Exactly
All three of us listen
The children are desperate to intervene in what the children are also not known. It is very dangerous
The dog guarding the only things that Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel knew
Nicholas Flamel?
I should not mention her last name to
Who is Nicholas Flamel that?
I do not know.
Merry Christmas Merry Christmas
Ring the Hogwart bell ♪ ♫
Cast a spell Christmas ♪ ♫
E knights box 5
The queen cell E 5
It was brutal
This is the witch that flag. I have seen him arrange luggage
I see you are not
Change of plans that he, his parents decided to go to Romania
to visit his brother, Charlie. He is researching the dragon there
We will find in the library of information on Nicholas Flamel
We have searched 100 times
Restrict area where it is not. Happy Christmas
I think we can influence him there
Harry rose and
- Merry Christmas Harry.
- Ron Christmas fun
What are you wearing?
His mother may it there. Looks like he has one
I have a gift à
it is here
My father asked me to keep taking this before he died
It is time we give it to you Use it for good
- What?
- Velvet mantle that
He even go into any
Whoa!
People disappeared and
I know this stuff. It's an invisibility cloak
His invisible
Why give this person again for his children?
There is no sender's name. It says only use for good
Where Mr. Nicholas Flamel?
Someone?
Who?
Lo away
Quiet.
I ...
He does not want me to be his enemy but, Quirrell.
- What is your Italian?
- You know what I mean ten thirty that.
We will talk together soon.
For a time he should consider his loyalty anywhere.
Professor. I found this in the restricted areas.
It is still hot. That means students have still to bed.
Mommy?
Daddy?
Ron, you really have to see this stuff! Go see it!
Ron, go do. Out of bed!
- Why?
- There are some things you need to see, go!
At this point, see my parents go!
I only see them yourself that.
Looking directly at. Standing here goes.
- That he saw them, right?
-It was his!
Huynh his head is! I'm holding the Quidditch Cup!
And can not imagine! I was Quidditch captain, too!
I looked great.
Harry, do you think the mirror will tell the future we do not?
No way? Lost both his parents then.
- He loves his gifts than Ron?
- Portuguese Christmas will be here the whole game?
Indeed it is.
Ron? Ron?
- I'll be right back.
Play chess instead?
- No.
- Visiting Hagrid not?
No.
Harry, I know you are thinking, but do not ...
There is something wrong with the mirror.
Return eh, Harry?
We see the same with many previous
also discovered the joy that brings Mirage mirror
He believes that children will recognize the things that it brings.
To see an example for children.
The happiest man on Earth if you look in the mirror
will see only his own image,
exactly what he
Therefore, the mirror shows us what we desire Anything we do not want to correct a
Yes. And wrong.
It does not add or take from us anything
except where the deepest and desire, the desire of my heart tremendously.
Now children, Harry, had never known his family.
So I see them standing beside me.
But remember, Harry,
The mirror is not put back a little knowledge
Where does the truth or
People will be wasted if one stands before it. This may even be that insane.
That's why tomorrow it will be moved to a new home
And he reminded the
Do not go looking for it again.
It's not good if you leave it tame dreams,
Harry, forget it and live it.
Hi, Hedwig.
Watch the pile of cards to play with the other. Vapor.
Coming final test there and then.
I ready. Ask away.
The three most important components of drug What is Neglect?
Forgot it.
So he would do if it is in the upcoming test?
- Watch the tigers away?
- No.
Besides, said Professor McGonagall ...
... They found their special kind of porcupine quill to fraud.
It's insulting! They do not believe us!
Both Dumbledore again.
- Curse tied rolls.
- Malfoy.
Bo said to resist it but, Neville!
How? I do not want more problems.
I will practice allows the curse.
No, what I need is ...
lakeshore his knees into the fire.
I do not appreciate what implies, Longbottom.
Besides, if anyone is interested ...
then his eyebrows grow back completely.
Found it.
"Dumbledore is really popular ...
... For having defeated the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945 ...
- Come on.
- ... by the discovery of 12 uses of dragon's blood and ...
... thanks to the work of composing tools of alchemy with Nicolas Flamel is the collaboration?
I know a name like that. I have read while on the train.
According to her.
Wait, how much you go?
What about the curse allowed?
I asked the boy looking in the wrong place then. Could I so stupid baby!
I was tracking back the atmosphere much thinner than last week.
It looks thin children?
Of course! Here it is.
Nicholas Flamel is known to be the only one who did the Sorcerer's Stone
What?
Really, why not read his two go?
Sorcerer's Stone is a legendary substance with amazing strength.
It turns any metal into pure gold,
... Help people to increase life. And that he becomes immortal.
- No U? That means he will never die
I know!
The unique stone exists currently is owned by Nicholas Flamel particular,
who last year was celebrated birthday of his 655.
That is what the guard on the third floor Fluffy
That is what lies under the door down. Sorcerer's Stone.
Sorry, do not want rude, but Uncle did not have time where the children entertained.
They grandchildren about the Sorcerer's Stone.
Oh.
- We I think Snape is trying to steal it.
- The child is still how u hate him?
Hagrid, Snape I know they stand behind the story of rock, but do not know what that reason only.
Snape is one of the teachers are protected rock. He can not steal it.
What's wrong?
The children hear and there. Come on, we are not free today.
Wait. One of a teacher?
Of course! So is there other things not to protect a rock?
Magic spells.
That's right. Ask us, only time-consuming.
No one to step through all the Fluffy.
No one knows how. Except for artillery and Dumbledore.
Uncle said it but should not children.
- Hagrid, so that's exactly what a?
- It's ... It is a ...
I know.
But Hagrid, how it silver?
Ta winning it from a stranger met in a bar.
He seemed glad to be liberated it is only common sense.
It is ...
A ... a dragon?
Not only time where dragons. It is bat witch Novigem.
His brother Charlie are working on it in Romania.
It looks really nice. Alas. Look, it realized there mother.
Hello, Norbert. Norbert?
It also needs a name, right?
Not true, Norbert?
It should also be trained a little, of course.
Who is it?
Malfoy.
Heaven and earth.
Hagrid always wanted a dragon. Uncle was always going to say that when you see your first time.
It's crazy. Worse than that, Malfoy had said.
- I do not understand, that's not good game?
- Bad bad there.
Good evening.
I repeat, students do not have permission
roam the school at night.
So the penalty for acts of the game, 50 points will be deducted.
50 U? Everyone.
And to make sure it's not happening again ...
... All four games will be subject to Gansu.
Sorry professor. Are not you heard wrong.
I heard her say "four" we.
No, the game was there to hear exactly Malfoy.
It deserves the intention of the game. Games have done something outside the bedroom for hours ha.
Games will be subject to Gansu with you.
Not a bad penalty.
Gansu will take better around the basement there.
Lord, we do not hear the screams of the game.
The game will be banned tonight sufficient to Hagrid
He has a little work to do in the Forbidden Forest.
Unfortunately, when the North to take it, Hagrid.
Good place, he will no longer be with the dragon damned right?
Nobert gone. .
Dumbledore gave it to Romania. Let it live up to the pack.
Good right? It will stay with the same type.
If it's not like Romania, why?
What happens if the other dragons field it desertion? Ultimately it's still just a baby.
For the sake of God, come together to remember all that boys and girls.
The structure will go into the woods. and think about their work.
U forests? I think it is only a joke instead. We can not go through that is.
Students are prohibited. And there are both ...
The Wolf!
Strange land over which there are many people around here Wolf.
The game can know for sure.
Black night. Yes.
We go.
Hagrid, what that?
We are here because this here. Not found?
This is the blood of the Centaurs. I found a few weeks before death.
And it was important that someone is causing injury.
So the task is to find the monster was pitiful.
- Ron, Hermione, along with your.
- Yes.
Harry, I go with Malfoy.
Okay, so I will get the Fang.
Good, but you need to know it is pretty shy animals there.
Fishing with you dad I'll know. It is true that the work of slaves!
If I know this will be bad, Draco, I think you're afraid then lower.
Fear of U, Potter?
You do not hear?
Come on, Fang.
Scared!
What is it, Fang?
Harry Potter, I should leave. Many organisms are known her here.
This forest is not safe now. Especially with children.
But he has nothing to save her from that?
A strange evil creatures. Killing a Sagittarius is a disgusting crime.
Drink the blood of a Sagittarius will help us maintain a temporary life. Even when he was dying.
But the price paid in disgust. If I kill something so pure pure
every moment I touch the blood that she is living through.
A cursed life.
- Who to choose such a life?
- I do not think anyone u?
Do you mean, guys that killed the Centaurs, drinking its blood,
U is Voldemort?
I know what he was looking every day of ko Potter?
Sorcerer's Stone.
Harry!
Hello, Firenze. I saw him live with you boy Potter.
But I'm okay, Harry?
Harry Potter, it is time to go.
Now she was safe. Good luck.
Ke-you mean that well-know-who-who-is-out-there are other woods, right?
But his weakness, he lives by the Centaurs.
You guys do not you see? We were wrong.
Snape did not want to take the rock to him. Which is to Voldemort.
There is more life, Voldemort will be stronger again.
He will reappear.
If his back ...
... You do not think to kill him but does he?
I think if he had the chance, he could kill me right tonight.
And then worry about his Potions exam last year.
Wait. We own forgotten something.
Who was the only wizard Voldemort always binary?
Dumbledore. As long as Dumbledore is around here, Harry, he was safe.
Dumbledore as long as he will not be touched him.
I always do the test so bad last year. But I found very interesting.
Go ahead and rhetoric. Why so, Harry?
- Scar. It aches.
- It was not true then.
- Not like this.
- Maybe you should see a doctor.
I think it is alarming. means that the danger is imminent.
- Of course.
- What?
You do not feel a bit weird u? Hagrid best thing to a dragon.
And when strangers are present, he has an Uncle?
I mean, how many people are wandering with a dragon egg in their pocket?
Why did not realize before the baby?
Hagrid, who gave the middle dragon? How he looked a?
Uncle do not know, Uncle guys ever face. He was holding the hood.
Even stranger, the Uncle has talked to him but
He wanted to know about the creatures that Uncle nursing
Uncle told him that Uncle Fluffy is child care. A dragon egg is also not a problem.
He is excited when talking about Uncle Fluffy ko? Of course he loves Fluffy.
I have a dog step by step through the first three before? Even if this is an exchange
But Uncle said to him, stories about monsters, the underground exchange every time.
Get Fluffy the example slightly. Just walk up music, it will fall asleep immediately.
We ought not to say that.
The children going?
We need to see Dumbledore. Immediately Asia.
Ta e Professor Dumbledore is not here.
Specifically he received emergency service from the Ministry of magic and then immediately to London.
Specifically it go already? But the important thing. It is the Sorcerer's Stone.
- How will the game know ...
- There are people trying to steal it.
I do not know how these kids know about rock, but we make sure the game is perfectly protected.
Now the game should go on living room a quiet way
It would not be a stranger at all.
This is Snape, which means he knows how to beat Fluffy.
- As soon as Dumbledore is gone.
- Hi.
3 children home Griffindors
are now huddled do here?
We just ...
Be careful. People will think the game ...
... Are attempting something.
Now I do?
We will come to shutter it. Tonight.
Trevor.
Trevor, go away. You should not here.
You guys should look like. The back of his hiding out right?
- Do not know.
- No, its not allowed!
You guys will again make the Griffindor trouble. I will ... fight with him.
Neville, I'm really sorry about this.
He sometimes terrible baby. You know that.
Great, but it was terrible.
We go.
Sorry. So it is good for you.
I stomped my feet. Sorry.
Alohomora.
Wait.
It is right here.
Snape was here before. He was cast onto the other harp.
Visit its breath.
- We must pull his feet away.
- What?
Come on!
Then, pulling away.
I will be down before. Do not jump in until his fame lightly.
If something bad happens, you take yourself out of here.
Sao seems to quiet the baby?
Harp!
It stopped playing then.
Ugh. Yuck!
Jump away!
Whoa.
May be this is the trees.
Whoa!
Do not move. This is a trap, vines of Satan.
You guys have to relax. If not it will kill you more quickly.
U Kill us faster? Now you can give up!
Hermione!
We're going to do? Just ignore them it!
- Hermione, Where is he?
- Follow what I say! Just trust yourself!
Harry!
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, their health.
- He not sit still, right?
- It looks like that.
- We must do something yourself.
- No. What?
I remember reading about them in the book Herbalists.
Satan vines, they cause death ...
... But will disappear when the sun rises. Itself! Satan vines photophobia.
Lumus Solem.
- Not right?
- Yeah.
May we not be confused.
May is a hard subject Hermione Herbalists it.
What is it? Do not know.
Sounds like wings.
Curious fact, I have never seen birds like this.
We do not have to birds, which are key
And I bet some of them open the other locks.
- All this is what?
- I bear.
Too.
Alohomora!
Well, worth trying to make.
What do we do? There must thousands of keys here.
We will find what looks to which was obsolete. Maybe it rusted so hold.
There they are, I see it. Bay with yellow wings.
Not wrong, Harry?
It's simply too much.
Go away, Harry. If Snape can catch the key on the broom, then he can.
He is the youngest range in this century.
It is only slightly more than a little trouble.
Catch the key!
Quick!
I do not like this much. Absolutely not.
Where are we? À graveyard?
This is not the cemetery.
Which is a chessboard.
In the other door.
Now what?
Clearly then right? We'll play chess to pass this room.
Okay, Harry, he stood on the empty squares away.
Hermione, you will be queen statue standing army.
In his own troops would be knights.
Now what happens?
Well, go ahead and white army.
Then ...
Our turn.
Ron, he is not for this ...
Wizard is a real game instead?
Other troops, cell D5!
're Right, Hermione.
I think it is exactly a game going on really.
Statue cell E4!
To cell C3!
Wait. You know why it there, Harry.
I just moved, my queen will begin immediately.
Then he will compare general comfort.
- No, Ron, no!
- What?
- He shall sacrifice myself!
- No, he can not! There must be another way than!
You guys want to stop Snape or not get it rock?
Harry, the boy must be doing it!
Not her, not Hermione. Which he is.
Knights cell H3.
Checkmate.
Ron!
No, do not move! Do not forget we are still playing there.
Checkmate.
Caring for Ron lightly. Then please leave.
Send a message to Dumbledore. Ron was right.
I have to keep time.
He'll be fine, Harry. He is a Great Wizard. Really like
How are you using.
I u? I shall only be per-intelligent and avid reader only. There are more important things.
That friendship and courage. Now, Harry, take care of.
As a teacher u?
No, impossible. Snape, he ...
He's new look seems to be what guys are scams right?
Beside him, one would suspect Quirrell pitiful teacher
to speak also stuttered as we here?
But the day is going Quidditch match, Snape tried to kill me that.
No, boys, is one who tries to kill mi.
Information we go, if Snape does not stick to interrupt fire and reciting the mantra of our eyes,
Then we have success.
Even if Snape used raw.
Snape tried to save me?
I know mi would become very dangerous. Especially after Halloween.
- And then he released the monster?
- Judging this level.
Ko may Snape did not naive at all.
When others fled, they dragged him up the third floor and one outside.
He, of course, never believe me again.
He has isolated us. But he do not understand.
I was never alone at all. Never.
Now, the mirror has a role?
We see what we desire.
We realize that we are holding this rock. But how to get it?
Use him.
Come here, Potter! Right now!
Tell mi hear What was that kid?
What is it, what you see?
I'm Dumbledore waved his hand. I won the House Cup.
It lied.
Tell the truth! Do you see anything?
- Let us tell it.
- Sir, that is not strong enough.
One powerful enough to do this.
Harry Potter ...
... We meet again.
Voldemort?
Yes, and you saw me there and become something.
I have seen work to do to survive.
Living behind a human body
Human blood will maintain a code of life.
But it can not give us one of their own body.
But one thing it can.
Something that has enough strength lies in people's pockets.
Block it!
Do not be so stupid.
Why suffer the death
while mi can follow me and live?
Never!
Very brave. Parents you have things.
As we listen, Harry,
you may want to look back at my parents again ko?
Together ...
... We can take them back.
All we require is.
It is there, Harry.
No angel or devil at all.
Only power.
And the other guys were too weak to have it.
Together, we can make something extraordinary.
Just take us to rock only.
You lie!
Catch it!
- What magic?
- Get the colors rock!
Hi son, Harry.
- Gifts from those who admire you.
- Admire?
What happened between you and Professor Quirrell in the basement is a complete mystery.
So naturally the whole school knows.
He saw Ron has helped reduce the problem by eating
This dish is chocolate frogs.
Ron here? He is so not him? What about Hermione?
Medicine. Both of them are healthy kids.
- Rock like already?
- Relax take any son.
Stone has been destroyed then.
You see Nicholas and he had a little chat
and agreed that it is the best way.
But that detail would not be a death?
Instrument was able to arrange everything for you.
But right then he will die tool.
How did you get the rock they found?
First few minutes I just stared at the mirror, then ...
Only those who want to find rock,
find it, not use it,
can get it.
That is one amazing teacher ideas.
This is a secret of our own two.
That means if I lose Stone, Voldemort will never be able to return to A?
He e is ...
... He was still way back.
Harry, I know
why Professor Quirrell can not let you touch him not?
That's because there mother. She has sacrificed himself for me.
He left the magical protection for children.
No, it is not visible.
- It exists in each of the muscles in children.
- So what is a?
Love, Harry. Love.
Bertie Botts, full flavored candy favorites.
He unfortunately when youth do not enjoy them.
He then again ... He no longer interested in them.
I will not fine.
With a delicious hard candy.
Hm, alas!
Indeed. This is the wax!.
- It's all rather, Ron?
- Very good. And you?
Good. Hermione?
Could not be better.
One year has passed again.
Now as we know, the Cup should be awarded.
In order of total points of the.
Ranked as the Griffindor Wednesday with 312 points.
Location Tuesday, Hufflepuff with 352 points.
Second place ...
... Ravenclaw with 426 points.
The head ...
... With 472 points, is the Slythetin.
Nice one, mate.
Well, Slytherin.
However, some recent events should also be calculated more.
And I have some points in the last minute.
Hermione Granger for her.
Because the ability to apply great speculation.
50 points.
Good job.
Monday, the game Ronald Weasley.
Because the past has won a rare game at Hogwarts, 50 points.
And Tuesday ...
... Is game Harry Potter.
Because the clear spirit and courage special.
I reward the more Griffindor 60 points.
We in the House of Slytherin then.
And finally, we need more courage to confront the enemy.
But will need more when we must stand up to prevent his own friends.
Therefore, I award 10 points ...
... To play Neville Longbottom.
I am confident that my calculations are correct,
So I believe we need to change the layout a bit here.
Griffindor won the Cup!.
Yes!
We won!
Board the time, hurry up. No games will be too late.
Any hurry
- Up time, Harry
- One minute.
Although I have not left a goodbye.
This should still be her.
Thanks Uncle, Hagrid.
Well go away. Listen, Harry.
If the guy of her cousin, the Dursleys, Dudley guy was, cause me any trouble,
... I take every threat it for Uncle ...
... That it will be commensurate with his ears tail in him.
But, Hagrid, we are not allowed to use magic outside Hogwarts.
Uncle said. But he is not their child, correct?
Strange feeling when you go home, right?
I do not go home.
Really are.
Unduh-movies.blogspot.com