Our story begins
high above New York...
... in a luxury penthouse..
. .. one of the greatest geniuses
that world has ever seen.
Sorry, you cut with
in the middle of yoga.
Do you expect the 'hunched Dog'?
(Yoga postures).
My name is Mr. Peabody.
And if you spend some time together
...
... I
tell you some things about me.
Viewing,
since I was a puppy,
was evident,
that I was different.
Tried to 'fit in':
"No, thanks"...
... But they never did it.
As I grew up, I saw more and more
'colleagues'
be adopted by new families.
But for some reason,
me never chose.
Come on, boy,
fetch the stick!
But why?
Do not discarded?
Is exercise in futility.
Do not want him him, Mommy.
Is sarcastic.
Wait, come back!
Drop the stick.
'll Fetch, will sit judiciously,
I'll even shake his hand!
Bark, bark.
Therefore, without my family...
... dedicated to search
knowledge.
In art, and
in sport.
I got my degree from Harvard.
Dogs  -Torah (dog = dog) course.
And then dedicated myself to help
humanity.
By evolve new
techniques in alternative energy.
To solve the geo-political conflicts
worldwide.
And in my spare time, I invented
-fist salute...
... the board and the lingerie
which can easily be...
... The back spin
with skateboard and...
... the Zouba!
But more than
all'm proud of my son.
Sherman.
Hello, Mr. Peabody.
You told them about "Back in Time"?
Now I say.
When I adopted Sherman,
vowed to be as good a father as possible.
Prepare him for all
wonders of the world, present and past.
So, Sherman
inspired the greatest invention of my life.
Time machine!
Of course, time travel
may be a little... unpredictable.
There may be several setbacks
path.
For example, the Leaning Tower of Pisa
was not always inclined.
But
nothing compares to learning firsthand
lessons of history.
Right, Sherman?
In what part would go today,
Mr. Peabody?
Not in what part, Sherman,
but at what time.
French Revolution-1789
The biggest house I've ever seen!
Is Versailles,
residence of Marie Antoinette.
Mostly   was known for one thing:
"Cake! How I love cake!"
She loves the cakes,
Mr. Peabody.
Indeed likes.
Maria was a woman with a huge appetite
For what had whipped up.
But the expensive taste of
made her a target for criticism.
Why?
Because, Sherman, during the reign of
...
The people of France were extremely poor.
- Got any bread?
- Not! I am very poor!
- Now we can have some cake?
- But of course!
Sorry, we could
Let's have some cake?
But, of course!
You can not hear me
through hair.
Sherman, what
means the queen is...
Let them eat cake!
And when the hearing including Queen
that the people of Paris...
... could not buy bread or...
... said:
"Give them eat cake!"
Yes, I heard it myself.
- Scandal!
- Shocking!
- Down with the Queen!
- Down with the monarchy!
Wait.
What kind of cake?
Long live the Revolution!
The party 'kicks ass', Your Majesty...
... But now, I fear
Sherman and I have...
Sherman. Sherman!
Sherman!
Sherman?
Seeerman!
- Sherman!
- Hi, Mr. Peabody.
What are you doing here?
Try other cakes.
There is a  here, with whipped cream and strawberries
, which is...
... fantastic!
Sherman, do not remember why I
I told you to stay close to me...
... during the French Revolution?
Because  after the French Revolution, it rained
?
Because, after the French Revolution...
... comes the panic!
Long live the Revolution!
Surround aristocrats!
The Queen  and classy
minions...
... must pay the price
for their greed!
Will slaughter them like dogs,
as they deserve!
Starting with this!
Mr Peabody, what to do?
Nothing Sherman,
stay where you are!
But Mr Peabody...
All will go well, Sherman.
You stay right where you are!
Cut his head off!
Mr. Peabody!
kantaloup? (Type of melon).
The worst of the food!
What else would tolerate now?
Find this dog!
Mr Peabody, how you escaped?
Simple, Sherman.
I watched
distance between the tops of the sewer...
... I thought that there must be some
just below the guillotine...
... I noticed the loose plank
under the basket...
... Calculate the angle at which the sun
will be reflected in the glasses...
... momentarily blinding the executioner...
... and chose that moment to put the
melon...
... Which gave me the extra weight
...
... to facilitate my escape.
Fantastic!
No. It was to keep my head
.
Keep your head...
not understand.
There he is!
Hunt them down!
Come on, Sherman, quickly!
This water has horrible taste!
Interestingly,
that is not water!
You got now!
Indeed, sir Robespierre...
... And what a terrible craftsman
to chase you!
Noticed.
But naturally. So as you came
behind me, it was genius.
Thank you.
I just hope not to get
my little accomplice of here,
because it is based entirely on it.
Come here you!
- You are fiendishly clever, sir.
- I know.
And much faster than you.
But you're quick enough...
... so what?
See? Express!
Express may,
but not so smart.
Another kantaloup!
Your sword.
Well, Sherman seems
that the time
A short quiz
in the art of swordsmanship!
Go!
Forward! Balance!
Shaking! Repeat!
- Missed!
- Do not miss ever.
Yes!
Do you smell something, Sherman?
I was not, Mr Peabody.
I know. Is the methane from
sanitation.
Since exploding
at 150 degrees...
... will use it,
to jump from here!
Hold on!
Yield  hearsay:
Calamity Jane
Nice landing,
not think, Sherman?
Well, what did you learn today, Sherman?
This French revolution
was madness!
That?
All these
executions and beheadings...
... and nobody dares to say that
was not right.
And think:
Marie Antoinette
could have avoided the revolution
If just issued a decree...
... to share bread to the poor.
But then, would not have dessert.
Why, Mr. Peabody?
Because Sherman,
can not be got and cake and decree.
Not understand.
Where to go tomorrow, Mr. Peabody?
In Ancient Rome? In the Wild West?
In 1492?
No, Sherman. Tomorrow will not go into
none of these places.
Why?
Why
tomorrow's adventure will be all yours.
What do you mean, Mr. Peabody?
Do not you remember?
It's your first day at school!
- Can I drive?
- Of course not!
New York-Today
And remember, Sherman:
Macro shortly before distracted.
I know, Mr. Peabody.
And do not forget the translational status:
2 +3 = 3 +2
I know, Mr. Peabody.
And if you have to go toilet...
... Proudly raised your hand,
and say, "I must go."
Okay, Mr Peabody.
And remember, the No. 2 pencil
do most things...
... but sometimes,
needed and the No. 1.
I put a small box in
Sacco your...
... you can use
whenever needed.
I think I'll be okay.
- Well, goodbye, Mr. Peabody.
- Wait.
'll See you after school.
- Sherman!
- I gotta go...
... must enroll in clubs.
Nobody supports more than me...
... participation in fraternities.
But before you go...
... I want you to have this.
Thank you.
What is it?
A dog whistle.
Not working, Mr. Peabody.
Works fine, Sherman.
Is simply a frequency
listening only dogs.
Good.
Let this be a reminder for you
...
... that whatever challenges you face
... however far it may seem to be at
...
Goodbye , Mr. Peabody!
... I am near you.
George Washington.
Who can tell me, what is
?
I! I can, I can!
O. .. Sherman.
The first president of the United States of America.
Good job.
And when President Washington was small
...
... what cut tree?
I, I! Me!
- Penny.
- A cherry tree.
Occult!
What tree is this?
There's a tree, a word:
Apokryfo.
Means that this story is not true
.
Seriously?
Yes. George Washington
not ever cut cherry...
... and never said that
can not be lying.
People skarfistikan
these stories...
... to learn
children a lesson about the lie.
But it is not true.
But he crossed the Delaware River,
Christmas 1776.
My father went there this summer
.
And he crossed the.
I fell into.
It seems that someone here knows
history.
So, Penny?
Glad to meet you,
children.
One day you come home to me, if you want
.
I could fetch
my new 'model'.
Is a hydrogen atom.
've Only got one, right?
Yes, you have to share.
Good.
Look, guys.
What you got there, Sherman?
Herrings or crumbs?
Basically, I have small carrots, apple juice
...
... and sandwiches with tuna.
super healthy and full of vitamins.
So eat human food, right?
Yes, why not eat?
Because you're a dog.
No, I'm not.
- Of course you are.
Your father is a dog, so
and you're dog.
I think I'm confused.
Is relative adoption.
- Shut up, Carl.
- Well.
'll Show you. Bring.
Go, doggy,
to get your food.
Fuck . Go take it!
What humiliation!
Sherman, go get your food.
Make like a good doggie.
- What is it?
- Is mine. Give it back!
What is it? Whistle?
The stupid thing.
Not even work.
's Whistle for dogs.
Works at a frequency that only dogs hear.
- Rear, Carl.
- Well.
This whistle belongs to me.
Give me back!
- Jump, doggy, jump!
- I'm not a dog.
Come on, Sherman. Admit it, you're a dog
.
- Sit down!
- Let go of me!
Not until you beg like a dog.
Come on, Sherman. Entreat.
Thank you for coming so soon
...
... to discuss the problem with
Sherman.
No problem, Chief Purdue
expecting this.
Really?
Yes, with respect to the Sherman,
I am prepared.
Here is a resume, showing
preparation in arithmetic...
... and that does not 'jump' class.
Mr Peabody...
Exercises
algebra and reading list...
and a link to the Site that I made...
... to be able to learn Chinese.
It is the language of the future.
Mr. Peabody!
I'm not saying that we should learn and French,
Warden Purdue just tell...
Mr. Peabody!
What? There is enough?
Swahili?
Sherman became involved in a fight today.
My God...
Photographs were taken,
for safety reasons.
Bitten.
I must say, it does not look good for you
, Mr. Peabody.
After all... you dog.
Can I ask, what are you?
I Miss Gkranion from
Service Security and Protection of Children.
The law requires that you call them,
happens when a...
... episode.
Sherman has never done before
something similar.
I'm sure I'd have a reason.
- The girl was a bit annoying...
- Stop, Purdue!
It is normal road  kids tease other children
.
Normal road but not to bite.
Obviously due to how it was raised.
In my opinion,
A dog can never be
suitable parent for a child.
I must emphasize, Miss Gkranion,
I won the right to adoption
Sherman in court.
And the court
can you get it back!
I'm coming home tomorrow evening, I
autopsy.
If you discover that you are unfit to parent...
... I will see you lose custody
Sherman.
Permanently.
I hope I am clear.
Totally.
Sorry for the bit,
Mr. Peabody.
I will not do it again.
Violence of this kind is totally unacceptable
.
And rather despicable,
based on how you feel about Mr. Gandhi.
What the hell caused it?
Called me a dog.
Well.
Thanks for telling me.
Try to sleep.
I love you, Mr. Peabody.
And I have deep feelings for you,
Sherman.
Peabody  Sir, you're a scientist
you've won the Nobel Prize.
Among the significant country.
'Captain' industry.
Why do you want to adopt a child?
Because, Mr. President, when I found
Sherman...
... reminded me of how I started
in life.
And now I want to give him
the only thing I like everything.
A house!
And you're sure you're capable
encounter all challenges
upbringing of a boy?
With all due respect...
... how hard can it be?
Very well, then.
If a boy can adopt a dog...
... I see no reason not to adopt a dog
a boy.
- Da-da.
- No, Sherman. No, da-da.
Call me Mr Peabody.
on more formal occasions, just
Peabody.
Exactly.
Lord Pimpampa.
What cook, Mr. Peabody?
Nothing special.
Salatoula lobster and passion fruit...
... And basil sauce, quail with truffle
sauce berries, and...
... ice cream cake.
Celebrate something special today?
You could tell.
- It's my birthday.
- No, it is not.
- Neither yours.
- Right.
Is Father's Day?
No, it is Father's Day.
- Does the President comes?
- No.
Then who is?
Let's just say, that if
the night a success...
... we can forget the episode
biting.
The Peterson!
Welcome!
- So is literally dog.
- PAUL!
Not okay.
If you would prefer
the "educated dog."
Funny!
No joke, Paul?
Not laugh easily.
We were very pleased
who were able to come so quickly.
So, not Sherman?
No rejoiced, Sherman?
Yes, you will definitely know what's up.
Greeted Penny, Sherman.
Hi, Penny.
Hey, Sherman!
Not going to show in Penny
your collection of minerals?
I am sure we will find exciting new
your geodes rocks.
Come.
Glad too
for accepting my invitation.
Now kids will be able
to settle their differences...
... before coming Miss Gkranion.
Shout the wrong guy, pal!
If it was Patty,
I would have already sued.
Gotta say, Peabody...
regarding my daughter,
nothing is more important...
Hello?
Yes, I will take part in polls.
All right?
Why do not you tell me she was coming?
Why I did not want to worry.
Well. Because I did not want to hear the sound of
your belly.
- Thanks for your honest.
- Please.
I do not know what
believed that we would be together.
Hates me!
Share with her your interests.
Tell her jokes.
Mr Peabody, I hate myself.
Sherman  every great relationship starts
-conflict...
... and evolves into something richer.
Good luck (in French).
Do to succeed.
Do not tell her about the Time Machine.
Do not even think.
Peabody, it was amazing!
Paul, it was amazing?
I like the more rock ' n ' roll.
Meant the flamingos.
Bagpipe?
Didgeridoo.
(Australian wind instrument)
Sitar .
Steel Drums
(drums from Trinidad).
Trombone.
Xylophone.
Drum.
Organ.
Oboe.
Piccolo
(small cello).
Touba.
Dobro
(type of guitar).
Whistle.
You know what?
This is a waste of time.
To get Penny,
and go house-Wheel ..!
Are you okay, Paul?
I'm... well!
This is done whenever in intensity.
Paul, if I could...
Stay away from me, Peabody!
Move back!
I need stretching.
You can trust me, Paul.
I am a graduate chiropractor.
Peabody!
I feel great!
I feel really great!
Peabody, doing wonders!
Look at me. Jig!
You know, Penny...
... Sigmund Freud said,
that if you do not like a person...
... Because it reminds you of something
by yourself you do not like.
And what do you know about Sigmund Freud?
More than you think.
Surely . As I knew that George Washington
not cut that cherry tree.
- What stupidity!
- But it's true!
- How do you know?
- I know!
- You read a book?
- No.
- Did you see a movie?
Do in said brain-father?
No!
Then how do you know, Sherman?
How-to Un-carriers?
Told me.
- Who told you?
- George Gouasigkton.
George Washington.
Yes.
Liar.
Do not tell her about the Time Machine.
The saying "Time Machine".
And what parts you go with her?
No where in, Penny.
In what season.
Well, smartass.
1965, 1776, 1620, 1492,
1215, 4...
Can
go back an hour ago?
Why?
Why go home,
will make the sick...
... and will not come
this stupid dinner.
Mr. Peabody says,
that you should not ever use the
Time Machine...
... to go at a time
existed too.
Why?
There would be two of you then.
Yes . I suppose that the world
still not ready for that.
Now that we have seen,
better to go back.
Kidding?
Where to go first?
Mr. Peabody says
not allowed to travel until you grow up.
You're everything says Mr. Peabody?
Yes...
You know what makes this Sherman?
An obedient son.
No. A dog.
Good move!
Bring it, Patty.
Raised his hands, Paul!
Here.
Yes!
Look at this.
This is a homemade cocktail
I like to call:
"O Einstein on the beach".
- The health of children.
- Cheers to them!
- Mr Peabody!
- Sherman?
I
I talk to you a minute?
Course.
Sorry.
I made with their parents.
I think we
To record this night
folder "unqualified success".
- Do not listings yet.
- What do you mean?
Where is Penny?
In Ancient Egypt...
Use the Time Machine?
What's up, dude?
We finish the drinks.
Coming soon, Paul.
How
... how could you do that?
Called me a liar,
Because I said that George Washington
not cut the cherry.
And so it went on to see
George Washington?
Yes.
- Hello, Peabody.
- Hello.
- Where is Penny?
- Plays hide and seek.
- Makes bad.
- Makes Bad...
- And playing hide and seek.
Well, which one Both do?
What's going on here?
Yeah, what's going on here?
- What did Penny?
- Penny?
Penny! Penny!
- God.
- Where is our daughter?
It's hard to tell you, Paul...
can be found here...
... or here, or here, or here, or here
...
This will keep.
I learned this trick from a Finnish,
in Ubud Bali.
Let !
Ancient Egypt!
Country Pharaoh.
Lighthouse progress for humanity.
But also tough and barbarian culture.
I just hope they do not suffer much
Penny.
What are you doing here?
We came to get you home.
How called in Egyptian
the word 'telltale'?
But this is irrelevant.
Put ​​your clothes.
I get home.
What you did your pharaoh?
Now bring my dresses!
You see, Mr. Peabody?
Impossible!
Indeed.
But look what happens...
... when an object does not move,
meets resistance force.
Penny, come here, right now.
Penny, come on.
I am no longer the Penny.
Now I'm the princess Chatsepat,
precious flower of the Nile!
Precious, perhaps, but if you believe that
will leave here...
... You are definitely in denial of reality
.
Not understand.
Now, come with us.
Leave!
What's up, my sweet, little Flower
Desert?
barbarians
those who annoy you?
Basically, yes.
Bow barbarians!
As you wish, Your Majesty.
Who is he, Mr. Peabody?
He, Sherman, is Ammon,
dynasty of the New Kingdom...
... King Tutankhamun.
- Otherwise known as King TOT.
- My boy.
King TCT is the boy?
You want to put them scratch,
to dip in honey...
... and put them in a pit
ants?
Would you do this to me?
Anything, Desert Flower.
As a wedding gift.
- What? You marry this guy?
- Why not?
First, his name rhymes with
'loss'.
I do not care.
I'll do a big, rich
Egyptian wedding.
Warning:
O king TOT dies young.
Are you sure that you thought right?
Believe me, I thought well.
'll Inherit everything.
The royal decree was passed.
Marriage should be done tomorrow.
Dawn.
- Who is he?
- It's Me.
That's you?
I am I, the Grand Vizier.
Yes, that is his name.
Vizier  Dude, you say
in Princess of here...
... what exactly does it mean to be married
the young pharaoh?
Happy.
Means that we are knit together the
eternity.
With
sacred ceremonies of the gut...
... and mummification.
As described in the sacred papyrus.
A minute.
Can someone explain to me this?
This means that, Penny,
Is that when I die,
will kill you.
And then I will uproot institutions,
will shove in your mouth...
... mummification and the rest of the body.
I get it now.
Thank you.
'll Go with them.
There's no turning back!
At the Palace!
Begin preparations wedding!
Mr. Peabody! Sherman!
Do something!
Do not worry, Penny,
'll save!
Wait !
Can not we...
... leave here.
- Mr Peabody?
- Yes, Sherman?
Can I Hold Your Hand?
And of course you can.
God. Your hand is cold,
Mr. Peabody.
- Sherman?
- Yes?
This is not my hand.
This was disarming.
Now, to find the way to exit
...
Look around you, Sherman.
These tombs have been painted hieroglyphics...
... To help the souls of the Pharaoh...
... in their journey toward reincarnation.
And it can help us.
This shows God Anubi,
to drive a boat god Ra
underworld.
Seems that boats
god Ra is the key to escaping.
We need to find them in time
to stop the wedding.
If you ask me, you should just let
to marry this guy.
Deserve each other.
What you said Sherman?
Daddy, do me a favor.
Bald, wearing a skirt and makeup
?
If you did not know, Sherman,
I would say that you're jealous.
Envy?
What?
The TCT affection for Penny,
course.
I think I like the Penny?
Do me a favor.
I do not want to hold the hand...
... or going to the park...
... or to see
brushing her hair...
. .. or whatever...
Quickly, Sherman.
Caution, Sherman.
Is mouse-trap.
- What's so funny?
- You mouse.
One wrong step and we pressed.
The boat...
... the god Ra...
... going straight...
... today.
Take-error-boat...
... people-will pay.
Okay, Sherman,
Now it's your turn.
Make the puzzle just like me.
Think it well.
One step at a time.
... I mean, 'will pay'.
God.
The boats of the god Ra.
One leads to the exit...
... while the other will send us
in darkness and in certain death.
What?
Sherman, get on the boat.
Just put together these boxes,
will move very quickly.
- Which boat, Mr. Peabody?
- What?
What is the boat that does not lead to certain death
?
That!
Succeed, Sherman!
Sherman?
Mr. Peabody!
What are you doing over there?
I thought you said it here.
Sherman?
Sherman!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
O god, the son of Helios, Ra,
commands us to begin...
... the sacred ceremony!
Bring the knife
for the oath of blood!
Where the blade meets flesh,
in sacred right hand...
... pay tribute
son of Helios, Ra.
Wait!
The Anubis, the god of Death!
The marriage must not continue!
Why, Anubis, why?
Wounds! Flames!
If sealed this deal wedding...
... I will pour upon the country,
countless wounds.
Again with wounds?
What I
and moved to Egypt?
Oy vay, Anubis, o son of the sun god, Ra,
decided...
... that this girl will become
wife of the boy-king.
This is very funny.
The other day I was talking to the god-son of the Sun...
... and told me he changed his mind.
Seriously?
Sudden change policy we call down here to Hades.
But it's too late.
We have already paid the catering.
Too bad you will lose the deposit.
And another smoke, Sherman.
This trick works.
Take the girl at the gates of the city...
... And leave it there,
from where you get the gods.
Only in thus,
can be prevented
wounds that country.
The Anubis spoke.
Go this girl
at the gates!
Anubis, you look like you're not good.
Felt a little sick,
but I'm much better now.
Thank you.
Penny, Sherman quickly.
- Come on, Penny!
- Sherman!
The bride TOSKAS!
Stop, you fool!
Penny Sherman, climb up!
Getting away!
We did it!
At what time will go now,
Mr. Peabody?
House. We have to go to the party...
... Before parents Penny
understand that missing.
No need to mention
all this...
... Episode marriage with King
TOT, is not it?
Of course not.
Moreover, it is my opinion...
... that marry too young
in Ancient Egypt.
Or... maybe I'm old fashioned.
Warning:
Insufficient energy reserves.
Charge now.
What is it, Mr. Peabody?
All this back and forth around
from the World...
... exhausted their energy reserves.
You must make a stop
except program.
As luck wishes...
... Our energy reaches barely
to the Renaissance.
Florence, Italy-1508
I can not pick,
nor the left hemisphere...
... from right now!
How many times do I have to say,
Mona Lisa...
Mona Lisa?
No, no, no!
I can not draw...
... if you do not smile!
Leonardo, tell me one thing,
for which should smile!
The  glow of the sun, spaghetti...
... all the things that make the
so popular in Italy!
I have not seen anything from this,
Leonardo...
... why sit on this...
all day!
I do not think that word means
'chair' Italian.
Peabody, old chap!
What a wonderful vacation!
Trust me, this woman is not
'played'.
Well, glad to see you.
What do you want?
Hurry
desperately to go home...
... but Time Machine
needs energy...
... and thought...
... who else better there,
except by Leonardo Da Vinci...
... To help us?
Peabody will be happy in helping...
... but come at a very bad time.
I do not know what to do,
with this crazy woman.
See what I mean?
What is the problem?
What is the problem.
I can not finish the list, if not
smile.
Okay. You smile.
No!
This is a fake smile!
Everyone knows that.
Why not do a real smile?
Why do not you say something funny?
I paint paintings,
construct machines...
... but not telling jokes!
Maybe I can help.
You see, humor is immune
loss of science.
Using algorithms, we can conclude
...
... what is considered funny
worldwide.
So we make a 'recipe'...
... that is scientifically sure that
lark.
For example, the drape.
Entertain you?
The evidence was so clear...
Do not worry, Mr Peabody,
I have!
No, no, Sherman...
Perfect!
Keep that smile!
Hold it there!
Do not move!
Well, Leo, if correct
my calculations...
... This machine will produce
enough power to get home.
I have a
last piece to be put in place.
Sherman, you can bring the hammer
by Mr. Da Vinci?
Okay, Mr. Peabody.
- Mr Peabody?
- Very good, Sherman.
But Mr Peabody...!
Helped me a lot.
Sherman!
Yes, Mr. Peabody?
Hammer...
the main Da Vinci?
Okay, Mr. Peabody.
Here, Mr Da Vinci.
Need Help?
No, no, I'm fine.
Thanks.
Sherman!
Go.
Let's explore.
Supposedly we
time father-son, with Mr. Peabody.
Would not you rather have fun with me?
Well.
Sherman!
Where are you going?
Exploring.
- But we need your help.
- No, I do not need it.
I mean, will succeed,
somehow.
It's a boy, Peabody.
Aston entertain.
Let him go.
Thank you, Mr. Peabody.
Grows, Peabody.
Like a little bird,
leaving the nest.
It is not wonderful?
It's like a museum.
It's like toy store.
Look at this.
It is the largest airplane-model
®.
There is a model, Penny,
is original.
And
probably best to leave it alone.
Well.
But it would be nice if
could fly with it?
I do not think it would appeal to Mr Peabody
.
Mr. Peabody is not here yet.
Just tell me how it works.
Please!
To learn.
Okay.
Starting at this point...
... and then proceeds
in this corridor...
... until you shake the wind sails.
But how it goes?
How  takeoff?
Just you download this driver.
Him?
God.
This is crazy!
There is Sherman.
It's fun!
'll Die!
Stop being so funky.
Nothing is more beautiful...
... as an elegant equation,
translated into flawless mechanics.
Why are not children and
so simple?
Because children are not machines,
Peabody.
Trust me .
I tried to build one.
It was scary.
Here, Sherman.
Drove you now.
But I do not want to drive it.
And of course you want.
Will be fun!
Honestly, Penny, I do not want.
I leave.
- One... two...
- Do not let go!
- Not!
-... Three!
Penny, fly high!
No, Sherman,
you tried to save it.
But I can not.
'm Serious, Penny.
Do not know how to fly!
You can do it.
I know you can.
Come on, Sherman.
Take the wheel.
See? You did, Sherman
You're right.
I did!
Mamas once!
The Da Vinci did it again the miracle.
Yes, but look at the child who made it.
Very scary.
Dad. Dad.
I finished up here, Leonardo.
And I'm done down here.
Not beautiful?
Each piece in place...
... To do exactly what you need.
Look, Peabody!
The fly my bike!
Fly my camera!
Sherman? Sherman!
Sherman, what are you doing up there?
I'm flying!
But Sherman does not know how to fly.
- I do not know?
- No.
Turn. Turn, Sherman.
Lean!
Sherman! Sherman!
Are you okay?
It was fantastic!
I can not believe it!
Fly my camera worked!
Sherman, you're the first
flying man!
You should be very proud,
Peabody!
Very very proud.
The word 'proud'
not enough to describe it.
Leonardo , you can start
mechanism?
Dad, Dad!
Mona!
I'm sorry I destroyed the plane, Mr. Peabody.
Should be sorry.
You could have been killed.
What you say now?
Sherman led plane.
It was fantastic!
Sherman destroyed a priceless historical relic
.
Any rate.
Should rejoice.
It turns out that
Sherman is not completely lost after all.
Yes, Mr. Peabody.
Turns out that I'm not completely lost after all.
Miss Peterson...
... Stop drift my son
become hooligans.
Not my fault they are hooligans.
Yes. Not his fault that I'm
hooligans.
Certainly not my fault, too.
I spent the last 7 years...
... teaching the Sherman
have good judgment.
If you are so awesome father,
why trying Miss Gkranion
get you the Sherman?
Is this true?
You'll get someone away from you?
No, Sherman.
I will never let that happen.
You only have to trust me.
Panagia mou, a Black Hole!
What happens?
If I can not pull us out of here
...
... will break the
event horizon of the black hole.
No
have enough strength to resist the attractive force.
Even if you burn everything...
Why do not you tell me?
What can I say?
Why do not you tell me that Miss Gkranion
was trying to get away from you?
Not
job to worry about these things.
Just do not think I can cope
...
This will be discussed later.
Now sit down.
I do not want to discuss it later!
Sherman, sat.
You can not talk to me
thereby.
I'm not a dog.
What?
I said I'm not dog!
You're right, Sherman,
're not.
're Just a very naughty boy.
10, 9, 8, 7, 6...
... 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Sherman? Penny?
Sherman, are you okay?
Sherman?
Gone.
Where are we?
No.
We are on the brink
one of the most brutal conflicts in history.
Trojan War-1184 BC
How we are heroes of Greece?
Feel good?
Feel strong?
Okay, let's warm,
if we are to succeed
something out there.
Remember what happened to Achilles,
and note well.
You look fine, Diomedes.
Menelaus, dude!
Dude.
Ready to enter the battle,
Sermanous?
And of course, sir Agamemnon!
Very sweet.
Messenger, what news you bring?
Someone left this for us.
Gift, nice!
Seems  same as our own horse.
To bring it in?
Why not?
Not expecting this.
My Lady!
What is that smell?
This is the smell of victory!
Hello, men of Athens,
Sparta and Thebes.
I am the Peabody.
I came to Sherman.
Do you know this guy?
I thought I knew,
but I'm not sure anymore.
Then  must be a spy.
Kill him!
No, no!
Is... my father.
Your father?
Are adopted.
Thank you
took care of my son, Agamemnon...
... But it's time to go home
.
Sorry, Mr Peabody,
I entered the Greek army.
The Sermanous is one of us now.
- It's brother.
- I am a brother.
Is my son!
- Gave oath!
- I gave an oath.
Is seven years!
Seven and a half!
All sons must show
deserve what their fathers.
Today,
Sermanous will show what it is worth on the battlefield.
But it  child.
Your father can not believe
you're ready to become a man,
Sermanous...
... but we believe.
Yes, Mr. Peabody.
Now
I will show you what I can bear.
FYI...
... all heroes have problems
with their father.
My father is a Minotaur.
Half man-half bull.
All  review.
Ajax from here,
is the strongest man in the world...
... but his father never accepted...
... that his real dream was to sing
.
I wanted to go to 'dance'.
And let's not begin to tell
for Oedipus.
Only say,
do not want to do
vacation home.
Is difficult.
Sherman,
worried that you have not thought well.
Here is a war.
Realize what's going to happen?
I'll tell you what's going to happen
.
Will destroy their homes...
... will demolish their temples...
... And paint red
the city streets!
With Trojan blood!
Yes!
Blood, blood, blood!
Attack 3!
1...
Sherman,
explicitly forbid you to fight in the Trojan War.
Not fair!
All my friends will fight.
2...
- Sherman is dangerous!
- I wear a helmet.
-3!
- There you go!
'll Go.
Storming!
Eat my ash,
dogs of Troy!
Eat  ash my dog
Troy!
Despite hair.
That's why I'm asking you to obey me,
Sherman.
Because I'm your father.
And
is my job to protect you.
Are you sure  But
that will not get me Miss Gkranion?
Not while I exist.
Mr Peabody, help!
Penny!
Smell my victory!
Smell it!
This is my horse!
Mr Peabody  fast!
I'll take it.
Did it, Sherman!
Help Mr. Peabody.
Now, let's get
in Time Machine...
... go back
to wake her parents Penny...
... Finish that party
to eat my ice cream cake...
... to cut the air in Miss Gkranion...
... and make sure that nothing
ever happened.
Sounds good.
I am inside.
Sherman !
Penny!
Sherman, no!
Mr Peabody...
Mr Peabody?
Mr. Peabody!
Dad!
Mr Peabody, what would you do?
What should I do?
There is nothing you can do, Sherman.
I just want to go home...
Home?
This is it!
I have an idea.
Come!
Where to go?
Coming home.
There
only one person who can help us...
... and this is the main Peabody.
What are you talking about?
This is not possible.
We have Time Machine,
Penny.
Can I configure
to reach home...
... that is still
Mr. Peabody.
But I thought I should
to travel in time existed.
We have no choice.
FALSE
Try to go at a time
that exist.
This could change
texture of spacetime.
FALSE
Hold on!
This is a homemade cocktail
I like to call:
"O Einstein on the beach".
- The health of children.
- Cheers to them!
Mr. Peabody!
Sherman? Penny?
Can you say then?
Course.
Sorry.
I made with their parents.
I think we
To record this night
folder "unqualified success".
- Do not listings yet.
- What do you mean?
Why are you dressed like ancient...
... Greeks?
Use a camera!
I did.
I know it's awful.
But why?
Disagreed with Penny
to George Washington.
And I made him show me
the Time Machine.
And lost in Ancient Egypt.
And betrothed King TCT.
So I came back and got
like you.
So we stayed out of fuel.
In Florence.
And we fell into a black hole.
And then you died
Ancient Troy.
Died?
I find it hard to believe that.
True!
But now you're here,
and everything will be fine!
I told you never to
prancing around in time when there were...
... because there will be two yourself.
Yes, but my other self
is in Ancient Egypt.
Who are you?
It's you, but from another era.
But I thought you said, not
never go back to that era existed.
Exactly!
I know, I know.
But what could I do?
Mr. Peabody died
Ancient Troy.
Die?
I find it hard to believe that.
Thank you!
What would you do?
In principle, can not stay here
both Sherman.
Why? We can take bunk!
And I was thinking the same!
Strange! Gemini!
And I was thinking it!
Viewing?
We can not have two Sherman
the same period.
Puts excessive pressure on the continuity of spacetime.
What to do?
What to do...
The Peterson
can not learn anything from all of them.
- Hello, Peabody!
- Hello!
How's it going?
Penny too hungry.
The
smells coming from the kitchen is wonderful!
Especially  that the ice cream cake!
Yeah... So, what's going on here?
Yes, what are these cloaks?
Party with togas!
Party with togas?
Yes, it's a party with togas!
And the food?
Starving.
Why not go to the dining room...
... try those quail
we advertise?
- Not!
- Why not?
Because... it's so fun here.
Miss  Gkranion !
What a pleasant surprise!
We were having so nice,
I forgot that you would come.
Why not come to the party?
I did not come here to party!
I came to research.
Nice! Why not start your search
from there?
Or here... or here... or here...
stop fro
shake your hands!
Sherman?
Wait!
This is not...
-... Sherman!
Two  Sherman?
What is going on here, Peabody?
Do not shake it!
Sherman, should get you out of here
...
... before you touch yourself.
Mr Peabody, not dead!
- Of course not died!
- Thanks!
How I came back eventually?
After some failed experiments...
... Got a combination of bone, stone and
fat yak (bovine type)...
... And I built a rudimentary
Time Machine.
You know what they say...
... if you do not succeed at first,
try, and try again.
Now is not the time for
puns!
Even if they are good.
Penny, Sherman quickly.
I will not go anywhere.
I saw enough to get
child...
... and two children,
of this house.
No, do not!
Miss Gkranion  please!
All my fault.
I started it.
I'm so sorry, Sherman.
No need to apologize, Penny.
Should not be allowed to adopt a dog
child anyway.
- Now, let's go!
- Madam Gkranion, beware!
What happens?
Mr. Peabody!
Sherman?
Where did the other two?
The secular  impersonators joined us,
to 'correct'
continuity in time and space.
Okay, makes sense.
I do not know what just happened,
but I know it was wrong!
This boy will come with me!
Mr. Peabody!
- No, Miss Gkranion!
- Leave me!
Come here!
With it hurts!
Bit me!
Yes, Hello, police?
I want to report an assault.
One bite!
Mr Peabody, what would you do?
Exactly.
Come as fast as you can.
Run!
Kidnaps the kid!
I can not believe that the
bit me, Mr. Peabody.
I know, Sherman was wrong.
False? It was awesome!
And now to return to normal
nowadays...
... will fix this mess.
There he is!
Keeps my daughter,
in this gigantic space apple!
Numb my face.
What?
Time Travel failed.
My God...
What is it, Mr. Peabody?
The secular  our impersonators opened hole
then spacetime.
This is why we went there in the past.
Hi, Peabody!
It seems that the past
comes to us.
I'll get you!
No exception!
Penny, my bride!
What?
My Lady!
Follow this boat.
Coming!
What kind of creature are you?
My name is Gkranion!
I'm in love!
I need to find a wormhole.
Einstein, the light is red.
I walk here.
Cake!
Here they are! Do not lose them!
I try to find another wormhole...
... But all lead back to the present.
Time Travel failed.
Journey time failed.
There is!
Follow them!
Penny, my queen,
I know you're there.
We come Sermanous!
Time Travel failed.
Mr Peabody, attention!
Sermanous, hold on.
'll Liberate from this egg.
Threw this weapon,
And removal
this futuristic vessel.
I do not take orders from anyone!
Freedom, Equality, Fraternity!
Me let me, bro.
Get out, Peabody,
walk on air.
Peabody  Sir, you are under arrest...
... kidnapping, dangerous driving...
... and much more serious offenses!
Not understand.
There slot then spacetime.
If you arrest me, I will be unable to fix
...
For too long
fooling the world...
... with your fancy walking
and your little red bow. ..
... and look what happened.
Get out of here!
Wait.
- Mr Peabody!
- Sherman!
What will happen to Mr Peabody?
You know what
happens to dogs that bite?
Let me go.
Do not know what you are doing.
Please,
before it's too late!
Wait!
Give him another chance!
Runs out of opportunities.
Now
must pay for his mistakes.
But
I'm the one who did all the mistakes.
I'm the one who walked
the Time Machine without permission.
The only mistake he ever did
Mr. Peabody...
... was me.
Sherman!
You're absolutely right, Sherman.
Father could be
this dog for a boy?
Maybe you're right, Miss Gkranion...
... but have not figured
a thing.
What?
I'm also  dog!
If being a dog means
be like Mr. Peabody...
... that you do not ever turning back...
... and is always there to
in pick up when you fall...
... And loves,
many times they screw up...
... if it means being a dog...
... then yes.
I am also dog!
I'm dog!
Me too!
A poodle!
I'm also a dog.
Inside myself the question 'dog'.
- I am too.
- I.
I'm also a dog.
I am Spartacus.
Okay, fine.
You are all dogs.
But
can not change the law.
I know someone who can.
George Washington!
We hold these truths to be self-evident
.
That all men,
and some dogs...
... Are made to be equal.
I ask here by Mr. Peabody
a presidential pardon.
Me too.
I've done worse.
Mr Peabody, look!
Hand!
What would you do?
It is the largest collection of
minds, that has ever existed.
Definitely would think otherwise
to go back to the past.
I can build a flying machine.
And we're going too fast!
But remember that as
approaching the speed of light...
... gravity will increase too.
And basically, for every action,
there is an equal and opposite reaction.
How about throwing a punch
in this hole?
I have an idea.
Listen everyone!
I have an idea!
Yes it is, Sherman?
Why not go in the future?
In the future?
I have never been there before.
So, probably not that bad.
Sherman, this is it!
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Not usually.
It's exactly what you said you all!
Only is exactly the opposite!
If we put the Time Machine
to go in the future...
... and go too quickly...
... You create your own gravitational field
...
... that is equal and opposite...
... the slot then spacetime!
I did not realize...
'll Fly up there,
and give a punch in the hole!
Yes!
Sherman, you're a genius!
Ma, Peabody,
how far in the future have to go?
Only a few seconds are enough.
Tzia  exfentonistoume after you back!
Are you sure this will work?
Do not worry, Penny.
Just remember, I'm...
... genius!
Sherman,
I need to reprogram the engine.
Okay, Mr Peabody.
This means that you should be
drive.
Yield hearsay:
Calamity Jane
To make the leap into the future...
... the Time Machine should
to go too fast.
Faster than as has ever been
until now.
're Ready, Sherman?
Ready.
Come on, Sherman,
you can do it.
Now, Mr. Peabody?
Sherman, we need more speed.
Now?
Little more.
Not yet, Sherman.
Not yet.
Now!
You hello!
- Ariventertsi!
- Dad, Dad.
To the Goodbye!
Aoufvinterzen!
'll See me again, Peabody!
'll Definitely make a mistake,
and when you do...
... I'll be there!
This is mine!
Come on, Sherman. Come on!
Yes!
If you want to watch TV before
get home...
... to press the input 3 times...
... and then use the
remote control as usual.
Indeed, Sherman.
And if worry if you make friends in the meeting
Parents...
... is a good idea to bring snacks
for everyone.
The cookies are always sought after.
Indeed, Sherman.
And do not forget, Mr Peabody...
... today I have my first race.
Sherman, wait.
Yes, Mr. Peabody?
Hello, Mr. Peabody.
Hey, Sherman.
Wait for me!
There is no doubt:
Every dog ​​should have a boy.
Pronounce you husbands!
You may kiss the Gkranion.
Come here, soldier!
Honeymoon