Hae-chan!
Are you okay?
Where am I...the hospital?
You were in a car accident...
The doctor says you're fine.
You can be released right now.
Isn't today the day for the press
release of "Iris?"
What?
That's good...we need to go to court
later anyway, we can go together.
Hey, Hae-chan!
I was on my way to court...I was
trying to avoid a truck
that was coming towards me...
[ Final Episode ]
She did get her memory back...
But it seems she's lost her
most recent memories.
It'll come back slowly.
What? I had amnesia?
No way!
How old was I?
18...
18?
I really wish I were 18.
You really were...
So, how was I?
Well..you were cuter and livelier...
You really liked me.
Stop talking nonsense.
How do you think I feel?
I've been cooking, cleaning and
getthing hit by you...
And now you don't remember that?
Hey! Kang Sang-young!
Huh? You're not calling me
Kang-bong anymore?
Yeah, right!
Regardless, I haven't changed my mind
so let's do the paperwork for
the divorce.
Oh, really...
But, aren't you working?
Huh?
Since when did you have time to
drive me around...
don't you have shoot?
Hey, no matter how busy I am,
I must drive my princess around.
Are you sick?
Hey, Hae-chan!
Did Ji-young make you this?
It's so childish!
Hey, you made that.
You think I'm an idiot?
You think I'm going to
believe that?
As you like, as you like...
Believe it or not...
Where are we going?
This isn't the way to the courthouse.
Let's go home first!
Why would we go home?
I want to get this over with
and get out of here!
Hae-won's getting married soon!
Just wait until that's over.
Hae-won's getting married?
Why isn't she answering the phone...
How can in-law's get married?
Hae-chan...go inside and
get some rest...
You were in an accident.
Rest? what do you mean rest?
I'm going to pack my things
and leave.
Leave? Leave where?
You really don't remember?
Do you know what I've been doing
for you lately?
I'm going to lose my mind!
No, we can get the divorce later but
you're going to stay here until you
remember what has happened.
There's no way, it's too unfair!!
Oh, Yun-oh..okay,
I'll be right there...
Hey, I'll be right back,
so stay here, okay?
What is this...
How can she forget that part
of her memory?
You really are unlucky!
I used your wedding as an
excuse to keep her there for now
so go and talk to her.
And because I had to leave so quickly,
I didn't get her anything to eat..
Will you take are of it?
Okay.
Oh, how am I going to deal with
this...I caused quite a bit of trouble...
I'm just going to pretend I don't remember.
You don't remember a thing...
Are you really just going to
quit the film?
I told you I would.
Ji-young finally persuaded
Director Kim to let you do this
so stop being stubbon
and let's go.
I'm sorry,
I want to rest for a while.
How are you going to make a living?
Hae-chan's pregnant now too...
Are all of you going to starve to death?
That's why...when we lost
our first baby,
I felt like I had done
something wrong.
I didn't do anything right as a father...
So, for this one, I'm going to do
everything I can from now on.
You're really the perfect husband!
The perfect husband!
But do you have to quit
all your work?
I'm going to look into another play.
I feel like the stage is
where I belong.
You make trouble for yourself.
Does Hae-chan know?
I haven't told her yet.
Hey, that's fine for you...
What am I going to do?
Where am I going to find another
Kang Sang-young?
Before my sister lost her memory
the first time,
she told me to stop spending
so much time with you.
She's going to have a fit when she
finds out I'm going to marry you.
The truth is, she once set me up
with another girl.
What? really?
That sister...!!!
Oh, it's good...
But, you don't remember anything
that's recently happened?
Huh...no...
Then why aren't you mad about me
and Bong-gyu getting married?
You've already decided to
get married, what can I do?
I have to be happy for you.
Anyway, don't think about
leaving the house.
Because of Bong-gyu, it'll be a little
hard for you to stay at my house.
And even if you do go out,
there's nowhere for you to go.
So, you stay here until our
wedding, okay?
Okay, I will.
Oh, Sang-young, you're home?
Sit down, I made your favorite stew.
Did you finish packing?
No...why would she pack?
That's right...
Do you remember anything?
N..no..
This is art..
Hae-won, you're so lucky...
It's much better that what you
made for Bong-man's birthday...
When?
Oh, last year...
I was abroad on a shoot last year.
Then was it the year before...
Oh, why does my stomach feel so bad?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I feel fine...
What's wrong with the two of you?
It tastes great...
Hey, after we finish eating, let's go
watch a really interesting film...
Why is he turning that on...
Hey, that's great.
You look great in your uniform.
Hey, isn't that Noon?
This is good.
Hey, you don't remember that,
do you?
What...what is it?
You and Noon even did
things like that?
This is what your friend made you.
You even borrowed his gym shoes...
What do you mean gym shoes...
It was his gym clothes...
Oh, I'm tired...
Oh, she remembers everything...
It must be because she
feels so baffled.
Well, I don't blame her.
Anyway, it seems like our
wedding is going forward...
Of course...
Straight on...
Thanks for coming out.
So, did you think about it?
I'm sorry.
I know...
He says that Grandpa
loves him too much
and that he'd very hurt
if he left him.
I'm grateful to him for raising
you both so well...
You  must be busy getting ready
for the wedding...
Yes..
Will it be okay if I hugged my son
for the last time?
The realtor's office will be calling
this afternoon.
Someone's coming to see the house.
When we sell the house,
I'll give you the money as alimony
so you can study abroad.
But, Bong-man, the truth is...
I know, you don't want to live
with me, right?
You really disliked me a lot
before the accident.
And if you don't rememer
anything after that...
Well, that's too bad.
Yes, when can you deliver
what I ordered?
I should've just told him that
I remembered everything...
Is he really upset?
Oh, Hae-won..
Oh, you don't know this right?
Bong-gyu's mother...
What about her?
She went to grandpa's house and
asked if
she could take Bong-gyu with her
and she got kicked out.
She's leaving in a few days...
I'm sorry about what happened.
No, I expected too much...
Mother, I'm pregnant.
Dear...
Is this okay?
Yes, please speak informally to me.
When are you due?
January 1st.
Give me your hand.
Thank you.
Thank you for loving Bong-man...
Mother...
This is the ring you father-in-law
gave me.
I only dreamt of this moment...
Mother, in a few days, Bong-gyu will
be geting married...
Do you really have to leave?
I'd be an univinted guest.
Bong-man wouldn't want that...
No, that's not how he really feels.
I had no right to expect so much.
I wanted to live with Bong-gyu...
even if it's late...
But their grandfather raised them well...
Bong-gyu wants to stay with his
grandfather.
Mother..
No, I'm grateful.
They were raised better than I
could have raised them
and I'm grateful for that.
Go on and eat.
Hae-chan, no matter what
anyone says...
Let's stay together...
It's hard enough trying to
live together...
How much harder will it be if you
and I tried to live separately.
And now it's the three of us.
In the future, we'll be happier
than we are now.
Congratulations...
You knew?
Of course...
You thinkg there's anything
I don't know?
Then...
Of course...
So why did you pretend you didn't
remember anything?
You were driving me crazy...
It was such a shock for me too...
And I caused you so much trouble.
Oh, Hae-chan...
You do have some morals...
But I wish I could go back
one more time...
This time to the age of 10.
When I got into trouble, you came
and fixed it for me...
When I acted childish,
you just took it all...
When I left the house,you came looking for me...
Why did you do all that?
You're normally selfish and rude.
What?
Was I really?
Why did you do that...
It scared me...
It scares me too.
How can your memory return like that?
Are you sure you haven't been
putting on a show this whole time?
You never know...
What!
Oh, yeah...I met with your
mother earlier...
She gave me this.
Why would you accept it?
It's the ring your father gave her
when they got married...
But, there's something I really have
wanted to ask you...
You wrote in your diary that
you loved me
but why were you trying to
leave me?
I felt like I was getting in your way...
If I only hadn't lost my memory, you
wouldn't be having such a hard time...
And I thought perhaps you were
living with me
out of obligation and not love...
Oh, you dummy.
From now on, tell me when you're
happy, unhappy, disappointed, joyful...
Tell me how you're feeling.
And don't ever try to
leave like that, okay?
Okay?
This is classy and pretty.
They'll only be able to wear it
on their wedding day...
It's simple so it can be wore often...
Yeah, but it's got to be
at least like this
for a special day like
their wedding...
That's not true...
You don't even know...
Why are you two having such a fit?
We've got to be happy with it.
Bong-gyu, isn't this nice?
This is pretty, right?
Look...does it compare to this?
Oh, forget it, forget it!
We're going for our last battle...
Whether you fight over it or not,
just bring back something nice, okay?
Let's go Bong-gyu...
We'll be leaving first...
See you later!
You can't just leave...Hae-won!
Hey, Bong-gyu...Hae-won...
They left because of this ring
you pulled out.
That's the only way!
But it's a lie.
There are different types of lies.
This is well-intentioned lie.
Can you live without me?
Right!
So, we are telling this lie
to save a person's life!
You understand, right?
Let's go!
Oh, the color's so nice...
So, you want your grandfather
to wear this to the wedding...
Let's see...
It looks good on you...
Get that away from me!
Oh, you like it...
Don't make me repeat myself!
I won't permit this
so you two give it up!
Grandpa...I was going to do that...
But I'm pregnant...
What?!
Pregnant?
Congratulations!!
What...
Grandpa, we're here...
What are you guys doing here?
We have something to tell you.
Grandpa, a baby is...
I know I know!!
Is that something to be proud of?!!
Problems after problems...
I thought you would be the
happiest about it...
You kept pushing Hae-chan to get
pregnant, aren't you happy?
What...is Hae-chan really pregnant?
What?
A baby...so, that's...really?
Yes, I'm 5 weeks pregnant.
Oh, dear, it's you
double lucky day.
Oh, you should've just been like
this from the start...
So, Bong-gyu, where do you want
to go for your honeymoon?
That's right...I'll send you
somewhere nice, so just tell me!
We've already decided.
Where?
America.
What?
Are you planning to see your mother?
Grandpa..
Please, don't hate her.
Okay, I know..
If you insist on seeing her,
end your relationship with me!
Please...
Grandpa.
What?
After finding out I was pregnant,
all I can think about is
what is good or bad for the baby...
That's expected out of a mother.
Mother is leaving tomorrow.
What's that to me?
Grandpa, I don't know well but...
I thought about how it would feel if
I couldn't see my children
for over 20 years...
I wish you would permit her
to come to
Bong-gyu's wedding for
Bong-gyu's sake.
She would be so happy and
so grateful to you...
Why did you do that?
You know how he is.
The moment I saw her, I knew she
was my mother...
It was strange because I felt like I
had just met her yesterday...
Even though I don't have
any memory of seeing her...
I want to leave her some
good memories...
Your mother's leaving tomorrow...
Are you really not going to
see her off?
Why would I...
Don't be like that...
Let's just go and at least say
goodbye, huh?
Forget it, I'm not going.
Oh, you heart of stone!
Stubborn mule!
What?
Then at least take me.
I don't want to.
Oh, my stomach keeps hurting.
If it hurts, why would you go out
to the airport?
If she leaves now, who knows
when she'll come back.
Go on.
You're really are not going in?
No.
Are you waiting for Sang-young?
Oh, no...
You really didn't have to come out.
It's just trouble for you.
No, of course I would've taken you.
Thanks.
I'm going to go to the bathroom.
Okay.
Oh, you're here?
She went to the restroom...
Sang-young didn't come?
Yeah, he had something to do...
I know it's late but congratulations.
You look really happy!
Thanks!
Bong-man...
Thanks for coming out.
I'll be going.
Mom!
I wasn't mad about you coming.
It was just that you were late...
That's why I was mad.
Aren't you coming to Bong-gyu's wedding?
Dear Bong-gyu...
You're already in junior high school,
but I just can't believe it.
How handsome must you look in
your uniform...
The Bong-gyu and Bong-man that is
in my heart has grown so much...
Do the two of you look like
each other?
You couldn't wait for the elevator.
Why waste time waiting for it.
Come up!
It was just yesterday you were
so against it but I guess
you're really impatient to see
your new grand-daughter-in-law...
There's still a lot of time...
What's wrong with going early?
Anyway, the two of us are left now...
What do you mean two?
When Hae-chan has her baby,
they're going to move in!
What???
Hae-won...I can't recognize you.
How's my make-up?
It's got to look good.
You're beautiful.
Really?
You're going to live well, right?
Of course...
Do you know how hard it was
to get here?
But, I'm thirsty.
I guess you're nervouse...
Wait a little bit...
You're beautiful, Hae-won...
This is your last chance.
Even now, we can do what they
did in the movie "Graduation."
Just do your job as the MC!
Fine...
I'm sorry..
I just wanted to see their faces...
You came all the way here,
why leave!
Stay for the wedding.
And when they go to visit,
take good care of them...
Mother, I'm glad you're here...
Grandma...
Oh, you're here...
Please give us some sausages...
Sure,
but what brings both
of you out here?
Come on in...
Here...
Oh, it looks good...
Grandma...I'm having a baby.
What? really?
Oh, I'm so proud, so proud...
All this time you've been
having a fit about
whether you were going to live
together or not...
but it seems you two still did
everything you needed...
Oh, that's great.
This is just great.
Now that you're going to have a baby,
your loyalty to each other
will grow stronger and you'll learn
how precious you are to each other...
And you'll think one more time
before you fight...
Be good to Hae-chan.
Yes, Grandma!
Sang-young!
You finished your class?
Noon, it's been a long time.
Hae-chan, I have somewhere I need
to stop by, I'll wait for you at home.
Noon, will you take Hae-chan home?
See you later.
So, are you 29 now?
Well...at first I couldn't believe I was
18 and I was a little embarrassed...
But now, I miss it sometimes...
You had a hard time because of me.
No..I saw the documentary we
made together.
I didn't do anything.
No...after the accident, I caused
a lot people trouble...
But at least I made a friend!!
I had lost my dream and confidence...
But you're the person who
helped me find it again.
I was able to go to film school
with you, make a documentary,
and be the recipient
of passionate love...
I borrowed money from Sang-young
when we were in Ahnmyun-do...
It's okay..he's got a lot money...
But, I remember you two
talking badly about me...
I'm not that pretty and I don't have
that nice of a body?
He started it...
But, it's a little strange...
You're not like the old Hae-chan
that I knew, but an adult...
Hey, that makes me sad...
I don't know about anyone else but
you promised to always see me as 18!
Just the way Howl was able to
recognize sophie!
Let's go!
Hae-chan, who came to a
strange world,
has returned to her own world.
But like that night we saw the
movie together...
I'm going to always remember Hae-chan
as the happy magic that I met in
my adolescence.
Hey...this is our story..
I'm Bong-su and Hae-chan is
Hae-young?
Oh, she has no imagination...
Wait...this isn't our story...
What? I'm the patient waiting
for death.
Scene No. 57
At the park...Hae-young waits for Bong-su...
For five hours she hasn't heard
from him and he hasn't come...
What's going on?
Scene 121...hallway of hospital.
After not hearing from Bong-su
in three months,
she reaces to the hospital...
Bong-su!
You dummy!
Why didn't you contact me?
How can you go and die on me like this?
Our relationship has ended?
What?
l...l...Lo...Lo...Lo...
Bong-su...
Why can't you say that
you love me...
Is it harder than dying...
What?
Why would I die...?
Hey, what are you doing?
What?
Are you crying?
Who's crying...
That's my screenplay.
Hey...when did you write this?
Oh, while I was at Ahnmyun-do...
I wrote it while missing you.
You hated me so much
you wanted to kill me off?
You read it all?
What do you think?
Was it good?
It was okay...
But why couldnt the male lead
not say he loved her even
as he was dying?
Well...was it because I was thinking
of someone while writing it?
You know men like that...
They'll regret it after they die...
I Lo..... I lo.....
Hey, is that something that
has to be said...
Who said that?
Anyway, I don't like the ending..
It's too dramatic...
Yeah, I wasn't crazy about it either..
Move over.
Hey...let's go out and practice
Lamaze breathing...I learned it today.
Forget it.
I'll do it later.
I better finish this.
Stop doing it and let's go out
and practice.
What's more important,
the baby or work?
Why are you being such a nag?
Stop nagging and go out!
Hey!
How can you just turn it off!
I lost everything!
It's because you don't listen to me!
You want something bad to
happen to the baby again?
Hey, how can you say that?
No..it's just that..
It's because you're being
so stubborn...
Hae-chan..let's go out
for a minute.
Where?
It'll only be a minute.
What's wrong with him?
Why suddenly did you
want to come here?
Do you remember how you got
caught jumping the wall
and had to do squat walks?
You pulled that cord on purpose,
didn't you?
No, it wasn't on purpose.
But, I'm a little scared...
What do you mean, I'm here...
What's wrong with you...
That time when I went to
Ahnmyun-do looking for you...
The tree we had buried our
time capsule udner was gone...
This has to buried for it
to take effect...
If we do this, you'll be mine until
you become like dust, right?
Well...if this tree doesn't get cut...
then maybe...
Hae-chan, for you, I'm going to
reduce the number of times
I'll get mad...
And I'll quit smoking for you...
And for the first time, I told the
world that I, too, have a woman...
But is there still something left
that you want to hear from me?
No...what' so important
about words.
It's more important to confirm it
once in a while.
So, you made all that trouble to
confirm it, didn't you?
You never know.
That's a secret only the heavens
and earth will know.
Are you sure you didn't
completely dupe me?
How did you know?
What?
Come over here!
Hey...stop where you are!
Bong-man...
I think I was able ot
realize this only after
I went back to being 18 years old...
I could never leave you.
And I thought I had given up
my dreams because of you...
But the truth is,
it was only an excuse...
Hae-chan...
If you hadn't gone back to being 18,
I wouldn't have ever found our
precious memories
of the past 11 years.
And I wouldn't have known that
you are that one person
I could never exchange.
Although everyone was happy that
Hae-young had her memory back,
the truth is, it was Hae-young's
plot to test Bong-su's love.
Hello?
Yes?
I know what happened with the other
script was a little disgraceful...
But this screenplay is really great.
Director Jang Jin-ho really wants to start
shoot the film as soon as possible.
Thank you...but have the
actors been chosen?
I would really like Sang-young
to take the leading male role.
It's not because he's my husband..
The reason why we've decided to take
on this project is because we were
interested in the screenplay, it has
nothing to do with Kang Sang-young.
However, I wrote this screenplay
with Kang Sang-young as the model...
I understand what you mean...
Why don't we just think about it?
Auntie, couldn't you give him just
one more chance?
I read the screenplay
on my way here...
And I honestly believe he would be
the best person for the role...
First, you wash the beans well
and lightly cook...
Hey! how can you spill all this!
Oh, you're home?
I was trying to make some beans.
Bong-man, I got great news today.
What is it?
Are we having a girl?
Is our baby a princess?
No...they're going to make my
screenplay into a movie!!
Really?
That's great!
Congratulations!
But, do you know who the leading
male role will go to?
Who?
The top star Korea,
Kang Sang-young!
Hey...no..
I'm going to start a new play soon.
Hey, what are you talking about?
I told them it had to be you.
Why did you do that?
Did I tell you I wanted to do a film?
No, but it's our story and I
fashioned it after you!
Still, I don't want to.
Well, then, we have no choice.
I better quit too...
Baby...mommy's sorry...
With the money from the screenplay,
I was going to buy you
lots of pretty clothes and
lots of yummy food...
Hae-young...don't go...
I'm scared.
Bong-su...
Director!
yes, what is it?
Oh, Ji-young's expression
was a little off...
When she turns around to
look at him, she needs to do it
with more emotion in her eyes.
Didn't it look emotional?
It was great...
And, instead of kissing here...
Wouldn't a hug be more natural?
What are you talking about?
It says right here they should
kiss on the script...
Let's go with the script.
A script can be changed at anytime...
Oh, it's okay...
We'll go with the script...okay?
Let's make it real, Sang-young!
Okay, standby...cue!
Oh, my stomach.
Is the baby coming?
Oh, my stomach...
Hae-chan...
Oh, it hurts...oh my stomach...
Oh, my stomach...
Here, hold this...
Play with it...
I'll be right back...
Don't cry...dont' cry...baby..
Okay, okay...
Oh, it's hot...
Don't cry...oh, it's hot...
Jin-sol, please help your mom and dad, huh?
You can't take care of one baby?
Why are you making her cry?!
What is it?
You burned the diapers?
Can't you do one thing right?!!
I want to be a widow.
Translated By : KBFD
Transcripted By : upikepik
Timer/Editor/QC : CraZyaH
KBFD version uploader: onoturtle
\^.^/
Thanks for watching