Timing and subtitles brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
♫ Because love is the most fragile line of defense ♫
♫ In the end, hate became the last outcome ♫
♫ I defenselessly melted into love ♫
♫ I became the amber of tears, hanging on your necklace ♫
♫ Selfish love is too sweet that it becomes salty ♫
♫ Uneasy hate is thrown out of my dictionary ♫
♫ I am helplessly frozen into love ♫
♫ I became the crystal of ice, piercing your eyes ♫
♫ We are both lost on the edges of the world ♫
♫ A consensus is like positively and negatively charged electricity ♫
♫ If tightly connected, it can brighten the loneliness of night ♫
♫ The flames of a broken wire can momentarily be destroyed ♫
♫ We are both lost on the edges of the world ♫
♫ Chasing after each other is like the black and white keys of a piano ♫
♫ If closely dependent on each other, it can produce the theme of love ♫
♫ How can parted strings perform the sound of joy and sorrow? ♫
Medalist Lawyer Heir
- Episode 42 -
I told Zheng Hao, the parent-child identification test
is only to recognizing the mother and son relations, not for the lawsuit.
Not for the lawsuit?
Are you being innocent or are you pretending to be an idiot?
Xue Han Zhi has already handed this thing to the court. You're saying it's not for the lawsuit?
You have always told me,
that my child is gone, it was a stillborn. But he is here.
He is still alive. Zheng Hao is my son.
What? I can't acknowledge my own son?
Did I say you can't acknowledge your son? I said it before, I'll repeat it.
The problem is not the son, it's the agreement!
Fine, then as long as you promise you won't harm my son,
I can still follow your words for everything.
Then leave the country immediately. Go to England, France,
America, anywhere is fine. Choose somewhere.
Without a call from me, you're not allowed to come back.
Then what about the case of Zheng Hao suing me?
No way. I must still attend court.
I must confirm me and Zheng Hao's mother and son relationship in court.
Fine. You can attend court.
But you must listen to me.
Defendant Xia Yun, please take a seat on the Defendant's seat.
I have said, the Judge will tell her to sit on the Defendant's seat with me.
Your Honor.
May I ask the Defendant, the thirteenth piece of evidence from the Defendant,
have you seen the identification report affirming your mother and son relations with Zheng Hao?
I have seen it.
Then you are certain Zheng Hao is the biological son of you and Tang Ji Ye, right?
That's right.
Then, do you agree, according to the will written when Tang Ji Ye was alive,
that Zheng Hao should inherit all of Tang Ye Corporation's property and wealth?
This question is a bit complicated.
I need to think over it.
Complicated?
If Zheng Hao is your biological son, then obviously,
he should inherit all of Tang Ji Ye's inheritance.
Could it be that, you're doubtful of Tang Ji Ye's will?
Did our Attorney Zhong,
sitting next to you, makes you feel pressured?
Your Honor, I object the Plaintiff's Attorney asking suggestible questions.
In truth, I have no said a word.
Your Honor, it is true he did not say a word,
but any one of his gaze or hand gesture
could influence Miss Xia Yun.
What can be done about that?
Should I sit in the audience rows?
No need for that.
Your Honor, I advise to have Miss Xia Yun sit on the witness seat.
That way, her nervousness could at least be reduced.
I think that is possible.
Miss Xia Yun, did you go to get this parent-child identification report on the screen with Zheng Hao?
No. I gave my hair to Zheng Hao so that he could send it to be tested.
Then do you think this identification report is real?
Is Zheng Hao your biological son?
It's real, he is my son.
Do you agree to, according to your husband's will, let Zheng Hao inherit all of his property and wealth?
Your Honor, I'm sorry. Let us repeal this question for now.
Today, it was definitely not because Xia Yun was nervous.
She must have some kind of other reason.
Because of Zhong Ke Ming.
This has further proven my previous guesses.
Do you know why I stopped your question back then?
You're afraid that Xia Yun's reply might be disadvantageous to our party.
Not only just that, I suddenly realised we have a rift.
Also, we have disregarded a very important point.
What is it?
Look, since Xia Yun has already admitted that Zheng Hao is her son,
she didn't challenge the will either. According to common sense,
it could be said that this case...has already been won.
But, why is there no reconciliation and we must continue to fight?
Oh, I understand.
Xia Yun is actually not being self-contradictory.
Her position is clear. Although she has acknowledged Zheng Hao as her son,
she doesn't agree to let Zheng Hao inherit Tang Ye's property and wealth.
I have been too careless. I thought that once she acknowledged her son,
I thought she would definitely agree to let her son inherit the wealth and property.
This is what's difficult about being a lawyer, questioning needs to stop at a reasonable stage.
Asking too much may actually bring problems.
I'm glad you were able to stop me in time.
Otherwise, if her response was disadvantageous to us, I would have acted extra.
This Zhong Ke Ming is not easy to go against.
When the questioning resumes in the afternoon, he will definitely attack this point primarily.
The opposition will also become more difficult. I actually would like to see what ploys he will use
to prove that you can't inherit Tang Ye's wealth and property.
I think, they only have one ploy now.
Xia Yun, your response just now has made Attorney Xue really confused,
it has also made me very befuddled.
To let the court understand this case's truth better,
I would like to ask you a few questions again.
You only need to answer yes or no.
First question, you have been avoiding Zheng Hao recently,
it was because you didn't want to do the parent-child identification test with him. Yes or no?
Yes. But there is a reason for this.
You don't need to explain. You only need to reply yes.
At the end of last month, Zheng Hao found you. He asked you,
he told you that, he really hopes
to recognize this mother and son relationship again so you agreed with him
to do the parent-child identification test. But you proposed a condition,
it was that the parent-child identification report
can only be used to recognize the mother and son relationship,
it can't be used in the lawsuit. Is that right?
Yes.
After the parent-child identification report was released, Zheng Hao said to you again,
he hopes that you could attend court.
He said, because, to establish the mother and son relationship,
a confirmation letter must be received from the court. Is that right?
Yes.
Then can I generalize like this,
you were willing to do this parent-child identification test,
as well as willing to attend court as witness for Zheng Hao,
the only intention was to establish your mother and son relationship
and not to have Zheng Hao, according to the will,
to inherit Tang Ji Ye's wealth and property. Is that right?
Your Honor, my party opposes to this question.
Please state your reason.
Because we have already repealed this question previously.
Yes, Attorney Xue, you did repeal it.
But I am still interested to know.
I hope to hear Xia Yun's answer.
Yes. I have told Zheng Hao before.
Your Honor, my party still opposes to this question.
If Zheng Hao could be proven to be Xia Yun and Tang Ji Ye's child,
then no matter if Xia Yun is willing to or not,
it still would not affect Zheng Hao's rights to inherit the inheritance.
Attorney Xue is very correct. But don't forget, the word you said just now was "if"...
What does "if" mean?
That's right.
"If" means that, you don't have sufficient evidence to prove,
that Zheng Hao is Tang Ji Ye's son.
Does Attorney Zhong believe that,
with just a parent-child identification report, it can't entirely prove that
Zheng Hao is Tang Ji Ye's inheritor?
That was what I meant.
Why can't it prove that?
You can't just give a conclusion and not a reason, right?
I have three reasons. One, it is that
this privately commissioned parent-child identification report has no legal effect.
It can definitely not be used in court to prove any truths.
Your Honor, Attorney Zhong is currently challenging this evidence's form.
We can entrust the court to have Zheng Hao and Xia Yun
do a legally commissioned identification test again.
These are words to save yourself, I have already said it.
These are latter words. The court can't use
evidence from tomorrow to prove today's truth.
Attorney Zhong, please continue. What are you remaining reasons?
Then please don't let Attorney Xue interrupt me.
Because the following two questions I'm about to ask,
Xia Yun will use the following two reasons
to reveal to the court clearly.
Is this the only solution?
This is the only solution.
How should I live in the future?
Isn't this too cruel?
This is the only way for you to recognize your son
and not break our contract at the same time.
But this kind of thing...how do you want me to say something like this?
You don't need to say it. I'll ask you.
Your answer only needs to be "yes" or "no".
Xia Yun, you told Attorney Xue just now,
you said you didn't personally go to the DNA testing centre,
you only gave a few hairs to Zheng Hao to do the test.
Is that right?
Yes.
Then that means, this identification report
does not only have problems with its process...
Your Honor, my party objects.
We object Attorney Zhong casually vilifying my litigant.
I am only letting the court know about a possibility.
You can deny that these hairs
didn't get contaminated in the process.
I think nothing in this could be fake.
I can guarantee that Zheng Hao is my son.
Sure. Since that is what you've said,
I'll put this question aside. I will ask you the second question.
You told Attorney Xue just now, you said Zheng Hao is
yours and Tang Ji Ye's son.
But actually, you can't confirm that, right?
Don't laugh, everyone. Why has
parent-child identification test become so popular recently?
It is because that a lot of children's fathers
are worth being suspicious of.
Silence! Quiet, everyone!
Attorney Zhong, can you change how you ask your questions?
Sure.
Xia Yun, let me ask you,
apart from giving a few hairs to Zheng Hao for testing,
did you give Tang Ji Ye's hair
or something like teeth to him?
No.
My husband has already died over ten years.
He has been cremated long ago. He didn't leave anything behind.
Then that means, you can confirm that Zheng Hao is your son,
but you can't confirm that he is Tang Ji Ye's son. Is that right?
Your Honor.
Even if Zheng Hao doesn't have any parent and child relations with Tang Ji Ye,
but Xia Yun is Tang Ji Ye's wife.
Zheng Hao and Xia Yun have familial relations,
so, Zheng Hao can be presumed as Tang Ji Ye's son.
This child was born from the mother's body.
The mother and child's relations can be determined
but the father and son or father and daughter relationships
must depend on presumptions. There are two prerequisites for presumptions. One,
the father must have the ability to reproduce.
Two, the mother may only have had one sexual partner,
who is the child's father.
Xia Yun, let me continue asking you,
when you got married with Tang Ji Ye, he was already sick.
Even if he was still not a vegetative person,
but did he have any sexual abilities or has he lived as husband and wife with you?
If not, how did you become pregnant with Zheng Hao?
Tang Ji Ye could.
I got pregnant with the child before I got married.
You were pregnant with him before you got married.
That means, you were pregnant first before getting married.
Then let me ask you, before you got married, did have a boyfriend?
You did. His name is Gao Huai Yi.
Is that right?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
Please say it. You need to say it loudly.
Because the court needs to record this in the case.
That's right, I had a boyfriend.
You boyfriend, you really love him.
Also, you two already had
that kind of intimate relationship. Is that right?
Yes.
So, when Tang Ji Ye chased after you,
you struggled between two people. During those few months,
you circulated between these two men. You liked Gao Huai Yi,
because you were looking for love.
But,
Tang Ji Ye could give you wealthiness.
Between love and wealthiness, you chose wealth.
But you couldn't forget Gao Huai Yi. In the end,
you even nearly sacrificed for him. Is that right?
Why did you have to mention him?
Didn't we agree we won't bring this up again?
Fine.
I won't mention this. I won't mention it.
But listen carefully, seriously answer my last two questions.
Therefore, before you got married,
you had two sexual partners in reality.
During that time, you became pregnant.
Nobody could not, including even yourself,
determine whether Zheng Hao's father is Gao Huai Yi
or Tang Ji Ye. Is that right?!
Yes!
Your Honor, my party opposes.
I have no more questions.
What the opposition's Attorney just said was not the truth.
With what basis could you say it wasn't the truth?
Even if it was the truth, you still can't ignore
the possibility that Zheng Hao is Tang Ji Ye's child.
I didn't ignore it.
But you also can't ignore that his father could be Gao Huai Yi.
If Zheng Hao wants to inherit Tang Ji Ye's inheritance,
he must prove their parent and child relationship 100%.
But he can't possibly do that anymore.
You can do that forever!
This case... We obviously held a strong card.
How did a Gao Huai Yi suddenly appear?
This is really just falling short of success at the last stage.
Who knew Zhong Ke Ming had this up his sleeve?
There's no use in regretting. Hurry and think of a strategy.
We're losing this case so badly. It's even the lead story in the newspaper.
It's all because we listened to your wise council.
You said the maternity test wouldn't get overruled, but then
we were utterly defeated by Zhong Ke Ming.
How could I know you guys would be dragged by Zhong Ke Ming?
Going where he wants you to go.
Wow, you're so sharp. How come you didn't even come to the trial?
You think I don't want to come? I really want to come. But these few days
I've been studying for the TOEFL to go to an American law school.
I'm not the Monkey King. I can't go to many things at once.
Oh, right.
It seems that Lu Zhi Qiang is trying to find our court.
He wants to investigate a case file.
Is it the Yu Fen Li relocation case?
Yes.
Why does he want to research this case?
I don't know. But I heard the presiding judge say that Lu Zhi Qiang was
the main judge for the Yu Fen Li relocation case.
Lu Zhi Qiang?
The administrator in the hospital's archives?
That's him.
What's wrong?
Wasn't the hearing yesterday very fulfilling?
Mother and son acknowledged each other. The law also did.
The problem is completely solved.
Yeah.
Everything was very fulfilling. The agreement between us
was able to be completed without any hindrances.
You'll soon be able to get what you have dreamed of,
full control of Tang Ye Corporation.
But have you thought about me?
Right now, gossip is all over the internet and newspapers.
I've become a bad woman who doesn't abide by female virtues.
How am I supposed to leave the house?
If you can't leave the house, leave the country. Isn't that the lifestyle you like?
Go out of the country. No one will care
or gossip about your affairs.
Zhong Ke Ming, I don't think this is fair.
It's especially unfair to my son.
A lot of things in life are unfair.
What do you want?
I want...
I want you to tell me Gao Huai Yi's new address in Hong Kong.
It's been about a year. Ever since Xiao Ning started her case,
Gao Huai Yi suddenly disappeared. I couldn't find him at all.
I asked you. You even said you didn't know.
But how do you not know?
Did you force him to leave?
You still don't want to give up your evil ways.
Why do you want to find him?
I want Zheng Hao and him to do a paternity test.
You want to use Gao Huai Yi and Zheng Hao's false
paternity test report
to reversely prove that Zheng Hao is Tang Ji Ye's son.
You're delusional!
No, that... Don't worry. Zheng Hao and I won't fight with you.
Tell me the address. Please.
Zhou Tong, you just said that we've been dragged around by Zhong Ke Ming.
Then do you have any suggestions that could reverse the situation?
Yesterday in court, Zhong Ke Ming
gave an irreversible reality.
It's that Tang Ji Ye is dead. You can't find him to do a paternity test.
At the same time, Gao Huai Yi appeared.
He used Gao Huai Yi to crush your last defense.
But I think this situation
might be a blessing in disguise.
If Gao Huai Yi is still living,
you can find him to do a paternity test to verify
that you have no blood relation to him.
If it's like that, the process of elimination
leaves only one person who can be your real father.
That would be Tang Ji Ye.
So, quickly call Xia Yun. Find Gao Huai Yi.
Can I still believe you? Can I still believe Zheng Hao?
Right now I can't trust anyone!
You guys have all betrayed me!
Let me tell you,
you'll never see Gao Huai Yi again.
It's impossible for him to do a paternity test with Zheng Hao.
Why?
He's dead.
He died in Hong Kong.
What?
H-he... He's dead?
Yes.
How did he die? Why didn't you tell me?
Tell you? Am I obligated to tell you?
Should I tell you so you can offer your condolences?
He has a wife and kids. Do you want to be thrown out by them?
Timing and subtitles brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
You're so malicious!
You knew he died and you didn't tell me! Why?
I know your goal.
You're afraid that if I knew Gao Huai Yi was dead, I would have nothing to fear!
I wouldn't keep being manipulated by you! I wouldn't keep accepting your threats! Right?
Are you sick? Are you?
Did I threaten you?
Did I manipulate you?
I used Gao Huai Yi to control you?
Do you have a problem?
Let me tell you,
you want to win this case with them? Impossible.
No one can take anything
from my grasp!
You can't find evidence. You can no longer
prove which one is Tang Ji Ye's son!
I've won.
I've won!
No one can fight with me!
No one can fight with me! Do you understand?
I've won! Do you understand?
Money... I can give it to you.
I can allow you to live a rich life,
but your son Zheng Hao cannot
take Tang Ye away from me!
No one can!
Not one person can!
Oh.
How is it?
Zhong Ke Ming told Xia Yun that Gao Huai Yi is already dead.
Dead?
He died half a year ago.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
If this is a dead end, then let's turn back and go another direction.
Zhou Tong, what happened to the Lu Zhi Qiang you mentioned last time?
I heard he's already done investigating.
At that time, he was transferred away because of the Tang Ye New City relocation case.
He's told me this.
He said that relocation case was very complex. It hurt
Xie Qing Ping.
Yes. I also heard the presiding judge say that Lu Zhi Qiang
was unyielding. He kept appealing for over 20 years. Finally, he
got the attention of the municipal party committee head.
A while back, he wanted me to help him find Zhong Ke Ming's diaries.
Can you ask him to meet us?
I want to see if he has any evidence that could help us.
I'll try. It's a bit difficult.
Doesn't he want to look into the relocation case? Tell him
we have important evidence.
Zheng Hao, you've gotten Zheng Yi Jian's diaries?
Was there any information inside?
There wasn't anything unusual.
The diaries have every year.
The only years missing are '87 and '88.
Huh? That even more so means that there's a problem.
It must be that relocation case. There must be something there.
Zheng Hao, keep looking carefully.
Find the diaries from those years.
Do you know why they attacked your father Zheng Yi Jian?
Isn't it just because of that Yu Fen Li case?
No.
It's not just that case.
The real reason behind it is because
Zheng Yi Jian
got evidence that Tang Ye Corporation was taking bribes.
Bribing Xie Qing Ping.
He was Pujiang county's deputy secretary.
So it's like that.
But my brother and I searched the entire house.
We just can't find these two diaries.
What about this. Keep looking for it carefully.
Believe that your father wouldn't just throw away such important things.
Okay?
So it's like that.
That anonymous letter really was written by father.
Hello? You're still not asleep?
Yeah, what are you doing?
I'm writing a statement.
I want to tell you something.
What is it? Say it.
I found evidence.
I know why my father wrote you that anonymous letter.
Why?
It's because of Zhong Ke Ming.
So Zheng Yi Jian wrote me that letter because of this.
Now the mystery behind the anonymous letter is solved.
But why did he have to switch us?
He didn't write exactly what happened when switching the babies.
But the diary clearly shows
that Zheng Yi Jian knows Tang Ning is Zhong Ke Ming's daughter.
How would he know?
He must know what really happened when you were switched.
This diary mentions Xue Han Zhi.
Good. Good, Zheng Hao.
Teacher Zheng's diaries
not only solved the question of Tang Ning's anonymous letter,
but also opened up a scar that I've had for many years.
Do you think that if I give these diaries to the court
that we would have a chance of winning?
This... Right now it's very difficult to say.
The next hearing is in a few days.
If the maternity test results between Xia Yun and I can't get support from the court,
then we can only rely on these diaries.
Right now, the most important thing is to verify the authenticity of these diaries.
Only this way would the court accept this as evidence.
We will now continue the court's investigation.
Honorable judge,
our side wishes to submit new evidence to the court.
- New evidence?
- Yes.
It's very important written evidence.
What kind of written evidence? What does it help prove?
Zheng Yi Jian's diaries.
Timing and subtitles brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
Honorable judge, Zhong Ke Ming and I are both Zheng Yi Jian's students. We've both been his assistant lawyers.
These are photocopies of Zheng Yi Jian's diaries.
We are very familiar with his handwriting.
As for the authenticity of Teacher Zheng's diaries,
Lawyer Zhong doesn't have any objections, right?
Alright.
Next, please look at page 233 in the diary. Teacher Zheng
wrote this entry on March 7, 2014.
The entry is written like this.
♫ The difference between red and black is only one thin line ♫
♫ Blazing regret is better than freezing perfection ♫
♫ I take one step forward and stand on the periphery of blackness ♫
♫ A pile of gray stained the edges of my shoes ♫
♫ The difference between love and hate is only one thin line ♫
♫ A clear end is worse than false lies ♫
♫ I take one step backward and say my farewells to hate ♫
♫ The sound of the word “forever” stabbed my heart ♫
♫ Never tell me “forever” ♫
♫ It is just a notion to fool people ♫
♫ Who can promise that they’ve never used this word before? ♫
♫ In the end, they blame the long night for never seeing the next day ♫
♫ Never believe anybody when they say “forever” ♫
♫ It is just an alluring mask ♫
♫ Who can promise that they’ve never heard this word before? ♫
♫ That is only a story found in legends ♫
♫ The world is constantly changing, as are the winds and clouds ♫
♫ I clearly know the danger, yet I’ve fallen for it once again ♫
♫ Never say “forever” ♫