Cinema is an illusion that does not come from fiction or reality, but from the work's own reality.
In this film, the close ups of the girl's body have been performed by a body double.
We cannot see the actress, but the fictional construction of the girl's character.
ANATOMY
OF HELL
CJMONSTERNATOR Titles
#Timeless Bass/D'Julz#
Why did you do that?
Because I'm a woman.
I don't understand.
You understand perfectly well.
Thank you.
Why did you come back down to the toilets?
People like you don't look at women.
It's because you touched me on the stairs,
it was you wasn't it?
Yes.
So what?
It touched me.
I wasn't paying attention then, but just afterwards.
I was scared.
I was sure of what you came to do.
I was also sure of what you came to do.
I know why you went to the bogs.
To get sucked, like all men.
Bitch!
That's what they all do.
I can't escape.
What do you want to do now?
I'll pay you.
What do you hope for?
Knowledge.
Because as you don't like women, you can look at me in an unbiased manner.
I mean, impartially.
What's this about?
About what I just said.
To watch me when I'm unwatchable.
We wouldn't need to touch.
You looking will be enough.
It'll be expensive.
I'll pay you.
And that's how the deal was made.
First night...
Excuse me.
You came early, so I didn't have time to undress.
I'm paid to observe.
You can't ask for anything else.
Yes, you're right.
But I can't stop hoping for other things.
You didn't tell me how far away the house was.
So I had to take a train then a taxi.
You'll have to take that into account.
I'll pay for everything.
And so he'd been tricked into this meeting.
It sickens him to be there.
As if it's something new and unexpected.
He knows it will be.
Finally, it's about time.
Why do you display yourself like that?
The delicacy of female flesh
inspires disgust and cruelty.
So you're dependent on one or the other.
What should we fear more?
Nothingness.
Or brutality.
There's a big difference between the offer and the demand.
Between the offer and when it's taken up.
That's what we call the first deception.
After that nothing's the same.
Everything goes wrong.
Then with a recovery,
that's fake,
the disease stays as
an active cruelty.
You speak too much.
Your speech was full of clumsy insults.
Should I maybe have shaved my armpits?
It's still visible.
Shave as much as you want.
You could even shave your butt crack,
but it would never rid you of your natural obscenity.
On the other hand,
as the skin stays lumpy,
like the neck of a plucked chicken.
From each dirty, dry pore,
with the swelling irritated by the hair being ripped away,
like mountains of
microscopic sexual beings.
So we can't do anything about it?
No.
Nothing.
It's the depth of this obscenity.
The feminine depth.
That you long for the boys who don't want you.
And hate the boys who like you.
That's not what we see.
When you spread your legs,
we're revolted,
by the overly bright colour,
of your hidden, shapeless lips.
And the delicacy of this skin,
although, here and there,
is lumpy,
it's a skin that sweats
and oozes.
It's a toxic skin.
Like frog skin,
but they at least,
have the decency of being green.
And their thighs,
symbolically,
have the same enormity
as yours.
That's not what we see.
It's you who deny
this most terrifying obscenity.
Keep going.
And so I ask myself for the first time what put me off women.
It isn't this deep violence that they bring from their stagnant depths.
Until then I was honest.
But you must wonder what I was thinking of,
as thoughts can wonder.
And you can't keep them attached to a course that's not theirs.
And you can't deny what you think of this shining, putrid black bush.
You think of a baby bird.
Still wet from the egg.
And that becomes so touching in its newborn weakness.
And up until now, the child
who would become all men,
still remembered the horror of this sight that mocked him.
Do you understand?
I believe that he was telling me what I knew, but refused to hear.
That a woman's body calls for mutilation.
And for you there's nothing.
Nothing at all.
This male anger against something visible.
You've been here a while and you still don't know anything about a woman.
Why did you go and sit down?
Come here and look.
Isn't that what I'm paying for?
Do you know why people usually drink?
As soon as they're together?
It's because they have nothing to say.
They hope that the intimacy of the bedroom makes things better.
But it's worse.
We drink because
we have no thoughts for one another.
Nothing.
Are you speaking about me?
About everyone.
Male or female,
there's no difference.
When you offer all of
your fragile flesh,
when a flesh opening is promised,
I have no more thoughts or words.
I need alcohol.
I need to forget this depravity.
This loneliness.
Aren't you afraid then?
No. I control my impatience.
As waiting's not become part of my pleasure.
Waiting's what I ask for.
Do you see what I mean?
This reminds me of the exact time
where I was still young and far from thinking about sex.
Some silly boys from the neighbourhood who already acted like a gang
knocked through to our garden
like a group of partridges in the shooting season.
After a short time of fighting,
as I was the only enemy and it was dishonourable to beat me,
we agreed to be nice.
And in order to make peace, we played doctor.
I was the patient of course.
A girl is a man's sickness.
So maybe now all these new young doctors
were at one point repulsed forever by the growth of young virgin girls.
I bless the day I was born immune to you
and all of your type.
The elasticity of a boy's anus
doesn't lie.
From the tightness.
of the lower intestine.
The deception of women's delicacy is odious.
This detrimental worthlessness
that makes them a trap.
The dream of nothing
is the enduring everything.
I'm sick of your dawdling.
You haven't even looked at me.
You need to look at me when I don't see myself.
Despite its misleading masculine image,
the ocean rolled through the darkness like a bitch on heat.
Because just like a woman, it was empty
and could open itself up
and engulf you entirely.
I feel trapped by a type of witchcraft
of the obscene signs and sounds of nature.
Surrounded by the begging pleas of the weak,
only I was strong
and destitute
against the whole world.
It doesn't matter.
It's fine, it's the first night.
It's the first night.
Second night...
Did you want to kill me last night?
You resisted that urge for a long time.
How do you know?
It's what men want to do.
It's just the way it is.
That's why they lie with us.
And these veils that they ritually place upon us
foreshadow our misery.
But you're not part of this?
Are you oblivious to all this?
You don't know the evil that you're capable of.
Third night...
Anyone could've come in.
Or anything...
That's what men can stand.
They've always wanted to lock women away
in all times, places and latitudes.
To protect them from themselves.
To ward off a woman's true destiny.
In reality,
they're scared that women don't belong to them.
They don't believe in sensual freedom.
They threaten us with their belts.
It's absolutely horrid.
They want us to embrace chastity.
Their morals
are insensitive.
Because they always need to be assured.
Yet they know they can't ask for proof.
Otherwise there'd be no point in love.
I put it there to keep the blood off the sheets in your absence.
But now that you're here...
Pull.
Come on, pull.
Pull, it comes out easily.
You see everything here.
Because of this blood, they say we're impure.
Sometimes they won't shake our hands.
They don't want to have sex with us
during this period they call our periods.
In reality,
they're scared of this blood that flows from us without any wound.
What they call impurity.
I...
on the other hand,
I put it into a glass of water, like old people do with their false teeth.
And I watch the blooming of red blood
flowing through the water.
Shouldn't we drink the blood of our enemies?
Aren't that what women are to men?
Here, drink.
We make a big deal about it,
You see the space it takes up and we don't feel anything.
It's the size of most human penises.
The proof
that we don't have sex for the act itself,
but its meaning.
I can push it in just like during sex,
as deep as possible.
There's nothing to feel.
And there's no sense of pleasure at all:
like an ordinary gesture.
Look!
There's a whole device to make it look complicated.
So you can put it in place
without touching yourself.
So you can keep your virginity intact.
Without exploring your genitals.
You insert the tip of the cardboard.
Then you push it in like a syringe,
to inject yourself like
you're shooting up into your veins,
to feel the hygiene
of the absorbent cotton,
as if to heal a wound
that's painful and extremely sensitive.
I don't feel anything!
Not a thing.
Don't you think this is laughable?
I'd laugh, but it seems to foreshadow something terrible.
For something terrible rests in the brain of
the person who branded this with his signature.
It's so subserviently used.
This infamous thing!
You can be sure that the creator's a man.
A man who thinks he's superior and a protector,
and who doesn't like us.
However,
he's never understood what we've been through.
They're scared of us,
like children are scared of the dark.
Tell me,
did I lose my dignity by acting like this in front of you?
Tell me.
Fourth night...
Do you see anything?
You don't see anything, do you?
See, I can hide it inside me as long as I like.
And I can make it come out.
When I want to.
What confuses you is that women sigh at men's desires.
No...no.
Yes.
You know.
We're everything you see there...nothing.
Nothing exists.
Perhaps apart from what gives me pleasure:
The movement of your hand,
as you put this stone dildo inside me.
As you see,
you can see.
It's beautiful. It looks like you're bleeding.
You're scared, as you think you're bleeding.
Even though you know you're not.
And this hemorrhage is from the fertile blood of women.
You're wondering if I've cursed you
and ruined your penis forever.
Yes I am.
When you thrust into a man's anus,
it worries you that sometimes you come out with your penis soiled.
And you're not angry with them, nor sad, nor scared.
That happens sometimes.
But fecal matter
is inert.
It's finished the life cycle.
It's part of a human nature.
A man can't give life.
He takes it.
He gives love,
and hence, eternal life.
Whilst leaving, she slipped me the money that I'd earnt.
By keeping the money, I lost the sense of illusion. I lost her.
I knew it at once.
But I actually felt intimidated.
And I had taken the money,
although I actually wanted to refuse it.
Here,
same again, please.
Two! One more for him.
Stop thinking about it.
Stop thinking about it; she was a bitch,
a whore,
just like the others.
Yes,
but the queen of whores.
I tore her pussy apart so badly, that nobody else will want her.
You're right.
You shag them like goats.
Just like goats.
As many as you can.
It's so that...
you're immune to them all.
Because if you let one get under your skin,
You're screwed.
You're fucked.
But she's ruined me.
You see? She's ruined me.
But there's booze and she can't take that.
They can't take that.
They cannot, you see?
I made her crap her shit
and lie in her piss.
The bitch.
She was ruined once I left her.
No human being would let me use her the way I did.
But she wanted it.
She wanted more!
She still wanted more!
She would've wanted me to rip her guts out and made her eat them.
Yeah, you're right.
Yeah.
I didn't even bother to find out her name.
I knew her.
I knew her in a very intimate way.
And I didn't even give a shit about her name.
I don't need it.
Neither do I.
I refused to believe that was she gave was now mine.
And I could draw my existence from it.
I so badly wanted to start over again from the beginning.
But this time knowing what I was doing.
I didn't want to admit that life was not like this.
Because nothing can ever exactly start again.
CJMONSTERNATOR Titles