Oh, my.
Hope you haven't
been waiting long.
I'm usually
the first one here.
Sorry about that.
All right.
I think you're gonna like this
three-bedroom property, Mr. Poole.
Right through here, this bathroom
has been completely redone...
new tiles, new sink.
There are walk-ins
in every room.
And right through here
is the kitchen.
Look at this skylight.
That is nice.
And the cabinets, I believe
are original, which some
people really enjoy.
And if you follow me
to the backyard...
And, uh...
What about the other house?
The one down the street.
Oh, right.
Well, I made the offer
like you asked,
but they didn't
want to sell.
Yeah, that house
is not on the market.
I mean, did you tell them
that I'd pay whatever they wanted?
I did, Mr. Poole.
They live there.
They like it.
That's their home.
But anyway,
back to this place...
Let me just show you
this backyard.
Are you from California,
Mr. Poole?
The weather's so nice here.
A lot of Californians
spend time in their backyard.
And look at this...
there's plenty of room for a pool
- or a hot tub...
- How much?
Well, they're asking 325.
I'm sorry, could you
mind repeating that?
I just have trouble
with this ear.
Oh, I'm sorry. I was
saying they're asking 325.
Okay, I'll take it.
Well.
Mr. Poole, I'm pretty sure I could
get them to knock off 25 or 30.
I mean, look at this place.
It needs to be re-stuccoed and...
It's okay.
I'll pay what
they're asking.
But look at the place.
I mean, it needs paint
at the minimum
and the landscaping really
leaves a lot to be desired.
I'd like to pay
what they want.
No negotiating,
no repairs, just...
But Mr. Poole...
Mrs. Wyat,
you need to just
let this go. Okay?
The higher the price,
the bigger your commission.
- So...
- Okay, then.
¶ Don't got a lot of time ¶
¶ Don't give a damn ¶
¶ Don't tell me
what to do ¶
¶ I am the man ¶
¶ If there's a God
up there ¶
¶ Something above ¶
¶ God, shine your light down here ¶
¶ Shine on the love ¶
¶ Love of the loveless ¶
¶ Don't have too many friends ¶
¶ Never felt at home ¶
¶ Always been my own man ¶
¶ Pretty much alone ¶
¶ I know how to get through ¶
¶ And when push comes to shove ¶
¶ I got something that you need ¶
¶ I got the love ¶
¶ Love of the loveless ¶
¶ The love of the loveless ¶
¶ All around you,
people walking ¶
¶ Empty hearts
and voices talking ¶
¶ Looking for and finding ¶
¶ Nothing ¶
¶ Don't got a lot of time ¶
¶ Don't really care ¶
¶ Not selling anything ¶
¶ Buyer beware ¶
¶ If there's a God
up there ¶
¶ Something above ¶
¶ God, shine your light
down here ¶
¶ Shine on the love ¶
¶ Love of the loveless ¶
¶ Love of the loveless. ¶
Hi.
I'm your neighbor from...
from next door,
Esperanza Martinez.
I just want to come by
and say hello,
um, welcome you
to the neighborhood.
Hello.
Homemade tamales for you.
Thank you.
I used to be...
good friends with the man
who lived here.
I was actually
the one who found him.
Found him where?
There in your kitchen.
He died of a heart attack.
Fue terrible.
It was terrible.
He had been laying there
for 10 hours, they think.
- Here?
- Yes.
We were good friends.
So where are you from?
Not here.
Thank you for
the tamales.
You're welcome.
Looks like you're burning.
- I am.
- Are you wearing any sunscreen?
Well, I would have called
before I stopped by,
but you still don't
have a phone.
- No.
- Yeah, and I rang the...
Anyway, I just wanted to make sure
you're doing okay
and that the move
went well.
And did you notice that
we re-stuccoed and painted?
Yeah, I noticed that.
Didn't I ask you
not to do that?
Yeah, well...
- I just thought...
- The thing is...
I'm not gonna be living here
that long, Mrs. Wyat,
so it's really just
a waste of time.
What do you mean, you're not
gonna be living here that long?
And for the record,
whoever did it,
they did kind of
a lousy job.
It's all discolored
right there.
Oh, well...
we can have
that fixed.
No, don't bother.
It doesn't matter.
Well.
Anyhow.
Looks like you're burning.
- I am.
- Are you wearing any sunscreen?
Well, I would have called
before I stopped by,
but you still don't
have a phone.
And I rang the bell.
Well?
And did you notice
that we re-stuccoed
and painted?
Yeah, I noticed that.
Didn't I ask you
not to do that?
Yeah, well...
- I just thought...
- The thing is,
I'm not gonna be living here
that long, Mrs. Wyat.
So it's kind of
a waste of time.
What do you mean, you're not gonna be
living here that long?
And for the record,
whoever did it,
they did kind of
a lousy job.
It's all discolored
right there.
Oh, well...
we can have
that fixed.
No, don't bother.
It doesn't matter.
Anyhow.
What are you doing?
Oh my God.
Yes! Really. Really.
Yes! Yes!
I don't know anything
for sure, but...
It's... it's like...
Oh, please please
please please.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you.
See you soon.
Mr. Poole, something very
wonderful has happened...
Were you just in
my backyard?
Did you not look?
Were you looking
in the windows?
Ay, no!
Of course not.
Did you not see?
See what?
- Oh my God.
- I...
I... I saw you.
You were running around.
Do you need
to borrow something?
Okay, I'll see you later.
You don't see it?
See what?
All I see is a water stain
from a lousy stucco job.
You are not looking.
I... I don't see anything.
Es el rostro de Dios.
The face of God.
The face of Christ.
It's... it's like a sign
from God.
Look, the only sign
I see is that
you seem a little overexcited.
It's probably the heat.
I think the heat
has gotten to you.
- Okay?
- Okay. Okay.
I... I... I know it's
hard to believe it.
But the proof is right...
right there.
All right.
You just going
to ignore it?
No. No.
I am gonna
ignore you, though.
So who were you
talking to?
To you.
No, I mean in your yard.
You were on the phone.
- Who were you talking to?
- Mmm.
Excuse me?
Stay there.
Yeah?
Hi, I'm looking for
Esperanza Martinez.
Said she would be here.
I'm Father Vincent Salizar
from St. Ramos
Catholic Church.
She called and asked me
to meet her here...
Discúlpame.
Qué bueno que llegó.
It's in the backyard.
I'll show you.
Ven. Come in, come in,
come in.
Mire.
Pares aquí.
Aquí aquí.
Pares aquí. Aja.
Look, I don't know
what you're up to,
but I didn't say
you could come back here
and I'd like you
to both leave.
You see?
Well, I do see something.
- Very sorry about the intrusion, Mr...
- Poole.
Henry Poole.
Mr. Poole, I apologize.
So...
you do see it?
Well, I can see how it could
be interpreted as a face.
- Oh my God.
- That's quite clear.
But the face of Christ?
I'm not so sure that
we can make that leap.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You see?
You understand?
And like I was saying,
I'd like you to both leave.
I'm kinda busy in there.
No no no no no.
Look. Look.
You can see...
the eyes here
and the beard here.
And the holy shoulder.
Everything. Everything, Padrecito.
Everything.
I can see how
it could be that.
These types of things should
not be easily discounted,
but we do have to take
these things at face value,
no pun intended.
Look, the face value of this
is that it's a water stain.
Right?
- Right?
- You're probably right, Mr. Poole.
Yeah. Yeah.
And by no means does
the church condone
any kind of frivolous
claims of this nature, but...
But nothing.
Look,
the game's over, okay?
That's not the face of Christ
and I want to be
left alone!
You're right.
You're right, Mr. Poole.
We've imposed enough.
Esperanza, let's go.
No no, espere un minuto, ¿sí?
Mr. Poole,
you can't ignore this, please.
- Es que espere, mejor... mejor, sí.
- Esperanza...
- vámonos.
- Por favor, espere un minuto.
Mr. Poole,
don't you believe in God?
Please! Please.
Es que... es el rostro
de Dios.
Sus ojos.
Excuse me.
No, wait...
These types of things
should not be
easily discounted,
but we do have to take
these things at face value,
no pun intended.
Yeah, well, I agree...
Please...
It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna be okay.
I'm sorry.
Hello?
Hi. I'm Henry.
I live next door.
Oh, yeah.
I saw you move in.
I'm Dawn.
- Hi.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
Anyway, your daughter,
I guess,
she dropped this
in my backyard.
Oh, God, I'm...
I'm so sorry.
I keep telling her to stay
out of other people's yards.
No, it's not a problem.
She was just walking around back there.
Did she tape you?
I don't know.
'Cause she does that
sometimes.
She tapes people.
Why does she do that?
Uh...
I don't know.
Um, well, I've got to go.
But thank you so much
for bringing this
back to Millie and...
I'll make sure that she
stays out of your yard.
You having
another party?
Sorry?
Well, I've seen you in here a couple
of times buying the same stuff.
I thought maybe... Uh...
That'll be $155.82.
I thought maybe you might
be throwing some parties.
No parties.
Well, that doesn't look like
a very healthy diet.
Just kind of a phase.
Andales. Andales.
Hurry hurry.
Go go go with me.
Hurry, girl! Hurry.
Hurry, Margie.
Oh my God, oh my God,
oh my God, oh my God.
- Hey!
- Oh my God, oh my God.
Run run run run!
I see you.
Hey! Hey!
Holy shoulder!
Hey.
Are these yours?
There you go.
You can have those back.
Let me ask you
a question.
Does that look like a church back there?
'Cause it's not.
It's my house.
It's private property.
And I don't want you four
wandering around back there
when I'm not home
with a bunch of candles
doing whatever it is
that those things do. Okay?
And you're gonna put
paint on my wall?
All right?
That's vandalism.
- Got it?
- Please. Please, Mr. Poole.
Calm. We didn't paint
anything on your wall.
- Really?
- Really.
- No, nothing?
- No no no...
Okay, so what's that?
Wanna tell me
what that is?
Oh my God.
That's not paint,
Mr. Poole.
And we did not
put it there.
So what is it?
It's blood.
It's the holy blood.
- Blood?
- Yes.
Okay.
- Oh my God.
- Let me tell you something.
All three of you are
old enough to know better
and I'm especially
disappointed in you.
Sick of it.
Please just leave me alone,
all right?
Blood.
¶ Whoo hoo ¶
¶ I got my head checked ¶
¶ By a jumbo jet ¶
¶ It wasn't easy ¶
¶ But nothing is ¶
¶ No ¶
¶ Whoo hoo ¶
¶ When I feel heavy metal ¶
¶ And I'm pins
and I'm needles ¶
¶ Whoo hoo ¶
¶ Well, I lie
and I'm easy ¶
¶ All of the time but
I'm never sure ¶
¶ When I need you ¶
¶ Pleased to meet you ¶
¶ Oh, yeah. ¶
Thank you.
Ooh! Oops.
- "Oops?"
- Sorry.
Oh, I missed.
You... you missed?
Eh, let me just
try again.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Damn it. Jesus.
Sorry.
- Oh, damn.
- Eh!
You know, seriously,
do you want to go
practice and come back?
Maybe warm up on, like, an orange?
What's the story?
You know, at this point, I'm just like,
"A razor blade and a coffee cup,
I'll do it myself."
You know what I mean?
One more time.
It's just...
this is the one.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, just relax.
Okay?
I feel it.
Okay.
- Ah, got it.
- Got it?
- Mm-hmm.
- Good.
Ouch! How many times
did she hit you?
Uh, three or four.
I actually kinda lost track.
Three or four, huh?
She's getting better.
She got some practice.
Let me just run through
a couple of standard Q and A.
- You sleeping okay?
- I could use a little more, yeah.
Diet good?
I eat, yeah.
Exercise?
Uh, you know,
here and there.
So no?
- Well...
- Other than that, Mr. Poole,
you're doing fine.
I'd probably try
a little more exercise.
Maybe some yoga?
Or Pilates?
I'll call you in a few days when
your blood and urine come back.
I can help you
over here.
Hope you're not using
that as a mixer.
- Huh?
- 'Cause you're not getting vodka.
Oh, yeah.
Did you know that in 1985,
Gorbachev, right after he became
the party's general secretary,
tried to eradicate
vodka in Russia?
The people wouldn't
have it, though.
Isn't that weird?
I mean...
something like 30,000
Russians die a year
from alcohol poisoning,
but the people,
they want what
they want.
Yeah.
What's wrong with you?
Hmm?
Well, I don't mean
to be rude.
It's just that...
something is clearly
wrong with you.
I don't know if you're sad
or angry or both,
but you're not normal.
I thought maybe you might
want to talk about it.
You want me to tell you
why I'm sad and angry
while you're ringing up
my bottles of bleach?
So it is both...
sad and angry.
- I didn't say that.
- Yes, you did.
- No, I didn't.
I was indulging you.
Okay? I was being polite.
Okay, indulge me
some more.
- Tell me what's wrong.
- Why don't you just ring my stuff up,
all right? Jesus.
I mean, I appreciate
your concern,
but I'd just like to
get out of here.
- All right?
- Okay.
I'm sorry I asked.
Don't be.
It's okay to be sad,
you know.
I mean, I've been
really sad before.
Sometimes...
you have to be sad to remind
yourself that you're alive.
Better than feeling
nothing, right?
It's not coming off, huh?
No.
No, it isn't.
I, uh, think I might have
even made it worse.
You, uh, you got
any suggestions?
Um, no.
But if it's what
Esperanza says it is,
then I guess it's gonna take a little
bit more than a bottle of bleach.
Yeah, well,
Esperanza's wrong.
So you aren't in
so much doubt.
You really think that's
the face of Christ?
Actually,
from this angle, it looks
a little bit like you.
I mean,
an abstract version.
I guess.
It's just a stain.
It's a bad stain.
Well, if you can't
get it off,
I guess it'll be something
to remember you by.
What?
Well, you're not gonna
live here that long, right?
Esperanza, she's like the local
newspaper around here.
I think she cornered
the real estate agent
and so we got
the lowdown on you.
Yeah.
So... so what are you doing? Buying it,
selling it and making a profit?
Yeah.
Yeah, something like that.
Well, don't sell it
to any weirdoes, okay?
No.
I won't.
Okay, well,
good luck with the face.
Thanks.
Or whatever it is.
Listen to me.
The man is clearly an atheist.
And he's not very nice.
The two go hand in hand.
Well, those without faith
sometimes need a little help.
That's it.
Psst, psst.
Now what are you doing?
- Your lawn is so sloopy.
- Sloopy?
- Yeah.
- Look, this is ridiculous.
Okay, people just don't go around
helping one another for no reason,
so just tell me
what it is you're doing.
- What do you want?
- I don't want anything.
Just tell him.
Just ask him.
Ask me what?
She wants to bring
the church in
to test the face
in your backyard,
to see if it's a miracle.
You've got to
be kidding me.
Nope. She's crafty like that.
- Aren't you?
- Yeah.
I didn't catch your name,
but anyways...
Listen to me, okay?
You can build me
a goddamn gazebo back there
and I still wouldn't let you
and your crazy church friends
into my house. All right?
So that face, whatever
you happen to think it is,
is a stain.
It's not a miracle.
Okay?
How can you say that?
Look, I really don't want
to talk about it,
so I just came out here
to give you that.
I just found it, so...
Oh my God.
Why did you have to
go and do that?
Um, why are you crying?
I just... I'm sorry.
I just found that.
That's Leo.
He was her boyfriend
before he died.
He lived in your house.
He was such a good man.
Well, look, there's
a cigar box full of them under the sink,
so you can come by
and get 'em when you want 'em.
He was so handsome.
I... I never thought
I'd find someone like him.
I... I was ready to...
to just be old alone.
I never married.
Never found anyone.
Then one day,
three years ago or so,
Leo came here.
And that was it.
Years of being alone
and one minute...
manages to take it all away.
A lifetime of sadness and...
suddenly
I couldn't even remember
what it was like to be sad.
And then he died.
And I remember.
And...
I pray to God
to help me stop
feeling that pain
and let me know
that he was okay.
And now...
the face appears...
the face of God.
Look,
Esperanza...
I want you to be
very honest with me.
Okay?
You really think that
that stain out there
is the answer
to all your prayers?
Do you?
So what exactly is it that
you want the church to do?
Just come and test
the wall.
Test the blood.
And to see what it is.
And if it's nothing,
then it's nothing
and I won't
bother you again.
I promise, really.
All right.
Just one day.
That's it.
I mean it.
One day.
Thank you, Mr. Poole.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You'll see.
Everything happens
for a reason.
Esperanza,
llevélo al dentro.
- Gracias.
- Who's that guy?
He has to open up the wall and look
at what's behind the stain
to be sure it's not
man-made.
We'll repair it.
It'll look as good as new. Don't worry.
No, don't repair it.
It's okay.
Don't be silly, Mr. Poole. We're not
gonna leave a hole in the wall.
Doesn't matter.
I'm not gonna be here
that long.
You know, Father Salizar,
the house was re-stuccoed
before I moved in,
so that's it.
There's really not
a lot to talk about.
Maybe not about the house.
Why did you say you were
not gonna be here that long?
I don't really want
to talk about it.
Oh, yeah, you do.
Oh, I do?
Otherwise you wouldn't
have mentioned it.
Let me ask you
a question.
What makes you think
you know me that well?
I don't think that.
I just think anybody with two eyes
could see that something is wrong,
- like you're...
- Sad and angry?
Yeah.
Something like that.
I'm a good listener.
Yeah? Me too.
I just think anybody with two eyes
could see that something
is wrong.
- Like you're...
- Sad and angry?
Yeah.
Something like that.
I just think anybody
with two eyes
could see that something
is wrong,
- like you're...
- Sad and angry?
Yeah.
Something like that.
What are you doing
in there?
Wow.
You really like
this place.
You don't talk,
do you, Millie?
It's okay.
Sometimes I don't like
to talk either.
You know?
I ought to go.
Okay?
I'd love to sit here and visit
with you, but I just can't.
I got a pretty long journey
ahead of me.
I wish I could stay
and talk with you.
I just don't have
the time.
Mr. Poole? Uh...
I... I'm sorry.
I rang the bell, but...
Well, I have something
for you.
How'd you know
this was the one?
I know everything
about this neighborhood.
You should know that
by now.
This used to be my room.
Mr. Poole, are you okay?
This is the last place
I remember being happy.
Even then
I can barely remember.
This is the room where they
used to scream at each other.
Mmm.
It's a strange thing
about standing here again.
It's doing absolutely nothing
for me, you know?
Mr. Poole,
I'm sorry it wasn't
what you hoped.
Don't be.
It never is.
But thank you.
This was very generous.
- Mmm.
- Thanks.
What did you expect?
You can't go to the past
to fix the present.
You sound like
a fortune cookie.
Cookies don't talk.
Now...
at least now you know.
Know what?
To come back to
the place you grew up.
Yeah.
Now I know.
It's like nothing.
You find out
there's nowhere to hide.
¶ Shadows are falling ¶
¶ And I been here
all day ¶
¶ It's too hot to sleep ¶
¶ And time is
running away ¶
¶ I feel like my soul has ¶
¶ Turned into steel ¶
¶ I've still got the scars ¶
¶ That the sun
didn't heal ¶
¶ There's not even
room enough ¶
¶ To be anywhere ¶
¶ It's not dark yet ¶
¶ But it's gettin' there. ¶
Millie?
Hey.
Come out, honey.
It's too late to be playing games.
Where are you, Millie?
Millie?
What are you doing?
Honey?
Hey, Millie.
Millie.
Hey.
What is it?
Hey, what did you say?
What?
Hey.
What did you say?
Mama.
Mommy?
Can you hear me?
We're okay.
I love you so so much.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, baby.
Mommy's here.
Mommy's right here.
Come on.
Let's go.
Hey, let's go home.
Thanks.
What happened out there?
You tell me.
She hasn't said a word
in over a year,
ever since her father left.
I mean, she loved him
so much.
And it's just been...
so unfair for her.
I mean, I... I couldn't
even get her out of bed
when this
whole thing started.
She just kind of
turned inside herself
and couldn't find
her way out.
I took to every kind
of doctor... therapists,
psychologists,
psychiatrists, and pretty much
everyone... nothing.
They'd just run down the list...
depression, post-traumatic
whatever...
abandonment.
And after a while,
she got a little better,
but she just
wouldn't talk.
Maybe she just didn't
have anything to say.
Maybe she wasn't ready
until now.
Maybe. But she touched
that wall and she...
You think she spoke because
she touched the wall?
No, I'm not saying that,
but that's what happened.
I mean, she touched it
and she talked.
And I'm just praying
that it stays that way.
Dawn, I think it's great
that Millie spoke.
But I think you
should realize
it was a completely
random event.
Things just... they don't
happen like that in real life.
I mean, if they did,
then I wouldn't...
You wouldn't what?
Ever feel like things
just happen for no reason?
That you're just kind of
going along for the ride
and there's just
nothing you can do?
I need to
tell you something.
What?
I want to tell you so that
I'm not the only one that knows.
Henry, this is so unheard of
here in the States.
I mean, it happens.
- But this disease...
- Disease?
It steamrolls
through the system.
Stopping it at this point...
You're saying
I'm gonna die.
Yes.
Mr. Poole.
Mr. Poole,
are you okay?
Mr. Poole?
Sorry.
The door was open.
That doesn't mean you can
just walk through it.
I need to talk to you.
No. No, you don't, actually,
'cause I know exactly
what you're gonna say.
No, you don't exactly.
So I guess you heard
what happened last night.
Now you think
that little girl spoke
because she touched
the wall?
And now we're all supposed to believe
that the Second Coming's happening
in my backyard.
And the next thing you know,
this whole goddamn street...
sorry... turns into a carnival
with every holy-roller freak
within a 100-mile radius
lined up around the block
to touch or catch a glimpse
of my stucco job.
Well, it's not gonna happen.
And in no way did Millie
finally speaking
have anything to do
with her touching the wall,
and you know that.
And God only knows... and I use
the phrase very loosely, believe me...
who knows what it was that caused her
to get up at 3:00 in the morning
and wander over here
and start palming the wall
like her life
depended on it?
- It was me.
- What was you?
I told her the wall would
take away her suffering
if... if she just had faith.
Why would you do that?
- It worked, no?
- No.
She worked. Maybe your
insane pep talk got to her,
but she got here
on her own.
Why it's so hard
for you to believe
that something like this
could happen?
Why is it so important
to you that I believe
that something like that
could happen?
- Because it...
- Because I'll tell you.
Because if you can convince me,
then suddenly your beliefs
become more real. Right?
The more people you can get to
jump on your God's-on-the-wall train,
the more your mission's made.
So until you get me
to swallow your world
and believe what you believe,
you'll never have the kind
of faith you want to have.
You'll always have
a little bit of doubt.
You'll... you'll never
know if you're quite right.
You'll always kind of
be wondering if it's real.
You'll always be sitting over
there waiting for that man
to come waltzing back
in from the dead.
And that's sad.
That's really sad.
I'm just trying
to help.
Just like that.
Yeah?
Esp...
Esperanza?
- Hey.
How you doin'?
I'm good.
Just getting some air.
I just wanted
to thank you
for helping me
with Millie last night.
So...
I made you some cookies.
Thank you.
It was Millie's idea.
- How is she doing?
- She's really good.
I'm just praying
that it stays that way.
You wanna go
for a walk?
Yeah.
Mmm, just came out of the oven,
like, 10 minutes ago.
¶ Her fingers touch
upon my lips ¶
¶ It's a morning yearning ¶
¶ It's a morning
yearning ¶
¶ Pull the curtains shut ¶
¶ And try to keep it dark ¶
¶ But the sun is burning ¶
¶ The sun is burning ¶
¶ Baby crying kept us
up all night ¶
¶ With her morning yearning ¶
¶ With her
morning yearning ¶
¶ Morning yearning... ¶
I just wish I could tell you that
everything was gonna be all right.
That's okay.
Now what?
Now I go home.
And then...
I wish I didn't.
¶ Like a summer rose ¶
¶ I'm a victim of the fall ¶
¶ But am soon returning ¶
¶ Soon returning ¶
¶ Your love's the warmest
place the sun ever shines ¶
¶ My morning yearning ¶
¶ My morning
yearning. ¶
My God.
Dear God.
Oh my God.
Patience.
What are you doing?
What's going on?
Are you... are you okay?
Yeah.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing is wrong.
Everything is right.
What are you talking about?
I touched the face.
I just put
my hand on it.
And my whole body
got all warm.
And then I closed
my eyes.
I saw light everywhere.
I opened them...
and I could see.
I can see.
Look at that.
I can see perfectly.
The house numbers,
the license plate.
You know,
this is amazing.
- This is a miracle...
- Don't say that.
What? Miracle?
- Yeah.
- Come on, Mr. Poole,
what else could this be?
What?
A coincidence?
I mean, there are
no miracles, Patience.
I don't believe in them.
Imagine that there was
something wrong with you,
Mr. Poole.
And you did this seemingly
meaningless thing,
put your hand
on a wall,
and you were healed.
It's okay, Mr. Poole.
You don't have to say anything.
I gotta go.
I gotta go
tell my mom.
This is incredible!
Wow!
Hi.
Hey.
It's getting harder,
isn't it?
What's that?
To pretend this
isn't happening.
Hey!
- Hi.
- You're home.
Yeah.
Millie wants to know if you
want to come over and play.
Really?
Um, I just don't think
I'm up to it.
- Henry...
- I think I'll just stay here.
...are you actually considering
saying no to a six-year-old girl
with actual words coming
out of her little mouth?
Give me a minute.
We'll be in the yard.
Millie?
Dawn?
I got you, Mr. Poole.
Let's get him!
- Get him, Mommy, get him!
- I got him!
Oh, gosh.
I surrender.
You win.
¶ A million tears ¶
¶ A million codes ¶
¶ 1:15 ¶
¶ No way to go ¶
¶ You point your finger ¶
¶ To the moon ¶
¶ It looks like rain ¶
¶ Coming soon ¶
¶ I figured all ¶
¶ My worst fears ¶
¶ Believe in
childlike heroes ¶
¶ But I don't want to go ¶
¶ That way ¶
¶ Surrender hope ¶
¶ Again ¶
¶ I don't want to go
that way ¶
¶ Surrender hope ¶
¶ And faith ¶
¶ Again ¶
¶ Your blood, your fire ¶
¶ Your kiss good night ¶
¶ Your words, sometime ¶
¶ They might be mine ¶
¶ I feel this love
could cross the sand ¶
¶ I want to feel
that way ¶
¶ The fire might linger
and fade away ¶
¶ The shadows run
from yesterday ¶
¶ Like everyone ¶
¶ And everything
were memories ¶
¶ And then appears ¶
¶ Your blood, your fire ¶
¶ Your kiss good night ¶
¶ Your words, sometimes ¶
¶ They might be mine ¶
¶ I feel this love
could cross the sand ¶
¶ I want to feel that way ¶
¶ Oh, don't make me
feel that way ¶
¶ Oh, I want to feel ¶
¶ That way ¶
¶ Oh, I'm breaking through ¶
¶ These walls of steel ¶
¶ Pushing that wall
for something real ¶
¶ I'm falling far
and faster still ¶
¶ Wake up, wake up ¶
¶ Wake up,
wake up ¶
¶ Wake up, wake up ¶
¶ Everyone and everything ¶
¶ Everyone
and everything. ¶
- All right?
- Yeah.
You ready?
- Okay, good.
- Hey!
Hey.
Hi, Mr. Poole.
Hey, there, Millie.
That's a really nice dress.
You look really pretty.
You look nervous,
Mr. Poole.
Oh, no, I'm... I'm fine.
I, uh, no.
I'm just a little tired,
that's all.
You kind of wore me
out yesterday.
Um, honey,
do you want to
get in the car?
I wanted to, uh,
return your dish to you.
Oh, thanks.
They were really good.
Thanks a lot.
Glad you liked them.
Really shouldn't eat
so many at once, though.
- Not good for you.
- No, it doesn't matter.
I mean, I'm...
Uh... no, you're right.
I shouldn't.
Well, listen, I...
I was wondering and,
I don't know,
it might seem a little unfair
seeing as how you know
my situation,
but I thought that maybe,
if you were able to get
a sitter and you had the time...
- Yes.
- Really?
Oh, wait.
- What?
- Can I ask you?
Well, you did just
ask me, didn't you?
No, I mean, really ask you...
to finish asking you.
Okay.
Would you like to
get dinner with me?
I can't.
I'm busy.
- I didn't really want to any...
- No!
Henry, I'm kidding.
I would love to.
- Great.
- What about tomorrow?
It's perfect.
And it's not unfair
for you to ask.
Would it be worse
if you didn't?
Thank you.
Okay, so...
- Tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Have fun.
Just this once, okay?
Okay, I promise.
Whatever you say, Mr. Poole.
Thank you.
What's wrong with her?
Bursitis.
And what about
the one next to her?
There's nothing
wrong with her.
So, preventative?
Just in case.
No, is it true that
the man in the red shirt
just wants to be
a better dancer?
Ay, Mr. Poole...
Um, what about you,
Mr. Poole?
Have you touched
the wall yet?
No.
But you will.
Hey, Henry.
- Hi.
- It's good to see you.
Funny.
It's good to see you too.
Oh, you...
you forgot these.
I wanted to return
those to you.
Thanks.
Don't really need them, though.
- Well.
- I guess they'll be a good souvenir
- of my previous life.
- Yeah.
So have you talked
to your doctor yet,
- your eye doctor?
- Not yet.
90 bucks for him to
tell me I'm 20/20.
- Yeah.
- I already know that.
But, I mean, you got to think
about all the write-ups
in the medical journals. Right?
You're still having
a pretty hard time buying into this,
- aren't you?
- You gotta admit that it's...
Do you know who
Noam Chomsky is?
- The writer?
- Yeah.
He's a linguist too, but...
once in an interview, he said,
"When questions of decision,
reason or choice of action arise,
human science is at a loss."
You actually believe that?
He meant that not everything
needs an explanation.
Sometimes things just happen
because we choose
for them to.
I chose to believe.
Okay.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Well, this is about
the loveliest thing
that I've ever seen.
I can't wait to see
what's for dinner.
Pizza!
Perfect.
This is... this is
very romantic, Henry.
- Thanks.
- Really.
Plastic utensils.
Oh, yeah, family heirlooms.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
The other night,
you came home kinda late and...
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
It's fine.
You want to know
where I was.
Yes.
I can't tell you.
No, I...
I'd just gone for a walk.
And it's kind of funny
'cause I'd just left the house
and started walking
and I... I don't even think
I really knew where I was going
till I got there.
Where did you go?
The river.
I, uh...
My parents,
they used to fight a lot.
So I would go down there
and even though it was
such a big place,
I always... I always just
kind of felt very safe there.
I'd kind of go there
and hide.
And that's why...
I came here.
So just like that,
you disappeared.
Since this thing
happened to me,
every morning when I wake up,
the first thing I think about
is... I mean, after I figure out
if I'm still actually here or not...
The first thing I think about
is how much time
that I have left.
And all I can really do
is kind of...
wait for the end.
But this morning
when I woke up...
the first thing
I thought about was you.
And Millie.
I'm just trying
to say that...
that I'm enjoying this.
I'm enjoying you
and being around you.
And I just...
it's a surprise
'cause I didn't ever think
that I'd feel this way.
Mommy?
Millie, what are you
doing up?
I can't sleep.
Where is Esperanza?
On the couch, snoring.
Okay, let's go inside.
Um, do me a favor.
Keep enjoying this.
All right, honey.
Come on.
Big sack of potatoes, huh?
What are you doing
up so late, Millie?
It's a school night.
Okay, you want Jasper?
Here he is.
'Night.
Sorry about that.
It's like she doesn't want
to miss a thing now that...
You know...
I... I think maybe we should
just call it a night
because this isn't...
Henry.
Sorry, this just isn't right.
What are you talking about?
Just you, me and everything
all at once.
I just... I'm sorry.
Hey, how can you say that?
Henry.
I know you're gonna die,
but all that either of us have
is right now,
and we should pay
attention to that.
I am paying attention.
That's the problem.
I'm sorry.
¶ On an ocean white ¶
¶ Of roaring waves ¶
¶ I see your light ¶
¶ And golden face ¶
¶ A precious gift ¶
¶ Of your longing arms ¶
¶ Hurt me not ¶
¶ Just sing to me,
my love ¶
¶ Ooh ooh ¶
¶ How come so ¶
¶ So ¶
¶ Sweetly, child,
you sing? ¶
¶ And all the joy ¶
¶ You bring to me ¶
¶ Goes ¶
¶ Goes our loved
ones home ¶
¶ And I will... ¶
¶ I will be waiting. ¶
Henry!
What's going on?
- It's Millie.
- What is it?
She's in here.
I mean, she's been
like this all morning.
She won't talk to me.
She won't look at me.
Nothing.
Millie?
Can you hear me?
Millie, you remember how
much fun we had the other day
when we played?
You remember that?
Please.
Please say something.
Henry's here.
He came over to play.
Sweetie?
Honey,
can you hear me?
Henry, I know you're gonna die,
but all that either of us
have is right now.
And we should pay
attention to that.
Was there any kind
of trauma?
Anything which could have
set her back like this?
You told me "one time."
You promised me.
Mr. Poole, God is
bigger than a promise.
Just let me talk to you, yes?
- Esperanza, please, let him go.
- No no no!
- Mr. Poole, just let us...
- Listen to me, please.
Listen to me!
Mr. Poole.
- Holy shit.
- No no no no.
No "holy shit." No "holy shit."
Holy... something else.
Mr. Poole,
the test came back.
Yeah, and what? And what?
There's no explanation for it, right?
- No.
- It's a big surprise, huh?
- No no, please...
- Yes, you're right.
There is no explanation.
That's exactly right.
You want to tell me
what's going on?
Why all these people
are here? Huh?
There here to see
something unexplainable.
- Yeah?
- They're here to find some hope.
Let me tell you something...
I never should have let you
come here in the first place
'cause this is insane.
You got people praying to the wall.
- Excuse me, is this your house?
- Yeah!
- This is my house.
- You know, you're a very lucky man
- to have such a...
- Yeah! Yeah, I'm so lucky
I ought to buy
a lottery ticket, shouldn't I?
You're all just kind of
staring at the wall?
Is that what you're doing?
Hope can't save you.
You understand that?
It can't save you.
Or her
or her or him!
You understand that?
Hope isn't gonna save you!
You know that.
Please, Mr. Poole.
No no no no no no, please.
Listen to me!
Listen, it's a miracle.
It will do things...
No no no no...
this is a gift from God!
This is a gift from God!
No no... oh my God.
I want this out of here!
I don't want this stain
on my wall!
I want...
This doesn't save lives.
Please.
¶ Oooh ¶
¶ Sweetly, child,
you sing ¶
¶ And all the joy ¶
¶ You bring to me ¶
¶ Goes ¶
¶ Goes our
loved ones home ¶
¶ And I will... ¶
¶ I will be waiting ¶
¶ On an ocean ¶
¶ Sweetly, child,
you sing ¶
¶ On an ocean... ¶
Mr. Poole?
Can you hear me?
Mr. Poole,
the blood was real.
Oh, God.
Thank God you're okay.
What are you
doing here?
I've been waiting
for you to wake up
to make sure you're okay.
...Dios mio.
What are you smiling at?
At you.
Why did you not tell me,
Mr. Poole?
Tell you what?
About your secret
you had.
Dawn explained it to me.
What do you mean, "had"?
I need to see a doctor!
You need to get back in your room.
- I need to see a doctor.
- Sir!
Mr. Poole, no no no.
You should not be walking around.
You need to get back to
your room... hey hey!
Hey hey!
Mr. Poole.
Please... okay.
Mr. Poole, just calm down.
Mr. Poole...
No no no no.
No no... don't do that.
Mr. Poole, look at
your arm, Mr. Poole.
- You're bleeding.
- Mr. Poole.
Please.
Mr. Poole.
Wake up.
Mr. Poole?
It's okay.
Wake up.
Millie, did you just
say something to me?
Mommy said
you're not sick anymore.
I'm...
I'm not gonna die?
No, Henry.
You're not.
How can that be?
Well, I told them what
was wrong with you
and they checked.
And you're fine.
You were never sick,
Henry.
So... so I was
never gonna die?
No no, we are all going to die,
just not right now.
And that is the miracle
for you.
after what I've done,
the miracle's gone.
No no no.
Don't worry about that.
It was here for as long
as it needed to be here.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Like everything
and everyone.
I'm glad you're better,
Mr. Poole.
Millie,
I'm glad you're better too.
You know, you should really
get some rest.
Okay?
We'll be outside
if you need us.
Come on, honey.
¶ I promise you will
get old ¶
¶ I promised you
everything ¶
¶ To protect you
wherever you go ¶
¶ I'll give you
this diamond ring ¶
¶ Just promise you
will remember ¶
¶ The promise should
last forever ¶
¶ Right up to
the dying embers ¶
¶ Of the fire that
burns so slow... ¶
- You're back.
- Yep.
I'm home.
What's left of it.
What do you make
of all this?
You're gonna live, Henry.
Yeah.
It's a gift.
Pretty miraculous, huh?
I don't...
I don't know what it is.
I don't know
if it was a mistake.
I don't know.
I don't think that
any of this
was a mistake.
What now?
¶ It's a beautiful
thing to do ¶
¶ Sometimes you just
have to walk away ¶
¶ Remember I do love you ¶
¶ Have courage in
what you say ¶
¶ And promise you will
remember ¶
¶ That promises
last forever ¶
¶ Still after
the dying embers ¶
¶ The fire that
burns so slowly ¶
¶ Sometimes you just
have to walk away ¶
¶ Wishing today
was yesterday ¶
¶ Yes, sometimes you just
have to walk away. ¶