Have you ever had a secret...
... that you couldn't
live with keeping?
And you think about it so much...
... you begin to think
that people can tell your secret...
... just by looking at you?
Hi, this is Janet.
I'm not here right now.
Leave a message.
You have one unheard message.
Hey, sweetie.
It's been a long time.
That's okay, though.
I know we'll talk when you're ready.
You've always done things
at your own speed.
Ever since you were a little baby.
I guess I still think of you that way.
Well, you just give a call when
you're ready. I'll be waiting.
Deleted.
You should stop smoking.
It makes me mysterious.
It makes you all wrinkly,
and your breath smells like ass.
You are such a Girl Scout.
They should give you
the Golden Virgin Merit Badge.
- What's up, Sarah?
- Hey, Chris.
Where's Jillian at?
She's in back.
Hey, J, come on out a sec!
J, I want to talk to you!
Hey, hey!
There's no shouting in here.
What a life.
Isn't there a bag of reefer
someplace with your name on it?
Jillian, would you get out here?
I can't get any work done
with these guys...
Just stand still.
Ooh, Mr. P.
I love a man who takes control.
Seriously, J,
is there anything with two legs
that you wouldn't rub up on?
Yeah, Billy. You.
What do you want, Billy?
Oh, I just came by to, uh,
invite you to a little party
that we're throwing tomorrow night
over at Chris' garage.
You should come, too.
Ooh.
A group grope
at the garage... classy.
Well, you always liked them before.
When I was younger.
I've grown up.
I'm more mature now.
Huh.
Well, something on you
has definitely matured.
Too bad that's not the case
with your little dick.
Ooh!
That's funny.
I never heard you complain.
I didn't have time.
You know what, J?
I just came by to be nice...
...you know, show you
no hard feelings.
But you are being such a bitch.
That's my name.
Don't wear it out.
Seriously, you could be
a little nicer.
You are so gonna get fired.
Sarah?
Your mom called,
and she said that she has to work late
and you should pick up dinner.
Again?
Yeah. Thanks.
To parents...
What?
You want some?
Come on.
Don't be such a pussy.
Leave her alone.
So, do you want to go?
To what?
The garage?
Why?
Oh, my God!
You're into Chris?
Take it from me... you don't
want to hang with those guys.
You do.
I know how to handle them.
So come with me, then.
Protect me.
I can't.
I have a previous engagement.
I thought you were done
with local boys.
Who is it?
My cyber-boyfriend.
Come on. Cut the shit.
Who is it?
Seriously.
We met on the Internet.
- Ser... Jillian?
- What?
You've got to step into the future.
There's like
50 million people doing it.
Besides, the local talent pool
is way too fucking shallow.
- Still...
- "Still" what?
Are you afraid I'm gonna end up
like Janet Melville?
Just vanish one night,
leaving the Goshen soccer moms
without their favorite babysitter?
The Goshen soccer moms
would be psyched if you left town!
Yeah. No shit, right?
It'd be safe
to let their sons out again.
What is this about?
Could we use the computer
at your place?
Well, we can, but Big Brother's
gonna be watching.
You don't have a brother.
I mean my mom put this spyware
on the computer that...
Screw that.
Wait a minute.
I think we have our answer.
No, Jillian. Don't.
Don't be so weird. Don't...
Hey!
Jasper!
Come here.
Time to take one for the team.
Hello, ladies.
We're having
some technical difficulties.
Let me take a look at that.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, you can't log onto this site
with the library computers anymore.
Why not?
Some parents' group
created all this drama over it
and said it was like
a grocery store for child molesters.
You know,
"too much mature content."
But I bet... you have the password.
Well, of course.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Look, I could get fired.
Come on, Jas. Please?
Just this once?
Please?
You can't tell anyone.
There. And please, don't let
anyone see what you're doing.
Thanks, Jas.
Yeah, thanks, Jas.
Oh! Excuse me.
You're so...
You're such a bitch.
No, he doesn't.
What? He so totally does.
Trust me, all right?
I have a knack...
...for men.
Okay, if that's
what you want to call it.
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
Bullshit.
- Oh, my God! Is that you?
- Shh!
Holy shit! That is you!
- Jillian, what are you doing?
- Would you keep it down?
You look like such a slut!
What the fuck?
Would you keep it down?
Are you even wearing anything?
Sort of.
Oh, my God! That's crazy!
Oh, please. This is nothing.
I've seen pictures of guys,
like, totally grabbing their dicks
and chicks like showing their bush.
Dude, why are you doing this?
I told you.
To meet men.
Well...
It looks like it's working.
What is this?
You love to snowboard?
I would if I had the chance.
Besides, men don't care
if you lie to them,
as long as they like
the lie that you're telling.
Oh, my God.
Look at this guy.
The "dumb show"? Yeah, he hits
my inbox like a couple times a week.
And that, seriously,
doesn't freak you out?
All these random guys
can just look at you half-naked.
That's the point.
Besides, it's not
like they know who I am.
And once you spend
enough time on this thing,
you can tell pretty quickly who's
being real and who's just a player.
- Oh, come on.
- Come on. I'm bored.
Want to get out of here?
- No. I have to train.
- Oh.
You want to come?
Um...
Track star...
...porn star.
No way.
Hey, hon.
What a day.
What's for dinner?
From the Point.
Penguin Point.
How was your day today?
It was fine.
Sarah...
...I know I haven't been
around a lot recently,
but as soon as this case is finished,
I'm gonna have more time.
Mmm-hm.
Speaking of which...
I have to finalize my travel plans
for the deposition next week.
You sure you're gonna be okay
staying by yourself?
Mom, I'll be fine.
Your father said he could take you.
Dad's, like, three hours away.
I'm old enough to take care of myself.
I guess that's what scares me.
Oh, you and Chris
make such a cute couple.
What's going on?
Batty Patty Melville strikes again.
So, I was thinking, you know,
just in case she stopped by
to have one of those
things she loved,
one of those...
oh, whatchamacallem... those...
Malteds, Patty.
She liked the malteds.
Yeah, the malteds.
She loved those.
Anyways, I thought maybe if you put
one next to the register when she...
Janet hasn't been in here
in over 5 years.
Yeah.
Anyways, I, I, I just thought
just in case she gets a craving...
...if you put one...
- All right. All right. I'll take it.
But then you have to go!
What's wrong with her?
Losing a child
does things to a person.
If you ask me, the booze did it to her
a long time before that.
Oh, my. I've got to get
back to the bank.
So soon?
Honey, I'll see you tonight.
Here, will you get rid of this thing?
That picture always
gives me the creeps.
La, la, la la!
- Candi! I want to use the computer!
- Good afternoon, Ma'am.
My name is Margaret,
and I'm a certified
lifestyle counselor with Endura Life,
a company dedicated
to enhancing your everyday life
with all-natural herbal products.
According to our database,
you've expressed interest in our
Megaboost Bust Enhancement...
And fuck you, too,
you flat-chested bitch!
We want to use the computer.
How many times do I got to tell you
not to come charging in here making
your noise when I'm on the phone?
We want to use the computer.
And I want a daughter
who can follow a few simple rules,
but don't look like neither one of us
is gonna get what we want.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Hold on there a second, Sunshine.
We've got a little matter
of last month's phone bill to discuss.
Don't you roll your eyes at me.
You went over $300 last month
on text messages.
What in the fucking world do you
have to say that is worth $300?
I've got lots of stuff.
Well, I've got lots to say about that!
Every penny
you spend on that phone
is a penny that don't go
towards our bills.
My disability
only goes so far, Jillian.
Well, then stop watching
all them pay-per-views.
I make my own money!
I pay my own bills! So fuck you!
You ungrateful little bitch!
Hello. Endura Life.
This is certified lifestyle counselor
Margaret speaking.
Did you read my journal, you beast?
I tried,
but your handwriting is for shit!
She's such a fucking bitch.
I hate her.
I hate it here!
Fuck it! I just...
I, I fucking hate it.
It's such a fucking dump.
You want to know a secret?
Is this my old suitcase?
Found it in the trash.
I figured you didn't need it.
What do you need it for?
Getting out.
Going elsewhere.
As in anywhere else but here.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
It sucks here.
What do you know
about sucks, Girl Scout?
You've got a great home.
Your mom's great.
You're set.
How do you get that stuff, anyway?
Same as everyone else.
It's my mom's.
It's "medicinal,"
for her "disability."
Yeah, what exactly is her disability?
It changes a lot.
What is that?
Is that new?
Oh, come on. Let me see.
What is that?
It's like a totally hard-core,
goth-rocker snake.
- I think it's cool as shit.
- Where did you get it?
Did you steal it?
No.
It was a present.
From who?
Oh, come on! Don't give me
any of that "secret admirer" bullshit!
What?
Fuck. Fine, suit yourself.
What's his name?
I call him "Mr. X."
- What?
- Gross!
Well, if I knew all about him, he
wouldn't be a very "secret" admirer.
Do you know anything about him?
He's romantic.
Oh, shit!
What are you girls doing tonight?
- Nothing.
- Really?
Looks like we're doing
a little drinking and...
...smoking contraband.
- It's medicinal.
- What's your disease?
Stupidity?
All right.
Both you girls on your feet.
We're going to the station.
Take it easy, Patrick.
Do I know you?
Not yet.
But I know you, Officer Gunshow.
Nice tattoo.
Now, let me see if I remember...
You only listen to classic rock
'cause Emo's for pussies,
Point Break is your favorite movie,
and you think my body
is so freakin' hot.
Right.
Well, maybe we can
make this problem go away.
Really? What did you have in mind?
An arrangement.
An arrangement?
Exchange a night in you
for a night in jail.
Gross!
I don't think so.
No, I have a better idea.
You forget you ever saw us here,
and I'll forget to tell Kathy
about your "exchange"
when I see her tomorrow.
I'm gonna let you two off
with a warning.
I'll be watching you.
I live for my fans, Pat!
Hi, Mr. Tod.
Oh, hi.
Looking sharp today.
Well, thank you.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Bless you.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
That's, uh, strong perfume
you have on there.
It's Negligence.
Do you like it?
Daddy's allergic to smelly things.
Cigarette smoke, cheap perfume.
Huh, Daddy?
Well, if the Lord had wanted us
to smell like flowers,
he'd have given us petals.
I think we'd better go, don't you?
- Yep. All set.
- Okay.
Where are you going?
Oh, every year we rent a cabin up
at the lake with my uncle's family.
You should come up sometime.
You'd really love it.
Oh, yeah. We have
lots of room and bunk beds. It's nice.
Okay.
Lucky.
You get to be bunkies
with the mole girl.
Yeah, shut up.
Maybe her daddy will tuck you in.
You're twisted.
Oh, man.
This place is so dead.
Will you close up without me?
I want to go get ready.
For what?
Oh, right.
Tonight's the big night, and
that's why you're wearing perfume.
It's his favorite.
Come on.
Come on! Let me go!
Please?
- Okay, fine. Fine.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Oh... And a piece of advice...
don't.
Oh, and one more thing...
What is this for?
So that he'll ask you
to go for a walk.
Spare us some change
to prevent teenage delinquency?
Well, thank you for your support.
Hey, Chris.
Hey.
Hey, Sarah.
What's going on, girl?
- You're looking good tonight!
- Thanks!
Yeah, I almost didn't even come.
Well, I am glad you did.
You can never have enough
hot chicks at a party, right?
Especially around here.
Some of the girls in this town
make the livestock look tempting.
- Have another beer, Jonas.
- Don't mind if I do.
Cheers!
What's that fool doing here?
Hey!
Hey, Ass-per!
What's up?
Did you bring your, uh,
Computer Club buddies with you?
No. No, I didn't.
Did you bring your brain,
Cro-Magnon?
Yeah. Hey, cheers.
Uh, what are you gonna be,
like, a junior this year?
Senior.
Senior. Nice.
So, does that make you, uh, legal?
That depends.
On what?
On what you want to do.
Uh...
...let's go for a walk.
All gone.
I can give you some of mine, but I
never share my beer on the first date.
First date?
Well, I invited you,
you came.
Sounds like a date to me.
You want to know why I invited you?
Because I think you're
the best-looking girl in town.
Come on!
Seriously.
You're much better-looking
than all your friends. No doubt.
Come on!
Your hands are cold.
Then let's warm them up.
Come on!
- You'll like it.
- Stop.
I promise.
Like what?
The party?
It's fuckin' raging, isn't it?
Get out of here, Ass-per.
Hey, hey.
And where are your drinks?
You want to share mine?
Sorry.
This is way too much work
to get laid.
...fucking manipulated!
You like seeing mad in me?
You're fucking evil!
And I'm fucking worth it!
Fuck you!
You know what?
I actually gave a fuck about you!
I actually cared about you!
You're fucking begging me!
J...
You want to be a fucking bitch, huh?
Listen to me.
Look at me, look at me.
Look at me.
What the fuck
are you gonna do, huh?
Oh!
- Asshole!
Ouch. Oh, what was that about?
Hey, why did you run off like that?
Are you okay?
Oh, yeah.
Ugh!
- I'm fine.
Um...
...thank you.
Thank you for doing that.
Yeah, sure. No problem.
Shh, shh, shh.
You are such a Girl Scout.
...a child does things to a person.
Hi. You've reached the bitch.
Leave it at the beep, freaks.
Hey, Sarah.
Tell your friend when she wakes up,
she doesn't get paid for the day
if she doesn't work.
Hi. You've reached the bitch.
Leave it at the beep, freaks.
That's right.
It was the best.
The manufacturers
have decided to make this...
What the hell do you want?
... 7 or 8,000. Not 5 or 6 or 4.
Not even 3,000.
Can you guess how many?
This edition is gonna
be limited to only 2,500.
That's right. Those 2,500...
You looking for Miss Sunshine?
Well, she sure as hell ain't here!
Hasn't been around here
since Friday.
Figured she was holed up
at your place.
Always seemed to prefer it anyways.
So you don't know
where she is at all, then?
Don't know. Don't care.
She sent me a message...
"I'm fine. Don't bother coming
looking for me," or some such shit.
Couldn't even bother to speak
to me herself, the little... bitch.
Mind shutting that door?
You're putting a glare on the tube.
Next time you talk
to that little tramp...
you tell her she better pray
my cable don't get disconnected.
I was talking all this shit...
you know, like, "Oh, I've been
paintballing for, like, seven years"
or whatever.
Got out there, right?
He had no clue what he was doing.
- We fucking lit him up...
- Hey, Billy?
...and he totally deserved it because
he was such a pussy, this guy.
- Hey, Billy?
- Just like "pop, pop, pop, pop"!
Billy.
What?
I want to ask you a question.
Yeah, well, as you can see,
I'm with my customers right now,
so you have to come back
another time.
When was the last time
you saw Jill?
You know, I don't,
I don't really keep track
of the bitches. Sorry.
Oh, and Chris called.
He said he had a really good time
with you on Friday.
You know, if I got
my ass kicked by a girl,
I'd probably want
to forget about it, too.
You guys want to do me a favor
and come back for these tomorrow?
Thanks.
So, I saw her at the party.
So what?
So, nobody's heard from her since.
Yeah, well,
I really couldn't give a shit.
Come to think of it...
...why do you?
- She's my best friend.
Hmm. J doesn't have friends.
She has victims.
Hey, you know, J always
talked a lot of mess about you.
Did you know that?
She said you were gonna bail out
on her the first chance you got.
That is so not true.
You're just pissed
because she dumped you.
Oh, ho, yeah.
For, uh, who was that?
Oh, Mr. X, her imaginary friend?
What?
Do you think you're the only one
she told that little fairy tale to?
Why would she
tell you that stuff, anyway?
To be a bitch.
Look, I couldn't really
begin to understand
how that girl's mind works,
and I don't care to.
She's gone, and I'm glad.
Hey, Darla?
Can I show you something?
What the heck was that?
Jill sent it to me
the night of the party,
and I haven't heard from her since.
And I know that it's not like
she hasn't taken off before,
but something really
doesn't feel right, you know?
I mean, we talk every day.
What about that bus?
Have you ever seen that before?
No.
She is the type, isn't she?
That goes missing?
Like Janet Melville.
But, Darla,
nothing happened to Janet.
They just say that stuff to scare us
away from doing anything fun.
Daddy said she probably ran off with
one of those guys she was sitting for.
He said she had a reputation.
That's why no one
bothered much to look for her.
The mailbox belonging to...
the bitch...
is full and cannot...
- Creepy.
- Right?
Look at this one.
"Don't worry. Everything fine.
Call soon. Jillian."
Yeah, what's so weird about that?
She signs her name.
Jillian hates her name.
She never signs with it.
That really doesn't prove anything.
I mean, someone
could just be messing with you.
What about that bus?
Have you ever seen that?
No. No.
What does this mean?
I don't... I don't know.
Hold on a sec.
What are you doing?
I'm decoding your message.
No, Jasper, we didn't write in code.
Maybe not intentionally.
You know, Mom does this all the time.
She sends me text messages
thinking she's using
the enriched-text function.
The T9 function?
Like, when she really isn't,
so what you end up with
aren't words you can read,
but a jumble
of letters and numbers instead.
So what I would do is write down
the letter combinations...
...and then see
what words it would spell.
What?
Now do you believe me?
You've got
to go to the cops with this.
So?
- "So" what?
- So, what do we do now?
We don't do anything.
But if her parents want to,
they can come on down and fill out
a missing-person's report.
Is her mom aware
that she's missing?
Well, she's the one
you ought to be talking to.
That's it?
What about that message?
It says, "Help me."
This is coincidence,
pure and simple.
You look hard enough, you can
see the Virgin Mary in a tortilla.
Look, you do a job like this
as long as I have,
you come to find
that good police work
is about keeping your eyes open.
Your dog ends up dead.
Ask the neighbor
he kept up all night with his barking.
Money missing from the register...
ask the cashier
with the expensive new shoes.
Cause and effect.
The world ain't as mysterious
as you think it is when you're a kid.
I'm not a kid.
My point is that a girl with a prior
history for running away...
...who tells her friend...
- Her best friend!
Who tells her best friend
that she's thinking on running away,
even shows her the suitcase...
...has probably done just that.
- I know Jill.
This isn't like her.
I've seen this happen
a hundred times before.
Girl gets to be a certain age,
she feels pinched,
like she's outgrown this place,
these people...
You don't outgrow your best friend!
That's all you have to say?
Come on!
You don't think
there's something weird going on?
Weird isn't a crime.
If it were, I'd happily
put every one of you kids in jail.
Well, what about rape?
Isn't sex with a minor
still considered rape?
I mean, what
was going through your head
when you were writing her
all those e-mails?
Better watch your tone, girl.
You're preparing to jump
in the deep end.
You don't have to run away
to the big city to find trouble.
There's plenty right here.
Tell me again why I'm risking
my future full-ride scholarship
to Stanford to do this.
Because the story
that Jillian ran away is bullshit,
and you know it and I know it
and I need you to help me prove it
and you like me.
No shit!
"Durtygrrl" was Jillian?
What?
Everyone checked out her profile.
She's the patron saint
of the Computer Club.
Anyway, what does this have
to do with her going missing?
The night she disappeared, Jill was
supposed to meet this cyber guy,
and I think she met him here.
Oh, if this really is the suspect,
you've got a huge job ahead of you.
Hey, I didn't know, okay?
Besides, you know how many hot girls
you have to hit up on here
before you find one
that will actually add you?
Looks like she was
everybody's friend.
Or nobody's.
Look, she hasn't logged in
since last Friday.
The night of the party.
Hey, check her e-mail!
Maybe her middle name or her pet's.
No, it wouldn't be something obvious.
Her mom was always into her stuff,
so she wouldn't want her reading it.
Where are you going?
... Tri-state area...
Thanks again for being here.
I really appreciate it.
Is that actually what they said?
What is it? That's crazy!
What's wrong with this world?
John, let's get a picture
up there, shall we?
Okay. And the number please.
Thanks. Thank you.
If you see Chelsea out there, folks,
if you see her
or someone who looks like her,
call that number anytime,
day or night.
It's an anonymous number.
But please, report,
whether or not you see her.
Let's just get this little girl home.
She really is a beautiful girl, Kelly.
Folks, if you see Chelsea out there,
you can call that number
anytime, day or night...
Hello?
Hello!
You've reached the bitch.
Leave it at the beep, freaks.
Jill, this is all
getting really weird.
Why won't you just call me back?
If you're in some kind of trouble...
Where are you?
Log on. I think I found it.
Jesus!
I don't think I've gotten 500 messages
my entire life!
You don't have boobs, Jasper.
Can you just look...
...at the messages
she got on Friday?
Yeah, that
whittles it down to, like, 200.
Let me see.
It could be any one of these guys.
Or none of them.
Half these guys are anonymous.
There's not much to go on.
Maybe we can get them
to tell us what the profiles don't.
Can you send them all a message?
Um... write,
"Durtygrrl knows what you are."
Nice... flirtatious, yet threatening.
Just send it.
I don't know.
Do you think it will work?
I mean, if I just did something shady,
I would be way on the D.L.
Maybe.
But you'd have to be curious.
Wouldn't you want to know
if you got away with it?
You know, we really
haven't had much time to talk...
...recently.
I guess I feel a little strange
leaving you by yourself.
I'm a big girl.
I'll be fine.
God damn it!
Honey, can you make sure the
raccoons aren't in the garbage again?
Take it easy, now. Take it easy.
You struggle too much,
you're liable to get hurt.
That's better.
Got a message from your friend.
Seems like she's alive and well.
Now, I don't know
what you think your game is,
but you might
want to keep this in mind...
A man's family is his castle.
Invade his castle,
well, that's an act of war.
Sarah? Everything okay?
Sarah?
I'll be watching you.
Honey, time to get up.
Come on! Get your clothes on.
You have to drive me
to the airport, remember?
I'm surprised
your phone didn't wake you.
It's been beeping all night.
When you guys finish,
I need someone up here on the floor.
Okay.
Well, what do you
want to do with these?
I thought you were
morally opposed to cigarettes.
Daddy says they are a dirty habit.
What's it like
just living with your dad?
It's all right.
It used to be more fun
before Mom died.
What happened?
Complications in childbirth.
With my baby brother.
After that, Dad got really strict,
and now I have lots of rules on...
...the Internet and makeup and stuff.
Yeah.
Oh, heck!
There's my dad. He's coming.
Don't panic. Don't panic.
It's fine.
- Um, spray some of this on.
- No! I can't wear perfume!
Darla, do you want your dad
thinking that you're wearing perfume
or smoking?
Uh, okay, hit me...
Vince!
Darla, ring up your dad, will you?
Take it easy.
- Hi, sweetheart.
- Hi.
Hi, Sarah.
I notice you've been down
to the library quite a bit lately.
Are you in summer school?
No, um... It's like
a personal research project.
- Oh.
- These are $5.30.
- Okay. All right. There you go.
- Thank you.
- Have you heard from your friend?
- My friend?
Yes, the, uh, the young lady
who was working here. Jillian?
No, uh, not yet.
I'm sure she'll turn up.
Thanks.
All right. Bye, honey.
You're not wearing perfume, are you?
Oh, no, um, that's me.
I think I, I think I was standing
next to her when I sprayed it on.
Okay.
All right.
I'll see you later tonight.
Hey, Daddy?
I invited Sarah over to our house
for my birthday.
Good! Good!
Well, we'll have
a good time, won't we?
It'll be a nice party.
Okay.
Thanks for covering for me!
You will come, won't you?
This Sunday.
I'm sorry about telling him
about the Jillian thing.
- I didn't mean anything by it.
- Oh, it's okay.
Um, yeah, of course I'll come.
It'll be really fun.
Any bites?
Are you gonna read all those?
Well, better get started!
Thought you could use a boost.
- Just hook up an I.V.
- What, boring?
Let me give you a sample.
"I know that you're
the girl of my dreams.
Hit me back. Let's hook up."
He misspelled "girl".
It just goes on and on.
It's like that or worse.
Like every cheesy little perv-boy
on the Internet was her friend.
She gets these messages from Peru
and Bangladesh and France.
This girl never left Goshen.
Slide over.
It's dead in here.
I'll take a shift.
Sarah, why are we doing this?
She's my best friend.
Yeah, I know. I know. I get that.
But this...
This is like above
and beyond best friends.
I guess it's because
I know if I got into trouble
I would always
have my mom and dad.
And I think that most people
have somebody who cares
about what happens to them.
And the only person Jill has is me.
I don't know what I'm doing.
I have to open tomorrow.
Yeah. I should lock up.
Oh!
Hey! What did you say
Jillian was calling this guy?
A "Mr. X."
You'd better check this out.
Here. Look.
Look at the name.
- Mr. eXperience?
Mr. X! How did I miss that?
He's still online.
- Do you think this is our guy?
- I'm trying to find that out.
Hey, he's logged off.
What the hell does that mean?
Jillian?
Sarah.
Up here.
Jillian?
Patty?
Oh!
I know what you are, too.
Now...
...how long you say
your friend's been missing?
- A couple of weeks.
- Couple of weeks?
My Janet was gone three years
before I realized.
Me and her old man,
we didn't get on so well...
I'm sure you've heard the stories.
Day doesn't go by
that I don't hate myself
for leaving her
with that son-of-a-bitch.
Her "Daddy."
By the time I faced up to him,
she was gone
and he didn't know where.
Is that when you started
putting up flyers?
Being a lowlife has its advantages.
People underestimate you,
but I'm focused.
I traveled, looked under a lot
of rocks, lived under a few, too.
I've heard some stories.
Like what?
Children... disappearing.
The kind of kids nobody's looking for.
The kind of kids they call "trash."
"Runaway."
Like... Brenda Stills,
Cindy Marker,
Debbie Hope.
Like your Jillian.
Like my Janet.
All lost.
They're all lost.
Sometimes when I...
...feel her slipping away from me,
I call her just to listen
to her voice on the message...
...so I don't forget what she...
...sound like.
Where did you get that?
- It's Jillian's!
- Jillian's?
It's The Serpent himself!
The serpent?
- The devil.
- Patty, I don't know what that means.
You can't see it in the flyers
because the copies are for crap,
but on the original...
...it's clear as day.
Holy shit!
Come on, Jasper. Pick up.
Come on.
Come on, Jasper.
Shit.
Oh, my God!
Jasper!
Look.
Fuck!
He just went in back.
Well, right on schedule.
Every day at 2:00 Billy hits the glue.
Yeah, give him a couple of minutes.
You'll see.
And you know this how?
I collect model trains, all right?
Have you ever tried to buy miniatures
from a stoner? It freaks them out.
You sure it was Billy last night?
The guy has tortured me
my entire life.
I think I can recognize his voice.
Okay. Let's get him.
Um...
... hold on a second.
Agh!
What the fuck?
Ah! Oh!
- Hey, Billy!
- Oh, man!
We just want to ask you
a few questions.
I'm on fucking duty any day...
First question...
when you jumped Jasper last night,
you said, "I know who you are, too."
How did you know
we sent that message?
You tell me.
You're the honor student.
Ugh!
Ow!
Well, I can guess the first part,
that you knew Jillian was Durtygrrl.
It's the connection to Jasper
that I'm missing.
Okay, okay. Okay. Okay.
I knew...
... how you think
you're such a genius, Ass-per.
Nobody's heard from J in weeks.
And all of a sudden
she's sending me messages
with your ugly face
all over her profile.
You'd never make Jay's Top 8.
You'd never even
make her Top 800.
I bet that really
pissed you off, right?
That Jillian had a profile like that
to meet men.
Yeah, and we all know you
do stupid things when you're angry.
Yeah, it pissed me off.
That was the point, wasn't it?
To piss me off.
Jay was always doing stupid shit.
She was always
playing games with me,
telling me how many guys
wanted to fuck her.
I never thought
she was serious, though.
What do you know, Billy?
Now you've got a choice.
Face or nuts?
You can't cover them both.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay. Fuck you.
Okay, I followed her...
...okay, after the party.
I thought it was part of the,
part of the game.
You know, she'd get me all mad,
and then I'd...
...you know.
I followed her downtown.
And then I saw her get into a...
...a car.
She was laughing.
Well, who was driving?
I don't know.
I was too far away and couldn't see.
What kind of car was it?
I don't know!
It was a piece of shit!
It looked like a rental!
You want to know
who she was with?
Ask your friend, the mole girl.
No, no, no. I'm serious.
I mean Darla. Darla. Ask Darla.
She was there.
Bullshit!
Why would Darla care
about what Jillian was doing?
I don't freaking know!
Come on. Let's go.
- Do you believe him?
- I have to.
Billy's too stupid to lie that well.
Well, what do we do now?
I'm going to wish Darla
a happy birthday.
Oh, Sarah. Hello.
Okay. Well, everybody's here.
Let's...
...start the party.
Dear Father, we thank You
for us to be seated
at this table tonight
eating this meal with good friends.
Good friends
who are like family to us.
- Amen.
Amen.
- Should I blow out the candles?
- Sure.
... when God created man and woman
and God graced them in the garden
and things, things were good.
But then ol' Lucifer comes along...
Darla.
I need to ask you a question.
- And I need you to tell me the truth.
- What is it?
Darla?
Darla, honey,
could you feed the dogs?
Their barking's driving me crazy.
I'll take over for you. Go on.
... guard themselves
if they're taking of the fruit
from the Tree of Knowledge.
Now, we all know Lucifer,
just as in the nature of birds
to sing and the bees to make honey,
so it is the nature
of the Devil to tempt...
Glad you were able to come tonight.
She, uh, ahem,
doesn't have a lot of friends.
... for God cannot be tempted,
nor does He kid anyone.
Oh! Sorry.
- I think my necklace is caught.
- You need some help with it?
Uh, sure.
... once desire has taken root...
Just a second.
I used to be pretty good at this.
Let me just...
... I want to read for you
from the Book of...
Oh!
... at the window of my house,
I witnessed among him
a youth who lacked judgment...
What is this?
An unusual piece.
Where did you get that?
- It's a friend's.
- Oh.
Ow!
Damn it!
Tie this!
Come here, would you, and tie this!
Tie it off!
Come on!
Give me it!
Um, I actually need to go.
Come on.
- Is something wrong with your car?
- Yeah, um...
No. It's, uh...
- I can just call my friend.
- Daddy?
You won't tell, will you?
I thought you were allergic.
Well...
...we don't always
love what's good for us.
Poe called it
"the imp of the perverse."
Take your friend, uh, Jillian.
I bet she's the type of girl runnin'
around with all the wrong boys.
The kind of boys that will
get her into trouble, you know,
give her a reputation.
You still searching for her?
No. I kind of gave that up.
She doesn't strike me as the type of
person to stay in one place too long.
You're different.
You have a better sense
of self-preservation.
Kids around here
just don't have that.
They're just brought up
too comfortable,
just too safe.
You still, uh, jog on the River Run?
No. Not so much.
That's a beautiful trail,
the River Run.
You feel like you're
the only person left in the world
when you're out there.
Do you want me
to walk you to the door?
No, thanks.
All right, then.
I'll just wait here
till you get in all right.
# For you're bound to die #
Jillian?
She doesn't want you looking for her!
Who is this?
She's moved on.
She has a new life.
She doesn't need you.
Why can't she tell me that?
She has!
She's happy with her new life.
She wants to be left alone.
Are the others happy, too?
Is Janet Melville happy?
Hello?
Don't tempt me.
I'm not the one who should be afraid.
Nobody here.
Now, what did he want?
Holy shit!
I think he wants us to stop.
He makes a good point!
We can't quit. Not now.
We can't? Watch this.
Hey, look, a tall, fucking psycho just
staked a snake to your basement door!
I quit!
- See? It's easy!
- You don't think I'm scared, too?
I am so fucking scared.
But somebody did this because they're
hiding something really horrible.
And my best friend is a part of it.
So that's why I can't quit, you know.
And that's why you can't quit.
She wasn't my friend.
Yeah, but you're mine.
And I can't do this without you.
All right.
But if I get killed
and lose my scholarship,
you have to explain to my mom.
Deal.
And one other thing...
Can you spend the night tonight?
Well, I don't know.
He wouldn't be the first guy
to swear after hurting himself.
Well, yeah, but it isn't what he said.
It's how he said it, you know?
If you ask me,
living way out here
would make anyone strange.
All right. Give it a try.
Nice!
What did you do?
Nothing.
You scared me.
What are you doing here?
Where's Jillian, Darla?
- What?
- Where's Jillian?
- I don't know.
- Stop lying to me.
Darla, you have her clothes.
You've been dressing up like her.
Where is she?
I found her clothes
in her locker at work.
What about this?
I know she didn't leave this behind.
Darla, please.
Where did you get this?
You left it for me to find.
You wanted me to have it. Why?
If you don't tell me
and something bad happens to her,
it's gonna be your fault.
It was supposed to be
a family vacation!
Have you ever had a secret...
...that you couldn't
live with keeping?
And you think about it so much,
you begin to think
that people can tell your secret
just by looking at you?
And you begin hoping that it's true,
that maybe someone
will tell your secret for you
and you don't have to?
Darla, I need more than that.
It was supposed to be
a family vacation.
But at the last minute,
he had to leave.
Something came up.
I don't know why it made me so mad.
It's the same thing every year.
But this time,
I took my cousin's car back into town,
and I saw him with her.
She was laughing at him.
Darla, did you get this necklace
from your dad?
Darla?
Is someone here with you?
I thought I heard someone talking.
I... I was speaking to myself.
Honey, what's wrong?
There were some things
said at church today.
Sometimes that stuff
can get so depressing.
Come here.
Sometimes those stories are meant
to teach us what's right and wrong,
and they're not always easy to hear.
I know, Daddy.
I'm glad you take them to heart.
Smile.
All right?
Are you sure there's not something
you want to tell me?
No.
Okay.
Darla, please.
The necklace.
Where did you get this necklace?
I found it...
...in the bus.
He keeps things there.
Whoa!
Shit.
- Are you okay?
- Uh-huh.
That's it.
We're not going in there, are we?
I am.
You keep an eye on the house.
Gannon...
... Girlscout.
Janet?
Janet, baby, is that you?
Patty?
Who the hell is this?
It's Sarah.
Sarah, what are you doing
with my baby's phone?
Patty... Patty, listen to me.
You have to call the police,
and you have to tell them
to come to the Tod house right now.
Why the hell would I do that?
Because I found your daughter
and the other missing girls.
What?
- You need to see this.
Please tell me
you didn't find anything...
Yeah. I think we're good.
Shit! Not good!
No, we are definitely not good!
Fuck!
Sarah?
- What are you doing here?
- What did you do with her?
I'm afraid I can't tell you that.
I have to think about Darla.
She's all I got.
What about the families
that you destroyed?
Do you think about them?
Now, let's be reasonable.
You can tell Patty Melville
to be reasonable!
And while you're at it,
you can tell the police,
because they're
gonna be here any second!
No, no, that's not gonna happen.
You can't comprehend
the sacrifices I've made!
They were tempting me!
They were trying
to get me to do things,
disgusting things!
They were trying to hurt my family.
The only thing
destroying your family is you!
Oh!
You!
Oh! Shit!
I thought...
Even though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil for thou art...
What is he doing?
He's praying.
Sarah?
Don't you fucking move!
The Lord knows my heart,
and He will judge me.
Like hell!
You'll never find the bodies.
You'll never know.
Daddy?
Come here.
Come down here.
What do you want?
I want to tell you...
...everything.
Sarah...
Closer.
The last thing she said
was your name.
Now do it.
Do it for me like I did it...
...for your friend.
Just...
...stop my breath.
Sarah.
No.
No, Sarah.
What about Darla?
She's so innocent.
None of us are innocent.
Daddy!
Subtitles by LeapinLar