In ancient times, unexplored regions on maps
would often be given
fearsome legends like "Here Be Dragons".
Unknowns were frightening,
and it gave some
comfort to at least be
able to label the unknown.
Hypothesized dragons seemed
a good enough explanation
for what would otherwise be ungraspable.
With a made-up concept and a few words,
the unknown becomes
simple and satisfying.
Those ancient cartographers
would have felt quite at home today.
De facto practice among most people is
still to give satisfying labels
to quantify and conveniently package the
unknown.
When faced with a phenomenon for which
one does not personally know
a rational explanation, like...
dreaming of your uncle the night before he dies,
it's much easier to accept a simple
explanation like "psychic connection"
than to grasp the complexities
of cognitive phenomena,
confirmation bias, and
the law of large numbers.
Here Be Dragons is so much easier.
The vast majority of the population
accepts dragons - or
their logical equivalents -
as natural components of
our world that should be taken for granted.
Let's have a look at some modern-day dragons.
There is something to be said for listening to the body,
as opposed to sort of imposing medical
information on what you
expect the body to do.
I do believe in ghosts.
I would go see them for
all the way from a cold to a cancer. I mean, I believe
I really believe in healing,
other than our conventional medicine that we have here.
9/11 I think was an attack on our own people,
by our own government.
I'm a really superstitious person,
and I do believe in not
stepping on the cracks and
if a black cat runs in front of your car
I will stop and turn
around and go the other way.
A great deal of research goes into
the development of many pharmaceuticals
and I think the primary research they
do is how to gain the greatest profits.
I think that we have the ability to
sort of sense and feel
sort of energy movements...
Detox tea... it tastes really good and...
...according to the label
it's supposed to
rid your body of impurities
and it seems to work, you know?
You drink it and your sweat smells terrible.
I had Cranosacrial therapy
a therapy where the energy from the
fingers goes into your
head, around your head.
...and I think that organic foods are often grown
by people who care about
their bodies and about the Earth.
I think that a lot of that is embedded in the food.
You can taste it and, in a way, you can
sense the love that was put into it.
I sort of believe in an additional dimension.
Homeopathic medicine is the same as...
it's a watered down version of
a combination of organic foods
and seeking out spiritual truth.
My name is Brian Dunning.
I have a free weekly audio podcast
on the Internet called Skeptoid,
at skeptoid. com, dedicated to
furthering knowledge by exposing the
widespread pseudosciences that infect
popular culture.
Each week I focus on one topic that
you've been hearing about in the news:
an urban legend, a useless
alternative medicine scheme,
a conspiracy theory or whatever the
latest supernatural phenomenon is.
But you can only reach so
many people with a podcast,
and I believe that this
material is important.
So I decided to make this short film
to reach a much broader audience,
and provide this general introduction
to critical analysis of pop phenomena.
Other people have made films to
distribute on the Internet, of course,
but more often than not
they're used to spread paranoid
conspiracy theories or
make political statements.
And whenever you turn on the television,
you find that the science channels
have largely turned into paranormal channels,
the news reports free energy machines
and miraculous crying
statues without critique,
and daytime talk programs have devolved
into promotions for the latest New Age
healing book or
celebrity-endorsed diet.
and that's why I made this film.
You'll often hear me use
the word pseudoscience.
A pseudoscience is an
idea that claims to be real
but in fact is not supported
by any science or any evidence.
Often they'll use
scientific sounding language
to describe how it works.
Usually it's a product that
someone's making money from.
Most complementary and alternative
medical systems are pseudosciences.
Psychic powers and
astrology and feng shui
and telekinesis are all pseudosciences.
People on television who
pretend to detect ghosts
using scientific instruments
are practicing pseudoscience.
Herbal detoxification is a pseudoscience.
Did I just make a whole series of really bold statements?
Not really. All I did was point out that
these ideas are not
supported by any evidence.
They have no rational scientific
hypotheses behind them,
and no experimental data
indicating that they work.
I'm not the one who
made bold statements.
It's the people promoting
these pseudosciences
who need to back up their claims.
But they don't,
and unfortunately they often don't need to:
victims continue
wasting money on worthless frauds.
But it's much more than that.
When we invest our
faith in a pseudoscience,
without questioning its validity,
we're recreating the medieval Dark Ages.
For 500 years, there was essentially
no progress in any scientific
field or in human rights.
Scientific experimentation,
and thus learning, was often illegal.
If we don't test,
if we don't experiment, we don't learn.
We don't progress.
Critical thinking is the
single most important driver
of the advancement of the human race.
The minute we let down our guard
and accept absurd pseudoscientific
claims at face value,
we're giving away our
progress back to the dragons.
Now, let's take a few minutes
and go through some of
the common warning signs.
These are the red flags
that you can watch for
that will help you
identify pseudoscience.
The Appeal to Authority is the
use of authoritative imagery
to lend the appearance of
credibility to a product.
Quite often, this means a picture
of someone in a white lab coat.
Instant credibility!
Other examples of
authority-based marketing gimmicks
include celebrity
endorsements, and mentions of
certifications, colleges,
academies, and institutes.
Good science presents good data.
It never needs to resort to hokey
marketing gimmicks to impress you,
and is almost never presented with a white lab coat.
Beware of any product or idea
that is said to be
based on ancient wisdom.
In ancient times,
very little useful or true information
was known about human anatomy
and many other sciences.
Since those days,
scientists have learned
entire encyclopedias of information
about our universe and our bodies.
It's completely illogical and backwards
to think that the ancients had a better understanding
of anything than modern science.
Their hearts were in the right place,
but in ancient times,
we simply didn't yet
have the tools developed
over the subsequent
centuries of learning.
That's why ancient wisdom
gave us things like the flat Earth theory,
human sacrifice, slavery,
a 30-year average human lifespan,
rain dances, the burning of witches,
and the medical
technique of bloodletting
to rebalance the four
basic bodily humors.
But alternative therapies
based on ancient wisdom
have stood the test of time, haven't they?
Well, it doesn't matter
how long a treatment has been around.
The only criteria medical science
has for a treatment is "Does it work?".
We don’t care whether the ancient Chinese believed it;
we only care about the test results.
When you hear any product advertised
as being based on ancient wisdom,
it's probably because they have
no real evidence to
support their claims.
Ancient wisdom should always be a red flag.
Confirmation bias is what we call our tendency to
remember events that coincide with our beliefs,
and don't take notice events that don't.
This is why you can walk out of
an hour-long session with a psychic
who asked 200 questions, made 300 probing guesses,
of which maybe 10 were close to meaningful
and say "Wow! She knew everything about me!"
Many hospital workers think that
a full moon means a
crazy night in the ER.
They all remember those crazy
nights when there WAS a full moon,
thus confirming the belief,
but they tend to forget the crazy nights
when there wasn't a full moon.
The data shows that
full moon nights are no busier than any other,
but we believe the myth because of confirmation bias.
Many people will often confuse
correlation with causation.
If you happened to take
an herbal supplement
around the same time your
cancer went into remission,
you're likely to think
the supplement caused the remission.
We confuse correlation with causation.
Here's a valid correlation:
People who eat a lot of rice tend to have black hair.
I think we can all come up
with perfectly logical reasons
why these two things happen to go together.
But fortunately, I don't think
too many of us think
one causes the other.
Here's another valid correlation:
Autistic children are often diagnosed
shortly after receiving
their regular vaccinations.
The reason for this correlation is
simply that vaccination age just
happens to be about the same age that
autism symptoms become apparent.
But many people have wrongly drawn a
causal relationship, and look at
all the trouble that's resulted.
Some people are actually preventing
their children from getting vaccinated,
due to a lack of critical thinking,
and irresponsible promotion of alarmism
and misinformation by the media.
Correlation is not necessarily causation.
A red herring is a distraction from
following a logical line of evidence.
In the old days, if a bloodhound was on
your trail, it was believed that
dragging a red herring across your path
would distract the
bloodhound off your scent.
Red herrings, therefore, are irrelevant
pieces of information thrown into an
argument to distract you from the real
topic.
Red herrings are
a favorite of conspiracy theorists.
If you listen to the people who try to
convince us that September 11 was
perpetrated by our own government,
their evidence consists of
virtually nothing but red herrings.
Who crashed the planes
into the buildings?
"Well, Dick Cheney had business
interests in the middle east."
Maybe so, but
who crashed the planes into the buildings?
"Well, the leaseholder had
an insurance policy on the skyscrapers."
Maybe so,
but who crashed the planes into the buildings?
"George Bush's younger brother Marvin
was a principal in a
security company,
and the World Trade Center was
one of their clients. "
Maybe so,
but who crashed the planes into the buildings?
"Brian Dunning visited
the World Trade Center
only two years before they collapsed,
and isn't it interesting that he did
a podcast episode debunking
9/11 conspiracy claims?"
Red herrings.
These are irrelevant distractions that
do not in any way address
the point under discussion,
they merely have the
appearance of relevance
because some of the names
or places are the same.
Be on the lookout for them.
And be the bloodhound that
keeps his nose on the trail;
don't follow the red herring.
While we're on the subject
of conspiracy theorists,
let's talk about their
other favorite device.
It's called "Proof by Verbosity",
and it consists of laying out
huge volumes of information,
more claims and allegations
on more subjects about
more people and ideas
than anyone could ever possibly respond to.
Such a blizzard of information
gives the appearance of being
comprehensive and thoroughly researched.
"If they have all that
amazing amount of evidence,
their claim MUST be true!"
But it's not the quantity
of information that matters,
it's the quality of information.
You can stack cowpies as high as you want;
they won't turn into a bar of gold.
Pointing out that the evil government fluoridates our water supply
does not support the claim
that a particular brand of
magically "ionized water" cures cancer.
Makes no difference whether it's true or not,
it's irrelevant.
Piling on red herring after red herring
will never amount to useful evidence.
Pay attention and soon you'll run into
another claim supported
with Proof By Verbosity.
It might be another conspiracy theory,
it might be an advertisement for
a new type of water with
medicinal properties,
it might be an herbal product
claiming to detoxify your body.
Look at all the wild claims they make,
and take careful note
of how many of them
are actually directly relevant,
and specific enough to be testable.
Notice how it would be impractical
to try and respond individually
to each of these many claims.
It's an endless game of whack-a-mole.
The only way to win?
Don't play.
Virtually every pseudoscientific claim
credits some form of "energy".
Life force, chi, negative energy,
positive energy, the
body's energy fields -
all meaningless nonsense,
which sound plausible
simply because they
throw in a scientific
sounding word: Energy.
New Age practitioners seem to think that
energy is a hovering, glowing cloud
that can go wherever it's needed
and from which adepts can
draw power and feel rejuvenated
or accomplish healings.
Imagine a vaporous creature
from the original Star Trek series,
and you'll have a good idea of what
New Agers think energy is.
Energy is a measurement of
something's ability to perform work.
Given this context,
when spiritualists talk about
your body's energy fields,
they're really saying nothing
that's even remotely meaningful.
Here's a good test.
When you hear the word "energy"
used in a spiritual or paranormal sense,
substitute the phrase
"measurable work capability".
Does the usage still make sense?
There's a good reason why
you don't hear medical
doctors or pharmacists
talking about energy fields:
it's meaningless.
This is usually a really frail excuse
for why mainstream scientists don't
take their claim seriously,
why the product is not
approved by the FDA,
or why scientific journals
won't publish their articles.
You'll often hear this in the form of a
a conspiracy of the medical establishment
to suppress a quack cure because
it's in the interest of the
medical industry to keep you sick.
In fact, any doctor or
pharmaceutical company
that could develop a new cure
would make a fortune;
they'd never suppress it.
The same goes for auto manufacturers
worldwide who are said to be
"suppressing" new efficient engine technologies.
As much as some people with
particular ideological agendas
would like you to believe it,
science never suppresses good science.
As we've seen time and time again,
by no definition can "all natural"
mean that a product is safe or healthy.
I'm standing next to a
gigantic stand of poison oak.
Consider other all-natural compounds
like hemlock, mercury, lead,
toadstools, box jellyfish neurotoxin, asbestos -
not to mention a nearly infinite
number of toxic bacteria and viruses -
E. coli, salmonella, bubonic plague, smallpox.
For those natural compounds
that are not harmful,
synthetic versions have been
engineered in many cases
to make them even safer, more effective,
or able to be produced
in large quantities.
All natural?
Often that's a great thing.
Just as often, it's not.
Some claimants suggest
that it's moral, ethical,
or politically correct to accept their claims,
to redirect your attention from the fact
that they may not be
scientifically sound.
In some cases, such as the
anti-vaccine or
anti-fluoridation activists,
proponents try to use
the court system to force
their beliefs to be adopted
in place of what we've
learned through science.
Generally,
when a theory is scientifically sound,
even if it's brand
new it will eventually
find its way into the
educational curriculum.
Good science is done in the lab -
not in the courts,
not in protest marches,
not in blogs, and not on Oprah.
A political or cultural campaign
to legalize or promote
some product or claim
is a major indicator that it's bogus.
When you learn to
identify these warning signs
and many others like them,
this list is certainly not complete,
you'll find that you start
seeing them everywhere.
And if you're having a
conversation with someone who's
trying to convince you to try some
herbal therapy or New Age meditation,
you can point out these
fallacies in their arguments
and it strips them of the
tools they depend on the most.
Now that we understand what to look for,
let's try applying these skills
to some actual claims out there.
But keep in mind that critical thinking
must not be just about debunking.
There’s no benefit in debunking for its own sake.
Rather, debunking
is only necessary when
pseudoscience stands in the way of progress
and then, it’s critical!
Precognition is where you dream
or imagine or foresee some event
that later comes true, when there's no possible way you could
have known about it.
One of the stories or precognition
you hear most often is of someone
thinking or dreaming about another
person only to find later that
that person died at that same moment.
It sounds like proof positive
that there must have been some psychic connection.
French Physicists Georges Charpak
and Henri Broch made a neat
calculation to show that this
is not only possible, it's inevitable.
On average it should happen to
about 1 in every 150 people
sometime in their lifetime.
Assume that everyone knows
about 10 people who die each year -
either family, acquaintances,
or mostly celebrities
and famous people -
people who might pop into your
thoughts no more than once a year.
There are 105,120
five-minute intervals in a year
in which each of
those 10 people might die.
That gives a 1 in 10,512 chance
that you'll think about someone
during the exact same 5-minute interval in which they happen to die,
in any given year.
That doesn't sound
very probable by itself,
but consider that there are
300 million people in the United States.
This improbable coincidence
must happen to about 28,500 Americans every year.
Only a tiny percentage of those get their stories
on television or in print,
but it's enough to convince
an uncritical layperson that
precognition and psychic connections
must be real.
And when you relax
the criteria even slightly -
you think or dream about someone,
then next time you talk to them
you find that something
unpleasant has happened in their life -
the probability goes up exponentially,
by a factor of millions.
The mathematics behind this
concept universally apply
to all pseudosciences that
depend on extraordinary coincidences
for their support.
The Law of Large Numbers -
the inevitability of improbable events -
proves that the most
bizarre coincidences are merely
mathematical certainties.
Understand the math,
don't turn first to paranormal explanations.
Next, let's consider
complementary and alternative medicine.
You'd think that with a century of
modern medical science behind us,
people would not still be looking
to the ancient state of knowledge
when it comes to their health.
But, unfortunately, it seems
that the more things change,
the more they stay the same.
Just a tiny sampling of
products and techniques still being sold,
still in demand among
21st century Americans,
and with no empirical or plausible
hypothetical foundations:
Reflexology. Homeopathy.
lonized jewelry. Magnet therapy.
Therapeutic touch.
Colonic irrigation. Chiropractic.
Herbal detoxification.
Vitamin megadosing. Psychic healing.
New Age blessings. Detoxifying
footpads and foot baths. Naturopathy.
Aromatherapy. Bioidentical
hormone therapy. Chelation. Iridology...
You'll notice that these
products are not FDA approved.
It's legal to sell anything you want
that's not overtly dangerous,
so long as you don't claim
that it is intended to diagnose,
treat, cure, or prevent any disease or illness.
And that's how billions of dollars
of worthless "supplements"
are sold every year.
They usually claim that their
product has wellness benefits,
but in order to avoid
running afoul of the law,
they leave these claims uselessly vague,
saying that their product
"restores balance", "builds the blood",
"boosts the immune system",
"restores vitality" or some other claim
that's medically meaningless
but that sounds reasonable
to an uncritical layperson.
When a product does have merit
and warrants FDA approval,
this merit is established
through a process called
the randomized controlled trial,
more commonly called a clinical trial.
A clinical trial is a very special process.
It's very different from
the way most alternative products
demonstrate their effectiveness,
which is through
personal testimonials and "studies".
Spend 5 minutes browsing
through Wikipedia, and congratulations,
you've just completed a "study".
Spend 2 minutes rubbing your chin
thoughtfully and looking at the sky,
and you've just completed a "study".
You can now legally sell
your product with the claim
"Studies show that this product
will repolarize your energy fields".
Not good enough for the FDA.
To conduct a randomized controlled trial,
a statistician will select
a sample size large enough
to produce a significant result.
Care must be taken that the
test subjects are properly representative
of the target population,
and not tainted by selection biases
that might skew the results.
The subjects are blinded,
knowing as little as possible about
what's being tested.
They are randomly and blindly
assigned to one of several groups.
There may be a group that will receive the treatment being studied;
a group receiving an established treatment;
and always at least
one control group receiving
a control or placebo treatment.
Test administrators are also blinded
- this is called
double-blinding -
such that they don't know
what group each subject is assigned to,
and whenever possible,
they also don't know
what the treatment is
that they are administering.
Everything is coded to
avoid experimenter bias and to cancel out
any effects like patients
trying to respond
the way they feel the experimenters want them to.
The trial lasts long enough to satisfy
the statisticians and the scientists.
Finally, when the results are
tabulated by a blinded statistician
(this is called triple-blinding),
we get the results.
The cloaks of anonymity
are whisked aside,
and we finally learn for
a statistical certainty
which treatments are
effective, and which are not.
When this process shows significant
benefits for a new treatment,
and the trial can be repeated by other
experimenters and
yields similar results,
then, and only then, do
scientists say that this is
a product that works, and
is supported by evidence.
Let's pick just one alternative
medicine to examine in closer detail.
Homeopathy. This is a
system, invented around 1800,
intended to bring into balance
your four basic bodily humors
- blood, phlegm, yellow
bile, and black bile -
by ingesting a
infinitesimally small amount
of whatever poison caused the imbalance.
Clearly, all of these
fundamental assumptions
homeopathy is based on are now
known to be complete nonsense.
Homeopathy is about extreme dilution.
The greater the dilution, the
more effective the treatment.
A tiny amount of extract, usually
from some herb, is diluted in water,
far past the point of
being chemically pure water.
Early in the dilution process,
they agitate it,
and this is said to give the
water a "spiritual imprint"
of the original compound, and
it can then be diluted infinitely
without losing its
effectiveness. This water is
then sold as is, or is
infused into sugar pills.
Let's look at some of these.
These come in pill form.
These are standard sugar pills,
same as you can get at a pharmacy
- sucrose and lactose, are
the only listed ingredients.
Each pill has supposedly been infused
with a single drop of the diluted water.
Essentially it's a very small hard candy,
without any flavoring.
This one is a 30C dilution of sulphur.
That doesn't mean 1 part
sulphur and 30 parts water;
it means C, or roman numeral
100, to the 30th power,
or 10^60, which is 1
followed by 60 zeroes.
Chemical purity is related
to Avogadro's number, 6x10^23,
so technically this solution
is 37 orders of magnitude
more pure than chemically pure.
This is far more
diluted than one sulphur
atom in all the oceans of the planet.
How likely is it that there
is even a single molecule
of sulphur in this bottle?
Impossible. It's pure sugar.
This whole shelf in the pharmacy,
simply pure sugar,
infused with pure water.
If all of this stuff is actually
unsupported by any good evidence,
that means that it doesn't really work.
But lots of people believe that it does.
Smart people, your
friends and neighbors,
and the professionals you work with.
Let's look at some of the reasons
smart people believe weird things.
First of all, the unexplained is cool!
Who doesn't love a fascinating subject?
Whether it's the Loch Ness Monster
or a black hole at the
center of our galaxy, it's cool!
Or what about a
new meditation technique
that will let you change your
body's physical appearance?
We're all naturally predisposed
to be excited about new weird stuff.
Not even the smartest people you
know are immune to this. It's human.
Second, simple answers are seductive.
You go to your doctor and he tells you
"Gee I'm sorry, but
you have kidney failure,
and you're going to need dialysis
for the rest of your life. "
Your neighbor, who sells an
exotic fruit juice from Brazil says
"Hey no problem, drink this
expensive juice, and you'll be cured. "
Which sounds more attractive?
Is there any surprise that people
who sell nonsense
continue to get customers?
Most pseudosciences sell
easy answers. We all want
to believe that anything
is attainable and easy.
Third, our inquisitive nature
encourages us to focus on possibilities.
Scientific explanations are called theories,
and they always are and always will be
subject to improvement or change
as we make new discoveries.
No matter how solid our
foundation of knowledge is,
and no matter how comprehensively
it's validated by experimentation,
every theory will always
be subject to improvement.
Some people take this
inherent incompleteness
of any theory to its logical extreme.
They latch onto that speck of
possibility that a theory is wrong,
and they give that speck equal or
greater significance than the theory!
"Gravity is just a theory, it could
be wrong; an alternate possibility
is that the Earth is expanding
and pushing against our feet. "
Let Einstein and the others hold up
their end; they know their business.
Give our strongest theories
the respect they are due.
It is rational to accept our best
theories even if you
don't understand them.
It is irrational to reject them for that reason,
or to claim that you know better.
Fourth, people simply lack the tools for critical thinking.
We love the unexplained;
we love easy answers;
we hate complicated stuff.
And nobody's ever given us
tools, like those we talked
about earlier, to tell
science from pseudoscience.
It's no wonder that most people,
no matter how smart they are,
believe in all sorts of
crazy stuff that's not true.
Most of us rely on pop culture
for our exposure to science.
As a result, our knowledge
is generally quite poor,
and that illiteracy is
constantly being reinforced.
What this exposure never seems
to include is healthy skepticism.
Don't expect pop culture to
arm you with the tools you need.
You will need to seek those out,
and then apply them, yourself.
So we know what the red flags are, and
we understand why people ignore them.
What can we do to become better critical
thinkers, and to help
other people do the same?
Number one, Act Locally.
The first thing you can do is to start
actively looking for the red flags.
Keep your eyes and
ears open for claims of
ancient Chinese wisdom,
the body's energy fields,
all-natural ingredients, pictures of
people in lab coats,
and television shows that
uncritically presume the existence
of ghosts or psychic powers.
And then, question it. Research
it. Go online and do a search.
But, beware of your sources.
A Google search for virtually any
pseudoscience is likely
to bring up sites that
are commercially dedicated
to promoting some product or concept,
and you're not
going to find criticism there.
Wikipedia articles about
controversial topics
always have a section on
Criticism or Skepticism.
Follow those links. Read the
references on the bottom of the page.
Your friend recommends acupuncture,
or thinks aliens landed
in Roswell in 1947?
Go and actively search
for scholarly criticism,
then make an informed decision.
Number two, Act Globally.
Take a stand when your
community considers the question
"Should education and
the media be balanced?"
Isn’t it fair and better
to show both sides?
Aren't free speech and academic
freedom of paramount importance?
Well, that depends.
In matters of opinion or philosophy,
where "academic freedom" applies, yes.
In matters of science, absolutely not.
Math class does not
give equal time to 2+2=5.
Geology class does not give
equal time to Flat Earth theories.
Medical school does not give
equal time to bloodletting.
History class does not give
equal time to Holocaust denial.
Pseudoscience should
never be given equal time,
and that's not being
biased or closed-minded.
Facts and fallacies
are not equally valid.
Embrace the information that
stands up to the scrutiny of testing,
not the information
that fails such scrutiny.
You want to make a difference globally?
Do whatever you can to end
this politically correct
fad of giving pseudoscience equal time.
Next time your TV show or
newspaper presents fallacy as fact,
let them know that you don't
support the harm they're doing.
Next time your local school board
wants to replace science with opinion,
help put an end to the
folly of "balanced" science.
It might be very politically correct to
want to accommodate that 5,
but I'm sorry,
the question on the board is 2+2.
There's one final present I'd like to
leave you with, and
that's a reading list.
Like any list it's woefully incomplete,
but I'm going to give you
what I consider the best books
to get anyone started on the
path to critical thinking.
First off, everyone in the
world should read Carl Sagan's classic
"The Demon Haunted World:
Science as a Candle in the Dark. "
This book is the magnum opus of
critical thinking for everyone.
It's easy to read,
approachable,
and every page is fascinating
no matter who you are.
Chapter 12 includes Sagan's
famous Baloney Detection Kit,
quite possibly the handiest Swiss army knife
for understanding our universe.
The second book is Flim Flam,
by James "The Amazing" Randi.
Randi makes no effort to be
everyone's favorite guy like Carl Sagan;
instead he hits
the nail on the head hard.
This book is chock full of no-nonsense
exposure of frauds and rip-offs.
You'll learn how easily
people can be deceived,
and it can
be a big wake-up call.
If you want to be able to
recognize when someone's taking advantage
of you with a
fraudulent product or service,
expertise in the art of Flim Flam
is your first line of defense.
Third, I'm going to recommend a
book that you probably didn't expect,
Mark Twain's The Adventures
of Huckleberry Finn.
Mark Twain was perhaps
the most effective critic
of human ignorance and
folly who ever lived.
Although on its surface it appears
to be an adventure story,
it’s really a collection of quite
shocking exposés of human weaknesses,
driven by superstition, racism,
greed, and ignorance.
If you think James
Randi pulls no punches,
try re-reading Mark
Twain with new eyes.
Finally, I'm going to recommend
my own book,
Skeptoid, Critical
Analysis of Pop Phenomena,
with a foreword by James Randi.
This is 50 short subjects based
on my podcast episodes,
quick and easy analyses of 50 phenomena
that you've always wondered about:
The Amityville Horror,
The Philadelphia Experiment,
organic food myths,
Bigfoot, spirit orbs.
There's something in here
to challenge everyone.
Some people criticize science
by pointing out that it
does not know
everything and doesn't have all the answers.
Obviously, this criticism is true.
Science is all about the fact that we don't know everything.
Science is the learning process.
If we want to improve the world, improve
the human condition, improve technology;
learning, and thus science,
is the essential way forward.
When your hear someone criticize
science because it
doesn't have all the answers, don't
argue with them;
instead point out that that's the central strength of science.
We couldn't be learning more every day
if we presumed to
already know everything.
Some people criticize skepticism
because it doesn't
leave well enough alone.
Many paranormal and alternative beliefs
bring comfort to those who practice them,
and are a positive force in many
peoples' lives.
But happiness and enlightenment
are all around us in our world;
you don't have to turn to
pseudoscience to find them.
And moreover, once we begin investing our faith
in unsubstantiated
or supernatural phenomena,
we are contributing to the
redirection of attention,
influence, and funding
away from technologies and concepts
that have been evidenced to be
beneficial to humanity and to our world.
The choice between pseudoscience and science
is the choice between
stagnation and progress:
progress toward long
life, health, happiness,
a cleaner planet, bountiful
food, knowledge, and peace.
There may indeed be
undiscovered dragons in our world.
But there is also
something we know for a fact:
we haven't
found any dragons yet.
We've looked in a lot of places,
and seen some extraordinary things;
but never yet has science been forced
to throw in the towel
and admit the reality of magic.