TOHO CO., LTD.
A TOHO-KUROSAWA PRODUCTION
HIGH AND LOW
Produced by TOMOYUKI TANAKA
and RYUZO KIKUSHIMA
Written by
HIDEO OGUNI, EIJIRO HISAITA,
RYUZO KIKUSHIMA
and AKIRA KUROSAWA
Cinematography by
ASAKAZU NAKAI and TAKAO SAITO
Music by MASARU SATO
Production Design by YOSHIRO MURAKI
Starring
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
TATSUYA NAKADAI
KYOKO KAGAWA
TATSUYA MIHASHI
ISAO KIMURA, KENJIRO ISHIYAMA
TAKESHI KATO, TAKASHI SHIMURA
JUN TAZAKI
NOBUO NAKAMURA, YUNOSUKE ITO
TSUTOMU YAMAZAKI, MINORU CHIAKI
EIJIRO TONO, YUTAKA SADA
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
So what exactly is it you want?
Look, National Shoes
is in business to make money.
That's right. You should
think twice about this model.
Do you really think
it will boost sales?
Hold on a second.
We're not losing money.
They're great shoes,
but they cost too much.
And they're old-fashioned.
And another thing.
They're too durable.
If shoes don't wear out,
we don't sell any.
Look, Gondo,
women see shoes as accessories,
like hats and handbags.
They flock to stylish designs
at affordable prices.
Exactly.
Our shoes are practical.
Women's hats don't wear long.
Why should their shoes?
You're wrong.
Shoes and hats aren't the same.
A woman wears
a hat on her head,
but shoes carry all her weight.
1 -0 for you.
Listen, you may be happy
with our product line,
but as director I have to ask
why sales have been flat.
That's why we're here.
What are you asking me to do?
Let me be frank.
We are the directors
of National Shoes.
I'm in charge of sales and operations.
You run the factory.
Ishimaru takes care of design.
Kamiya handles marketing.
Kawanishi is your right hand,
and a future executive.
We're all agreed
on what our problem is.
And what might that be?
Our president.
The Old Man's backward.
His dream shoe is an army boot.
But he holds enough stock
to dominate the shareholder meetings.
We can't do a thing.
Show him the sample.
Look at this style, this taste.
It's a sure winner.
Ishimaru,
this is a masterpiece.
And we can make them
at half the cost.
Well?
What would the Old Man say?
We won't let him say anything.
He may own a lot of stock,
but what if we join forces?
He holds 25%.
You three together hold 21 %.
Not enough to vote him out.
Gondo...
we included your holdings
in our calculations.
What do you say?
Will you join us?
With your 13%,
we'd have 34%.
More than enough
to boot the Old Man out.
And who'd be
the new president?
Well, you're certainly
a candidate, but -
But since this plan
was Baba's idea,
he'll be the next president.
You'll be executive director.
Fair enough?
The Old Man may be old-fashioned,
but at least he makes real shoes.
Yours are trash.
Listen to me.
I started as an apprentice
at National Shoes when I was 16.
Aside from time in the army,
I've spent 30 years of my life there.
I know every sound
and smell in that factory.
We've made many shoes.
I remember them all.
They were all good,
durable shoes.
I can't put our name
on garbage like this.
Listen!
This shoe wouldn't last a month.
There's no steel shank.
The insole is cardboard,
glued rather than
properly stitched.
The inner lining is flimsy.
You want money for this?
But the costs -
Costs are eating our profits.
- Business is business!
- I know that!
I love this business
more than I can say.
Shoes are my life.
I won't do slipshod work.
So you'll keep making
the Old Man's army boots?
No. He's wrong too.
He's wrong. We're wrong.
What's left?
I'll make my ideal shoes:
comfortable, durable, yet stylish.
Expensive to make maybe,
but profitable
in the long run.
How romantic.
Only we won't let you.
If we vote with the Old Man,
we can force you out.
Be my guest. The shareholders'
meeting is next month.
Kawanishi,
show the gentlemen the door.
Leaving already?
Pardon us, Mrs. Gondo.
Why isn't my husband
seeing you out?
If you'll excuse us.
What just happened?
Nothing.
It certainly didn't look
that way.
Don't worry.
You wouldn't understand.
It's business.
You always say that
to keep me quiet.
What's he got up his sleeve?
You're his right-hand man.
You must know his plan.
The son of a bitch, kicking us out!
Must be pretty sure of himself.
What's he up to?
Why didn't you
ask him yourself?
Don't be a wiseass.
You may not know his scheme,
but help us stop him
and we'll make you a director.
Please don't tempt me.
You want to be his flunky forever?
Think it over.
Jun, that's enough!
They're furious.
Will we be all right?
Wait and see.
A new round of feuding?
Sure looks like it.
They want to kick me out,
but I've taken measures.
They'd have to be pretty serious.
What measures?
I don't want to say
until everything's in place.
Then I'll do them all in.
Jun really takes after you.
You both love blood sport.
Jun!
Oh, Shinichi, it's you.
- I'm the sheriff this time.
Jun, is it your turn
to be the outlaw?
Well, don't run.
Hide and then ambush the sheriff.
A man must kill or be killed.
Now go. And don't lose.
- You get worse by the day.
- What do you mean?
Your attitude.
Success isn't worth
losing your humanity.
A woman can't understand.
This isn't about wanting
to become president.
I just want
to make shoes my way.
Yes, it is.
Osaka Hotel?
Did you call Osaka?
One moment.
Hello?
Room 310, please.
Gondo calling.
Hello. It's me.
How'd it go? All settled?
How much?
Within my limit?
Great work!
Good. Settle the deal.
And quickly.
Call me again when it's done.
I'll send the deposit tonight.
I'm counting on you.
I want you to go to Osaka.
Book a flight.
Use the phone upstairs.
I'm waiting for a call.
Is everything all right?
Something about this
scares me.
Hello. Yes, it's me.
It's all set?
Great, thanks.
Just a moment.
Well?
10:00 p.m. flight.
Kawanishi's off at 10:00
with a check for 50 million.
Time for a toast.
I kept you two in the dark,
but now I can talk about it.
My share isn't 13%.
I've bought 15% more
over the last three years,
and just now on the phone,
I bought another 19%.
That's 47%.
Even with the Old Man,
they only have 46%.
It was a risky move,
but National Shoes is mine.
But where did you get
that kind of money?
I borrowed against everything,
including this house.
It was hard work
raising 50 million.
One yen less
and Osaka would have refused.
Now I don't even own
the clothes on my back.
I've bet my entire fortune.
But wait a minute.
This is just
the deposit, isn't it?
That's usually one third.
Where's the other 100 million?
If I gain control of the company,
I'll get the rest.
In shock?
Have a drink.
Excuse me.
Have you seen my boy, Shinichi?
He and Jun are outside.
What is it?
I brought this for him.
I'll call Jun.
Aoki, drive Kawanishi
to the airport.
My flight's at 10:00.
Yes, this is Gondo.
What?
You've kidnapped my son?
What kind of joke is this?
It's not a joke.
Listen.
I have your son.
If you do as I say,
I'll let him live.
Get 30 million yen.
Thirty million?
No consecutive serial numbers.
- One thousand 10,000-yen notes -
- Wait a second!
- One thousand -
- 10,000-yen notes.
Three thousand 5,000-yen notes,
and five thousand 1,000-yen notes.
Total: 30 million yen.
Thirty million!
Have it ready by tomorrow.
I'll have more details then.
If you love your son,
don't call the police.
No, of course not.
So long, Mr. Gondo.
Thirty million yen?
Just hurry and pay it!
Get Jun back!
Calm down!
I'll get him back,
no matter what it costs.
I can raise more money later.
I'll call the police.
Fool!
You'll put Jun in danger.
- Kingo!
- Don't worry! It'll be all right!
Mom, did you call me?
Jun!
What's the matter, Mom?
What's going on?
What kind of sick joke is this?
Jun, where's Shinichi?
Don't know. I hid like you said,
but he never came.
Some sheriff!
Wait, Shinichi was wearing
Jun's outfit.
Even I got them mixed up.
Shinichi!
Call the police.
No, you can't!
What'll happen to Shinichi?
The kidnapper will realize
he has the wrong kid.
A chauffeur can't pay a ransom.
He'll let him go.
But I won't let him
get away with this.
- Is that the police?
- No.
A department store delivery.
Odd at this hour.
What the hell's
taking them so long?
Aoki, don't worry yourself
to death.
Any way you look at it,
Shinichi has to be safe.
Kingo, it's the police.
Madam, would you mind
closing all the drapes?
I'm Chief Inspector Tokura.
From the streets below,
if he has a telescope,
the kidnapper can see
this entire room.
Any other phones in the house?
- One upstairs.
- Are they listed?
- Just this one.
The phone's over there, guys.
We'll install a listening device
to record his calls.
But, Inspector,
I doubt he'll call again
when he realizes
he has the wrong child.
He may still think
he has your son.
Broadcast the mistake
on radio and TV.
If we do, he'll know
you contacted us.
So?
He warned you
he'd kill the boy if you did.
That's when he thought
it was my son.
He has to return a child
whose father can't pay.
You may think so,
but he may not.
Kidnapping cases are difficult.
The hostage is his protection.
On our way here
the chief told us,
"Save the child first,
then catch the kidnapper."
We must be especially careful
in this case.
The highest ransom ever demanded
was two million,
with most in the range
of 200,000 to 300,000.
Thirty million
is an extraordinary sum.
The kidnapper's extreme.
He may be mentally disturbed.
Are you the boy's father?
He's a widower.
It's his only child too.
Will you get my boy back?
We'll do everything we can.
What will you do next?
Wait for his next move.
It's all we can do.
I know how hard
it is just to wait,
but it's safest for the boy.
All set.
Have the phone company trace
all incoming calls.
This way, please.
- Where's your son, Mrs. Gondo?
- In the dining room.
Taguchi, ask him everything
about the kidnapping.
No, wait.
Nakao, you do it.
Taguchi might frighten the boy.
Taguchi,
you talk to the father.
Do you have a recent picture?
Yes. I'll get it.
I should drive Mr. Kawanishi
to the airport soon.
You're in no shape to drive.
Kawanishi, take a cab.
Wait. It may be
the kidnapper.
Upstairs phone.
Keep him talking.
We may be able to trace him.
Go ahead.
Hello. Gondo speaking.
I got the wrong boy.
But before you start
celebrating, listen:
I don't care whose boy it is.
You're still paying.
You can't be serious.
Why me?
Don't ask questions.
It's simple:
Pay the 30 million or the boy dies.
This is absurd!
Exactly. It's absurd.
Taking the wrong boy
was a lucky break.
Did you know, Mr. Gondo,
that it's only extortion
when you threaten
a person or his kin?
In other words,
this doesn't count.
But you have to pay anyway.
You're a fool to pay,
but pay you must.
Who says I'll pay?
I absolutely will not!
You will.
You won't let him die.
You don't have the guts, Mr. Gondo.
He's a monster.
Smartest crook I ever saw.
Kidnap any child off the street,
then pick a millionaire to squeeze.
And he's right:
It wouldn't be extortion,
or even kidnapping for ransom.
Just simple kidnapping.
He'd get five years at most.
This is no joke.
I won't let him
laugh at me like this.
Inspector, he's not just
after my money.
He wants to humiliate me,
see me suffer,
make me throw away
my hard-earned money!
He wants to make
a laughingstock out of me.
I'll say this loud and clear:
I won't let him. I won't pay.
I'll spell it out next time he calls.
No ransom! Never!
Ow! Mom, that hurts.
Put Jun to bed.
I'm not sleepy.
I'll wait for Shinichi.
He understands very well
what's happened.
He feels responsible for it.
I feel the same way.
No one's responsible.
The man is a maniac!
But Shinichi was kidnapped
in your son's place. That's why I -
So you think
he should pay the ransom?
You know the position
Mr. Gondo is in.
But he was willing
to pay for his own son.
He said he could raise
more money later.
How? From where?
He's mortgaged everything.
He couldn't raise more money
to save his own life.
Giving 30 million
to a madman -
That's enough!
- Let's go to bed.
- But I -
You don't have to sleep.
Just go to your room.
Inspector.
Can you guarantee
the boy's safety if Mr. Gondo pays?
The boy may already be dead,
or he may be killed afterwards.
Then what's the sense
in paying?
That's true.
But if he's alive,
paying may make the difference.
We can only hope it does.
And what would
the kidnapper do if he isn't paid?
Would he actually kill the boy?
He seems intelligent,
from the way he talks.
Killing a child
is a capital offense.
I doubt he'd risk death
just because he wasn't paid.
But as Mr. Gondo pointed out,
he seems obsessed.
His cynical logic
betrays a sick mind.
We must believe
he'll carry it through:
If he's paid,
he'll return the child.
If not, I'm afraid
he'll kill the child as threatened.
This is a vicious case.
I'll ask the chief to deploy
the special investigation unit.
See what you can find out here.
Mr. Gondo, please alert us
before answering this phone.
What about me?
Am I still going to Osaka?
If I am, I'd better hurry.
Why are you hesitating?
What's there to think about?
Pay the ransom and we're ruined.
It's that simple.
Go.
I'm going,
no matter who's calling.
All right, go.
Kawanishi, wait!
Inspector!
Keep him talking
longer this time.
Upstairs phone, okay?
Hello. This is Gondo.
The boy's fine.
I'll let him talk to you.
Daddy? Are you there?
Shinichi!
Whether he lives or dies
depends on you.
Think it over carefully.
Good night, Mr. Gondo.
He got away again.
Please save my son!
Asking you to pay
that kind of money -
Until I heard his voice,
I just couldn't
bring myself to do it.
But now I'm begging you.
Once he's safe, the police
will get your money back.
If you could just lend it
to me for now,
I'll do everything you want
until the day I die.
I'll make Shinichi work too.
Anything you want.
Stop it! Get up!
Damn it, stand up!
Please save Shinichi!
Stand up!
Please, stop it!
I want to pay, but I can't.
You don't understand.
I'm going, all right?
Wait.
Get up.
Please get up.
He won't let your son die.
I'll ask on your behalf.
Put your mind at ease.
It'll be all right.
Isn't Shinichi back yet?
Postpone Osaka until tomorrow.
I said we'll wait!
Then I'll return this
for the time being.
Excuse me. I'm tired.
Pardon me, but could you
keep the curtains closed?
Oh, sorry.
You all slept here?
No, the Bos'n and I -
Bos'n?
Bos'n is head
of the detective squad.
In Yokohama, much of our work
is connected with the harbor.
"Bos'n" fits him perfectly.
He's a real slave driver.
He dragged me out
all last night.
You're the one
who dragged me out.
Sneaking over walls,
hiding until morning, not knowing
if we're detectives or thieves.
Last night the chief
set up a special investigation.
We can use the whole
prefectural police force.
Also, though the kidnapper
claims it isn't extortion,
he's driven you into a corner.
He's exploiting your suffering,
and that's "kidnapping for gain."
It's a maximum
of 15 years' imprisonment.
His being in prison
won't stop me from going under.
His deadline is today.
I thought it over all night.
This is my decision.
The boy's father wants me
to lend him the money.
He says once his boy's safe,
you'll get my money back.
But even if you guarantee me that,
I won't pay the ransom.
I'd get it back too late.
Without that money now,
I'll lose everything.
Please understand me.
This is who I am.
My work is a part of me.
I'd be as good as dead
without it.
You may think it's heartless,
but I refuse to pay.
That's not true.
I know he'll pay.
Just stop it.
I won't - no, I can't pay,
no matter what you say.
I told you why last night,
yet still you persist.
Listen: You know
what'll happen if I pay?
I'll be penniless - no, worse.
I'll be saddled with debt
and forced out of the firm.
You'll be all right.
You can start over.
You don't know
the first thing about poverty.
From the day you were born
you've had big houses and cars,
servants tending
to your every whim.
Your whole life has been luxury.
Maybe I could start over,
but you - never!
Yes, I could.
I don't care about luxury.
It's all you've ever known.
That's why you can tell me
to pay 30 million yen.
It means nothing to you.
You're spoiled.
It's not that.
Don't you feel anything
for poor Aoki?
Of course! It takes all my strength
not to cave in to his begging.
I'd pay in a second
if I could.
But I can't sacrifice
everything for him.
There's you, and Jun,
and my own survival.
This is ridiculous!
There are plenty of people
richer than I am. Why me?
And at a time like this!
It would be suicide to pay.
Why should I?
I know.
But there's no other choice.
Aoki has nobody
to ask but you.
I'm asking too.
So is Jun.
Enough! Nobody has the right
to ask this of me.
That's final.
I'm not paying any ransom.
Kawanishi, you're just in time.
Take this check
and get to Osaka.
Well, I've been thinking it over.
- What?
- About that check.
Whether I should take it or not.
You said there was nothing
to think about!
Well, I was confused.
But just hear me out.
If I go to Osaka
and close this deal,
you'll take over
National Shoes.
But you'd be hated by the public
for sacrificing a child!
You'd be ruined.
No one would buy your shoes.
That's enough!
You're not paid to think!
Stop arguing and go.
Please think this through.
Think how
Mrs. Gondo must feel.
After all, wasn't her dowry
the basis of your fortune?
She has a say in this,
and she wants you to pay.
And destroy myself?
I know how much
this money means to you.
But a human life means more.
We're talking
about a helpless child -
"Human life"?
"Helpless child"?
I've never heard such words
from your lips.
What happened
to the cold-blooded businessman?
When were you reborn?
What happened
after you left last night?
Nothing happened. I just. . .
If my takeover succeeds,
you'll be made a director.
Knowing that, you were ready
to go last night,
arguing with Reiko, bad-mouthing
the cops, even pestering me.
Yet today -
You want to sabotage
my takeover, don't you?
No. I just -
Answer me! If I pay the ransom,
the deal goes up in smoke.
That's what you want!
What are you up to?
Shall I answer for you?
If this deal fails, so do I,
and three men stand to celebrate.
Bastard, you sold me out
to those three, didn't you?
Yes.
- You told them about Osaka?
- Everything.
Worthless scum!
Maybe I am.
But let me have my say.
You weakened last night -
enough to pay the ransom.
What would happen to me then?
If I stake my life on you, I have nothing.
You'd be selling out
your loyal servant of 10 years.
What I did was self-defense.
Get out!
I'll go.
But you'll be the next
to hear those very words.
Baba and the Old Man
are talking as we speak.
But I still have this,
so I can still kick you all out.
I wonder.
Maybe the kidnapper's right.
You don't have the guts to let him die.
Get out!
Mr. Gondo.
I know it's late
to be saying this. . .
but you have the right
to protect your own livelihood.
It's our duty to help you.
We want to save the child,
but not by sacrificing you.
Still, we hope
you'll do one thing:
When the kidnapper calls,
say you'll pay.
You only have
to say the words.
Just ask him when and where.
We'll take it from there.
Forgive me, boss.
I didn't realize how unreasonable
my request was.
Please don't worry
about Shinichi.
I think the kidnapper
was just bluffing.
No human being
could kill an innocent child.
Anyway, Shinichi
is a clever boy.
I'm sure he'll find
a chance to escape.
Where's Mr. Gondo?
Mr. Gondo!
Phone! Hurry!
Hello. This is Gondo.
Mr. Gondo, you're not
up to any tricks, are you?
What do you mean?
Curtains closed in broad daylight.
A first time.
- You can see us?
- Quite well.
You're on a hilltop.
It's hot as hell down here.
An inferno.
Feels like 105 degrees.
But you must be nice and cool
with your air-conditioning.
I understand the closed windows,
but why the drapes?
What are you up to?
Nothing.
Nothing?
People always say that
when they're up to something.
Then I'll open the drapes
and prove it to you.
Good. I can see you now.
Your wife, the chauffeur.
Just the three of you?
That's right.
Well, then, let's continue.
Have you decided to pay,
Mr. Gondo?
I have no choice.
I'll pay.
And is the money ready?
It will be by evening.
But only if the boy's unharmed.
- You heard him.
- No, I want to see him.
- And if I refuse?
- I won't pay. That's final.
Sounds fishy.
Well, I'll think it over,
Mr. Gondo.
Stay there!
Be careful!
The kidnapper's watching.
Damn.
Just a little longer
and I could've traced it.
Thank you, Mr. Gondo.
By saying you'd pay,
you bought us more time.
Your demand was also
very helpful.
If he accepts it,
we can formulate a plan.
Bank of Tokyo?
This is Gondo of National Shoes.
The branch manager, please.
Yes, hello.
This is short notice.
Send over 30 million yen in cash.
No new bills,
and no consecutive numbers.
Sorry to trouble you,
but I need
one thousand 10,000 notes,
three thousand 5,000 notes,
and five thousand 1,000 notes.
Yes, right away.
Thank you.
That's enough.
Don't say anything.
I don't know what to say.
Enough.
Leave me alone.
- What is it?
- Mom's crying.
Hello. This is Gondo.
Mr. Gondo, you're not
up to any tricks, are you?
I hear a coin dropping.
Check all the pay phones
in this area.
The kidnapper's right.
One case holds 15 million yen.
What a sight, eh?
Hello. This is Gondo.
Got the money?
Yes, but -
I accept your condition.
You'll see the boy first.
- When?
- Tomorrow.
We'll swap the boy
for the money.
Where?
Calm down and listen carefully.
Get two briefcases,
less than 2.75 inches thick.
The money should just barely fit.
Close them tight but don't lock them:
I want ready access.
Take them on tomorrow's
Kodama No. 2 express train.
Understood? That's all.
- Where am I going?
Get on and you'll see,
Mr. Gondo.
Bos'n,
I doubt he's dumb enough
to make the exchange on the train.
Will he try a station?
That's risky, too.
I wouldn't try it if I were him.
Two briefcases
under 2.75 inches thick.
What's that all about?
"Get on and you'll see."
Shit.
By the way, Bos'n...
where should we hide these
in the cases?
That's not a job for amateurs.
I'll call a specialist.
What do you need?
We want to find him
with these briefcases.
We intentionally chose
an unusual style.
They're so conspicuous,
he'll have to get rid of them.
He'll have to bury them,
sink them, or burn them.
If the powder
in this capsule gets wet,
it gives off
a putrid smell.
The powder in this pouch
emits a pink smoke when burnt.
It's not much to go on,
but it just might
give us a lead.
Reiko!
Would you find
my old tool kit for me?
How long to record
just the 1,000-yen notes?
At ten a minute,
that's 5,000 in 500 minutes.
That's eight hours, 20 minutes.
Ten hours with breaks.
Isn’t that a waste of time?
I never notice serial numbers.
We can't neglect
any possible means of finding him.
When the boy's back safely,
I'll flush that rat out.
I'd burn him alive.
Fifteen years maximum?
To hell with that!
The capsule should go here,
and the pouch goes there.
In the old days,
shoemakers made cases too.
My training as an apprentice
comes in handy once again.
It's like I'm starting over
already.
He's really something.
I waste no love on the rich,
since I grew up poor.
At first I despised him,
but now. . .
Excuse me.
THE BOY'S NOT ON THE TRAIN
This isn't a pleasure trip.
Railway Telephone Service
paging Mr. Kingo Gondo
of National Shoes.
Please take your call
in the buffet car phone booth.
- It's the kidnapper.
- What do we do?
The next stop is Atami.
Will they do the switch there?
Go get some coffee.
I'm Mr. Gondo.
Coffee.
We just passed Kozu.
Perfect.
Listen carefully.
You'll cross
the Sakawa River in two minutes.
You'll see him
at the foot of the bridge.
Coffee.
The boy's at the foot
of the next bridge.
I'm to toss the money
at the other side.
These windows don't open.
He said the washroom windows
open 2.75 inches.
Son of a bitch!
That explains it!
There's no stop until Atami.
He'll get away clean.
The bastard thought of everything.
A real monster.
An emergency stop
would endanger the boy.
He's got us from every angle.
There must be two of them:
one with the kid, one to grab the money.
We'll get a glimpse.
Which side is the boy on?
- The left.
- You'll toss the cases from here?
Yes, from the washroom window.
We'll confirm it's the boy
from here.
You all split up
to take pictures.
Still photos on the left,
8mm in the front and rear.
The bridge is coming up.
Get a good look at the boy.
I only know him from photos.
It could be a switch.
Don't worry. I'm trading
my life for that boy.
I won't make a mistake.
Shinichi!
Are you sure?
We can't rest
until we find that kidnapper.
For Mr. Gondo's sake,
be bloodhounds.
Can you see
inside the living room?
This is the best view so far.
He may live around here.
But would he use a phone
this close to home?
Let's try the next one.
The kidnapper's right.
That house gets on your nerves.
As if it's looking down at us.
CLEVER KIDNAPPER
USES EXPRESS TRAIN
RANSOM FOR DRIVER'S SON
IS 30 MILLION YEN
SHOE EXEC THROWS ENTIRE
FORTUNE OUT THE WINDOW
ALL POLICE UNITS MOBILIZED
Police say money was not
the kidnapper's only motive.
His phone calls
have a taunting tone,
suggesting extraordinary
hatred for Mr. Gondo.
The kidnapper wanted
not only to steal money,
but also to torment and ridicule
Mr. Gondo in the process.
Yet Gondo's sacrifice
has not gone unnoticed.
Words of sympathy have grown
into national acclaim for him.
How will the kidnapper
react to this?
If he's listening,
I'll tell him this:
Mr. Gondo is having
the last laugh!
We learned from Shinichi
that a woman held him.
Unfortunately, hats hid the faces
of both the man and the woman,
making identification impossible.
But their movements
may provide important clues.
Watch carefully.
Well?
Any idea who they may be?
Don't hesitate to say
if you have any idea.
Delivery boys, milkmen,
gardeners,
junk collectors, salesmen.
Try to remember everyone
who's come through here.
This kind of thing
might come to you suddenly.
Take your time.
Bos'n, the 8mm films are well shot,
but not much help yet.
The figure is blurred in the photos,
but they're helpful.
Look at this.
This is the accomplice.
See this tiny figure here?
That's a farmer leading a cow.
He gave us
some useful information.
He saw a man with two briefcases
run into the shadows here
and then drive off.
We checked the area
and found skid marks.
It seems he ran
into a concrete railing,
leaving behind paint scrapings.
By having them checked,
we determined the following:
The car was
a gray '59 Toyopet Crown.
This is the car you rode in,
isn't it?
Yes.
- Can we go?
- Sure.
Shinichi, try harder
to remember everything.
You were at a house with a view
of the sea and Mt. Fuji?
What road did the car take
from there to the river?
- I don't remember.
- Try harder, damn it!
What did you see
from the car window?
Lots of things.
That's not good enough!
I'm asking you to try harder.
What did you see?
- I can't -
- Shinichi!
Aoki, stop this.
When you remember, kiddo,
come tell us, okay?
Mr. Aoki,
we know how you feel.
We feel the same way.
We're desperate to capture
the culprit and return the money.
We owe Mr. Gondo
at least that much.
Guests, sir.
Anyway, Mr. Aoki,
go easier on the boy.
Excuse me.
Shinichi's already recalled
some key information.
They covered his face
with gauze soaked in ether.
He went to a house with a view
of Mt. Fuji and the sea.
Well, that's all for today.
Oh, one more thing.
We've received
a mountain of mail.
Mr. Gondo went through
a horrible experience,
but everyone admires him.
That lifts
our spirits a bit too.
You're a hero, and the public
is very sympathetic,
but what about
National Shoes?
A battle for ownership
won't be pretty.
We hear your position is shaky.
Is that true?
Frankly, we're worried.
Sympathy costs nothing,
but we've invested real money.
We have no sympathy for you.
As your principal creditors,
we've reached
a decision together.
We're returning the interest
you sent yesterday
to postpone
paying us the principal.
Pay us in full
when it falls due.
If you don't, we'll seize
your collateral property.
Public opinion aside, Mr. Gondo,
you can't pay a kidnapper
and leave us footing the bill.
The Gondo residence is visible
from Nishi Ward
and parts of Naka Ward.
There are some places
where changes in elevation,
trees, or large structures
block the view.
Those locations
are shown with hatch lines.
The Gondo living room
can be seen clearly
with an ordinary telescope
from any point within this circle.
It can also be seen
from the inside
of seven phone booths
within this perimeter.
Those are indicated
by these X marks.
Three of those seven
allow a good view
even when using a telescope
while on the phone.
Those are indicated
by these circled X marks.
We believe the suspect used
one of these phones.
He also complained
that it was very hot.
He called
a little before 9:00 a.m.
We checked which booths receive
the most direct sunlight at that hour.
Of these three,
this one is shaded
in the morning.
So it is safe to assume
that the suspect used
one of the other two.
The recorded
conversations suggest
he was looking through
the telescope while on the phone.
So we can narrow down
his place of residence
to this vicinity.
Judging from his voice,
he's a young male.
But with the boy he wore
a mask and dark glasses.
Not much to go on there.
Next we have a report
on the railway phone.
You can only call the express train
from Tokyo, Osaka or Nagoya.
The call is relayed by microwave,
but with a long delay,
so it was easy to trace
the origin of the call.
Yurakucho 2-6,
Chiyoda Ward, Tokyo.
A tobacco shop
near the train station.
But the old lady at the shop
had bad eyes
and even worse hearing.
It was hopeless.
We asked around
at all the shops in the vicinity,
but no one could recall
a man placing a call
at the tobacco shop at that hour.
Next.
The boy mentioned
Mt. Fuji and the sea.
Any leads?
We had him draw a picture.
The call with the boy
was a direct-dial local call.
Places with a view
of Mt. Fuji and the sea
where you can call Yokohama
without an operator
include Zushi, Fujisawa,
Chigasaki and part of Kamakura.
The sun in the picture
appears to be setting.
This appears
all along the coast.
Next, the ether.
It's not easy
to trace back to a source.
Pharmacies don't carry it.
Hospitals and larger clinics
buy it wholesale.
There is also industrial-grade ether,
used in welding.
So it's too early
to say the suspect
is a doctor, pharmacist,
or medical student.
Industrial-grade ether is used
in building ships, railroad cars
and automobiles,
as well as in small iron works
and repair shops.
That's all.
Next, the car.
The farmer said it had white plates,
so it's privately owned.
Crooks generally
don't use a family car,
so I checked
on stolen vehicles.
This month,
18 Toyopets were stolen.
However, 12 were recovered
before the kidnapping.
That leaves six. Only one is gray,
like our paint sample.
It was stolen
the day before the kidnapping.
The license number...
is Kanagawa SO3059.
Since the plates
may have been changed,
Vehicle Theft is checking
all gray '59 Toyopets on the road.
That's all.
Good.
Next, the 1000-yen notes.
We compiled a list
of serial numbers
for tobacco shops, cafeterias,
cafés and movie theaters.
Goodwill for Mr. Gondo
makes the owners eager to help,
but none of the notes
have turned up yet.
Next, reports from the public.
We've received
1,305 reports of sightings,
only a few of which
are from cranks.
All reported seeing
men with boys of Shinichi's age,
but many of the sightings
occurred before he was kidnapped
or after he was recovered.
And he was seen
at the same time
in places far removed
from each other.
We're trying
to corroborate the reports.
One promising report
we received today
was from a turnpike
toll collector.
About 7:00 p.m.
the night of the kidnapping,
a man in dark glasses
drove up.
A boy was sleeping
under a blanket in the back seat.
The car was dark.
He couldn't see the boy's face,
but he did notice a toy rifle
and a cowboy hat.
The man was headed
toward Fujisawa.
This is our best lead so far.
We're now reexamining
all reports from that area.
Next, the railway connection.
The Kodama train's infrastructure
is not that different
from other express trains.
The suspect is very familiar
with the system,
but that doesn't necessarily mean
that he's a railroad man.
We nonetheless ran a check
on all employees
with connections
to express trains
who were absent
during the kidnapping
or had quit just prior to it,
and those living in view
of the Gondo home.
There were very few.
I'll have a final report tomorrow.
That's all.
Next, grudges or other motives.
I met today with
the National Shoes executives.
What a bunch of assholes.
A grudge?
Inspector, you think
we were behind the kidnapping?
Think we set it all up
to get rid of Gondo?
That's absurd. We went that night
to join forces with him.
On bended knee even.
- He almost did us in.
We had no idea of his plans
until Kawanishi informed us.
Serves him right.
He was secretly buying stock
to take over the company.
Then this incident
comes along and ruins him.
I'd call it divine retribution.
It's not that I doubt you,
but you've known
Mr. Gondo a long time.
I just wondered
if there was anyone
who might have held
a grudge against him.
Where should we start?
We couldn't even
name them all.
One more question.
The kidnapping occurred
just after you left his home.
Did you notice anything
near the gate?
A car, for instance,
or a suspicious person?
Look here! He'd just thrown us out.
We weren't admiring the view.
They were no help.
But at the factory -
Mr. Gondo has
a sharp temper for sure,
but he also cares a lot
about the work.
He's an excellent boss
if you do a good job.
I doubt anyone here
holds a grudge against him,
except maybe the front office.
Here's what I think:
Nobody holds a grudge
against Mr. Gondo...
except the big shots.
They'd give
the kidnapper a medal!
Taguchi, calm down.
Now for the results
of this meeting.
Inspector Tokura.
So far, this case seems
impossible to break.
But the criminal
must be in these details.
Follow every lead through
to the bitter end.
It may be fruitless,
but when you're discouraged. . .
think of what
Mr. Gondo's going through.
Take the boy tomorrow
for a drive along the shore.
Cover every mile
until you find this view.
If you can jog his memory,
you may find the hideout.
It's Vehicle Theft.
Tokura speaking.
That's great news.
We'll be right there.
Don't touch anything.
They found the car.
Abandoned on a highway.
Call the crime-scene unit.
Have more men bunk at the station,
with the rest on call.
It's spattered with mud,
but there's been no rain lately.
It's actually dust
combined with splashed water.
What's this?
- What's wrong?
- Everybody listen to this.
Hello. This is Gondo.
The boy's fine.
I'll let him talk to you.
Daddy? Are you there?
Hear that trolley?
So?
A trolley passes
by the hideout.
Three lines pass through Zushi,
Fujisawa, Chigasaki and Kamakura:
the JR, Odayaku
and Enoshima lines.
Each has a distinctive sound. Maybe
a specialist could tell which it is.
I'll be back.
Enoshima Rail?
You're sure?
You bet your boots.
I live right next to the tracks.
That sound
isn't a pantograph trolley.
It's an old-style,
single-pole trolley.
Only the Enoshima line
uses those old lines nowadays.
Plus, their line has
a lot of curves,
and they use short rails
with lots of joints.
Also, the wheelbase is narrow,
so it goes. . .
instead of...
Thank you very much.
Is Mr. Aoki in?
I'm sorry. He's out.
Is he at your husband's office?
No.
Where is he?
He took Shinichi for a drive.
He wants to jog Shinichi's memory
to help find the kidnapper.
He just won't let up, will he?
Give him a break.
He feels he has to do something.
You're sure
he let you out here?
- From which way?
- That way.
Watch carefully
out the back as we go.
Tell me
if you remember anything.
Now what?
We can't do anything
without the boy.
My guess is Aoki
will go to the Sakawa River.
Take the Tokaido Highway.
Daddy!
What?
Remember something?
I peed over there.
We're looking for Aoki. Once we have
the boy, we'll head for the shore.
Hold on.
I just got word from the lab.
There's a lot of fish blood
and oil on the stolen car.
They also found
mackerel scales and bonito.
That's what was splashed
on the hood of the car.
He drove through a lot of fish offal.
It must've been at a fish market.
The Koshigoe market
is the only one near that trolley.
Take a look over there.
We'll handle Aoki.
Got it.
Around here we mainly catch
bonito and mackerel.
But that's not enough
to fill local demand,
so we have other kinds
trucked in from Tokyo.
Thanks. By the way, where does
the Enoshima trolley run?
Under that bluff.
Does the view from there. . .
look anything like this?
Let's see.
You should be able to see
Enoshima Island from there.
But if you go further right,
to the hill near the station...
that cape is in front of Enoshima,
with a view just like this.
You saw Enoshima Island, right?
You must have.
But we didn't come this way.
Bos'n, I feel
we're getting closer.
Let's go up that hill.
Try not to look like a cop.
I'm not the problem.
You, on the other hand,
would need plastic surgery.
Daddy!
I saw this tunnel!
What?
You passed by here?
From which direction?
That way.
Shinichi, is this the spot?
Hey, look at that.
Enoshima doesn't look
like an island from here.
Let's head back.
They must have Aoki by now.
We'll wait at the fish market.
If the boy shows us the way,
with any luck we'll raid
the hideout tonight.
You got your pistol?
Of course. I'm not going
after a madman with my bare hands.
Let's look around on foot.
That car!
That's Gondo's car.
Don't be stupid.
Stop playing detective.
When I pulled the car up
this morning, Mr. Gondo said,
"Aoki, all we have now is time.
We're not going
to the factory anymore."
He was smiling,
but I know how he felt inside.
The directors are horrible men,
but in the end it's all my fault.
That's why. . .
But walking around here
with the boy is madness.
What if the kidnapper saw him?
Imagine the consequences.
Bos'n, he's gone!
Daddy!
Here it is!
Uncle and Auntie
are sleeping.
Take the boy away.
They're dead.
Thanks for coming,
everybody.
- Why the press conference?
- Yeah, what'd you find?
Inspector Tokura
will fill you in.
However, we ask you
not to print what you hear today.
Earlier today,
two accomplices, one male,
one female, were found dead.
Both from heroin overdose.
- An accidental overdose?
- I'll explain.
Their arms were covered
with needle marks.
Both were long-term addicts.
It's unlikely
that experienced addicts
would misjudge the dosage.
Dealers, furthermore,
don't sell heroin that pure.
Both died in bed,
their heads resting on pillows.
Next to the pillows
we found two empty packets,
two syringes,
and a cup of water,
maybe to dissolve the heroin.
In addition,
we found two unopened
packets of heroin.
So they obtained four packets,
They took two right away
and saved two for later.
These facts
don't suggest suicide.
So then why did they die?
The heroin
was unusually pure.
We analyzed the unused samples.
They were over 90% pure.
When heroin is smuggled in,
its purity ranges
from 70% to 95%.
Dealers cut it
with glucose
and hydrochloric procaine,
down to a purity
as low as 30%.
So a one-gram package
contains only 0.3 grams
of pure heroin.
What happens to an addict
who takes heroin
three times more pure?
An ingenious murder.
There's corroborating evidence.
We found a notepad
in their room.
The top page
bore impressions
from scribblings
made on the page above it.
Please observe.
It's been reconstructed
and enlarged in this slide.
The agony of withdrawal
can be clearly seen.
"Get us more dope.
Bring it fast.
If you don't,
we'll spend the money.
We won't do
what you say anymore."
Clearly, they tried
to blackmail him.
- That's why he killed them?
- We're not 100% certain,
but it certainly looks that way.
Was there money around?
We found 2,500
of Mr. Gondo's 1,000-yen notes.
The serial numbers matched.
The kidnapper may have
figured that out too.
He gave them a share
but made them wait to spend it.
We can gather that
from the letter.
Have you identified
the accomplices?
Caretakers of the villa.
We learned that
from the villa's owner.
So you're close?
No, we're back to square one.
Of course,
Narcotics is doing its best.
They may provide us
with valuable information,
but the accomplices' deaths
are a terrible blow
to the investigation.
The thread leading back
to the kidnapper has been cut.
That's why I'm asking you:
Don't print a word of this.
Why not?
The kidnapper has yet
to confirm that they're dead.
We know this because
if he had returned to the villa,
he wouldn't have left 2.5 million yen
in evidence lying around.
As far as he knows,
they may still be alive.
If we nurse that doubt within him,
how will he react?
If he is the killer, he'll probably
try to kill them again.
If there's no report
of their deaths in the papers,
he won't be able to stay put.
He'll surely return
to the scene to check.
- And you'll nab him then?
- That's right.
Even if we keep quiet,
won't their deaths
be impossible to hide?
The neighbors will talk.
That's not a problem.
It's a new development
with few houses.
It's also the off-season,
so hardly anybody's there.
Drug addicts are cautious.
They kept to themselves
and had no visitors.
But will our keeping quiet
really convince the kidnapper?
Well, that's why
I have another favor to ask.
I'd like you
to run a story today
saying one of the 1,000-yen notes
was spent.
Of course you can say
it's our announcement.
I know it's a lot to ask.
I'm asking your cooperation
for Mr. Gondo's sake too.
Did you know he was dismissed
from National Shoes
and kicked out
as factory manager?
That's terrible.
They seem to have no sense
of public opinion.
At the next shareholder meeting,
he'll be voted out completely.
In place of an article
reporting the deaths,
shall we slam
National Shoes?
Why not? Let's give 'em
a good thrashing!
GONDO FORCED OUT
PUBLIC OPINION IGNORED
WOMEN START BOYCOTT
OF NATIONAL SHOES
RISING TIDE
OF SYMPATHY AND ANGER
1, 000-YEN NOTE
FROM RANSOM FOUND
30 MILLION IN RANSOM
IN BRIEFCASES LIKE THIS
We've recovered 2.5 million
from the accomplices.
We can hand it over at the station,
if it's not too much trouble.
We're sorry that it's so little.
No, it's a great help now.
We believe the kidnapper
hasn't spent any yet.
We hope
to recover it all intact.
The twist is that he's harder
to catch if he doesn't spend it.
Kingo,
Mr. Kawanishi is here.
Kawanishi?
What does he want?
He has some kind of request.
- We'll be leaving then -
- No, stay. Send him in.
Please, help yourself.
Sorry I haven't been in touch.
Well, look who's here!
I must thank both of you.
You've made Mr. Gondo a hero.
That was a great help.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Don't be so cold.
I was your right-hand man
for over ten years.
Did you think I would stand by
while they booted you out?
I risked my own position
to try to keep you on.
But the Old Man's stubborn,
and the executive director's a viper.
It was a hard-fought battle.
Fortunately,
public opinion's on your side,
so I convinced them
to keep you on.
Get out!
Tell this to your new masters:
You can't trot me out
to ease the public's anger.
I refuse to be an ornament,
an executive without power.
I won't be your puppet.
Can you afford
to bluff like that?
You're going too far.
Right now you have
nothing but debts.
It may be a position in name only,
but your credit will be intact.
Get out!
I'm still the man I've always been,
even more so.
But you're nothing,
not even a human being.
Excuse me.
I'd like you to see something.
What is it?
It's nothing much,
but the last picture
seemed to be of some help.
Shinichi drew it.
He says it's the kidnapper.
Dark glasses and a mask.
Not much to go on.
What's this?
A handkerchief.
He always wore it.
Mom!
Look at the pretty pink smoke
from that chimney.
You lit the incinerator
around 9:00 a.m., right?
Yes, every day I burn
the trash from the day before.
What do you burn?
Dirty stuff,
junk that you can't disinfect.
They're always bringing stuff
that won't burn, damn it!
- Who is?
- Handymen and janitors.
Anyone else?
Sometimes hospital nurses
and attendants.
Anyone like that
come by today?
Come to think of it,
a man brought a cardboard box.
- How big?
- Like this.
- Anyone you know?
- No.
An intern maybe.
A young medical intern?
Sure looked that way.
Too young
to be a regular doctor.
"Burn this, pops," he said.
Doctors don't call people "pops."
- Anyone else?
Who'd wanna come
to a place like this?
Now why'd they bring -
You can't burn tin!
Do you know what department
that intern is in?
How would I know?
But he was headed
toward Internal Medicine.
Thanks a lot.
According to Bos'n's report,
his name
is Ginjiro Takeuchi.
An intern.
He took three days off
during the kidnapping.
He lives in a studio apartment
at 4-278 Sengen-cho
in Nishi Ward.
Sunrise Apartments, No. 12.
His room faces north,
right at the Gondo residence.
One of the two phones
that we suspect the kidnapper used
is right next to his apartment.
The male and female
accomplices
had been examined
at his hospital.
Takeuchi wrote up their charts.
Both had pulmonary edema,
a result of their drug addiction.
So we have two addicts
suffering from pulmonary edema,
as well as from withdrawal.
An injection of pure heroin
would cause death from shock.
As their intern,
he would have known that.
We may conclude
that he is the kidnapper.
But we can't arrest him.
Here's why:
If we arrest him now,
he'll only get 15 years.
Mr. Gondo,
on the other hand...
is serving a life sentence of debt
for paying the ransom.
We won't let that happen.
A criminal like this
deserves capital punishment.
What's more, it's clear
he killed his accomplices.
But if we arrest him now,
we'll have no material evidence
to prove it.
There's only one way to bring
this vicious criminal to justice:
Leave him at large
to reenact his crime.
But how?
By giving him this.
Please lower the blinds.
GIVE US MORE DOPE.
WE'LL TALK IF YOU DON'T.
A perfect forgery.
You Mr. Takeuchi?
He'll make his move today.
First, he'll go buy the heroin.
Then he'll try to kill them tonight.
There's no way
to predict anything else:
where he'll go,
how he'll get the drugs.
We can only know that
by keeping him in our sights.
Listen carefully:
Don't let him notice you,
but don't lose him.
Bos'n, Nakao, Arai and I
will head to the hideout as soon as
we hear he's obtained the drugs.
I'll give orders
from the car radio.
Is he waiting for a dealer?
Just killing time, I'd say.
He's walked up and down
this street for two hours.
If the same people keep tailing him,
he may catch on.
Inspector!
Yes. Tokura here.
He went into a florist's.
A florist's?
Have someone buy some flowers.
I'm afraid none of us
fits the part. Wait -
What?
One carnation?
Yes. One red carnation.
Is today Mother's Day?
Earlier, the suspect spoke
on a pay phone.
He was told
how to find the dealer.
The red carnation
must be a sign.
Watch for anybody
approaching the suspect.
Watch how the money
and dope change hands.
Inspector Tokura!
Tokura speaking.
- He changed his course.
- What?
He got out at "Dope Alley."
So he didn't actually
buy any in the club?
We're sure he did, but. . .
Okay, we're turning back.
Don't lose him!
What are you staring at?
This ain't a picture show.
Get the hell out!
This ain't no place
for the likes of you.
Lotta strangers snoopin' around
tonight. Be careful.
What are you, a cop?
We don't know any of you.
Get out.
Get out, I said!
Bos'n, I don't understand
what he's up to.
He should be taking the dope
straight to the hideout.
And why go to the junkies
if he hasn't got it yet?
They don't have
any pure heroin.
- Inspector!
- Tokura here.
He picked up a junkie
and took her to a flophouse.
KOGANE-CHO INN
I've got it!
He'll use her as a guinea pig.
She's in withdrawal,
and he can test it on her.
- He left the area.
- And the girl?
Just a minute.
Two men went to check.
Where to now?
The hideout?
Wait a minute. The girl's a clue
to what he'll do next.
He's headed
toward the Isezaki district.
What? We're there right now.
From which side?
Facing Yoshida Bridge,
the left side.
- Stop here.
- It's a no-parking zone.
It doesn't matter.
I've just received word:
The girl's dead.
Syringe in her hand.
Death by overdose.
He's coming.
We found him.
I'm cutting off the radio.
The guy's a real prize.
To the hideout.
Excuse me,
you can't stop here.
It's 12:15 a.m.
Hey, I brought the stuff.
Takeuchi, you're gonna hang!
We've recovered
another 27,480,000 yen.
All that's missing
is the 20,000 he spent on heroin.
We wanted to let you know
as soon as possible.
Thank you.
Were we too late?
Have a seat.
Please.
No, please. You're free
to use them until the auction.
SEIZED PROPERTY
GINJIRO TAKEUCHI
GETS DEATH SENTENCE
Thank you for coming.
He refused to talk
with the prison chaplain.
He insisted on speaking
to you instead.
Mr. Gondo, thanks for coming.
You seem well.
What are you doing now?
Making shoes again.
It's a small company,
but the owner gives me free rein.
I'm working hard
to rival National Shoes.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
I'm going to die,
but I'm not afraid,
so stop looking at me
so pitifully.
That's why I refused
to see the chaplain.
He'd tell me to repent
and pray for mercy.
Why should I waste my time?
I'd rather be told the cruel truth
than be fed gentle lies.
Speaking of which,
you must be glad I'm going to die.
Aren't you?
Why do you say such things?
Why do you think
we have to hate each other?
I don't know.
I'm not interested
in self-analysis.
But I do know my room
was so cold in winter
and so hot in summer
I couldn't sleep.
From my tiny room,
your house looked like heaven.
Day by day I came
to hate you more.
It gave me a reason for living.
Besides, it's amusing
to make fortunate men
taste the same misery
as the unfortunate.
Were you really
so unfortunate?
You want my life story?
Forget it.
I won't share my tales of woe
to earn your sympathy.
I'm just glad my mom
died last year,
so I won't be sickened
by her pathetic slobbering.
Then why exactly
did you call me here?
I couldn't stand having you think
I died crying and afraid.
You think I'm shaking out of fear,
but I'm not!
It's just a physiological reaction
from being in solitary too long.
Just leaving the cell
makes me shake.
I'm not afraid of death.
I don't care if I go to hell.
My life has been hell
since the day I was born.
But if I had to go to heaven,
then I'd really start to tremble.
THE END