I die for the revolution.
No Chinese woman has yet
shed blood for the revolution.
I shall be the first...
... although the world doesn't know
much about the revolution...
I leave behind my husband
and children.
My death...
... is my contribution
to the revolution.
It will build an indestructible
home for all people...
... a peaceful and calm world
for all children.
These long-enslaved
masses are numb.
They know not peace nor calm.
These two children...
... will soon lose their mother.
I die for all children.
I die for the revolution.
I'm not afraid,
nor do I care about death.
I rejoice at my martyrdom.
At this moment...
... I cry with blissful tears.
Put the donation boxes
in prominent spots.
Go over to the door.
Be vigilant.
Yes.
Let Mr. Sun rest more.
Don't disturb him.
Yes.
Juemin.
Who's that?
Who?
Look.
What?
Go, quick.
Get up, there's a woman here.
Don't bother, just go.
Keqiang.
Time to get up.
Get up.
Let me sleep three more minutes.
Alright.
Get up.
Two minutes.
Fine.
One more minute.
I'll get up.
I should go to Guangzhou
for the uprising.
What?
You forgot the committee's
decision last night?
Keqiang, listen.
I won't.
I must throw myself into battle.
Then last night's meeting
was a waste.
Why can't we talk it
through again?
There's nothing to discuss.
Huang Xing leads
the Guangzhou uprising.
Sun Wen handles
fundraising overseas.
We voted.
Promise.
These are donations
from abroad.
Overseas Chinese helped us.
I promised them.
I cannot fail them.
I must carry out my pledge.
It's not a personal promise...
... but Tongmenghui's promise.
They wrote these letters.
Who's this woman?
Zonghan.
Xu Zonghan.
Tongmenghui member
from my village.
I'm Huang Xing.
Zonghan coordinates underground
organizations in Guangzhou.
You two pretend
to be husband and wife.
It's a good cover.
No, it's not appropriate.
Why not?
I'm a woman and I don't care.
What are you afraid of?
It's easy to die in battle...
... but hard to motivate
the living.
You have the difficult task.
The Guangzhou uprising
will finish off the Qing Dynasty.
Take this pocket watch.
On the day of the uprising...
... we'll monitor time together.
Go!
Charge!
Quick.
Destroy this wall!
Yes.
You rebel!
You dare revolt?
You revolutionary!
You...
Where's Zhang Mingqi?
I don't know.
Quick!
And my wife.
Comrades taking part in
the uprising know me better.
It's easier for me to coordinate...
Nonsense.
I can wield my pen and scalpel,
why not a gun?
Remember, you're still a wanted
man by the Qing court...
... you can't risk it.
If you return to China
to lead the uprising...
... you're being irresponsible.
Yu Peilun.
Here.
We couldn't contact
the other groups.
Zhang Mingqi ran away.
Keqiang said...
... if the uprising fails...
... you must inform
Sun Wen immediately.
What else did he say?
He said if he's not
back by dusk...
... you must leave
Guangzhou at once.
Quick.
Back off!
All of you!
Listen to my command!
Attack from the sides!
- Yes!
- Hand grenades!
- Yes.
- Follow me.
Charge!
Keqiang!
Your hand.
Keqiang.
Don't mind me, charge!
Yes.
Charge!
Go away!
Run!
- What are you doing?
- Run!
Let go!
Let me go!
Yu Peilun!
Gentlemen...
... our fundraiser today...
... was originally organized
for the Guangzhou uprising.
But just now...
... I received news.
Fighting in Guangzhou
has ceased.
The uprising has failed.
The telegram states,
the uprising failed...
... many of our core
members are dead.
You've never met them.
These young people
who died were talented...
... some came
from rich families...
... some have just
gotten married.
They were willing
to sacrifice themselves...
... whatever the cost.
They sacrificed their lives
for the cause...
... because they have faith.
What do your lies
have to do with us?
Good question.
Most of you gathered here
are overseas Chinese.
You know well our faces
mark us as Chinese...
... and we've suffered untold
discrimination and bullying.
We've endured unfair treatment.
All because the country
of our people...
... has long been
corrupt and weak...
... writhing in pain!
Our Chinese compatriots...
... face adversity...
... our land taken by others.
Our revolution...
... ensures people
can pursue happiness...
... that our race
will regain dignity.
The Chinese revolutionary
movement is blessed...
... by support from
overseas Chinese.
For many years...
... I strongly believe this.
Overseas Chinese are the
mother of the revolution.
Gentlemen...
... your children...
... have died for you.
Fang Shengdong.
Lin Shishuang.
Yu Peilun.
Chen Gengxin.
Lin Juemin.
This young man
will soon be a father.
What's this?
US$300,000.
Donation from Zhigongtang.
I won't hide this from you,
Yat-sen.
We sold our ancestral house.
Yat-sen...
... we're overseas Chinese...
... we have to settle down
here eventually.
The Qing Dynasty
is no longer our home.
Without a home...
... why keep an ancestral house?
Take it.
If the revolution fails...
... you'll owe us for generations.
Another one!
Yat-sen...
... your pocket watch
can block bullets...
... but not cannon shells.
Fire!
Empress Dowager...
... I heard Sun Wen has
long escaped abroad.
He hasn't returned
for more than a decade.
We might want to arrest him,
but it's going to be hard.
Didn't we alert our envoys
and foreign governments...
... about Sun, telling them they
should monitor his movements?
But Sun gives public
lectures everywhere...
... raising funds,
organizing rebels...
... trafficking arms,
plotting uprisings.
Minister Xu,
perhaps you overstated.
He hasn't appeared
before our eyes.
He's only mortal,
not the Monkey King.
What power can he wield?
Sun's done enough
to rock the boat.
These years, unrest seethes
everywhere.
Rebellions follow one
after another.
Sun's been misleading
others with his lies...
... so many follow his path.
What a troublemaker.
As if he doesn't make
enough trouble.
The Qing Dynasty will not
fall because of him.
If he dares enter
the Forbidden City...
... our Manchurian imperial
army will kill him.
Yes...
... let's just eradicate
Sun Wen and his cohorts.
We'll destroy them
once and for all.
Stop carrying on like this!
... or whatever other solution...
... I only have this to say.
Please, all of you...
... let us have some peace.
Recently...
... the mortgage of our railways
against the Four Nations Bank loan...
... has led to riots.
What's the use of your rifles?
Tell them...
... if they revolt...
... they'll all die in vain.
Lin Juemin.
You're educated...
... you come from a good family.
Why did you join the rebels?
Zhang Mingqi...
... why do you hide
in darkness?
What are you afraid of?
What am I afraid of?
You're afraid of my youth.
I have chosen death...
... but I'm still young.
You might live...
... but you are old.
Have you read
the study of evolution?
Survival of the fittest.
Have you considered...
... the leading nations in the world
were all borne of revolution?
China must also
have a revolution.
Affairs of the nation
are not your concern.
Sun Wen said...
... China is weak.
There's no way out.
The royal family, aristocrats and
officials all follow their old ways.
But what of the people?
They barely survive,
ignorant of the world.
China is no match for other
countries, it's a dire situation.
Young man, the Qing court
has a hard time too.
The court?
The court gave Hong Kong
to England...
... and Taiwan to Japan.
That's the good work
of the Qing court.
What's the use of keeping it?
I'm interrogating you...
... yet you turn around
to question me?
Because you have no grounds
to sentence me.
Lin Juemin...
... I had wanted
to exercise clemency.
There's no need.
My comrades and I
fought together...
... we'll die together.
I can't be an exception.
If you die...
... you'll be left with nothing.
The Qing court wants my life...
... I'll destroy the dynasty
at its heart.
Hello, Your Royal Highness...
... this is a car
used by British royalty.
As a member of Chinese royalty,
let me try.
Please.
You've come because
of the Sichuan railways?
The loan agreements
between our countries...
... and the mortgage of your
railways cannot be written off.
That's the trouble.
I knew it.
The mortgage of the Sichuan
and Guangdong railways...
... against your loan will lead
to trouble down the road.
If you forcibly take the railways,
it'll be a catastrophe.
Can't we find a solution,
my dear lord?
Look at this invention.
It's an iron machine.
It can move forward
and backward, left and right...
... whatever you wish.
My lord...
... please enjoy this humble gift...
... and steer it in
the right direction.
Mr. Ambassador...
... we've already sent troops
from Wuchang...
... to suppress the Sichuan riots.
Don't you worry.
Your Royal Highness,
you're a great strategist.
You're the one
holding the steering wheel.
You have money...
... you have navel fleets...
... you've always been better
businessmen than us.
In 50 years...
... the car you gave me...
... will be scrap metal.
But my little gift to you
will be priceless.
Thank you.
Open the door, Huang Keqiang.
Quick, open the door,
Huang Keqiang
I know you're inside.
Open up.
Huang Keqiang.
Huang Keqiang,
open the door.
Open the door for me.
What are you doing.
Huang Keqiang?
Put it down.
Give me the blade.
Let me go.
What are you doing?
You can't die!
I know you saw
all of them being killed.
I know we failed.
I didn't want to die, Zonghan.
I want to keep this hand...
... to wield the gun.
Help me chop it off.
- No. No!
- So we failed...
... we've failed before!
No.
Children...
... do you know
what the telegram says?
No.
Huang Keqiang is alive.
Fate has been kind.
Who's he?
Huang Keqiang...
... is a strong and
determined man...
... a man who won't die.
We don't know him.
But do you know Homer Lea?
Yes.
Take me to him, please.
Where's Homer Lea?
There.
Homer Lea.
Homer.
Homer!
- Homer!
- Hey, I'm here.
Mr. Lea...
... tell me.
Why are you so interested
in Chinese revolution?
Nowadays...
... a Chinese revolution...
... is the only thing that can
make exciting history.
Exciting?
That's not what
our revolution is about.
Why a revolution?
I was once a doctor.
I used to save a lot of lives
with my scalpel.
But sadly...
... in my country,
life is so miserable...
... it might be worse than death.
I always wonder...
... why my compatriots have to
endure their lives with no dignity.
They survive like animals
with very basic needs...
... suffering the oppression
from the ruling class...
... and foreign powers.
Now...
... I cannot accept it...
... I will not accept it.
I want to change.
I want a revolution!
Come...
... I'll show you.
Recently, in Sichuan...
... the central part of China, where
people have launched a movement...
... of protecting railway projects...
... against the hopelessly
corrupted Qing government.
It is said that
the Qing government...
... has to mobilize the army
from Hubei province to Sichuan.
What they don't know...
... is many officers who stayed
behind in the army of...
... Hubei, Hunan, and Jiangsu...
... are active members
of Tongmenghui...
... the Restoration League.
I have a feeling...
... that in the south
of Yangtze River...
... an even bigger movement...
will take hold.
I want to join your revolution.
That's fine.
I would like to invite you...
... to join the Chinese revolution
as a military advisor...
... but I'm afraid I cannot afford you
and pay the attention you deserve.
This...
... this is not about money.
It's about you, Sun.
You must be China's
first president.
I promise.
Peng Chufan!
Liu Fuji!
Yang Hongsheng!
The three of them
plotted mutiny!
Heaven's punishment
is upon them.
We execute them today
as a warning to all.
Governor, we found the name list.
What should we do?
What else can we do?
Starting tonight,
kill everyone on the list.
No one will be spared!
All of you,
ask your own conscience.
The Qing court supports
and protects you...
... yet you plot to rebel,
following such thugs as Sun Wen.
Isn't that the behavior of
unfilial sons, killing their parents?
Stop, you two.
What are your names?
Xiong Bingkun of the 8th regiment,
8th engineering battalion.
Jin Zheolong of the 8th regiment,
Lie low.
This is a crisis.
Don't be hot-tempered.
Yes.
What is this?
A mutiny?
Not sleeping?
What do you want?
What?
This is a mutiny.
Tao Qisheng!
Brother...
... put down your rifle.
I'm leading a mutiny.
How many more will you kill?
You're lucky that
I'm aiming at you.
Brother, this is not a joke.
If we don't do it now,
then when?
Help!
Tell Zhang Zhenwu to bring
two of his battalions.
Aim all artillery at the
Governor's mansion.
When Xiong Bingkun lights
the torch, fire at the mansion.
Yes.
Charge!
Hand grenades!
Go!
Jin Zhaolong!
Xiong Bingkun!
Lead two platoons.
Order everyone
to bring gas canisters.
Rush in to fuel the fire.
Light the target.
Yes!
- Quick!
Quick!
Quick.
Ready!
Target is the
Governor's mansion!
Load!
Done!
Fire!
Load!
Good morning, Mrs. Johnson.
Good morning.
Here.
Oh, yes.
Oh, Dr. Sun.
Yes?
It seems like there's something
in today's paper about China.
Thank you.
Do you need some help,
Dr. Sun?
Can I give you some water?
I'm alright.
Yat-sen.
Hey, what's going on in here?
What are you guys doing?
Come on.
Yat-sen.
The revolution has succeeded.
- Hey, what's the matter with you?
- Sorry.
On October 10...
... the revolutionary army
took over Wuchang.
Governor Rui Cheng
fled overnight.
Wuchang revolutionaries
telegraphed the entire country...
... asking them to join in the
rebellion. The world's in shock.
Yat-sen...
... you should return
to China immediately.
I'll reserve a boat ticket for you.
It takes 20 days
across the Pacific...
... then you'll reach Shanghai.
It happened in Wuchang.
Send a telegram
to Keqiang in Hong Kong...
... so he travels to Wuchang
to lead the revolution.
Yes!
Sun...
... I'm ready.
I'll go to China with you.
No, no, no.
I'll go to Europe first.
Huang Xing is much better
than me to handle this in China.
Why?
The unrest in China
will be closely linked...
... to the Four Nations Bank
loan to the Qing court.
The court's out of money now.
But if they get the loan,
they can thwart the revolution.
Reserve tickets for Europe.
Zonghan, don't bother
making dinner.
We're running out of time.
Put it down.
Why are you so anxious?
You don't need it.
The battle in Wuchang
will be intense.
I'm concerned for your safety.
What about your own safety?
Don't worry...
... I won't die.
Fate will be kind to me.
I should go now.
Leave.
What happened?
Only yesterday Rui Cheng
reported to us...
... that the rebel leaders
were killed.
A day passed and...
The New Army had it easy.
Clearly...
... the Wuchang regiments were
sent to Sichuan to stop the unrest.
The city was leave unguarded.
Tell me something
I don't already know.
The Qing court has ruled
for more than 200 years.
We've ridden through
many storms.
It's only a small flame,
we'll extinguish it.
Who should we send
to extinguish this flame?
Empress Dowager...
... I humbly believe...
I recommend Yin Chang,
head of the Imperial Army.
This is his duty.
Xu Shichang.
Yes.
Just now...
... what were you saying?
Yuan Shikai can fulfill this task.
Better to appoint Yin Chang.
This is family affair.
It's better to send over a Manchu.
- Hand it over.
- Yes.
Empress Dowager...
... I would like
to submit a request.
Say it, Royal Prince.
Food and supplies
precede an army.
There's this old saying...
Be precise...
- ... don't just quote the classics.
- In my opinion...
... we should finalize the loan
from the Four Nations Bank...
... we'll have less
to worry about later.
Haven't we discussed
this for months?
Why hasn't this been done?
The Four Nations Bank felt
we've been indecisive...
... about mortgaging our railways.
There's been criticism outside.
People say that we're giving
away our sovereignty.
If we're not rulers here,
is this even a country?
General Li, for the sake
of the times, please decide.
I've treated you well.
Why are you making
it so difficult for me?
We ask that you lead the
Military Government.
We're not making it difficult!
Drop your gun!
Ask him to drop his gun.
Put it down!
General Li,
you've treated us well.
We wish you'd lead
the Military Government.
You have great talents
among the revolutionary ranks.
Why don't you ask Sun Wen
to be your leader?
Li Yuanhong!
The revolutionary party
will select our leaders.
At present...
... Sun Wen is still abroad and
Huang Keqiang is on his way here.
That's why we offer you this.
Li Yuanhong...
... do you understand
your predicament?
I can give up my position
in the Qing court...
... but I don't want to become
a revolutionary official either.
I only want to return home.
You have no idea
of the real situation.
Though Rui Cheng and Zhang Biao
have gone into hiding...
... if the court's troops
were to counterattack...
... they can destroy
Wuchang in a second.
Come back!
Stop!
- Come back!
- Go!
Stop!
Go!
Lie down!
Yin Chang's firing at us
from a German battleship!
General Li, are you alright?
What damned battle is this?
I'll die because of you.
Remove the ammunition, quick!
Then we'll die together.
We'll count you
as a revolutionary martyr.
Li Yuanhong,
General of the Mixed Brigade!
I'm Military Governor
Li Yuanhong!
If you want to live,
return to your stations!
Attention!
Yes!
Target: Battleship Chuyu!
Distance: 2400 feet!
Load!
Prepare for rapid firing,
first round.
Rapid firing, first round.
Fire!
Distance: 2350 feet!
25 degrees to the right!
Load!
Fire all three cannons!
Fire!
Cease fire!
Why did we stop?
Since I'm the Military Governor,
I make all the decisions.
Why did they stop?
They ran out of ammunition?
Doesn't look like it.
Should we fire back
to test them?
What for?
Better keep our lives.
Run.
Even if we annihilate
Yin Chang, so what?
He's of no consequence.
The real battle is ahead of us.
Yes.
You want to cut my queue?
Fine.
Come.
Since you revolutionaries have
bestowed such honour on me...
... I'll be presumptuous
and break the law.
Father.
Good news.
You scared away my fish.
You're coming out of seclusion.
You can't hold your horses,
can you?
General, Huafu is here.
Huafu.
Let's show the revolutionaries
and those in the Forbidden City...
... our great Beiyang Army
and our great power.
Yes.
Attention, artillery!
Target ahead!
25 degrees to the right!
Distance at 500 feet!
Load!
Ready!
Fire!
Alcohol!
Keqiang.
Where should we go?
Wherever there's heavy gunfire.
Make way!
Commander!
Avoid gunfire!
Hide in the trench!
Don't run!
Go back!
Retrieve the gun!
Remember,
a live soldier is useless...
... without his weapon.
Tell me, Huafu.
Tell me.
General.
We've taken Hankou.
Your order to attack
scorch Hankou.
With Hankou, it now
gives us access to Wu...
What's your next step?
Morale is high.
We attack Wuchang right away.
Great.
We take Hankou first...
... then attack Beijing.
We'll conquer the world.
Sit down, have some food.
This is a Heaven-sent
opportunity.
Sit down!
Keding...
... you're not far from death.
Let's wait on Wuchang.
After the rabbit is killed...
... the hunting dog
will be cooked.
Enemy positions have advanced.
Once they cover
their firing range...
... the infantry will attack.
The key to combat
is to avoid gunfire.
Yes!
Idiot!
Trying to run away?
I'll kill you!
Drop your gun!
He's Huang Xing,
our Commander.
Salute!
I command you all.
From now on,
follow my orders!
Yes!
Always be prepared
to enter the frontlines.
Yes!
We torched Hankou well...
... it was a great offense.
But now...
... we won't follow up.
If the revolutionaries
can be easily defeated...
... the country still belongs
to the Qing court.
If the Qing court is also weak...
... the revolutionaries
could seize power.
Somehow...
... we must be get a share of it.
Here's my condition
to the Qing court.
I take full power over the
army and its supplies.
Now...
... Empress Dowager Longyu
and the princes must know...
... that they must get the loan
from the Four Nations Bank...
... in order to continue
this battle.
As for the revolutionaries...
Should we contact Li Yuanhong
and test the waters?
But he's not a revolutionary.
In the long run...
... we should find someone
we can connect with...
... Sun Wen and Huang Xing.
Report.
Wang Jingwei is here.
Please.
Isn't Wang supposed to be
in Beijing, in prison?
Zaifeng released him.
You were locked up for a year.
You've suffered.
Times have changed,
don't mention it any more.
I admire you the most
among the revolutionaries.
I was just telling Keding...
... we should swear
as blood brothers.
Zhaoming...
... tell me.
What do you
revolutionaries want?
We want to establish a republic.
Republic?
But why?
Feudalism has kept China
back for far too long.
As long as there's an Emperor...
... we cannot rid ourselves
of the old system.
The revolution must
depose the Emperor...
... and the imperial system.
That's all theory.
We have to put it in practice.
When the republic is established,
who will lead it?
A leader of the republic
is elected by all citizens.
Brother Zhaoming...
... the General pondered seriously
before inviting you from Beijing.
He'd like your help.
You're the one who knows
the revolutionaries well.
Zhaoming...
... is Sun Wen still abroad?
Gentlemen.
Gentlemen!
You know who I am
and why I'm here.
It seems to me...
... that you have decided that
you're against the revolution.
Am I right?
Go.
If that's the case...
... the Qing government
will take this loan...
... buy guns and shoot through
the hearts of revolutionaries.
Your money will support
the corrupt Qing government...
... in exchange for what?
Railway?
Our railway.
Sir.
Sir...
... please keep your voice down.
You're deciding the future
of my country here.
Being a Chinese...
... I have the right to know
what's going on here.
We've already informed
your government...
... regarding our decision.
What's happening?
You must tell me that.
Let me remind you
that we're in Europe.
I'm sure you're a man
of the world...
... but you really should
behave like a gentleman.
Do you understand what's
happening in China now?
Mr. Sun Wen.
He won't answer you.
They are bankers...
... they only care
about their money...
... not other people's fate.
Mr. Hillier...
... do you know who he is?
No.
He's the man who will
decide the future of China.
You are?
Tang Manrou.
Wretch!
Your father is the Chinese
Imperial Ambassador...
... and you spoke for Sun Wen?
Do you know who he is?
Who is he?
He's a traitor
of the Qing Dynasty!
He's a wanted criminal!
He's a revolutionary.
Don't you know?
Tang Manrou.
Precisely because I know
who he is...
... that's why I helped him.
Mr. Hillier.
Hillier.
I must go before
this person arrives.
We cannot be present
in the same place.
Why leave, Minister Tang?
I beg you,
you still haven't done us...
... the honour of
accepting our invitation.
You really mustn't leave.
Please.
Don't leave.
Ladies and gentlemen...
... I'm well aware that
I've come here uninvited.
However...
... as the leader of the Chinese
revolution, I only ask you...
... please reconsider
the 6 million pounds...
... your loan to
the Qing government.
Sun Wen...
... you're a subject
of the Qing Dynasty...
... yet you show no respect
for your country.
How can you claim any respect
regarding our country?
You've lost it all
a long time ago.
I represent the whole
Chinese people...
... and speak in the name as
leader of the Chinese revolution.
Dr. Sun...
... we will not break such an
important business contract.
Mr. Thompson...
... this is not a business contract,
it's a political deal.
If this contract is signed,
what's at stake here...
... is Chinese sovereignty.
Mr. Sun...
... our German banks
only care about business...
... we don't care
about domestic politics.
My dearest German delegates...
... every time the Qing
government fires a gun at us...
... your money
presses the trigger.
The Qing government will buy
weapons with your loan, nothing else.
Perhaps you've misunderstood.
According to my understanding...
... this loan is intended
to help rebuild the railways.
Mr. Sun...
... our minister in Peking,
Sir John Newell Jordan...
... said the same thing
about the loan.
Dear Sir Buchanan...
... I believe when
Mr. Jordan realizes...
... that the money is used to
destroy the Chinese revolution...
... he will change his mind.
Sun Wen!
This is my second warning.
Do not defame
the Qing Dynasty here.
Defame?
Minister Tang...
... you underestimate us.
We want to depose
you and the court.
Gentlemen...
... we all know that
to give good money...
... to a bad client
is a fatal mistake.
The Qing government is like
a patient diagnosed with cancer.
Your loan is like sugar pills...
... it'll only make him feel better,
but the fate is sealed.
It seems that you are quite pessimistic
about the future in China.
No, I'm not.
On the contrary...
... my vision of the new China
is very positive.
I see huge miles covered with
plenty of natural resources.
I see thousands of banks
providing new capital.
I see a mountain of railways...
... connecting all the
modern communities.
Gentlemen...
... you are bankers.
You should know how
to invest your money wisely.
Would you rather
invest your money...
... into a dying government
or the emerging one?
Mr. Sun Yat-sen...
... I know you are the leader
of this revolution...
... and I respect your revolution.
However, we cannot invest money
against the interests of our own nation.
You may know
that I'm a surgeon.
As a doctor, my duty
is to save my patient's life.
One day...
... I find my country
is suffering from cancer.
Mr. Hillier...
... the situation of China
is like this roast lamb.
It's unlikely our people
would enjoy freedom...
... equality and fraternity.
Yes...
... that is to say,
this is China.
And all of you want a piece.
Germany...
... here's your piece...
... the Shandong peninsula.
Good location, isn't it?
What's all this?
Sir Buchanan...
... your piece...
... left rather small on this plate...
... only Hong Kong.
And you know very well,
this is a gate to reach China.
Mr. Thompson, let me cut out
this special piece for you...
... in memory of all
those Chinese lives...
... that were lost
carving out your mountain...
... for the transcontinental railway.
Where they sleep, buried,
the bones of Chinese labourers.
It's a pity, that all those countries
not here today.
Russia...
... Japan and Portugal.
They want Pescadores,
Liaodong Peninsula...
... and Macau.
Gentlemen...
... this is the last time you can
gather to feast on China.
I really hope...
... I made my point clear.
Mr. Tang...
... please wait a moment.
Go home.
Please.
Please stay.
Stay.
Here.
Can you tell me
what does revolution mean?
Like a doctor
who heals patients...
... a revolution saves
an entire people.
Mr. Sun...
... I heard girls in China...
... have to bind their feet
from a young age.
Is it painful?
Yes, it's painful.
But, it will be gone very soon.
I see.
Thank you.
Must people lose their lives
in revolution?
The final goal of revolution
isn't death, but to change fate.
Young people sacrificed
themselves for the revolution...
... so those living
can lead better lives.
Extend firing range!
Come!
It's overheated!
It won't fire!
Piss on it!
Lie down!
Nurse!
Little Hubei,
gather hand grenades.
Give them to me!
- Give them to me!
- No!
Let go.
- Commander!
- Let go!
Don't pull me back!
Let go!
Go!
Little Hubei!
Ammunition handler.
Charge!
General, Huafu is here.
General, we've taken Hanyang.
Should we continue fighting?
There's no need for us
to be in such a rush.
We nave to let
the Qing court understand...
... if they don't pay up...
... we won't move.
Your words mean...
Can't you read?
Read it yourself.
Fight slowly...
... wait and see?
- But morale is high.
- I must return to Beijing...
... and see what
the Empress Dowager says.
Let me tell you
my bottom line.
If the court doesn't
give me enough money...
... I won't fight.
I'd thought it'd be easy
to defeat them...
... but Sun's rebels are resilient.
I also lack ammunition
and supplies.
Empress Dowager...
... I was forced to cease
the battle of Wuchang.
Yuan Shikai.
Yes, Empress Dowager.
How much do you need?
Tell me.
If I have 12 million
taels of gold...
... I can finish off the revolutionaries
within a few months.
If we have no money for battle,
we only have one choice.
To make peace
with the revolutionaries.
You dare?
Making peace means
we acknowledge them.
My Beiyang Army is on its
last round of ammunition.
I'll never agree to
your making peace.
If you really care
about the Qing court...
... do something useful,
donate your riches.
Why don't you donate your
own money to the cause?
Yuan Shikai.
Empress Dowager,
as I had reported earlier...
... we must have enough money
to support the army.
Yuan Shikai is indeed
hard pressed.
You love to argue all the time..
... pretending to be
loyal ministers.
Now in times of crisis...
... you've all become selfish.
The dynasty is destined to fall.
Your servant...
... will give up all
of his possessions.
This is a time of crisis,
I will lead...
... my entire family
to protect the country.
Your servant
doesn't want a coffin...
... nor does he care
about his ancestral grave.
If money can help
destroy the rebels...
... then I'll leave everything
and return to my home village.
The Four Nations Bank has
been persuaded by Sun.
I'm afraid we won't receive
a cent of this loan.
I know.
Heaven will punish
Sun Wen for this.
Empress Dowager...
... even though we run out of
money, food and ammunition...
... we still have for centuries
our loyal subjects.
I only have this to say.
I will die for the Qing Dynasty.
Sun Wen, your interference
with the Four Nations Bank loan...
... has generated controversy
in China.
This is the Prince Regent's
order to assassinate you.
This one looks more like
a portrait of the deceased.
I don't agree with you,
but I respect your courage.
I won't kill you.
I want to persuade you.
Sun Wen, we are both
past middle age.
Confucius said...
... at 50, I knew my destiny.
He also said...
... at 40, I am not deluded.
I've never wavered
from my beliefs.
I know why you won't kill me.
You're a father.
... will eventually
destroy your children.
We all want a strong and bright
China for our children.
Go.
I don't want to see you again.
Mr. Jordan...
... you're the first guest
in my new house.
Now that you've moved to Beijing,
we can see each other more often.
Yes.
I don't intend to leave
the city this time.
How's the situation
in the South?
Difficult.
Sun Wen and Huang Xing are
southern barbarians with big appetites.
You could have conquered
Wuchang but you stopped.
We all know the Qing Dynasty
has run out of money.
The end is near.
You want to profit
from the power balance...
... between the Qing court
and the revolutionary army.
So now you want peace.
So what do you think...
... of this balance between
my left and right hands?
Truth be told,
I'm very impressed.
But the revolutionaries
won't talk to me.
Now I understand. You hope
we could extend a hand.
You...
We'll pave the way for you
to negotiate peace...
... with the revolutionaries.
It's not good for anyone
if fighting continues.
What's most important now
is holding onto power.
Real power.
We are looking
for a collaborator...
... to protect the interests
of Britain in China.
Well, you've found him.
Military Governor,
let me explain.
I sent Keqiang to Shanghai...
... because of the overall strategy
of the revolutionary movement.
I don't understand.
The Wuchang uprising
attracted the world's attention.
Isn't that also part of
the overall strategy?
Since we can attack Nanjing,
why can't we defend Wuchang'?
In Wuchang, we're at a stalemate
with the Beiyang Army.
Our trainee soliders
have suffered heavy casualties.
In Nanjing,
the enemy is weak.
Our plan is to attack Nanjing,
than retake Wuchang.
That's our overall strategy.
This is the decision made
by the Tongmenghui.
I must abide by it.
Fine.
Whatever you say.
But I won't go to Shanghai.
Please understand...
... it hasn't been easy to
forge our paths together.
My home is here.
My power base is here.
Military Governor Li...
... it appears we won't
be sharing the same path.
Don't move.
Lie down.
Listen...
... if you want to live
for the revolution...
... we must amputate your leg.
Do you hear me?
Alcohol.
It's fine.
Ready?
- Be brave.
- We begin now.
Listen to me.
Stop.
Stop!
Come.
Take him away.
You've said it before.
So we failed.
Haven't we failed before?
I'm talking to you.
Useless.
Mr. Sun, I've just received
your telegraph.
Okay.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Mr. Sun...
... I must inform you right away.
The Four Nations Bank
decided to hold off...
... on the loan
to the Qing government.
You once told me...
... that revolution is life,
not only living, but fate.
I don't understand revolution...
... but I've struggled
and fought, I was angry.
I also knew...
... I'd end up as sacrifice
along with my father.
I wish your revolution...
... no...
... wish our revolution...
... every success.
Yat-sen!
Keqiang!
Where are you?
Keqiang...
... I'm here.
Can you hear me?
I can.
Where are you?
Huang Keqiang!
Yat-sen!
I'm starboard.
Me too.
Keqiang.
At the welcome ceremony,
you have to put on...
... the revolutionary
army uniform.
Yes.
Yat-sen.
Binglin, come with me.
Not in first class?
- No.
- Second class?
No.
Yat-sen.
It saved my life once.
Keqiang...
... your hand.
Guangzhou uprising.
Doesn't matter.
Yat-sen.
Mr. Sun.
Dunchu.
You're here.
Yat-sen, we searched
all the way to the beam.
You're all here.
A hug.
Let's go.
Yat-sen, we waited
so long for your return.
Shiping, you haven't aged a bit.
Mr. Sun...
... after your ship
departed from Europe...
... on your journey back...
... what thoughts came over you?
After 16 years of tribulations...
... I've returned
to my motherland.
Mr. Sun...
... we hear you've returned
with huge donations...
... is that true?
I don't have any money.
All I brought back
is the revolutionary spirit.
What is the ultimate
goal of the revolution?
The goals of the revolution
are simple.
We overthrow imperial rule
and save our people.
Mr. Sun...
... what did you tell
those bankers in Europe?
I told them...
... it's the Chinese people
who will steer the fate of China...
... not foreigners
or Manchu royalty.
Mr. Sun, the north and south
are now negotiating peace.
What is your opinion?
My opinion is this.
We haven't reached our revolutionary
goal, we won't negotiate.
Tie up them.
Our position is that unless
the Emperor abdicates...
... there'll be no
peace agreement.
Our position is that the
monarchical system cannot change.
This is a family dinner.
Shaochuan, you're part of the family.
Come, try this.
A specialty from home.
Lotus root with glutinous rice.
Come, sit.
To thank you.
You put in so much effort
in the negotiations.
You've worked so hard.
Please tell me
what's on your mind.
You're the only one among us
who understands Sun Wen.
I want to know more
about Sun Wen.
What type of a man is he?
Zhang Shizhao said,
China will rise because of Sun.
He's the person
who will revive the country.
Miyazaki considers Sun...
... a hero who will save China.
Kang Youwei
claimed Sun is illiterate.
Wu Zhihui says that Sun
is a hardworking scholar.
Some say he's like Robin Hood,
an outlaw.
Some say he's a real scholar...
... an itinerant doctor
holding a scalpel.
Others call him
a good-for-nothing liar.
There are many versions.
Shaochuan...
... he has so many followers.
How does he do it?
I did hear this
from many people.
That Sun is selfless.
A selfless person?
Where in the world
can we find one?
It's been 2000 years,
we can't wait any longer...
- ... for China's first republic.
- Representatives from...
... the 17 provinces
have decided...
... not to elect a President,
but to elect a Grand Marshal.
Mr. Sun, please sign.
A Grand Marshal
cannot be head of state.
We must elect a President.
On the Presidential election...
... should we wait to hear
from Yuan Shikai?
If he can really hasten
the Emperor's abdication...
The negotiating parties
already made a pact.
Whoever first deposes the Qing
government will become President.
Yuan Shikai hasn't deposed
the Qing court.
We didn't break our promise.
It you insist on
a Presidential election...
... people will use that
as an excuse to resume fighting.
So what?
We fought and look what
we've achieved today.
Keqiang.
If we resume fighting, what
are our chances of winning?
We have no money...
... morale is low...
... we have no sure
chance of winning.
How can we fight?
This is impractical.
When the revolutionary
army had nothing...
... we were willing
to sacrifice our lives.
Now we have half a country...
... what are we afraid of?
The international community
expressed support for Yuan Shikai.
Overseas Chinese all hope
we could set up government...
... as soon as possible
and elect a President.
To be safe,
I think we should wait.
If Yuan doesn't depose the
Emperor for another 100 years...
... do we still wait?
Let's put pressure
on him now.
If Yuan makes
the Emperor abdicate...
... do we have to keep
our promise?
Even if Yuan makes
the Emperor abdicate...
... he isn't qualified
to be President.
Not true.
If Yuan keeps his promise,
he can become President.
If you've promised him anyway,
why bother holding an election?
Good question.
It's worth it.
First...
... we have to establish
the concept of a republic.
It's just like building a road
in the wilderness...
... so the revolution
can continue its path.
In future in China,
no one can turn back.
Lie down!
Against the wall!
All of you!
He's the assassin.
Release him.
Who sent you here?
Sun Wen is a sinner.
He's corrupt!
He's sullied the Qing dynasty!
He's immoral!
He misleads the people.
He's beyond pardon!
Everyone can kill him!
It's no use interrogating him.
We live in entirely
different worlds.
Understood.
Two days ago...
... on December 27...
... provincial representatives
voted and approved...
... the Provisional Government
Organizational Draft.
They also approved
the Presidential system...
... as well as the nomination
of candidates.
Elections will take place today,
December 29...
... for the position
of Provisional President.
I declare each
of the 17 provinces...
... though some with more
representatives than others...
... is only given one vote.
A candidate receiving more
the two-thirds of the votes...
... will become
Provisional President.
Those in favor,
raise their hands.
This is the Presidential ballot.
Your decision is crucial.
We hope you will not
disappoint your people...
... in your choice.
Please fill in your ballot.
Homer.
Sun.
What are you doing here?
The Presidential election
is ongoing in the council hall.
I'm one of the candidates.
History, you're making history.
I'm witnessing history.
I'm standing right beside history.
For thousands of years...
... in Chinese history,
we the people...
... never received the opportunity...
... to elect the head
of government.
Never.
That...
... is what we've been
fighting for.
Our people have been fighting
ongoing for so long.
And now we finally done it.
Homer...
... when did you get here?
Why didn't you tell me
you were coming?
Now, as head of the Assembly...
I must be there.
I declare the results.
Out of a total of 17 votes...
... Sun Wen received 16.
The Provisional President
of the Republic of China is...
... Sun Wen.
Dr. Sun...
... I heard your name.
I told you you'd be
China's first President.
Tang Shaoyi...
... didn't you say he's selfless?
What an slap in the face!
General.
Go.
Order.
Feng Guozhang
and Duan Qirui..
... to issue a joint telegram
against the republic.
Tang Shaoyi is sympathetic to the
republic, unable to fulfill his duties...
... he's dismissed as representative
to the negotiations.
Yes.
Send a telegram
to Wu Tingfang.
I recognize neither the Nanjing
Provisional Government...
... nor its so-called
President Sun Wen.
... Zhang Xun has amassed
his troops around Suzhou.
Also...
... some Qing soldiers
have been sighted...
... near Qinhuai River
this afternoon.
Mr. President, we advise delaying
the inauguration ceremony.
Yes, better to be cautious.
Today is New Year's Day
of 1912...
... everything is renewed.
The Provisional President
of the Republic of China...
... must be sworn in today.
Fine.
I'll take care of all
security details...
... for the Provisional President.
Photo session.
Please, look here, here.
I pledge to overthrow
the Qing dynasty...
... strengthen the
Republic of China...
... foster better
livelihoods for all.
These I promise to the people.
I will follow them.
I will serve the country
with faith.
I will serve all people.
Until the hegemony of the
Qing dynasty is overthrown...
... and the country
has no strife...
... when China will stand tall
in the world...
... recognized among nations.
At that time...
... I will resign from the position
of Provisional President.
This is my pledge
to all citizens of China.
Just now...
... I pledged myself as the
Provisional President.
Now, I have a few words to add.
Today...
... the Republic of China
is established...
... but the feudal court still stands.
Unless feudalism is uprooted,
our revolution isn't complete.
I await the day...
... I'll relinquish my position
to the person...
... who carries through the
abdication of the Qing Emperor.
What's going on?
I'd said it before, we shouldn't
rush to elect a President.
The Beiyang Army has been
mobilized, war will erupt very soon.
I heard Yuan Shikai has
even engaged assassins.
Who's afraid of assassins?
Mr. Sun, may I suggest,
in view of the situation...
... please ponder this seriously.
If Yuan Shikai doesn't
depose the Qing court...
... President Sun
will not step down.
Does Mr. Sun want to indulge
in the position of President?
Wang Zhaoming,
Sun Wen isn't that type.
Since he's so selfless,
what's the harm of my asking?
It's all about trust...
... belief...
... and faith...
... without any doubt.
I'm only afraid of an all-out battle
between the North and South.
Who'd be responsible for that?
If our revolution is
stolen by someone else...
... who'd be responsible for that?
Huang Keqiang, you...
Zhaoming.
Stop arguing, please.
I protect you
in front of everyone...
... but we must be frank
behind closed doors.
You don't have
to close any doors.
Just say it, Keqiang.
We cannot accede to any
of Yuan Shikai's demands.
But he has the power.
He can quickly
depose the Qing court.
To establish our republic...
... we need not only battles
but also politics.
This is revolution, not giving
a crown to someone else.
Sun Wen...
... the revolution doesn't
belong to any single person.
Keqiang...
... what do you mean?
You don't understand.
I don't?
You're accusing me of not
understanding politics.
But I know Yuan Shikai.
Keqiang.
You've never seen
how he killed young men.
I'm worried...
... he might become
an enemy of the republic.
He might even restore
autocratic rule.
It's my ninth wife's birthday.
Westerners celebrate
birthdays with cakes.
But we don't.
We eat peaches.
Look how festive they ere.
It hurts.
Please let go.
Where's Weiting?
I need to talk to him.
What happened?
Weiting...
... let's step aside.
What are you afraid of?
So what if I want to revolt?
So what?
It's high time
we race against Sun Wen.
Look at them.
Electing a president and
setting up a government.
The best peaches on the tree
are picked clean by others.
I'll kill you!
You're a madman.
Stop him!
Sputtering madness!
Help!
Please stop him!
Weiting.
Calm down.
Why did you hit him so hard?
At this moment, I can't
afford even one mistake.
You're right.
It's simple.
I'm sitting on a bed of nails.
If I don't force the court,
the situation is dire.
The revolutionaries
control half the country.
I can't oppose them
much longer.
But if the Emperor
abdicates because of me...
... I'll be blamed
for generations to come.
This is indeed a tricky situation.
The crux of the matter is,
I want to become President.
This is our room.
When I arrived,
I was full of resentment.
But now that I've seen you...
... I'm no longer angry.
Now, our baby is inside me.
Keqiang...
... this painting
will soon be finished.
But I can't decide
where to hang it.
I want to propose...
... Wu Tingfang to issue
a public statement.
If the Emperor doesn't abdicate,
the ceasefire will end.
Whoever tarries...
... whoever resists...
... will be punished by all.
If the truce cannot
be maintained...
... we'll declare war again.
If we resume war,
I'll lead troops to the North.
Keqiang, you were right.
I've thought long and hard.
We have to establish
provisional laws.
It's unimportant
who serves a single term.
What we must establish...
... is a system.
To restrain not
only Yuan Shikai...
... but anyone who ever dreams
of becoming an emperor.
Painter...
... please use bright red
for the flag with 18 stars.
Yes.
Comradres, I hear you are
disputing my resignation...
... but it takes more than a day
to rid 2000 years of feudal hegemony.
I do hope you will not
just focus on one official title...
... but create a truly relevant...
... legally protected
revolutionary system.
The world is immense. Those
who follow the righteous path thrive.
Those who do not
become extinct.
I hold fast to the revolution...
... knowing it will bear fruit.
After such a long journey...
... we will reach
our revolutionary goal.
What does Sun Wen want?
What telegram?
What declaration?
What war?
Mr. Jordan is right.
It is most important
to hold onto power.
The President's chair
isn't comfortable.
Even if it's full of pins...
... I still want to sit on it.
The British Ambassador
told me...
... that winter, like today...
... the winds were chilly.
It was snowing.
It was around Spring Festival,
but the entire city was desolate.
The atmosphere almost tragic.
The guillotine was placed...
... in the middle
of the public square.
Icicles of blood
still hanging on the blade.
Louis XVI...
... was bound and taken there.
He was cold,
without even a coat.
He was shivering.
Everyone brought their family
to witness this great occasion.
When the hour came...
... the executioner put the
King's head on the block...
... the blade was released...
... there was ice on his face.
Listen...
Go on, Yuan Shikai.
Go on.
Listen.
The whoosh of the blade.
Then?
Go on, Yuan Shikai.
Then it's the end.
The end?
That quick?
Yuan Shikai...
... you're fooling us.
You're making this up.
You've made up this story
from the West for us.
I reappointed you against
my better conscience...
... yet you do this to me?
Royal Prince,
appease your anger.
Did the French also
celebrate Spring Festival?
Royal Prince, calm down.
Royal Prince.
I've received news that...
... Sun Wen insists on a republic.
They will not compromise.
Empress Dowager...
... I tell you the story of
the French Revolution...
... because I don't want
you and the princes...
... to share the same fate.
I'm loyal to you.
Heaven can attest to it.
Yuan Shikai...
... come over here.
Come over!
Empress Dowager...
... I'm at your command.
If that day comes...
... you mustn't let us
face the guillotine...
... or let us starve.
Certainly.
Go back.
The South is eager
to resume battle...
... Empress Dowager,
please ponder this.
I know.
I take my leave.
- Prince Regent.
- Here.
Yuan Shikai has
broken his promise...
... he's banded with the rebels.
I do regret this.
I dismiss him as Prime Minister.
Things have developed thus.
It won't help.
They're still dragging their feet,
prolonging their dynasty?
They are acting against
the people's wishes.
How they overreach themselves.
They're becoming enemies
of all people!
What a pipe dream...
... thinking they can still hang on!
What happened?
Mr. Sun.
What is it?
Send a telegram.
Make it public.
Our Revolutionary Party's
patience is running out.
Don't these feudalists
have any shame?
Reporting to the
Empress Dowager...
... our Ambassador to Russia and
others have sent telegrams to you...
... hoping that you treasure
the Chinese people...
... rather than insisting
on one man's position.
There are mutinies in the
Northeast, Xinjiang and Tibet.
43 generals, including
Feng Guozhang and Duan Qirui...
... have signed a petition
in support of the republic.
Tell me something
I don't already know.
Empress Dowager.
We have served you
and the royal court.
We do not support
the idea of a republic.
Please do not falter
in your position.
Why would I falter?
It's all Yuan Shikai's doing.
Yuan had betrayed
Emperor Guangxu...
... now he betrays
Emperor Xuantong.
He's a real traitor!
His family has received
such grace from the court...
... yet he's such an unfilial cur.
He has the ambition of Wang Mang
in becoming Emperor.
If the Emperor doesn't abdicate,
he can't make his deal with the rebels.
I'd told you before,
he's not to be trusted.
As long as Aisin Gioro is here,
the Qing Dynasty will not fall.
Ancestors in Heaven...
... now other countries bully us...
... the revolutionaries run wild...
... our ministers are corrupt...
... they sell whatever they can
for their own gains.
There's nothing left now.
We have failed you.
At least Sun Wen is clement.
He doesn't invade the Palace...
... there are no guillotines.
We want a bloodless
revolution.
No more sacrifices...
... or needless killings.
Abdicate!
Friends, greetings.
This is a historical day.
Let's begin.
- Mr. President, this way.
- Come.
Have a angled pose.
How is it?
Mr. President,
please lift up your hat.
All right.
Let's change a pose.
Mr. President, this way.
Mr. President,
you look so young.
Such glib words.
When you cut my queue...
... don't hurry, take your time.
Move slowly.
This is a historical moment,
do you understand?
Yes.
You talk about revolution
and republic all the time.
A revolutionary has to
have a revolutionary look.
Let me show you today
Ambassadors...
... today I meet you as the
Provisional President...
... for the first time.
It's also the last time.
I can't believe this.
Before I leave
the Presidency...
... I hope you will request
your respective governments...
... to recognize our new country.
To you...
... and to the entire world...
... this is truly significant.
Mr. President...
... how do you plan to treat
the Qing royal family?
They'll also become citizens
of the republic.
The Revolutionary Party
has decided...
... to pay the royal family
4 million taels of silver.
Is that how you treat
your citizens?
Money cannot
be a measure here.
Not all revolutions
need guillotines.
What do you say,
Mr. Ambassador?
I agree.
When I was in England...
... I once met one of your
parliament members, Mr. Hillier.
I told him...
... when China is freed...
... I'd invite him as my guest.
I'll use Chinese liquor...
... Revolutionary liquor,
to toast you all.
Come.
Cheers.
Mingbao, Xinwenbao
and other newspapers...
... have published articles questioning
your decision to step down.
I read them.
We're in financial trouble.
We can't find funds for restitutions
to the martyrs' families.
We must find some money
no matter how.
People's representatives
want to meet you.
Please set up a time.
Oh, yes.
Homer Lea is determined...
... to resign from his post
as Military Advisor.
What's his reason?
He said he won't work
with Yuan Shikai.
Tell him...
... he's helping China,
not just a person.
This is a letter from Juemin.
Mr. Sun has been
keeping it for you.
He asks that I give it to you.
A few days ago, members of
the Tongmenghui came to see me.
They are planning a new grave.
They asked that I prepare
a funerary outfit.
I went to the shop.
When he was alive...
... Juemin and I always made
decisions together.
So I asked...
... "Juemin, which one
shall we choose?"
Only then did I know...
... he's really no longer with me.
Zhongxin...
... this is a letter
from your father.
Look.
"This letter to my wife...
... shouldn't be kept
only in this household."
"Keep it,
let others know about it."
Yesterday, the Qing Emperor
abdicated...
... ending two millennia
of monarchy.
Countless revolutionaries
have given up their lives...
... for our new republic.
Today, February 13, 1912...
... 26th day of the 12th moon
of the Xinhai Year...
... I'm fulfilling my promise...
... to resign from the post
of President.
We strive for the success
of the revolution...
... but do not covet recognition.
We are all of the same minds
to realize the goal of revolution.
This goal is to establish...
... an independent country
for the Chinese people.
We build a Chinese Republic
where land is divided among all.
Nationalism, democracy,
livelihood.
These are what
we strive to attain...
... The Three Principles.
Today you ask me...
... what does revolution mean?
Perhaps people will ask the
same question a century later.
Qiu Jin, our Tongmenghui member
who was killed in Shaoxing, said...
... "Revolution will provide
all children...
... a peaceful and gentle world."
Lin Juemin, one of the martyrs of
Huanghuagang, wrote this to his wife...
... "Revolution seeks eternal
happiness for everyone in the world.
I believe...
... the revolution enables
a republican system...
... to reach the people.
People will understand
we'll fight whoever...
... dares support the monarchy.
Revolution enables factories,
banks, railroads, mines...
... owned by the Chinese
to benefit the people.
Revolution enables our Chinese
race to become strong...
... no longer bullied by others.
We will no longer
be anyone's slaves.
Revolution can take place
anywhere, anytime...
... in any heart...
... forever...
... no longer afraid
of foreign powers...
... ridding the country of
feudalism and royalty.
No one will be impoverished...
... and the Chinese people
can stand tall in the East.
This is the meaning
of revolution.