See, the New Yorker in the Chanel
jacket that doesn't quite fit in?
That's me, Doctor Zoe Hart.
Yesterday,
I took a cab to my job
at one of Manhattan's best hospitals.
Today,
I'm on bus in the middle of nowhere.
But I guess
my journey really began four years ago
when I gave the commencement address
at my medical school graduation.
The first time I held a scalpel,
I was nine.
My publicist mother complained
that I didn't thank her enough
in my speech.
My dad and I snuck off
and dissected...
But there was somebody
in the crowd who liked it.
Dr. Hart?
It was quite a speech.
Thank you.
My name is Dr. Harley Wilkes.
I'm from BlueBell, Alabama.
I have a small private
practice there.
It's great town with great people,
and a great place
for a young doctor to hone her craft.
I'd like to offer you a job.
Thanks.
That's really flattering.
But I have a plan.
After I finish my surgical residency,
I'll do fellowship in thoracics.
Then I'll go on
to become a cardio-thoracic
surgeon like my dad.
Our last name's Hart,
so it's predestined.
Your offer is really sweet.
Thanks, though.
Bye.
My mother never wanted me
to be a surgeon.
Congratulations!
She thought the fluorescent
lights would give me wrinkles.
I know you'll be happy following
in your father's footsteps.
Can't help but notice
he didn't make it.
I know that must be
disappointing for you,
but that's your father.
Always thinking about himself.
He wanted to be here, but he
couldn't get out of Germany.
Some diplomat needed
a pacemaker put in.
Is that Katie Couric?
Katie!
Despite Mom's support, I had it all.
The most amazing boyfriend
who got what it was like
to be a surgeon, too.
Best part was, we both were
going to do our residencies
in the hospital where my dad did his
in the best city
in the world... New York.
My plan was on track.
Well, it's four years later,
and you know I wouldn't
be sitting next to a guy
who smells like fake cheese and chum
if it had turned out like I hoped.
First, the man I loved dumped me.
Because I liked
talking about surgery more
than I liked talking about his day.
But my dad taught me
that to be a great surgeon,
you can't let feelings
get in the way.
So, I kept my pain inside.
I could because
I was a shoe-in for...
What do you mean, I didn't get
the cardio-thoracic fellowship?
No one wanted this more than me.
I already did a solo coronary bypass.
Zoe, you've got the best hands
I've seen in 30 years,
but if you want
to be a heart surgeon,
then you got to work on your own.
By I do cardio five days a week.
You know what I'm taking about.
Last week, you ignored Mr. Zucker
when she asked you to read to her.
But I'm surgeon, not a librarian.
And Nicholas Sparks? Come on.
This morning, when that guy
came in with Horner's syndrome,
I'm the only one who
suspected aortic dissection.
I saved his life.
Yeah, but do you know his name?
I need to be
a cardio-thoracic surgeon.
What do I need to I do
to get next year's CT spot?
You need to learn to see
patients as people to help,
not puzzles to solve, so
if you want my recommendation
next year,
spend the next 12 months
as a general practitioner.
First of all, diarrhea
and diaper rash?
Ew. Second of all, I will never work
in private practice
without a specialty.
There isn't a single GP job
in this whole city.
That may be true,
Dr. Hart, but there are other places
to practice medicine
besides New York.
♪ ♪
Dad?
No, I didn't get the fellowship.
I know. Mom thinks it's, like, a sign
that I should be
a hand model or something.
You still believe in me,
though, right?
I know, I just have to figure
a few things out first,
but then, look out.
You're going to have a partner.
Oh, I know it's not that easy. I...
Okay. You go.
I love you, Dad.
Dad.
♪ ♪
I was lost.
Every fellowship was taken.
I had put all my eggs
in the wrong basket.
But then I saw it.
Another postcard
from that Southern guy, Harley.
He'd been sending me them
the last four years,
ever since graduation.
My speech really
must have inspired him.
"Tark Twins keep wrestling
in poison oak.
"Real busy.
Could use an extra,
extra-talented hand."
Dr. Wilkes, this is Zoe Hart
leaving a message.
You win.
I'm on my way.
DRIVER (over P.A.
BlueBell, Alabama.
Last stop on the Gulf Coast.
It wasn't New York.
It really, really wasn't New York.
But I was going to figure out
a way to make this work.
First, I needed a cab.
Can I offer you a ride, ma'am?
Thank you, but I have a strong policy
against strangers chopping me up
into a million pieces.
If it helps, I'm-I'm an attorney,
not an axe murderer.
All right, just...
just leave that there.
I'll get it for you.
Okay. Um, thank...
thank you.
No problem.
So, let me guess.
New Yorker?
I lived in, uh, Tribeca for a
while, when I worked at Cravath.
As in Cravath, Swaine and Moore?
Yup.
What are you doing here?
Take it you're not in town
for the crawdads, huh?
Um, I've been exiled from Manhattan.
This is my purgatory.
Well, if, uh, you consider purgatory
to be a place where neighbors
take care of each other,
and, uh, every third Tuesday
demands a parade.
And you can call
it what you want, but
I call it home.
♪ ♪
Thank you.
No problem.
I'm, uh, George Tucker.
Zoe.
Dr. Zoe Hart.
Well, uh...
Well, good luck, Dr. Zoe Hart.
I hope you find
what you're looking for.
♪ ♪
Hi.
Hello?
Is Dr. Wilkes around?
What rock you been living under
the last four months?
Harley passed away.
What?
He just sent me a postcard.
Are you Zoe Hart?
Yeah.
He told me if I kept
sending you his postcards,
eventually you'd show up.
Guess he was right.
Why would he want me to show up?
'Cause Harley left you his practice.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Okay. It's beyond weird.
Why me?
Harley never really explained.
Well, clearly, the man was one
avocado short of a Cobb salad.
But oddly, it works in my favor.
This is the catch of the day?
What were you expecting?
Sous-vide grouper
with a yuzu-mint gelée?
It's a gulf.
We got catfish. It's fried.
Ugh.
You... Hmm.
Look, Chief says I have
to spend a year as a GP,
and I don't want to waste a day,
so notify the town crier or whatever,
and let him know
I'm open for business.
Oh, no, no.
The thing is...
See, technically, Harley only
left you half the practice.
And he shares it with Dr. Breeland.
And Brick... he's been
waiting a long time
to get BlueBell all to himself.
Okay, well, let's just find him.
Tell him I'm here for only a year,
and then he can be the big fish
in the world's smallest pond.
No. Brick's hunting.
And that ain't the sort of news
you tell an Alabama man
when he's got his hog rifle
locked and loaded.
Whoa.
♪ ♪
Okay, someone needs to tell
the people of this town
that's it's 2011.
♪ ♪
Dancing in celebration
of the Confederacy? Really?
No. Dr. Hart, the Belles
are elite young ladies
chosen to keep our history alive.
You mock all you want, but,
actually, I wouldn't do it out loud,
because, uh, they're meaner
than they look.
The Belles?
Mm-hmm.
Emmeline, come on.
Oh, you can call me
Mrs. Hattenbarger.
And my husband put the
satellite in last year.
We watched every
episode of The Sopranos,
and believe me, that family
has got nothing on these girls.
When I heard there was a new
lady doctor in town, I painted myself
quite a different picture,
but you are just so pretty!
Zoe, this is Lemon Breeland.
Oh, okay.
You're Brick's daughter?
All right. Um, yeah,
it's really nice to meet you.
I'm dying to talk to your dad.
I know he's hunting or whatever,
but you must have a way
to contact him?
Oh.
Honey, there's no need for that.
He knows that you're here.
And if I were you, I'd be gone
by the time that he returns,
because Daddy can be quite...
imposing.
Well, you tell Daddy
that if my medical career
hasn't been killed by my mother
or the Chief of Surgery
at New York Hospital,
it most certainly won't be
by some Southern xenophobe
dressed up like a stick of butter.
Well, you have a good day.
I'm gonna see some patients.
Could you get me a venti soy
latte so I don't fatigue?
The nearest
high-falutin' coffee place
is 11 miles away.
Thanks. That is so nice of you.
Mom. Hi.
Sorry I haven't been answering.
No, actually, there's
something I need to tell you.
I moved to Alabama.
Mom?
Are you there?
Is Dr. Breeland around?
He's hunting.
Uh... my mom.
Freaking out.
I told her I moved here.
What's up? You sick?
Oh, I feel as good
as anyone my age would.
But there's been a little
mix-up down at the DMV.
Don't suppose you could sign this
for me?
Let me give you an eye test first.
Mom. Uh...
E, F, P,
T, O, Z...
No, you know
what happened with the fellowship.
It's a GP position.
...P, E, C, F...
Alabama, Mom.
The state?
- E...
- No, I'm not having a nervous breakdown,
okay? I...
D, F, C,
- No, it's the TV. Good-bye.
- Z, P.
All right.
Eh...
Thank you very much.
Oh, my latte.
Oh, yeah. Got thirsty
on the way and drank it.
You got a patient.
Oh.
I'm using subcuticular sutures.
So there will barely be a scar.
Well, it's not like I'm gonna
catch a fella now.
Hey, maybe you could give some
dating tips to my daughter here.
You know that thing
about the potato chips,
how you can't eat just one?
Big Mabel feels that way about lunch,
don't ya, honey?
She's always been chubby, but
she's put on a good half ton
since that boyfriend of hers
dumped her.
You'Yo all set.
Use the antibiotic cream twice a day.
Mabel, those dark
patches on your face,
how long have you had those?
I told her to use sunblock.
Come on.
No offense, but we'll be seeing
Dr. Breeland from now on.
You understand.
Clearly, I needed someplace to live.
Mrs. H. arranged for me
to stay at the mayor's plantation.
I was like, I'm not sleeping
at some old confederate guy's house.
But she said it was either that
or the sidewalk.
So...
No way!
You're the mayor?
Lavon Hayes, the linebacker?
Two Super Bowls, five Pro Bowls.
Four actually.
Well, I rounded up.
You got robbed in '06.
Oh, Lavon Hayes likes your math.
You must be Zoe.
- Yeah.
- Let me show you to your quarters.
All right.
- I got it.
- Are you sure?
Lavon Hayes will get your bags.
Thank you.
You know, you being the mayor here
is the first thing about
BlueBell that I actually like.
Thank you.
How'd that happen?
Well, after ten years in the NFL,
I was a little lost.
So, Lavon Hayes moved back home.
Having played for the Crimson Tide,
I was quite popular around here.
I ran, I won.
Here it is.
Let me get the door for you.
- Watch your step.
- Thanks.
Well, sorry about the
look of the place.
I think you could put your bags
in the back room there.
Huh, it's not my loft in Soho, but
I'll order some stuff
from Barney's online.
Make the place more homey.
You share a generator
with the guy in the gatehouse.
Looks after the place...
Wade Kinsella.
If you've got your curling iron
going while he's got his AC. on,
could be trouble.
Oh, if you do
decided to wander, um, keep your
eyes peeled for Burt Reynolds.
All right.
What?
♪ ♪
That sounds good.
I'm crushing the solo, ain't I?
Whoo!
- I'm killing it.
- You overheated the generator.
Nice nightgown.
I'm Wade.
Well, that smile might
make all the girls
at the church social swoon, but
it's not going to work on me.
Well, if you're not going
to be polite,
I'm not going to show you
where the fuse box is.
Good night.
All right, Wade.
Keep going, ladies, come on.
I'm just getting warmed up now.
Shh, shh, shh.
George?
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, what?
- Alligator.
- What?
- An alligator!
I'm sorry, I must have got
some mud in my ear.
An alligator.
And alligator?
Why didn't you say so?
That is an emergency.
Just stay, stay back.
Beat it, Burt.
That's Burt Reynolds,
the mayor's pet alligator.
His favorite movie's
Smokey and the Bandit, so...
- That's funny.
- Yeah.
All right.
Oh, come on.
Hey, hey.
I know you're a New Yorker
and everything,
but down here in Alabama, when
somebody interrupts their nightly jog
to climb into the mud
to save our well-toned ass,
we, you know, we say thank you.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
Oh.
Well, thank you.
I guess I'll be seeing you around.
Yeah.
See? Hey, small towns
have their perks, huh?
BlueBell isn't so horrible, Dad.
The people here aren't so bad.
Maybe I can make a difference.
I have another call.
Call me.
Are you getting my messages?
Bye.
Hello.
Did you sign Old Man Jackson's
eye exam for the DMV today?
Yeah. Why?
'Cause he just ran someone over.
Can't you tell a legally blind man
when he's right in front
of your face?
All you had to do was open his file!
Everybody knows Old Man Jackson
memorized the eye chart.
Oh, my God, I feel so bad.
I was distracted.
Well, you should be.
He nearly killed George Tucker.
If you wanted to see me again,
you could have just asked.
It's my shoulder.
Just...
All right.
Ready?
It's dislocated.
It's no big deal. I just
have to put it back into place.
What the hell?!
That's just the morphine.
It's the easy part... baby.
Eventually,
you're going to find out
this whole
getting-run-over-by-a-car thing
was kind of my fault.
Ow! You did it again!
Okay, have you never heard
of bedside manner?
Why is everyone so obsessed
with that?
Because it's nice!
George?
Good. Morphine's working.
OMG, it's true.
Rosie, honey, come on,
it's time for bed.
Aunt Emmeline, this is breaking news.
Rose Hattenbarger,
BlueBell beat blogger
for the otherwise torpid
official town Web site.
So, how does it feel
to be responsible
for maiming George
Tucker, town golden boy?
He is not maimed.
Off the record-- why would
anyone ever leave New York?
New York is everything, and I know.
Read the Daily Intel,
own all the SATC DVDs.
I bet you're a Carrie.
I'm a Charlotte, but
I wish I was a Carrie.
You guys really like
your classic HBO, huh?
But I am a Miranda who also
wishes she was a Carrie.
I knew you and I were
going to be friends.
Well, I guess I could use a friend.
Damn straight.
Brick's here.
Hello, Pickle.
Hi, Brick.
Um, I'll see you later.
We haven't met.
I'm Dr. Zoe Hart.
As far as I'm concerned,
you're just the girl
who almost killed
two people and spoiled
my hunting trip.
How dare you see my patients.
Well, technically, Harley left
his half of the practice to me.
Miss Hart, I'm not going
to share this office...
not for one minute.
I see you have met my lawyer.
When he's conscious, he doesn't lose.
I'm going to be contesting the will.
Harley wasn't in his right mind.
You haven't even given me a chance.
I believe I can do some good here.
Well, bless your heart.
But thingsave been working
just fine here in BlueBell.
We survived Katrina, we survived BP,
by boarding up the windows
and piling up the sandbags
to keep the rot outside
from fouling our community.
And believe you me, Zoe Hart,
we are going to chase you away
from our waters.
Well, my night
had quickly gone downhill.
But in times like this,
I find one thing
really helps me through.
Wine! Tell me you have
a nice dry chardonnay.
Yup. Come on.
You're Mabel, right?
Bad day?
You have no idea.
Ugh. Oh, yes, I do.
You met my mama?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, my mom isn't
exactly supportive, either.
Mabel, I know
it's none of my business,
but the dark patches
on your forehead and face...
you have melasma.
You know you're pregnant, right?
I don't know that.
I haven't taken a test.
Well, I'm sure you can get one here
over by the Slim Jims and duck calls.
Long day.
I didn't think...
We only had sex once.
He told me
he wouldn't do it
if he had to wear a condom.
I didn't want to lose him,
but he left anyway.
So, my mother's right.
I'm stupid.
Look, you need a doctor.
Here. Take this.
Can I have this?
I'm gonna give you my number,
and you can call me,
and I won't tell anybody, okay?
Okay, I'll take that.
Hmm.
Thank you.
Owe you some money.
Do you realize that my
engagement party is tomorrow?!
Huh? I mean, what
am I supposed to do?
The photographs!
The press!
The whole thing's
just gonna be ruined!
Seriously, Lemon,
what are you blabbering about?
Well, thanks to you,
my fiancé was in a car accident.
You're engaged to Old Man Jackson?
No, you twit.
I'm engaged to George Tucker.
Clearly, BlueBell
wasn't the answer.
I'd messed up as a doctor
and gotten the guy
I kind of liked run over.
Oh, and it turns out he was engaged.
♪ ♪
I had sunk to my lowest point.
Well, maybe not my lowest.
Nice first day.
Everyone knows Old Man J
memorized the eye chart.
Don't you have some cows to tip,
Wade?
Oh.
Look at you, girl.
You're drunk as a boiled owl.
I'd offer to give you a ride, but
I don't want you getting any ideas.
I was making out
with the electricity-stealing
buffoon from next door.
But it gets worse.
There it is.
Rock bottom.
Oh, my God.
I just played "Dixie" with my butt.
This never happened.
You hear me?
My lips are sealed, Doc.
Get me out.
Oh! Oh! Ow!
♪ ♪
Mom!
What the hell are you thinking?
I get that you feel
you had no choice.
What I don't understand is why
this Harley would try so hard
to get you down here.
I mean, no offense. Your speech
was great, but really, why?
I'm not sure.
It's possible he was nutballs.
I don't care what the chief said.
Nothing is worth you
spending a year here.
And your father agrees with me.
Wait. You talked to Dad?
Well, he called me after
he heard your message
that you left last night.
How do you think I found you?
Well, he called you instead of me?
Um, you know him.
He can't deal with complications.
But, honey... do you belong here?
Let's go home.
She was right.
I didn't belong in BlueBell.
We made arrangements
to leave at 5:00.
I called George.
That was awkward.
He asked to meet me on the pier.
Guess he wasn't dying
to be seen with me in public.
Can't say I blamed him.
Glad to see you're feeling better.
Uh, I know you have
your party to get to,
but this is time-sensitive.
I'm going back
to New York this afternoon.
Really? I'll take it
that, uh, exile was lifted?
Can I have the papers, uh,
for, you know, signing
over half the practice
to Brick?
Yeah, of course.
I, uh... I heard about
your run-in with Lemon
last night, and I...
I-I should have told you.
What? That you're engaged?
I mean, between
the alligator
and getting hit by a car,
you kind of had a lot
going on last night.
Look, you should've known Lemon
when we were younger.
I mean,
she's funny, she's irreverent.
And I just was honored that she...
that she chose me.
But, uh,
you know, after law school, I just...
I needed, uh... change.
You know, so I decided
to move to New York, and
I loved it in the city.
But I woke up dreaming
about the sunset,
and, uh, having sand beneath my feet,
and I realized that BlueBell,
and, uh, Lemon...
they're who I am.
You know, can't really be
my best self without them.
Wow. You're a lucky guy.
A girl you feel the same way
about as a town.
The papers?
Thanks.
Uh, I'll mail them
when I get back to New York.
Okay.
Good-bye, George Tucker.
♪ ♪
Hello?
Dr. Hart?
It's Mabel.
I don't feel...
well.
But I'm-I'm working
at the Breelands'.
I can't leave.
Can you come here, please?
Mabel, I have a plane.
If you're at the Breelands', why
don't you just talk to Brick?
Brick the dick? No way!
You said you'd be my doctor
if I needed you.
Didn't you take an oath or something?
I know I'm
not invited,
but I'm a doctor.
This is a medical emergency.
Silly, this is
Brick Breeland's house.
He is the doctor.
Actually, she's here with me.
Lavon Hayes.
Mayor.
Yeah.
I do believe that
entitles me to a plus one.
Mm-hmm.
♪ ♪
How you doing, ladies?
Good to see you.
Thank you.
I gotta go find Mabel.
Oh? Well, not a problem.
This party could use
a little shaking up.
I do believe
Lavon Hayes needs himself a cocktail.
Look, I am sorry
about the photographs.
I know how hard
you planned today and...
Oh, honey, I don't care
about the pictures.
That much.
I don't know what's become of me.
All the stress from the wedding has
just turned me into a
real... 'Bama beeotch.
But...
I love you.
I really do.
And nearly losing you last night
just reminded me of how much.
And I promise that I'm gonna try
real hard to be the same old Lemon
that you fell in love with, okay?
Oh!
- Uh, Zoe? Is everything okay?
- What are you doing here?!
I came with the mayor.
Lavon?
Okay, well, uh, welcome.
And the bar is over...
that way.
Thought you said she
was leaving town.
I thought she was.
Mabel?
Thank you so much for coming.
I'm having these bad pains.
Oh, my God, there's another one.
Okay.
Oh, they're getting worse.
Mabel, how long has it been exactly
since your last period?
Not sure.
Another one?
They're 15 seconds apart.
Okay, Mabel, stay calm.
Look, we're not gonna make it
to the hospital.
You're having a baby,
and you're having it now.
Come on.
What is going on here?
Brick, she's ten centimeters,
ready to push.
Contractions are on
top of each other.
We need to deliver this baby.
No, I need to deliver this baby.
Have Emmeline get me my
medical bag, my drug box.
- Get me some towels.
- No, no, no, no, no,
don't you come near me!
Dr. Hart and I,
we're in this together.
She's my doctor.
Guess I'll be needing the towels.
Okay, Mabel, Mabel,
are you ready?
I'm gonna need you to
start pushing, okay?
I'm gonna come check on you later.
Make sure you're all right.
All right.
So, Mr. Mayor, is it true?
You're here on a date
with that, uh... Dr. Hart?
How is that any of your business?
I mean, if I do recall,
we are at your engagement party.
Lavon...
come on.
You know how difficult
this is for me.
Difficult never stopped me.
You're doing great, okay?
I see the head.
Another contraction.
I need you to push again
on the count of three.
One, two, three.
Go, go. Push!
Oh, no!
Brick, the shoulder.
It's lodged in the pelvis.
Push her head back in, I mean...
The ambulance is on the way.
They'll have to do
a C-section in Mobile.
Isn't that 20 miles away?
All right. Mrs. H, I need you
to hand me my scalpel.
- What are you doing?
- A symphysiotomy.
No, I can't let you slice
open her pelvis like that.
It is way too dangerous.
We have no choice, okay?
This baby comes out now,
or we lose both of them.
Okay, Mabel?
I'm going to give you
a local to dull the pain,
but I can't have you numb
r when you need to push.
You're going to feel a little pinch.
Ready?
Ahh!
Now, I need you two
to hold her steady until
it's all over, no matter what.
And after she delivers,
I'm going to close her
up as soon as possible.
Brick, that means the baby's
all you. Are you with me?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
Okay. Ready?
Hang on, hang on.
Come on.
I... ow, ow, no,
please, please, it hurts too much!
Losing way too much blood.
Come on, Mabel.
Mabel, don't you pass out on me.
Mabel, come on.
I need you to push.
Hey.
I know you're tired, and
I know you're in pain,
but I need you to be strong.
Stronger than you've
ever been in your entire life.
You can do this.
Now give me one big push.
- Here you go.
- Okay?
♪ ♪
Oh...
Is she okay?
Yeah.
She got ten fingers and ten toes,
and those lungs that would
make Carrie Underwood jealous.
You got yourself
a healthy baby girl.
Nice job.
You know, it's too bad you're
not going to be staying.
George told me you were going
to sign the practice back over.
Well, I'll go tell the
paramedics we're fine.
Mabel,
what you did for your daughter...
you were amazing.
Don't ever forget
how much strength you have.
A baby?!
You have got to be kidding.
I have a patient recovering here.
Dr. Hart, it's okay.
Look, Mama...
I made a beautiful, perfect person.
How she grows up,
how she looks at herself,
that's on me now.
And I'm not gonna
expose my baby to you.
So, please...
get out.
Yeah...
You ju...
You just can't leave now.
Thank you, Mrs. H.
That means a lot, coming from you.
I was happy I could help.
It was nice.
Great, actually.
But I mean, come on.
BlueBell?
I don't fit in here.
Everybody hates me.
Plus the humidity is
really ruining my hair.
I'm not a family doctor.
I'm gonna be
a cardio-thoracic surgeon.
I've known since I was nine.
I just have to figure out
another way.
You asked me before why Harley
left you his practice.
I didn't tell you the whole truth.
I didn't think it
was my place. But...
I've been carrying this
around since, uh...
since you got here.
Didn't know if I should
give it to you, but...
Here.
That's my mom.
And...
Harley?
Yeah, Zoe.
Harley Wilkes was your father.
Wha...?
You're here! Great!
There's a superb Sancerre
chilling in the car.
We need to talk.
Oh, my...
Oh my God.
Zoe, I can explain.
What's there to explain?
That my entire life has been a lie?
This is the answer to
everything, isn't it?
Why Harley left me the practice,
why Dad stopped loving me?
Because I wasn't his to love.
He knew, didn't he?
When you were ten,
you fell off the swings,
they thought you would
need a transfusion.
But when he donated blood...
He tried to stay in your life,
but I guess it was too hard.
That's why he left?
And what about Harley?
Why not tell me about him?
Was he a psycho?
A pedophile? What?
He was a mistake.
I met him on a cruise.
It was Greece.
He was handsome, older, a gentleman.
It was a fantasy.
But I was engaged.
To someone real.
Did you love him?
It doesn't matter.
I did not belong with him,
just as my child
does not belong in a place like this.
I gave you a father
who was from our world.
I protected you.
That should've been my choice.
I am sorry, Zoe, okay?
I am truly, deeply sorry.
But, please, can we just go home
and discuss this in therapy
like normal people?
You go.
I'm staying here.
Growing up, I was told
that to be a surgeon,
I couldn't let myself feel.
But then, I came to BlueBell.
All the food here is fried.
The whole town smells like mold.
And clearly, the sex
education system is lacking.
They could use a good doctor.
One who cares about her patients.
Maybe, even though you're gone,
there are still some things
you can teach me.
No one ever believed
in me like you did.
You kept sending me
those postcards...
knowing one day I'd be lost.
And maybe following in your...
my real father...
your footsteps for a while, um,
I might find my way.
Thanks.
♪ ♪
Hi.
Zoe, where are you?
I got the Tark Twins here again.
Let me guess.
They were wrestling
in poison oak?
You got it.
I'll be right there.
See you soon, Dr. Hart.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com