Previously on "The L.A. Complex":
Investigator:I'm the insurance
investigator assigned to your case.
Connor:
Can I give you my number?
Oh, I've got your number.
I know a way you can make
a lot of money real fast.
I pay you $25 dollars,
every card you swipe.
We're making a movie,
do you wanna be in it?
- Do you die at the end?
- Yes.
When do we start?
Admit it,
you miss this a little bit.
You signed me up
to take the S.A.T.'s?
- Who are you?
- I'm your sister.
It breaks my heart to think
that you're not living
your ideal life.
I wanna help you do that.
How?
I'm with the church
of scienetics.
I'm in.
I'm not Simon's legal guardian.
Dad! Put him down!
Please!
Dean:
This is for his own good.
Put the boy down.
Dean:
Okay. Buddy...
What're you doing?
I need more than 4000 minutes.
Dynasty:The studio has
security cameras.
They record everything
all onto one little hard drive.
Kaldrick: What the
hell you doing here?
Rook:
He's with me.
I wanna do this, you and me.
Who is it?
Sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com
We probably shouldn't
be doing this.
It's a terrible idea.
Cam:
Aaaaand... cut.
You guys killed that!
Cam: Okay, I wanna go one more time.
Connor and Raquel:
Why?
Uh, let's just do a loose one,
see what you guys find.
He can't do loose takes.
Play around with it,
you know how the scene goes.
Play around, have some fun.
Connor: Play arou-
Cam: Good. Ready?
Play around.
Okay.
Cam:
Aaaand... action.
Whenever you're ready.
What?
You're so beautiful.
Detective:
Connor Lake?
Connor:
Yeah?
Uh, what the hell is this?
Detective: Connor Lake,
you're under arrest
for arson
and insurance fraud.
You have the right
to remain silent.
If you give up
that right,
anything you say can
and will be used against you
in a court of law.
Christopher:
Here.
Anyone come by
to give you an update?
Not yet.
Let's sit.
(Sighs)
Thank you.
It's a fifty-cent cup
of hospital coffee.
No. Thank you
for being here.
Your dad just had a stroke.
Where else would I be?
Nurse:
Mr. Kiing?
Kaldrick:
How is he?
Without more tests,
it's hard to say.
Then why aren't you
doin' those tests?
Your father's
insurance provider
is refusing to cover his care.
They're claiming
he missed a payment.
The hospital needs proof
his bill can be paid
before we continue
to treat him.
Christopher:
The man's in a coma...
Kaldrick:
You want proof?
Do you know who I am?
Do you?
Here, you want proof?
Here's your proof.
Take that.
I am just doing my job, sir.
Your job is to take care
of my father!
He needs something,
you get it for him.
This is not some bum
off the streets!
Matter of fact,
get him his own room.
I don't want him sharing a room
with these other people.
He shouldn't be moved
right now.
Then move them!
Get them another room!
This one belongs
to Walter Dougan.
Christopher:
Kal! Kal! Kal!
Kaldrick:
The hell is wrong with you?!
Christopher:
Stop!
Just let me handle this.
I apologize for his behaviour.
He's obviously very upset.
But I assure you
it's in your best interest
to provide this patient
with the highest level of care
available.
Do you really wanna be
the reason
this hospital gets sued?
You wanna help me with this?
Charlotte: What do you mean?
Where did they take him?
All:(Talking all at once)
Uh... well... they um...
You didn't ask?
(Talking over one another)
One of you didn't go with him?
I mean, it all happened
pretty quickly...
I think we just need
to concentrate
on what to do now.
I'll handle it.
Raquel: I get that you're
upset - I'm upset also...
Charlotte: I'll handle it!
(Door bangs shut)
I guess she's gonna handle it.
Hi, this is Charlotte Lake.
I need to speak to Roxanne.
Can you try calling me?
(Phone rings) Dammit!
Who is it?
Is it Nick?
Ugh!
Let it go to voicemail.
These Will Arnett
sketch-show jerks
said I would hear today
if I was moving on
and I still haven't heard yet.
Nick: Well, you know, it's
today all day, right?
Maybe let them eat breakfast
before you start
calling them jerks.
Sabrina:
I didn't get it.
I did all new material
because of my bad back
and I just-
I blew it.
I watched your whole set
from the wings.
You tore it up out there.
Sabrina: I don't have a job,
my parents cut me off,
my bank account is plummeting.
Nick, what am I doing?
You're freaking out!
Relax.
We don't need to worry
about money...
We both still have checks
coming from the PFT show,
right?
Plus this gig I'm doing
for Chuck today
apparently pays really well.
So what is this gig?
It's uh... just a...
private party
for some network executive.
It's his birthday or something.
Oh God.
I'm gonna be sitting around
watching my prospects dry up
while you're schmoozing
with a room
full of greenlighters.
Hey...
You're gonna get it.
Meanwhile...
Let me be
the breadwinner today.
(Sighs heavily)
At least your back's
feeling better.
Connor:
I didn't do anything!
Detective:
Then this should be easy.
Did you or did you not
set fire to your home
for the purpose of making
an insurance claim.
I did not.
Detective:But you did set fire
to your home?
Connor:
No! Uh...
(Sighs) Not on purpose.
It was an accident.
Detective: Why didn't
you try putting it out?
I did.
Not with the fire extinguisher
in your kitchen you didn't.
And why were you
drinking a beer
on the front lawn
when first responders arrived?
It was hot.
In your statement
you claimed the fire started
while you were making tea.
It was less hot then.
So after your kitchen
exploded into flames
you moved towards the fridge,
away from the exit,
to grab a beer?
It's illegal to have
bad judgment?
Why didn't you call 911?
My phone was dead.
Detective:
You're an actor, right?
My wife watches you
on that show.
I can't stand it,
but she says
you're pretty good.
Real believable.
I'm on a tv show!
You think that's
gonna help you?
Connor:
No. I have money.
Why would I commit
insurance fraud?
It doesn't make any sense.
You're the star
of a network tv series
and you live in
a long-stay motel.
Patrons at a bar,
earlier in the year,
witnessed you
instigate a fight
that got you thirty stitches
and almost cost you an eye.
Do these sound like the actions
of someone who's concerned
with making sense?
I want a lawyer.
You okay, buddy?
Dad's not very grown up
for a grown-up, is he?
(Knock at the door)
Beth:
Who is it?
Cam: Hey, it's just us.
How you guys doing?
We've been better.
Kevin: Wanna help
me make a movie?
Can I steal him?
(Clears throat)
Bad choice of words.
Sure.
Kevin: How do you feel
about wearing a dog suit?
Simon:
What type of dog?
I have something
that might cheer you up.
Oh really?
And what's that?
S.A.T. Results came.
Oh God!
No? Not...
Not cheering you?
No, I don't wanna...
I can't open it.
Okay.
I don't- cam!
Oh my God!
I got nineteen-hundred.
I got nineteen hundred
on my s.A.T.'S!
Oh my God!
(Cam laughs)
I knew you'd own that thing!
Well, what do I do now?
Go to college?
(Laughs) Yeah.
I'm serious.
(Gasps)
No!
Oh my God!
You should get some sleep.
I don't wanna sleep.
What if he dies?
He's not going to.
But what if he does?
He still has no idea who I am.
Christopher:So tell him,
as soon as he wakes up.
What did we do?!
We got married.
Abby:You think I don't know
that we got married?!
I know we got married!
I'm asking why?
Why did we get married?!
Because we wanna spend
the rest of our lives together?
I don't even know
your last name!
It's Sanders, okay?
And technically
it's your last name now too.
Unless you wanna keep
your own name,
'cause that's fine.
I can't believe
I let you talk me into this.
Whoa! Hey, look,
all I did was propose.
I mean, you're the one
who suggested
the road trip to Vegas.
Yeah, after we had
three bottles of champagne
and you gave me your whole...
I-need-more-than-4000-minutes
line!
What are we gonna do?
Go on our honeymoon?
I'm serious, Gray!
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Come here, please?
What do you wanna do?
Do you really...
think that we can do this?
(Sighs) We did do this.
When's my birthday?
What's my favourite movie?
What foods do I like?
I don't know, tell me.
We don't know each other.
I like you and...
I might even love you,
but this is a mistake.
Charlotte:
Hi, this is Charlotte Lake.
I called earlier
about my brother's arrest,
and I was wondering if...
Well, can I talk to Roxanne?
I really...
Well, can you just pull her
out of the adjust?
Don't you think this is
a little more important than...
No, I can't hold,
my brother's just been arrested!
Shouldn't you be
shooting the movie
with Kevin today?
Nah!
Raquel has to work.
Kevin's just gonna grab
a bunch of little shots
around the Lux.
What's the point of this?
I can't go to college,
it doesn't matter
how good my test scores are.
There's no harm
in looking, right?
Right.
Taylor:
Cameron? Cameron!
Cam: Taylor!
Taylor: Hi!
Cam:
What're you doing here?
I got back from Brazil
last semester.
I'm doing my phd here!
What?! That's crazy!
Good for you.
Thank you.
(Awkward laugh)
Sorry, Taylor,
this is my girlfriend, Beth.
Beth, this is Taylor...
His first girlfriend.
Hey, I had girlfriends
before you.
Taylor:
Oh, sorry,
I thought "girl he lost
his virginity to"
would make everyone
uncomfortable.
Well, thank God
you didn't say that.
(Awkward laughter)
What are you studying?
Taylor:
I'm doing my dissertation
on pornography
and sexual politics
in the age of universal access.
Wow.
Cool.
Whatever happened to submission
in the modern marriage?
I got bored.
What about you?
Still making movies?
Cam: Um, yeah, well, you know...
Trying.
Are they like the movies
we used to make?
Cam:Uh... no.
(Awkward laugh)
No, no, they're different
than those.
I'm just showing Beth around.
She's thinking of going here.
We're dating.
Yeah. I'm thinking
of studying English.
Oh, well, you'll have
such a great time here.
Cameron sure did.
But, uh, I should go,
I'm late for a lecture.
Whose class?
Mine.
Anyway, it was really nice
to meet you.
Good luck.
Thanks. Bye, Cameron.
Bye.
(Clears throat)
So... campus tour?
Yeah.
Good morning.
Yup.
Mark:
Or not...
What's wrong?
One of my friends
just got arrested.
For what?
Arson and insurance fraud?
(Laughs)
Sorry, that's not appropriate.
No, I don't know what
the appropriate reaction is.
Well, are you okay?
Do you need to leave?
How close are you?
He's an ex-boyfriend.
Well, I think he's guilty.
He has family
taking care of it.
I think I just need
to keep busy.
I can keep you busy.
With restaurant-things,
I meant.
I meant restaurant-things,
I swear.
(Dull thud of loud
thumping music)
What?
Manny: Sup.
Raquel: Sup.
Did I give him a raise
I don't know about?
Sabrina:
There's no space in here!
This is not a room
for two people!
Nick:
Hello?
Sabrina: And did you know
you have a whole drawer
full of workout gear?
Who are you kidding?
We're throwing this out.
Nick:
Hey, hey, hey!
Sabrina: You need to
buy more shelves!
You need to buy more shelves,
you need a dresser, or...
Nic:Okay, calm down.
I'll buy you a dresser.
Oh! Everything's so easy
for you.
Nick:
What is this about?
Nothing!
You sound weird.
How's it going?
Has the network guy
got you your own pilot yet?
Nick:Turns out it's his daughter's
bat mitzvah.
Ugh!
That's almost better.
There's probably dozens
of celebrity parents there.
Nick:
Yeah, I'm...
Super-psyched about it.
Planner: No! No, no, no!
No phones!
Oh, I-I gotta go.
Uh, sorry, I just...
S-s-s-stop! Stop.
No, no, no.
You can't take off your head
in front of the children.
But the children
are around all the time.
Well, Chuck never
breaks character.
So? I'm not...
Do you see that girl
right there?
This is the most important day
of her life.
Today she leaves
childhood behind
and she becomes a woman.
Nick:
If she is a woman,
then she knows full well
there's a man inside
this bunny costume,
who's sweating
and would love to take
his head off.
You take the head off,
you don't get paid.
Detective:
All right,
give Dr. mcdreamy here
his phone call.
Charlotte:
He didn't do it!
Connor:Charlotte,
what are you-?
Charlotte:He didn't burn
his house down.
Detective:
How do you know?
Because I did.
Charlotte: It was me.
I set the fire.
That's not what
your brother says.
Charlotte:He's always been
over-protective.
Let me guess,
he's probably saying that-
Connor:
She's lying!
She had nothing to do with it!
It was me!
I set the fire!
Detective:That's not
what you said before.
Well, I was lying before!
Detective:
Why'd you set it?
A lot of reasons.
I suffer from depression,
among other things.
Connor: Why would she
set my house on fire?
That doesn't make any sense!
What does she have to gain?
Charlotte: Mostly I just
wanted to watch it burn.
Sometimes the only way
I can let go
is to release something
that feels more out of control
than I do.
What did my brother say?
Insurance money?
(Inaudible conversation)
Mark: Hey, man, get back to work.
Can I talk to you
about the new drink special?
Raquel:
Mm-hmm.
Hey, is Manny running scrips?
Scripts?
Like...
What, do you mean
screenwriting?
No, "scrips" scrips.
Like is he a "pharmacist"?
What do you mean?
A drug dealer -
is he a drug dealer?
Does he deal drugs?
Uh, no, I don't think so.
More importantly,
is he dealing drugs in here?
No. Where is this
coming from?
The guy makes
$8 dollars an hour
plus tip-out,
how can he afford
that spaceship
sitting outside?
Well, I'm sure
it's a lot more practical
than it looks.
You know, it probably
gets great mileage.
(Sighs) No, it doesn't add up.
You don't think
he's stealing from me?
No. (Laughs)
Manny stealing?
Come on, no.
Look, no.
Mm-mm.
Something's not right.
♪ Nails and lipstick ♪
♪ just a quick fix ♪
♪ guaranteed to make you shine ♪
♪ shine ♪
♪ on the surface... ♪
Nick: Oh hey, kids!
Do you wanna...
Right.
Hey, Chuck, you feeling okay?
You gotta get in there, man,
mix it up.
Oh, ah, I'm not Chuck.
I'm just filling in
for the day.
Magician:
Oh. (Laughs) Sorry.
Nice to meet you.
You like magic?
Nick:
Uh...
Wow. Cool.
Magician:
Jeff the incredible.
So you gonna be the new
Mr. barnsworth p. Bunnyton
from now on?
Nick: No!
No, no, no, I'm just...
I'm filling in for the day.
Magician: Yeah, that's
how I got started,
filling in for a friend.
That was seven years ago.
Have you met Francis yet?
Nick:Why is he staring at me
like that?
Magician: Because clowns
are on their way out
(raises his voice)
And he knows it!
He's the past,
we're the future...
Mitzvah-wize.
Think of a card.
Ace of spades.
Nick:
(Dryly) Yup.
Beth:
So...
Taylor seems... beautiful.
How long did you guys
go out for?
Four years?
And when did you break up?
Six... seven months ago?
Wow, so recent.
What happened?
Taylor's...Exhausting -
in a number of ways.
Ah.
Uh, not like that.
I mean...
She's exhausting emotionally.
Uh-huh.
How old is she?
She's like twenty-three,
and she's already
going after her phd,
and giving lectures?
Uh, yeah, I guess.
How can you like
someone like her
and someone like me?
I mean, you're clearly
still into her,
I'm not-
by the way.
You're both smart.
What is this?
What am I to you?
Is this serious
or is this just convenient?
What part of our relationship
has been convenient so far?
Okay, yes, I am still
attracted to Taylor...
She's attractive.
And a cuckoo-bird -
she's crazy.
I broke up with her
because I wanted
to break up with her.
Where is this coming from?
What am I doing here, cam?
(Knocking)
Professor raynor:
Cam!
Cam: Hey! Thanks so much
for seeing us, Dr. raynor.
Professor raynor: No problem.
You must be Beth.
Yeah.
Dr. raynor: You know, the
way he described you
I thought you'd be taller.
He said you had some questions
I might be able to answer?
Yeah.
Come on in.
Thank you.
Court clerk:
Okay.
If you both just sign
and date here, and here...
And just initial here,
and here...
That should just about do it.
Tick tock,
tick tock.
Sorry.
All right.
Once I file the paperwork
your marriage will be
null and void.
Great.
Court clerk:
Relax.
People make mistakes.
Abby: Oh, no, I don't think
it was a mistake, really,
as much as, you know,
we just kinda rushed into...
That'll be
five hundred dollars.
(Clears throat)
Abby: Do you...?
Gray: Yeah, no, I do.
Dawna:
Sean?
Hey.
They called as soon
as I got into work.
I'm so sorry.
How is he?
They don't know.
He hasn't woken up.
They're running tests.
How are you?
I don't know.
I'm sorry,
I should've called you.
Dawna:
I missed you.
Christopher:
Hey.
This is all they had.
(Sighs) This is dawna.
Hi.
I'm Christopher.
Nice to meet you.
(Tearful sigh)
I uh...
I'm sorry,
I don't... I just um...
I thought...
Okay, I don't know
what I thought.
I hope Walter's okay.
Bye, Sean.
It was nice meeting you.
Yeah, you too.
I'm gonna take a walk.
Nurse:
Mr. Kiing?
Your father's awake.
Manny:
You hit it just right,
you don't even need to use
the clutch to shift.
Raquel: Hey, Manny, can I talk to
you for a second over here, please?
Manny:
Sup wasteland?
I always got time for you.
What the hell are you doing?
Talkin' to Zeus?
You know what
I'm talking about.
What're you doing
driving that car here?!
I got tired of taking the bus.
You give me all this talk
about how safe
and low-profile
this credit card scam is
and you show up driving
the time machine
from back to the future!
What're you doing
playing footsies
with the guy
we're stealing from?!
First of all,
we're not stealing from him,
we're stealing
from his customers!
No!
And second...
I am not playing
"footsies" with...
You might as well be!
Tell him that's not your car!
But it is my car.
Tell him it's not your car.
Fine! You keep it
in your pants!
Fine.
He suspicious, okay?
That's all.
So make him unsuspicious.
What?
You want out?
No.
I want a bigger cut.
If you can afford that car
off of this scam,
I want more
than $25 bucks a card.
Fine. Forty.
Fifty.
Fine.
Detective:
Sit down.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Detective: Talking to you separately
doesn't seem to be working,
so let's all have
a big conversation together
and see if we can't get
our stories straight.
Charlotte:
It was me.
I don't know why
you keep covering for me.
Charlotte, stop-
enough!
Now, one of you torched
the house,
and one of you
is obstructing justice.
Come clean right now
and I'll drop
the obstruction charge.
Don't, and you're both
going to jail.
Connor: Look, I appreciate what
you're trying to do for me,
i really do,
but there's no point in us
both getting in trouble.
Just tell him the truth.
(Door opens)
Dale Roberts: Stop talking.
Detective: Do you mind?
Detective: I'm in the middle
of an interrogation-
stop talking to them.
Excuse me?
Dale Roberts: I'm their lawyer.
This is over.
I think people do what
they do for a reason, okay,
and we got married.
On a whim though.
We didn't think it through.
Yeah! Absolutely!
One hundred percent!
Okay, but admit it.
Part of you was happy
this morning
when you woke up
with that ring -
a hell of a lot happier
than you are
sitting in this truck
right now.
Maybe a little bit.
I leave for another tour
tomorrow.
What if we just stayed married
while I'm gone?
That's crazy.
Is it though?
You could get your green card,
I'd get a bigger paycheck...
Half of which I'd send
to you every month.
Let the air force
pay the bills,
you just focus on acting.
What happens when you get back?
We buy a house with a fence
and have a bunch of kids?
I don't know.
I mean, we just...
We figure that out then.
You keep this ring...
And you think about me,
cuz I'm gonna be
thinking about you.
Maybe it was a mistake
to get married this quick,
but I know, sitting here
looking at you right now,
that getting unmarried
would be a way bigger one.
So what do you say?
(Circus music plays)
Nick: So I'm having
sex with this girl
and she informs me
that the only way
she can have an orgasm
is if I choke her.
Stop!
You are in a bunny suit!
You gotta do Chuck's material!
Chuck told me I could do
my own material!
You cannot, sir.
You cannot.
He didn't leave you a set list?
Yeah, yeah,
he left me set list.
You wanna see his set list?
Here it is!
Raccoons, me and Santa,
flippity-flop.
What am I supposed to do
with this?
I don't know,
but you cannot go out there
and tell jokes about
sexual asphyxiation
to a bunch
of 12-year-olds!
(Smattering of applause)
Magician: Francis is done.
You gotta get out there.
Nick: Wait! I don't have any material?
What do you want me to do?
Listen, it's not my problem.
Don't do magic.
Ladies and gentleman,
girls and boys,
direct from carrotsberg,
north hareolina,
please put your paws
together for...
The wacky joke-stylings of
Mr. barnsworth p. Bunnyton!
(Kids applaud and cheer)
Magician:
Hop! Hop!
Nick:
Thanks. Thank you...
(Mouths "go")
Okay, so the other day,
I'm having...
Milkshake the other day...
With this girl
and she informs me
the only way she can
enjoy her milkshake is
if I'm holding her hand.
(Kids chuckle and snicker)
Uh... so I'm holding her hand
and it's not going great...
But in my defense,
what about this suggests
"good at hand holding"?
(Kids laugh)
I mean if you're gonna cast
your fantasy hand-holder,
why would you pick a James
Franco-looking bunny rabbit?
Uh, and not a... dimply,
Justin bieber?
(Kids cheer and applaud)
Yeah! Or uh...
The vampire show guy?
(Kids cheer)
Yeah! There it is!
Now imagine those two
holding hands!
(Kids cheer and applaud)
You guys know
what I'm talking about!
Beth:Thank you so much,
Professor raynor!
Thank you!
I'll see ya!
That guy is amazing!
Right?
I can't believe all the things
that he's done with his life!
And he still finds time
to write books?
He's so cool and smart
and funny and sexy.
Hey! Easy.
Are they all like that?
Well, Professor raynor's
on another level,
but everyone else
is pretty amazing
in their own way.
Cam, why are you
doing this to me?
Why are you torturing me
like this?
Even if I could get in,
and even if I could somehow
Beth-
figure out child care,
how could I ever afford tuition
like ever?
Oddly enough,
they have a whole department
devoted to helping you
figure that out.
(Sighs)
I just...
I just can't picture it.
I can't picture actually
being a student here.
Come with me,
I wanna show you something.
Come on, get in.
Where are we going?
You'll see.
Can you picture it now?
Beth:
Oh my God!
Cam: I know, so many
boring things to memorize.
Beth:Can we go
to the periodical section?
Yeah, sure.
Beth:
Isn't this amazing!
Cam: Yeah, everyone
else clearly thinks so.
I wanna show you something.
Is it a book?
What're you doing?
Did you bring your camera?
My phone has a camera.
Wait - you're not
just doing this
to compete with Taylor,
are you?
Do you honestly care?
No. No, I don't.
Nick: You know why?
It's the...
Kids:
The United States of bananas!
Nick: All right, thank you!
That's my time!
I'm bunny p. Bunnerson
or whatever!
Hey, thanks!
You guys have a great night!
(Kids cheer and applaud)
You did it, man!
Hey, you better
get back out there
before they start
tearing the place apart.
Go! I don't have
any new material,
so I can't-
go!
Okay!
(Kids cheer and applaud loudly)
I think of all my bags,
my favourite bag is the one bag
I keep under the sink.
(Kids chuckle)
And all the other bags
know it's my favourite
because they have to inside it.
(Kids laugh)
So their like, "man, next time
bunny needs to take a banana
and a juice box somewhere,
I'm a goner!
(Kids laugh)
But look at that
old miracle mart bag...
He ain't even scared!
(Kids cheer and applaud)
(Laughs)
Right?! Right?!
Hey, Walter.
Hey.
It's Sean, your son.
You had a stroke.
The doctor said the right side
of your body is paralyzed.
It's affected your speech,
so you can't talk right now.
But hopefully...
That's okay.
You rest, I'll talk.
There's something
I need to tell you.
(Takes a deep breath,
then sighs)
Dawna came by,
she told me to make sure
I told you that.
(Tearful)
She says she loves you.
Nick: Ooh! Perfect!
Thanks, girls!
Okay. Bye!
Thank you. Thank you now.
See ya!
Here you go.
Five hundred bucks -
worth every penny.
What? Five-
five hundred dollars?!
I haven't made this much money
doing stand-up comedy ever.
They usually pay me
in drink tickets.
How great for you.
It is!
Thank you!
Hey! You know,
I can talk to the people
who run these things.
We can get you in the regular
rotation if you like.
- Yeah?!
- Yeah.
You have to sign this
exclusivity thing,
but after that the money
just starts rolling in.
Well, I don't know
if I can do that.
I'm still trying to actually...
Look, look.
When I started out,
I thought I was gonna be
the next Jason latimer,
Andrew goldenhirsh,
or Shawn farquhar.
I don't know any of those...
But at a certain point,
I realized...
Maybe I'm not world class,
you know?
And once I realized that,
and committed
to this mitzvah circuit,
oh, my life got
a whole lot easier.
So what I'm saying is,
maybe you set aside your dreams
of being the next Jeff Dunham
or Terry factor...
Those are both ventriloquists.
Just settle into the life
you're meant to have...
Barnsworth p. Bunnyton,
bunny comedian.
Hmm?
♪ ...Feels so good ♪
♪ why can't I talk to you ♪
So we-
so we can just leave?
Dale Roberts:
They don't have anything.
The sheriff here is a friend
of the church.
He doesn't like to see
its members needlessly harassed.
I don't know how to thank you.
Dale Roberts:
No thanks needed.
Your problems are our problems;
that's how it works.
Okay, what do we have here?
Charlotte:
Hey, let's get out of here.
Abby:
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
We changed our minds!
But you already changed
your mind.
Yeah, well,
we're changing it back.
I'm sorry, but it's too late,
you already signed the forms.
Abby:
These forms?
Well, can't you just pretend
we never signed them?
You want to annul
your annulment?
Abby: Yes!
That's exactly what we wanna do!
I don't think
I'm allowed to do...
(Rips forms up)
There:
Annulment annulled.
A lot of those weren't yours.
♪
♪ nothing to do
with the clothes you wear ♪
Manny:
Yo, wasteland.
Your raise -
instated retroactively.
Thank you.
The car is used, all right?
It's not as expensive
as it looks.
But I shouldn't have
brought it here.
Well, I'll try and stop
"playing footsie""
with the boss...
Not that we were doing that.
Are we good?
We're good.
See you tomorrow.
(Knocking)
Raquel: Hi.
Mark: Hey!
I'm gonna head out.
Okay.
So, you still think
Manny's stealing?
Oh, no.
Turns out it
was his cousin's car
and he was just showing off.
I was being paranoid.
Yeah?
Even about the "scrips"?
Shut up.
No, I think that
the kitchen staff
is cooking meth in there
after hours...
I am sorry.
I thought I was cool there
for a sec.
Well, you are not.
Understood.
♪ It's not the game,
it's how you play it ♪
(Door bangs shut)
(Exhales)
Kaldrick:
I couldn't do it.
I couldn't tell him.
Christopher:
You will.
Kaldrick: And I should
have told you about dawna.
Yeah, you should have.
But under the circumstances,
I'm gonna give you
a get-out-of-jail-free card.
You're lucky your old man's
in the hospital.
I wish I could kiss you
right now.
Me too.
Rook:
Yo, Kal.
Kaldrick:
What you doing here?
We need to talk.
What's my favourite...
Colour?
Red.
What are my parents' names?
Paul and Stella.
When's my birthday?
October fourth.
When's mine?
September...Eighth?
Yup.
What's my favourite movie?
"Top gun".
I'm just joking -
"it's a wonderful life".
Yeah, it is,
but what's my favourite ***?
Oh, that's lame.
When's our anniversary?
Today.
Yeah.
Sabrina:
Hey!
How was your day?
Um, actually...
I had a callback!
They brought me back for
the will arnett sketch show!
What? That's...
I'm sorry I was such
a downer this morning.
You were right,
they totally loved me,
and they only brought back
fifteen of us
and I was one of them,
and I destroyed it!
That's... amazing.
Okay, I'm done spazzing now.
How was your big fancy gig?
Did you dazzle
the network executive guy?
(Sighs) Yeah.
I think I really made
an impression.
This is so great.
It's really happening, Nick!
It's happening for both of us!
Can you believe it?
No. I can't.
Sorry about your pops.
Why are you here, rook?
(Sighs) Come here.
(Sighs heavily) I messed up.
I shoulda never started
working with infinite
when we fell out.
It was a big mistake.
Man's gotta eat, right?
I mean the kid's a punk,
but I guess he got
a little potential.
Nah, see, it wasn't even like that.
So when I heard what
he did to your car,
I thought
if I stayed close to him,
then I could watch him,
make sure he didn't do
anything else.
It didn't exactly
work out that way.
Last night, in the studio,
he started recording this track
calling you out,
talking all kinds of nonsense.
And when I shut it down,
and I wouldn't let him,
things kinda went sideways.
Sideways how?
I got back to my crib...
He had torn it apart.
He took anything that looked
like it was worth something,
even something I took
from you when I left.
What the hell you take from me?
The hard drive.
That night at the studio...
With tariq.
You know,
I was mad at Walter...
I thought...
I don't even know
what I thought.
Did you watch it?
Man, I've known you
since we were four years old.
I didn't need to watch it.
♪
♪ just a paper cut ♪
So now you're telling me
infinite's got it.
Yeah. I messed up, man.
I know it.
I'm sorry, man.
Beth: Okay, but if I go,
(Cam's phone buzzes)
What courses should I take?
What would you take
if you were me?
Kevin: Beth! Beth!
They have Simon!
Beth: What?!
Simon: Beth! Beth!
Beth:
What? Hey! Hey! Stop!
Who was that?
Who took him?!
Eddie:
Child protective services.
Kevin: They showed me their
badges, I didn't know what to do!
Connor:
Here is to my sister,
the bravest person that I know.
I told you, I don't drink.
Come on, come on,
you have to have just one drink,
celebrate our victory!
I can't!
Okay, all right.
Fine, I'll have yours.
Mm!
I don't know how to thank you
for what you did today.
I mean it.
No one's...
Nobody's ever stood up
for me like that.
Connor, there's no one else
in the entire world
I care more about than you.
What?
I've just never felt this
close to someone before.
I love you, Charlotte.
I love you, too.
Sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com