I like these.
I been gettin; like, two a week
from the school for...
a couple of months.
So that's quite a few.
I know you're game,
but, Monica,you seem very overwrought.
I had Division I offers.
I had even signed at Marquette
'cause they thought I
was gonna make the grades.
The great ballplayers...
they care about basketball
more than they care about school...
and I know they do.
Shaky. Shaky.
Ohh.!
Let me try somethin;!
If you're looking for
a progressive college basketball program...
with experienced leadership
and a winning tradition...
then the Marquette Warriors
are for you.
William's first home recruiting visit.
Three top schools postpone visits...
preferring to wait and
see how William will do
his senior year at St. Joe's.
If you don't make the test score,
it doesn't mean we don't want you...
because we still do-
that's what I'm telling you.
If you tear your knee out
again this year...
and you can't
play ever again...
you're gonna have your education
paid for at Marquette University.
I know that the scholarship
is one-year renewable.
Gene's right about this, but any school
worth its salt is gonna give you four years.
The bottom line is this-
we want to win the national title.
Number two- I wanna make you
the best player I can.
I wanna give you an opportunity
to, maybe someday...
be one of those guys that makes
some money in Europe or in the NBA.
You're one of seven guys
that we're recruiting right now.
- You're recruiting seven guys?
- Seven guys for three spots.
Where he fit in?
- Where does he fit in?
- Yeah.
As soon as William tells me
he's not looking at any other schools...
then I'm not looking at
any other players.
So, what?
The first one sign, that's -
Well- Well, that's what
it's gonna come down to.
If I tell you that, hey,
you're our guy and this and that...
and I lose you to Kansas, Indiana,
North Carolina State or something...
I'm out ofluck.
The president's saying to me,
"I thought you were recruiting a guard. '"
It's a tough situation,
but it's something that has to be done.
It's a great place.
We're gettin'ready
to have it rockin;
The best is yet to come.
Lot of serious ballplayers
been through this building-
Junior Bridgeman, Sidney Moncrief,
Bob Lanier, Oscar Robertson.
Can you see yourself playing
in this place here, 18,000 in it?
Big difference from St. Joe's, now.
We stayed at the hyatt.
Man, it was nice. Real nice.
They had these balloons
all hangin' up on the ceiling, everything.
They-They really did it up.
And I must say, we did it up too.
We - Room service.
Man!
had these phony newspapers written up.
Notre Dame 77, Marquette 76.
Gates is out high, calling for the ball.!
There are six seconds left.
The freshman spins past the defender,
slicing to his left to the foul line.
Three seconds left.
Marquette down by one.
Gates launches a running one-hander.!
It's on the way.!
It is good.!
Gates buries a 13-footer
just ahead of the horn...
and Marquette
has defeated Notre Dame.!
If you think we care about you
a lot in recruiting...
we're gonna do more
when you're here.
Don't let it get to a
point where somebody else
comes in and takes a scholarship away.
Let us know what you wanna do-
unless you know what you wanna do right now.
he knows, but he won't say.
You talked to any, uh...
leading black people on the campus?
- The leading black people?
- Yeah.
- Such as?
- Whoever might be in charge...
of all the black students on campus -
what kind of community life
they have for the blacks there.
- Uh -
- Did you talk to anyone about it?
- Did you ask the players
how they're treated?
- Yeah.
- What'd they say?
- Players say they treated fine.
I mean, they get
the best of everything.
- You think that's where you wanna go?
- Yeah.
That's fine.
Obviously, if you wait you'll have
all the other schools
that were on you before...
like Kansas and Indiana
and North Carolina State.
That's all right, uh, but...
I discussed it with -
I think you should take a few days.
Because you just came back.
You understand?
- Poop!
- Yeah!
Yea!
Boo!
Is there any cash with this?
Uh, it's in the mail.
To four years of excellence.
- hear! hear!
- It's alcohol-free.
- It's not that bad.
I am fixing him
a birthday dinner today.
It's his 18th birthday...
and I want to show him
how much we appreciate him and love him...
and care for him.
Everything that you can imagine
was going wrong with this family...
but now everybody's together.
It's his favorite cake.
he's a great kid.
And some kids don't live
to get this age, you know.
That's another thing
to be proud about -
that, you know,
it's his 18th birthday, he lived...
and to get to see 18, that's good.
I wanna tell you that I love you very much.
I'm very proud of you.
It seems like I was 18 just yesterday.
here. happy birthday. I love
you.
- Ohh.!
- hey-hey.!
- happy birthday!
- I love you too.!
- Come over here.
- Where you goin', homes?
Where you goin', homes?
Blow out the candles.!
Two months after his 18th birthday...
Arthur is cut off public aid.
This is what I brought to their attention.
he's still a full-time student.
he hasn't graduated yet.
So why would you-all cut him off?
- I'll bite you!
- I'll bite you back.
They feel like when they get 18...
most the black kids
they drop out.
So that means that the child
is just thrown out there.
I was gettin' 368.
Now I get 268.
And that's it.
And that's to take care of me
from one month to the next.
Now, can you imagine
a person living on that?
Do you-all wonder sometime,
how am I livin'?
Or how do my children survive,
or how they livin'?
It's enough to make people really wanna go
out there and lash out and hurt somebody.
A message to the Oreo cookie.
No matter how much you wanna switch,
here's what they think about you:
Fried chicken
and biscuit-eatin'monkey, ape, baboon...
big-thighed, fast-runnin;
high-jumpin; spear-chuckin;..
360-degree basketball-dunkin;..
pit-swingin'spade moulanyan.
Go the fuck back to Africa.
Think about it. Fuckin'sellout.
Play the music, motherfucker!
Put the music on!
Shoot it.
Rebound.! Go, go, go.!
Gates stinks.
You got that? he stinks.
he doesn't play with confidence,
like he did before he was injured.
I don't believe the other players
have complete confidence in William.
They were in awe of William
when he was a sophomore.
They're not in awe ofhim anymore.
Sophomore year...
I was just carefree.
If it could be done,
I was gonna do it.
I wish I could
get that attitude back.
Go.!
hold up.!
That's crap.!
That is dog-shit crap.!
Why did you have to
do something unnecessarily?
If you would've kept it over here, William -
Look at me!
If you had kept it over here, wide,
you could have gone all the way.
What is that crap,
the shovel pass?
There was never any point in our school...
where wejust-
just played outright,you know.
Now, remember, think about the ball game
on the way to the game.
I'll bet a nickel.
If I got a nickel.
Yeah, I got it!
Marshall began its season well...
winning four of six.
Today's game will be their first
against a city power.
The only way you gonna beat them
is to play good basketball.
All that bullshit that you be playin' -
You play half of a game, for two
or three minutes you play pretty good...
then you go to sleep.
You have to play a whole ball game.
When we start out,
Arthur will be completely in the ball game.
But as the game progresses,
then he digresses.
By halftime, Marshall trails
highly favored Dunbar by 15 points.
But late in the fourth quarter...
Arthur and the Commandos
claw their way back.
On a crucial possession...
the ball goes to Arthur.
hey, boy!
Gimme some, boy!
hey, Arthur G!
hey, Arthur G! You ever got rich,
they'd catch you for sure! Come here, dog!
That's it, man.!
Showin'your beef!.
I want it up high, G.
I want it up high.
Led by William's 16 points a game...
the Chargers have a 20 and 3 record.
But Coach Pingatore feels they're not ready
for the impending play-offs.
Alabama.! Alabama.!
Alabama.!
Well, don't throw the ball!
Jesus, will you cut it out
and quit acting like a baby!
Will you quit cryin'!
This team just drives me crazy.
It's been a struggle all year.
You think you're better than you are.
The two big guys are prima donnas.
They should be killin'people.
For you people
that are really agonizing...
andjust hate all this stuff
and all the hollering...
if you don't make a turn,
it'll be over next week...
so you won't have to worry about it.
That's the point.
I wanna end this game
in the next three to four minutes.
Otherwise it's gonna be a ball game.
All right, let's go get 'em. Come on.
hail Mary, full of grace.
Blessed art thou -
holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
All right, let's go.
Come on.
William's just too nice of a kid.
I don't know ifhe has
the killer temperament.
the eye of the tiger.
he's gonna need that
when he goes to the next level.
Remember, square up!
It's business, it's big bucks...
and that's what the scholarship's for.
Good job.
- his coach is stingy and selfish.
- My coach is not -
he just want William
to run out there and play-
- My coach is not stingy and selfish.
- Yes, he is!
The day she was gonna be born
I told him he had to be there.
I don't care what his coach say.
I know the game was important.
But this was more important,
and his coach doesn't see it like that.
I just can't miss a game...
just because, you know,
an incident occur...
unless it was like a death
or somethin' like that.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
Ain't like the girl was born every day.
That's what I was tryin' to get you to say.
Especially around that time
of the year too - state tournament.
It was simply out of the question.
he tells me,
"Well, it'll benefit us in the future. '"
I'm, like, "But what about now?"
he keeps sayin' in the fu -
Basketball was my ticket
out of the ghetto.
If I wouldn't have been playin'ball,
I would not even be goin'to college.
I'm goin' to college, and I have a daughter.
So what's my excuse?
- Because the situations are much different.
- No, it's not.
I haven't been workin'for about a year.
And if it wasn't for William
knowing Miss Wier...
I wouldn't even be here.
'Cause I walked in the door and that's
the first thing I see on the sign
- "No openings. "
It ain't much better than a person
without a college degree can get.
So I feel like I'll be here
for quite a while.
What you lookin' at?
I don't believe people
when they be sayin; "Wow, school's hard.!'"
The work weren't hard for me.
All right. I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna do it. I'm gonna do it.
If I gotta do, like,
a report or somethin;..
I don't like none of the topics,
so I'll just pick somethin'that's simple.
So, what's the topic of your paper?
The life cycle of the butterfly.
- Gonna read it for us?
- Mm-mmm.
Aw, come on.!
No, man!
- I wanna hear it-
- I'm just doin' this stuff!.
I know, but I just wanna hear
how you write.
"Well, as the people bloom
into another year-"
You know, the year just changed,
January 1.
"The butterfly also blooms.
The butterfly are very beautiful
flying objects. "
Then it say at the
beginning of the butterfly,
it goes through a change and all that.
Then I keep goin', man.
I just wanna, like, do that stuff.
Then I'll just keep goin'
on and on and on...
and I won't never stop.
Move out the way! Move!
Look out! Move out the way!
Its botanical name is Cannabis sativa.
Millions of Americans
break the law and use it.
Arthur's latest report card shows...
he's failing
both Spanish and Science.
he rushes through his work.
As you see,
he just missed one assignment.
Mm-hmm.
But his test scores were pretty low.
- he had a 10 on one test.
- Mmm-mm-mmm.
Will you do me a favor?
When you see things are slippin' like this,
give me a call and let me know.
Let me make sure I have
the right phone number.
So I can stay up on top of this boy.
Because he tells you one thing -
I say, "Where your book?" "We didn't have to
work on the book. It's
in my locker. "
he gonna have to start
showin' me somethin' better.
he probably on the borderline,
and all that clownin',
people just give him an "F."
That's what I would do too.
But I'm gon' stay up on his behind
this time around.
'Cause I told him we payin' 181-odd dollars
out there to St. Joseph's...
Right.
for his transcripts.
he got the transcripts
and he ain't doin' that?
Uh-uh. It ain't gonna happen like that.
Man.!
You remember I told you,
whatever I start I finish.
I'm not like some people I know.
I don't need nobody to push me.
All I gotta do is have the goal
and the motivation, and I'm ready.
It's Sheila's graduation day...
from a nurse's assistants class
at a local community center.
A high grade
will assure her certification.
I want to be an R.N. nurse.
I've always had that dream.
Well, Miss Agee.
- Sheila.
- hmm?
You scored 89 on the exam.
You're gonna get the highest
grade point average for the class.
Really? Really?
No, no, no, no!
Oh, I love you, I love you, I love you!
Oh, I'm so happy!
Oh, thank you, Miss Martin!
You did it yourself.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, you so good.
I didn't think I could do it.
- I knew you could do it.
- Yeah, you did.
You gave me that belief in myself.
You're really inspiring me to go on.
Not just stop right here,
but go farther.
And people told me
I wasn't gon' be anything.
The gym is packed for today's
game against West Side rival, Westinghouse.
Marshall's rebounded
from last year's dismal 9 and 16 record...
to go 16 and six.
And Arthur has emerged as the Commandos'
second-leading scorer and assist man.
Rebound.!
Somejunior colleges have begun to notice.
A lot of these kids won't talk
to a junior college...
really until after they've seen
the dream of, you know...
Illinois and Nevada, Las Vegas
and Georgetown kind of fade.
Ajunior college could be Arthur's only hope.
Without better grades
and an 18 on the A.C. T...
major colleges can't offer him
a scholarship.
It's just too bad
those kids don't realize...
hey, if they had an 18,
the door is so much wider open.
You're in the middle.!
In the fourth quarter, the Commandos
fight back from an
11-point halftime deficit.
They trail by one.
We gotta play more aggressive on defense.
We're not good at playin'
on defense.
Yeah, man.
Defense!
Derrick Zinneman's layup
pushes Marshall to a one-point lead.
Moments later,
a Westinghouse foul...
and then a double technical puts Arthur
on the line with a
chance to ice the victory.
One more! Whoo!
The upset win is sweet vindication
for the unranked Commandos.
- Arthur Agee, you lead the books.
- Junior!
You got seven.
Seven turnovers.
Even for the guards, that's too many.
This is a good win for you,
but it doesn't mean anything.
You gotta do better than that, man.
You have to do better than that.
Yeah, man.
That was a good game though.
You could have played better though,
you know.
Oh, Mom. You know he did good.
You'rejust killing me.
You know your mother's proud of you.
he been gettin' down.
Like a real star.
Number 11...
Arthur Agee.!
Nearly four years
after discovering Arthur
on the playground...
Earl Smith shows up to see Arthur win
his first play-off game.
I figured this game and the next game
may be his last high school ball game.
- Where you been, man?
- Where I been?
- Yeah. Where you been?
- I've been workin'.
- Oh, yeah, right.
- I've been following you in the paper.
- Oh, yeah. You impressed or somethin'?
- Yeah. I'm impressed. I'm here, ain't I?
- If I wasn't, I wouldn't have followed you.
- You been talking to Ping?
- For what?
- You don't talk to him no more?
- Why not?
- What do I have to talk to him about?
- Well,Jamal -
- You ain't there.
- Yeah, you're right. I had to break out.
- Yeah.
So I was thinkin' about goin' tonight
to see, uh, St. Joe and Nazareth play...
but I wasn't sure
if you had time to do it.
Yeah.
I've got a bitter taste in my mouth
about a lot of things that happened.
A lot of people accuse me
of taking youngsters...
out of the inner city and taking them out
to St. Joe high School...
and they ask
what did I get out of the deal and...
a lot of racial slurs and so forth from
my own people about me, about what I did.
I still felt and feel
that I was doing the right thing...
for that particular time.
Uh, sometimes I have second thoughts...
when I see the net results
of what happened with the youngsters.
Arthur.
- Arthur-
- Arthur Agee, sophomore.
My gosh. What are you doin'?
- What are you doin' now?
- Goin' to school.
- Where?
- Marshall.
Oh, I taught him.
Can you believe it?
- So you came in case you
have to play St. Joe's?
- Yeah.
Arthur. Arthur.
- What's up, man?
- What you been up to?
You playing basketball?
- What? Yeah.
- how'd you guys do?
- We did a'ight. Still playin;
Still playin'?
When's your next game?
- We gotta play Crane.
high school in Chicago.
- That's cool.
It'll be all right.
William is benched
for arriving late to the locker room...
and Nazareth threatens.
William enters the game to go head-to-head
with Nazareth star Sean Pearson...
his friend and roommate
from the Nike camp.
The favored Chargers
race to an early 14-point lead...
in this second-round play-off game.
Give me an "E"!
Give me an "R"!
But near the end of the game...
St. Joe's begins to unravel.
William takes control.
Pearson responds.
his three-point shot gives the Roadrunners
their first lead of the game.
For the Chargers, their whole season
may come down to this possession.
Down by one,
with just over a minute remaining.
A loss tonight would be their earliest
exit from the play-offs in six years.
And for William,
there is no next year...
no more chances to get downstate.
It ain't but one thing: bad coaching.
Bad coaching.
Well, we got him here
about five minutes late.
So what? This -This ain't no time
to be teaching nobody no lesson.
All right, boy.
It's all right, bro.
- You all right? You're crying, man.
- Shut up.
Yeah.
- It hurt, don't it?
- Yeah. More than ever, man.
- I didn't never want
to go out this way, man.
- Your last year, man.
I'm trying to get it, man.
I'm striving for the same thing.
hey, man. We'll call you.
Give me a ring. All right?
- All right.
- You played a good game, boy. All right.
You're gonna be all right.
- I love you, boy.
- I love you too, man.
All right.
William was 20 minutes late.
The team was dressed and already talking.
Then he came strolling in.
Maybe he has to learn something from that.
Even in a big game.
The game was a mirror-
It was a mirror
of all of the games all year.
To quote Isiah, the toughest loss
he ever took was the-
My toughest. And that
was the De La Salle game
in 1979 when we got beat at the buzzer.
On a 30-footer. And we were favored
to win the state that year.
Um, now we look back on it
as just one of those great moments in -
in our high school scene.
Our toughest loss to take,
and we talk about it.
So that's what I look at, you know,
with these things now.
- Arthur, we could have used you tonight.
- Yeah.
Good luck.
I'm gonna be watchin'. Don't forget.
Stay in touch.
- 'Cause we've talked about -You know.
- Yeah.
- School.
All right. I'm watching you score.
how's your grades?
- They're all right.
- Good.
- We missed you.
- I missed y'all too.
- Well, I'm proud of what you've done.
Mr. Bedford said
a lot of good things about you.
- You be in touch. Okay?
- Okay. All right.
- Good luck.
- All right. You too.
Marshall's second-round opponent,
Manley, presents little challenge.
This just explains a little bit
about our program...
where our program's headed.
I like what you're sayin;
and I want him close to home.
- Yeah.
- You know. And, uh -
I think, you know -
I'm kind of leaning your way...
because I just thank God
that he's getting into it -
you know, somebody do want him.
I'm Tommy Travis,
Northeastern Illinois assistant coach.
- Okay. Nice to meet you.
- I'm Arthur's father.
- Arthur hester.
- Okay. Arthur hester.
Us Arts gotta stick together.
- I'm over at Kennedy-King.
- Kennedy-King?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
May the best man win.
- I thought mom was a cheerleader.
- Oh, thanks.
Thank you for the compliment.
his parents seem to think
he may, uh, pass the A.C.T.
- he may what?
- he may pass it.
Oh, yeah.
Well, I hope he does.
- Us Arts gotta stick together, guy.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- hey.
Would you get excited if a college coach
came up and talked to you?
Not really.
Really, it's just-
You'rejust going...
to another level
ofbasketball. That's all.
I'll be excited when I get there.
That's when you'll be
excited the whole year.
I'll be excited as soon as I step up
in there - first day of practice.
If I graduate, I think I'll be
the only one in my family...
besides my uncle,
to finish college.
Me too.
In the fourth round
against heavily favored Taft...
Marshall meets their first
true test of the play-offs.
But the Commandos have been
bucking the odds all year.
Arthur plays one ofhis best games
of the season...
scoring 19 points...
and the Commandos claim a spot
in the city semifinals.
The final four! I told y'all
he was going all the way. All the way!
Do you guys feel you can play with
any team in the city?
On any given day, we can play with anybody.
We can beat anybody.
Marshall now faces
the ultimate test::
King high School,
the rulers of the public league.
Winners oflast year's state crown,
they were labeled the
best team in the country.
King has sparked controversy
by out-recruiting rivals...
for the biggest and best
grammar school players.
We don't understand what
we're really doing to these young kids.
Kid not even 12 years old...
and you're baiting him
to come to your school...
you know, to play basketball.
Falls back in the paint.
I'm not going to start
recruiting in that manner.
No, I'll probably get out
of the game before then.
The winner of these two semifinal games...
will play for the Chicago Public
high School Basketball Championship.
King's strategy is to
go inside to its two seven-foot starters.
Only Arthur seems
unintimidated by theJaguars.
And King's poor play
keeps the game close.
We are the... best.!
We are the team!
I think they gonna take it.
But in the second half,
King makes their move.
- What are you doin'?
- Come on. Get in the game.!
King grabs a four-point lead.
hey, Mookie, Mookie, Mookie!
Y'all playing
with no confidence whatsoever.
None!
None.!
- All right! Go get in charge of that ball!
- Don't foul him! Don't
foul him!
Let's go! Let's go!
The Commandos get aggressive on defense...
Too soon now!
and use their superior speed on offense.
Players, sit down.
We got three minutes to go. Sit down.
Marshall grabs a six-point lead
late in the game.
We got a long time to play.
Coach Bedford wants to force King
out of their zone defense...
and make their big, slow players match up
man-to-man against Marshall's quick guards.
One, two, three. Defense!
Arthur simply holds the ball
as the clock ticks away.
The King coach has no choice.
For the defending national champions,
it's all over.
And unranked Marshall
will play for the city title.
Whoo! 26-2 now!
They're 26 and 2 now.
That's my Man!
All right, Man!
- I told you we could do it.
- Yes!
- I told you you were gonna do it.
I knew y'all was going all the way.
I told ya.
I said, "You're going all the way. "
This is your last year.
You're going all the way. Yeah.
They got the best shot ofhim,you know.
And it's great.
That was a great shot, wasn't it?
But this one in the, uh, Tribune
is what I really like.
It says,
"Arthur Agee stood as still as a statue.
Time after time was on his side. "
You know, the championship
that I missed when I was in high school-
Yeah.
Twenty-one years later I got a chance
at getting a championship through him.
You know, you're always trying to
build your children up...
and saying, "Well, you-all can do it"...
but, you know, really lying on
the inside a little bit, saying...
"Well, you know, you got a long haul. "
But, you know,
this make you even more confidence...
because if he's sure of hisself,
then you know you can bank on it.
Yesterday, you know, when he won the game,
you know, he told me he loved me.
And, you know, I haven't heard that
in, uh -You know.
You can feel it, but I haven't heard it
coming verbally from him.
In a rematch with rival Westinghouse...
Marshall proves to everybody
they have what it takes to be city champs.
Inside pass. Shot rejected.
To the lane with the layin.
Busts this game wide open.
Did you see that?
Did you see it? Did you see it?
They are celebrating because they know...
their high school is headed
to the elite eight in Champaign.
And the Marshall Commandos
have won the Public League Championship...
in convincing fashion-
58-38 winners over
the Westinghouse Warriors.
What's up, man?
Told you on the phone what I was gonna do.
Told you, boy.
Marshall, baby. Marshall!
Marshall!
Marshall.! Marshall.!
Your A.C.T. came in, William,
and you received a 14 for a composite...
which is not high enough.
Uh,you've taken the test-
Now, this was for the fourth time.
Now, if you add all those up,
it comes out to 17.2.
In order to play at Marquette,
you're gonna have to get the 18.
And they're very, very concerned.
One assistant called twice this week,
and Bo Ellis called today.
Smile, William.
It's not the end of the world.
- Right?
- I hope not.
Well,you gotta work at this
as hard as you worked at yourjump shot.
And it was missing a lot this year.
Okay.
Now you are down to the final inning
and the last strike.
We're going, going downstate!
We're going downstate!
Now let's, let's celebrate!
Now let's celebrate!
- What are we gonna be?
- State champions.!
Your Marshall Commandos.!
- Yeah!
- We're gonna take state!
Take state! Number one!
Beat B-A - B-A-T-A-V-I-A.!
Beat B-A - B-A-T-A-V-I-A!
Downstate Marshall plays
its familiar role as underdog...
to third-ranked Batavia.
Justice has it. Justice, one-on-two.
- Spins up-
- Nice move.
In the media glare of a statewide
audience, Marshall shows big-gamejitters.
Now bust out.
And Marshall missed the layup.
Sealed off,blocked by Williams.
You got easy shots.
You gotta make your easy shots.
I can't shoot for you.
Now he's gonna penetrate.
Left it for Christian. Missed the shot.
Luther Bedford looks like
he's ready to commit suicide over there.
Y'all better get on your job,
Commandos!
- Now into the corner.
- Get in there.
Batavia's got these guys on the run.
One, one, one, one!
One, one, one, one.!
But in the third quarter,
the Commandos charge back.
And a steal by Marshall.!
Agee gonna take it all the way.
Yes! That's the way you go!
- here we go.
- Picked him clean.
Dale. Marshall leads.
Marshall's first lead
since the first quarter.
Like a lightning bolt,
the Commandos have struck.
37-36, Marshall leading Batavia.
Chicago Marshall has exploded-
I always dreamed of,like...
me and William taking
them downstate together.
When I was at St. Joseph...
maybe we could have went downstate,
and maybe we couldn't.
But we did when I'm at Marshall.
Arthur's big fourth quarter
helps add Batavia...
to Marshall's growing list of upsets.
Spectacular comeback
in the fourth quarter by the Commandos-
In the postgame news conference...
Coach Bedford labels
his unranked team "the giant killers. '"
- Y'all are playing the number one team.
- We're playing the number
one team.
We're playing the number two team.
This is the first time in the history
of the school that we've gone
this far.
- Really?
- In the history of the school.
Just like the Commandos.
See, we been the underdog.
I'm glad we are because then
it just show you how you could come up.
And then you beat your opponent.
Oh,yeah.
Be a good place for Man to come.
Yeah. This is really, you know,
something that a -
a child would really miss out on.
Like a whole different world.
It's beyond different.
Uh-huh.
In this semifinal game,
we'll see some great individuals...
just as we saw many years ago.
Remember Isiah Thomas,
one of the great guards.
here you see the same moves
he plays with in the NBA today.
Well, we've got someone like that:
howard Nathan, number 34...
for Peoria Manual.
Marshall got here because of
one reason: quickness.
The reason: Arthur Agee.
Look at this man. he just explodes, Dan.
he can get downcourt
as quick as anyone I've ever seen.
In the semifinals...
Arthur goes head-to-head
with howard Nathan, the all-American.
Make him work for it, Man.
Make him work for what he get.
All right! Let's go!
All the way, Man! All the way!
Yeah! That's it! That's it! That's it!
Arthur Agee, spinning inside,
tough shot. Good.
Arthur has a great first half...
but the Rams play even better.
he's got it.
Get up for the Rams!
Everybody get up!
Get up for the Rams.!
In the second half,
Arthur tries to pick up where he left off.
Penetration move by Agee. Slapped
out of there by Manual.
They've got two-on-one.
Ooh, and a nice fake and a score.
But it's the Rams who don't miss a beat...
pressing the tempo against
the tired Commandos.
You're not in the offense at all.
You're just out there
playing individual basketball.
Completely.
hey, hey, guys. No fouls.
We want to keep the clock going. Remember?
Let's go, Marshall!
Let's go!
Let's go, Marshall.!
Let's go.!
Marshall showed us last night
they have the ability to come back.
Let's see what they can do here.
This is Nathan.
Nice pass.
Knock it down.
Biggest lead of the game now,
and the Rams fans can smell it.
Been a great run
for Luther Bedford's team.
The string of upsets stops here.
- And a foul on Agee.
- he fouls out.
But hejust never quit.
hejust kept going for the basketball.
I wouldn't be surprised
ifhe made the all-tournament team tonight.
- Number one!
- We're number one.!
We're still number one.
All right. All right.
Though they lose to Peoria Manual...
they finish third in the state, the highest
a Marshall team has finished since 1960.
This was a great season you had.
There is nothing sweeter
than going downstate as a young person.
I mean, the record's
gonna stay there, you know.
1991, there was a team
from Marshall played.
- You know, and you're part of that.
- Yeah.
- That's part of history.
- Ah!
But for you seniors,you know-
Best wishes to all you seniors,
and whatever you try to do, uh...
Mr. Williams and I
will be around school...
as we always are -
to help you if you want to be helped, okay?
Winning five games in six days,
that really takes a lot out of you.
Like Coach said,you just gotta sacrifice-
you know, sacrifice everything you have.
Like, if you love the
game of basketball,
you just go out there
and give all your heart.
he got a little ways to go,
but he's - he's gonna get there.
hopefully he's got his head
screwed on pretty good, you know...
and now, you know,
he's gonna be on his own to do whatever.
hopefully he'll do it right.
When we got down here, people don't expect -
"Marshall? how'd they get down here?"
They lookin' like: "Who
they got on their team?"
I had to come out and prove myself.
I think I could play Division I basketball.
'Cause all I need is just a scholarship.
That's -That's all I'm looking for.
Arthur Agee.
All right!
All this area through here
is our new computer labs.
We'll take you through
all those rooms.
Arthur's first recruiting visit...
takes him to a junior college
in Southern Missouri.
The strength that I see here
is the tremendous
teaching that goes on here.
have you decided
what you want to go into?
Uh, communications.
Are you more interested
in the overall communications -
That, and, uh -
I like that and accounting.
- Like business.
- Oh. Okay.
We enjoy winning things,
but the primary purpose is your education.
What are some of your career goals,
may I ask?
I want to fall back to,
like, make - have my own business.
Like real estate.
This is where it all happens.
Beautiful place.
And it gets to rockin;
- You gonna try it on there?
- Yeah.
Those are about $ 120 apiece.
You need to be very careful
with this decision.
You know, if you come in and act right,
you're going out ofhere...
with two years
of your college finished...
a scholarship to a Division I university.
Exactly where you'd want to be-
on track to graduate in four years.
Mineral Area doesn't have dorms...
but it does have a basketball house.
All the ballplayers
on scholarship live here.
Get your ass up, nigga.
Of the seven blacks
in the entire school...
six live in this house.
You come in and look at this little house,
then after a while you get used to it.
Try to make a little home, you know.
home away from home anyway.
We hang around each other most of the time.
We know who to trust,
who not to trust.
I just want to go somewhere
where I'm gonna play.
I can get the grades.
I love basketball.
how many of your
players that leave there
and they end up going
to a four-year college?
- Thirty-one sophomores in a row.
- Really?
Every last one of'em he coached.
- hi. how you doing?
- hey. how you doing?
- Arthur Sr.
- Bo and Sheila have been separated.
She asked him to return today
over Arthur's objections.
I'll show you exactly
what the scholarship entails.
Is this a full scholarship
for the two years?
The reason I'm skeptical is because of
the promises that was made in the past.
From the time he comes down there
until he leaves, you will
not have a financial need.
Now, when you make this decision...
you got to live and die with it.
'Cause it's your decision to make.
Now, I'm here to support you if you -
if you done searched this whole thing.
And it's what you really want.
Not,you know,
'cause Mama said this or your dad-
Or because you're saving
Mama money, because if we have to...
we will still pay-
if you have to try to pay-
if we can put some-
I'm just sayin;
You - Understand what you're saying.
You want to save somebody money, but still -
But you have to still do
what is best from here.
But still we want the best for you -
even if you have to -
or we have to go in the hole, you know.
You understand what I'm
saying? I'm just saying.
But still, the decision is up to you.
So, what do you think?
Ah.
- Ready to sign it?
- Yeah.
- Yep.
- Let's do it up.
- What time is it?
- 1:56.
56.
Come on, Bo.
Whip it to him.
When I was 23, how old was he?
And I whupped him then.
Aw!
You want to see it rain?
Let it rain.!
- You want to see it rain?
- One more time.
Let it rain!
You want to see it rain?
Oh!
Peoria Manual.
Remember what they did to you now.
Yeah. Do you know howard Nathan?
And I strung him up,
just like that.
Uh-oh. Like father, like son.
What's up with that?
You better stick to church music,
leave that basketball alone.
hell, no. You can't do that.
Foul! Foul!
Foul. Foul, foul, foul.
- That's 32.
- That's 34.
- 34!
- That didn't count 'cause he called "Bo. "
- That's 34!
- That's 32!
- he didn't hit nothing else.!
- I did!
- he didn't hit nothing else!
- It's 34-28, Bo.
- Bo's a sore loser.
- All right!
- No. I know how to count though.
- Ain't no con game. I'm older now.
- Yeah.
- Ain't no con game going on no more.
- No more. Ain't no more.
- The score is 32 to 28.
Now, you can play for 32 if you want to.
Game over with.
I can con too.
Losers quit. I'm ready to play.
Now,youse a coward if you don't-
Check ball.
- You're mad now.
- Check ball.
- Throw it over there.
- You ain't two years old.
You ain't gettin' no pacifier.
- Give me that.
- Yeah.
Your mama ain't here
to give you this ball. Let's go.
- Give me the rock.
- Let's make it rain. Make it rain.
Bang. Bang. Right there.
ha! Go sit down.
Go sit down.
Bo, it's raining.!
Bo, it's raining.
- It's raining, Bo!
You're on punishment when you get home.
And you're on punishment
when you get home. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
It's gonna rain on your head, Bo.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen...
and welcome to St. Joseph's
Annual Basketball Awards Dinner.
We had a...
difficult year.
Most of you are aware of that.
When I first went to St. Joe's,
I really did sleep, eat
and drink basketball.
That was all I did.
But it became more of a job
than a sport to play.
Things here have not changed since-
You know, Coach Pingatore
just had these dreams in his head.
hejust wanted me to go
the same route he took Isiah.
The most steals.
he played as a freshman.
Not even Isiah was a four-year starter.
You know, basketball was just like-
he was possessed with it.
You know, it was his life.
And he wanted it to be
everybody else's life too.
All-conference in the SCC.
All-state in the Sun-Times.
A McDonald All-American nomination.
M. V.P., 1990-1991 season,
William Gates.
When I had some real problems...
I couldn't go to
none of them about it.
You know, I was having some problems
with Catherine's family and my
family...
and I said, you know, "Coach Pingatore,
their family's been getting
on me about...
you know, I'm not doing this,
and I'm not doing that. "
And the only thing
Coach Pingatore could say is...
"Write 'em off. "
That was all he told me.
And I was, like, "What
kind of advice is that?"
Well, how's it feel to be finishing?
Uh, I mean-
Now, don't say anything
you don't mean, William.
I mean, I'm serious, Coach.
I enjoyed my four years.
I mean, we had our run-ins, and, uh -
- Who had run-ins?
- Me and you.
- We did?
- Yeah. Like that time
you made me run 75 stairs.
- I never f-
- You never forgot that.
Never.
See,you should have been
happy and enthusiastic
about doing your punishment.
But someday
you're gonna learn that, uh...
everything that was done
was for your benefit.
So that you can come
back four years from now
and say, "Coach,you were right.
"Everything that happened
at St. Joe's helped me a lot...
and as a result I got a degree. '"
That's what I'm hoping for.
I'm going into communication...
so when you start asking for a donation,
I'll know the right way to
turn you down.
I'm sure you'll never turn us down.
Ah.
I never really felt
that he bought into the system.
he was never convinced
what he was doing was the right thing to do.
But overall he had a good career-
not a great career.
It's never good-bye.
Could've been different
if the injury didn't occur.
But it did occur.
- And that was the big difference.
- I'm proud of what you did.
- Okay.
- I expect you to do a lot better.
I don't want this to be the-
- Yeah.
- You know, the highlight of your career.
You've got a lot of
bigger and better things to do.
I'll see you later.
Good luck.
Well...
another one walks out the door,
and another one comes in the door.
That's what it's all about.
It came through for me.
- Got the score I needed.
- All right.
And, hey...
I'm eligible.
You know, this is one
of the greatest feelings
in the world. That's about it.
I mean -
After five attempts,
William's composite score of 17.5...
is rounded up to 18...
and he can finally accept a scholarship
to play at Marquette.
I think my mom...
all through high school
really, really was proud of me.
She said, "Everybody's throwing
their dreams into you...
but you got to throw
your own dreams into yourself. '"
When I gave her the diploma
after the graduation...
she was, like,
"This is it, one of my proudest moments. '"
My baby graduated.
Curtis always wanted to go to Marquette...
and his grades weren't
good enough for him to go...
and now it's like
he got the grades,you know?
Excuse me, Curtis.
You gonna give anybody else a chance?
What two countries
are we competing with for world trade?
Before Arthur can graduate,
he must pass summer school.
And for the first time in three years,
Shannon isn't there with him.
The other country, of course, we said-
he thought he could sell drugs
and don't get caught,you know.
But he found out the hard way.
And I told him, while
he was doing all that -
I wasn't hanging with Shannon then.
I was like, man, "Shannon,
you should stop, man.
Stop doing that stuff. "
We always said we weren't
gonna never do no stufflike that.
We werejust gonna go on
and graduate and go on to college.
But,you know, he had to be the one.
One week before his graduation,
Arthur is robbed at gunpoint.
At first I thought he was gonna shoot me
because I didn't have no money.
'Cause he kept asking me, "You got -
You got some money. Where your
wallet at?"
Be like, "What you driving
a car like this for?"
I was, like, "I ain't got no wallet. "
And then,you know,
he grabbed me and stuff,and I was-
and I was about to panic and stuff,
and I just calmed down.
I sit down
and had a long talk with him and his sister.
Someone pulled a pistol on her
right down the street from the house.
I said, "Do you all
understand what is going on
out here in these streets today?'"
Even with me, when I was out there -
you know, out there strung out
-
you know, I looked for somebody
that seemed like they had something.
hmm. After this, I -
I - I'm ready.
I'm ready to leave.
'Cause there ain't no -
Everybody up here going to jail
or- or either in drugs.
Or dead.
James Davis.
Arthur Agee.
Please hold your applause
so everyone can hear.
Christine Bowman.
Erica Byrd.
Sandra Crockett.
I never thought he would
get to the place where he's at now.
Arthur's self-esteem
was really drained from St. Joseph's.
I said, "Well,you are somebody.
"No matter where you go,
it's what you have in your heart...
that you're gonna go somewhere. '"
Come on.
Move out of the way, boy.
Everybody out there, there's gonna be
a party tonight. There's
gonna be a party tonight.
You know it.
These flame-broiled burgers -
It's scary, man. I'm telling you.
I'm telling you the truth.
Scary generation, man.
- I thought you might
hit me in my head, fool.
- I didn't hit you in your head.
To my son.
I hope you pursue all your dreams
and your desires...
that you have within you.
I love you very much.
- Ooh, that is so nice.
- Whatever.
Oh, no.!
God, we thank you
for this day, Lord.
And we ask you to
go with junior, Lord.
And we thank you, Lord. Go with him
as he try to better his education, Lord.
And we thank you for him
for coming this far.
We came this far by faith, Lord.
And we ask you, Father,
when he get in college, Lord...
to keep him, Lord-
keep him protected.
We thank you for him,Jesus.
- In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
- Amen.
Oh,you can cry like a river, girl.
You're crying so bad,
I won't even make fun of you.
Oh, God.
- I'm gonna miss you.
- I'll miss you too.
I want you to be good, okay?
And don't, uh, get mixed up in
none of that old stuff that, uh, you
know.
I done told you what to do.
Don't get no alcohol, no wine coolers.
None of that stuff.
Bye-bye.
I just hope he stay in there.
That's what worries me most.
Once he get in the door,
I want him to stay in there for four years.
Think he gonna make it?
You do?
I think he gonna make it.
Well, I hope so anyway.
When I was young- When I was little,
that's all I used to think about- the NBA.
If I set my mind, I can - I can go.
I can st - I can go.
Get in good college. I can go.
But if I don't, you know, I ain't gonna be
no drug dealer, you know...
cry about it,
come back and, you know...
stick up gas stations
or nothing like that, you know.
Probably go into comedian or architecture,
something like that.
You don't think that you'll have the kind
of tough times like your dad's been through?
No.
I can't say- I can't say that I will.
I can't say that I don't. I don't know.
Four years ago, that's all
I used to dream about
was playing in the NBA.
I don't really dream about it
like that anymore.
You know, even though...
I love playing basketball, but, you know...
I want to do other things
with my life too.
- Say, "hi, Daddy. '"
- hi, Daddy.
- "how you doing?'"
- how you doing?
- Say, "I love you. '"
- I love you.
If I had to stop playing basketball
right now, I think I'd still be
happy.
- I think I would.
- Thank you, Daddy.
- Where'd Daddy get to?
- Uh, Marquette.
Marquette?
That's why when
somebody say,you know...
"When you get to the NBA,
don't forget about me,
'"and all that stuff...
I should say to them,
"Well, if I don't make it,
watch you don't forget about me. '"