My Secret Hotel
Goo Hae Young...
Did you really mean it?
What do I do?
What do I do now?
Excuse me.
Yes, sir.
Another bottle please.
Jung Eun.
Stop crying.
Tears keep coming.
Hae Young is married now.
You should give up now.
I can't find another man like Goo Hae Young.
Did you look carefully?
Holding onto someone who's
not interested in you.
That's...
...obsession.
I know.
Why is Hae Young holding onto her like that?
Why don't you talk to him, Shi Chan?
Tell him he's obsessed.
Do you have more tissues?
Shi Chan.
Come to the bar near the office.
Sir.
Let him be.
He's my friend.
Did she go to the restroom?
Jung Eun?
Jung Eun!
Jung Eun.
Ugh, really...
By chance...
Las Vegas?
Goo Hae Young.
I'll let you stay over.
Any time you'd like.
Bye.
I knew this would happen.
What?
Where did you sleep last night?
Who did you sleep with?
Wearing the same clothes...
Look at you...
You were with Joo Jung Eun, huh?
I saw you two disappear in her car.
Hey, you forced her to marry you and...
you made her move in with you.
How can you cheat on her now?
Were you always such a jerk?
Samantha.
I brought some cookies for you.
Samantha, are you leaving?
What about the hotel?
Without him...
it's all meaningless.
I need to go.
I have to see him.
By chance...
Las Vegas?
Did you really...
come looking for him?
Excuse me?
Hae Young is in the shower right now.
Do you want to wait inside?
Joo Jung Eun.
Did you see my dress shirt I left out?
I need to go to Hae Young.
Do you want to come in or not?
Joo Jung Eun, I'm late.
Later...
Just...
don't say anything to him.
Samantha...
Are you really going to leave like this?
I warned you before.
Falling in love at first sight is very risky.
You even quit your job...
He's not worth it.
He's going to regret it for the
rest of his life for leaving you.
That memory...
I didn't want to remember it again.
I really don't want to think about it.
It's all in the past.
It's all over.
Whoever Goo Hae Young is with...
it has nothing to do with me now.
But...
why am I crying so much?
You like Joo Jung Eun, right?
This isn't about whether
I like Joo Jung Eun or not.
Nothing happened.
I said nothing happened.
How can I believe that?
Fine.
I went over to her place
last night in her car.
I got sober by the time we got to her house.
Really, nothing happened.
I told you before.
I can't see her as a woman.
Then why did you sleep over there?
Why didn't you go home?
Huh?
What if she's not there?
What?
What if she left and wasn't there?
Are you here to see Manager Nam?
Ah...
No, I just...
I was walking by.
You must really miss her.
It's too early for her to be here.
No, I was really just passing by.
Alright.
I'll take your word for it.
Thank you.
Wait...
Assistant Manager Yang.
Please look after Manager Nam.
For awhile...
a lot will happen in the hotel.
Team Leader.
You know Cha Dong Min?
He was charged with manslaughter
over the death of his classmate.
The classmate who died was no other than
the nephew of General Manager Lee Moo Yang.
What?
The more shocking things is...
Cha Dong Min who killed his own nephew...
Lee Moo Yang forgave him and
looked after him in jail.
He didn't want to ignore...
someone so young.
Follow me.
I didn't want to hurt Manager Nam.
It was a warning...
to you, Managing Director Jo.
A warning?
Leave this hotel.
If I don't accept your warning,
will I die like others?
What's your reason for going
this far for General Manager?
This has nothing to do
with the General Manager.
Do you expect me to believe that?
Go tell the General Manager.
He made a mistake hurting Nam Sang Hyo.
I already requested an open investigation...
with the police.
What's up this early in the morning?
I have a favor to ask you.
Go ahead.
No matter what you hear about me...
...just ignore it.
Tell me you'll do that.
Can you promise me?
I promise.
That's enough then.
I'm fine with that.
Cha Dong Min.
You're under arrest for the
attempted murder of Nam Sang Hyo.
You have the right to remain
silent, but I don't recommend it.
Anything you say can be used
against you in the court.
But it's better to confess everything.
You can hire an attorney, but...
you'll end up in jail anyway.
Oh, my...
What's going on?
How could this happen?
Let's go.
You've come a long way.
Oh, my.
What's going on?
Team Leader Cha is...
the serial killer.
What?
Team Leader Cha...
tried to kill Manager Nam.
Manager Nam
Yes, Manager Nam.
Where's Assistant Manager Yang?
She's not here at the moment.
Gi Chul.
I don't think I can go in today.
Oh, oh... why? What's going on?
Did you get hurt by any chance?
Did Team Leader Cha...
It's me.
Yes.
I'll take care of everything.
Don't worry.
Okay.
Don't ramble on.
No, you can't.
Step aside!
Are you trying to destroy the Secret Hotel?
I'm okay. You can go.
What do you mean open an investigation?
If everything is publicized...
the hotel will be critically impacted.
Why?
Are you afraid?
Behind this beautiful hotel...
dark secrets will be revealed.
Is this about Manager Nam?
I'll be responsible for that...
Did you order Team Leader Cha...
to hurt Manager Nam?
Are you making your confession?
That's not it. What I'm saying is...
People are dying in this hotel.
We can no longer try to hide it.
One by one...
I'll unveil the truth.
Once I start digging like that,
I'm sure the truth behind
my father's death...
...will be revealed.
In the end, it comes down to Jo Min Tae...
It's about him.
Because of someone who died thirty years ago,
how dare you place the hotel in danger?
It's already...
way past the statute of limitation.
Even if you find the perpetrator,
you know you can't punish him.
Is that really the case?
Your dark secrets will
come to light soon enough.
From your face...
the mask that display a gentle
and respected general manager...
...will fall away at last.
It's a bit late, but...
That's a good enough punishment.
Do you think I'll just
stand back and watch...
someone like you destroy this hotel?
Stop immediately.
I have no intention of doing that.
Your father was human trash.
Killing your father...
What are you doing?
If you don't stop right now,
you'll be the one who'll regret it the most.
Please leave the country with
Managing Director Jo immediately.
Before it's too late.
Nam Sang Hyo
Hey.
You should go home early today.
You stayed out last night.
You should go home early and...
prepare the dinner table.
Beg forgiveness from Sang Hyo.
If she asks you what happened last night,
tell her you were with me.
I'm your...
...alibi expert.
Did you forget?
Last time when the detective came by...
"He has an alibi."
"He was with me last night."
Hurry up and go home.
Will she be home?
What...
What if...
...she's gone?
Hey.
if you...
go home late tonight again...
even if she was home...
she'll leave for good.
Go home.
Be a man.
Tell her you were with me.
You want to taste?
Yes.
It's so good.
You came.
Goo Hae Young.
I'll let you stay over.
Any time you'd like.
Did you eat?
Do you want me to make you something?
No.
I don't feel like eating.
Last night...
Are you mad I stayed out last night?
Actually...
I was afraid you wouldn't be here...
I didn't want to come home.
Sorry.
So?
Where were you?
Huh?
Ugh...
With Shi Chan...
At work.
I see.
Alright.
Are you mad?
No.
I'm tired.
I'll get some rest.
I won't cry over you again.
Nam Sang Hyo.
Nam Sang Hyo!
Are you okay?
What about me?
I thought Team Leader Cha tried to kill you.
What?
Didn't you know?
Oh, my...
He tried without your knowledge?
What are you talking about?
Team Leader Cha was arrested yesterday.
For attempting to murder you.
Team Leader Cha tried to kill me?
That's what I'm saying.
The police arrested him yesterday.
The hotel was completely upside down.
Then...
that day, too...
No, there's no way...
Something happened, huh?
Right?
Oh, my...
What should I do?
The reporters are calling already.
What should I tell them?
Hello, Reporter Lee.
Yes.
I can't believe it.
Manager Nam.
It's Team Leader Cha for sure.
No...
until the police investigation is over...
I'm sure.
Gi Chul, stop it.
You didn't witness him yourself, Gi Chul.
You shouldn't say...
...something you're not sure about.
I mean...
Ugh, I should've never come to this hotel.
Sang Hyo.
You have to go somewhere with me right now.
What?
What about the hotel serial killer?
Say that again?
What did the serial killer
try to do to Sang Hyo?
Hello.
Joo Jung Eun.
Joo Jung Eun!
Goo Hae Young
Where are you going?
To Sang Hyo...
What about her?
Hey, you look crazy right now.
Police Station
I don't know what I should tell them.
I still can't believe...
Team Leader Cha tried to kill me.
You just need to tell them what happened.
We're almost there...
...General Manager Lee Moo Yang.
Wait a little longer.
Let's go, Sang Hyo.
- Sit, sit.
- Okay.
Everything is completely...
...solved.
What are you talking about?
Cha Dong Min confessed.
Cha Dong Min confessed?
Yes.
He said he killed Hwang Dong Bae,
Heo Young Mi and tried to kill Nam Sang Hyo.
Oh...
It's okay.
No need to be afraid.
Since he confessed all that,
he he'll never see the light of day.
What was the motivation for the murders?
Well, that...
This is...
...what he said.
What's your reason for murdering them?
Do I need...
...a reason to kill people?
I just didn't like them, so I killed them.
Managing Director.
Do you really believe what he's telling you?
He's trying to hide his tail right now.
I'll tell you honestly.
Now that we have a confession
without evidence,
there's a good possibility
the case will be close soon.
What you're telling me is...
Your request for an open investigation...
is water under the bridge.
Ah...
They caught the perpetrator?
Okay, Jung Eun.
Did you hear that?
Nothing happened to Sang Hyo and...
they caught the perpetrator.
But...
earlier...
you ran off like a crazy man.
Why did you stop yourself?
Just...
didn't feel like I needed to be there.
I thought they'd be together.
Do I need...
...a reason to kill people?
Sang Hyo.
Don't think about anything today. Just rest.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
Scary thoughts keep coming to me.
I'm so sorry.
I was so angry.
I didn't consider how scared you'd be.
I'm really sorry.
That's okay.
Sang Hyo.
I won't put you in any danger in the future.
So...
don't be scared.
You think you can do that?
Come here.
You won't be scared anymore.
Goo Hae Young.
Where are you?
I'm scared.
Ugh...
What are you doing?
Why are you drinking again?
You didn't make up with her yet?
I want to let her go now.
What?
I don't think she needs me now.
I wanted to believe I'm the one for her.
But...
I don't think I'm the one.
Like you said...
I forced her to marry me and...
made her go on the honeymoon...
and made her move into my house.
I'll stop now.
I'll let her go now.
Goo Hae Young.
What's...
...wrong with you?
I've been acting like an idiot.
Singing like an idiot...
Floating around everywhere like an idiot.
Like an idiot...
I won't do it anymore.
I don't care if I'm an idiot or...
it's okay if I act crazy.
But Sang Hyo may be suffering.
Because of me...
I think she struggled a lot.
Now...
I'll let her go.
Careful...
Over here...
Sang Hyo.
If there's a misunderstanding, don't be.
The night he stayed out...
he was with me.
With me...
Okay.
Alright then...
don't walk me out.
Take care of...
...Hae Young.
Okay.
Today was...
...really a long day for me.
But right this moment...
is the hardest moment.
Hae Young...
It's so hard for me.
What brings you here at this hour?
Do you plan on getting away with everything
by putting blame on Team Leader Cha?
Do you think I'll give up like this?
Whatever you do...
you'd better do it fast.
Soon...
with the agenda to dismiss you...
there will be a board of directors meeting.
You want to kick me out now?
Things won't go as planned.
Well...
Don't underestimate me.
Alright then.
You're still up.
Yeah...
I'm still up.
Was it the General Manager?
Sung Gyum.
You and the General Manager...
What do you two have to
talk about at this hour?
What are you hiding from me?
There's no such a thing.
Mother.
You really don't have anything to tell me?
Let's stop.
Okay?
I'm...
I'm begging you.
No.
I'll find father's killer and...
make him pay for his crime.
If truth is unveiled...
you and...
she will also get hurt.
If the truth is unveiled...
you and...
she will also get hurt.
She?
So, stop here.
Nothing good will come out
of digging old wounds.
I...
can't forgive her father.
But...
if you stop digging into this...
I'll also forget it.
Don't shake up Manager Nam.
The General Manager...
He's like a father to me.
Hi, Simon.
Find the adoption paperwork on Nam Sang Hyo.
Eat.
I thought this would be better than ramen.
Really?
Whoever you meet...
Whatever you do...
I don't care.
But...
don't drink 'til...
you can't walk straight.
Okay.
It just happened.
This is really good.
Your cooking has improved.
Enjoy.
Sang Hyo.
You staying here...
aren't you uncomfortable?
Jo Sung Gyum...
must not be happy about it
either. You living here.
If you're doing it for the reporters...
I'll do my best to stop them.
So...
no need to...
stay here reluctantly.
You must be running late.
Go ahead.
Manager Nam Sang Hyo.
Here is her adoption document.
Hae Young.
Someone's...
...here for you.
Don't you...
...remember me?
True...
An old man who walked the
bride down the aisle...
Of course you didn't have time to see me.
With a beautiful bride in front of you.
Ah...
I'm sorry.
Nam Sang Hyo. Wore a bonnet with lace.
Wrapped inside the Secret Hotel tablecloth.
Guardian - Lee Moo Yang
Manager Nam Sang Hyo is...
...like a daughter to me.
When she came to me...
and said she's doing the wedding with you,
I opposed it.
It was to replace a runaway bride.
I said it's complete nonsense.
But...
I ended up...
walking her down the aisle.
Do you know why?
In Manager Nam's eyes...
I saw her true feelings.
I'm sure it wasn't feelings for me.
- It was just for the hotel.
- No.
She is a responsible person, but...
she wouldn't do something like
that if her heart wasn't in it.
Trust me on this.
Manager Nam...
I know her very well.
Managing Director Jo and Manager Nam...
They should never be together.
The minute...
you let go of her...
Manager Nam will become unhappy.
Why does it have to be you?
You staying here...
Aren't you uncomfortable? So...
you don't...
have to stay here reluctantly.
In Manager Nam's eyes...
I saw her true feelings.
Sang Hyo.
Thanks.
Please go.
Samantha left already.
She's too pretty to be left alone.
Samantha already left with someone.
Someone better than you.
Someone who truly loves her.
Managing Director.
Sorry for calling you out.
I just...
...missed you.
Maybe you'll never...
...want to see me again.
Perhaps I...
may not be able to wait for you.
That's why I came.
I said I'd wait for you.
I asked you not to forget
about me waiting for you.
I'm sorry for...
saying this to you first.
No, Managing Director.
Don't feel bad toward me.
Everything's...
...my fault.
Just like I can't...
forgive that person...
you probably couldn't...
forgive me either, right?
Now...
I won't be able to...
hold onto you any longer.
No matter what happens...
the fact that my feelings were genuine...
please know that.
I'll get going first.
Bye, Sang Hyo.
See me for a minute, Lee Moo Yang.
What do you have in mind for my Sung Gyum?
Do you want...
everyone to know our relationship?
Follow me.
Why are you dismissing Sung Gyum?
That's the only way we can remove
Managing Director Jo from this hotel.
My Sung Gyum...
He has a bright future.
I can't let you leave a
tainted mark on his career.
So that Sung Gyum can resign on his own...
please wait.
I can't do that.
Lee Moo Yang.
You told me to trust you.
Is this the outcome for trusting you?
Is ruining my son's life the
result I get for trusting you?
I'll tell all.
I'll just tell everything!
Calm down.
Do you really want to end everything?
Everything can be destroyed this way.
What are you doing?
Sung Gyum.
No.
Killing my father wasn't enough for
you? You're trying to kill my mother?
A moron like you...
should never be forgiven.
No.
- Someone like you...
- Sung Gyum, no!
No, no!
With my own hands...
I'll take you out!
By doing so...
No, Sung Gyum! No!
I killed him!
Your father...
I killed your father!
I did...
I killed your father.
Don't!
Without the child in your womb...
you probably wouldn't be with me, right?
Please don't do this.
Just because you're saying that...
you think I'll stop?
Hey!
What are you doing?
Huh?
You always seem to know when to show up.
Drop it...
...now.
You want to kill me, right?
Jo Min Tae!
If I hadn't...
taken her away from you by force...
you two would be happy together.
Do you know this?
Around her neck...
she still has the necklace you gave her.
Today...
either you or her...
I'll have to kill one of you.
Please...
put that down.
Stop!
Stop, stop...
Calm down.
That's it.
No!
Hwang Dong Bae
I...
ran away with you after that.
His sin...
is covering up for my crime and...
protecting me all my life.
Because of that sin...
he struggled with...
Hwang Dong Bae's threats for thirty years.
That's a lie, right?
Mother.
You're lying, right?
I was out of it for a moment.
I hated him to death.
I really wanted to kill him, but...
I wasn't really going to kill him.
Really...
Please...
tell me you're lying.
Don't forgive your mother.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, son.
Sung Gyum.
Nam Sang Hyo.
What do I do now?
Sang Hyo.
Without you...
how should I go on?
Nam Sang Hyo.
who are you...
crying over right now?
I'm leaving for the States
after this project.
I can't forget you completely here.
I submitted my resignation letter today.
Nam Sang Hyo!
Sang Hyo!
If you ask me to stay if you need me,
then...
I'll take you back.
Why did you ask me to come back?
Why didn't you leave me alone?