Eunsu's father is someone I know?
Yes.
Who is he?
Whoever it is,
you're saying this is all because of him?
Yes.
Just who is he...
Mother...
Hiding?
What am I hiding?
Why is your mother meeting Hyeondo?
What is she going to tell him?
- Mother! / - Mr. Jang Taesu...
Your father.
Eunsu?
Is Eunsu my daughter?
Talk about insolence!
If you weren't Sangjun's son, I would...
Are you saying this is a misunderstanding?
Misunderstanding?
Out of nowhere, your family
drew this conclusion without my knowledge,
and now you want me to answer
this ludicrous question?
Just how big of an idiot did you think I was
to ask me such a thing!
Get out right now.
I said get out!
What about my father?
Did he tell you that himself?
Did he
tell you Eunsu is his daughter?
Hyeondo!
What did you and my mom talk about?
Your call is being forwarded to an automated...
He should rush here, demanding my answer,
but he won't even pick up his phone.
How far is he trying to go with Han Eunsu?
Your secretaries are out looking for them.
Hyeondo and Eunsu, they're bad news.
What did you talk about with my mom?
Where are we going right now?
We're running away.
I'm kidnapping you.
So don't feel badly about your mom.
Your call is being forwarded to an automated...
Eunsu,
I know you're having a hard time.
But you need to talk to me.
Call me when you get this, okay?
So are we
running away for the sake of love?
I guess we are.
So you're not willing to
talk about it with me and try to resolve it?
But then again,
if you were willing to do that,
you wouldn't run away like this.
So where are we going?
To an island of some sort?
That'd be nice.
I'll abandon my family,
and you'll abandon yours.
We'll see each other every day
and talk about things we couldn't talk about.
Are you sure we'd be happy that way?
Jiwan, it's you.
I'm home, grandma.
Where's mom?
She's in her room.
She won't eat, talk to me or come out.
Something must have happened.
Do you know anything about this?
I'll go in and talk to her.
Don't worry, grandma.
Jiwan.
Eunsu, I can't reach Eunsu.
I think Hyeondo and Eunsu are together,
and if Hyeondo says anything to her,
if he does...
Calm down, mother.
We shouldn't be sitting idly by like this.
Jiwan, why don't you call Eunsu...
Mother.
Listen to me carefully.
I just talked to Mr. Jang Taesu.
Eunsu...
Eunsu isn't Mr. Jang's daughter.
Jiwan...
What are you saying?
Look at this.
This is your dad's passport.
When Ms. Lee Jeongae was pregnant with Eunsu,
Mr. Jang and father were overseas in China.
Jiwan...
I don't know why,
but I think Ms. Lee lied to you.
Your call is being forwarded to an automated...
Jeongae...
Why would Jeongae tell me such a lie?
Jang Taesu, he said she isn't her daughter?
Yes.
Mr. Jang said she wasn't.
Those were his exact words?
Yes.
My mom, Jiwan,
my grandmother and my aunt
must be really worried.
Can my family live without me?
Hyeondo, how about you?
Can you live without your family?
How cruel you are, Han Eunsu.
You're making it impossible for us to run away.
You're home?
Hyeondo isn't home, is he?
No, he's not. Why are you asking?
He's with Eunsu right now.
What?
Han Eunsu?
That idiot!
That's no use. He won't pick up.
What do you do all day at home?
Why did you let him go around doing this?
I can't control his private life.
You shouldn't have let things get this far!
You really think I did nothing?
I've been busy, too.
I'm not letting him get away with this.
Mark my words!
Do whatever you want!
That jerk!
What's he doing with Han Eunsu?
What's your blood type?
I'm A.
You can tell I'm A, can't you?
I'm B.
Oh, a type B man.
Very attractive.
You can't get enough of me, right?
What's your favorite season?
Summer.
I can't stand cold weather.
I can't stand the heat, so I like winter.
How come we're so different?
So?
You're turned off?
So I'm turned on.
What is it?
You're not going to tell me?
For a split second,
I thought something was really weird,
but I don't think it's right.
It just doesn't make any sense.
Mr. Jang Hyeondo.
Yes, I'm Jang Hyeondo and you're Han Eunsu.
Nothing will change.
Are you still waiting for Ms. Lee to call?
Why don't you get some sleep?
You can go see her tomorrow.
I'm not waiting for her call.
Eunsu hasn't called me yet.
What if she finds out
she has a birth mom from Hyeondo?
Mother,
you're Eunsu's mom and my mother.
Nothing's going to change that.
And Hyeondo
isn't that thoughtless.
He wouldn't say anything that'd hurt Eunsu.
So get some sleep, mother.
You, too. You have work in the morning.
Okay.
What were you going to do to a sleeping girl?
You were pretending?
Wow, talk about being coy.
A coy woman is...
Not attractive?
So very attractive.
How did you know I love coy women?
What are you trying to do with me?
You're such a player.
Han Eunsu.
Yes, Mr. Jang Hyeondo?
Eunsu.
What is it?
You seem to love my name too much.
Hyeondo.
Yes?
Let's go home now.
I'm mad at my mom and Jiwan,
so I want to leave them, but...
I think I'll end up regretting it.
You can't leave them?
If you can't leave them,
you must live with them.
Let's try to get through it.
Whatever awaits
in our future,
I can't wait to find out.
You keep saying things I can't understand.
What are you hiding from me?
You couldn't even begin to imagine.
You have no sense of loyalty.
Yes, Seonhui, I'm on my way.
I'll be there shortly.
Step on it.
Yes, sir.
You remember about what happened back then.
Back then?
Around the time Jiwan's mother passed away.
I didn't stay in touch, so I don't know much.
Sangjun was in China for six months on business.
Do you remember about that time?
Your call is being forwarded to an automated...
Jeongae, pick up the phone.
I need to see you right now.
Pick up the phone!
Jeongae?
I think she might have moved back
to where she lived before she went to America.
I'm not sure.
I haven't talked to her much these days.
She might come for Eunha.
Eunha?
Will she be here on her birthday?
When is it?
No.
Eunha's birthday has passed already.
Is Eunha one of the kids Jeongae is sponsoring?
Well, something like that.
Thank you.
You have five new messages.
Jeongae, it's me.
Seonhui was just here.
Did you tell Seonhui about the child?
Call Seonhui when you hear this.
She needs to see you urgently.
Jeongae, pick up the phone.
I need to see you right now.
You are unbelievable.
What's so urgent that you're running
around like a chicken with its head cut off?
What?
What is it this time?
Do you know how offensive that look is?
If you're going to start preaching
to me about how to live my life, just go.
Jeongae.
What?
Back then,
why did you chase after Taesu?
Knowing people were gossiping about you?
Because I was pregnant with his baby!
Is Eunsu really Taesu's daughter?
Oh, you're driving me nuts.
How many times must you ask me?
Is it true?
How annoying!
Are you going deaf or something?
Yes, it's true.
Eunsu is Mr. Jang Taesu's daughter!
Seonhui, are you crazy?
How could you tell such a lie?
Of all things, how could you
lie about who the father of your child is?
I'm not lying!
That's Sangjun's passport.
Sangjun and Taesu
left Korea together and came back together.
When you got pregnant with Eunsu,
Taesu wasn't even in Korea.
Why did you do it?
Why did you tell me such a lie?
Why are you making such a fuss over that?
I did it because I knew you'd bother me!
What?
Don't you see?
Sugyeong was going crazy,
and you flipped out on me, too!
You heard the rumor and jumped to conclusions.
Had I told you it was someone else's,
you would've pestered me more.
So I didn't correct you.
I mean,
who cares who the father is?
You're worried about who the father is?
You're offended now that it's not Taesu?
Don't worry.
Her father wasn't a bad guy.
I have standards, you know?
You lied to me because I might pester you?
That was the reason?
What else could it be?
Must I have some other grand reason?
Of course you do!
Maybe someone's life was at risk
or maybe it was for Eunsu's sake!
You have to have some grand reason!
Or else, I!
Jeongae!
Because of your lie, I've worried about her
dad coming and taking her away all my life.
I was scared to death about Eunsu finding out
and being hurt by it, or my mother or Jiwan
finding out.
I had to avoid Taesu and all my old friends!
I would've told my mother the truth
had I known Taesu wasn't her father!
I didn't ask you to live that way!
Over some silly little girl.
How dare you call her a silly little girl!
To me, she's the most precious daughter.
It breaks my heart to see
her the least bit hurt.
And because of you,
I made my baby cry so many tears!
I was heartless and cruel to her!
I was afraid Eunsu would
become hopeful if I softened up,
so I was harsher and meaner to her!
I had to break my own baby's heart, because
I thought that would prevent more heartaches.
Do you know how I felt,
doing all those horrible things to Eunsu?
What are you talking about?
You don't deserve to be Eunsu's mom.
Oh, boy.
I never want to see you again, Jeongae.
Don't come see Eunsu ever again.
As if I would care!
Right.
That's the way you've always been.
Eunsu.
Eunsu!
Why are you here?
What more do you have to say?
I have nothing to say to you.
I'm sorry.
To both you and Hyeondo,
what I did was wrong.
I know I did something I shouldn't have.
I know he's the man you love.
I know he's very dear to you.
And I know you're the only one he loves.
I'm sorry, Eunsu.
I shouldn't have done those things
to you or Hyeondo.
Do you mean it?
You won't scream or get mad at me
even if I keep seeing Hyeondo?
You won't hate me?
Have you been eating?
You look so pale.
Have you been eating at all?
Eunsu...
I haven't been eating.
Why not? That upsets me so much.
I did it to upset you.
I wanted you to know how miserable I was,
how I couldn't eat or sleep.
I wanted you to hurt as much as I did.
Why would you do that?
Why?
Why were you so mean to me?
That's not who you are.
Doing that would cause you greater pain.
I'm sorry, Eunsu.
I'm to blame.
This is all my fault.
Listening to you blaming yourself,
I know you're back.
My real mom's back.
The woman I'm seeing
is Jiwan's little sister Eunsu.
But I heard
she's your daughter.
She's not, right?
Is it true?
Father.
Father!
If that's true,
if that happens to be true,
what would you tell your mother?
And how would you treat me?
You moron.
I have failed as a father.
My own son thinks I'm capable of that!
How could you ask me such a ridiculous thing?
You didn't think to defend me in front of
those who told you such a ridiculous lie?
Do you really think
I would cheat on your mother like that?
You're saying it's not true?
You are crazy.
If you that is how you think of me,
I must disown you.
Father, so it's not true?
Father,
I'm sorry for doubting you.
Thank you.
Tell her to come in.
Oh, you must be crazy!
You spent the night with Han Eunsu?
What did you all night? Tell me!
Mom, this is my workplace.
And we're in front of father.
Who care about that?
Why are you making me repeat myself!
Break up with Han Eunsu right now!
Father,
did you hear what Ms. Jeong Sugyeong said?
You said anyone was okay
as long as I was in love,
so please talk to mother for me.
That was when that woman wasn't Han Eunsu.
Father.
With Han Eunsu, it's a different story.
Your mom and I feel the same way.
So break up with Han Eunsu.
Father...
That's not what you said.
Why? You can't do it?
If your mom's not enough, I'll do it myself.
If you don't want me stepping in,
you have only one choice.
End things on your own.
Father, what's wrong with you?
Let's keep this short and simple.
I can't give you much time.
Grandma,
Eunsu's home.
How dare you come crawling back in?
Are you returning in glory?
Don't you know what a scary world it is?
Grandma, I'm sorry.
I know what I did was wrong.
Mom, you're trying too hard to please Seonhui.
Get out.
How could you act like that?
Don't you have any respect for us?
I spoiled you rotten!
Mother, please don't be mad.
Eunsu feels really badly about it, grandma.
Grandma,
didn't you miss me?
All I could think of was you.
Then why didn't you call?
Mother, Eunsu hasn't eaten dinner yet.
She doesn't deserve dinner!
Haengsuk bought atka mackerel.
You should eat that.
If you try this again, you're dead, okay?
Do you know how scared we were of Seonhui?
Haengsuk, please stop.
You!
Don't even think about taking time.
Break up with Han Eunsu right now.
First it was you, and now it's father.
Why are you doing this to me?
I told you I'm never breaking up with Eunsu.
Your father looked like he meant every word.
Mom, I mean every word, too.
I'm in no mood to joke around!
You want me to get involved?
You want me to threaten her and beat her up?
You think I do this because I enjoy it?
Oh, my!
Why is he being so stubborn?
Taesu and Hyeondo are bound for trouble.
Man!
My head...
Your call is being forwarded to
an automated voice message system.
You just couldn't keep away, huh?
Why didn't you answer your phone?
Is something wrong?
Did you get scolded for staying out all night?
They scolded me,
pestering me about what I did with you.
I wouldn't be mad had I really done something.
I called because I have good news.
What?
You know what?
My family is okay with you.
Mom and Jiwan all said they're okay with it,
as if they never objected to you.
I feel like I'm dreaming.
We can see each other now.
Why is it so hard being your girlfriend?
It's not like you're all that special.
Why is it so hard?
What's wrong?
Why won't you say anything?
Hyeondo?
Right,
that's great.
That's really great.
Nothing bad will ever happen again.
Everything will be all right.
Good morning.
Isn't this a letter of resignation?
Yes.
Why would you turn this in?
You know Mr. Jang didn't sumbit any names.
He's going to try to keep us all.
For how long?
He can do it once,
but when the bigwigs keeps asking for the list,
no one would resist it forever.
I can't do this anymore.
An old friend from school
is starting a small business,
and he needs someone in accounting.
I'd rather get a smaller paycheck than
end up losing all my hair from stress here.
Are you sure about that?
What about you? Are you all right?
You haven't met your quota for this month.
The Best Global loan isn't working out?
What are you going to do?
Well...
I'm just hanging on.
I've gotten this far.
Oh, my!
What brings you here?
I came to get consulted about getting a loan.
It's a very small amount, though.
Don't say that.
I'll get you a personal loan person.
Just a second.
How nice of you.
Both Taesu and you are so nice.
This is why I love old acquaintances.
Taesu...
You mean the president of Best Global?
Yes!
You still keep in touch?
You were always like siblings back then, too.
We're involved in each other's lives too much
not to keep in touch.
And Taesu believes
long-time friends are the best.
Right.
That's how he became so successful.
There was a reason why Taesu liked you so much.
What was it?
Mr. Jang liked me?
Why...
Well,
oh!
You used to make notes on everything.
Taesu said you were meticulous
and scolded me to be more like you.
You mean the transaction notes?
Mr. Jang remembers that?
Yes!
Hyeondo.
I'm sorry.
What!
I'm sorry about saying mean things to you.
I didn't mean them.
That's all you're sorry about?
Why didn't you talk to me about it?
You just demanded me to break up with her.
Well,
I get that you were miserable, too,
but from now on, talk to me first about Eunsu.
I'll have to see about that.
You're such a jerk.
Honey, why aren't you getting ready for work?
I am, just a second.
Isn't that from over 20 years ago?
Why are you going through that?
An old client wants to see her records.
Here they are.
If you found it, go wash up.
I made mugwort soup for you.
Girls, come and eat. Yeongju, Eunsu...
Wait, Eunsu went home.
Oh, boy.
They say you notice it when someone's gone,
and I miss having her here.
Right.
She didn't make a sound, but it felt lively.
Did you see how Eunsu just left
when I asked her to stay for dinner?
She wanted to eat her mom's cooking.
Of course!
She couldn't like someone else's mom's cooking.
And all you want is meat, right?
You only made dad's favorite dishes, right?
Mom, you only care about dad.
Is it that obvious?
Being too lovey-dovey at your age is unsightly.
When am I getting a new baby sibling?
How could you say that in front of your dad?
Answer your phone.
Hello?
Who is...
An agency president?
Ohyeah Media?
I've never heard of it.
Wait, I think I've heard of it.
I don't know much about this field, so...
That's okay.
I came to make you a special deal.
Instead of struggling in the small Korean market,
how about China?
China?
You know?
The Chinese market is on the rise.
And that's why we need a writer like you.
I've heard from so many people in the field
how great your ideas are.
Who? Where?
From different places.
Was it the director?
Director?
You mean my director?
Who cares who I heard it from!
The important thing here is
your brilliant ideas.
Can you send me a synopsis?
I'll use that
to break into the Chinese market.
I feel his absence.
The office feels so empty today.
People come and go every day.
Next month,
your desk might be empty.
Or yours.
Meet your quota for this month.
Eat up.
This is domestic pork, so it's very tender.
So eat up.
- Mr. Yun. / - Yes?
If we're going out, let us know in advance.
We all ate dinner already.
Really?
Then eat a little bit.
There aren't many team leaders who take
their teams out to encourage them.
You should be happy
you met a team leader like me.
We're happy, Mr. Yun.
Thank you. Let's drink to that.
Okay.
Drink up.
Hyeondo,
is Eunsu doing well?
Well, she's doing okay.
Did she find a better job somewhere else?
Yes!
She has to get a better job than here.
Jiwan,
cheers.
Okay.
Jiwan, what kind of women do you like?
Me?
Well,
I'd like her to be near me.
It'd be good if it's someone
I work with so we can help each other.
Someone who seems grown-up
but at the same time, a bit immature.
Weird, right?
Do you like women with bright personalities?
Bright is good.
Do you also like eccentric women?
Yes, very.
But you're a bit shy,
so you can't ask women out, can you?
If I had to, I would.
But that would depend on the situation.
It depends on the situation...
So if the situation is right, you can?
I guess I could.
Jiwan,
you want to leave?
What?
It's boring here.
I'll buy you coffee.
Juri!
Despite how casual this dinner seems,
don't forget to remain professional!
But I didn't...
We're here for encouragement,
but you're going on about nonsense!
Eat the pork!
It's cooked.
What did Juri say?
Nobody heard it.
Some nonsense.
How did you hear her?
Do you have the Bionic Woman's ears?
Eat the pork.
Jiwan, you have some pork, too.
What's wrong with you?
What did she say?
Come and have some fruit.
My head's itchy.
Yeongju!
Even if you're home, you should put on makeup
and wear something pretty!
Why would I put on makeup to write all night?
I put up with you because you're my daughter,
but how could any man ever like you like that?
What?
Mom, you shouldn't be like that.
You're the only one who thinks little of me,
but at work, I'm very appreciated.
Where and when do people appreciate you?
Is that deal with that agency working out?
Yes, he said my idea will be a hit in China.
Really?
Of course.
So don't scold your daughter who works hard.
Okay, Ms. Successful Daughter.
Go and wash your hair.
- Ouch! / - You're filthy.
- Don't eat with your hand! / - Stop!
Go and wash your hair!
Why did
Ms. Lee tell such a lie about Eunsu?
It wasn't just Jeongae's lie.
I jumped to conclusions, too.
She had a bankbook with a lot of money in it.
There were rumors about her and Taesu,
and when she told me Taesu gave her the money,
I just jumped to conclusions.
Money?
Are you sure she got it from Mr. Jang Taesu?
But when I think about it,
Taesu couldn't have had that kind of money.
You said Ms. Lee worked at Taehu Industry?
Yes.
She was the bookkeeper.
Bookkeeper?
Yes.
Maybe
she took money from father's company...
Jeongae wouldn't do such a thing...
You said Director Lee was in charge of finance?
Should I call him and ask?
Oh, Ms. Lee Jeongae.
You closed the account in '93.
Yes, I closed it and withdrew all the money.
My...
You kept all that in your notebook?
But it happened over 20 years ago.
How interesting.
It was a force of habit.
I'm not this bad now,
but that was my first corporate client,
so I kept notes on everything.
I hope you're not offended.
No, I'm not.
Why would I be?
May I take a look?
Excuse me?
Oh!
When did Taesu send me this text?
Is it urgent?
Is it a text from Mr. Jang Taesu?
Yes.
Why does he want to see me next week?
I'll have to see if I have time.
Ms. Lee,
if possible...
Yes?
Where are you meeting him?
May I accompany you?
Well, that's...
I'm not sure how Taesu would take it.
If I can't come with you,
we can make it look like a coincidence.
I would really love to
see him, if that's possible.
If it's too much...
It's okay.
You're helping me out with my loan, so okay.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
It's nothing.
Oh,
may I take a look at your notes?
Sure.
Your family...
It's nothing.
Director Lee!
I still have questions about that day.
I know he failed to develop new technology,
but where did Sangjun's great fortune go?
So he closed all the accounts
in the second half of '93?
There weren't just a couple.
How many is this?
There were at least 40.
40 accounts?
How much was it?
I don't believe him.
I thought he got a couple accounts like me,
but that wasn't it?
My!
He stole 40!
He stole all of them?
That means Taesu stole all of Sangjun's money!
He tried to contact Director Lee.
Is Jiwan suspicious of me?
What does he have? How much does he know?
If it's about your past,
he might go away if you gave him money.
No, that won't solve anything.
The past isn't such a simple matter.
Those documents are very important to me.
Tell me how much you need.
Isn't it money you need?
Kang Jaecheol...
He's at Segi Bank, so find out about him.
They want to see the blueprint.
Do you think that's okay?
You finished early.
They wanted to see the blueprint, too?
He obtained the blueprint.