Subtitles transcribed from audio by Herilas.
"One third of all women and one quarter of all men
In the US are on a diet."
Colorado University.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
It seems really odd in today's world
that we have more than ever before,
and yet, I think, in a very lax state,
it is a world of abundance and an attitude of lack.
The truth is that we are no longer eating food any more,
we are eating food-like products,
and they are adorned, they are made to look better,
and smell better,
so that people are attracted to them.
"More than 60 billion dollars is spent each year
on diet and weight loss products in the US."
Marketing essentially lies to you,
because it presents you with the promise
that you'll be sexy, popular and cool
but in reality you'll be obese, miserable and sick.
I think we are barking up the wrong tree.
People are looking for a result that is
superficial, just to look good.
And they don't really consider that
that could be done
from the inside out.
"Up to two-thirds of those on a diet"
"regain more weight than when they started."
University of California, LA.
The first chapter of the first book I ever wrote was called
"Diets Don't Work", because they are temporary.
They have failure built right in to them.
You can lose weight on a diet,
but it's a little bit like borrow from Peter to pay Paul.
You can get 4 kilos off your body from sheer force,
but you'll have to pay back with interest.
People know this,
Then why highly intelligent people do not stop it?
Because they don't know the nature of the trap.
There was a point where I allowed myself to get to 300 pounds [136 kg],
and that world, as opposed to the current world,
is vastly different.
Life was just not fun.
The only fun I had, you know,
was watching people on TV having fun.
I was over 400 pounds [181 kg].
I had very bad sleep apnea,
I was borderline type 2 diabetic.
I was a cheeseburger away from a heart attack.
And I said "no more."
This is how we are, as mammals.
It's not your fault.
You are programmed to put on fat
whenever there is food available.
I was 31 when I realized
I don't know what I am doing,
I don't know how to take care of myself.
And I am sick.
So I had to go back and learn
all the things that I wish I had known as a child.
"The average American consumes"
"more than 150 pounds [68 kg] of sugar
and sweeteners each year."
U.S. Department of Agriculture.
Sugar is without question *the* cocaine of the food world,
but they're trying to get a way of hiding that drug
within "food".
Sugar is in everything.
In America,
we are eating about 22 teaspoons of sugar a day.
When we get on to a real diet,
in the sense of what a species habitually eats
to sustain itself,
Not to think about these things any more
This is really the problem today,
because people are overfed,
but they're also starving to death.
Pool party this Saturday. I hope you can make it!
Jason will be there. Amanda
Won't be coming.
Having a bad fat week.
We are violating our body's basic survival laws.
The whole dieting paradigm is flawed.
HUNGRY FOR A CHANGE
It's not just what you're eating, it's also what's eating you.
All through our history as a species,
the big challenge is to find calories.
And so, our bodies
are biologically adapted to this.
We seek calorie sources.
When I say that, particularly what I'm talking about
are fats and sugars.
If we taste something fatty or something sweet,
Daniel Vitalis :
the immediate signal is "yes, I want more of this."
Because for our hunter-gatherer ancestors,
and that goes right up to a few hundred years ago,
anywhere they could find fat or sugar,
meant survival for those people.
And carrying forth their genetics.
Dr. Christiane Northrup :
It's not your fault.
This is how we are as mammals.
We've lived on the Earth for millennia
where there was a food shortage.
You are programmed to put on fat
whenever there is food available.
But now there is a lot of food available,
but it's the wrong kind.
And so we've been programmed for millennia,
to store up for the winter,
but winter doesn't come.
Jon Gabriel : Thousands of years ago,
when we lived outdoors and we didn't know where
our next meal was coming from,
if there was a famine
because it was a cold winter or whatever reason,
your body is going to want to hold extra weight to protect you from that.
And famine is a stress.
And if you go through that stress, your body is going to say,
"We need an extra 10 lbs [4 kg] to protect us from famine."
One of the really interesting things about hunter-gatherers
or people who do a very moderate amount of agriculture.
We can call them hunter-gatherer gardeners.
What we see in those people is that
they have an extremely high amount of nutrition
And an extremely low amount of calories in their food
Compared to people in modern civilizations
which have a very high amount of calories
and a very low amount of nutrition available to them.
Today we have so many calorie sources,
but we still have the same signal.
So if somebody bites into a burger
or they take a sip off a milk-shake,
and they get those fats and those sugars,
and their body says "Yes, more",
because it is used to behaving in
an environment where there are feasts and there's famine.
The problem is that we've got feasts like nobody's business,
and we just don't have any famine.
Nutrition Facts
You can eat to your heart's content,
you can eat 10,000 calories a day.
And if you are not getting the specific nutrients
your body needs
in a way that it can digest and assimilate them,
then you are starving on a nutritional basis.
And as long as you're starving on a nutritional basis
your body is going to stay hungry,
to get those specific nutrients.
Now, man-made foods, like bread and sugar,
trick your body into thinking (...and table salt)
trick your body into thinking
you're getting specific nutrients.
And so your body stays hungry for them, but
then the cells don't get nourished.
And as long as the cells aren't getting nourished
you're starving on a cellular level.
So what happens for the average person,
today in our civilization
is they're not getting enough, say, vitamin A. ..
or they're not getting enough vitamin D,
they're not even getting enough vitamin C.
They are chronically starved of nutrients.
So they keep eating and eating and eating.
But the foods that they keep eating
don't have enough of these nutrients
for them ever to get the stock that they need.
But what those foods do have, is a lot of calories.
So what happens is that they start to pack
these calories onto their body in the form of body fat
And the body starts to accumulate or bio-accumulate,
too much, not just fat, but also
all the associated pollutants that are in that food supply.
We see things like diabetes,
we see blood sugar imbalance issues,
and we see a lot of weight gain.
So this is really a problem today,
because people are overfed,
but they're also starving to death.
Kris Carr : Author of "Crazy Sexy Cancer", 2007.
Kris Carr was diagnosed with Stage 4 cancer
in 2003 at age 31.
KRIS CARR : I was 31 when I realized
I don't know what I am doing,
I don't know how to take care of myself, and I am sick.
So I had to go back
and learn all the things I wish I had known as a child,
as a teenager, as a young adult.
Step 1 was just going back and understanding
how do I take care of myself
what do I put in this body,
that is compromised at this point?
How do I boost my immune system,
how do I increase my longevity?
And again, that comes back to what you eat,
what you drink and what you think.
David Wolfe :
From a very cursory surface perspective
what's actually happened is that we left farms,
we got to living in cities, and forgot about our instincts.
And that's led to an obesity crisis,
it's led to a crisis of misunderstanding
of what a natural diet includes
and it's also left us with a little bit of ...
a disparity and confusion. We don't know what to do now.
Dr. Alejandro Jünger :
The problem is that we are not eating food any more,
we are eating food-like products.
And they are adorned, they are made to look better,
and smell better and be presented
so that people are attracted to them.
And not only that,
they are also made so that they can have a long shelf life.
Otherwise the supermarket would be losing money,
and the manufacturers as well.
So the objective is not really to give you ...
a healthy product,
it is to give you a product that will make you buy it,
that will last long,
and will make a lot of profit for
the company that's producing it, right?
Ugh!
Okay, 9:15, it could be worse.
Oh yeah, it's worse.
Oh my goodness, it's Jason.
- Hi there.
- Hi.
Your hair looks nice today.
He likes my hair.
What's that supposed to mean? What about every other day?
He's looking at you. Quick, say something!
Thanks, you too.
Mike Adams : We've got these processed junk food diets,
that people are on ...
but it's also combined
with this relatively new indoor lifestyle.
Our bodies were not designed to sit at desks,
under fluorescent lights, in office cubicles
and chow down processed junk food all day long
without getting exercise.
If you do just one of these things,
it may not be so bad
but by combining them both,
then you end up with a disaster.
Where you've got way too many calories,
not enough nutrients,
and not enough use of those calories.
David Wolfe : And those particular factors,
when combined together
create an obesity epidemic,
they create a low energy epidemic,
they create a fog in cognition,
they create an environment where people begin
to lose the will to take self-responsibility,
so then they turn it all over to a doctor
who is only able to prescribe a pharmaceutical pill
which doesn't address the real symptoms,
which are varied and complex.
Jason Vale : For me, the biggest cause of obesity,
bar none, is addiction.
But to understand the level of addiction that we've got
might be challenging for some because
people can understand addiction to cigarettes,
because that has now been proven,
they can understand the addiction to alcohol ...
But with food, people say "look, I can stop eating".
But unfortunately, like the tobacco companies,
if you go back to the late 60s and early 70s,
who knowingly added more Nicotine
to cigarettes in order to make them addictive.
I used to smoke 40 to 60 cigarettes a day. Why did I?
One cigarette led to a chain reaction,
which then led to another one, another and another.
I said to people that the reason why I smoke
is that I enjoy it,
that I love it.
But I would hit my head
on the pillow praying that I would wake up
and become a non-smoker every day.
Every smoker on Earth would love to
not want cigarettes, if they could.
There is an invisible prison
that catches people in the Nicotine trap.
The need for a cigarette is only caused by the last one,
because when you have a cigarette,
Nicotine goes in your system,
Nicotine has to get out of your system
or you would die.
When somebody has a cigarette, after the
withdrawal from nicotine
it replaces the Nicotine back into their bloodstream.
And they feel better, they feel good.
But that's like putting on a pair of tight shoes
to get the pleasure of taking them off.
And the way that cigarettes are addictive
is much the same in the way that certain foods are addictive.
They know why they shouldn't do it,
but they have no idea why they *are* doing it.
The food companies engineer addictions,
I believe, into many of the foods.
Dr. Joseph Mercola :
The food industry is worth tens of billions of dollars.
And they have the wherewithal and the science resources
to really identify very carefully
what appeals to the average consumer,
and as a result of that, they can
use these chemical derivatives
to create these concoctions which really taste quite good.
And it can have an addictive component.
"MSG and free Glutamates "
"are used to enhance flavor in about 80%"
"of all processed foods."
Raymond Francis.
SOY PROTEIN HYDROLYSED,
Glutamic Acid, Sodium caseinate
MSG and free glutamates can be hidden
behind over 50 different names.
MSG is in 80% of all flavored foods
that you get in a restaurant, get in a grocery store.
It makes you want to eat more, but it does something else.
It actually excites a part of your brain
that's in charge of the fat programs.
The chemical MSG excites the brain,
and due to that excitation,
your body actives the fat programs
and gets fatter. And everybody knows this.
Everybody... scientists know this.
Everybody knows this and no one is saying anything.
How do I know that everybody knows this?
When you want to study obesity, and you want to study a fat mouse,
you've got to make a mouse fat, because mice aren't fat.
So the way you make a mouse fat is you feed it MSG.
And there is even a term for it,
"MSG obesity induced mice".
If you do a search for MSG obesity induced mice,
you will see tons of research reports
where they talk about ...
The protocol was we make the mouse fat
feeding them this much MSG bla, bla, bla
And then we study this, this and the other thing.
They are not studying that,
that is the protocol for making the mouse fat,
feeding it MSG.
And this is in 80% of modern-day foods.
"Help yourself"
A food... let's say a ...
a processed or refined sugar food, or a soda.
You will deliver something, a bio-chemical change in your brain,
it will make you momentarily up-lifted,
or momentarily happy.
And people get used to that feeling,
and they want to slam cookies, or cake, or soda
to get that momentary feeling of ... feeling elated.
But then that feeling soon, very quickly drops off,
and you're left empty, wondering
"where's the food, where are the nutrients?".
Where are the things that the body and the mind really crave?
And the answer from the food companies' point of view is to go back and buy another can.
If I was in the food industry? What am I looking to do?
I want to sell you more food. That's all I want to do.
Now, how I can do that?
I can manipulate the chemical structure of the food,
so that now it becomes not fulfilling, but empty.
But gives the impression, when they're very first ingested
that it is the most fulfilling thing they've ever had.
Nothing else does it in your brain quite like a diet cola.
That's because there's a deadly combination there
of Aspartame and Caffeine.
And those two together create a very unique blend
of Excitotoxin that kills off brain cells.
But before they die, they have this ...
excitement
like a buzz.
So what you find with the diet cola addicts,
is that they'll drink sometimes a liter, 2 liters a day.
And, particularly women, do it as a way
to keep their weight down.
Then don't eat, they just have the next buzz
of diet cola.
Foods containing Aspartame: mints, gum, cereal,
canned fruit, gelatin diets, sorbets
Aspartame causes formaldehyde build-up in the brain,
it causes frontal lobe inflammation.
Migraines can be a common one, visual disturbances.
Symptoms that mimic multiple sclerosis,
there's headaches, there's neurological problems.
Seizures, in more serious cases,
Cognitive problems, and can in fact lead to different types of cancers.
Actually most pilots are aware
that they can't drink diet sodas,
because it is well recognized within the Pilots Association,
that you just don't drink this, because it
could really cause severe aberration to your vision
that will potentially lead to problems when you fly.
If you look at the studies that examine
the toxicity of Aspartame, done by Dr. Walton
Of the ninety studies that were done
that showed that there was no side effects
from Aspartame,
over 90% of those were funded by industry.
And we have almost the same number of other studies,
that were independently funded,
finding the exact reverse
90% of them showing problems with it.
"Research studies suggest that artificial sweeteners"
"contribute to weight gain".
Yale Journal of Biology.
Some of the artificial sweeteners have been proven
not only to have terrible side effects,
over a long period of use,
but they cause carbohydrate cravings.
So if someone has a diet drink
and they wonder why they're not getting thin,
and why they're craving even more carbohydrates,
it's because those substances have been very very
carefully designed, not to help you,
they're into just selling and marketing.
So, yes, there are zero calories in diet soda,
but studies have shown that if you drink diet soda,
within a couple of years,
you'll be fatter than when you first
started drinking the diet soda.
Unfortunately,
when a food additive, like Aspartame,
or any artificial sweetener is manufactured,
the process of getting approval is really...
the manufacturer, the company that's making it,
is the one that funds the studies.
And those are the studies submitted to the Regulatory Agency
to provide approval.
So it's not this independent third party,
objective evaluation that's being done,
as is most people's impression.
I think most people believe the FDA
have their own scientists that do this analysis,
but nothing could be further from the truth.
It basically evaluates the studies
that the industry submits that they funded.
We know that the food companies realize
that many of their ingredients are very addictive.
And the tobacco companies did for decades, they're still doing it.
If you addict a customer,
you have a customer for life.
The food companies do much the same thing,
with different chemicals.
It's not Nicotine, it's the MSG,
it's the processed sugars, it's the Aspartame,
it's these other chemicals, but it's the same idea.
It's just like selling cigarettes.
They're selling food that's harmful.
And you want people to keep coming back,
so you put in those chemicals that
make them want it again, and again.
"Leave your worries behind. Diet soda".
The Marketing essentially lies to you,
because it presents you with this image of a can of soda, let's say,
and it doesn't tell you what's in the can.
What that says is that this can, if you drink it,
it's going to bring you these benefits by association.
You're going to be cool, you're going to be sexy, you're going to be happy.
You're going to be surrounded by friends wearing skimpy bikinis,
or whatever their message happens to be.
This is a lie. The truth is if you drink that soda,
you're going to lose bone mineral density,
because of the phosphoric acid it contains.
If it's a diet soda,
you may suffer neurological problems due to the chemical sweeteners.
And if it's not a diet soda,
it probably is made with high fructose corn syrup,
in North America and elsewhere around the world,
and that's going to promote diabetes type 2 and obesity.
So, on one hand, here's the promise
"you're going to be sexy, and popular and cool",
but in reality you're gonna be obese, and miserable and unhealthy, and sick.
The Marketers are telling you this, but what they deliver is this.
We are now coming to a point where we are wary,
more and more people are wary about this falling
into this marketing of "zero calories", no fat,
no sugar type of messages.
Many of the food labels at the grocery store
are very deceptive.
For example, there's a cereal, made by General Mills,
called "Total Blueberry Pomegranate Cereal".
It contains no blueberries and no pomegranates.
you might wonder, "how did they come up with the name?"
And the naming of food products
often is a little too loose and creative.
It's almost as if they're naming these products,
and this is from the major food companies
whose products are in every major grocery store
all around the world.
It's almost as if they're naming them based on what
they hope you might imagine you're eating,
rather than what's really in the box,
because a lot of times it's not in there.
And then there's stuff that *is* in there, that they don't want you to see on the label.
So they don't put it on the label,
such as Propylene Glycol.
This chemical is used in a lot of blueberry muffins.
It's part of what makes up the blueberry bits,
that aren't blueberries.
They're made of Propylene Glycol, partially hydrogenated oils,
liquid sugars, and artificial colours.
You can also use Propylene Glycol
to winterize your RV.
It prevents the pipes from freezing in the winter.
It's also used to clean out your colon
before a colonoscopy.
So there are multiple uses for this ingredient
that you get in your blueberry muffins.
"99.9% Fat Free. LIGHT, 97% Fat Free".
America loves enemies.
When America chooses an enemy
it deploys all it's forces against him, right?
So at some point, when we were noticing
that we were getting fat as a population,
we attacked, we made the enemy was fat.
And everything became "fat-free", fat-free this and fat-free that
And the calories that fat was occupying,
were replaced by, mostly, carbohydrates.
That resulted in the fattest country in the world.
"68% of US adults are overweight or obese"
The Journal of the American Medical Association.
"Fat-Free" normally means it's loaded with sugar.
I can get a 1 kilo bag of sugar, in my hand now,
and I can put a label that says 100% fat-free.
The fact that once the sugar is ingested,
will turn into fat in the body, because why?
Because it sends the sugar levels sky-high.
What does the pancreas do? It has to secrete insulin
in order to bring that down so you don't die.
Insulin is the fat-producing hormone.
So the 1 kilo bag that I put "100% fat-free",
although factually correct, is unbelievably misleading.
So all this excess energy
comes along and says "where we can store it?".
In the short term, in places like the liver.
But what do we do with the excess?
I know what we will do:
we'll produce some fat cells.
Store them in there, use them later.
The problem is: there's never a later.
Fat is really good for you, if it's the right kind of fat.
And that's the key, it's getting the right kind of fat into your body.
If you are in a low-fat diet of some kind,
you are constantly hungry.
Why? Because you need the correct fats and proteins
to feel satiated.
So therefore if you negate that side of what the body is crying out for,
you'll be constantly looking for it.
We know that the cheap low-grade fats
such as soybean oil, even canola oil and the corn oils,
these are not healthy for you to consume
in large quantities over the long term.
The worst kinds of fats are the partially hydrogenated fats.
These are the hydrogenated oils that are used in many baked items
and crackers and cookies, and margarine spreads,
the butter spreads.
Oh, those are some of the worst foods you could possibly eat.
If you want healthy fats,
then you've got to get into the natural plant-based fats,
from avocados,
and chia seeds and flax seeds
and even the healthy fat from salmon,
wild-caught salmon.
That's a healthy fat for you.
- Want a bite?
- I thought you loved me.
- I do! Take two bites.
- It's got high-fructose corn syrup in it.
- So?
- Well, you know what they say about it.
- What?
- That ...
When it comes to high-fructose corn syrup
a lot of people don't realize the dangers of
refining and concentrating ingredients from a product.
In the 70s,
Japanese scientists developed a technology
to separate fructose from corn,
thus radically reducing the cost
of this high-fructose corn syrup,
relative to traditional forms of sugar.
So high-fructose corn syrup comes from corn, obviously,
but it's not natural, because it's so concentrated and so refined
it's an isolated nutrient.
For example,
cocaine is probably not good for your health
but it comes from the coca leaf.
And coca-leaf tea is perfectly safe for your health.
I drank it when I was hiking in the Andes mountains, and
it's used throughout the culture there
and it's a very important nutra-ceutical medicinal plant,
that's used throughout South America.
And there is no harm in drinking coca tea
and it's not addictive. Nothing like that.
But you wouldn't want to snort cocaine from the highly refined coca leaf.
Well, eating high-fructose corn syrup, in my view,
is a lot like snorting cocaine.
It is the highly refined, isolated, concentrated, chemically manipulated version
of something that's found in corn and grown in corn.
It's very similar to what white sugar is.
White sugar is the purified sucrose extracted out of
beets or sugar cane.
It's a pharmaceutical sugar.
White flours are pharmaceutical carbohydrate
in the same way that cocaine is extracted out of the coca plant,
so you have the native cocaine in the matrix of the plant itself,
or you have the pharmaceutical version.
To me, white sugar, cocaine, white flour
they all fall into the same category of a whitened extracted
purified substance drawn out of the plant kingdom,
all of them create imbalances in the body
and lead to a host of problems.
But if you eat corn, it's fine.
You will not get that much high as when you eat a dose of corn syrup.
The number one source of calories in the U.S. is fructose,
and fructose is highly addictive.
In the 1900s,
the average person was exposed to about 15 g. Fructose,
and another term for that is fruit sugar,
and of course it's why most fruits are sweet.
And fructose in small amounts,
15, 25 g., which is less than an ounce a day,
is probably OK and healthy,
but the average person is consuming 70-80 g. a day.
And there are many kids, primarily teenagers,
who are taking 120-150 g. of fructose a day.
Literally, ten times the amount
that they were taking a century ago.
So when you abuse that type of sugar,
and you have that exposure, it has very severe metabolic consequences,
that can lead to these addictive processes and change brain chemistry.
And, really, make it very difficult
to get out of this cycle where you have these food cravings,
and really addicted to food that's not going to make you healthy.
In terms of just the glycemic index
high-fructose corn syrup
is like jet fuel for your body.
If you pour jet fuel into your car,
into your car's gasoline tank, you're going to ruin your engine. You'll burn it out.
Much the same thing happens in the human body.
You can find high-fructose corn syrup in
so many products in the stores it will amaze you.
If you turn them around and look at the ingredients
"No way, I can't believe it's in here".
Salad Dressings will have it.
You have high-fructose corn syrup in
pasta sauces, and pizza sauce especially is loaded with it.
You really have to watch out with everything in the grocery store.
Read it and make sure it doesn't contain this high-fructose corn syrup,
and other ingredients that are dangerous.
Stay away from the isolates.
Stay away from high-fructose corn syrup.
Stay away from anything that is an unnatural,
and highly concentrated chemical
from a plant that should be consumed
in its full spectrum bio-available nutrient complexity.
That's the way nature delivers food,
as a nutrient complex
not as one isolated nutrient.
One of the most important realizations
that people need to get onto here when they're eating,
is that the breads and any of these fluffy carbohydrates
they're converted into sugar right in your body.
So within minutes after you eat them they become sugar.
So a lot of people say "I'm avoiding sugar"
because they're not eating crystallized sugar in that form, or drinking liquid sugar,
but they're eating a bread, or a pancake, or a muffin or a corn bread.
Corn bread used to be made out of corn,
and not sugar, and now it's like a corn cake.
It's sugarized corn cake.
And when you eat that, it becomes sugar internally
and has a very high glycemic index.
And a high glycemic load.
- I'm just going to lunch.
So when you're thinking about what to eat if you're working to reduce the sugar,
your definition of what is sugar really needs to expand.
It's more than just the white powder.
There's breads, pasta, cereal, rice, potatoes, corn,
waffles, pancakes ...
Pretty much any food for breakfast that most people eat
In America,
we're eating about 68 kg. of sugar per year, each person.
35 kg. of high-fructose corn syrup.
That's about 22 teaspoons of sugar a day.
There's nothing moderate about that.
Sugar is in everything,
from cough syrup, to crackers to sushi.
I mean it's very hard to avoid.
The more sugar that we're consuming,
the more increased chronic diseases that we're experiencing,
and also these incredible ups and downs and mood swings.
Because, what sugar does is it increases beta endorphin in the brain,
and that's a feel good natural opiate,
morphine-like substance.
And so, when you are depressed or under stress,
you want to eat what we call "comfort food",
macaroni and cheese,
all the foods that have a virtual delivery system of sugar,
right into body fat.
So, it is not fat that makes you fat, it's sugar that makes you fat.
And it is very easy and cheap to produce foods
that become sugar quickly.
Think of something like a croissant.
Many people I know that just say
"You know I've gone on a sugar-free diet",
and they say it while eating a croissant.
And I think, that sugar, what do you think is going to happen?
As soon as it enters the bloodstream, that *is* sugar.
What we're really talking about is, getting that hit,
getting that sugar high,
getting that beta-endorphin rush, that people are looking for
to soothe themselves when they are under stress.
But once you understand
that sugar is a drug, just like alcohol is a drug.
And so what happens with any addiction is this:
you become habituated to the effect.
And therefore you need more and more and more, over time
to give you the same effect.
It is no different than it is with sugar.
We know the problems caused by something like cocaine, purified cocaine.
We know that causes problems. We're comfortable with referring to that as a drug.
We're becoming culturally more comfortable
with recognizing white sugar as a drug.
I think people are starting to understand how addictive a substance it is.
If you walk the aisles in the average grocery store,
and you look at the amount of sugar
in a child's breakfast cereal.
You might as well be rolling up the kid's sleeve and putting in heroin.
Because it's the same.
Jamie Oliver TED Talk, February 2010
Milk ain't good enough any more
because someone at the Milk Board,
don't get me wrong, I support milk,
but someone at the Milk Board probably paid a lot of money
to some geezer to work out that if you put loads of flavorings and colourings
and sugar in milk, right, more kids will drink it.
For me, there ain't no need to flavor the milk.
There's sugar in everything.
I know the ins and outs of those ingredients - it's in everything.
Even the milk hasn't escaped the kind of modern-day problems.
There's our milk, there's our carton.
In that, is nearly as much sugar as one of your favorite cans of fizzy pop,
and they're having two a day.
So, let me just show you. We've got one kid here
having, you know, 8 tablespoons of sugar a day.
There's your week.
There's your month.
And I took the liberty of putting in
just the 5 years of elementary school sugar.
Just from milk.
Now I don't know about you guys, but judging from circumstances,
any judge in the whole world,
would look at the statistics and the evidence,
and they would find any government of old guilty of child abuse.
That's my belief.
The challenge we have with food, and in particular sugar
is because it's illegal to give a child a cigarette,
and so it should be.
It is illegal to give a child alcohol.
It's not illegal to give a child white refined sugar, or refined fats.
Food, as far as I am concerned,
kills more people than all drugs on earth combined.
And again, to go back to the beginning,
people know this, so why are highly intelligent people
not stop it?
Because they don't know the nature of the trap.
I used to be so addicted to sugar that I would literally
throw my food out and take to the garbage.
So I would go get ice cream and cherries, and donuts,
I'd have a pig-out fest.
And I had to throw my food in the garbage and ...
then I would go dig through the garbage and get the sugar.
And then I got to a point where the only way I wouldn't take to the garbage
was to spray it with Windex.
So, you tell me that that's healthy and imbalanced?
Now, we think about: "Wooo, cocaine, heroin?"
All those big drugs, but the truth is that premature death
is coming from sugar and alcohol, and smoking of course.
So if you begin to think about these massive doses of sugar
as no different from drugs and alcohol,
then you get a handle on the situation.
Hey everyone. Welcome back.
Now I would like to introduce you to our special guest I have with me in the studio,
Harvey Diamond, health guru and the author of "Fit for Life".
Harvey is here to talk to us about something he is very passionate about: Dieting.
Harvey, tell us what you think about diets.
So many people want to know about diets,
because people are going to try them, but they don't work.
The first chapter of the first book I ever wrote
was called "Diets don't Work" because they're temporary.
What they're doing is taking one of the food categories that
we must have to live: Protein, fat, carbohydrate.
And one of those is eliminated and if you do that,
some weight will be lost temporarily.
Let me ask you something:
Do you want to be healthy temporarily? No.
But you want to lose weight temporarily.
They have failure built right in to them.
There was a study done at UCLA once
that said 90-95% of the people who go on a diet
will not only gain that weight back
they will add more weight,
because they're so happy to be eating again
that they don't eat intelligently.
Maltodextrin, cocoa, artificial flavor,
Gum Arabic, ANS, ...
Sodium phosphate, aspartame, acesulfame-K
colour, caramel,
Phosphoric acid, aspartame, potassium benzoate,
Natural flavors, caffeine, sodium benzoate
You can lose weight on a diet,
but it's a little bit like borrowing from Peter to pay Paul.
I mean, you can get 4 kg. off your body through sheer force,
but you're going to have to pay back with interest. You will pay back with 6 kg.,
because every time you force yourself to lose weight,
your body is going to want to have extra weight
to protect you from a "perceived famine".
And I've lived through this, where I'd lose 4 kg. gain 6 kg.,
lose 4 kg., gain 6 kg,
until I had gained over 90 kg.
When I say I tried every diet
besides meeting face-to-face with Atkins, going to a Pritikins,
I had naturopaths, homeopaths, acupuncture.
I had these seeds taped to my ears from an acupuncturist.
It was supposed to be an acupressure point.
So every time you're hungry you're supposed to press it.
I walked through the streets of New York, every time I'd smell pizza,
I'd sit there and press these seeds in my ear.
This is what I lived with, and I really did work at it.
You know, people think that overweight people
are just weak and lazy and overindulgent.
I am a very disciplined person,
but when my body wanted to be fat,
I could not lose the weight.
Dr. Alejandro Jünger: I think we're barking up the wrong tree.
People are looking for a result that is superficial,
just to look good.
They don't really consider that that could be done
from the inside out, right?
So people go into diets, and all these fads,
in order to lose weight, and lose weight fast.
And that's just not the way to approach it.
The results prove it.
We are violating our bodies' basic
survival laws, over and over and over again.
The whole dieting paradigm is flawed.
And every diet that comes out, every week there's a new diet,
based on the same idea that you could somehow
force yourself to lose weight.
And it's flawed, it's based on a fundamental flaw
that every time you force yourself to lose weight,
your body will force you to gain weight.
So I think what happens is we set ourselves up for failure,
because yes, you can manipulate the ratios of calories,
you can manipulate the ratios of fat to protein,
to carbohydrates infinitely.
We keep seeing all these variations.
I remember the high carbohydrate low fat,
and then it switched to "well, let's go high protein low carbohydrate",
and then it switched to high fat moderate carbohydrate.
It just keeps switching around. And all all of these things have an effect
because what you're doing is restricting calories from people,
or you're manipulating the way the metabolism works.
And that's why the Atkins diet was so miserable for me,
because I was so addicted to carbs.
You know, to what I call now "dead food".
I was so addicted to it, to try to go off that
at the end of the day
I was just miserable, and what I used to do I used to swap diets,
because the Atkins diet is zero carbs,
And then the Pritikin diet is all carbs.
My wife used to joke with me that
I was on the Atkins diet during the day
and the Pritikin diet at night,
because I would come home at the end of the day
and I just couldn't take going a whole day without carbs.
I had to have bread.
The definition of a diet, is the foods
that an organism habitually eats to sustain itself.
So what we are talking about is a real diet,
in the sense of what a species eats.
When we get on to a real diet,
we will not have to think about these things any more.
But if we're going to eat from those sweetened foods that exist in the supermarket,
we're going constantly to have problems, and we constantly have to monitor ourselves,
because these foods make you fat.
So, if you look around the world,
we see human beings have been able to inhabit the whole globe.
And they have been able to do it on a host of different foods. From the extreme Arctic,
where people eat almost exclusively
animal fat, and muscle and organ meats,
to the jungle, where people had access to far more fruits, and far more plant material.
We see people thriving and people staying lean and healthy,
and avoiding degenerative disease and not putting on extra weight,
almost no matter what they eat.
Now, we are eating a diet that no longer resembles that.
So it's kind of like if we lived in a zoo.
If you put a human being in a zoo,
the way you put a chimpanzee in a zoo,
the question would be: what do we feed that human in the zoo?
We don't feed chimpanzees in zoos
Captain Crunch cereal, Twinkies and donuts.
We feed them a diet that looks like the diet they eat in their ecosystem.
We sort of live in a zoo-like environment now,
we live in this artificial environment.
And unfortunately, we are not feeding ourselves
the foods we're biologically adapted to.
If you cut down on any food, regardless of what the food is,
you say "as of Monday ...", it's always a Monday.
Everyone's always going on a diet on a Monday.
They tend to consume enormous amounts of food,
from Friday to the Sunday.
Sunday, they tend to go shopping,
and they put in stuff that they wouldn't ordinarily, if ever, put in,
fruits and vegetables, as an example.
And it's funny, because I've been on a million diets,
and, in the past, when I went on those diets,
when I was overweight myself,
I would arrive at the check-out, on the day before my diet would begin,
I would have so much healthy stuff.
I would be so proud of my trolley.
And I'd wanted the check-out person to say something,
"Look, this isn't ordinary. Look how much fruit and veg I've got."
I would then start on the Monday morning,
and I would immediately start to feel deprived.
Now think about this.
I could have gone sometimes till 2 o'clock in the afternoon
not thinking about food, when I wasn't "on a diet"
without consuming any food. Sometimes I'd grab some water, or ...
sometimes nothing. I hadn't thought about it.
But the very second
I told my brain, that I was on a diet,
I went into the mode of CAN'T.
If you go through "I want that but I CAN'T have it"
to "I CAN have it but I don't want it",
there's a massive paradigm shift.
Don't turn in to a diet.
Keep the focus always on adding,
if it's for example ... the types of food we need
are foods that were not man-made, because man-made foods
our body doesn't know how to process,
doesn't know how to digest
and it causes hormonal chaos that causes us to gain weight.
David Wolfe : The best strategy we've got is to just add in the good stuff.
Eventually, it's going to crowd out the bad stuff,
and that works for everybody.
It makes everything so simple
it completely deactivates all the mental neuroses we have about diets
and what we have to eat and all that kind of stuff.
Let's just add in the cucumbers.
Let's add in the apples.
The simple foods: the plant foods, the fruits, the nuts, the seeds,
the vegetables, the animal foods of high quality.
Start looking at the foods in your house and asking yourself,
"Could I replace this food with a well-grown
local option, that is not as processed?"
For instance, if you are used to making pancakes out of white flour,
can you go to a farm locally that
produces flour and stone grinds it?
Can you find that?
If you look in your fridge and you've got milk in there
and you know it's processed milk, and it's got growth hormone in it,
and you know it's pesticide laden, you know there's pus in it.
Can you find a farm locally
that can produce that food for you the way people used to get it?
If you've got bananas in your house from the supermarket,
can you replace them with an organic option?
Can you move in a direction that brings you towards
the re-approximation of your Natural diet?
Can you do that?
If you start adding that in, all of a sudden all those other choices start moving away.
Inevitably
you're going to feel so much better eating the good stuff,
that the choice for the bad stuff is no longer valid.
I had very bad sleep apnea, I was borderline type 2 diabetic,
elevated triglycerides and cholesterol.
I'd worked with Dr. Atkins face to face in New York
and in the end the best he could do was yell at me for being
so fat and because I was killing myself.
"What are you doing? You're killing yourself."
And I thought to myself, "You've sold two-hundred million copies of your books,
do you think I'm going to lose weight because you're mad at me,
that's the best you can do?"
I was over 180 kg.
After I had that sort of epiphany and changed my focus from diet to
finding the real reasons why my body wanted to be fat,
I then went on to lose more than 100 kilos over a two and a half year period.
That was 7 years ago.
Hey gorgeous,
thought you might find this interesting
after our chat this morning.
www.hungryforchange.tv
Hope you're all good. Amanda.
There was a point when I had allowed myself to get to 136 kg.,
and that world, as opposed to the current world,
is vastly different.
When I was overweight and when I was sick,
I didn't even know that I was sick.
But I just thought that life was passing me by,
life was just not fun.
The only fun I had was watching people
on TV having fun.
It's a very dispiriting thing,
you wake up in the morning and you ...
I was immediately aware of my body.
And I was immediately aware that I didn't like it.
It felt a little bit like being wrapped in a blanket,
with 3 holes in it.
Two to watch TV and one to eat. And that's it.
I got to this point where I was 40 years of age,
I was fat, sick and nearly dead.
I was 310 lbs, (or 141 kg.),
I was taking high doses of steroids
every day, day and night, for 8 years.
"I was a cheeseburger away from a heart attack."
And I said, "No more.".
"Got to do something about this, Joe.".
"You're not as smart as you thought you were.".
What actually happened after that
period of time was that
my body gave up to the pressure
of what I was putting it under.
When I talk about the pressure I was putting it under,
it was like: lack of sleep,
poor diet, too much alcohol,
smoking, no exercise. I mean, you know ...
throw everything in, I had it all.
Now, a lot of us have some healing to do.
We have recovery to do, because the world we grew up in
has been such a barrage against our nervous system,
our endocrine system. Our health has been under attack.
So sometimes there's going to be a period of healing.
We decided, as a race, to experiment with chemicals.
We've created over 75,000 synthetic chemicals since 1940.
We've released them wholesale into the environment.
They're in the food chain, they're in us,
they've contaminated every single creature on Earth.
We now have to clean up.
Now we have to actually turn it around
and decide that we're going to move away from "better living through chemistry"
and move towards the idea of better living through working with nature
and natural laws.
And the body has two ways of defending itself,
which are generic ways.
One of them is the production of mucus
to coat these chemicals,
so that they buffer the irritation,
or it retains and even generates more fat
because, as we said,
most of these chemicals are lipophilic, or fat-loving.
They don't dissolve in water, they dissolve in fat,
so they attach to fat.
Now, if you just sweat it off,
and force the body into burning fat,
without creating the conditions for the
body to be able to cleanse and detoxify
and neutralize and make these chemicals water-soluble so that they can be
sweated off and peed off,
you're burning fat, but not really getting rid of the toxins.
These toxins are left to cause the damage
that they were not causing because they were surrounded by fat.
So as long as you are taking in more toxins than you're eliminating,
your body is not going to let you burn fat.
Because burning the fat will just put more toxins into your body.
So you have to address the fact that you're being assaulted with toxins
before your body will allow you to let go of weight.
The body only wants to heal, it's crying out to heal,
that's all it wants to do.
It wants to naturally detoxify
Only the body can detoxify itself,
provided there's no toxins coming in.
Probably the best thing a person can do in the beginning
is kind of clean themselves out, get on it like a detoxification program.
Foods that detoxify the body,
some are really obvious and some are not.
Some of the more obvious ones are green vegetables.
Chlorophyll-rich foods. In hospitals, chlorophyll
was used as an "internal deodorant".
For people who had a lot of body odour.
Chlorophyll is a great way to clean our bodies out.
So, those are of course all of our well-grown organic vegetables
These are fantastic for cleaning our bodies out.
There's some less obvious stuff as well though,
like gelatinous plant foods, for instance things like Chia seeds,
or Aloe Vera or the seaweeds.
These foods that have a gel that they secrete when they get wet.
What those do: those gels move through our intestinal tract.
If we eat something like chia seeds.
If we can blend that into a drink some way or something like that and get it into our bodies,
these gelatinous fibers move through our intestinal tract
absorbing things, binding them and passing them through.
Particularly what they do is they absorb the bile salts
that are released by the liver,
bind those up and pass those out with all the fat-soluble
toxins that the liver is trying to get rid of.
If you don't have these gelatinous fibers, we tend to re-absorb a lot of that.
So, our liver tries to get rid of something,
puts it in bile and dumps it into the small intestine
hoping that it eventually gets out of us, but it gets re-absorbed.
So gelatinous fibers can really do a lot to clean out the liver.
I want to mention two other ingredients
that are specially useful for detox.
That is: parsley and cilantro.
Parsley cleanses your entire blood supply
and it also gives you fresh breath.
Parsley has so much Chlorophyll that it just cleanses your whole system.
Cilantro binds with heavy metals.
A lot of people are getting mercury
especially through the fish that they're eating
or through their dental fillings.
And if you eat cilantro, it can bind with that
and remove it from your system,
so that the mercury doesn't get lodged in your body's cells.
And mercury, as you know, is very toxic.
It's a neurotoxin.
You don't want that anywhere in your brain cells, right?
But cleansing our bodies is not complicated, it's not difficult.
It's just going to require high quality green plant food.
It's going to require gelatinous fibers, it's going to require good water.
It's going to mean needing good air,
it's going to mean getting sunlight.
Our body *wants* to cleanse itself.
It's looking to cleanse itself and knows *how* to cleanse itself.
You don't even have to do very much.
Just input gentle foods, be out in nature,
your body will cleanse itself very easily.
And when the weight starts coming off
people become so excited they don't want to stop.
And then eventually, starting to add more and more foods back in, from healthy sources,
that looked like the foods they used to eat,
but are actually more satisfying and more nutritive.
And they'll find that they can live a life of
not just being fit and trim,
but actually feeling how they've always wanted to feel,
in a body that works properly
and that stays healthy for ever.
For me, it's back to nature and it's back to the garden.
If it's made in the garden, then I eat it.
If it's made in a lab, it takes a lab to digest.
If it has a shelf life longer than me, I don't eat it.
That's just common sense.
The simpler I get, the healthier I get.
Dr. Joseph Mercola: So, as you seek to improve your health
you're going to want to include certain types of foods, classes of foods
that are typically ignored in the American culture.
Now this is not controversial.
The most conservative Nutritionist
will recommend that we need 6 to 8 servings of fruits and vegetables.
I always twist that around, it should be vegetables and fruits.
Because vegetables are really the most beneficial food group that we can have access to
and most people are not getting enough.
They just aren't. I mean you need a lot of good vegetables
because they're full of the full range of vital nutrients
and Antioxidants and everything that you need to stay healthy.
Now one of the ways that I cheat this,
because getting vegetables is a challenge,
is that I do vegetable juicing.
So I'll typically buy 20 lbs. [9 kg.] of vegetables a week, maybe more,
and juice a few pounds a day,
essentially a quart [1 lt.] of dark green vegetable juice
that consists of, as a base
I like celery and cucumber as the base,
and I add the dark deep green leafy vegetables,
like kale, or collards. There's a number of different types of kale.
Those are the two big ones
but then you can also use other dark green vegetables.
Jason Vale : Juicing is important for two main reasons.
People often say to me, you know, "why don't we just eat it?".
That's a good question first of all.
Why don't we just eat it?
We don't. That's the first thing to address.
The point is that most people don't consume
enough raw fruits and vegetables in the spectrum of colours.
That's the number one.
Secondly,
most people are overfed and they're undernourished.
And so their digestive system is beaten up
over years and years of trying to digest,
extract the nutrients and dispose of the waste
of the wrong kind of foods.
Juicing is important as well because it's easy to absorb.
It's the ultimate fast food.
If you say you want a fast food diet, get juicing.
Because if you think the average
dinner will take anything from 4 to 16 hours
to leave the stomach and the body try to digest it.
Freshly extracted juice is the 15-minute nutrient express to health.
That's what it is.
It goes into your stomach and in 15 minutes into your cells.
And also let's be fair
you'll consume far more raw, fresh vegetables
the kind of vegetables you
wouldn't ordinarily eat.
Juice, mix with a little bit of apple, pineapple, a bit of lime.
You can jazz up some of these juices so they taste divine.
So, can you imagine, you remove refined sugars
refined fats, junky-type foods,
all the wheat, the breads, the man-made foods coming in to your body.
And all of a sudden, overnight
you replace it with high water content, that's what it is,
pure high water content, organic-rich mineral
Vitamin-rich fuel, going into every single cell of your body.
And it's easy to digest and absorb forms
With the spectrum of colours, with everything the body requires.
What do you think the body is going to do?
It's not going to reject this at all.
It's going to look and say: "Now I'm on board.",
"Now you are good for me,"
"let me shine for you".
Joe Cross : Twenty years ago, this is what I saw when I looked in the mirror.
Looking good. Well the years rolled by
and I kept seeing that same fit-looking bloke looking back at me.
Who was I kidding? I didn't look like that any more.
I looked like I'd swallowed a sheep.
So now I started a switch to alternative paths.
I tried everything. I did witch-doctors, I did mud-baths, I did ...
acupuncture, I did the lot.
The one thing which I was really afraid to face up to
was changing what I put into my mouth.
Frank Ferrante : I'd never heard of a raw food restaurant.
Raw food? How do you cook raw food?
- Look at that breakfast!
- This looks like it should be mowed.
- It actually was mowed and then turned into that.
I didn't know anything about vegetarians.
I knew Gandhi was a vegetarian.
Vegan? I thought vegan was a planet.
I had no idea of that world.
Evita Ramparte was diagnosed with ovarian cancer in 2000.
Evita Ramparte : So I decided to experiment.
I was fighting for life here. What if it worked?
So I went to a farmer's market and got a lot of veggies, beets, and kale
and all sorts of things. They all didn't look attractive to me
because there was no dessert there.
And then I cleansed for three days, juicing, juicing, juicing
and detoxifying my body.
Joe Cross: I guess the way I looked at it was I'd turned my back on Mother Nature.
And I wanted to conduct an experiment where I was the lab rat.
What would happen if I ran towards her full steam,
would she open her arms and embrace me? And would I be healed?
I went straight to juicing and a plant-based diet.
Now within basically ten to fifteen days
the fog had lifted and I was on the path.
After about two weeks, I did notice my energy coming back.
Colours just a little bit brighter.
Just after three days of plan, I lost 7 lbs. [3 kg]
After four months, while continuing a healthy diet
I was cancer-free, my skin clear.
It was the first time ever that I lost weight naturally so fast.
At the end of the day
This is kind of like your last area of control in the world.
What you do with it is what you take and what you put in here.
Nobody can control you on that.
Dr. Alejandro Jünger : Cleansing and detoxification has a side effect.
It will make you lose weight.
It will make your eyes white,
it will make your skin glow.
There's no need to think about that, right?
Those are side effects of cleansing and detoxification.
Whatever you're going for
I think you can ultimately get it
when you start to change your diet and lifestyle.
A lot of people look at me and tell me you must be in your twenties.
Well, no, I'm not.
And that's always a nice compliment.
I love hearing that people think I'm a lot younger
than I am, and I am headed into my 40s.
And certainly I think that this lifestyle
has helped me not only live
with a chronic disease, but also
feel young, feel young in my skin
and depending on the light, it looks pretty good too.
The truth is that we were programmed as a species
to be attracted to the people who look good.
Why? Because they are the healthiest ones.
We are naturally designed to "screen" each other for health
for reproductive purposes.
When we look at each other and we see glowing skin, we see shining eyes
and that's sexy to us. A confident person is sexy to us.
Unconsciously, people look for symmetry,
they look for skin tone,
steady skin tone,
not a lot of splotchy type of colours on your skin.
Why? Why is this built in to our definition of beauty?
Why does the beauty industry spend so much time
trying to create products that you put on your skin
to make your skin look artificially monotone?
The answer is because those are the cues that we pick up on.
It makes you look younger or more sexy.
Ultimately, that, to me, is what we're striving for:
is a deep richness of skin tone.
A deep richness of hair, a lustre in our nails,
an overall feeling of shine and glow, even almost an aura.
This is possible through natural foods.
This is possible through certain strategies of using natural foods
and certain supplements.
Through juicing especially. If by avoiding fried foods
and avoiding the highly oxidated foods
that destroy your skin and destroy your internal organs.
Fried foods are the worst, in my opinion.
And barbequed foods. They're highly toxic
and loaded with carcinogenic chemicals.
If you can avoid those or at least greatly reduce those
and increase your intake of super-foods:
Chlorella, Spirulina, fresh juice from vegetables and fruit
that you can make in your own kitchen.
And your skin within 30 days, it will turn around completely.
Your friends will ask you what's your secret.
And when you tell them "I've been juicing fresh produce"
they will say "well, I was going to buy a skin cream",
because they want the easier way.
But if you have good friends, they might start juicing with you.
Because your juice beats their skin cream.
The skin is a true symbol of our health
because it is the last place to get nutrition.
If you can drive all those nutrients all the way through to the skin
then you know it's gotten everywhere else too.
And that's something that we all recognize.
If somebody's got beautiful skin
it tells us and invites us to a deeper understanding
of what's going on inside the body.
We know that they're generally having a healthier liver,
kidneys, heart, lungs, etc.
So, let's take vanity.
It is a very good entryway,
because your skin looks better
when you're eating a diet that is low glycemic,
where the blood sugar is stable.
As a matter of fact, that's one of the first things that happens.
Your skin, your hair and your nails begin to look better.
One of the reasons that I personally stopped eating
so many grains and high-glycemic foods
is over the years I noticed a couple of things.
First of all, there was weight gain.
Every year, a little more.
And every year harder and harder to keep off.
Second, me and my patients
all started to have fingernails that broke,
hair that broke
and skin that was getting all red, and broken blood vessels and all that stuff.
When you eat well, that goes away.
We can only eat so much in a day. Therefore, the idea of eating for beauty is:
let's make those foods beauty foods.
Like olive oil and olives,
cucumbers, radishes, hemp seeds
Aloe vera, coconut products.
Properly fermented food, talking about yoghurt,
talking about kimchi and talking about sauerkraut.
We use those foods to help us digest
and to replenish the bacteria that colonizes our intestinal tract.
Let's focus on the beauty minerals, like Silica
and Iron and Manganese that give glow and charisma.
Sulfur and what it does to our connective tissue
and how it reverses age-related lines
and how it fills out our protein make-up
so that our musculature and our overall build
reflects the higher qualities
almost the symbolical qualities that beauty points to.
The cosmetic industry
seems to be a wholesale dumping ground
for just about every single type of chemical that exists.
From Lead compounds, Mercury compounds
compounds that are made from horse urine, namely "urea".
There are all different kinds of synthetic compounds
that make it into the cosmetic industry
Like sodium lauryl sulfate
and other sudsing agents
that are used in detergents, that are used in shampoos and body lotions.
All this kind of stuff.
Mike Adam : The skin creams that you buy are almost all
loaded with toxic chemicals.
Most of them contain fragrance chemicals.
We did a lab analysis of a popular perfume product
and it showed that it contains 21 different toxic,
potentially carcinogenic chemicals,
none of which are listed on the label.
So if you think about it: How do you want healthy skin?
Do you want your skin to be treated
with Nutrition from the inside out,
or do you want it coated with petrochemicals
and toxic chemicals, and artificial fragrance products
from the outside, which will be absorbed in?
And then they will get into your liver, and your heart, and your kidneys and your brain
and they will cause disease inside.
200 lbs. [88 kg]
Kris Carr : It's not just what you're eating, it's also what's eating you.
So, where is the sweetness missing in your life?
What else is going on? What kind of suffering are you going through?
What's going on between this ear and this ear?
Dr. Christiane Northrup : There is an interesting study, called "The A Study",
the "Adverse Childhood Experiences" study
done by Vincent Felitti, at Kaiser Permanente in San Diego.
And they were working with obese people
and what he's coming to the conclusion of is
that obesity is not the problem, it's a solution.
So let's take a look at that.
It's a solution to chronic stress.
It's a solution in many people to sexual abuse,
dysfunctional family situations and so on.
Jon Gabriel : You know, I've talked to so many people
that have been overweight all their life,
and I always ask them "when did it start?".
- "When I was 4 years old."
- "What happened when you were 4 years old?"
- "Well, my father was an alcoholic and he beat me."
Or "we moved to another country and I was really scared".
Let's look at why you're not satisfied.
Are you in a dead-end job?
Are you married to someone who treats you like crap?
Are you suffocating under the weight of too much pressure in your life?
Are there some old residual traumas and dramas
that need to be attended to,
some unfinished business, that's getting you stuck,
and making you keep spinning your wheels,
that are ultimately encouraging you to make poor food choices.
"Dear diary, today I feel very sad
And I want to eat *everything*.", right?
I think a lot of people when they're stressed
or sad they turn to food for comfort.
Especially all foods that they ate growing up.
Meatloaf, mashed potatoes, cake, cookies,
all those things that you ate or you got from your mom.
And it goes back to that time of
being nurtured and nourished and what-not.
One of the best pieces of advice I ever got from my spiritual teacher was
"If you're upset, don't eat."
And I think it's so profound
because, often times when we are upset,
we have no connection to whether or not we are satiated or not.
Whether or not we're full,
because we're trying to fill
a void that can never be filled with food.
So the type of stresses are like nothing that
you would ever associate necessarily with waking,
sleep deprivation, dehydration, mental and emotional stress.
You're driving to work, you're stuck in traffic,
your boss is going to get mad at you.
That's causing chemistry.
Every time you have a mental or emotional stress
it's causing chemistry in your body. Real chemistry.
And when that chemistry is the same
chemistry as a famine,
your body is going to want to gain weight. It's trying to protect you from the stresses in your life.
It doesn't know what to do.
We're living in a world that's so different
from the way it was thousands of years ago,
where all we had to worry about was not being eaten by a tiger
and where our next meal was coming from.
Now we've got to worry about how we're going to pay our mortgage,
or our credit card, or if our kids are going to go to school,
or if the world will get blown up.
All these stresses are causing chemistry
and our bodies are trying to protect us.
People get so mad, we get so mad with our bodies.
We hate our bodies
because we think that the body is trying to sabotage us, it's out to get us.
No. It's just a protection mechanism. It's nothing more.
When you are under stress,
you have the stress hormones cortisol and epinephrine.
And if you've ever seen anyone on steroid medication,
such as Prednisone,
you see that the first thing that happens is they gain 20-30 lbs [9-14 kg.],
no matter what they're eating.
In fact, when your cortisol, stress-hormone levels, are high enough,
they've documented the fact that looking at a donut
actually changes your metabolism.
The number one best way to digest stress hormones
is sleep.
And deep sleep
will metabolize excess cortisol and epinephrine,
better than anything else.
So I want people to try something.
If you've been under stress, and you sleep for only 3-4 hours a night,
you will gain 2 lbs. [1 kg.] just from that alone,
because the stress increases fluid retention.
So I call those "liquids pounds."
You want to take care of these "liquid pounds"
before they turn into real pounds, which they inevitably will.
Many many people are sleep-deprived now.
So I'd first like to give people permission to sleep,
and sleep as long as you need to, whenever you can.
So that's sleep.
The second thing that really metabolizes stress hormones,
and this is how the body was designed,
is exercise. When you lift weights or you simply take a long walk,
You're doing a couple of things: one is you're increasing those feel-good hormones
that you would normally have gone to sugar for.
So, Exercise. Taking a walk 3 or 4 times a week
is as good as antidepressants for mild to moderate depression.
I mean this is insane, just exercise alone.
And you know when you get out there and you do it when you're out in the fresh air.
You feel much better, and that's biochemical.
Anything that is sustainably pleasurable
will decrease stress hormones.
Laughter decreases them enormously.
So I would recommend that you have some funny movies lying around.
And that's been clinically shown to improve immunity
and also decrease pain.
I like to look at my before and after pictures
and I wonder how I did.
I can tell you that the body I have now
is exactly the body that I visualized having.
And I'm not sure that's a coincidence.
And I thought about why is visualization so powerful for weight loss.
And visualization for body changing in general.
Arnold Schwarzenegger said he used to use visualization
to become a champion bodybuilder
and he was one of the best bodybuilders.
I've talked to so many other people that have been so successful in visualization,
but what I realized is visualization is like a language
that you can use to talk to your subconscious.
Your subconscious is the part of your brain that's
in charge of a lot of things, but one of the things it's in charge of
is your body's unconscious processes.
How much oxygen you need, it's not a conscious thought.
You don't think how much you need to breathe,
that's unconscious.
How much your heart beats, that's unconscious.
And how fat or thin you should be,
is an unconscious decision,
but it is a decision.
And the problem with this subconscious
or unconscious part of us
is that it doesn't speak English.
And so we're being run by a brain
that we can't talk to.
But when I realized that visualization is like a language
that you can use to talk to your subconscious
because, just like you can't talk to someone
who doesn't speak your language ...
say you have to go to the bathroom in a foreign country,
You could ask a thousand people where the bathroom is, they won't tell you.
But if you draw a picture of a bathroom, on a napkin
in the restaurant or something, and show it to anyone
instantly they know what you mean.
Visualization is the universal... or symbols
is the universal language, for people that don't speak your language.
Your body doesn't speak your language.
When you make a visual image of the way you would like to look,
it could be you at another time,
when you were fit and healthy and happy,
or it could be somebody else, doesn't matter.
Just look at the picture for 30 seconds,
with kind of like as if you're looking through the picture,
and unconsciously, don't look with your eyes, look through it.
Let your subconscious absorb it.
For just 30 seconds.
And then close your eyes,
and either see yourself, feel yourself,
imagine yourself being in that body.
Imagine yourself walking on the beach with that body.
Whatever way you can do it,
and you do it when your mind is calm and powerful, and relaxed.
Your subconscious understands.
And it understands that it doesn't need fat,
and that it's confusing the stresses.
Because it really doesn't know what to do with the stresses of modern-day life.
"Do I get fatter, do I get thinner?"
"How do I protect this person who is so scared?"
So sometimes it uses fat,
but when we can communicate with our subconscious
and say "no, that's not the answer",
"I appreciate it, but that's not what's happening".
"OK, I'll turn the fat programs off".
Just like that, everything changes.
"Whatever you hold in your mind on a consistent basis,
is EXACTLY what you will experience in your life."
Anthony Robbins.
Joe Cross : Unfortunately, most people
and when I say "most" that's like over 50%
of people get out of that morning shower
have a look at themselves in the mirror, when they're alone,
and they're not happy with what they see.
They're just not happy.
And they start out their day
by berating themselves, telling them they are losers
they are no good, they gotta lift their game and all these things.
Now, if you had someone who was with you 24/7
that was just whispering that in your ear all the time
I mean, I don't know about you, but they wouldn't last 5 minutes with me.
Yet, we allow ourselves to do it to ourself.
We do it to ourselves.
Frank Ferrante : There's a group that I go to that says
"Let us love you, till you love yourself"
And when I first heard that
I was so sad.
I became aware of the depth of my self-loathing.
Death seemed, at least ...
I wasn't suicidal.
I occasionally had thoughts.
But it was like, I wasn't suicidal, but I welcomed death.
You know what? Like just turn the switch,
you know, flick the off button.
"I'm ready for the big sleep, man"
And it takes ...
But it's at that point, the genesis of willingness emerges.
That was the genesis of willingness.
And, that crack, as Leonard Cohen says
it's the crack that lets the light in.
That crack let the light in.
Evita Ramparte : Something miraculous, something powerful
happens when you take care of yourself.
You realize you're precious,
you become in love with yourself, basically.
And it shines, it overflows to others, it becomes contagious.
You give others the permission to be in love with themselves and in love with life.
What was the most important thing
to keep off the weight?
What do I believe was the most crucial component? Without question, love.
Love for myself and love for other people.
When we think about love, what love is really,
is love is safety.
Because when you're zero years old, you're a couple of weeks old
if your mother doesn't love you, you're going to die.
Your mother has to take care of you, has to feed you.
You are totally helpless.
So from the moment we are born,
we equate love with safety.
So when you feel like you're not being loved because your partner
or boyfriend or girlfriend doesn't love you,
or because someone out there doesn't love you
then your safety, your primal feeling of safety
has been triggered and activates the stress.
That's going to make you want to hold on to weight.
Thousands of years ago, if your community didn't love you,
you were excommunicated.
If the tribe didn't love you, you were excommunicated.
And so, then you die, because you can't survive on your own
in a tribal world.
So it's totally hard-wired into us, that love equals safety.
SLEEP MORE, EXERCISE, LAUGH MORE!
DETOXICANTS FOODS: CILANTRO AND PARSLEY
DETOX: SPIRULINA, CHIA SEEDS, ALOE VERA
I actually think that the concept of loving yourself
is key to all of it.
Without that, nothing else is going to be sustainable,
because if you have a message in your head:
I'm a worthless piece of crap,
and my life doesn't count for anything, and I'm always a failure and I screw up all the time,
and I'll never be good enough, and I'll never make it
and no one loves me.
The first thing you do is you know that they're probably there.
And Louise Hay, Hay House, has a wonderful practice.
And if anyone would just do this, really do it, for 30 days. And for years
I wrote it out on a prescription. So here it is:
"I accept myself unconditionally right now."
Write it on the prescription.
Their job was to paste it on the bathroom mirror
and twice a day, look deep into their eyes and say
I accept myself unconditionally right now.
Then you wait.
Then you wait, for the messages to arrive.
"You're a piece of shit, there's no way that you can love yourself."
"Look at your size."
"See all that cellulite? What about that body of yours?"
"You're 30 lbs [13 kg] overweight."
"You're unmarried, you're a middle-age woman with cats."
"There's nothing acceptable about you."
That's what's going to come up. That's okay! That's okay.
If you do this for 30 days,
right about day 28, something shifts inside.
And you begin to believe it,
because you're planting a new affirmation.
Rudyard Kipling said
"I am, by nature, a dealer in words,
and words are the most powerful drug
known to humanity."
So you are giving yourself different messages,
and when you start to do that,
you begin to have, you develop, like a muscle,
this witness-self that listens to you talk.
And the stronger that witness-self gets,
the healthier you get.
As a doctor, let me tell you what self-love does.
It improves your hearing, your eyesight, it lowers your blood pressure,
it increases pulmonary function, cardiac output,
helps wire in the musculature.
So if we had a rampant epidemic
of self-love,
then our health care costs would go down dramatically.
This isn't some little fru-fru New Age notion
"Oh, love yourself, honey",
this is hard-core science.
So you can improve your life, and your mind,
and your mindset, your outlook on life
can improve. You've got to ask just basically three simple questions:
Where does my food come from?
What went into the food in terms of attitude
or care, or love or compassion?
And then, thirdly: What is my intention
of doing with the food?
Is the food to support me, for a good purpose,
to do something productive, or is it just entertainment?
Your body was designed to be healthy, health is the natural state.
If we let our body do what it wants to do
in an environment where all the foods are healthy choices, all of them,
we don't have to be concerned with these things any more.
We can live without fear of weight gain
and without fear of degenerative disease.
"Hey Gorgeous!
"Dinner party at mine tonight."
"Don't think Jason knows. Amanda."
"Don't worry. I'll tell him."
- Hi.
- Oh, hey.
- I'm sorry, did you say something?
- Actually, it doesn't really matter any more.
ARE YOU HUNGRY FOR CHANGE?
visit www.HungryForChange.tv
A FOODMATTERS ® FILM
www.FoodMatters.tv