Are you ready?
Didn't think I'd be
this nervous...
Now or never.
Alright, papi, let's do this.
He's over there.
You must be Michael.
Your friend, Fernando, tells me
you can use my services today.
Very much so.
And I assume... thats the
other half of your team?
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
And it's my understanding
you'd like to keep this simple?
We've never actually manage
to keep anything simple...
You can try.
Well.
Let's begin then, shall we?
Family and friends,
we gather here...
To celebrate the union between
Michael Scofield and Sara Tancredi.
- Sorry to break up the party.
- What the hell's going on?
We have an arrest warrant.
- What?
- Wait, wait, wait.
We've talked to Agent
Paul Kellerman in D.C,
we've settle this with the feds.
We settle this with
the feds weeks ago!
Sir, back up!
- We were exonerated.
- Sir...
- We were exonerated!
- Back up!
We're not here for you.
We're here for her.
She didn't do anything.
She wasn't involved.
Don't make this escalate!
Sara Tancredi,
you're under arrest for the
murder of Christina Hampton.
What?
She didn't kill anyone!
Funny. Surveillance camera
footage says different.
Michael.
- Please, right this way.
- Michael. Michael!
- The Final Break -
Edited By:
.: thesurferguy :.
They'll not gonna
let me see her.
Why did Kellerman send you
if you can't do anything?
They're trying to break both of you.
Look, she has constitutional
right to reasonable visitation.
I'll draw up an order to show cause
and get it before the judge immediately.
What do you argue in?
- Do you argue in self defence?
- How?
Anything that might
help her is out of frame.
Security camera only shows Sara
stepping up and firing at the victim.
- Pull the trigger, Michael.
- Drop... the gun!
Misfire.
- She worked for the Company.
- To you.
To a jury, she's Christina Hampton,
Technology Consultant.
And because she was so good
at hiding her true identity,
we can't prove otherwise.
Look, you all get exonerated
did not set well with law enforcement.
If they can make Sara
pay for it, they will.
How much time
is she looking at?
25 to life.
You.
Over here.
Here.
You.
This one's yours.
- Am I supposed to be in a different facility?
- I don't think so.
I haven't been convicted of anything yet.
I'm supposed to be in a jail. This is prison.
Overcrowding and budget cuts, fish.
This is the jail.
That's the prison.
Was'sup homey?
You need some help?
You've got everything
you need over there?
Why don't you go help
and make her bed?
Don't let them spook you.
They just like to intimidate.
They are good at it.
Look.
This jail-prison hybrid thing's B.S.
Come on.
The other one's practically empty.
You can ride it out to
your court date there.
Thank you.
Here. This should be a little
bit more comfortable for you.
Okay.
What's going on?
You know...
At first, I couldn't place your name.
Tancredi.
It sounded so familiar.
But then, Haggs here, figure it out.
I remember your pretty
face from the papers.
You are not going anywhere, fish.
This is going to happen.
Half a dozen guards lost their jobs
and pensions at Fox River.
Another dozen were put on probation,
after you decided
to leave the door open for your boyfriend
and his seven convict pals.
And we... ain't gonna let anything
like that happen again.
Don't worry, we won't
hit the baby basket.
Looked like that welcome wagon
ran over your face.
It looks that way, huh?
Alright, well...
If you need something,
you just ask for me.
Everybody calls me "Daddy".
Special delivery.
You know, all we need is a little cash,
spread around in places.
I told you. The government's
exposing my assets.
You tellin' me you can't get
your hands on the cash?
Unless, that's the least you can do.
Considering you're gonna
kill me not too long ago.
Goodbye, Theodore.
You ain't never been
incarcerated before,
and I never been
incarcerated here. Therefore,
Now let's just say
this handicapped connie
got the juicy hand back
in Fox River.
Your pathetic existence here
can be ameliorated.
As can my life, all with
a little "Roberto De Niro".
One of our friends has been
apprehended by the authorities.
Looks like we've got
a new neighbour.
I'm never gonna get out of
this prison alive. I know that.
I wanna bring my enemy down with me.
I want her...
Dead.
Either way, it's going to
require a capital.
A capital you no longer have.
My rainy day plan.
You know where it is.
Jonathan. I'd assume that
that would be use for your defense.
It's good money at the bad, Joe.
They're not gonna
let me out of here.
No matter how many shots that I have.
Get that. To our friend, in the
sister cells, across the compound.
Excuse me.
Bad move.
Last time someone touched her,
they got a crack kneecap.
You're much braver than
I gave you credit for.
Either that,
or you're amazingly nice.
Do I look like
I wanna talk to you?
I just say, a woman in your position
laid up for some protection.
Join the prison gang?
I don't think so.
Not a gang.
No.
A family.
They don't call her "Daddy"
for nothin'.
That's her wife.
And those are her kids.
- Are you okay?
- Stay the hell away from me.
I need the infirmary.
Can't go down to the infirmiary
without the release form.
I'm having muscle contractions on my throat.
And my jaws tightening up.
It's just--It's just could be indigestions,
I'm not poisoned.
No. That's government cheese.
You'll get used to it.
If I don't get to the hospital
in the next 15 minutes,
I will die and my baby will die.
Please.
Boss.
Why don't you let her
go see the doc?
Please.
This is Kaorla. We have an
inmate going into the infirmary.
We were able to administer
the charcoal ???
You and your baby
are gonna be okay.
You know the ??? didn't get into
my meatloaf all by itself, right?
Well then, you need to talk
to the warden about it.
Then how about talking
to me about your face?
You want to tell me
how that happened?
I caught an elbow
playing basketball.
We should discuss your...
situation.
As I'm sure you've ascertain this isn't
going to be a run-of-the-mill pregnancy.
Can I deliver in here?
No. The day we're induced,
we'll secure you in an ambulance.
We'll take you to St. Lucia
down the road.
We'll cordone off a room.
There'll be 3 armed guards
in there with me,
when you give birth.
Do I get to see my baby?
You'll have 30 minutes
before we take it away.
I've seen this process a dozen times.
After the mothers come back here,
the depression's almost unbearable.
My advice,
it's a lot less messy, if you'd just
think of yourself as a surrogate.
Yeah?
Michael, this Lou Phillips.
Your wife had an incident earlier today.
Someone tried to poison her.
What are you talking about?
Michael, I need you to focus.
Do you have any idea
who might have done this?
Michael?
Michael?!
Go ahead, let him in.
If I had a list of all the people
who might come to visit me,
Your name will be at the bottom,
somewhere below
Jesus Christ and Scooby Doo.
- Someone tried to poison Sara today.
- Mercy--
Only you
would be depraved enough,
to think that killing an innocent woman
and an unborn child
will bring you some kind of peace
before your execution.
Sara is with child?
Congratulations!
This is like the 4th of July and
Christmas day rolled into one.
I am asking you,
father to father,
to leave her alone.
You can kill me
if you want to kill me,
I'll trade my life for hers.
But leave Sara alone.
Michael,
If you were killed,
your pain will last a moment.
If Sara were killed,
your pain will last
the rest of your life.
Now that's got to be appealing
to whoever who put out this hit.
But don't worry, Michael.
If I find out anything,
I'll be sure to let you know.
Prison life can be tough.
If I remember correctly,
you have two missing toes
that can attest to that bag.
I don't think you understand.
She's not safe here!
Please.
Please just approve the
transfer to another facility.
If I grant her a transfer,
everybody's gonna want one.
What about segregrated housing?
Is there something
that I should know about
the structural integrity of shoe?
I can see where this is going.
I know who you are.
And I'm not going to let you turn
my prison into the next Fox River.
All I'm trying to do,
is keep my wife alive.
You do know she's pregnant.
I don't care.
Here.
- Thanks.
-In case I haven't made myself clear--
Sara Tancredi is not getting
any preferential treatment.
And you've made yourself perfectly clear.
Thank you for your time.
- What happened?
- The General wants Sara dead--
And the warden's just
gonna let that happen.
We gotta lure in her case and
needs to get her out, right?
Which is not enough time.
If she stays in that prison,
someone's going to kill her.
I guess we don't have a choice.
We're breaking her out.
In my 16 years in the Bureau,
I've worked cases under
43 different agents.
Alexander Mahone,
is the smartest,
bravest,
most honorable man, I've ever
had the pleasure of serving with.
As one of those 43 agents,
I can't help but feel a bit offended.
Because obviously, I am not as honoured
as this drive addicted murderer.
Alex has been clean and
sober for four months.
And he's been completely
exonerated of all crimes
associated with his
involvement with the Company.
That doesn't include the shooting
and the murder of one Oscar Shales
- and burying his body under his bird bath--
- That is just an allegation--
Let's move on, shall we?
All those in favor of
reinstating Alexander Mahone,
a Special Agent in the Federal
Bureau of Investigation--
Aye.
- All those oppose?
- Alright, alright, I've--
Thank you for the invite, Richard.
It's always a pleasure.
You know, Alex.
This ruling can't be revisited.
If you're able to
sufficiently demonstrate,
just how committed you
are to a life of service.
Now, as you may know,
Sara Tancredi was arrested recently,
and is currently being house at
the Miami Dade State Penitentiary.
We have concerns that Michael Scofield
may have other plans for her.
So this-- this is why
you're invite me in here.
Well obviously, if Scofield were, to be able to
pull off this plot of another breakout,
the public embarassment will
be immensed to the Bureau.
So... having someone to get
us a credible information,
that would be worth something to us.
Agent Whitley is set up in Miami.
He will be your contact.
You're something else.
Now...
We both know...
How badly you want
that badge back.
Give me a reason to give it to you.
What's your plan after we break her out?
We're on the run again?
First thing first.
Let's get her out of there.
Hey papi.
The fed that arrested Sara,
is outside, staking us out.
Look, if you're worried about
getting into trouble again,
go back to Chicago,
go back to your family.
I'll understand.
Are you kidding me?
After all the crap we've been through,
I'm just going to leave you here
and Sara in there?
You shut up and
don't bring it up again.
- What's all that?
- Newspaper clippings--
Covering 7 different escape attempts
from Miami Dade's State Pen--
over the last 60 years.
None of them--
None of them successful.
So we weigh them all,
and we learn what not to do.
Well the prison officials learned a lot,
They re-evaluated,
they retrofitted,
The prison's pratically escape-proof.
- Are you alright?
- I'm fine--
I guess so if we can't go through,
what if we go down?
Like down into the prison?
We--we parachute in.
Yeah.
- Yeah. You parachute in, we find her--
- Are you kidding?
- I'm serious--
- That's suicide!
Newspapers clippings only
going to get us so far.
We need some more
information about the prison.
So let's do some recon work.
Camera, electronic tape measure,
dry ice. What's this?
It's a shopping list.
You need to come with me, doc.
I have a doctor's appointment
for my pregnancy in a few minutes.
It'll wait.
In here.
Hold it.
I don't know what you want,
but I promise you,
I won't go down and fight it.
Damn baby, I ain't gonna hurt you.
Hell, I ain't even gonna touch you.
See, I run the motor
pool detail in here.
And I was thinkin' if you want to
get yourself a little fresh air,
and not have to worry about
getting stab in the back,
then you could come in,
work with me...
You're the fed from my wedding.
Yeah, you can call me Agent Whitley.
I could call you a lot of things.
- Where are you headed?
- Sea World.
Sea World?
There isn't one in Miami.
- My loss.
- No. What really be your loss,
is getting your wife killed,
by doing something stupid.
- Are you threatening Sara?
- No, no. Not at all--
I'm just saying that if you gonna try
and revoke her sentence.
Bullets fly, Michael.
And if she'd get hurt,
that'll be on you.
Funny hearing that from the guy who
put her in prison in the first place.
No, I didn't put her in prison.
State of Florida did.
It's just my job to make sure
that she stays there.
So ah...
where's all your little buddies?
Alright. Drop in some more dry ice.
Fence line is 4 feet...
from the road.
And 32 feet...
from the east camera.
- Hurry up. They're gonna see the laser.
- I'm going as fast as I can, papi--
- He followed you?
- Yeah, but he's gone now--
You guys almost done?
- Almost.
- Great. I'll meet you back at the loft--
Well, you're just a natural.
I bet you are a hell of a surgeon.
Handing out condoms to cons
were makin' you no damn surgeon!
What in the hell
is the matter with you?
- You ain't even ask me if she can come...
- One day, for real!
Can we go one day without
your mouth? One!
Let it be today.
I'm sorry. You've got to
forgive my old lady, she's--
You just a little bit
easy on eyes, you know?
She's just the jealous type.
Crazy is the type she's more like it.
What? You're gonna
watch your tone, Agatha.
Sorry--
- Or you want me take off my belt?
- Sorry--
Kids.
It's rough.
It's hard running a family.
It's important though that, uh--
That you have one--
I have a family.
I have a husband.
Oh, you've got a husband?
Is he here?
They let you bring it in here,
with you, when you came?
No.
Yeah, I had a husband too.
18 years is a long time to wait.
So, you know.
If this ain't for you,
that's cool.
Then you pick up that nasty oil,
take it out and put it
in the repository.
Okay.
We gotta go, bro.
- Take your hands off me.
- When I'm good and ready.
What's Burrows doing at the fence?
Please don't make me
ask you again, Sara.
Nobody here that'll help you but yourself.
Are you going to answer me?
You tried to kill me.
Line it up, cons.
Go back inside.
You, get back to your detail.
Now!
I want you to pass along
an offer to your boy.
What he's paying his people to
dust that Tancredi chicken bitch pop,
my woman are good for a cut rate.
Just what kind of discount
are you proposing here?
Tell him uh--
if he's offering a 100 grand,
my girl will take 30.
No, 40. 40.
Perfect.
I'll tell him.
Hey, five stars.
So you have no cash,
whatsoever...
I'm sorry, I couldn't hear you over
the sound of that broken record.
Got it.
I won't ask again.
Oh, to what do we
owe the honor?
I've been thinking...
Well, no need to be uh, shy.
Just spit it out.
I've change my mind.
No, well maybe Daddy
change her mind.
Maybe she don't want you
here no more.
Sports right. I recently rolled up
my welcome mat. Peace.
- Please.
- Please, what?
Please, may I be a part
of your family?
Take a walk.
Take a walk!
I would love that. I would--
Sit down. I really would.
You see, its not that easy.
It's just saying "I do".
See, in order to make a commitment...
to a family,
It's something you gotta prove.
That's right, we all did it.
It's a commitment...
to the family code.
It's a code you gotta wear.
Alex!
- What's up?
- How are you doing, man?
What's going on?
We gotta talk.
Alright.
They're watching you.
- We know. We gotta a fed on us.
- No. Not just one.
The whole department.
Sounds a lot like inside
information, Alex.
What you do?
Make a deal with the feds?
They offered me my old job back,
if I came down here to spy on you.
Now the fed you're talking about,
his name is Whitley.
He's running point.
So now we know.
So if you really gonna do this,
you gotta do it right.
And I'll help you
if you need me.
What else do you get?
Sara's working the motor pool
today at 4 o'clock.
Motor pool is here.
This hold by two security cameras,
along the perimeter of the prison.
- What about secondary entrances?
- No loading dock, no personnel entrance--
Fences?
15 feet high,
covered with rave wires.
- Electrified?
- No. Why?
If Sara can get herself
back to motor pool,
I think we can find
a way inside.
With all the different retrofits over
the years, the fence line is widened.
But security cameras remain
exactly where they've always been.
They've never accounted for the difference.
- There's a blindspot.
- Yeah. Right here --
If Sara can get back to that spot,
we can breach the fence.
It's risky, Michael.
That's all we've got.
How much time to tell Sara
where we going to meet her?
How? We've got no visitations,
no phone calls.
It's clean.
Take it to Tancredi.
Remember when I taught
you about flowers?
I wish I was with you now.
To see you holding one
in your hand.
Tomorrow. PM.
Seven. Oil dump.
- Sure looks like you've been busy.
- Do you have a warrant, Agent Whitley?
A warrant?
No, I don't need one.
My testimony will be
your brother let me in.
Once inside, saw all this evidence,
right in plain sight.
What judge gonna take
your word over mine?
What evidence?
Those pictures were taken
from public property.
That prison, was paid for
by the taxpayers.
So all you have evidence of,
is an exonerated citizen,
standing on a public road,
taking pictures of a public building.
Last I checked,
it's not a crime.
What if I said that I
could get you on attempt,
just for having all these stuff?
What if I told you that all this
was peace offering?
The warden won't let me see my wife.
So I figured, if I found a
few lapse in the security,
pointed them out as a
gesture of good faith,
she might change her mind?
Is that so?
Find anything yet?
No.
Looks airtight.
Well thank goodness for that.
You guys will let me know
if anything comes up, right?
You'll be the first to know.
On the outside, I was known
for getting the job done.
No matter what.
I got paid well for it.
Now I'm broke.
But I still need things.
- Like what?
- A favor.
I don't do favors for cons.
Really? It's not what it
says on the bathroom walls.
As I understand, you'd do favors
for those who reciprocate.
Is that true?
This is bullshit, Boss!
I'm a veteran around here.
Ain't no reason to toss me!
You low leaf!
Looky, looky here.
No! That brown ain't mine, boss.
You know this!
I do no drugs!
Who put that in here?!
You ugh--! Take your hands off me.
I know where the hold is.
What y'all looking at?
I do no drugs!
Somebody is going down there!
I love you too.
Sofia's making arrangements
in Central America.
Once we break Sara,
we're on the boat, we're gone.
- Hey.
- It's Lou.
Just got a decision from the court.
They're ordering the warden
to allow supervised visitations.
- Where are you going?
- They're letting me Sara.
Pera, pera, pera, pera--
If you going to be listening to every word
you say, you gotta be careful about this.
If she understood my letters,
she'll find a way to tell me.
How? She's going to blink
the Morse code?
Oh my God!
Who did this to you?
I'm okay.
Baby's okay.
Sara, I'm so sorry.
You're in here because of me.
I'm sorry.
This is hard.
- I miss you so much
- No touching--
I miss you too.
You just have to
hang in there, okay?
I'm trying.
But my protection's gone.
- Did you get my letter?
- I did.
I know sometimes it's hard for me
to express what I want to say.
But I hope you understood...
what I meant to tell you.
I did.
Isn't he cute?
You were there for me.
And I will be there for you.
- Okay.
- Alright, that's it.
Time's up.
See you soon.
Bye.
Michael.
I was thinking a lot.
About the photos and the mock-up
that you showed me at the loft.
And I ran a few tests.
Lo and behold,
I've found a blindspot.
Right along the fence line over here,
due to our retrofit.
You didn't know about this, did you?
No, no of course not.
Because you would've told me or the warden
about it if you did, right?
Well, it's a good thing I found this when
I did, in case anyone tries to escape.
Well if we can't go through the fence,
then that leaves under or over.
Look, how she gonna climb that
fence without being seen? Huh?
I'm guessing there's no telephone
wire for her to climb across.
- Then she's gotta go under.
- Alright, lets get some shovels--
What was that you were
saying about parachutes?
Parachutes--
Guys, come on.
You can be ser-- Parachutes?
Couple of thoughts on that.
A - We don't have a plane,
B - We don't have a pilot.
- Have you ever worn a parachute?
- Don't worry, I think I've got a plan.
But we're gonna need some
help from an old friend.
Who?
- You want a favor from me.
- Just hear me out.
Of course. I mean,
when you and Michael send
me back to that prison,
you did give me
a piece of chewing gum.
I mean what kind of man will I be
if I don't quit your pro-quote?
Look,
All you gotta do is sound off
the fire alarm, in here
Tomorrow night
at 7:30.
That's it.
- You're breaking her out.
- Krantz has put a hit on her,
that's a one shot,
of keeping her alive.
Well you're on a pivoted
kind of damn, Lincoln.
We'll put 5 grand on your cake
once this whole thing jumps off.
The love of Michael's life
is only worth of $ 5,000?
That's the best we can do.
- I need six figures.
- That's all we got--
Alackaday for you, I know somebody
who does... the general's man.
He's got the payout for Sara's hit.
You wire that money to me by 7pm
tomorrow, and we're in business.
What is his name?
It's your brother to you
that agony is.
- Come on, you gotta give me more than that.
- Tomorrow. 7pm. Go on, fetch.
You should have seen the
look on Michael's face.
When he saw me fixing that fence
and installing that camera.
You did a great job.
Job's over now.
If Michael has this misguided belief
that Sara's life is in danger,
he's gonna find a way back
into that prison.
Your job will be over until
you give us enough evidence
to put him back behind bars.
So what's the latest?
There's nothing concrete.
But I'll let you know
when I get something.
Alright.
Good man.
Tough going alone.
I know he's breaking you out.
I'm coming with you.
Relax.
Krantz sent me to kill you,
but after what he's put me through,
I'm done taking orders from him.
You're sitting next to me at
the mess when I was poisoned.
You'd think you would've lasted
this long if I wanted you dead?
I want you dead.
You're still alive.
Don't you think it's hard to stay alive
when you know who's coming after you?
There's 200 women in this prison.
Bet do you even get to Gen Pop?
I'm coming with you.
Or nobody's going.
Well, if you're watching this,
I'm glad.
Because that means you're safe.
- How does he think he's gonna do this, bro?
- He's going to jump out of the plane.
I know he's gonna jump.
The question is, can he land?
Not without getting caught.
And how is he going to get
out of cell block, even if T-Bag--
It's a big "if".
Trusting T-Bag is... crazy.
Michael, we uh--
we really have to re-think this.
I have.
And there's no other way.
Okay.
I'm going to drop down
into this outer area here.
And I cut the parachute off
before anyone can reach me.
They're going to be
right on your ass.
I can hide behind this building,
wait for a window.
Then I'll make my way over here.
That's the chapel. Well hopefully uh--
Sara will be waiting.
Why the chapel?
During the riot in '88, prison employees
escaped through the administration building.
They wound up here,
outside the fence.
The administration building,
is connected to the chapel.
Which means that
somewhere in that compound,
there is a subterranean exit.
If we can get through it,
you can meet us there.
- How's Sara gonna get to the chapel?
- She'll have to find a way.
Look, we're doing this at 7pm tonight,
just like we've planned.
- Where have you been?
- What did I missed?
I need you to find a plane
and a pilot.
And you two,
to take care of T-Bag.
Find out exactly who has this money,
and where they're keeping it.
- And then we have to get it.
- By 7pm tonight.
Or Sara's going to die in there.
Is everybody onboard?
Okay.
Tell me, you've completed
your assignment.
Well, I got the cash. But there'll
may be some delay in final delivery.
The woman we hired is having trouble
getting near Sara Tancredi.
Then hire somebody else.
Call it open season.
Put a bounty on her head.
I don't care how you do it.
I want Sara Tancredi
dead by the end of the day.
Open cells!
One hour!
We're about to play cards,
do you want in?
I'm okay.
Thanks.
You should.
With Daddy gone,
you're gonna need your backup.
Hell, we all did.
- I've got uh-- a pre-natal thing.
- It's cool.
Thanks.
Not too smart though, for a
girl with a bounty on her head.
Aren't you heard?
Tancredi, you have a visitor.
Say hello to your husband for me.
What's wrong?
Look, um...
I know you don't have any control
over what's happened here, but uh--
Things aren't working out.
Okay.
I'm trying to find a way to--
To do... this.
But from where we're standing
right now, there's only one option.
Do you need more time...
to think?
No. No, it's not
about that.
I've made up my mind. Cause there's
nothing you could do about it.
Except...
pray for us tonight.
Pray for us?
You can pray for us
to be together.
Maybe I'll do the same.
How can I rob someone if
I've no clue who he is?
The logbook outside says that
Krantz had one visitor yesterday.
A Joe Daniels.
Well if he was in the power deduction,
I'd say, Daniels is your bagman.
You know how many Daniels live Miami?
Thousands. I need more.
Well you better get crackin', cause
if I ain't get that money by 7 o'clock,
you ain't got your fire,
you ain't got your fire alarm.
And that means Pretty
ain't got his Mrs. Pretty.
Listen my friend, you're in
no position to makin' demands--
Okay, shh--
I ain't talking about
backing out the deal.
I put my ear on the ground
and come up with some details.
Good.
And now, fetch.
We've got a pilot.
There's a guy I'd busted 20 years ago,
running drugs across the Gulf.
Went legit.
Went to charter business now.
He must've jumped
out of a few planes, huh?
Yes, several. Some for sport.
Some necessity.
It's a big difference, Michael.
It's not easy hitting the X,
especially at night.
Don't worry.
I can go alone.
- What do you got?
- It's a test.
See, the prison was built
in the mid-80's,
so that exit in the
administration building
is probably protected
by an electronic code of lock,
modified by a security card.
Those locks don't have power protection,
which means you can overwrite them.
Then you can't just go to the building,
shut it and blow it out?
No.
1200 volt power surge will
just set off the other alarms.
Not to mention
that it'll kill you.
- So we have to find another way.
- Yeah--
Yeah.
Talk to me, Mahone.
What have you got?
- Nothing yet.
- I don't need updates on the hour.
I need evidence, intent.
It's not crap.
Call me when he's in the
process of committing a crime.
Yeah.
I'm not going to let him walk
away from me like he did from you.
It's going down if I've
got to shoot him in the back.
Sorry.
Are we friends now?
Get out of the way!
What happened here?!
I didn't see anything, sir.
Move!
Bad news.
Agatha Warren is dead.
- Who did that?
- No one's talking.
But I hear it says fish.
Tancredi and Morgan.
No!
There he is.
If you don't like this guy,
we can still find someone else.
Good to see you, Sni.
What you get into here, Mahone?
Jumping off 1500 feet
ain't going to be easy.
You've gone back
on your word already?
Let's not forget who's
doing who a favor here.
Favor?
Favor that I bust your old lady
for traficking. No, I did not.
If anyone asks,
I was flying tourists to the Keys,
- And it's not my fault they jumped.
- Sounds good to me.
If you don't like this guy,
we'd take a day
- We come up with a new plan.
- No, there's no time, Alex.
-It's not just Sara's life at risk.
- I understand that.
I know you do. That's why I also
know I can ask for your help.
- Yeah. What do you need?
- If I don't make it--
I want you to make sure Sara and
my brother get out of the country alive.
I need to know
they're gonna be okay.
And I'm gonna trust that you'll do
everything you can to make that happen.
Take this.
I trust you, Alex.
Remember that.
Special delivery.
- What is it?
- I don't exactly know.
It came via messenger from uh--
the lady side.
"My man on the outside needs to know
who to call for the birthday present."
Who's birthday is it?
Well see to it that it gets back
to the same place.
Will do.
So this is Joe Daniels number, right?
Is that enough information or you need
a social security number too?
- That'll do.
- Remember--
I want that money wired to
the account number specified.
No wire, no fire.
You boys do me wrong,
I have no qualms at all about singing
it loud and clear, you understand?
You know what?
Just be ready.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
That was Sofia.
She'll meet you at San Andreas harbor
in Dominican Republic and then
- you guys can fly to Costa Rica.
- Cool.
I know where Daniels is.
And after we rob him, I'll take
the money to Quik Green and uh--
wire to the bank.
- You will meet us at the airstrip, right?
- Might give a shot now.
Okay.
This is it.
We're ready.
Thanks, buddy.
For everything.
Good luck, papi.
See you on the other side.
Nobody's talking, huh?
Girl's dead. No one's said any?
I made it in the workshop.
Want to give to my daughter Emily
a birthday gift on her actual birthday.
So I need to get out of here.
- You're never sentimental.
- Oh, I'm not. It's just for her.
We need to get to the chapel.
We?
There's no way out of here right now.
I'm gonna need you.
Yeah?
Mr. Daniels, American Paint Company
here for the job.
Well, this is Mr. Daniels but
I didn't order any painters.
It's Wednesday, sir.
I believe you did.
Hold it right there.
I'm calling the police.
Get out!
This is it.
I'll be right back.
Gotta get that parachute.
Michael!
Come here.
There's a better way.
Mess!
Mess, half hour.
Little faster.
We don't have all day.
Let's go!
Got any ideas?
Yeah. Keep your head down and follow me.
I'll think of something.
You better think of something fast,
'cause we have company.
I hope you're ready
for a fight, princess.
This one's to the death.
Do you think you can overpower her?
Yeah. I don't think it's her
you have to worry about.
Just be ready.
- Hello?
- It's me.
I've got the message
about the birthday present?
- Was the gift earned?
- What in the hell are you talking about?
- The birthday present!
- Birthday present?
Two guys showed up at my house,
they took the money and they beat
the crap out of me.
Howdy, General.
I just thought of let you know
how I came up with some green.
My personal preference is two
Zegna bars and a copy of the Times.
So I see you in the AM?
You worthless son of a whore.
Go to hell!
Careful I don't get there first.
Unless I become the
king of that prison, too.
Alright, from takeoff, the
prison's gonna come up real fast.
So whatever you gotta do
to get ready, do it now.
You get it.
We've got the money.
Sucre's just dropped me off
on the way to wire it.
Good.
That means T-Bag's set.
I'm goin' to see how long it's
gonna take and we get going.
- You sure that thing's gonna hold you up?
- Yes, it'll be fine.
What about you?
This is not my first time
inside a prison.
But hopefully...
Will be my last.
Think about all the amazing stories
that you're gonna tell your kid.
You're gonna be the type
of father our dad never was.
Someone to look up to.
Take care, Michael.
Unless you've got details,
I'm hanging up.
And you can forget about
getting your badge back.
He's got a plane.
He's got a parachute into the yard.
- What?
- I swear to God,
he's gonna be over
prison airspace at 7 o'clock.
Call in reinforcements.
I want 20 armed COs in the yard.
And be ready to turn off
all exterior lights.
Scofield won't see what's coming,
until it's too late.
And bring me Sara Tancredi.
Wait, wait.
What do you think happened with
Agatha, it's not what happened.
I need to make this
right with you, okay?
Go ahead.
I was hoping I'd see you here.
You know I still owe you
one big juicy favor.
Later, blue eyes.
I swear to God she wanted to kill me
and I was just defending myself.
- You remember that?
- Yes, I do.
My momma gave me that.
Told me I was going to give it
to one of my kids one day.
Not only did I get knocked up,
but the girl in the family...
And I practically raised Agatha
and she was no killer.
Now I can say
that much for myself.
You didn't know
what I had in mind yet.
Okay, listen, you're right.
Agatha isn't a killer.
She was just a-- real bitch with
a bit of more than she need to.
Skittles.
Okay.
We cool. We cool.
We cool, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Kaorla. She'd want you to
bring Tancredi to her office.
A'ight? Okay.
Son of a bitch!
They coming right
through here, okay?
Federal agent Todd Whitley.
I need to get inside right now.
Emergency team takes priority, sir.
I'm the leader of the emergency team.
Now let me inside.
- Sorry. Strict orders.
- Go talk to your supervisor. Come on!
No weapons!
Let the suburban through.
The plane should be overhead
any minute.
Hey, fellas!
Kill the lights.
As soon as he hits the ground,
I want one of you to start firing.
Standby.
We're standing by.
Easy now.
Hold your fire.
Standby!
Now!
Let's go.
Move in, men!
Where the hell's Scofield?
Emergency team takes priority, sir.
I'm the leader of the emergency team.
Now let me inside right now.
I've strict orders.
No one gets inside at this point, sir.
I don't know what your orders are.
Go talk to your supervisor.
Why isn't Tancredi
in front of me right now?
We've just got the situation under control.
We're looking for her right now.
Oh my God!
- Are you alright?
- Yeah. It was Morgan.
Check the kitchen.
They might be in the kitchen.
I'm not gonna make it on my own.
Either leave me with tools here
or make up your damn mind.
- Are you gonna be able to make it?
- Yeah.
Okay.
It's now.
Alright, hold up.
Nah, I think we're good.
Don't move!
- Stood on the dark, now!
- Please, I just ...
On the ground!
You're here alone?
Damn it, con. When I ask
you a question, you answer.
Is there anyone else here?
Yes.
Who?
- God.
- Excuse me?
He's always here.
I was worried about my little girl
on the outside.
So I came to pray.
See if someone would watch over her.
Go check it out.
The stove mess is open.
Need support right now!
I've got to get
these animals lockdown!
We better head over there.
I hope that daughter of yours
- is hell a lot smarter than you.
- So do I.
Are you ready to go?
Nobody gets in or out of this prison.
I don't care if it's the President
having to take a piss,
you tell him to turn the hell around.
Get a team.
I want every inch of that fence line
checked for points of compromise.
Yes, sir.
Michael said this is where
they're gonna come out.
You think Sucre make the drop on time?
I don't know.
No, no, no.
Please enter your account number.
9248. #
Your account balance is
zero dollars and zero cents.
If you would like to
access another account--
9248. #
Your account balance is
zero dollars and zero cents.
What the hell you thinking you're
doing, fish? We're in lockdown.
What for?
Something's going on in
bitch block. I don't know.
What's it worth to you
to find out?
We're going to get through here?
On the other side is a kind of an
escape patch for the administrators.
In case of a riot.
If this is the same system
they have in Fox River,
that door can only be open
remotely from the Centre Control.
That's why we've gone
and ask for help.
T-Bag.
Tell them what you told me.
Michael Scofield is about
to stage a prison break.
And I know exactly
how he's gonna do it.
Exactly what did
Scofield asks you to do?
Just light a fire in my cell.
And the rest...
the rest will just take care of itself.
A fire alarm. If that goes off,
what's your protocol?
State law, mandatory evac.
Hell, he won't go break, I was
goin' to get you and escort her out.
- Shut up!
- Get him outta here.
Alright, the evacuation's only
going to get him out in the yard.
Whatever he's up to, he needs noise
and he needs chaos.
Deactivate the smoke detection system,
the fire alarm,
and while you're at it,
kill the horn.
If anybody so much as bends a
blade of grass in this place,
I want him to be able to hear it.
- Why are we waiting for?
- We made a deal.
With the right price,
T-Bag will set off the fire alarms.
That's what we're waiting for.
- Michael, there's a--
- It's okay.
See, there's only one thing you can count on
when you're dealing with T-Bag.
He's a rat.
Anything?
So far just a female inmate
loose in the yard.
- Tancredi?
- No, Morgan. First name, Gretchen.
- Over by the chapel.
- Alright.
Alright.
Great.
Let's go.
Okay, down there.
Okay.
Beyond this door should be
a hundred yards of tunnel.
On the other end of that, is Linc,
and after that,
there's a boat mounted
for the white sands and blue water.
A power surge to the system, will override
the reader, for just a few seconds.
Just long enough for you
to open that, so get ready.
3, 2, 1.
One more time.
I was afraid this might happen.
It's okay.
It's alright.
We're going to keep moving and
we're gonna find another way out of here.
I know what I have to do.
I need units to the chapel.
Now!
- Where are they?
- I don't know.
They should've been here by now.
The battery wasn't
generating enough power.
We have to blow up the system
for the whole building.
Okay.
What do you want to try?
This is the main fuse.
If I yanked that,
everything will go dark
for a second.
I reconnect these two cables...
If I reconnect these two cables,
there'll be a lot of noise,
every light bulb in this place
is going to blow.
As soon as that happens,
you need to open that hatch.
And I want you
to start running.
Okay.
What about you?
Michael?
Sara...
Someone has to stay here,
and someone has to
open the hatch.
And that someone's gotta be you.
Okay. So I'll leave it
open for you.
You don't understand.
This is the only way.
I'm not leaving unless
you're coming with me.
But I am coming with you.
I love you.
God, I love you too.
Go!
Go, Sara.
Go.
Downstairs.
Where's Michael?
Sara, where is he?
Where is he?
He's not coming back.
What do you mean, he's not coming back?
What do you mean by that?
He's not coming back.
He'll be here.
He's gone, Lincoln.
Linc, we've gotta go.
We've gotta go.
Why am I being punished?!
I'm the guy through the window!
You aided and abetted
an escape, Mr. Bagwell.
And as far as the authorities are
concerned, you're an accomplice.
Scofield!
Michael asked me to give you this,
if he didn't make it out.
He said it would help you understand
why he did what he did.
It's his bloodwork.
This is the General's money.
I was supposed to wire it down to
Costa Rica for you to pick up but uh--
I ran into some trouble.
I'm sorry.
You take care of that baby, okay?
You take care yours.
This is for you.
He never said anything to me.
Why didn't he just tell me?
'Cause he knew you'll try
to stop him.
He knew you do anything
to protect your family.
But I didn't.
Well...
You will soon.
Take it easy.
Sara.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Well, if you're watching this,
I'm glad.
Because that means you're safe.
And that's all I ever wanted.
I wish I could...
be there with you.
But as you probably know now,
I wouldn't have much
time anyway, so--
I've made my choice,
and--
I don't regret it.
Anyway,
not too long from now,
there's going to be another
Scofield running around.
And Linc,
I want you to promise me,
no matter what,
they're going to grow up knowing
their uncle is never far away.
And Sara,
I want you to promise me that
you're gonna keep an eye on Linc.
As you may have notice, he has
the tendency to get in trouble.
You know we spend
so much of our lives,
not saying the things
we want to say.
The things we should say.
We speak in codes,
we send little messages.
Origami.
So now, plainly,
simply,
I want to say that
I love you both.
Very much.
And I want you to promise me,
that you're gonna tell my child,
that you're gonna tell my child
how much they're loved every day.
and remind them
how lucky they are,
to be free.
Because we are.
We're free now.
Finally.
We're free.