Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Is it good?
All right. Are you ready?
Not at all.
We talk to Graham Windsor.
He had his first chord our public
interview to give since the incident.
Good morning, Graham.
- Good morning.
Thank my story
to share with you.
It is therefore promises to be fascinating one story.
Tell me ... where did it start?
Was it on the set?
No, actually it started
in Palm Springs.
I answered today
no phone, Bernie.
You just did, Graham.
To remind you
Today I want to talk to anyone.
Not even with you.
You can not keep hiding.
The press desperate for an explanation.
Let them do.
Graham, they can make
or they can break you.
I'm already broken.
End of story.
We can work this out.
- You can do it, it's your job.
Before I pay you
outrageous amount of money.
Are you going to tell them the truth or what?
Bernie, you're a great manager.
But you're telling the media
never the truth.
Graham, I'm your manager.
And I tell you that you ...
- Bye, Bernie.
Graham !
For the third time,
this is not a nudist residence.
Before you can go anywhere
in Palm Springs.
But where do I get a service like this?
- In the sauna down the street.
Just be a good boy
and pull it to.
Everyone has' m already seen.
What does it matter?
Because I have rules.
- You know what they say about rules?
That you will be thrown out,
if you do not show up.
Jesus, rejected
by people I trust.
Why does that look familiar?
- The Martyrdom suits you not.
That might make me over
not cast for the new series.
Yeah, that's probably the reason.
Put this on.
Coffee? - Can you make in your room
with those expensive coffee.
Do I look like I know
how a machine works?
If you're not fucking was so clever ...
Then I was not in this shit.
Coffee in five minutes.
If you're dressed.
What?
I need time for myself,
I have already told you.
Stop. Stop calling me.
Really?
Well, there it was but should have thought
for you gave that interview.
No! No, we ...
We would not disclose
until the right time.
You blew it, because you love
've become on Anderson Cooper.
You know ... I'll let you know
when I come back home.
No, I thought you
though it would be gone.
Where do you think I am? We have this
two months ago reserved.
Yes ...
Talk to anybody about this, please.
Can you do that for me?
Thank you.
And call me no more
while I'm gone.
Hey! Do you know where I can check?
Thank you.
Are you Graham Windsor not?
That soap actor?
Not anymore.
Yes, I have seen on the internet ...
What did you do on the Internet?
What? You mean your sex video?
Yes, I have seen.
Course. What did you think?
I've seen better.
Wait a minute ...
I know you too.
- Yeah, right.
You're the big gay marriage activist,
Trey Reed.
That's me. "Marry her."
I've read all your statements
on Proposition 8.
And I've seen the manifestations
you have organized. Impressive.
Apparently not impressive enough
for you ...
your closet to drag you to join us.
That's not fair.
Please, say that all actors
in which the cabinet.
Too bad that video was needed you ...
seriously in the zijk turn, so you
would admit that you are one of us.
No, wait.
You do not have any official statement
made, is not it?
It's nobody's business.
You're a public figure,
it affects us all.
By the way ... I've read
about your divorce.
Your case will be yours now fixed
totally awesome.
'Gay marriage activist cheating spouse.
The divorce is deployed.
Apparently the gay community
the marriage is not so good. "
And that does not even Fox News.
There is much more to it.
You must understand that anyway?
The media distort the truth.
When you do, and not with me?
The immortal words of Dolly Parton:
"Come down from the cross,
anyone who has required pole. "
Well, a pole need
apparently your specialty.
You're in Suite No. 3.
That's it.
Are you alone?
The reservation was for a couple.
The plans have changed.
I am sorry
Should I leave the cake in the room?
I had clean forgotten.
I can 't take away ...
Forget it.
Well, it is very quiet.
There is a very quiet young man
Suite No. 4 in.
And a nice couple in No. 1.
And in No. 2?
There's ...
Super.
Hopefully his room many closets.
It is a suite, room no.
And let him alone.
It's a nice boy.
It is one of the reasons
why we have so many problems ...
to be accepted
by society.
If more actors came out of the closet ...
I know people like you would want
that all actors were gay.
You know what? They're not.
Really?
Believe it or not, but I'm two years
reporter been bought for us this hotel.
I have interviewed many actors whose
everyone assumed they were gay.
And you know what?
Maybe three of them were that maximum.
Who then?
Do not bother.
Trust me.
And those who were gay, found that they
had good reason to stay in the closet.
Financial reasons, you mean.
- You probably never do anything for money.
He's coming here for years.
I like him.
He just wants to work.
What's wrong with that?
Nothing ... I think.
Well, you think is correct.
Until now this hotel
their hideout.
Where nobody cared who they were.
They?
He and his friend. Ex-boyfriend.
Well, at this point probably
nevertheless ex-boyfriend.
Was the one who
with him was to be seen in the video?
Are you a reporter?
God, no. I hate reporters.
Except you, of course.
- I hate reporters.
So we came to Palm Springs
and we bought the hotel.
To start a new life.
We?
- My partner, Philip, and I.
And then he died and ...
I sat here all alone.
I am sorry
- That's a good thing ...
You would also be grateful
for everything you have.
How are we going to such a topic?
I asked about the sex video
the queen in the closet.
Right, right, right ...
I honestly have no idea
with whom he was on that video to be seen.
I'm not looking at anything.
Okay, I saw the pictures on the internet.
What?
If the Grahams boyfriend
those video leaked ...
the pain should not do?
Happy birthday, dammit.
Sorry about that later.
- Rightly.
I mean, thank you.
It's just ...
It's just what?
I do not understand.
I really do not understand ...
that you do not get up and say:
"This is who I am. Point on the line. '
You would not really understand.
Your whole existence revolves around being gay.
Pardon?
You work every day with gay issues.
You live firmly in the middle of West Hollywood.
Your friends are probably all gay.
In the evening, you sit in gay clubs.
You spend your holidays by
on gay cruises.
You are a professional gay.
- So what?
Somebody has to fight for our rights.
And that's your choice.
I chose to be an actor.
And the only way I work
can get by staying in the closet.
The audience does not need to know everything
about my private life.
How can you two so easily
separated from each other?
The public has a right to know.
- No.
The public has a right to know
of cases in the closet ...
politicians who vote against
laws for gay rights.
They have no right
to know who I sleep.
You would be better to understand
than anyone.
Do not you dare.
You fight for years
equal marriage rights.
What is great. Somebody has to do it.
But you pretended to be someone who
believed in the sanctuary of marriage.
If someone who is dedicated,
monogamous relationship.
You do yourself
as the ideal gay man and ...
look what's to yourself.
You appears not to be different
than all others in this country.
You're perfect for you,
while your spouse is cheating.
You shouted to the world:
"Gay people can the marriage!"
And you can not even think of yourself.
Fuck you.
Are you going to hide it.
Just pretend everything is okay.
We will all do
if everything is okay ...
Hey.
- Hey ...
Important evening?
We shall see.
Now it's my turn to say sorry.
It's not your fault,
not quite.
My ex had even phoned me earlier.
Before we ...
changed in Krystle and Alexis?
Who are they?
The youth ...
No sense of the gay culture.
I know enough about the gay culture.
Did you ever
"Whatever happend to Baby Jane?"
Yes.
This is a TV movie about a girl
that fell into a pit, right?
Never mind.
Listen, I want to make it
because I have just had such a bastard.
What did you think?
Alcohol, lots of alcohol ...
Thanks for letting me use your computer for.
I can not believe my laptop
forgot.
No problem,
just not at my watch porn.
Porn on a laptop?
Never thought of that.
I am really nailed to the cross.
The Republicans?
Of course, that was to be expected.
But a slap in the face of the
gay media, since I had not counted on.
Like what?
This gay news site says
I gave all the opposition ...
what they need to say
that the gay marriage can not handle.
That sounds familiar.
- Shut up.
The hearing of a foreign
is a ...
but to read it
as the full printed.
Stupid gay blogs.
One moment you're the hero
and following the pariah.
So is that it is.
I gave them exclusive interviews, photos,
everything.
All they needed to get people to
persuade it to accept gay marriage.
And they turn against me
at the first opportunity.
Surprised you serious?
Journalists love scandals.
And even more gay journalists.
Yeah, but you'd think
they at least make an effort ...
to the community and its leaders
to support.
So you're a leader.
Yes ... I am.
And I'm proud.
Let's drink to leaders.
At that level you're no different than me.
What do you mean?
There is a public image of you
where you need to answer.
Everyone expects that you're perfect ...
that you meet the image
that they have of you.
Yeah, but you can not meet everyone's
expectations.
Not always.
But if you do not,
they turn against you.
Yes we can ...
I've read about you, you know ...
in the press.
Really?
Yes, really.
You also get mail when you are in the closet.
And it's clear that you really believe in
to fight for our rights.
Yeah, whatever that may be worth
these days.
That's worth a lot.
And I always get angry when people in the
gay community criticize ...
because you would fight for a
in their lost cause.
Or if they say you better money can
funds for AIDS research ...
or you can fight better
against discriminatory laws ...
instead of fighting
for equality of marriage.
What are you saying?
I've never seen tricks
to the critics.
You seem totally focused
on your mission.
This is the person you should show.
But undoubtedly there are also days
you might want to scream ...
to those bastards that you
just want to attack.
Whether you feel like your fight
complete to give.
Yes, right?
Everyone has their own purpose.
And everybody thinks that its purpose is much
is more important than that of another.
But you can not say
in public.
Everyone fights for the same ...
'Pink dollar, "so ...
Yes, it's frustrating.
And now you sit still
with your own personal problems.
And I'm not asking you what happened.
That's nothing to me.
You are the only one.
And I understand how difficult it must be
every day to go out ...
and the virtue of marriage to speak,
while you have it so hard.
You have no idea.
For me it is just as.
I always have that soap opera star,
every minute as I appear in public.
I have the series representation and the joy
to be part of a super torque.
Super Couples are stupid
if you see them during the day.
I know all of this.
But that's the role I play,
in public anyway.
Home here or am I just Graham.
An insecure actor. Someone more
will then play in a soap.
Someone who always gets the notes
production that he must shine on TV.
Someone who values ??his career
and in his spare time ...
and who knows that it is important to both
to be kept separate.
Would not it be great
if you could have two roles merge?
To be yourself 24 hours at 24?
Frankly, I would not like to live.
And I'm not alone.
So-called 'normal people'
are also different in the office than at home.
So we survive.
So when people like me say ...
people like you
out of the closet should come ...
is the same as when you
against an accountant says ...
that all his customers need to know
that he loves SM ...
or that he loves knitting
or that he is an alcoholic.
Wait, you compare a gay to be
Well with an alcoholic too?
No ...
Well ... yes!
In the sense that it is something
that most see it as something private.
Something they do with anyone else
sharing, unless they want to.
People can not live
without their private lives ...
their secrets and their fantasies.
What you get to see people on the surface,
is but a fraction of who they are.
And if you find better public figure
than the private person?
Then you need more wine.
Speaking about the clash between
your public and your private life ...
I got an offer
got a job.
Really?
Yes, even for the lead.
Which?
Porn.
It's called "The Hunk & The Restless."
And who would you be?
Do you think you will get home safely?
Probably.
You're there.
Sleep well.
Thanks for the wine.
When you want ...
To rest.
I'm not here first public statement
on passing through a video on the internet.
There's just say all problems
started, remember?
Good, good, good.
And Twat?
The what?
The Twat! If they have a short statement
passing through the Internet.
I do not think that's so hot.
No matter, the youth is crazy.
If I do this, I want to do well.
That I owe my fans.
You are your fans owe nothing.
They are what you owe.
They owe you their support.
And a national tabloid?
Not big enough for a cover.
A soap-sheet?
I doubt still interested ...
the cover to devote
to an actor who was fired.
The TV company has too many
control over those magazines.
Let me just explain something to you ...
- If someone once did.
This is no ordinary
coming-out story.
You are now
continuously from the cabinet.
But not everyone is filmed while he
had sex with another man.
That makes you a villain,
a pervert, a sex addict ...
in their eyes,
not in mine, Boobula.
What should I do?
Well, I have something for you to find
in England ...
where nobody cares
with whom the actors sleep.
But no dispensation from American press,
if you wanted to mean.
There is a gay site ...
referred to one or other
trivial pop star.
And they want to do an interview,
but only if it is exclusive.
Is that our best option?
When people see you,
make them for you while you ...
you know,
anally penetrated.
Bernie, use those words
Please never more.
As you wish.
What if ...
- What if what?
What if we Parkers name drop?
Graham, think 's after what you say.
A. You come across vindictive.
B. Would you do that to him?
No, indeed not.
What then?
Bernie, how much I enjoy
of these early phones ...
You need me here just to think about.
I'll call you soon.
Hello?
You really need to stop
with me always calling.
No, I'm not with anyone else.
That was you, remember?
Listen ...
I took the blame so no
would know why we really are apart.
What do you want from me?
No ... No, no.
Talk to my lawyer.
I give up!
Good morning.
Sleep well?
Very good.
Coffee?
I'd love to.
That was the best coffee ever.
Did not you prefer decaffeinated?
Absolutely not!
Shall we 's drink?
This was definitely not your sex video.
They always say that I
such a versatile actor.
Yeah, tell that.
Would the manager heard us?
Honey, your manager
Beverly Hills has heard about us.
It is not the first time he
two men working together properly.
Yes, that's true.
Hence they condoms and lube
lay in the rooms.
That was always so nice here.
Are you serious?
Could me and my ex
busy ever heard?
If it also so toeging,
then probably.
We thought we were so careful.
We were never together
to public events.
We lived separately.
This was one of the few places
where we could be ourselves.
What happens in Palm Springs
remains in Palm Springs?
Something like that, yes.
We have seen good times.
How long have you been together?
If I may ask ...
Five years.
What happened?
Life, I guess ...
Well, that's not true.
It started when he was discharged.
By who?
- The series.
Was he in your series?
Did I not tell you?
No ...
Who was it?
Will you not tell?
Our little secret.
It was my brother.
- What?
Parker Ryland.
That's not his real name.
Graham Windsor is your real name is?
Sadly though.
I think my parents wanted
I would be beaten at school.
I can not believe ...
you had sex with the man
that your brother was playing.
My twin brother.
Pardon?
He played my identical
twin brother.
And how did that exactly work?
Well, first I played two brothers,
but that was I was sitting.
So the writers sent
one of my characters ...
to a fire in the jungle of Peru,
where he was looking for our mother and ...
the plastic surgeons did not
what he looked like, so ...
They found easily another person?
5 inches shorter and 5 years younger.
That was never really explained.
Anyway ...
he was fired, I was promoted
and a better storyline ...
and he received no other offers.
That must have been difficult.
Very difficult. Everything went wrong then
and eventually we broke up.
It is now six months ago.
Do you think he leaked the video?
Who else?
Are you sure?
What happened, happened.
Want some coffee?
I think the filters are.
Then we have to improvise.
I'm so sorry ...
I'm so sorry.
There no one answered when I knocked.
- No problem.
I brought new towels.
And you just need one.
Thank you.
Can I get you anything else?
Hey!
You seem to have everything you need.
- Can I have one?
Well, then I'll go.
Let me know
if you need anything else.
There is something ...
Learn more condoms and lubricant,
I get it. How soon?
Now.
- Of course.
And ...
Yes, there is a shop in the city
who specializes in such things.
They have everything you want.
What did you ask him now?
What we talked about earlier.
You know, do not you
we were talking about ...
I have one of these in my room.
Really?
Come on.
Not true.
- Well true.
But he is one of the largest
actors ever.
Please ... He is one of the largest
fagots ever.
Why nobody knows him?
Why do I not love him?
Because they do not want to know,
the fans anyway.
He is discreet and macho.
Well, not so macho
if you think about it.
And how do you know him?
It is an open secret in the industry.
And start the hell not
about all those secret queers.
No, you know.
Everyone knows it.
The players know it,
the producers know it ...
And the public?
Who believe everything the pr.
the TV station tells them.
I had three real engagements, invented
and made public by the TV station.
All about the image to protect.
But they want themselves
good looking actors, right?
Young, good looking actors are
for the media and for extra gay audience.
But when I fixed values
is anyone still interested.
You're not that old?
In the series are my children as old
that they themselves already have children.
I'm forty and I have three grandchildren
in the series.
Well, I did anyway.
No chance that your job is still
back?
No.
Why did not you process
filed against them?
Moral clause.
They did not fire me
because I'm gay.
They fired you
for the sake of sex video.
What actually everyone
can happen ...
gay or straight, male or female ...
They have in fact already someone else
for my role.
That was quick.
They use someone else temporarily
for a few days ...
and they leave a big name show up
of a series that last year stopped.
The irony is that with many more men
West Hollywood then I slept.
That did not sound quite right.
It sounded very good.
Good morning.
What are you doing?
Put that thing away.
What? The camera of this thing?
The camera, asshole.
If you mean a direction would indicate
I'll be right.
Good morning, fans.
This is Ryland and Graham Parker
Windsor of your favorite TV series.
Hold on.
Say 'hi' to your fans, Graham.
There's not really a tape in, huh?
Do you really want to do?
Who is to know?
Erase it again afterwards?
After we have seen it a few times.
You like that?
You know I like it.
Shut up and fuck me.
You refused your partner in the video
to be identified.
Indeed.
Why?
What do you care?
Well ...
- Exactly what I thought.
I ask you, not what you have in your bedroom
performs or with whom you do it.
Why should I answer questions
about my private life?
Because you're famous.
Here I best to just touch.
On a bathrobe two sizes
too big for you?
Indeed, one size ...
fits like a rod on a pig.
Too many jokes, too little time.
I meant this.
- This did not only owe me.
Alex has made the coffee
and bought sandwiches.
I poured the juice.
Not.
This ...
Outdoor seating breakfast.
I know. It seems that the second
season of "Dallas".
Tells you nothing?
No.
How old are you again?
Old enough to know that I am home
outside wants to eat, as here.
Have you any patio or garden
to your home in L.A.?
No, it's an apartment.
In West Hollywood?
Guilty ...
- I knew it.
Hey, I need to be where the action is.
You live firmly in the Hollywood Hills.
Well, what?
- Typical actors.
All your money on big houses
and fast cars.
Most of my money I
actually to expensive takeaway ...
I eat for my huge TV,
while I'm looking to DVDs.
How many gay movies you have in your collection?
Not much.
- Of course.
People like you are too afraid to gay movies
in their rack already.
Someone had better at thinking you ...
"Oh, a gay '.
I 'Brokeback Mountain'.
Honey, please!
My grandmother 'Brokeback Mountain'.
Have you gay magazines
lie on your side table?
Typically, but not really surprising.
Apparently nobody reads it
gay publications.
Most go bankrupt
together with the gay bookstores.
Many gay men have gone bankrupt.
We are sorry. I remember that I secretly gay
bookstores went, when I was young.
Before I became a professional actor.
I leafed through the magazines like
to about famous gay people to read.
When there were not so many.
And now they read about you.
Oh, God ...
I'm working on an article about why
gay publications fail.
Really? Where do you publish?
Funny.
Do you want to hear my theory or not?
- Yeah, you know.
It's not the economy
and certainly not to a lack of stories.
I believe the gay media
die ...
because they have turned their backs
to the community.
Previously they published
real gay stories.
Profiles of gay artists, actors, musicians,
writers, leader figures, whatever.
And when they realized
that they had sold more advertising ...
if they are on the cover straight up.
A straight ally
with the community.
And then came the divas.
The divas?
Yeah, who would want to read about
an emerging gay singer ...
if you can read a profile of ...
Madonna and Vanessa Williams?
I think Vanessa Williams super.
Yes, all of us.
But that's not the point.
The point is that ...
when the national gay publications
stopped really gay men to profile ...
they will no longer were
a weekday tabloid ...
same content offered as others.
Besides the pictures of handsome models
in their underwear.
Yes, indeed ...
Here, we are of course.
But the worst is that we accept,
and we love it.
We beg to report
Kylie's last tour ...
rather more reviews on
latest book by Christopher Rise. Yet?
It is no wonder that all our gay
bookshops go.
You give Kylie Minogue is to blame for
that gay bookstores closing?
No, no.
Well ... yes, in a sense.
Look, if our own media stores
really gay books would promote ...
and gay movies and gay musicians ...
then people would buy their work.
Everyone supports his own people.
Except us.
What do you think they will write about me?
Either you are a pathetic
not dare to come out of the closet ...
either a bad role model
because you had unprotected sex.
We had long been a solid relationship.
They do not care.
They saw you fucking without condom ...
so you're a villain.
I do not have to apologize because I have sex
had with my friend. - I know, I know ...
But you have a third option.
You become a 'professional gay'.
What? Unfair outed
by homophobic press.
You serves as the Grand Marshal
and Pride Parade over the country.
You come up against the double standard
in the industry.
For example, if I know
filmmaker had been ...
then gave one to which sex video.
- Right.
And you act in a reality TV show ...
You have someone write your memoirs.
And you're doing local theater productions ...
of 'Bent'.
Seriously? Are my options?
I set the rules do not.
You're not Chad Allen.
Jesus, thank you.
You're much sexier.
That's better.
Do you know the rules or of bowls?
Are we playing?
Play your not happy with big balls?
And ...
I am now playing or what?
Yes, you won.
Hello ...
Sorry to disturb you.
I'm going out to dinner tonight.
In an Italian around the corner.
You guys might want
to go?
Thanks, Alex, but ...
I do not think it is smart for us to
together to be seen in public.
I was just thinking the same thing.
Who would you see here now?
You'd be surprised.
Well then ...
Maybe Trey cooks it for you,
if you ask him politely.
Would you like to cook for me?
I can do that.
You follows no soaps on TV?
Not really.
Only when I hear that there are gay
story lines in it.
So not really often.
Why do you ask?
I just had to think of someone ...
Your ex?
No. A friend ...
A mentor, actually.
He died last year.
Sorry.
He was 92 years old.
It did not really unexpected.
He was one of the original
actors of the series.
He was there from the very beginning.
That is ...
That is very long.
Almost sixty years.
Why did you think of him?
When he died,
the station was worried ...
that his death would be announced
by his partner since 55 years.
Then he came just out of the closet.
Seriously? Did you?
Course. Everyone knew it.
Another open secret
of our industry.
But the fans did not know.
He was one of the patriarchs of the series,
had romances with the great ladies ...
fought against business rivals.
He was a sounding board for the children
of his character ...
and his grandchildren and great-grandchildren.
Not long after I
the series started ...
he invited me to his home
out on a dinner.
Frankly, I was terrified.
Why?
Because he was a legend.
And I had almost not
worked with him.
I felt honored
he invited me.
And what happened?
I came to him,
alone, nervous ...
He welcomed me and introduced me
his partner, Donald.
"No questions, no hesitations,
this is my partner, Donald. '
So he was open to people
with whom he worked.
You wonder why there are not more
actors coming out.
And I asked him the same question
when I got to know him better.
Someone of that age would never
come out of the closet when he was young.
Yet?
No, and that's a part of it.
But for him it was more than that.
How?
We talked a few years ago,
when I thought about it from the closet.
Really?
Did you think about getting out of the closet?
Everyone talked of course out of my head.
And, well ... here we are.
And what advice did the man
you given?
"I'm perfectly happy with my life,
as it is, "he told me.
He loved being so long
same character to play.
He loved to be recognized
by his fans as he came out.
But who knew only the character,
not him.
And that was enough for him?
He said: "I am almost 60 years
as an actor at work.
I am incredibly well paid
for what I do.
And I have all the time to spend
with the love of my life ...
and with my family in the series.
I could not have asked for more. "
That has always stayed with me.
Well ...
He seems like a happy man.
That was he.
Maybe it nobody ever knew
who he was until he was dead.
Would you like to live ...
if that whole video thing
had not happened?
I do not know. These are different times.
Lifetime employment security
is something of the past.
As well as privacy.
How's that guy that you're out?
Usually harmless.
You're a natural.
One of the two must have money.
Or a giant penis.
- Or both.
So why are you after me ...
Funny how you rarely see gay people
dating outside their own world.
Says the man who datete
with his own fictional twin brother.
I mean it.
Bears bears, teenagers with teenagers,
elderly elderly.
And then you see such torque.
How did your ex look like?
What I thought he wore fixed
the same clothes.
He saved his money.
What are you saying?
Nothing, it's just an observation.
They look happy.
Yes.
That should be fun.
Do you mind if I get my emails still at nakijk?
- No, go ahead.
Thank you.
A folder named 'Parker' ...
Do you have pictures of your ex on your laptop?
Well ...
It's okay.
It is difficult for someone to let go.
Right.
Can I see what he looks like?
- No, do not.
What is this video?
Wait, this is your sex video.
Is that your ex?
I can explain.
- You can see him in the video.
This is Parker Ryland
and Graham Windsor ...
of your favorite TV series.
You can see him.
This is not the video on the internet.
Which was updated. This is the entire recording.
If Parker had let him drain, why
you have the entire film than on your computer?
Was it you?
I can explain.
- Really?
Can you explain why you own
sex video leaked on the internet?
There is ... it's complicated.
Probably.
It was a PR stunt.
What?
I wanted out of the series of steps,
but they would not let me go.
And I wanted to come out,
but that was not my manager.
I wanted people knew who I was.
I can not believe you're saying this.
- Do you know how hard it is ...
in order to find other roles
if you sit in a soap?
And people need you so than
seriously? Really?
I wanted to be noticed.
I have been working for twenty years as an actor ...
and who really knew me
until last month?
And I thought, since gay actors
currently so in vogue ...
Did you know the following
Neil Patrick Harris to be?
I see myself more
as John Borrowman type.
Why did not you just out of the closet?
You said it yourself! Also in soaps one begins
gay actors to adopt.
I was afraid they would let me stay
and my character gay would make.
That would ruin everything I past
twenty years before that series did.
Eventually they will forget the video
and only me ...
an openly gay actor as good
a heterosexual can play as another.
Do not fool yourself.
They call you a fagot
once you turn your back.
Yes? Maybe they do.
But finally I will speak the truth and
my public and private life to flow together.
Since we're talking about?
Why grind your Parker
not with you out of the closet?
Because he did not want to, okay?
Why we broke up.
Because I wanted out of the closet
and he did not.
All the more reason for him outing ...
I could not do it.
I love him.
I will always love him,
but that is past.
It is not the same as what we have.
- Do not pretend you care about me.
You've been lying to me
since the moment we met.
And you're not?
What I thought
Judge me for what I did.
I deserve it.
But if you're ready to give me your truth
to tell, I will waiting for you.
He's right.
About what?
About telling the truth.
You have no idea
what's going on.
I know he cares about you.
That everyone sees.
And you apparently to him, otherwise
you were long gone after that fight.
Walk fuck.
No, thanks, man.
Do not be.
Do you see? So you can not be angry,
if you still can laugh.
Why would I take advice from you?
Because I'm gay and I
and wen there Just to.
You got me here, no time
noticed, huh?
Course.
You're in ...
this.
Almost, it's that one.
I am literally 'The boy next door'.
Sorry, I had the ...
quite busy?
Yes, I have several times heard.
Since your first hug ...
you only focus
for that man in suite # 2.
Furthermore, have I not
so many times, I'm usually within.
And now you tell me your story
of your lost love ...
and that despite everything still in love
believes. Blah, blah, blah ...
That I could, but let's
in essence, okay?
'Ricky's life, episode 101.
I'm Rick way.
I'm Trey.
"Trey, Celebrity 'will tell you.
Do you see? It is al
My life in a nutshell:
I grew up in Kansas ...
I moved to Los Angeles on my 18th,
have far too much partying ...
and I was far too busy
with my appearance.
Now you hear me say
I'm pretty good look.
Sorry, you look pretty good.
- I know, right?
Well, I am now thirty years ...
I've never had a serious relationship ...
and I have skin cancer.
I am sorry
- That's okay.
Of course it is not in order,
but everyone says it's okay.
So remember, use your sunscreen.
It'll be okay, but ...
if not ...
Otherwise I would do anything
so someone would give me enough ...
to come after me to tell me the truth
to tell you about something that hurts me.
It is not so easy.
No, indeed. It is easy
to say 'I love you'.
It is difficult to say
"I messed up, I've hurt you. '
"But, damn,
I still love you. '
That they had a pillow
embroidery or so.
You're right, that they had to do.
Well, I gotta go.
Tonight my dinner with Andre.
Great movie.
What movie? I'm just eating
with my friend Andre.
He gave me before the best drug.
The good old days ...
Remember: if you do something
to tell you, do it ...
before it is too late.
An atoning sacrifice.
I'm busy.
What?
I'm working on a statement to the press,
if you would like to know.
My big outing.
Good for you.
I mean it. I'm happy
you that step.
'Coming out' ...
I sound like a southerner.
This is a role that I give you
ever want to see play.
Can I come in?
I want to tell you the truth
about my divorce.
I've read them all
on the Internet.
You should know that you do not
must believe what you read.
Have you not deceived him?
It's more complicated than that.
You see, we were not really married.
I mean, are legal and all, but ...
not like you're a real marriage represents.
I do not understand.
It was just a marriage.
A marriage?
What does that mean?
I fought so many years
for the right to marry.
And when we got just that opportunity,
for Proposition 8 was through ...
I found that I had to marry
to prove myself.
This is unbelievable.
How could it happen ...
as the main protagonist of the case
stood on the side?
All others hurried to
San Francisco to get married there ...
even though they knew that it probably
not legally would remain valid.
I really believe in marriage.
Really.
And I believe ...
that the gay community
it better than anyone.
The problem is ...
my husband that believeth.
Go on.
I wonder what else is coming.
He has fallen in love with someone ...
and he wants to be with him.
I suppose not blame him.
We had no such relationship.
We were just roommates
with additional benefits.
Financial and legal,
not sexual.
Why does he apparent than
no longer?
That boy that he is in love,
lives in Toronto.
He wants to move there
and married.
Start a new life.
I can not stop him.
I do not want.
Why write them all
you're the one who has gone weird?
Graham.
I owe him so much.
I put him in this shit
concerned.
I could not let him blame
by the press.
If I get the criticism over me,
then he gets no criticism.
I know it's a stupid plan.
But I thought that the best
solution.
You know, for the matter ...
You talk about the case as if it is real,
if it were a person.
The case would have gone,
whether you're married or not.
I thought I could make the difference.
But all you've done,
the whole thing is ridiculous.
Those of us
who really like to get married ...
and yes, I would love to get married ever ...
we turn to the deeds
of people like you.
What do you mean?
- That we always heterosexual couples accuse ...
she married for the wrong reasons.
Whether they were drunk in Las Vegas,
or accidentally pregnant geraakten ...
But you ...
What? Say it.
You married for the attention of the press?
Do not be a hypocrite.
That's exactly what you did,
by that video of your release.
That's not the same.
People look at me with
same standard as you.
I'm an actor, dammit!
Everything we do revolves around publicity.
Even this?
No. Absolutely not.
It is different.
There are people who really look up to you.
You make a difference in the world.
How can marry for publicity
good or noble?
That's not, okay?
I know now.
And now I have the effects of wear.
I've lost everything, Graham.
I lost my 'technically seen'
husband, who is also my best friend.
I lost the respect of my colleagues.
And now you.
Allows for you than from
you've lost me?
Come on, you know that well enough.
I do not know much more.
Just go.
What's wrong?
- Nothing.
That's my 'public face'
Graham where it always has.
You ask what's wrong and I
answer automatically with 'nothing' ...
as you know well enough
that there is something wrong.
You should always keep your self confident face
up, huh?
You do not have to do
you do not want.
Not to me.
I know I have a few more days
had reserved ...
but I have to leave early.
Is that okay?
Of course that's fine.
But you get no money back,
if you wanted to ask.
Since I do not care.
Where do you do it?
Never mind.
You care for him.
That is clear.
- Not for him.
Please, most gay men have
the maturity of teenage girls.
And that is exactly
how he behaves.
He'll come around.
I think not.
If we're 'normal' people were ...
then we could perhaps solve this.
So since you're a bit famous
in a certain part of society ...
the rules of love
not for you?
I will take the almighty Debbie Allen
quote:
"You had big dreams ...
and now you will learn eventually
that famous little cost. '
Debbie who?
Let me not start ...
But that's not the point.
Why is that?
You've worked hard to stand
where you stand today.
You have worked hard for our
community and for our rights.
And that is something that nobody
of you may decrease.
But ...
- There's always a but ...
Papa Do not interrupt
if he 's word is ...
But if you are familiar,
people will judge you.
Right or wrong, they will have a higher level
of responsibility you expect.
That's not fair.
Do you think America is built
on honesty?
Do you think the people around honesty
give? No.
Finally give the people
but for one thing:
Sex.
Truth.
That.
Be honest with yourself.
Be honest with the media
and the public.
But especially ...
Be honest with Graham.
Tell him what you feel for him.
And if he says no?
Send him here
and I lay it all out.
I fucked up.
What did you say?
I fucked up and I've hurt you,
but, damn it, I still love you.
It is an old saying that I've somewhere
've seen standing on a pole.
What was that last one?
I might be in love with you.
Good to know.
We are clearly not perfect.
- That is clear.
And unfortunately, we must consider
how our relationship ... - Our relationship?
will affect our careers
and how the media will jump on it.
You're in the middle of a divorce.
And you stand for something bigger,
be yourself.
Where is it us?
Where would you like?
We will always have Palm Springs.
We can also have West Hollywood.
Perhaps, once ...
But not now.
I am leaving tomorrow.
So do I.
I see you before I leave?
I would like it.
Hey, it's me.
Do not hang up.
I call not to argue.
You stay in our house
as long as you deem necessary.
And I want you absolutely have to see
before you move to Toronto.
You know ...
You were my best friend since ...
longer than I can remember.
And I will not lose,
but so forget what I said earlier.
I blame you not know what you've done.
Yes, yes ... Anderson Cooper
is to puke.
No, no, that's okay.
It's okay.
I do not really care anymore
what the press says about me.
I know the truth.
Yes ...
You too.
Bernie? I'm sorry to call so late,
but it is important.
I want you to make a statement tomorrow
for the press.
I want you to say that I am proud to
an openly gay, ...
and an openly gay actor.
And I apologize opposite
my fans because I was not honest with them was.
No. No apologies for the video.
It was wrong for him to bring.
But I pay every day of my life
for in one way or another.
I tell you the details when I see you.
I do not do interviews with the media.
We post it on my website
and that's it.
No exclusive interviews,
not begging for a front page story.
Now I'm done with it.
I hope I am ready.
We see you again?
Count on that.
Are you going to leave?
- Yeah, I gotta get back to my old business.
So do I.
I'm waiting for you in the car.
Despite what happened between you ...
I hope you 'll also come back.
Absolutely.
Properly. You like something easier to
in the pool than he.
And I know we are not alone
which make use of the pool ...
our naked.
Maybe I will change that rule.
Do that.
Best of luck.
Thank you.
I'm gonna need it.
This was it so?
You know it is not currently well
for us to be seen together.
Familiar faces.
Always worried about how something happens.
Perception is everything.
Love is everything.
Maybe I'm not ready.
Not yet.
When you're ready, you know
where you can reach me.
Well then ...
Will I see you again?
I'll see you at.
You know that saying that what happens
Palm Springs in Palm Springs continues ...
Yes ...
- To hell with it.
I do not care what other
and thinks that you should not do.
You're right.
I'm always right.
What did you have in mind?
Going back to L.A.
eating in a restaurant,
maybe a movie ...
Too old?
Not for me.
Step over but.
And my car?
I came back riding
with a big romantic gesture ...
and you're worried about your car?
Do you have room for here?
Throw it in the trunk.
Happy.
And my luggage?
Smarty.
And if there's a photographer on hold
and the pictures on the internet move?
Nothing would make me happier.
And how did it go with
Graham Windsor and Trey Reed?
How we went?
Coffee?
Coffee sounds good.
We're going to drink coffee.
Lots and lots of coffee.
And then what?
And then?
What happens next ...
that is not your business.
Translator?
Checking and editing: Goffini
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org