(One day in April)
Good to see you all.
Nice.
The fifth anniversary special was a success.
It was perfect with Seung Ri, TVXQ,
and Daniel Henney.
- Some people are curious. - About what?
About our days.
They're curious about our days.
So was I.
I've actually checked it on social media.
- He posts a lot. - Me?
- Yes. - What about you?
Probably because you're a waiting actor,
you post so many pictures of you waiting.
- You post everything you do. - Really?
(Various pictures of him while he waits)
Other people here saw you went to see flowers.
He did?
With Choong Jae.
Right. I saw it.
Kian84 rarely posts anything.
He uploads a post every 3 to 4 months.
I don't want to look like an attention seeker.
That's absurd.
Why are you not on social media?
I quit at some point.
- It just doesn't make sense. - I mean...
Kian84 worries about looking like an attention seeker,
but Hyun Moo is the original attention seeker.
- It's what I'm known for. - Yes.
If you were a king, he'd be...
- the king of attention-seeking. - The king of attention-seeking.
He'd be the king of attention-seeking.
- The king of attention-seeking. - The king of attention-seeking.
Well said.
That's right.
- Why are you not on social media? - He's busy dating.
- Well... - That's my guess too.
Do you have a secret account together?
No.
- A couple's account. - Attention-Seeker and Dhalsim.
I'm 42. How can you think we'd have a secret account?
You've been trying everything young people do.
You celebrated your 100th day.
- Their 22nd day too. - Exactly.
You asked us for a dollar and seven cents.
Why didn't you give us any money that day?
I didn't have seven cents.
(I Live Alone)
(A perfect day for sports)
(We haven't seen Hye Jin's apartment in a while.)
It's been a while.
(It's not even 7am.)
(Hye Jin is preparing food.)
(Cramped)
(What's happening today?)
My agency has a sports day for models today.
- I've prepared lunchboxes. - What?
(Surprised)
44 models are participating...
- as far as I know. - That's a lot.
- It is. - Also,
there will be other staff members too.
So I was going to make 60 to 70 portions.
- 60 to 70 portions? - That's impossible.
- That's just impossible. - Na Rae.
Not even a professional cook could pull it off.
It's just too much.
- You'd hurt your back. - Yes.
(Frustrated)
What should I do? I don't have a rice paddle.
(She uses a kitchen tool instead.)
You don't have a rice paddle?
I found out after 10 years.
You don't make rice at home?
- She doesn't eat a lot of rice. - I don't use a rice paddle.
Then what do you use?
- A spoon. - I use a spoon too.
- Me too. - It's because she eats little.
(Surprised)
I've never made this much rice in my life.
I already made a full batch the night before.
(She has to prepare a lot of food.)
As much as possible.
I need a lot.
I'm starting a new batch.
I have only one rice cooker.
Dhalsim is surprisingly sweet.
She's preparing lunchboxes for everyone.
I need to add water.
Oh, my.
Use a bowl or something.
How much water do I need?
Making rice is so difficult.
(When she baked last time,)
(she used measuring cups.)
(But it didn't help.)
That's too much water.
- The rice will be sticky. - It's flooding.
How do you know that?
I can tell. The water should go just up here.
(It's obviously too much water.)
(Instead of moving on,)
(she turns back.)
The rice hasn't been soaked, so...
It's not been soaked.
- So I... - Are you making soup?
- I'm making rice balls. - Then you need even less water.
The rice...
would soak up the seasoning and become even stickier.
Seasoned salt.
Gosh, salt.
Sesame oil.
You put so much of both salt and oil.
Rice balls need a lot of oil.
The rice was sticking together and wouldn't blend with the seasoning.
So I had to keep massaging them.
It looks more like a rice cake.
It became a rice cake.
The rice was too sticky in the first place.
That's right.
And then you kept massaging it.
- That's why. - It became a rice cake.
It's rice cakes, not rice balls.
(Rice cake)
(The rice is ready.)
How big should they be?
Would this be big enough?
What's that?
- They won't be able to finish them. - Look at that.
It's a field ration.
It's what Hyun Moo ate as a kid while fleeing from the war.
- Carrying a bundle. - Carrying a bundle.
My mom used to make them for me.
They're models.
Each of these would have 400kcal.
(She's making calorie bombs.)
I got the idea...
from Na Rae's Summer School.
- But the size looks so different. - You think so?
(Na Rae's Summer School)
(Na Rae prepared rice balls.)
Roll it.
They'd have to quit modeling after eating those.
They'd make them fat.
That's so much rice.
They're going to play games using those.
They're going to throw them.
That's what it is.
Now I understand.
- Hey. - It's a ball that tastes good.
Roll it.
Ta-da.
It looks okay. One is done.
(A rice ball is done.)
- She's doing a good job. - Right?
She is, but...
it should be completely covered.
(It's too little mayonnaise.)
I feel too guilty.
Adding mayonnaise and ketchup...
makes me feel guilty.
- I feel too bad. - But...
You're already using too much rice.
- It's too much. - Dhalsim usually tries to...
eat less salt and everything,
but why does she drink so much?
- Exactly. - It's because she eats little.
- She drinks so much. - Alcohol is not seasoned.
She wouldn't drink if alcohol was salty.
What kind of logic is that?
She only cares about her total calories intake.
I'm exhausted.
Let me see.
(Pressing)
Who is it?
It's a rice cooker.
Rice cooker!
Who is it?
- A rice cooker is here. - Rice cooker.
- A rice cooker is here. - Are you Mathilda?
Oh, it's Hyun Yi.
(Korea's top model)
(Hye Jin's good friend)
(Top model Lee Hyun Yi)
This is my first time here.
- So? - I wanted to bring something.
What did you bring?
I brought a pointy plant that resembles you.
How dare she!
Daniel had that plant at home.
Did you memorize everything about his house?
- I keep watching that episode. - Where did he have it?
He had a big one in his garden.
We thought it was an aloe vera plant.
Oh, that agave plant?
- Yes. - The big one.
- I should put it here. - Yes. It's the perfect size...
- for your bedroom. - I see.
Thank you.
Your place looks like a couple's apartment.
All it needs is a man.
- I have one. - Exactly.
(Oh, my.)
"I have a man."
Hyun Moo looks restless.
Is he hiding in the smaller room?
(Joking)
I was hiding in the other room like this.
(Covering his mouth)
(Funny)
Look. This is one batch.
The rice looks too sticky.
It wasn't at first. It looked okay,
but as I massaged it with the seasoning,
it became stickier and stickier.
- You did what? - I seasoned it.
- Oh, I see. - She doesn't hear well.
- Oh, you seasoned it. - She's like us.
Do we need more rice?
- We need one more batch. - One more?
That's why I asked you to bring your rice cooker.
Try half a ball and see how it tastes.
Okay. It looks tasty.
- Try half a ball. - You put some stuff inside?
I asked Seol Mi for the recipe.
It looks tasty.
(Enjoying)
Are you sure you like it?
(Are you sure you like it?)
It's sticky.
- Hey. - The rice...
sticks to my teeth.
Is it supposed to be a rice cake?
- I mean... - It gets between my teeth.
(The rice gets between her teeth.)
What?
She can't speak because of the food between her teeth.
Why don't we...
call the gimbap place across the street?
Gosh, I don't know what to do.
It's cool now.
- Oh, my. - That looks so sticky.
- Is that a rice cake? - What should you do?
It's turning into a rice cake.
Should we make rice cake soup?
(Dumbfounded)
I'll do it right this time.
Gosh.
(She pours rice into the bowl.)
(Spilling)
Oh, my.
Dhalsim.
But it all went into the bowl.
What should I do?
Let me make the rice.
- No. - You should make pancakes.
No.
- You're a pancake expert. - What should I do?
Hyun Yi has a child. She must be a good cook.
- She looks experienced. - She's very skillful.
She's drying the rice.
Eat just half.
You'll have to eat all of them later.
Tuna and mayonnaise rice balls taste okay, right?
I think we should put more mayonnaise.
No. I feel too guilty.
- What are you doing? - Tuna and mayonnaise rice balls...
are about the taste of mayonnaise.
What are you doing?
I'm eating mayonnaise.
Did you see her add all that mayonnaise?
A friend of mine carries mayonnaise around...
- in her clutch. - She does?
- Yes, she dips everything in it. - That's what Hyun Yi does.
Look.
Are you out of your mind?
This is it.
(She shudders.)
She said that's it.
Tuna and mayonnaise rice balls have to be moist.
Do you know how much mayonnaise is needed to make it moist?
I mix mayonnaise into my rice.
- Why do you do that? - Because it's delicious.
She eats a lot, but doesn't get fat.
(This is good.)
She doesn't get fat, but I do if I eat like that.
If you're friends with someone like that,
you're the only one gaining weight.
- That's right. - You're right.
Do Yeon eats way more than I do, but doesn't gain weight.
She's very thin.
(I think it needs a bit more mayonnaise.)
- Also. - Yes?
I thought about it...
- You need at least that much. - Hey.
She must be scared of you.
We won't eat too much.
It'll taste good this way.
Do you know how many calories mayonnaise has?
We're going to exercise.
- We'll jump around. - You must be out of your mind.
It'll taste good this way.
It looks delicious.
- I don't believe it. - That's right.
That's how you make it.
- That's how you should make it. - That's right.
It's tuna and mayonnaise rice balls.
(There is a difference in their tastes.)
Look.
(Watch how I do this.)
Wrap it tight.
She seems to be doing all the work.
- She's good. - It's pretty, isn't it?
- She's good. - This is how you make it.
I would've had a hard time if it weren't for Hyun Yi.
She's a good cook.
I thought about it...
and I won't tell everyone...
I made this with you.
- You won't tell them? - No.
- Why not? - If I do,
they'll be forced to eat it even if they don't want to.
You know that, right?
You do know.
Are you still here?
I'm here to stay.
- Will you say you bought it? - Everyone will be asking...
- each other to eat it. - No.
They'll be telling each other to hurry up and finish it.
"Hurry up and eat it. Hurry up and swallow."
"Hurry up and eat it."
"She's looking at us. Hurry up and eat it."
Hey.
(When did I do that?)
That must've happened often.
(You seem to have a lot of fun together.)
(They start picking up speed in making the rice balls.)
We should've counted them as we made it.
Oh, no.
This is bad.
It's okay.
I think we should start making the jeon.
(They leave the rice balls piled up on the counter.)
I'll start makingn the jeon.
The whole house will smell of it when we make it.
(She takes the air purifier to the kitchen.)
Okay.
I couldn't open the windows...
because of the fine dust, but we had to cook.
Cooking creates a lot of smoke...
- at home. - You're right.
I always turn this on before cooking.
You can stack more on top.
(Hye Jin prepares the ingredients for kimchi jeon.)
(She starts with chopping kimchi.)
What are you making?
- Rice balls and kimchi jeon. - Just two of them?
You'll learn my true value now.
You'll be surprised...
and call me the master of kimchi jeon.
- You're the jeon master. - That's right.
- Jeon master. - We saw at Na Rae's grandmother's.
- She's really good. - Yes, she is.
(The jeon looks delicious.)
She's really good at making jeon.
That looks delicious.
(She starts cooking the jeon.)
(Carefully)
(She is more careful than ever.)
(She makes jeon to recover her image.)
(She makes them into sizes that are easy to eat.)
Shouldn't kimchi jeon have large pieces of kimchi in it?
You're right.
- Is that kimchi jeon? - Isn't it?
Isn't that kimchi water jeon?
Kimchi-scented jeon.
Kimchi jeon is different from other types of jeon.
I used too little kimchi.
It's different from the jeon we have at holidays.
You have so many excuses.
(The comment burns.)
Are these too thick?
That's not the problem.
It doesn't have the ingredients it should.
- You have to look closely. - It's called kimchi jeon.
Oh, you're making kimchi-flavored jeon.
Hey.
- Like fake crab sticks? - That's right.
(It doesn't seem like she'll be recovering her image.)
- It's kimchi-flavored jeon. - No, it isn't.
I'll make a random rice ball.
(She makes a random rice ball.)
- What is she doing? Hyun Yi. - Yes?
What are you doing?
This won't be very spicy.
You need to add at least this much to call it the unlucky rice ball.
I don't believe it.
(Who will get the random ball?)
Are there any sports you're good at?
My nickname used to be Carl Lewis.
(Carl Lewis won the gold medal in the 1984 and 1988 Olympics.)
Really?
That proves how old you are.
- There's another track athlete. - Ben Johnson?
Not him.
(Ben Johnson, Age 58, A friend of Carl Lewis)
Ben Johnson?
- She's talking about Usain Bolt. - Yes, Usain Bolt.
Ben Johnson was caught for doping.
Do you know we have good runners at our agency?
That's just because they're tall.
Everyone is tall.
I almost became a basketball player.
- Is that true? - Yes, when I was in middle school.
(She dreamt of playing...)
(at a basketball court.)
(Do you know who that is?)
That body doesn't suit you.
(Hye Jin stretches her legs.)
I'm making you work too much.
- Didn't I make a lot? - You really did.
Everyone will get at least one.
How many did you make?
I think we made at least 80.
We have to clean up and leave.
You cooked rice the day before.
It took us three hours to make that.
We started at 7 am.
That must have been tiring.
Right? I woke up at five,
actually 4:30 am.
- Thankfully, the weather was nice. - It's such a relief.
The weather is so nice.
It's the best weather we've had recently.
You're right. How did they decide on the perfect date?
I don't know.
Look at the weather.
- The weather is nice. - It's really nice.
- Where is this? - Han River.
Isn't it such a relief?
Yes, it is.
- The weather is amazing. - Yes.
- It was the perfect date. - It's unbelievable.
We should have a sports day too. It sounds fun.
That would be fun.
- Let's not play basketball. - No, we shouldn't.
- Let's leave basketball out. - Okay.
(During their game with Daniel)
(The ball goes over the hoop.)
(They lose without being able to score a single point.)
- What is your strongest sport? - What would you like to play?
- Aren't you good at ssireum? - I'm good.
- You're good, right? - Yes, I am.
- I'm good at dodgeball. - Dodgeball?
- It'd be hard to hit you. - You can't.
How will you hit me?
No one can hit me.
I just walk around during the game.
- That sounds like fun. - I've never run around.
I walk around during the entire game.
- You walk back and forth? - Yes.
I always participated in the relay race.
You said you're good at basketball.
Our opponents were too good.
You were too bad at it.
What?
Are you the last runner of the relay race?
Yes, I'm that good.
- I'm a good runner too. - What?
- I'm good too. - What are you talking about?
You can't be as good as I am.
Let's find out who is better.
Yes, let's have a sports day.
- Okay, when the weather is nice. - Let's bring a friend each.
- Just one friend each. - Who are you going to bring?
I'll bring anyone I can.
Why don't you bring "It's Rain"?
- That sounds good. - It's Rain.
He's good at all sports.
He is?
We can't compete against him.
- Hye Jin. - Don't bring Kim Dong Hyun.
- That's right. - Why not?
- You can't bring an athlete. - Of course.
You can't bring an athlete.
He can be the judge.
He's a martial artist.
- Come on. - Still.
- Who should I bring? - Okay.
- I think it would be fun. - Yes.
- Look at the weather. - The sun is blinding.
This is unbelievable.
You're so tall.
It's just the two of you, but I can tell you're tall.
Hi.
It's Jang Yoon Ju.
- Hi. - She's much older than everyone.
- It's someone we know. - She's like an archaeopteryx.
You did a great job.
Yes, I did.
She's so tall.
Yoon Ju, you're on Team White.
I'm on Team White as well.
- We're on the same team. - You're on a different team.
Yes, but Hyun Yi was on Team White.
(The teams were divided into black and white.)
- I'll think of myself as a new... - Why would you?
You've been a model for 22 years and suddenly you're a new model?
I was talking about my attitude.
You always come last.
I'll have a different attitude today.
Go and sit in the shade.
Your face might get too much sun.
My daughter's name is Lisa.
I was born again with her.
It's been less than a year since I made a comeback.
I'll do my best.
I'm back with the attitude of a new model.
Let's make a palanquin for her.
Get on, Yoon Ju.
Come here.
She's practically an empress.
Let's go now.
Here comes the empress.
I'm not my old self.
I was born again with Lisa.
(I'm Lisa's mom and a new model.)
You can go over there and take a nap.
- See you later. - Good luck.
(The models' sports day is finally revealed.)
There's a field.
Look at everything they prepared.
It's Team Han and Team Yi.
It must be Hye Jin's team and Hyun Yi's team.
- Are you the team captain? - Yes.
We're on different teams.
(The model agency has everything set up perfectly.)
That's impressive.
They have so much prepared.
- Look at that. - It's a bubble suit.
What are those cameras?
- They're broadcasting it. - I don't believe it.
- Oh, my. - They're so tall.
Look.
- I'll have to stay away. - They're so tall.
You can't tell we're tall...
because everyone is tall, can you?
- Everyone is the same height. - You're right.
You're like a different tribe in "Lord of the Rings".
Cho Min Ho.
Hi, Hye Jin.
Stop it.
Don't do that.
Let's go.
Come over here.
Let's eat.
(Everyone claps.)
Don't clap.
I didn't make it.
Don't get it wrong.
- Kimchi jeon. - I didn't make it.
Try some.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
The sizes are all different.
- Pyeon Hee. - They're different.
That's Jin Jung Sun.
Who?
She's a famous model.
- It's Hae Na. - Yes.
Is that man a soldier?
Is he on leave?
It's Jung Hyuk. I know all the models.
How do you know so many?
- How do you know so many? - I like them.
They have something I don't.
Do they like it?
- How's it? - It's good.
How is that possible?
Come over here.
It's good, isn't it?
Yoon Ju is enjoying hers.
Take your name tags.
Wear your name tags.
- It's wasabi. - Wasabi?
(He got the wasabi rice ball.)
I should make a random rice ball.
You need to add this much for the person to realize he got unlucky.
It was a random rice ball.
It's in a few.
- It has too much wasabi. - Hyun Yi did it.
I was surprised.
I was so surprised.
No wonder it tasted weird.
Is he on leave?
No, that's just his hairstyle.
That's his hair.
Look.
He looks like Lee Jae Soo.
He looks like he's a marine.
Hyun Yi.
(She feels bad.)
Isn't it wasabi?
It wasn't very spicy.
Is this kimchi jeon?
The color is weird.
(What do they think of the kimchi jeon?)
- The kimchi jeon is salty. - Hey.
What did you just say?
Hyun Yi must've added salt to it.
I made it.
I was surprised when I tried it.
How were we supposed to eat that?
It should've been cooked to a crisp,
- but it was barely cooked. - It must've been rare.
She can't seem to say anything to Hye Jin.
It was a disappointment.
It smells like kimchi, but tastes like flour.
It was salty and I was disappointed.
- Oh, no. - Hey.
How are you going to handle the aftermath, Hae Na?
We will begin with having the athletes' parade.
Why are we having a parade?
What's a parade?
You'll find out.
- It's part of the ceremony. - Do you line up in fours?
Do you mean walking in with the flag?
Yes, even the idols do it.
Please stand in lines of two.
Everyone.
Let's line up.
Everyone?
Hurry up.
Hyun Yi, can you come this way?
Line up before the other team does.
Nice, nice.
It looks like bootcamp.
Can we stand over there?
It reminds me of bootcamp.
She's like a marine.
(The commanding officer is satisfied with the men that follow orders.)
That's good.
- We're ready. - That team is ready.
You need to be like that.
(She was eating and is late.)
Team Yi is ready as well.
Since you are all models,
imagine you're walking down the runway...
- as you parade. - Make sure you do well.
- Let's begin. - Good luck.
Team Han...
goes first.
I actually don't like...
being the leader of something.
goes first.
(She suddenly turns her model switch on.)
Oh, my.
You said you didn't like being a leader,
but you went first.
(The model that doesn't like being a leader...)
(struts confidently.)
You're enjoying it.
(Her facial expression...)
(is as charismatic as it is when she is on the runway.)
Hyun Moo loves it.
She's cool.
(Dozens of models escort her from behind.)
Oh, no.
(She turns.)
(I am Han Hye Jin.)
Did you have a drink?
That's enough.
(They hold an emergency meeting after seeing Team Han parade.)
Yoon Ju is upset.
All right.
Let's have Team Yi go next.
(Team Yi parades next.)
They are excited.
I think Yoon Ju will show us something.
The marine is excited.
- Are they comedians? - This looks like a comedy show.
Comedy show?
Look at Yoon Ju.
She can't let you steal the spotlight.
All right, line up please.
Can we all take a seat?
Let's have the team captains come forward...
to tell us how determined the teams are.
Can you tell us...
what your team strategy is?
It isn't important whether we win or lose.
We just hope to get closer.
It's nothing more or less than that.
Second place is not an option.
Really?
What was that?
You shouldn't have done the interview.
This is discordance between your words and actions.
Let's do this!
(Their eagerness is boosted.)
Please hand the microphone over to Hyun Yi.
How are you going to lead your team?
We're Team White.
We'll gather positive energy...
and win today.
That was boring.
What does white have to do with positive energy?
What is she talking about?
Could you point out a member of your team...
the other team should watch out for?
You can see her.
It's Jang Yoon Ju.
Yes, I see her.
- Suddenly. - She suddenly strikes a pose.
- All right. - Jang Yoon Ju!
I think it'll be a tight match.
- Stop that. - Don't take it away.
We'll make sure...
their white uniforms turn black.
- Look how dark she is. - I know.
She is competitive.
- Are you two rivals? - No.
Hyun Yi and I were hosts of a designer survival show.
Whenever there was something involving models,
I lost.
- You lost to Hyun Yi? - Yes.
It's become a trauma to me.
That's why you were so eager to win.
Yes. That's why I wanted to win so badly.
- She's competitive. - Yes, she is.
You were rivals in shows.
You were in "Devil's Runway" and "Sold Out".
- You know everything. - Are you a model?
- It was a secret. - Really?
I'm a children's model.
I wear children's clothes.
I saw you on the runway.
- She was on a runway? - I saw it.
- It was shocking. - Why?
Can I talk about this?
The male model held her head...
- and walked in carrying her. - I saw that.
- I saw it. - He carried her.
Attention.
Let's give the team captains a hand for encouragement.
Applause.
(Excited)
Why is Yoon Ju so excited?
She didn't drink, did she?
I don't think so.
Before we begin the sports,
we have to warm up.
It's for your safety.
Hold each other's hands.
It's best to have fun...
while warming up.
Let's start this. Start the music.
(They begin their warm up.)
Ready.
(They start moving to the upbeat music.)
All right.
1, 2, go.
Hold your hands and turn.
That's the typical recreation.
That's fun.
I had so much fun.
Gather in groups of five.
Hold hands and turn to the left.
I got more and more excited.
I haven't heard that song for a long time.
Gather in groups of seven.
(We have seven people.)
(Jump up and down, everyone.)
- It looks like a college camp. - You're right.
It's a game from over 20 years ago, but it's still fun.
Cheering is essential on sports day.
Let's have the team captains...
stand in the center of the circle.
It will be hard...
for the team captain to lead the cheer alone.
Pick one person that gets along with you well.
Come on.
It's Jung Hyuk.
- He's a popular model. - I know.
Make up a cheer for your team.
The board members will be the judges for it.
It's a secret.
We're supposed to talk secretly.
- He's cheerful. - Good job.
I hope it's perfectly synchronized.
- Perfect synchronization. - Yes.
Watch this.
You go, and you, then you at the end.
- I don't understand him. - Me neither.
What?
We'll color everything black.
- Right? - Yes.
- What about the moves? - The moves...
We'll have to think about it.
I don't like to come forward.
That's not like me.
- How about this? - Think of a song.
(There goes the discordance between her words and action.)
- Line up. - Okay.
When I say ready, you move like this.
Everyone in the back follows us.
- I'll face them. - I'm starting to see it now.
You go like this.
Then you clap with everyone.
Then here...
"We'll turn everything black."
That's good.
(That sounds like a good idea.)
One of the teams seems to be done.
- We'll report first. - Then...
- We'll turn everything black. - we'll grade you.
There are judges.
50, 100 and 150. Yes.
That's it.
Chant.
Go.
- Team Yi. - Team Yi.
(Cheering)
- That sounds good. - That sounds good.
That's not bad.
Really? Was that fine?
- That wasn't bad. - That's pretty good.
We'll win. It's worth trying.
Here's your score.
1, 2, 3.
Make sure to wave right.
They clapped. It's 400.
Left to right. Left to right.
(She teaches them the moves again.)
Left to right.
400.
(It's a festival for them already.)
Yoon Ju must've been very stressed.
Team Han will begin now.
(It's Team Han's turn.)
Chant.
Come on.
They're at odds.
Chant.
Go.
- What's she doing? - What's she doing?
- What's she doing? - What's that?
- That's terrible. - Oh, dear.
Hye Jin's excited alone.
You're running like an idiot.
- What's she doing? - She's excited alone.
(They're lost for words.)
- 1, 2... - 3.
- We'll turn everything black. - We'll turn everything black.
What is that?
Did they say that twice?
(Embarrassed)
(Sighing)
I didn't catch what they said.
What a mass.
We said we'll turn everything black.
Oh, "we'll turn everything black."
Okay. I see.
You'll get 200 max.
I expect 100.
- It's humiliating. - I expect 100.
Let's see the score. Here we go.
One...
Oh, my goodness.
- Good luck. - You went down on your knees?
(As a failed team leader...)
Goodness.
(She lays her pride as a model aside.)
My goodness, Hye Jin.
(Victory isn't important.)
It's nothing more or less than getting to know each other.
It's making me cry. I can't watch this.
They're all going down on their knees.
It's all turning black.
1, 2, 3.
(150, 100, 100)
- 350. - They're cold.
She lost.
(Team Yi wins.)
(This is why you cheer.)
(Sad)
Come on. It's fine.
I was wrong.
That's what Hyun Yi's good at.
She can come up with an idea on the spot.
- Doing something on the spot. - Are you sure you're not bad?
- I was going to say that. - I don't have that skill.
When I saw them lining up,
I knew I was going to win.
You must stay together to cheer.
I see.
- Right. - To be loud.
- She's right. - So...
I knew their formation was wrong.
Let's start the game now.
Please line up.
- They're all standing. - Yes.
No one's squatting.
I don't see anyone.
- I always squat down. - Really?
I always do this, but they're all standing.
It's normal for us.
We always lean on one foot.
Or we go like this.
- As if you're posing. - Yes.
When you come to comedians' sports festival,
Jung Ryul stands like this.
When's it going to be over?
- How about Joon Ho? - He's already lying down.
- Lying down? - He lies down.
He drinks rice wine as soon as he comes.
It's crazy. No one stands like that.
It's Up and Down game.
- Have you ever played it before? - What?
- What is it? - It's so long.
Does that require running?
Flip it over your head.
- Do you roll that stick? - Over your head from toe.
It's like a group skipping rope.
Hey. Cross your arms.
Or your can hold hands.
We'll begin soon.
Get ready.
Safety is most important.
- Be careful. - Don't trip.
Set,
- I was so nervous. - go.
Cheer, Team Yi.
- 1, 2, 3. - We can do it.
Cheer, Team Han. 1, 2, 3.
- We can do it. - Get ready.
(The game starts.)
- Be careful. - There it goes.
(Team Hye Jin outruns.)
You're doing great.
(What?)
They tripped.
They trip because of their long legs.
Be careful.
(It's all right.)
(The gap is noticeably big.)
Faster. My goodness.
It's because they're tall.
- It's because they're tall. - Faster.
(They're catching up.)
It looks nice with all the models playing.
They're tall.
They're tall, but slow.
Faster.
Last round.
(The gap has narrowed.)
Team Yi is coming.
- Which team would win? - Hurry up.
Who's the winner?
(Team Han chases.)
- Hurry up. - Who's the winner?
And?
(Will they win the breathtaking chase?)
- Hurry up. - Who's the winner?
And?
(Who's the winner of this unpredictable game?)
(It arrives first by a head.)
Good job.
- Good job. - Team Yi wins.
They won twice in a row.
(We won!)
Hold on. The game's not over yet.
- We don't have much time left. - Yoon Ju is so excited.
She's way too excited.
She's relieving all her stress from babysitting.
- She's overly excited. - Applause please.
(Applause to both teams for their effort)
(I'll win this time.)
- From now on, it'll go up. - What is it this time?
We'll measure the time it takes to pass this.
You'll have to crawl.
- Please sit down. - You have to crawl.
I'm really good at crawling.
Team Yi who's winning by 51 points...
will play first.
Whoever believes he served the most difficult time...
in the army, please come out.
- The Marine Corps. Yes. - The army.
He said he's not.
(Kim Do Jin wasn't in the Marine Corps.)
He wasn't in the Marine Corps.
Victory.
- Salute. - I see.
- You have to crawl. Can you? - Get ready.
Lie on your stomach.
(He's ready to crawl.)
No. Don't.
(Battle mode)
(As soon as the starting signal rings...)
He was really fast.
(Marching mode)
(Strong friend, Korea's army)
Good job, army.
Ministry of National Defense can use this as an ad.
Come to the very end.
He's good.
(He instantly passes the finish line.)
He's very fast.
Communication security.
He's good. He's good.
Their record is...
Everything is in order, sir.
Their record is 5.95 seconds.
- 5 seconds? - How can he be so fast?
- He's too fast. - He's really fast.
Next person is a former marine...
from Team Han.
- Is he a former marine? - He's from Marine Corps.
Tei.
- Come on, Lee Jae Soo. - He's a real marine.
(Tei, also known as Lee Jae Soo)
(He's the one who previously suffered from eating wasabi.)
Here we go.
- The former marine. - Go, Tei!
He's all bent.
- He's bent. - He's a former marine.
- He's a former marine. - He will finish in five seconds.
- Ready. - Let's go!
(Go.)
(He moves awkwardly.)
He's long.
He's long. He's long.
(Using his long body,)
(he finished in two leaps.)
(Striding)
That's it.
- He's really long. - Isn't he really fast?
- Isn't he like a centipede? - He's a little scary.
(The former marine is possessed by the spirit of a centipede.)
(What's his record?)
How many seconds did he take?
- Five seconds and... - Okay.
(5 seconds and...)
(The aggressive former soldier got the record of 5.95 seconds.)
Five seconds and...
11.
- He's fast. - Team Han won once.
They won.
(They won for the first time.)
(Thanks to the former soldiers, the atmosphere is heated up.)
He was good.
All right, now.
What's going on?
- It's hailing. - What's going on?
(Suddenly strong wind blows.)
Be careful.
(Even the MC is flustered.)
- What's going on? - Is it raining?
Why did that happen so suddenly?
What do we do?
(The strong wind unexpectedly hit them.)
- No way. - My goodness.
Even the sky is...
(It's like everything is going to be blown away.)
(A strong wind warning was issued all over the country that day.)
- Right. - So that was the day.
That day a truck fell because of the wind.
- Signage flew too. - Right.
(The weather is so nice.)
(The weather couldn't be better.)
- Why are they taking down the tent? - It's dangerous.
It's dangerous.
(It's an emergency situation.)
It happened really suddenly, didn't it?
Suddenly there was a strong wind.
An unbelievable thing happened before my eyes.
It was a natural disaster.
It was. It was a natural disaster.
Why is the wind blowing so hard?
Everyone's here for Hye Jin.
And she must've been really bad to the crew.
That's why the wind is not helping her.
I realized it once again.
Even now...
My goodness.
It turns out I was causing the wind.
It wasn't Hye Jin.
Yoon Ju was so excited.
- Hye Jin's rage brought the wind. - It's because of Yoon Ju's feet.
That's what brought the wind.
(Whoever caused it,)
(the wind is very strong today.)
(She joined the sports day with resolute determination.)
They only played two games, didn't they?
Those were just opening games too.
(We just started. We can't stop here.)
Guys. Right now,
the situation is bad.
The weather condition is really bad.
We are going to play just two more games.
We will play tug-of-war and relay race.
Relay race is the highlight.
Then we will go to a bar...
and damage...
our fresh liver.
(Dhalsim boosts everyone's morale.)
Is Hye Jin buying the drinks?
(The eldest model asks a sharp question.)
(What?)
(Everyone waits for her to say yes.)
- There are so many people. - Yoon Ju is nasty.
Yoon Ju is nasty.
My gosh. She's cruel.
Wait.
- Hyun Moo's busted. - Wait.
Wait. Hye Jin would be the one treating them.
Why would you hate Yoon Ju?
What?
(Right.)
I accidentally sympathized with her.
I should remain neutral.
(Dalshim is standing at the crossroads.)
(While she's hesitating,)
Thank you, Hye Jin!
(they thank her first.)
Thank you. Thank you.
(Leadership...)
(comes from your wallet.)
(Money made her leadership more solid.)
- That's good. - By the way, when that happens,
even if Hye Jin pays,
- they will thank Yoon Ju. - Right.
I will pay.
Thank you, Yoon Ju.
- Thank you. - It's as if she's paying.
Let's cheer up a little...
and get it done.
(Dalshim successfully boosts their morale.)
Okay.
(And the great tug-of-war begins.)
Stand.
- I hope she will at least win. - Of course.
I know.
Come forward. Stay closer.
Stand with your feet wide apart.
Ready.
I love this. I love this.
(The game begins with much excitement.)
- You have to lie down. - Just lie down.
They're good.
1, 2.
- What's going on? - You have to lie down.
Why are they so bad?
(Team Han is falling apart.)
(They get dragged.)
(It's a mess.)
Team Yi wins!
(Team Han lost the balance and crashed.)
Please be careful.
Don't get hurt.
Attention. Attention.
(Li Sa's mom is the most excited one.)
It's too windy. Let's hurry and get it done. Attention.
Here's why we lost.
I thought the force had to be in the front to pull well.
- I told everyone to move forward. - Lee Su Geun taught me this.
To win the tug-of-war,
you have to lie down as soon as the judge blows the whistle.
You have to really stretch your arm to hold the rope.
Then you have to lie down like this.
I didn't know.
I told everyone to come forward.
That's why all the people in the front fell.
Everyone fell.
You have to lie down.
It's important to choose the right leader.
(He carelessly criticizes Hye Jin.)
He said a harsh criticism.
- Please move to the right. - We have to spread out a little.
We have to spread out. I am sorry.
- We have to spread out. - Let's switch the sides.
Go forward.
(They change the side to the background music.)
Ready and sit down.
Ready.
- We should just lie down. - Right.
Just lie down. Will you do it right?
See? She's lying down.
Ready.
Do it well.
That was really fun.
- You have to lie down. - You should lie down.
(Everyone cheers for Team Han.)
- Lie down. - Lie down.
Lie down.
(Please do well.)
(As soon as the whistle is blown,)
You have to lie down.
(she frowns and tries hard to lie down.)
She...
You shouldn't do that. You just have to lie down.
(Laughing)
She didn't care about her image at all.
(Winning is all she cared about.)
(Wanting to win, she desperately pulls the rope.)
She really didn't want to lose.
That's...
That's how a novice plays the tug-of-war.
My gosh. She is...
(Hye Jin, I won't cut you slack. You know that, right?)
(Burning with desire to win, she seems merciless.)
- They won. They won. - They won!
- They won. - They won.
Team Han wins!
(Dalshim seems relieved.)
- It's 1 on 1 now. - It was so fun.
The leaders will play rock-paper-scissors...
and choose the side first.
Where you play is important.
- I wanted to stay where we won. - What side?
You have to choose one of two sides.
I felt stronger when I was pulling from that side.
- Come on. - Come on.
We don't have time. Let's hurry up.
Ready.
(Let's take it slow. I am too excited.)
She drank makgeolli, didn't she?
- Honestly, did she drink or not? - She didn't drink.
- She must've been drunk. - She needs to be tested.
(He learns the dance.)
Look at her.
- Why is she doing that? - This arm comes first.
(She gets to relieve all the stress she got from raising a child.)
What kind of a dance is that?
Ready.
Come on, Yoon Ju.
- Here we go. - Hey.
The one who wins...
What will you give?
You get to...
There's always someone like her.
Dalshim can't do anything.
I know. It's our first time to see her like that.
- You don't have to turn back. - I won't see it.
Will you play like that?
Please!
You can just look at her and play.
You lose if you don't play. Rock, paper, scissors.
Rock, paper, scissors.
- Hey! - If you... We don't have time.
- Rock, paper, scissors. - Rock, paper, scissors.
They're going to grab each other by the collar soon.
They are going to grab each other soon.
Rock, paper, scissors.
(Yoon Ju wins.)
I am really bad at rock, paper, scissors.
- Which side would you like? - That side!
All right!
(Lisa, mommy won.)
Hye Jin!
(Team Han loses a good spot.)
The wind is blowing left to right.
The wind will hit their faces.
- They are at a disadvantage. - We can do it!!
We can do it!
(Strong wind blows once again.)
That's right.
(Team Han grabs the rope with their eyes closed.)
They are at a disadvantage.
Work together.
I hope they win.
They are like yellow croakers that are roped together.
That's a good tactic.
(The 3rd round)
(It begins.)
That's good.
(You can imagine her expression from the sound she is making.)
Come on.
(Imagining her expression makes her laugh.)
(Kian84 is absorbed.)
I bet my life on the round.
Pull! Pull!
(They are ready to lie down.)
Heave-ho!
- It's working. - It's working.
The other team is getting pulled.
Team Han won!
(She is so excited that she dances.)
This is embarrassing.
(The mood is festive.)
(Dhalsim is overjoyed.)
This is embarrassing.
(Team Yi is devastated.)
Please gather around in the middle.
Now...
(Amidst them,)
(Lisa's mom is excited even though she has lost.)
- Why is she excited? - What is wrong with her?
(They don't understand her.)
What is wrong with her?
It doesn't matter whether she wins or loses.
You should take her to a club.
Now,
- the last match remains. - It's exhausting to clap.
It's a relay.
- Relay is the most important. - Please pick...
the runners.
Can you run fast?
Isn't Hyun Yi a good runner?
This is how I run.
It seems like...
my feet push the ground like...
(Tap, tap, tap, tap, tap)
What?
- Are you drunk? - What was that?
It seems like...
You seem like a stranger today.
- What is wrong with her? - You seem like a stranger today.
When I run...
- What is wrong with her? - She became a fool.
Why did she take off her shoes?
What is wrong with Yoon Ju and you?
- This is how I run. - Show us.
(Tap, tap, tap, tap, tap)
- What was that? - Must you hold your hands that way?
(Her hands don't move.)
What was that?
- Let's do a doping test. - What is wrong with her?
- What is wrong with you? - What is wrong with her?
(Everyone comments on the way she held her hands.)
- Why did you hands go like this? - I hit the ground hard...
when I run.
I run very fast.
- You run with short strides. - Yes.
- I run very fast. - I see.
Why do your hands go like this?
Why?
(They ask her again.)
She is like tyrannosaurus.
It's not like that.
(She puts her hands together as if she is pushing a cart.)
She turned strange.
You are stranger than Yoon Ju's dance.
- You are stranger than her dance. - What is up with her?
- What is up with your hands? - She runs with short strides.
- What is up with your hands? - I am very fast.
(I am fast.)
We understood.
That's how fast my feet move.
- Your feet almost go invisible. - That's right.
- Why didn't you say that? - Do they almost go invisible?
Tell me what is up with your hands!
People with stiff bodies put their hands like this.
They move with my legs.
Let's see how she runs.
They are in a circle.
(There is tension in the field.)
- Get ready. - What are those?
- Are those batons? - They are batons.
(They aren't body pillows.)
Do models need long batons?
The baton was too big.
During the relay,
it was hard to run with it.
I bet it was.
Even the batons are long.
(With the batons for models,)
(the relay begins.)
The two of them are very fast.
They are good runners.
The batons are too big.
Run!
(Lisa's mom overworks her vocal cords.)
Run! Run!
My goodness.
(Team Yi drops the baton.)
All right!
(Screaming)
The runner begins.
(Team Han is leading.)
Get ready.
He is good.
(He runs like a thief.)
(There is a distance between the runners.)
Yoon Ju and I were next.
(It's Hye Jin and Yoon Ju's turn.)
Yoon Ju.
- She is slow. - My goodness.
(How well can Hye Jin run?)
See? I am running very fast.
You aren't running very fast.
You are simply running.
(Her legs look slower because of their length.)
Why am I so slow?
(Lisa's mom is just as slow.)
Yoon Ju couldn't close the distance.
The fifth runners are waiting.
He is fast.
He runs like the wind.
I thought I ran like him.
You ran a bit differently.
He can run very well.
(The last runners)
She can run very well.
- That person... - It's Hyun Yi.
It's Hyun Yi.
(Hyun Yi is determined.)
Hyun Yi was...
- in track and fields. - You can't win against her.
- She is so fast. - Hyun Yi is fast.
(She gives her last spurt.)
(If you don't run fast, she will catch up.)
- She is fast. - She is really fast.
(She chases after the other runner.)
She is like Na Ae Ri.
She resembles Na Ae Ri.
(When Hyun Yi is close to catching up,)
(the other runner crosses the finish line.)
Team Han won.
(Team Han won.)
Okay! Team Han won.
She closed the distance.
It's a landslide victory.
We should have run another lap.
Then I would have caught up.
(All matches end.)
That's sad.
More games were prepared.
There were 8 to 9 games.
Thank you for your hard work.
(The event ends.)
2018 Family Sports Day.
The winning team is...
(Although they didn't play many games,)
(they competed fiercely.)
(The matches were thrilling.)
(Which team won?)
Congratulations, Team Han!
Team Han won.
It was my first time.
She beat Hyun Yi for the first time.
You did a good job.
(She is happy.)
(We won.)
(She gets her photo taken despite the strong wind.)
(Staggering)
- She almost fell. - It's very windy.
People like us can't imagine getting pushed over by the wind.
Usually, MVP comes from the winning team,
but we don't care about that.
I will announce the MVP.
(It's time to announce the MVP.)
Jang Yoon Ju!
(Lisa's mom becomes the MVP.)
Where is Ms. Sung Ye Jin?
Ms. Sung Ye Jin will deliver the award.
Jang Yoon Ju!
- She is the MVP. - Jang Yoon Ju!
(Yoon Ju is the best.)
(Unable to contain her good cheer,)
(she gives a ceremony.)
My goodness.
(She high fives down the runway.)
Attention. Bow.
Please bow.
(Yoon Ju is happy to receive a gift.)
(Hye Jin can't stop laughing.)
Click. Thank you.
(They take a group picture.)
(The strong wind made it an eventful day.)
Thank you for your hard work.
(Working together brought happiness to Dhalsim's sports day.)
(I Live Alone)
(The idiot goes out on a spring day.)
The star of prostate.
He will make us laugh again.
(Two months ago, he got an endoscopy...)
(and made everyone laugh.)
I will get ready to laugh.
My goodness.
(How will he make people laugh this time?)
- What is that? - That's the car.
My goodness.
- He always brags about it. - It's a supercar.
- It's a supercar. - Is that Si Eon's car?
Of course it is.
(It has an elegant body...)
(and a smooth front.)
(What kind of a car is this?)
In the early 90s,
this car was 1 of the 3 supercars in Japan.
Mazda RX-7.
And skyline.
It was released at an affordable price for a supercar.
That's why the model was very popular at that time.
I happened to get the car,
so I'm taking care of it now.
I think this model appeared in...
- "Initial D". - Right. "Initial D".
- "Initial D"? - I know "Initial D".
However, isn't it expensive?
- No, it's affordable. - Is it?
- It's an old model. - It's made in 1993.
- 1993? - But it was registered in 1994.
Daejeon Expo was held in 1993.
That makes me realize how long it's been since then.
This car looks great though.
- It just falls down. - Goodness.
The trunk lid shock damper is broken.
What if it falls off?
I should clean you since you're going to meet new friends.
I haven't seen that car duster for a while.
People used to use that a lot.
You can often see the chauffeur of a CEO do that.
Blue Chip, please do well today.
- Why do you call it "Blue Chip"? - The car is blue,
so I named it "Sangdo-dong Blue Chip".
"Sangdo-dong Blue Chip"?
Gosh.
I hope I'll drive this car well.
- That car can move? - Of course.
- It runs well. - Does it have windshield wipers?
It has only one.
(Struggling)
- What are you doing? - The seat belt wouldn't lock.
- Gosh. What's that? - It has so many problems.
The shock damper, windshield wiper, and seat belt.
My goodness.
What are you doing?
- It wouldn't lock up this side. - Really?
He should put it on in any way, but still, he should fix it.
Look at that. It's so...
- It's just amazing. - Look at that old car stereo.
(The interior looks so old.)
- What's that? - What's that?
- Oh, it's a manual car. - Do you have a license?
- Yes, I do. - You have a manual driving license?
(Vroom)
- It runs well. - It runs well.
The wheels might fall off on Gangbyeon Highway.
Just like teeth fall off.
- Thump, thump. - Thump, thump.
If that happens, I'll acknowledge him.
As a great entertainer.
- He's so mean. - If two wheels fall off.
After that, he moves the car with his feet.
(He moves the car with his feet instead of the wheels?)
- If that happens, - Hang on.
I'll make a deep bow to you for the rest of my life.
- For the rest of my life. - He moves the car like this.
The four of you should go on without me.
- I feel so uncomfortable. - Where are you going?
- This isn't right. - You always do this to us.
- That's right. - Yes.
This car is so difficult to drive.
(The hazard lights suddenly come on by themselves.)
Why did the lights come on again?
The lights kept coming on by themselves.
Let's go to Ilsan safely.
(You didn't seem to be used driving Blue Chip.)
I hadn't driven a manual car for a long time before then.
And the clutch was much more sensitive...
than other manual cars.
So it was hard for me to get used to driving it.
Hey, hey. Calm down.
- I'm getting used to this. - You can drive a manual car.
Of course. I have a license.
I'm getting the hang of it now.
(He's getting used to driving Blue Chip.)
Nice.
(Squeak)
- The car makes a squeaking noise. - Where is it coming from?
Could there be a rat in your car?
Then I'll acknowledge you.
I'll reward you the grand award if there's a rat in there.
I'll acknowledge you if you stepped on the rat.
You got me.
There's a rat at the back.
I put a rat in the car to make people laugh.
(Squeak)
I think the noise is coming from his seat.
It makes me nervous.
(The squeaking noise makes him more nervous.)
- Stop squeaking already. - I hate that noise.
- He made it squeak on purpose. - It's so annoying.
- Why are you honking? - "Honking"?
He's speaking in Busan dialect.
I grew up near the beach.
(The nostalgic sound of seagulls)
Near Haeundae Beach?
(Blue Chip is running cheerfully.)
But it's running at 40km per hour.
(Embarrassed)
It feels like it's running at 150km per hour.
(Other cars pass by him.)
It's running really well.
Gosh, the hazard lights.
The hazard lights kept coming on by themselves.
(The hazard lights won't behave themselves.)
The hazard lights... Gosh.
(Pressing)
Oh, I forgot. The car horn doesn't work.
Even the car horn doesn't work?
Honking the horn only causes a fight.
- What are you talking about? - It's better without it.
Doesn't the radio work?
(Sniffling)
My hands are cold.
- Doesn't the heater work? - I'd feel sleepy if it's too hot.
"I'd feel sleepy if it's too hot."
(It's a very inspiring comment.)
- You would feel sleepy if it's hot. - I removed the function.
- Really? - I removed the air conditioner too.
It should be hot in summer.
"I'd get sick rather than dozing at the wheel."
"Honking the horn only causes a fight."
- To keep the peace, - That's right.
- I removed the horn. - It's a new paradigm for cars.
All it can do is run.
That's enough for me.
Blue Chip's current condition is...
The car has been completely overhauled.
- What does that mean? - "Overhauled"?
Just like a watch,
I had the engine and everything else checked thoroughly.
The engine made a really loud noise.
I thought someone was calling me.
When I first heard it, I got startled and looked back.
I realized that it was Blue Chip who was calling me.
I left the interior as it was in 1994.
The radio isn't working.
I saw this color when I turned the heater on.
- What? - It shocked me.
- What do you mean by that? - You mean fine dust?
- I turned the heater on. - Blue smoke came out?
Then some yellow smoke came out.
I got so startled.
That's why I removed the heater...
along with the air conditioner.
(The seat belt is choking him.)
- Look at the seat belt. - It's too tight.
- Where is he headed? - Where is he headed?
- Is he headed to a junk yard? - What's that?
Right? I thought it was a junk yard too.
- The holy land of classic cars. - "The hold land"?
(He exclaims while getting out of the car.)
- That's amazing. - I know that place.
(It's an outdoor warehouse where various classic cars are displayed.)
That looks great. I see a lot of old cars.
- It's amazing. - Look at that Volkswagen car.
All the cars there can move.
(This is the world Si Eon was dreaming of.)
- Is it you? - Hi.
I met him when I filmed a TV commercial before.
He runs a class car lending business.
I heard he has a lot of old cars.
So I wanted to get some information...
and take a look around his warehouse.
Sir, are all these cars yours?
Yes.
Where did you get such a nice car?
A friend of mine collects classic cars like this.
- So... - It's a rare model.
- Exactly. - He's an expert.
How did you repair the engine?
He said he got the engine overhauled.
- In Korea? - Yes.
- He's an expert. - He's an expert.
There aren't many repair shops that can fix a rotary engine, right?
That's right.
My car has an unusual engine.
- A rotary engine? - It's called a rotary engine.
It's called the legendary engine.
It doesn't move up and down. It rotates like this.
Instead of cylinders.
It's difficult to maintain.
(He opens the hood.)
(How is Blue Chip's condition?)
Please tell me your honest opinion.
- Isn't it too old? - I can see the history.
First of all, judging from the way it seems at a glance...
- What if he says it's bad? - It looks like rats are in there.
I think it's in good condition. It's not bad.
- Is it okay? - Yes.
I heard the car had been overhauled.
What's the total mileage?
- 100,000km. - I see.
- It's quite low. - It's low.
I should leave the hood open.
He said I should cool it down after driving.
That's good for the car.
You have to take care of it after driving.
What's that one?
This is Volkswagen Karmann Ghia made in the 1950s.
It's gorgeous.
(Park Hae Jin)
- It's used for a TV commercial. - That's right.
(The car appeared in a lot of photos with celebrities.)
People who have many classic cars lend their cars...
- They lend their cars. - for a TV commercial shoot.
They feel so proud of it because their cars appear in a commercial,
not because they can make money from it.
- They're proud as the owner. - They have pride.
Right.
(Si Eon looks at the car more closely.)
(Exclaiming)
- Old cars have better interiors. - It's so pretty.
All the parts are genuine.
(It makes us exclaim.)
That car is gorgeous.
How did he manage the car so well?
He didn't manage the car. He restored the car.
He bought the car in a really bad condition.
He repainted it and fixed everything inside of it.
He restored the interior as it was in the past.
(He restored the interior as it used to be.)
This is unbelievable.
Was this made in 1950?
- In 1957. - In 1957?
- My father was born in 1957. - So was my mom.
Then you can buy him this car as a gift.
That car is...
(Mercedes Benz W114 made in 1968)
- That looks amazing. - It was made in 1968.
- In 1968? - Yes.
It's so gorgeous.
CEOs in the past used to ride in that kind of car.
We can see it in movies.
It's gorgeous. The gear shift stick is on the steering wheel.
- It's on the steering wheel. - That's right.
It this a manual car?
- This is an automatic car. - It's so beautiful.
He gets the parts from overseas if he can't get them in Korea.
It says, "automatic".
At that time, an automatic car was something to show off.
- At that time? - Yes.
An automatic car was rare at that time.
It's hard to believe that it's an automatic car.
- It's gorgeous. - I know.
- I think this one is the best. - I know.
(Welcome to the world of classic cars.)
- It's beautiful. - It's so pretty.
It's pretty.
- I should visit there too. - You had a lot of fun.
I had so much fun.
(Various old cars catch your eyes.)
I like this one. What is it?
- Classic cars are attractive. - It's fun to watch.
- This is an amazing place. - Is it?
Yes.
I love that red car.
Look at this car.
My goodness.
- Honestly, - It's beautiful.
this is gorgeous.
(He can't stop exclaiming because of the beautiful exterior.)
Take a look at the interior.
(It's time to see the interior.)
- Take a look. - Gosh.
Unbelievable. Look at the steering wheel.
(Exclaiming)
- They're all genuine parts. - I see.
It's so...
- beautiful. It's beautiful. - Look at the headlights.
Gosh. It's beautiful.
(The supercar entertained Si Eon's eyes.)
- Shall I play some music for you? - Music?
What's that?
- It's a turntable. - Yes.
(Won Seok gave Si Eon...)
It looks good.
(a retro style turntable as a gift.)
- It's over 100 years old. - 100 years?
He has real retro items...
(It's a hand-operated turntable.)
- He's expert in retro items. - Yes.
(Twang)
- Is it Japanese samurai music? - It's 100-year-old music.
(What?)
I feel like a ghost will pop out.
It was scary.
It's creepy.
- When Hyun Moo marries Hye Jin, - Will you give this to them?
I'll play this music as a wedding march.
(What is he talking about?)
(It would feel like this.)
How slowly should we walk?
He'll give you that when you two get married.
- Really? Did he say that? - Yes.
Among all the cars I have here,
this one is the oldest.
In what year was it made?
- It's cute. - It was made in 1956.
- In 1956? - Yes.
(It was made in 1956.)
It has only the essentials inside of it.
- This is so... - It's very small, isn't it?
It's so pretty.
How did they design a car like that in 1956?
There are a lot of beautiful old cars.
Check out this one.
(What car will he show us this time?)
- Look at the color. - It's from J brand.
I prefer old car designs to the designs these days.
Last November...
Henry took a photoshoot with this car.
Aren't there cars designed like this these days?
Yes, there are.
I should visit there. It's so fun.
It felt like a new world.
You know I like retro items.
They say you fail if you're drenched in the past.
However, I liked it so much.
I was so happy.
May I test drive this car?
That car is really gorgeous.
- He managed it so well. - I love the headlights.
(Dazed)
Is this your first time in a car with an air-cooled engine?
- Yes. It's an air-cooled engine? - Yes, it is.
(Vroom)
(Exclaiming)
It feels like I'm watching an old American movie.
- Unbelievable. - Driving that car...
It's so comfortable to ride in.
It runs so well.
It's a manual car.
The engine sound is great.
It's really nice.
(The engine sound makes all men's hearts pound.)
- It's fabulous. - My car makes a similar sound.
The engine sound is amazing.
Does the heater work too?
He's jealous.
Blue Chip doesn't have it.
I can hear the engine clearly.
(Vroom)
I like the sound.
This car is really great.
(He enjoys the supercar's engine sound.)
It's unbelievable.
(They arrived at Heyri Art Village.)
We came to the place where it suits the car.
(Laughing)
Look how this car is drawing attention.
The car drew everyone's attention.
- Of course. - I'm not surprised.
I think they looked at the car first.
That's right. I'm riding in such a nice car.
But it's not my car.
It looks amazing.
I should take some photos.
(He gets out of the car to take a photo.)
He must be proud of his car.
Of course.
He's posing as if it's his car.
(As if it's my car...)
The car is the main model.
(I'm the main model.)
Sir, may I just go around here?
Are you sure?
- I'll stop if I can't drive it. - Okay.
- What if you crush it? - The insurance won't cover that.
His insurance covers all drivers...
because the car is used for filming.
That's a relief.
(Nervous)
How should I start the car?
Turn it to the right.
(The engine starts.)
(He's proud to have started the engine.)
The feeling in my hands when I changed gears...
You seem more confident.
(His confidence increased.)
That's good.
It feels amazing how the car changes gears.
This is why people who drive a manual car...
prefer it to an automatic car.
It was so difficult for a beginner.
You didn't make the engine stop.
(He arrived safely.)
It's beautiful.
(Was it really different?)
It's definitely different.
The model I test drove...
is a very famous model among that brand's cars.
It's like red bean paste in red bean paste bun.
It was amazing. I was happy.
I thought I didn't deserve to ride in that car.
I mean it.
I don't think I can drive it around.
(Si Eon came back safely in the car that's too good for him.)
It must've been fun.
Yes. It was so good.
I'll get going now.
See you later.
- I'll come back soon. - Please come visit me.
Thank you for everything.
- Thank you, sir. - Go home safely.
- I'll visit you again. - Okay.
(He calls someone as soon as he gets in the car.)
- Hi, Si Eon. - Young Joon, I'm on my way.
Prepare the cars for me.
- Okay. - See you soon.
- "Cars"? - See you.
This will be...
(Are you going to see more cars?)
There's no fixed market price for old cars.
Even if you buy an old car today,
and it breaks down tomorrow, you can't complain about it.
It's an understandable situation.
So many old car owners exchange cars with each other.
I posted a message because I wanted to exchange Blue Chip...
with an automatic car.
Classic car owners often exchange their cars.
- They change cars often. - That's his real name.
"Lee Bo Yeon".
- He revealed his real name. - Or I can't get a membership.
- That's right. - You have to take responsibility.
Hello? Hello.
Yes. I was wondering if you're interested in buying my car.
Honestly, it's not in the best condition.
You sound like an expert.
(Inquiries about his car continue.)
(Si Eon arrived at some place.)
The person who owns the car I wanted was close by.
So I asked him to show me his car.
You two will check each other's car before making a decision.
(Smiling)
(Who is Si Eon's friend?)
Hi.
He is...
the CEO of my agency.
We became friends as we're the same age.
We became friends once we met.
I turned on the heater, and something came out.
- It's because it's old. - It looked like a moth.
You have to enjoy that too...
- if you like retro items. - You shouldn't fall for that.
You must love...
- even the dust on the item. - He's right.
That's total nonsense.
It's just beautiful.
That model was made after the red car I drove before.
- It's pretty. - It's nice.
You used only genuine parts, right?
(The car won Si Eon's heart.)
- This one is also amazing. - Right.
- It looks like a recent model. - That's right.
- It's not a recent model. - Is that also an old car?
It was made in 1997.
But the parts are still being produced.
Then I can also manage this car.
No. You have to be able to speak English.
You can get the parts only from overseas.
He doesn't hold back.
I'm fluent in English. Don't worry.
- I can do that. - Is that so?
I just wanted to exchange my car with his car.
But this car is worth 20 cars of yours.
- Of course. - I met my car when I was in my 20s.
Did you?
Let's talk again when you bring 20 cars of that model.
(I'm disappointed, my friend.)
- Honestly, I prefer this one. - You do?
This is the car that I want the most.
(Simple, straight lines are the special feature of this car.)
That's good. I like it.
Right? This is the sound.
(Do you hear the sound of sensibility?)
- Move your car. Let me get out. - Try it first.
(How's the quality of riding?)
(This is it.)
It's good, isn't it?
It's perfect.
- It feels great. - I know, right?
I think you look better in that car.
- I think that's your car. - He keeps insisting.
- We agree with him. - That's your car.
He shuts him out.
Get out of there.
Let me take a look at the engine.
You want to? Sure.
I... Oh, gosh.
(That scared me.)
- What was that? - Do you know how to open it?
It's different from cars in this generation.
- It opens this way. - Yes. That's it.
Have you seen a bonnet opening like this lately?
- It's old. - Hold on.
- Why? - I thought you imported it.
- I did. - It's written in Korean.
- What's this? - One sung.
- What? - What's this?
Oh, come on.
What's it doing here?
- He's flustered. - How dare you lie to me?
- Hey, reduce it by 50,000 dollars. - What?
Check out the engine.
Ignore other stuff. This is the whole point.
This red engine.
Do you know everything inside here?
- Close it. - Why?
- I don't know. - No?
- Tell me what you want. - This is my dream car.
How about monthly installment?
- What? - Installment for 20 years.
Does that mean you'll stay in that company for 20 years?
Sometimes you can find it on the internet.
- "Installment for 640 months." - Come on.
- Really? - Yes.
Actually I...
- You love cars. - love cars.
I actually met a dealer...
to buy a classic car,
but when I was test driving,
- the left turn felt like a u-turn. - Why is that?
I had to keep turning it.
It's not power steering wheel.
"How long do I have to turn it?"
- Then... - "Just a bit more."
if you try my car, it'll change your mind.
- He's trying to sell it. - Does it turn well?
Bye.
(He failed to persuade his friend.)
Yes. Keep it up.
Okay.
Keep up the good work.
- Bye. - Bye.
Call me.
Your car looks great. Great job on the repair.
I bought a car last year and painted it.
- That was terrible. - That broke down.
- I heard it broke down. - I know.
I purchased a new car recently.
New cars are the best.
Listen to me.
Sensibility doesn't last long.
You have to keep repairing the car again and again.
- New cars are the best. Done. - Done.
(Neat ending)
(Leaving his dream car behind,)
(where's he heading to?)
- Where are you going? - I went to eat.
I haven't had a meal all day.
(To satisfy his hunger...)
(Worried)
Pork belly meat please.
- What? - Alone?
Pork belly meat alone.
(He attempts eating pork belly meat alone.)
(Pork belly meat looks delicious.)
It's cruel especially at this hour.
I'm so hungry. My gosh.
It looks delicious.
Enjoy.
(Enjoy.)
(Eating)
I can't watch it.
- Many people eat meat alone lately. - Yes.
There's a pork belly meat restaurant for single customers.
(Everything's fine as long as it's delicious.)
(She's dying.)
(What have you learned today?)
I fell in love at first sight.
Is this the car I know?
It looks more wonderful and beautiful than before.
I think that's why I'm chasing it again.
I'm going to study classic cars by participating in...
classic car group,
and make it into a fun hobby...
which doesn't cost much.
(He focuses on eating pork belly meat for now.)
(For the day he meets his dream super car.)