Previously on "The Americans..."
If we start killing scientists
"on U.S. soil,
who knows where it leads?
At best,
the secret war escalates.
At worst...
He got one of the scientists.
God damn it.
This is our worst failure
in 15 years.
I swear to God, they'll pay.
This will not stand.
I've been so stressed lately.
You know I could get anything
that Agent Gaad has.
Oh! What?
You just... you startled me.
Did something happen
between you and Irina?
Nothing happened.
There's only you.
I asked you not to lie to me.
I made a terrible mistake.
Can we please just...
Try and start over?
No. We can't.
Can I have
another piece of fried chicken?
Of course.
Me too.
Uh, white or dark meat?
- White.
- Dark.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
I wish we could
have fried chicken every week.
Twice a week. Every day.
Your dad and I, um...
Want to talk to you guys
about something.
Oh, my God.
You're too old.
I'm too old for what?
To have a baby.
Jen's mom is ancient,
and she's pregnant,
and she's
light years younger than you.
- You're having a baby?
- No.
No. Where did you
get that idea?
- You just said...
- No, no.
Dad is going to be
staying somewhere else
for a little while.
Are you going
on a business trip?
No.
You're separating?
Well, no, we're not...
we're not separating,
not exactly.
We're... it's a little bit
more like, uh...
hitting the pause button.
For how long?
I don't know. We don't know.
You're kidding, right?
I mean, this is a joke,
isn't it?
Why?
Your dad and I have...
you know,
we've been fighting a lot.
You always fight a lot.
- Too much.
- We know.
Then stop.
- We can't.
- Tried.
When Henry and I fight,
you tell us to stop.
If we can, why can't you?
I don't know.
The important thing is...
Other than the fact that
we love you so very much,
is that dad and I
need some time
to figure things out.
Do you guys not
love each other anymore?
It's... it's complicated.
And when you're grown up,
you'll understand.
- Bullshit!
- Paige...
You don't just
stop loving someone!
Are you gonna stop loving us?
No. That is...
I mean, it's impossible.
That would never happen. Never.
This is so stupid.
This is your fault! You're
always giving dad a rough time!
It's not mom's fault.
Why are you defending her?
I'm not. Look, this is...
Our decision.
We... we both
made this decision.
Henry, please open up.
I just want to talk.
I love you so much.
More than you'll ever know.
So, I'll see you tomorrow
at the Beemans'?
Are we really gonna
go to a party together?
If Stan's work friends
are gonna be there,
I think we should be, too.
Mm.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
I got fresh meat, fresh meat.
- You want a dog?
- Yeah, I'll... I'll have one.
Paige, do you want a hamburger?
No.
Rough night?
No one is doing
particularly well right now.
Paige slept in Henry's room.
How is Henry?
Not great.
Where are you staying?
Motel in Peterborough.
That sounds depressing.
It's okay for now.
It's for the best.
Yeah, I know.
I suppose we should mingle.
Watching game 7
of the eastern quarterfinals
here in Philadelphia.
Hey, how you guys doing?
We're doing great.
That's a big old...
that's a big, old
plate of meat you got.
Yeah. Sit. Rest your dogs.
Oh! Funny man!
All right.
So, we're gonna do something.
We're gonna take one of them out
right here in D.C.
They're on the boards...
Is this approved?
If anyone should ask, no.
Who's the target?
The acting KGB Rezident.
Arkady?
That's a big target.
They just killed
three of our own.
If we don't hit them
hard and fast,
those won't be
our last casualties.
How's it going down?
Arkady likes to jog
Monday and Wednesday afternoon.
He's back in his office
at 5:00.
When? Tomorrow.
And, uh,
this is not an assignment.
Participation
is strictly voluntary.
I'm in.
Me too.
I'm sorry,
if this is extrajudicial...
I would rather stay away.
Okay.
Hey.
What's up with your brother?
He looks like
he lost his best friend.
He did.
My parents are taking
a vacation from each other.
My dad moved out last night.
For good?
Who knows?
They say they're
hitting the pause button,
whatever that means.
Okay. All right.
Sorry.
Only one way
to stop a bully, Stan.
I can't go in on this,
Chris. I can't.
Your shoes squeak. I get it.
Me? My shoes...
they don't squeak.
I'm fully lubricated.
Who's, um...
Who's the babe?
Not your wife... the other fox?
That's my neighbor.
That's your neighbor? Mm-hmm.
I'd borrow some sugar
if I was you.
You're a putz.
You know, I was sitting
by the window the other night,
and I was reading,
and I saw Philip leave.
I mean, I wasn't spying.
No, no. Of course not.
Is everything
okay with you guys?
We are taking some time apart.
But I guess
that's not something
you can keep quiet
for very long.
No. Um, why would you want to?
Privacy, I guess.
There's no shame in it.
Do the kids know yet?
- We told them last night.
- Oh.
Well, you know,
if you need anything,
you don't hesitate
to ask me, okay?
Thanks. Yeah.
Dad, I want you to come home.
We both do.
I-I can't.
Why not? I...
I just can't, sweetheart.
Please?
I'm sorry.
See you soon.
Ooh, shoot yourself
into me, Clark!
Oh! Take me!
Oh, God, take me!
I have to go. There's
a situation with the department.
What's going on?
Three Agents got killed
and a scientist.
I know. Everyone's upset.
Yeah.
Clark...
I'm in love with you.
I waited my whole life for you,
and I would do
anything for you.
Anything.
All you have to do is ask.
Just please...
Just tell me one thing?
Is this real?
Yes.
Well, then, stay with me.
Please.
Just this once.
Where's Henry?
How should I know?
Henry!
What should I tell my friends?
Why do you have to
tell your friends anything?
If they ask.
Tell them whatever you want.
Tell them the truth.
Which is what?
That your parents aren't
living together right now.
Henry, get down here right now!
We're gonna be late!
Rise and shine, sleepyhead.
Oh, wow.
Hi. Hi.
It's been a long time
since I've had a man sleep in my bed.
I think I can get used to this.
But I got to go to work.
What's the rush?
Well, there's a lot going on.
Agent Gaad got a call
from the white house
a couple days ago,
and since then,
he's been in and out,
having secret meetings
with his old buddies
from the C.I.A.
He thinks that
I don't know, but...
I'm his secretary,
not his potted plant.
What are they planning?
Well, I think they're gonna
kill a KGB Agent.
It's an eye for an eye, Clark.
But you
Can stay as long as you like.
Mm. Bye.
Bye.
Can I help you?
I don't know.
I'm with the Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Can I ask you a few questions?
About what?
Why don't we start
with who you are?
W-who I... I'm...
I'm just a guy.
Yeah, you're just a guy
who spent the night
with a girl... Martha.
Oh, look, my friend, I don't...
I'm not your friend, friend.
What are you doing here?
You know what?
You got me dead to rights,
'cause me and Martha...
we've been banging each other
into ecstatic oblivion
for the past... wow...
10 hours.
Look, why don't we take
this conversation downtown?
Lock up your car.
Okay.
Holy shit.
No, no.
No. No!
Aah!
What happened?
He followed me
coming out of Martha's.
I need to go back
and move his car.
I've seen him before. Yeah.
At the Beeman party.
He's FBI.
Does he know
you're working Martha?
I don't know. I suppose.
Uh, or this just could be a...
what? What?
A total screw-up.
He might have been
seeing Martha himself.
A jealous suitor?
But I got something
from Martha.
The FBI
are planning retaliation.
They're gonna kill a KGB Agent
here in D.C.
- He'll know what they're planning.
- Yeah.
I brought morphine.
He needs to be in a hospital.
We'll do what we can.
The wound's pretty deep.
We're gonna have to
pack it or cauterize it
once we take the knife out.
You seen Amador?
No. He was supposed to meet me
an hour ago.
He never showed.
It's not like him.
You've reached Amador.
If I'm not working,
I'm out having a ball.
Leave it at the beep.
Hey, it's Stan.
Where the hell are you?
Call me.
What'd you do with his car?
I wiped it down for prints
and parked it around the corner
from his apartment.
All right.
Now, when I pull this,
it's gonna gush
like a broken pipe.
Ready? Yeah.
Okay, lift him.
Oh!
Okay. Put him down.
It's all right. It's over.
The hard part's over.
Thank you.
Chris?
Chris!
You've reached Amador.
If I'm not working,
I'm out having a ball.
Leave it at the beep.
Hey, it's Cheryl.
We met at the crab shack.
I thought we could
get together again.
You have my number, right?
Hello, Amador. This is Julie.
I'm in town for a few days
and wanted to see
if we could catch up.
Call me, cutie.
Chris, aunt Lyla's
coming for dinner tomorrow.
I told her you're busy,
but you know what she's like.
You and papa can
watch the game on TV, okay?
So, you'll come?
Good?
Come.
Hey, it's Stan.
Where the hell are you?
There's just no way that Amador would check
out like this, without touching base.
He didn't answer his phone.
He didn't show up this morning.
I went to his apartment.
He hasn't been home all morning.
His car was around the corner
from his apartment.
- I had forensics check it out.
- And?
No prints.
None.
What? He wiped his own prints
off his car?
We don't know that
the KGB has him.
I know it. Look, I've got
every available Agent
out looking for him.
If he spent the night
out on the town
and woke up
in the wrong room...
I'm telling you,
that's not what's happening.
Or if the KGB does have him,
we'll find him.
Let's not jump to conclusions.
Let's just do our job.
I have to get back. The kids
are gonna be home from school.
Yeah, go, go. I'll, uh...
I'll give him some more morphine
when he wakes.
There's nothing else
we can do now.
Okay.
A counterintelligence artiste?
Yeah, I'm like Picasso...
Only with a gun
and not a brush.
My work is my life,
and my life is my art.
I have no wife, no kids,
no pets, no hobbies,
no distractions...
except for pussy.
I got no attachments.
I'm as unencumbered
as bedbugs in a flophouse,
and I like it.
It works for me.
El Lobo.
Sí. Yo soy El Lobo.
Yeah. I am a lone wolf.
That's good, Stan.
Anybody home?
Could use some help.
Hey.
I got Mac and cheese and
those pretzels that you love,
the ones that are
as hard as rock candy.
And I bought a wok.
What for?
To make Chinese food.
You've never made Chinese food.
First time for everything.
Is that what this is about?
You and dad split,
and you start...
Cooking Chinese food?
So we'll have
spaghetti and meat sauce, then.
I don't care what we eat,
and I don't want to pretend
that your life is a do-over,
because mine isn't.
So that's what you don't want.
What do you want?
I want things to be
the way they were.
I know.
Paige, I know
things are hard right now.
But it's for the best.
For who?
Hello, Mrs. Jennings.
This is Mrs. Costa,
Henry's teacher.
Mrs. Costa? No.
Is this a bad time?
Uh... This is...
no, this is not a bad time.
Henry, you okay?
Yeah.
Tired?
I just got a call
from Mrs. Costa.
You have something
you want to tell me?
No.
Henry...
I know this is...
A terrible thing
to do to you right now.
My parents... wouldn't have
even considered it.
It would have been unthinkable.
But times have changed,
and your dad and I...
Mrs. Costa said
you didn't do
your social-studies project.
I did.
Are you saying
she's not telling the truth?
Show it to me, please.
Is this it?
Yeah.
But you only wrote
one sentence.
I didn't have
anything else to say.
The KGB wants to know
what your next move is.
They don't think you're
just going to sit back
after losing your scientist
and three of your Agents.
Has something happened?
Who put the finger on Amador?
Who?
My partner.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Don't lie to me, Nina.
- Do not lie to me.
- You're hurting me!
- I don't know! I swear! Let go.
I don't know.
I swear I don't know.
You find out who took Amador.
You find out where he is.
Now.
Water.
More?
Cold.
What do you want?
Information.
Who are the FBI
planning to take out?
I don't know.
I think you do.
Several of my friends
from the C.I.A.
Will be working with us
on this.
This is Ms. Kendall.
Arkady will be leaving
the Rezidentura in one hour.
In approximately
1 hour and 14 minutes,
Arkady will be
running his usual path
through Danbury Park.
Agent Samuels
will be sitting on a bench
30 meters up the path
from your post
at the interception point.
If he raises his newspaper,
that will be your signal
that the target
is in the field.
But if Agent Samuels
drops his paper at any point,
we will abort the mission.
Because of
the high value of the target,
any decision to take action
will be verified by us
through the signal.
Any questions?
Stan...
I'm glad you're with us.
Any word on Amador?
We're still working on it.
If we'd hit the KGB earlier,
they wouldn't have him.
Maybe. Who knows?
Listen, if we kill Arkady,
we're signing
Amador's death certificate.
We have to take him alive.
There's something else
we have to consider.
Amador knows the name of
your mole in the Rezidentura.
If the KGB has him
and he talks,
she's finished.
Henry's teacher called.
Why?
He was staring
out the window all day,
was not participating,
not talking in class.
How's Paige? She hates my guts
and isn't shy about
letting it be known.
I'm sorry.
How's Amador?
He's weak, but he's awake.
Says he doesn't know anything.
He's lying. I know.
They're gonna be looking for him
all over town.
We have to get
the hell out of here.
No. He's too weak to move.
We can't wait for him
to come around.
We need information,
and we need it now.
It's my turn to try.
Da.
We've met before.
I don't think so.
I would have remembered.
In a bar.
We both had too much to drink.
And we screwed our brains out.
You couldn't get enough of me.
And you?
I came and went.
I don't know anything
about a hit.
If I did, I'd tell you, baby.
Scout's honor.
We both know that's not true.
You're gonna lose this war.
You know that, right?
You can torture me...
And you can kill me...
but we're gonna kick
your motherland's marbled ass,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
He's en route.
Okay. We're good to go.
Stand by.
Where's Arkady?
Abort.
Abort!
Grab him.
Our orders are to stand down.
To hell with that.
Grab him now.
What?!
Just keep your mouth shut.
Move, move.
God damn it, Beeman.
What the hell
did you think you were doing?
They got my partner.
What would you have done?
Go on.
We'll get into this later.
Uncuff him.
And his mouth.
Do you Hunt?
I don't understand.
Do you Hunt...
you know, shoot.
Kill things... animals.
No.
When you shoot a bird...
duck or pheasant, say...
your dog, your retriever,
picks it up in its mouth...
its soft mouth.
Soft mouth is key...
otherwise, the dog sinks his
teeth into the bird's flesh.
Anyway
your dog brings it to you
and lays it at your feet.
But sometimes,
when you shoot the bird,
it's not dead.
It's just wounded.
Strange thing is,
whether the bird
is dead or just wounded,
once the dog
gets it in its mouth,
the bird goes limp.
Like a rag... doesn't move.
It acts like it's dead.
Doesn't struggle or scream.
It just... Goes limp.
Don't you think that's strange?
You know what I think it is?
Fear.
The bird's scared
out of its goddamn mind.
Who wouldn't be? I know I would.
Then again,
maybe the bird is faking.
You know what I'm saying?
Maybe it wants you...
talking about the bird now...
to think it's dead
so when the dog
drops it out of its soft mouth
at its master's feet,
it can take off.
It works sometimes.
You wouldn't think it does,
but it does.
Not a lot.
Once in a blue moon.
Please, I swear...
I'm not KGB.
I don't know anything.
Please... I swear.
You're scared. I know.
I would be, too,
because I've got you
in my soft mouth,
and you're not dead... not yet.
Maybe you think you can run
when I drop you
at my master's feet.
Maybe you can. Maybe you will.
But the thing is,
you have my partner.
If you don't
tell me where he is,
you will never get dropped
at my master's feet.
My bite will go hard,
and you will know you are dead
before
your heart stops beating.
Please, please,
I swear, I'm a diplomat.
I don't know.
Please.
I need morphine.
You'll get morphine
when you tell me
what I need to know.
What time is it?
It's after 5:00.
Arkady.
What?
The Rezident is the target.
Too late.
He's already dead.
Soviet embassy. May I help you?
I need to talk to
the head of cultural affairs.
What is this in reference to?
I have information
about Vladimir Kosygin.
One minute, please.
Hello?
To whom am I speaking?
I have him.
Your man. Vlad.
He's nobody.
He has nothing for you.
Well, that's probably true.
So, then, let him go.
Well,
it doesn't work like that.
Tell me, how does it work?
Amador... release him.
This man...
I do not know.
Listen to me.
Listen very carefully.
I'm listening.
If anything happens to amador,
vlad is dead.
I will personally
send you his balls
To wear around your neck
at your next may day parade.
_
Hello.
Hello!
- Arkady?
- Yes.
Arkady is alive and well.
- How do you know?
- I called the Rezidentura, I spoke to him.
- So we need to contact Grannie.
- I did.
She said there was a different target.
Vladimir Kosygin,
a first-tour officer.
Went out for a run,
never came back.
What I don't understand is why.
Why would amador lie
about Arkady being the target?
He fingers
the head of directorate "s"
To protect
a first-tour officer?
It doesn't make any sense.
He's playing us.
He's hiding something else.
What are you gonna do?
Whatever it takes to get him to talk.
I'll do it.
I didn't want this to happen,
but it happened.
Things just got a little crazy,
you know?
Yeah.
I wouldn't let a dog suffer like this.
Would you?
No.
After he talks
give him the morphine.
Just let him drift off.
All right, Chris. No more time.
We need to know what you're holding back,
and we need to know n...
Goddamn it.
I'm gonna pull every Agent.
This will be the top priority.
It's family.
How did he die?
Slowly... he was stabbed.
He was dead before they
dumped him here.
What's strange is, that whoever did it
then took the trouble
to try and save him.
It's probably to late
to exfiltrate your girl
in the Rezidentura.
Amador didn't give her up.
Everybody talks, it's biology.
He didn't give her up.
Gonna risk her life on that?
And mine.
Vietnam
turn you into a skirt chaser?
I was straight as an arrow
when I signed up.
Was an altar boy `til I was seventeen.
- Really?
- Yeah.
`Nam changed things.
It was crazy shit over there.
You never knew when your number
was gonna be called.
I learned two things,
One, Tempus Fugit...
"time flies."
One way or the other,
you snatch it,
or it's gonna snatch you.
There's no pause button.
And, two...
there are worse things than dying.
- Like?
- Shame.
Shame is not an option for me.
I don't understand
How that has anything to do
with you chasing pussy.
[ Laughs )
Pussy is a thing,
and it's not a thing Stan.
It's real and it's not.
It's a metaphor.
For what?
The whole enchilada.
- Thank you.
- Mhmm.
What are you going to do?
Eat.
Enjoy.
So you're KGB right?
Come on we both know it's true,
I just wanna hear it.
Yes.
But I don't know anything.
I believe you.
That's good huh?
Mm, nothing beats American fast food.
It's probably filled with all kinds
of nasty shit that'll kill you, but man...
it sure taste good.
*** a drink?
Yes please.
Think I have a Cola here.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com