Who is it?
- What's going on?- My cat...
give her back.
If Bok Gil were really Haru, then I
think I could really sleep comfortably.
If we do a DNA test with Haru's fur and
Bok Gil's fur, we will be able to know.
Can I really do this?
If we do the DNA test, we can
find out if Bok Gil is Haru.
Don't appear in front of me ever again.
You submitted only your name to the
competition, and you have nothing to say?
Do you have proof? Do you have
proof that it's really yours?!
I don't need a friend like you.
The collar I made Haru is a one-of-a-kind.
The fact that Bok Gil has
it on doesn't make sense.
You anticipated that. Why
don't we go check it out.
The test results are out.
Bok Gil is not Haru.
I think I'll be able to
sleep really well tonight.
If Jong Hyeon knows that Bok Gil is
Haru, won't he probably hate me?
It looks as though Bok
Gil was Haru after all.
Do you want to see Bok Gil?
Episode 7Bok Gil, open your eyes.
Listen to me carefully.
Bok Gil.
Bok Gil, you're listening to me, right?
You are... mmm... Bok Gil,
but Haru at the same time.
Ah, I'm sleepy.
I can't tell if this world has
really gotten better or not.
Even a cat can get a DNA test.
You were too young, so you
probably don't remember.
The fact that you are Haru has
been proven scientifically.
Stop talking nonsense and go away.
After losing you, Na Woo has not been
able to have a comfortable night's sleep.
So, Na Woo will be coming to visit you
once in a while. Do you understand?
Okay? Why do you keep on calling me Haru?
Are you talking in your sleep?
She must be here.
Hi!
What? She's here again?
♪13: The One in My Heart Is You.
Bok Gil.
Let me go. Let me go!
You wanted to do this so badly?
Giving Haru a bath was my wish.
I don't like taking baths! Don't touch me!
Cover Bok Gil's ears.
Hey, Bok Gil hates bath,
so let's do it quickly.
No. You have to do it thoroughly.
So, you both are going to
keep doing this? Move!
Ah! Hurry! Hurry!
Bok Gil!
You're all wet!
Hey, you dry off first.
I'll bring you something to change into.
Ah, I-I'll do it.
Bok Gil, Unni brought you presents.
Hey, what's that?
What else? Presents for Bok Gil.
Ah, that's enough. Enough, enough.
Why? Bok Gil likes it too.
We can only accept one item from that box.
Just one?
Why don't we take the rest
to the animal shelter.
I wanted to do all the things I
couldn't do during the past 7 years.
You don't have to do that. There's plenty
of time to do things in the future.
And, this may be Bok Gil's house,
but it's also my space as well.
You're right. I can't just bring in anything
I want to someone else's home. Sorry.
- Especially, there.- The desk?
When I'm working, never,
ever touch anything.
I didn't even think that things could get
uncomfortable because of me. Sorry for that too.
Haru. Bok Gil.
Since you brought me toys,
I will let it slide.
Hold me as much as you want.
Ah, please! Seriously!
Wait, you're saying Bok Gil
was really Na Woo's cat?
Yeah.
To think that Bok Gil had that
kind of a birth secret story.
It's so touching.
Hey, then, are you dating Na Woo now?
Ah, seriously!
Think however you want.
Well, anyway, it's not like
you have time to even date.
This is an important time in your life since it's
all about whether you get to make a debut or not.
It looks like it's going to be you anyway. Jin Seong
isn't good enough to be competition with you.
He got first place for our
bookstore's bestseller.
Really?
Forget it. Let's go to church.
Church? Why?
You only go during Christmas because the
pretty girls give you good food to eat.
We should pray in the name of the
Father, Son, and The Holy Spirit.
The company said they are
making their decision tomorrow.
My baby...
Editor Dokgo said that she'll be supporting
yours, so we have one supporter for sure.
For the rest, we can just pray about it.
Hey, live nicely every day.
Don't get in trouble with God for going
to him only when you are like this.
This is not the time for
you to be so relaxed.
You don't want to lobby. You don't want
to pray. Then what are you going to do?
I better get to work.
Hey, how can you work in this situation?
You can't even debut, and you have tons of stacked up
drawings to do. Are you going to make origami or what?
Hey! Every time I am talking to you...
Am I a person that has to
always look at your back, huh?
Ah, they are still contacting me.
It's already so late...
Oh, oh!
What are you doing during work hours, Mr.
Part-Timer?
Manager, please give that back.
I'm supposed to get an
important call today. Please.
What is most important to you, Mr.
Part-Timer?
Customer Service.
No. It's your superior's command. Until
you get off I will be holding on to this.
Go on.
Princess Heo's number has
to be in here for sure.
I will try 100,00 times
and certainly find it.
100,000 times.
7224, 7225
Bok Gil's flower has bloomed.
You're playing well all by yourself.
Bok Gil's flower has bloomed!
What... you don't feel
like playing right now?
Human, send her away. She's annoying.
Then, should I get you some snacks?
There's no water.
Jong Hyeon, do you have any water?
I'll go buy some.
Where are you going?
Don't leave me alone with this girl.
I don't want it!
Bok Gil. Play well.
Should we play, just the two of us?
Ah! Don't come any closer.
No! If you go up there,
Jong Hyeon will get mad!
I'll do what I want.
Aiyoo, seriously. Get down.
It looks fine.
Ooh, it's good.
Oh. Hey, hey.
What are you doing?
Oh, the thing is...
I told you not to touch my things!
I didn't look at it because I wanted to.
I went to get Bok Gil and saw it.
But, it was so interesting.
That's enough now. Leave.
Aren't you going?
What did I do that was so wrong? You said I
could come over to take care of Bok Gil.
I also told you not to touch my things!
Did I do it on purpose?
While you when to buy water, Bok Gil went on your desk.
I was trying to stop her and I saw your drawings.
Then, was I supposed to keep my eyes closed? Have
you been like this towards Bok Gil all these years?
What?
You seem to be feeling extra sensitive because you
are working. I'll take Bok Gil with me to the cafe.
What the heck are you doing?
Lately, Bok Gil has not been eating well and she's
not doing well. But you want to take her with you?
Are you in your right mind? If you are
going to do this, don't ever come back!
You're really mean!
Yes, Editor.
Jong Hyeon, I think we have to
meet tomorrow. Do you have time?
What is this about?
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Sit down.
Ah, seriously.
Oh, you awesome kid! I
knew you could do it!
- I think your prayers worked.
- Whatever.
Prayer no prayer, when it's
meant to be it will happen.
I told you, you were
going to make it right?
Thanks.
Writer Hyeon Jong Hyeon.
You must be feeling great!
Next, it's your turn.
I decided to just help out my
father's gas station business.
What do you mean? What about drawing?
Not all dreams come true.
Hey! You haven't even tried that long. Just
keep trying for a little longer. If you do...
Yeah, I was thinking the same thing.
But I know myself too well.
I have no talent.
Are you confident you won't regret it?
No, but is there anything in life
you can guarantee you won't regret?
Sometimes you give up, you regret
at times, and that's just life.
When I was in high school, I really
loved going to the art studio.
You were there, Soo In was there too.
Back then, I loved drawing.
It was good... crazy good.
But now, one of us is no
longer in this world,
the other has given up. Now
there's just you left.
Hey, you know you have to succeed
enough for me and Soo Im.
Writer Hyeon Jong Hyeon, fighting!
Aigoo. It fell.
Should I go down?
Soo In isn't in this world anymore, punk.
♪There is only a faint glimmer ♪
It's all done.
Your drawings are really
good.♪ Strewn on the path ♪<
I like you.
I... don't seem to know anything about you though.
♪ The faint glimmer I caught is slipping away ♪
♪like the path to a rainbow ♪
But still... you liked me.♪ Somewhere it's waiting
for me but even though I look, I can't find it. ♪
Back then, why couldn't I tell her?
♪ Darling, be strong. ♪
That I liked her. ♪ The path
which was given to me ♪
♪ So that you can find the path given to
me ♪ subtitles ripped and synced by riri13
♪ Darling lead me to the path. ♪
Oh my joints... from jumping
off that measly height.
Human, take a look at me. My leg hurts.
Miss Bok Gil.
Just because you are doing this, you
think I'm going to forgive you?
Coming home late meant
you came home late
- Bok Gil.- Hm?
I finally am able to make
my debut, but why... why...
Why am I...? Why?
Why?
Human.
Do you think I'm here because I want to see you,
Jong Hyeon? I'm here because I want to see Bok Gil.
Fine, I did wrong! So forgive me.
No. I'm sorry. Please forgive
me just this once, huh?
Who told you to make your
drawing so interesting anyway!
Fine, let's do this.
What's going on today? My cushion is
staying here for a very long time.
It feels much warmer than normal.
I like it.
- Bok Gil.- Huh?
Human, what's wrong? Why are you so weak?
- You're hungry, right?- No.
You're sick, aren't you? How sick are you?
I'll get you food. Hold on.
No, just stay here. I'm not
here and I don't have to poop.
Just stay still.
I'm fine.
I'm sorry, Bok Gil.
It's fine, it's fine. Huh?
I'll get it for you later.
Yeah, I can wait.
This is a big problem.
Huh?
Excuse me? Is there someone there?
Please help my human. Okay?
Jong Hyeon.
That's a relief.
That girl. I guess she can be useful.
Jong Hyeon, what is it?
Should I get you water?
Soo In.
♪14 Goodbye, and Hi
- You're up?- Why are you here?
You don't remember yesterday?
Jong Hyeon.
Ah, that was you.
Your fever's gone down.
It was serious last night.
You had a fever, broke out in
a sweat, and mumbled a lot.
Mumbled?
You were calling for someone.
For Soo In.
I did?
Who is Soo In?
You didn't have to do all this.
I'm really sorry.
I think I'm okay now, so...
I should go?
No, just...
I made you some porridge. Can't I stay
until after I see you eating some of it?
I'll eat it later. I have an
appointment to go to today.
You are so stubborn.
Excuse me...
Thank you.
If you know, then it's fine.
- Miss Bok Gil. You were
surprised, right?- Yeah.
- Don't get sick again.- I understand.
I'm sorry. I won't get sick again, Bok Gil.
- Where are you coming from?- Huh?
Gong Ju seemed very angry.
Really?
I should just go home.
You're coughing.
My throat feels a bit scratchy.
I know that once you start
coughing, it lasts a while.
If Gong Ju find out, she going
to send me back to Jejoodo.
Where did you go?
- Were you with Bok Gil again?- Yeah.
With that person?
Jong Hyeon was really sick,
so there was nothing...
But you... why do have to take care of him?
Let's go to the hospital.
I'm okay.
I'm not okay.
PLUS Webtoon Contents
Congratulations Writer Hyeon. I
knew you were going to make it.
Thank you.
From now on, you are going to hate me.
That's how much I'm going
to be pushing you.
You do know about my
evil reputation, right?
You better prepare yourself.
Yes. I'm confident I'll be able to do well.
Up to now, it's been practice. The
real work will be starting now.
So going forward...
Editor Dokgo.
How can I help you Writer Park?
Exactly, what happened here?
Hyeon Jong Hyeon, rather
than I, was selected?
Does this make any sense?
What doesn't make sense?
How could I...?
How can I lose to an amateur like him?
Writer Park. I didn't want
to have to tell you this...
The vote was 8 to 3.
Jong Hyeon was the front runner.
It doesn't make sense.
Hyeon Jong Hyeon
You guys will regret this.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Here.
Do you have something
you want to say to me?
No.
You told me last time you're
working on a webcomic.
How did that go?
Oh that? I signed the contract today.
Contract? Then your book should
be coming out in no time.
Well, I'm not sure...
With Writer Park, the webtoon...
Once the webtoon is a hit, the
book comes out shortly thereafter.
Yes, that usually is how things work.
Do you have any issues
working part-time here?
Do you know why I've always spoken to
you with honorifics, Mr. Part Timer?
Ah! That's why you asked
for time off that time.
Then you should have told me more clearly in
detail. I defintiely would have let you go.
- Oh, what is it?- My arm, my arm.
- Ah, this too.- Ah, this.
Would you like to take a vacation day?
A day? Two? Or indefinitely?
No... I mean, I can give you
as many days as you need.
Well, that would be great for me.
I was needing more time to write.
You know, I have an amazing item.
It is such an entertaining story.
A dog is the main character.
But the dog can speak it's thoughts.
What do you think?
Bok Gil, look.
It's not enough with just the grooming.
Cats need baths.
See, you have to take a bath!
No, I hate taking a bath.
Here.
Is this cats cafe's concept is camping?
You want to go?
Yeah, it looks fun.
- Wow, it looks nice.- Ohhh.
It looks nice.
Ah, hey, let go, let go.
What are you going to buy me?
What? Buy what? You should pay.
Wow you are something.
Noonim, give us two of your
most expensive coffee.
I don't see Na Woo today.
Is she busy preparing for her exhibition?
Have you told Na Woo? She
would be so excited for you.
Later. I can just tell her later.
Wow. If Soo In found out you
debuted, she would be ecstatic.
I wish I could have been there.
What did Jin Seong's face look like?
He was totally frustrated, right?
Regardless, he always has
that frustrated look.
He must have looked even more frustrated.
Tell me more specifically.
How many times do I need to
tell you that he just went out.
How can you lack descriptive
ability being a webtoon writer?
Look... He'd say, "No way, that can't
be"... with his nostrils flaring.
Stop it. Stop it Yook Hae Gong.
Look like something really
exciting has happened.
Of course! It's the best day
for Writer Hyeon Jong Hyeon.
- Is that so?- Yes.
I've tried to be patient, but
listen here Mr. Hyeon Jong Hyeon!
W-what?
Because she took care of you all night,
do you know she had to go to the ER?
The ER?
What? Sick?
Who? Na Woo took care of you?
You were sick, punk?
You! Please shut your mouth.
Excuse me, is Na Woo really sick?
If you don't see someone, should you
be concerned about their health first?
How can you be so cruel to someone
who took care of you all night!
I-I-I'm sorry.
Is Na Woo at the hospital right now?
She was released.
Do you know that Na Woo used to be
very sick when she was a child?
I heard.
Can I perhaps meet with Na Woo now?
Forget it.
I should have stopped her when she was
following you around like a lost puppy.
So upsetting.
What are we going to do? It looks
like Na Woo is really sick.
What the heck are you doing?
Lately, Bok Gil has not been eating well and she's
not doing well. But you want to take her with you?
You. If you're going to be like
this, don't come here again.
You're really mean!
Because she took care of you all night,
do you know she had to go to the ER?
Oh Na Woo
Who are you thinking about?
Soo In.
I'm a little jealous.
Rather than me, you're
thinking of a different girl.
It's not like that.
You look good.
Me?
You laugh a lot more than before. And
you know how to care for someone.
It's a relief that you aren't alone now.
I'm sorry.
For sending you off like that.
No, I'm sorry. For leaving like that.
Soo In.
Right now, you have someone
you're worrying about, right?
You are curious about her
because you miss her.
Call her. Hurry.
Oh Na Woo
Jong Hyeon. Jong Hyeon. Hello?
Hey, if you called, then talk!
Jong Hyeon, where are you right now?
♪ After a tiring day has passed two people
in the moonlight form a single shadow♪
- Did you run here again?  - I
thought you might just leave.
I told you we can see each other tomorrow.
No, my cold's gone. It's really gone.
♪ Happiness that seems reachable
is still faintly there ♪
♪ But your sorrowful heart ♪
I'm okay though. ♪ casts a
shadow even over your dream ♪
When you are healed from your cold,.
♪ Remember so that even if it hurts, ♪
let's go ride our bicycles. ♪ will
be next to the one who loves you. ♪
- How much are you planning on yelling at me
this time? - Forget it if you don't like it.
No... teach me.
Okay then.  ♪ Sometimes, even if
the path appears too far away ♪
It's been a long time since I've ridden this. It's fun.
even if within your sad heart you are shedding tears,
♪ even if within your mournful
heart you are shedding tears, ♪
Miss Bok Gil, I'm here.
Bok Gil. Miss Bok Gil.
Where did she go now?
Miss Bok Gil, are you there?
Bok Gil...
Bok Gil! What's wrong with you?
Bok Gil! Bok Gil! What's wrong with you?
- Bok Gil!- Human.
What's wrong with me?
♪ open your eyes and shout ♪
This is totally awesome.
Congratulations, writer Hyeon Jong Hyeon.
Thank you.
I saw "A Beautiful Mind."
- And what... - It was fun.
Thank you for all this time.
If you're really thankful,
To the goddess, try to package me nicely...
Are you the next story?.
Bok Gil, you must be so happy because
there are so many people who love you.
Each and every day...
is precious.
Miss Bok Gil, should we start?
Are they real stars?
Endure it just a bit longer!
You're a veterinarian.
Surgery...
Please do it.