Subtitles brought to you by The Scandalous Team @ Viki
I'll go pick you up so whether you'll come out or not, it's Soo Y...
Yesterday, weren't you very much surprised?
From now on, even if you trail me,
you cannot murder anymore, Secretary Kim Joong Yeop.
You won't report me, will you?
Ha Soo Yeong
Ha Soo Yeong, answer the phone.
Answer the phone.
Why did you call?
There's no way you're already here.
I was just curious about what you were doing.
What were you doing?
I was debating whether to go out or not.
I don't think so.
I think you're putting make up on.
What do you mean by make up?
I haven't decided yet if I'll go camping or not.
Oh yes! Your brother, what kind of person is he?
I hear he was a detective.
Why my brother, all of a sudden?
Just because.
So later, if I happen to meet your brother,
I was curious if your brother would like me.
Well, the guys his little sister will meet
will be thieves and bad guys,
and he will treat them as criminals,
so avoiding him will be your best solution.
Father, please answer.
Please answer, Dad.
Eun Joong
Dad...
We have arrived.
I'm a detective from Jongro Precinct.
I just lost a suspect before my eyes.
I ask for your cooperation.
Well... how...
Hurry, there's no time.
I am sorry.
Episode 34
Dad!
I ...am going camping with my friend.
How many of you are going?
F.. four!
The kids I hung out with in high school, you remember.
Hey.
Take these cucumbers and tomatoes.
This batch is a real killer.
I'll pack you some, so share them with your friends.
The cucumber eaten there is honey. A real honey.
Go and have lots of fun.
Play as much as you can.
Play with no regrets.
Next time, I'll go with you, Dad.
For real.
For real, I promise.
Your glasses?
Ah, I put them on or off depending on how I feel.
You look different.
Like a different person.
Really! I am the same person.
Ha Eun Joong
Ha Eun Joong?
Who is he?
He's my brother.
For now, I'm confiscating it.
Because after you answer his call and say you won't go, it won't be good.
Then, shall we leave?
♫ These days I'm All Right, Even if you leave All Right, ♫
♫ A Breakup, All Right ♫
♫ Your thoughts, All Right, You're to me, Delight, ♫
♫ These days I'm All Right, Even if you leave All Right, ♫
♫ A Breakup, All Right ♫
♫ Your thoughts, All Right, You're to me, Delight, ♫
♫ In the fog, Some Light. ♫
♫ It's just this, Everything of mine you owned ♫
♫ What you didn't have was just this. ♫
♫ Your worry-filled last good-bye ♫
♫ You're not all that, I'm All Right. ♫
♫ All Right. ♫
♫ Don't assume, Don't worry. ♫
♫ Don't even ask how I am doing.
The plaintiff's witness Kim Sung Hoon, is he absent?
Yes, he will be absent, Your Honor.
Your Honor,
I, the Plaintiff, Yoon Hwa Yeong, hereby
am terminating Attorney Koo Jae In.
Here is my request for withdrawal of the designated attorney.
You've prepared ahead?
Because you didn't trust me?
Get out.
Written Promise
Good bye.
Then when would be a good date for the next hearing?
You will need time to look for your new representing attorney.
No.
From now on, I will carry out my own proceeding, Your Honor.
Your motion is accepted.
Then, let's continue with the proceedings.
Wait a minute!
Then, me too.
I am going to fire my lawyer.
Then as a new lawyer,
I am going to appoint Attorney Koo Jae In.
Ha Soo Yeong!
Hey, Eun Joong!
Ah... I...
Soo Yeong! Where is Soo Yeong, Dad?
Huh? She went camping with her friends.
She'll be back tomorrow.
Oh!
What's wrong? What about Soo Yeong?
Why is your expression heavy like lead?
What's going on?
Oh...
It's nothing. We were going to meet and the punk stood me up.
Then, she was supposed to meet you
but went camping instead?
Seems like it.
She may still be mad at me.
That kid...
To maintain a marriage, both the husband and wife
have to put in effort and make sacrifices.
The Plaintiff, Yoon Hwa Yeong, claims that she has made
endless sacrifices during her marriage, but
what exactly did you sacrifice?
When your biological son got kidnapped, to ensure inheritance of the estate,
you took an innocent orphan.
You lied that he was your biological son, and you put him in his place.
Is this what you call "sacrifice"?
Or, was planning with your son's kidnapper,
and turning your back on the husband
whom you lived with for 30 years,
using the press conference as a violent and malicious method
to expose him to the world.
Is this what you call "sacrifice"?
Did you even once during the 30 years,
with sincerity,
with love,
think of your husband as your husband?
Without doing anything, without putting in any effort,
you always just looked blankly at the far away mountains.
Yet, you claim that the fault for divorce lies entirely with the Defendant.
The Plaintiff is being ridiculously arrogant and selfish to make such a claim.
I'll ask you again.
Plaintiff, for the past 30 years,
what did you do?
Was it sacrifice?
Or was it revenge?
Plaintiff, please answer.
Before the Defendant, Jang Tae Ha, got married,
he already had a woman, and
he even had a child.
He maintained this relationship with them for 30 years.
According to Civil Law...
Chapter 840, Section 1,
a marriage partner's cheating...
can be considered as a grave reason for divorce, Judge.
Isn't that child legally your daughter?
According to the paperwork, she had been legally
added to your family record in 1992.
According to Civil Law, Chapter 840, Section 2,
after 6 months of discovering or forgiving the partner's cheating,
or after 2 years since the date of cheating,
a suit for divorce cannot be filed.
Don't you know this?
If so,
then let's discuss Civil Law, Chapter 840, Section 3,
which outlines the mistreatment of marriage partners.
The Defendant, Jang Tae Ha,
gave me medication for schizophrenia, and he faked a doctor's diagnosis
to make me a legally incompetent person.
Thanks to him, I lost my legal license.
That's an outrageous claim made by the Plaintiff,
and there is no proof of it, Your Honor.
Then, I'll begin proving it, now.
Instead of the witness who failed to appear today,
in place of Dr. Kim Seong Hoon,
I request to bring a new witness, whom the Defendant, Jang Tae Ha has been maintaining an affair with for 30 years.
I request to bring Ms. Go Seok Bong as a new witness.
W- who? Go Seok... Bong?
Hey, did you find them?
Soo Yeong's phone has been turned off, and Kim Joong Yeop's current location...
looks like he is moving from Paldang and heading in the direction of Yangpyeong.
That means he's headed somewhere near Yangpyeong or Namyangju.
Call the car rental companies in Seoul, and find out what car
was rented by a Kim Joong Yeop born in 1981.
Put out an arrest warrant with the rental car's make and model,
and keep me updated on his location.
Sunbaenim, you know that if I get caught doing this, I'll be suspended, right?
Jang Tae Ha is trying to kill me.
Please help me.
Please get me out of here.
Jang Tae Ha...
Jang Tae Ha is trying to kill me.
Please help me.
At that time, how was my condition?
Frankly, you were a crazy person...
You were a crazy woman.
You were a woman whose consciousness was paralyzed... I mean,
your arms and legs were paralyzed, so you couldn't stand,
and you were crawling on the floor.
I have an objection, Your Honor.
The Witness is not a medical doctor.
Also, when you look at the video, there is no proof
that the Defendant drugged the Plaintiff.
It can't be considered as direct evidence.
That video could have been falsely produced by the
Plaintiff and the Witness, under conspiracy.
Taking such a recording and holding onto it is proof of that!
What else could it be?
Hey!
The conspiracy was between you and me!
Between you and me!
What conspiracy would I have created with Yoon Hwa Yeong?
Do you know why I'm here?
I'm here, thanks to you!
Witness, please calm down.
Okay.
I will try to solidify the evidence in a few moments.
I will call forth the husband and wife custodians and ask them further questions.
In the list of witnesses, only the husband's name is on there.
However, the wife who was forced, under unfortunate circumstances, to drug me...
She is here at this court, in place of her husband.
Ms. Go Seok Bong.
Please call me Go Joo Ran.
Okay.
Ms. Go Joo Ran.
- Yes?
The world calls us as the wife and mistress.
It may be hard to believe, but for 30 years
we have lived that way, at times together, at times separately.
You, the Witness...
Why didn't you leave the Defendant, Jang Tae Ha?
Did you love the Defendant so much... that you
were willing to endure this situation for 30 years?
It wasn't because of Jang Tae Ha.
It was because I loved my daughter.
It was because I loved Jang Tae Ha's money, not Jang Tae Ha.
I wanted my daughter to inherit Jang Tae Ha's money.
If he didn't have money-
- I would have left him already.
I would have left him 30 years ago.
He has the personality of a dog, is self-centered,
and he is worth nothing as a man, nothing as a person.
Also, as a husband...
and as a father, he is worth zilch, nothing!
If he didn't have money, why would I stay by a man like him?
Ms. Yoon Hwa Yeong, you're still by his side because of the money, too.
Does Jang Tae Ha have anyone by his side who's not there for the money?
Everyone is gathered around him, because of his money.
Because he knows that, he tries so hard to grip onto his money, and
he tries hard not to have his money stolen from him.
I'm just like them.
To get back my father's inheritance that Jang Tae Ha stole...
To get it back and to give it to my son...
I have endured (this marriage) for 30 years.
If I endure this for 5 more years...
If I endure this for 10 more years, then...
there is a possibility that my son could inherit the Defendant's estate.
My son might one day inherit all of his estate.
However, now...
I am unable to endure any more,
not even one more day, Your Honor.
For me to endure further...
Today,
tomorrow, and...
every day has become too valuable to me.
As of now, I want to live everyday to the fullest.
Divorce...
Please allow it, Your Honor.
I feel sorry for the times that have wasted by...
I'll be sure to live my life to the fullest.
I'll give myself another chance at living again.
Dad gave this for us to eat.
He planted this himself. He said it tastes as good as honey.
Then, should we peel some honey and try it?
Why do you have a knife in your back pocket?
When you come to place like this, a knife has many uses.
Wow, it's really like honey!
- Right?
It's definitely different from the ones you purchase, right?
Here, should we grill the meat now?
Let's do that.
Mr. Driver! Why do you drive like that?!
Oh, Sunbaenim!
W- why did you drive a taxi?
Are you sure this is the place?
We traced his movements from Namyangju, and he ended up here.
Kim Joong Yeop's current location is found to be at...
Yongin-si, Cheoin-gu, Baekam-myeon, Yongcheon-ri, 778-15.
Even if we take into consideration an error in radius of 1.5 Kilometers, this place...
I'm sure that this camping site is the right place.
Does he have any record of past offenses?
He was arrested for murder, but due to insufficient evidence,
he was determined to be innocent.
At the age of 16, he already had a past offense in 3rd degree burglary.
After the age of 20,
he had a record of fraud and assault.
Let's go.
We must find Soo Yeong.
Woo Cheol, we need to find Soo Yeong.
We'll find her. Really.
Be careful. He knows how to use a knife.
How's the wine?
I don't really know.
I just think that wine tastes like wine.
I've only drank so-mec (soju+beer) and makgeolli (Korean wheat/rice wine).
I haven't had much exposure to wine.
It's the wine that Earnest Hemingway,
the author of "The Old Man and the Sea" and "Resurrection", loved.
He even named his granddaughter Margaux,
(after the wine, Chateau Margaux)
so that tells you how much he loved wine.
But "Resurrection" was written by Tolstoy, the old man who's famous for his quotes.
"Like the fruit that comes from a seed,
actions come from thoughts."
"Everyone thinks of changing the world, but..."
"no one thinks of changing himself."
"He who loves is alive."
I don't know why I wrote and memorized these things.
I'm sorry.
Just a moment, Joong Yeop.
How about we just listen to some music?
Are you all that great?
Is your dad, your brother... all that great?
What are you saying?
Do I look funny to you?
Oppa! Oppa!
Oppa, what are you doing?
Oppa!
J- Joong Yeop...
Sunbaenim, that's enough!
Let me go, let me go!
That's enough!
Sunbaenim, that's enough.
Cuff him.
- What?
Even so, handcuffs seem like too much.
This guy is the person who murdered Chief Song Jae Moon.
What?
A murderer?
Cuff him, quickly!
Okay.
Before you hand me to the police, how about you call your father?
I was following the Chairman's orders.
Song Jae Moon, and even your younger sister!
It wasn't my idea. It was your father's!
I'm not like Kang Ho hyung-nim. I'm not going to take the blame alone.
Fine.
But now that I think about it,
I have one more thing left to do.
I need to pay my respects to Chief Song Jae Moon.
Hand this over to the evidence team.
Okay.
Take him in.
Yes.
You didn't make any mistakes, and...
you didn't do anything wrong.
It's not your fault.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry, Soo Yeong.
It's okay.
It's okay, Soo Yeong.
It's okay, it's okay.
It was nothing.
[Seoul District Court, Witness Subpoena]
[Murder of Gong Ki Chan, Murder of Song Jae Moon]
[Regarding the above-mentioned case of murder instigation,
the court asks for your presence for questioning.]
I figured that you were stopping all of the police
and prosecutors from handling this case, so...
I went directly to Seo Joon Yeong, the Seoul District Attorney,
and asked him to take this case.
Father, go with me and turn yourself in.
Instigating the murder of Gong Ki Chang and Chief Song Jae Moon...
Go with me and turn yourself in.
Your Honor, I the Plaintiff, Yoon Hwa Yeong, hereby
am terminating Attorney Koo Jae In.
Goodbye.
Eun Joong, it's Mom.
Yes, it's me, Mom.
What were you doing when you took this call?
Are you at Sajik-dong?
How about dinner? Did you eat?
Did the trial go well?
Yes, I think I'll win.
You worked hard on it.
I hope that you'll be able to rest comfortably soon.
When it ends, when all of this ends, everything will get easy, right?
I heard that District Attorney Seo sent out a subpoena to you as well.
You're going in tomorrow, right?
Yes.
He says that all the police records have been destroyed,
and that there isn't even a trace of evidence.
Ah Mi said that you might have the investigation records, and...
she said that you did a re-investigation on your own.
So, I told District Attorney Seo that...
you might have the investigation records.
I have them.
Eun Joong,
turn them in tomorrow. Be sure to turn them in.
I'm in front of the house. I was going to leave, but I'll come in.
Ha Soo Yeong.
If you're not going to get out, I'm going to carry you out.
Starting from where
did things go wrong? Oppa.
Was it started from my father?
Or was it started from your father?
We have to continue to live like this, right?
Butterfly
I found the video so you can just learn through watching this.
They said, it depends on how you practice.
Butterfly.
Fly
to here.
Yellow butterfly.
White butterfly.
Dance
and come here.
Wow. Genius. Genius!
It hurts.
Kids came.
Ah.
What happened? Why is your hand injured?
Guitar was yours?
Yeah. Ah Mi said to learn so..
You said you're coming back tomorrow.
What happened?
Your clothes are a mess, and the wounds on your hand.
Soo Yeong seemed abstracted. What happened?
Why is it like this?
I'll do it for you.
He's a murderer.
- Yeah.
- Jang Tae Ha.
That person ordered him to do it.
From your Oppa..
I heard.
Without knowing that, I...
If Oppa didn't come, I...
Today, I...
It will pass.
Everything will pass.
Let's believe it like that, Soo Yeong.
What should we do about Oppa?
Ah Mi, Oppa apologized to me.
He said, he's sorry. He's really sorry.
That stupid person is apologizing to me, Ah Mi.
He'll probably live his whole life apologizing to me, right?
Everyday, he'll probably live with guilt, right?
Instead of that person Jang Tae Ha,
he'll live by saying sorry to other people.
Do you think there's a way to save Oppa, Ah Mi?
My Oppa's shackles..
Is there really no way to release him from that, Ah Mi?
If we want to end this,
if we don't want to repeat the same things over again,
if we don't want to commit any more sins,
we have no choice but to put your father in jail.
He's not a person who could change.
He thinks of himself as at the same level of a Joseon Dynasty King.
He thinks that he is the law and he is the Republic of Korea.
This might be too cruel for you,
but we have to make your father be punished.
Investigation record.. and testify to everything that you know.
Including what happened today.
If not,
Soo Yeong and Ah Mi will continue to be in danger.
Okay, all done.
Is this the only one you want opened?
Yes. I only locked there, but I lost my key so...
Oh, how much is it?
Give me just 30,000 won.
Thank you. You can go now.
You're working hard this late.
Take care.
Case No. 2013-005941 Gong Gi Chan murder case disguised as death from a fall.
Death Certificate
I want to say goodbye before I go.
Thanks for the guitar.
Father's performance was shocking, but
Ah Mi's singing was even more shocking.
In my whole life, it's the first time listening to such a sad butterfly.
Sleep well.
On that shoulder, on that back,
and on your mind that is loaded with burden,
if there's also me,
put mine down.
I'll take mine.
Don't be sorry to me.
Don't try hard to apologize in your father's place.
Can you drive?
Drive? Why all of sudden?
You have a driver's license, right?
Yes.
The distance is not that far, so can you drive to Jongro?
♫ I'm really tired now...♫
♫ I got tired waiting for you...♫
♫ This heart that lives alone is too...♫
♫ The image of you turning your back on me so coldly ♫
♫ though it may not appear awkward, ♫
♫ I can't believe that this is the last. ♫
♫ To where, my love ♫
♫ Even though I don't know why you're trying to leave ♫
♫ at least don't erase our memory. ♫
♫ because it will be a dream that lasts forever to me. ♫
♫ I'm imploring you like this. ♫
♫ My shining eyes which smiled ♫
♫ My whispers which were sweet ♫
♫ and the past we've had together, have you forgotten? ♫
♫ I make a wish that you may return. ♫
♫ I wish everyday that you'd return to my side. ♫
♫ Before these tears dry up,♫
♫ before my heart becomes hardened, ♫
♫ I'm hoping, like the first time you held my hands ♫
♫ I wish that you'd return. ♫
♫  to return back to my side, I wish for it. ♫
♫ Before this season ends, before a wicked illness takes hold ♫
♫ Like the first time you held my hands. ♫
What are you doing?
I'm trying to burn up Detective Ha Eun Joong's
investigation records from the Jongro station.
What?
Did you get permission?
Permission? Whose permission?
Father's permission?
If not, Ha Eun Joong's permission?
I suppose. It's not like you got permission
to burn up Eun Joong's vehicle either.
It was your mother who did it, for your sake.
It was you who conspired together, instigating the incident using shares as the bait.
Right! For your sake.
To make you the heir.
For my sake?
Did you really do it for my sake?
Then, I'll admit that it was for the two of us.
Yes, it's for both of us.
Let's not fight, Noona.
If we want to protect Father and the Group,
then we must gather our forces.
We have to stick tightly together and block Ha Eun Joong.
So what if we stick "tightly" together and block Ha Eun Joong,
then what?
Then will you strike against me?
What does that mean? How could I do that to you?
The you that I knew was a kid who couldn't do things like this.
The you that I knew was a kid who memorized
law books and lived within the law.
Upright like Mother, straight like Mother.
The one who wanted to emulate Father was me.
It's true.
Then,
why are you being this way?
Why are you being this way as well?
Are you really trying to become like Father?
Are you being this way because you really want to become like Father?
How can you go as far as to hurt someone...
You should have dissuaded them. You should have said they couldn't.
What were you going to do if he actually died?
What were you going to do if Eun Joong actually died there?
Jang Tae Ha
I am more afraid of you than our father.
When I look at you, it feels like I'm looking at myself.
Like I'm looking at myself becoming hideously similar to someone.
I feel you're horrible and scary because I feel I'm looking at myself.
Jae In, let's not cross that final line.
Let's not do things that we shouldn't do, please, Jae In?
Jae In.
Then I guess you can exclude yourself from this race.
Okay. You take yourself out. As for me, even if
I may become more horrid,
and become more hideous,
I want to protect my position, my life, and myself!
I don't want to lose it to him again.
Can you only think of having lost your position,
but not as having taken his position?
Wh-what?
From Eun Joong's perspective, you have taken his position
and his life away from him.
You have lived enjoying all things he should have enjoyed.
For you it's only been mere few months,
but for him, he's lost his rights to you for 25 years.
Calculate it properly.
Stop acting the victim now, I'm saying!
Aren't you curious about what I'm burning?
I'm telling you because you don't seem to know very well,
but you can't win against Father.
Never, and no one can win against him.
Either adjust to him or leave are the only two options.
That's why Mom left in the end.
I will take you to the Prosecutor's Office tomorrow.
Because I think tomorrow will be a long day.
Let's get some sleep.
Don't go tomorrow morning.
I can't do that.
I will be there tomorrow.
Even if the record of investigation disappears, and
Shin Gang Ho and Kim Joon Hyeok perjure themselves,
you won't be able to escape this time, Father.
You will have to pay for your crime, for sure.
That's a far-fetched story.
You can't win against me. It's not possible.
I've battled a lot.
And I have never lost.
This time you will lose.
Because you are fighting
me and not the law.
You will be fighting against your son.
Sleep well.
"Wake up Tae Ha Construction, the vampire who takes off
with people's traveling expense to the next life."
Four City is conning innocent locals.
You must leave us!
"Wake up Taeha Construction, the vampire who takes off,
with people's traveling expense to the next life!"
You say you will connect
Munyoo, Jecheong, Gooyi, Yoong islands,
to build culture and welfare center? Even dogs would laugh!
Four City be gone!
It's still at the beginning stage. If it gets more "ripe"
I'll brief you.
You said you'd put Construction on diet. (cut down on
excess investment or programs not necessary to core business)
You said you'd ensure internal stability by managing its weight (cut down on excess).
When I look at other groups collapsing overnight,
it reminds me that that could happen to us as well.
Business wise, we have reviewed the land development thoroughly,
and putting it roughly, if we don't think it will pan out, we can just pull out.
Did we lay a bridge across an ocean or build a structure above land?
We only purchased a boatload of land is all.
The fact that a "boatload" of land was purchased
means that Taeha Construction's funding...
That land price has skyrocketed.
I'm earning money at the moment, Jang Joo Ha.
Aren't you going to go to work? Why do you keep coming
around when you must be busy?
I'm appearing in court to answer the summons from the Prosecution,
and was wondering whether I should hand this over as well.
That's what I came here to tell you about.
Would you tell what you know if the Prosecution were to contact you?
Even if you hand it over, the Prosecution won't be able to touch (him).
Rather, the prosecutor who touches the case would be fired.
You know that's happened numerous times.
Still, I can't just let it go.
Stuff like that is meant to be held on to.
To use as insurance or as blackmail. Especially,
when you have something to achieve, even more so.
What's the scale of Taeha Group's slush fund?
I'm asking approximately how much money is contained here?
I'd say it's about $6 billion. Why?
So that you can wipe out the account again?
I mean,
really, for real, you're going to steal it?
Just what are you going to do with all that money that you'd...
Should we steal it together?
Let's do that. Let's steal it together.
To celebrate having been born again on the same date.
(surviving the car explosion)
You said, let's live properly, right?
I'm sure you're stealing to live properly, no?
Hell with it. Let's just do that.
Ah, so what are you going to do after stealing your father's slush fund?
So that I can have people buy up Taeha Group's stock.
You mean, you yourself won't be buying, but
letting other people buy up Taeha stock?
So in a word, though you don't have any intent to become
the majority share holder,
but you will secure friendly investors.
(More people own shares more accountable Taeha Gp becomes to public).
That's right.
Ah, by the way, why are you appearing at the Prosecutor's Office?
Did District Prosecutor Seo Joon Hyeong summon you, perhaps?
Yes.
I was told to make a plot so that he'd be forced to resign
over blocking a tax withholding investigation.
I finished the plot already.
What did you do? Create a plot?
As to make him resign?
All we need is a believable picture as we can manufacture
any story that goes with it.
Whether it is true or false, once it becomes a controversy,
then he has to resign regardless.
It'd be piece of cake.
I bet he will make a deal using the threat of releasing
the picture to the press.
It's a big trouble if it's true,
and even if it weren't true, there's no way to prove it
otherwise so he'll be in quite a fix.
He can do nothing but give up on this game.
I know it'd be difficult for you, but please come with me
to the outside of the hospital.
What? Go out of the hospital?
What is it?
Chairman, there's a person named Ha Myeong Geun,
insisting on seeing you and waiting for you stubbornly at the lobby.
He said that if you were told his name, you'd certainly meet with him.
What should I do?
Tell them to send him up.
Yes, Chairman.
Father.
I'd like to hold on to time.
The last time
with you, Father.
I was hoping for the punk I handled and
your wench of a daughter to have a happy ending,
it's too bad.
A murderer boyfriend to an abductor's daughter.
It's a well suited pair, don't you think?
As a last parting gift, I was hoping to
hold that thug and your daughter's hands
and wail refreshingly at your funeral.
Well, it's regrettable but you're someone about to depart
this world soon,
and your wench of a daughter will continue to live on,
so I can take my time and slowly consider it.
Don't you think?
I'm sorry.
I've been wrong, Jang Tae Ha.
I did wrong. Taking Eun Joong from you,
for having taken him away from you for 25 years,
I was wrong.
What would appease you? What can I do to make it up?
Jang Tae Ha. I will do everything. I will do everything you say.
I will do whatever you want, as much as I can do.
Tell me what you want.
I will do it.
Tell only to me.
I beg you to just tell me.
Don't do that to my Soo Yeong. That bastard can't be the one.
Please just leave her be. I beg you.
I will beg like this, okay?
I beg you. I did wrong.
I did wrong, Jang Tae Ha.
Cut the crap!
Don't make an apology not in your heart.
You did wrong? Now you talk of wrongdoing?
When my cub is thinking you are the father!
You, not me, as the father.
He still thinks of the abductor as the father.
How is it so simple to you, to just mention your wrongdoing? WHAT?!
How come it's so easy for you?
How come it's so simple?
I... I... I!!!!!
Let's stop. Let's just stop here.
Jang Tae Ha, let's stop now.
For god's sake, let's just stop.
Stop it?
Okay, I got it. Let's stop it.
Let's stop it. Get up. Let's end it today!
Come out!
District Prosecutor Seo Joon Hyeong
What did you say just now?
I just said that I abetted in the murder of
Agent Gong Gi Chan and Deputy Chief Song Ji Moon.
Mr. Jang Eun Joong?
I will turn myself in.
I've come
to turn myself in.
I was the one who abetted both murders to
Shin Gang Ho and Kim Joon Hyeok.
Jump off.
You said you did wrong.
Don't spew inanity and jump off, if you really think you've done wrong.
You said let's end it.
If you want to end it, jump off in front of me, Ha Myeong Geun.
Why don't you jump off? For a jerk who says he'd
do everything I want and everything I wish for,
why can't you jump off?
Why can't a jerk who's nothing to lose, whether he dies
today or 10 days from now?
Don't just apologize with your trap.
Don't just care for your kid with your trap,
and show your sincerity! Sincerity!
Show with your actions.
If you really feel in your heart that you've done me wrong,
jump down!
JUMP!
♫ It hurts my love. ♫
♫ Even if I just try to look at you, tears form in my eyes and run down. ♫
♫ Even if I die, I can't forget you. My bruised heart ♫
♫ Cast me aside for you. My painful love. ♫
♫ My painful love. ♫
♫ My love. ♫
♫ It hurts my love. Even if I just try to look at you. ♫
♫ Cast me aside for you. My painful love. ♫