I guess we better get
out and fix it.
What are you getting so
worked up about?
You got to be kidding me.
Dude, is this a sign,
or what?
I've heard nothing but bad
things about this place.
Chow is awful.
Racks are uncomfortable.
Just help me get the jack, and
the spare out of the trunk.
Why don't you just call it in?
It'd be a hell of a lot
easier, you know.
I'm not going to call it in. My
first day assigned to a new base.
Alright.
Whatever you say.
Come on.
You know, it is
beautiful out here.
I heard there's some
hiking out here that's great.
Well there you go, sergeant.
It's not that bad after all.
Are they supposed to be running
test today?
Not that I'm aware of.
What was that?
Let's go check it out.
Let's go, Sargent!
Slow down, small fry!
I haven't run in months.
INDEPENDENTS DAY
Subrip: Pix
As parents,
the well being of our children
is one of our greatest concerns.
We strive to give them every
opportunity in life.
I am honored to represent the
President,
at a dedication of what will be
cornerstone in that foundation of our
children's health for many
generations to come.
The first of many I hope.
Stagecoach, I need extract. I say
it again, immediate extract.
We need to get you to safety
right now, Madam Vice President.
Mr. Taylor?
What is the situation?
We need to get you and your
family to Virginia Bunker right now.
Get in.
What do we know?
Western Air Defense Sector
reported an unidentified aircraft,
estimated at one kilometer in
length,
entered our airspace at 07:00
hours, Mr. President.
Air assets are already en route.
Early reports report the
aircraft as a "beehive", Sir.
Reports. We don't have a visual,
in here?
Negative. Something
seems to be interfering
with some of our
satellite relays.
Civilian channels are up.
Ours are down.
NORAD is trying to get us in the air.
As of right now, all we have are eyes
on the ground doing their best
or whatever intel they can get.
Take us to DEFCON 3.
I'm not messing around.
How's NORAD doing?
They switched the back up
channels to deploying now, sir.
Great. We need all the assets at
the ready.
At slight provocation. I'm going
to blow this thing from the sky.
Is the Vice President at the
Virginia Bunker?
Yes, sir. The Vice President has
just arrived.
Great.
Vice President Raney.
With 200 feet below the surface
and a fully sustainable habitat
that could withstand a direct
hit from nuclear warhead.
This is Captain Goddard, Bio
Weapons Division.
Vice President Raney.
Captain Goddard.
Why is Bio Weapons
Division here?
He's here at the request of the
President.
Have they exhibited any
threatening actions as of yet?
No, Ma'am. Not as of yet.
Tactical Air Command
has relayed that two jets
are on approach to
intercept the space ship.
Alpha Bravo, Raptor 311,
we're on approach to target now.
Getting a fair amount
of turbulence in its wake.
Rabbit why don't you
hang back, just in case.
Roger that.
One mile to target.
I'm beginning to see
surface detailing now, protrusions,
plating material unknown. No
visible windows or hatches.
Jesus.
I'm gonna descend to
17,000 and have a look underneath.
I am now seeing
what appears to be a
blue light emanating
from the core of the...
311 hit! He's hit!
I'm getting out of here!
Our jets are down.
All assets are clear to engage!
And get that damn
satellite up there!
I need to see this thing!
Approaching target.
Alpha Bravo, we now
have multiple targets, inbound.
Report.
He's on me, I'm going
to try flying closer to the ship.
Maybe he won't
be so quick to fire.
Coming from behind.
Here we go.
Yahoo! You got him!
Take that
space trash.
Come back.
You alright? Hello?
No.
Eyes on, reports.
All of our conventional assets
are failing, Mr. President.
All of our efforts are failing.
I'm declaring DEFCON 1.
Clear to go nuclear.
Nevada Launch Facility MX2 has
just been attached, Mr. President.
There's been no detonation but
the systems are showing offline.
The launch has failed, sir.
It's right on to
of us, sir.
Everybody, everybody
get out now! Let's go!
Evacuate the PEOC.
Everyone out!
- I'm not leaving you, sir.
- Out! Just leave!
- I'm not leaving you...
- Just leave! Go!
Without a specimen, sir, it's
difficult to proceed.
My god!
What is it, Ari?
The White House.
It's been attacked.
No survivors.
Including President Oliver.
Ari?
Do you have confirmation?
Yes, Vice...
Under the
Federal Continuity Directive.
Ensuring the continuos
performance of the essential
functions of our Government
during a time of war.
I will need to swear you in,
Vice President Raney.
I do solemnly swear that I will
faithfully execute the office of
the President of the
United States,
and will to the best of my
ability, preserve, protect,
and defend the constitution
of the United States.
The country is now on
your hands.
What are your orders, Madam
President?
Lexi.
Relax.
Put your finger up there.
Yo!
Yo! Yo! Stop shooting.
What is it, Red?
You gotta come listen to this.
This morning, not more than 20 minutes
ago, the White House was attacked.
We are standing at DEFCON 1.
All though no nuclear launches
have been confirmed at this time.
Over 2,000 people work
in the White House,
and evacuation was in
process, I... Hold on.
President Oliver is dead.
We now have confirmation that President
Oliver was in the Bunker located...
Wasn't your brother assigned
to the President's detail?
It was a nuclear Bunker capable
of with standing nuclear attacks.
Yeah.
Yeah he was.
Vice President Raney was not
with him at the time.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe...
Maybe he was off the
President's detail.
I kept up with him
through the ex.
She just said last week, he was
still assigned to Oliver.
I'm sorry, Kelly.
He was a good kid.
Break silence.
Contact all the
militia chapters.
We're going to war.
These aliens picked the wrong
planet to mess with.
Today, we not only as Americans,
but as creatures of the Earth,
are under attack.
Are nuclear assets
having any success?
Negative, President Raney.
They've all failed.
Same with other nuclear nations.
All ordinance has been... frozen.
Okay.
Stand down from DEFCON 1.
Go to 2.
Meredith? What are you doing?
Our nuclear assets aren't
working, Randall.
But we can't stop trying.
It's not working, Randall.
And the more we try,
the greater the potential we
destroy ourselves in the process.
The fact that the only disabled
them, gives me hope.
Yeah, Dad. Maybe they felt threatened
that our jet fighters approached.
They may have, son.
But the fact remains, they
attacked first...
We're receiving a transmission!
It's...
It's coming from the Hive.
Put it on.
People of the third planet.
We shall refer to ourselves as,
"Orions",
as our planet resides in solar
system much like your own within
the constellation of the
stars you call, "Orion."
It is not our intent to destroy you.
Our mission is one of peace.
But your race is a violent one.
And for this reason, we must
guarantee our safety.
Therefore, we have eliminated the
threat of your nuclear weapons.
In the next two hours, all other
remaining military installations,
and government capitals, will
be destroyed.
In time, you will receive
further instruction.
How the hell is that
a mission of peace?
Ari, was that communication
on an open channel?
No, Ma'am. I tried
to place a lock on it.
But I was only able to grab it.
I want to open a dialogue
with them.
Make this happen.
Yes, Madam President.
I need to address the nation.
Let the people know
what's happening.
I need a few minutes to
compose my thoughts.
Dark Echo is still two hours
out, Madam President.
Thank you.
And may we remain
ever vigilant, and strong.
Just as our country has done
countless times before,
we will get through this.
God Bless you,
and God Bless the Unites States
of America.
Madam President, the Kremlin has
been destroyed.
As well as the Kantei,
both French and British
Parliaments.
Thank you.
We're receiving another
transmission.
Can you identify the
frequency signature?
I'm still trying Madam
President.
All government and
military installations
world wide have
now been destroyed.
You have ravaged your
world too long.
We will provide you a chance to
restart on a new a new world.
Momentarily, transport ships will begin
arriving in all capitals and cities
with populations in excess of
1 million people.
Go to them.
Everything else will be
provided for you.
You have 120 to evaluate
your planet.
At the end of this period, all
remaining humans will be exterminated.
You will not survive this.
Go. Now.
They expect us to evacuate a planet
of 7 billion people, in just 5 day?
They're out of their minds.
People are already lining up to
board the ships.
See, it's on my phone.
Why would they destroy all
our weapons,
but keep civilian
communications open?
They're taking prisoners.
That's what they're doing.
That's 25 confirmed
ships so far.
Members are on alert
across Pennsylvania.
Let's head into Philly.
When we find the location of the
ship, we attack.
I've got it! I've got it!
I've isolated the Orion's
frequency signature.
Okay, Madam President.
Try to speak at a slightly
slower than normal pace.
Avoid any overt emotions,
just because the matrix
may scramble your
intentions on their end,
and spit out the wrong words
or symbols.
Unfortunately, there is no way to
translate our language from our end.
I bring you greeting from the
United States of America.
I am President Meredith Raney.
We wish to open a peaceful
dialogue with your leaders.
We regret if our initial
actions were taken as offensive,
and caused you to defend
yourselves.
I was not our intent to
display aggression.
I request we open a
channel of dialogue
so that we may convey our
desire for peaceful,
and harmonious relation between
our two races.
They're responding!
You attacked us.
Again, It is common procedure to
send jets in the air...
We are open to dialogue.
However, our intent will remain
unchanged.
You have 119 hours in which to
evacuate your planet.
We are grateful for your help.
However, we are a race that is
inherently suspicious.
Therefore, to alley our fears,
we need some form of proof, to
substantiate your claims to aid us.
We will prove our
intentions by demonstrating our
technological and medical
superiority with your race.
There are places in your world, where
people suffer from starvation.
We will feed them.
Your race is plagued
by diseases.
We will offer cures.
There are but only a few gifts
awaiting your peaceful surrender.
I don't like it, Meredith.
What for? For us to give up
everything?
Get on a ship and go to a
foreign world?
This proves nothing.
President Raney.
You have a son.
Yes.
That is correct.
In further effort
to prove our intentions,
you will go to the transport
ship in Washington D.C.
There, we will heal him.
Heal me?
Sweetheart.
You don't know what these things
might do to you, Bobby.
To me?
What are they gonna do
to all of us?
Sweetheart, we can't risk having
you part of some experiment.
Mom.
If they're not trust worthy,
then we're already dead.
Where are they?
There's no body here to greet us
because the less we know about them,
the more strategic advantage
they have over us.
Let's go, buddy.
Perhaps you can accompany them.
Obtain a little intel.
Yes, sir.
You got it.
Okay.
You don't need to
through with this, Bobby.
Yeah. I do.
I think it's best you remain
here, Madam President.
I can accompany them,
Madam President.
Thank you, Captain.
I suggest I enter first, sir.
Check things out.
Halt.
Weapons detected.
These items are not allowed
aboard this vessel.
You must remove them
immediately.
You have 5 seconds to comply.
Scanning.
You may proceed.
Bring us the
child of President Raney.
We will heal him.
Bring the child to us.
The ship must be equipped with
some sort of surveillance.
It knew that Goddard was armed.
Well, they either
didn't catch the camera
or they didn't mind
us taking a peak.
My god.
Bring us the
child of President Raney.
We will heal him.
Bring the child to us.
They're asking for him, sir.
It appears safe, as far
as I can tell.
Remember when I use to pitch in
little league?
Of course I do.
I was really good.
Lets go.
Come on.
My God.
We welcome
the child of Raney.
What's that smell?
Could be bio-sensory
of some kind.
Come on.
You will proceed
to the regeneration chamber.
There, we will prepare your
body. Continue.
Continue.
It's right there.
Lets go.
Come on.
Assist the child
enter the regeneration chamber.
Let's go.
Come on.
I love you, buddy.
I love you too, Dad.
You will secure
the chamber.
We will no initiate the
regeneration sequence.
And prepare his damaged body.
Please stand back.
No!
You're hurting him!
Madam President!
Taylor, disarm!
Let him go!
Stop it!
Stop this thing!
Bobby!
Stop it!
The procedure
is nearly complete.
Step back.
Process Complete.
Are you alright?
Come on.
Hey. Slow. Slow.
Take your time.
Hey.
You're alright.
Come here.
Hey!
Hey man! How you doing?
Slowly.
Let's get you out of this thing.
Come on.
That a boy.
You got it.
Take your time.
Mom, stop staring at me.
Sorry.
I'll feel a lot better once we get the
doctor to completely check you out.
Mom, I feel great.
Honestly.
I'm glad.
Guys, I think it's a good idea we
don't stick around here too long.
It's dangerous.
Perhaps you're right.
Madam President?
Yes, General?
I've got some important developments
I'd like to discuss with you.
Go on.
Can we step over there?
Very well.
Alright.
Ari discovered an
encrypted signal,
hidden within the natural occurring
CMB radiation in deep space.
Before the arrival of the
Orions,
this signal was not being
detected.
Furthermore, its source of origin is
nowhere near the Orion Constellation.
They're lying.
Can we listen in on this deep
space channel?
We could, Madam President, but
not from here.
If we can go back to the bunker, I can
access it through the main frame.
I can try to upgrade the logic
gate matrix,
and then run the signal through
the virtual machine.
There's a slight chance we might be
able to decipher their language.
Slight chance is better
than no chance.
Lets go.
Red.
On me.
Rocco, Flanking, David and Michael.
Keep the perimeter secured.
I don't want any civilians
getting passed.
Halt.
What the hell is that smell?
Holy shit
Robotic Voice: Weapons detected.
Hold steady Lexi.
It's gonna shoot us!
Get down! Get down!
Take cover!
The Philadelphia transport ship
is under attack.
And I have the same reports
thing in Huston and Atlanta.
By who?
A militia group calling
themselves First Earth.
And I have reports of riots in
other cities. People are pushing
past barricades, and
boarding the ships.
What do we know about
First Earth?
It's a united militia front,
led by a Kelly Reed.
I know who that is. It's Agent
Norman Reed's brother.
Former Army Ranger.
Left the service, became a
freelance contractor.
Now he head up to the Pennsylvania
militia, and we're in.
This thing looks crazy.
You sure you can work
on this Ari?
I think so.
Mobilize the National Guard. I
want this faction down now.
And I want all hands on deck to
keep civilians off those ships.
But why?
After all, they did heal me,
didn't they?
Let's not forget that their first
move was to destroy the White House.
The fact remains that they yet to tell
us where they're taking our people.
And until they do, I'm not
letting anyone on the ships. No.
What is it Ari?
We have a message coming
through the Orions.
What's the problem with that?
I don't want to add any stress
to the Virtual Machine.
I think we need to hear
what they have to say.
What's the worst it can do?
The most simple way is
to think of when a wire
takes too much current,
it explodes.
The heat has to go somewhere. The
whole main frame can shut down.
They could be launching another
attack at the First Earth's antics.
Put it through, Ari.
Several of our transport ships have
come under attack in the United States,
and suffered damages.
It appears people are not being
allowed to board our ships.
We are prepared to withdraw all
extraction efforts,
and commence with
immediate extermination
procedures of the United States.
We were unaware of the attacks
on your vessels,
They were committed by a faction
outside our government.
We will put a stop to them
immediately.
This is acceptable. You will
allow your people to board our ships.
No, no I will not.
Not until you tell us where they
are being taken.
Their gone, Madam President.
Reports are coming from all over
the country.
People are boarding the ships.
After the world saw
what happened to Bobby?
It's the matter of trust.
We won't be able to keep these
of those ships.
The Mainframe is overloading!
Well whatever it is you're
doing, just shut it down.
The whole system is failing.
That's life support!
The issue is not environmental control.
The system is no longer venting oxygen.
How long do we have?
I don't know what's happening.
We only have a few minutes
before we run out of air.
I'm trying to restart the system
but the override is jammed.
What do we do?
Somebody's got to go all the way
down to EC and fix it manually.
Then I can reboot it
from here.
I know where it is.
I'll need all hands just incase.
Let's go.
Go!
You stay. Stay with the President.
Yes, sir.
I love you. I'll be back.
Bobby!
You okay?
Yeah, go, go.
This is it.
Madam President?
Is there anything you can do,
Ari?
No, President Raney.
We just have to hope they radio
back to us before its too late.
Over here! This way!
Right here.
Under the...
Let's do it!
Ready? Go!
Here it is.
Here.
It's stuck.
Look, there's a pipe.
General, use this for leverage.
I can't.
Let me try, sir.
I can't breathe.
We did it. I
think we did it. Reset.
Reset.
You guys alright?
Okay.
This is over.
Seems like life support is are
returning to normal.
General, get Bobby up to the
main level.
Dad, I'm fine.
Go!
Yeah.
Is this Kelly Reed?
Who's asking?
This is Senator Randall Raney.
You know you're making quite a
mess out there.
I wanna know why you're
attacking the transport ships?
It's an attack on American soil,
Senator.
Well look, I was thinking
if we could work together
maybe we can
solve this problem.
This conversation is over.
Mr. Reed. The President
is ordering the
National Guard and
local Law Enforcement
around the country to shut you
down by whatever means necessary.
Now I can call those hounds of,
if you help me.
Mr. Reed, I think we both have
the same goal in mind here.
What do you want?
Look, there's a great deal of suspicion
what the Orions true intentions are.
We don't know where they're
taking our people.
We don't want anymore people
getting on the ships.
So you need some kind of
deterrent?
Something that will make the
people stay away.
That's where you guys
would come in.
Can we do this?
We can probably help with that.
How do you feel?
I'm fine. How about you?
Did we make
any progress?
Ari's transferring
everything he was able
to download before
the system crashed.
General Roundtree, you were able to
relay my orders to the National Guard?
Yes, Madam President.
Lose your weapons.
We're going in unarmed this
time.
We'll see if the security scan
can pick up on these.
Cops aren't gonna be able to keep
those crowds at bay for long.
Ever since they healed
the President's kid,
they all want to
get on those ships.
Can't let that happen.
When we first step in, the laser
is going to scan us.
Assuming we make it past the
first laser,
we'll split up, plant the C4, meet
back here in 10 minutes to detonate.
Understood?
Roger that.
Copy that.
Move out.
Halt.
Scanning.
Everyone's unarmed, right?
You may proceed.
Look for an instrument panel or
imperfections in the haul.
Doesn't pick up that plastique,
Not so far.
What's that smell, man?
I don't know.
What I'm worried about is getting
the plastic caps on here.
Get back, please.
These oughta do some
damage.
Wait, do you hear that?
Weapons detected.
Go!
Take cover.
There has been another attack in
the Philadelphia transport ship!
It's First Earth again.
Mass casualties this time.
Madam President, the Orions are
contacting us.
Crap.
Make sure the National
Guard and local law
enforcement understand
their duties, General.
Yes, Ma'am.
Put them on.
President Raney.
You have failed us.
There have been further attacks.
An isolated incident,
I assure you.
It is being dealt with.
We are prepared to
withdrawal extraction efforts,
and proceed with extermination
procedures.
Please, do not do that.
They terminated the
connection, President Raney.
Of course they did.
God!
Put down
your weapons.
I'm receiving reports of Orions
attacking and firing on crowds.
Raise the Orions, Ari!
Yes, Ma'am.
They're not responding.
Keep trying.
Madam President,
ministry of defense.
Hell Minister Brighton.
Yes.
Yes, I understand your position.
We are doing everything that we can to
suppress the action of First Earth.
Yes, sir.
Hold on one second, please.
What?
Minister Brighton, an urgent matter has
take place. I need to call you back.
Hello?
What the hell happened out
there, Reed?
It's FUBAR, sir.
People pushing their way
in with the cops in tow,
and the friggin' lasers dropped.
Well, this is no what I
had in mind.
They still don't appear to be
shooting civilians. I apologize, sir.
What do you want us to do?
Just stand down for the moment.
Who you talking with out here,
Randall?
General Roundtree just
spoke to the Captain
in charge of the
National Guard detail.
They received orders to assist
First Earth?
From you?
I made a bad move, Meredith.
I asked them to do what they could
to keep people off the ships.
Dark Echo has arrived.
Easier to follow orders when you
agree with them, Senator.
Go, go, go!
Put down your weapons.
We're fucked.
Put down your
weapons.
What are you doing?
Toss your weapon.
President Raney.
I'm Major Fry. This is Lieutenant
Zuber from the 45th space wing,
Extraterrestrial Avionics
Intelligence unit.
We believe this is what
we are up against.
On August 14th, 2003, the sun released
a larger than normal plasma tendril,
resulting in a massive
electromagnetic explosion.
It downed all satellite, radio,
and cellular communications.
That's the same dates as the
east coast black outs.
That's correct, Captain.
It turns out, our friend here,
was paying us a visit as well.
What make you think this is the
race that's attacking us?
A unique signature in the Cosmic
Microwave Background radiation.
Our team detected a similar signal
when the hive arrived this morning.
Our technician, Mr. Ari, has
identified a CMB encryption signal.
We'll be happy to share that
with you.
We smelled an odor when Bobby was
healed on the transport ship.
And the guys on the
field are smelling
something on other
transport ships as well.
We learned from the
Cheyenne ship that the odor
is a short of
chemical pheromone.
It enables access to vital
components of the ship.
Our chemist were able to replicate
that formula in the laboratory.
We call it, CH5N.
We should be able to use it to access
restricted areas of the alien vessels.
But is impossible to say for certain
without a more recent specimen.
Now, I think it would be fitting
to use your militia, Randall.
I'm sorry, say that
again.
I want you to capture
an Orion.
And how are we supposed to do
that, senator?
There was a firefight over
the Virginia mountains this morning.
If you go digging in the wreckage,
you might find a pilot.
I can be dead or alive.
It makes no difference.
Well, I might know a
couple of mountain boys.
Leave it to us, sir.
We'll do our best.
They're going to do it.
Good.
Major Fry, let's get
you over to the D.C.
transport ship. See
what you make of it.
Certainly, Madam President.
I have been analyzing the Orion signal
from the CMB and comparing it against
another signal that I found embedded
from the broadcast in the mothership.
So far I have isolated about 30
unique patterns that keep showing up.
It seems that this is
their alphabet.
Impressive work.
On the Cheyenne ship when we tried
to broadcast the CMB signal,
the controls would flutter like
an energy pulse.
Didn't get us anywhere.
We've had several English broadcast
aline these patterns up against.
It's not gonna be perfect but I
do have a translator algorithm
for us to try and access
this data base.
Pheromones should get us access.
Hopefully your alphabet will get
us some answers.
General, what do we know about
their boarding procedures?
The ship is equipped with some sort
of a weapons detection system.
The laser deterrent enforces a
no tolerance policy.
We're not quite sure how they're
surveilling their ship. Understood.
Let's see what they
make of this.
Whatever their
surveillance, I'm willing to
bet with CH5N, they'll
look the other way.
- Lieutenant.
- Sir.
Sir.
Halt.
Scanning.
You may proceed.
Same as the Cheyenne ship.
Unlike the vessel
recovered in '03, this ship
doesn't appear to be
designed for man flight.
Looks like it's trying to
establish a link.
Let's see what it's
trying to say.
I don't even know if any of these
alien bastards is out here.
We don't.
Hello?
That's great news, Mr. Reed.
Text me your coordinates, I'm
sending a chopper to you.
Bye.
We have our selves an Orion.
Dr. Goddard, Have you
ever do an autopsy?
Yes, I have.
Carbon base life form. Oxygen
and Nitrogen present in their
blood suggest they breathe a
similar atmosphere to ours.
Same alkaline based cell
structure...
But with slightly different
attributes.
The First Earth captured Orion
has a more mesomorphic build.
Bigger and stronger.
Cheyenne specimen, slightly
thinner, more ectomorphic.
But I'm willing to bet their both
symbioses of the same colony.
Much like workers to a
queen bee.
Now.
We just need to find a match.
Major Fry,
what happened?
Lasers dropped, I lost
Lieutenant.
Are you hurt?
No, Madam President. I'm fine.
Just need to wait for the AI
reset. And I'll try again.
Please be
careful, Major.
Yes, Madam President.
Okay, we try again.
I'll be ready to move.
We're in.
It looks remarkably
similar to earth.
Flight mission.
Navigation.
Colonization.
What's
happening, Major?
It appears they're trying to
colonize earth like planets.
They are using the hive to
terraform them.
Can you find out where
they are taking our people, Major?
Yes.
Trajectory.
This doesn't make any sense.
Four ships are going to the
hive, briefly.
Then they hoover over the atmosphere
for 10 minutes, and reenter.
They just Jettisoning the
people into space.
I'm sorry, Major. Please repeat that.
I didn't get it.
I said they are just Jettisoning
the people into space.
Like throwing out the trash,
Mrs. President.
That can't be right. He said that
the ship first goes to the hive.
Major, are you sure? Are you
absolutely certain?
No one appears to be getting off
at the hive?
Yes, Madam President.
This has all been
downloaded to my PAMD.
I'll show you when
I return.
President Raney. What about
the people across the country
wait to board? Across the globe.
Let them board.
Mom.
They're going to die.
We have to tell them.
We can't let them
board those ships.
know we're on to them.
We would be giving up
all our intel.
Finally, we know something about
them they don't want us to know.
Have we gotten an
update from Captain Goddard, yet?
I spoke to him a little earlier.
He said he's making progress.
But preferred to explain it
when he returns.
We better get back to
the bunker.
I wanna know what I can
about that alien.
Why are they doing this?
This is what I don't understand.
Why don't they just destroy us?
Why bother with the deception?
Less man power.
Less chance of engagement on
their behalf.
Less loss of men.
They're terraforming
planets.
The more destruction they cause, the
more work they give themselves.
Their plan is actual quite
efficient, but...
What I don't understand si why they're
returning to the bee hive first.
We better get back to
the bunker.
Less we need to prepare.
But we will not give up.
Madam President, I have
an idea.
It's incredibly simple, but every
test I've run seems to confirm it.
Have you made an
analysis of the aliens?
Yes, Madam President.
I've mapped most of its
anatomy, and NS.
And I believe I can highly
contagious airborne pathogen.
And we can infect them, like
passing on a cold.
Do it.
Yes, ma'am.
Sir, the ships are feeling up.
People are passing the barricades
and forcing their way in.
Thank you, soldier.
Thank you, sir.
What if it's a nice place?
The new world they promised.
What if it's a great new alien
place with thing we've never seen?
What if we're actually
killing people,
by not letting them board
their ships?
Do you really think there's a chance
in hell of any of that being true?
No.
This is my home.
My country.
It's our world.
It maybe over, but I'm
gonna fight till my last breath.
Damn right!
You're god damn right.
Rally every militia group.
In every city.
It's time to blow up
some more alien shit.
Everything we got, as
long as we got it.
Good work out there, Major Fry.
I'm sorry for the loss of
your men.
I will see to it, he receives
the highest posthumous merit.
Thank you, Madam President.
Captain, Goddard? Please
explain your pathogen.
Yes.
Well, I have successfully
developed an
airborne replicating
agent called GS57B.
It's "cooking" right now.
It's highly contagious, and I believe
if we can introduce it aboard the Hive,
it'll be a successful weapon.
Could GS57B have
repercussions in humans?
Are we at risk for catching it?
There is a risk.
Now the contagion can't
replicate in our bodies.
So it shouldn't be a problem.
But there is no way of
knowing for sure.
I believe we have
no other choice.
Our only problem is how we get
it to them?
And how do we infect them?
We can outfit the D.C. Transport Ship
with Captain Goddard's viral agent.
Send it back to the Hive.
Release it via time
controlled device.
Sounds like a great
idea but why would the
Hive bring a transport
ship back aboard.
We infect the navigation
system with the bug.
Make it appear the ship
isn't functioning properly.
It'll have to go back for
maintenance.
First Earth has success just lobbing
grenades and C4 timers in the ships,
to make them return.
We can't do that, General.
The heat wave from the blast
will kill off the viral agent.
I'll make a virus to infect the
ships computer.
I'll get on it.
Thank you, Ari.
Yes, Ma'am.
Captain. Notify me at once
when it's ready.
Yes, President Raney.
Clear.
3.
2.
Give me the shot.
Mark it.
You're good.
3.
2.
First Earth has
launched attacks on
transport ships in
several major cities.
Dallas, Atlanta, Miami, Chicago.
Chancellor Kafka is demanding you
to put a halt to the violence,
as is Prime Minister Avenir,
President Casillas...
Let them, Ari. Let them
say what they will.
Not my concern at this point.
Yes, madam President.
Madam President?
The Captain and I are ready.
Is that the contagion?
Yes, Ma'am.
Very well.
Let's go.
President Raney! The Orions
are contacting us.
Put it on.
President Raney.
Other world leaders have
cooperated peacefully.
Still the United States
remains defiant.
There are continued attacks on
our ships.
We had hope to avoid...
Turn it off, Ari.
Yes, President Raney.
We're in.
So far the pheromone is still
allowing us access to the ship.
I'm going to upload the bug into
the navigation system.
Stand by.
The virus is set.
Got it.
We are go of the GS57B
transponder.
And we're going on
maintenance issue.
Time to leave, Captain.
Yes, sir.
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
What the matter, Major?
They're trying to hack into the
Navigation system.
Who is?
The Orions.
Madam President?
They're contacting us again.
President Raney.
You will meet with us,
immediately.
Yes.
I heard you the first time.
What is the purpose of
this meeting?
Despite our warning,
you continue to resist us.
Still we are prepared
to discuss the
details of the
relocation of your people.
Alright.
I will come to you.
What are you doing,
Meredith?
It's out of the question.
I'll go.
We accept your terms.
A transcription will be
sent to your location.
Thank you.
I'll take Captain Goddard's
contagion with me.
It would be too dangerous,
Madam President.
No, they asked for me.
I'm the only one that can
get us on that ship.
It's the perfect plan.
If we can get at least one of
these aboard the hive,
that would be sufficient.
Meredith.
I'll do it.
The country needs you.
Don't mom.
Come on.
Major Fry, I'd like for you to
come with me.
Your expertise maybe applicable
in some way.
Captain Goddard, I request your
accompany as well.
Yes, Ma'am.
The captain and I will wear the
CH5N to conceal our presence.
Very well, gentlemen.
Shall we go?
Madam President.
You wouldn't be second guessing
yourself, would you Captain Goddard?
No, President Raney.
It will work.
Good.
It better.
Here you go, Madam President.
One of these is enough?
The pathogen is highly
contagious.
Now Major Fry and I
will go aboard the ship,
and try to put a few
of these on there.
Give a few to Agent Taylor,
as well.
Aerosols is distributed
throughout the ship.
But you have to make direct
contact with the Queen.
And how long until it
takes effect?
It should be within minutes.
And I'll know?
Yes, Madam President.
The effects are agonizing.
Very well.
I guess I'll just try to keep
them talking.
Welcome President Raney.
Follow the corridor to your
left.
Let's go.
That's the last of
the GS57B bombs.
I'm going to see if I can jam the
Orions CMB encrypted signal.
On some ship to ship interference.
In case things go south.
Welcome President Raney.
Welcome to my Hive.
Who is speaking?
Is there one leader among you?
I am speaking,
President Raney.
Who are you?
I am the leader of this colony.
What do you think of my ship?
What is all this?
This is the fate of you people.
Our voyage to Earth as well.
Human blood is viable,
to replenish our energy source.
You're killing all of them?
It is the natural way.
One life ends and it contributes
to another cycle.
Then why have you
brought me here?
You will allow your people
to aboard our transport ships.
And they will replenish our
energy source, here.
Why would I help you?
Why should I lead my people to
their slaughter?
In 4 days, your people are going
to be exterminated.
Your race has always
defined nature.
You selfishly ravage your
planet.
Imagine you were a species with
no predator.
You refuse to accept your place
in the universe.
Accept it now.
We are your predator.
Surrender.
Absolutely not.
We are prepared to offer you a
barter.
In exchange for your
cooperation.
You and your family will be
spared.
You will allow your people
to board our transport ships.
And you and your family will not
be harmed.
And where will we be safe?
Here.
Aboard our ship.
Until the extermination and
terraforming is complete.
This is acceptable.
You leave me no choice.
You have a deal.
Most acceptable.
You will allow your people to
board our ships?
No.
Not until I know my
family is safe.
Then,
we'll have a deal.
On Earth,
this is the universal gesture of
friendship and agreement.
You will stop the attacks on our
ships.
We need to get you out of here
right now, Madam President.
Come on.
Okay.
Madam President?
It's working!
Let's move! Let's move!
Go!
Let's go!
Come on.
Now what?
- There's gotta be a way to override.
- I'll check the hatch.
Just get us out of here, Major.
System override.
Navigation override.
Helm override.
Let's go.
Captain Goddard?
The Dragonflies are on us.
Stand by.
President Raney's transport
ship is on the way.
And Hive motherships are
collapsing in every city.
Their defenses are
down.
General, can we scramble
some jets?
Definitely.
There's only one more dragonfly
in pursuit of the transport ship.
Hang in there.
Delta 82. Approaching.
Ready to intercept.
In coming! Look out!
Get down! My god.
Okay.
Hey, you did it.
We all did it.