Edited at https://subtitletools.com
"Nobody can blow the
candle of life.."
"..which is protected
by God himself.."
"Roll sound. Camera. Action"!.
Have you ever loved someone?
Yes!
Have you ever given your heart away?
Me too!
All my young friends out there!
Don't you fall in love here!
I have loved and lost
my mind and sleep.
People around don't lie,
it's all true!
There is no ailment
like falling in love.
There is no control in the matters
of heart, what to do?!
And there is no cure for
this ailment, too!
So sing, 'Om Shanti Om'!
'Om Shanti Om'!
'Om..
- Shanti Om'!
'Om Shanti Om'!
'Om..
Hey Sidekick! What do you
think you are doing?
You are not the hero of the film.
What is it to you? Are you
the director of the film?
If I was, I would
Kick you out first!
Buzz off! - Cut it good shot.
- Lunch break, good shot!
Hey you! Mr. 'Hero'!
Who me?
Yes you!! Is that your
father's jacket that..
.. you are happily sneaking
out with it?!
E! Don't drag my father into this!
Why? Is your dad some 'Raj Kapoor'
who will stop our shoot!
Come on, return the jacket! Quick!
Relax! The 'hero' gave it to me with
so much love, that I just wore it!
Come on! Wearing this jacket
will not make you a hero..
You need a good face and personality
as well! Now give it back!
Idiot! Spoilt the jacket -Every
fool wants to become a hero!
Uncle.
Pappu! Did you hear that!
Don't worry Buddy!
How will a drunk dressman recognise
a superstar like you?
Superstar?!
Pappu you're sure l
will become a hero?
Of course! You Will definitely
become a hero.
My mom also says that!
I bet every comedian's mother says
that to her son as well Omi!
Really!
- Yes! That's how mothers are!
But you will surely become a hero.
But l, Pappu Master am telling..
..you that you will become a hero.
Because you have everything
it takes -
Style, Hair style, Grace,
Face, Talent!
But there is just one thing standing
between you and your stardom!
What's that?
Your name!
My name? Om Prakash Makhija!
Your Credit for two months
is still pending!
Ok OK! I will clear it!
When, in this lifetime or the next?
By the way, your soggy cream rolls..
.. are also from the silent
movie era! Pappu!
The day I become a superstar, l
will shut down this canteen first!
You better remember my name Mister,
Om Prakash Makhija.. Go.
That's the problem Omi! We could have
managed with just Om and Prakash.
But 'Makhija', how will you ever
become a star with this name?!
I will not? - Of course not!
Now look at that poor guy.
He is also struggling
to become a hero.
You! Over here!
- Ya!
What is your name?
Govinda Ahuja!
God! You will never become
a hero with this name!
Why don't you change your name to a
dashing Rohan Kapoor or Raj Kiran.
The producers will start
queuing up instantly!
Just Govinda will do?!
Try it!
Thank you! Thank you!
You're right Pappu. Why did
father give me this name?
Out of all the amazing
actors in the..
.. industry like Jeetendra,
Dharmendra.
But my Dad's favourite had
to be Om Prakash! Gosh!
Look! Here comes everyone's
favourite-Rajesh Kapoor!
Autograph, please.
- Please, sir.
Now that is a Hero's name
- Kapoor! A name to reckon with!
Now get rid of this Makhija and
try changing your name to..
.. 'Kapoor' or 'Khanna', then see,
how your life takes off in one shot!
You're Right Pappu! I would have
changed my name today itself. - But?!
But you know what Mom will say!
Nooooooooo!
Oh My Lord! What am I hearing?
My darling son wants
to change his name!
I ask you what is wrong
with your name?
Om stands for the Lord and
Prakash for Light, and..
And Makhija! Makhija stands
for shooing a fly away!
I can tolerate 'Om' and 'Prakash'.
With a name like Makhija, I will
never become a hero! Never!
You will definitely become
a hero one day my darling!
My heart says so. A mother's
heart is says so.
Mother's heart can go to hell!
I know I will never become
a hero with this name,
in this lifetime atleast!..
..I will die a Junior Artiste.
Just like dad!
Om Prakash's Father! I am glad you
died before hearing all this!
Quit overacting mom! Now I know why
you could never become a heroine!
Overacting and me?!
Do you know, I was called by the
Great K. Asif to screen test?
If it wasn't for you in my stomach..
.. then your Mother would have been
Anarkali of "Mughal-e-azam"!
Madhubala was not too bad herself,
but if I was the heroine of the film-
- Then the film would
have flopped badly!
Mom the truth is..
..that you are a Junior Artiste,
dad was a junior artiste.
And may be, I too shall always..
.. remain a Junior Artiste!
Case Dismissed!!
Om! Wait! I have made
your favourite pudding.
Silly boy has got upset.
What happened, Mummy? Why
are you standing like this?
See Pappu! Your Useless friend
fought with me again and stormed off.
Really? Then he must have gone to
meet his girlfriend on the bridge.
Girlfriend?
How are you Shanti? All well?
You know why I keep
coming back to you..
..because you are my inspiration..
..my strength, my dream,
my destination. You.
Hey! Hope you are not getting
bored Shanti.. Thanks.
You know I am a very good actor.
Mother and Pappu also say that
one day I'll become a big hero.
But do you know, I want to become
a star only for you Shanti!
So that I can stand next
to you and say..
Hey! Hope you are not
getting bored? Thanks.
You know what I love the most about
you, that I keep talking..
.. and you never get bored.
You just keep smiling at me.
I know, you have millions of fans,
but let me tell you one thing..
.. no one can love
you more than I do.
Oh! And even if you were not
Shanti, the 'Superstar'..
..but Shanti the 'super
Junior Artiste',
I would still love you as much.
And believe me, we will
definitely meet one day.
And that day is not
very far my friend.
Pappu, Mother-when did you come?
Why didn't you say anything?
There was no need! Now get a side!
Let me take a look at
my Daughter-in-law.
God! She is like a
sparkling diamond!
Oh Mother! Stop it.
Listen please forgive me today for..
.. getting angry and
saying nasty things.
Don't worry my darling Prince.
One day you will become a hero..
..and your face will be on a poster
as well, just like this one.
This is a mother's heartfelt
blessing, and a mother's heart..
..Was a silver jubilee film!
Shut up! Mother's heart
is always full of love.
Here my son, tie this thread.
It is blessed by a sage.
He will fulfill all your wishes and
you will meet your Shanti very soon.
Really?
- Really!
And this can happen tonight!
Tonight? But How?
Ladies and Gentlemen welcome to
the Premiere of Dreamy girl!
Hold your hearts, here comes the
king of Romance Rajesh Kapoor..
.. and his lovely lovely wife!
Hey! Rajesh! He touched me!
Wow! Am I looking nice?
We always look nice
in rented clothes!
Welcome! Isn't it a lovely evening.
You are looking so lovely.
Ya, myself lovely! ok.
So when are you giving
us the good news?
Good news? Next week. I am very
confident that just like last year..
.. I will get this year's
best actor award as well!
She is talking about
the other good news!
What other good news?
Oh! Baby? That also soon, soon.
And here comes the star
of the evening!
The dreamy girl herself
- Shantipriya!
The beautiful night
is here after all,
fortune is smiling as well you see.
The beauty who is loved
by the world, from far..
.. Is standing right
here, next to me.
There are a million things
I want to say..
.but my heart questions me here.
What I tell you in my dreams every
day, should I whisper it in your ear?
In your eyes there is this magic
I see, magic of a moonlit night.
Your breath blows like
a wind around me..
..carrying my heart away
like a weightless kite.
Grace and beauty walk with you.
Oh what a lovely sight!
And the moon bows down to you,
to beg for some ivory light.
Your gaze has seared my heart
so bad, hope it is not in vain.
I want to drown in your eyes
forever never to surface again!
He! Leave him! Don't you
know he is a superstar?
You were awesome Tiger!
People die for just
a glimpse of her..
.. and you literally
latched on to her!
Are you just going to stand here?
Don't you want to go in
and watch the film?
Who will let us in?
'Pick Pocket!'- Saw that film in
black. It was worth the money spent!
But these are.. I know,
flicked them while..
.. taking an autograph.
Hurry up now!
Oh Mr. Manoj Kumar! Welcome sir!
Sadhu Raam! 'Long live lndia'!
Vimy! You look lovely
lovely tonight!
"My motherland.."
- Long Live the freedom struggle!
Mr. Ramesh, what would you know
about the worth of this vermillion?
It's a gift from God.
This crimson dot!
Pushpa It's a crown of pride.
For an lndian bride!
It's every woman's dream.
It's ruby sheen!
Oh Pushpa.
Look at the screen Omi!
You will get us killed.
If the real Manoj Kumar comes,
we will be beaten up!
Of Course not, Manoj Kumar is a very
good man. He will not say anything.
Madam.. please believe me,
I am Manoj Kumar.
Security check him!
See my driving license!
Liar! Liar!
- No, I didn't lie.
How do I look into your
eyes, tell me how?
When ever you come near me now..
How do I not shy away, just
touch me not today!
My darling, you don't know..
The love in my heart is the truth.
This restive soul will be at peace..
.. after gazing at the
splendor of your youth.
Your body is like a bloom. And
your limbs the colour of noon.
I will be tinted in your beauty
- very soon!
Your colour is sated with beauty.
Your beauty warms a room.
And your warmth is unique,
My fair one!
Why feel shy from your beloved?
Let me touch you today my love!
I walk in a drunk pace
I totter in a daze.
My youth is a glass
of wine it seems.
I catch your eye with mine..
I dwell in your dreams I reside
in your hearts with ease!
Stay in my heart for eternity,
never will I stop you!
But let me recount my desire..
Why feel shy from your beloved?
Let me touch you today my love!
How do I heed to this
wandering heart?
How do I make an emperor mine?
How do I wear the crown of love?
Why do you rule my heart beloved?
My darling, you don't know..
..the love in my heart is the truth.
This restive soul will be at peace..
after gazing at the splendor
of your youth.
The tune of your love,
is in my songs.
In your love for me, is my victory.
Winning this toss, is my loss.
But a loss like this
has your love in it.
Forget all the chores for the day,
let me touch you today.
How do I not shy away, just
touch me not today!
Mr. Ramesh, what would you know
about the worth of this vermillion?
It Is a gift from God.
This crimson dot!
Wow It is a crown of pride,
for an lndian bride!
Wow It Is every woman's dream,
it's ruby sheen!
Wow. Applause!
Wonderful! Wonderful.
Can I say something?
- Sure!
This year's Film fare award for
best actress will definitely..
.. go to your sister-in-law!
Of course she will get it.
But if the award jury was here, they
would have given the award to you!
Really? When I become a star you
think I will also get an award?
Of course you will!
Good! When I will become a star..
..the first thing I will do is,
buy off this bungalow!
Ya! Buy it! - Ya! Buy it!
Today Rajesh Kapoor
owns this bungalow..
..but one day it will be mine.
Right said.
- He lives like a pauper..
Cheap!
- I will stay in style!
In style!
I will have 15-16 imported cars!
- 50-60 servants will be around me!
In style!
I will have a luxurious bedroom,
just like the one we see in movie..
..with a round bed!
In style!
And you know Pappu, as soon as l
will wake up in the morning..
..before my feet even touch
the smooth marble floor..
.. a servant will slip velvety
slippers under them.
The other one will be waiting on
me with a silk dressing gown..
Jani, The third one will be standing
there to serve fresh fruit juice.
Wow! -What happened?
You almost made me cry!
- What happened?
You will get the 'Filmfare'
award later..
..first accept this 'Bottle
Award' from my side!
For me? Wow! Press click
some pictures. Photo.
You know Pappu!
- Tell me.
I have even written a thank you
speech for receiving this award.
Will you listen to it? Will you?
Of Course! Come on everybody!
Sit down!
Ladies and gentlemen..
I Have wanted you so much
and so badly it's true.
That the entire universe has
conspired for me to get you.
One minute! Hold on! Poetry!
Didn't get it.
Ok! Shall I do something simple?
- A bit. - Take 2!
Ladies and Gentlemen..
They say, if you want something
with all your heart,
then the universe will work in every
way possible, to help you get it.
Today, you all have given me
everything that I wanted.
Thank you very much. I feel
like the king of the world!
Thank you for making
me believe that..
..just like in our films,
in life too.
Finally in the end,
everything is ok.
Happy Endings.
And if it is not happy then it's
not 'the end' my friends!
The film is not over yet!
I love you! I love you! I love you
all! I love you Rajesh Kapoor.
What a pathetic speech! That also
in the middle of the night!
I love you.
- Get lost!
Pappu! Look at him..
Hey you drunkard. You
did not recognize him?
Who are you?
He is superstar Om!
And you didn't recognize him? He
is the famous hero Manoj Kumar!
Then I am the famous wrestler
- Dara Singh! Get lost!
Om! Is that you?
It is mom.
What took you so long?
I was so scared!
Oh! My melodramatic mom! What
is there to get scared in it?
You know however late I may get, l
will always come back home- to you!
Ok then, freshen up! I
will get food for you.
No
- I have eaten.
And you are drunk as well!
Please forgive me today..
I am sorry!
Today was special.. you always
tell me that this moon is..
What moon?
Look here mother
- the one in the sky! Over there!
You always tell me that
you have a dream for me..
..to reach for the
stars and the moon.
Tonight I went for the
stars and beyond.
I almost lived my dream. I even
touched it- with my own two hands.
Really?
Really! Oh my Prince!
Now sleep! You have to go
for shoot early morning!
This foolish make up man has pasted
my moustache so tightly..
.. I can't even open my mouth! How
Will I say my dialogues now?!
Look at brighter side, no one will..
.. recognize you with
the moustache atleast!
That's so true!
- That's why I've also put a mole.
Wow! I can hardly recognize
you with that!
You get lost! Assistant Sir! Here!
Am I supposed to do all
the work around here?
Sir, please tell me
what is the scene..
..exactly and what are my dialogues?
The scene is, that this
field is on fire!
Actions!
- And your dialogue is - 'RUN!!
And?
That's it!
RUN!
Assistant Sir! Sir!
Only 'run'?! But it is hardly
a dialogue! It's miniscule!
Miniscule!? I Have written it!
Oh wow! Amazing dialogue! How
creative! People will love it.
But Sir, if I had a better 'hero like'
dialogue, I would be so grateful.
Yes sir!
The hero of the film will say 'Hero
-like' dialogues, not you.
And he is there
- Ricky Sandhu!
Ok Madam, no problem! Someone
Call the Producer!
Oh God! This mad director is acting
up again! You Get lost from here.
Ricky Sandhu that ass..
Hush! He is the hero!
My shot is ready and she will not
shoot till the Producer comes!
She is telling me
- 'Partho Roy'-the great Director,
That she will come out only
when the producer is here.
Call the damn Producer!
Call Mukeshji!
Suresh Uncle, what
is all this drama?
Same old story! The heroine
is refusing to shoot..
.. they must have not paid
her for the last schedule!
Of course not! The
Producer of this..
.. film is a very big man
- Mukesh Mehra!
It doesn't matter how big
or small the Producer is..
..these stars treat all
of them like dogs!
Uncle!!!
- Control!
Our Shanti ji is not like that!
Correct! Mukesh Mehra is the one
who gave her the first break!
In a film called 'ode to youth'.
Then Shanti was only sixteen!
"Greetings.."
Hey! Mukeshji is here! Mukeshji
Now watch, how the shooting
will start in ten minutes?!
Mukesh ji is amazing.
-What personality!
Totally Dashing!
He should become a hero!
He is Tall as well!
Smarty pants!
You know uncle, we would never..
.. do this measly dacoit role
for any other producer.
It is Mukeshji's film
that's why we agreed!
You seem to be coughing
a lot suddenly.
All ok.. Shanti will be ready in
10 minutes. You set up the shot.
Very good! Problem solved!
Mukeshji. My creativity is sinking..
Stop crying for every
little thing Partho.
This is Bombay. This is
how we make films here.
And make sure you finish
this scene today itself.
Of course! Of course!! I have
placed three cameras.
Just like the great art house
makers - One Satyajit Ray angle..
..One Bimolda angle, One Gurudott
angle.. totally in the shadows.
Put a Manmohan Desai angle as
well! The mainstream one.
That's the one that will work.
Camera ready! Wide angle!
Take it to a bit right.
Shanti baby! You are too much really!
You took so long! What are you
doing after pack up darling?
Committing Suicide!
Baby I am ready to die
with you as well!
Ok! Going for the shot!
Field clear! Field clear!
Sir you are in the field!
What? Ok!
Light the fire! Start
rolling! Action!
Sir you are supposed
to say Camera first!
Uh yes! Camera..
Saarjoooo!
- Hey, somebody help her.
Run!
RUN!
Saarjoooo!
- Help very good.
Very good! Sarjoo!
Jump into the fire!
This fire is too hot! Let it cool
down a bit-I will jump!! I will jump!
What the hell is happening?
Put out the fire!
Sir, Cut the shot! Sarjoo
is refusing to jump in!
No!.. Till I get an okay
shot I can't cut it.
The Producer wants to
finish the scene today!
Jump. Some one help!
While shooting 'Mother lndia' -
Sunil Dutt saved Nargis from the fire
Just like this.And then
they got married.
But I am already married.
So what's the point.
Help!
Shantiji is alone there.
Please help her.
If you are so concerned, why don't
you jump into the fire?! Packup!
I don't want to shoot anymore.
Somebody please cut the shot!
Somebody please jump in the fire!
Om.
Om Fire!
Where?
- Behind you!
Hey, somebody help me.
Omi! What happened! Hold him.
Omi! What happened!
Cut the shot! Very good!
Doctor can't you cut down your fee?
You came for half a shift only!
It's hurting a lot Omi?
- Yes.
Have you lost it? Look at me,
I am talking to you!
What would I go and tell mother, if
something were to happen to you?
Look at me, I am talking to you!
Oh ho! Shanti was in the fire.
Shanti can go to hell! There were
lots of people to rescue her.
But who would have come to save
you? Look at me, I am talking to you!
Then stop moving around!
Shut up! Thank God your back
was burnt and not your face!
Otherwise, instead of
becoming a film star..
.. you would have to work
in a horror film!
Fine, I would have worked
in a horror film.
So what?
Worse come to worse I would have
died in that fire? So what?
Pappu, I did not think that time.
All I could see was Shanti trapped
in that fire, helpless.
And you know, if need be, I will
jump in that fire again and again!
Not once but hundred times,
thousand times, to save Shanti!
Because nothing is more precious
to me than Shanti's life.
My life, my dreams, nothing matters!
Now you look at me!
You look at me! What are you doing?
What are you doing?
I have known many people in my life,
but nobody has ever done anything
like this for me..
.. what you have done,
being a stranger.
Shanti! I may be a stranger for you.
But you are already a part of me,
without you, I am incomplete.
What is your name?
My name is something which is
always connected to Shanti.
Om, before Shanti and
Om, after Shanti.
See, I know you are not mute.
If you will not tell me your name
then how will I thank you?
Om!
- Om!
Shanti.
- Om.
I think I have seen you somewhere.
Ya.. that night at the Premiere.
On the Posters! You must have..
.. seen the Posters of
his film 'Madras King'.
He is the rising star from the
south - Our Omaswami Shantinatahan!
Omswami who?
You! Who else?
He is so down to earth!
Who can tell that his last
film was a blockbuster hit?
Really?
- Really?
Really! You will see Shanti..
..very soon our Om will be the king
of Bombay lndustry as well.
Really?
- Really! - Of course!
By the way, you have made
one fan here already.
Not a fan, a friend Shantiji.
Call me Shanti.
Shanti?
- Shall I leave? - Ok..
Thank you once again.
Rule number one of friendship.
No sorry, no thank you!
Is this a dialogue of some film?
Not yet!! Om writes
his own dialogues.
Madam.. no.. sorry..
no.. thank you..
Sooraj what are you doing here?
Our set is over there. Let's go.
Daddy I was writing dialogues.
Oh Ok. Sing a sing a song..
Come on, hurry up.
Where is the camera?
You shotgun. me Quick Gun Murugan.
What is it, Rascal?
To die! Mind it!
Wow, what acting!
Never mind it!
You Rascal! Mind it!
Wow, what acting!
Pappu! Tiger!!
Tiger, tiger, tiger..
Mind it! Tiger!!
- Tiger catch!
Wow, what a tiger!
Wow, What a tiger!
Bad cat! Fat cat! Rascal cat!
Naughty pussy!
Who is your daddy?
You want to say sorry..
come on pussy cat,
pussy cat where have you been?
Have you been to London to see
the Queen! Go See the queen!
Find it!
You fly! You die!
Wow, what flying!
You rascal! Mind it!
Cut it! Super!!
Wow, what Acting! Wow what acting!
Move on! You've just mugged
one line and rattling it!
Pappu! Is she coming?
Yes, you keep signing autographs!
Yes, I'll do it.
- Keep signing. - Yes, you go. Go.
Not me, but Shivaji Ganeshan,
Kamala Hassan, Gemni Ganeshan.
Autograph please!
No autographs on hands.. Oh Shanti?
When did you come?
Just now. You gave a superb shot.
Thanks.. a..
..this is nothing. You should
see my death scene some day.
I die splendidly! Very lively.
Is it?
- My spot!
Sir. My on the spot!
And the best thing is, get going,
whichever film I die in..
..becomes a super hit.
In this film, I die four times.
Four Times?
- Yes!
Double role sir! - Double role.
We are twins in the film.
Before lnterval, the villain
kills both of us.
And after the interval
we are reborn.
We kill the villain in the climax
and die again. Mind it!
You are the first person who is
so happy after dying four times.
Thank you! Actually, I love
everything about shooting.
Action! Lights!
Costume! Autograph!
Hey, hope you are not getting bored?
Absolutely not!
Thanks..
What do you like the
most about shooting?
Pack up!
- Pack up!
Hey! Who said pack up?! Break time
is over! Hey you! Sheila, Ramu!
Move towards your set everyone!
Sir Om Prakash,
will you please go on the set?
Come on, move everybody.
Hey! What are you all staring at?
Everybody is looking for
you on the set next door!
Take it easy.
Give the vest also.
This is mine!
- Ok.
No, It is really mine.
Please forgive me Shanti.
I lied to you.
But what could I do?
You are such a big star and
I am just a junior artiste.
Who says you are just
a Junior artiste?
You jumped in the fire for me Om!
You are a hero!
And if I can do anything for you,
I would be delighted to.
Anything, except jumping
in the fire!!
No.. There is something that
you can do for sure..
..but it will be almost like
jumping in the fire for you.
I don't think she will come.
Even I think so.
- Really?
I'm just joking. She will
definitely come. - Shut up.
Is everything ready inside?
Of course! She will have the time
of her life today! Good look.
A promise made, has to kept!
Even if the world stops you..
Wait.. - Hey, this is sister.
- Who is Om Prakash?
If you've to give something then me.
If you've to take something,
then him
Actually Shanti Ma'am has sent me.
She is very sorry that
she cannot come today.
See Pappu! With what style
she has broken my heart!
Forget it, dude. All I had asked
for, was an evening with her!
Please go! And tell your Shanti..
..not to play with someone's
emotions like this.
After all it is not a glass bangle
but my heart that she has broken!
Tell her yourself.
Your culprit is standing right here.
I was telling this idiot
that you will come!
This idiot kept saying you won't!
What Rubbish! I was saying
that you will come.
You are a liar! I was saying that.
You are a liar!
- Un.. unn cut it!!.
How could I not come?
It was a promise made to a
friend I had to keep it.
You have stopped me from
saying thank you..
..but please don't say no to this.
"l have found you but it
seems I have lost myself!"
I want to tell you but
then how do I tell?
I have found you but it
seems I have lost myself!
I want to tell you but
then how do I tell?
In any language that is known
I can't find the words alone..
To tell you, what you mean to me.
What if I say, a beauty like yours..
Can't be found in this cosmos!
Your beauty and allure I may extol..
.. but all this is truly,
nothing at all!
I have found you but it
seems I have lost myself!
A sparkling demeanor flows
from your face..
Your deep dark tresses, descend
in a dazzling maze!
Your scarf that is flowing.. is
like a whiff of cloud blowing.
Draped in your embrace.. are
both beauty and grace!
If I say, charisma as yours..
Can't be found, and
will never be around!
Your beauty and allure I may extol..
.. but all this is truly,
nothing at all!
I have found you but it
seems I have lost myself!
You are very generous today.. then
here is the story from this day.
here is the story from this day
Now me and you cruise the same way,
I'll come with you,
where ever you say!
My beloved, if I say
to you, you are....
a fairy, or a riveting
nymph it's true!
"Your beauty and
allure I may extol.."
"..but all this is truly,
nothing at all!"
You know Om! I don't even remember..
..when was the last
time I was so happy.
But not more than me!
Have you seen heaven? It is
right here, at my feet!
Hmmm.. so you never get sad?
No. Never.
And if I do get sad,
I watch your film.
Because happiness for
me means Shanti!
The queen of hearts! Who is
loved by the entire world!
Sometimes, the entire world's
love is not enough Om.
Sometimes getting love from that
one person is what counts.
You will get that love Shanti. All
you have to do is reach out for it.
You will get whatever you want.
You deserve all the happiness
in the world.
All you have to do is ask!
And then see, happiness
will follow you around!
Really?
- Really!
I will ask Om.
I will go for it. And
I will be happy.
And I will be the king of the world!
Brother!
Why is this Junior Artiste getting
so excited. He's not the hero!
Cut it!
Omi! Look at Salma!
She is playing my sister. Forget it!
Here, take this, I have to go.
Where are you going?
Floor number 7, your sister-in-law
is shooting there.
You Bastard! For God's
sake! Leave me!
If we leave you for the Gods,
then what are we going to do?
Fantastic! Very good!
Forget it Om! These heroines
are heartless!
Om!
Wait here.
Good afternoon ma'am. Please come.
Shanti!
- Wait! Where are you going?
Shantiji knows me!
There are only star's
make up rooms here.
But I am also a star!
- Get lost from here.
Sir is here. Greetings, sir.
I don't know, he was here right now.
Yes I have checked.
Look at this magazine Mukesh.
It says that you are getting
married to Harsh Mittal's daughter!
And getting Mittal Studios
as your wedding gift!
God Dammit! It is all rubbish.
You will hear Gossip like this
everyday, you know why?
Because we are making the biggest,
the most expensive..
.. film ever made in lndia!
Om Shanti Om! I am the Producer of
the film, you are the heroine..
.. and Mittal is the man who
is making all this possible!
Shanti, Mittal has already invested
forty lakhs in this project.
So now stop behaving like
a child and go and shoot.
Delays in shooting schedule
means bad business.
You always think about business.
That's why you are marrying
Harsh Mittal's daughter?
But how are you going to go through
with this wedding Mukesh?
Because you are already married!
To me!
Shanti please! Be quiet.
What if some one hears us? Please
try to understand Shanti!
Why don't you understand Mukesh?
We have been married
for two years now..
..and I can't be acknowledged
as your wife in public!
I don't care for anything
else Mukesh.
Not even Mittal's forty lakhs. All
want, is to be accepted as your wife.
Really? Let me tell
you something Shanti.
The day you will step out
of the house as my wife..
..'Om Shanti Om' will be finished!
Because no one will invest a penny
in a married heroine's film!
Everything will be doomed!
Not only your career,
but my future as well!
You are my future Mukesh.
I am your wife.
You have to accept me in front
of the entire world.
This is what will give me happiness.
And today I want to
make that choice.
Don't I deserve to be happy?!
What is this madness Shanti!?
You will do Om Shanti Om..
..and after it is finished,
we will tell everyone. OK?
But it will be too late by then.
What do you mean?
I mean that I am pregnant!
Mukesh! You're going to be a father!
What? You are Pregnant?
This is.. fantastic!
Why didn't you tell this
to me earlier? - Really?
Of course!
"Neither do I live.."
Nor do I die.
Tell me what to do, l
want to say good bye!
Hearts were torn apart, before
they could be tied.
Souls were separated
in a chasm so wide.
What has destiny in store who knows!
These eyes well up with
tears yet again.
Seeking a glimpse
of you but in vain!
My beloved, this is destiny's game!
How do I live each day? Without
you, it's a desolate bay!
Neither do I live.. nor do I die.
A dream when destroyed..
makes your world a void.
Your love is not your's anymore..
your life is a barren core.
Why does this happen..
..when this heart sobs, around
me the howling winds toss.
And my life seems totally lost.
A dream when destroyed makes
your world a void.
"Your love is not your's anymore.
Your life is a barren core."
Shanti, you did the right thing.
You chose your happiness.
Don't think you have
broken my heart!
I am happy, because you are happy.
But you must tell Mr. Mehra, that
this I am letting him go..
..only for you.
But if I ever happen to meet him
again in any other life time..
..he better watch out! Mind it!!
"There is only solitude
all around me.."
Hey! Hope you are not
getting bored? Thanks!
A dream when destroyed makes
your world a void.
Your love is not your's anymore.
Your life is a barren core.
A dream when destroyed makes
your world a void.
Your love is not your's anymore.
Your life is a barren core.
"Solitude all around.."
Mukesh! Where are you taking me?
I Don't want to see any set!
You don't even want to see
the venue for your wedding?
Really?
It's beautiful Mukesh!
Come! This is the magnificent
set Of 'Om Shanti Om'!
The biggest set of the biggest
film to be made in lndia.
But there will be no shooting here.
Infact, we will dismantle
this set in a few days.
Because I was making this
film only for you..
..and no body can
replace you Shanti.
But before breaking the set..
..we will have a huge party here.
Our wedding party!
Really Mukesh?
Of course! Of course my darling!
Our guests will arrive from here!
Walking on carpets of rose petals.
And there! We will have
a forty piece orchestra..
..playing your favourite songs.
And right here will
be a huge fountain..
..with champagne flowing
in it, instead of water!
And right here! Under this
magnificent chandelier..
.. we will exchange our wedding
vows and get married..
..in front of everyone!
I can't believe it Mukesh!
Mukesh I never thought you
could love me so much!
I am sorry, I didn't trust you.
No! I am sorry too, that
you trusted me Shanti!
If you had not.. then I couldn't
have dreamt so big!
But I did!
I dreamt of being the biggest
and most powerful..
..producer in this industry.
And now, this dream is so big..
..that I can break your trust
but I can't break this dream!
You're hurting me!
No you are hurting me! Did you ever
think about it? Obviously not!
Why did you do all this?
Everything was going perfect!
We had Mittal's Money.
You were going to be the
top heroine of lndia!
That I become a producer, but no..
..you just wanted to be my
wife and ruin everything!
But now you listen to me!
I can not marry you!
And neither can I return
Mittal's money!
Now there is only one way out!
Mukesh!
Because of you this beautiful
set is going to be destroyed!
I am sorry!
- What a shame.
And I've already arranged
for it to burn down!
But this set will not burn alone!
The reason for its ruination
will be burnt with it!
That's you!
I am sorry Shanti! But l
think it is fair enough!
No! Mukesh!
No!
Mukesh!
No! Mukesh please.
Please open the door!
Please open.
Please No, no Mukesh!
Shanti!
Please let me out!
Check that she doesn't come out!
- Ok sir.
Shanti!
Om!
- Shanti!
Shanti.
Congratulations Mr. Kapoor!
It's a boy!
What happened doctor?
Mr. Kapoor. I'm afraid,
it's bad news.
That man you brought in, we could
not save him. He is dead!
Oh my god! Now what Nasser?
Don't worry sir! It was an accident.
The doctor said, the
guy was half dead..
..and injured even before
the accident.
But Nasser, What about his family?
Don't worry sir, I am your
secretary. I will handle everything.
Today it's superstar
Rajesh Kapoor's son..
..Superstar Om Kapoor's birthday..
..and all his fans are
here to wish him!
Happy birthday! Om!
'l will have a luxurious bedroom,
just like the one..
..we see in Yash Chopra's movies..
..with a round bed.'
'When I wake up in the morning,
before my feet..
..even touch the smooth
marble floor..'
..a servant will slip velvety
slippers under them.'
I will wear silk dressing gown like
the prince, when I'll move out..
'The second servant will be standing
there to serve fresh fruit juice.'
Superstar Om Kapoor, better known
as OK, is in his balcony now!
Love you guys, dudes.
Yeah, dad.
- Happy Birthday Son!
Thank you dad!
- Love you!
Wow!
Look, here he comes,
superstar Om Kapoor!
He is only 4 hours late!
Hello everyone!
Sir, Autograph
Sir, Autograph Please
He is so short in real life.
Pappa it's 4'o clock! When
is the hero going to come?
I think I am getting an attack!
C'mon c'mon everybody! Wakeup!
Pappa he's here!
Wakeup! Wakeup! Ready, action!
Sir OK sir, ready sir!
Director?!
- Yes sir!
Tell me the scene!
Sir, as you see sir, this
is the climax scene..
.. where heroine Natasha
is getting married to -
Villian Ranbeer!
Ya, that so rocks babe! Rocks?!
Uh-huh! Nokia! Bluetooth!
You keep talking and I'll keep
talking! Talk! Talk! Talk!
Sir Raj, that's you, his
heart is breaking.
He wants to tell the heroine that
'Natasha I really love you!'
But he can's say it!
Why? Am I mute?
Correct Sir! You remember
your mother's death scene?
Now there is a mother also?!
Sir, sir in mother's death scene,
you scream so loudly..
..that you loose your voice.
Now for the last time, you
want to look at Natasha..
..but sir, you can't even do that!
- Why? Why?
Because you are blind as well sir!
Oh I am blind also! I see.
No sir you don't!
- I don't!
Sir music starts in the background!
You leave foreground!
Natasha turns to look at you and..
One second. Natasha looks at
me, but Natasha is blind!
No sir, you are Blind!
- But I was mute!
Sir you are mute and blind and when
Natasha calls out to you saying,
.."Don't go Raj!" you
don't stop sir..
..because in the film
you are deaf as well!
What the fish! I don't know
what he is talking!
Yes sir, the wedding is happening
in the background..
..and in the foreground it's just
you and your heart's voice!
One second! I am angry now!
- Sir voice over..
Voice over, one second..
Let me read the dialogue.
"Natasha I just want to say that..
..I want to take you away
from this place..
..but I am helpless, l
am on a wheelchair..
..and I have lost both my hands!
Cut Sir! Gone.
I have lost both my hands!
What is this?!
In this film does the Hero have any
of his body parts in working order?
Of course Sir, as you see,
his aching heart!
There won't be any heartache..
..but the audience will definitely
have a headache!
This film will get critical
acclaim and award..
..but let me tell you one thing..
..this film is a flop! - Flop!
This film is gone! You are
dead old man! Dead! - No! No
Unless, I think of
something as usual.
In this situation to express all
this pain, let's put an item song!
Item song. - Yes. A sad item,
may be a trance number..
.. no a sad rock-n-roll,
done to death!
I think it should be a painful..
..disco
Disco!! But Sir..
..in the script we have a handless,
footless, blind and mute actor..
..how do we fit in the disco factor?
Idiot! Dream sequence!!
OK can do anything.
Come on, give me a kiss.
And come here, your heroine is
quite sad. Your girlfriend?
No Sir! My Pappa's.
Pappa! I am sorry Pappa!
We'll have to change her.
Get 5-10 hot girls instead.
I tell you only this song
can make your film a hit!
Come on cheer up now and Pack up!
Pack up?
- I've got an attack!!
"Hey my beauty, My Precious one!"
What spell have you cast on me.
My eyes can't sleep a wink
And my heart is ready to sink.
Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.
My eyes can't sleep a wink
And my heart is ready to sink.
About my poor heart, and
my wandering soul..
Who should I go and tell.
All I can say is, well..
..My heart is full of
the pain of disco.
Pain of disco!
My heart is full of
the pain of disco.
Pain of disco!
My heart is full of
the pain of disco.
Pain of disco!
My heart is full of
the pain of disco.
Pain of disco!
There was a time when the flowers
were blooming all around.
There was a time, lost in
Love's whispering sounds.
There was a time when the flowers
were blooming all around.
There was a time, lost in
Love's whispering sounds.
What a time, when I lived in dreams!
What a time, when l
was drunk on youth!
But that time was short
and I got hurt..
As the bubble of my love
and dreams just burst.
Now I am a wanderer, and a lover
of disco, as I wander around..
..London, Paris, New York,
L.A., San Francisco!
My heart is full of Pain of disco!
Pain of disco!
Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.
Every second was a wild wanting.
Every second was a daring fire.
Blessings were showered
on me in abundance..
And after this shower
I had no other desire.
But once again I find myself alone..
Oh my beloved!
You broke my heart and you left.
to this day, I feel the rift.
And the date you left
was the twenty sixth!
My heart is full of Pain of disco!
Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.
My eyes can't sleep a wink
And my heart is ready to sink.
About my poor heart, and
my wandering soul..
Who should I go and tell.
All I can say is, well..
My heart is full of Pain of disco!
Pain of disco!
Oh God! Cut it! Cut the shot.
OK! OK!
Who put the fire? Don't you know
he has a phobia of fire?!
Phobia of fire? Pappa I didn't know!
You don't know!
- Anwar. Take me home.
Take me home.
- Yes. Pack Up!
Pack up. Father, pack up.
- Pack up!
I am gone. Please everyone-I am ok!
Om! My son! My son!
Where do you keep disappearing
my son?
You know how much I wait for you!
Anwar! Security!
When are you coming
home dear? Tell me.
Listen to me Om! No leave
me! Let me go! Om!
Who is this old woman? She
lands up in every studio!
I feel weird looking at her!
Poor thing is mad! She
thinks you are her son!
Dude, I am a star! Every mother
in lndia thinks I am her son.
That's good! But this is not.
Make sure this doesn't happen
again. Hey! You will get hurt!
Come on! Move it man!
See Pappu, Om has gone and
left me again. Stop him!
Why do you do this
to yourself mummy?
He is not our Om. He is Om Kapoor.
Only his face resembles our Om.
No Pappu, he is my son Om.
Brother! He is my son Om!
Yeah sure! And Amitabh Bachchan
is my dad! Move now!
There are many reasons for
headaches and blackouts.
But he doesn't have any of them.
Anwar! Cancel my dates
for that horny..
..producer and his
idiotic son's film!
And give all my dates to the
superhero project!
Superheroes are in.
I will give the dates but..
..how will those superhero guys
put up a set in one day?
Oh Shut up.If they
don't have a set..
..tell them to shoot
at real location.
Everything is ok with OK!
And please shove this
up your nose, go on.
Shove this up your nose, go on.
What did you say?
Come on, shove it up
your nose, go on.
Come on. No sneezing ok?
Now after this we will
try other holes.
I have been driving for hours now
-Where is this goddamn location?
Couldn't they put up
a set near the house?
They were building a
set near the house..
..but you said to shoot
at a real location.
At such short notice this is the
only place they could find..
What is so special about
this location?
Except being in China
of course!? Ya, idiot!
This studio is completely burnt!
What?! Then why are
we shooting there?
The director wanted an
old abandoned ruin..
..and this place fits perfectly.
In fact this is one of the
most damned places ever!
What do you mean?
30 years ago there was
a big calamity here.
A huge fire broke out
on one of the sets.
The film got shelved and the studio
destroyed! Very unlucky place.
What a wonderful location! It's
unlucky. The set was burnt.
Studio was ruined, even
the film got scrapped!
Well done Anwar! Idiot!
Anwar have we come here before?
Of course not, Nobody comes here!
We will be the first ones
to shoot here in 30 years!
Your credit for two months
is still pending!
Style, hairstyle, face..
How will you become a
star with this name?
Where are you going? There are only
star's make up rooms inside!
Welcome sir!
Dude what a location! Check
it out! Wild place!
Please let me escort you
to the make up rooms..
where are the make up rooms?
This building, second floor.
Right! How did you know?
Let's go take a look at
the rooms! Come on!
Take the shot, man.
Come on. Let's go.
Freaky dude.
Sir, the shot isn't here.
It is downstairs.
Yes, damn!
God! I am so hot! Babes!
What is this costume?
Actors get tortured. I am a star.
And this harness is going up..
Hey! Don't touch my hair please!
And why am I made to wear my
underwear over the costume..
..what is this?
Dude! You are a superhero!
Savior of love!
Love
- man!!
Oh shut up! I feel more
like a moron man!
Come on OK. Spiderman..
..Superman-they also wear
their underwear like this..
Really? Give me a kiss then.
Anyways you are playing
a double role.
In the part where you are a
villager..
..you wear your underwear inside.
Infact the way you wear
your underwear..
..tells us who the
real superhero is!
Oh yeah! That's a good idea.
Whatever, this is my last shot, and
you know I don't give retakes!
That's right! Because when Ok gives
a take- it is an Ok take!!
Roll sound!
- Speed!
Actionsssss
Help!
- "Love- man" to the rescue!
"Love- man"! - To the rescue!
Come, fly with me.
Baby did you enjoy? - Yes!
Come on! Let's dance!
"Oh my God.."
Mongesh it's you? Where is Love?
- Man?
"Oh my God.."
What a fish.
Why didn't they check
with the weather guy?
Come on, come on, move it.
I don't believe this.
Hey Hero! Get some coffee!
Hello. Who is there dude?
Hello. Anyone here?
Sir! What are you doing here?
Who will win the best
actor award today?
My friend, Om Kapoor should win!
Am I right, uncle?
I think Om Kapoor is just.. 'Wow!'
It's Stupid! I am going
to win! Of course.
Ok!!
Good evening Ladies and Gentlemen
and welcome to the filmfare awards!
I have come to fight for the
rights of slum dwellers!
And protest against
this award function!
Who is Om? Chunkey Pandey will win!
OK!
- What OK? Only FK!
Just like a jeweler knows the true
worth of a diamond, likewise..
..Only a 'Johar' knows the
true worth of a hero!
Of course. My son will
get it, Hrithik Roshan.
I think, it will have to be me.
Om and me.. you don't say
these things on camera..
.. we are just good friends.
Om Kapoor and me, we are
just good friends!
Om Kapoor and me are
just good friends.
Om Kapoor and me, we are
I think it should go to Om Kapoor.
Om Kapoor? Who?
OK!
Let's take a look at this year's
nominees for the best actor award!
The best actor nominees..
Abhishek Bachchan in Dhoom 5.
This time he's not a cop!
This time he's not with the babes!
This time he's not going to lose!
Because this time he's
not in the film!
What?!
Come on, Abhishek.
Come on. Come on. - Abhishek.
Om Kapoor for 'Phir
Bhi Dil Hai NRl'!
Rahul's my name, sounds familiar!
Om Kapoor once more in
'Main Bhi Hoon Na'!
Rahul's my name, sounds familiar!
Come on, Akki.
Akshay Kumar in 'Khiladi Returns'!
Tough Fight! Right!
Anyway to give away the best
actor award we have..
..the living legends, Mr. Subhash
Ghai and Rishi Kapoor!
Good evening Ladies and Gentleman.
Good actor brings out somebody's
else's soul..
..into his soul and projects..
..the right kind of emotion,
and the good actor is..
Yeah.
And the winner is..
..Om Kapoor!
Yeah.
I'm the man!
Why are you laughing?
You're in his team?!
This is my award! This is cheating!
This is fraud.
This award is a fraud.
You think I will get an award?
- Of course!
But if the award jury was here, they
would have given the award to you!
Really
- Yes. First accept this..
..'bottle award' from my side!
- Really - Yes.
Love you!
I just want to say..
I have wanted you so much..
I have wanted you so much
and so badly it's true..
..that the entire universe has
conspired for me to get you.
They say, if you want something
with all your heart..
..then the entire universe
will help you get it!
Today, you all have..
Today, you all have given me
everything that I wanted.
Thank you very much.
Thank you! I am thankful
to you all that..
..you've turned my dreams
into reality.
I feel like the king of the world!
Thank you for making
me believe that..
..just like in our films,
in life too..
.. finally in the end, everything
is ok, Happy Endings!
And if it is not happy..
..then it's not 'the
end' my friends..
The film is not over yet!
OM!
Om! Come on! This party is for you!
..and people want to meet you.
Are you ok son?
I don't know dad!
I was thinking
- what if I was not your son?
If I was not Om Kapoor
- only some random guy called Om..
..then I wouldn't get all
this stardom, fame..
..and instead of this award l
may be holding this, who knows!
Lying drunk some where!
I want to promise you today Dad..
that I will really work hard..
.. and I will try to
be a better actor.
If not that, I will try
and be a better son.
Yeah.
I am so proud of you my son!
Come on, this party and all these
special guests are here for you!
And get ready for a surprise!
Ladies and Gentlemen, this one is
for my dear friend and hero..
.. Om Kapoor! OK! We love you!
Tonight is a mystical night we
hail, bit by bit it weaves a tale.
This beautiful sight
takes my breath away!
Stars of heaven are on earth today!
There is no sense of time
no guiding light.
It's just us and the crazy night!
A crazy night! A crazy night!
There is no offense today, and
no one to lead the way..
On whom should this blame we lay?
A crazy night! A crazy night!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
The night is mythical,
it's bliss enticing..
It's casting a spell all around,
which ensnares and bounds!
The night is mythical,
it's bliss enticing..
It's casting a spell all around,
which ensnares and bounds!
"Silky tresses of yours have let
down. - Breaths are fragrant.."
"These are the gestures.."
There is no sense of time
no guiding light!
It's just us and the crazy night!
A crazy night! A crazy night!
There is no offense today, and
no one to lead the way..
On whom should this blame we lay?
A crazy night! A crazy night!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
There is peace and calm around,
yet this heart is fervor bound!
Eyes will knit such furtive
dreams! To her and him..
..it'll tell all and scream!
There is no sense of time
no guiding light.
It's just us and the crazy night!
A crazy night! A crazy night!
There is no offense today, and
no one to lead the way..
On whom should this blame we lay?
A crazy night! A crazy night!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
All cool boys c'mon make some
noise and say 'Om Shanti Om'!
Om, meet my friend Mukesh Mehra!
One of the top producer
of our times!
He was in Hollywood for
the last 25 years.
He wants to come back and make
a very big film with you.
It's great Mukesh!
Call me Mike! Everyone
in Hollywood does.
Om shake hands! Come on!
Fantastic! Let's celebrate Mike!
It's wonderful that you could come.
Om.
You came here, dear.
It is mom.
What took you so long?
I was so scared!
My melodramatic mom!
What is there to get scared?
You know however late it may get,
I will always come back home..
..to you! - Really?
Then why did you leave
me and go? Tell me?
Please forgive me today mother.
I couldn't recognize you.
But you recognized me!
It's so true! Mother's
love is exceptional!
Oh! My Prince! My Prince!
Omi!
Hey! You have grown old!
But you are still the same..
..and now you have become
a star as well!
You only told me to change
my name to a 'Kapoor'!
See Pappu! Didn't I tell you that my
son will definitely become a hero?!
Now you will not leave me and go?
No, I will not go
anywhere this time.
And this time all will be just fine.
Really?
Really!
No one will believe your story.
Sometimes truth is stranger
than fiction.
Om, we won't be able
to prove anything.
And that bastard will
get away again!
Shanti's body was not even found!
And Om, you also disappeared!
Without any proof..
If you want something
with all your heart..
..then the entire universe
conspires for you to get it!
This is what we believed in Pappu!
Mukesh Mehra thinks he has
gotten away with murder!
No evidence! No witness!
But look at this divine
intervention..
..which made me go back
to the same studio..
.. made me recognize myself
made me meet mother, you..
..all this is not just
a coincidence Pappu! No.
This story is being written
by somebody up there!
But this time the climax of the
story will be decided by us.
I can't forget Shanti's
pitiful screams!
I couldn't save her that time..
.. I was helpless, I was a nobody..
..but this time, the
tables have turned.
This time Mukesh Mehra will
pay for all his sins!
This time Shanti will
get justice Pappu.
This time everything
will be all right.
Because the film is not
over yet, my friend!
You want to start 'Om
Shanti Om' again?
That's ridiculous!
You must be joking!
I'm serious Mukesh.
You know I get 3 to 4 scripts
offered everyday..
..but I reject all of them!
But 'Om Shanti Om'!
That's cool!
It has emotion, drama,
romance, action.
I'm sure it's going to be
a blockbuster Mukesh!
Re-incarnation, rebirth..
..who's going to believe all this,
in this day and age?
How does it matter if anyone
else believes in it or not?
As long as you believe in it..
.. as a maker, you have to believe
in the script Mukesh.
Call me Mike. Everyone
in Hollywood does!
Mike! Mukesh becomes Mike..
that's funny Mike!
Thanks to Mike.
That film didn't even have a climax!
I mean that project was jinxed.
Bloody doomed!
Jinxed? The project was jinxed
for that lnsurance Company..
.. who paid you four times the
actual price of your set!
Then you got married to that
Harsh Mittal's daughter..
.. and got a big studio
as your wedding gift!
Then you went to Hollywood,
earned millions of dollars..
..you didn't even take a single
shot and 'Om Shanti Om'..
.. became the biggest film of your
career! So where is the jinx?
You know a lot about me Om!
Call me OK! Everyone
in Bollywood does!
Alright.
- Got you, dude. - OK!
And I Also know that a big accident
happened on your set..
.. and your heroine,
what was her name?
Shanti..
Ya Shanti, what..
..Shantipriya
Shantipriya. What happened to her?
She disappeared!
Oh. I tried to find her
but she was just gone!
Oh gone-if you search hard enough,
you can find God himself!
I don't think you tried too much!
I Like you man. It's a joke. Chill
dude. Hey.. Take it away!
Hey, take it away.
Are you Ok? Ok!
I am not Ok.
I am scared of fire!
Really?
I am scared of fire.
I don't know why.
And.. Seriously speaking if you
want to make any film with me..
.. then it has to be 'Om Shanti
Om', otherwise I am not interested.
You know you are very stubborn OK.
I know that.
I like that.
I am going to America for a month.
If you find a heroine till then..
..we'll start the shoot!
You got it.
You got it. And don't worry
about the climax Mike.
This time I will write the end of
this story myself! Come on, Cheers.
To a new beginning!
To a new end, Mike!
'Pinch of this vermillion'..
shot 1, take 5!
Worth of a pinch of this vermillion
how would you know Ramesh!?
Worth of a pinch of
this vermillion..
.. how would you know Ramesh!?
Worth of a pinch of
this vermillion..
.. how would you know Ramesh!?
How would you know Yogesh..
Not Yogesh! Ramesh! Say!
Worth of a pinch..
What is this pinch of
this vermillion..
Say it with love!
With love? Worth of a pinch
of this vermillion..
..how would you know Ramesh!?
Gift from god..
Gift from what?
I'll kill myself. - You'll die!
- What are you doing?
It's a crown of pride..
..pinch of this vermillion
And what?
It's every woman's dream,
it's ruby sheen!
Say!
A handful vermillion!
It's every woman's dream,
it's ruby sheen!
Aunty, who let you in?
Who did you call Aunty?
Your mother?!
Bye ok!
Later babes! Thanks mom!
If it was 15-20 years earlier, then
I could have played Shanti's role!
We've packed up Om.. and
this was the last batch.
Ya whatever!
But none of them even remotely
resemble Shanti, you know that dude!
We'll find her Omi, we will
definitely find someone.
We don't have much time Pappu!
Mukesh Mehra will be
back in a few days!
How will we find her?
Where will we find her?
Excuse me!
- What?!
Is Om Kapoor here?
No Om Kapoor is not here!
Go! We have already packed up!
Come for auditions tomorrow!
Tomorrow? But the watchman said
auditions are still going on..
..and Om Kapoor is inside.
See, I have come to give an
audition all the way from Bangalore..
.. please give me a chance!
By the way, I am Sandy,
as in Sandhya.
I just love OK, and
I'm his biggest fan.
Actually audition is just
an excuse to meet Ok.
I only want his..
Oh Fish! She's fallen! Pappu
switch on the lights please!
What?
Grace and beauty walk with you.
Oh what a lovely sight!
And the moon bows down to you,
to beg for some ivory light.
Your gaze has seared my heart
so bad, hope it is not in vain.
I want to drown in your eyes
forever never to surface again!
In your eyes there is this magic
I see, magic of a moonlit night.
Your breath blows like
a wind around me..
..carrying my heart away
like a weightless kite.
Good morning everybody!
Dad the hero is here!
Already! But it is
only 11 'o clock!!
'Crippled Love'! Shot 3! Take 1!
- Action!
Cut it! Superb!
One minute director sir.
One more for me!
I can do better than this,
at least give me a chance..
Worth of a pinch of this
vermillion, how would you know?
It's a gift from God!
This crimson dot.
This crimson dot
It's a crown of pride,
for an lndian bride!
What's so funny?
What is so damn funny!
What is so funny?
Why are you laughing?
Is this a joke?
Why don't you understand?
Pappu she can't be our Shantipriya.
She is not like Shanti at all!
She is so stupid!
I know you are not an actress
and you can't act..
.. but you can try at least!
We are all trying here!
You are laughing!
Incompetent Mutt! Get out of here!
Now you've made her cry!!
Om, we all are trying!
But the poor thing doesn't even
know why are we doing all this!
What is our plan?! What plan!
This plan can only be
successful when..
.. Mukesh Mehra believes
that Shantipriya is back!
She only looks like Shantipriya!
She can't be like Shantipriya.
It'll take one second for
Mukesh Mehra to figure out,
that she's not Shanti!
Then he's gone! He'll take
the next flight out!
The plan will be finished!
Then we'll have to tell
her everything Om!
We'll have to tell her what is all
this.. and why is it so important?
Before being Shanti, she will
have to understand her Om!
Om Shanti Om's story is
the story of my life.
I should have told you
all this before Sandy!
Because without understanding
Om's pain..
.. you won't be able
to be his Shanti.
But how could I tell you?
No one would have believed my story!
Not even you!
I will not believe your story Om?
When you jump from a fifty
storey building..
.. and manage to stand on your
own two feet, I believe you.
You fight 100 goons and save
the heroine, I believe you!
You fly in the air, run on water!
I believe all this Om!
Then how could you ever think that
I will not believe your story?
I'm sorry Sandy. I really am..
It's ok. There is still time!
And this time I will try
with all my heart Om!
And I won't let you down!
Thank you Sandy.
Mummy? - These are tears
of happiness my boy!
That's unbelievable OK!
In such a short while..
The set, script, and
even the heroine?
..you have finalized everything.
- That's nothing.
My people have organized an
inaugural ceremony as well!
Oh God, no. This ceremony!
This offering of prayers..
.. taking the prints to
a temple for blessings..
.. all this still happens here?
It's so damn primitive!
Even I don't believe in all this!
That's why I've kept the ceremony
at a very unusual place.
Stay cool, Mike.
I like surprises!
Oh yes! You will be surprised!
What the hell is this OK?
From all the places, you
had to find this place?
You know this is the
same place where?
This is the place where
the accident happened..
.. and the entire studio
was burnt down!
I know, I know everything!
That's why I have chosen this place.
It's called the 'circle
of life' Mike!
An unfinished story
should always start..
.. from the point where
we left it, right?
Rockstar, okay.
Why did you resume making
Om Shanti Om?
How else would we finish
making the film?
And this place..
- Mike! Come on!
Sir. - And he is the director of
the film, what's your name?
F. Khan.
- Yes! My childhood friend F. Khan!
You should have checked with me
once. I wasn't expecting this!
There are lots of unexpected
things in store for you..
Dudes! The producer!
His friends call him Mike!
You can call him Mukesh Mehra!
And now dudes, let's
talk about the babes!
The heroine of the film is,
what's her name? - Dolly!
My childhood friend, Dolly!
Oh! Here she comes!
Oh wow.
You will really like her Mike!
She's very sexy!
I hope so!
"When I touched it with my lips,
there was a commotion.."
That's her?!
No! That's Dolly's mom!
"There was a commotion.."
What's her name?
- Kamini.
Kamini my childhood friend!
Hello Mr. Producer!
Baby was so excited to see you that
she didn't sleep the entire night!
Only the fear of dark
circles made her sleep!
But I never compromise
on my beauty sleep!
I can see! You look
as fresh as a daisy!
Thank you! You 'cutey'!
Where is baby?
- There's baby!
Hey, answer our questions, please.
Beautiful girl!
Baby, touch his feet! Oh!
She is so talented!
Hello Omi!
- Yes Pappu!
I am taking all of them on the set.
Is mom ready?
Yes she is ready, but she
is really over acting!
That's our family problem!
Ten for.
- Oh mom! Let's go!
What let's go! You don't understand!
Let me come in the character!
You'll come in the
character for sure!
But we have to go now, they're
all ready! Let's go!
What was the line?
- Don't go inside!
Don't go inside!
In my next film, I want a ponytail
like Mike's! It's cool!
What happened Mike?
Why have you put up a set here?
Obviously man. I told you..
'circle of life'!
An unfinished story should
always start.. - I know!
You know! That's cool buddy!
Let's go!
Come, we'll have fun.
Come on, let's go inside.
Beware! Don't go in!
What the hell is this?
Don't touch me! Leave me!
Security. - She has been waiting
for you for a long time!
What's up, dude?
She will not leave you!
Who will not leave him?!
- Who will not leave him?!
Shanti!
Mummy! - Don't cry baby,
your liner will get spoilt.
She is a psycho mummy,
why are you getting scared?!
Is there someone inside?
Possible..
Mike! Isn't the set nice?!
Oh, Mr. Rajesh. - Oh Dad!
Hey Mike.
Hi Mukesh!
- Hi Rajesh!
Mike meet Shahwar.
Shahwar meet Mike!
He is the villain of our film!
A dude like you dude!
OK, it is time to break the coconut.
We have to break the coconut!
- What?!
Coconut breaking time!
Everybody, let's go. Coconut time.
Priest. - Take this. Take this.
This is for peace.
'Om shanti shanti shanti'!
Oh for Peace! But Mukesh, the
coconut should break in one go!
Otherwise it's considered to
be inauspicious! Right Dad?
Oh of course! C'mon Mukesh!
You can do this.
Oh fish! Didn't break! Don't
worry Mike, try again! Go on!
Oh God! It's very bad luck!
- Yeah! - Mike! Let me do it..
No! I'll do it!
Ok! One more time! C'mon guys!
Are you ok Mikey?
What is this nonsense!
Don't worry Mikey, I know
you are out of practice..
.. you don't break coconuts
in Hollywood!
But here, before starting
any auspicious project..
.. we break a coconut..for peace!
We can break all kind of nuts!
Come on!
Come on.
Congratulations.
Ladies and Gentlemen.. Babes!
Lots of speeches today!
On this occasion we would
like to pay a tribute..
..to that actress for whom this
film was originally written!
I believe wherever she is..
..she is watching over us.
Right! Ladies and Gentlemen..
..Shantipriya!
And now I request Dolly
,my childhood friend..
.. to light the lamp and take
Shantipriya's blessings.
While she does that I will
come down! Come on Dolly!
As soon as you press this button..
..there will be a spark
behind that photo.
If there's no spark behind that
photo, I'll whack you!- lt'll happen!
One! Two! Three!
What's happening? Why
is it not working?
It seems the wire is loose,
one minute..
How can it be loose? I told you
to check! - I'll just see!
Oh shit. Oh fish.
Help!
Come on, hurry up.
Someone put out the fire!
Run out.
Move back.
Don't go inside!
Mummy! What superb acting!! Take
this fake coconut from my side!
And take these fake eye
brows from my side too!!
It must have been good fun today?!
We'll have fun tomorrow!
Big day tomorrow Sandy!
You remember the plan?
Yes.. but I'm nervous. What
if I make a mistake?
No! There will be no mistake.
Don't be nervous.
Let's discuss the plan
once more, alright?
Tomorrow we'll all be
there for the shooting.
Baby! Stop playing with your phone
and practice your dialogues!
Mukesh Mehra will also be there..
Madam your shot is ready.
Oh! Shot is ready! Let
me touch up my makeup!
Not yours, Dolly madam's shot..
As soon as I get a chance..
..I will send a message to
Mukesh from Dolly's phone..
.. telling him to meet her
in the make up room, alone.
As far as I know Mukesh,
he will definitely go.
Pappu, he's coming!
You take Sandy with you and
reach the make up room. Yeah.
Nothing can go wrong now dude!
Where is she?!
Where is Dolly's mother Kamini?
She has gone to touch
up her make up!
Why does she need touch..
where has she gone?
Greenroom.
Where is she?!
Oh Fish!
Kamini!
Kamini! Kamini!
OK, you! Why is he following me?
I know you don't need this..
..but you forgot your compact,
I came to give it.
Oh! Very sweet of you! Why
did you take the trouble?
You should have sent
it with a spot boy.
No problem at all ma'am!
You cutey!
Kamini! One minute!
What are you doing?!
Compact was just an excuse..
..actually I wanted
to meet you alone.
Why?
Because, you know..
..I've always liked older women!
You know darling, when l
saw you the first time..
.. I knew that something
would happen between us.
But I didn't know it'll
happen so soon.
A sexy girl like you should
be in Hollywood!
I can take you there!
Just make sure this is our secret..
Mike what happened?
Hey, look at your hair,
it is a mess man.
What happened?
- lnside! - lnside?
There is somebody inside!
Oh God! Here also there is somebody?!
Mike you look as if
you've seen a ghost!
Ghost! I told baby not
to remove her make up!
Don't worry. Take it easy!
What are you doing Kamini! Please!
Mike come here! There
is nobody here!
See. There is nobody here!
- But I saw..
Did you see anyone going
out of this room? - No..
Did you see anyone going inside
the room?! Nobody is here Mike.
Dude, old man, relax!
By the way, what were you
doing in Dolly's greenroom?
Yes, what were you doing?
I was looking for a bathroom.
I was lost.
If you want to use the
bathroom next time..
.. please go to my green
room, not Dolly's!
You should respect women,
what say Kamini?
And love them too!
- Kamini! Take it easy.
Cheers Mikey!
How are you feeling now?
I mean you've not been coming
for shooting lately.
The entire unit was missing you..
especially Dolly and her bathroom!
A producer has many other important
things to attend to Ok.
Anyways, you are there to
take care of the shoot!
Yeah of course! I am there!
Let's watch the Scenes?
- Yeah!
Projectionist put reel number nine.
After watching these scenes..
you'll be stunned! Intense man!
I didn't know Ramesh that
you love me so much!
And you want to marry me!
That also here..
Forgive me Ramesh!
I didn't trust you!
You will come down from there,
dressed like a bride..
.. just like a fairy descending
from heaven..
Ramesh!
What's that? Take it easy!
What's wrong man?!
Did you see?
- Who?
Who?
- Her.. - Dolly?
NO! Not Dolly! That girl..
You're obsessed with Dolly!
Which girl? - The other girl!
It's a gift from God!
This crimson dot.
It's a crown of pride,
for an lndian bride!
Mikey stop drinking! I think
you are getting high!
And Watch!
It's every woman's dream!
It's ruby sheen!
There! Look!
Stop the Projection!
Put on the lights!
Hey dude what are you doing?
What is this nonsense?
There is nobody on that
screen, except Dolly!
What's wrong with you?
You don't believe me?
One second! One second!
Projectionist play this reel again!
Ok Boss!
Relax! Watch now! Nobody
will come, watch!
It's a gift from God!
This crimson dot.
It's a crown of pride,
for an lndian bride!
It's every woman's dream!
It's ruby sheen!
What?! Everything is fine! See?
How is it possible?
- What is possible?
I swear OK! I saw her! She was here!
She was here, there! Who is
this girl you see everywhere?
First on the sets, then make
up room, and now here!
You know the entire unit is
already saying you are mad!
Tell me Mikey am I working
for a mad man?
If the press gets to
know about this..
I'm not crazy goddammit!
I'm not crazy!
So then what? Am I crazy?!
Am I mad?!
I am handling everything be it
casting, ceremony or the shooting!
You don't even come on the sets!
And now this madness! What's
wrong with you Mike?
I don't know OK. I can't
understand anything!
I think I should go back
to America! - What?!
Yeah! That's what I'm going to do.
I think I will leave tomorrow
night itself!
No! You can't leave!
I mean we have our music
launch in two days!
You will have to stay
back for that atleast!
No OK! I can't stay here anymore!
I have to go.
No. Anyways you are here to take
care of the Music launch..
.. what's the big deal?
It is a bloody big deal Mikey!
Media, guests, distributors,
everybody will be there..
And if the producer of the film
won't come how will it look?
And I am not your servant! No!
I can't handle everything for you!
I am a star Mikey, I'm a superstar!
So let me tell you one thing..
I am through with your 'Om Shanti
Om'! Take your film and stuff it!
Go back to L.A. Whatever!
And one more thing, I can
do ten other films..
.. but you have borrowed a lot
of money from the market..
..and if 'Om Shanti Om' is shelved
again, you will be on the roads!
You will be finished Mikey!
No, you can't do this!
Oh shut up! Don't
show me the finger!
I can do this and I will!
If you want 'Om Shanti Om' to
finish, and get released..
..then be there for
the music launch!
Otherwise you and your film
both, can go to hell!
Because frankly my dear,
I don't give a damn!
So fish it!
Have you lost it Om?
How will we prepare everything
in two days?
This plan was supposed to be
carried out after three weeks!
What could I do Pappu?
You were there!
He was saying he will
go back to America.
So I used any excuse to stop him!
But Om, how will we make
it work in two days?
We have to fix the cameras
on the entire set..
..we have to build a monitor room!
Everyone will have to be briefed.
And even Sandy is not
fully ready yet!
Om I will try, but what
if I make a mistake..
There can be no mistake now Sandy!
He can't get away this time!
We'll have to make Mukesh
Mehra believe that..
..that Shanti has come back!
That's the only way he'll confess!
It's all upto you Sandy!
You'll have to scare him so much..
..that he blurts out the truth!
Frankly I have serious
doubts about your plan!
Scaring him off! Letting him think
that Shanti is back, forget it!
Nothing is going to happen
Om! He won't come.
He will run away tonight itself!
If you want something
with all your heart..
.. the entire universe conspires
for you to get it!
He will definitely come Om!
Don't worry Son!
Pappu! You go and arrange
for everything!
I know he will come..
..because the film is not over yet!
There is tale I have to tell
About a man who lost his heart,
and gave up his life as well!
The one who loves this way..
Can he die? Even if
death takes him away?
Come, hear this fable today!!
Once upon a time a man
loved a beauty..
..but his love for
her he had to hide!
For the lady was famed for her
beauty..
..in the world far and wide!
A tale of these two hearts alone..
..is the saga of 'Om Shanti Om'!
The man had only one dream.
For the beautiful lady to
be his heart's queen!
The man had only one dream.
For the beautiful lady,
to be his heart's queen!
Little did he know,
it was all in vain..
What he thought was happiness,
turned out to be pain!
Why did this happen, and for
what..is the entire tale!
The story goes..
The beauty had already
given her heart away.
Our man unaware, was
still ensnared..
But his dreams had
to shatter one day.
Tale of shattered dreams and
a broken heart left lone..
.. is the saga of 'Om Shanti Om'!
There is a tale I have to tell..
The one who laughs the most,
one day he cries as well..
The beauty was, madly in love..
In return she was battered!
Listen how her trust was
completely shattered!
The story goes..
The man, the beauty had her heart
on, from inside was a con!
Because she loved a rogue..
She was caught in his lies, and
one day he left her to die!
The heartbreak of a woman who died
lone..
..is the saga of 'Om Shanti Om'!
Why does a murderer not understand?
It's a crime that cannot
be buried in the sand.
It's a stain that never will
fade,but is stamped.
And will remain etched
forever on his hand!
When the beauty was slayed..
Someone did reach there in haste.
He tried to save her,
but it was too late.
Love had to shed
tears for the loss!
The story goes..
That someone who saw
the killer's face..
..that man has come back today!
Listen to the life's pace..
what it says..
The felon should know now, death
is dancing around him and how!
This circle of life, death
and karma well known!
Is the saga of 'Om Shanti Om'!
What happened?
Guests will walk on carpets
of petals and come in.
There we'll have a forty
piece orchestra....
playing Shanti's favourite songs.
Over there is a fountain with
champagne flowing in it..
..instead of water!
And under this magnificent
chandelier, we will get married.
Who are you?
And how do you know all this?
Ya, you said all these things..
..to Shanti when you were alone.
But there was someone
else there as well..
..who not only heard all this..
..but also witnessed your
horrifying crime!
That was me Mukesh!
No! That's not possible!
Impossible, but true!
That night Shanti did not die alone!
I died with her!
Om Prakash!
Who used to play small roles in
your big films, a Junior artiste.
I could not save my Shanti.
But I will get justice for her!
You will be punished Mukesh!
You will pay for your sins!
Sandy this is your cue.
You know what to do?
Yes Pappu. But I am very scared!
This is no time to get scared, you
need to scare other people off!
Everything depends on
you now. You can do it!
Best of lucks! Go dear!
That's brilliant OK! Fantastic!
You got me!
So you will send me to Prison? How?
You will stand in the court and
narrate your saga of reincarnation?
Why don't we do one thing,
let me confess everything!
But who will make me confess?!
You or your duplicate Shanti?
You thought you will get a two
bit actress and scare me off..
.. so that I admit everything?
But you see OK..
Ghosts don't get hurt,
they don't bleed!
So now why don't you and your
goddamn Shanti go to hell!
Oh God! He knows everything!
Anwar stop Sandy! This
bastard can do anything!
Pappu the door is jammed!
And you know what the problem is OK?
Court of law wants evidence..
..which you don't have.
Even if I have killed Shanti,
then where is her body?
No one has found her body yet!
And believe me..
..OK, Om whatever!
Without this evidence..
.. even God can't touch me!
I will give the evidence, Mukesh!!
Oh God, Sandy.
Come! We were missing you!
- He knows.
You don't need to continue with
your rubbish acting now!
Go away, Sandy.
- Stop this acting or else..
Else what? You'll kill me? - Sandy
he knows everything, keep quiet!
How many times will
you kill me Mukesh?
Sandy he knows everything!
You just go from here.
Oh, just shut up. I don't want
to listen to your nonsense!
You will have to listen Mukesh.
And listen carefully.
You came back that night!
After the fire died down,
you came back Mukesh!
Yes I did, so what?
- Sandy, listen to me Sandy.
To put away my dead body!
What rubbish!
I wasn't dead Mukesh!
I was still breathing!
How do you know all this?
- But you buried me alive!
Under this chandeliar!
- Who are you?! - Stop it, Sandy!
The court needs proof..
- Stop it, I said, stop it.
..they will get the proof Mukesh!
They will not get anything!
Right here under this chandelier,
they'll find Shanti's dead body!
I said shut up! There
is nothing here!
Which you buried that night!
There is nothing here!
You are going to pay
for your sins Mukesh!
You are going to die!
Shut up! Or I will shoot you!
No!
Mukesh!
Om.. you don't kill him.
No!
He's destined to die!
He's destined to die..
..but you're not going to kill him!
No!
Om!
- Omi.
'So you buried me alive.'
'Under this chandelier.'
'You'll find Shanti's body
under this chandelier.'
Om! I'm sorry!
I couldn't..
- It's ok.
Because the film
is not over yet, my friend!
Wow!
Wow! - Love you!
"Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.!"
"My eyes can't sleep a wink. And
my heart is ready to sink."
"Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.!"
"My eyes can't sleep a wink. And
my heart is ready to sink."
"About my poor heart and my wandering
soul. Who should I go and tell?"
Wow!
"Pain of disco.."
There was a time when the flowers
were blooming all around.
There was a time, lost in
Love's whispering sounds.
There was a time when the flowers
were blooming all around.
There was a time, lost in
Love's whispering sounds.
What a time, when I lived in dreams!
What a time, when l
was drunk on youth!
But that time was short and
I got hurt as the bubble of..
..my love and dreams just burst..
Now I am a wanderer, as
I wander around London..
..Paris, New York, L.A.,
San Francisco!..
Pain of disco!
Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.
Every second was a wild wanting.
Every second was a daring fire.
Blessings were showered
on me in abundance..
And after this shower
I had no other desire.
But once again I find myself
alone. Oh my beloved!..
You broke my heart and you left..
to this day, I feel the rift.
And the date you left
was the twenty sixth!
"Hey my beauty, My Precious one!
What spell have you cast on me.!"
"My eyes can't sleep a wink. And
my heart is ready to sink."
"About my poor heart and
my wandering soul.
Who should I go and tell?"
Pain of disco!
'Om Shanti Om'!
There is peace and calm around,
yet this heart is fervor bound!
Eyes will knit such furtive
dreams! To her and him..
..it'll tell all and scream!
There is no sense of time
no guiding light.
It's just us and the crazy night!
A crazy night! A crazy night!
There is no offense today, and
no one to lead the way..
On whom should this blame we lay?
A crazy night! A crazy night!
All the hot girls put your hands
up and say 'Om Shanti Om'!