I would say...
...that you are now on a place -
- where we have buried something
from you to protect you.
And we have taken great... pain -
- to be sure that you are protected.
We also need you to know -
- that this place
should not be disturbed.
And we want you to know -
- that this is not a place
for you to live in.
You should stay away from this
place, and then you will be safe.
I am now in this place
where you should never come.
We call it Onkalo.
Onkalo means "hiding place".
In my time it is still unfinished -
- though work began in the 20th
century when I was just a child.
Work will be completed in the
22nd century, long after my death.
Onkalo must last 100000 years.
Nothing built by man
has lasted a tenth of that time.
But we consider ourselves
a very potent civilization.
If we succeed, -
- it will most likely be the longest
lasting remains of our civilization.
If you,
some time far into the future, -
- find this,
what will it tell you about us?
Once mankind started to use nuclear
power to generate electricity -
- it was obvious that we would
also generate some waste -
- which has to be treated
so that it doesn"t... harm anybody.
And you can"t make
nuclear waste go away.
You cannot make
nuclear waste harmless.
So... several ways of how to get
rid of the waste were explored.
Send it in a rocket out to the sun.
It disappears;
it will never make harm to anyone.
But how to ensure that the rocket
doesn"t explode on the launch pad?
Or sinking it to deep sea...
We would never be able to claim -
- that we can safely put something
into the bottom of the oceans.
Because still we have an impression -
- that the oceans are
really the mother of all life.
It"s not a safe way of handling spent
nuclear fuel or radioactive waste.
How much waste
exists in the world today?
Totally?
I am not quite aware.
I would say between
200000 and 300000 tons.
Somewhere between these two.
We already have enormous
amounts of nuclear waste.
If this waste spills out into nature
it will cause death and destruction.
Large areas will become
uninhabitable for a long, long time.
Did that happen? Are there forbidden
zones with no life in your time?
A hundred years ago,
just three human generations ago, -
- when radiation
was first discovered, -
- we didn"t understand
that it was very dangerous.
But we noticed that it can be useful
and we started to work with it.
Radiation is a sort of energy which
can penetrate deep into your body -
- and harm your health.
But it is an invisible danger.
We have no sense for it: You cannot
see it, feel it or smell it.
And still it may even kill you.
Radiation may be described
as small packages of energy.
And when they hit the genetic code,
the DNA molecule, they can break it.
If you have a very serious whole-body
exposure you don"t feel anything -
- until one hour or so afterwards
when you start to feel nausea, -
- and you may vomit, and you may
think you have got food poisoning.
In between you may feel better.
After two weeks you start to bleed.
You have diarrhoea and fever.
And after a few weeks
you may even die from this.
Radiation can also
leave a trace in you.
It can change the genes.
Mutate the genes.
It may cause malformation
or disease or dysfunction.
So: Beware! Never stay in an area
with an enhanced radiation level.
And never, ever touch upon
a strong radiation source!
So we are storing the waste today
above ground in water pools.
The reason why
it"s kept in water -
- is that water creates
a shield for radiation.
Keeping the waste in tanks -
- is probably possible for the next
ten years, 20 years, 100 years.
1000 years...?
You just can"t guarantee stable
conditions above ground -
- for instance... for...
...well... for one hundred years,
let alone thousands of years.
These storages need surveillance.
They need power in order
to cool the water pools.
They need maintenance.
But we can"t keep this waste forever
in the water pools.
There"ve been two world wars
during the last 100 years.
The world above ground -
- is unstable.
We have to find a permanent solution.
Or a safer solution -
- in the long run.
My civilization depends on energy
as no civilization before us.
Energy is the main currency for us.
Is it the same for you?
Does your way of life
also depend on unlimited energy?
What we must do is to take care of
the waste from nuclear power plants.
More and more, societies
that are using nuclear power -
- are realising that
they have to do something.
We obtained the energy.
We have used the energy.
Of course it is our mission
to also take care of the waste.
There is no way of doing nothing.
This is something which ought to be
the responsibility of all citizens.
Irrespective of whether
they like nuclear power or not.
Linking the issue of
nuclear waste with nuclear power -
- could easily divert attention
from the material which we have -
- and must somehow handle
in a responsible way.
Not to harm future generations.
This tunnel feels like
a time capsule sometimes.
When you arrive in the morning -
- it may be sunny,
almost like summer outside.
When you come out again
at the end of the day -
- it may have
snowed like hell.
The weather will have
changed completely, -
- and you think "How long
did I actually spend in the tunnel?"
And likewise:
You go to work and it"s dark, -
- and when you come back up
after work it is dark.
And it feels like time has stopped.
Five, four, three, two, one, fire!
Final disposal
of spent nuclear fuel -
- hasn"t been implemented
anywhere so far.
We are forerunners in this field.
And we are dealing with
very, very long time frames.
Meaning that this repository
should last at least 100000 years.
100000 years is beyond our
understanding and imagination.
Our history is
so short in comparison.
How is it with you?
How far into the future will your
way of life have consequences?
That"s what we really want to prove:
That we can isolate the waste -
- from human beings and other
live organisms for 100000 years.
We have come to a conclusion -
- that the bedrock,
the Finnish bedrock -
- 1.8 billion years old -
- is the medium that we can
predict far into the future.
At least 100000 years ahead.
A very important factor is that
the repository is self-contained.
We shouldn"t have
to guard it in the future.
It should just be able to be left.
And that"s a necessity. Because
conditions on the ground will change.
The conditions down
in the rock will be stable.
But on the surface you never
know what"s going to happen.
There could be wars, there could
be an economic depression.
At the surface
the clock runs very fast.
In the rock
it goes very, very slowly.
It"s the most stable
environment we know of.
Olklluoto, Eurajokl
has been chosen
- as the slte of the dlsposal
faclllty for spent nuclear fuel.
Onkalo.
Where are you now on the plan?
We"re here somewhere.
Then we"II start widening this area.
More, more, a bigger area comes.
Like a big cave, or...
An unimaginable big cave...
it"s like a big city underground.
The repository acts like a cocoon,
if you like, a Russian doll.
With barriers that
complement each other.
If one barrier might fail -
- other barriers are able to
mitigate all the consequences.
The flnal dlsposal faclllty
wlll be constructed In stages -
- and decommlssloned In the 2100s.
When It Is ready-
- a thlck concrete closure
Is cast at the tunnel mouth.
We will fill the chambers of Onkalo
with nuclear waste from Finland, -
- one little country in the north.
After one century we will seal
Onkalo for all eternity, -
- just like the tombs
in the Pyramids were sealed -
- never to be opened again.
The safety of disposal
shall not be dependent -
- on any active management,
or active surveillance, -
- or any acts of
human beings to be safe.
So it has to be fully passive.
The repository will be closed down;
it will be back filled.
The idea of this back filling
is to return the conditions -
- to those which prevailed
before we excavated the tunnel.
There will be forests,
there will be houses.
Hopefully
there will still be people, -
- not perhaps the same persons
who were there from the beginning.
But perhaps their
children and grandchildren -
- will still live
and use the land.
We always bring up
the question of the Ice Age -
- as some kind of very
dramatic change -
- in the situation.
And of course it will have an impact.
If we look at our
assumptions and scenarios -
- it will happen
within 60000 years from now.
So everything... disappears...
...disappears from here
when the ice comes.
Everything gets frozen,
the vegetation will die -
- and then this will be
more like a... tundra.
Would it be forgotten
during an ice age?
Yes, I think it would be
forgotten in such a case.
If you were a person evaluating
this concept from the outside -
- what would you be afraid of?
Nothing.
Once upon a time
man learned to master fire, -
- something no other living creature
had done before him.
Man conquered the entire world.
One day he found a new fire, -
- a fire so powerful that it could
never be extinguished.
Man revelled in the thought -
- that he now possessed
the powers of the universe.
Then in horror he realised that his
new fire could not only create, -
- but also destroy.
Not only could it burn on land, -
- but inside all living creatures, -
- inside his children,
the animals, all crops.
Man looked around for help
but found none.
And so he built a burial chamber deep
in the bowels of the earth, -
- a hiding place for the fire to burn
...into eternity.
You are now in the tunnel.
This place is not
a place of honour.
No esteemed deeds
are commemorated here.
You should not have come here.
You are heading towards a
place where you should never go.
What is there is
dangerous and repulsive.
The danger will still be present,
in your time, as it is in ours.
Please turn around
and never come back.
There is nothing here for you.
Go no further.
My personal belief -
- is that no human intrusion will
take place at any time scale ever.
We recognized that this could happen.
That you might find and open Onkalo.
We refer to it as "human intrusion".
We don"t want this to happen
because you may get hurt.
But most of all -
- we are afraid of human intrusion
because if Onkalo is opened, -
- the waste will no longer be
isolated from all living organisms -
- and we will have failed.
In fact we consider you the main
threat to the safety of Onkalo.
If someone in the future is able
to dig down to the repository -
- it will probably be a civilization
of the same kind as we have.
In such a case they would
also be knowledgeable -
- to know that
this is radioactive material.
I think that"s the most probable
scenario but l"m not so sure.
It could be another situation.
I think if someone found
a facility like that in the future -
- they might interpret it
as something religious.
A burial ground.
Or a treasure.
If we look at the pyramids, -
- we cannot really say that
we understand everything -
- about the significance
of their erection.
But we can assume that
this could be the same -
- for our repository.
It will be interpreted the same way
as we interpret the pyramids.
There is no clear understanding
and it is quite possible -
- that we will not be
understood by the future, -
- especially
by the distant future.
What if someone
finds the repository?
How should they know what it is?
They should have some measuring
tools to measure the radiation.
What if they don"t have that?
Then they"II have
to make a chemical analysis.
What if they can"t do that?
Then they cannot
do the drilling either.
Ancient civilizations have
done remarkable things.
Look at the mining
industry in Sweden -
- in the 16th century; they went
down several hundred meters.
We must realize that
the future scenarios -
- are notjust hi-tech or very
low-tech stone-age scenarios.
We have scenarios in the middle -
- where people may drill
but may not understand, -
- may not have the technology
to understand what they meet.
The Roman empire was born,
lived, prospered, and died.
Similarly also the West will go
through the same kind of phases.
Being born, flourishing,
developing, crumbling, and dying.
What do we know about
society in 300 years?
Virtually impossible
to say anything.
We might expect society
as we know it -
- to exist for 50 years more.
For 100 years.
If you are convinced
of what will happen then, -
- let"s put the question
on 300 years, 500 years" time.
Then the darkness thickens.
We know that
society changes very fast.
Could we imagine
a society in the future -
- where science and technology did
not matter as they matter for us?
Well, that is of course
entirely possible.
They might go up in technology,
they might go down.
And we don"t really know. If we
assume something in the future -
- they could go back
to the Neanderthal.
I think it is the changes
that we will... get short for.
The design and the construction,
the implementation has to be done -
- so that no knowledge
is necessary for the future.
So that it can be safe
also in the case -
- that people have
lost the knowledge.
We used to have a joke.
"When we start the
digging for the repository -
- the first thing we will experience
is a copper canister -
- of exactly the same
kind we want to place ourselves."
Of course you would start to think:
"There must be a reason for this."
You have the scenario
of the hidden treasure.
You have the idea that something
is there, that it is valuable.
People would start to dig for it.
You could have the scenario
where people even know -
- it"s dangerous. But it"s also
valuable at the same time.
Could the waste also in the future
have the value of gold or even more?
Well, just to answer the question
honestly, yes, it could.
It is a treasure.
There is a lot of copper, uranium,
plutonium... It could be valuable.
What is unpredictable
is human behaviour.
Who knows why people
might come and drill a hole?
There must be a reason
to start to dig down 500 metres -
- in just average
ordinary rock!
But what could prevent them
from doing that?
I wouldn"t know.
Could it be that the knowledge
of what"s there is incomplete?
- Of course.
- What if a sign said "Don"t drill"?
That might be a case for, let"s say,
a certain period of a time at least.
- What do you mean?
- If you put a marker...
They"re called markers.
So this is a concept that...
It"s an idea which has been
been thought over.
An area
where disposal has been made -
- could be marked using markers.
The obvious marker
is an object with text on.
Just like a rune stone.
This is a typical marker -
- with messages repeated in different
United Nation languages.
General information about the area,
and more detailed information also.
And that in turn is part
of a whole marker system -
- where you might have
more detailed information yet -
- if you went to another
place at that same site.
There would be a message
kiosk, for instance.
It is a more detailed message
than the one on the monolith.
Further on you"d have messages
like a small library in carved rock.
Perhaps underground.
What would be
the content of the information?
To say that this is not an important
place; it is a place of danger.
Stay away from the site.
And not disturbing the site.
We will leave written
information for you -
- in all the major
languages of our time.
Will you understand any of them?
Can you read?
And that"s of course
a mind-boggling scenario.
How do you communicate?
We won"t speak the same language.
They won"t have the same symbols.
We have to find
something very general.
This is where the cartoon comes in, -
- with low sophistication
but a robust message.
This is an attempt
to give you a feeling, -
- rather than a detailed message.
Intuitively you would expect people
to react to something frightening -
- better than to a detailed message.
Forbidding blocks,
"Landscape of Thorn", -
- landscapes
that would get you to feel -
- that this is
something which is wrong, -
- this is something not inviting.
When you opened Onkalo,
did you see "Landscapes of Thorn?"
Did it make
you hesitate?
Or maybe curious?
What drove you to enter?
Was it the scars we left
on the surface? Or a rumour?
In terms of emotional information, -
- there was an interest in a picture
by Edvard Munch, "The Scream".
To portray something
that was negative.
It shows the feeling of despair.
It is very clear to the observer
that it"s not something good.
But do you think this will be
clear to all ages, all times?
I think it has a fair chance,
yes, I do.
- It"s universal?
- Universal for humans.
We are not sure how
to overcome the problem -
- of leaving markers to warn you.
Messages from long-Iost civilizations
were found in our times -
- but it took years to understand
the language and the signs.
Some, we still cannot read.
If we put something that is
not completely understandable -
- and the future people don"t
understand what it means -
- they"II want to find out.
People are curious.
Take the example of the rune
stone in Norway found face down.
It has a requirement that
no one should move this...
"It should not be touched
by misguided men".
But of course this warning was
not supported by archaeologists.
They disregarded it completely.
So this is a quite
probable fate -
- of a marker in
the distant future.
If we put those markers there, -
- it"s not clear that they understand
the point that it"s dangerous.
And even if they understood, they
still may want to know what it is.
Then there is
the philosophical point -
- that some people think that
it would be better to forget, -
- because then
it would be less likely -
- that anybody would hit
exactly the repository.
It has been discussed
to let the facility be forgotten.
Yes, I guess there
are two schools here.
Those who think you have to
leave markers on the ground -
- and those who say
it would be better to walk away -
- and forget about the site.
Do you actually think -
- that leaving markers
creates a higher risk of intrusion?
Well, I would say so, yes.
Personally -
- I don"t see the situation as severe
if the site is forgotten over time.
But how is it possible to create
oblivion and forgetting?
How is it possible to make a facility
like Onkalo disappear from...
Well, you say it,
you say it, it"s not very easy.
When the burial chamber
was complete -
- man laid his new fire to rest,
and tried to forget about it, -
- for he knew that only through
oblivion would he be free from it.
But then he started to worry -
- that his children
might find the chamber -
- and awaken
the fire from its sleep.
So he bade his children
to tell their children -
- and their children"s children too -
- to remember
forever -
- to consign
the burial chamber to oblivion.
To remember forever
to forget.
Some of the main principles
included in the legislation -
- are firstly, limit the burden on
future generations, -
- so we should not impose undue
burdens on future generations.
The second principle is the
protection of future generations.
That means the safety
level for future generations -
- should not be lower
than we are enjoying currently.
And the third principle -
- is that we should pass
information about the repository -
- to future generations.
Our law states that we
must inform you about Onkalo:
Maybe you will need to enter -
- if we"ve overlooked something
or if repairs are required.
Were our calculations and
assumptions accurate?
Did we make mistakes?
Is that why you are here?
Knowledge transfer...
what does the law say about it?
I don"t think it says anything yet.
- Are you sure?
- No.
It is required in law
that assessment is made.
But it is not popular.
Many people react to it.
They think it"s too ambitious.
It requires
that each generation -
- let"s say -
- looks at whether
the system is adequate.
But the legislation says that you
should pass on the information.
It doesn"t talk about generations.
It says that it should provide -
- the repository information
in a permanent manner.
"In a permanent manner".
That"s the phrasing.
What do you think they mean by that?
I think you should ask them.
Because we"ve just talked
about the problems of that.
"Permanent" is too strong a word
to use here.
And what about the people
who work with these things?
They get the scientific disease,
so to say.
It"s all routine for them.
They have "the task".
- I don"t really understand.
- I don"t think anybody does.
Responsibility is moved
to the state -
- after they"ve decided -
- that this has been now done
in an acceptable way.
So the Finnish state is responsible
for passing on information?
- Into the future?
- Yes, yes.
Does that mean that when you deliver
the information about the facility, -
- it is in a way -
- that is comprehensible for all
future generations to understand?
No, no. There is no requirement of
making that comprehensible -
- for all future generations;
it depends that it"s in Finnish.
We have no archives with
information on nuclear waste yet.
If we build archives future societies
and new generations -
- must maintain the information
and update the language.
But can we count on continuation
for thousands of generations?
What if people
starve and suffer?
What if there are wars
or floods or fires?
The archives have
the same requirements -
- as our interim storages.
Requirements we cannot guarantee.
After all, this is why
we are building Onkalo.
The point is that the safety of
the disposal and the repository -
- is not dependent on these records.
But then why is this law needed?
I don"t know.
The legislators
have decided that the record -
- shall be handed over to state.
But it doesn"t say more than that.
So the idea is that the archive
of today should last for a period -
- but then be renewed
by next generations?
Yes.
Each generation should consider -
- if the archiving method
is appropriate for the future.
Do you think this will happen?
Yes. I hope so, at least!
Can we learn anything from the past -
- that may help us communicate
100000 years into the future?
Usually, when we look at these
time scales we go back in time.
Obviously, when you go
100000 years back in the past, -
- we come to our ancestors in Africa.
And we also
cover our ancestors in Europe -
- in the form of the Neanderthal man.
And you realise
that we have very little in common.
How would you make a parallel -
- from people
hunting a mammoth with spears?
It is difficult to explain to these
people something with nuclear waste.
We cannot assume that
people or creatures in the future -
- will really understand
very much.
But they might have different
kinds of senses than we have?
Yes. Senses, appearances,
needs, and knowledge.
Everything goes away. There is no
one true statement that will survive.
Do you basically trust
the future generations?
We are trying to do Onkalo -
- as independent of human nature
as possible.
Because we can"t predict -
- exactly how the humans
will behave in the future.
It is very difficult
to answer that question.
Because... trust...
and that aspect also...
I cannot say that I trust but
I cannot say that I don"t trust.
It"s an open question, -
- whether it"s a possibility -
- that anyone will interpret
anything at all in this time scale.
I have to say -
- that the quick answer is
nobody knows anything at all.
If we cannot rely on markers
and archives how will you know?
Maybe our legends will reach you -
- by being told over and over
from generation to generation -
- like ancient legends
have reached us?
Were you warned about Onkalo
through legend?
Did your parents tell you stories -
- about the fire in the chamber
deep in the bowels of the earth?
The chamber you must always
remember to forget?
Onkalo is our very first permanent
repository for nuclear waste.
But when Onkalo is sealed -
- it will hold only a fraction
of the waste we have.
We must build many Onkalos far
from earthquakes and volcanoes -
- to keep the waste away
from the surface of the earth.
We must build many more
chambers we hope to hide from you.
Do you think it"s reasonable to
talk about a nuclear renaissance?
Many people seem to think so.
And many politicians believe
that nuclear energy is needed...
...to curb the CO2 emissions
from electricity production.
If we"re going to take the people
in China and in India -
- to the same level as the western
countries in the next twenty years -
- you have to start
three new nuclear reactors a day.
Spent fuel is considered as a
material that could be reprocessed.
It could be used again.
We shouldn"t reprocess it.
Due to the fact that in such a case -
- the plutonium, which is extracted
in the reprocessing process -
- could escape,
and be used for fabricating bombs.
There has been
research into transmutation -
- in the hope that the waste
could be made harmless.
- Is that a possibility?
- Theoretically yes.
But in practice probably never.
We will never be able to do away with
all the nuclear waste in that way.
So there is no way
around nuclear waste?
At the moment
nobody"s found a way around it.
If you want to use nuclear energy,
we will have nuclear waste.
I am not so sure that
nuclear energy is the solution.
Maybe in the short term.
That"s my personal view, too.
But I don"t think
it"s sustainable in the long run.
- Maybe for the next decade. Century.
- Why do you think so?
Because we won"t
have enough uranium.
It"II be just like the oil.
I think we all can agree that
oil isn"t a sustainable solution.
And we will come there
with the uranium assets, too.
Running out of energy sources -
- could lead to very
unstable conditions globally -
- because those last energy
sources will be competed for -
- and this can even lead
to wars between nations.
The point with the permanent
disposal is that it"s permanent.
It"s put underground permanently
and you never change it.
We have coined the term
"decisions under uncertainty".
And that is clear
in the nuclear waste issue.
There are decisions
under uncertainty.
When you do a project like this
you must state what you know, -
- and you must state that you know
what you know that you don"t know.
And also what you don"t know
that you don"t know.
Could you now try
to address the audience?
I mean the future audience,
the far future audience?
I personally have a strong belief -
- that no human intrusion
will take place ever into Onkalo.
But if I am wrong...
I would love to be able to meet you -
- and to try to communicate with you.
This is probably
the only testimony of our time...
You are now entering a repository
with spent nuclear fuel...
- It must be stored in a safe place.
- It should not be disturbed.
Don"t go there. It"s dangerous.
It"s radioactive.
You can"t see it.
You can"t smell it.
- Don"t touch anything.
- Go back up to the surface.
Take better care of our world
than we did.
You will be safe
if you stay away from it.
Good luck.
You have now gone
deeper into the tunnel.
And you have reached a place
where you should never have come.
Down here radiation is everywhere.
You do not know it, but something is
happening to your body right now.
It is beyond your senses.
You feel nothing.
You smell nothing.
An invisible light
is shining right through you.
It is the last glow
of my civilization, -
- that harvested
the powers of the universe.
A vast black sleep
Descends upon my llfe
Sleep, all hope
Sleep, all deslre!
I no longer see anythlng
I lose my memory
Of the bad and the good
Oh, the sad story!
I am a cradle
Rocked by a hand
In the depths of the vault
Sllence!