Here you go, there she be.
Awesome.
It's gnarly.
Man that's massive.
The ridge looks stable but it is
going to be gnarly trying to
figure that shit out.
Looks like pow.
What's that?
Yeah, looks awesome.
Let's keep going.
I don't think this is going to
go.
No good?
I think the spines might have to
wait another day.
Oh man this is so not going to
go it is like full on trench
warfare up here.
This seems like a pretty good
way to get worked.
It's getting warm.
Um, I think we have to make a
decision we probably got another
hour if we're lucky?
You're going to bail?
I don't know it's right on the
edge.
I think we should go down.
I'm going to go for it.
I don't know if it's a good call
but...
I'll see you down there.
Okay.
Jimmy do you copy?
Jimmy I'm not reading you? Do
you copy?
You going to drop it bud?
I'm going to take my skins off,
put my skis on and have a look.
Alright man, keep me posted.
Copy.
I'm just going to check your
pupils here... alright, good.
Holy shit.
What was I thinking?
Woo, go Angel!
Hahaha dancing with it! Way to
hang on in your sluff bud.
These moments make everything
worth it.
Woo, magnificent.
Jimmy do you copy?
Yeah I copy.
Uh, I am up here on the
ridge, I don't know it is not
looking so good.
I am going to bail and down
climb, it is just to warm,
these cornices are sketchy.
Alright keep me posted, be
careful.
10-4 see you back at the camp.