- Honey, I'm home.
- Roger that.
Copy at the boathouse.
Right on time.
Faisil, get your butt in here.
Harry's inside.
Yeah, yeah, I'm coming.
I'm coming.
- Hey, were you born in a barn?
- Whorehouse.
All right. You got
your fur-coated razor blade there...
and a bunch of guys with guns.
I'm switching to sub-vocal now.
Check, check.
- Check, check.
- It's talk radio.
- You're on the air.
- Check.
That guard nearest to you
is moving away.
He's at the service door.
He's inside.
Have you seen Khaled yet?
Yep, there he is.
How come billionaires
are always short?
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Colonel! How are you?
- It's so good to see you again.
- Yes, it's been a long time.
- Terrific.
- Who was that guy?
Could you hold this
for a second? Thanks.
You should be crossing the main foyer,
heading for the stairs.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
I'm in the library, heading out
to the second-floor balcony.
Modem in place.
Transmitting now.
Affirmatory.
It's a good hook-up.
These are encrypted files.
It's going to take me a few minutes.
I got your password.
- Magnificent, isn't it?
- Yes, quite.
I thought I knew Khaled's friends,
but I don't believe I've met you before.
We haven't met,
because I certainly would remember.
Renquist, Harry Renquist.
-Juno Skinner.
Come on!
""Juno Skinner,
arts and antiquities dealer...
specializing in ancient Persia.""
This is Persian,
if I'm not mistaken.
Very good.
Sixth century BC, to be exact.
- Do you like the period?
- I adore it.
We got a problem.
Guards are going apeshit down there.
Acquired most of these pieces
for Jamal.
Do you tango?
Tango?
Harry, you do not have time
to tango, buddy.
You copy?
Don't be stopping to smell
the roses now. You hear me?
- You gotta get out of there.
- Yes! Files are unlocked!
Fast Faisil strikes again.
I'm in. I'm down, baby.
I got my hand up her dress,
and I am going for the gold--
Just copy the goddam files, okay?
Wow. And I thought
this was just gonna be...
another bunch of boring bankers
and oil billionaires.
Seconds count.
Ditch the bitch.
Unfortunately, I have to leave.
I have a plane to catch.
Well, call me sometime.
My offices are in Rome.
I would like that.
Son of a bitch is with her two minutes,
and she's ready to bear his children.
Twinkletoes,
what's your exit strategy?
I'm going to walk
right out of the front gate.
Ballsy. Stupid, but ballsy.
Sir, may I see
your invitation, please?
Sure. Here is my invitation.
Shit. Here we go.
Slight change in plans.
Stay!
We're en route to
the lower rendezvous point.
Repeat, back-up rendezvous point!
- Watch it!
- It's called ice, and it's slick.
- Harry, do you copy? Whoa!
- I got it.
Shit!
Whoops!
Oh, my God!
Whoa! I got it!
I got it! I got it!
- There he is!
- Shit!
Hi, guys.
That worked good.
Right out the old front gate.
Can you lean back a second?
Let's go.
We can still make our flight.
All right, that's it
for Mr Renquist. Okay, go.
We got Harry Tasker billfold,
Harry Tasker passport, ticket stub.
Hotel bill, Tasker.
I got two postcards here from Geneva.
Got some house keys right there...
and I've got a souvenir
Swiss snowing village.
- What's that for?
- It's for Dana, stupe.
Bring your kid home a gift,
the dad thing.
Nice touch.
- Pick me up tomorrow at 8:00.
- Will do.
The debriefing is at 1 000.
- See you at 8:00. Bye.
- Hey, Harry.
Did you forget something?
What a team.
Sleep fast, buddy.
Hi, honey. How was your flight?
- It was fine.
- Good.
Brought you a little gift
from Switzerland. Snowy village.
Wow. Thanks, Dad.
- I've never had one of these.
- You're welcome.
You're late for school.
You better get going.
- Don't forget to feed Gizmo.
- Okay.
It's pretty lame.
- I'm late.
- Yeah, me too.
How'd it go at the convention?
Make all the other salesmen jealous?
It was fantastic.
You wouldn't believe it.
You should have been there.
We were the big hit of the show.
With that new model ordering system,
the 680 I told you about...
I can write up an order
and immediately...
as soon as the customer's name comes up,
you see what his credit line is...
what he has ordered in the past,
what discount he has gotten.
- Every little detail.
- Sounds great.
It's fantastic. That's why
I love the computer business.
Listen, the plumber called.
He says he has to dig under the slab
or something that's gonna cost $600.
- That's okay.
- It's not okay. It's extortion.
What did you tell him?
I slept with him and
he said he'd knock off $ 1 00.
That's good thinking.
Bye, honey.
Hello!
Boy, I remember the first time
I got shot out of a cannon.
- Good morning. Go to school.
- Yeah, I am.
Thanks, dear.
Check these out.
Check them out.
Where's the image coming from?
Got a CCD camera and a transmitter
in a pack of smokes out there.
It's pretty cool, huh?
What the hell?
Bye, Dad!
- She's ripping you off.
- I knew it.
Let's go!
Can't stop! I'm late! Bye, Dad!
God. Shit.
Kids. Ten seconds ofjoy,
30 years of misery.
I got married three times, but at least
I was never dumb enough to have any.
She shouldn't be stealing.
I taught her better than that.
You're not her parents any more,
you and Helen.
Her parents are
Axl Rose and Madonna.
Five minutes a day you spend with her
can't compete with that bombardment.
You're outgunned, Daddy-o.
It's not just
because you're a bad parent.
Kids today are ten years ahead
of where we were at the same age.
- Morning.
- Morning, Mr Tasker.
- I bet you think she's still a virgin.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- She's only-- What is she now?
- She's 1 4.
- She's only 1 4.
- Her hormones are going like an alarm.
It's even money she lets that physicist
on the bike boink her.
- Not Dana.
- ""Not Dana.""
Denial. It's not just a river
in Egypt no more, is it?
She's probably stealing the money
to pay for an abortion.
Why don't you open the door?
Or drugs.
Twenty here, 50 there. I figured
my wife's boyfriend was taking it.
He takes everything else. There's
never a beer in the goddam fridge.
- Thought you moved out.
- I had to move back in.
My lawyer said it'd give me
a better shot at getting the house...
during the property settlement,
but don't change the subject.
- You still owe me 200 bucks.
- Good morning, janice.
- Good morning.
- Identify yourselves to the scanner.
- Harry Tasker, 1 0024.
- Albert Gibson, 34991 .
All right, Frances. I don't believe
we need you any longer now. Thank you.
Sweet Jesus. You sure screwed
the pooch last night, didn't you?
Would you please tell me how I can see
this as anything but a total disaster?
""Total"" is a strong word.
There are different
degrees of totality.
It's a scale, really, with
a perfect mission on one end...
and then a total pooch screw
on the other, and we're more on this--
Faisil, you're new on Harry's team,
aren't you?
Yes.
So what makes you think the slack
I cut him in any way translates to you?
Let me show you what we got.
Jamal Khaled. We think he's dirty,
so we raid his private financial files.
One hundred million in wire transfers
from the Commerce Bank International.
Which is a front for certain countries
to finance terrorist activities.
That's why we think
something really big is going down.
We know that a week ago
four MIRV warheads were smuggled...
out of the former
Soviet Republic of Kazakhstan.
We think Khaled's group bought the nukes
and is trying to bring them to US soil.
So far this is not
blowing my skirt up, gentlemen.
Don't you have anything
remotely substantial?
Harry, do you have any hard data?
- Nothing you would call rock-hard.
- Actually it's pretty limp, sir.
Then perhaps you better get some...
before somebody parks an automobile
in front of the White House...
with a nuclear weapon in the trunk.
It's not like
he's saving the world or anything.
He's a sales rep, for Christ's sake.
Whenever I can't sleep,
I ask him to tell me about his day.
Six seconds and I'm out.
He acts like he's curing cancer
or something.
I guess this means you didn't
get away for the weekend after all.
- Harry had to go out of town.
- I'm shocked.
Yeah, well, you know Harry.
- What's up?
- Check this out.
There's a $2 million disbursement
from Khaled to Juno Skinner.
That's right.
The babe at the party.
That doesn't mean anything.
She buys antiquities for Khaled.
He keeps his antique buys
on a completely separate ledger.
This is a little above market rate
for the horizontal bop...
even for a total biscuit
like her.
I want a complete workup on her.
- Do we know where she is?
- Right here in River City.
She lives in Rome, but she does stuff
for the Smithsonian.
She has a lot of diplomatic connections,
so she has offices here.
I guess it's time
to send in a specialist.
- Care to tango?
- Yes, I would.
Assholes.
It's all set up. You got a fax machine,
ghost phones, all the usual stuff.
You have a suite at the Marquis Hotel
under the name of Renquist.
Reality check. Let's go.
My name is Harry Renquist. I own
an art consulting firm in San Francisco.
I have an appointment
with Miss Skinner.
- Harry!
- Hello.
Hello.
I thought I'd see you again.
I just didn't know it would be so soon.
- What's the point of waiting?
- I agree.
Your clients are looking for something
for the lobby of their new headquarters?
They would like to see something
very dramatic.
That's a nice piece.
I talked to a number of people,
and they all said you're the one to see.
Really? Checking on me.
So what did these people
say about me exactly?
That you can read ancient Sanskrit
without having to sound out the words...
and other art dealers and archaeologists
don't like you very much.
Those wimps.
It's because I use my diplomatic
contacts to export cultural treasures...
from countries which tell them
to take a hike.
Most of our pieces
come from ancient Persia.
Unfortunately, ancient Persia is 20 feet
under the sand of Iran, Iraq and Syria.
Not the most popular places
lately.
So I've had to become an expert
in international diplomacy.
Well, Mr Renquist?
Do you see anything you like?
Maybe.
Give me a break. I don't think
they bugged my tuna sandwich.
She's importing stuff
from all over the Mideast.
She could be moving
money, guns, anything.
The second you left, we started
getting calls to the ghost numbers.
They were checking out
the Renquist front.
Let's step up the surveillance
and put on two more guys.
Maurizio, I said Saturday,
not Tuesday. Saturday.
Miss Skinner, may I have
a word with you, please?
Stupid, undisciplined bitch.
It's a good thing
you're paying me a lot of money.
Do you realize there are surveillance
teams watching this place right now?
Your telephones are
almost certainly tapped.
And you were busy laughing and flirting
like a whore with this Renquist--
He checked out okay--
We do not tolerate mistakes.
What would you like me to do?
Find out where this Renquist is.
Hello, Tektel Systems.
Mr Tasker's office.
Hi, Charlene? Hi, it's Helen.
Is he in?
Harry's in a sales meeting, Mrs Tasker.
Let me try him in there. Hold, please.
Relay, 1 0024.
It's a patch from Tektel.
It's Helen.
Hello, honey. How are you?
What's going on?
Hi. I'm sorry to bother you
in the middle of a meeting.
It's just that Dana and I want to make
sure you were gonna be home by 8:00.
We're going to a lot of trouble
for your big birthday.
We just wanted to make sure
that you were gonna be home.
Absolutely.
This time you can count on me.
- Promise?
- Trust me.
- Great.
- Got to go. Bye.
Bye.
- That's disgusting, Dana.
- Calm down.
We got a friend.
Three cars back on the inside lane.
They've been on us
since we left the hotel.
- You mean the station wagon?
- Yes.
- You want me to lose them?
- No. We need this lead.
Unit Seven?
Seven here.
We need you at the Georgetown Mall
in three minutes.
- Copy. We're rolling.
- Helen's gonna be pissed.
This is the problem with terrorists.
They're really inconsiderate
when it comes to people's schedules.
Pull over here. This is good.
- Okay, testing, one, two, three.
- I got you. I got you. I got you.
They're right with us.
I make three of them in the car.
- Dickhead.
- Blow me.
I got a couple of them getting out
of the car and coming after you.
Think I'm blind?
You do look like Ray Charles.
So what's the plan?
Just trying to get a closer look
at Beavis and Butt-head.
- There's a third one still in the car.
- Stay on him.
Hi, Helen. Yeah, it's Gib.
Oh, not much.
Listen, Harry forgot something
back at the office.
You know Harry.
Yeah, Gib, I know Harry. Bye.
Bye. See you soon.
See?
I lost the third guy.
Shit!
Shit! Hold it! Shit!
Here. Cool off.
Sorry about this.
Look out! Get out of the way!
Hey! Freeze!
Oh, thank God.
Get in the car.
Here we go.
Federal officer
in pursuit of suspect.
Sorry.
- Harry, what's your 20?
- Westbound in the park.
Suspect is on a motorcycle,
and he's coming out on Franklin.
Copy!
I want you on 1 4th
in case he turns south.
I want Seven on the north side
to box him in.
Make it quick, because
my horse is getting tired.
Your horse?
- There he is! That's him!
- Come on!
- Go around to the back.
- Copy that.
Out of my way!
Sorry.
Excuse me.
-Jesus!
- Sorry.
Open it!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Out of the way!
Move! Move! Move!
Federal officer! Get down! Now!
Get off or die!
- Get down! Now!
- Move!
Turn around! Hold still!
Come on!
Whoa!
Hold still!
Will you press the button
for the top floor, please?
Thank you.
Help!
Shut up!
Whoa.
Say something.
That's a fine animal.
Stay against the glass!
Come on.
So sorry.
Stay there! Don't move!
Come on, come on, come on!
Okay, back up.
Back up.
You can do it.
Come on.
Good horse. Good.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, go back now.
Come on.
Yeah, that's teamwork now.
Keep pulling. Come on.
A little bit more.
That a boy.
Okay.
What the hell were you thinking?
I had the guy,
and you let him get away.
Look at me when I talk to you.
What kind of a cop are you anyway?
Hi, honey.
I know you're upset.
I'm sorry.
I hurried home
as fast as I could.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for the party.
Yeah, it was great.
Hey.
That's him.
- Pause it right there.
- Salim Abu Aziz.
This guy is really hard-core.
Highly fanatical.
The man's a real psycho. He's been
linked to dozens of car bombings.
You know that cafe bomb
in Rome last year? That was his.
As well as a 72 7 out of Lisbon.
This guy's a major player.
Now he's formed his own splinter faction
called Crimson Jihad.
I guess he thought the other terrorists
were too warm and fuzzy for him.
- They call him the Sand Spider.
- Why?
Probably because it sounds scary.
This is impressive, gentlemen.
It would be even more impressive
if you actually knew where he was.
We'll get him.
- Why don't you pull over here?
- What's up?
I really screwed up
with Helen last night.
I'm going to see if she's available
for lunch to smooth things over.
- You just want me to hang?
-Just hang.
I'll just be hanging.
Hold, please.
- It's your mystery man on two.
- Simon?
Oh, my God.
Hello? Simon?
Simon?
Yes, I can talk.
You mean right now?
Yes, I can meet you.
Okay, I can't wait.
Bye.
Can you cover me for an hour?
Just an hour? You should tell
that stud to take more time.
Would you shut up?
I should have never told you about him.
Have a good time.
Get a little bit for me
while you're at it.
Hey! Hold it! Fucker!
What's going on? Sick?
Looks like you got gut-kicked.
It's Hel-- It's Helen--
It's Helen.
It has something to do with Helen,
I'm guessing.
Helen...
is having an affair.
Welcome to the club, man.
It can't be. Not Helen.
Nobody thinks it could happen to them
the first time.
Same thing happened to me
with wife number two, remember?
I had no idea nothing was going on.
I come home, and the house is empty.
She even took the ice cube trays
out of the freezer.
What kind of a sick bitch takes
the ice cube trays out of the freezer?
- It's not Helen.
- Helen still loves you.
She just wants to bang this guy
for a while. It's nothing serious.
- You'll get used to it soon--
- Stop cheering me up!
What'd you expect?
Helen's a flesh-and-blood woman,
and you're never there.
It was just a matter of time.
I say we concentrate on work.
That's what I do every time
my life turns to dog shit.
I concentrate on work,
and that gets me by.
Right, buddy?
It's gonna be great.
We're gonna catch some terrorists.
We're gonna beat the crap out of them.
You're going to feel a hell
of a lot better.
Watch your head.
Okay. All right.
Women. Can't live with 'em,
can't kill 'em.
I came by your office today.
I was in the area, and I thought
you might want to have lunch.
Really? Well,
you must have just missed me.
That's what they said. They said
you had to run out or something.
It was this rush job--
They needed these documents
down at the district courthouse.
So, of course, the big problem--
our printer shut down.
So I went to the third floor
to use theirs, but they have the 1 720.
Of course, the disk
isn't formatted for the 1 720.
So I had to go back upstairs
and reformat...
go back downstairs
and use their printer.
By the time I got there,
I couldn't get my car to start.
Then traffic--
I barely got there.
So a little excitement
in an otherwise dull day.
Did it work out okay?
Yeah. Great.
I'll check on dessert.
I'm done.
The great thing is that he's practically
given us a blank cheque on wiretaps.
I set them up on all of Juno's
shipping agents and her clients.
Faisil's made a list
of all the possible contacts...
the Crimson Jihad
may have in this country.
Now all we have
to do is sit around--
Hey. This national security stuff
boring you?
- Put a tap on her phone.
- What? I already did that.
I'm talking about Helen's. Put a tap
on her office line and the house. Now.
Come over here for a second.
That sounds great.
I want to ask you about something.
I got two words to describe that idea--
In-sane. An unauthorized wiretap's
a felony. You know that.
And you're doing it 20 times a day,
so don't give me that crap.
Do it.
- Hello?
- Helen, it's Simon. Is it safe to talk?
Yes, go ahead.
I can't talk long. Can you meet me
for lunch tomorrow? I must see you.
I suppose so. Where?
Same place, 1 :00.
I have to go now. See you tomorrow.
Remember, I need you.
I thought that we might
have lunch together tomorrow.
You know-- darn it--
I'm going to meet Allison.
We're going to go shopping. Sorry.
No problem.
I think you're going about
this whole thing all wrong.
Women-- they like you
to talk to them.
Maybe it's just that you're not
in touch with your feminine side.
I was watching Sally jessy Raphael--
All right.
I got all the usual stuff here--
a telemetry burst transmitter.
I got a GPS tracker, an audio
transmitter and a power supply.
I've got it sewn into the lining here--
Hey, Harry?
If you need to talk,
speak into the purse.
Here she comes. She's gonna pop out
right in front of us. Watch this.
Bingo.
Looks like she's going
into Chinatown.
She's parking.
Okay, give me audio.
You sure you weren't followed?
No. I kept looking behind me like
you taught me, but I didn't see anyone.
Okay, it's just that things
are a bit hot right now.
If I get a signal,
I may have to leave suddenly.
I understand.
Look, it's my job to take risks,
but not yours.
I feel bad about bringing you into this,
but you're the only one I can trust.
Were you out on a mission?
We say ""op,"" covert operation.
And this one, well, got a little rough.
- Worse than Cairo?
- Cairo.
Cairo was a day at the beach
next to this.
- The guy's a spook.
- But for whom?
He could be working her
to get to you.
- Did you read the papers yesterday?
- Yes.
Sometimes a story is a mask
for a covert operation.
You see two men killed in a restroom
and two unidentified men...
in a running shootout,
ending at the Marriott?
That was you?
- Me.
- You're very good.
You recognized my style.
You're a natural at this.
The guy's a fake.
He's taking credit for our moves.
- What happened?
- Hardly worth talking about.
Two of them
won't bother me again.
- Unbelievable.
- You chased one?
Something came over me. I had to nail
this guy no matter what the risk.
Pretty hairy. I thought
he had me a couple of times, but I--
- I really can't take credit.
- Why not?
It's the training. It shapes you
into a lethal instrument.
You react in a microsecond
without thinking.
I'm starting to like this guy.
We still gotta kill him.
That's a given, you know.
The guy is a goddamned
used car salesman.
This keeps getting better and better!
I'm sorry.
I know this has gotta be painful.
But you gotta admit it's funny.
If it was just some idiot, not you...
you'd be laughing your ass off.
One born every minute.
It wants you too.
Feel it vibrate?
- Say, how about a little spin?
- Sure.
See, it's not just a car.
It's a total image. An identity.
You have to go for it.
This isn't some high-tech sports car.
To tell you the truth,
it doesn't even handle that great.
But that's not the idea, is it?
What are we talking about here?
Pussy, right?
Absolutely.
Let's face it.
The 'Vette gets 'em wet.
But it's not enough.
If you really want to close escrow,
you gotta have an angle.
I suppose you have an angle.
It's killer.
I mean, look at me.
I'm not that much to look at.
No, no, no.
I can be honest.
But I got 'em lining up,
and not just the skanks either.
- Well, some are.
- What's your angle?
No, sorry. Trade secret.
Okay, just ask yourself:
What do women really want?
You take these bored housewives
married to the same guy for years.
They're stuck in a rut.
They need some release.
The promise of adventure,
a hint of danger.
I create that for them.
So basically you're lying
your ass off the whole time.
- I couldn't do that.
- What are you, a Boy Scout?
Think of it as playing a role.
It's fantasy.
You gotta work on their dreams...
get them out of their daily
suburban grind for a few hours.
- What about their husbands?
- Dickless!
I mean, let's face it.
If they took care of business...
I'd be out of business,
you know what I mean?
Those idiots.
You mind keeping it under 90?
I'm still trying
to pay for this dental work.
So, who are you
working on right now?
I always got a couple on the hook.
There's this one right now,
I got her panting like a dog.
- It's great.
- What does she do?
Some sort of legal secretary
or something.
You know,
uptight and conservative.
But she could be so hot
if she wanted to be.
And with you,
she gets to be real hot.
Red hot!
Her thighs steam.
It's like a dying plant.
Just needs a little water.
- Married to some boring jerk.
- Some boring jerk?
He doesn't appreciate her.
She's like all these babes.
You get their pilot lit,
they can suck-start a leaf-blower.
She's got the most incredible body,
and a pair of titties...
make you want to stand up
and beg for buttermilk.
Ass like a ten-year-old boy.
So, then she must be
really good in bed then, huh?
Slow down.
You'll miss the turn.
See?
You and this car were made
for each other. Why fight it?
Sure, I got a couple other buyers
on the line, but I like your style.
So, what do you say?
Should we start up
the paperwork?
Let me think about it.
Hold it for me for a day, okay?
Hey, because it's you.
I got today's transcripts.
Not much going on.
- Nothing from Simon?
- No.
- My turn to drive?
- Give me the page.
- What?
- This jumped from page 9 to 1 1 .
- Where's page 1 0?
- It's gotta be a typo.
Give me the goddam page!
- Seek help, Harry.
- Hello?
Helen, I need your help.
Can you meet me tonight?
- What's happened?
- It's serious.
Meet me on K Street...
under the Key Bridge,
8:00 sharp.
Gotcha.
Shit. It's almost 8:00.
She's still at the house.
The purse is still at the house.
Shit.
Unit Two, Unit Seven,
immediate roll.
Acquire subject
at K Street and Key Bridge.
Vehicle is red and white convertible.
You got exactly six minutes.
Wait a minute.
Are you out of your mind?
You can't pull agents off a priority
surveillance to follow your wife.
That's a misappropriation of resources
and a breach of national security.
You copy?
You're losing it big-time, man.
- I have to stop you.
- What are you gonna do, tell?
Look, goddam it.
Both of our butts are on the line.
So your life's in the crapper.
Your wife's banging a used car salesman.
It's humiliating, I know,
but take it like a man!
- You tell on me, I tell on you.
- What are you talking about?
I'm as clean as a preacher's sheets.
I'm as clean as--
What about when you blew
a six-week operation...
because you were busy
getting a blow-job?
You knew about that?
Let's take Franklin.
It's quicker.
Quick, get in.
Hurry up. Let's go.
Two here.
Suspect vehicle in sight.
One male, one female.
Now, don't be alarmed.
If I'm spotted, it'd be best
if they didn't see you.
You should keep your head down
till we're out of the city.
Here, let me help you.
That's better.
Now the woman has her head
in the guy's lap.
Southbound on the Key Bridge.
Two in pursuit.
Roger, Two.
One to Condor, you got a visual?
Roger, One. This is Condor.
Subject is in sight.
Repeat.: We have the ball.
We got a pretty good lockup
on infrared.
She's got her head
in the guy's lap, all right.
Maybe she's sleepy.
This is a safe house.
My place in the city
is a little too hot right now.
So is the penthouse in New York.
What is it exactly
you need me to do?
I want you to be my wife.
But I'm married!
It's just for the operation in Paris.
I need to be married.
They'll be looking for a man
travelling alone.
You want me to go to Paris?
Paris, with a quick stopover
in London.
There's a double agent in my outfit.
I don't know who.
There's no one I can trust,
except you.
Can you get away,
just for a couple of days?
I just don't know.
Of course. I'm rushing you.
Forgive me.
Sit down.
Make yourself comfortable.
Let me pour you some more wine.
I'll do it.
You just saved my life.
You are incredibly brave.
I have to remind myself
of the fear you must be feeling.
You see, for me
fear is not an option.
Now, in order to pull
this cover story off...
we have to look like two people who are
completely intimate with each other.
The enemy can spot a fake easily.
- You see what I mean?
- Sorry.
That reaction could
get us both killed.
- I'm sorry.
- We can't afford that.
Try to relax.
It's just been a long time...
since anybody but Harry's
touched me like that.
- It's a little difficult.
- I know.
- It's awkward for me too.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.Just sit back.
- I'm okay.
There. That's better.
Just let yourself
slip into the role.
That's it.
There you go.
Just let yourself go.
That's good.
That's great.
That's it.
No, I can't do this.
I can't do this.
- What's wrong? It's okay.
- I cannot do this.
I cannot do this!
If not for me...
do it for your country?
Oh, God!
Don't hurt me!
I'll do whatever you want!
Please!
I didn't do anything!
Damn it!
Take her! Take her!
Oh, God, don't hurt me!
Son of a bitch!
Sit down.
I said sit down.
Who do you work for?
Stern, Kessler,
Goldstein & Krumpnick.
- I'm just a legal secretary.
- Sure, Mrs Tasker.
What were you doing
with the international terrorist...
Carlos thejackal,
taking dictation?
How long have you been
a member of his faction?
I don't know anything
about a faction.
I just met Simon...
or whoever you say he is...
just a couple weeks ago.
I barely know him.
That's not what it looked like
when we found you.
How did you meet him?
Well--
Keep this for me.
I can't afford to be taken with it.
- What?
- It's a matter of national security.
Please, it's important.
I'll contact you.
Oh, shit.
Why did you continue
to see him?
He said he needed my help.
Not because you were
attracted to him?
You were not attracted
to him at all?
Well, maybe just a little.
-So, is cheating a common thing for you?
-Never.
So you're telling me
this was your first time?
I wasn't cheating!
Tell me about your husband,
Mrs Tasker.
What can I say about Harry?
He's a sales rep
for a computer company.
So sex with him isn't exactly
waving your flag any more?
That is none of your goddam business!
What kind of questions are these?
You're in a lot of trouble,
so I suggest you cooperate.
If we want to know the most
intimate details about your life...
you'd better tell us.
My husband is a good man.
But he's not exactly ringing
your bell these days, is he?
Let me handle this part.
Do you mind?
Why did you go
to Carlos'hideout?
He wanted me to go to Paris with him
on a mission...
to pose as his wife.
And you agreed?
Why?
I don't know.
I guess I needed something.
What did you need?
I needed to feel alive.
I just wanted to do
something outrageous.
And it felt really good...
to be needed.
And to be trusted.
And to be special.
It's just that there's...
so much I wanted to do
with this life...
and it's like
I haven't done any of it.
And the sand's running out
of the hourglass...
and I wanted to be able
to look back and say...
""See? I did that!
I was reckless and I was wild
and I fucking did it!''
Quite frankly,
I don't give a shit...
whether you understand that or not.
This Simon...
did you sleep with him?
- No.
- She's lying.
You did not have
sexual relations with him?
Listen, if you're gonna ask me
every question twice...
this is gonna take a really long time,
and I have to get back to my family.
You're not going anywhere, lady.
Just let me out of here!
Answer the question.
- Answer the question!
- No!
I did not...
sleep with him!
Calm down, please.
You hear me,
you chickenshit bastard?
- Calm down.
- She could be telling the truth.
Calm down, Mrs Tasker.
Calm down, please.
I've only one more question,
Mrs Tasker.
What?
Do you still love your husband?
Yes, I love him.
I've always loved him...
and I will always love him.
She loves you.
Now what?
There's only one solution
to your problem, Mrs Tasker.
You must work for us.
What are you doing?
-Just giving her a little assignment.
- You gotta be shitting me!
She wants a little adventure,
so I'm gonna give her one.
I'm offering you a choice.
If you work for us,
we will drop the charges...
and you can go back
to your normal life.
If not, you will go
to a federal prison...
and your husband and daughter
will be left humiliated and alone.
Your life will be destroyed.
Gee. Let me think.
Yes or no?
Of course yes.
What's involved?
You will be contacted
with the assignment.
The code name of your contact
will be Boris.
Your code name will be--
- Natasha?
- No.
Doris.
Pricks!
You son of a bitch. Did you think
you could elude us forever, Carlos?
Wait! You got the wrong guy.
My name's Simon.
Just let me go.
There's no need to kill me.
I haven't seen your face--
Don't! I didn't see it!
I didn't see it!
It's you!
Hey, you still interested
in that 'Vette at all?
Hey, Carlos.
The game's over.
Your career as an international
terrorist is well documented.
- No!
- Oh, yeah!
I sell cars.
That's all!
Come on.
I'm not a terrorist.
I'm actually a complete coward.
If I ever saw a gun I'd-- Oh, God!
Oh, please, don't!
Don't kill me!
I'm not a spy.
I'm nothing!
I'm navel lint!
I have to lie to women to get laid.
And I don't score much.
I got a little dick.
It's pathetic.
Oh, God.
Would a spy pee himself?
Huh?
Please, I'm not worth a bullet.
- Have mercy, sir.
- Get the fuck out of here.
Just beat it.
Go on.
As soon as I turn,
you're gonna shoot me!
You're gonna shoot me!
Please! You can have
the car for free.
What do you say, huh?
Get lost, dipshit.
So last night must've been
pretty exciting for you.
My flat tyre?
Actually, it was a little scary...
because the tow truck driver
took such a long time.
I'll get it.
Hello?
Doris?
Yes?
Listen carefully.
In exactly one hour,
go to the Hotel Marquis.
Pick up an envelope marked ""Doris""
at the front desk...
- and dress sexy.
- What?
No, no.
Turn around.
Do it doucement.
Do it very slowly.
You've reached a new
all-time low.
I can't believe you're crazy enough
to use the suite at the Marquis.
Do you think I can afford
a suite like this on my salary?
- Is jean-Claude done yet?
- Hang on.
Who wrote this shit? Harry?
It's going great.
Do you have an envelope for Doris?
This is Doris.
Listen, you are
a prostitute named Michelle.
Go to the room.
There will be a man there.
He is a suspected arms dealer.
Now, wait a minute.
You don't expect me to, uh,
you know.
No. He has particular tastes.
He likes to watch.
Tell him that his regular girl,
Carla, is sick.
If he likes you,
he will tell you what to do.
You must plant the bug...
near the telephone by the bed
before you leave.
If you do not
complete your mission...
the deal is off.
I'm gonna go to hell.
Have some champagne.
Come in here.
My name is Michelle.
Carla thought you'd like me.
Let me do the talking.
You may start by
unzipping your dress.
No, no. Turn around.
Do it doucement.
Do it very slowly.
Good.
Now slip the dress down slowly.
Now slide your nylons off
one by one.
I'm not wearing any.
That's good.
Now, dance for me.
Dance sexy.
Let your hands be your lover's hands
on your own skin as you move.
Now lie on the bed
and close your eyes.
I thought you only
liked to watch.
Now lie on the bed
and close your eyes.
You pig!
Bastard!
Wait, wait, wait.
Yes, it's Harry. I know it looks bad,
but I can explain.
Nobody move!
Don't move!
Helen, just don't do anything.
No, he has nothing to do with it!
I'm the one you want!
Shut up!
Quiet, Helen.
Do what they say.
Come on, guys, let the hooker go.
She's not important.
You don't need her.
Harry, please,
just let me handle this.
Shut up!
What were you doing there?
- You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
- Talk again and I'll kill you!
I wish I could say
it's nice to see you again.
You know her?
You know, this shade's
totally wrong for you.
So who's your little friend?
I'm Helen Tasker.
Harry is my husband. And you are?
So now it's Tasker,
not Renquist.
She's just some wacko hooker
I met down at the bar.
What is the matter with you?
Just tell her the truth!
We are married,
and we have a daughter.
I don't know what
the crazy bitch is on.
You should cut her loose
so we can get down to business.
Where did I get this then, huh?
Where did I get this?
Something before takeoff?
That hurt, you b--
She was telling the truth,
wasn't she?
She really doesn't know.
How interesting.
Bring them.
Incredible, aren't they?
I call them the Four Horsemen.
They're warrior figures...
from the Persian Empire
of Darius I...
around 500 BC.
They're absolutely priceless.
Pity.
Wait, wait!
Open it.
Do you know what this is?
I know what this is.
This is an espresso machine.
It's a snow cone maker.
That's what it is.
Is it a water heater?
Do you know why
you've been brought here?
So that this man
can verify to the world...
the Crimson Jihad
is now a nuclear power.
How can he do that?
He's just a salesman, for Christ's sake.
If I'm wrong about him,
the last thing you'll see...
will be your blood
spraying across his face.
It's a Soviet MIRV-6
from an SS-22 air launch vehicle.
The warhead contains
1 4.5 kilograms of enriched uranium...
and a plutonium trigger.
The nominal yield is 30 kilotons.
What can I say?
I'm a spy.
You bastard!
You lying son of a bitch!
- Sorry, honey.
- Don't you call me honey!
You don't ever get
to call me honey again!
You understand me, you pig?
And I can verify that
they have the arming box...
and all the equipment necessary...
to detonate all four warheads.
You have killed our women
and our children...
bombed our cities from afar
like cowards...
and you dare
to call us terrorists?
Now the oppressed
have been given a mighty sword...
with which to strike back
at their enemies.
Unless you, America...
pulls all military forces
out of the Persian Gulf area...
immediately and forever...
the Crimson Jihad will rain fire...
on one major U.S. city each week...
until our demands are met.
First, we will detonate one weapon
on this uninhabited island...
as a demonstration of our power...
and Crimson Jihad's willingness
to be humanitarian.
However, if these demands
are not met...
Crimson Jihad will rain fire...
on one major American city
each week--
Battery.
Get another one, you moron.
I think I have one in the truck.
- What?
- Look at this.
- That's not mine.
- Nice transmitter.
Miami Tower,
Jet Star 64 7 9 Delta on final.
- We'll be on the ground in 1 2 minutes.
- All right.
Tell those D.E.A. boys
to have the helos...
hot and ready to fly
in 1 2 minutes.
Signal's definitely stopped moving.
It's an island in the Keys.
- We lost the signal.
- Shit!
All right, everyone.
This is Samir.
For 50 points,
see if you can guess his specialty.
Oral hygiene?
- Not exactly.
- What's going on?
Samir's just gonna ask Harry
a few questions.
We're not even sure
which agency Harry works for.
Now, Samir's absolutely first-class.
On the other hand we have Harry,
who's managed to lie convincingly...
to the woman he loves for 1 5 years.
So it'll be interesting to see
how long he can resist.
This will help.
You know, you should
swab that with alcohol.
I might get an infection.
I'll return when
this has taken effect.
Then we'll talk.
I'm looking forward to it.
Now, why are you helping
these raving psychotics?
Because they're very well-funded
raving psychotics...
and I'm getting a lot of money.
What, you think I care
about their cause?
Or yours?
Not at all.
You're damaged goods, lady.
Did you tell her about us?
There is no ""us,""
you psychopathic bitch.
Oh, sure.
You say that now.
Thanks for everything.
It wasn't bad while it lasted.
Let's go.
You two stay here.
There was nothing.
I swear.
What did they give you?
Sodium Amytal,
or some other truth agent.
It makes you tell the truth?
Is it working?
Ask me a question
that I normally would lie to.
- Are we gonna die?
- Yep.
I'd say it's working.
They're gonna shoot us in the head,
or they're gonna torture us to death...
or they're gonna leave us here
and let the bomb--
How long have you been a spy?
Seventeen years.
Have you ever killed anyone?
Yeah, but they were all bad.
Is there anything you want to tell me
before we start?
Yeah.
I'm going to kill you pretty soon.
I see.
How, exactly?
First, I'm going to use you
as a human shield.
Then I'm going to kill
this guard over there...
with the Patterson trocar
on the table.
And then I was thinking
about breaking your neck.
And what makes you think
you can do all that?
You know my handcuffs?
I picked them.
Let's get out of here.
Come on!
Drop the gun!
Honey, next time, duck.
- Let's go.
- I married Rambo.
What are they doing?
It is done.
In 90 minutes,
a pillar of holy fire...
will light up the skies...
to show to the world...
that we speak the truth.
We are set on our course.
No force can stop us now.
We're cool, we're bad-asses,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
If we're on an island,
why are they using trucks?
We must be in the Florida Keys.
The overseas highway connects
the islands to the mainland.
There's no borders, no customs.
They can go anywhere in the U.S.
There's nothing to stop them.
Just us.
- Here, take this.
- Oh, shit.
Shoot!
Shit!
Let's go.
My condolences to the widow.
We may need the hostage.
Okay, let's go, Suzy Homemaker.
Hurry up!
Just get her in the car.
Let's get going.
- I thought this looked like your work.
- Let's go. I'll brief you in the air.
You're welcome. Let's go!
Let's get out of here!
Let's go!
Come on!
Well, you tell that son of a bitch
this is a Bright Boy Alert.
I repeat:
A Bright Boy Alert.
This is not a drill.
Do you understand that?
Hold on.
Put me through to the White House.
The minimum safe distance is 1 2 miles.
Get the marine patrol in right away.
I want the Coast Guard
and the sheriff's department too.
Anyone that cannot make that distance,
you gotta get 'em out by air.
You've got exactly 34 minutes.
I can get you two Marine Corps Harriers
here in 1 1 minutes.
- They're on manoeuvres outside Key West.
- Get them.
- I'll brief them on the way in.
- Send 'em in right away.
Would you like one?
I want the state police driving through
the streets on their damn loudspeakers.
Here they come.
Lime-Zero-One, got a tally on
three trucks eastbound on the bridge.
Roger, Lime-Zero-One.
You're clear to engage.
Ringo is padlocked.
In hot with guns.
Let's get some.
Okay, marines, time to kick ass.
Recommend using your Mavericks
to take out the bridge.
Roger that.
Lime flight, switch Mavericks. Two.
These missiles won't
set off those nukes, will they?
That's a negative.
Fire.
- Bingo!
- Good shooting, marines.
I'll kill you!
- It's out of control.
- Somebody capped the driver.
Bitch!
Like one?
How about two?
Get down to the limo!
Come on!
Take it down! Let's go!
- Get down!
- Take it down.
- The bridge is out!
- What?
The bridge is out!
I can't hear you!
What?
Oh, God!
The bridge is out!
Come on! Come on!
Speed up a little bit, now.
Get down there.
Come on! Hurry!
Hurry, Harry!
- Grab my hand!
- Come back!
- Okay, to the right.
- I can't reach! Get lower!
Here we go!
Hold on!
Hold on really tight!
Harry! Come back!
Pull up!
Grab my hand!
You can do it!
I can't reach!
Oh, God! Please!
Harry!
Oh, shit.
Come on, baby.
Hold on!
I got you!
- Oh, God!
- Hold on tight!
Let's get this thing on the ground.
Let's get these aircraft
on the ground.
We got a nuclear bomb going off
in about one minute.
Any minute now.
Go, go, go.
Come here.
Give me a bullhorn.
All right, it's show time.
Do not look at the flash.
Do not look at the flash!
We should be safe here.
This is the wrong finger.
Come here!
- Go to work.
- Okay. Bye.
Aziz's copter landed about 20 minutes
ago on top of a high-rise in Miami.
He rendezvoused with some faction
members. They're on the 20th floor.
I got SWAT down there.
The cops cordoned off the area.
They got a hostage.
It's Dana.
What do you mean?
My Dana?
I'm real sorry.
I don't know what to say.
I guess he grabbed her
in the middle of the night.
We just found out about it.
But I don't want you to worry.
We'll get her back.
I've got a guy on the inside.
Listen.
We're gonna get her back.
Here we go.
Excuse me, Captain. I got to
borrow your plane for a minute.
Listen, Force Comm cleared you
to give us total cooperation, right?
And you know that comes directly from
the president of these United States.
But, sir, you're gonna have
to sign for this aircraft.
I'll sign for it. You got a pen?
You take care of it.
Do you realize
it has been ten years...
since you've been behind
the wheel of one of these?
I break it,
they can take it out of my pay.
Listen, we got a guy on the inside.
Gotta move back, everybody!
Let's go!
All right, everybody,
it's gonna be all right!
He's got hundreds of hours
in the Harriers there.
He is a little rusty,
but that's a trademark Tasker takeoff.
It's like riding a bike.
You never forget, really.
We might wanna seek shelter!
Sorry.
Fuck!
The streets are filled with people
as police try to evacuate the buildings.
They appear to be shooting
wildly into the air as I'm speaking.
These seem to be warning shots.
So far...
they have not fired at us or police.
This apparently is the same group...
which just detonated a nuclear bomb
in the Florida Keys.
Crimson jihad will rain fire
on one major U.S. city each week...
until our demands are met.
This tape was released to the media
just minutes after the terrorists--
I have to go to the bathroom.
We'll repeat the tape following
this live report from the scene.
Hold your fire!
- The video crew you wanted is here!
- Send them!
They're coming in.
They're unarmed.
Come on. Let's go.
Go.
This is a communique
from Crimson Jihad.
You have seen a demonstration
of our power.
Do not force us
to destroy this city...
and do not try
to use force against us.
I, we are all prepared to die.
With one turn of that key...
two million of your people
will die instantly!
- What key?
- That key!
Who's taken the key?
Shoot her!
Holy shit!
Unit One to Unit Seven.
Give me a situation report.
One to Seven. Give me a sit rep.
Faisil, do you copy?
Seven here.
2 1 st floor secure.
About 1 2 faction members
on the 20th floor. No hostages there.
- Where's Dana?
- She's on the roof.
Okay, stay put.
Give me that address again.
You shoot me, this'll fall!
Stay where you are!
- Give me the key!
- I'll drop it, I swear!
Give me the key.
Come on, child.
You don't want to die, do you?
Give me the key
and you won't get hurt.
I give you my word!
No way, you wacko!
Help me!
Please don't come any closer!
Help me! Help me!
Somebody!
Dana, jump down!
Jump down!
Dad?
Help me!
Daddy, come back!
Daddy, get me down!
Jump!Jump!
Daddy will catch you!
-Jump!
- I can't!
Hold on!
Don't you let me fall, please!
- Daddy!
- I got you!
I'm slipping!
Help me!
I'm gonna fall!
Hold my hand!
Hold on tight, honey.
He's behind you!
Take this plane down, now!
I'll kill her!
Take it down, now!
My God, do something!
You're fired.
It's okay.
Honey, it's over.
Hi, pumpkin.
Just seconds after thejet landed...
the unidentified pilot was escorted
from the scene by Federal agents.
Though it is unclear at this moment
which agency was responsible...
for the operation which ended
the terrorist threat...
so dramatically
early this morning...
we've learned from Miami Police--
Do it properly.
One, two, three, four,
I declare a thumb war.
Five, six, seven, eight,
try to keep your thumbs straight.
Don't! Stop it!
- Wait!
- I got you!
Just listen.
Listen to the rules.
- Hello?
- Boris and Doris?
We're on.
Yes? Go ahead.
Colonel, how nice to see you again.
Good evening.
Who was that?
What's the scoop, team?
You see your contact yet?
Haven't seen him yet.
But I see somebody
I'd like to say hello to.
Let me pour you
some more champagne.
I got to keep up the waiter bit.
These stakeouts can be tricky.
You never know when things might
explode into a life-or-death situation.
If it gets rough, stay low until
it's over and I'll contact you later.
- Maybe you should give me your--
- So, we meet again, Carlos.
Honey, I'm just gonna
do him right here, okay?
Go for it.
Oh, God.
Fear is not an option.
Dance?
- Tango.
- Here we go.
Harry? Helen? Guys?
Come on, now.
Let's not get distracted.
We got some work to do.
All right, guys.
Come on.
You guys better get serious in there.
I'd be serious if I was in there.
Don't ignore me, Harry.
That's rude.
All right, guys.
Come on.
National security, guys.
Come on. Life and death.
Helen, I was always on your side.
I was always there for you.
You know what?
I'm sick of being in the van.
You guys are gonna be
in the van next time.
I been in the van for 1 5 years.