MAN: I don't know.
Feels like our grave.
Their Queen is here.
And we have our orders.
It's a trap.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Hold on!
No!
NARRATOR:
This is what is known,
there has always been man
and there have
always been vampires.
(ROARING)
(YELLING)
Since the beginning, the two
have been locked in conflict.
The vampires were quicker,
stronger,
but man had the sun.
It was not enough.
And so it went
like this over many years.
The two races destroying
not only each other,
but the world itself.
Facing extinction,
mankind withdrew behind walled Cities
under the protection of the Church.
And then the ultimate
weapon was found,
the Priests.
Warriors with
extraordinary powers,
trained by the Church
in the art of vampire combat.
They alone turned
the tide for man.
The remaining vampires
were placed on reservations.
And, fearing the power
of the weapon they created,
the ruling Clergy
ordered the Priests disbanded.
The former warriors to be
integrated back into a society,
that no longer needed them.
And as the years passed,
the few surviving Priests
faded into obscurity
like the vampire menace
before them.
Residual radiation's
still spotty,
but the soil contamination's
close to zero.
With a little luck,
we can finally start planting.
I'm proud of you, Owen.
Great. Pershing stew again.
Atoning for your sins?
No, why?
You're wearin'
your nicest dress.
Where else would you have
been all day, but church?
I was in town.
I figured someone here needs
a life outside this outpost.
Thought I said I didn't want you
spending so much time out that way.
I'm old enough to go
where I want.
You're 18.
That's not old enough.
Not out here.
I know it's hard, but we all
have to make sacrifices.
"Sacrifices"? You mean living
out here like a prisoner?
Lucy...
No friends?
No fun?
Just so that someday, you might
be able to grow something
in these godforsaken lands?
Enough.
Bow your heads and say grace.
Dear Lord, we thank you for
what we are about to receive...
Daddy?
(RUMBLING)
SHANNON: Owen?
Get her down below!
LUCY: What's going on?
Hurry, child.
(BANGING ON ROOF)
Hurry!
(VAMPIRES GROWLING)
Mama.
Whatever you hear
(WHIMPERING)
Don't scream.
SHANNON: Oh, my God!
(VAMPIRES GRUNTING)
OWEN: Get behind me!
No! Oh, God!
(SHANNON SCREAMING)
OWEN: Shannon!
(OWEN AND SHANNON SCREAMING)
(VAMPIRES TEARING AT FLESH)
(WHIMPERING)
(VAMPIRE EXHALING SHARPLY)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(TRAPDOOR OPENING)
(SCREAMING)
MAN: (ON PA)
Repent. Absolution.
ORELAS: (ON PA)
Faith. Work. Security.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
ORELAS: (ON PA)
God protects you.
The Church protects you.
The City protects you.
Absolution is the only way.
Faith. Work. Security.
Remember,
to go against the Church
is to go against God.
Remember, to go against the
Church is to go against God.
MAN: (ON PA)
Confessional 5 is open.
Confessional 37 is open.
GUARD: Move forward.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Initiate
confession sequence zed/5.
Please speak at the tone.
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
Yes, my son.
I had the dream again.
Come on!
About the war.
Tell me more.
We were in the hives
like always.
He fell.
And I wasn't strong enough.
Tell me more.
I have questions.
Doubts.
The Devil comes in many shapes.
The best way to combat him is
through personal sacrifice
and an honest day's labor.
Yes, Father.
Now say three Hail Marys
and four Our Fathers.
And remember,
to go against the Church
is to go against God.
BOY: Mom...
MOM: (SHUSHING) Don't point.
Mom, what's on that man's face?
It's a tattoo.
Did it hurt?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Level 14.
Why can't I talk to him?
We don't talk to Priests.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Who are you?
Name's Hicks.
I'm the sheriff from Augustine.
What do you want?
There was a vamp attack.
They took Lucy.
Your brother, he's hurt bad.
He told me where to find you.
And Shannon?
No.
Lucy talked about you.
Said you were a hero
during the war.
Said that when it came to killing
vampires, you were the best.
I'm going after her.
I'm gonna get her back.
I just thought I should let you know
in case you wanted to come along.
Figure I could use someone
like you by my side.
Okay.
Thank you for meeting with me on
such short notice, Monsignors.
Monsignor Chamberlain has
informed us of the situation.
Your family is in our prayers.
PRIEST: Thank you.
I come before you because I
need my authority reinstated.
On what grounds?
This was a vampire attack.
Vampires?
(CHUCKLING)
Nonsense. We've had no reports of
any escapes from the reservations.
This is obviously the work
of Wasteland bandits.
Monsignor, the boy was clear.
The boy was mistaken.
There is no vampire menace.
The Wastelands are a haven for
the lawless and the immoral.
To send a Priest out there after such a
lot would be both ridiculous and futile.
This is best left
to the local authority.
Monsignor Orelas, this man has been
of great service to the Church.
If it weren't for the Priests, we
would have been overrun by the...
We are well aware of his accomplishments,
Monsignor Chamberlain.
Thank you. You may sit.
I am begging you.
Allow me to find her.
You must understand
something, Priest.
The sanctity of these
walls is absolute.
And the citizens from the
Cities have complete faith
in the Church's ability
to keep them safe.
You will not shake that faith.
What good is that faith
when it's a lie?
Questioning the authority of the
Clergy is absolutely forbidden.
If you take any action
to leave the Cities,
it will be seen as an act of
aggression against the Church.
You will be stripped from the Order
and excommunicated immediately.
Do I make myself clear?
I said do I make
myself clear, Father?
Yes, Monsignor.
Try to remember your vow,
to go against the Church
is to go against God.
(SCREAMING)
Come on, now.
Don't be shy.
Give us a kiss.
BLACK HAT: That's no way
to treat a friend.
Please. Let me go.
You're in there
for your own protection.
If I let you out,
you'll be torn apart.
Piece by piece.
My uncle's a Priest.
He'll come after me.
Really?
What makes you so sure?
He'll come after me.
He'll come after you!
Now that's something
I'm absolutely
counting on.
CHAMBERLAIN:
Judgment is final.
I'm sorry.
I sacrificed everything
to serve them.
Now they won't listen to me.
The war is long over.
You and the other Priests
did your jobs.
It's not over.
Not for me.
You can't break your covenant to hunt
down a small group of scavengers.
It would be sacrilege.
I have to.
That's what I was afraid of.
(DOOR BANGING OPEN)
GUARD 1: Move.
GUARD 2: Get out of the way.
Stand back.
If you go out there right now, you
risk stirring things up again.
You have to look at the bigger picture.
It's for the greater good.
Is this the world I fought for?
No,
but it's the only world
we have left.
I'm begging you,
don't do anything foolish.
Remember your vow,
to go against the Church
is to go against God.
Then I go against God.
(GRUNTING)
God help us.
PRIEST: Dear Father,
forgive me.
It was never my intention
to offend you.
I would like to firmly resolve
with the help of your grace
to sin no more, and to avoid
the near occasions of sin,
but I can't.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(GUN COCKING)
HICKS: Lootin's not such
a good idea, mister.
Well, I'll be damned.
Vampires are a vicious lot.
I have seen a vampire
bite a man clean in half.
Salvation is right here
in my very hands.
Authenticated by
the Clergy themselves.
SALESMAN: Purchase this holy water...
Excuse me a minute.
...and keep your loved
ones safe tonight.
(GUNSHOT)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
I am tired of you comin'
around here scarin' people
selling your superstition.
Show's over.
And it's time for you to go.
Give me one good reason
why I should.
That's one.
Two.
All right, all right!
All right!
Goddamn son of a bitch!
Now, y'all listen up.
This stuff is good for nothin'
but linin' that man's pockets
with your hard-earned cash.
VILLAGER: You don't know that.
You're just a kid.
We gotta do somethin'
to keep us safe.
Move out of the way!
I don't blame any
of you for bein' scared,
but the vampires are gone
and they're not comin' back.
You'll have to excuse the attention.
Strangers aren't too common out here.
Is it true what they say
about Priests?
You wield the hand of God?
How is he?
He's awake.
The Clergy took away a boy
and returned an old man.
After the war was over, Shannon
figured you'd come back.
I wanted to.
Didn't seem right anymore.
I couldn't save her.
I tried, but I never
had your gift.
You gave her a life
I no longer could.
I will always be
grateful to you for that.
Never a day went by when I didn't
wish she'd forget about you.
You find Lucy.
You bring her home safe.
And you promise me
somethin', brother,
kill 'em all.
Most people out here know the Clergy think
of us as a bunch of godless heathens.
And that's how we like it.
It means they tend to keep their
noses out of our business.
So you can imagine
how surprised I was
when they contacted me
askin' if I'd seen you.
Sayin' that anyone goin' after Lucy
is to be arrested immediately.
Said she's in God's hands now.
Problem is, we both know outside
of a week, Lucy will be dead.
Or worse, infected.
So with all due
respect to God...
You're wasting your time.
No, no, no, you are not
cutting me out of this.
I am the one that
came and got you.
People in this town don't think
you can keep them safe here.
What makes you think
you'll do any good out there?
You any good with a gun?
Better than I am with a knife.
We leave at dawn.
All right.
What's with all the bullets, anyways?
I thought Priests didn't use firearms.
We don't.
They're for you.
ORELAS: (ON PA)
God protects you.
The Church protects you.
ORELAS: You have been called
to serve once more.
One of your own
has broken his sacred vow.
His actions are a threat
to the entire Order.
You will find him
and bring him back to me.
Dead or alive.
PREACHER: "And I will teach transgressors
your ways, and sinners will turn back to you.
"Save me from bloodguilt,
O God, the God who saves me.
"And my tongue will sing
of your righteousness.
"And my mouth will
declare your praise.
"You do not delight in
sacrifice or I would bring it.
"You do not take pleasure
in burnt offerings."
What is it?
Vampire tracks are random.
Sets of two, three, four prints at a time.
But these are two by two.
It must have been
one of the Familiars.
Vampires don't bring Familiars on the hunt.
They slow them down.
No, this...
This was something else.
Tracks head north.
There's a reservation
up that way.
Well, then that's
where we start.
Nightshade Reservation.
Nothin' but red-outs and rejects.
They're a fallen tribe.
Either way, we don't have
much time to get in and out.
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
No guards.
I thought Familiars
were illegal.
Nobody really enforces it.
So long as it's voluntary.
PRIEST: Voluntary?
HICKS: Yeah, they come from the fringes.
Drifters wantin' to get infected.
I mean, becomin' a vampire slave
ain't my idea of belongin',
but people get all
sorts of strange ideas.
So long as they keep to themselves
it makes no difference to me.
You're not welcome
here, Priest.
These lands are protected.
I got this.
We're lookin' for a local girl kidnapped
about four nights ago by a vamp pack.
Came through this way.
Nobody comes
through Nightshade.
That's the way
we like it. Nice
and quiet.
Good. I'm sure we won't
have any trouble.
They excrete it.
Use it to build their hives.
HICKS: I guess now we know
what happened to the guards.
(METAL PANEL OPENING)
(WHIMPERING)
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
No, no.
You must go.
Master will be angry. Please.
(SHUSHING)
Where's the girl?
I don't know what you're
talking about. Please. Please.
Master doesn't feed on humans anymore.
See? See?
Yeah, tell that to the guards.
Where is she?
Please, don't.
(METAL SCRAPING)
Shit.
Priest! Priest!
(YELLING)
(PANTING)
Save your bullets.
(SCREAMING)
Now we can do this
the easy way, or...
Oh, good.
I've always preferred
the hard way.
Tell me where
they took the girl.
Haven't you done
enough already, Priest?
Tell me!
Look around you.
Look what you've done to them.
They once ruled this land.
They were warriors.
They were gods.
They were murderers.
They were what nature made
them to be. Just like you.
You got 10 seconds
to start talking.
Ten seconds is all I need.
You're too late, Priest.
This is their time now.
They get your gun arm?
Why?
You're gonna need it.
(MAKING CLICKING SOUNDS)
(RESPONDING WITH
CLICKING SOUNDS)
"Yea, though I walk through the valley of the
shadow of death, I will fear no evil..."
Your words mean
nothing to them, Priest.
"...for thou art with me."
Focus!
(CALLING)
Should we go after him?
No need.
He'll die at first light.
No more masters.
Just you and me.
Tell me where
they took the girl.
West. They took her west.
Why?
You have no idea
what's coming, Priest.
(ROARING)
(VAMPIRE GROWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
PRIEST: The Familiar said
they traveled west from here.
Sola Mira.
A hive?
One of the largest.
But I thought all the hives
were liquidated after the war.
They were.
That's why we need to go look.
There were more than
50 crypts in this reservation,
but only six vampires left.
The weak.
The left-behind.
We find the missing,
we'll find Lucy.
I may not have seen the war,
but I know the look a man
gets when he likes killing.
It comes easy to you.
It just comes.
Easy's got nothing
to do with it.
Give me your gun.
What?
Vampires don't move
like humans.
Their body weight pulls them
into concentric patterns.
You need to anticipate their
trajectory to get a kill shot.
Are you teaching me to shoot?
I'm teaching you
how to kill vampires.
There are always
two points, A and B.
Know them both,
and you'll kill a vampire.
A man came aboard,
says he has something for you.
You
told me to come
if I had any information.
But before I tell you,
and I hate to bring this up,
but there is this small
little matter of compensation.
Now, you've been
really good for business
so I am more than willing
to cut you a deal.
I can smell the blood
running through your veins.
Smells like
dinner.
Okay. All right.
After you snatched the girl, a couple
of nights later, a Priest showed up.
A Priest?
And he was with this sheriff.
A real hard case.
He run me out of town before
I could make a single sale.
You've done well.
Thank you.
(GASPING)
BLACK HAT:
There's your compensation.
Put him to work.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
HICKS: I used to ride out here
a lot when I was little.
Stare at all this stuff.
Wonder what it used to be.
After a while,
it just made my eyes ache.
Did Owen know?
About you and Lucy?
No.
She wanted to tell him,
but Owen wasn't the easiest
man to talk to.
Besides, he was so focused on his work,
there wasn't much room for anything else.
Do you love her?
(SIGHING)
You know, if she's infected,
I'll kill her.
You'll try,
but you won't be able to.
I wasn't there to protect her once, I
won't make that same mistake again.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Feels like our grave.
It's a trap.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
This is a waste of time.
There's nothing here.
Stay here.
Anything comes up
that isn't me, shoot it.
Great.
(GRUNTING)
What are you doing here?
The Clergy sent me.
Ordered me to bring you back.
(PRIESTESS GRUNTING)
They sent four of us to track you.
We split up at Nightshade.
I rode out here hoping
to get ahead of you.
The others went on to Jericho.
I didn't believe it when they
told me you broke your vow.
They left me no choice.
(GUNSHOT) Hicks!
What the hell is that thing?
PRIEST: It's a Hive Guardian.
Who the hell are you?
It's too big to get down here, which
is the only reason you're still alive.
Who the hell is that?
You ready?
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
PRIESTESS: Hey!
Not bad.
(GUNSHOT)
Point A, meet point fucking B.
The hive's been abandoned for years.
Why would something be protecting it?
Does the lawman know what
you'll do if she's infected?
He knows.
He'll try to stop you.
He won't be able to.
It's been hard all these years.
Not seeing the others.
Not talking.
Sector Seven was the only
place I could find work.
Waste management.
No one would hire me.
"No applicable skills."
I heard that, too.
I didn't come here
to bring you back.
I came here to warn you.
There are nights when I wake up
and I think I'm back
on the front lines.
I'm sweating, my muscles are clenched
like I'm ready for something.
Nights like that,
I don't go back to sleep.
I have bad dreams.
Me, too.
There are other nights.
The good nights.
I dream about other things.
HICKS: Why doesn't it look
like the rest of the hive?
PRIESTESS: This section's new.
They must have rebuilt it.
HICKS: My God.
They bred a new army.
Where did they all go?
(BATS CHIRPING)
Only one way to find out.
Um... Are Priests allowed
to have relations?
We take a vow of celibacy.
So you mean, you've never...
I was a young girl
when the Clergy found me.
What about him?
PRIESTESS: His talents
developed later.
He was nearly your age
when the Clergy came for him.
That made his sacrifice
greater than most.
The air is changing.
PRIEST: Well,
there's your answer.
They dug right through
the mountain,
made a hole big enough
to fit an army through.
What town is that?
It's Jericho.
Where'd you say
the others went?
(RUMBLING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
What the hell?
(GASPING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Hello?
Is anybody there?
Let's begin.
(OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(POUNDING)
(HEAVY RUMBLING)
I don't see anything.
(SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(VAMPIRES GROWLING)
(YELLING)
(GROANING)
Brothers, you have a choice.
You could follow
in my footsteps,
or you can follow in his.
We're too late.
We separate.
PRIEST: Go through each
building, see what we find.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
HICKS: There's nobody left.
Not a soul.
Too many mouths to feed.
HICKS: Killing three Priests?
What kind of vampire
could do something like that?
Nothing we've ever seen before.
HICKS: How could they take an entire
town overnight and vanish by sunrise?
There are no other hives
around here. No reservations.
PRIEST: Where's
this rail line go?
It's an old mining line.
It starts in the Dunkirk Mines
above Augustine.
Jericho's the last stop before it reaches...
The Cities.
Heading back to the Cities
would be suicide, right?
The sun will kill 'em.
There is no sun in the Cities.
Not anymore.
Without us,
they're defenseless.
I'm responsible.
No. This was systematic.
Whoever took Lucy knew that you'd come
for her and that we'd come for you.
They were drawing us out.
They must have been picking up
different factions along the way.
Moving during the day
and feeding at night.
It's going to be a massacre.
It's gonna be a war.
A train carrying
an army of vampire?
What chance do we have of
stopping something like that?
I'll overtake the train, blow the rail line.
You two get aboard, find Lucy.
I'll start charging the bikes.
It's gonna take everything we have to stop
that train before it reaches the Cities.
BLACK HAT: You must be starving.
You haven't eaten in days.
Have you ever had
real roast duck?
It's very rare.
Very exotic.
Of course not.
Try it. You'll never
have better.
What do you want?
I want the same things
that you want.
I want to be free from a life
of suffering and sacrifice.
To no longer be told that
your every desire is a sin.
I mean, after all
if you're not committing sin,
you're not having fun.
What are you?
The Church teaches us that the
eyes are the windows to the soul.
And that since vampire
evolved without eyes,
it is a soulless creature to be
eradicated.
And I have seen
the soul of the vampire,
and let me tell you, it is far
more pure than that of any man.
Now you ask me what I am.
I am the bringer of the tide.
I am the wave that will wash
clean this unclean world.
And you and your
Priest will help me do it.
He's gonna kill her, isn't he?
If she's infected.
She talked about him.
Said she never got to know him.
She wanted to.
What kind of man would kill
his own flesh and blood?
If she becomes a Familiar, she's
no one's flesh and blood.
Not anymore.
I've held on to it
all these years.
To remind me of everything
they stripped away from us.
Our honor, our abilities,
our faith.
Today, when we ride, I want you to remember
our power doesn't come from the Church.
It comes from God.
With or without the Clergy,
we're still Priests.
(SHIVERS)
I can't.
When I heard
what happened to Shannon,
I prayed for her salvation
and then I prayed for mine.
Because in the darkness
of my heart,
I hoped her death
would free you at last.
(GUN COCKING)
Tell me you won't kill her.
Hicks, don't do this.
Tell me, or I will shoot
you where you stand.
It would be easier to face your bullet
here than to face what might lie ahead.
Why do you even care?
She is nothing
but a stranger to you.
She's his daughter.
She was just a baby
when the Clergy took me.
You're lying. I knew Owen.
The child needed a father.
We all made sacrifices.
Hicks,
if you do this,
it won't matter
if you find Lucy.
You won't stop the train, and
you won't be able to save her.
You won't save her.
We ride out
and meet this together.
When the time comes, you blow the
tracks, then you get out of there!
What if you're still
on the train?
Good luck.
Focus.
(SCREAMING)
Shit.
Shit. Shit.
(VAMPIRE GROWLING SOFTLY)
Shit.
Hello, my friend.
You fell!
You let go.
No!
In the depths of that hive,
I crossed the threshold
between life and death.
And do you know what I found?
The Queen we had come to kill,
my angel of mercy,
she turned me into something that
had never existed in this world,
a human vampire.
Join me.
Accept the blood of the Queen,
and together, we can return
to the Cities as brothers.
Where's my daughter?
Waiting for your decision.
(EXCLAIMING)
You can't win.
I'm stronger now
than you ever were.
(BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(PANTING)
This is your
last chance, Priest.
The Queen's hands
have not been idle.
Mankind will find no quarter
from what's coming.
Join me,
and your life of
sacrifice will be over.
Never.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Shit.
LUCY: Hicks!
Lucy!
Shit.
Did you find her?
I couldn't get close.
They took her to the front.
You would have made
a good Priest.
Thanks.
Don't let it go to your head.
Hicks!
Lucy!
No!
(GROANING)
Stop it!
No!
No, Lucy!
Very good.
You're fast.
Just like your father.
He never told you.
(SCREAMING)
Burn.
In this time of need,
strengthen me.
You are my refuge and strength.
I do not fear,
for you are with me.
(GRUNTING)
(LUCY SCREAMING)
I won't let you go!
Your faith has failed you.
(BEEPING)
No!
(PRIEST GRUNTING)
(LUCY SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(MOTORCYCLE APPROACHING)
(SIZZLING)
"For the life of the flesh
is in the blood
"and I have given it
to you upon the altar
"to make an atonement
for your souls."
(CONGREGATION CHATTERING)
How dare you come back
to this holy place.
A man who would defy the Church
for his own selfish crusade!
(ALL GASPING)
Look inside the burning train
just beyond these City walls
you'll find hundreds
more like it,
and their Queen
was not among them.
Lies!
This man is a charlatan.
A risk to the security
of the Cities.
There is no vampire menace.
The war is over, Priest!
No, it's just beginning.
I've notified the others.
We'll meet you at the
rendezvous in City Seven.
Godspeed.