Grandmother!
Grandma, please open up the door!
-You should see somebody else.
-Grandma!
Excuse me.
This is private property.
Janet Hardy's family might not appreciate
you going all demolition derby on it.
We don't mind.
Oh, wait a minute.
You're her granddaughter, Katie Lawrence.
I played a little girl on TV
called Katie Lawrence.
My name is Cilla McGowan.
And please, don't tell me I haven't changed
a bit 'cause I know that's just not true.
No, you've changed.
A lot. Your grandmother was amazing.
Working with Brando and Beatty
and McQueen.
Those hit songs. An Academy Award winner.
Two-time Academy Award winner.
Yeah, and I never met her.
She died before I was born.
Listen, you're not gonna brain me
with that sledgehammer
-if I come a little closer, are you?
-Well, not unless you give me cause.
Ford Sawyer.
I live across the road.
Who names their kid after a car?
Apparently I was conceived
in the back of a Ford Mustang.
Good thing your father didn't have a Camry.
Well, I'll let you get back to work.
I work at home, too,
so if you need anything, give a holler.
Thanks for the help, neighbor!
Grandmother?
Cilla?
Hi.
Did you bring my pills?
Oh, that's a good girl.
Grandma needs to sleep.
Where's your mother?
-Where's Johnnie?
-Grandma, Johnnie's dead.
I have to hurry.
Don't do that. No! Don't do that, Grandma.
Don't take those! Don't do it.
Are you kidding me?
What the heck happened here?
Somebody just cut down my new trees.
You know, some guy's been lurking around.
He must've really disagreed
with your landscaping choices.
-You must be Brian.
-I am. You're definitely Cilla McGowan.
-Hi.
I'm gonna get this fixed up for you, okay?
I'm gonna give Shanna down at the nursery
a call and get you some replacements.
Thank you, Brian.
This is the master bathroom.
Buddy, we're gonna take this wall back,
push it back four feet.
That toilet is gonna end up right there
and this whole entire wall's gonna be
all glass bricks.
Whole shower wall, right there.
You know, you won't have any privacy.
That's so that the natural sunlight
gets in the shower.
Why in God's world does anybody need
this many showerheads?
It's body jets, Buddy. It's very modern.
Oh, it's not just a shower, Buddy,
it's an experience.
Wait till you try it out. Come on,
check out the kitchen. You'll like it.
-You want me to get that for you, Cilla?
-No, thanks, I got it.
Check this out.
-Awesome.
-Right?
Yes.
Isn't that amazing?
I'm surprised anything's left in here
with all the tenants that this place had
over the years.
Will this not make the most incredible
office space, though?
It would.
Would you have the guys move all this stuff
into the barn tomorrow?
-Absolutely.
-That'd be great.
Have them be careful.
It's all my grandmother's stuff.
I don't even know what's in here.
Look at this.
So the gardens will be restored
to their original glory.
Yeah, I'll get rid of all the vines
and squatter bushes that have taken over.
Perfect. That tree. That oak tree, l...
Shanna, who is that man?
That's Carl Hennessey.
Hennessey. Thank you.
Excuse me, Mr. Hennessey!
Mr. Hennessey.
Hi, Mr. Hennessey.
Did you see who cut down my trees?
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
What is his problem?
Oh, wow.
Grandma, you kept your rare ones.
You saved them.
"Songs for a Rainy Afternoon."
Wow.
Perfect.
Grandma, Mom and Johnnie.
Oh, Grandma.
"Trudy, my heart pounds as I write this.
"Every night I dream of you,
"your laugh, your smell, your taste.
"l dream of making love to you.
"I'm yours forever."
A secret admirer.
-Cilla, you in there?
-Yeah.
Hi.
Housewarming present?
Actually, no.
It's payment, in advance.
I'm a graphic novelist and I'm creating
a new character for a new series.
And I need you. You're my woman.
Will I be needing my sledgehammer?
Wait. Look.
This is Dr. Cass Murphy.
She's an archeologist,
professor of the same.
She's a quiet, cool, solitary woman,
emotionally repressed, you know?
She looks boring.
She'll find an ancient weapon when
she's trapped in the cave by an evil sorcerer.
Naturally.
Listen, Ford,
I have a lot of work to do still, okay?
She transforms into a Celtic goddess
with china doll skin, amber eyes.
Fierce, sexy.
Her weapon of choice,
a two-headed hammer.
I need you, and your sledgehammer.
I think you should go now.
I just need a couple of shots of you
while you're working around the yard.
-This guy bothering you?
-I can handle him.
Hey, Brian.
What, does everybody know
everyone else around here?
-Pretty much.
-Yeah, we went to high school together...
And still play a poker game that our
daddies' daddies started 50 years ago?
-52 years ago.
I didn't get to go to high school.
I had a tutor that came to the set.
-Well, that's cool.
-Oh, no. No, no, no. Not cool.
Especially when it came time for the prom.
My parents used to hang here all the time.
There were some wild-ass parties here.
We're talking wild-ass.
Well, there's a tradition that I'll restore.
Ford, go home.
-You're married.
-I know.
Nice.
Nice. Hold that right there. Up, up, up.
Beautiful.
Can you do one with the...
Like up over your head, both arms?
Nice. Beautiful. I'm loving it.
How about one just regular like you're gonna
swing it right above your head?
Beautiful.
Could you hold it up there?
Look, Ford, I don't know
if you've noticed or not,
but I'm actually trying
to make some progress here.
Just pretend like I'm not even here.
Oh, easily done.
Wait, wait, can you go back to that,
just hold that for a second?
Real good. Hold that.
That's beautiful. Freeze.
So, it can't be nice staying in a house
without running water.
If you want, you could shower at my place.
Now that is actually an offer
I don't think I can refuse.
So, what's next?
I have to take my Virginia State
Contractor's License test.
So, listen, could you help?
Yeah, no, I don't do hammers.
But I wield a pretty mean spatula.
How do you like your steak?
So I can hear it whisper, "Moo."
I brought your bottle of wine.
The return of the prodigal Pinot.
I was just in the middle
of saving the universe from aliens,
but the universe can wait.
Naturally.
My mother, who's an actress,
always hated it here,
but she just couldn't bring herself
to sell the place.
So I'd been thinking about buying it
from her for years.
-Even though you'd never been here?
-Janet loved The Little Farm.
And I always wanted to know why.
Besides, it's where she died.
I never really liked Hollywood anyway.
-More wine?
-Sure.
-Hit me, baby.
-But you were so successful.
Well, one hit show, several, thanks,
several B movies,
yeah, does not a career make, so...
-Madame.
-Thank you, monsieur.
My mother loved the idea of us
being this big acting family,
Iike the Fondas or the Barrymores.
She pushed me into it.
But, you know, the one good thing
about being a child star
was that my TV family and l
became very close.
All I wanted was a home.
What? What?
What?
You know, from the movies and the pictures
I've seen of your grandmother,
you're way more beautiful than she was.
This would be me officially hitting on you.
That's not a smart idea.
I've already hit my quota of mistakes
for the decade.
-What?
-Live a little.
Oh, I have. See, I've lived a lot.
For instance, if I were to sleep over,
right, I wouldn't sleep in the spare room.
I'd sleep with you.
Would you like some salad now?
Yeah.
Thank you for the lovely dinner
and the wine.
Appreciate everything.
Being hit on, you know.
Thank you.
Let me walk you home.
I just live right across the street.
-Who's that?
-Steve.
Steve!
Hey!
-Cilla!
-Steve!
-Hey, hey!
-Steve, give me a hug!
-I'm so excited that you're here.
-It's beautiful. Come on, let's go.
We can make something amazing
out of this, right?
-And we create a space right here.
-Why didn't I think of that?
-And you can go straight to the porch.
-You're a genius.
-Excuse me.
-Okay.
Hi.
Just wanted to see if you got home okay.
Who is it?
This is Steve Chensky, to whom
I was married for about five minutes.
It was five months, Cilla.
Steve taught me everything I know
about flipping houses.
And a few other things.
Steve, this is Ford Sawyer.
-Ford Sawyer?
-Yeah.
The Ford Sawyer?
No fricking way.
Ford here created the Prodigal series.
He is The Prodigal.
Oh, dude, check this out, man. Look at this.
You did that?
Not that, but yeah. The Prodigal, he's mine.
-Cool.
-Cool?
Really cool.
You know, I'm really happy you're here.
And you can stay as long as you want,
but you really need to get
your own sleeping bag, okay?
Excuse me. Please.
-It's just, I can't get this side zipped.
-Okay.
Oh, for crying out loud.
You know, we'd take up less room
if we spooned.
And, even less if we...
Harsh.
Okay.
Did you hear that creak?
-It's an old house, Cill.
-No, that was a creak.
It creaks.
Somebody already vandalized my trees.
I just wanna make sure.
Should we go investigate?
No.
Steve.
Prodigal Man. How goes it?
Thought you might like these.
Prodigal originals, issues one through six.
Bro.
Wow. Thanks, man.
So, Steve, you mind if I ask you
why you and Cilla split?
Took us about five minutes to realize
we were better at the friend gig
than the marriage thing.
I love her, like a sister.
Thanks.
You know, if you're gonna be
hanging around for a while,
you can crash at my place.
No sense you sleeping in the barn.
-I'm not sleeping in the barn.
-Oh, really?
I just figured, you know, I saw a flashlight
going down there last night.
No fricking way. When?
3:00 in the morning.
-No way.
-The place is trashed. Look at this.
They tore through these boxes.
And all her jewelry.
What are you boys up to?
Ford saw somebody skulking around
last night.
Oh, my God.
-Same time you heard that creaking noise.
-Oh, no.
If I were you, I'd start locking the barn.
Look at all this.
-What?
-What is it?
It's a splinter.
Oh, I feel so much safer
with you boys around.
I offered Steve a room.
Well, that's very neighborly of you.
Not really.
I couldn't sleep knowing the two of you guys
were sharing a bedroom.
-Thanks.
-Well, thank you, neighbor.
-All right.
-Thank you.
Wanna come to dinner
with me tonight in town?
Sorry, I got a date with Shanna.
The landscaper. That was fast.
-Life's short.
-Yes, it is.
All right.
Have fun!
Don't wait up.
Pregnant?
You were pregnant.
Oh, Grandma, what happened to you?
Hollywood is where the magic happens.
In the real world, we're just ghosts,
but here, we're real.
But this isn't real.
I hated acting. I felt so alone
being the center of everyone's attention.
I was always happy on set.
But you killed yourself.
-And if you were pregnant...
-lf?
If, if, if
"lf" is for tomorrow.
Who is the father?
Hey!
-Good morning, Cilla.
-Morning.
-I brought delicious donuts.
-I love donuts.
Hey, is Steve up yet?
-I thought he spent the night with you.
-No.
This lock's been cut.
I locked that last night.
-Oh, God.
-Oh, no.
Oh, God. Honey.
Will somebody call 91 1!
Stay with me, baby.
Just breathe.
Why would anyone wanna hurt Steve?
-lt was probably just some scavenger.
-No.
Steve was just in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Ford.
-Hey.
Cilla, this is my mom, Cathy.
You poor dear.
Mom works here as a volunteer.
Your friend is in very capable hands.
Dr. Patel is operating,
but it's gonna be a few more hours.
Thank you, Mrs. Morrow.
-Please, call me Cathy.
-Cathy.
Thanks, Mom.
-And I'll call you if I hear anything.
-Thanks.
I'm gonna go back to your place and make
sure everything's okay. Are you okay?
-Okay. Thank you.
-Yeah, thanks.
-Bye.
-All right. See you later.
Ford, you don't need to stick around.
-I'm not leaving you alone.
-Okay.
May I help you?
-I'm looking for a Cilla McGowan.
-That's me.
-Ms. McGowan.
-Yes.
-I'm Detective Wilson.
-Nice to meet you.
-Hello, Al.
-Ford.
I'd like to speak to you alone.
-Fine, I'll go make a phone call.
-Thanks.
Okay.
What exactly is your relationship
to Mr. Chensky?
Exactly, we used to be married.
-Was Mr. Chensky jealous of Mr. Sawyer?
-Oh, no, no.
Steve absolutely idolizes Ford.
You know, you should
check into Mr. Hennessey
and see what he was doing last night.
Carl Hennessey? Why?
I had just planted some new trees
and somebody chose to chop them down.
Hennessey's van was parked
outside my house.
I confronted him about it. He spat at me.
-You know, Hennessey does have motive.
-What do you mean?
Well, his son died last year
and he still blames your grandmother
for what happened.
What happened?
You don't know
about your Uncle Johnnie's accident?
I know my Uncle Johnnie died in a car crash.
Well, Hennessey's son was in the car
with him and he was left a quadriplegic.
Oh, my God.
Your Uncle Johnnie was driving
and he was drunk.
So Hennessey blamed my grandmother
and now he blames me.
I'll talk to Hennessey.
In the meantime, I'll send a cruiser
past your place every couple of hours.
Thank you. Thank you.
You should probably get an alarm system.
Or a big dog.
I'll get an alarm system.
Less cleanup.
-Thanks, Al.
-See you, Ford.
Thank you.
Sleep at my house tonight.
I don't want you staying alone.
Oh, no. I'm gonna be sleeping in my house.
Fine. So will l, then.
In my own bag.
This is not negotiable.
You could put your sleeping bag
on the mattress next to me... Mine.
Okay.
You can turn around now.
I sleep in boxers.
I've seen boxers.
I'm not as decent as you.
Okay.
I've never seen those boxers before.
I get Prodigal swag for free.
I'm glad you're here.
Glad to be here.
Good night.
Cilla. Cilla, over here. This way.
-Who are you looking for?
-Trudy.
But you are Trudy.
Of course.
But Janet's much more interesting. Here it is.
Oh, my.
Who did you kill that night, Janet or Trudy?
I'm pregnant.
I'm finally happy again.
Cilla!
Would you keep this here for me?
There are so many people
in and out of my house.
Sure.
"Trudy Hamilton."
That was my grandmother's real name.
It seems like the affair started just
about a few months before Johnnie died.
The last letter was mailed
and sent to The Little Farm
about a week before Janet killed herself.
They're all unsigned.
But they're all postmarked from around here.
He was married.
And Janet was carrying his baby.
If she was carrying his baby,
and if Janet knew she was pregnant,
why would she kill herself?
Maybe it was an accidental overdose.
Listen to this. The last one.
"This stops now. The calls to my wife,
the threats, the hysteria stops now.
"Whatever we had, it's over, Janet."
And there's a section...
"Don't threaten me again
or you will pay for it.
"l promise you."
What if she didn't commit suicide?
Wilson should have these.
No, not yet. Letters from Janet Hardy's lover.
No.
All that speculation, the press,
the obsessed fans.
My grandmother's name
would be dragged through the mud again.
And any chance that I had at a normal life
will go up in flames.
So for now, this will just be our little secret.
You wanna go get some ice cream?
You are a very confusing man, Ford.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Thanks.
-That's Janet's granddaughter.
-Hi.
See what it's like being
Janet Hardy's granddaughter?
Complete strangers just stop you
and stare at you,
tell you that you remind them of her.
Do l? Am I like her?
I don't even know who I am.
Well, I'm not sure
what your grandmother was like,
but I'm getting to know you.
What, neurotic, self-doubting?
-And smart, self-assured. Driven.
-Okay, right.
-What do you think?
-Okay.
So, you want to replace
all the broken rosette medallions
-with these...
-Shamrocks.
-...shamrocks?
-Yes. Yes, they are lrish and lucky,
and I think my grandmother
would've gotten a big kick out of them.
What was she like, my grandma?
I remember her laugh.
She kind of lit the place up.
Do you remember any talk of her
getting friendly with a local man?
Lots of folks said all kinds of things.
Most of it wasn't even
in the same neighborhood as the truth.
"What distance is required
between masonry veneer and sheathing?"
All right, we've got, "A, five inches.
"B, one inch. C, two inches."
All right, this one's easy.
I know you hate losing to a girl. Come on.
It's a no-brainer. Okay.
I'm going with one inch.
Come in.
This is really fantastic.
And extremely disappointing.
-You don't like it?
-I love it.
Means you won't be showering
at my place anymore.
I might.
If you ask nicely. Towel, please.
Thank you. This is huge.
-It's a beach towel.
-You said big.
A Prodigal towel.
I thought I might make you dinner tonight.
Thank you, but I'm not hungry.
I'm really nervous about that test.
It's coming up soon. I have to study for it.
Well, you can't study on an empty stomach.
Besides, I'm making
my number two specialty.
You all right?
Mac and cheese?
What's your third specialty, Lunchables?
You know when a guy offers
to cook dinner for you,
especially when your kitchen's a disaster,
I wouldn't complain.
Why are you doing all this for me?
Because I believe you matter.
That's the second time
you've said something to me
that nobody's ever said to me before.
What was the first?
That you wouldn't leave me alone.
Hey!
Hennessey! Hey!
-Get away. Get away.
-I've had enough of you!
You have hurt us enough.
I've hurt you?
What the hell are you talking about?
-You'll not get away with it.
-You almost killed Steve.
Do you know he's in the hospital?
-Stop spinning your lies to the police.
-Did you know that?
I'm not lying to the police.
You stay away from me.
You stay away from my house!
You stay away from everybody I know!
You stay away!
-Cathy, hi.
-Hello, Cilla.
-How are you?
-How's Steve?
-He's doing better, getting stronger.
-Yeah? Good.
-I'm Tom. Cathy's husband.
-Hello.
How's our son working out?
Is he doing the job for you?
Brian's doing fantastic.
So you are Tom. The Tom,
finally the real estate guru.
Maybe we could talk sometime
about the local market.
I'd love to find some fixer-uppers.
-Anytime, I'd love to help.
-Thank you.
You really are putting roots down.
That's fantastic.
Well, I better go see Steve.
But I'd love it if you two could drop by
and maybe see some of Brian's work.
Okay, I was hoping you'd invite us.
Take care. Be strong.
-All righty.
-Bye. Thanks.
The reason to make this place home
is because of people like the Morrows,
and Brian, Shanna and even cranky Buddy.
And Ford.
I know that I don't have the best track record
when it comes to relationships,
present company included,
but I really think I'm falling for this guy.
Damn.
Steve? Steve?
Steve, did you just say something?
Did you just talk? Talk to me, baby.
What are you doing here?
You're here, you're in Virginia.
-Oh, right.
-You're fine.
Everything's going to heal.
I'm so glad you're okay.
-ls my bike okay?
-Yeah. Your bike is perfect.
It's perfect. I already shipped it back to LA.
Little Farm. I'm not here right now,
but you can leave
your message after the beep.
Hi. You didn't answer the door
and now you're not answering this,
so I'm wondering if I should worry
or be insanely jealous
because you ran off with someone.
Anyway, give me a call
so I know one way or the other.
Man, you are so cute,
and if I wasn't so tired right now,
I'd go right on over there
and jump your bones.
They bypassed the alarm by busting the lock
off the cellar doors here.
Well, I'll get Brian
to wire the cellar doors, too.
Whoever did this knew
you were out of the house.
I strongly believe that Mr. Hennessey
had something to do
with my grandmother's death.
Your grandmother committed suicide.
Now they're all unsigned.
That could've been Hennessey.
The lower case Ys are really distinctive,
like little fish hooks.
I mean, it would be easy
to check his handwriting.
Yeah.
That would make Hennessey
and your grandmother lovers.
Think about it. I mean,
if Hennessey was sleeping with Janet
when his son was killed,
it would be a really heavy guilt trip.
The tenor of the letters,
they all changed after the accident.
Then Janet found out she was pregnant
and wanted to keep the baby.
Hennessey could've killed my grandmother
and made it look like a suicide.
Well, Hennessey claims he was at home
with his wife when Steve was attacked,
and she backs him up.
I'm gonna talk to them again.
And I'll get a writing sample.
Why am I still here?
I could go back to LA with Steve, make
a perfectly good living flipping houses.
Go is not an option.
You know you wanna stay.
Yeah, but what if it's a mistake?
I don't think so.
I think this house is worth fighting for.
Would...
Would you hold me for a little while, please?
Sure.
Thank you.
Better?
Yeah.
We'll figure it out. But not tonight.
Tonight we'll just lie here
and listen to the house settling
and the night, and the bugs.
Why aren't you in a relationship?
-Been saving myself.
-For what?
You.
What if I never came here?
Well, I'd have been a very lonely man.
Hennessey, open up!
Hi. Excuse me, I need to speak
with your husband, please.
-He isn't here.
-Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
-Listen, little girl, you've got to stop this.
-Me?
-What the hell are you talking about?
-What?
-Lying to the police.
-No, no, tell your husband to stop.
-Stop what? My husband is a good man.
-Stop the vandalism, stop the attacks.
-Stop stalking me.
-Yeah, you, just go away, now.
-Do you know that your husband's a stalker?
-You and your kin
have done nothing
but bring us sorrow and misery.
That guy is absolutely crazy.
You do not come to my house
-and you do not talk to my wife.
-You are one crazy son of a bitch.
Hey! What are you doing?
Get back.
Stay down or I will need to keep you down!
I called the police.
I see you in there, Janet Hardy.
Take Mr. Hennessey to county.
He's absolutely crazy.
He thinks I'm Janet Hardy.
You better get that arm checked out
at the hospital.
No, I'm fine. Thanks.
It's all over now, Cilla. Hennessey's gone.
Come here.
Wow.
This is incredible.
Oh, my lord. She's a goddess.
-An ass-kicking goddess.
-She looks so strong and bold.
-And fierce and sexy.
-And nothing like me.
Where's this coming from?
I got all this from you.
I'm thinking about giving Brid a tattoo.
Wow. Celtic symbol of female power.
-Like Steve didn't tell you.
-No. Kismet.
All my life people have watched me,
took pictures of me, observed me.
And, I didn't have control over it.
This little tattoo is private.
I control who I share it with.
-I can change her face if you want.
-No, no, no.
I love being the inspiration
for a comic book heroine.
It's just...
I just think that the cup size
is a bit exaggerated, you know.
Well, let me get it right.
Let you see yourself as I do.
How do you...
-Just...
-Do you want me to pose like?
...make yourself comfortable.
-What, I'm not comfortable enough for you?
-Somewhat.
-Just lie back.
-How do you want...
Baby face, come here.
Nice.
You wanna move that leg up a little
and give me a little space?
That's nice.
Bring your hand up
above and next to the other arm.
-There?
-Yeah. Little more comfortable.
Beautiful.
So why a Celtic tattoo?
My grandmother's mother's name
was Annie Rose McKenna. She was lrish.
You're not gonna put the tattoo
on her behind, are you?
Sexy. Very sexy.
What about on her bicep?
-I can do that.
-Like a real superhero.
-Done and done.
-Thank you.
-Fabulous.
-Can I see it?
-Sure.
-It's ready?
I have had my picture
taken about a zillion times
and nobody's ever actually captured me.
We should do that again sometime soon.
At least try, if you can manage.
Well, the first time
I was only going about 75%.
Now for round two.
Oh, no, that's my alarm.
My truck!
Ford? Just stop it!
Oh, man, my tires.
Ford. Ford, they slashed my tires.
They keyed
the whole entire side of the truck.
-What the hell's that?
-What?
It's me.
It's a Katie Lawrence doll.
My God.
This is what they wanna do to me.
Give me that.
-It's not over.
-Come here.
We'll take the doll in and see
if we can pull any evidence from it.
Has anyone else threatened you
or treated you oddly?
I've gotten some looks, stares, comments.
I'll double the drive-bys
and park a cruiser out front.
-Well, where was Mrs. Hennessey?
-We're looking for her.
There you are.
-Can I get a hit of your coffee?
-Sure.
Sitting here, for the first time,
I can see why she felt the way she did
about it here.
I feel it, too.
That's 'cause you're not just rebuilding
a house, you're bringing it back to life.
As a tribute to my grandmother.
But it's really... It's for me, too.
Morning, Alvin.
-Morning.
Forensics couldn't lift any prints
from the doll,
but we found some residual cornstarch.
-Cornstarch?
-Modified cornstarch.
Whoever did this to your car
was wearing latex gloves.
They're very common,
but we're looking into it.
Good.
And we found Mrs. Hennessey.
She was staying down at a motel
near the prison.
She was visiting her husband.
She's back, so I'm gonna pay her a visit.
-Thank you.
-See you.
-Have a good day.
-You, too.
Hey, shouldn't you be getting going?
Excuse me.
-ls this the Contractor's License exam?
-Yes, ma'am. Take a seat.
Gentlemen.
Wow. Things are looking up, huh?
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Okay. All right, everyone, you got two hours
before the break. Good luck.
I am Contractor Girl.
To your success.
No. Yeah, I can't...
So I've been doing some detective work.
After the test,
I went down to the Hall of Records.
Look what I found.
That's Janet Hardy's autopsy report.
"Janet Hardy was a 38-year-old
Caucasian woman,
"died of acute combined drug
and alcohol intoxication.
"The manner of death
is determined to be accident."
There's no mention of a pregnancy. Look.
It's possible that Janet lied
about being pregnant.
Well, that's what I'm gonna find out.
Excuse me. Dr. Rice?
-Do I know you?
-No.
But my grandmother was Janet Hardy.
Here, look at this.
You examined her heart, her stomach,
her blood.
How did you miss the pregnancy?
Look, I was persuaded
to leave that detail out of my official report.
-By whom?
-I got a frantic phone call.
It was the publicist who called me.
She begged me not to note the pregnancy.
Why would you listen to her?
The way I saw it,
the only victim of my omission
was the unborn baby.
Unless Janet didn't kill herself,
then they're both victims.
Young lady, I didn't see any hand
in Janet Hardy's death except her own.
If Janet's publicist knew she was pregnant,
she probably knew she was having an affair.
-Let me try something.
-Who're you calling?
-Hello.
-Mom, it's Cilla. Yes.
No, I know you're busy.
I know, I just have to ask you
one quick question.
Who was grandmother's publicist
when she died?
She had the same publicist her whole life.
It was George.
-Who?
-You don't remember?
-Are you sure?
-You're coming to...
No, I don't wanna fly there
and be in your show.
-Okay? I'm sorry.
-You should be in my show.
Did you know that Grandma was pregnant
when she died?
Or that she was having an affair?
-You are obsessed.
-Mom. I'm not obsessed, Mom.
-Yes, you are.
-Mom?
Okay.
I come from a dysfunctional family.
Well, that was interesting.
So, it couldn't have been Janet's publicist
that called Dr. Rice.
Janet's publicist was a man.
Mrs. Hennessey.
-Mrs. Hennessey, please.
-Haven't you done enough?
No. Listen,
let's just stop this craziness, okay?
-Just go away.
-I'm not going anywhere.
Mrs. Hennessey, what happened
to your son's a tragedy, but...
But it was an accident
that I had nothing to do with.
Mrs. Hennessey, please.
When my grandmother died,
was it you that called Dr. Rice?
Mrs. Hennessey, please.
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine.
Just need to mail this to the publisher.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
-Oh, sorry. You okay?
-I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Yeah, I'm fine.
I saw Ford's truck
and my office is right there.
Okay.
-And following up on our conversation...
-Cool.
...current comps and listings.
That's great.
This soft market is a great opportunity.
Well, I will check it out.
She's not selling you Little Farm, Tom.
-Now, look at you.
-We're talking about
future business ventures, okay?
-I'll see you kids later.
-Okay. Have a great day.
-Get out of here.
-Get out of here, you.
This is what I was telling you about.
All up here, original plaster, man.
Oh, look at the little shamrocks. I love them.
The parties, they were so much fun.
I especially remember
that last Christmas party.
That's the last time I was here.
All the decorations.
Oh, and the lights.
They were all over.
And music.
Oh, the music.
Oh, and the amazing pink couch right here.
And Janet in her sexy blue dress.
Everybody just begged her to sing.
There was a box
baby grand piano over there.
Oh, and who was it...
Everybody thought she was having an affair
with a composer.
-Lenny Eisner.
-Lenny Eisner. Right.
But then it turned out that he was gay.
It was happier times.
It was...
It was that Christmas, too,
before Johnnie's death.
I'm sorry.
I took a morbid turn.
Old houses, they're full of life and death.
Cathy, do you remember
Janet having an affair with some...
A local married man?
Somebody local?
I don't know, honey.
No jealous wives beating her door down?
Not that I ever heard of.
Okay.
You are so very much
like your grandmother.
Your spunk and your determination.
And all these horrible things
keep happening to you, but you stay.
I think your grandmother
would be very, very proud of you.
Maybe you could help me with something.
I'm just trying to put names to all the faces.
Why, honey, that's Big Drew Morrow,
Brian's grandfather.
He died about 20 years ago.
Sweet. Look at him.
-Hey.
-Hi.
-What's the matter?
-I'm depressed.
I thought I found out something,
but it was just another dead end.
Well, let me make you feel better.
Sit.
Okay.
Close your eyes.
Close them.
-Can I open them now? I hate surprises.
-Not yet.
Can I open my eyes, please?
Open them.
Oh, my gosh.
It's fantastic.
-Wow.
-You're the first to see it.
It's such a work of art.
"Her quest had taken her far away."
I couldn't have done it without you.
Seriously, I had nothing
before you came here
and started swinging your sledgehammer.
Be mine.
Be your what?
My family.
Ford, please don't do this.
Look, I draw comics and I play video games.
But I make a pretty decent living.
I'm a fairly good cook
if you like steak and Mac and cheese.
Which I think you do.
Ford, listen to me.
You're steady.
I'm disordered.
All right?
Yeah.
-Marry me.
-Okay.
Look. I am a third-generation screw-up
when it comes to men.
My grandmother, complete disaster.
My mother,
my mother has been married five times.
Yeah, five husbands. Five.
Can you believe it?
Me, I was even married once
for like five minutes.
Trust me, save yourself a lot of heartache.
Open it.
It's not poisonous, I swear.
You don't wear a lot of jewelry.
When you do, you don't go in for the flash.
You're not the type of girl who's gonna
impress the other girls with a big, fat rock.
And you work with your hands,
so that had to be considered.
You put a lot of thought into it.
It's not that hard.
All right, say I said, "Yes, yes,"
you know, "Let's get married,
"let's go to Vegas,
like my grandmother and my mother,
"let's go to The Little Chapel of Love."
You pack the bags, I'll book the flights.
What is wrong with you?
You're making my head spin here.
You're not thinking about any practicality
or the reality of the situation.
-Like what?
-Like where would we live?
-The Little Farm.
-Okay, what would we do with this house?
This house I bought as is.
You've made a home for yourself
at The Little Farm.
Let me into your home, Cilla.
-I'm drowning here.
-I just wanna try it on.
It's pretty.
Okay.
-Okay.
-Okay?
-Oh, great, an audience.
-I need my construction gloves.
Yeah, you big toughie.
Would you focus on the mattress?
I can't focus on anything else.
This is just ridiculous.
Let's not forget,
I taught Brid everything that she knows.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Ford! Ford!
What does it say?
"Leave or die."
Put it in the van for me.
I'm sending this doll to Forensics.
We found a couple of footprints in the mud
near the kitchen.
They're small like a boy's
or a woman's prints.
-What about Mrs. Hennessey?
-I sent a car to check on her.
Whoever's doing this is coming
in your house while you're at home.
I wouldn't stay here anymore.
-Well, we can stay at my house.
-That's a good idea.
Good news is, they're getting sloppy.
We're gonna get them.
Hey, Sam, did you get your note?
Guess we shouldn't have brought
the mattress over here.
Unit 11, Unit 11, come in.
-What's your 20, 11?
-I'm about...
-I believe in love.
-Love never made you happy.
But it gave me Johnnie and Dilly.
And this one.
Maybe this one will be another boy.
Who's the father?
Did he hurt you?
He loved me.
-Did the baby ruin everything?
-Not my baby, Cilla.
Her baby.
His wife was pregnant?
You've read all the letters.
What's his name?
-Janet, tell me his name.
-Pay attention.
You have the answer.
Morning.
Can't you ever sleep in?
Had another dream last night.
I missed something.
"l have my wife, my children,
and the one on the way to think about."
His wife was pregnant, too.
The guy was a baby factory.
And the kid would be about 35 now.
My age.
We have to find out who was born
in the months following her death.
We'll know exactly who the father was.
Monday we could drive up to Richmond
and look at the birth records.
What about your yearbook?
The kids had to be in your class.
-You're good.
-You think?
Robert Mach, Mark McCorkle.
They moved out of town.
Okay, Denise Messenger.
She's gone.
Brian Morrow. Even Brian's the right age.
About half the class is.
You were a math nerd?
Algebra tutor and great kisser.
And there's Janet and Johnnie
and that's Hennessey's son.
There's Tom. That must be Cathy.
I hardly recognize her.
This must be the last Christmas party
before Johnnie died.
They all look so young and happy.
Oh, that must be Brian. Go.
-No.
-Come on, go, have fun.
-Go.
-I'm not leaving you here alone.
-I'm fine.
-Brian will understand.
No, Brian's gonna blame me. Go.
All right.
But lock the door behind me
and set my alarm.
And if anything happens you call me.
I promise. Okay?
Scram!
-Hey, guys.
-Hey, Ford.
Hello?
Ford?
I'm out.
Come on, we're just teasing.
Anyone want another beer?
What the heck, bro.
Okay, you're living on the edge, huh?
Hello?
Wait one sec.
Cathy, you frightened me.
-I'm so sorry to bother you.
-It's okay.
I went by your house first
and then I saw the light on here.
I lost one of my rings
and it was my grandmother's.
That's terrible.
I took it off when I washed my hands
in your powder room.
Okay, I don't remember seeing it.
The place is a real mess,
but let's go down there,
Iet's look for it.
-Thank you so much, sweetheart.
-Don't worry about it.
I've had my ring for a few days.
If I had lost it, I would go berserk.
What? What ring?
Well, Ford has asked me to marry him.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Oh, I can't believe I didn't notice that.
We're gonna live here at The Little Farm.
And it looks like
we're gonna be staying for a while.
-What was that?
-I don't know.
-Did you hear that?
-Okay...
Come on. All right, I don't know what it was.
Come on, let's get in there.
You can't hide in there all night.
I'm just looking to delay
losing the rest of my money.
-Well, that's inevitable. Come on back.
-We miss you, man.
-Let me just run and see.
-All right.
-I found it.
-Great.
Thank goodness.
Look at me, I'm shaking.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Cilla, could I trouble you for a glass of wine
and maybe an Aspirin?
-I've got such a headache now.
-Of course.
The kitchen's right that way.
I think there's already an open bottle
of wine. I'll get your Aspirin.
-All right, thank you.
-No problem. Help yourself.
Hi. You found it.
Yeah. Here.
I'd like to make a little toast.
To you and Ford,
may you have a long and happy life together.
Thank you.
Please excuse this mess.
I have been sorting through
all of these images, old and new,
just trying to tell the right stories.
The house and my grandmother's life.
What a wonderful idea.
What's up?
-You had an affair with Janet Hardy.
-What?
Cilla found your letters.
The handwriting matches.
I love Brian and Cathy. That's why
I'm talking to you before I go to the police.
With what, a bunch of unsigned letters?
Never said they were unsigned, Tom.
Look, I was mesmerized by her.
I betrayed my wife.
And when I heard from Brian
that things were found,
personal things...
You went to Cilla's house
and nearly killed Steve?
I never meant to hit him that hard.
Did you kill Janet Hardy?
You all look so happy.
Look at Tom.
He was so handsome.
He means everything to me.
You got the timing mixed up.
The couch wasn't pink.
She must've bought that
after that Christmas.
And she's not wearing the blue dress.
Marriages are tenuous things.
They take work.
There wasn't anything
I wouldn't do to keep Tom.
I'd do anything to keep him.
I starved myself, exercised,
liposuction, facelift.
Tom would never look at me
and want another woman again.
Again?
Again.
You...
Cilla?
You okay?
That wine must've went straight to my head.
I have to get something to eat.
-I just have to get something to eat.
-Here. No, it's all right.
Come on, sit here.
I think you need to drink the rest of that.
Oh, I better not.
I insist.
Just a little more.
Finish the job.
I went to her house.
She said that she was keeping the baby
and we argued.
But, I swear to you, she was alive when I left.
I couldn't kill Janet.
She was carrying my child.
Janet called your house.
Yes. She spoke with Cathy.
Oh, my God. What did she do?
Cilla's at my house alone.
You call the police.
You...
You put something in my drink.
Yeah. Yeah.
Seconal.
Same as your whore of a grandmother.
The pictures.
You were remembering the pink couch
the night she died,
not the night of the party.
Aren't you a little smarty-pants.
Oh, no, you don't. No.
Just relax, dear.
Soon you'll pass out just like Janet did.
And then...
I'll help you to another drink or two or ten.
Come on, Cilla, pick up.
I don't think
you wanna be disturbed tonight.
Janet.
She could've had anybody.
But she took my husband.
And she made a fool out of me.
I didn't have anything to do...
You came back
and you shoved it in my face!
You know, I tried to get you to leave.
Yeah, I cut down your trees,
destroyed your truck.
If only you had gone away.
Why couldn't you let this house die?
Cilla? Cilla?
Cilla! Cilla!
Cilla!
I'm sorry.
I tried to help you.
You did, honey.
Help me. Help me.
But I couldn't save you.
Save yourself, Cilla.
All right. That's it.
Cilla.
Missy-May.
Go to sleep.
Save yourself.
Cilla!
Tom?
Cilla? Cilla.
Cilla?
-You move again, I'll shoot you.
-Ford, it wasn't me.
It wasn't me. I didn't do it. I didn't do it.
It was her. It was her. It was her.
Cilla, come on.
-Come here, baby.
-Ford,
I did it like Brid.
I CSI'd her ass.
Cilla.
Cilla, stay awake, baby.
Come on, baby, help's coming.
Come on, stay awake.
-Cilla. Stay with me, baby.
-I did good.
We have to be at Brian's in an hour.
Well, if we've got an hour, let me draw you.
The last time you drew me,
I think it took a little more than an hour.
Well, we can skip the preliminaries
and go right to the intimate stuff.
In an hour? I don't know.