The Allies have landed in Italy,
which is occupied by the Germans.
where Mussolini is still in control,
the American, British, Canadian and French armies
are held up by the solid German defense belt
along the Gustav line,
in the area of Monte Cassino.
Perched on top of the mountain
is historical St Benedict's monastery.
The Allies think that the Germans have turned
this 1.400 year old monument into a lookout post.
More than 200 allied bombers will drop
over 500 tons of bombs on the monastery.
In Word War 2, nothing is sacred.
It turns everything into an inferno.
World War II
The Apocalypse
Episode 6 (final episode):
Retreat and Surrender
March 15, 1944
The Allies launch their attack.
But the German paratroopers push them back.
The German shock troops are now firmly
entrenched in the ruined monastery.
Nothing was achieved by the bombing.
These scenes were filmed by the American director
John Houston who was sent to this front in Italy.
He would later say:
It was a massacre in the freezing cold
And yet Churchill had called Italy
"the soft underbelly" of Europe.
By moving in from the South via Italy,
Churchill's aim was to take Berlin
before the Russians could.
The Red Army continues to advance
steadily from the East.
Kiev is liberated.
The German Wehrmacht army pulls out of the Ukraine,
obeying Hitler's orders to
systematically destroy everything.
Ukraine
In Italy, several months later, the
Wehrmacht is still holding the Gustav line...
and Monte Cassino.
The French General Juin proposes to
surprise the Germans,
who have left those slopes,
thought to be too steep, undefended.
The rugged soldiers of the North African
and Polish regiments however,
managed to climb up the mountain
and put the allies on the road to Rome.
Rome
June 5, 1944
As the Wehrmacht retreats,
it once again leaves a path
of destruction behind it.
But, together with Mussolini
and his remaining fascists,
the Germans will retain control of
northern Italy and its industries.
They are the target of attacks
by Italian partisans,
and they retaliate with
indiscriminate violence.
Great Britain
June 5, 1944
At the same time in southern England
Great Britain
June 5, 1944
the allied war machine assembled
for the Normandy landings,
is gearing up.
On the evening of the 5th of June,
the paratroopers get ready to leave...
decked out in their Indian
style war paint and haircut
to make themselves feel brave.
The supreme commander of the allied forces,
General Eisenhower, comes to tell them:
Dwight D. Eisenhower
The supreme commander of the allied forces,
General Eisenhower, comes to tell them:
"You are about to embark
upon the great crusade!"
The plan is to land on 5 beaches,
along a 100 km stretch
on the Normandy coast,
from the Seine to the
Contentin peninsula,
where the German Atlantic war
defences are the weakest.
At midnight on June the 5th,
British gliders and Dakotas full of British,
American and Canadian paratroopers,
slip silently in land
over the Normady region.
The paratroopers were the first
to set foot in occupied France.
Their mission, to secure the
flanks of the landing zone.
The allied fleet is on its way.
It is the biggest armada
ever assembled.
Nearly 5.000 landing ships
and assault craft.
Yet it is not detected by the Germans,
who are prevented from carrying out
reconnaissance flights by the stormy weather.
Bombardment and shelling from
the battleships pound the coast,
but completely miss their targets
on the beach codenamed "Omaha".
The German bankers remain intact.
June 6, 1944
The first assault wave of American troops
is getting ready to tackle the German defences...
on "Omaha" beach.
Among them is American
writer Ernest Hemingway,
who is a war correspondent.
He writes:
As we moved in towards
land in the grey, early light,
the coffin-shaped steel boats
took solid green sheets of water
that fell on the helmeted heads of the troops,
packed shoulder to shoulder
in a stiff, awkward, uncomfortable,
lonely companionship of men going to a battle.
Omaha
Saint-Laurent-sur-Mer
Another war reporter,
the photographer Robert Capper,
is also caught up in this inferno.
He says:
It was the ugliest beach
in the whole world.
Exhausted from the water and the fear,
we lay flat on a small strip of wet sand.
Over 2.000 American soldiers
will loose their lives here.
As the tide rolls in,
the soldiers are trapped
between the sea and gunfire
from the German blockhouses.
Eisenhower had prepared a communique
in case the landing failed.
In a hand-written letter,
he said:
"My decision to attack at this place was
based on the best information available."
"If there is any blame or fault
attached to the attempt...
...it is mine alone."
But a small group succeeds in
climbing up under enemy fire
and neutralising the German cannons with
the help of the Royal Airforce's fighter bombers.
Juno
Bernieres-sur-Mer
In the meantime the Canadian troops
have landed on Juno beach
have landed on Juno beach.
There is indeed very little resistance,
Gold
Arromanches
only a few shots that do not deter the British
on the next beach along.
The few German defenders
who survive the bombardments
finally surrender.
Sword
Ouistreham
British and French commandoes
land on the 5th beach.
The allies plan to land 326.000 men,
in just one week,
a daily average of 10.000 men,
3.200 vehicles and 15.000 tons
of supplies are ferried across.
In order to accomplish this
a harbor is needed,
but the allies decided to
stay away from the big ports,
which were too well defended
and to land on the
beaches of Normandy.
Instead they brought
their harbors with them.
Gigantic construction kits
called "Mulberries".
146 concrete caissons, 61 meters
long and weighing 6.000 tons
were assembled to create
break waters and piers,
where the "Liberty" ships as they
were called, could unload their cargo.
American shipyards had turned out
one of these ships (Liberty) every day.
In less than three years,
the war industry had turned
the United States into a superpower.
The country has mobilised
more than 11 milion men.
Its armies are now in France,
Italy, North Africa and Asia.
The power of the United States is such that just
a few days after the Normandy landings in Europe,
it's able to assemble a second fleet
on the other side of the world,
in the Pacific...
...in order to attack the Mariana Islands
which are under Japanese control.
Having taken the island of
Tarawa the year before,
the Americans now want to use the island of Saipan,
as a base for bombers taking off at Japan
Some 127.500 troops, 2/3 of
them marines, prepare for combat.
15 aircraft carriers and 900 planes
will crush the Japanese airforce
in an air battle which will come to be known
as the "Great Marianas Turkey Shoot".
A fatal blow is also dealt to
the Japanese Imperial Navy.
After which Japan's defences
in Saipan are battered.
Saipan
But when the marines
land on this tiny island,
which is only 9 km wide,
one of the bloodiest battles
of the war begins.
Over 15.000 Americans and
at least 27.000 Japanese,
will be killed or wounded.
A month and a half after D-Day
the fighting is still fierce.
The Allies are advancing
but Eisenhower is worried.
Hitler is determined to
contain the Allies in Normandy
in order to protect the launch
ramps for his weapon of terror,
the V-1, which he fires at
London from northern France.
It is the first cruise missile
ever to be used.
The V-1 is a flying bomb with a
pulse-jet engine and 1 ton explosive warhead.
This small, swift, pilotless aircraft
is difficult to intercept and shoot down.
London
The British call them "buzz bombs"
because they make a motorcycle noise
that alerts Londoners
to their arrival.
By the time the V-1s
reach the capital city,
their fuel is used up
and their engines die out.
Londoners never know
where they will fall.
Nearly 20.000 of these missiles were launched
against England and continental Europe,
killing 11.000 people.
But even under these conditions,
the British retain their
pluck and their composure.
If the V-1s fail to
demoralise the British,
their purpose was also to
boost the morale of the Germans.
Germany
their purpose was also to
boost the morale of the Germans.
Germany
For years they have had to
live in underground shelters.
American bombers by day
and British bombers by night,
demolish Germany's cities
under a carpet of bombs.
American planes dropped
1.4 million tons of bombs.
Allied bombing led to around
600.000 casualties, 7 million homeless.
Such is the outcome of the
strategic bombing campaign,
who's purpose is to destroy the
industrial and human potential,
behind Germany's wartime effort.
The Wolf's Lair
East Prussia
In the Fuhrer's headquarters,
the Wolf's Lair,
beneath the obligatory smiles many
of Hitler's officers are deeply troubled.
Especially those from the old
Prussian military aristocracy.
In the past year, many of
them have joined a plot
to get rid of Hitler.
One of these officers, Colonel
Count Claus von Stauffenberg,
places a bomb under Hitler's desk
during a conference in the Wolf's Lair.
July 20, 1944
It is this heavy table
that saves Hitler.
It deflects the blast that would eventually
kill 4 men and wound 20 others.
Of the failed assassination
attempt, Hitler says:
Having now escaped death
I am more than ever convinced
that the great cause which I served
will be brought through its present perils
and that everything can be
brought to a good end.
Hitler is only slightly injured,
a bruised arm,
his eardrums punctured,
his hair singed,
but the incident deeply
traumatizes him,
affecting his mental state,
intensified his cruelty and his paranoia.
He unleashes his revenge.
The main conspirators are tried,
5.000 suspects arrested,
200 of them executed
and their familes
deported.
He has no second thoughts about
executing his marshals.
Because he agreed to replace
Hitler at the head of the army,
Rommel is forced to
commit suicide.
Hitler hypocritically gives
him a state funeral.
Henceforth, power is in
the hands of the SS.
Nothing can save Germany now.
The Russians continue
to advance in the East.
The "Great Patriotic War" as they call it,
has taken a new turn for them.
The Red Army is suddenly able to strike
with a force that amazes all sides.
An endless supply of men,
even after the extremely costly
battles of Moscow and Stalingrad.
The offensive in Belarus
in the summer of 1944,
is one of the biggest battles
of the 2nd World War.
The eastern front
is 1.000 km wide
but the Russians are able to push forward
hundreds of kilometers within 2 months,
destroying 17 German
army divisions.
The Wehrmacht retreats
towards East Prussia,
leaving behind many
thousands of casualties.
Some 50.000 captured Germans
would be paraded through Moscow.
Normandy
August 6, 1944
In the west the Allies are gaining the upper hand.
For the Wehrmacht, the
situation is deteriorating.
50.000 German soldiers are taken
prisoner in the Falaise pocket,
or as the Germans call it:
Stalingrad in Normandy.
It is a much needed
victory for the Allies.
The Allies tighten their noose
with a new landing in Provence.
Saint Tropez
August 15, 1944
The reassembled French army
plays a major part in this landing.
Africans, Moroccans, Algerians,
Tunisians, French colonials
and young Frenchmen who are
part of the free French forces,
aid the liberation
in Provence.
It takes them just 2 weeks to liberate
the entire coast, up to Marseille.
Marseille
The resistance movement comes
out of the shadows
and participates in the liberation,
as it would do in Paris.
Paris
August 19, 1944
Paris rises up.
Barricades are erected
across the city.
Most of the German army
has retreated to the east.
But 20.000 men
remain behind,
under the command of
General von Choltitz,
who has reveived orders
from Hitler to destroy the city.
Violent fighting breaks out.
On the 4th day
of the insurrection,
a French unit, General Leclerc's
Second Armoured Division,
arrives from Normandy and
the capital is finally liberated,
Leclerc
arrives from Normandy and
the capital is finally liberated,
Leclerc
the next morning.
The Germans surrender
and General von Choltitz is taken to Leclerc's
headquarters in the Montparnasse train station.
Choltitz
and General von Choltitz is taken to Leclerc's
headquarters in the Montparnasse train station.
Choltitz
Hitler has just called and asked
his famous question:
"Brennt Paris?"
"Is Paris burning?"
Choltitz preferred to turn himself in.
This highly disciplined officer
from the airborne regiment,
disobeyed Hitler's order
to fight to the last man.
Then De Gaulle arrives with
eloquent words for history:
Paris has been offended,
Paris has been shattered,
Paris has been tortured,
but Paris has been liberated!
While France and Belgium are progressively liberated
and the Red Army awaits outside Warsaw,
on the other side of the globe,
the American General MacArthur
is returning to the Philippines.
After escaping from the Japanese
siege 3 years earlier, McArthur said:
I shall return.
His return is sumptuously staged
by his public relation staff.
Philippines
October 20, 1944
His return is sumptuously staged
by his public relation staff.
Philippines
October 20, 1944
complete with his legendary
"Popeye" corn cob pipe
Douglas MacArthur
he proclaims:
People of the Phillipines,
I have returned!
The hour of your redemption is here!
But it would take 4 months
to liberate the Phillipines.
Manila, the capital,
will be the second most
devastated city of the war,
Manila
will be the second most
devastated city of the war,
Manila
after Warsaw.
The savagery and the
cruelty of these combats,
can be explained by the
American troops discovery,
of the mass execution
of hostages.
And the camps with the surviving
U.S prisoners from 1941.
Everywhere in the Pacific,
the war is marked with this type of savagery.
Everywhere the same confusion of marines
trapped on the beaches of these infernal islands.
The same suicidal obstinacy
of the Japanese.
For them surrendering is
the ultimate disgrace.
The Americans are no longer
taking any risks.
They follow the instinct to
shoot first and ask no questions.
Along with imperialism, another
underlying cause of WW2 is racism.
liberated by the Russian
offensive of January 1945.
Hatred of the Jews, exterminating them
was as Hitler wrote in Mein Kampf, his mission.
He sent 1 million Jews to their death
in the gas chambers of Auschwitz.
Six million died of starvation,
brutal treatment, were shot,
and burned in the crematoriums
in Majdanak, in Sobibor, in Treblinka.
The Russians find a few hundred survivors,
tattooed for life.
They also intercept the trains
full of deportees.
The Nazis continue to give priority
to these death trains,
even over the munitions convoys.
They make their trips to the approximately
100 concentration camps,
that are still operating
at the beginning of 1945.
Millions of Jews, political
activists, opponents...
christians, homosexuals, gypsies
have been deported to these camps
and 5 million of them have died
of hunger, abuse and exhaustion.
Like the slaves in
the Dora tunnel,
the underground factory where the Nazis
are assembling another secret weapon,
the V-2.
The first ballistic missile
with a one-ton explossive warhead,
that has a range of 300 kilometers.
From the German coast 1.500 of them
are launched against London
and 2.000 against Belgium adding to the
devastation and the civilian casualties.
The Allies greatest fear is that it might
one day carry a nuclear charge.
Los Alamos
New Mexico, USA
The eminent scientist Einstein himself
had warned Roosevelt about the urgency
of getting ahead of the Germans.
Huge funds were provided and a team
of scientists secretly went to work...
...on the first atomic bomb.
A bomb that uses a metal, Uranium
that makes it possible to split the atom.
It is expected to have the
power of 20.000 tons of TNT,
more than 2.000 times more powerful
than the largest bomb used to date.
In addition to lethal
radioactive fallout.
The designated target was Berlin.
But this first atomic bomb would
not be finished in time for Germany.
In Germany, are there any
factories still standing
that would be capable of
producing such a weapon?
Even synthetic fuel
is becoming scarce.
The carpet bombing, carried out
day and night by the Allies
continues to devaste German cities.
The Allied bombers will
destroy Dresden,
an important center of communications
for the German armies on the eastern front.
and one of the biggest
industrial cities in the Reich.
Dresden
February 13, 1945
Until now, it has remained untouched.
Dresden, known as the
"Florence of the Elbe"
was one of Europe's
finest medieval cities.
Phosphorous bombs
create a fire typhoon,
in which an estimated 25.000 people
are burned to death.
The city continues to blaze
for 7 days.
Churchill had said:
We will make the German people
taste and gulp a sharper dose
of the miseries they have
showered upon mankind.
Their cities are dying and now
Goebbels and the Nazis
want to send all Germans from
16 to 60 years old to their deaths,
as part of the Volkssturm,
the people's militia.
They shout:
I vow to fight courageously
for my homeland,
swear to die
for Adolf Hitler.
Hitler says:
There must not be any
weakening of Germany.
His generals, those who survive the massive purge,
following the July 20th assassination attempt,
no logner dare to
oppose the Fuhrer.
They obeyed his order,
which seemed obsured
to launch an attack in the West
in the Ardenne during winter.
They would have preferred to devote
all of their efforts to fighting the Russians.
Hitler was hoping to recapture
the port of Antwerp
in order to stop the Allies from
unloading their equipment,
which would enable them
to move into Germany.
Bastogne
Belgium
But the German offensive
in the Ardenne, failed.
Due to the extraordinary defense put up
by the American paratroopers in Bastogne,
to the intervention of
General Patton's tanks
and to the overwhelming
power of the Allied airforces.
As for the Russians in the East,
they are crossing the German border.
Millions of Germans flee in panic
from the approaching Soviet troops
especially the German women who fear
the mass rapes that are being perpetrated.
There is no dissention between
the western Allies and the Russians.
Moreover, in Churchill's mind the problem
with Germany is practically over.
He is now thinking about how
to divide up the occupation zones.
He and Roosevelt meet in the Crimea
for an important conference with Stalin.
Yalta, Russia
February 4, 1945
Concerned about the increasing
losses being suffered in the Pacific,
Roosevelt has come to press Stalin
to join the war effort against Japan.
Stalin has made Roosevelt come
all the way out to the Crimea,
which takes a toll on the
ailing president's health.
He is drawn and emaciated, he barely has
the strength to hold out his arm.
Roosevelt smokes cigarette after cigarette.
He is very frail.
He will pass away a few
weeks later.
His main priority is Japan.
At the same time he does not have
the strength to oppose Stalin,
who liberates but also
occupies the Baltic states,
Romania, Bulgaria, Hungary,
Poland, Silesia and Prussia.
And there is no way
to make him leave.
The only one who tries to negotiate
is Churchill.
Finally he gets Stalin to promise
to hold free elections in Poland,
a promise that will never be kept
and to give up Greece,
which will leed to civil war.
The Greek communist partisans will rise up
and Stalin will let them be massacred.
One of the goals of this conference is the
founding of the organisation of the United Nations,
which would soon be
convened in San Francisco.
The U.N.'s mission will be to seek
a peacul settlement for all disputes
and to protect human rights.
This picture heralds the beggining
of the Cold War...
The war in the Pacific,
continues.
The marines raise the American flag
on top of Mount Suribachi,
Iwo Jima
February 23, 1945
the volcano that dominates
the island of Iwo Jima.
The battle took the lives of 7.000
Americans and 20.000 Japanese.
It is now possible for the Boeing B29
"Super Fortress" bombers,
taking off from Iwo Jima
and other islands in the Pacific
to reach Japan.
Humans have invented something even more
vicious than the phosphorus used in Dresden
Napalm, gasoline mixed
with incendiary jelly.
1.700 tons dropped on little houses
made of wood and paper.
Tokyo
March 9, 1945
1.700 tons dropped on little houses
made of wood and paper.
Tokyo
March 9, 1945
The Japanese are victims
of their fanatical military leaders,
who plunge them into this inferno
and who wanted to pursue the war.
In spite of the 80.000 victims
and the 1 million homeless,
from this air raid
over Tokyo.
Berchtesgaden
Hitler was at his chalet
in the Bavarian Alps,
along with his dog "Blondie", of whom he
seemed to be fonder than any human being.
He predicted:
The next war will not end
like the 1st World War.
There will be no
11th of November.
It will be either victory
or annihilation.
Perhaps this vertiginous feeling
of all or nothing,
is what kept him from marrying
his mistress, Eva Braun.
He said:
I'm already married
to Germany.
The Soviet forces have
surrounded Berlin.
But Hitler refuses
to admin defeat.
He says:
It will be the opposite
of Stalingrad.
Berlin
April 17, 1945
But his remaining soldiers,
overwhelmed by the Russian rocket launchers
surrender one after the other.
Beneath the ruins of the chancellory
in his underground bunker,
Hitler rants and raves and
manoeveurs his imaginary armies.
The last of his faithful followers
take advantage of a lull
Garden of the Chancellery
April 20, 1945
to come out and celebrate
his birthday on April the 20th.
Hitler is 56 years old.
He consoles these Hitler Youth,
who have been chosen because their parents
have just been killed in the bombing of Dresden.
As the Americans advance westward,
they capture thousands of these Hitler youths
sent to the front to replace
the soldiers who have been killed.
The Americans can hardly
believe their eyes.
These boys-soldiers
are afraid of nothing.
They have undergone years
of brainwashing.
Hatred and racism have been
indoctrinated into them.
The old men in the Volkssturm
who were also captured
have no words of
comfort for them.
The Americans meet up with the Russians
on the Elbe near the Torgau bridge.
Torgau
April 25, 1945
East meets West.
The final act of the alliance.
The atmosphere is friendly...
...for the cameras.
Stalin's portrait is
superbly displayed,
but Roosevelt's is draped
in black mourning crape.
He died on April the 12th.
One of America's most renowned generals,
George S. Patton, is furious.
George S. Patton
He thinks the Americans should have
entered Berlin before the Russians.
Patton, the man with the
pistols in his belt,
who drove his tanks
through Africa,
through Normandy,
through the Ardenne.
He says to Eisenhower:
The 9th Army is
60 miles from Berlin.
Not to go all the way there is a historic error
whose consequences will be very grave.
Eisenhower says nothing.
The only thing that matters to him is
to eliminate Hitler and the Nazis.
A few days earlier,
Patton had called him up urgently,
wanting him to witness the horrors
of the concentration camp at Buchenwald.
Eisenhower had the inhabitants
of the nearby city of Weimar
taken there in trucks so that
they could no longer say they did not know,
in order to show them that
such things did exist,
so that they would be able
to testify in Germany.
To say that they had seen the tattoos
collected from the corpses of the deported.
The lampshades made
of human skin.
The shrunken-head paperweights.
Then, in accordance
with the Yalta agreements,
Eisenhower withdrew his troops
from Buchenwald,
which was located
in the Soviet zone.
Stalin immediately puts
the camp back to work.
It will become part of
his prison system,
where people suspected of hostility
towards his regime will be imprisoned.
Berlin
April 30, 1945
In Berlin the Russians are 300 meters
away from the Fuhrer's bunker.
Hitler kills his pet dog Blondie,
after marrying Eva Braun.
She swallows a cyanide pill.
Hitler shoots himself
in the head.
Goebbels and his wife also
committed suicide.
Before that, Magda Goebbels had
poisoned her six children.
In her last letter,
she wrote:
That we can end our lives together
with the Fuhrer is a blessing,
for which we never dared to hope.
May 2, 1945
The Soviets will raise their
red flag over the Reichstag.
The main Nazi leaders
will be captured.
Goering
Like Goering, one of Hitler's
most diabolical accomplices.
In Italy, Mussolini is executed by Partisans
and his body is lynched by the crowd.
Mussolini
In Italy, Mussolini is executed by Partisans
and his body is lynched by the crowd.
Everywhere in Europe
a wave of revenge
is unleashed against those
who in one way or another
collaborated with the devils.
In Berlin, Anna Pavlovna directs
traffic at the Brandenburg Gate.
To defeat Nazi Germany
Russia paid a very high price.
20 million civilians and
soldiers were killed.
Nearly 15% of the population
of the Soviet Union.
Soviet General Georgy Zhukov
has himself filmed in the ruins
Georgy Zhukov
Soviet General Georgy Zhukov
has himself filmed in the ruins
Georgy Zhukov
of the Grand Grand Chancellery of the Reich,
the very symbol of Hitler's
delusions of grandeur.
And finally in Hitler's office...
...with the famous globe
that Charlie Chaplin paradded
in his movie the "Great Dicator".
Hitler had ordered
the SS to burn his body.
The Soviets will get rid of the bones in
order to prevent any kind of hero-worship.
May 8, 1945
Wehrmacht commander Marshal Keitel signs
the unconditional surrender of Nazi Germany
in front of the General Zhukov, his
mortal enemy and the Allied officers.
The British Air Marshal Tedder,
the American General Spaatz
and the French General
de Lattre de Tassigny.
Keitel will later be tried at the
international Nuremberg trials.
He will be hanged like
many other war criminals.
Berlin
To stop the Nazis,
Germany had to be annihilated.
Will it also be necessary to annihilate Japan?
Okinawa
In the Pacific, the suicide pilots
that the Japanese call "kamikaze",
nosedive their planes
into the American fleet.
Clutching on to their power,
the military chiefs in Tokyo
sacrifice what remains of their
country's youth and their aircraft
in order to prevent the Americans
from landing in Japan.
In the end, the United States
decide against an invasion of Japan
which it thinks will cost
the country a million lives.
Hiroshima
August 6, 1945
Instead, it detonates the atomic inferno.
The first 2 nuclear bombs ever exploded
kill in one second over 100.000 people.
Nagasaki
August 9, 1945
And finally enable the emperor, Hirohito
to seek peace
without loosing face.
The atom bomb had to be dropped
before these Japanese soldiers and officers
would finally consent
to perform this act
which is entirelly contrary to the Bushido,
their code of honour.
A few Japanese soldiers
take to the Jungle.
Some never even learn
of their country's defeat.
The last of these will come
out of hiding and turn himself in...
...in 1975!
September 2, 1945
In Tokyo bay onboard
the USS Missouri,
the representatives of the Allied nations
from China, Great Britain, Russia and France
are filled with emotion.
They have the privilege of attending
the signing of the Japanese surrender,
that marks the end of WW2.
General McArthur
represents the victors.
Mamoru Shigemitsu
The Japanese minister of foreign affairs
in a top hat
walks with a limp,
having lost a leg in
a bomb attach in China
will sign on behalf of the emperor
with whom he had met the day before.
He had told him:
We must make of
this day of mourning
the first day of the
birth of a new Japan.
In that way, we can go to the ceremony
with our heads held high.
McArthur concludes with these
historic words:
It is my earnest hope and
indeed the hope of all mankind...
that from this
solemn occasion...
a better world shall emerge out of
the blood and carnage of the past...
Hiroshima
This war took the lives
of some 50 million people.
Most of them innocent civilians
in an outbreak of pure violence.
Thousands of victims suffered
for many years afterwards
Nagasaki
Thousands of victims suffered
for many years afterwards
from the appauling after-effects
of nuclear radiation.
Or from the terrible loss
of parents or children,
exterminated in the Nazi camps.
This series is dedicated to the
victims of all forms of totalitarianism.
Let us be grateful
to the cameramen
the unarmed heroes, who recorded
these combats for posterity.
And to all who filmed the war in
all of its atrocity and its familiarity.
They introduced us to Rose
Rose Gowlland
who on the last day of the Apocalypse
wrote:
The end,
on a bomb...