(Episode 8)
When are you going to stop treating me like this?
I don't know what you're talking about.
When are you going to stop being mad at me?
Listen carefully. I'm not going to say this again.
You and I broke up two years ago.
Especially when I struggled the most.
Look at you.
You're the one who wanted to break up.
Yes, that's true.
But I didn't expect you to turn your back on me so coldly.
If you really loved me,
you would've done your best to help me when I was in debt.
Hey. I was also struggling in the army.
Besides, you never helped me...
like other girls who help their boyfriends in the army.
What? Have you already forgotten...
that I joined the army girlfriend contest for you?
Oh, that one.
The one where you were supposed to send me a knitted scarf,
but you only sent a photo of it?
I'm sure...
Corporal Kim's girlfriend won the first place...
who wrote him a letter every day.
Wasn't it?
Oh, it was Private Lee's girlfriend...
who made lunch for everyone in the camp.
Oh, no, no. She wasn't the winner.
It was Sergeant Choi's girlfriend who always visited him...
even though it took her five hours both ways.
- Are you done? - My seniors...
punished me for over a year...
because you lied to the whole camp.
Is that so? I'm so sorry.
I won't ever date you again,
so you wouldn't suffer because of your liar girlfriend.
But why are you talking so much?
You even have a new girlfriend who carries a fake brand purse.
You look so desperate.
What did you say?
Desperate?
Oh, gosh. I was talking to myself. Did you hear it?
Look at you.
Right. Young Ha.
That's the person you are, but I've forgotten.
I can't stand how pathetic I am...
for going through all that to find you.
Anyway, it's enough.
Like I said before, I'm not someone who looks back.
I don't play push and pull either.
So stop lingering,
and be loyal to your new girlfriend.
Seriously!
He's beyond reason.
He's seriously beyond reason!
Kyung Ha?
Kyung Ha.
Hey, Seo Hee.
What was that? Did I catch you trying to ignore me?
I didn't know it was you.
Here.
Not at this hour.
You're always worried about getting fat, but you bought so much.
I bought everything he had, so he could go home.
You and Yong are so nosy.
You're always on diet, but you bought a cake too.
Oh, this?
Someone gave it to me.
Who? Is today a special day?
Is it someone's birthday? No. An anniversary?
Stop guessing wrong.
You have a boyfriend, don't you?
You must be hitting it off well with the guy you met last time.
Believe whatever you want.
I'm going home. I'm tired.
Don't be so cheap.
Take this.
It's an expensive cake from a really famous place in Cheongdam-dong.
Bye.
Why would you give it to me if it's so expensive?
(Plumbing, Water leakage detection)
Yong.
I don't expect you to be from a conglomerate family,
but I wish you were born in a wealthy family.
(Director Nam Tae Il)
I'm back.
Let's get some tea after I'm done.
(Kim Young Ha)
Are you back, Mr. Nam?
Sure. I'd love to.
You're back, Director Nam.
What's he doing?
I don't know either.
He's here to work as a part-timer.
Could you please tell him to stop and just leave?
- Where's Mr. Lee? - He's in the kitchen.
Let me do it, Gwang Jae.
Go and clean the bathroom.
You think I'm gambling?
It's not true.
If that were true,
I'd put my head in a bowl full of water and...
Then where do you go every night? How dare you?
After Tae Il went on a business trip,
you never stay at home.
Am I wrong?
Please be quiet. I know that.
Hey, Mr. Nam.
You must be tired.
Nothing much happened here.
- Yes. Have you been well? - We have.
I'm back, Mr. Lee.
- Take a look at this. - Okay. Good work.
You should have gone straight home to take a rest.
You're so hardworking. Here.
You should take a look at it thoroughly.
I know you've taken a good look at it.
Well done, well done.
Gami would be nothing without you, Mr. Nam.
Don't you agree?
He's the best.
I'll go outside and clean the car.
Good luck, Mr. Nam.
Sir.
I saw Gwang Jae working as a waiter.
I don't know why,
but he suddenly wanted to work here.
So I told him to.
Why did he suddenly do that?
Why else?
He must have been sorry...
for hurting me so much by saying...
that he wanted to become a travel writer.
He's just like me.
He has weak spots.
Take good care of him, Tae Il.
I don't know how long it will last,
but still. Okay?
All right.
Gosh, why does he pee for so long when I'm cleaning?
Seriously.
Why is this so dirty?
It's filthy.
Come on!
Why am I going through so much trouble?
You got me.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Why aren't you in bed?
Why did you come here?
- Seo Hee called me here. - What?
- Gosh. - Congratulations
Congratulations
Congratulations to my dear family
Clap. Clap. I can't clap.
- Clap for me. - Gosh, turn on the lights.
I will if you blow this candle.
All right.
What day is it?
It's not.
She's just overdoing things.
We can't get in mood for anything.
Here, have some cake.
Where did you get the money to buy it?
It's not even your payday.
Can't you just eat it without asking me anything?
Try them.
It's from a really famous place.
How much did it cost...
to buy this?
It must be really expensive as it's from a famous place.
- Gosh. - Gosh, it hurts.
How much did it cost?
I don't know. I didn't buy it.
I don't know where good cake shops are at in Cheongdam-dong.
Then where did you get it?
Did your boss give it to you?
- It's delicious. - You only say it's delicious...
after knowing that I'm not the one who bought it.
Is it really from your boss?
- No, from his daughter. - What?
Maybe it's from the man Kyung Ha went on a blind date with.
- Did she go on a blind date again? - Yes.
Why did she give it to you?
I don't know.
Maybe it's because she didn't like him.
Or maybe it was because she did like him. It's either of the two.
Why would she give it to you...
if she liked him?
No one likes a fat woman.
She wants me to eat this and get fat instead.
Anyway, it's delicious.
What's wrong?
I need to get something.
Gosh.
What are you looking at?
They even imported the cups here.
They're from England.
These details must be important if you want to own a coffee shop.
Your head seems to be full of business ideas.
It's mostly filled with them.
How was your business trip?
I heard there are a few restaurants in Shanghai that won Michelin stars.
- Have you been to any? - No.
I haven't been to any.
That's a pity.
You must have worked all day there.
That's how it is.
But...
- I did get you a present. - Really?
Give it to me.
What's wrong?
I think...
the present is a little too much.
This looks like a proposal.
It's a bit too much.
Is it?
Of course.
When I get presents from my friends who went on a trip,
I usually get bottle openers, key rings, or magnets.
Those are the common ones.
Some even bring me salt in a bottle.
Salt?
It's not important.
Anyway, I've never received a gift in a case like this.
It's not like there's a ring in there, right?
Well...
Is it a ring?
I...
Gosh. What's this?
- It can't be like this. - What?
- What do you mean? - I was going to open it,
and then give it back to you...
saying it looks too expensive,
but it's too pretty.
- Do you like it? - Yes.
That's a relief.
I didn't have time, so I asked our employee there to buy it for me.
I was worried it'd be too much because it's a ring,
but I had no time for anything else.
So I hope you don't think it's too much.
Is it really okay for me to have it?
Of course.
But you can't look for its prices on the internet.
It's cheaper than you think.
I feel much better now.
Thank you, Mr. Nam.
Where is it? Is it here?
Gosh.
Gosh, it's fine.
Stay still. I'll spray it for you.
Gosh, it's fine. Just leave me alone.
Why do your legs hurt?
Is it because you've been riding motorcycles instead of cars?
Your dad bought you a car.
Why don't you drive it?
It's not about that.
Gwang Jae. Get up.
Seriously. Mom. I'm going to sleep.
Leave me alone. I'm going to sleep.
Gosh.
I'm home.
He's been saying his legs ache for a few days now,
but he won't say why.
Gwang Jae. Put on the patches before you sleep.
Do you want me to massage you with hot water?
It actually works really well.
If they still ache tomorrow, let's go to the hospital together, okay?
It's upsetting.
By the way, did you just arrive from China?
Yes.
Did you have dinner?
I work in the restaurant, Aunt Soo Hee.
Get some rest.
Here?
More to the left. Yes.
Is it because you waited tables?
What do you mean?
You know I have so much work to do in the hall.
Why are you playing a waiter all of a sudden?
I'm not playing anything.
Undercover boss. Don't you know?
Undercover boss?
Are you really interested in restaurant business now?
That would never happen.
I was just bored. That's all.
Gosh.
Slide down a bit. I'll massage you.
- Slide down. - No, thanks.
You must be tired too. It's fine.
- Come here. - Hey.
Your father's still not home...
even though his only son is back.
Isn't it a busy season for Dad?
He's not idling.
He's working hard to feed his family.
I forgot you were here.
By the way, Myung Ha.
You didn't bring any of your stuff. Did you send them separately?
Actually, my bags didn't arrive in the airport when I landed.
They made a mistake, and my bags are in Nepal now.
My goodness.
- Nepal? - Nepal?
Your bags are traveling abroad alone?
Is that why you wore such ugly pants home?
Don't get me started.
I'm glad I was returning from China.
What if I was returning from Europe?
I almost jumped out of the plane because of her.
- Oh, gosh. - My goodness.
If someone so naive like Myung Ha can't handle,
she must've been a troublesome woman.
That's what I mean, Mother.
Do you have to return those pants?
I don't even know her number.
I didn't charge her for laundry. We're even.
You should've lied that they were expensive...
and charged her a lot.
What? You're talking like a swindler.
No, Grandma. I'm joking.
Goodness. Come on.
Anyway, I'm glad...
my adorable Myung Ha is back.
- Me too. Welcome back. - Yes.
- Welcome back. - Welcome back, my son.
Don't drink too much.
You'll have a headache again and suffer.
Mind your own business.
Is your dad leaving soon?
You should leave with him.
I should leave too?
Yes. You can't live selling pork backbone stew forever.
You should go back to where you grew up.
Do you find me uncomfortable?
You worry about me too much.
I'm getting sick of it.
You must be tired from the business trip. Why are you still up?
You got a new car. Why aren't you driving it?
The new car only shines when you have someone to ride with.
Don't girls have to line up to sit in the passenger seat?
You know you seem to treat me like a womanizer.
You remind me of someone.
I don't know who that someone is,
but she surely knows what she's dealing with just like me.
I'm not in the mood for a joke.
What's wrong?
- What is it? - Gosh.
Nothing.
There's just this girl...
who doesn't get me at all.
Who is she?
I think we're really over. There's nothing to talk about.
But you want to work as a part-timer?
What's the reason?
That's over now. It wasn't that fun.
I knew it.
Your mom told me to go back to the US.
So?
Are you going to?
I'm thinking.
I...
always had a question.
Was it...
easy for you to call Aunt Soo Hee as mom?
It was awkward at first.
But...
I started to like her more as time passed by.
The fact that I have someone to call as mom.
I just liked that fact.
Mom.
It feels nice and cozy just by saying it.
I just liked it so much.
I didn't know what mom is until I became a teenager.
Then one day, all of a sudden,
I got a new wonderful stepmother.
It was nice.
The title of mom...
was like a genie out of the bottle.
Even when I ran out of toilet paper in the restroom, I'd call for her.
When I got in trouble at school, I'd call for her.
Every time I called her,
she showed up and took care of everything for me.
Tae Il.
Do you...
happen to know anything about my mom's past?
How would I know?
Have you heard anything from the adults?
No.
How can you know nothing about your own aunt?
I only met her a few times until I turned 20.
I'm going back inside. I'm tired.
What? Are you leaving again in the middle of conversation?
Tae Il.
Tae Il. You really need to work on your cold personality.
Girls these days hate it.
A cold city guy? That's so over now.
Sweet guys, cozy guys are in trend now.
Come on.
Seriously.
Kim Young Ha is stupid to reject a sweet guy like me.
No way.
Cleaning became my habit because of her.
Does Mr. Nam...
It can't be.
The employee was being too much.
What?
I threw this out. What's it doing here?
- Mom. - Yes?
Did you put this back in my room?
Yes. Why did you throw this out? It's in good shape.
Why did you put it back in my room when I threw it out?
Give it to me then. I'll use it.
- It looks like salt. - Never mind.
I thought it's something important because there's a paper inside.
- A paper? - Yes.
He left me.
What does he want now?
Your return to school is registered well, so don't worry.
Thank you.
- I'm leaving now. - Bye.
Myung Ha. I have a favor to ask.
It's not my favor,
but it's actually the dean's favor.
Tell me.
We're having a transfer student.
He wants to you help him until he adjusts to school.
I'm barely returning to school.
He's actually from China.
Please help us out. It could help you learn Chinese.
He's from a wealthy Chinese family.
It's probably worth knowing him.
Sure. Okay.
(Student Hall)
Goodness.
Whose shoes are these?
Gosh, that old lady.
What on earth is the passcode?
- Thief! - What?
I'm not a thief. Where are you going?
Help me!
Be quiet!
Hey.
What's all this noise?
- Grandma. - Goodness.
- Wait. - Mom.
What's going on?
What were you two doing?
Mom?
Young Ha's youngest uncle?
Hold on.
Did you just hit him with this?
Actually...
She tripped me and hit me so much, Mom.
Why did you do that?
Some black guy...
was trying to open the safe.
- I thought he was a thief. - Why would I open my mom's safe?
She's killing me twice.
- You were trying to open the safe. - No, I wasn't.
You're mistaken.
Wasn't beating me enough?
I saw it with my own eyes.
Young Ha's uncle tried to open the safe.
No, Mom. Oh, gosh.
(The Rich Son)
He swore at me and my boss.
I'll kill you, jerk!
If my oldest son finds out,
the whole family will go crazy like the last time.
Don't make me a bad guy anymore.
I beg you, Kyung Ha. Please!
You took the store deposit and ran away to Seoul alone.
You said you were going to make a theater company.
Hi. I'm Wang Mo Mong.
You get to live a luxurious life thanks to your husband.
What are you doing? This happens every time.
You don't know anything about me.
You can't even imagine my pain!