Is anybody there?
Jeanne.
I'm always happy to see you, but to
keep coming twice, three times a day--
- I need to confess.
- You already confessed this morning.
I need to confess again.
What terrible sin
have you committed since then...
that can't wait till tomorrow
to be forgiven?
I saw a poor monk without shoes,
so I gave him some.
There's no sin in charity, Jeanne.
- They weren't my shoes.
- Whose were they?
- My father's.
- I'm sure he'll forgive you.
He already did.
But I want Jesus
to forgive me too.
If we were to ask forgiveness
all the time...
we'd spend our whole life
in church.
- Is that bad?
- Well, no, but--
- Are you happy at home?
- Oh, yes, very.
And your mother?
Everything's fine with her?
Yes, she's wonderful.
And your sister, Catherine,
she's still your best friend?
My sister's just--
She's wonderful.
And what about your other friends?
You don't like playing with them?
Oh, yes.
I play with them, lots.
Everything sounds wonderful.
Yes, it is.
Then why are you here so often?
I feel safe here.
It's where I can talk to him.
Him?
Well, I try to talk to him...
but mostly he's the one
who does the talking.
Who is this ''he''?
He never says his name.
What does he...
look like?
Beautiful.
And what does he say to you?
He says--
He says I must be good...
and help everyone
and take care of myself.
Do you think he's coming
from the sky?
Perhaps.
But wherever he's coming from,
I think you should listen to him...
'cause it sounds like
he's giving you very good advice.
It's--
It's wonderful!
It's wonderful.
Jeanne.
Mother!
Catherine!
Jeanne, are you all right?
Did they hurt you?
I'm fine, really.
We've all been looking for you.
The English are everywhere.
- I was in the church.
- Really?
I was talking to the priest.
Do you know what he said to me?
Burn over there!
Tell me later.
Quick, hide in here.
- Where are you gonna be?
- I'll be right here.
I promise.
Well, that's what I call booty.
Comrade.
A woman with a sword.
Look at this.
Frenchmen are such cowards,
they've left all the fighting to women.
If that's God's will,
then so be it.
Fine with me.
I love women.
Hold still, bitch.
How can I do it
if you keep wriggling about?
Your turn now.
God, preserve and bless the soul
of this, our dearly departed.
Keep us safe from fear and sin.
Amen.
Come on.
Listen, Jeanne.
Your aunt and uncle are gonna take you
to their house for a couple of weeks...
just to give us time
to rebuild things here.
You understand?
Lord, we give thanks
for the food you've given us.
Teach us always
to love this land...
and to save it from those
who seek to destroy it.
- Amen.
So, good night, then.
- What's going to happen to her?
- She'll be fine.
She'll grow up, find a good man,
make him some children. Don't worry.
She's been hurt, but she'll survive.
Tomorrow she'll be
as right as rain.
You'll see.
I want to see a priest.
- Why did she have to die?
- Only God can answer that.
I know Jesus says
to love your enemies, but I can't.
I just want the English
to burn in hell forever and ever!
I realize your anger, Jeanne.
But we must learn to forgive.
It's hard...
but revenge will never
bring about peace.
What will?
And what will bring her back?
And why did she have to die
in the first place instead of me?
Why didn't He take my life
instead of hers?
It was my fault!
I was late!
She gave me her hiding place!
Why did He save me?
Calm down, Jeanne.
Calm down.
I don't pretend
to know God's will...
but one thing I am sure:
The Lord always has a good reason.
Perhaps He chose you because
He needs you...
for some higher calling.
As long as you answer that call...
your sister will not
have died in vain.
I don't want to wait
for His call.
Be patient.
I want to be with Him always.
Soon you will be able to take part
in your Holy Mass.
When you eat of His flesh
and drink of His blood...
you will be at one with Him.
I want to be at one with Him now.
So, what did he say?
He says we must bring her to church
whenever she wants.
Easy for him. He's not the one
who has to do the bringing.
Come on.
This is important.
We mustn't let her out of our sight.
Don't worry. I will watch her
like my own shadow.
I want to be at one with You now.
A message for the dauphin of France.
A message.
Captain, a message for the dauphin.
I'll take it.
The dauphin!
Louis. Louis. Hey.
Shouldn't you be learning your lessons?
I don't want to learn.
I want to fight.
You will. But for now, you must
at least learn to wipe your nose.
A letter for His Majesty.
Another one from this girl
calling herself the Maiden of Lorraine.
I can read for myself,
you know?
She pretends she's been sent by God.
Charlatans.
It's a pity there isn't enough wood
to burn them all.
- She says she'll be here tomorrow.
- You mustn't see her, My Lord.
We know nothing about her. We don't
even know if she's from Lorraine.
What difference does it make
where she comes from?
If she comes from Burgundy,
it makes a difference.
It might be a trap.
Look, signed ''X.''
What sort of a name is ''X''?
Or must we assume that a messenger
of God can't even write her own name?
My Lord, Trémoille is correct.
She says she hears voices.
She may be a sorceress,
a witch.
Regnault, you see witches everywhere.
She's just a peasant.
A peasant who cares about her king.
All she wants is to see me crowned
and permission to fight for me.
Not exactly. She wants you
to give her an army at your expense.
Bearing in mind your mother stole every
last piece of gold in the treasury...
I fail to see how you can afford
such an adventure.
I can see her if I want to.
After all, with half of France
in the hands of the English...
what have I got to lose?
The other half.
You mustn't see her,
Your Majesty.
She may be an instrument
of the devil.
Well, I think you should.
Well, here's an amusing situation.
I would love to know why my devoted
mother-in-law thinks one thing...
and my two most loyal
and trusted advisors...
think precisely the opposite.
Because I care about you.
Come here.
Your health and happiness has always
been my first concern, Charles...
ever since you were a little boy.
And I think I know you
better than your own mother.
You think so, eh?
Yes.
I know, for example,
the sickness that plagues your heart.
I know how painful it is
for you to have loved a father...
without ever knowing
if he was really yours.
Do I know you enough? Hmm?
What has that got to do
with this maiden?
Who better than a messenger from God
to give answers to your questions?
You think she was sent from God?
You're a fine judge
of character, Charles.
It'll take you less than five minutes
to expose her if she's a fake.
But if she's not...
then she will give you
your answers...
and place the crown on your head.
With respect to my lady, I think it's
going to take more than a peasant girl--
I'm not interested
in what you think, Trémoille...
or even what I think.
It's what simple people think
that matters, and the fact is that...
simple people up and down this country
are already talking about her.
Now, you know
what simple people are like--
always ready to believe
any old prophecy.
Like this one...
about a virgin from Lorraine...
saving France.
And now...
this girl comes along...
from Lorraine.
And suddenly, there's a spark
of hope in their simple minds.
You shouldn't disappoint them.
If they believe in her--
if she can put back
the fire in our army--
then I believe in her too.
Stop it!
Louis, be quiet for once.
- She's coming, Your Majesty.
- All right.
Calm yourself.
Your Majesty, I urge you
not to see this woman.
It all reeks of a Burgundian trap.
My astrologers assure me the timing
is propitious: Leo with Virgo rising.
Have you never noticed
on the astrological chart...
that the virgin
is next to the lion?
Supposing she's an assassin?
My-My-My dear Trémoille...
I'm not even king yet.
Who would want to assassinate me?
She's arrived, My Lord.
She's in the guards' room.
Fine, fine.
I suppose I shall have
to make a decision.
Why is life so complicated?
Sometimes I really wish
I could be someone else.
That's a good idea, sire.
What do you mean?
Let someone else
pretend to be you.
And see if she can find me?
That's a brilliant idea.
If she's really been sent by God,
she'll discover the trap.
And if she's an assassin,
she'll kill the wrong man. Brilliant.
Please. Please!
We're - We're going to play
a little game.
Now, let us pretend
that my throne is empty.
Just pretend.
Who wants to be king?
Now, there's a heart warming sight.
Now, let us see which one of you
could possibly pass...
as the king of France.
Alençon, my noble duke.
My royal cousin.
So fine, so brave, so rich.
So very rich.
So far-too-rich to be king of France.
Everyone knows I'm the poorest man
in my kingdom.
Gilles de Rais.
Marshall of France.
Formidable to men,
fascinating to women.
Feared by all.
You would be perfect
to sit on my throne.
So perfect that you might
like it too much...
and therefore disturb
my - my fragile peace of mind.
La Hire.
My angry captain,
and bravest in France.
Scarred by a dozen wars, but with
a heart and a stomach for a dozen more.
- You could pass for the king.
- Damn bloody right I could.
Until you open your mouth,
because no one...
with a tongue like that
could possible pass as king of France.
It looks like it shall have
to be me after all.
Why not you, Jean d’Aulon?
The only man
who's poorer than I am...
therefore the only man
I can trust.
Dignified, honorable, wise.
What more can we ask of a king?
My lord, I'm not sure that--
Are you not prepared
to die for your king?
- Of course I am.
- Good.
Until then, feel free to live
like a king. Bring her up.
Sire, you know how bad I am
at this sort of game.
Pretend it's not a game.
Make way for the dauphin.
- Mother?
- Not now.
I have come to see the dauphin.
Who are you?
I'm - I'm --
His most gracious majesty,
Charles de Valois...
dauphin of France.
I can see you are a good man.
But you're not the dauphin.
I'm sorry to insist,
but I must see the dauphin.
We have no time to lose.
Where is he?
He's here.
Find him yourself.
Now you'll see
who'll pass for a king.
There's no need to be afraid, sire.
I'm not the king.
I know you're not yet,
but you will be soon.
Out. Out.
How did you know who I am?
- Her voices, of course.
- ''That's him,'' they said.
''The one in the corner
with the big nose.''
Back off!.
Oh, my gentle dauphin.
I have a message...
from the King of Heaven...
for you.
You only.
Follow me.
Your Majesty, I really think --
My dear loyal Trémoille,
I know I can count on you...
to - to ensure our privacy.
I need to talk to her alone.
He needs to talk to her alone.
Fine.
I was about ten years old.
It was a beautiful spring day.
I was taking a shortcut home
through the forest...
when a strange wind...
began to blow.
It was such a strange sound,
almost like words...
calling me.
The second time...
was many years later.
I was coming back from church,
when suddenly...
the same...
violent wind.
Then...
a shape...
appeared...
in the middle of the sky.
The shape...
of...
of a man.
Everything was moving so fast.
So fast.
The wind, the clouds.
I couldn't move.
I couldn't breathe.
I was so frightened.
He was...
so...
here.
And then I knew
that God had chosen me.
But I did not understand
what it was He wanted me to do.
What was my mission?
What could I do to help my country?
But how? I was nothing.
I was just a poor girl.
I did not know anything about--
about making war or riding.
So I decided to wait...
and not to speak of it
to anybody.
You did well.
I didn't wait long.
I was going to Mass,
like I do every day...
and the same...
strange wind--
Everything was made clear.
God had given me a message.
A message to deliver.
What--
What was the message?
He said...
that I must save France
from her enemies...
and bring her back
into the hands of God.
And He told me that I...
Jeanne...
will lead you
to the altar at Reims...
where you will be crowned...
the king...
of France.
- Sire, are you --
- I'm fine.
This is, in fact, Jean d'Aulon,
my loyal friend and finest archer.
I put her in your care.
Find her suitable lodgings
here in the castle...
and guard her with your life.
Sire, I won't be needing any lodgings
if we're to be marching on Orléans.
Orléans has held out
for six months...
so I don't suppose a few days more
will make much difference.
Take some rest.
Put the bags here.
Please accept my apologies...
for me pretending
to be the -- you know.
Do you think
that I can have some water?
Water. Yes, of course.
Would you get some water?
- Anything else?
- I need to see a priest.
- Now?
- Yes. I didn't confess today.
All right.
Raymond, a priest.
Anything else?
I shall also be needing
a new war horse...
a sword, armor...
and an artist
to make a banner for me.
- Now?
- Better today than tomorrow.
This might take a little time...
but let me see what I can do.
Oh! I shall also be needing someone
who can read and write.
This I can do.
I was studying at the University
of Paris until the English invaded it.
- I thought you were an archer.
- Yes, I am.
I'm an archer who can read and write.
Who do you want to write to?
The king of England.
I want to give him the chance
to leave in peace...
before I get to Orléans.
The archbishop and I have just begun
negotiations with the Burgundians.
If we can bring them over
to our side--
Negotiate, by all means,
but from a position of strength.
If the English take Orléans,
there'll be nothing left to negotiate.
The rest of the country
will be theirs.
My lady, it will be
the height of folly...
to let this child
lead our army...
in the king's name
without verifying her true motives.
My Lord, Trémoille is right.
We must be absolutely certain that
she is not an instrument of the devil.
How can anyone be
absolutely certain about anything?
Sometimes, our intuitions
are our best counselors.
We must listen to Mother Holy Church
before we listen to our intuitions.
Wait.
She claims to be a virgin.
Well, that's something
we can examine...
and be absolutely certain about.
Let's find out.
What if she's not?
If she's not,
I'll kill her myself.
There is no sign
of corruption or violation.
She is intact.
And what, exactly,
was this vision wearing?
I don't remember.
This vision,
did it give you anything?
An object?
A ring or a rosary...
or anything by which
we can verify your claim?
He gave me good advice.
During your child hood, did you have
any sort of military experience?
Are you practiced in the skills
of swords man ship?
No, but I'm good with a stick.
Do you know what
a Dijon Culverin is?
It's an item of artillery.
How can you expect
to raise the siege of Orléans...
if you're ignorant
about modern artillery?
The road to Orléans is long,
and I have good captains with me.
I will learn fast, believe me.
We would like to believe you, Jeanne,
but we feel...
that if God wanted us
to believe you...
he would've sent a sign with you.
So, can you do something?
Show us something?
A sign to prove...
that you are sent by God.
I did not come here
to perform tricks.
You are all much cleverer
than I am.
I mean, me,
I don't know ''A'' from '' B.''
But this much I do know.
While the people of France
lie bleeding...
you sit around
in your fine clothes...
trying to deceive me...
when you're only
deceiving yourselves.
You say you are men of God...
yet you do not see His hand
in having guided me...
through 500 leagues of enemy country
to bring you His help.
Is that not proof enough?
Or do you still need more signs?
Give me an army.
Take me to Orléans.
And there you will see the sign
that I was sent to make.
Dunois.
- What?
- A big one, straight at us.
What side?
Window side.
What?
I have wonderful news, finally.
He is sending her to us.
Thanks be to God. We're saved.
It's--
It's wonderful.
Calm yourself, Xaintrailles.
Who has finally done what?
The dauphin. He's sending us
food and supplies and an army...
led by Jeanne,
the maiden from Lorraine.
Isn't it wonderful?
Yes, it's a miracle.
I can't believe
they are sending a woman.
I wonder what color dress
she'll be wearing.
Blue.
With a blue ribbon in her hair
to tie up Talbot.
Does anyone know if
she even knows how to ride a horse?
She knows.
Were you sent by Lord Dunois?
Yes, we were.
- Where are the English?
- Everywhere. Where's the food?
It's coming.
I rode on ahead.
I have a message
for the captain of the English army.
- His name is Talbot.
- I know.
- Can you take me to him?
- He's on the other side of the river.
So, who gave the order for me
to be brought to this side of the river?
Hey, my friend. It's good
to see your ugly damn face again.
- La Hire, I'm warning you. Don't swear.
- Sorry, Jeanne.
Let me introduce the king's
half-brother, the dogged Lord Dunois.
Lord Dunois, will you show me
to the other side of the river?
Wait. Wait!
Fine! Go now, if you want!
But not with me!
You may have a duty to God,
but I have a duty to my people.
And my people are starving.
Right now, I'm going to take
the food back to the city.
And if you can please calm down
and let me accompany you to Orléans...
it will be my honor
to welcome you.
Jesus Christ.
The goddamn English
will pay for this.
Yes, they will, and so will you
if you don't stop swearing.
Come on. I'm happy
to welcome you in my tavern.
Come on in.
La Hire, Gilles,
let me show you something.
Tourelles are around here.
The river crosses there.
Calm down.
You can't blame those people.
They've been hearing
about you for weeks.
There's nothing to hear!
And why is there nothing to hear?
Because I haven't done anything!
And why haven't I?
'Cause none of you
will listen to me!
Why don't you join us?
We're about to discuss
the campaign.
I'm sorry.
So from here,
Talbot has spread his forces...
between these forts up here.
But in the last few days it seems,
according to our scouts...
that some troops have been
deployed to this fort here.
What about this huge pile down here?
That's the Tourelles.
The English were planning...
to launch an attack from it,
but then we broke down the bridge--
- I did.
- Yeah.
Which should keep them quiet
for a while.
Now, my hunch is...
the attack will come
from St. Loup, here.
And what does Jeanne think?
I don't think.
I leave that to God.
I am nothing in all of this.
I'm just the messenger.
So...
what is the message?
We give the English...
a last chance
to go home in peace.
And if they refuse?
If they refuse...
we recross the river...
and attack here...
at the Tourelles.
That makes no sense at all.
The Tourelles is virtually impregnable.
If we are on the other side of the river
attacking the Tourelles...
what's to stop Talbot
attacking the city from the north?
- God.
- God. Why, of course.
We'd forgotten about Him.
I feel a great sorrow for you
because you are laughing now...
but by tomorrow night,
some of you will be dead.
With respect, we can't just
attack the Tourelles like that.
- It's a very complicated matter.
- What's so complicated about it?
All you have to do is what you're told.
What could be simpler than that?
I am the drum...
on which God is beating out
His message.
He's beating it so hard,
it's bursting my ears!
You have to understand,
it's not easy for us.
I mean, for our pride
to suddenly be usurped by--
Well, with all due respect,
by a--
by a girl.
So that's it.
To you, I'm just a girl.
Put yourself in my shoes for a moment.
How would you feel if you were me?
Knowing what I know...
enormous gratitude.
One hell of a girl, huh?
I warned you.
I do love her when her fire
gets well and truly stoked.
Me too.
Hello, my friends!
What a journey.
But we made it.
Back together again.
Let's have some fun.
Fine.
I shall look like a man.
Stop it!
How dare you stop me
from doing God's will!
He didn't tell you
to cut all your hair off!.
How dare you tell me
what God tells me to do!
Whatever! But since He's not going
to come down and cut it Himself--
At least let someone
cut it properly!
Raymond, bring the scissors.
Louis, fetch the mirror.
Stop getting so angry about everything.
Calm down.
I am calm!
It's God that's angry.
I need to send a letter, now.
Fine.
''To you, Henry, king of England...
and to you, Duke of Bedford,
who call yourself regent of France...
obey the King of Heaven
and abandon your siege.
Give back the keys
to the other towns you've taken...
and go back home
to your island.
To you, Lord Talbot, I beg you
as humbly as I can beg you...
for the sake of the lives
of your soldiers...
do not bring about
your own destruction.
Surrender to me, Jeanne the maiden,
who wassen there by God. ''
Message!
''But if you do not
heed my warning...
then we shall raise
such a battle cry...
as there has not been heard in France
for a thousand years. ''
Sire, message.
''This is the third and last time
I will write to you.
If you are still here at noon,
I warn you...
you will hear from me
to your very great destruction.
Please give me your answer
speedily. ''
Go fuck yourself!
What did they say?
They said
they'll think about it.
Good.
To be honest,
I don't think they'll leave tomorrow.
I can't wait for tomorrow.
French blood is spilling.
Wake up! Hurry!
They've started the battle
without me.
There's a battle to fight
and a war to be won.
Damn.
Sound the retreat!
My banner.
My banner!
Open the gate!
What happened?
Who gave the order to attack?
God knows.
It was a bad idea.
Were the men confessed?
Where are the priests?
We didn't take them.
We wanted to make a surprise attack.
Dunois, was it you
who gave the order to attack?
- Answer me!
- Can we discuss this later?
Sooner is better than later.
Wait!
You'll be killed!
Follow me!
Follow me
and I will give you victory!
Close it!
Close the drawbridge!
To the drawbridge!
- What is she doing?
- To the drawbridge!
- The drawbridge is closed.
- Not for long.
Let's go!
That's mine.
It's a great victory--
your victory--
but we must follow it through
and pursue the English...
back to Talbot's camp unless,
of course, you have another good idea.
First, we find
the biggest army we can.
- Then we return to Orléans.
- The bridge has been pulled down.
- The English are rebuilding it.
- And how do you know?
You have been with your counsel,
and I have been with mine.
Come on!
Hurry up!
Be careful with my baby.
- That's the Tourelles.
- Wonderful.
Captain!
Looks like the froggy whore's
coming to pay us a visit.
I'd better tell Glasdale.
Let's put the horses over there.
Fathers, please, bless them.
- Please, bless them all.
- We will.
Let's plan this attack a little more
carefully than this morning.
Good idea.
Sire.
We've got, uh, visitors.
Glasdale!
Do you hear me?
You, who call me a whore...
I feel pity for you,
for your soul...
and for the souls of your men!
Yield! Yield now
to the King of Heaven!
Or go back to your island!
And you, go back to your pigsty!
Man the walls.
This morning...
God gave us a great victory.
But it is nothing compared
to what He is ready to give us now.
I know you are all
tired and hungry...
but I swear to you...
that even if these English were hanging
from the clouds by their fingertips...
we would pull them down
before nightfall.
Now...
let all those who love me...
follow me!
Follow me!
You were saying?
Come on!
- I go right.
- I go left!
Come on!
Get that fucking pot of oil
up here now!
Get that fucking thing moving!
Come on!
Move that fucker faster!
You're beautiful.
Let's see if you're powerful.
- Do something!
- Like what?
I don't care!
Do something!
And fire!
Fire!
What the fuck?
Too high.
Reload!
- Get out of here!
- Where are the men?
You're gonna get killed!
Get out of here!
Come on, fight!
Go!
Bring the culverin!
Get out!
I'm going up the side!
- Jeanne!
- Leave me alone!
Hurry!
Come on! Come on!
Yes!
Hey, you just killed my woman!
Captain!
Go to hell.
Call the physician!
The physician!
Damn it!
Louis, find the physician.
We have to take out the arrow.
She'll bleed to death.
There must be something we can do
for her, for Christ's sakes.
- Yes. You can pray.
- Good idea.
I swear that I will
never swear again in my life...
if You save her life.
But I'm warning You,
if You let her die...
then You're the biggest--
- Don't swear.
- He heard me.
Why--
Why aren't you fighting?
You've been badly wounded.
- It's nothing. It's --
- It's an arrow.
And it's in deep.
You must stay still
till the physician arrives.
Physicians are a waste of time.
We'll have more luck with this charm.
It saved my life at Agincourt.
I'd rather die than use magic.
You will die if that arrow
stays in you much longer.
Well, at least this
won't bother us anymore.
Now, let's go to the battle!
Please!
She's nuts.
You must stay calm.
You must rest.
I'll rest.
But you have to...
promise me...
that you'll --
that you'll go back to the battle.
I promise.
Hurry!
Quickly!
Do something!
She's sleeping.
What?
Come on back!
Why are you running away?
- Jeanne is alive.
- Good.
- We have to press on the attack.
- Sound the retreat.
- I promised Jeanne we'd fight on.
- I made no such promise.
- Sound the retreat for the night.
- No, that was her order.
I'm fed up
with taking her orders!
She swore she'd defeat
the English before nightfall!
Instead, she goes and plays the fool,
gets herself nearly killed!
Look!
Look at the mess we're in!
That's her mess, not mine!
We are worse off
than if she'd never come at all.
Now do as I say
and sound the retreat!
Where are you going?
Hey, come back!
Come back and fight!
- What are you making?
- A message for the English.
So, what are the men saying?
She's a gift from God.
Some even call her a saint.
- I'd gladly follow her through hell.
- Will you go that far if she asks you?
Of course I will,
and I've been there before.
There's one thing
I don't quite understand.
She's been sent to us by God.
Why does He allow her
to be wounded so badly?
Maybe the good question is,
is she really sent by God?
Who knows?
God knows.
Ooh.
A woman with a sword.
You've hurt my feelings.
Frenchies!
What happened to your precious angel?
Huh?
Frenchies! Frenchies!
I'll tell you what happened!
We sent the little bitch
back to hell...
so she can go fuck
with the devil!
What are you gonna do now,
Frenchies?
Why not come out and fight?
Come on!
Bastards, wake up!
Or are you too busy praying...
to bring your little fucking witch
back from the dead?
Do you hear me?
I hear you!
I'm alive!
May God forgive your blasphemy...
for I never will.
I never will!
What are you doing?
You need to rest.
We must wake up the soldiers, now!
My fine soldiers, wake up!
To arms!
Wake up! Wake up!
We must fight the battle!
My fine soldiers,
the battle has begun!
Wake up!
The time has come!
The battle has begun!
- To arms!
- Yes?
My soldiers, we need this tower up!
We need this tower up, now!
Pull!
- What's going on?
- We're taking back the Tourelles.
Get ready!
Go wake up Glasdale.
- What are you doing?
- Sending a message to Glasdale.
- With that?
- Yes.
But you've got it back-to-front.
Listen, I know what I'm doing...
so either lend a hand
or get back to bed.
I'm going to send a message
to Glasdale too.
My lord?
What?
The French witch,
she's back from the dead.
Hurry up, men!
Don't you think we should take
some time to think about this?
Sooner is better than later.
To arms!
Good morning.
This one.
What the fuck is she playing at?
I don't know! The question is,
what is she doing now?
How can we plan anything
if she doesn't consult with us?
- Did we consult with her yesterday?
- Don't even start.
- You agreed to attack yesterday too.
- Yes, but that doesn't count.
- Why is that?
- Because I always agree to attack.
To arms!
Crazy bitch.
She doesn't even know
how to use it.
Oh, my God!
- Fuck! Close the doors!
- Close the doors!
- Open the door!
- Load the porcupine!
Pull!
And pull!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Never wait for miracles.
Stay there.
French whore!
Come and get me!
What are you waiting for?
Yes? Oh, Jeanne!
Find your archers
and burn that door!
Right away!
Push!
Prepare the gate!
Come on!
Position!
Fire!
Water!
Oh, my God!
Kill her.
Fuck. Reload!
More archers!
Perfect.
Help me!
Get your men!
We'll load this up as a battering ram!
Already done.
- What?
- Nothing.
Help me with these men, please.
Yes.
As you command.
Wait.
What are you doing?
We're going to open that door.
Isn't that what you want?
Get out of my fucking way!
Fill the cauldron!
Fucking French!
What the fuck do you know about me?
Reload.
Reload!
Fill the fucking cauldron!
What are you waiting for?
More men!
Ready!
Pour the oil!
What are you doing, Jeanne?
I'm playing.
What are you doing
to me, Jeanne?
Do you hear me?
Are you all right?
Calm down.
It's over.
We won.
- We won?
- Yes.
Fucking bitch.
My friend! My soldier!
In my arms.
- We won?
- Won?
No. No, Jeanne.
So small a word will never do.
This is victory!
This is glory!
What's the matter?
This is glory?
Doesn't matter.
This is not possible.
It is not possible.
You look disappointed.
Isn't this what you wanted?
No.
Not like this.
For weeks you've been asking for this.
Well, now you have it.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
I'm just taking his teeth.
But you just can't kill a man
for his teeth.
Why not? He has good teeth.
Because--
Because you can't!
What about all this?
But that's different.
I mean, we were fighting for a cause.
Not me.
He's my prisoner...
I can take his teeth
if I want to.
No, you can't!
Stop it!
Here. Take this!
He's mine now.
Here, you.
Go.
Bravo. And what about
all the other prisoners?
- Do we let them go too?
- I don't know.
Maybe.
We must confess.
Please, we have to be confessed.
All of us.
I know this is not normal custom...
but, uh--
Everything's gonna be fine.
He's gonna confess us.
Kneel. Kneel.
Alençon brings bad news.
Thousands of English are forming up
on the far side of the river.
I think we should count our men
and get ready.
Let's go.
I'll go.
Alone.
I have a message for your King Henry!
It is a message from God!
Go home!
Go now, in peace!
If you do not go now,
you will be buried in this field!
I've seen enough blood!
But if you want more...
I can't stop you!
I can only warn you
that it will be your blood...
not ours!
I'm waiting for your answer.
Never wait for miracles.
Stand by to attack.
Please.
My Lord...
please.
Now that's what I call
a goddamn bloody miracle.
She was on her white horse alone...
facing the whole English army,
and she drove them away...
and now Orléans is free.
We lost Orléans.
I want that girl.
I want that girl burned.
May I see the seamstress?
It's too tight. I can't breathe.
That's meant to be a crown?
Don't you have something more regal?
The English took the real one.
It's been muddy so long I forgot
how good it looked cleaned up.
But did you remember to clean up
what's inside as well?
I ask for a grandiose coronation,
and this is what you give?
This whole thing is going to be
an utter fiasco!
You gave me 3 days to prepare.
Your father's coronation took 3 months.
He's right.
We should call for a delay.
No time.
We can't hold up the ceremony.
No telling when the English
might come back.
Let them come. Let them see
who is the true king of France.
Those damn English. We should be
doing this in Paris in Notre Dame.
It is much more prestigious
and twice as big.
It is the sacred place that matters,
not the size. Correct, Bishop?
Yes, my lady.
True kings of France must be anointed...
in our great cathedral of Reims
with the holy oil of Clovis.
Your Grace!
There can be no anointing.
- What are you talking about?
- The holy oil of Clovis is all gone.
Gone?
That's impossible.
It's a magic oil. A miraculous oil.
It can never be exhausted.
- Look for yourself.
- Problem?
I just don't understand.
The oil of Clovis. It was quite full
the last time I saw it.
- And when was that?
- At the coronation of King Charles VI.
Thirty years ago?
Does it surprise you it's gone?
But you don't understand.
It's no ordinary oil.
It's a miraculous oil.
It was brought
by a white dove from heaven...
to crown King Clovis
in this very cathedral.
- What are you doing?
- Performing a miracle.
With this sacred oil, blessed by
the hand of God the Father Almighty...
we do anoint thee, Charles Valois...
to be sovereign lord and king
of this great kingdom of France...
charging that we should defend
the faith of our Mother Holy Church...
as long as we shall live.
Amen.
Long live the king!
- Jeanne, are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- Why are you staring at me?
- You have an arrow in your leg.
So there is.
But that doesn't stop you
from climbing!
Well, climb! Go! Go!
Take this arrow out of my leg.
Look out!
- Be careful!
- Jeanne, the men are exhausted.
I know, but so is the enemy.
They're falling back. Paris is ours.
Jeanne, we are not enough.
So bring up the reinforcements.
Reinforcements? Where?
Right behind us.
Dunois with another 10,000 men.
- Jeanne, look behind you.
- Never look behind. Only ahead.
Do you know how to count?
Of course I do!
So, bring them up!
Jeanne, that is not
10,000 reinforcements!
That is 100...
very loyal
but very tired soldiers!
But where's Dunois?
And where are the men
the king promised me?
He never sent them!
Don't you understand?
He doesn't want this war anymore.
He has his crown now.
That's all he ever wanted.
But my voices, they promised me.
To hell with your voices!
It's time to face facts!
We have nothing to do here!
None of us!
Not even you.
You don't believe in me anymore?
Jeanne, of course we still
believe in you.
If it were up to me, I'd chase every
goddamn Englishman into the ocean.
But it's not up to us anymore.
It's up to the king.
You should go home, Jeanne.
We cannot possibly afford to pay
for the size of army she's demanding.
Girl is crazy.
Her victory at Orléans
was a miracle.
But we can't wait for a miracle
when we build a future for France.
Paris was a disaster.
God wasn't with her then.
If God deserts her,
what do you think we should do?
Why did you betray me? Paris was ours.
All I needed was a few hundred men.
- Why did you take the army you gave me?
- Gave you?
- I wouldn't quite put it that way.
- So how would you put it?
We are, of course,
enormously grateful...
for your past efforts...
but now your task is done.
Now is the time for negotiation.
Peace will only be got with the English
by the end of a lance.
Why are you so blood thirsty?
Doy ou enjoy it?
Diplomacy is far more civilized...
far safer and far cheaper.
I've letters here from towns under
siege, where your people are starving...
begging God on their knees
to help them.
I'm here to answer their prayers.
And you want to stop me?
France does not belong to you, Charles.
She belongs to God.
If only she would just go home.
So what am I supposed to do now?
- What do your voices say?
- They haven't spoken to me in weeks.
Not since the coronation.
No signs, nothing.
Maybe their silence is a sign.
- Maybe it's a sign to go home.
- No.
It's not time yet.
My mission isn't over yet.
- There's still more I have to do.
- But how do--
How do you know that these--
these voices aren't just really you?
Well, they are me.
That's how God speaks to me.
Even you could hear them
if you listened hard enough.
You make it sound so simple.
So even you don't believe in me anymore.
Jeanne, I believe in you
more than anyone.
I just wish I could...
help you.
There is one thing you can do
if you want to help me.
Tell me.
Tell the king to give back
the army that he gave me.
We have to stop her, Your Majesty.
If she raises an army
and attacks the Burgundians...
months of negotiations
will have been in vain.
Jeanne has done so much for us.
I can assure you, the maid has
no greater admirer than myself.
Whatever our personal feelings,
we cannot allow her to conduct...
her own private war.
For the sake of the kingdom, you must
stop her from going to Compiègne.
I can't stop her.
Well, if you don't, I'm sure the
Burgundians would be happy to oblige.
If they capture her at Compiègne--
No one could blame us.
But it could sound like
we betrayed her.
- No, never.
- Good heavens, no.
Don't worry, Charles.
If God is still with her,
she will be victorious.
But her army's so much smaller.
Then her faith will have to be bigger.
- What are you doing? Open this gate.
- I can't risk the safety of my town.
Take my banner!
My Lord.
I can't believe it.
Your romantic vision of death
with all that grass growing everywhere.
I must admit,
you have a big imagination.
But maybe not big enough.
Death is much more simple.
After a few months,
it gets more interesting.
Then after a year,
it finally becomes...
romantic.
Who are you?
You don't like my face?
Maybe you'd prefer this one.
Too young, maybe.
How about this one?
Better now? But incomplete.
Get thee behind me, Satan.
Who are you to even think you can know
the difference between good and evil?
Are you God?
I'm just a messenger.
He needs me.
How can you imagine that God,
the creator of heaven and Earth...
the source of all life...
could possibly need you?
I don't know.
You don't think He's big enough
to deliver His own messages?
What do you want from me?
Nothing.
I'm here to set you free.
I said smile.
You have visitors.
The Duke of Burgundy.
So here's the famous Jeanne...
savior of Orléans,
terror of the English.
My king will pay
any ransom you ask.
Your king?
Oh, yes, of course.
What's he gonna pay me with?
Cows? Chickens?
I prefer gold,
and the English have plenty.
I wonder how much they'll pay to have
the witch of Orléans in their clutches.
The English are so arrogant, they can't
accept being defeated by a peasant girl.
It has to have been the devil's work.
God defeated the English.
And God allowed you to be caught?
Personally, I don't believe in God.
I don't believe in the devil either.
That's why I'm never disappointed.
Sell her.
To pay Jeanne's ransom.
The captains gave what they could,
as well as citizens of Orléans.
That's very generous of you.
How much?
- Ten thousand gold crowns.
- Ten thousand?
That's a lot.
Your Grace, I place you in charge
of this very delicate negotiation.
Get yourself ready.
You're leaving.
Who are you?
Pierre Cauchon, bishop of Beauvais.
As you were captured in my diocese, the
duty to conduct the trial falls upon me.
Trial?
What trial?
Your trial, Jeanne,
on a charge of heresy.
But my king--
Didn't he pay my ransom?
It seems the English care
more about you than the French.
- The English?
- Yes.
They paid your ransom.
Tomorrow you'll be transferred
to their great castle at Rouen.
Our serene and Christian king, Henry VI,
king of England and France...
has placed this girl in our hands,
accused of heretical deeds...
to be tried in a matter of faith.
Take the Holy Gospels in your hand...
and swear to tell the truth regarding
anything you may be asked.
I don't know what you will ask me. You
may ask things I won't want to answer.
You will swear to tell the truth
about everything you are asked.
I will willingly tell the truth
about all Earthly things.
But as to my revelations,
I've told no one except my king...
Charles VII, the one and only
king of France.
You must take the oath.
Not even a king would refuse to take
an oath in a matter of faith.
I will tell you all
that I'm allowed to tell you.
But as for the rest...
even if you threatened
to cut off my head, I won't tell you.
Begin by telling us your name, assuming
you're allowed to tell us that much.
My name is Jeanne.
My little cross was taken from me.
May I have it back?
Show us a little more
cooperation first.
Where were you born?
In a village called Domremy.
How old are you?
Nineteen, or thereabouts.
Were you baptized?
- Yes.
- Recite our Lord's Prayer.
Not unless you hear my confession.
Listen to me very carefully.
We are all men of faith...
and we shall earnestly strive for the
salvation of your body and your soul...
in the name of our Church who never
closes arms to those who return to her.
But we cannot help you...
unless you submit to our
learned judgment and authority.
Take heed of this
charitable admonition...
for if you persist
in refusing our help...
we shall have no choice but to
abandon you to the secular powers.
And I think you know well enough
the punishment that would await you.
Now...
will you please recite
our Lord's Prayer?
Not unless you hear my confession.
Be careful. You aren't helping yourself
by refusing to submit to our judgment.
You...
who claim to be my judges,
you be careful!
For you too one day will be judged.
Guards, take the prisoner away!
- Silence!
- Sorceress!
Silence!
Clear the room!
In future, we should conduct inquiries
privately, away from public pressure.
Let the English burn her if they want.
Why does it have to involve us?
Because it's our duty to root out
heresy wherever we find it.
Father Vincente.
You're the most venerable among us.
What do you think?
I think this trial is a masquerade...
and I won't be part of it anymore.
I'm willing to be her judge,
but not her executioner.
That's what I'm trying to ensure.
The verdict comes at the end of
a trial, Cauchon. Not at the beginning.
I am going back to Rome...
to give my report
to our Holy Father, the Pope.
This is ridiculous. Now I'm the one
who's on trial and being judged.
- Arrest him.
- What are you doing?
This is an ecclesiastical court.
You've no right to do this.
This is English territory.
I have the right to do anything.
Is that clear?
Our Father who art in heaven--
Thy kingdom come--
Forgive us--
Forgive them--
Forgive them, then forgive us.
Forgive them.
Why were you yelling?
What are you doing here?
You can't stay here! Go away!
Why? Are you waiting for someone else?
Yes.
- Who?
- My visions.
Your visions.
They're going to visit you in here?
Yes. That's what I pray for.
I want to see that.
Do you mind if I stay on the side here?
- I won't bother you.
- No!
No, you can't! You can't!
- Or else they won't come.
- Why won't they?
Because I have to be alone.
Oh. They won't come anyway.
- What do you mean, they won't come?
- Why would they?
Because I've always been faithful
to God...
and I've followed everything
He's ever said...
and I've done everything
He's ever asked me to do.
God asked you to do something?
Yes, lots of things.
You mean, God said...
''I need you, Jeanne''?
But He's sent me signs.
Signs? What signs?
The wind. The wind.
Wind.
And the clouds. Ringing.
Ringing cloud.
The dance. The dance.
The sword. The sword lying in the field.
That was a sign.
No. That was a sword in a field.
No. No. That was a sign.
No, that was a sword in a field.
It can't just get there by itself.
It can't.
A sword just doesn't get there
by itself.
True. Every event has an infinite
number of causes, so why pick one?
There are many ways a sword
might find itself in a field.
Seems a perfectly valid explanation,
but how about this one?
Then again, there are other
possibilities.
Or even faster.
And that's without counting
the inexplicable.
Yet from an infinite number of
possibilities, you had to pick this one.
You didn't see what was, Jeanne.
You saw what you wanted to see.
This voice that you say
appears to you...
is it an angel or a saint,
or does it come from God?
I won't tell you any more about that.
I'm more afraid of displeasing Him
than not answering you.
You're afraid of displeasing God
by telling the truth?
Did God forbid you
to tell the truth?
My revelations were for
the king of France, not for you.
When you saw your king
for the first time...
was there an angel over his head?
If there was one, I did not see it.
Why did your king believe in you
without any proof?
Go ask him yourself.
Dinner.
When you were taken prisoner,
did you have a horse?
Yes. A half-steed. Black.
- Who gave you that horse?
- My king.
How many did he give you?
Five steeds...
and a few hackneys.
As much as for a lord.
What an honor.
Did your king give you other wealth
apart from those horses?
What about all those dresses
you were given?
Silk dresses, weren't they?
Yes.
Yes, I was given a few.
But I never had time to wear them.
Still, pretty wealthy
for a peasant girl, wouldn't you say?
You look pretty wealthy
for a servant of God, wouldn't you say?
You launched an attack on Paris,
didn't you?
I tried to.
And didn't you order the citizens
of Paris to surrender the city...
in the name of the King of Heaven?
No. I said, ''Surrender in the name
of the king of France.''
That is not what is written
in the evidence.
Look yourself.
I can't read.
Yes, I forgot.
God sent us an illiterate peasant
to carry out such an important mission.
Do you think that God
made the right decision?
To take an ignorant girl
to save the kingdom of France?
I leave that answer to God.
Fuck!
Calm down, my lord.
I beg you.
How can I when I'm made
the laughing stock of the whole court?
You've seen how it is.
This girl has a way with people...
but we're making progress every day.
As long as that bitch remains alive,
our armies refuse to fight. Understand?
They need proof
that God is on their side.
It's not for us to burn her.
That's your prerogative.
And it's your prerogative
to find her guilty!
But we can't do that
unless she admits to blasphemy.
What are you waiting for?
You've got a castle full of racks,
ropes and pulleys. Torture the bitch!
You'll never get anything
out of her that way.
And besides...
you must realize that several
of my colleagues are, well, scared.
Scared? Of a girl?
Scared to make a mistake.
Suppose she's right.
Suppose she has been sent by God.
- Who's side are you on, Cauchon?
- I'm on the side of Holy Mother Church.
Do you have a sword?
- Quite a few.
- Didn't you also carry a banner?
Yes.
Which do you prefer?
Your banner or your sword?
I was 40 times more fond of my banner.
Why? Did it have some
particular value or power?
It's just--
- A sword is a weapon.
- And?
And so, I prefer my banner.
Why?
To avoid killing anyone.
Are you saying if you'd not
been carrying your banner...
you'd have killed more people?
Of course not.
I never killed anyone.
Then perhaps the temptation...
to kill would have been stronger--
too strong, perhaps.
I warned the English to go back home.
I begged them not to force us to fight.
They knew that I--
We have numerous witnesses
who can confirm...
you were not always
carrying your banner.
Yes, perhaps.
Sometimes you were carrying
just your sword.
Yes. I don't know.
Did you use the sword
you held in your hand?
Yes, I used it--
I held it up--
You held up your sword
and flourished it about like this!
I don't remember.
So, you were on the battlefield
with your sword in your hand...
waving it above your head,
charging against the enemy...
screaming at the enemy,
fighting for your life...
and you expect us to believe...
that in the middle
of all this excitement...
you never killed anyone.
No. I never killed anyone.
I can't believe
you can lie like that.
I'm not lying. I'm not lying.
Leave me alone. I can't remember.
-I didn't kill anyone. I can't remember.
-Let me help your memory.
I don't want to hear any more.
Leave me alone. I didn't kill that man.
Leave me alone!
Stop. Stop. I can't remember.
The battles were so confusing. I was
only defending myself as best I could.
There was so much dust, smoke and noise.
I was being attacked on all sides.
So maybe perhaps I fought back.
- But it was only to defend myself.
- So your memory's coming back.
- Yes.
- Good.
Now, you tell me why God let all those
battles happen in the first place.
He's so powerful. You said...
'' He's the creator of heaven and Earth,
the source of all life.''
He could easily have stopped
all that blood and misery.
Why didn't He--
Is He the one who spread
all that blood and misery?
- Is He?
- No. But He could have stopped it.
What, did he get pleasure--
pleasure--
pleasure from watching us killing
each other in His name?
In His name?
In His name. We fought and killed
in His name--
- the King of Heaven.
- Really?
Let all those who love me
follow me!
'' Let all who love me
follow me!''
Where does God get mentioned?
Come on, Jeanne.
Be honest.
You fought for yourself.
In your name.
No!
I was defending myself
as best as I could.
Everyone has the right
to defend themselves, don't they?
Yes, they do!
Should I have let myself get killed?
- Is that it?
- No. You did fine.
I'd even say well done.
As a matter of fact...
most of the ones you killed
probably deserved it, don't you think?
I never thought killing each other
would bring about any peace.
I agree.
Peace will only be got from
the English at the end of a lance.
I don't agree. Why do you keep
changing your mind all the time?
You. Why--
Why are you doing this to me?
Do you get pleasure from hurting me?
Pleasure.
That's a difficult word to define.
When does pain end and pleasure begin?
When did your pleasure begin?
With that sword in your hand?
I never took pleasure...
in hurting anyone.
Really?
Set me free. Set me free.
You will be, Jeanne.
You will be.
Jeanne, my very dear
friend in Christ...
we, your judges and assessors...
desirous of reaching
a true and lawful verdict...
submitted a transcript of your trial
to the University of Paris...
to attain their opinion.
After careful consideration...
the learned scholars
have concluded with us...
that you have committed
many grievous sins.
I ask you now
to listen most carefully...
to their opinion,
as detailed in these articles.
Article One.
You said that by God's command you have
continually worn men's clothes...
and that you have also worn
your hair short...
with nothing to distinguish you from
the soldiers with whom you fought.
Don't abandon me. Please.
Where are You?
Where are You? Please.
Is this what You want?
You want me to...
to burn...
without...
being confessed?
Finally, Article 12.
You have said that you are not
willing to submit yourself...
to the judgment of the church militant,
but only to God.
As to this article,
the scholars say...
that you have no comprehension
of the authority of the Church.
That you have perniciously erred
in the faith of God...
and you are a child of superstition,
a wanderer from the faith...
an invoker of demons, an idolater...
and a heretic.
We once again admonish,
beg and exalt you...
to cast out and recant
your erroneous beliefs...
by signing this recantation.
Please.
If the Church...
wants me to say...
that my visions are evil...
then I do not believe in this Church.
Perform your office.
Wait.
Jeanne, I beg of you, sign.
In God's name, don't you understand?
I'm trying to save you.
I want to be confessed.
Sign this and I will confess you
myself, if you want.
And may I--
May I go to Mass?
As often as you like.
Now, for the love of God, sign.
Sign, Jeanne,
and you'll be free of your chains.
Free of the fire, Jeanne.
Thank you.
Do you know what you just signed?
You just signed away His existence.
- I didn't mean to.
- For you, He's a lie.
An illusion.
No, no.
He told me that I would be confessed.
In the end, it was you
who abandoned Him.
- May I have that back, please?
- You have nothing to regret.
Give it back to me!
- Give it back!
- Take her away!
Silence her!
There. She has recanted.
And we accept her repentance...
for the Church never closes her arms
to those who would return to the fold.
Now she's your martyr, not ours.
Please!
Enough.
Here.
If you want to get dressed,
try these for size.
My lord bishop.
Come to see for yourself.
Well, take a look.
You see?
Dressed as a man again.
Her touching repentance
didn't last very long, did it?
The Bishop of Senlis was passing by
and was on hand to witness her relapse.
And by what miracle did these clothes
find their way in here?
Not a miracle, my dear Cauchon.
An evil spell.
This girl is a witch,
and tomorrow she will burn for it.
Have the stake prepared
in the market place.
Jeanne, I don't understand.
Why did you do it?
- Why?
- And you.
Why did you lie?
You promised to have me confessed.
I know. It was the only way
to have you saved from the fire.
It's not my body I want to save.
It's my soul.
I ask only one thing.
Please, hear my confession.
I can't, Jeanne.
I can't hear your confession.
I'm very sorry.
You want to confess?
I'm listening.
I've committed sins, my Lord.
So many sins.
I saw so many signs.
Many signs.
The ones I wanted to see.
I fought...
out of revenge...
and despair.
I was all the things...
that people believe...
they're allowed to be...
when they're fighting for...
a cause.
For a cause.
I was...
proud...
and...
stubborn.
Selfish.
Yes. Cruel.
Yes.
Cruel.
You think you are ready now?
Yes.
Good.