Subtitles by Jeong@Netflix
Actually, I heard...
he's bald.
I hear he's bald.
That's all I heard. Here he comes.
Wow, look at this bastard.
He certainly has a great impression.
Wow.
Do you feel better...
Die, you jerk.
Isn't Je-hyeok here?
Where's Je-hyeok?
PRISON PLAYBOOK
That's the bastard who stabbed Je-hyeok
on the shoulder.
I know. I read the file too.
But what can we do?
I heard Crony is Seagull's boy.
Every wing is filled with Seagull's boys.
They're everywhere.
You know we can't put accomplices
and members of the same gang
in the same wing.
That's why Wing 2 must be
the only wing available.
Still, how can the assailant and victim
be in the same cell? That's not right!
CRPT is going to monitor Crony closely
at all times. 24 hours a day.
He won't be able to make trouble.
It's not him, but Je-hyeok.
What?
Do you think Je-hyeok will leave
that bastard alone?
Crony is a total scumbag.
Come on. Just give it a few days.
The warden will move him
when he finds out.
Why did he have to be transferred in
while the warden is away?
What a big mess.
Where's the warden?
Training.
He went to Switzerland for training.
What about Lieutenant Na? I'll ask him.
He went with him.
I told Lieutenant Paeng
when I saw his file,
so Lieutenant Paeng
will take care of it, okay?
You know how much he cares
about the inmates from his wing.
You asshole!
Shut up! Keep it down, you bastard!
Please, enough with the "bastard."
I said, "No." Hey, listen carefully.
Inmate 6667. Headache.
How many times must I tell you
I won't do it, you shit?
No! I won't do it! I refuse!
Yes, please don't.
Please ask my sister to come. Please?
Please ask my sister to visit me.
All it takes is one phone call!
Why won't you do it? Why?
Hey! You devil bastard!
Do you think I have time to kill,
that I'd call your sister?
I won't do it, bastard.
Do you take me for a fucking fool
or something?
CUCUMBER SOAP
Mr. Baldy.
If you get caught with those,
they'll send you to the hole.
All of those items are banned.
Throw them away before I report you.
Do these assholes want a beating?
Butt out,
before I kill both of you.
That's my spot starting today.
Got that?
You. Do you get it?
You're the cell boss, right?
Why this bastard.
Why the fuck do you keep staring at me,
you shit?
Kaist! Bring me a spoon knife.
I'll cut this bastard's tongue off.
This asshole won't stop talking.
It's annoying as hell!
Don't even try it.
Shut your trap.
If I catch you do anything shady
in this cell,
I'll kill you right then and there.
Got it?
Got it, asshole?
I'm sure he'll be fine.
Je-hyeok isn't a child.
If you're that worried,
live in the cell with him.
Je-hyeok is so lucky.
Everyone has his back.
If any incident occurs in the cell,
you'll get a demerit too.
I'm already maxed out.
I see. Lieutenant Lee.
You were worried about me.
I'm so grateful.
So very grateful.
I see.
OPEN REFORM, EMPATHETIC REFORM
How did you know?
Lieutenant Paeng told us.
He was so shocked
that he ran over and told us who he was.
He's the jerk who stabbed you
in the shoulder, right?
That evil bastard.
Lieutenant Paeng said
to take control first,
so I did that for now,
but it's obvious he's a scumbag.
Don't do anything alone from now on.
Crony will target you when you're alone.
Lieutenant Paeng said
he'll try to move him
when the warden gets back,
so hang in there for a few days.
Why should he do that?
Je-hyeok Kim. You get him first.
That asshole. He destroyed your shoulder.
Don't hold it in. No, I couldn't.
Kim, you stab that bastard too.
Get back at him.
Stab whom?
Stab, stab, block, block.
Side, side. Turn.
The Drums of the Frontier
with Hyung-rae Shim.
My mom loved that.
"Hello, there."
I did that a lot.
Stab...
Wow.
Look who's here.
You're playing baseball again?
How?
I was sure I tore up your shoulder.
You son of a bitch!
I said to shut your trap!
Say one more word.
I'll pop every single blood vessel
in your body.
Shit!
I'm going to sleep. Goodnight.
Looney, sleep here tonight.
I want to sleep next to Jung-woo tonight.
Come here.
I'll protect you.
Will it be curry-flavored shit,
or shit-flavored curry?
That is the question.
I'm worried about Crony.
I know that bastard. He's like a parasite.
He survives by being a servant
to the number-one guy.
I'm sure he's frantically searching
for his new boss.
He's found him already.
I'm sure he's frantically searching
for his new boss.
He's found him already.
He found him
and is being a servant already.
The worst trash in our prison.
The aggravated rape bastard,
and the negligent homicide punk.
He stuck to them.
He knew exactly where the garbage was.
Those scumbags.
Here. Split these among yourselves.
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
You're Seagull's boy?
Yes, sir.
Boss, please take me in.
Take what in, you bastard?
Do you want this?
Thank you, boss.
Wasn't Seagull transferred
because of Je-hyeok?
I hear his sentence was extended
and he's south somewhere. Is that right?
I keep myself informed even in here.
Je-hyeok ratted him out, right?
That's why he stabbed Je-hyeok.
He's the bastard
who killed Je-hyeok's shoulder.
Then he must want to kill you
whenever he sees you.
You'd better keep running.
A lot of people have his back.
If he catches you,
he'll stab you for sure.
I'll strike first.
If you strike him hard enough,
he'll retaliate right away.
That's why I plan
to kill Je-hyeok this time.
I promised Seagull.
How?
Look around. There are eyes everywhere.
How will you get Je-hyeok?
He's surrounded by people.
How will you get him?
When he's alone.
I'll get him when he's alone.
I'm sure I'll get a chance.
Do you need some boys?
No, I'm fine.
I'll stab him in the throat in one blow.
I stabbed him in the shoulder
to keep him from playing baseball,
but not this time.
This time, I'll stab him in the throat
once I get a chance.
I don't need anyone, boss.
Hey, you!
Disperse!
INCINERATOR
Hello.
How have you been?
Should I just leave these here?
Have a nice day.
What are you doing there?
Return to the yard. Exercise time is over.
Okay.
I said not to go anywhere alone.
Looney, Jung-woo.
You take out the trash now.
-Okay.
-It's okay.
I can do that much.
It's okay. I'll do it.
Doesn't your wing have an errand boy?
Our wing's errand boy
had an allergic reaction,
and has been in the infirmary for 13 days.
I never thought he was useful,
but it's so inconvenient without him.
It's so annoying.
What is he saying?
You understood, you bastard.
I barely understood. Barely.
I'm so tired.
Have you no manners?
Who taught you to be rude to adults?
You should act like an adult
to be an adult.
You're a gambler and scammer.
You're no "adult."
I'm too tired. Don't talk to me.
You can't even function because
the drugs wore out. Don't judge me.
The drugs didn't wear out.
I'm doing my best
not to take drugs anymore.
I don't live by my instincts
like some animals like you do.
I am...
fighting it with my own will.
Fighting it, my ass.
How long do you think you'll last?
It's imminent. Imminent.
It is not. It's been a really
long time since I took drugs.
Of course, not. There are no drugs here.
I didn't take cold medicine either.
I'm the only druggie here
who quit even cold medicine.
Show some respect.
Show what? Don't use fancy words,
you bastard.
Hey, Jung-woo!
Bring me some boiling water.
I'm going to pour it on them.
We can just pour it on Looney.
Being rude to adults is just despicable.
The worst.
Hear that, punk? He's on my side too.
What the... Fine.
You're on the scammer's side, is that it?
A scammer over a druggie.
I despise druggies the most.
They're weak and have no will power.
Did you come in here
for doing volunteer work?
For me,
my right hand is the assailant,
and my left hand is the victim.
I'm different from you.
At least I didn't hurt anyone else.
Hey.
He's suffering from withdrawal.
Now? He quit so long ago.
He really must've hung in there
without taking cold medicine.
You know, when heavy drug addicts quit,
they become more out of it
like someone who's high,
and once that fades, most of them
can't handle it and get high again.
But this guy fought it well,
and didn't take anything.
Why? The constant yawning
and chills are symptoms.
These are typical withdrawal symptoms.
What does that mean?
It means he's been enduring very well.
Good job.
Good job, Looney.
Can he stay a few days?
Yes, sure.
It may be more dangerous for him
to be walking around in that state.
Thank you.
This punk...
Inmate 6256, Dong-ho Ahn. Training.
God...
He's gone.
I'm freaking tired
because of that bastard.
I was dying to talk. That asshole.
My head hurts from staring him down
so hard.
Does anyone have anything for headaches?
Let me have one.
Thanks.
Hang in there until the warden returns.
I'm really okay.
I'll protect myself.
Crony isn't here right now.
It became a habit after one night.
I got confused too.
I didn't sleep a wink last night.
Who did? I didn't sleep a wink either.
How long do we have to live like this?
What a joke.
Min-chul.
Must we really go this far?
Didn't you see Crony's eyes?
His eyes glazed over.
He's on the brink of doing something.
We'll protect Je-hyeok. Got it?
Okay. It's just a few days.
Oh, right.
How is your retrial petition going?
Did you submit it yet?
Not yet. My brother is preparing
the documents now.
Soon.
We'll submit the petition soon.
It'll go well.
Don't worry.
A picture of Private Park's watch
stopped at 1:55 a.m.
This one photo made Jung-min and me
come this far.
NIGHT DUTY LOG
SEPTEMBER 20, 2016
PRIVATE JUN-YEONG PARK
We have the night duty log
with Private Park's name on it,
and now, an eye witness.
We're set now, right?
Let's request a retrial right away.
Our attorney, Mr. Kang, is very cautious.
Sorry?
Okay, we have our bullets ready to go.
Now, we have to report Sergeant Oh.
The most important thing for the retrial
is to prove Sergeant Oh committed perjury.
That means we need more soldiers
to testify that they witnessed
what actually happened.
That makes our case stronger.
We need that to get the petition
for retrial granted.
Then I'll meet with the soldiers
and talk to them.
If they won't agree,
I'll threaten them or something.
I'm sure Corporal Choi
and Corporal Lim will listen.
That would be great.
We need to gather
anything we can right now. Why?
Because Sergeant Oh's side
is on the move too.
Next on the news.
And at least because of that,
it'll be bad if the case
gains attention again.
This morning,
Senator Tae-gu Oh announced
his candidacy for a fourth term.
He was a member
of the National Defense Committee
and led many movements
such as reviving commercial regions.
Senator Oh came in first
in a recent survey by a large margin,
and is favored to win the election.
He has a lot of money and has
many connections in the legal world.
He'll have an impressive legal team.
Hey.
Your firm is huge too.
That's right. Of course. Trust me.
Don't worry. We will win, no matter what.
Bro. Just a minute.
Ice cappuccino.
How did you know? Thanks.
I've been cleaning the office lately.
I sneaked a peak in the computer.
I hear you. Shit.
I looked at your fan site
and read Gocheok Gunman's blog.
It has 100,000 Q&A about Je-hyeok Kim.
You should read it sometime.
He knows everything about you.
Joon-ho. Can't you ask Gocheok Gunman
to come visit?
If you let him meet Je-hyeok,
I'm sure he'll love you like a brother.
No way.
Seriously, meet him.
You may know him already.
I didn't think of that.
Yes, I'm sure he does.
Diehard fans usually know each other.
They're closer than most brothers.
You bastard.
You didn't take Crony out yet, right?
Do you want to just sleep here?
I'm too worried. I can't take it.
I'll protect myself.
Everyone must think I'm a weakling.
No. I'm not worried about you.
I'm worried about Crony.
I'm worried that you'll cause trouble.
Hey. If he loses his mind,
he's worse than most of the thugs here.
Wasn't that in that 100,000 Q&A?
It probably is, but I read only
10 pages so far.
There are 1,000 pages.
And I know Je-hyeok is psychotic.
I saw it myself. I saw him take down
Seagull at the detention center.
I'm also worried about Crony.
He'll get stepped on good this time,
if he acts out.
Then Je-hyeok may have his sentence
extended or get demerits or something.
Don't you worry. I won't cause trouble.
I can finally play baseball again.
I finally got my form back.
Why would I do that? I won't.
Don't you worry. Nothing will happen.
Wow. You have your temper
under so much control now.
How can you not get angry? I can't.
HOLY BIBLE
TALMUD
HEART SUTRA
CAIGENTAN
FORGIVENESS
QURAN
BECOME BROTHERS WITH YOUR ENEMIES
-What is this?
-I'm cultivating my mind.
I'm honing my mind.
I can't ruin my life
because of that bastard.
I'll hold it in.
I'm trying to forgive him.
I'm trying my best
to think only about baseball.
What if he suddenly stabs you?
What if he comes and stabs you
while you're cultivating your mind?
What, would I just sit there
while he comes at me?
I'll try to avoid him.
I won't let him come at me.
It's okay. Nothing will happen.
My cellmates are helping, too.
Oh, my goodness. What a saint.
Gratitude.
No. Courage.
Edelweiss' meaning is "courage."
Have courage.
You'll take the mound again.
Thank you.
What's with them?
No clue.
Min-chul's been exuding estrogen lately.
He's so sappy.
What about that?
Guess what that flower means.
What's its name?
Poppy. Red poppy.
You can grow it.
What does poppy mean?
Looney?
Looney should be okay, right?
Wow. Is he Sleeping Beauty or something?
How many hours is he sleeping?
He does open his eyes, right?
Amazing. Who knew
a person could sleep so much?
He woke up an hour ago and had porridge.
Did you just get here?
Did you come straight here?
The afternoon shift?
Yes. Lieutenant asked me to do something
on his way out.
He said to bring a gift for Looney
for really quitting drugs.
-Here.
-Wow. Ice cream.
That's something you can't have in prison.
But he's sleeping. What should I do?
They'll melt.
What else? We'll eat them all.
Thanks for this.
Enjoy.
I thank you too.
-Cheers.
Hello.
Hey, Song. What are you doing?
It's time for Wing 2's bath.
They're freaking out
that we're not taking them.
Okay.
-Move quickly.
-Geez.
The poor guy can't even eat his ice cream.
He's quiet when he eats.
Okay, then.
What? Where are you going?
Shower.
I'm not sick at all anymore.
Please let me take a shower.
I want to take a shower.
I'm all better, doctor.
I'll take him.
Just let him go.
Sure. But you have to be careful.
You can't go in hot water yet.
Goodness. It's too hot for hot water.
Hurry up and change.
I'll take you to the shower room.
Seriously, he's so annoying.
What is that? Where did you get it?
Officer Song gave it to me.
He saved his life.
Coffee isn't a big deal.
Why didn't Han-yang stay in the infirmary?
What's so great about showering?
Right? What's so great about showering?
I don't get it.
In light of that, I will pass
on the shower today.
No shower today!
-Please!
-Please, wash up! Please!
Let us live too, please?
Geez. You scared me.
If you don't wash again today,
I'll break your legs.
I'll submit a formal complaint.
Screw you both.
Like you're so clean.
Crony doesn't wash that well either.
I don't care whether or not he...
It's okay. It's okay, Jung-woo.
I need to use the toilet.
Okay. Sure.
Yikes!
Min-chul.
I think I broke my back.
What do I do?
Min-chul, are you okay?
Oh no.
What do we do?
-Slowly. This way. Here.
-No.
Freeze. What are you doing?
I said to stop!
What do you take me for? Get over here!
Shit.
SEOBU PENITENTIARY
Nice! Good job, Je-hyeok.
His speed and control improved a lot.
He should be able to face
a batter or two with that.
That's right. He's capable of
at least a one-point relief.
If lucky, if he can do more,
he may be a middle reliever.
He almost made it into the major league,
but now...
hopes to be a middle relief.
-Lieutenant Lee.
-Yes?
Can you do the night inspections
for my wing tonight?
I need to go to the hospital.
Are you sick?
No. I have a medical checkup today.
Why don't you ask Lieutenant Paeng?
He worked two nights in a row.
You can't call him, okay?
-Fine.
-Thank you.
Oh yeah, Lieutenant Lee.
I heard reporters are calling
Je-hyeok Kim for interviews.
Shouldn't you become his manager as well?
Why is he suddenly doing interviews?
-There was that article.
-What?
Why is he suddenly doing interviews?
-There was that article.
-What?
Didn't you know? It just came out that
Je-hyeok Kim is playing baseball again.
That he changed his throwing arm to right,
and that he's doing rehab in prison.
The Internet's buzzing about that.
Je-hyeok is most trending.
I bet the warden was really disappointed.
He was saving that
for his favorite reporter Mr. Yong.
How did that get out?
True. There are so many people here.
It's surprising it didn't...
Do the inspection for me.
-I heard.
-How?
Min-chul sent me a message.
What do I do? The warden will flip out.
That was my first concern too.
We can worry about him later.
So? Will you do the interviews?
An inmate can't do interviews.
I should know my place.
I won't give interviews straight up,
but I don't want to avoid it.
I have to look into teams anyway.
If anyone will even take me.
Joon-ho.
What if no one calls?
What else? There's a way.
We'll call them first.
You still think you're on top.
Don't you get it yet?
If none of the teams calls you,
we'll call them.
If no one wants to sign you,
then we can beg and plead.
I'll go and beg.
I'll ask them to give Je-hyeok Kim a shot.
Saying that out loud...
It's crazy sad.
Joon-ho.
Try reading in times like that.
It helps if you cultivate the mind.
I've been...
reading Holy Bible,
Heart Sutra, the Conan,
and Talmud all together.
There are so many nice sayings.
There's this saying in the Conan.
"Allah protects them,
so do not go astray,
and do not pursue the greed
of the heart."
Shut up!
It's the "Quran," not "Conan."
You ignorant bastard.
Detective Conan.
Get over here. I'll put you in your cell.
Yes, sir.
CELL 2B6
CELL 2B2
Hello, inmates. You did great today.
We will now lock the cell gates.
My goodness.
Is it because it's summer? They turned in,
but it's still bright outside.
What are you mumbling about alone?
What? Why are you on the second floor?
Don't you work on the first floor?
Song asked me to fill in.
Chief.
May I look over personal details
of Wing 2's inmates?
Why? Who? Whom do you want to know about?
I was just bored,
so I thought I'll flip through them.
Hello?
Who is this?
Hello. I'm sorry to call
suddenly like this.
I'm Officer Joon-ho Lee
from Seobu Penitentiary.
You're Tae-uk Kim's guardian, correct?
I'm calling because your brother
asked you to come visit.
He's been asking for you for a few weeks,
which is why I'm calling today.
I'm sure I said to stop calling.
I'm in no position
to visit my brother, officer.
I don't have money to send
commissary money,
and I can't visit
because it's so far away.
I live paycheck to paycheck.
I told Lieutenant Paeng
several times already.
I really want to stop getting these calls.
I'm sorry.
I said to stop calling.
What's wrong with you?
I'm sorry.
Still, can't you come and see Tae-uk
just once?
He was asking for you all day again
until he fell asleep.
I'll pay for your transportation.
Lieutenant Paeng.
I'm... I'm a despicable human being.
I don't deserve to be his sister.
I'm very sorry.
-I'm ashamed.
-No, don't be.
I understand.
My husband doesn't know.
My family doesn't know anything
about this.
I want to cut ties
with my brother.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
Goodness...
You called again, didn't you?
Just tell Tae-uk
that his sister doesn't want to come.
Tell him you called her
more than 100 times, but she won't come.
Why are you letting him curse you out?
Just tell him the truth.
It's better to let him curse me out.
He asks for his sister all day long.
What if he finds out
that she doesn't want to see him?
Would you be able to carry on?
It's better for me to be cursed out.
True.
Being cursed out is your daily routine.
You'll be able to handle it
much better than anyone else.
Right?
You little bastard...
Are you sleepy? Geez.
Have some coffee.
It's worse because of the heat.
I'm so out of it.
Just sweat it out.
What?
Lieutenant Lee! Thanks!
I'm here, so you may go.
Okay, I will. Thanks.
What's gotten into you,
helping other officers like this?
Will wonders never cease?
He's such a prick.
I just can't like him. I just can't.
You're up? Don't you have work tomorrow?
Can't you see I'm working?
What is that?
What else?
It's Gocheok Gunman's tearful
welcome back post to Je-hyeok Kim.
Why am I more excited than concerned about
his transformation from lefty to righty?
Hey. You're missing a line at the end.
What? What's missing?
"Do you believe me?"
This isn't a column. It's a biography.
Are you jealous of Je-hyeok?
How petty.
You're petty. So petty.
Hey.
Come out.
Come out, you bastard.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Lieutenant Paeng.
-Sorry.
-I know.
If you were sick,
you should've stayed in the infirmary.
Why, I ought to...
Did that bastard pick on you?
I can hear you.
Just kidding.
I...
-Tomorrow is my visitation day.
-What?
I have a visit scheduled tomorrow.
What if they cancel it for being sick?
You can't cancel my visit for being sick,
okay?
I wait all week long for that day.
What if they say I can't go
to my visitation
because I'm sick?
It's your lover, right? Ji-won Song?
I thought it was someone else last time.
Was I wrong?
Anyway, don't worry.
I'll carry you to the visitation room
if I have to.
-Thank you.
-Sure.
Now, I can
sleep in peace.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Paeng.
Yes?
-I love you.
-Oh, my.
RULES OF CONDUCT
Only I didn't know.
I thought I'm like your manager
and your big brother.
But only I didn't know, right?
Sorry.
I wanted to tell you first
once I got in shape.
Sorry.
Sorry for not visiting for a while.
You look good. You're smiling too.
Is it because you can play again?
Je-hyeok. Don't worry about a thing.
I'll hit the ground running from now on.
I'll meet with all ten teams
and tell them you're still alive and well,
and that you can still throw well enough.
I'll make 100...
No, I'll make a million calls a day.
Forget your pride, okay?
They'll call, right?
Still,
at least one team
will want to sign me, right?
Of course.
They'll call for sure. Don't worry.
You should stay in bed if you're sick.
If you faint, you'd just be
a nuisance to the guards.
Please shut up, will you?
My head really hurts.
Han-yang, your lover
is really hanging in there.
Most couples break up after coming here.
-Don't you have someone?
-I'm not interested.
Girls aren't interested in you either.
Why you little...
Wow... You guys fight a lot.
At least you won't be bored in here.
It's nice to have friends.
We aren't friends. I'm older.
My parents just registered me late.
I'm even older than you.
Mentally, I'm 50 years old.
-You're so immature.
-You're more immature.
Both of you are immature.
You're like little kids.
Let's go in.
What?
Enough already.
How does your IQ drop by ten every day
ever since you got here?
-It's because of that bastard.
-Don't blame Han-yang. You're the same.
Go in already.
Your brother must be waiting. Go.
Are you sick? You look terrible.
I'm very well. I'm very healthy.
I haven't taken drugs in...
Okay, okay. I believe you.
I mean it.
I haven't taken drugs
in over three months.
Good job. That's great.
I love you.
I said I love you.
Is it funny that I love you?
You say things like that
so easily.
Yeah.
It's my only virtue.
I'm always true to my feelings,
unlike you.
Is that why you do drugs?
I said I quit.
I mean it.
Believe me.
I won't take drugs again. I won't.
So,
you have to come visit me
once a week.
Okay?
UI JUNIOR HIGH
42TH REUNION
December 31, 2009
Han-yang, you're such a punk.
Why am I a punk?
You wouldn't come to any of the reunions.
You came today
because Ji-won's coming, right?
No.
I came because I haven't seen you guys
in a while.
Like hell you did.
You look much better
now that you live in Gangnam.
Do you think Ji-won will make it?
He lands at 10 p.m.
Wouldn't he go straight home?
Ji-won may not come.
What will you do?
I came to see you guys.
Like we'd fall for that, asshole.
I texted to ask where he was,
but he didn't respond.
-Landing.
-Hurry up.
-In cab.
Chill. I'm coming.
-Where are you?
-Near Jamsil.
Hurry up. Come on. Hurry up!
How long has Ji-won been gone?
He emigrated when we were 17,
so five, six years?
Almost there.
-Where are you going?
-He's almost here. I'll go get him.
Okay.
Hey, guys.
Those guys...
No, right?
What are you talking about?
No way. They're close, that's all.
What are you saying, you bastard?
Han-yang hasn't seen Ji-won
since he moved to the States either.
That's right. Are you nuts?
Don't drink too much today.
Hey, Han-yang.
You look the same.
You were texting me like crazy
to hurry up. What's wrong with you?
It's been a while. How have you been?
It's cold. Where is it?
-Everyone must be drunk.
-It's just around the corner.
-You look like you've lost weight.
-I lost a lot.
I worked out like crazy.
-Aren't you cold?
-I am.
Let's hurry.
Wow.
Do you know what this punk said?
Don't. Don't tell them.
"Hey, guys.
They're not, right?
They're not dating, right?"
What are you saying? Freaks.
It's because Han-yang cares
only about you.
God... You asshole.
He never showed up once,
but once he heard you were coming today,
he got here before they even opened.
Of course not.
Not Ji-won.
However,
I don't know about him.
You're drunk. You punks are totally drunk.
The truth is,
I'm interested.
If Ji-won asks me out,
Seriously.
Drink.
Excuse me! Can you change the music?
Enough with the ballads!
It's New Year's Eve.
Don't you have anything fun?
Okay!
Drink! Cheers!
-Cheers.
-Clink.
She's my type.
She's pretty.
Hey. Drink.
Drink.
-That's enough.
-Shit.
Whom did you see in the army?
I didn't go to the army.
-Shit.
-Whatever.
Are you waiting? I guess so, right?
Sorry.
Did you drink a lot?
Hey, guys. It's the countdown!
-10!
-Should we go?
-9! 8! 7! 6!
-5! 4! 3! 2! 1!
-Happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
The store got a new shipment.
They'll sell anything to make money.
Je-hyeok is still in the greenhouse,
right?
-Is he okay?
-He's very okay.
That loser.
He talked like he'd kill him right away.
Hey. Je-hyeok may finish
serving his term at this rate.
How will you get him with a toothbrush?
-What's your labor assignment?
-I don't have one yet.
You're in maintenance, right?
Swipe a tool for him to use.
He'll never get it done otherwise.
What a loser.
When will you get him
if you hesitate like that?
You're such a coward.
What are you doing there?
Disperse, please!
I said to disperse!
Don't you hear me?
I said to split up!
What are you staring at?
You shithead.
What? Want to hit me?
Hit me, asshole.
You don't have the balls to hit a guard.
That loser.
-I have a wish.
-No.
Go to the hospital with me
next Saturday afternoon.
What kind of a dialogue is this?
Are you pregnant?
No. When I went for my checkup,
I couldn't get an endoscopy.
Next Saturday was the only availability,
but I need a guardian present.
Then go with a guardian. Why should I go?
Don't you have family?
I'm an orphan.
I have no friends either. Since I started
this job, I never had time to meet them,
so they drifted apart from me long ago.
Okay. I won't get an endoscopy this year.
I'll get it next year.
No. They say I can't get
a regular endoscopy
and need to be put under,
but I have no family or friends,
and colleagues won't go,
so I'll never get an endoscopy.
If I develop a problem
with my stomach or intestine,
I'll say it's because my colleague
wouldn't...
Okay, fine. I'll go. Let's go.
Don't do that.
Don't do that. I don't like that.
Don't do that. I said to stop it.
I don't like it. I said I don't like it.
But, I like it.
Why is your hand so ugly?
What? What do you mean?
I think it'll work.
Give it to him then.
I can't get it now since we're out here.
Yesterday,
I went to fix a fan in the woodshop,
and there were tons of paint thinner
in the corner.
I think they bought them to use
for paint jobs. There's more than enough.
They won't notice if I steal a couple.
When are you going back there?
Exercise time is over!
Head to your labor locations!
Now.
If we're lucky, I'll give it to you
later this afternoon.
Just get the money ready, punk.
Throw this away.
You may leave it by the incinerator
out back.
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
-I don't need to go, do I?
-No.
You go with him.
Hey. I want to buy some cigarettes.
Now? Officer Kang is in there.
You can sneak them out.
I'll wait outside the greenhouse.
Hurry up.
Boss wants it now, that's why.
I'll give ten transportation cards.
-For real?
-Yeah.
Where's Je-hyeok?
He's taking out the trash.
He went alone?
I sent the guy who runs the store.
Ouch.
Why is that punk here?
He'll be okay alone, right?
Yes. Lifer is there too. He'll be fine.
Anyway, I heard that
Lifer killed more people
than anyone here at Seobu.
Is that true?
That's right. That Lifer gramps
killed four people, right?
Who's "Lifer"?
You know,
the one who always looks pissed off.
He used to work in the woodshop,
but now he burns trash in the incinerator.
I've never seen him smile.
Most people at least smirk when I talk.
But I never see him smile.
Will he really be okay?
I heard Lifer killed people
and gouge their eyes out.
I never heard that before. Is that true?
Is that true?
Yes. He hit them with a hammer
and killed them,
and then gouge their eyes out.
INCINERATOR
Sir!
Call the office and ask for backup.
Emergency. Fire in the incinerator.
Need backup.
-There's a person inside.
-What?
-Where's the hydrant?
-It's far away. It'll take time.
Fire extinguisher.
There should be a fire extinguisher.
My Je-hee.
How did you know
I could talk right this instant?
You have the morning shift, right?
Yeah. I'm about to leave.
Your brother is doing well.
He's taking his herbal tonic,
and training well.
Don't let him work out too much.
He works out like crazy when he trains.
Yes, ma'am.
Also,
what are you doing
next Saturday afternoon?
Your brother said you have
morning shifts for a while.
I already have a plan that day.
With whom?
Officer Song. He's a junior guard.
I agreed to go with him to his endoscopy.
Do you have to go?
I promised.
I feel kind of sorry for the kid.
Lieutenant Lee.
Please come to the incinerator. Quickly.
I said he's fine. Sit down.
Sit down.
Lifer would never harm anyone.
He wants to die every day
and barely carries on.
That man
was an executive at a large corporation,
but as soon as his daughter
started college,
she went to some sort of a trip
with her club members,
and was gang raped.
There were four of them.
The daughter committed suicide,
and his wife also committed suicide
from the trauma.
Oh, my.
Those jerks were all
from wealthy families.
One of them was a son of a chairman
of a well-known company.
They did a horrible thing to her.
They destroyed an entire family,
but one of them got off with probation,
and the other three got
less than a year in jail.
So,
how do you think Lifer's life was?
As soon as they got out,
he went to kill them with a hammer.
Why did he gouge their eyes out?
Why did he do that?
For his daughter.
They'll meet his daughter again
in the afterlife.
He didn't want them to recognize her.
He was afraid they'd harass her
even in the afterlife.
That's why he did it.
Would you be able to smile?
Would you?
Would you be able to smile
after going through that?
HOPEFUL REFORM
Why did you save me?
You should've let me die.
I need to die to see my daughter.
I need to die to see my daughter again!
My...
What are you doing? Carry him.
Je-hyeok Kim. Are you okay?
I'm fine.
What happened?
I think someone set fire
to the incinerator.
-We'll check the surveillance video.
-What?
Hello.
I'll do it.
Put this on.
The back of your shirt is worn out.
If you don't want to wear it,
burn it with the rest.
I'm going to take a piss out back.
Lieutenant Lee.
I'd like an autonomous pass.
IF AN INMATE HAS AN AUTONOMOUS PASS,
HE CAN MOVE ABOUT WITHIN THE FACILITY
WITHOUT A GUARD'S ACCOMPANIMENT
Okay.
I'll take full responsibility.
Should we go there?
-Is someone inside?
-Sorry?
Is someone inside?
Yes. How did you know?
Does he look like...
The bald guy was throwing up in the yard,
so I asked if he was okay,
and he asked if he could wash up.
So, I brought him here.
Je-hyeok.
I'll do it, okay?
You fucking shit.
That's enough.
Je-hyeok. Stop it.
That's enough!
-Hey!
-This bastard needs more beating.
-Stop it.
-He's still fine! You shit!
Stop acting, asshole!
-Je-hyeok, please!
-Let go!
-Stop it!
-I'm going to kill this bastard.
-I'll kill this asshole!
-Stop!
Hey. Je-hyeok.
-Stop it!
-Asshole. Get over here.
A broadcast shared with 50,000 inmates.
I am Min-joo Lee, your host
of the Borami Broadcast.
It's the hottest day of the summer.
In Gyeongju, Gyeongsang Province,
temperatures reached 40°C.
Even pro baseball had to take the day off.
Tomorrow,
the 2017 Pro Baseball All-Star Game
will be held in Gocheok Dome.
-The stadium is surrounded...
-It's so hot.
with people trying to get tickets.
Lieutenant Paeng.
What's the cafeteria serving for dinner?
Kimchi fried rice.
It's summer. Can't they make
cold noodles or something?
Does it taste good?
Well, it's just...
Long sleeves and a fan in the summer...
The air conditioner...
Gocheok Dome means Nexen Heroes,
and "Nexen Heroes"
reminds you of this player, right?
Je-hyeok Kim, who is serving his time
diligently and faithfully,
at Seobu Penitentiary.
Je-hyeok Kim, are you listening?
Of course.
I'd like to send Je-hyeok Kim
and the other 50,000 inmates
a song of encouragement
for the last song today.
I hope all of your lives
will be like this.
"Bravo My Life."
Knock, knock.
Are you the Hulk? Put on a shirt.
I don't have one.
You didn't eat yet, did you?
Lieutenant Paeng
brought me kimchi fried rice.
Joon-ho, I won't be here for life, will I?
Why you...
That little... How can you laugh?
Since Crony instigated it,
that will be considered.
And luckily, the guard from the shower
testified nicely for you.
His testimony was very favorable
toward you.
He's good-looking too.
You freaking psycho.
You almost killed Crony.
You were almost going to rot in prison
for the rest of your life!
You crazy freak.
Do you think I'm that stupid?
I knew you were there.
Thanks.
I mean it. Thanks.
Whatever.
Access granted.
Why would you ruin your life
because of a scumbag like that?
You almost hurt your right hand,
extended your sentence,
and killed your career.
Those scumbags aren't even worth hitting.
Anyway, you can be at peace
for the next few days.
Crony is in the hospital until next week.
Don't worry until then.
Right hand. You must get it treated.
Oh, my. So, you like flowers.
Leave. I'll take Je-hyeok Kim
to the infirmary.
He's my inmate from my wing.
Please stick to the rules.
When? This Saturday? Endoscopy?
Must I really do this?
Can't a fan do that for his star?
Are you sure that's wild rose?
Yes. The greenhouse gave it to me.
Whom is it for?
Let's go.
Like this. Okay. Good, good.
You must've hit him properly.
Still, you should always be careful.
Let me see.
-Can we talk outside...
-What? Me?
Why? Are you hurt?
Well, everything aches...
Gosh. It's because
you don't exercise enough.
You can't hurt your back.
You're not even married.
Why don't you want to live?
It's so discouraging to the person
who saved you.
I heard from Min-chul
about your daughter...
and wife.
Do you think your daughter would be happy
to see you like this?
It's wild rose.
This flower means...
"I miss
the cottage on a hill
in my home country down south,
where wild roses bloom."
Isn't that a song?
How did you know?
Okay, then.
What does poppy mean?
Looney?
Looney should be okay, right?
What is this flower?
-It's wild rose.
-I see.
Wild rose means...
"Solitude, cautious love."
And...
"Longing for family."
Do you want to take it?
No, thank you.
I'll look at it here.
It's pretty.
RECONCILIATION
FORGIVENESS
Are you throwing these away?
Yeah, throw them out.
Je-hyeok, what's your sign?
I'm a rabbit.
Let's see.
"What you want desperately will happen,
and you'll receive good news"?
Good news? A woman?
Good news for Je-hyeok would be...
Je-hyeok, visitation.
It's your attorney.
Je-hyeok.
Are you ready?
Just tell me. I'm fine.
Good news, bad news,
I'm ready for both.
I called all ten teams
after coming to see you,
and I met with them all.
All ten teams...
want to sign you.
Even Nexen.
You did well, Je-hyeok.
Let's start over
like when we first met.
Je-hyeok?
It's you, isn't it?
If you were going to call like this,
why did you break up with me?
We broke up. Wake up.
Where is our Je-hyeok Kim going?
On what terms?
Hey, Je-hyeok Kim!
Buy dinner once you sign with a team.
-Good luck.
-You didn't even sign yet.
Are there any terms you want?
Want me to bury Je-hyeok Kim for you?
He went through so much, and was wronged.
He can say that much.
Je-hyeok.
-What happened to his hair?
-Han-yang...
Looney's cute.
Why do you hate him so much?
-Just get treated, bastard.
-I am, bastard.
-In the summer
-Aren't you hot?
I'm cold.
It's withdrawal. Please understand.
Jung-woo, help him out. You're friends.
You'll be there, right?
If you quit. It's up to you.
Is he really trying to quit?
It'll be impossible.
He's being treated and stuff too,
so he'll be cured.
To be honest, I'm not sure.
He neglects his duties,
jokes around with the inmates...
Lieutenant Paeng is delinquent
and emotional.
Hey, Kang! What's that smoke in Wing 5A?
Lieutenant! Fire!
Fire. Fire. A fire has broken out.
Please follow the guards' instructions
and escape quickly.
Over 50 inmates died,
and there were numerous injured.
-What are you doing?
-He finally caused trouble.
Transfer Lieutenant Paeng elsewhere.