'Who in the world are you?'
'I am the greatest
magician of the age.'
He murdered her. Dig up his bones.
Let him be punished for...
'The magician of Hanover Square!'
Mr Norrell!
I am come, Sir Walter, to offer you
my help in our present difficulties.
~ You mean the war?
~ Yes.
'There's a wonderful street
magician, Vinculus.
'He's all lies and doom.'
I met a man under a hedge who
told me I was a magician.
Then buy these two
spells from me, sir.
"One spell to discover what mine
enemy is doing presently."
'Why on earth would
you want to do that?'
'These are horrible, Jonathan.'
'Sir Walter's bride is dead.'
£1,000 a year and quite dead.
It is a very dangerous thing to
bring someone back from the dead.
'It has not been done in 300 years.'
Aaargh!
'Should I agree to restore this
beautiful young woman to life,
'what would be my reward?'
Miss Wintertowne!
~ My Lord.
~ 'A miracle. The magician of Hanover Square
'has restored the young lady
to life and to dance.'
L'ennemi arrive! Aux armes!
Allons-y!
Well done! The hero of the blockade!
You, sir, are a hero!
You showed those Frenchies!
Is that Gilby?
Hello, there!
Gilby!
No, they cannot hear you, my Lord.
Can we see what Wellington is up to?
Good God!
Of course, the most useful
thing would be to have a
magician on the spot.
The Peninsula. Mr Norrell?
I-I am a poor traveller.
What about Nelson, for
another resurrection, sir?
Bring him back to life.
He was always the Navy's
man. Surely, Mr Pitt...
~ Lord Marlborough!
~ Sir Walter Raleigh!
~ I'd say Clive of India.
No, no, g-gentlemen, this magic
is extremely dangerous.
Consider the condition of Mr Pitt's
body and indeed, Lord Nelson's.
Ah, yes. I suppose they must have
both come a deal unravelled by now.
But I can furnish more
blockades, gentlemen...
All manner of weather spells.
.. and, and, and I-I have in
mind a line of sea beacons,
magical defences to ensure that these
islands can never be invaded again.
However...
it is my belief that we should
do all in our power,
even in a time of war, to ensure that
English magic is... respectable.
Er, indeed?
Assistance from the Government
in putting down disreputable,
old-fashioned magic,
the banishment of street magicians
and the like, would help me
wonderfully for the matter in hand.
Do the business you have
offered, Mr Norrell.
My Government will assist
you in any way you wish.
We shall be the closest
of companions, sir.
Starecross Hall, formerly the
shadow house of Miss Absalom.
I think this will suit our
purpose nicely, don't you?
In strict accordance
with our contract,
we should not be doing this at all.
I did not sign that contract.
What an awful lot of work.
Yes, but there is so much history
here to inspire the pupils.
Mr Honeyfoot.
To think this house was built
with stones from the castle
of the Raven King himself.
Up there will make a splendid
refectory for the boys.
I think there is... someone
performing... magic...
~ What in hell do you think you're doing here?
~ 'John.'
John!
Mr Segundus! Mr Segundus!
~ I said, what in hell do
you think you're doing here?
~ Jonathan!
~ You, you with the twice-turned sleeves.
Sir, I would beg you to speak to
this gentleman with more respect.
We're here to view this
house. It is for sale.
~ You were in my dream.
~ The dream, sir, was mine.
I lay down here on purpose to dream
it. I'm rather of the opinion that
in England, a gentleman's dreams
are his own private concern.
Jonathan, calm down. You'll
give yourself a nosebleed.
It cannot be the same dream.
Arabella, I no longer
have nosebleeds.
I have not had a nosebleed
since I was 17.
Of course it was the same dream.
A lady in a blue gown
with stars on it?
Miss Absalom, the enchantress?
Yes, Miss Absalom the ench...
Of course Miss Absalom
the enchantress! This was Miss
Absalom the enchantress' house!
Now, really, this is most
frustrating. I'd finally managed to
summon her, and I cannot
now remember how I did it.
How can I call myself a magician
if I cannot control the magic I do?
You summoned her, sir?
Yes, and you, you
frightened her away.
~ What?
~ But... nothing like that has
been done in England for...
300 years.
Oh, well.
I-I got the idea by reading
about Paris Ormskirk, you see.
Ormskirk's spells never worked.
Well, they never worked for anyone.
Not even Ormskirk!
Are you magicians?
We were both members of the
York Society, sir, madam.
Our brotherhood was alas
closed by Mr Norrell.
Oh, him. The patron saint
of English booksellers.
"Ah, sir, you've come too late.
"I did have a great many
magical books at one time,
"but, alas, I sold them all to
a learned man of Yorkshire."
You mean to say you have
done all this without books?
In a few months?
Well, I... I do have one book.
My wife gave it to me.
Your husband is a marvel, madam.
Oh, I know nothing of magic.
Do take an egg before
he eats them all.
So, tell me, what brings
you two to Starecross?
Mr Segundus has it in mind to
establish a school for magicians.
Oh.
Could do with a school of magic.
I-I cannot make it
do as I wish, you see.
'Tis a continuous leak, an accident.
~ Then you should apply to Mr Norrell, sir.
~ Huh.
No, no. In the Raven
King's times, sir,
his times, when there
were no books of magic,
a young fellow with a talent would
knock on the door of an older
~ magician, and ask to be apprenticed.
~ Gentlemen, you of all people should
know that Gilbert Norrell does not
look favourably on other magicians.
Not theoretical magicians,
to be sure, sir.
Have you read his periodical,
The Friends Of English Magic?
Huh, it's about the most ironical
title for anything I ever heard of.
But you are his equal, Mr Strange.
You are his equal.
Well?
"Jonathan Strange and Mr Norrell."
It sounds very well.
We shall write to him
on your behalf, sir.
Look at what one magician
has been able to accomplish.
Only consider what two might do.
'He was no more a magician than
I'm the Duchess of Devonshire.'
In every provincial newspaper,
there's two or three reports.
I read in the Bath Chronicle, there
was a man called Gibbons who
turned two housebreakers into mice.
Believe me, my Lady, there
was no magic. We examined it.
It was mice all along.
All these stories prove
false in the end.
There is no magic but Mr Norrell's.
There is no-one, my Lady.
In order to perform his
extraordinary deeds,
Mr Norrell shut himself away for
years and years, reading books!
Because I think you must
be a little lonely.
Oh, one is never lonely
when one has a book.
Agh!
(Oh, beg your pardon, sir.)
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mr Norrell.
Stephen, would you mind?
(Sorry.)
Allow me, sir.
I'm most humbly sorry, sir.
Lady Pole's servants have arrived
with her from Hampshire.
They are...
country people.
I've not had the training of them.
"Country people"?
They bring with them the
most absurd superstitions.
I do not know why.
They have it in their heads
that the house is haunted.
Bells where there are no
bells and such the like.
It is really very inconvenient to
the proper running of the household.
There.
The only thing he was able
to make disappear was claret.
~ What is it?
~ We should go dancing.
Yes, of course we should,
dear, but perhaps later.
No, I should like to dance now! Come.
I'm being asked to dance,
I cannot refuse my wife.
Um, Lord Liverpool, will
you join us, please?
Dancing, everybody.
So, slow down. I'm coming.
'Grant me half her life.
'Half a life is better than none.'
Good morning, my dear.
Good morning.
Shall I fetch your glove?
Are you well, Emma?
Yes, Sir Walter. Quite well.
Forgive me, I must be at the house. There
is a dance tonight at Lady Godesdone's?
I'm tired of dancing. I'm sick of it.
I do not wish to dance any more.
My dear.
Mr Norrell.
S-S-S-Sir Walter tells me you
have not quite been yourself.
Yes. Um....
Well, so, you see...
it began two or three
nights ago. I...
There was once a Christian
named Julius Caesar, who...
Forgive me, um... who...
who landed in England
and was met by three gentlemen,
all named John Hollyshoes.
Sir, forgive me...
Forgive me, that was
not what I meant to say.
Please, say what you wish.
~ Would you like a glass of water, my dear?
~ No, um...
The master of the castle of Pity-Me
had a magical ring that was stolen
by his daughter and eaten by a Christian
goose at St Matthew's feast.
Forgive me.
Mr Norrell... Walter...
.. please, please.
As much as it pains
me to say it, sir,
I do not believe that whatever has distressed
her ladyship is within my power to remedy.
But the doctor's found
nothing. Not even a cold.
Is it not part of the magic?
Whatever ailment her ladyship has
seems to me to be more spiritual
than physical and so belongs
to neither magic nor medicine.
What is her ailment?
I'm sorry. I can do
nothing for Lady Pole.
Magic cannot cure madness.
What do you mean by
summoning me here?
What have you done to Lady Pole?
I am bringing my lady to a ball.
A gentleman must prepare.
I summoned you because
you cheated me.
I have kept to the terms
of our agreement.
~ Half her life.
~ Yes.
But I thought she would just
live to 40 and then seem to die.
I never said so.
I have done what you asked and
now I may come and go as I please.
If you were truly concerned
for Lady Pole's happiness...
I do not care about her happiness, I
care about the success of English magic.
Her husband is my champion and
you are bringing him very low.
It is entirely mysterious to me why
you prefer the help of this person...
~ .. to mine.
~ What if he were to mistrust me?
Then I shall raise him up,
to some lofty position.
He shall be Prime Minister.
Or Emperor of Great Britain, perhaps?
No, I merely want him
to be pleased with me.
Her husband will never know.
No-one will ever know where
she is when she sleeps.
Half her life...
that was our bargain.
I wish for you to return
to your lands.
I wish for you to go there
and never come back.
And I was going there when
you summoned me so rudely
and in such ignorance
of the proper customs
and forms of magical etiquette.
I could teach you these proper forms.
I can teach you to
raise up mountains...
.. crush your enemies beneath them.
Yes, and you can shackle
English magic to your whims.
You can steal English men
and women from their homes
and you can trap them in a
world of your degenerate race.
Well, I forbid it, sir. I forbid it.
A person may call and
call in this house
and yet no-one comes.
There is to be a ball,
tonight, at Lost-Hope...
.. and look at me.
How can I meet my lady like this?
I'm sorry, sir.
Nobody told me you were here.
I must say, my own ignorant fellow
has not half your skill.
This is exactly the sort
of task I like, sir.
How splendid we look.
But I have taken you for
a servant in this house.
That is quite impossible.
As your reward, Stephen...
as my gift...
I invite you to join
us at our ball tonight.
Do you accept?
Thank you, sir.
The bargain is done.
Will you pass me my little box?
It is a token I wish my lady to wear.
I invite you to our ball, tonight.
The bargain is done.
Mr Black?
I am so troubled by this bell, sir.
It calls to mind everyone I
have ever known who's died.
Geoffrey.
I have accepted a position at
the Duchess of Devonshire's.
Are you all right, Mr Black?
I ache.
As does a man who's been
dancing all night.
Well, I wish you the
best of happiness of it.
Alfred...
it is your task at this time to lay out
the silver for Mrs Brandy to polish.
Alfred is going back
to Hampshire, sir.
To look after his uncle's chickens.
This looks like a
magician's house to me.
Do you remember my mother?
Just.
She used to bring me to
London when I was small.
An escape from Father, I suppose.
I'm sure my husband will
be kinder than hers.
He will do his best.
Come. Let's see that you're ready.
Never met a magician before.
Not a real one.
A gentlemen's magazine is an
odd place to write about magic.
Mr Murray's Friends of English Magic
is the only reputable periodical.
It's personally approved
by Mr Norrell.
~ Yes, I-I-I have read it.
~ Mr Lascelles is the editor.
Perhaps it was reading the Friends that
made you decide to become a magician?
No.
No, to own the truth, sir, I'd
not even heard of Mr Norrell.
~ I-I met a strange man under a hedge.
~ Well, this is all most entertaining
~ and strange, but the fact of the
matter is, that it really won't do.
~ Oh?
Mr Norrell is the only
magician in England, sir.
That is a fact.
It's understandable for an idle chap to want
to amuse himself in this fashionable way.
I should be very glad to see
some of Mr Strange's magic now.
~ Mr Norrell...
~ If he would favour us.
~ Mr Norrell, please.
~ Let the man do his trick, sir.
Nothing would give
me greater pleasure.
This is one of my own spells.
Oh, Mr Strange.
Oh, my dear Mr Strange,
this is remarkable.
I have never even
heard of such magic.
This is not recorded,
sir. This is not in S...
This is not in Sutton-Grove.
Is it a different colour?
Pick it up. Pick it up, pick it up.
It is backward, it...
That is the reflection.
The real one is in the mirror.
I apologise, sir, I do not
know how to bring it back.
To own the truth, I have only the
haziest notion of what I did.
Well, how did you do it, if you
did not know how you did it?
It's like music playing
at the back of one's head.
You understand what
I mean, Mr Norrell?
Hearing it for the very first
time and yet one, somehow,
simply knows what the
following note will be.
Yes. Yes, I do understand
what you mean.
I have taken the liberty
of drawing up
a plan of study for
the next ten years.
It is such a very short
time, Mr Strange.
I cannot see that we
will achieve very much.
Er...
Ten years.
There is rather more to learn
than I had supposed, sir.
The practice of magic
is full of frustrations
and disappointment, but the
study is a continual delight.
Where do you begin?
Here we are.
Ah, yes, I see.
Ah, how many centuries
is it do you think
since two English magicians
last sat down together?
I'm not so very clever on magicians.
I only really know the Raven King.
Yes, well, we must have
respectable magic, above all.
Let us make that our first task.
The magio-historian, Valentine Munday,
has many failings but he is
very strong on the Magicians of the
Golden Age, the so-called aureates.
I am sure we will get from him
the last time an English
magician took an apprentice.
I have his book here.
You wish me to read this book, sir?
Yes, indeed.
Then you must give it to me.
Yes.
And Chester's Language of Birds.
My favourite book. Here we are.
What is that? Most peculiar sound.
I think Mr Norrell is laughing.
We shall have to do something
about this "friendship".
I was wondering when we will
come to the magic of fairies?
I mean to say that,
well, for example,
Lanchester here quotes a book
by Ralph Stokesy detailing
the spells by which he found
his fairy servant, Col Tom Blue.
Well, I, I, I, I don't know that.
I do not have that book.
On the contrary, sir, you've made
a note of the shelf reference.
No, I do not have that book.
Er, um, yes... Perhaps,
perhaps I'm wrong.
Stephen! Stop them,
Stephen! Stop them.
Argh!
My lady. My lady, be calm.
~ What is it?
~ Be calm.
My dear? What might I do?
These bells. These
bells. They summon me.
~ They call me to the dance and
I must go through the mirrors.
~ Bells?
St George's. They struck seven
and it sent her to this.
~ Perhaps you have tired yourself. Stephen.
~ No!
~ Please.
~ Yes.
~ No, I must not go to sleep.
~ Come on.
No! No! No! No!
Stephen, my dear fellow.
How noble you look.
Seeing you so, I know you are
truly destined to be a king.
The nameless slave shall
be a king in a strange land.
I have... I have certainly
dreamt of you.
Lost Hope is no dream. It is
the finest of my mansions.
You are merely under an
enchantment that brings you
each night to join our revels.
We have been dancing there
for days and days and days.
Forgive me, sir.
If you were to find it in
your heart to release...
No. That is impossible,
the bargain was made.
I do not know what I've done
to deserve such kindness, sir.
I'm sure I've not done
anything at all.
Sir?
Yours are the most excellent
manners, Stephen.
Sir.
Lady Pole?
Lady Pole!
I do find it queer that he
is so against the Raven King
and the whole notion of fairies.
The Duke of Roxburghe has died.
It says here that he has a lot
of debts and a very large library.
I mean to say we are not
to touch upon it at all.
It seems to me the key to everything.
I need to find out more about that.
You need your own books, Jonathan.
There's a myth that the
Raven King wrote a book.
We ought to visit your aunt.
~ We should thank her for finding Mary for us.
~ Who?
New maid.
Do we have a new maid?
You're greatly changed by
your occupation, Jonathan.
I'm sure a month ago you would
have certainly noticed a new maid.
It's like attending
a priest's seminary
and being taught nothing about God.
In fact, being given the distinct
impression that God is wholly
irrelevant.
What do you mean I would certainly
have noticed a new maid?
Sir Walter Pole, sir.
Excuse the interruption, Mr Strange.
Madam. Er, we have a problem
with our blockade.
Three French destroyers
have slipped through.
We do not know where they are.
Er, I believe Mr Norrell has gone...
We do not have the time
to find Mr Norrell, sir.
Our boats must catch the tide.
You will do, will you not?
Um...
Come in.
~ Dratted watch must be fast.
~ Sorry?
Midday, no bells.
~ Uh, the bells in this
neighbourhood are no longer rung.
~ Why ever not?
My wife's illness has left
her nerves in a sad condition.
The tolling of a bell is
very distressing to her.
I shall not detain your husband
long, madam. Perhaps a tea?
~ Seed cake?
~ Oh, Arabella does not
care for seed cake, it is
a thing that she
particularly dislikes.
Arabella is not a
three-year-old, Jonathan. Go.
The locating of objects
is a particularly imprecise form of
magic, that I have not yet mastered.
Indeed. Well, I'm sure
you'll do your best.
Mr Norrell seems particularly
disinclined. Er, through here.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Don't think of going. It is
so rare that I see anyone.
So many mournful little boats
and buildings and skies,
they seem to lose the people.
Venice is a labyrinth.
A vast and beautiful labyrinth, to
be sure, but a labyrinth no less.
I would give anything to go there.
If you had spent eternity, as
I have done, wearily parading up
and down dark alleyways,
you would feel differently.
I'm Arabella Strange.
My husband has the, erm,
~ honour of being Mr Norrell's
assistant and pupil.
~ Norrell?
Mm. We've heard much of the
great friendship that he's
extended to you.
Norrell is no friend to me.
I would be better dead than as I am.
Looks to me as though they have
headed for the West Indies.
And there I think Captain McBrien has
gone in search of them,
if that would make sense?
I should take this to Mr Norrell.
Does he ever speak of my wife?
I...
No, sir. He is a very modest man.
He will not speak of
her to me neither.
It is a closed subject.
Tell me, does your husband perform
magic by himself or only
under Norrell's eye?
Well, if there's anything
that your Ladyship would like me
to ask Mr Strange on your behalf,
if there's any service
that he can do...
What I have to tell you is more
for your husband's sake than mine.
I fear I am lost.
Mr Strange should know what kind
of a man he is dealing with.
What was done to Lady Pole?
How was it done?
There are many books that I
am not yet permitted to read.
Is there any way in which
it may be undone?
Undone?
I fear neither of us
can bear it much longer.
I will enquire. I cannot
promise an answer, sir.
Thank you.
I should warn you, I have
made many attempts to tell
people of what has been done
and I have not yet succeeded.
In 1607, there was a silversmith
named Redshaw who lived in the
Kingdom of Halifax, West Yorkshire,
who inherited a Turkish rug.
He woke to find the carpet covered
in legions of tiny people,
about two inches high.
They rode white polecats and were
battling with knives and forks.
I'm sorry, that is not
what I meant to say.
Madam, may I implore you deeply
to say nothing of what you've
heard here today?
When anyone new comes to the house,
Lady Pole is excited to these...
outlandish speeches.
It is of great distress to
Sir Walter that anyone should
know of this private grief.
I hope they will let you
come again, Mrs Strange.
I see no-one.
Or rather I see roomfuls of people
and not a Christian amongst them.
Except for Stephen, of course.
I'm sorry, my Lady.
It's hardly your fault. Goodbye.
I do not understand why Sir
Walter would have come to you,
Mr Strange, when it was only
the matter of an hour or two.
There was some urgency
about the tides.
It really was an ill-mannered
thing, especially
since I was engaged in attempting to
establish his wretched sea beacons.
And of little use since you can
hardly have found the ships.
You did not find the ships, did you?
They wish this in an
impossibly short time.
1,000 miles of coast are surround...
Er, er, it will take years.
Do you wish me to assist you,
sir? Where do you begin?
Portsmouth, naturally.
And you're using Belasis?
I'm adding Pevensey's spells
of Ward and Watch. There.
May I ask a question?
I mean to say, Sir Walter
is primarily concerned that
I should put a bell on them.
A bell! I ask you!
I'm so sorry. What was your question?
Well, I read more and
more of the Raven King.
Is not fairy magic useful?
It's usefulness is much exaggerated
and the dangers are
much under-estimated.
~ But what are the dangers?
~ Mr Strange, please believe me
when I say that almost
all forms of respectable
magic are perfectly achievable
without the assistance of anyone.
What have I ever done that
needed the help of a fairy?
I do not know.
The question was rhetorical.
But does not all English magic
come from the Raven King?
Who was stolen away to a fairy
court and who was raised
and learnt his magic...
The Raven King rode out of
these lands 300 years ago.
Abandoning us, and
abandoning English magic.
If we cannot make his name
and the name of his fairy
servants utterly forgotten,
then it is our duty, yours and mine,
to broadcast our hatred of him.
To let it be known everywhere our
abhorrence of his corrupt nature
and his evil deeds.
Forgive me, Mr Strange, I
have a, I have a headache,
I have a terrible headache.
Yes, yes, of course.
Gentlemen.
You should read this.
~ The Duke of Roxburghe...
~ Is dead.
~ Should we, um...
~ No, no. Let us wait.
Oh, well.
Ah, there you are.
I hope you do not mind me
bringing you here, Stephen.
Oh, do not concern
yourself about him.
He can neither see nor hear us.
He attempts to summon me, but I
do not allow myself to be seen.
Look, he is just as stupid
as the other one.
The other one?
And very nearly as ugly.
What?
Bell? Bell!
~ Yes, darling?
~ Sh, sh.
Can you hear voices next door?
I could swear I heard one person
call the other stupid and ugly.
Really? I think two old
ladies live on that side.
Well, we should be going soon.
Norrell is not likely to be late.
Jonathan, do you remember the
first spell that you cast?
The spell to find out what
my enemy is doing presently?
~ That was only the name of the spell
on the little scrap of paper.
~ Sir?
Do you remember who you were
shown? Who your enemy was?
How could Mr Norrell be my enemy?
Come, dear, we must be ready
to leave for Portsmouth.
What a strikingly attractive woman.
Sir.
The Government's situation
is, I'm afraid, madam,
about as bad as it could possibly be.
The French are
everywhere, triumphant.
Our allies have discovered their
mistake and become our enemies.
Trade is ruined by the war.
The harvest has failed
for two straight years
and the King has gone mad again.
Everywhere things are going to ruin.
Apart, of course, from magic.
Magic has become a booming industry.
It is done. The sea defences
are now in place.
I cannot see anything.
You will not see anything.
They are invisible.
But they are there.
It is done.
Huzzah to Mr Norrell. Hip hip...
~ Huzzah!
~ Huzzah.
Huzzah to baffling the
French Navy! Hip, hip.
~ Excuse me.
~ Huzzah!
Well, congratulations.
You must be exhausted,
an extraordinary feat.
What about these beacons, sir?
Why did he not put a bell on them?
Will they work, do you think?
If Mr Norrell says they work, then...
You really think it
will repel the French?
I believe Strange and Sir Walter
accord very well together.
They are men of a
similar temperament.
How are you finding Portsmouth, sir?
I dislike Portsmouth intensely.
Jonathan.
Beg pardon, sir.
The Port Admiral has sent to
say that a packet ship has run
~ aground upon Horse Sand.
~ Right.
The other magician has a
headache and will not come.
~ Right, well tell the Port,
whatever he's called...
~ Admiral.
Tell him to wait, I'm coming.
Don't dozens of ships go in
and out of here every day?
~ How did this happen?
~ Presumably, the invisible beacon.
So, the boat's on her side.
Um, shall I just turn her up?
Good God, no. You'll split the
keel in two. They'll all drown.
A fresher breeze will
move her at high water.
Well, I can make a fresher
breeze. We've done that.
No, good God, what are you thinking?
It's coming sou'west, you'll
batter her on the sands.
They'll all drown.
~ What is the sand called?
~ The sand?
The thing... What the ship is standing
on, the Horse's something.
It is a shoal and it is called
Horse Sand. Excuse me.
Good.
What the hell are they?
They're called horses. I
made them out of Horse Sand.
Hot rolls and marmalade, anyone?
Morning, sir. Gentlemen.
Do you still have that newspaper?
Yes, Henry. I do.
We should send Mr Strange
to the Peninsula.
~ Norrell won't be pleased.
~ Norrell never is.
Send him to Portugal?!
I'm astonished you would
even suggest such a thing.
Every man must be prepared to
make sacrifices for his country
in time of war.
Many thousands have already done so.
Yes, but they were soldiers.
Though I dare say a soldier
is valuable in his own way.
Have you considered, sir,
the great respect it might
achieve for English magic?
But nothing is more likely
to evoke the Raven King
and all that mischievous,
reckless sort of magic than
the sight of an English
magician on a battlefield.
People will start to think
that we consort with fairies
and talk to owls and
bears and... No, sir.
No, no, no, I'm afraid not.
Mr Strange must stay
and assist me and learn.
And nothing will sway
me from this. Nothing.
They are going to sell the
Duke of Roxburghe's books.
Well, now that he is dead,
the first concern of the new
Duke will be the estate's debts.
He will be looking for something
to sell, and yes, as you know,
he does have a very fine library
with many magical volumes.
What you afraid of now?
Book sales generally the thing
most calculated to please you.
Yes, but that was before.
When no-one in England had the
least interest in books of magic
but myself. Now I fear a great
many people might try to buy them.
And he has a copy of Revelations
of 36 Different Worlds.
I've been after that for years.
But if these books are bought
by someone else, you may
complain to the Ministers.
It is not in the interest
of the nation that
books of magic should be in anyone's
possession but your own.
Oh, except Strange, of course.
Oh, I had forgot Strange.
But surely Mr Strange would
understand that it is proper
~ for the books to be mine, would he not?
~ Oh.
Mr Strange is a gentleman.
He will behave as a gentleman
and expect you to do the same.
If the books were offered
privately to you alone then
I expect you may buy them.
But if they are auctioned, he will
feel entitled to bid against you.
And how do you suppose
these books will be sold?
By private transaction or by auction?
Auction.
Mr Strange, please.
Your leaving is of
great pain to me, sir.
It is of great pain.
I hope, sir, that your change of
heart does not result from any
offence I may have given you?
Oh, no, no. Mr Strange, in the past
I've feared the appearance of another
magician, but when it happened
I was in fact delighted.
I fear I am sending you
to the war unprepared.
In which case...
I wonder if I might take
some books with me?
Books?
I fear I shall need books,
if I am to perform magic.
I should not imagine I would need
to take more than about... 40.
~ 40!
~ Yes, you couldn't carry more than 40.
Carry them about?! No! No,
they must be in a library.
No, you must put them in
a library in a castle.
It is so very dirty abroad.
They shall be little use
to him in a library, sir.
He will be in camps and on
battlefields and so must they.
~ Can we not have some sort of iron box made?
~ Saddlebags.
Thank you, Childermass.
You have done so very
much for me, sir.
I hope with all my heart
to come back safely
and to live as your friend
and assistant once again.
Give me your list.
I believe Mr Strange will do
very well in the war, sir.
He's already outmanoeuvred you.
I wish I had never come to London.
I wish I had never undertaken
to restore English magic.
I should have stayed
at Hurtfew, reading
and doing spells for my own pleasure.
None of it is worth
the loss of 40 books!
You are of no help! Why
do you make me sleep?
Why does every request
you insist that I sleep?
Why can you not control yourself?
You're of no help! Nothing
you do is of any help!
Nothing is of the least help.
You do not understand.
~ What is it?
~ Sir, I...
Stephen, why is the house
in such disorder?
~ You don't understand.
~ Sir.
~ Why have you not found new staff?
~ I, uh...
You are as dull and heavy
as the rest of them.
Lost. I am lost.
Lady Pole is to be
confined to her room.
Lost. I am lost.
Good morning.
Well, not married a year and
he runs away to join the Army.
Wars do not last for ever, Bell.
But they do tend to be dangerous.
Jonathan, when I saw Lady Pole
at Harley Street I promised her
that I should tell you something.
What is it?
She told me that a man from
Halifax bought a new rug
and he fell asleep beside the fire
and when he awoke he saw lots of
little people running about upon it.
Lady Pole is not in her wits.
She hates Mr Norrell, Jonathan.
I must go. I love you, Bell.
I love you too.
Be careful.
I shall write every day. I
will look out for you, Bell.
I would rather you
look out for yourself.
Ah, ladies and gentlemen. If
I could have your attention.
Thank you. Gentlemen.
And we'll begin with an
assortment of volumes from the
Duke of Roxburghe's library.
This is the second greatest
collection of magical books
in the land.
And this first lot, who will
start me at 200 Guineas?
200 Guineas.
Do I hear any advance on
two...? 220 Guineas, sir.
Thank you. 240. 260. 260 Guineas?
280 Guineas. Thank you. 300 Guineas.
300 Guineas. Do I hear any
advance on 300 Guineas?
And 300 Guineas.
350 Guineas, madam. Thank you.
400 Guineas. Thank
you, sir. 400 Guineas.
500 Guineas.
600. 700 Guineas. 800 Guineas, madam.
Thank you.
800 Guineas. Any advance on
800 Guineas? With the lady.
~ At 800 Guineas and...
~ Mr Norrell.
Going once, going twice, and...
Sir, sir, your books. Your books
2,000 Guineas!
2,000 Guineas.
Do I hear any advance on
2,000 Guineas? Going once.
Going twice. And sold.
Mr Norrell. Hanover Square.
No, thank you, no. Excuse me.