ANDREW MARR: Our planet
is in the middle of a mass extinction.
It's estimated that every hour
three species are lost forever.
That's 70 a day, 500 a week,
27,000 species every year,
which would make it the fastest rate
of extinction in the Earth's history.
And there's no doubt about the cause,
it's us.
150 years ago, Charles Darwin
gave us the key to understanding
the intricate connections
between all life on Earth.
Remove or damage one part
of the delicate web of life,
and you can cause catastrophic
consequences elsewhere.
But we have been reluctant
to listen and slow to act.
In this programme,
I'm going to discover how Darwin
opened our eyes to the beautiful
but fragile relationship
between all life on Earth,
how we've struggled
to understand and accept
the full implications of his legacy,
and how Darwin has given us
the knowledge we need
to help avert one of the greatest
disasters in the history of our planet.
We are causing mass extinctions,
including, perhaps, our own,
because we're not alone.
We are part of a great web of life,
and if we wreck that web, we go, too.
The answers to this challenge
aren't easy,
but they're not impossible either.
Just so long as we at last understand
the scale and the urgency
of Charles Darwin's dangerous idea.
In 1832, aged just 23,
Charles Darwin arrived here in Argentina
on board the government survey ship,
H.M.S. Beagle.
In this wild, seemingly empty landscape,
he would make one of
his most significant discoveries.
When the Beagle dropped anchor
near the small military outpost
of Bahía Blanca,
Charles Darwin was deeply unimpressed.
He wrote in his diary, "I never saw
any place before so entirely destitute
"of living creatures."
But this admittedly rather bleak beach
had a surprise in store.
It would help Darwin unlock some
of the mysteries of the natural world.
And these clues came
not from the living, but from the dead.
Strolling along
this battered cliff face,
Darwin came across
some gigantic fossilised bones.
This was a big moment for Darwin.
The next morning, he came rushing back
to see if he could find
some more fossils,
and this time he really struck lucky.
He spotted something
much more impressive
and he spent three hours digging it out.
"To my great joy," he noted,
"I found the skull of some large animal
embedded in a soft rock."
It looked to him like
some kind of giant mammal,
but he wasn't entirely sure.
"As far as I can judge," he wrote,
"it is allied to the rhinoceros."
But it was unlike
any rhinoceros living at the time.
Darwin was thrilled by the thought
that, just possibly,
the giant bones might belong
to an ancient, extinct species.
The idea of extinction was
still quite new.
Most people thought it was
the result of the great flood
sent by God to punish man,
as described in the Bible story
of Noah's Ark.
Darwin doubted this.
The evidence in the rocks suggested
that his fossil species
had not been killed
by a violent Biblical catastrophe.
They seemed to have died
during a state of tranquillity.
He was starting to think extinction
might be a regular fact of nature.
And he found new evidence
everywhere he looked.
Mingled among the fossilised bones
of extinct mammals,
he found fossilised seashells.
And yet, they were
the same species of sea creature
he could see happily living
in the water nearby.
So, why did some animals become extinct
and others survive?
Big question, and Darwin would
chew it over for years to come.
Heading out with the gauchos,
Darwin revelled in sleeping rough
and living off the land.
In a letter home, he said
that his experiences in Argentina
were giving him a most strange
assemblage of ideas.
Out on the Argentine Pampas,
Darwin came into close contact
with the local wildlife,
and he was particularly fond
of the plucky little armadillo,
which, perhaps sadly,
was often served up for dinner.
One evening, picking through
the bones on his dinner plate,
Darwin realised
that they were uncannily similar
to the giant fossilised bones
he'd been digging out of the ground.
Darwin now saw that he had
some kind of extinct armadillo
in his fossil collection.
Only, one the size of a small horse.
He also thought he had fossils
of giant llamas and sloths,
which would have stood
three metres tall.
Eureka! Darwin saw a clear link
between his ancient fossils
and the animals now living
on the Pampas.
Darwin became increasingly excited
by what he called,
"This wonderful relationship
between the dead and the living."
Why were modern species
so similar to extinct ones?
What was the connection between
the still living and the long dead?
Darwin would return
to these questions again and again.
During the rest of his five-year voyage
on the Beagle,
he saw many extraordinary things
that fuelled his curiosity
about the nature of life on Earth.
But it was his discoveries
here in Argentina
that first gave him the idea
that extinction was
a vital and necessary part
of the process of evolution.
By the time he left Argentina,
Darwin was asking all sorts of questions
about life and death
and survival and extinction.
He always said
that what he discovered in South America
was crucial to his understanding of,
what was for him,
the mystery of mysteries.
The origin of species.
There wasn't
a lot of space aboard the Beagle,
so Darwin sent his strange,
giant fossils home to England,
back to his former Cambridge tutor,
the reverend John Henslow.
"I trust they will be recognised,"
he wrote.
And they were.
Henslow was so excited
that in Darwin's absence
he arranged for them to go on show.
Towards the end of his voyage,
Darwin got a letter from his sister
saying that his fossil discoveries
were already making him famous.
Now even great minds need a bit
of great PR, and Darwin had plenty.
Henslow was already whipping up
excitement among the Cambridge dons
by reading extracts
from Darwin's letters,
and a very famous geologist
called Adam Sedgwick
went to see his father to announce
that Charles was about to take his place
among the leading scientific figures.
By the time Darwin returned
to England in October 1836,
his fossils had indeed
made him a scientific celebrity.
He rather liked the attention at first,
but burdened by his thoughts
about life, death and extinction,
he soon began to retreat
from the limelight.
He knew he had the seed
of a dangerous idea,
one that would undermine
the Bible and Christian teaching.
The accepted belief was
that species were fixed,
unchanged and unchangeable
since their creation by God.
But ever since his time abroad,
Darwin was having vague doubts
about the permanence of species,
and he began to believe that one species
does change into another,
and that species which didn't change
would become extinct.
At first, Darwin kept his most
provocative thoughts to himself,
but he couldn't quite keep
his mouth shut.
He needed help to develop his theory
and he turned to
the botanist Joseph Dalton Hooker,
who later became director
of the Royal Botanic Gardens at Kew.
Darwin was a cautious man
with a deep fear
of public humiliation and rejection,
but he felt to close Joseph Hooker,
comfortable with him,
and he began to give him
the first details of his dangerous idea.
There's a letter to Hooker,
in January 1844,
which reveals Darwin's deep dread
of the work he was engaged in.
"I am almost convinced," he wrote,
"quite contrary to the opinion
I first had,
"that species are not immutable.
"They do change."
And he confided,
"It is like confessing a murder."
Darwin suspected
his theory of evolution would upset,
even enrage, many fellow Victorians,
and it was a tough message.
He saw that, in nature,
only a tiny fraction of those born
survived to produce
offspring themselves.
He thought the natural forces
limiting the chances of survival
might also drive species to change.
Darwin saw that life
was a struggle for existence,
but that this struggle was
a fight not just between
individuals or even between species,
but with the physical
conditions of life.
The environment.
Those animals well-adapted
to their environment
would live and produce offspring
and pass on their useful adaptations
to the next generation.
Those not well-adapted would die.
Darwin believed
he'd discovered the mechanism
which drove evolutionary change.
He had, and it gave him
a profound insight,
one that would later lead us
to a deeper understanding
of our relationship
with the environment.
He saw that all life is connected
through the struggle for survival.
Relationships exist
between members of the same species,
between predator and prey,
and between the living world
and the physical environment.
Darwin wrote that all living things
are bound together
by a web of complex relations.
But Darwin was a cautious man
and he spent the next 15 years
gathering evidence
to support his theory.
Unknown to Darwin,
thousands of miles away
in the jungles of Indonesia,
an explorer and naturalist
called Alfred Russel Wallace
was soon wrestling
with exactly the same ideas.
The two men could
hardly have been more different.
Darwin was a wealthy member
of the scientific élite.
Wallace struggled to make ends meet,
often paying his way
by collecting animals
to sell to rich naturalists like Darwin.
During one of his expeditions,
Wallace was struck down with malaria.
In February 1858,
burning up with a malarial fever,
Wallace was facing his own mortality.
Stuck out in a little hut
in the middle of the jungle,
he also began to ask
why some die and some live,
and he came to the conclusion
that those animals capable of adapting
to the changing conditions
around them would survive,
while unmodified creatures
would die out and disappear.
Wallace recovered from his fever
and then he wrote a letter
to Charles Darwin.
Darwin was horrified,
shaken to the core.
"All my originality will be smashed,"
he wrote.
Wallace had arrived
at the same conclusion
that Darwin had been sitting on
for nearly 20 years.
Darwin's friends and allies urged him
to finish his book
as quickly as possible.
Faced with the threat
of being pipped to the post,
at last he found
the courage to go public.
In November 1859, Darwin finally
published his earth-shaker,
On the Origin of Species.
Darwin ensured his place
in world history
by presenting to the public
his laws of life,
what became known
as the theory of evolution
by natural selection.
And Wallace, poor guy,
became the forgotten man of evolution.
Just as Darwin feared,
his book was greeted with outrage.
The uproar rested
almost entirely on the suggestion
that man is an animal,
and that we are related to apes.
At the time, Darwin's vital insight
into the intricate connections of life
on Earth was almost entirely overlooked.
One of his most fervent supporters,
a German scientist called Ernst Haeckel,
did see behind
the immediate shock headlines.
Darwin's ideas inspired him
to define a whole new science.
He called it ecology and described it
as the study of
all those complex interrelations
referred to by Darwin as the conditions
of the struggle for existence.
For many decades to come, the science
of ecology was hardly more than a word,
but working away
in the jungles of Indonesia,
Alfred Russel Wallace
was one of the first to witness
the ecological implications
of Darwin's web of interconnections.
Wallace agreed that extinction
was a natural part of evolution,
but as the Indonesian
rainforests were felled
to make way for tea plantations,
Wallace began to see
that extinction was something
that could also be brought about
when mankind interfered
with what he called
the nicely balanced relations of nature.
Decades ahead of his time,
Alfred Russel Wallace warned
that if ever mankind
penetrated the recesses
of the virgin forest,
he would bring about the extinction
of numerous forms of life.
Humanity now had the power
to change the environment so fast
that many ancient species
would lose the struggle to survive.
Charles Darwin's awareness
of the profound
and surprising connections
that exist between species was,
to start with, pushed to one side,
but for the rest of his life,
he continued to explore
these linkages in nature.
Darwin discovered that many species
depend on each other
with far-reaching implications
for our own survival.
At the age of 72,
just a year before his death,
Darwin published his final book.
Its subject matter had captivated him
for more than 40 years,
most of them spent working here
at Down House, his home in Kent.
Darwin's last book was about worms.
He gave it a catchy little title,
The Formation of Vegetable Mould
by the Action of Worms,
With Observations on Their Habits.
Unlike Darwin's earlier work,
his worm book was
widely applauded and celebrated.
During his lifetime,
it hugely outsold The Origin of Species.
In it, he wrote that,
"The humble earthworm
"has played a more important part
in the history of the world
"than most persons would
at first suppose."
Darwin conducted endless experiments
on his garden worms,
studying their anatomy and behaviour
with fascination.
He revealed how earthworms
carry out their stupendous work
as nature's ploughmen.
He saw that worms prepare the ground,
recycle nutrients
and help the germination of seeds.
Darwin traced the impact
of the humble earthworm
and concluded
that these little wrigglers
play a vital role in our lives.
In his autobiography,
Charles Darwin wrote
that he was superior to
the common run of men in noticing things
which easily escape attention.
Even at the end of his life,
his astute observations
were giving us vital clues
about how our survival depends on
what he called
an invisible web of complex relations.
Even the loss of an organism
as apparently lowly as the earthworm
would make large parts of this planet
hostile to human survival.
Darwin's dangerous idea contained
a vital insight
into mankind's relationship
with the world around us,
and it came at an important
moment in history.
Britain was changing very fast.
The look, sounds and smells
of much of the country
were being overwhelmed
by the development of the steam engine
and the rise of the factory system.
The Industrial Revolution
was literally casting
an ominous shadow over the environment.
By the 1880s,
voices of concern were being raised,
but not by scientists.
The artist, writer
and Utopian socialist William Morris
was among the leading Victorians
to publicly question
the benefits of industrialisation.
William Morris was enraged
by the appalling living
and working conditions
being forced
on the industrial working classes.
But he also had grave concerns
about our changing relationship
with nature.
"The latest danger civilisation
is threatened with," he said,
"is a danger of her own breeding."
And in one of his famous
lectures, he said that,
"The beauty of the face of the Earth
"was disappearing beneath
a crust of unutterable grime."
Morris campaigned to preserve
the beauty of the countryside
for the enjoyment
of the working classes.
At this stage, Darwin's insights
still hadn't been used to shed light
on the wider impact
of industrialisation.
Enter an amateur moth collector
called James W. Tutt.
He was about to apply
Darwin's ideas to solve
one of the great environmental mysteries
of the industrial age.
James W. Tutt was
an enthusiastic Darwinist
who devoted his life
to the study of moths.
Devoted, enthusiastic,
more than 900 articles, mainly on moths.
Twenty books, moths again.
But he's remembered for just one thing
he noticed about one moth.
Biston betularia, or the peppered moth.
Peppered moths had
excellent pale camouflage
and were almost invisible
on pale, lichen-covered trees.
But there was
also a dark form of the moth.
This was much rarer
than the pale variety,
as it was easily spotted
and eaten by birds.
By the mid-1800s, entomologists were
puzzled by something strange.
In areas pumping out foul, sooty smoke,
the darker form of the peppered moth
had dramatically increased in number.
James Tutt noticed
that the pale peppered moth
stood out against the dark,
soot-blackened trees,
very conspicuous,
easy for birds to pick off.
But the darker version was
now very well camouflaged
and it thrived and multiplied.
Tutt suggested
that by polluting the environment,
humanity was now directly affecting
natural selection for the peppered moth.
By 1896, when Tutt published
his book, British Moths,
98% of peppered moths in the polluted
industrial north were black.
His study remains
the classic textbook example
of Darwinian selection in action.
Tutt had shown that by radically
changing the environment,
humanity had the power
to change the course of evolution.
Charles Darwin understood
that environmental change
was a significant motor
behind evolution.
"When a country undergoes
some physical change," he wrote,
"the original inhabitants must cease
to be as perfectly adapted
"to the changed conditions."
But he thought this happened slowly.
What James Tutt had witnessed
was a much faster process,
now driven by us.
(ENGINE REVVING)
By the early 20th century,
we were just beginning to grasp
the wider implications of Darwin's
understanding of the web of life.
In the 1920s,
a rebellious young zoologist
called Charles Elton was one
of the first to study the relationship
between animal populations
and the environment.
The science of ecology was
at last about to come into its own.
In 1926, Elton set out
with three colleagues and 20 mousetraps
to begin a detailed study
of the rodent population
in Bagley Woods, near Oxford.
When Charles Elton came
to check his traps
on the first morning of the study,
big disappointment.
Three mice, one vole.
But they were persistent fellows,
he and his team,
and over the next three years,
they set 70,000 such traps
and collected data on innumerable
thousands of specimens.
They called themselves
the Mouse Society.
Elton discovered
that the size of the rodent population
fluctuated with astounding regularity.
He saw how changes in the environment,
such as weather,
food availability and disease
could directly affect the size
of animal populations,
and this could have highly disruptive
impacts on the local ecology.
The rat is a public enemy.
He takes our food
and endangers our health.
ANNOUNCER: If there are
rats in your home or business premises,
please let us know.
We can help you to rout the rat.
During the Second World War,
the government turned to Elton
for his knowledge of animal populations.
Their problem was
that the huge food storage depots
essential to the war effort
were being overrun by rats and mice.
(SQUEAKING)
They were eating the equivalent
of a shipload of food every month.
Not what the ministry had planned for.
They drafted in Elton
to help control the pest problem,
and that set him thinking about
what he called ecological explosions.
(SQUEAKING)
Elton pointed out that by gathering
so much food in one place,
humans had changed
the rats' normal environment,
in this case,
causing an explosion in numbers.
This wartime experience inspired
Charles Elton to study
population explosions around the world.
He saw that human activity
could alter local environments,
often with devastating
and unpredictable effects.
He was the first to grasp the scale
of man's impact on the web of life.
Elton spelt out the consequences
of mankind's growing interference
in the natural world.
He issued
an early environmental warning cry.
"We are living in a period
in the world's history," he wrote,
"when the mingling of thousands
of kinds of organisms
"from different parts
of the world is setting up
"terrific dislocations in nature."
And our impact on the planet was
about to accelerate.
To increase food production
after the Second World War,
there was a massive expansion
in intensive, mechanised farming.
This in turn caused
an explosion of pests.
Scientists thought they'd come up
with a fail-safe, high-tech answer.
Pesticide sprays!
But in our attempts
to manipulate nature,
we were finally forced to come to terms
with the full implications
of Darwin's web of life.
In 1956, the United States'
Department of Agriculture
began spraying millions of acres
with the chemical insecticide DDT.
DDT was dropped indiscriminately
on ponds and waterways,
livestock, even on children.
There were reports that one beekeeper
lost 800 colonies of bees,
and a horse seen drinking
from its water trough
was found dead hours later.
The local wildlife was devastated.
One ecologist called it
"an amazing rain of death".
In the small town
of West Southport, in Maine,
a biologist called Rachel Carson
received a letter from a friend
telling her that all the birds
in her garden had died
soon after the sprayers had flown over.
Carson started investigating.
She discovered that the indiscriminate
spraying of pesticides
was killing not just pests,
but insects beneficial to agriculture.
And that was
just the start of the story.
We poison the caddis flies
in the stream,
and the poison travels
from link to link of the food chain,
and soon the birds
of the lake margins become its victims,
and the following springs are
silent of robin song.
Rachel Carson was ill at the time.
She was fighting breast cancer,
but she felt she had to do something
about what she saw
as an impending ecological catastrophe.
"I seem now to have, as writers should,
"a sense of urgency and passing time,"
she wrote,
"and so much to say."
In 1962, Rachel Carson published
one of the most influential books
of the 20th century, Silent Spring.
Silent Spring was
a surprise bestseller.
In it, Carson used
Darwin's theory of evolution
to explain the far-reaching effects
of spraying DDT.
Using his key insight that animals adapt
to changing environments,
she came to a chilling conclusion.
Carson dug up the fact
that the pest insects
were developing a resistance
to the insecticide,
something she described
as a triumphant vindication
of Darwin's principle
of survival of the fittest.
She pointed out that the insects
had evolved super races
immune to the particular
insecticide used,
so that a deadlier one has
always to be developed,
and then a deadlier one than that.
So this was an arms race against nature
that man could never win.
Silent Spring triggered intense debate
about the indiscriminate use
of pesticides.
Many scientists from the chemical
industry briskly rejected her findings.
The major claims in Ms Rachel Carson's
book, Silent Spring,
are gross distortions
of the actual facts.
MARR: Carson was subjected
to a sustained and personal attack.
Struggling with her own illness,
she defended her discoveries
with steely determination.
One U.S. Government
scientist accused her of
"reckless misinterpretation
of the scientific facts".
And in a sinister echo
of the McCarthy era,
a politician simply branded
her a communist.
The intensity of the attacks
on Rachel Carson
were compared directly
to the assault on Charles Darwin
when he published The Origin of Species.
The New York Times
summed up the mood with a headline,
"Silent Spring Is Now Noisy Summer."
MARR: Not everyone rejected
Carson's claims.
When asked at a press conference
about the long-term effects of DDT,
President John F. Kennedy
referred to Rachel Carson's work.
The U.S. Government
then launched a full investigation.
Silent Spring was found
to be a disturbingly accurate
and, if anything,
understated account of the situation.
Our eyes were finally opened
to the urgency of Darwin's discoveries
about the interconnections in nature.
Two years after Silent Spring
was published,
Rachel Carson died at the age of 56.
Decades on, her book is regarded
as the original battle cry
for the modern environmental movement.
COMMENTATOR: The rocket is beginning
to rise agonisingly slowly,
and here we go,
we're on our way into space.
MARR: At the dawn of the 1960s,
as we started to unlock
the secrets of the solar system,
Darwin's dangerous idea
was about to go far out.
(ON RADIO) Oh, that view is tremendous.
MARR: In the small Wiltshire village
of Bowerchalke,
a scientist called James Lovelock
was working freelance for NASA.
Studying data on the Martian atmosphere,
Lovelock was exploring the possibility
of life on the Red Planet.
The more Lovelock learned
that Mars' atmosphere was
hostile to life,
the more amazed he became about
our planet's ability to sustain life.
Working away in this cottage,
what his bosses at NASA
called his thatched lab,
Lovelock began to wonder.
How was it that the Earth's
atmosphere was able to sustain
exactly the right composition of gasses
over so many millions of years
to allow life to flourish?
His answer would propel Charles Darwin's
ideas about life on Earth
into the space age.
Darwin showed us how living organisms
are connected to their local environment
through the struggle for existence.
James Lovelock took this much further.
Describing his theory as an offshoot
of Darwin's great vision,
he believed that the vital connections
existed also on a huge scale,
right across the planet.
Ever since his school days,
Lovelock had been inspired
by Charles Darwin,
but he was now uncovering
a much deeper relationship
between life and the planet
than anything Darwin
could have imagined.
Lovelock was developing a theory
that the Earth as a whole
was behaving like a self-regulating
living organism.
He was the first to describe
a global ecosystem.
Lovelock believed
that plants and animals help regulate
the physical environment of the Earth.
He called this biological feedback,
and he suggested that the oceans,
the land, the atmosphere
and all living things form a vast,
delicately balanced system
of interconnections.
Lovelock was keen to share his ideas.
As it happened, one of his neighbours
was the author, William Golding,
who wrote Lord of the Flies.
The two men spent afternoons chatting
about space research
and science fiction.
One winter morning in 1967,
James Lovelock was walking along
on his way to the post office
when he bumped into William Golding.
And he began excitedly
to tell the novelist about his ideas
of the Earth being
a self-regulating entity.
Golding was impressed
and he told Lovelock,
"If you're going to propagate
a large idea about the Earth,
"you'd better give it a proper name."
He thought back
to the Greek goddess of the Earth
and suggested "Gaia".
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Lovelock's Gaia hypothesis
was almost too much in keeping
with the spirit of the age.
As the hippy movement
swept through Europe and America,
its followers seized his ideas
and decided that the Earth
herself was a living thing.
Along with free love and flower power,
Gaia became a gospel of the hippy age,
and it wasn't long before the world
was to see Gaia in all her glory.
ANNOUNCER 1: The engines are on.
Four, three, two, one, zero.
- We have liftoff.
- ANNOUNCER 2: The clock is running.
MARR: On Christmas eve, 1968,
the astronauts of Apollo 8
circled the moon
and saw for the first time
the Earth rising over
the lunar landscape.
They read aloud the story of creation
from Genesis,
the first book of the Bible.
WILLIAM ANDERS: "In the beginning,
God created the heaven and the earth.
"And the earth was
without form, and void:
"And darkness was upon
the face of the deep.
"And God said, 'Let there be light'.
"And God saw that it was good."
MARR: This one image
proved to be a pivotal moment
in the rise of environmentalism.
Here is everything we have.
We could now see
with beautiful simplicity
that we are all part of one world.
We are all connected.
For the first time, humankind was
able to see our whole planet.
Lonely and isolated
in the darkness of the cosmos,
the pale blue dot
that is our home looked fragile.
This image of earthrise made people
look at the world in a new way.
It emphasised the Earth's vulnerability
and it helped to create
a new kind of politics, one which
put the environment at its heart.
In the latter part of the 20th century,
Darwin's knowledge of the relationships
linking plants, animals
and the physical environment
would help us understand the impact
we as a species are having
on the whole planet.
One of the habitats where this is
becoming most obvious is the coral reef.
And the first person to write
a scientific study on coral reefs?
Charles Darwin.
Darwin was not a good swimmer,
but when he saw his first coral reefs,
he waded in to get a closer look,
and he described what he saw
as "mountains of stone",
much more impressive than the vast
dimensions of the pyramids,
and yet built by an infinite number
of minute architects.
By studying coral reefs,
Darwin would learn key lessons
about the relationship between
life and the rest of the planet.
Darwin spent nearly two years
writing up a detailed paper
about how the various types
of coral reef are formed.
He concluded that corals
only flourish in shallow water,
building amazing reef structures
by growing on top of the rocky skeletons
of previous generations.
Charles Darwin discovered
that coral reefs are intricate
and finely balanced living systems.
He recognised that sunlight,
temperature,
even the chemical composition
of the oceans
regulate the growth
of these dazzling underwater cities.
But he gave us this warning,
"Changes to the composition of the sea
"not obvious to our senses
may destroy the coral reefs."
Just sometimes, you wish he hadn't been
such a damned fine prophet.
Coral reefs all over the world are
now facing an uncertain future.
With our knowledge
of the interconnected web of life,
we not only know why it's happening,
but also that their loss could have
dire effects on our planet as a whole.
Back in the 1950s,
here in the Caribbean,
the biologist Thomas F. Goreau
was the first to understand
that corals have evolved
an astonishing partnership.
Microscopic algae growing inside corals
provide them with energy
by converting the sunlight into sugars.
In turn, the corals give the algae
somewhere safe to live.
But Goreau observed that even
small changes in the ocean environment
cause the corals to expel
their algae helpers.
The coral then loses its colour
and begins a slow death,
a process called coral bleaching.
Thomas Goreau Jr continued
and expanded his father's work,
and he made an ominous discovery.
Fluctuations in ocean temperature
were causing coral bleaching
all over the world.
Throughout the 1980s and the 1990s,
mass coral bleaching was occurring
everywhere where the ocean
temperature had been raised
for a considerable period.
Goreau's work showed
that the coral reefs
were the global warning system
for global warming.
We're all too aware that global warming
is being caused by the accumulation
of greenhouse gases
like carbon dioxide in the atmosphere.
For millions of years,
coral reefs have played a vital role
in countering this effect,
absorbing carbon dioxide from the ocean
and locking it away
in their rocky skeletons.
Thomas Goreau Jr showed
that Darwin's prophecy
about the vulnerability of corals
to environmental change
is now established fact,
and their function as a regulator
of the Earth's surface temperature
is also being compromised.
Of all the world's living systems,
coral reefs are
among the most sensitive,
and if the planet's temperatures
carry on rising,
they will be the first of the global
habitats to die out completely.
Now, if the planet cools,
they can regenerate,
but at the moment,
they're being simply overwhelmed.
And this is more than a pity,
because if we lose the corals,
we also lose their ability
to absorb and lock away carbon dioxide,
and we lose it forever.
In the 150 years
since Darwin shared his dangerous idea,
scientists have made great progress
in grasping its wider implications
for life, death and extinction.
But while we've been struggling
to comprehend his insight,
our impact on the planet
has hugely increased.
In the tropical rainforests,
mankind's assault on nature
is having a catastrophic effect.
Rainforests cover just 6%
of our planet's surface,
but they're home to at least half
of all the species living on Earth.
There's the lush canopy above,
the shadowy forest floor below
and the dense, multilayered structure
of astounding complexity in between.
When Charles Darwin first saw
a tropical rainforest, he was overcome.
He spoke afterwards of feelings
of wonder, astonishment and devotion.
Sounds almost as if he was having
a spiritual experience.
In time, his own work
on the interconnectedness of nature
would help unlock the secrets
of these extraordinary places.
They really are
the boiling cauldrons of evolution.
For more than 100 million years,
rainforests have survived
geological upheavals
and severe climate change.
And throughout this time,
they've been home
to the fastest rate
of evolution on Earth.
But now rainforest plants
and animals face extinction.
In 1971, a Berkeley University
biology student called Norman Myers
was studying
the impact of human activity
on the rate of animal extinction.
The textbooks told him that
the estimated global rate of extinction
was around one species per year.
This was the level that Darwin
saw as a normal part
of the evolutionary process.
No cause for alarm.
Lounging around outside one morning,
Norman Myers was going through
the statistics on extinctions,
and he noticed a ludicrous omission.
The extinction figures gave the rates
for mammals, plants and birds,
which you might have thought
was a pretty comprehensive group,
but together they comprise
just 4% of all known species.
The rest are insects
and other invertebrates.
The vast majority of species
on the planet,
and their fate had been forgotten.
Myers investigated further.
He spent the rest of the day
rechecking the official estimates
of the extinction rate.
And then he made a new calculation,
this time including invertebrates.
Myers' research tools, he said,
"were a pencil,
a pocket calculator and curiosity".
But in the right hands,
a pencil can be devastating.
Myers' calculations showed
that species weren't becoming extinct
at the rate of roughly one a year,
but more like the rate of one every day.
The Earth was going through
something terrible.
Darwin proposed that there's
a fine balance between extinction
and the birth of new species.
But on five occasions
in the Earth's history,
the fossil record suggests the rate
of extinction increased so much,
it threatened the future
of life on Earth.
We call these catastrophic episodes
mass extinctions.
There are many theories about
what caused them, from global cooling,
incredible volcanic activity,
cataclysmic meteor strikes.
But whatever the reason,
each event resulted
in the extinction of between 65 and 95%
of all living species on Earth.
Myers was now suggesting
that we are in the middle
of the sixth mass extinction,
and this one is being caused by us.
Norman Myers estimated
that this new mass extinction
was the fastest loss of species
ever seen on the planet,
and the greatest number of casualties
was from tropical rainforests.
The rainforests were filled
with an abundance
of especially well-adapted species.
Myers knew from Darwin
that if the forests were destroyed,
these species would
then be poorly adapted
to their changed environment
and they'd face rapid extinction.
(CHAINSAW WHIRRING)
By the mid-1970s, nearly half
of the world's virgin rainforests
had already been destroyed.
Much of this was caused
by clearing forests
to raise cattle
for the fast-food industry.
What Myers called
the hamburger connection.
And the yearly rate of destruction
was increasing.
Darwin's legacy was
helping us to understand
the consequences of our actions,
but it was also giving the tools
to help save the planet
from the full impact
of this man-made mass extinction.
In 1988,
Norman Myers came up with a plan.
Myers discovered that there are
some areas around the world
that contain super-high concentrations
of animal and plant species,
and he worked out
that if we could preserve those places,
we had a chance of saving up to a third
of the 10 million or so species
now alive on Earth.
In effect, he was proposing a little
fleet of Darwinian Noah's Arks.
Myers called these areas
biodiversity hotspots.
He identified 25 of them
around the world,
including here,
across the islands of the Caribbean.
His hotspots conservation strategy
has attracted nearly
a billion dollars in funding,
but it will be many years
before we can judge its success.
This visionary, optimistic experiment
is based absolutely
on Darwin's original work
on the interconnectedness of all life.
If we remove the rainforests,
we also lose their extraordinary,
supercharged ability
to produce new species.
One scientist put it like this,
"Death is one thing.
The end of birth is something else."
Over the last 150 years,
the implications of Charles Darwin's
dangerous idea have slowly
but decisively transformed
our understanding of the living world.
His theory of evolution
first caused outrage
by challenging the belief in God.
His description
of the survival of the fittest
was then hijacked to attack
democratic ideals of equality.
But his ideas also highlighted
the connection and interdependence
between all living things
and the Earth's environment.
This vital part of his legacy
has been the most difficult
for us to accept and understand,
and now it is a matter
of life and death.
It's taken 150 years for us to catch up
with the full significance
of Darwin's theory of evolution
by natural selection.
If we want to prolong our own existence,
we have to preserve the environment,
the natural world inside which we live.
And it's that, not equality
or the existence or not of God,
that is the most urgent message
from Darwin's essential idea.
We have to change
our behaviour as a species.
If we don't, we now know what follows.