Peter.
You could not watch even one hour with me?
Master, what has happened to you?
Should I call the others, Lord?
No, John. I don't want them to see me like this.
Are you in danger? Should we flee, Master?
Stay here. Watch...
pray.
What is wrong with him?
He seems afraid.
He had spoken about danger while we ate...
He mentioned betrayal and...
Thirty.
Thirty, Judas.
That was the agreement between me... and you?
Yes.
Where?
Where is he?
Hear me, Father.
Rise up, defend me.
Save me from the traps they set for me.
Do you really believe...
that one man can bear...
the full burden of sin?
Shelter me, O Lord.
I trust in You.
In You I take refuge.
No one man can carry this burden...
I tell you.
It is far too heavy.
Saving their souls is too costly.
No one. Ever.
No.
Never.
Father, you can do all things.
If it is possible, let this chalice pass from me...
But let Your will be done...
not mine.
Who is your father?
Who are you?
Who are you looking for?
We're looking for Jesus of Nazareth.
I am he.
Hail, Rabbi!
Judas...
you betray the Son of Man with a kiss?
Peter!
Put it down!
Those who live by the sword shall die by the sword.
Put it down.
Malchus! Get up!
We've got him. Let's go!
What, Mary? What is it?
Listen...
"Why is this night different from every other night?"
"Because once we were slaves...
and we are slaves no longer..."
They've seized him!
Everyone you can, hear? To the courtyard of the High Priest.
Quick! Go!
Halt! Not so fast.
This is not your party, you toothless vermin.
Peter...
Hey! What's going on here?
In there! Stop them!
They've arrested him!
In secret! In the night!
To hide their crime from you!
Stop them!
What are you yelling about, woman?
Who have they arrested?
Jesus.
Jesus of Nazareth!
Shut up!
She's crazy.
A criminal. Brought in for questioning, that's all.
Broke the temple laws.
I see.
Better go tell him there's more trouble brewing.
Tell who?
Abenader, you idiot.
Get going!
Go!
Jesus...
Are you hungry?
Yes, I am.
This is certainly a tall table!
Who is it for?
A rich man.
Does he like to eat standing up?
No. He prefers to eat like... so.
Tall table, tall chairs!
Well, I haven't made them yet.
This will never catch on!
Oh, no you don't!
Take off that dirty apron before you come in.
And wash your hands.
It has begun, Lord.
So be it.
Sir, there's trouble at...
What, in the middle of the night, Abenader?
I'm sorry.
What's the problem?
Trouble within the walls.
Caiphas had some prophet arrested.
Who?
Some Galilean.
The Pharisees apparently hate the man.
A Galilean? Who are you talking about?
Who is this beggar you bring to us...
chained up like a condemned man?
He's Jesus, the Nazarene troublemaker.
You're Jesus of Nazareth?
They say you're a king.
Where is this kingdom of yours?
What line of kings do you descend from?
Speak up!
You're just the son of some obscure carpenter, no?
Some say you're Elijah.
But he was carried off to heaven in a chariot!
Why don't you say something?
You've been brought here as a blasphemer!
What do you say to that?
Defend yourself.
I have spoken openly to everyone.
I've taught...
in the temple where we all gather.
Ask those who have heard what I have to say.
Is that how you address the high priest?
With arrogance?
If I have spoken evil...
tell me what evil I have said.
But if not, why do you hit me?
Yes, we'll listen to those who heard your blasphemies.
Good!
Let's hear them.
He cures the sick by magic!
With the help of devils!
I've seen it.
He casts out devils, with the help of devils.
He calls himself the king of the Jews!
No, he calls himself the son of God!
He said he would destroy the temple...
and rebuild it in three days!
Worse!
He claims he's the bread of life!
And if we don't eat his flesh or drink his blood...
we won't inherit eternal life.
Silence!
You're all under this man's spell.
Either offer proof of his wrongdoing...
or be quiet!
This entire proceeding is an outrage.
All I've heard from these witnesses is mindless contradiction!
Who called this meeting anyway?
And at this hour of the night?
Where are the other members of the council?
Get him out of here!
Get out!
A travesty! That's what this is, a beastly travesty!
Haven't you anything to say?
No answer to these accusations?
I ask you now...
Jesus of Nazareth...
Tell us, are you the Messiah?
The son of the living God?
I AM...
and you will see the Son of Man seated at the right hand of power...
and coming on the clouds of heaven.
Blasphemy!
You heard him.
There's no need for witnesses!
Your verdict. What is your verdict?
Death!
Haven't I seen you in the company of the Galilean?
Yes! You're one of his disciples!
I recognize you!
Quiet! I've never met the man. I don't know him.
You are Peter! One of the disciples of Jesus.
I don't know the man! You are wrong!
Stop! Stop!
I've seen you before!
Stop him! He's one of them!
You're wrong, damn you!
I swear I don't know the man.
I've never seen him before.
Wherever you go, Lord...
I will follow.
To prison, even to death.
Amen, I say to you...
before the cock crows...
three times you will deny me.
Peter?
No, no... I am unworthy!
I have denied him, Mother!
Denied him three times.
Let's go! You take care of it.
Let him pass. He's harmless.
Release him!
Take back the silver.
Here!
I've sinned, betrayed innocent blood.
Take back your silver. I don't want it!
If you think you've betrayed innocent blood, that's your affair.
Take your money and go.
Now go!
What's wrong? Are you all right?
Look at his mouth. Hey, can we look at it?
You need help? Can we help?
He's bleeding! Look! Blood!
Leave me alone...
you little satans!
Aha! Cursing! Are you cursed?
He's cursed!
Yes, a curse! It's inside him, look!
Watch out, it's like burning oil from his bones!
Get away from me! Leave me alone!
Don't condemn this Galilean.
He's holy.
You will only bring trouble on yourself.
Do you want to know my idea of trouble, Claudia?
This stinking outpost, that filthy rabble out there.
Do you always punish your prisoners before they're judged?
Governor...
What accusations do you bring against this man?
Well...
If he weren't a malefactor, we wouldn't have brought him before you.
That's not what I asked.
Why don't you judge him according to your own laws?
Consul, you know it's unlawful for us...
to condemn any man to death.
To death?
What has this man done to merit such a penalty?
He has violated our Sabbath, Consul.
Go on...
He has seduced the people...
taught foul, disgusting doctrines.
Isn't he the prophet you welcomed into Jerusalem only five days ago?
And now you want him dead?
Can any of you explain this madness to me?
Your Excellency, please...
So far the high priest hasn't told you this man's greatest crime.
He has become the leader of a large and dangerous sect...
who hail him as the Son of David!
He claims that he is the Messiah...
the king promised to the Jews.
He has forbidden his followers to pay tribute to the emperor, Consul!
Bring him here!
Go!
Drink.
Are you the king of the Jews?
Does this question come from you?
Or do you ask me this because others have told you that is what I am?
Why would I ask you that?
Am I a Jew?
Your high priests, your own people delivered you up to me.
They want me to have you executed.
Why? What have you done?
Are you a king?
My kingdom is not of this world.
If it were...
do you think my followers would have let them hand me over?
Then you are a king?
That is why I was born.
To give testimony to the truth.
All men who hear the truth hear my voice.
Truth!
What is truth?
I have questioned this prisoner, and I find no cause in him.
This man is a Galilean, is he not?
He is.
Then he is King Herod's subject.
Let Herod judge him.
Governor...
Hand him over.
Jesus of Nazareth!
Where?
Where is he?
This...
is Jesus of Nazareth?
Is it true that you restore sight to the blind?
Raise men from the dead?
Where do you get your power?
Are you the one whose birth was foretold?
Answer me!
Are you a king?
How about me?
Will you work a little miracle for me?
Take this stupid fool out of my sight.
He's not guilty of a crime, he's just crazy.
Give him a fool's homage...
What is truth, Claudia?
Do you hear it, recognize it when it is spoken?
Yes, I do.
Don't you?
How?
Can you tell me?
If you will not hear the truth, no one can tell you.
Truth...
Do you want to know what my truth is, Claudia?
I've been putting down rebellions in this rotten outpost for eleven years.
If I don't condemn this man...
I know Caiphas will start a rebellion.
If I do condemn him, then his followers may.
Either way, there will be bloodshed.
Caesar has warned me, Claudia. Warned me twice.
He swore that the next time the blood would be mine.
That is my truth!
Herod refuses to condemn the man. They're bringing him back here.
We're going to need reinforcements.
I don't want to cause an uprising.
There is already an uprising.
King Herod found no cause in this man.
Neither do I.
Men! Attend to the crowd!
Quiet!
Have you no respect for our Roman procurator?
As you know, every year I release a criminal back to you.
We are now holding a notorious murderer...
Barabbas.
Which of the two men would you have me release to you?
The murderer Barabbas?
Or Jesus, called the Messiah?
He is not the Messiah! He is an imposter! A blasphemer!
Free Barabbas!
Again I ask you: Which of these two men should I release to you?
Free him.
What would you have me do with Jesus the Nazarene?
Have him crucified!
No!
I will chastise him...
but then I will set him free.
See to it that the punishment is severe, Abenader.
But don't let them kill the man.
My heart is ready, Father...
my heart is ready.
My son...
when, where, how...
will you choose to be delivered of this?
If the world hates you...
remember that it has hated me first.
Remember also that no servant is greater than his master.
If they persecuted me, they will persecute you.
You must not be afraid.
The Helper will come...
who reveals the truth about God...
and who comes from the Father.
Stop!
Enough! Your orders were to punish this man...
not to scourge him to death!
Take him away.
Get going!
Get him out of here!
Your majesty...
Take care of it.
A beautiful rose bush.
Look at him... king of the worms!
Hail, wormy king!
A color fit for a king!
We're here to pay our respects.
A leader for our brotherhood!
Behold the man.
Crucify him!
Isn't this enough? Look at him!
Shall I crucify your king?
We have no king but Caesar!
Speak to me.
I have the power to crucify you, or else to set you free.
You have no power over me...
except what is given you from above.
Therefore, it is he who delivered me to you...
who has the greater sin.
If you free him, Governor...
you are no friend of Caesar's.
You must crucify him!
It is you who want to crucify him, not I. Look you to it.
I am innocent of this man's blood.
Abenader...
Do as they wish.
I am your servant, Father.
Your servant, and the son of Your handmaid.
Why do you embrace your cross, fool?
All right, your highness, let's move!
Help me get near him.
This way.
This way, Mother.
Mother...
I'm here...
See, mother, I make all things new.
Who is that?
Who?
She's the Galilean's mother.
Let's go.
Come on!
Don't fret, my daughter.
Don't fret.
Are you blind?
Can't you see, he can't go on?
Help him!
You!
Yes, you! Get over here!
What do you want from me?
This criminal can't carry his cross by himself anymore.
You will help him! Now get going!
I can't do that. It's none of my business. Get someone else!
Help him! He is a holy man.
Do as I tell you. Now move! Let's go!
All right, but remember...
I'm an innocent man, forced to carry the cross of a condemned man.
Stay here. Wait for me.
Permit me, my Lord.
Who do you think you are?
Get away from here.
Impossible people!
Someone stop this!
Stop! Stop!
Leave him alone!
If you don't stop, I won't carry that cross one more step.
I don't care what you do to me!
All right, all right, let's get moving.
We don't have all day. Let's go!
Let's go...
Jew!
Almost there.
We're nearly there.
Almost done.
You have heard it said...
you shall love your neighbor and hate your enemy.
But I say to you...
love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you...
For if you love only those who love you...
what reward is there in that?
I am the good shepherd.
I lay down my life for my sheep.
No one takes my life from me...
but I lay it down of my own accord.
I have power to lay it down...
and power to take it up again.
This command is from my Father.
Get away now, you're free to go. Go on! Go on!
You can get up now!
Get up, your majesty.
Can't you get up?
We haven't got all day.
Come on, move! We're ready.
Get up, your highness.
You are my friends.
There is no greater love than for a man to lay down his life for his friends.
I cannot be with you much longer, my friends.
You cannot go where I am going.
My commandment to you after I am gone is this...
Love one another.
As I have loved you...
so love one another.
You believe in me.
You know that I am the Way...
the Truth, and the Life.
And no one comes to the Father but by me.
Further out...
Idiots! Let me show you how to do it.
Like this!
There! No, get in there. Hold the hand open like this.
Father, forgive them...
Father...
Father my Father... my God...
They don't know... they don't know...
Stupid mongrels!
Turn the wood over on its face, idiots!
Take this and eat.
This is my body which is given up for you.
Take this and drink.
This is my blood of the new covenant...
which is given for you and for many, for the forgiveness of sins.
Do this in memory of me.
If you are the son of God, why don't you save yourself?
Prove to us...
you are who you say you are.
You said you could destroy the temple...
and rebuild it in three days...
and yet you cannot come down from that cross.
If he is the Messiah...
I say let him come down from the cross...
so that we may see and believe.
Father, forgive them...
they know not what they do.
Listen...
he prays for you.
We deserve this, Gesmas...
but he does not.
I have sinned...
and my punishment is just.
You would be justified in condemning me.
I ask only that you remember me, Lord...
when you enter your kingdom.
Amen, I tell you...
on this day you shall be with me...
in paradise.
I thirst.
Flesh of my flesh...
heart of my heart...
My son, let me die with you.
Woman...
behold your son.
Son, behold...
your mother.
There is no one left.
No one, Jesus!
My God...
why have you forsaken me?
It is accomplished.
Father, into your hands...
I commend... my spirit.
Cassius! Hurry!
He's dead!
Make sure!