King Leopold's Ghost
"This wonderful African cake"
Diary, 1875
"Stanley shoots negroes as if they were monkeys"
Author "King Leopold's Ghost"
Letter to Col. Strauch, 1881
"Ivory", they sighed, and it sounded like a prayer.
Letter to H.M.Stanley, 1881
Former colonial official, Congo
Letter to the US - President, 1883
Letter from Leopold's advisor,
undated
"The independent states of Congo"
Senate enactment
Philantropist King Leopold
to protect
Humanitarian objectives
Benevolent venture
Kanaan for modern Israelites
Free state founded
Leopold fights slave trade
Speech to NY Chamber of Commerce, 1879
Former policeman, Congo
Former Senator, DRC
"Crimes against humanity"
Open letter to Leopold II, 1890
Open letter to the US - President, 1890
Open letter to the US - Secretary Of State, 1890
"Beasts of burden with thin monkey - legs"
Letter to the Belgian Prime Minister, 1890
Newspaper interview, 1906
Author "Assassination of Lumumba"
Letter to the governor-general of Congo, 1890
Reverend mother's letter to colonial offical, 1895
"The most abominable prey of human history"
Unknown missionary
Eldest of village Luebo
Diary, 1892
Wire to British State Department, 1899
Diary, 1895
Diary, 1899
"The horror, the horror"
Writer
"A secret society of murderers"
Printer for W. Sheppard
"Shameful, shameful, a despicable system"
Report #32 to British State Dept., 1903
Ilanga from village Waniendo
Journalised by Edgar Canisius, 1899
Germans whipping women in Cameroon
England's wicked war in South Africa
French aggression in Africa
Report #32 to British State Dept., 1903
"A cry for justice and mercy sounds from Congo"
Never to be published for research
Letter to advisors
"This wonderful African cake"
Former colonial offical, Congo
Former minister, DRC
"A secret society of murderers"
We must fight,
even make a deal with the devil,
for the unity of Congo.
Congo is indivisible!
Development expert
Former vice president, DRC