“The King Loves” is the story about
Prince Wang Won, attractive woman Eun San and prince Wang Won’s only friend, Wang Rin.
The drama traces the turbulent love triangle and the romance.
I played “Wang Won” in this drama. To introduce more,
he’s the crown prince during the Goryeo Dynasty.
It’s about King Chungseon’s story before he ruled the country.
He is a profound character, and has both good and evil w
I played the unpredictable character Eun San who is a daughter of the wealthiest merchant in the Goryeo Dynasty.
She is loved by Wang Won and Wang Rin.
What did you think of me?
For me, at first,
we just ran into each other a few times.
But we didn’t have a chance to work together or to talk.
Before getting to know him,
he looked very handsome and acted well.
So I was curious how he was in person.
When meeting him,
he is much more masculine than I thought and he is still professional.
Kind
I’m about to say that.
He is kind and very very
Delicate
He is delicate, and took care of me a lot.
He was helpful during the filming and I learned a lot from him,
so he was a wonderful male partner for me.
Thanks. I didn’t know you thought of me like that.
Before filming the drama, she debuted in Girls’ Generation before me.
And she was working actively when I was a trainee.
Her popularity and power of influence were amazing from the beginning.
Of course, her charms are great.
When I heard she would be my partner in the drama,
[when hearing],
I felt blessed to have the honor of working with such a celebrity.
Thanks a lot.