-We draw?
-Yes.
Wait a minute. Mama!
Close the window!
Basically I was a long skinny guy
Stop. I have something wrong here.
We give you a break.
When I first saw a professional game
It was a heavyweight match.
I first heard
as a human fist inside the glove strikes the head of a human being.
The sound of the beat I do not like
then I thought: Wow that's brutal!
When I had my first match, I was very nervous
I was afraid to fight, my legs were quite weak
felt that the audience is there a danger
and felt a lot of fear, but also that you have to survive
The difference between looking outside the ring and inside the ring is huge
Klitschko
Our opponents know our secret weapon
Only one of us is in the ring, but the opponent has to fight against us both.
The pair are much stronger.
One other psychological power supply
and nobody can stop it.
Vitali is fighting in the heart,
born as a warrior
I did it had to happen.
As a boxer, but as you sekundant gets too much adrenaline
And as we enter the tunnel
has absolutely do not think about anything,
just what you expect and strategy.
As will be hit on the right and left.
has long range arms
you have to cover or retreat to the side
you have to catch up fast to cover a series of
but as you walk into a half away from you
you do a series of short strokes
lose balance and you have won
Zameriavaj ?drery the hull, no punches below the belt
the tail and no blows to the kidneys
If you send your opponent to the ground and throw on the side
accompanied him one more blow
you earned two points
If contact occurs without a fight I'll give you a sign STOP
Protect yourself time and was down by two steps back
The risk is enormous box
Every blow they could break the nose
You can lose an eye or even your life
However, if the athlete is afraid of injury or loss of health
If the athlete is not willing to give maximum
then can never be successful.
It is always terribly afraid when my kids boxes
but it is their life and have my blessing, but when boxes
Always I walk alone and I have cell phone with you
and waiting when it rings.
It brings you into madness
Vladimir will permanently leave the balance
Vladimir has a much stronger punch
no offense but Vitaliy Vladimir strike is really powerful.
All success starts outside the ring
You can sleep with empty stomach?
You can live without sex with your girlfriend?
We motivate each day enough?
Do you suffer from muscle?
Your nose is broken? A what?
You have to continue because this is a real ?ampi?nstvo!
Box sorts men from boys
It's really a male sport
Box is fair, if you are in the form turns out to
unless you are also to be seen.
If you're afraid to show it.
Box will be punished for your sins.
If you eat the cake and then enter the ring
show it!
Mama! I'm okay
I'm fine.
Not anything like
Gash under the eye
Otherwise all good.
Avola from me and say everything is fine.
Then call again. And I said to him:
Vladimir did not forget anything for you?
I forgot to tell you that I love.
One day I was standing at the airport with Vital
away from us stood the father and son
When the boy saw Vitali asked:
It really is Vitali Klitschko?
Can I touch it?
For a child it was something special touch Vitali.
In the eyes of the boy was a lot of joy.
My son quickly won the hearts of people.
Vladimir and Vitali have a really unusual situation in their family
Their parents have two sons, who are champions in heavyweight.
It is unusual that their parents never attempt to watch the games their children,
On the other hand, family is very closed
and you have to understand how growing up that you all understand
I never heard them talk about no one else
and it seems that there are only Vladimir and Vitali their parents.
I was born in Central Asia in 1971.
I Ukrainec, my father was in the military
As long as I lived with my parents
We traveled, almost across the Soviet Union
Then I worked. Vitaliy was 6 and Wowczik
what was pet name for Vladimir had one year
Vitali took care of his little brother
and I have flexible working hours
I went home and cooked for my young sons and then went back to work.
It was for me a huge responsibility
I had to take his brother wherever I go
and still take care of his little brother.
If I try to give him some advice today
It was not like him so much.
But he still remembered that when we were children,
parents gave me the responsibility to take care of him,
and still to this day I bear the responsibility.
I know that many people can not recognize Vladimir and Vitali
Many people think they are twins.
In fact, however, very different.
If Vitali is a goal
is behind
Vladimir also has its objectives
But goes beyond them carefully and diplomatickej?ie.
My father always traveled
from city to city
so I also constantly changing schools.
Vitali was always provoked by the school
So I taught him to defend himself.
And I said to him:
If you fight you win
no matter at what price.
We never foresaw,
that our sons to become a professional boxer.
One day a mother came with her son to us home
her son bleeding from the nose because he had broken
I told Vitaliy:
You need to apologize.
Vitali, however, said no.
I asked him: Why not?
He replied that it was just
because he threw the hat in a puddle,
I warned him but he threw me there again.
So I hit him.
My father was then in the army based in Kiev.
We came here from Prague, former Czechoslovakia
The father said that there is indeed only a few weeks
But these few weeks became two years.
In this small room to live five people.
Grandmother, mother, father, brother and I
and sometimes even a grandfather.
There was, however, the kitchen
directly, there was a wall once, but it's gone.
So there was a kitchen.
No shower, no toilet.
Toilet is outside.
And right there on the floor ...
Vitali shouted at me:
Come Vladimir Put the gloves and we box.
I was only 10 or 11 years and he wanted to box.
I stood right here, I remember it like yesterday
Vitali was standing right in front of me and udral me in the face.
I did not like it, I feared box.
Often I would take the children with me to the shooting
I showed them how to handle a weapon,
as well as charge and hit something.
Vitali as a kid always got himself
so little to the problems and
experimented a lot.
Once the shooting found some ammo and grenades
So we threw them into the fire
that erupted.
It was fun: D
And once we found anti-tank mine
She looked like a plate,
I took it home and
jedniné place where I could hide
was under his father's bed
Then I went to sleep.
Suddenly I hear the father screaming, then came into my room
He asked: What is it?
"Mine" I say.
You took it home?
-Yes.
We had very strict parents
We often carried away with the belt.
Colonel!
Report the arrival of troops to secure the Chernobyl disaster ...
First they said that was something very wrong
Therefore, our base was Alarmed
Then I was commander of the air units,
immediately took us to the place where it became a disaster.
Immediately after the explosion sent the workers there
with bare hands had odprat?va? radioactive waste.
You should go! Go away!
We used helicopters for stopping reactors
until I have been completely covered
Helicopters flew day and night away
only 100 meters as the crow flies from the window
But the point came
when we just got used to it.
The government hides the truth from the beginning
and wanted to downplay the situation.
We were told that the situation is under control.
Vehicles and helicopters had to be washed
There were a lot of water, naturally radioactive
and there I played with paper boats.
It was a great tragedy
Especially children are transported away
We sent to the camp of Vladimir Azov Sea
Who had the opportunity to leave, he went
But as a soldier must fulfill orders.
Many of my friends has absorbed a lethal dose of radiation
and died.
His father spent much time in Chernobyl
and eventually became a victim of Chernobyl
Doctors said that is the result of Chernobyl ...
Cancer.
In Germany, the father got very good medical care.
Today he is doing given the circumstances quite well.
This is our gallery, here are all the photos
Our guest was also Chuck Norris.
Combat sports have long been banned in our country
even punished
as well as watching those films.
But as you know forbidden fruit tastes najle?ie
Boys and girls were fascinated Read these sports
People trained in karate every yard
Parents for us strive kimono of bed linen
We screamed like crazy and also tried rozb?ja? board.
We wanted to imitate everything.
In the rooms of my sons were posters Schwarzenegger, Chuck Norris
and all the stars of the Western world.
All these stars were in perfect form
and my sons wanted to be just like them.
The whole room had obve?an? posters and photos
Once when I was one of the illegal training
some teenagers came
when I show them some basics
one of them was completely uncoordinated
When I told him to rob the right made it to the left
always did the opposite as I said.
That's how I met Vitali Klitschko.
In 1989, the prohibition of the operation was canceled Kickboxing
He became a champion in Kickboxing in Ukraine
then master of the Soviet Union
Then he went to America at the invitation of tender.
When I was growing up we were scrubbed brains
every morning at school we had to write
what is bad for America
Taught us: America is our enemy,
America means capitalism
They said that there are some people use others as slaves
Fed us from the nursery
Going to America was for me to go to the moon
I had heard a lot about Coca Cole
When I first tasted
I thought that I could drink it all K?bel.
I was absolutely thrilled
that we could run all day to shop.
We looked left, right with mouth open
Of course I had no money
so we have targeted only the smell and touch things.
I thought, why is whom 100 kinds of cheese?
That's incredible
We are only one kind of cheese: Cheese
They are 100 species that I could not understand.
Also, many pairs of shoes.
In our country, I needed a few
be two - one for sport
When I returned home I asked the father
who was a Communist
What are the things that you hear every day?
America is a beautiful country with friendly people
I remember his reply:
Not only do you want to show the good side
this is america is evil propaganda.
My parents like to go to Florida in the winter
because it is winter in Ukraine.
I understand what you went through my father in my life
but now can see America with different eyes
so now go to Florida Due to leave.
And I like him not only weather but also the people and country.
Look at her father, a soldier who believes in discipline
senior military officer
That nothing would be achieved without discipline.
Vladimir and Vitali are very proud of him
These two brothers are not long-haired guys
with piercings and earrings and such things.
Someone should be able to present them as soldiers or policemen
or as chairperson of a company.
This fact has been conducted.
Vitali came from kickboxing.
He was perfectly trained body but only 90 pounds
I knew immediately that it would be difficult to be switched to boxing.
Ran around the stadium and finished
if it nepichalo in the side.
Vitali is not so fast!
So add.
Today, for the laughs and says that I tortured him.
and I think it was true, I tortured him.
But the result is not really good.
Wadim, my coach gave me a lot of power when it was really hard
I remember that I wanted to quit
because I have non-government, I had no strength
I thought, I do not want to train, I'm sick of it
My body is nezvl?dalo
Mind telling me: you do not need to do these things
but still I trained
and it was not easy.
One day he came Vitali
and can not say whether his brother come?
I say: Sure no problem.
Since then, always went together
How can you compare Vitali and Vladimir?
Vitali is like a stone
Vladimir is like clay.
With Vitali it takes some time to learn if
but it takes time until the stone breaks
Vladimir was easier to train but also easier to break.
They are two different boxers
I had to treat them and train differently.
I met them at a disco in 1993
the American Club in the city center
arrived there on the ice, which was then very popular car
the color of wet asphalt
It was the most car then what you have.
Mali wearing sports jerseys and so entered the disco
It was a top disco across Ukraine
We cried because of panthers
always went together and moved onto the Panthers as
The girls rotate and said: Wow these are Klitschkovci
were then still known as such, but now given the easily recognizable
they were moved onto high and as a panther.
I think not dance, but always played billiards and looked at pretty girls ...
You must understand that in 1992 the city of Kiew
that people are leaving to move somewhere else.
After the collapse of the Soviet Union
the intelligent and wealthy people aware
in Kiew is the future.
Then emigrated to Germany or America
They were difficult times for Ukraine.
They were difficult times for the company
economy fell
the whole Soviet system fell
He wanted the new system, but how old was killed
there were no laws regulating just nothing
There were huge social problems
Many professional athletes have become criminals.
Rob people in broad daylight.
They became mafia, real mafia.
When I was a child my father would say:
Boy you're everything, you have strong skills.
You do not go to school, join the army.
Such advice my father tried to give.
But it is not easily earned money on this trip is not for me.
You know what you want from life.
Somewhere here was the center of the ring.
Ring was on the green line to ...
no, it was a 5x5 meter here somewhere
Need team of 11 to 15 boxers
because some of them may opt out for any reason.
Each victory gives you points so you can not afford to waver
We participated in the amateur boxing federation Berlin
to help us in finding new hope.
We saw Vitali and thought that has very good potential
We offered him spar in the German league
which began in November.
He agreed, but before
there was a military facility in Bankogu,
where he received suspensions.
We learned about it only three weeks before the start of our league
We had paid for his money
Therefore it was with us in Flensburg.
But not now compete for the suspensions.
We looked like idiots, but when we called on Ukraine
They said: No problem, we have a boxer
Vitali-looking just like
and it's just as good.
Actually, we had no other alternative as we arrived at the airport
We see in this guy who comes out of the hall and looks exactly like Vitali.
We look at ourselves and say: It must be Vitali Klitschko.
Impossible to someone so similar to
until we found out that Vitali has a brother,
No one told us about it and
or about to come his brother.
Here in Flensburg to achieve a new dimension of the box
New Star came from Ukraine
and the only 19 year old Vladimir Klitschko.
The match ended in a minute.
Vladimir Klitschko lost only 10 of his 120 amateur meetings.
Ukraine has in him the great hope for the Olympic Games.
We watched Oplymp?jske games
because we had a contract with Vladimir for next season.
There he became an Olympic champion, which was fantastic
We were proud that we have a team Olympic Champion.
Have we a new hall for more people
because matches will now want to see more than 1200 people
It was said to number 4,000 people.
But then we heard the news that both brothers
go into professional boxing.
So plans for the arena fell.
When Vladimir became the Olympic champion,
guy next to me says: Congratulations to success.
Here is the phone Don King wants to talk to you.
Hello, here is Don King. Congratulations to the success of a brother.
I would be happy if you and I could see his brother
You are welcome in my house.
I was completely surprised.
Don King? Don King!
Manager Muhammad Ali, Mike Tyson.
Complete surprise.
I told about Vladimir
and we decided to go for him in America.
If you want to sign any contract you have a good lawyer
I've seen it many times
A friend, a good boxer has signed a contract with the promoter itself completely
whose name we all know, but I will not appoint him now,
I asked him why he signed a contract without a lawyer?
He said he showed me more money than I had ever seen in my life.
The promoter told him that he offered the money only once
times offer comes.
So you just signed.
Well signed to the devil.
Hi Vitali.
Great to see you.
Hi guys. I watch your entire career.
You are the best.
Sign the contract and you have mountains of gold.
What did he say? Mountains of gold?
Simply just sign ...
I thought not.
Vladimir I say: do not sign anything.
Will earn lots of money
We will be one big happy family
Piano. Don King said that a special play for us.
A really began to play professionally
It was really impressive
not only the boxing promoter, but also an artist.
Don Giovanni - W.A. Mozart
Yes, the real artist ...
Except when I underwent a piano to see that he does not play at all
piano keys moved up and down all by yourself.
It pedals that moved without the help of Don King.
So!
I'm from Berlin.
He was a good actor.
We decided not to sign
contract with Don King as played fairly.
Do not get a better promoter.
It is normal that when you become Olympic champion in the heavyweight
so you want to sign any contract.
But we should then have a closer relationship with Klitschkovcami.
Now give it to all!
There are many ways to train boxers
But Vladimir was very young, and had no experience with professional box
Vitali as well.
No matter how much sparring and training you have
professional ring is something else.
PROFIDEBT 16th November 1996
When I had my first pro fight, it was something new
smaller gloves, no shirts, no head protection
I was a little nervous.
You feel the heat reflectors ringo
then you see your opponent in the second corner and suddenly you will,
struggle that awaits you.
I felt a tremendous power in the hands of
and at the same pastes,
because I had a smaller glove,
the blows landed on an opponent.
It went very quickly
and the opponent was on the ground.
I thought not raised!
I felt a killer instinct.
Not raised! Not raised! Because I'll kill you!
He got up.
Before the match I expect him to knock
but I realized what I was capable.
That's how I started in the professional ring.
Won by KO in the first minute and 36 second
Vladimir Klitschko.
From the very beginning they were very curious.
What is the plan? What happens next?
The plan was to become world champions
I knew it from the beginning.
People laughed at because they were tall and completely different.
As a professional boxing began, distributing itself KO
Usually both the same night in an event
all realize that they are incredibly strong.
Vitali has an unorthodox style
His brother Vladimir is called severe style.
Vitali is very nepredv?date?n?, fights as a Cowboy
his hands are very low and suddenly shoots powerful punch.
Moreover, great reflexes,
therefore used to cover his sufficient defense reflexes.
Vladimir has a classic style
has a very strong left punch
which controls the fight.
That is his main weapon.
Also very smart boxes
According to him it's like playing chess.
I quickly realized that both are special Klitschovci
and both can become world champions.
Maybe both of them but at least one of them.
I am happy because it was a record,
which is still registered in the Guinness Book of Records
I knocked him to start the second round
which was quicker than Mike Tyson,
who previously held the record.
In 2000 I began writing about boxing for full-time
Klitschkovci had already been stars in Europe.
Since then I started to follow their career
Vitali took the WBO title Herbie Hidovi
but in America no one took him seriously.
People in America think:
If you want to prove something
Americans must fight to earn respect.
When I entered with him into the ring
I relied tall boxers that are slow
against them, I was always faster, so the fights I overindulge
But Vitali was different, I could not reach him.
Vitali had a phase where he believed that his body tells him enough
It was Vitali biggest handicap.
And that's exactly happened against Chris Byrd.
In the third round I got hit in the arm
or it was some movement
after which I began to feel great pain in the shoulder.
From that moment I saw more of the opponent.
As if I had eyes in the fog.
pain intensified and I began to lose power.
Vitali has a point prevalence
Once surrendered the match, no one understood it
He had a lot of pain
and when I realized that it can no longer defend
and no further chance so I track match.
I know the people in their charge
So I know whether or not they have more chance
and if I close match.
He resigned in the championship match with an opponent with whom he won
He remained vysmiaty from fans and the media
People did not see any blood
no broken nose, broken eye or any other cause
They did not know that the shoulder injury.
I remember that after the match
I could not sleep so I went to Vitaliy
He was sitting at home alone and I saw that
reads all the newspapers in which he cursed variety.
I knew he needed psychological support
I told him that we have to hold press conference
and say that doctors have confirmed that if it continued to struggle
You can complete tendon tear supraspinat?lnu
and it would end his career.
Then I received a letter from Max Schmeling
Really helped me psychologically.
Max wrote: I have been a few times in my life counting down on the ground
but most importantly do not stop at country
You find the strength within himself to pick up and move on
First, we are not weak!
The second time, now I'm world champion
Third, I love my brother.
The title is returned to the family through Vladimir.
One brother always compensate for the failure of the other
all in the family has returned to its place.
It was a match that right to take
well-known in Germany,
mainly because they identify with their country
and in what they do is exceptional.
People see that Klitschkovci
Germany seems to have adopted the
for his second home since 1996.
Therefore Klitschkovci so popular.
That's me?
I like how boxujete.
Your brother also.
Max Schmeling was a great inspiration for me
Inside the ring, but mainly outside the ring.
I am very glad that we became friends.
Max once said:
To be a true boxing champions, you have to go to America.
You have to box in the U.S..
We were preparing for another opponent as was Lewis.
While we train in Los Angeles
we heard that Lewis was wounded opponent.
Op?tlali us whether we are willing to fight against Lennox.
Once we have agreed to fight remained three weeks.
We also exchanged our sparring partners.
Vitali was excited about this opportunity.
In Kiev, the Ukraine, Vitali Klitschko!
It should be remembered that the battle with Lennox
Vitali was in the public reputation of a fighter without heart
because they gave up fight with Chris Byrd.
All of America stared at him as a weakling.
A champion is coming, who said that Klitschko eats for lunch.
He said that is not paid for overtime.
Until the end of the career coach Lennox Lewis Emanuel Steward.
Never before have met two such
heavy and tall boxers to world championship belt.
Lennox has always been more boxer in the ring
but suddenly was no longer out of reach.
Vitali hitting from all angles and very hard.
After the first round, I realized that we are in trouble.
The atmosphere in the arena was completely changed.
In the beginning was against Vitaliy,
and suddenly cried out Klitschko, Klitschko!
I said Lennox: You lose the title, beating you
You have to start a strike force to be dominant,
because if you get between the hooks can not spar with him.
Lewis began to believe more
but the points still to play so well.
Nevertheless, Vitali was able to injure.
It happened that the power head blow hole was right where the eye ball
Orbital bone has sharp edges.
This edge can cause substantial damage
if the skin is hitting over this edge.
There are 3 things that can stop bleeding.
First - what is Avertine substance that promotes blood clotting.
The second is epinephrine, which has the same effect as epinephrine and stops bleeding
the third is a gel foam, which also stops bleeding
but it must be attached directly to the wound.
Do you know the wounds are in the normal box.
But in boxing, people who complete the match for such a blow.
The real fighters, however, continue to struggle.
Is there a way to induce bleeding.
Gloves are in fact tied with twine at the bottom of the glove.
then when you hit your opponent by tying it can cause
bleeding, or increase an existing wound.
When I looked at the wound
tampon in the wound has completely vanished.
It hurt me just when I look at it.
On a scale from 1 to 10 the wound was on the 8-ball.
Number 10 is the damage to arteries.
The greatest danger is that the wound increases
in which case there may be permanent damage to the eye.
So at this point
need to think about the end of the match.
I remember only that the doctor came
in our corner, looked at the wound and shouted:
Full Time!
I think that no one wanted to end the match. We all wanted to continue.
But when it turned out that the wound was really serious
and the doctor made the decision to protect the health of Vitali
I realized that it was a good decision from Ring's official.
Stopped the match despite the fact that Vitali wanted to continue.
Despite losing the match was memorable
exactly what the fans want to see.
Great action, both were injured.
And even though Vitali lost the match
American audiences began to respect him.
My friend Lerry Merchant of HBO said it best:
Lennox won the match, but Vitali won the evening.
Now it has become like Vitali Gallic warrior.
Despite his great victories
this was the most dramatic match.
This game changed the look of it more than any other game.
The wound was so deep that I had
Fails to keep the two layers.
Outside it was about 120 inside and about 60 stitches.
Boxing is no joke. It's brutal, dangerous.
People who go box must understand
Every opponent is dangerous.
In history there are many examples. For example, when
Max Schmeling beat the previously undefeated Joe Louis.
or Mike Tyson
lost the match with Buster Dougles in Tokyo.
I also lost a match with Corrie Sanders
Nobody would say that I play.
So in heavyweight history there are many examples
when one decided to blow the match.
I was on the ground and I was angry
You little ... This I will not do.
Anyway plowed my ego as a tractor.
I wanted him to reciprocate
Vladimir made a mistake,
had to knock box with the front shock.
but he wanted to reciprocate quickly and so are not controlled.
He was too open and Corrie Sanders
old veteran who was just waiting for it.
Moreover, a very hard blow.
This is a sport where everyone who has hit hard
even if it can not say that,
has a chance to end the match with one blow.
In that one second can turn the match.
Boxing is a brutal sport
I've already had four operations and will have another
I hope that I get a sight again.
Lamon Brewster lost his sight after the match with Robert Heleniusom
If you do not have anything in your life, no family, money, work, no chance
then you can box.
That is why I do not understand that Klitschkovci become boxers
The whole world was open to them, they are intelligent and educated
They could be doctors or lawyers.
Year later I had the chance again to a world boxing title
We prepared with Vitali in Los Angeles.
We wanted to become masters at the same time in different organizations.
This is the heavyweight never happened before
Brewster and style was just for me.
Vladimir gave a lot of hits
but those punches, he returned with his
opponent can continue to struggle.
It was one of those rounds that everything will change.
Vladimir is with the never knit reconciled.
I heard a gong and the referee came between us
I completely lost his balance
and so I made a step forward that I did not fall
However, I stumbled on the referee's legs.
Then I felt that I can not get up
The woman was tested
look into my eyes but could not because I could not keep his head
I also could not open my eyes.
then said that my pupils are too open
and that there is a suspicion of a brain haemorrhage.
Of memory as we were in the ambulance, and I heard sirens
My brother was with me, but I could not tell
one brother, what I said was:
I'm sorry that I broke it.
When Vladimir was in the hospital,
Vitali called their mother and they both wept.
There were bad moments.
Vitali told me the whole truth, so I will not bother
had to carry everything yourself.
An hour later I woke up
I could talk again,
I stood and I left the hospital
The next morning we Vitali and I sat on the plane
Vitali said: Look directly into the mirror
Then he said: I think your boxing career is over.
I think it is the end of the road Vladimir.
Vladimir and I have walked the streets of New York
Suddenly a guy came up and said: Hello Mr. Stewart, health Klitschko
A great match with Lewis, I really enjoyed it!
I tell him: This is Vitali's is Vladimir.
The guy says: Oh, Vladimir, the boxer is unable to stay and has no stamina.
It was really embarrassed I wanted to hit this guy.
Vladimir me and let's not just
left in tears because it hurt him.
Vladimir told me since I started playing sports
I was always a star, I was always top.
Suddenly I am on the day.
Vitali if he did not believe his brother was difficult for Vladimir.
Vladimir completely changed the whole team.
He told me:
We need to focus on my strengths
and my team needs me to do everything
They must stand behind me.
I think I'm the only one who actually replaced.
Vladimir likes praise, but does not like criticism.
I like criticism, because it gives you the opportunity to improve.
I came to the training center, I saw a pair of Vladimir
He was not in good shape.
He made beginner mistakes and his coach said: Excellent, excellent.
I said, Stop! What is excellent which is great?
This is terrible!
I criticized him and coach him praise,
Vitali should always talk about things that do not like him
This was the first time we were screaming at each other.
Vladimir said: Everything was fine until you came.
Then he told me: Vital news for me something
Vitali, do not be angry
but I do not want to be in my training camp.
I train alone.
I said that I know is that adult
I have a good team.
If you want advice from older brother, will not hinder him.
What always struck me was that the box appeared to be a sport for them
You can play football, baseball, basketball
But you can not play boxing, boxing a serious thing.
American boxer believe Klitschkovcom,
believe they have the mental strength to be true boxer, let alone champions.
Vladimir realized that everything must change
I told him that I believe in white.
White shoes generates more power.
Black is too slow, with black shoes you slower.
We started using cocoa butter instead of grease
because cocoa butter is absorbed into the skin and makes it softer.
Vaseline just remains on the surface.
It was on his protective belt too much weight
so he took a razor and cut some skin from there.
so we focused on many details
Because the small things make big rodiely in battle.
Ponatieraj the sauce by the man!
Relax, this is not your concern.
Did you know at all what it is grill until you recognize me?
We do not use any special diet.
Mainly fresh products.
Not too much salt, no fatty foods, creamy sauces and things
Many proteins, fruits, vegetables
Just common sense ...
And in addition to desserts, chocolates, cakes ...
Usually no one but me to touch the grill
because I grill
David has learned how to broil.
Before I knew it but after 4 years is quite.
Sometimes I call and Vitali says:
Emanuel can ask Vladimir
if I can come to camp for two days? I will not say anything.
So I go to the gym and I ask Vladimir and Vitali could lose.
Vladimir says Vitali can not come.
Did not you lower your skin?
It prip?lnen?.
And then we natrafili the most feared boxer in the time
undefeated Samuel Peter
Nigerian nightmare.
Sam Peter was undefeated and won all KO
Maybe he won two matches at the time
and 25 or 30 times won the KO.
It should be clear:
Klitschko is a walking corpse.
Vitali and all the team was really scared.
No one wants this game except for Vladimir.
Vladimir said, Peter is best, there is no better return than this.
I think of this match up I have gray hair
It was something incredible.
Vitali likes of Vladimir will always be his older brother.
When Vladimir nevidar? anything, including Vitali is rozhoden?
He will always protect his little brother.
Peter was incredibly strong
I'm hitting it from all power
but I could not pass him.
He was also very fast and I got bangs, so I had to be careful
The match was back and forth in small time periods.
Vladimir was on the ground three times,
twice for illegal blows to the tail head
a third time after a strong blow that really shook him,
although in the opinion of experts was not written for losses
even if Vladimir has hardly stood on his feet.
This was the most dramatic 12-round TE in my 56 year career.
Vitali looked at me and says Emanuel handle it?
Still, we think that has a point prevalence
So we prayed to pass through the 12-th round.
I hit him left hook and was seen to have enough
I wonder to this day that he did not go down.
It was like a toy that
is varied to the right and left.
Ladies and gentlemen we have a winner
All three judges decided the same
114 to 111 for Stealhammer Vladimir Klitschko!
Highly respected Vladimir
They are both true champions.
Both experienced the bad part, but admits returned.
These are the real champions.
It was very important to win this battle in the IBF and WBO
My goal now is to match the title.
I am a fatalist, I believe in fate
I prepared the camp and I suffered a slipped disc.
Then I had another injury, after other ...
I did not quite match a long time
and my opponent was this time my body.
Then he had problems with knees, with shoulders.
It all started with kickboxing, then had their first challenges
which showed him at a later time.
Everything that had accumulated in the preparation of Rasim Rahman
That was my most expensive day in his career - $ 10 million.
In the last training session the weekend before the game
you picked cross ligaments in the knee.
Vitlali still wanted to wrestle,
wanted to deploy a bandage but I told him that it will not work
I told him, let him present,
the game ends for knee without being hit.
Everyone would think that a cheat or something worse ...
They said that they took the money and cheated them.
If you can not change anything, you begin to relax
So I said, Okay.
Vitali parents and also I have advised him
to try something other than politics.
Politics is a very thankless matter
But he said: I've decided.
Ukraine has great potential, but development is not in the right direction
Corruption destroys the country again and again.
It is embarrassing to read ?tatisktiky that Ukraine is the most corrupt country in the world.
MEPs have immunity
and not afraid to persecute innocent people.
There are many exemplary cases.
Democracy is not able to change everything
and is unable to unite order
make reforms
I think that is why Vitali
built his own party
on Western principles.
The party has only 15 people in parliament, which is not much
because Parliament has a total of 120 people.
Although this is the third largest party.
The mayor of Kiev Czernowiecki
and his party earns money from their policy decisions
often make decisions that are against the law.
Privatized public goods
for almost no money.
So therefore, we blocked the lectern
Czernowieckeho because people tried to remove Vitalij
Then I said: Listen, once you touch me
may expect the same response.
Keep from me the distance.
In our country people go into politics to make money
This is their main goal.
With Vital is different
Vitali has not been active for 100 percent, but at 130
Two times in major elections ended in second place.
So my hat made from his courage,
but sometimes it seems to me, as if
Don Quixote fighting windmills.
Politics is big and physical stress psychyck?
The reason why we do it
gives me the motivation for further work.
After the match with Sam Peter
I became number one candidate for fight
but I could not get a match for world championship
because I do not condone. I spent a lot of money
since I sued the IBF organization also Don King
Emanuel has not trained to fight with Byrd and it went perfectly.
One of the most important things of our training is not pugilism
it's just talking about anything
I've never not train
their ward and psychologically as Vladimir
We are like two murderers waiting for his victim
We know that our victim thinks the breakfast, just everything.
Boxing is for me a very logical thing.
I do not think more: Can I knock out!
It's all about tactics and strategy.
Since 2005, it is not a box for me is to chess.
Match of the IBF IBO heavyweight Champion.
Emanuel Steward, Vladimir actually changed.
It is more upright and uses more of his weight.
It is aggressive and finishing to KO.
Now you will systematically
with the front shock.
It has more weight on his hind leg
so it is difficult to achieve.
I was surprised that of a vyt??alo me.
I stopped sticking to your plan, which was obviously nonsense.
At the same time I watch it and tell you
this is more difficult than our first fight.
Have systematically slaughtered the entire battle.
We have destroyed his plan and rhythm, we forced him to play our game
and still keep it at distance.
When the time came, Vladimir get tough
and launched a cannonade.
It was about him a lot of questions
and has the inner strength to cope with its weaknesses inside the ring.
It took some time until we saw that really wants to return
We must realize that after his defeat,
Vitali always clean up the mess which remained
This time, however, Vladimir had to do it yourself.
And he did it, trusting you.
My son screamed: Keep the belt.
He was surprised when I came to him,
expected that angry since I beat my father.
I thought that my dad is the best in the world and no one can beat
Vladimir I brought the error.
Father, you have to put both belts Vladimir?
Yes, but do not be ashamed because he is a true champion.
I was sad, because who likes to see his father play
It was a groundbreaking game in USA
Vladimir and since then did not lose.
Can he stood like a phoenix from the ashes.
Needed to prove to his brother that he can prove it.
Then Vladimir changed
the little brother of peers to Vitaliy.
The Vitalio Vladimir is a natural rivalry, which is normal.
In one paper was a survey of who is the better boxer
The result was 52% to 48% for Vladimir Vitali, which is almost the same
It is still far from victory.
I was hoping that Vitali wants to return but I did not know when.
He had too many injuries and operations ...
His will power is great and also resistance to pain.
So he came to me and says Fritz I need to do something for me.
You can test me? I want to box again.
The family was in shock.
We asked why?
But I understood backwards
that wants to end career in this way.
career complete game like no injuries.
Fritz is more to me as a coach, my close friend
I talk to him about everything.
He knows my body better than my wife.
The question is healthy living? Did not take too many hits?
But Vitali did not get them too
This is in contrast to other boxers.
Other boxers take a lot of hits
and their health does not allow them to continue to struggle.
I always wanted to be world champions at one time
It did not happen when I was their manager,
but it was great to see how their dream fulfilled.
It was also my dream and it was great that it became a reality.
It was unreal,
I never smoke cigars so as not use that time.
Cigars victory. It was like a dream.
We remembered where we were two years ago and where we are now.
I will not forget it when Vitali called Bernd, you will not believe it
They want me to grant the German Federal Cross of Merit.
I just said: Wow!
Vitali told me that they feel that they deserved it
All things as social projects to promote democracy in Ukraine
He did from the heart.
I am very proud of my children.
I want to thank the German President and all
Vitali who was nominated for the Honorary Cross.
But my biggest thanks goes to the German people for their understanding
Klitschkovci are unique as a team.
something like this is never so heavyweight happened.
What makes them special is their Soviet past,
their family and also got the talent.
For me Klitschkovci
most intelligent boxers in heavyweight history.
Combining power and culture,
killer instinct and intelligence.
All these components make them special.
People still complain about the quality of opponents for Klitschkovcov,
but not yet for their produce rivals.
They can box against Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier because they are not all here.
They spar with those who are and those are definitely defeated.
So I do not know what they should do more ...
The box can only be one champion, one king
Only one can be at the top.
Now we have two boxers who want to be champions.
There are four bands, so they can be divided between Klitschkovcov,
However, it destroys some of their value
because people want a video of a champion.
So someone might say, maybe I was too,
brothers that they should fight each other.
I told my son that their veins flows the blood of one.
Let not fight each other, even for fun.
I have one suggestion for you
Draw?
Okay, but just because you are my brother.
Only with their help we can endure, that the boxers
They told me Mama you're our center and we are your satellites
Only if all of you right then and for us.
And to ensure that everything is okay and feel no sorrow
I promise that will never fight each other.
Still keeping that promise. So it was.
translated feriop
You understand, you dream, you must do your dreams bigger.
This is the way to evolve.
Not enough to have a mountain of muscle.
You can train just as mozok train biceps.
I have always mentioned as a model of Lenin,
Defend yourself with words unless the words are not enough
You can hit someone.
One day my coach said:
One will hang a poster of Vladimir next Mike Tyson.
I was wondering what the hell is this guy talking about?
The most common injuries: a broken nose,
orbital bone, jaw
If you eat the cake and then go into the ring ... it turns out.
So here is a great cheesecake.
Cameraman stuck in front of the camera eye
There was much blood and it looked really bad.
If you do not see the punch coming, it hits you full force, you can lose your neck
We saved 10 or 15 euros.
I have one suggestion for you.
Draw?
In any case!