Mail guy.
Angry,
head-shaking brian.
And "never wants
to make two trips" andrea.
You okay there?
Oh, it's all the same,
man.
Day in, day out.
I'm stuck, neal.
I'm in a rut.
You're in a rut, too.
Uh, no, I am not.
Thank you very much.
Oh, look.
It's 3:45.
Yogurt time!
Every day,
like clock work.
Boys,
what's the rumpus?
Milo says
we are in a rut.
We are not.
Hey,
isn't it yogurt time?
Come on, guys.
Let's go out on an adventure tonight, huh?
-Can't.
Why? 'cause you got a date with
a model you shot for the magazine?
Yep.
Gibbs, don't you
ever get tired
Of the same routine?
You mean the routine
where I date models?
I'm just saying --
No. I win.
What up?
Tyler, my friend,
How would you like
to shake things up
And be my adventure sidekick
this evening?
Sorry, charlie.
I got to --
Oh my god! You totally do
look like a charlie.
I always thought donald.
-Or a beard-o.
Anyway,
I got a date with katelyn.
Neal: Here we go again.
The white whale?
Please
don't call her that.
That makes it sound like
you're saying she's --
It's
a literary reference...
From the menu at long john silver's.
-...From "moby dick."
What if we call her "the girl you
will never, ever move on from
Even though she blows you off
every single time you have plans"?
That's
a really long nickname.
She doesn't blow me off.
There's just been a series
of unforeseen circumstances
That have stood in the way
of our dates.
But tonight,
all that's about to change,
Because we have
an 8:00 reservation at --
[ cellphone beeps ]
Isn't it yogurt time?
What was that?
Nuffin.
Did you just say
"nuffin"?
She blew you off again,
didn't she?
She did not!
[ softly ]
she has a family thing.
You are so sad.
You're
just as bad --
Trying to
manufacture adventure.
Neal here is the only one of you
guys that's got it going on.
Got him a pretty lady
to go home to.
I'm not
going home tonight.
Hear that?
Got himself a girlfriend
and a social life.
I'm lining up for
the midnight video-game release
Of "ice knights of drogar vi:
A fire and" --
Shh! Shh!
It'll be over soon.
Just go to sleep.
Don't j-- hey, uhp!
There you go.
That was for the best.
- Men at Work -
- S01E08 -
Sync and Correction by lala123
For www.Addic7ed.com
Riddle me this.
How would you feel
about going out tonight
And delivering
some street justice
To the small-time criminals
of this city?
Walk away,
and come back in normal.
Come on, man.
I need an adventure.
Let's go get weird.
Milo, you gotta stop
with this adventure stuff.
We're not the goonies.
You know who didn't realize
they were the goonies
At the start
of the goonies?
The goonies.
[ cellphone rings ]
Hey, it's katelyn.
See, she probably realized
what she was missing.
Hello?
Oh, I think
she pocket-dialed me.
What's she saying?
How much she wants you
to go out and have an adventure?
Damn, she's
going to meet some guy.
Oh, well, I guess
that officially frees you up...
For an adventure.
Now she's worried
she's gonna get too drunk.
Why don't we
go get drunk...
On adventure?
They're meeting
at 614 varick.
This is
unbelievable!
Do you know
what that is?
A post-it note with "614 varick"
written on it
By a serial killer?
No,
it's an adventure map.
It's our time
down here.
Is that
from "the goonies"?
Do you seriously think
You're gonna convince me to
stalk her by using movie quotes?
Frankly, my dear,
I don't give a damn.
Look, I just --
I hate seeing that girl
Make a fool out of you,
you know?
Nobody
puts baby in a corner.
Wow.
You watch a lot of movies.
Hey.
I'm just a guy standing
in front of another guy
Asking him
to go out on an adventure.
You had me
at goonies.
Yes!
Gibbs?
Gibbs!
Nope.
Gibbs! Gibbs! Gibbs!
Come on!
What are you doing here?
Wishing
I had taken a cab.
This is a new level of geek
you got going on here.
I know.
I'm letting my geek flag fly,
and proudly.
"ice knights of drogar vi"
is not just a game. -Yes, it is.
It's a passport
to another world.
No, it's not.
This is the costume
of my game character,
A fourth-level conjurer
named norkas windsword.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'm a sixth-level grown-up
named "holy crap, neal."
Well, what happened to your date
with the model?
Oh, had to pull the rip cord
after 20 minutes.
Was that bad, huh?
How is there not a popular
italian restaurant called
"penne
for your thoughts"?
Omg!
Tweet it!
You so should tweet that!
Tweet it right now!
I'm so cereal!
Uh, yeah,
I'm not on twitter.
What?!
Hashtag craycray?!
Where do you put your thoughts
if you're not on twitter?
Oh, my god!
I am totes tweeting that!
Well, you're welcome
to hang with us.
Gibbs, I'd like you to meet
my in-game family.
This is my father,
fistel brandythorn.
[ deep voice ]
good welcome, my young moor.
[ normal voice ]
my real name's glen.
My earth mother
is around here somewhere.
Oh, this is my wolf sister,
florandia swiftlace.
I-I am a virgin.
Neal...
Blink your eyes if you're being
held here against your will.
See, you don't get it.
This game has everything --
Light magic
against the darkest arts,
Loyalty forged
in the fire of --
Neal, I think on this we're
just gonna have to agree to --
What was that?
Neal?
Boob city.
I never thought
I'd say this,
But I want to
get with that goat girl.
Really?
She bailed on me
To go to some pretentious
hipster bar with no sign?
That's right.
Use that anger.
And you know they're selling
$15 cocktails served in mason jars.
And sure,
they'll be delicious,
But will that justify
the terrible service?
I mean, maybe,
If they're making their own
juices and simple syrups.
Kinda
losing the anger here.
But they probably aren't!
And it's back!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Tyler?
Shame on you.
You cancel on me
for some "family thing,"
And now I find you here
With all these well-dressed
people of varying ages
And floral arrangements
and a giant photo
Of a guy whose name
I'm guessing is not rip...
...Because this is a wake.
So, shame on you...
For thinking
I wouldn't come down here
And comfort you
in your time of need.
Oh, tyler.
Mm-hmm.
Tyler, I can't believe You came
down here to comfort me like this.
Please believe that.
I have to go
check on my grandmother,
But I'll be right back.
You're amazing.
Well played. Very smooth.
You made me
crash a wake!
I know!
I'm sad!
I'm sad, too!
See, I told you katelyn
wasn't blowing me off.
You were right.
Now let's get out of here.
I heard about a secret village
under madison square garden
Where patrick ewing
will wrestle anybody for $100.
I can't just -- where the hell
did you hear about that?
From a guy who wrestled
patrick ewing!
I can't leave now.
I've been chasing this girl
for months.
Because she's
your white whale.
Will you please stop
calling her that?
But yes.
And I'm not
gonna throw away
The first real chance
I have with her.
Just give me 15 minutes.
Fine.
You've got 15 minutes.
I'm gonna get a drink.
But remember, patrick ewing
isn't gonna wrestle himself.
Although, I heard for 200 bucks,
he might.
Hello, sir.
I will take your most expensive
scotch in your tallest glass.
Thank you.
Cousin stanley?
Is that you?
Yeah, it's me --
cousin stanley.
It's gus!
Gus! Right!
Your great uncle!
There it is!
Great uncle gus! Of course!
Good to see you, man!
[ laughs ]
Look, fellas!
Look what the patriotic cat
dragged in!
Cousin stanley made it!
How are you back
from the war already?
We won!
[ cheers ]
I think I just got shot down
by a half-woman/half-goat.
What'd you say?
Well, I asked her
If she wanted to get out of here
and grab a drink.
[ all groan ]
Gibbs,
everyone on this line is here
Because they want to be
transported
To the world of magic
and wonder that is
"ice knights of drogar vi:
A fire and song" --
Neal...
What is your point?
My point is
you got to respect the game.
I respect the hell
out of the game.
Really?
What's it called?
I said it
pretty recently.
Yeah.
"ice knuckles
of drunk girls four."
Look, neal,
Milo’s right.
I have been in a rut -- same types
of women, same conversations.
But these girls
are different.
I just need to know
how to speak their language.
Help me.
I will, but only because
I believe your intentions
are pure.
Ish.
Listen well,
my young apprentice,
For the journey ahead
is infinite and --
You got three minutes.
I can work with that.
So, that's my aunt penny
and her husband, lenny.
And -- brace yourself --
their son, kenny.
So you're, what, like,
three-quarters dr. Seuss?
[ laughs ]
shut up.
I will not shut up.
I will not shut up at a wake.
I will not shut up on a lake.
[ laughs ]
As we used to say
in our tank battalion --
Down the hatch!
I thought you said
you were a pilot.
Yup -- flying tanks.
Highly classified.
Highly awesome.
You know, I think
We should probably cool it
with the drinking.
You're right.
We're at a wake.
We don't want to
get carried away.
Oh, no, no.
I just thought
we should go smoke
Some of my
glaucoma medicine.
Mission: Impossible...
To turn down.
'tis true
what the elders say.
Wood nymphs are
the most beautiful creatures
Of our forest.
Tell me, good swordsman,
Whereupon your person
did you etch your speech?
On-eth my hand.
Alas,
I must take my leave.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I am new to this world
And was rendered speechless
by your beauty.
Did I offendeth
thy thouness-eth?
No, it's just this twig bra
is super uncomfortable.
I have the same problem
with my pine-cone thong.
[ both laugh ]
They call me Drusilla.
They call me...
Gibbs...Eses.
The eulogies
are about to start.
I gotta get my mom
out of the bathroom.
Will you save me a seat?
Well, I don't know...
You might have to fight off
your great-aunt irene.
She seems pretty into me.
I think I can take her.
She's lost a step since she got
her foot amputated.
[ both laugh ]
Oh, my god.
That's so good.
Hey, I don't want to
jinx anything,
But I believe
I've landed the white whale.
When I die, I want to be buried
with a sandwich like this.
No, no, no.
I want to be buried
in  a sandwich like this.
Milo, are you high?
Yes.
But around here, you got to
call me "cousin stanley,"
Because I'm pretending to be
a guy they call cousin stanley.
Damn it.
I need you
to pull it together right now
So you don't screw up
my thing with katelyn.
Hey, my thing has nothing to do
with your thing.
Boop!
Relax. You won't even know
that I'm here.
As you all know, I've never
been one for speeches.
So, cousin stanley,
why don't you get on up here?!
You bet!
Showtime.
What the hell
are you doing?
Relax,
I have two purple hearts, man.
I can handle this.
Hey.
I found
the most amazing girl.
She's kinda quirky and funny
and creative.
Plus, she's a wood nymph,
so, you know...
[ crowd murmurs ]
Yeah! Yeah!
Where is she?
Well, she's got a tent way back
at the end of the line.
So, I guess now I'm a member
of the "mile-long club."
[ all ooh ]
mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
You're
the coolest guy I know.
And I know a guy
with three dirt bikes.
What's her name?
Uh,
Drusilla of the camden forest.
[ all gasp ]
You guys know her?
Gibbs...
You had sex with my mom!
Our F-14 was in a flat spin...
And goose was dead
before we hit the water.
I couldn't deal with it.
Every night, I'd ride
my motorcycle up the coast
Wearing
the dopest leather jacket.
Isn't this
from "top gun"?
Is it?
Or is "top gun"
from this?
I knew I'd never
see my friend again,
No more sing-alongs
at the bar,
No more
shirtless beach volleyball games
Wearing cut-off
jean shorts.
It's kind of hard to describe,
you know?
It's like...
You've lost
that loving feeling.
No, this is definitely
from "top gun."
Does this guy
seem weird to you?
Life's
all about friendship.
Like the first time I went
shrimping with my buddy bubba
And our legless leader,
lieutenant dan.
I couldn't say, really.
You know, war changes people.
But I've never met him
before, so --
Tyler knows what I'm talking
about. Right, buddy?
I guess there's
another tyler here.
Wait -- how did you know
I was gonna be here today?
I read
your grandfather's obituary.
The obituary
runs tomorrow.
Spoiler alert?
Unbelievable.
So there it is.
Life moves pretty fast.
You don't stop and look around
once in a while,
You could miss it.
Does that
answer your question?
Sincerely yours,
"the breakfast club."
Katelyn, I swear
this is not what it looks like.
Oh, good, because it looks like
you brought
Some drunk, delusional hobo
to my grandfather's wake.
Actually,
that's pretty accurate.
I needed to know
if we had a chance.
It's just -- we've had
so many "almost" moments,
And you keep
blowing me off,
But there's something about you
that keeps me coming back.
And I thought
by staying here,
I'd get a chance
to find out what it is.
So, you used my grandfather's
wake as a speed date?
See, your ability to summarize
is one of the things I'm liking.
I guess I never really
gave you a chance.
I just thought you were
some conceited pretty boy.
I'm not conceited.
All right, listen.
If you're not busy tomorrow,
the burial's in the morning.
You could meet me there,
and we can hang out after.
It's a date.
And remember, you can't
spell funeral without "fun."
But we will tomorrow.
[ chuckles ]
[ smooches ]
Hey ty.
Ty. Ty.
Ty. Ty. Ty.
Ty. Ty. Ty. Ty.
Ty. Ty. Ty. Ty. Ty.
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! What?!
You have my full attention!
Did I screw things up
with katelyn?
Actually, uh,
despite your best efforts,
I think the white whale
may finally be a normal whale
That likes me.
Great.
Can I borrow 50 bucks?
Gus and I are gonna go halvesies
on patrick ewing.
No, you are not.
I'm sorry, sir, but I got to
take this little fella home.
Say goodbye to gus.
Bye to gus!
Sorry for bailing on you, man!
It's all right.
We had enough adventure
for one night.
We did, didn't we?
Hey, ty,
we got weird tonight.
Yes, we did.
Okay, I'll go first.
I'm still upset with you.
And even though
I know it's just a game,
For some weird reason,
It feels like you really did
sleep with my mom.
Yeah. But I didn't.
Exactly!
Round and round we go,
right?
[ sighs ]
but clearly, we're left
With this undeniable tension
between us.
Okay.
So, I think the only way
to make things right
Is for me
to sleep with your mom.
Your virtual mom.
Okay.
You would have to create
a character
And then create
that character's mother
So I can seduce her.
Which, I know,
it doesn't make us exactly even,
But it's the symbolism
that matters to me.
Okay.
Great! Thanks!
Look, we both said
some things we regret.
The point is, I'm sorry.
And you know what?
Breakfast is on me!
Okay.
We have
an officer and a gentleman.
You wore that
to the funeral?
Cousin stanley
wanted to pay his respects,
And this is what someone
of my rank wears to a funeral.
Aren't you supposed to be
on a date?
She, uh...
She didn't show.
-No way.
She bailed
on her grandfather's funeral?
She had a work thing!
Oh, come on, ty!
You're buying that?
People have work things!
You can't handle
the truth.
Fine.
Maybe she did blow me off,
But I think I like it better
when she's my white whale.
All potential,
no disappointment.
Except for
the continual disappointment
Of her blowing you off.
You can't handle
the truth!
I just admitted
she blew me off.
Sorry, I've got to
rn this by noon,
So I'm trying
to get 'em all out.
Did you order
the code red?!
You're damn right I did!
Yeah.
And "shouldn't have eaten
indian food" mike.
Uh-oh. Are you gonna want to go
on another adventure?
Nah, I'm gonna enjoy the routine
for a little while.
That adventure gave me
a massive hangover.
So,
what are we watching here?
We're in the bedroom
of my castle.
That's gibbs' mother.
And you're playing
as your mom
So neal
can have sex with her?
I guess. I --
All right, gibbs.
That is me
entering the bed chamber.
I am now removing
my armor of invincibility.
Oh!
Hey, man!
Wow.
Didn't know
you went commando
Under
the armor of invincibility.
And now, gibbs,
I am going to even the score
With the most
thorough ravaging
Your virtual mother
will ever experience.
You're gonna want to
tap "s."
What -- what are you doing?
[ keyboard clacking ]
What -- no!
I said "s," not "a"!
Aaaaaaaaaaah!
Noooooo!
What just happened?
Your mom killed me!
Do you have any idea how long
it took me to build my character?
Sure died easy.
It's 'cause
I took my armor off.
I wanted to make it special.
Hey look, your armor
fits my mom. Ha!
All right, mom.
Let's take a walk
around our new castle.