The civil war between the Sri Lankan army
and the Tamil Tigers militia
has caused more than 100,000 deaths to date.
For this reason,
many Tamils have left their homes in Sri Lanka.
About 40,000 of them
are now living in Switzerland.
ZURICH, SWITZERLAND
Maravan, rotary evaporator.
Mackerel with wild garlic sabayon,
poached salmon, and fire the 7.
Coming right up. Maravan, carob gum.
Maravan.
Carob gum.
For warm foam,
guar flour is better than carob gum.
Or your sabayon will collapse.
You're teaching me how to cook?
Did you hear that? Maravan's teaching us
how to cook. He can do better.
So, one wild garlic sabayon.
Marinated mackerel fillet on hearts-of-fennel
with wild garlic sabayon.
Poached salmon with lemon cream.
Look at that.
Take it back.
- Of course.
Is something not to your satisfaction,
Mr Dalmann?
Oh, yes. I'm terribly sorry.
May I offer you another appetizer?
Fine, but none of the green stuff.
Dreadful.
Such a smart ass.
C'mon then, Ghandi.
Show it to me. Here.
Show me your Indian sabayon.
Go on.
I'd love to try a sabayon
that doesn't collapse.
Will you make me one?
We need
the non-reexport explanation for the M40.
If you don't mind me saying,
we should conform to all formalities.
Arms exports to conflict zones
are getting a lot of press.
Yes...excuse me.
The American gets 8%.
And we have the same non-reexport
confirmation that's totally legal fully...
that's legal.
Look out. Careful, careful.
Careful...
Good God, Eric, Eric.
Hurry up now, hurry.
- Yes, yes.
Go clean up the puke. Go. Hurry.
- Eric.
Hello.
Ulagu!
See you.
- Where are you going?
Out.
Bye.
- Bye.
Come on.
We have to go. Sandana.
Is our nephew giving you any trouble?
No.
He's a very pleasant guest.
You mustn't take that.
It'll make your heart stop.
Where did she get this?
The doctor has strictly forbidden it.
Just the essence?
Cook for Sandana.
Two mackerel fillets with sabayon.
- Maravan, carob flour.
Maravan.
Ciao.
- Ciao.
Yes?
Excuse me.
What's up?
I just wanted to ask:
Did...
Did you really mean it?
Should I make you the sabayon?
Yes.
Why not?
When?
Whenever you want.
Tomorrow?
Before work?
Sure.
My address.
At yours?
See you tomorrow.
Get up.
Get up!
Do you have a reservation?
Yes.
This is the kitchen.
I want to open my own restaurant.
Is that yours?
No.
It's...
Actually,
all I need is a business partner who...
So where's your sabayon?
- All in good time.
Compliments of the chef.
In my restaurant I could
cook dishes from Sri Lanka and southern India,
but different.
New.
What's that taste?
My childhood.
Man and woman.
Which one's the woman?
Both.
It's cold.
Hard.
Soft.
Warm.
Do I get a fork?
Curry of chicken with sashtika rice
and coriander sabayon.
- With guar flour?
Mackerel with coconut and cinnamon smoke.
The masculine element.
More for me.
Very sweet.
It's a little small.
No?
Whipped mousse of ginger and asparagus
with a green mango and avocado tip.
I can't eat anymore.
There's always room for dessert.
I'm not finished yet.
A tea?
Are you OK?
I'm...
sorry, I...
didn't want to...
I mean it was very nice...
What didn't you want?
I..-
So you've got it.
Maravan has it.
Unbelievable.
Oh no, the Indian's got it.
And looking as innocent as Ghandi again.
Do you have anything to do with this?
With What?
Out.
Be glad I don't press charges.
You're finished in Zurich.
He'll never get another job.
Andrea.
Andrea!
The exit is at the back.
Maravan!
What was in the food?
What do you mean?
You know exactly what I mean.
No. They were all just traditional recipes.
I'm lesbian.
I don't sleep with men, only with women.
I know what it means.
So don't tell me there was nothing in the food.
What was in the food?
And stop lying to me.
Ayuveda is a healing art.
I know what Ayuveda is.
- Want to know or not? - Yes.
The eighth branch of Ayuveda
is concerned with aphrodisiacs.
That includes certain dishes...
- That I ate?
I..-
I wanted to ask
if you could help me with my restaurant.
I need someone with a Swiss passport.
I didn't think it'd be so strong.
They're my grandmother's recipes
cooked with molecular techniques.
You can't be serious.
You didn't want to screw me?
No.
I thought you'd loosen up...
"Loosen UP-"u
What are you going to do now?
I don't know.
I can ask around.
Lie back down.
- What?
Alright then:
Elbow.
- El... bo... bow.
Knee.
That tickles...
- "Tickles."
No, no, no. No, no, no.
Like this: That tickles!
Wash your hands.
Red Bull and vodka.
Maybe you should go
and have a Red Bull and vodka with Sandana.
Red Bull and vodka?
A new face in the community?
- Ulagu, Mahit's nephew.
He brought my grandmother to Zurich.
- So I heard.
So we'll see you at services?
He'll bring my grandmother home soon.
You lost your job?
That's what they're saying.
I can deliver every clay.
Good.
Sorry, we haven't discussed payment.
- 30 francs, as always.
You mustn't forget
that the mothagam is for use in worship.
Yes, 30 francs of course.
Can we help you find a wife?
Sandana isn't a good woman.
She neither comes to services,
nor obeys her parents.
Be glad she rejected you.
He's with the Tamil Tigers.
Let's go.
Let's go!
What do you have against a free Eelam?
They're fighting for you.
They're terrorists, so they've been banned.
That's in Sri Lanka.
Here, they're not banned.
That's because they only raise money here.
You have no idea what's going on back home.
The bypass we performed on Mrs Vilasam
was successful.
You understand?
- Yes.
But the coronary vessels are restricted.
We'll need at least one more bypass
and further operations.
I've prepared a cost schedule for you.
Excuse me.
Mrs Vilasam
would remain in hospital for a while.
So there'd be additional costs.
- We can't pay that.
You'll surely need time to discuss this.
I hope her tourist visa
is valid for the duration.
I can raise the money.
- You?
Let him.
How do you do that?
- What?
Make your hair stand up?
Maravan.
Wait.
It's too much money. You can't pay it all.
I can contribute something.
She's my grandmother.
- I know but...
Nangay was there for my family, too.
Please, let me help.
- I've saved up a bit.
For your restaurant. Nangay told me.
I know you don't think much of me anymore.
I didn't want to hurt you.
Don't take it personally.
You don't want to marry me, Sandana.
That's personal.
Hello, Maravan.
Can I have a quick word?
I want you to cook the same meal again.
Not for me. For friends of mine.
A married couple.
They need help.
Support.
But the food has to be the same,
with the same effect.
Can you do that?
I don't have a rotary evaporator.
- I know. I have one.
They're marriage counsellors.
If your food works, they'll have
lots of patients you can cook for.
It's up ahead.
The pink one.
Need a hand?
No, thanks.
- Robert?
They're here.
- Come on. Let's just go and say hello.
Hello.
- Hello.
So. This is Maravan.
- Very well.
Andrea Peters.
- Robert.
Our practice is there, there's the kitchen
and I'll show you our little temple.
Upstairs is our private space.
Come with me.
Familiar with this?
- Me?
Yes, gas.
Oh, yes. That's the little temple
where we'll serve the meal.
It's lovely. Romantic.
Can I do anything? Anything you need?
No, we're all set.
Alright.
What do we always say to our patients?
- Just relax.
I'm relaxed.
If anyone here needs to relax, it's you.
I'm excited.
- But relaxed. - Yes.
Of course.
And if he cooks as good as he looks...
What are these?
Agar-agar with asparagus tips and beetroot.
But bigger.
That's no good.
- Why not? You said I should do the same...
You can't. They look like they're from
a tacky sex shop. Can we leave them out?
You ate it.
So...
chop off the balls.
I'll show you! I'll get you!
Be a good boy!
Who's the boss?
I'm gonna get you!
No!
- Come here.
Did it work?
- No.
Of course. Fifty-fifty business partnership.
Know what we can charge for your special menu?
Unbelievable!
They're getting naked. Want to see?
Thanks so much
It was wonderful, and tasted great.
Spread the word. OK.
Bye.
Saffron and curcuma.
Is that Japanese?
Chinese.
Nany.
Maravan?
Excuse me.
You can't discharge her, she's sick.
I can't keep her against her will.
Mrs Vilasam is refusing surgery.
But I can pay for the operation.
I can't operate on your grandmother
if she doesn't want me to.
But
she'll die.
I'm not going back!
Don't you shout at me.
It might be better if we stop shouting.
Especially you. - Speak our language.
She can't even speak our language.
- Get out.
Out of here. Everybody.
There's nothing else to say.
I don't want to go back to Sri Lanka.
- You should be happy to have a job.
I won't go back to become a waiter.
Nany...
I said you'll go back, and back you'll go.
He likes it here. He has friends.
Why can't you understand that?
Maravan.
- I can't stand it.
Talk to him. He won't listen to his uncle.
Maybe he'll listen to you.
Ulagu.
I'll pay for your language course,
driving license,
and I'll bring you back as soon as possible.
We're not just kitchen hands.
We're free people.
I'm not like you.
Here.
Sorry I'm late.
- No problem.
This is Maravan, the cook.
Makeda, "Lady of the House".
Cuba.
Sri Lanka.
How old is her husband?
Why?
She's so beautiful.
I can't imagine they'd have that sort of
marriage problem. Is he Cuban, too?
Andrea.
Hello, Isa.
- Where is he? - Who?
Don't deny it. His car's outside. Robert!
Robert isn't here, please. We want
an intimate atmosphere for your patients.
Patients. Is that a joke? Who's he here with?
Isa, Isa please.
Damn it, let me through.
Your dentist?
- It's an exercise, Isa.
An exercise? Whoremonger!
And you, black slut.
Enough. Don't be vulgar.
- Vulgar?
I was trying to deal with our marital crisis.
- Stop it.
No more clients. Forget about your "Love Food".
Isa, I'm sorry.
You should've thought of that earlier.
- Don't be hysterical. - Hysterical?
Shut you're trap, you dirty bastard.
- Don't be like that, Ina.
Have they left?
What are you doing?
- I'm done.
It's over.
- Wait a minute.
How embarrassing.
But what a meal.
What a cook.
That's what people eat in Sri Lanka?
- Yes.
These dishes help unite desire and fulfillment
when man and woman are bound by love.
Right. It could make my job fun for once.
I have a lot of clients
who'd pay a fortune for that.
Especially when the starter gets them hard.
Listen.
Why don't we work together?
- Great.
This is indecent.
- That's why it pays so well.
Thanks for the offer. We'll... think it over.
You said they're all married.
- They are. Just not to me.
Let's talk about it later, OK?
It was my mistake, I apologize.
Just think of the money.
- All you Swiss ever think about is money.
What about your restaurant?
You need money.
I want 70% and you double the price.
60.
- 70.
So...
what are you doing tonight?
I don't know.
This here. I told you about that, right?
It's really good.
With coconut oil.
- Yeah? - And no artificial colouring.
Really?
- Yes. In two different sizes.
OK.
- But pay attention to...
Pay attention to...
Hello. You heard anything from Ulagu?
No.
This is good, too.
Me neither.
Does that surprise you?
Who sent him away?
The family wanted him to go back.
- And you do what the family tells you.
Children should obey their parents.
- Yeah?
Some do, anyway.
Should we go into town?
Got any plans? I still have time.
Like this.
Wait.
We're hungry.
No, I counted them. Leave them alone.
One.
- No.
I counted them.
I'll have one.
Give them... Andrea.
Makeda, stop it.
Give them back, Andrea.
Makeda.
So...
I just wanted to make sure everything's ready.
These are my friends from Love Food.
Andrea Peters and our cook, Maravan.
The name's Dalmann, a pleasure.
Lovely. You've done good.
Recovered from the heart attack,
Mr Dalmann?
I used to wait tables at Huwyler's.
- Yeah, that was a close call.
"Dodged the grave-digger."
Well good luck with our Love Menu.
You wanna kill me?
I'll leave that to others for now.
I wouldn't bite into one of those.
- You don't have to.
Yes, others will.
Listen, Razziq wanted Michèle, have you...
- Just like you said.
Super.
That's them.
Hello, do come in.
The ladies will take a taxi, right?
Alright, see you all soon. Have fun, everyone.
You already know Michèle.
Right, Putschi?
A glass of water, please.
- Sparkling or still?
I don't know. Water.
Dalmann.
Who?
No, he won't write that.
They wouldn't dare publish that.
When I want to read about myself,
I'll let you know. Thanks.
What's that?
- Nothing dangerous.
Just comforting.
Were you ever in love?
And?
Her name's Sandana.
Sri Lanka?
Our families decided we should marry.
She didn't want me.
But you love her.
Maravan, Ulagu's disappeared.
- What?
His parents think he joined the Tigers.
They wouldn't tell my dad anything at the temple.
You cook mothagam for them, right?
- Yeah.
Think you could go to the temple and ask...?
- Yeah. This is for you.
Without raisins.
Without raisins. You remembered?
Yeah.
- Pantone without raisins. What a treat.
Thanks. I...
have to go.
Hello.
I have a question.
Remember Ulagu, Mahit's nephew?
They're saying---
he joined the Tigers.
- No one knows our fighters.
That's to protect our brave young heroes.
Don't ask such things.
- Of course not.
I just wanted to...
I want to support our valiant young Tigers
with a contribution.
We want to know if he's alright.
Fine.
What was the name?
- Ulagu Amar.
Thanks.
All I've done is take down the name. Alright?
For years, certain people have tried
to associate my name with illegal exports.
Arms exports? - Well, I find it regrettable that
Swiss television contributes to the speculation.
So you support the public inquiry?
- Of course. That's a must.
Say that again.
Since when?
Are you sure?
What's wrong?
The M40's are on the water, but without shells.
Good, we still don't have a deal.
But the shells are on the ship with supplies
for the army. Cluster fuck. Sonofabitch.
What'll you tell Waen now? What'll you say?
Not a bloody thing.
Mr Kung Fu will sign the contract tonight
and all will be well.
Right, Putschi?
Look. Nice, eh?
We need drinks.
Hear me?
Clean this up.
If you don't buy, someone else will.
Richard, what's the trouble?
Richard,
I expect you to get your MPs under control.
So they vote down the inquiry.
Who? No surprise there. Who else?
Let's get started.
Has Dalmann gone?
- Yeah.
Who is that man? Is he from the Tamil Tigers?
- Mr Waen is from Thailand.
Two more champagnes, please.
What are you doing?
Are you nuts? Stop it.
Man!
I'll have one of those.
- It's with alcohol.
We're leaving.
Don't worry,
we won't ask you to come up to our room.
Everything OK?
Dalmann sells weapons to the Tamil Tigers.
- Oh, yeah?
If it's any consolation,
he also sells weapons to the army.
What army?
- Yours. Over there. In your country.
We really need some sleep.
- How do you know that?
I have eyes and ears, sweetheart.
- I'm glad you have eyes and ears.
Mint?
Mojito.
Last week's share and for shopping later.
Think you'll manage the shopping?
What's wrong?
Dalmann is an arms dealer.
He paid well.
Maravan, Ulagu wrote me a letter.
Can you translate it?
What are the Tamil Tigers?
It says:
And there?
"You'll be filled with pride.
The days of my people's enemies
are numbered.
I'll soon return as a hero
and hold you in my arms."
Someone wants to impress you.
- Think he'll be back? Soon?
Rathinam?
I'll let you know if I hear anything.
Ulagu wrote.
We'd like to speak with him.
I'll support the movement more in the future.
Are my parents here?
You're late.
- No, I'm not. You said 9:00 and it's 8:57.
She's always right.
I've made food. - Sure.
- No, thanks. We don't want any.
Vegetable fried rice with prawn chutney.
- We're not hungry.
How many times?
- I'd love some. Thanks.
Sandana, please.
- I've had nothing to eat.
It's ringing.
Is that him?
Yes.
Ulagu.
Ulagu. Can you hear me?
Ulagu,
I'm pleased to see you.
Are you alright?
Your aunt and uncle are here.
Ulagu, where are you anyway?
- Ulagu.
You can't ask that.
He can't say where he is.
- Ulagu,
you must go home to your parents.
They're so worried.
Your mother is crying her eyes out.
This is no way to behave.
Ulagu.
- Ulagu, come back.
We just want to chat.
- What's with his leg? - What's wrong?
Ulagu!
- Why's he limping?
Aninda...
Would you like a tea? A calming one?
It's all your fault.
- Aninda!
Ridiculous, Mama.
- Don't talk to her that way.
We should've never
gotten mixed up with his family.
Sandana, come on, we're leaving.
- No.
Aninda, wait a minute.
- This is your daughter.
Oh, dear. Sorry.
How about your prawn chutney?
My mother also believes that Nangay's chicken
soup saved her eldest brother.
Chicken soup is good for a lot,
but not snake bites.
Unless you hit the snake
with the chicken beforehand.
What do you use that for?
- What?
That machine.
For...
transformation.
They say that Nangay
taught you how to cook food that...
food that...
for passion.
Is it possible?
And how...? How...? How does it work?
It just works.
Nangay, for example,
transformed rice,
lentils and coconut into dough,
and the dough into little balls.
And using milk, sugar and steam,
she transformed the balls into fake figs.
Cooking is transformation.
Cold into warm,
sour into sweet,
soft into hard...
And...
does the food transform people, too?
To some extent.
Can I sleep here tonight?
No, not like that.
I just can't stand my parents right now.
Sure.
Thanks.
Oh, the lamps. Sorry.
I'll turn them off.
- They don't bother me.
Now it's... nighttime for the curry trees, too.
Hello. Traffic was terrible.
All this goes in the car? - Yes.
Anything else?
- It's all in the kitchen.
This?
And, um...
Hello.
Andrea
We... work together. Sandana.
You go ahead.
I'll be right there.
Nice to meet you.
So that was Sandana? And?
Did you sleep with each other?
Why not?
Oh, that'd be improper, right?
You like the new car? Enough space now?
You don't know anything about Tamil women.
- You don't know anything about women.
She just doesn't want her parents
to choose her husband. - I know.
Good, because I invited her for dinner.
You can come too.
When?
That's 24,000 francs.
I want Ulagu sent back home.
I see.
So how much money are we talking about?
Tell her.
She really wants to know exactly.
5,785,000.
What if something happens to me
on my way to the bank?
They'll bring the money to the bank
and you'll deposit it.
She'll need a visa for Sri Lanka.
- Sure.
I could tag on a week of holiday
and take a friend.
Why not?
It would be less obvious that way.
No?
The whore'll screw you over.
- Don't call her a whore, it sounds so ugly.
What should I call her?
- Do you want to go?
See?
The shells won't dock
before I'm 100% sure the money's there.
And if she gets out of line, she'll be rolling
Havanas before you've finished dessert.
And she knows it.
You could've told me straight away.
But he only just told me yesterday.
That pig does what he wants with you.
- That's none of your business.
He sends you off on a whim.
Can't he open his own account?
His doctor won't let him fly.
Our guests are here.
Hello Maravan. Hello, I'm Makeda.
For you.
- Thanks.
Sorry.
We won't be going away.
Dalmann wants her to fly right back,
and she's such a good girl,
she does whatever he wants. - Andrea, please.
What do you want to drink?
White wine, Sandana?
Water, please.
- Sure? Wouldn't you prefer a tea?
Tea is good.
- I thought you were going to Sri Lanka.
I thought so too, but she'd rather do business
with the arms dealer.
What sort of business?
This way.
I'll warn you up front:
I'm not as good a cook as Maravan.
I hope you like it anyway.
- What does he pay you? Do tell.
What does he pay you? And who does the cooking?
- That's different.
Oh, cooking for him is alright?
- At least I don't fuck him.
Shut your face.
Sorry.
I'd like to go. Now.
Good of you to come.
So...
this Dalmann sells weapons
to the Tamil Tigers?
Your parents were killed in the war
and you cook for him?
Does Nangay know what you do with her recipes?
I'm getting out here.
I'll stay at a girlfriend's.
Take care
Good night.
Who died?
I don't know. It's coming from Mahit's place.
Sandana.
- Let me go.
Stop it.
He was shot.
They...
broke into an army munitions depot.
And were caught in the act.
I'm sorry.
But you won't bring him
back to life by not cooking,
I did something wrong to earn money.
And you think that's why Ulagu was killed?
Because of your Love Menus?
You didn't force him to join the Tigers.
How old was he?
Hello.
You didn't shoot him.
- You don't understand.
12,000 for the rotary evaporator.
The new car, the advertising.
We have eleven bookings in Basel.
We don't have to stay. Fuck Zurich.
We can start up something in Berlin.
What's going on?
He wants to stop cooking.
Too bad. Dalmann wants a love menu.
His doctor says his blood pressure's OK
and he wants to screw again.
Don't worry, there won't be much action.
I don't care. I don't want to hear about it.
Do what you think is right, OK?
I'm flying the day after tomorrow.
Why the hurry?
- Some ship can't be unloaded otherwise.
I don't know.
- You're flying to Colombo for Dalmann?
And are you coming over to mine or what?
Dalmann will get his Love Menu.
- You don't have to. It won't help anyway.
Yes, it will, but before you fly to Colombo.
I'll do it.
He has no time.
Call him.
Call him!
And Basel?
Hi, darling. It's me.
Are you busy?
Can I come in?
- Yeah.
A man from the temple came to see us.
They didn't want us to get the wrong impression.
They wanted to share our grief.
Sorry.
They suspect that you banged up that car.
I said I didn't believe you could do that.
- Hello?
I've got the Campari. Dalmann wanted
champagne, right? Do we have enough?
Three bottles...
are left.
- Oh yeah, that's plenty.
Sorry about the other night. We feel
really bad about it, I hope Maravan told you.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
I'll get the fish. Need anything else?
I have everything, thanks.
- OK, fine. See you.
You're cooking for Dalmann?
Why?
- I have to.
You think you can transform him?
What are you making?
A cocktail. Campari balls with...
"quid ginger.
Very interesting.
Never seen this before.
He can really cook, that Indian.
Where did he pick it up?
I don't know,
it's called something like "Man and Woman."
What's his name again?
- Maravan.
Maravan.
- Any more?
Later.
Eat.
Open wide.
Careful.
Let me. I'll do that.
The drinks.
Campari caviare on chilled champagne
with glazed slices of navel orange.
Red... for the lady.
What are you staring at?
Come on.
What's up?
Want to go home? I can do the rest.
No!
Darling, it's not working. Don't be sad.
Fuck, be creative. I need it so bad.
How much do I need to eat for it to work?
I couldn't say, Mr Dalmann.
Come here. Do it to her.
How much do you want? I'll pay.
- Please stop.
Come here.
- No.
You think I don't know what you two are up to?
Come on. Don't be like that.
You're being impossible!
- I want to see you two get it on.
Get undressed.
- Stop it.
Undress.
- No!
Stop. What are you doing?
Let her go.
Think I don't know what you are, huh?
Kiss her. I said kiss. Come on, kiss.
Stop it.
Leave them alone.
Can I see?
- Leave me alone. No.
Fucking Indian.
He just made... a big mistake.
The curry-eater.
A shame. A real shame.
I would've been glad to help you
the way you cook.
Ingenious but now...
I'll finish you.
- Come down, what's got into you?
I need a whisky.
- No whisky. Water.
I want whisky.
Now go, get out.
Get out.
Go!
I'll take care of this.
Darling, you're being impossible, know that?
No.
Yes.
- Please call me back, OK?
I can't get through to his doctor.
What can I do?
I think he's dying.
Andrea,
what's the matter? Why are you crying?
Come on, what is it?
Everything's OK.
Andrea. He's here.
At the staircase.
Shit, I...
Makeda flew to Colombo
the next day as planned.
She accepted the money
and transferred it to Macau
where Andrea was waiting for her.
When I received the cheque,
I knew they had made it.
As far as I know,
the weapons on the ship
never made it ashore.
At least not in Sri Lanka.
Nangay died two months later.
I don't know if what I did
brought some justice to the world.
Maybe just for a brief, insignificant moment.
At least I tried.
I had inherited Nangay's knowledge,
but not her wisdom.
A cook can transform cold into warm,
hard into soft,
sour into sweet...
But he can't turn evil into good.