Everyone stop!
Isn't today the important entrance exam day?
I always wanted to go to Tachibana Ichi High.
But during my parent teacher meetings,
my homeroom teacher said Ichi  High was a bit tough.
Can we watch it together?
I couldn't fulfill my dreams.
I wonder what problem
this anonymous person has with the exam.
Maybe they're challenging the test itself.
So you're saying we should just
place people in the
closest high school, without any regard to ability?
We'll all be
tied to our areas for so long
- it'll ruin the country.
- But people have other
things to offer besides their grades.
In these kind of arguments it seems
like the smart people are
always so mean and the other people seem so kind.
So why do the people who do study get rejected?
The people who go to lower
- ranked schools didn't study?
- Another extreme argument.
People have always recognized that
we have different ability levels.
We should all try our best.
From those efforts then
we can figure out how far we can actually go.
But your ability
to study isn't something that can be judged.
- So where?
- Parents should
praise their kids at home.
You should be able to do it on your own.
That's what everyone used to be like.
We didn't all hold hands when we ran in a race.
Even though I was last I did my best.
And my mother,
she told me I did a good job to
keep running to the end.
My parents always had
my bad drawings decorating their room.
The high school exam should be the same way.
On results day, my number was not among the ones
being posted up.
No matter how many times
I blinked, it wouldn't appear.
Everything fall apart for me.
Why? My self grading
had me over the borderline.
There was a classmate
who was four points below me and he got in.
Down with the exam?
Perhaps the person doing this is
not angry with the test but with the grading.
Ah, we had a grading
problem here 4 years ago that we had to deal with.
Maybe someone who is still holding a grudge?
The ringleader may not be someone now
but a person who was affected by a previous grading mistake?
They're no victim then, just someone who didn't pass.
Really? Is that so?
Ogino-kun, you know we can't really say that.
- It would be in the papers.
- But...
Everyone thinks
the school is full of bad, evil people.
But we're actually trying to save them.
If we went against what the rules say
the media would've been all over it a long time ago.
Yeah, that's true.
There have been plenty of protests
against grading mistakes.
But we have the rules in place to
deal with any kind of disturbance fairly.
I've decided what we'll do.
Ogino-kun, call everyone in.
What about the student?
Matsushima-kun can take her home.
They can go back now.
Matsushima-sensei can go home now?
We can't have the relative of a test taker in here.
That's always been the rule.
I got into Narasawa Academy.
Then I joined the Broadcasting Club, famous for their computers.
In order to find good material for a documentary
I'd read the newspaper front to back every day.
And then this June,
I found an article that started it all.
People around the prefecture
made formal claims to see their entrance exams.
So I also made a claim to see my own exam.
Just one day.
To decide three years...
No, to decide your life.
You know all this, right?
This isn't some time for a lovers' fight.
And to damage the exam just
so someone doesn't go to a resort hotel?
I can't forgive that.
It would be terrible if the exam failed.
So I
would do what I can to clear things up.
I would do whatever I could
to make sure this exam was a success.
I thought that's what we all wanted.
But, I don't think that's true at all.
What are you planning?
Tell everyone, right here, right now.
Haruyama-sensei.
Translation: Rollins    Timing: furransu     Timing/QC: SacredCultivator
High School Entrance Exam
Support fansubbing by not watching on streaming sites! Find all your favorite dramas at d-addicts.com!
Wait, what's going on?
Just calm down.
But...
really?
Is it a mistake?
What do you want me to say?
Sorry to interrupt.
Everyone, please come back to the office.
However, Matsushima-sensei
please take Ishikawa-san back home.
Why me?
The Principal is ready
to decide what to do about the grading.
It may have something to do with you
- personally, so in order to avoid any misunderstandings.
- I see.
I can go home?
Are you done talking to her?
Is there anything else you're hiding?
- No.
- Then, it's fine.
We'll talk with you again on another day.
Ogino-sensei, I'll go with them.
Ishikawa-san may try to get out of
what she did by lying to
Matsushima-sensei, I believe.
She wouldn't...
No, I agree with Takimoto-sensei.
There's a good percentage of that happening.
- I think we should do it.
- I'm okay with it.
But maybe you'll fight again?
Then we'll have another problem on our hands.
I can't deny that but
another female teacher is fine too.
Takimoto-sensei, please.
You can go home too if you'd like.
I'll come back. But
I'd need my phone.
I see. Well, let's get back then.
In regards to the grading issue...
Wait a second!
Murai-sensei said that Haruyama-sensei
is responsible for everything.
We can't talk about grading until we figure that out.
Is it true, Haruyama-sensei?
What do you want me to say?
The poster.
Down with the entrance exam!
Ishikawa never said she did that.
When we were getting ready for the test
yesterday, I opened the key box a little early.
All the second year keys were gone.
I thought everyone had left
so I hurried upstairs.
Then I went back to the staff room
and Haruyama-sensei was back plus all the keys.
What were you doing there?
I hate to do this but I can ask a question first?
Sure.
Murai-sensei, are you not involved with today?
Not at all. What do you think?
I didn't put up the posters.
Down with the entrance exam!
But.
I supported the
accidents today.
Really?
Murai-sensei, sorry to have suspected you.
I'll tell you everything I know.
The real leader is someone in this school.
I heard about all the plans from that person.
There's only three people in the school supporting it.
But it's not like we all agreed on it together
the leader reached out to people individually.
3 people? Kyoko-chan, Ishikawa Erina and then...
- It's not me.
- Yesterday,
when I was cleaning the rooms
I knew that Erina was going to
put the phone on the B class blackboard.
Is there a secret site about the school?
Mm, I wonder.
I don't know.
That's when I noticed I wasn't the
only one involved in today's plan.
I wondered who was really behind it all.
I was worried that someone would ask me
but I hoped that no students were involved.
But no students could come on exam day
so I figured it was okay.
So then you went to look
- for the phone.
- That was my intention.
But then that poster was in the classroom.
Down with the entrance exam!
We were finished with preparations.
It would be hard for a student to get all five keys.
I think another teacher is involved here.
I was worried that person
would know I was looking for the phone.
But everyone knew that
Kyoko LOVE
Aida-sensei was big on cleaning.
So to make sure, I placed something in every classroom.
You wrote "Kyoko Love" on your own?
When the leader
found out about the phone on the blackboard
I asked what we should do.
They suggested that I use my own phone instead.
That's why it was in the locker.
I put my phone in a desk in the hallway.
But they thought it wouldn't be effective.
So they moved it.
It may have been a bit much.
You really were surprised.
Ishikawa Erina was in the charge of the phone.
So what was your part in the plan?
During the English period
I was supposed to give the leader two sheets.
Oh? I'm missing a sheet.
I'll take an extra.
There would be a blank sheet to keep the numbers level.
The plan was for the actual answer sheet to appear somewhere else.
So you did that!
But you didn't know who the leader was.
We had a code.
Excuse me,
when do you think the cherry blossoms will bloom this year?
Two days before the entrance ceremony?
I was asked the same thing too.
The phone going off would make a small panic
and make it easy to get the paper ready.
Why did you do that?
Isn't it obvious?
To take down the exam.
And why would you want that?
Right, it's a bit vague.
I didn't intend for the exam to go away.
So then what?
- I just wanted to create an incident.
- What?
I wanted to see how the school would react.
How they would deal with high school entrance issues.
But the cell phone going off was an exam disturbance.
It doesn't make the exam takers out to be victims.
The plan was for it to go off after the test was complete.
Then what about Shibata Asami's phone?
An unexpected happening.
I was supposed to take the completed sheet
after the test was complete but
I had to take Shibata Asami to the nurse's room.
So looking for the answer sheet was just a ruse?
No, I really looked for it. I wasn't
sure if he gave the
answer sheet to someone else helping.
But then, Sawamura-san found it.
And he wrote a tester's number on it too.
So then he was involved too?
I don't think so. He couldn't have made the posters.
Down with the entrance exam!
Another person? Didn't you do all this?
- No.
- Then how
- much did you do?
- I was just supposed to get the sheet.
What about the message board?
They're just all worked up about the exam.
Down with the entrance exam!
Can you really take it down?
They're just all worked up about the exam.
The plan is perfect. Ignore the idiots.
What did Ishikawa do?
I didn't know anything about the plan to put up questions.
First is kanji problems. Overflow, a little while...no problem.
When was the Onin War?
I didn't know anything about the plan to put up questions.
But there is the issue of timing.
It seems like someone from the school helped with that.
- And after the test?
- All the talk about
Cell phone mom
- And after the test?
- All the talk about
Chairman
- And after the test?
- All the talk about
fighting!
- And after the test?
- All the talk about
who was involved, the details, the grades, it really surprised me.
One is 82.
The other is 100.
who was involved, the details, the grades, it really surprised me.
Perhaps it was all from Erina being here?
However, I think my former company was a reason for it too.
I think Erina was here this long
to get in the way of the trip of her special someone.
So that's why you suspected me?
You think she got me to help her out?
- Right.
- But that's not it.
I knew about Aida-sensei, Takimoto-sensei, and Ishikawa.
But anyone would have done the same in that situation.
- What do you mean?
- I'm serious
about Midori-sensei.
There was nothing going on with Ishikawa.
At her entrance exam, her phone went off
so the other female students were being mean towards her.
- I didn't know about that.
- Me neither.
I knew that Aida-sensei
was always looking after the cute girls but
I didn't know this about Ishikawa.
Wait a minute
are you trying to defend yourself?
No, that's not my intention. But
I just want to clear up doubts.
I'd rather find out
why Kyoko-sensei is doing all this
rather than look into who
else is involved. We've got this
far, trying to figure out who knew
what was going on in the school.
But that's not the whole story.
What's your real motive here?
My motive?
I want to learn about this school.
But you probably don't understand
why it got to this point.
You won't know unless you tell us.
That's right.
Everyone knows that
I lived in a foreign country until graduating high school.
I'm a returnee to Japan.
After graduating university I found work as a travel agent.
Then I was in charge of school trips in this prefecture.
It was my first chance to interact with Japanese high schoolers.
To me, it just seemed like they were having fun.
We all lived in Japan
but there was an innocence to them.
Hey, you guys. If you
smoke here it'll
- be all over the news.
- It's fine!
We're on a trip. A little
smoking won't make the news.
That's when I met him.
Okay okay okay.
This beautiful tour guide already explained it to you.
There's hundreds of years of history in this place.
If it burns down, what do you think would happen?
The moment there's fire the
police will come. Then
- that's the end of the trip.
- Really?
Yikes.
We'll finish this talk up at school.
Don't smoke anywhere else, okay?
Anyway, you should do things you can only do here!
The dumplings at the entrance are the best in Japan!
- Hurry up!
- Whatever.
Get to it!
Sorry for the trouble.
Ah, no...
Could you keep this
a secret from the other staff?
Sure, but why?
They'd cancel the trip and suspend the kids.
They may be big but they're still kids.
I don't want to just get them in trouble.
I want them to know what they did wrong.
I thought that he knew what it was like
to be a high schooler.
Ah, say hello to Tokuhara for me.
Tell him we'll go drinking next time.
- Oh, you know Yu-chan?
- He's my junior in university.
If you'd like...
Haruyama.
Kyoko-chan, you can come too.
I think high school is a good place
for kids to get ready to enter society.
You have to get angry at what they do wrong.
But you also want to leave them
with a lot of good memories.
My job is to help out with that.
I really respected him.
Terajima-san, do you have a girlfriend?
No, I don't.
- Still?
- Girls don't like
the hotblooded type nowadays.
I love that type, actually.
Well, let's drink first.
Yeah.
Why are you looking at that?
I'm researching what teenagers are into nowadays.
I see.
How about you try this out?
Come on...
I think it'd look good.
Sensei!?
Ah, oh man!
Rebound the ball!
Nine is open! Check it!
- Here's a gift from Kyoto.
- Thanks.
It's fun to guide students on the trips but
I'd like to be more involved like you.
- How about you become a teacher?
- Me?
I think it'd suit you.
- You'd be an energetic one.
- Like you?
No, more than me!
That trip we met, you got angry at the students, right?
Really? Could I do it?
You could.
- If you did...
- If I did?
I'll tell you when you do!
Haha! What!?
If I became a teacher
he was going to tell me something.
But I never heard what.
He died?
- It had something to do with...
- Sakamoto-sensei.
Well, we need to find out.
Maybe Haruyama-sensei
is out to get revenge, right?
Sakamoto-sensei. Let's hear Haruyama-sensei tell us.
I'm sorry.
I don't really know.
- What?
- They say he died
after drinking and stumbling into a roadway.
I don't know if it was an accident or suicide.
But he was thinking long and hard about it.
About the entrance exam.
- So then...
- Sakamoto-sensei!
Before that,
please tell me something.
What is the high school entrance exam?
I've only been a teacher for a year.
I thought I was lucky to get into Tachibana Ichi High,
one of the highest ranked schools in the area.
The exam to get in is very hard so
I thought I'd figure out what the exam was very easily.
But, it wasn't that simple.
What surprised me is that the
students don't really have pride about going to Ichi High.
They probably studied very hard for it but
when they get in, they act like it was natural.
The best kids end up going to university
but what do they think of the high school exam?
Why does it have influence over your entire life?
And on the other side,
there are many people who still obsess over Ichi High.
The alumni who stay here and talk so much about Ichi High.
Isn't that natural?
The school we loved as kids
we still continue to love as adults.
Is there something wrong with that?
No, I think it's great.
But does that love of your school have anything to do with the exams?
But in reality...
It was the calculator's fault. Not mine.
There were so many grading mistakes.
Do you know about garbage day?
There it is, an Ichi High tradition.
It was just boasting.
I'm praying for my daughter's happiness!
What's the problem?
He's from San High!
Looking down on others.
It was just fooling around.
I thought it was all pointless.
Maybe we could do without the exam.
What's wrong with supporting our past?
I'm doing what I can for Ichi High.
Maybe you wouldn't understand but
we need the entrance exam.
You don't think the kids need to put in effort?
You think those who have that one flash
of brilliance are better than those
- who work their whole lives?
- No.
Those people should probably stay where they are.
As long as they don't force their values on others
it won't bother anyone else. They're probably happy.
But those who obsess over Ichi High
are not all like you Sakamoto-sensei.
Why me?
You told us how you really felt
back there, Murai-sensei.
One teacher can have a tremendous impact on a student's life.
That's so much responsibility. That's
probably what I want to learn about.
A person who never had
a setback in life wouldn't understand
how important the entrance exam is.
I don't think so.
You don't?
I don't think you could understand how I felt.
- Why?
- You're a returnee here.
Without any connection to Japan you got into university.
Then you got your travel agency job.
Then you decided to become a teacher. You passed
in one try. And your experience
abroad probably got you this far.
Sure, but because of that I can't relate?
I know what you think of Sakamoto-sensei
but didn't you have to use your own past to get here?
My past?
- Is that what it is?
- What?
Come on.
Haven't you noticed? You're chained to your past.
I'm not chained to anything.
But your past will always follow you!
Just forget about it, Murai-sensei.
You passed the written exam but you failed the interview, right?
They were all Ichi High alumni
it couldn't be helped!
If I were them, I'd want people from my school to get in too.
I don't think that's true.
You went to Seikou Academy!
Perhaps. But you can't
keep blaming other things.
In a group interview, do you
think about how your answers stack up against other people's?
When you see the
numbers of successful people in your group
do you think about how they answered?
Did you try doing that?
I did. My answers
included a lot of thought about school
and environment issues.
We don't need any teachers that just worry about problems.
Rather, we want those who may have some fantastic goals.
But they have a purpose for being here,
something they want to do. Those are the people who are picked.
It doesn't mean that they pick just Ichi High alumni
or someone from their high school.
Did you ask Matsushima-sensei?
- Matsushima-sensei?
- He was your
high school teacher.
He's come to me
whenever he's needed some advice.
He said it.
He said the same thing you just told me.
But he was also from Ichi High. So I thought
he didn't know what it was like to be disadvantaged.
It's not a disadvantage, it makes you a good friend.
Haruyama-sensei, I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry for being out of line.
- No.
I'm the one out of line. I've been doing
all the talking.
But,
I wish I could've told him one thing.
The test that he supervised had a grading mistake.
Even if the student committed suicide over it
you needed to go on.
You needed to stay a teacher to make sure it would never happen again.
Four years ago, in April,
a boy hung himself at home.
They said it was because he didn't get into his first choice for high school.
If there was no mistake
my son would have got in!
It's your fault that he died!
The boy's parents
requested to see his test that November.
There was a three point grading mistake.
He was involved in the mistake.
He blamed himself.
I did whatever I could to support him.
It isn't all your fault.
How long are you going to blame yourself?
I said whatever I could to
try and get him back.
But he always had the same reply.
A girl returning home to her country
wouldn't know anything about Japanese schools.
And then he died
three months later.