I heard the news of my nomination
and there's just one thing I wanna say...
Here with the admitted arch-enemies...
...in a state of apparent friendship,
World War II had begun.
In January 1943...
...just days before the final German
surrender at Stalingrad...
...Roosevelt and Churchill met
at Casablanca in French Morocco.
Stalin was not in attendance.
He'd withdrawn his ambassadors from London
and Washington. The alliance was in crisis.
The Red Army was moving west
against the Germans.
The momentum had shifted.
Appreciation of the Soviet sacrifice
was finally growing in the U.S.
Even fervent anti-communist
media-baron Henry Luce...
...made Stalin Time magazine's
Man of The Year in 1942...
...praising his industrialization, stating:
"Stalin's methods were tough,
but they paid off."
Another Luce magazine, Lite, painted the Soviet
Union as a "quasi-America, with its citizens...
...one hell of a people who to a remarkable
degree look like Americans...
...dress like Americans
and think like Americans."
His ruthless secret police was even described
as a National Police similar to the FBI.
Roosevelt felt he had to take action,
or he risked the break-up of the alliance.
Both he and Churchill feared Stalin
might indeed make a deal with Hitler...
...to save the Soviet Union
further destruction.
After all, he'd done it before.
But on many issues Roosevelt, unlike
Churchill, saw eye-to-eye with Stalin.
Both wanted a weakened, pastoralized
postwar Germany without industry.
Germany's militarism
was the cause of unrest.
We either have to castrate
the German people...
...or we have to treat
them in such a manner...
...so that they can't just go on
reproducing people...
...who want to continue
the way they have in the past.
It was at Casablanca
that the president announced...
...a policy of Unconditional Surrender.
He wanted to send a message to Stalin
that the U.S. would not rest...
...until Hitler's Germany was destroyed.
Unconditional Surrender was a declaration of
war not merely on the enemy governments...
...but on the German
and Japanese people themselves.
Which in its unintended way would lead to
terror bombing of civilian populations...
...harden the resistance
of those populations...
...and result in the most
controversial decision of the war...
...the dropping of the atomic bomb
on Japan.
In hindsight one might argue that the
declaration of Unconditional Surrender...
...was one of Roosevelt's
greatest blunders.
To make matters worse, Roosevelt
and Churchill confirmed at Casablanca...
...the Allied decision to land in Sicily
after North Africa...
...again postponing the second front
in Europe...
...and relegating their nations to further
irrelevance...
...in determining the outcome of the war.
This would lead to the disastrous
Italian campaign of 1943 to '45...
...that achieved little but a fierce
bloodletting of allied troops in Sicily...
...and at slaughterhouses
like the beachhead at Anzio...
...and the four battles for Monte Cassino,
which did little damage to the Nazis.
With the Allies bogged down in Italy...
...and the Soviets increasingly suspicious
of British intentions...
...Roosevelt and Stalin met
10 months after Casablanca...
...for the very first time
in Teheran in Iran...
...in November 1943.
After trying unsuccessfully
to exclude Churchill from the meeting...
...Roosevelt accepted Stalin's offer
to stay in the Soviet embassy.
But Roosevelt found Stalin cold and aloof
during the first three days of meetings...
...and feared he would not succeed.
But on the fourth day...
...after teasing Churchill in front of Stalin
about his Britishness and about his cigars...
...Churchill, according to Roosevelt,
grew red and scowled.
And the more he did,
the more Stalin smiled...
...until finally Stalin broke out into a deep,
hearty guffaw at the expense of Churchill.
And before long,
Roosevelt was calling him Uncle Joe.
The ice had been broken...
...and Roosevelt felt that he and Stalin
were now talking like men and brothers.
Roosevelt reiterated to
the Soviet leader...
...that he would open the long-delayed
second front the following spring.
Churchill was forced to commit...
...but argued still the landing should be
made to the east through the Balkans...
...heading off the advancing Soviets.
The PM is thinking too much of
a postwar world and where England will be.
He's scared of letting the Russians
get too strong.
Roosevelt clearly indicated he would allow
the Soviets considerable latitude...
...in shaping the future of Eastern Europe
and the Baltic States...
...requesting only that Stalin
implement changes judiciously...
...and not offend world opinion.
Roosevelt had written Stalin
a persona} note promising:
The United States will never
lend its support in any way...
...to any provisional
government in Poland...
...that would be inimical
to your interests.
Crucially,
Roosevelt made important headway...
...when he got Stalin to agree
to enter the war against Japan...
...when the war against Germany
was concluded.
Exhausted, Roosevelt wrote of the
Teheran conference, we made great progress.
To use an American,
and somewhat ungrammatical colloquialism...
...I may say that I got along fine
with Marshal Stalin.
And I believe
that we are going to get along very well...
...with him and the Russian people,
very well indeed.
The Soviet war continued
with a bloody campaign in Belorussia...
...followed by their entry into Poland
in January 1944...
...Russia's ancient border enemy.
The retaking of Poland and particularly
Warsaw is a tragic and bloody story.
Few suffered as much as the Poles
in this long war.
Six million were killed,
3 million of them Jewish.
But the U.S.S.R. too paid a stiff price
to free Poland.
Six hundred thousand Soviets perished.
It was here that the first death camps were
actually found in 1944 by Soviet troops...
...and revealed unquestionably to the world,
pictures of the true insanity of Hitler's regime.
The Soviets quickly set up
a friendly government in Lublin...
...that cracked down on the opposition,
triggering a civil war.
They had excluded the fiercely
anti-communist representatives...
...of the Polish exile government
that had been set up in London.
The westerners thought of them
as democrats...
...but Stalin said they were terrorists
descendants of the white Russians...
...who had fought against the revolution
in the Russian Civil War of 1919-1922.
No stranger himself to terrorist tactics...
...Stalin, in order to prevail against
the hated anti-communist Poles in London...
...committed the dual atrocities of killing
thousands of Polish army officers...
...in the Katyn Forest in 1940.
And then in 1944, he ordered
the Red Army to halt outside the capital...
...white the Germans crushed
the native Warsaw uprising.
Soviet defenders argued that the Red Army had
exhausted itself in a grueling 45-day...
...450-mile advance
against tough German troops...
...over-stretching their supply
and communication lines...
...that they needed to stand down.
Differences over Poland would become
the single greatest source of distrust...
...between the US, Britain, and the
Soviet Union during and after the war.
But to be fair,
many westerners did not understand...
...that anti-Semitism had long been common among
a significant portion of Polish Catholics.
Or that to Stalin, Poland was a matter
of life and death for the Soviet Union...
...because the Polish territories were the
corridor through which the hated Germans...
...had twice passed into Russia
in the 20th century.
For these reasons, Stalin demanded and
enforced a friendly government on his border.
It was no fess an issue to him than Canada
or Mexico was for the United States.
Through 1944 and '45,
the Soviets continued to advance...
...taking Romania, Bulgaria,
Hungary, Czechoslovakia...
...and with the significant help
of Partisan Guerillas, Yugoslavia.
Mile by mile across eastern and south-eastern
Europe, the Germans fought to the last man.
Cities became fortresses
and were reduced to rubble.
Warsaw, Budapest, Vienna.
An estimated million Soviet troops
perished liberating these areas.
And as the Soviets fought their way
to Berlin from several directions...
...in the west on June 6th, 1944...
...the long-delayed second front
was finally opened...
...one and a half years after Roosevelt
first promised it to Stalin.
The largest armada
the world had ever seen...
...involving 11,000 planes
and some 4000 ships.
Over 100,000 allied troops...
...and 30,000 vehicles
landed on the French beach at Normandy.
An estimated 3,000 men died
in this landing.
Allied forces were now approaching
Germany from both east and west.
Victory was inevitable.
A month later in July 1944, a key event in
the future of the world was taking shape.
The Democratic Party convention
opened in Chicago.
His health clearly failing...
...Roosevelt easily secured the nomination
for an unprecedented fourth term.
Henry Wallace, his vice president, was probably
the second most popular man in America...
...the people's choice
to be his running mate.
But he had made many enemies
over the years.
In May 1942, Wallace
had given the acclaimed Common Man speech.
Some have spoken of the American century.
I say that the century on which we are entering,
the century which will come out of this war...
...can be and must be
the century of the common man.
There must be neither military
nor economic imperialism.
The march of freedom of the past 150 years
has been a great revolution of the people.
There were the American revolution,
the French revolution...
...the Latin American revolutions,
the Russian revolution.
Each spoke for the common man.
Some went to excess,
but people broke their way to the light.
He called for a worldwide peoples'
revolution and an end to colonialism.
His speech was received coldly
across the Atlantic.
Churchill charged his secret agents
in the U.S. to spy on Wallace.
Wallace detested the British Empire.
I said bluntly that I thought
the notion of Anglo-Saxon superiority...
...inherent in Churchill's approach,
would be offensive to many.
Churchill had had quite a bit of whiskey...
...said, why be apologetic about Anglo-Saxon
superiority, that we were superior...
...that we had the common heritage that had been
worked out over the centuries in England...
...and had been perfected
by our constitution.
Wallace's hatred of imperialism
was universally known and widely acclaimed.
In March 1943, Roosevelt sent him
to Latin America on a goodwill tour...
...secretly charging him
to recruit nations for the allied cause.
Sixty five thousand greeted him in Costa
Rica, 15 percent of the population.
More than one million cheered as he
moved down the streets of Santiago, Chile.
The Vice President returned with a dozen
countries declaring war on Germany.
It was more than anyone
had imagined possible.
Back home in a Gallup poll...
...Wallace was the choice of 57 percent
of democratic voters to succeed Roosevelt.
But opposition to him
from inside the party was enormous.
Jesse Jones was allied to
powerful Democratic Party bosses...
...led by party treasurer
and oil millionaire Edwin Pauley.
United by their hatred of Wallace...
...their champion was a man known
to many as the assistant president.
James Byrnes had been raised in the hot-house
politics of sultry South Carolina...
...an environment where white superiority
and segregation trumped all other issues.
He was a driving force behind blocking
a federal anti-lynching bill in 1938.
After making his name
smashing trade unions in the south...
...Byrnes became a powerful U.S. senator.
If you wanted something done
on Capitol Hill, you saw Jimmy Byrnes.
By 1943,
the mood in Washington had shifted.
It was no longer the New Deal...
...and Roosevelt removed Wallace
from the Bureau of Economic Warfare...
...and put Byrnes in charge
of the new office of war mobilization.
But Wallace still had a powerful supporter,
the American working man.
Today, few remember that the Second
World War saw more strikes...
...by organized labor
than at any other time in U.S. history.
In 1944 alone 1 million workers
were on strike at one time or another.
The war had rejuvenated
American capitalism.
Corporate profits rose
from $6.4 billion in 1940...
...to $10.8 billion in 1944.
Put simply, the war was good business.
But in the face of rising corporate
profits, workers' wages were frozen.
As a result,
a wave of strikes rocked the nation.
Americans versus Americans...
...a tragic spectacle in
these critical times...
...when unity is essential
to the preservation of democracy.
Detroit was the key city
in Roosevelt's Arsenal of Democracy.
A great arsenal of democracy.
Many African-American
families migrated north...
...in search of work in
the armaments factories.
Racial tensions soon escalated.
One demonstrator jeered:
I'd rather see Hitler and Hirohito win...
...than work beside a Nigger
on the assembly line.
In June violence exploded...
...exacerbated by the city's
nearly all-white police force.
Federal troops arrived to restore order
with live ammunition.
Thirty four were killed in the riots,
25 of them black.
Wallace went to Detroit
to survey the damage. He was appalled.
We cannot fight
to crush Nazi brutality abroad...
...and condone race riots at home.
Years later this remark
would be echoed by civil rights leader...
...Martin Luther King
in reference to the Vietnam War.
By 1944, powerful labor leaders
Sidney Hillman and Scotsman Phil Murray...
...expressing complete confidence
in Wallace...
...had taken a dislike to the new men like
Byrnes taking power in Washington.
But the Anti-Wallace forces
told the president...
...that a Wallace re-nomination
as vice president would split the party.
The president would not answer
their ultimatum. He stalled for time.
Eleanor Roosevelt reminded him that Wallace had
been there with him since the beginning...
...a fellow visionary.
But the president's attitude
towards Wallace remained a puzzle.
He sent Wallace to evaluate
the war's forgotten front in China.
U.S. any Jiang Jieshi had been
fighting Japan since the early 1930s...
...and with his wife, the powerful
American-educated Madame Jiang...
...had strong ties to the US conservatives.
Wallace, however, saw the growing power
of Mao Tse-Tung's communist army...
...and was unsure of Jiang's future.
His final report was considered
too controversial and suppressed.
On his return, Wallace was summoned
immediately to meet the president.
The ticket would be
the subject of discussion.
It was the moment
Wallace had been dreading.
His affection for me
seemed to be completely undimmed...
...because I can remember him
pulling me down...
...so his mouth was next to my ear
and saying:
"Henry, I hope it will
be the same old team."
When the convention opened,
he was waiting for that support.
But increasingly iii, the president
staying in San Diego, only sent a note.
Franklin Delano Roosevelt said,
"If I were a delegate to this convention...
...I would vote for Henry A. Wallace."
Despite these words,
it was a cruel blow.
The president was not willing
to fight for his vice president.
But Wallace remained the favorite.
Labor told the president that the strike-
breaking Jimmy Byrnes was not acceptable.
He was out.
Desperate, the bosses
led by Edwin Pauley, Robert Hannegan...
...Ed Flynn, Ed Kelly and others
needed an 11th-hour substitute.
And they settled on Missouri Senator
Harry Truman...
...a man of limited qualifications,
but one with few enemies.
A graduate of high school, he'd been
involved in three failed businesses.
He'd served honorably in World War I.
His most ambitious business venture,
a haberdashery, went belly up in 1922.
And in 1933, he wrote:
Tomorrow I'll be 49...
...but for all the good I have done,
the 40 might as well be left off.
A year later, Kansas City
political boss Tom Pendergast...
...after having been turned down
by his first four choices...
...picked the 50-year-old Truman
to run for the senate.
When asked why, Pendergast replied:
I wanted to demonstrate...
...that a well-oiled machine could send
an office boy to the senate.
Shunned by most senators...
...who dismissed him
as the Senator from Pendergast...
...and failing to gain Roosevelt's
endorsement in his re-election bid...
...Truman worked hard to achieve
respectability in his second senate term.
But a Gallup poll on the opening day...
...showed 65 percent supporting Wallace
as vice president...
...Jimmy Byrnes had 3 percent of the vote,
and Truman came in eighth with 2 percent.
As Wallace arrived at the convention labor
leaders Hillman and Murray had delivered.
Wallace supporters were there
by the thousands.
Murray, in a thick Scottish accent,
shouted to his men:
"Wallace! That's it! Just keep pounding!"
The future must bring equal wages
for equal work...
...regardless of sex or race.
Wallace's speech
was interrupted constantly by applause.
A chant of, "We Want Wallace,"
filled the hall.
We want Wallace! We want Wallace!
We want Wallace!
Someone hijacked the loudspeakers...
...and played Wallace's campaign song
with its chorus:
"Iowa, Iowa,
that's where the tall corn grows."
Iowa...
That's where the tall corn grows...
Furious, Ed Pauley threatened
to cut the sound to the amplifiers.
A victorious vote was almost a foregone
conclusion, a Wallace victory was certain.
Florida Senator Pepper realized if he got
Wallace's name in nomination this night...
...Wallace would sweep the convention.
He fought his way through the crowd
to get to the microphone.
But the bosses were now demanding
that Session Chair Samuel Jackson adjourn.
This chaos was a fire hazard,
they screamed.
Not knowing what to do,
Jackson called the vote for adjournment.
A few said aye,
but the overwhelming majority boomed nay.
And yet, Jackson had the gall to announce
that the vote to adjourn had passed.
It was outrageous.
Confusion filled the hall.
Pepper had reached the first step
of the stage, only five feet...
...probably nine seconds
from the microphone...
...before the bosses forced adjournment
against the win of the delegates.
If he could have nominated Wallace
in those moments...
...there's no doubt Henry Wallace would've been
overwhelmingly returned as vice president.
"What I understood," Pepper wrote,
"was that for better or worse...
...history was turned topsy-turvy
that night in Chicago."
Samuel Jackson apologized to Pepper
the next day...
...and Pepper wrote in his autobiography
that Jackson said;
"I had strict instructions from Hannegan...
...not to let the convention nominate
the vice-president last night."
Hillman and Murray rallied the same troops
to return the next day...
...and see it through to victory.
But over that night, Edwin Pauley and the anti-
Wallace forces united behind Harry Truman.
Deals were cut. Positions offered.
Ambassadorships,
postmaster positions. Cash payoffs.
Bosses called every state chairman...
...telling them that Roosevelt wanted
the Missouri senator as his running mate.
Bob Hannegan managed to put up
16 favorite son nominees...
...to draw votes away from Wallace...
...and then channeled those votes
to Truman.
Even so, the next day when voting began,
things started to swing Wallace's way again.
Iowa, the greatest agricultural state
in the union...
...gives to this convention and to the
Democratic Party its illustrious...
...distinguished son Henry A. Wallace...
...for this nomination of the vice
presidency of the United States.
We want Wallace!
We want Wallace! We want Wallace!
When the first ballot ended,
it was Wallace 429, to Truman's 319.
Then a second ballot got underway...
...and now the deals the bosses
had made kicked into action.
Jackson announced that the second
ballot would begin at once...
...therefore, no new convention tickets
would be honored.
Mayor Kelly's police barred thousands
more of Wallace's supporters from the hall.
But those inside began chanting as before,
attempting to drown out the proceedings.
Wallace started the second ballot
firmly in the lead...
...but gradually he lost
ground to Truman...
...as the nominees put up by Hannegan signed
over their votes to Truman, one by one.
Truman prevailed. It was over.
I guess this is just another lost cause,
Mr. Paine.
All you people don't know
about lost causes.
Mr. Paine does.
He said once they were the only causes
worth fighting for.
And he fought for them once.
And I loved you for it.
And you know that you fight for the
lost causes harder than for any others.
Yes, you even die for them.
You think I'm licked.
You all think I'm licked.
Well, I'm not licked!
And I'm gonna stay right here
and fight for this lost cause!
Even if this room gets filled with lies
like these...
...and the Taylors and all their armies
come marching into this place...
...somebody will listen to me.
Henry Wallace, accepting his defeat..
...pledged his loyalty
to the Roosevelt-Truman ticket...
...and agreed to remain in the cabinet.
Today, buried by the traditional tale
of the Second World War...
...the events of the 1944 Democratic
Convention have been largely forgotten.
They would however change
the course of history.
The man who might have been president...
...could now only watch from the sidelines
as events unfolded.
There were other deals going on
behind the scenes in this critical year.
Mistrusting Roosevelt's
optimism in Europe...
...Churchill flew to Moscow in October
1944, to meet alone with Stalin.
Based on the previous experience of U.S.
isolationism after the First World War...
...neither leader seriously believed...
...that American troops would
remain in Europe after the war.
Therefore it was vital to Churchill that he shore
up the British position as strongly as possible.
On the back of a scrap of paper...
...Churchill proposed the share of influence
each nation would exert in postwar Europe.
The U.S.S.R. would get
90 percent in Romania...
...75 percent in Hungary and Bulgaria.
Yugoslavia would be split 50/50,
but Britain would get 90 percent in Greece.
Greece was vital to the British position
in the Mediterranean...
...close to Egypt
and the strategic Suez Canal...
...through which came the trade
which kept the empire alive.
From Eastern Africa
through the Middle East, the near east...
...and at the heart of this empire, India,
the crown jewel...
...and beyond it the far east,
where Singapore was now British again.
Although
Churchill wanted a non-communist Poland...
...the truth was that Poland was simply
off the agenda...
...and Churchill was more concerned
with safeguarding British power.
Stalin took the paper and made a large check
with a blue pencil before handing it back.
Churchill remarked:
Might it not be thought rather cynical...
...if it seemed
we had disposed of these issues...
...so fateful to millions of people
in such an offhand manner?
Let us burn the paper.
But Stalin urged Churchill
to hold onto the historic scrap of paper...
...which Churchill called
a naughty document.
For the first time on record...
...Stalin came to the airport
to wish his guests Godspeed.
This was exactly the kind of secret deal...
...that Roosevelt had set out to prevent.
At a press conference in 1944, he'd said
of British Gambia in West Africa...
...which he had visited the previous year:
It's the most horrible thing
I've ever seen in my life.
The natives are 5000 years back of us.
The British have been there 200 years.
For every dollar that the British have
put into Gambia, they have taken out 10.
It's just plain exploitation.
Roosevelt spoke repeatedly
about a postwar trusteeship system...
...that would prepare the colonies
for independence.
One of these would be Indochina...
...which he insisted not be given
back to the French after the war...
...as Churchill and the French exiled
leader Charles De Gaulle demanded.
Roosevelt told Cordell Hun,
his secretary of state in 1944...
...that France has had the country 30
million inhabitants for nearly 100 years...
...and the people are worse off
than they were at the beginning.
Churchill told his number two,
Anthony Eden, in late '44:
There must be no question...
...our being hustled
or seduced into declarations...
...affecting British sovereignty
in any of the dominions or colonies.
Hands off the British
empire is our maxim...
...and it must not be
weakened or smirched...
...to ease sob-stuff merchants at home
or foreigners of any hue.
British soldiers have returned to Greece.
And historic Athens, capital of ancient
freedom, eagerly awaits liberation.
Churchill sent British
troops into Athens...
...to repress the left-wing
and communist partisans...
...who had led the underground resistance
to the Nazis...
...and were now battling for power...
...against reactionary forces
who wanted to restore the king.
But the Greek people did not want
to exchange the Nazis for the old monarch.
Street fighting raged
through the Greek capital.
Churchill ordered his men
to treat Athens as a conquered city.
The British General Scobie
called in dive bombers.
Stalin however, refused to back the partisans,
delivering on his bargain to Churchill.
Roosevelt is reported to have said:
How the British can dare such a thing!
The lengths they will go
to hang on to the past.
With the dawn of victory in Europe...
...Roosevelt, Stalin and Churchill met
for the second and last time at Yalta...
...on the Back Sea in early February.
The Soviet Union was preoccupied
with its security.
Britain was preserving its empire.
The U.S. wanted Soviet assistance
in ending the Pacific War...
...and support for a world economy
open to US trade and investment...
...and for establishing a United Nations
to preserve the new peace.
Roosevelt's doctors had begged him
not to go to Yalta.
The president was weakening daily,
but his vast spirit kept him going.
It's been a global war, and we've
already started making it a global peace.
There was little time to waste.
And though they didn't see eye to eye
on Germany, the big three agreed...
...to a complete disarmament, demilitarization
and dismemberment of Germany.
They would divide the conquered nation
into four military zones...
...with one controlled by France.
The U.S. still had one
major card to play...
...postwar economic assistance to help
the Soviets rebuild their shattered nation.
A reparations commission was established based
on an estimated figure of $20 billion...
...with half going to the Soviet Union.
This was the carrot.
Poland was the focus
of seven of Yalta's eight sessions.
Ultimately the three leaders compromised...
...on a Polish provisional government
of national unity...
...which was admittedly vague...
...intended to include democratic leaders
from outside Poland.
Naval Chief of Staff William Leahy, a veteran
of the Spanish-American and first world wars...
...warned Roosevelt:
This is so elastic that the Russians can stretch
it all the way from Yalta to Washington...
...without technically breaking it.
- Roosevelt agreed.
- I know, Bill. I know it.
But it's the best I can do for Poland
at this time.
In truth, the United States
and Britain had lost their leverage...
...by failing to open up the second front
until very late in the war.
So at the end of the day, F.D.R. didn't give
anything at Yalta that Stalin didn't already have.
On the other hand, Stalin was in no rush to
institute revolutionary change, if at all.
As in Greece,
he recognized that the communists...
...although they'd often played a leading
role in anti-Nazi resistance movements...
...represented a minority element
in most of these liberated nations.
Never having shared Trotsky's zeal
for international communism...
...he had once remarked that communism
fit Poland like a saddle fit a cow.
It was these conflicts,
primarily over Poland...
...that would eventually tear
the alliance apart.
But most importantly to Roosevelt...
...Stalin definitely committed the U.S.S.R.
to join the war against Japan...
...three months after the close
of the European war.
There were still close to 2 million
Japanese soldiers in China.
And without Soviet aid,
the war could drag on indefinitely.
In return Roosevelt and Churchill promised
territorial and economic inducements...
...that would essentially restore what the
Russians had lost to Japan in their 1904-5 war.
Additionally, the big three reached
some agreements on the United Nations...
...which was set to convene
in April of '45...
...and a system of trusteeships to deal
with the liberated colonial territories.
Although there were many vagaries left...
...when it came to the British and French
empires in Indochina Africa and Asia.
News of Yalta ignited a kind of optimism
that hadn't been seen for decades.
Former President Herbert Hoover called the
conference a great hope to the world.
C.B.S. war correspondent William Shirer, who
later authored the renowned bestseller...
...The Rise and Fall of the Third Reich
declared it a landmark in human history.
Roosevelt returned in triumph.
Addressing Congress for the first time
without standing on his braces...
...he called for acceptance of the results.
As the beginnings
of a permanent structure of peace...
...upon which we can begin to build,
under God...
...that better world in which our children
and grandchildren...
...yours and mine...
...the children and grandchildren
of the whole world, must live and can live.
For Franklin Delano Roosevelt...
...it was an amazing conclusion
to an amazing life.
The Yalta Agreement
would forever be controversial...
...and Roosevelt would be unfairly attacked
for capitulating to Stalin.
And in the weeks to follow...
...disagreements with the Soviets surfaced
over Poland and other issues.
But Roosevelt never lost hope
and in his last cable to Churchill wrote:
I would minimize
the Soviet problem as much as possible...
...because these problems in one form
or another seem to arise every day...
...and most of them straighten out.
Roosevelt truly thought
he would live to enforce the peace.
But less than two months later
after 12 years in office...
...his great, great heart finally gave out
when he died of a massive stroke.
The longest-serving president
in American history...
...Roosevelt saw
the country through its hardest times...
...the Great Depression and Great War.
Without him, the postwar peace
that was achieved at Yalta...
...between the British and American empires
and Soviet communism...
...could not be maintained.
In-between these giants, America's new
president was a shadow of his predecessor...
...and he openly admitted it.
As the nation is plunged into mourning...
...Harry S. Truman becomes president,
the seventh American...
On his first day in office...
...a group of reporters asked
how the job was going and Truman replied:
Boys, if you ever pray, pray for me now.
I don't know whether you fellows
ever had a load of hay fall on you...
...but when they told me yesterday
what happened...
...I felt like the moon, the stars
and all the planets had fallen on me.
We got the most terribly responsible job
a man ever had.
- When a reporter yelled out,
"Good luck, Mr. -
I wish you didn't have to can me that.
This was not false humility
on Truman's part.
He'd only been vice president for 82 days
and only spoken to Roosevelt twice.
But neither Roosevelt or anyone else...
...had ever bothered to inform
the tightly-regarded vice president...
...that the United States was building
the most powerful weapon in history.
On April 15th, Truman and Wallace...
...who had remained in the cabinet
as Secretary of Commerce...
...met the funeral train
at Washington's Union Station.
There was another man with them,
Jimmy Byrnes...
...Truman's old mentor
from his senate days...
...who had befriended the Missourian
at a time when most senators avoided him...
...as a Pendergast political hack.
Impressed with the fact that Byrnes
had accompanied Roosevelt to Yalta...
...although he found out later
that he'd left the conference early...
...and was not in
on the important discussions...
Truman came to rely on Byrnes
above all others for advice.
Byrnes gave Truman his first real briefing
about the atomic bomb...
...which he described as an explosive
great enough to destroy the whole world...
...that might well put us in a position to
dictate our own terms at the end of the war.
He did not specify exactly to whom
the U.S. would be dictating those terms.
With great humility,
I call upon all Americans...
...to help me keep our nation united...
...in defense of those ideals...
...which have been so eloquently proclaimed
by Franklin Roosevelt.
This turns out to be a crucial moment
in the history of the world...
...and much of it has been forgotten,
but it is well worth revisiting.
The first to see Truman after Roosevelt's
death on April 13th...
...was Secretary of State
Edward Stettinius.
The former U.S. Steel Chairman of the Board
had had very little influence with Roosevelt.
But for Truman, Stettinius painted a
picture of Soviet deception and perfidy...
...saying that Britain's Churchill
felt even more strongly.
And Churchill wasted little time
confirming that view both in cables...
...and in a hurried visit to Washington
from his Foreign Secretary Anthony Eden.
The British ambassador to the U.S.,
Lord Halifax, sized Truman up...
...saying the new president was an honest
and diligent mediocrity.
A bungling, if welt-meaning amateur...
...surrounded by Missouri county courthouse
caliber friends.
That afternoon Truman met
with Jimmy Byrnes.
Admitting his abject ignorance...
...he implored Byrnes to tell him about
everything from Teheran to Yalta...
...and everything else under the sun.
Byrnes gladly accommodated.
In a series of meetings,
Byrnes reinforced Stettinius's message...
...that the Soviets were breaking
their Yalta agreements...
...and implored Truman to be, above all,
uncompromising with them.
Truman made clear his intention
to make Byrnes Secretary of State...
...as soon as Stettinius had gotten
the United Nations off the ground.
In this atmosphere ambassador
to the Soviet Union Averell Harriman...
...having rushed back from Moscow...
...warned that the U.S. was facing
a barbarian invasion of Europe...
...and urged Truman to stand firm and tell
Foreign Minister Molotov in Washington...
...that we would not stand for any
pushing around on the Polish question.
As soon as the Russians had control
over a country, Harriman said...
...the secret police moved in
and wiped out free speech.
But he clarified that the Soviets
would not risk a break with the U.S...
...because they desperately sought
the postwar reconstruction aid...
...that Roosevelt had promised them.
Truman masked his limited understanding
of the issues with bluster and bravado...
...telling Harriman he didn't expect to get 100
percent of what he wanted from the Russians...
...but he did expect to get 85 percent.
It is important to note that many of the most
vociferous critics of the Soviet Union...
...shared a similar class background and a deep
hatred for anything that smacked of socialism.
Harriman was the son of a rail road tycoon
who had founded Brown Brothers, Harriman.
James Forrestal had made a fortune
on Wall Street.
Stettinius had been chairman of the board
of the nation's largest corporation.
They were joined by enormously wealthy
international bankers...
...Wall Street and Washington lawyers...
...and corporate executives
who had mostly inherited...
...or made their fortunes
during the interwar years.
These men would come
to shape postwar U.S. policy...
...and included Dean Acheson, Robert Lovett,
John McCloy, John Foster and Allen Dulles.
Nelson Rockefeller, Paul Nitze, and General
Motors President Charles Wilson...
...who as head of the war production board
had said...
...that the United States
needed a Permanent war economy.
Although they had sewed Roosevelt,
they had in fact little influence on him.
Opposed to this antagonistic point of view
towards the Soviets were the veterans.
Secretary of War Henry Stimson, Army Chief
of Staff General George Marshall...
...and Former Vice President
Henry Wallace.
Admiral William Leahy again noted the
elasticity of the Yalta agreement...
...and the difficulty of alleging bad faith
on that basis.
In fact he said, after Yalta
he would have been surprised...
...had the Soviets behaved
differently than they had.
Marshall, who Time Magazine
had named Man of The Year for 1943...
...contended that a break with the Soviets
would be disastrous...
...given U.S. dependence on them
to help defeat the Japanese.
The Conservative Secretary of War
Henry Stimson...
...who had fought the Ute Indians
in the 19th century...
...and still liked to be called The Colonel
was long practiced in the ways of the world.
When confronted by the issues
of acquisition by force...
...he explained that the U.S.S.R.
had been a trustworthy ally...
...often delivering even more than had been
promised, especially in military matters.
He reminded the president of Poland's
importance to Russia, and said:
The Russians
are probably being more realistic...
...about their own security than we are.
He had previously noted that Russia:
Prior to 1914 had owned
the whole of Poland...
...including Warsaw, as far as Germany...
...and that she was not asking
for restitution of that.
He added that,
outside the U.S. and Britain...
...very few countries shared the western
understanding of free elections.
Nonetheless in his first meeting with Soviet
Foreign Minister Molotov on April the 23rd...
...11 days after Roosevelt's death...
Truman wasted little time accusing the Soviets
of having broken their Yalta Agreement...
...particularly in Poland.
When Molotov tried to explain the Yalta-Polish
agreement through Stalin's eyes...
Truman dismissed his clarifications.
When Molotov raised other issues,
Truman snapped:
That will be all, Mr. Molotov.
I would appreciate it if you would
transmit my views to Marshal Stalin.
I've never been talked
to like that in my life.
Carry out your agreements
and you won't get talked to like that.
Molotov stormed out of the room.
After the meeting, Truman boasted:
I gave it to him straight.
I let him have it.
It was a straight one-two to the jaw.
His bullying of the Soviet
Foreign Minister...
...probably conjured up images...
...of 5'4" John "Peanuts" Truman...
...the 5'8" President's father...
...who, back in Missouri, would pick fights with
men a foot taller to show how tough he was.
He wanted that same toughness in his sons and
found it in Harry's younger brother Vivian.
Harry however, was diagnosed
with flat eyeballs...
...and forced to wear
coke-bottle-thick glasses.
He could not play sports
and he was bullied by the other boys...
...who called him Four-Eyes and sissy
and chased him home after school.
When he arrived home trembling, his mother would
comfort him by telling him not to worry...
...because he was meant
to be a girl anyway.
Gender issues plagued him for years.
He would often refer
to his feminine features and attributes.
Economic hardship added to his woes.
No sissy anymore, he now proved...
...he could stand up to leaders of the
second most powerful nation in the world.
His father, whose approval he struggled
unsuccessfully to win when he was alive...
...would have been proud of him now.
Stalin, feeling betrayed...
...wasted no time cabling Truman the following
day, insisting that Roosevelt had agreed...
...that the pro-Soviet Polish government
would form the kernel of the new government.
He added he didn't know if the governments of
Belgium or Greece were really democratic...
...but he wouldn't make a stink because
they were vital to British interests.
These were strong words.
And where the opening of the United Nations in San
Francisco two days later on April the 25th...
...should have been an occasion to celebrate
a new era in International peace...
...it was instead ruined by tension
between the allies.
The Russian request to have the pro-Soviet
government seated to represent Poland...
...was rejected.
After that
relations continued to deteriorate rapidly.
Realizing that his get-tough tactics
had not produced the desired results...
...Truman met twice with Joseph Davies,
the former ambassador to the Soviet Union.
A conservative corporate attorney,
he'd surprised liberal critics...
...by sympathizing
with the Soviet experiment.
Davies counseled Truman that the
Soviets had always been sticklers...
...for reciprocity between allies.
So they accepted British-imposed
governments in Africa, Italy and Greece...
...even though they did not represent the
anti-fascist forces in those countries...
...because they understood these were
vital interests to America and Britain.
And they expected similar consideration for
their vital security interests in Poland.
Davies noted how fundamentally
the relationship had changed...
...in the last six weeks,
with the British acting as instigators...
...and warned that if the Russians decide the
US and Britain are ganging up on them...
...they'll respond by
out-toughing the west...
...as they did in concluding
the 1939 Pact with Hitler...
...when it became clear that the west
would not help them stop the Nazis.
But he assured Truman that when approached
with generosity and friendliness...
...the Soviets respond
with even greater generosity.
Davies agreed to set up a meeting
between Truman and Stalin.
In that same crucial month,
a few days after Roosevelt's death...
...the Soviets had amassed three armies
of 2.5 million men to take Berlin...
...and end forever
Hitler's 1000-year Reich.
But incredibly, the Germans
were still able, with all their losses...
...to muster an enormous defense of 1 million
men with fortified bunkers, air, artillery.
Their most fanatical recruits in this
terrible Gotterdammerung, child soldiers.
It was the Third Reich's last stand.
The battle was bloody.
Eighty thousand Russian
troops were killed...
...at least 300,000 casualties,
fighting street to street.
Berlin fell in four days.
Hitler and his long-term mistress Eva Braun
married and the next day committed suicide.
Seeking revenge for the German rape
of the U.S.S.R...
...and further fueled
by what they had witnessed...
...liberating the concentration camps of
Majdanek, Sobibor, Treblinka and Auschwitz...
...en route to Berlin, the Soviet soldiers
behaved brutally towards the vanquished Germans.
Stalin did nothing to stop it.
But when reports began to fill the world's
airwaves of vast hordes of Soviet soldiers...
...raping their way through Germany...
...orders came from above to stop
and the rapes stopped.
The stories continued up to
2 million women, some claimed, were raped.
In just a few weeks over 100,000
did seek medical care for rape.
As part of the intended Roosevelt-Stalin
plan for the pastoralization of Germany...
...Soviet officials in
the first few months...
...shipped 100,000 rail cars
of construction materials...
...and personal goods back to Russia.
Some to help rebuild
the shattered economy...
...and some like furs, paintings, gold
and jewels for purely monetary purposes.
But as a result, the worldwide perception
of the Soviet Union endured...
...that it was a barbaric and brutal
semi-Asian nation...
...invading what had once been
civilized Europe.
The dictionary definition of empathy
is the imaginative projection...
...or capacity for participating
in another's feelings or ideas.
But Truman did not seem capable
of comprehending the pain and suffering...
...of the Soviet people or their motives.
Roosevelt, a man who had suffered
from polio in his life...
...had understood that the war had been won
by Soviet sacrifice...
...and that peace now
depended on mutual respect.
Even Churchill had admitted
the Soviet army tore the guts...
...out of the German military machine.
Stalin was a tyrant, absolutely,
a ruthless paranoid dictator...
...who disdained
the U.S. concept of democracy.
But he was also in the tradition
of the cruelest tsars.
He had clearly gotten
along with Roosevelt...
...and had, according to
several high-level witnesses...
...kept his word to Roosevelt.
He desperately wanted friendly relations
with the U.S. to continue.
But as the cold war descended...
...the laurels of the U.S.S.R.'s victory
over Nazi Germany were stolen...
...or rather, forgotten.
It would take another 20 years
for another U.S. president and veteran...
...John Fitzgerald Kennedy, who had lived
his entire life in some degree of pain...
...and with the prospect of death...
...to pay homage
to the Soviet contribution in World War II.
No nation in the history of battle...
...ever suffered more than the Soviet Union
in the Second World War.
At least 20 million lost their lives.
Countless millions of homes
and families were burned or sacked.
A third of the nation's territory including
two-thirds of its industrial base...
...was turned into a wasteland.
A loss equivalent to the destruction
of this country East of Chicago.
Germany officially surrendered May 7th.
The war in Europe has ended.
Unconditionally and finally our German
enemy has surrendered to Russia...
...to Britain and her commonwealth,
to America...
...to the millions who fought with their hearts
and souls, to the people of all free nations.
As V-E Day was celebrated
around the world...
...it also meant
that the Soviets as agreed at Yalta...
...would enter the Pacific War
around August 8th...
...almost three months
before the November 1 start date...
...for the planned allied invasion
of Mainland Japan.
When Truman and Byrnes,
now appointed Secretary of State...
...met with Stalin and Churchill in the most
important conference of World War II...
...at Potsdam in a suburb of Berlin...
...they were waiting for news of the secret
atomic tests in the desert of Alamogordo.
Truman had pushed the start
of the summit back two weeks to mid-July...
...and hoped the bomb would be tested
before negotiations with Stalin began.
In the desert Robert Oppenheimer said:
"We were under incredible pressure
to get it done before the Potsdam meeting.
It turned out, from Truman's perspective,
to be worth the wait."
On July 16th while Truman was
touring bombed-out Berlin...
...and preparing for the next day's meeting
with Stalin...
...scientists exploded
the first atomic bomb.
It exceeded all expectations.
Some scientists even feared
they had indeed set the atmosphere on fire.
Groves cabled the preliminary results
to Stimson...
...who rushed to brief Truman and Byrnes.
They were elated. They knew that
they had a date with destiny.