Before the war,
the Republic of Bosnia and Herzegovina
was part of one of the most
ethnically and religiously
diverse countries in Europe.
Muslims, Serbs and Croats
lived together in harmony.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Bosnia and Herzegovina 1992
(POP MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(BABY COOING)
(BOTH SINGING ALONG)
Go get ready.
Get out of here.
Come to Mommy.
Go, go, go, go.
Okay.
It's too much!
You look gorgeous!
Great! Come here.
What are you doing?
Just this.
A bit like this.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, come on!
Okay, show me "sexy."
What?
(IN SULTRY VOICE)
What time is it?
(LAUGHS)
(IN NORMAL VOICE) And this.
Don't forget this.
Thanks for helping me with him.
That's what I came back here for.
I'm so excited for you.
Do you remember how to get there?
No, no. Keep it.
Bye.
Have fun.
I love you.
(PLAYING SLOW MUSIC)
You are worth the wait.
(LAUGHING)
Stop.
I have something for you.
(PLAYING UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC)
(ALL SINGING ALONG)
(ALL CHEERING)
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
And this song is for lovers.
(PLAYING SLOW MUSIC)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(FOOTSTEPS RUSTLING)
(SIREN WAILING
IN THE DISTANCE)
(WOMAN WAILING)
Have them make more space outside.
Secure the area.
We need more blood.
Okay?
Everything will be all right.
(HUMMING SOFTLY)
IN THE LAND OF BLOOD AND HONEY
Four Months Later
Ajla. Wake up.
(MEN SHOUTING OUTSIDE)
Is that Azra?
I can't see.
Where are they taking the men?
Where's your passport?
I don't know.
I don't know!
SOLDIER: Open the door!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Get your coats and get out.
Out!
Let's go!
DURJA: All the men, up!
Go.
SOLDIER: Let's go!
DURJA: Come on!
Let's go!
MITAR: Come on, come on!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(ALL SCREAM)
(WEEPING)
(FIRING CONTINUES)
(WOMEN WEEPING)
(BABY CRYING)
Come. To the bus.
MITAR: Let's go, let's go.
To the bus.
DURJA: Let's go,
let's go, let's go!
Come on.
ALEKSANDAR: To the bus.
(BABY CRYING LOUDLY)
Where are you taking her?
Don't, don't.
Hey, let's go.
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
(SHUSHING)
(GUNSHOT)
Let's go!
Hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!
Hurry up, grandma.
SOLDIER: Hey!
Tell me.
(CHUCKLES)
Do you know how a shepherd counts sheep?
No. How?
One, two, three, mwah, five, six.
(LAUGHING)
MITAR: Left!
MITAR: Give me your purse.
Give me that coat.
VUC: Which of you can cook?
Not a shit cook, a real cook.
I'm a doctor.
I can sew. Anything you need.
Coats. Curtains.
I can make something for the beds. I can. . .
Can you fuck?
No!
(WIMPERING)
(ESMA WEEPING)
(ESMA SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(ZIPPING PANTS)
SFR JUGOSLAVIJA
DANIJEL: What is all this now, eh?
Is everybody having fun?
Let me do this one.
Are you hiding something from me?
This one's done.
Hurry up! All this is taking too long.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
(BABY CRYING)
(PANTING)
Are you okay?
(SOBBING)
I'm in constant fear that they will come for us.
Everything's going to be all right.
You'll see.
They cut our electricity.
They cut our water.
How can you say everything will be all right?
I don't even know if my sister is alive.
(WEEPING)
I know.
What am I going to do with him?
I have to get out of here.
I have to run away with him.
Maybe on a humanitarian aid convoy.
They're attacking humanitarian aid
convoys as well.
We have to stay calm.
Why don't you get some sleep and let me
play with the little one.
(BABY CRIES)
(SHUSHING)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(WOMAN SINGING SOFTLY)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
You think we are too harsh?
I understand you.
You are young.
You don't care about the past.
We Serbs fought the Turks for 500 years
and stopped them from conquering Europe.
In 1914, we stood against
the Austro-Hungarian Empire,
and we brought it down.
We kicked Hitler's ass, and we won.
One million Serbs were killed in World War ll.
This land is soaked with Serbian blood.
And now they want us to live here
under Muslim rule?
In a Muslim state?
(SCOFFS)
I recognize people.
Sometimes I get into a house
and I recognize their faces.
They're just pretending to
be good neighbors, Danijel.
Under Tito, they hid
their treacherous faces,
waiting for the opportunity to destroy
Yugoslavia and attack us.
I am a Serb patriot.
You don't have to question that.
Are you?
Then why are you questioning our methods?
You think the rest of the world will ignore
all this? I don't.
The UN has already sent peacekeepers to Croatia.
They will not turn their backs
on all of this.
Of course they see everything,
But they will not attack us.
They won't do anything.
And they know we are the right partners
for negotiations.
They need us.
They will not attack.
Bolster your men.
And finish cleansing this area.
You don't want your men to doubt you.
And you, Father?
I had my doubts.
I have to go now.
Do strong work, Danijel.
Make me a proud father.
(ENGINE STARTING)
ESMA: No. No!
Not again,
you swine! No!
Oh, please!
No! Please! No!
(GASPS)
DANIJEL: Enter.
Why did you sit there?
Stand up.
Ajla.
Remember how things were
when it was just you and me
in the club,
before this madness.
Remember.
I couldn't
find you anywhere.
People are often not
what they seem to be.
Do you want to know my secret?
I'm trying to have a conversation
with you here.
Do you want to know my secret, Ajla?
Yes.
I don't like taking part in this war.
To kill people I've gone to school with.
I find this war very difficult to stomach.
But my father, Nebojsa Vukojevich,
General Vukojevich,
thinks differently.
I told my men that they are not
allowed to touch you,
that you are my property.
Go.
Come on, get out!
MALE REPORTER ON TV:
People who leave their homes
are at risk of being shot.
Red Cross and
UN relief convoys,
even women and children
looking for food,
are being targeted.
The images of this attack
galvanized international
opinion against the Serbs.
But Western governments
don't want to intervene
in the conflict.
The American Secretary
of State says, "We don't
have a dog in that fight."
Across Bosnia,
nearly 6,000 people have
been killed to date.
More coffee over here.
A million have been
forced from their homes,
creating Europe's
biggest refugee crisis
in close to 50 years.
The causes of conflict
lie in the breakup,
after 40 years
of Communist rule,
of old Yugoslavia.
Come in, Ajla.
Don't be afraid.
Would you like a drink?
No, sir.
"Sir"?
Danijel.
I had a clear shot today.
One of your Muslim friends was in my scope.
And I'm thinking about you,
wondering,
"Would she thank me if I spared
this poor man's life?"
And then it hit me,
"How can people kill so easily?"
And then I wondered,
"Would she kill me if she could?"
"Would Ajla kill Danijel?"
Did you kill him?
I didn't.
(EXHALES)
Is everything okay with you?
Everything is fine.
MITAR: Hey!
(LAUGHING)
We got a report from headquarters.
The front line is stable.
Muslims are running all over the place.
You have to be more careful of who you shoot at.
UNPROFOR is increasing their presence.
They can see everything now.
The whole world is watching.
So now what?
Radovan and politicians will be kissing
international TV's ass?
They will try to make it look like nothing's
happening. Why?
The UN and UNPROFOR are doing nothing.
They're just standing on the other side.
We won already.
I'm just telling you people,
watch yourselves.
(DOOR OPENING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Enter.
Good evening, Ajla.
Thank you for dinner.
For cleaning up after me.
It's nothing.
It's not nothing.
You have a beautiful smile.
Thank you.
I never asked you,
who were you before the war?
What did you do?
I wanted to be a painter.
I was a painter, I suppose.
I have a painting hanging at the Sarajevo
Municipal Gallery.
In the Gallery?
Really?
Mmm.
But that doesn't really matter now,
does it?
And what did you paint?
People or, what do you call it,
still life?
People.
Usually my sister.
And did you always want to be a policeman?
Some of us don't have a choice.
This was always my family tradition.
SOLDIER: Captain?
Did you find it?
Yes. Yes, that's the one.
Copy it.
Watch and learn.
Yes, sir.
(SOLDIERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
DURJA: Watch where you're going.
Come on, clean it up.
(GASPS)
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
DURJA: Keep practicing.
DURJA: That's it, that's it.
I'm going.
Tomorrow, after lunch,
I'll go to the back of the building.
In the bathroom, above the radiator,
there is a window.
Crawl through it.
I'll wait for you on the other side.
I will not stop you.
Tomorrow?
Get out of the city as soon as you can.
Find a shelter.
And do not come out.
If you have to, do it at night.
We can't see that well at night
and, by then,
my soldiers are drunk.
This will not end soon.
Things will only get worse.
You should know.
Are we so terrible that we all should
be exterminated?
You're not.
I'm sorry.
It's all. . .
It's politics, not murder.
All of this is complicated.
The politics of all this are very complicated.
It is murder,
for political gain.
But still murder.
All the more reason for you to leave tomorrow.
The sooner the better.
I can't protect you forever.
No matter how much I'd want to.
Get some coffee.
Thank you, captain.
(NADJA SOBBING)
I pray I never see my husband again,
so he doesn't find out
what they've done to me.
I want to die.
Try to get some rest.
Got ya.
(LAUGHS)
Careful!
Here's the backpack.
You sure you want to do this?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I'm sick of doing nothing,
and everybody's out of medication.
Bye. See you later.
Don't worry.
(COOING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPS)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
SOLDIER: Get out! Come on!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Get the fuck out,
everyone! Hurry up!
MITAR: Keep going!
Get out! Come on!
SOLDIER 1: Sign it!
SOLDIER 2: Come on, come on!
SOLDIER 3: Step out!
WOMAN: My child is still in the apartment.
SOLDIER 2: Come on, come on!
PETAR: Take your things and sign these papers.
We are returning tomorrow to evacuate you.
Thank you.
Will this be temporary,
or will you have ownership indefinitely?
I won't sign it.
I have nowhere to go.
I have lived here for 30 year. . .
(GUN FIRES)
Sign it.
SOLDIER 1: Get out! Come on!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
PETAR: Get out, everyone!
Would you like me to pour it for you, sir?
Yes.
(WHISPERING)
Listen to me, Ajla.
I have been transferred to Sarajevo.
I have to leave immediately.
I want to remind you of that window.
The best time to escape is one hour after dinner.
By then, everyone is drunk.
Now finish with my coffee,
and go.
(GASPING IN FEAR)
(MEJREMA SOBBING)
(WEEPING) She did everything she could.
She couldn't keep him quiet.
She did everything she could.
Oh, please forgive me.
Where is my son?
(SOBBING)
(WEEPING)
(WAILING)
Headquarters - Sarajevo
Hello.
Welcome.
Happy to see you.
Very good.
Two klicks to the left.
(GUN FIRING)
(GRUNTS)
Let's go home, kids!
My girls are done!
Go home and get some rest.
What's up?
Are you still alive, motherfuckers?
Any news?
This is from Santa Claus.
There's nothing new.
Look!
There's nothing new!
Hey, dicks!
Come on,
fucking pussies!
(FIRES GUN)
That's enough.
Don't fuck around.
(SOLDIERS CHUCKLING)
SOLDIER: Look at that.
Darko.
Where did you go?
My wife is pregnant.
Three months.
Congratulations, my brother.
That's the best news in days.
Captain,
we're gonna finish this war
before the little man is born, huh?
It's a little boy?
It has to be.
(CHUCKLES)
I would love a little girl too much.
She would drive me crazy.
She would make my head spin.
A little girl.
We are doing this for them, huh?
So they don't have to go to war,
when they grow up.
Yes. It's for them.
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
(PRAYING)
(SOLDIERS JINGLE BELLS)
SOLDIERS:
♪ Jingle bells, Jingle bells ♪
♪ Jingle all the night ♪
SOLDIER: Ho, ho, ho!
PETAR: Come on!
DANIJEL: Merry Christmas.
PETAR: Merry Christmas.
Hey. I know this place.
I came here with my mother once.
Fuck your mother.
Watch your language, or I'll fuck you up.
Do you hear me?
What's wrong with you?
It was a joke.
Save your jokes
for someone else.
What's wrong with you?
Fuck off.
Suck my dick.
Aleksandar, look!
Fuck you, too.
Holy warrior.
I've never been to a museum.
(SOLDIER WHOOPING)
(SOLDIER LAUGHING)
ALEKSANDAR: Look at all
these faces here.
(SOLDIER WHISTLING)
Hey, I found this one.
(WHISTLING)
SOLDIER 1: Take it over there.
SOLDIER 2: Throw the sandbag over here.
SOLDIER 3: Bring it here.
I'll help you.
(GUNSHOT)
Who's been hit?
It's all right.
Hey, you all right, old man?
ALEKSANDAR: Are you okay?
Can you hear me?
DARKO: It's okay, it's okay.
You're alive.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Can you hear me?
DARKO: You'll be fine.
You'll be fine.
FEMALE REPORTER ON SPEAKERS:
...Bosnia and Herzegovina
today issued
in half of towns...
Spring 1993
...being pounded
by Serb forces.
The Bosnians say
UN arms embargo...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
...favors the Serb's side
because it already has
all the weapon it needs.
A government spokesperson says
Bosnian patriots are fighting
to defend their territory,
but find themselves
surrounded and outgunned.
Still, they fight on.
HANA: Hey, it's all right.
It's me. Hana.
(SNIFFLING)
Esma.
Esma...
(SCREAMS)
You, in the back.
You, you.
You.
SOLDIER: Come on, hurry up.
DURJA: Come on, get out of the truck!
(GUNSHOTS)
Come out with your hands in the air
and surrender!
It's over!
You don't want to kill your own people!
(MEN WHISPERING)
It's over!
(ECHOING) Come out!
(SCREAMING)
(CUPS BANGING)
Come on!
Hurry up!
Come on, come on!
Get up! Get your things!
Come on!
(POP MUSIC
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
I can't anymore.
(SOBBING)
I just can't.
You know that little window
in the bathroom?
I know.
When they drink after dinner,
the guard is usually a little late.
I think there is a good chance the men will
be distracted tonight.
And why are you telling me this?
Because if I succeed tonight,
you should know how.
Get up! Come on.
Come, come.
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
(SOLDIERS WHOOPING)
Look at them.
Mitar.
Mitar!
Stay behind.
I'll handle it.
And don't drink too much.
I need you sober tomorrow.
Okay, let's go.
Give it to me.
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(GUN FIRING)
(PANTING)
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
What's your name?
Ajla.
What?
Tarik.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
Are you okay?
She's alive?
Yeah.
You know where she is?
Yeah, I do.
She's not far, about two hours away.
Hey, slow down.
I can't, I'm too excited.
Slow down or they'll see us
and kill us. Slow down.
TARIK: It's down here.
Watch your head.
You know, when my mom used to sew,
she wouldn't stop for two days.
TARIK: Lejla.
Come here.
Where is Adi?
They killed Adi.
(SOBBING) They didn't.
They didn't. They didn't.
They didn't.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(PANTING)
TARIK: Dinner! Dinner!
MEHMET: Real food.
LEJLA:
Let's see what we got.
MIRALEM: It's good, it's good.
LEJLA: Here.
MEHMET: (IN ENGLISH)
Oh, look at it.
Meatballs.
TARIK: Anyone have peanut butter?
MIRALEM: Here it is.
I brought it for you.
MEHMET: (IN BOSNIAN)
Here, here.
Look what we got.
Black pepper.
I would kill a man
for small glass of juice.
Yeah. Hey, hey.
Cevapi.
(GASPS)
(MEHMET LAUGHS)
Or sopska salad.
And cola.
Who misses cola?
Steak. Big steak.
Medium rare.
It can be rare.
Or burnt.
Or whatever, just a steak.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Do you know when the plane
with aid arrived?
Early this morning.
And do you know where it was from?
Italy.
Forty minutes away.
No, less.
Peace. Shopping. Dancing.
Yes.
Some tourists sitting in the sun,
Worrying about getting an even tan.
OLD MAN: Everything as it used to be.
You know, it left empty.
It just stopped to drop off supplies
and it left empty.
They took no one.
Not even children?
No.
Lejla, I saw your painting today
in Danijel Vukojevich's office.
My picture?
Yeah.
What is my picture doing
in Danijel Vukojevich's office?
Trust me.
I was peering in with the binoculars and
thought you were standing in the room.
LEJLA: They're all disgusting.
Come on, hold on.
They're not all the same.
MIRALEM: What do you mean?
I can't hate all Serbs.
My mother is a Serb.
LEJLA: Well, I didn't mean Serbs.
I meant Chetnik Serbs.
There is a difference.
MEHMET: We have to do something.
LEJLA: Think again.
Anyone have any ideas?
TARIK: If we get you inside, you can help.
MEHMET: Guys, we're surrounded.
LEJLA: Please be careful.
MEHMET: It's up to us to do it.
No one will help us.
They have surrounded us.
We have to do something.
We need some information.
LEJLA: I don't know.
MEHMET: Will you help us?
I can try.
MEHMET: We have to figure out how to. . .
LEJLA: Are you sure?
AJLA: Of course I want to help.
LEJLA: How will you contact us?
Think about it.
Where should I be?
TARIK: At the water point.
MEHMET: We need. . .
LEJLA: Please watch yourself.
Be smart.
TARIK: Ajla, don't worry.
Be careful.
I'm always careful.
Be cautious.
AJLA: Yes, I will.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on, Bosnian.
Tell me a joke.
No, I don't know any.
Yes, you do.
They caught him in the convoy.
He said he's got information on
hideouts and sniper points.
VUC: You're a good guy.
(TARIK WHIMPERING)
ALEKSANDAR: Let me talk to him.
First and last name.
Tarik Paho.
What is your occupation?
What was your occupation before the war?
I was an assistant baker.
Erlagich.
You had the best rolls in town.
Sir.
I can be of great help to you.
I worked as a spy for them.
And now you're gonna spy for us?
I know where they moved the army of
Bosnia and Herzegovina.
If you give me a map,
I will show you.
Okay. Might as well try.
He's not going anywhere.
That's a nice painting.
Looks like a friend of mine.
And I know her sister.
She's the one who painted it.
Okay.
Show me.
Here. Here, they have been deployed.
(TARIK CONTINUES TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
DANIJEL: Aco, bring me that painter. I want
to have my portrait done.
Why are you fucking with us?
Where is she?
I don't know.
That's her.
Right there.
(PANTING)
(SHRIEKS)
(DOOR LOCKING)
(DOOR OPENING)
I was so happy to see you alive.
Last time I saw you,
I couldn't get you to leave.
Was I wrong to assume
you wanted to be with me?
No.
Don't be afraid of me.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Good morning, Ajla.
And what do your men think of you bringing
a Muslim breakfast?
You worry about me.
Am I your prisoner?
You're a prisoner only if you don't
want to be here.
You are my official painter now.
Am I?
Yes, you are.
Then I have nothing to fear.
A pear.
Probably the last pear in all of Bosnia.
Enjoy it.
(SOLDIER WHOOPING)
(INAUDIBLE)
The room at the far end.
Do you know where to go?
SOLDIER: Yes, sir.
Don't.
You look like a pirate.
Winter 1994
Just yesterday these Muslims killed
47 people. Civilians.
Those motherfuckers will pay for this.
I swear.
This is going to be the last winter of the war.
We now control more than 80%
of the territory.
By springtime,
we will finish our work,
and there will be peace in Bosnia.
SENIOR OFFICER: Danijel is a good boy.
He grew up into a real man.
Strong.
His men love him.
Just. . .
He's been keeping a girl for too long.
A Muslim girl.
I don't know, maybe it's not true.
People like to talk. . .
They say he doesn't let anyone near her.
I'll gather the men.
AJLA: Wine.
Is it your birthday?
No.
Is it yours?
When is your birthday?
End of November.
Yours?
May 11th.
I missed it, then.
(SIGHS)
We now control more than 80%
of the territory.
I'm not sure how I'm supposed
to feel about that.
I'm sorry.
You were at the camp today.
How do you know?
I heard your men talking in the courtyard.
What is it like there?
Is it the way I imagine it?
It's worse.
Camps are the worst part of war.
Nobody can deny that.
Why aren't you eating?
Come on, eat.
Look how skinny you are.
What's wrong?
What is going on, Ajla?
Sometimes I feel so much guilt for
being here with you.
Come on. It really doesn't matter.
(POURS WINE)
It would make no difference if you
were out there with them.
But I don't have to sleep with their murderer.
(SIGHS)
You think your people don't kill, huh?
You think you're better?
Innocent?
You know nothing about my war.
Nothing.
Just so you know,
you started the war.
And I'm the monster now?
I didn't mean it.
Then what did you mean?
(GASPS)
You are afraid of me now.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SOBBING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Let's dance.
Excuse me?
You're crazy.
Am l?
You're there lying alone
and I'm here dancing.
Who's the crazy one, then?
(INAUDIBLE)
(DOOR OPENING)
Get dressed.
Did you paint this?
Yes.
Paint my portrait.
Name?
Ajla.
Surname?
Ekmecic.
Age?
28.
Are you married?
No.
(CAP CLATTERING ON FLOOR)
You have gentle hands.
Lady's hands.
My mother's hands were rough and cracked.
Always black from the earth
she had to work,
so that Muslim ladies
could wear silk dresses.
She had to feed seven children.
She was in the field
that morning when they came.
August '44.
With her three older sons,
and my sister, Milica,
four years old.
I was the youngest.
My grandmother had taken me
and two of my brothers
to the side of the mountain
to look after the cows.
Thirteenth Handzar Division,
full of Turks and Ustashas,
was passing by.
They found a woman
with children in the field,
and they killed them all.
They slaughtered them.
And left them to rot.
Half of my village was killed that day.
Your hands are white.
My grandfather was a Partisan.
I was raised to know no difference between
Serbs, Croats and Muslims.
Yeah.
Some of you were.
Clear your desk.
You and your driving.
Cold, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
(AJLA WHIMPERING)
It's an old truck, captain.
We need a new one.
A better one.
Yeah, it could be a Red Cross truck so
no one shoots at us.
An ambulance?
Stop fucking around.
MARKO: Captain?
You need to sign this.
What is it?
Do you have a pen?
Wait.
Come on.
Here it is.
Give it to me.
Thank you.
Hey, boss.
Open the door!
Open the door now!
(DOOR OPENS)
You.
What did you do?
You brought me here!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You did this!
What did I do?
Your father did. . .
Liar!
What did you do?
You're lying, you bitch!
You're lying!
Your father!
He let him in!
No, he didn't!
You're lying, you bitch!
You're lying!
(BOTH PANTING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
How was she?
Good.
What do you see in our future, Petar?
See these buildings there?
Yeah.
We'll wait for the fire to go out,
and then we'll clear it.
Start afresh.
Maybe we could. . .
Get out.
Knock before you enter the room of
a commanding officer.
(PANTING)
Do you hear me?
Your mother would turn in her grave
if she knew what you're doing.
You think it's all right
to be with a Muslim whore?
Do you think it's all right?
Danijel.
Son, get rid of her.
That's not for you.
Trust me.
That's bad blood.
Danijel.
We must get rid of them.
Do you hear me?
Get rid of her, son.
Let me deal with this on my own.
On my own.
(DOOR OPENS)
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTING)
Don't!
(PANTING)
PRISONER: Nebojsa.
My friend!
We are the same.
We're all Bosnians!
Nebojsa, I know you!
(ENGINE STARTING)
(GUN FIRING)
I should be able to trust you.
Did I make a mistake?
No.
(SOBBING)
I'm afraid I did.
Are you my enemy?
No.
Am I your enemy?
(BOTH PANTING)
Why weren't you born a Serb?
MAN ON RADIO:
In other news...
Summer 1995
...at the United Nations
today, the U.S. Ambassador,
Madeleine Albright
presented evidence of mass
graves near the Bosnian
town of Srebrenica.
Albright says the satellite
photos support allegations
that the Serb forces,
who captured the area
last month,
systematically executed
the Muslim men and boys
who came into their custody.
The Red Cross claims
at least 7,000 men
from Srebrenica
are missing and feared dead.
Three men who escaped
from the Bosnian town
were reported to have...
(RADIO CHANNEL CHANGING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(LAUGHING)
Thank you.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(DOOR OPENING)
I thought you left.
Put this on.
(DOOR OPENING)
You look beautiful.
Where is everyone?
I gave them a night off.
Beautiful, huh?
I love his brushstrokes.
So bold.
I always wanted to touch it.
So do it.
I can't.
(CHUCKLES)
There's no one here.
We're alone, just you and l.
It's more about the empty space.
The "empty space"?
Mmm-hmm.
It's the choice not to do something there.
Look!
I found one I like.
No, really.
I like this one.
The Story of Empty Space.
Very funny.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I have to go to the front line
again tomorrow.
Do you?
When are you coming back?
I'm not sure.
But by Wednesday night,
I'll get in touch with you.
How?
I will order my cook to punish you.
(CHUCKLES)
If you get no dinner
on Wednesday night,
that means I'm safe.
Then I'll be happy to starve that night.
Why Wednesday?
On Wednesday,
we meet in the church
across from the museum.
Whoever makes it there is safe.
They're not bombing churches?
They're not bombing churches,
which works in our favor.
So don't worry.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Stay here.
Darko.
Your father is asking for you.
Did something happen?
I don't know.
He called an urgent meeting
for all senior officers.
You go.
I'll follow.
(VEHICLE DEPARTING)
(DOOR OPENING)
I have to go.
What's happening?
Go home on your own.
Just follow the road up the hill.
Will you be all right?
Yes.
NEBOJSA: Here it is, my friends.
NATO has already started bombing
our positions.
That fucking Clinton
is trying to save his political ass
at home in Washington.
Ljubo, give it to me.
Here.
Just read this.
"Intervening to put an end
to ethnic cleansing
"and mass atrocities."
Apparently they need to save face,
make some noise,
and throw their idea of justice at
a country they know
nothing about. That's it.
We expect that our position,
our area,
will be hit at any time.
But it doesn't matter.
Six hundred years after
the Battle of Kosovo,
here we are again.
On the eve of the Kosovo battle, King Lazar
chose the heavenly kingdom
over the earthly one.
And tonight, my brothers,
we have the same choice before us.
We will not negotiate.
We will not be humiliated.
That's right.
They're attacking us.
And, once again,
we Serbs will be unbreakable.
To Serbs.
ALL: To Serbs!
To freedom!
ALL: To freedom!
(ALL SINGING)
(PLAYING ACCORDION)
(EXPLOSIONS IN THE DISTANCE)
MITAR: Left, left!
Go left!
(GUN FIRES)
DARKO: Let's go down there!
(EXPLOSION IN THE DISTANCE)
(SOBBING)
Aco!
(GUN FIRES)
That piece of shit!
(GRUNTS IN ANGER)
(DANIJEL YELLING)
(PLANES WHOOSHING OVERHEAD)
VUC: Go, go!
Go, go, go!
Go, go, go! Go!
(EXPLOSION)
VUC: Hey!
Hey, Darko.
(GASPING)
Darko.
(EXHALES)
SOLDIER 1: It's okay, it's okay.
SOLDIER 2: I got it, I got it.
Watch out.
Watch yourselves.
SOLDIER 2: Come on, hurry up.
It's me, we are at the church.
No dinner tonight for the painter, okay?
Understand?
(GUNS FIRING IN THE DISTANCE)
Are you surprised to see me alive,
you Turkish pig!
Why are you here?
To be with you.
Where did you go that night?
(SCREAMS)
Were you with your Muslim friends?
Did you tell them I was in the church?
I saw your sister.
I'm sorry.
(GUN FIRES)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING
IN THE DISTANCE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Hey!
Stop!
I said stop!
Raise your hands up.
Stop!
Put your hands up.
My name is Danijel Vukojevich.
I am a war criminal.
For three and a half years,
the international community failed
to decisively intervene
and stop the war in Bosnia.
The siege of Sarajevo was the longest
in modern history.
Across the country, 1 in every 2 Bosnians was
forced to flee their homes.
During the war, as many as fifty thousand
Bosnian women were raped,
leading to the first conviction
for sexual violence,
on its own,
as a crime against humanity.
The war in Bosnia was
the deadliest conflict in
Europe since World War ll.
Since 1995, an uneasy peace has prevailed
in Bosnia and Herzegovina.
Still deep divisions remain,
and the struggle
for reconciliation continues.