Swedish House Mafia.
They're all from Sweden:
Axwell,
Sebastian Ingrosso,
Steve Angello
and the Swedish House Mafia.
Make some noise!
Swedish House Mafia headlined Coachella
and sold out
Madison Square Garden.
Thousands of gigs.
Millions of fans.
You can't explain it.
You got to experience it.
News has reached us
that the successful group
Swedish House Mafia
is splitting up.
Swedish House Mafia are breaking up.
They stated on their
website it was no more.
Axwell,
Steve Angello and Sebastian Ingrosso.
..their next tour
is their final one.
I don't know
why they would end it.
It's ridiculous.
They should keep going.
They can get better.
Got to move on
and make new things.
Maybe they'll rejoin, who knows?
Steve Angello,
Axwell and Sebastian Ingrosso!
What's the plan now? A big tour?
Yes, a big world tour.
That's the plan for now.
And what's happening
after the tour?
Well, I guess we're all going
to pick up on our solo careers.
And keep making music. As usual.
Have you guys fallen out?
Is there a problem?
No, no.
How is it going to work if it is like this?
It's not going to work.
I like to make
music while I'm getting ready.
You're listening,
but in a passive mode.
This is the best bit.
The best part is
when the beat comes in,
and then there's
an immediate pause.
I mean, it just started!
It's awesome.
Then it comes back.
It's like...
Just got my laundry back.
When I arrived,
I only had five clean T-shirts.
But now I've washed
pretty much everything.
Well, now I have 16 T-shirts.
I'm not feeling this T-shirt.
I feel fat and swollen.
Damn, I didn't bring a hoodie
or anything.
Weird.
I don't feel comfortable
in this.
Wait...
Goddamnit.
Can't forget the wedding ring.
Where the hell are
my cigarettes?
Oh, well, fuck it.
Swedish House Mafia have released tickets
to their One Last Tour.
50 shows in 26 countries.
It's all about
getting into tour mode now.
We need to be warmed up
and ready.
There are obviously reasons
why they're breaking up
the band.
I mean, how are they
going to keep it together
for that whole world tour?
Swedish House Mafia
sold out Madison Square Garden
in nine minutes.
It's Jojo. In the studio
with me is Swedish House Mafia.
They're unique from
anything else in the industry.
And they made
house music popular.
They say two minds are better
than one. How about three minds?
It puts you in a good mood,
lifts your spirits.
Their own individual styles,
the way they've
come together as a group.
We're so excited about it.
The stage is built of 26 Kinesys motors
that are holding up
three flying video screens.
Two in front, one in the back.
It pushes all the energy out
front. They're very powerful.
That's a lot of laser.
There's 800 LED panels on there.
That's so bright.
It's the most elaborate pyrotechnics
these guys ever had on any tour.
These are the PRG Bad Boys.
We have three, one for each guy.
It's going to be
an assault on all senses.
It's very important
that we are at the top of our game,
because this is
the biggest thing
we've ever done together.
This is THE essential new tune
and it is the brand new single
from the Swedish House Mafia,
eagerly awaited.
It's called
"Don't You Worry Child".
Steve Angello has arrived. Over.
It's small, isn't it?
It's massive.
Yeah, no kidding. What's up?
It's big, but...
But also intimate.
It feels kind of naturally big.
It's not like "aaah"...!
Maybe a bit, actually.
Oh, damn.
Massive.
Oh, God, it's massive.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Before it
drops, what happened there?
What happened with the lights?
Dun, dun, dun!
That was a different
mix to the other one...
You're always going
to hear a different mix.
Oh, I know.
We need some: "Dun, dun!"
Something.
It looks kind of dead there.
Let's do it.
I like this part best,
'cause you can see
how big it is.
Check it out now.
Everyone is gonna go like this!
The love is everywhere.
Can we take a picture real quick?
We don't have time.
We came from California...
Yeah, awesome. Cool.
My shrink just told me:
"Try to avoid stress and take it
easy over the next few days."
Swedish House Mafia!
Stand by.
Fifteen seconds to go.
We got artists walking.
It's the beginning of the end.
What emotions are
going through all of you?
I don't really think of it as an end.
Now it feels like
a beginning of something.
You're going around all
these parts with your best friends
and just having fun
and exploring,
playing the biggest
venues around the world.
It's a dream come true.
I'm looking forward to hanging out,
really, with all of the guys.
I'm sure we'll have some fun.
I'm happy we're
traveling the world together
and that we're going
to do this once and for all
and just go out with a bang
and just do this.
Swedish House Mafia!
Ingrosso!
Axwell is tight!
Fuck me,
that was awesome. Insane.
Swedish House Mafia are legends.
They are in my heart, my blood
Swedish House Mafia,
you can't stop now!
Hey.
Messy girl.
We can wave you off outside.
Daddy loves you.
Goodbye.
She doesn't care as long
as she gets to play.
Bye, Mum.
Goodbye.
What do you want for Christmas?
A watch.
A watch?
I want a daddy-watch.
Do you want a watch like daddy's?
In black.
You want it in black?
OK. Same size?
What?
I'll see you soon.
Sing opera.
You want me to sing opera?
Hm.
Like you were singing
in the car.
In the car?
That was our secret!
Daddy, come on!
Do it, fatty!
Come on, please, Dad!
OK, fine, hang on
Daddy, do it, you lazy man.
Leon!
OK, thanks.
You're welcome.
Yeah, that's good.
At the end of the tour
we're going to quit this.
One last cigarette.
One last...
I don't have a lighter.
"Partouze".
My father started a record company in '89,
Plumphouse and Loop Records,
that released
a lot of deep, tech house,
techno, acid house.
I fell in love with the energy
and the intense, you know...
The whole, "My God,
what's happening?"
Something happened to my body
with the beats coming in
and the bass drum
and the toms and everything
building up to something
I'd never heard before,
it was something new.
I felt that some day
people will feel this.
People will love this
because I can't be wrong.
So my mission was to find
other people doing what I did.
I'm going to tell you
how I met Steve.
He was a DJ.
He was a hip hop DJ.
We would hang out
with the same people
and we grew in to each other.
We saw that we had
the same interests
and he had two turntables
before anyone,
because you couldn't get
the Technics 1210s anywhere.
I always bought vinyls
and went to him to listen to it
because I didn't have
a vinyl player.
He was like, "Man, you need to
stop listening to this music.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?"
I had orange pants,
my hair in the back,
my glow-in-the-dark T-shirt,
standing and jumping in his room
and he was sitting there
smoking weed with his,
you know, baggy pants
and the whole swagger Steve has.
A lot of energy. He was always
very happy and very funny.
And he always
wanted to do stuff,
you know,
he had spikes and Buffalos.
This real rave kid.
He made hip hop beats.
I was just partying
and coming into my
puberty and drinking beer.
And he just wanted to work.
Then we went
to my father's office.
I'd just got this CD
called Homework by Daft Punk.
I saw in Steve's face
that something happened
and the same thing
happened to me
when I was a kid
and listened to techno.
When I heard this the first time
I was so shocked.
And he was like,
"I don't know what happened,
but I got a musical orgasm
listening to this."
I remember me and him
coming into
the same world from hip hop
to techno and we met.
Did I shit my pants, man?
Ha-ha-ha!
What is it?
Wow. I'm going to throw up.
Is it me that smells?
I don't know.
Is it my mouth?
No.
What is with your hat?
Is there something?
You crapped in your hat.
Is it that?
Yeah, I think so.
No, it's not that.
Wow, somebody ate dog shit?
Yeah. I think it's my mouth.
Did you eat dog shit?
Oof! Wow!
What? What?
What is it?
It's here.
It's the fucking food.
In school, I discovered
this music-making software.
Nerds, much like myself,
would get together
and make a demo,
which meant a programmer
would program the most
advanced possible stuff
he could on the screen,
like make a square spin
and that would be like,
"Oh, my, God!"
Then you would have a guy
making music to this.
And this was a demo.
Basically computer nerd music,
demo music is amateur
versions of techno and trance.
And the better I got
and the better computers got,
the more it started
to sound like the real thing.
You can find it,
it's really fast
and actually sounding
quite amateurish.
I remember hearing
the drums in that song.
It was funky. It was groovy.
Well, we met at a restaurant.
He was just some kid
who came in and just like,
boys are coming in
being like boys, hello, just...
"Oh, my God, you are that guy.
I just heard your song on
StoneBridge 2. It's amazing."
I remember Ax
was looking at me like,
"What is this guy talking
about?" He was like, "Whoa!"
He was very flamboyant.
I guess the Italian in him
was very apparent. Ha, ha!
I'm like, "Do you have
a studio in Stockholm?
I'll come tomorrow."
He's a bit of a pushy guy.
He's a bit weird, you know.
I'm coming there at 3.
But you have to bear in mind,
I came from south of Sweden
and it's very low key, you know,
just very calm and Swedish,
I guess.
I grab some music, I take Steve
with me and I go to the studio.
When you met somebody
that was into dance music,
it's as if you let
two dogs into a room,
they smell each other's asses
and run around in a circle.
We were like, "Wow,
you're also into dance music?"
So we had to become
best friends on the spot.
Let's get into the mode.
Can you rewind a bit?
Oh, there it is.
Always the same high hats.
There it goes.
Say "Greyhound."
- How are you?
- I'm a mess.
Come over here.
You want water?
I can't breathe.
We're just three normal guys
from the suburbs of Stockholm.
Don't destroy the illusion.
We're not normal.
What are you talking about?
One, two, three.
The artists are on stage.
Where the fuck are we?
I can't ski at all.
Me neither. I suck.
It's incredible.
The more you think about it,
the more you realize
how big of a step
dance music has taken.
We couldn't go to Madison
Square Garden ten years ago.
They would say
we're out of our heads.
And suddenly we can
play any stadium in the world.
Blows your mind, opens your
heart always, always.
I love Russia.
Who quits when they're at the top?
What do we do after this?
It doesn't get bigger than this.
So that would mean
repeating ourselves.
So we were, like,
"The biggest change we could
do right now is to stop."
Even though it's really early
and it might not be
the best decision ever made,
it's still exciting.
It's going to be very sad,
obviously,
but also, a little bit,
"Oh, finally", in a weird way.
You know, it is an end, but it's
also a fucking amazing final.
The first time
I heard " Greyhound,"
that breakdown, I just lost it.
It was one of the best songs
I heard in my life.
Do you know they open
the show with Greyhound?
Yeah, I did know that.
What'll you do when you hear that?
I'll lose my marbles,
scream my head off.
Lose my mind as I usually do
when I listen to music.
All alert.
Go!
The winner of the Grand Prix, Axwell!
Hey, honey, it's Daddy.
♪ One chilly night,
night, night My boat I steered ♪
♪ On the wavy Wavy, wavy sea ♪
Great crowd.
Yes.
Damn good crowd.
Coming from 20,000 people,
all going bananas,
adrenaline pumping
and us playing the drums
to a silent,
not so romantic hotel room.
I shouldn't complain,
but I get this kind of anxiety.
I almost panic.
I have to wind down.
I thought about something.
I wonder if we will ever be on
that MTV show,
One Hit Wonders.
Whatever happened to?
You know, like Right Said Fred,
they had one hit
and then what happened?
Do you remember this group,
Swedish House Mafia?
They had this one song,
"Don't You Worry Child."
All three members now
went off to do their own things,
not as successful as the
"Don't You Worry Child" single.
And one of them went on
to become a crack addict, also.
One of them bought
a lot of houses
that he later had to sell.
And they tried to make
a reunion tour
after a few years, nobody came.
So, on our number ten
of One Hit Wonders,
Swedish House Mafia.
That could happen.
Like I've said before,
it feels like
we have been given the key
to the golden city
and we are throwing it away.
We could have kept going
and gotten even bigger.
It was very organic.
It's more the fans
forming Swedish House Mafia
than us sitting down saying,
"Shall we become
Swedish House Mafia?"
We were a bunch of guys having
a great time and loving music.
We've loved every second of it.
That was the feedback from the
shows and comments afterwards.
That was what people
wrote about us:
They are having
an amazing time up there.
Then it became a festival,
then it became
a residency somewhere.
We started for fun,
not knowing what we started,
didn't think about
what we started,
we didn't plan anything.
Are you ready
for some Swedish House Mafia?
We didn't see this
as a long-lasting career
even if we had a dream of,
you know, the dream was that,
but we were like, "Oh,
my God, we're going abroad?
This is a first." That's how
we felt with everything.
It'll be the first
and the last gig,
so we need to
party our asses off.
It was at the right moment in time
at the right moment
for this music
where we were with our music.
We really hit the mother lode.
It's just become this big
machine, you know, monster.
This is the UK's official number one,
"Don't You Worry Child."
Today is a good day.
We partied
for six years straight.
Constantly, five days a week.
Then two days travelling.
We didn't just consume alcohol.
We did pretty much everything.
I woke up after my birthday
party a few years ago.
There were beer bottles, liquor,
all kinds of shit all over
the place, people everywhere.
This is enough.
I threw everyone out
except for my friends
and said, "Those of you who want
to quit this can join me,
those of you who want
to keep going,
delete my number
and never call me again."
That's how it went down.
And I've been good
from that day on.
It started with us just messing around
with no responsibilities.
The requirement was
that we showed up,
drank booze and partied.
But since we've reached
this level,
people expect more from us
to not make us look like fucking
failures, I don't want that.
I feel there is a difference
in how much we put into this.
Can you see the one in there?
Damn, check out the lion!
- Look at the lion over there.
- Go inside there.
That's the sound I was afraid of.
That's the sound
I did not want to hear.
They're going in there,
check it out.
Wait,
they are going in with the cheetahs?
That's amazing.
Are they dangerous?
I hope you guys
are going to enjoy it.
I hope there's no sissies
amongst the lot of you.
I'm a sissy. I can tell you...
I'm a sissy. Yeah. I admit.
Like there, like there.
Beautiful.
You can leave if you don't like it.
You can walk straight back out.
I'll be standing right there.
No, no, no...
You just stand and watch.
I don't want to.
Come on, if they try anything
on, I'll kill them.
I promise you.
The best way to get used to you
is allow it to lick your scent.
He's purring so he's OK.
Can I take my hand away?
You don't take the hand away.
Now?
Yeah, you can.
OK.
But it's not a problem.
No. OK.
You did it, though.
I didn't like it.
You didn't like it at all?
No. It's not my thing. Look.
Do you remember
about two years ago, when I said
we should focus on Swedish
House Mafia 100 per cent?
I don't remember if we were
on drugs or not.
We should have focused on SHM
and given up on our own stuff.
Yes, you said that.
Then nothing happened
If we had committed,
then we could have done
this properly.
We're playing
for 2 x 27,000 people here.
To be on the level they deserve,
we should focus
on this thing only.
Get into the studio for months,
say goodbye to our families
You mean commitment.
Just got here?
Yeah, we did.
The question on a lot
of people's minds,
is this it, is it over?
Is it maybe just
a start of things,
you guys take a break,
do your own thing,
maybe come back later on?
What do you think?
Um...
How about you take this one?
I think we all feel the same way
since we all agreed
to this decision.
It's just that we haven't talked
about it.
A couple of hours a week,
everything is awesome.
We get nostalgic about the music
and we feel the magic.
But then it's back
to this emptiness.
There is an elephant in the room
The times when we've tried
to address it,
it's been very difficult
and nothing has come out of it.
So instead, we have just swept
it under the carpet.
We have our opinions,
but we don't talk about it.
That's how it is.
I mean, who likes arguments?
It's really stuffy in here,
I can't breathe.
This tour should be called
One Last Complaint.
We're complaining all the time,
even though everything
is perfect.
We're looking for things
to complain about.
It's messed up. I've never seen
anything like it.
Open the window.
See, now you're
complaining again.
I'm not, I just asked you
to open the window.
It's true. We're just trying
to find faults all the time.
Just enjoy, man.
We all grew up,
it becomes different,
we don't hang out as much
as we used to,
you know, we live
in different places.
It's not the same anymore.
We are three people that
have had individual agendas
all the time, living in
different parts of the world.
We've not been able to give
Swedish House Mafia
the type of commitment
that it deserves.
I guess it's for every friendship
and long-distance
relationships,
it's tight in the beginning
and then it just fades out.
It's a sick view from up here,
isn't it?
OK, let's check. Billboard.
Number one, Bruno Mars.
- Yeah! Number seven.
- What?
- Top ten!
- It's crazy.
- That's fucking wild, man.
- That's unbelievable.
Why the decision to finish
it with all this success with you?
It's about, you know,
us doing a world tour
and putting our other
projects on the side for a while
and saying hello and goodbye
to our fans.
And, yeah, I mean,
you can continue this, maybe.
I think, yeah, we've had
an amazing time and...
It's like my father once said,
if the cheetah approaches you,
you have to push
the cheetah down.
And so that means that,
you know, this became so big
and we really,
like Sebastian said,
we wanted to finish it
on the perfect level,
you know, so just,
"Down, cheetah".
They must be like:
"Shit, it's the president!"
No, it's three DJs from Sweden."
I can't see shit.
Here.
No, I'm gonna puke!
I'm gonna puke, I'm gonna puke!
What the fuck!
Where is it?
Someone is
running around with it!
We went to Australia.
We rented a big house on the water.
We were, like, we'll try and do
"Don't You Worry Child."
Damn, it's warm now.
Is it warm now?
Are you kidding?
Well, not that warm.
It's set to 33 degrees Celsius.
OK.
They say there are sharks here
and that you shouldn't go
in the water.
We won't then.
I want to make music
that sounds like this view.
You think we can make music
that sounds like this?
Sure.
What does this sound like?
I think up a few notes.
Maybe one more.
One more up.
There!
I'm gonna do the beats now.
That's fucking tight, man.
Yeah, for sure.
See if any of these work.
I'll just try all of them.
You mean...
So it plays over here.
I want this to
come together with a baby angel
that I want to have on my neck.
He's not picking up?
He can't pick up if he's getting
tattooed right now.
How long does it take
to get a tattoo?
It depends on how complex it is.
This one took four hours
because it's got several layers.
What a retarded thing to do now
when we've rented a house for
half a billion to make music?
You can get a tattoo in LA,
right?
Last time I checked.
This is gonna hurt.
Nobody cares anymore.
I left my family, he left his
family, Steve left his family
to come to work
and spend five days.
Fuck that shit, man.
I'm tired of it.
Nothing's going to happen.
We won't finish this record
on this trip, we are not.
We need to be in the room
and be creative and have fun
and when he comes he's going
to be fucked. It hurts, man.
- I mean, it's just bad, man.
- Yeah.
Me and Ax are going to speak
to Steve when we have time
and if he doesn't
really understand it,
then we have
a huge problem, I mean...
The lost member is back.
I didn't know it was
gonna take that long.
- That was the worst idea.
- To get a tattoo?
I told you that three months
ago by e-mail.
But we're here working.
Yes, but still.
It sucks.
Whatever, let's just work now.
We felt that we've taken
it in the right direction.
But we didn't really
get that far.
And then we had to leave.
At the same time,
things were not really
going so well with
Swedish House Mafia.
I can skip it,
our stuff is more important.
Or we can do it tomorrow?
You can count on me tomorrow,
I swear.
There's a lot of stuff
that everybody puts
time and effort in
that doesn't get credited for.
If I go to loads of
meetings about something,
I'm not going to put that
on the spreadsheets.
Seb dropped out of many
studio sessions for reasons
but I have never
accounted him for that
and said, "You didn't show up."
I don't care.
We're in this together.
You know what?
We already had the best
time with Swedish House Mafia,
so why not just leave it there,
because we know that
we're not going to commit.
We don't want to have some sort of group
that's half-assing it.
I feel like nobody's
pushing anything further.
We don't want to
mess up our friendship,
because we're angry at each
other for not working enough.
And then actually I dropped
what I'd been thinking
for a bit:
"How about we quit
Swedish House Mafia?"
It was after they left the stage
they put a thing
up on their website
saying it was no more.
"Swedish House Mafia,
forever in my heart."
"Assholes, you don't
care about your fans."
"Something died in me,
faggots!"
"Swedish House Mafia break-up
is death of house music."
"You guys rewarding your fans
in this matter,
question mark."
"Now I think my biggest hope
and interest in life
has died, damn,
I'm really fucking sad."
"Why, why, why. No, no, no.
Please, don't do it."
The call I got which was like,
"We're going to break up,
fuck this shit. It's evil."
It got so big, so fast.
It's only real
if you all mean it.
And you all
really love each other.
But the energy
is no longer pure.
And so One Last Tour was born.
The success of Swedish House Mafia
is something no one can deny,
you've released hit tracks,
played sold-out arenas
across the globe.
Aren't you afraid of
the future without SHM?
Not really.
I mean we're here now
and enjoying
the moment right now
and I'm just looking forward
to what's going to happen next.
There's no sort of big scheme or plan.
We've always done what we do
and released our stuff
and played big events
individually.
We just see this as
an end of an amazing journey
that we've done
together as friends
and, you know,
it just feels right.
We all saw an end to the limbo.
We were like,
"We need to do this."
And we got really excited
about ending the band.
And that then led to
us announcing Milton Keynes Bowl
as our last show in the UK.
We said in an interview,
"We are premiering
our last single there."
So that kind of
set a time schedule
to finish that fucker,
because if we told 60,000 people
they're going to hear
"Don't You Worry Child"
at our show,
we better fucking finish it.
Great to meet you guys.
You played some massive shows.
What makes this one so special?
It's our last Swedish
House Mafia show in the UK.
Can you confirm that your next single
is going to be
"Don't You Worry Child"?
Yes.
So for the last time ever in the UK,
Milton Keynes, make some noise.
The Swedish House Mafia!
"Don't You Worry Child"
received a Grammy nomination.
You are officially number one in the UK.
iTunes number one in 42 countries.
Swedish House Mafia's
first ever UK number one.
We want everybody to sit down.
Every single person out here,
please sit down.
When the track kicks in,
we want you all to jump up.
Are you ready?
Don't you worry...
It's nice and warm here, huh?
Yes.
Am I in Hawaii? Is this Hawaii?
This is Malaysia.
Malaysia.
You have this thing here also?
Nice.
- Maybe you should sing a song.
- What up?
I'm OK, I'm OK, thank you.
You need to take one.
No.
Come on, it's impolite.
Just put it on.
Why is that?
It's impolite.
Who says that?
It's their culture.
I don't give a shit.
You know this is a theme park?
Oh, yeah?
It's so weird this whole thing.
I can't see myself DJing
when I'm 40.
I'll still be involved,
but I don't think
I'll be touring.
And you can't know how long
this scene will last
Time will tell.
Everything comes to an end.
I cried myself to sleep last night.
Really?
I'm going through some rough times.
That's life sometimes, I guess.
You have to clean out
all the shit.
That's too bad.
Otherwise it gets to you later,
you'll see.
I've come to a point in my life
where I want to clear things up.
Why can't we sit down and talk
about this like adults?
What the hell are we doing?
We're behaving like teens!
This is not gonna fly.
It's not working.
It really isn't.
I focus 100 per
cent on Swedish House Mafia.
If you don't feel that everyone
is on the same page,
it gets really boring.
Come on, just spit it out!
If you've got something
to say, say it.
What's the fucking problem?
If you don't deal with problems
straight away, leave it!
It wears you down, you know.
But do we want to start a war
now? 'Cause it will be a war.
Aah, aah!
We need to relax, OK?
So fucking stupid!
I think Steve took off.
Where to?
I don't know.
Curly just showed him to a car.
You know, ahem,
it is what it is, man.
You know, it's like,
it's over, you know.
So...
A lot of things happened this year
and made me realize that,
you know, we're not
best friends anymore.
And that's the truth.
Normally, we say, "Well,
we've taken it as far as we want",
and so and so and so,
which is also true but
maybe we are not meant to be.
It's coming.
Come here, shark!
The winds have spoken.
She's grown.
Look.
You want a flower?
Hey, honey.
You can never go away again.
What's up?
Daddy.
Daddy, I love you.
I love you too.
I've missed you.
And a kiss too. How are you?
Fine.
Look, I'm going to swim.
Aha!
Welcome to Indira Gandhi
International Airport,
New Delhi.
The outside temperature
is 27 degrees Celsius.
- Thank you so much.
- Have a nice day.
Nikhil, when was the first time
I came to India?
2007.
It was so different
and the energy was so amazing
that I was just like,
"Wow, this is something else.
I have to come here
more often."
The scene that we have
in India today
with millions of fans
of dance music.
This guy's fault.
He started it.
An old friend of mine.
I think Axwell's going to be surprised
by the number of fans
he has in India now
compared to what
was going on in 2007.
I would like to go crazy
and hear the music like...
There're so many fucking people
here to see them right now.
I've got a special connect
with them so when I see them play
I get a special feeling
which I don't get
when I see other DJs play.
My name is Axwell.
This is Sebastian Ingrosso
and Steve Angello,
and we are
the Swedish House Mafia.
Whoo!
What happened tonight?
Axwell,
Sebastian Ingrosso,
and Steve Angello,
killed the fuck
out of this place.
Tonight was madness.
I can't even speak.
We've been waiting for this
for so long. You have no idea.
I think we're going
to say that it's probably
the change of house
movement in India, you know.
Let's say it's come of age.
Seeing about like
15,000-20,000 people,
EDM has come of age in India.
Let's put it that way.
I want to smoke so bad seeing you do that.
You look like Burt Reynolds.
I could give you a blowjob.
You'll just feel bad
if you smoke. Don't do it.
Relax and pass me that thing.
It's just a damn cigarette.
I just want your best, bro.
I know, bro.
Hey, Michelle, it's Amy.
I really have got to be quick.
I'm in the middle
of literally running a festival,
so when can we do this call
and how long will it be?
I'm basically the
chairwoman of Swedish House Mafia.
They are kind of like
my second family, I suppose.
I rang Steve Angello,
"Can I book you?
Can I do some stuff with you?"
He was like, "Sure."
I also called Axwell.
Steve introduced me
to Sebastian.
I just remember
that they had swagger,
especially Steve,
especially Steve.
I think they knew
they could have swagger
because they knew their
music was so fucking good.
You know, they knew what
they were hearing.
They knew what they were making.
And they were kind of like,
"Yeah, listen to that." Ha, ha!
And you are?
Steve Angello.
OK, good.
Comments?
Phat.
Axwell, what do you have to say?
In the beginning,
there was house.
In the end, there was house.
And in the middle
there is Axwell.
I think some of us made some mistakes
and the fact that we haven't
been able to sit down
and say sorry to each
other is a tragedy.
But I also think that
even if we said sorry,
I don't think it would fix it.
And I think that we all
want to be happy
more than we want to be
in Swedish House Mafia.
We're pleased to have with us today
the members of
Swedish House Mafia:
Axwell, Steve Angello
and Sebastian Ingrosso
to help us light
the Empire State Building.
Hello, New York,
this is actually
the first time we visit
the Empire State Building.
And what an awesome way
to visit it in,
you know, having it
lit up in the Swedish colors.
It's coming to an end very soon.
The circle is about
to be completed.
It's starting to feel
very emotional.
At the start of the tour,
it never felt like the end.
The end was so far away.
I wasn't thinking that it would
all be over so soon.
Do you regret it?
Sometimes. Sometimes.
Look, here comes
Sebastian Ingrosso.
And look now,
I'm Swedish House Mafia.
Ta-da!
Can we have a picture before you go on?
With your badass outfit.
Yeah!
You need to chill out
in a big way.
I'm saying it's good.
He said it's my best
outfit ever if I added oil.
I mean, I'm just saying,
that's not right.
Alex, who am I?
Sebastian.
And now?
Swedish House Mafia.
We needed Ax to be
the guy that always was there.
And I myself,
pretty bad in the beginning,
partying and, like,
taking maybe Ax or Steve
for granted a little bit.
I can be with these
fucking people here
at this after-party,
they will fix that.
And then four years later
I woke up and was like,
"What have I done?"
But, you know,
this year and the year before,
I've been working my ass off
to prove to both Ax and Steve
that I wanted to give
something back to them
for how many years
they have been there
and got my back.
What's up? You want to party?
What's up?
She's like, "I'm Paris Hilton",
and I'm, "I don't give a fuck."
I just want a hug.
I'm just so hyped.
Wow, I'm going to fuck
this nightclub into pussy.
You've got swag.
Never seen so much
people smile. Kind of like...
Who can say that they have
been playing drums
at Madison Square Garden?
I can.
Steve! Ax!
I took off my earplugs.
I took a vodka shot,
because it was so great.
Oh, you took a vodka shot?
Yeah, like this big.
I needed to.
If it continues like this,
by the end of the tour
we'll be back to doing coke,
just getting hammered
all the time.
Yeah, I think so, too.
We're going to, the last show:
Back to the start again.
Ha-ha-ha!
Why not?
Why the fuck not?
So just tell us why you chose Miami
to end the Swedish House Mafia?
We always come back to
Miami every year for the conference
and it kind of felt natural to
spread the ashes here
so we can come and visit
from time to time. Ha, ha.
Say hi to the boys.
I will.
The best of luck
and thanks so much
for everything that
you've done for everybody
and then the good times
you've given everybody.
Thank you, man. Thank you.
This is something
we were doing on our own before.
And we will keep doing it
on our own after this.
It's actually not that strange.
We're all different, you know.
It's hard to...
Anyway it's over now.
This was the last...
I feel that you have a lot of things
between you three
that is unsaid.
Yeah, it's probably
never going to be said either,
maybe in the future.
Well, you never know.
Then we will be older and,
hopefully,
we'll meet each other in Ibiza
or have a glass of wine
or whatever
and talk about it or not.
At the start say:
"I'm...
This is Steve, this is Sebastian,
we are still
the Swedish House Mafia."
Or I can say:
"We are the Swedish
House Mafia for one last time."
No, I think it's better
to say...
It's much better.
More massive. When you said it
last time, I was like aaah!
I felt like I was in the crowd
and wanted to fuck everyone.
OK, fine then.
Yes, it's like poof!
Damn, are we up soon?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Very shortly.
We should go up there
and get into the vibe,
play some drums.
Need to get into the rhythm.
Damn, I'm stressed out now.
Miami.
I'll always be their friend,
obviously.
But it's just not
the same work-wise anymore.
We had an amazing thing
and it's always sad to see
things go that you loved.
But look at us now,
we've endured.
We have this thing
to look back on
and I think that's something
that I would like to treasure.
Gracefully, we will
have a friendship,
we will have
a graceful friendship.
It's sad, you know,
when you think about it
but it's also very beautiful
because we made
something together
and we were best friends.
And we took
this journey together
so it's not this little thing
just in the end
of not committing to things
that breaks this up.
It's just we want to leave it,
we don't want to end our
friendship in a super bad way,
it could be worse, it could be
flying chairs
in the fucking faces
and hitting
each other with knives. Heh.
But that's what we
don't want, you know.
Let us hear you singing, Miami.
You can do louder!
I think I speak for
all of us when I say
thank you for this great
journey that you've given us,
all the places we've been
and all the love we got.
Words can't describe
how I feel right now.
I'm so sad.
I'm like happy but sad.
At the same time.
Madison Square Garden,
Barclays, Barclays,
I only go to my brothers
that many times, you understand?
Vibes are strong, energy.
I'm never getting
over that ever.
Best night of my life.
It's sad to see them leave.
They're going to be fine.
You mean individually, yeah,
but it would be nice
to see them together.
Maybe they'll
come back from there.
They should stay together.
Because everyone loves them
and they're just
a great group of people.
They were
the best thing happened
in my entire life.
The best thing.
Human beings can't
take emotion out of me,
but Swedish House Mafia
apparently can.
I can die happy.
We are still
the Swedish House Mafia.
Miami, thank you so much.
You know that we came,
you know that we raved,
and that we love you!