Give me your number.
Shut your mouths!
Go on...
I think everyone's horny tonight!
4 - 2...
Shit, I'm feeling randy.
I'm sizzling hot.
- 3...
2 - 4...
Lisa calling...
Cool it!
It ends in four numbers,
I won't give you the beginning.
Penelope, are you there?
Penelope, the slut!
Lisa calling...
INVISIBLE
Bruno, it's Noel. Are you there?
Are you awake?
You haven't forgotten the meeting
or the demo?
I've promised the producer
she'd hear something.
I hope you're on your way.
See you.
She helped, not like your mum!
I don't need help. I'd like us
to enjoy moving in alone.
That's fantastic, zilch!
I have to put these boxes away!
Don't, just push them!
I thought
these were the men's tollets.
I'II go out. I'm sorry.
A quarter of an hour Iate
Is no blg deal.
Everyone's here now.
- I'II lnform Mlss Stevens.
- Thank you.
Well?.
You brought the demo?.
No, we aren't ready.
Shlt, I promlsed we had a demo!
You know how Iong It took
to get thls meetlng?.
What wlll we Iook Ilke
comlng empty-handed?.
If only you'd plck up the phone!
"Mlss, would you Ilke to joln us
In a subllme muslcal adventure??'
"Yes, I've been chaslng after you
for years."
Instead of that
he comes empty-handed and Iate.
Well done!
Flnlshed?.
Hello,
Carole Stevens. You're Noel...
We spoke on the phone.
You're Bruno.
We've already met, I thlnk.
Follow me.
We had started more New Wave...
OId Wave!
A perlod of lnfluence,
Ilke everyone.
You even nlcked
entlre pleces by Sulclde.
We were part of the trend, but...
We only stole two pleces,
It's nothlng.
Two whole pleces
and blts and pleces, here and there.
That's water under the brldge,
no one cares now.
I'm lnterested
In what you're dolng now.
An album, well under way.
We'II have demos for you soon.
Very good.
A soon as we know
who we're golng to copy.
What's trendy out of thls Iot?.
He's klddlng, we're almost ready.
Stuck... at a dead end.
Perfect!
I Iove to step In at that moment.
I'm a medlum,
I've a knack
for communlcatlng wlth the dead.
Thls meetlng
was In the knlck of tlme.
When you have somethlng
for me to hear, Iet me know.
Otherwlse I'II turn tables.
Goodbye.
See you soon.
We aren't ready, I told you.
Stop lt. You're scared.
So you're actlng up.
I won't Iet you sabotage thlngs.
We've been struggllng for years,
we've a chance to make lt.
Next tlme I'II knock your head off!
- You haven't hung up?
- No, I tried to call back.
You didn't want
to give your number.
Take it again.
I did take it the first time,
0 1-44-54...
No, it's 0 1-45...
Who's calling?
Who is it?
Marquis is fine,
I noted your number, but...
I tried but got no answer.
I know It's Iate but you aren't
often In durlng the day.
I wanted to lntroduce myself.
I'm your new caretaker.
Flne...
Good, I hope you'II Ilke It here.
Thank you, you're very klnd.
Good evenlng then.
Good nlght, rather.
What can I...?.
You can help me,
I've an awful mlgralne.
Wlth thls heat wave
and my stuffy Iodge.
Any palnklller would do.
I'II go and see.
It's dark,
you can't see a thlng.
Wlll Tylenol do?.
That'II do flne.
Good ldea, soundprooflng,
not to bother nelghbours.
Dld you know
nolse was the maln cause
of complalnts and lncldents
In towns?.
That's why I soundproofed the place.
Not to hear other people's nolse.
Keep the box.
No, you probably
often have headaches too.
It's been a long time.
Yes, I'm here.
It's Lisa.
Llsa?.
The Marquis wants to talk.
Lisa calling.
Llsa?.
Who is it?
Bruno...
Bruno for Llsa. Can we talk?.
Bruno, give me your number.
Lisa, won't you call me rather?
Give me your number!
Bruno, do you want my number?
Llsa?.
Your number!
- Bruno isn't answering.
- 0 1 -45-50-54-26.
OK, hang up.
Shlt!
It's Lisa.
What are you doing?
Nothlng.
Let's forget it.
No, walt, It's your volce...
- What about my voice?
- I Ilked lt.
I Ilke lt. I Ilstened
to your volce, that's all.
I don't like eavesdroppers.
Nelther do I, very much.
You aren't a regular
on the chatline.
- What are you after?
- I don't know.
And you?.
Don't put the light on,
wait for me in the room.
Don't talk to me, do nothing.
I decide.
And after?.
I leave first, we never meet again.
You're in a hurry?
Couldn't we talk a bit?
Or smoke a cigarette?
I can't find my cigs.
I need the light on.
Calm down. I won't start a fire.
I'd like to see you and talk to you.
Th Is lsn't a datlng servlce.
Slnce we won't meet agaln
I'm golng to turn the Ilght on.
Cheat!
You don't Ilke lt?.
What's that...
Where dld you get that from?.
Volces from the chatllne.
Not bad, Is lt?.
Yes, maybe.
Maybe wlth more work.
You're not lnto that, are you?.
Really?.
Slnce when?.
I thought these chatllnes
were full of welrdoes.
There are all sorts.
Depends what you're Iooklng for.
What are you Iooklng for?.
When I've found It I'II tell you.
- Anythlng else to put away?.
- Hand me that cable.
- The red or the green?.
- The red one.
Have you taken your drawlngs?.
Yes, who Is lt?.
Same time, same place, same rules.
Why dld you call me agaln?.
I felt Ilke lt.
You'II pull the same trlck
each tlme?.
There's no trlck.
- And no each tlme.
- Stay then.
- You're never scared In the dark?.
- Yes.
Each tlme I thlnk
It mlght be Jack the Rlpper.
No one would know.
But I'm dlsappolnted,
no one's trled to klll me.
There have been many?.
I'm not very convincing.
Gentle rather.
Can you guess what I look like?
I'd rather imagine.
I want to know.
The cheeks...
Full cheeks.
The nose...
Straight,
with perhaps a little bump...
I haven't finished.
The mouth,
the teeth...
A prlckly cheek,
the Adam's apple,
the chest,
not too hairy.
The hole of the belly button...
and...
You tease!
I found your earrlng.
Really?.
Do I walt for you to call?.
Sorry I'm Iate.
Pretend I'm not here.
That's dlfflcult.
What's she dolng here?.
- If there's a problem...
- There's no problem.
I lnvlted Mlss Stevens.
Carole. It's slmpler.
- Let's be slmple.
- I lnvlted Carole to see us at work.
- You forgot to tell me.
- You never check your messages.
I wasn't at home!
I don't want to cause a row.
It's much more lnterestlng
when you play.
Rlght. Bruno, from the top?.
Carole Stevens speaking.
Really?.
Disappointed or am I waking you?
No, I'm surprlsed.
We ended on a bad note last time.
I thought about what you said.
Are you free for lunch?
It would help break the ice.
I'm ready to draw up
the contract now.
- I haven't sald yes.
- What's mlsslng?.
A blg cheque.
Apart from that?.
Belng obsessed...
In a state of obsesslon.
Obsessed!
- I see.
- No you don't.
- Thank you.
- I lnslst.
It's my way of breaklng the lce.
Evening.
The Itallan snorlng above,
have you heard hlm before?.
How do you know he's Itallan?.
You're talklng nonsense!
You can't recognlse
an Itallan snorlng?.
Ever broken your contract?.
I mean, see someone several tlmes?.
See hlm agaln?.
How do you know
there've been other guys?.
I don't know much,
that's the problem.
AII the charm, on the contrary.
Charm, problem...
that often descrlbes women?.
Macho!
Ifyou knew me better,
you wouldn't say that.
I should get to know you better.
I hear your volce,
I want to make Iove.
I thlnk we're already maklng Iove.
Because your volce ls...
Intlmate...
Wet...
Wet?.
It wets the words.
I'd never been told such a thlng!
Walt!
Before Ieavlng, say somethlng
you've never sald to anyone.
I don't know...
Don't you trust me?.
Yes...
The flrst tlme I experlenced deslre
was when I saw a nall varnlsh ad.
The glrl's hand was superb.
I was twelve or thlrteen.
I was In my room.
And I felt the deslre
to fondle myself.
Here...
One, two, three flngers...
I was fllled. I was happy.
I must go.
You really want to leave?
Ifyou'd rather we stopped.
You remembered my earring?
Return it
and we have no reason to meet.
Here's the demo.
A rough draft.
I thlnk Bruno explalned.
I promlse I'II be merclless!
I also have rough drafts...
of a contract proposal.
Great, we'II take
a close Iook at lt.
Once that's sorted out, tell me
how Iong you need to rehearse,
so I can book the studlo.
A month should be flne.
Bruno, you Iook very penslve.
You thlnk I dance faster
than the muslc?.
Yes...
No...
Everythlng's flne?.
It's because Noel and I
have a Iot to do. We must go.
Walt, I must go too.
You're pleased?.
Wlth the rehearsals, I mean.
Yes, I guess so.
The closer we get to recordlng,
the more doubts.
It's normal.
What are you trylng to tell me?.
I'd rather you talked to me
and I'd Ilke you
to be more confldent.
Are you feellng lll?.
No, I'm flne, but In these blg cars
I get car slck.
That's a funky old cassette player!
I used to use It to record concerts
and I've kept It to Ilsten to them.
A few years ago
I often went to London.
On the ferry too,
there was no Eurostar back then.
You never go back?.
Sometlmes, but Iess often.
And the condltlons have changed.
I'm lnvlted now.
You mlss lt?.
It was another perlod.
You have to grow up.
Shlt...
She won't see anyway.
Here's your post, Bruno.
Can I call you Bruno?.
I wanted to brlng It earller.
You weren't back.
You needn't have,
I have a Ietterbox.
It's no bother!
Wlth all the stolen post
I prefer to hand It In person.
What If an lmportant Ietter
got Iost?.
Of course.
Thanks agaln. Goodnlght.
You're all dressed up,
are you golng out?.
Exactly.
Flne.
Can I come In a second?.
It's about the post.
It seems you are behlnd
In your rent.
What buslness Is It ofyours?.
Don't take It badly.
I dldn't want you to be too upset
by thls Ietter.
I don't Ilke
to brlng people bad news.
Especlally,
slnce everyone goes through
bad patches, don't they?.
That's why I became a caretaker.
Not to pay rent.
No more horrlble formal notlces.
I always have my place to stay now.
Of course, It's cramped
and you keep bumplng lnto thlngs.
A caretaker's Iodge
Is a blt Ilke a prlsoner's cell,
but wlth a Ilttle lmaglnatlon...
I'm sorry but I must...
Is that a DX7 or a DX9?.
A DX7.
Aren't you surprlsed
I know these thlngs?.
Yes... no...
I don't know.
I really don't have tlme.
No tlme to be surprlsed, Is that lt?.
I see, I feel thlngs.
You have an lmportant rendezvous.
Wlth a Iady, I suppose.
I really must go, I'm already Iate.
People don't connect nowadays,
don't you flnd, Bruno?.
They protect themselves,
they're more lndlvlduallstlc
or too attached to appearances.
They pass each other by. It's sad.
To please, you must charm,
play the game...
It tlres me out.
There!
Good dog, good girl.
Walt a second.
I Iook awful!
The value's malnly sentlmental.
That's why I thought
If someone found lt
they'd glve It to you.
No, I'm sorry.
Last week,
we were In room 18, I thlnk.
No, I assure you.
Before leaving, say something
you've never said to anyone.
Don't you trust me?
The first time I experienced...
I was twelve or thirteen...
The girl was superb.
I was twelve...
The Baron is here...
What? Red?
Bruno for Llsa...
I'm the Little Red Riding Hood...
Bruno for Llsa.
Get a hold ofyourself, pervert.
She's a pro.
You sound strange, Penelope.
Bruno, you seem In a hurry.
Get off my back!
What If I had the key
to all your problems?.
I have the spare key.
AII caretakers have spare keys.
Shlt!
Bruno seeklng Llsa.
Bruno for Llsa.
I haven't come for the room.
Remember the woman wlth me,
In the red dress?.
We see all sorts here.
I'm sure you do,
you saw her several tlmes.
Maybe you know her name.
We never glve such lnformatlon.
I understand
but I really need to flnd her.
Glve me a clue, anythlng.
In case she comes back,
I'II rent a room
and walt for her.
You'II make money.
Don't lnslst, I know nothlng.
Are you trylng to torture me
by Ilstenlng
to that mushy muslc?.
Incredlble, you plck up a glrl
and ask for her number!
Get off my back!
Probably a fake number,
she gave you a phoney name.
Your affalr's offto a bad start.
Damn lt, I should have shut my trap!
We got a good plece out of lt.
Carole Ilked It a Iot.
- We should work on lt.
- I don't thlnk so.
- You should...
- You can't understand, shut up!
You're In Iove?.
You hardly know her!
Get off my back, wlll you?.
All the women on your mind...
Should you marry them all?
Shlt, you're a paln wlth your songs!
You're the paln, Bruno.
Katia, how old are you?
- I'm 35.
- 35?
Your voice is strange.
You think so?
The Baron is here.
Bruno seeklng Llsa.
- Bruno seeklng Llsa.
- Katia, it's Monica.
- Is the Shark here tonight?
- Yes, he's here.
- I can call you?
- No, I'm Iooklng for Llsa.
Don't turn the light on,
wait for me to come to you.
Don't talk, don't do anything.
I decide.
You know Llsa?.
Relax.
Answer! Do you know Llsa?.
I don't know her.
Are you crazy, stop that!
You're Ilke a cop.
Turn the Ilght on,
you mlght as well.
You dldn't unscrew the bulbs?.
You're really slck.
- What do you know about Llsa?.
- Nothlng.
I don't know her.
You sald the same words!
You're hurtlng me!
They're not her property.
I don't belleve you, you're Iylng!
- Llar!
- Help!
Forglve me. I'm really sorry.
Why don't you open the wlndow?.
It's hot In here.
- What are you dolng?.
- Bastard!
I hear your voice,
I want to make love.
I think we're already making love.
Your voice is...
intimate...
wet.
Wet?
Good evening, it's Carole.
We haven't seen each other for ages.
I knew It would lnterest you, Bruno.
I see you Ilke Blll Evans.
You'II be pleased to Iearn
he lsn't deceased. On the contrary.
He Ilves on a desert lsland.
He's put on welght.
He's stopped all drugs
and spends hls tlme playlng Bach.
Llke AIbert Ayler who...
He's stlll allve?.
No, he was murdered.
Everyone knows that.
Not by the CIA,
by the BIack Musllms.
Mr Wllllam has proof.
He even has a phantom record
by Buddy Bolden.
I don't know who that ls.
You don't know Mr Wllllam?.
You'II tell me some other tlme.
Bruno, no one Is waltlng for you.
Your Ioss.
- Why are you hummlng that?.
- What?.
That tune, Peter and the Wolf...
You're tlred.
It's for helplng chlldren sleep.
You had better go to bed.
I won't Iet you go now.
Get up, Bruno,
Mr Wllllam wants to see you.
What's golng on?.
You mustn't keep
Mr Wllllam waltlng.
He was a model employee,
Mr William
Full of enthusiasm, Mr William
He reached forty
without being naughty
Without the slightest mishap
But one August evening,
the weather was so nice and balmy
That Mr William
went for a nice long stroll
Mr William you lost your manners
Why go down 13th A venue?
He met a young woman, Mr William
He bought her a bunch of violets,
Mr William
He took her to hotel of ill repute
But a Black
wanted to take the woman
Mr William, in a fury,
hit him with his brolly.
But the man in the dark
slashed his neck twice
Mr William, you lost your manners
Why go down 13th A venue?
You wanted to see me?.
I'm Iooklng for Llsa.
You know Llsa?.
Come closer.
Our frlend really Ilkes you,
you know?.
Can you help me flnd Llsa?.
Glve me a good reason to help you.
You want money?.
Bruno, are you mad?.
The BIack Swan.
There may be
an answer for you there.
BIack Swan?.
Yes, Ilke the blrd,
The BIack Swan...
Ask for Marco.
"The twlllght Is grand."
How many are you?.
I'm alone. At Ieast...
I thlnk so.
The club's reserved for couples.
You have to be two.
I'm Iooklng for Marco.
Marco?.
Yes, Mr Wllllam sent me.
I don't know any Marco or Wllllam.
"The twlllght Is grand."
I'II deal wlth hlm.
- You're dlsturblng the patrons.
- I don't care.
I don't want to see you around here!
You'd better get Iost!
You're slck!
Go on, scarper!
What's your problem?.
You want to get beaten up?.
Want some more?.
Son of a bltch!
I'm Carole, a frlend of Bruno's.
I know who you are,
I got the messages.
He can't see you now,
he needs to be alone.
He's In creatlve mode.
I must see hlm for work,
It's lmportant.
- Let me ln, please.
- Don't lnslst, Mlss Stevens.
He can't see anyone now.
Tell hlm I dropped by.
I expect to hear from hlm soon.
Of course, you can rely on me.
Bruno, that won't do.
I Iook awful!
Lisa calling...
- Good evenlng, Bruno.
- The Shark?
- You've been dolng thls Iong?.
- What?.
The chatllne, the recordlngs,
the tapes...
I've always done lt.
Impresslve, lsn't lt?.
Llsten to that.
Lisa calling.
No games, tell me
what you know about Llsa.
We must talk about you Bruno.
We're here to help you.
I don't glve a damn about your help!
Where's Llsa?.
Calm down, Bruno. Don't be afrald.
We know nothlng about Llsa.
Why send me to The BIack Swan?.
We thought It would allow you
to understand.
Nothlng happened
at The BIack Swan?.
You Iove Llsa?.
You should have known
she wouldn't be there.
There's nothlng there
apart from what you brlng yourself.
The BIack Swan lsn't Hell,
and you're not Orpheus
seeklng Eurydlce.
Besldes, you can't enter alone,
can you?.
We thought
It would help you understand.
You know what I thlnk?.
The guy hlt so hard
I haven't yet come round.
Lisa calling...
A handsome guy for Lisa?
Lisa calling.
Lisa for a big tomcat.
Evening, it's Sacha.
Yann, can you hear me?
It's Lisa, call me.
Sacha seeks a boy.
A wolf for Lisa.
It's tlme to go.
I have a few vlnyls
that could be useful.
I should have called,
we should have rehearsed.
Shut up,
Carole thlnks we've rehearsed.
You've put us In a jam.
What happened to your head?.
It's psychosomatlc,
It must be the stress.
It better be good.
We're supposed to be ready.
I've brought help.
Now everyone's here,
we can get down to work.
Bruno can't Ilve wlthout you.
He's always dreamt
of belng at a recordlng sesslon.
It's good to fulfll one's dreams.
I'd Ilke to say...
If I gave no slgn of Ilfe,
It wasn't because...
Because we fucked
doesn't mean you have to explaln.
AII I care about Is that you record
thls damned album.
The rest doesn't concern me.
I fuck wlth whom I Ilke when I Ilke!
The samples are great,
but there are too many of them.
Afrald the rlghts
wlll cost too much?.
No, of It belng "over-sampled".
I thought you Ilked thls plece.
Yes, but It's become too Ilkeable.
Isn't that what you wanted?.
If It's to Iayer cool sounds, flne.
But It doesn't tell a story.
How do you know
It doesn't tell a story?.
It doesn't work wlth me.
You're supposed to make muslc.
For your personal messages,
there are other means.
Can we get back to work?.
Calm down. We'II move on
and come back to thls Iater.
Good ldea. We're Iate
and studlo rental Is expenslve.
You only care about money!
I care about that too. And
lmposlng your muslc wasn't easy.
Maybe It can't be lmposed!
Would you Ilke a coffee?.
What?.
That was stupld and unfalr.
It's a blt Ilke when Charles Mlngus
had a falllng out wlth Atlantlc.
Mr Wllllam had sald...
That was Mlngus.
He probably had good reasons.
Glve me a fucklng break!
Bruno must have hls reasons.
Slnce I've known hlm,
I feel much better.
I sometlmes felt
I was wastlng my tlme
collectlng all these vlnyls
and not knowlng
what to do wlth them.
Now, I thlnk...
I prefer to spend my tlme
dreamlng wlth muslc
rather than suffer at composlng lt.
Carole, It's Bruno.
I wanted...
to apologlse for earller.
I wasn't very... I was uptlght.
I also wanted to say...
To wlsh you a good nlght.
See you tomorrow... and to say...
Thls Is pathetlc!
Rene speaking.
You're alone?
Bruno seeklng Llsa.
Julien speaking.
Bruno? Vanessa for Bruno.
Hang up, Bruno, I'll call you back.
- Call me back?.
- I've got your number.
- You're Vanessa?.
- Vanessa, Sonla, Sophle...
Even Llsa sometlmes.
Not cross about Iast tlme?.
It was your fault, you scared me.
- Why dld you call me?.
- My husband dled
one year, four months
and three days ago.
Slnce then at nlght I eat
and meet men through the chatllne.
I meet as many as I want.
Amazlng, lsn't lt?.
Durlng the day,
they wouldn't even Iook at me,
whereas at nlght...
I only go to bed wlth them.
Nothlng else.
I stlll Iove my husband.
Understand?.
I dldn't know. I'm sorry.
I was joklng.
I'm a wrlter.
I'm researchlng my next novel.
I'II send It to you lfyou Ilke,
lt'II be hot.
There's a scene
wlth a guy who ends up
naked In a hotel room
because hls clothes
have been thrown out of the wlndow.
Do you understand now?.
That's the chatllne.
Llsa dldn't try to make me
belleve anythlng.
One can just say nothlng,
fuck In the dark
and Ieave before daybreak,
Ilke a vamplre.
- If that's all you have to say...
- Walt!
I know Llsa.
She won't get lnvolved agaln,
chatllne or no chatllne.
- You know her then?.
- Vaguely.
What does vaguely mean?.
We have boys the same age.
Llsa has chlldren?.
A Ilttle boy.
For the rest, she's Ilke me.
What tart have you got today?.
PIumb tart.
Flnally, you know nothlng.
Yes I do.
She has a son.
Couldn't she have made that up?.
No, he's a frlend of my son.
I've even babysat for her once,
all nlght.
In the mornlng
she took them to school.
I have to go to the tollet.
Watch my bag.
Ifyou want a Ilttle tart,
help yourself.
What were you thlnklng about?.
A teddy bear wlth one eye.
He was my favourlte
when I was a kld.
I was once attracted to a guy
at a party. He had one eye
Ilke my teddy bear.
I thlnk If I was so attracted to hlm
It was because of that.
When you're attracted to eyes,
to a volce,
It's always somethlng
from chlldhood, lsn't lt?.
Have you thought It over?.
Then we can contlnue.
Translated by Paul Belle
Subtltllng TVS - TITRA Parls