Do you remember
the time we were in Canada?
We thought that no one will be able to
find us, but the house caught on fire.
That's why.
I can't let you die because I love you.
Can you trust this PI?
No. He's a bad guy.
That's why I gave him the job.
It won't matter if he gets hurt or
dies because of me.
Detective Yun!
He got away! He's too fast!
What? Again?
- Oh, no! / - What happened?
Find me a route in the city!
Hurry!
Hurry! It's an emergency!
Keiko called again.
Wish her a happy birthday and send her flowers.
Are you done yet?
- In a minute. / - Hurry!
Go 60m, turn left, then turn right,
go straight, left, left, right, left,
then right after 4 stops, then left.
Okay!
That jerk!
Jiwoo! Stop!
Run! Run!
Turn right! Turn right!
Good! Stay calm! Turn left!
I can get him. I can get him.
You were supposed to turn left!
Get in! Come on! Get in the car!
Taxi!
Where did he go? Have you seen him?
Oh, him?
He gave me $10 and told me to go straight.
When I turned around...
He was gone.
You mean...
Do you want me to tell you again?
You let a cuffed man get away!
How many black belts do you have, Detective Kim?
I have a 2nd degree black belt in Judo
and a 4th degree black belt in Hapkido.
And you, Detective Lee?
A 3rd degree black belt in Taekwondo
and a black belt in Kung Fu.
I don't have a black belt because I was a boxer.
What are you doing?
What?
The insurance won't cover the damage.
Use the department's credit card.
It'll go over the credit limit.
There's no credit limit during investigation.
Get Jiwoo on the hold-departure list
and get a list of all the PIs in Japan.
Yes, Sir.
Detective Park, analyze the international
calls between PIs.
Yes, Sir.
What about me?
Drive.
Okay.
Okay, Dosoo.
Access denied.
Let me try.
Don't our eyes look alike?
Your eyes look like stars,
but his eyes look like a technician's eyes.
I can't believe him, but I want to.
If he really found him, he'll come for me.
I owe him money, and he'll have questions.
It's possible,
if he knew about it beforehand.
He turned my parents' death into a suicide.
Long time no see, Jiwoo.
How have you been?
Cut it out. That's tacky.
How have you been, beautiful?
I missed you, Jiwoo.
Your Korean improved a lot.
Mr. Nakamura Hwang taught me well.
I'll give you a private lesson.
Really?
Anytime is good for me.
Stop being ridiculous.
He has a girlfriend.
Really?
I don't have a girlfriend.
Can you trust this PI?
No. He's a bad guy.
That's why I gave him the job.
It won't matter if he gets hurt or
dies because of me.
Jini, every death matters.
I'm sorry.
I don't want to be like this, but I can't help it.
It makes me mad that I have to live
this way, but I can't get mad.
I have to get mad at him in order to find
who killed my family.
You know what?
I heard that men hug like this when they can't
find the right words to say.
Am I being delusional?
You're not like most women.
Where's the hotel? Is it far from here?
Why don't you just stay here?
This is an expensive house.
I don't want it to catch on fire.
It's me.
I think Jini came to Japan with the PI.
Really?
He didn't come here. Kai...
Kai isn't showing any signs.
I'll tell you when they meet.
Sowol.
Yes?
I have many people,
but you're the person I trust the most.
I know.
Bye.
Let me use your computer.
Uh... Go ahead...
Did you do it? What about Jini?
Your password?
It's password protected.
It's me. Wire $1,000 to Nakamura's office.
Why are you spending $100,000 for a password.
We're not like that.
Give me the password.
Why do you have so many questions?
They're going to send the money.
You're always talking about money.
You don't have the human touch.
Sir, $1,000 has been wired from Korea.
It's "Hurray for Nakamura."
I cracked the password.
Thanks. Can you leave me alone for a minute?
It seems like you got into a rough fight.
My father told me that
a bad friend could ruin 10 years,
and a bad girl could ruin your life.
Still, we need to keep appearances
in order to get work.
We should go and get you a new suit.
The car key?
What?
I'll drive.
You've gotten polite ever since
you got back from Korea.
It's like telling a cancer patient
not to catch a cold.
He said that Melchidec is in Japan.
There are 70,000 people in the world who
use the ID Melchidec, with 4,000 in Asia.
There are 600 of them in Japan.
If you take out the 89 inactive accounts
and the minors, there are 13.
9 of them are men. 4 are women.
Is that so?
But there's a very peculiar guy in that list.
He committed 4 crimes, but got out
all 4 times for insufficient evidence.
Aren't you curious?
Why did you come to Japan?
To buy clothes! Clothes!
You've come a long way to buy clothes.
I think he organizes his data well.
You look great.
You look great in a suit.
Why don't you get a few more?
I think you're overspending.
I'm not the one who is paying.
I thought you were buying this for me.
Me? For you? Why?
Okay, then maybe I'll get shoes too.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
The computer logged in.
Who is it?
I'll send the location.
Is it your girlfriend?
I love you.
It's my girlfriend.
Who is this guy?
Does this look passionate to you?
Do you watch this stuff too?
Me?
This is my first time.
He's well-organized.
I'm hungry.
Let's eat.
Something's not right. Can you get me that hat?
That one?
The second one from the bottom.
That thing?
At our age, it's stylish to be unbalanced.
That's how a thug dresses.
How can you think this is cute?
Whoa, it's expensive.
This looks like a trekking hat...
Sir, you didn't pay yet.
That bastard!
Can I put it on the tab?
It's me. Where is he going?
He's passing the Tokyo Provincial Office.
I see. Track him well.
How big is this case, anyway?
I have to make him share.
The air is fresh.
This place should go into development soon.
If you buy 150,000 acres over there...
Put the cigarette out.
I guess you don't smoke.
Take your sunglasses off.
Stand up straight.
Attention! At ease! Attention!
Do you know why I dragged you here?
Maybe it's because of the development.
Or maybe not...
Take your pick.
Either get buried in that coal heap
or fall down from here.
I'll let you pick how you want to die
for old time's sake.
I'll pay you back!
No, that won't be necessary.
Your death will put everything to an end.
Pick where you want to die.
You're taking too long. It'll be over after you die.
I'm a busy man. Think fast.
I have a business partner named Jiwoo.
He lived in the US for a long time.
Unless he's going to pay off your debt, shut up.
Do you know who his girlfriend is?
She's Kieko, a top singer in Japan.
Who?
I don't know her that well either.
What is he saying?
She makes over $10 million a year.
She has a lot of stalkers too.
My partner is working on a case to catch
her longtime stalker.
Wasn't today awesome?
It was very energetic.
Thanks.
So...
I don't want you to get on stage anymore.
Huh? Why?
I want you to myself.
Jiwoo always said that betray comes
from your back.
I've been waiting for a long time.
You can't call this love.
Who do you think you are?
Why are you getting in the way of my love?
Guess who I am?
I'm a PI.
Who are you?
Your guardian angel.
He made money and found love.
So?
We're taking on a great case!
Guess how much it pays? It pays a lot!
So you want me to wait?
Join me!
Are you trying to haggle with me?
Like the old saying goes,
you have nothing to lose.
Yeah, right.
There's a guy named Melchidec.
1 out of 6 people in this world is Chinese.
I'm sure he's in here.
And with a gang like yours,
I'm sure we can find him in no time.
If you add up the reward, interest, and more...
You'll have enough money to give bonuses
to your men and buy them a car each!
So I'll know in a week...
Whether I get to kill you or my boys will.
Or you can thank me for helping you.
I hope we find out soon.
I can't come up with that money in a week!
What am I going to do?
Oh, man...
Sir! Can you pay me in advance
for the Melchidec case?
I'm going to die!
Who was behind you when you were
stabbed in Hong Kong?
Jang Shifu, I'm Hong.
Ms. Hong! Why did you answer the phone?
Mr. Jiwoo got a new number.
Again?
I'll tell him that you called.
Tell him right away! Right now!
You must've made a lot of money.
Nice...
A bugging device.
What's going on?
Do you think the department
credit card is a joke?
Do you think you can spend as much
money as you want with it?
Do you want to get a gold card?
Okay, fine.
I'll get you one. You don't think I can?
Hello? Is this the credit card company?
I'd like the ABCD card...
I'll correct it, chief.
Leave the corrections
to the department of corrections,
and the state affairs to the
department of state affairs.
Then what do you think the police should do?
I'm not sure, but... I'll jump on it.
Yes! Jump! Run!
Don't go to Japan and drive an uninsurable car!
My boss yelled at me
because of the repair costs!
Do you want an imported car?
Okay, I'll get you one.
Why? You don't think I can?
Hello? Do you sell imported cars?
I'd like a German...
I'll go, chief.
I'll go to Japan and take care of this.
I didn't promote you to work well.
I promoted you so you can work on my side.
Yes, my father told me.
I'm always on your side, chief.
Don't ever make me come here again!
Wait, wait...
My arthritis is getting worse.
My ear...
This is driving me nuts!
Hello, Sir!
Where's Dosoo?
Is he in the restroom?
Does he have constipation?
He's with you, right?
Yes!
- What do you think? / - Add the salt!
What? No!
We don't know either.
You're always screwing me over.
Whose side are you on?
You know that I'm always on your side.
I'm going to Japan right now.
Don't do anything. Just wait for me, okay?
Yes, Sir.
I respect you, Sir.
This is driving me nuts. Where's Mr. Dosoo?
He's probably somewhere, acting lonely.
Detective Yun! Do you know where he is?
I heard that you two have something going on.
Not all lovers know everything about each other.
Are you two really lovers?
Why?
Are you jealous?
You can get arrested for sexual
harassment for doing that.
Let's get to work.
There are 2,000 registered PIs in Japan,
and we need their phone records.
Okay, fine.
This is hard labor.
I knew this was going to happen.
You always say that.
Where is Mr. Dosoo?
$6.80.
Receipt, please.
Are you Korean?
Yes, I'm from Korea.
No discount.
Dosoo! Where are you?
How do you say ‘receipt' in Japanese?
Are you eating without us?
It's an emergency. Tell me.
"Ryoshusho."
Okay, bye.
Oh, a receipt.
Ramen restaurants don't have receipts.
We don't have receipts.
"Ryoshusho."
I know that you contacted
the FBI for the Las Vegas incident.
But they said it was a suicide too,
just like that PI.
I can't trust the Korean prosecutors either.
At least they're more trustworthy than that PI.
There's Kevin.
He'll do this in order to
get to that bottom of that case.
Bingo.
Here's your room key.
Thanks.
Aren't you going inside?
I'll go inside by myself.
Let me stay for a little while.
No, I think we should draw the line.
If we go inside together, I won't want you to go.
Okay, I'll go home for today.
Good night.
You have a very dirty hobby.
There was a dance that the aristocrats of
Argentina called dirty in the 19th century.
Pope Benedict XV called it an indecent
dance that destroys homes and the society.
Guess what the dance was?
Tango.
The intellectuals of the time slashed
a culture, based on what they think.
Still, it's forbidden...
"No forbidding allowed."
It was one of the May 1968 slogans in France.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I deleted them.
What?
Where's Melchidec?
You deleted them all?
What about Laura and Kelly?
It was my lifelong collection!
I deleted them all.
I'll give you the information first.
Kevin didn't go to China.
His destination was Korea from the beginning.
Why did Kevin go to Korea without telling you?
Do you still trust Kevin?
Do you still think that he was your friend?
What does that mean?
Let's take turns. Where's Melchidec?
Let's go and get Melchidec tomorrow.
Is that all?
Then do you want to take this
conversation to the bedroom?
Beat it.
Lady first.
Happy birthday.
I got the message from your staff.
I got the flowers too.
I love you.
I heard that from your staff too.
Detective Yun! Thank you very much!
How long are you going to stay in Korea?
Just a little longer.
I have an unfinished case.
I'm going to America soon.
My dad and I met the producers there too.
Do you want to come with me?
Your father doesn't like me.
He's just being stubborn.
He doesn't want me to have a boyfriend
or a scandal before I make it in America.
It is okay to have a scandal
after you become a world star?
When that day comes, I'll go public.
Are you coming to tomorrow's concert?
I have a song for you.
Okay, I'll go.
Really?
I never broke my promise intentionally.
If you come...
If you really come,
I might ask you to the stage.
I want to get on the stage with you and
tell everyone that you're my boyfriend.
Dad! Right now?
No, I was practicing.
Okay.
Sorry. I have to go.
I love you.
I love you. I love you.
Snap out of it, you two.
People get cheated by love and cry over money.
That's life.
I'm not sleeping. I'm thinking.
Detective Yun.
Just call me Soran.
Why do you think Jiwoo came to Japan?
Why did he board a ship instead of a plane?
Who is the woman who disappeared
from the ship?
I don't know.
Did you even think about it
before you answered?
Yes.
Okay. Get back to work.
Have you been shot by a gun?
No.
I've been shot twice.
By the same man.
I heard that the PI is in Japan.
He's not an easy man to persuade.
Why did he come to Japan?
I think he came to find me.
Chairman Yang was too greedy.
He kept all that gold
and silver for himself during the war.
It's about time it backfired on him.
Aren't you the one who dealt
with the gold and silver?
I believe that you got to
where you are today thanks to that.
Mijin.
Are you blackmailing me?
I'm asking you for a favor.
Now that he found out about me, it'll be
a matter of time before he finds you.
You should take care of your own problem.
Go home for today.
If you want...
I'll stay over tonight.
You've turned quite
provocative over the time.
You've been very nice to me.
Dad!
I think my daughter is here.
Do whatever you want.
Wake up.
Wake up!
Take a look.
He's one of the few PIs in
Japan who regularly call Korea.
Do you see his call records?
Yes.
Nakamura Hwang?
A lot of calls overlap.
When we were after Jiwoo in Thailand and
Hong Kong, he called Thailand and Hong Kong.
Find Nakamura Hwang.
Do you want to have breakfast before we go?
Tell me where we're going first.
To get Melchidec.
Are you sure it's him?
Almost.
Let's have breakfast at lunchtime.
I wanted to have lunch.
You're early.
How did you know?
Let's save that for later.
I have to go somewhere.
No.
Let's go.
Sure thing.
Where's Nakamura Hwang right now?
Who are you?
Do you have a warrant?
"She wants a warrant."
What?
Oh, she wants a warrant.
He's passing by Shibuya right now.
Here's the tracking device.
Detective Park, take over.
Yes, Sir.
Melchidec?
Who is Melchidec?
If you really want to pretend, you should've asked
"What is Melchidec?" instead of who.
Let me ask you bluntly.
Why are you trying to kill me?
Because you're with her.
Did you kill my family?
No, you were my assignment.
He was added because of you.
Are you Melchidec?
Do you want to know?
Let's go to Osaka.
Why? Is there a trap?
Why do you think that?
Because you confessed too easily.
You'll see when you get there.
Where is Nakamura?
Nakamura's car is coming this way.
What?
Nakamura? Where?
Jiwoo!
- Jiwoo! Jiwoo! / - Where? Go after him!
Mr. Dosoo!
Will you look at that!
I haven't done this in a long time!
He's a racer!
What's going on?
Something that happens all the time.
It's okay. This isn't my car.
Geez!
Mr. Dosoo!
Oh, my...
What the? Why, I ought to...
Darn! And I was so close!
Move!
Oh, my gosh!
Detective Yun! Are you okay?
Detective Kim! Are you okay?
You idiot!
Detective Yun, tell him.
We're the police.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Do you think this is America or something?
This doesn't work in Japan.
You're Korean! Move!
I'm a member of Chongryon!
You're still our people!
Move! Detective Lee! Take over!
I'm sorry.
Hey!
That idiot!
You're good.
It's part of my job.
Would you like to work for me?
Sure, if you pay me a lot.
Did the person here kill my family?
Don't think about who killed them.
Think about why.
Can we just go in like this?
Hey, this is all part of the plan.
You're annoying me.
I already told you.
If they find me, they'll end up here.
You won't be safe either.
You should take care of them first.
We can put our differences aside later.
Are you that PI?
Are you Melchidec?
You should change the way you talk.
Answer me.
Did you kill my family?
I'm not the one who killed your family.
But you were supposed to be gone too.
Who killed my family?
That's an air gun.
You said that it was a real gun.
It's a real air gun.
Get them!
You said that this is all part of the plan.
Of course.
Don't you have any other plans?
Yes, there's a plan B.
What is it?
Go through them.
There are a lot of people on the left side,
so let's take that side.
But there are only two of us!
No, it's every man for himself.
Let's run forward on the count of three.
1, 2, 3!
Sorry!
I'm here to save you.
What?
Let's put our hands up.
He has a gun.
He's a wanted murder in Korea.
I'm not a murderer.
Let's not stab each other in the back.
I was going to say that first.
What kind of a VIP service is this?
They know who Melchidec is for sure.
I don't think Jini and the PI know anything yet.
Let's get to the bottom of this.
You'll soon hear from her.
Kai is the only person she can rely on.
Jiwoo sent a message to Jang Shifu to meet him.
We have to go to China to find Melchidec.
I'm scared.