Loving You a Thousand Times
Ahjussi!
Can you kick the ball over here please?
It's cold.
Let's go somewhere indoors to talk.
It feels like we're somewhere far away;
like we're sitting in a distant land.
Everything seems like a dream.
Before, I was rash
and I said things I didn't mean. I'm sorry.
Yesterday,
I heard from Grandmother that you did it so
you could pay for Father-in-law's surgery.
Last night, I stayed up all night thinking
about us.
But after I was done thinking,
and thinking some more,
We can no longer be together...
Let's get a divorce.
You should also know that
we have no other choice.
I'll let my family know so you take
care of things at your house.
What is this?
It's alimony.
I'll call you when the divorce
papers are ready.
Kang Ho!
Kang Ho! Wait just for one moment.
I can't take this.
What do you mean you can't take it?
Just take it.
I'm not someone who deserves
to receive alimony.
If I tell you to take it, just take it!
If you and I divorce and you fall
into hard times again,
what are you going to do then?
Kang Ho...
That's why you should have just
taken it without saying anything!
What is this?!
How were we reduced to this?!
So why didn't you tell me?!
If you had told me before we got married,
something like this wouldn't have happened!
Why didn't you tell me?! Why?!
Because I... loved you.
What?
Because I love you so much.
That's why.
I'm sorry...
I was wrong.
Go Eun Nim,
listen to me carefully.
I'm going to forget about you.
So you should do the same.
Forget about me completely,
Okay?
When will I forget about you?
The one and only person in my heart.
Even though I try to forget
I keep on thinking about you.
So it hurts, it hurts,
it hurts, it hurts.
The happy memories
fade away into scars.
When you said you'd be there for me
And that I was the only one for you.
Why did you tell me those things?
And made me fall in love with you.
In the end I feel like a fool.
I thought we were forever.
Like a fool I still
believe in those words.
When will I forget about you?
The one and only person in my heart.
Even though I try to forget
I keep on thinking about you.
So it hurts, it hurts,
it hurts, it hurts.
The happy memories
fade away into scars.
Let's forget, let's forget, even though
I keep telling myself again and again.
I can't forget about you
Even though my heart tells me to
Will I be able to erase everything?
You, the one person in my life
Let's get a divorce.
Even though I try as hard as I can.
I'll let my family know so you take
care of things at your house.
It hurts I'll let my family know so
you take care of things at your house.
It hurts
The happy memories
fade away into scars.
Miss, please stay healthy.
Sister, thank you so much.
I must have been such an inconvenience.
Be well, okay?
Ah, Mommy! Why is this so painful?
All you're doing is grating two onions.
What's taking so long?
I'm grating right now.
When you're done grating these onions,
peel these pears and grate them too, okay?
Grate the pears too?!
Of course!
When you're making bulgogi*.
(*marinated BBQ beef),
grated pears need to be added to soften
the meat and give it a sweet taste.
Then do you want to wipe
down the living room?
Should we switch?
No, it's okay! I'll grate the onions.
Ah, all we're making is bulgogi.
Why is it so complicated?!
This is so tiring.
Oh my! Oh dear! What? What is it?
What? Does your stomach hurt?
Yes... aahh..
Nan Jung! Nan Jung! What's wrong?!
My stomach hurts a little, but it's alright.
What do you mean it's alright?!
Go into the room! Hurry!
Why did you even do chores like
this and tire yourself out?!
Aunt, how could you?
I have to go finish grating
the onions and the pears.
If your stomach hurts, then why are
you worrying about those things honey?
We have to grate them to make bulgogi.
Aish, really!
Nan... Nan Jung! Are you okay?
Can't you see for yourself, Aunt?
She's not okay!
Why did you go and tell Nan Jung
to do things like that?
She didn't even do anything!
I was the one who made breakfast and lunch.
Did she clean or make food?
That's just...
I'm worried about my sister Eun Nim and
if Chul's chicken restaurant will go well.
My heart is so uneasy and anxious lately,
that's why I couldn't do anything, Aunt.
Oh, my Nan Jung. Nan Jung,
is there anything you want to eat?
What do you want? What should I make you?
No. Maybe it's because my stomach hurts,
but there's nothing I want.
Well, then, if there's anything you want
to eat, just tell me whenever.
Get some rest!
But...
I suddenly do want some homemade hodduk*
(*sweet sesame rice pastries).
Hodduk?
I think I have feelings for you, Writer Kim.
Oh! I can't concentrate.
Oh my. How can a person... oh, what is this?
That person must be crazy.
He's insane.
He's not in his right mind.
Ohhhh I can't work!
I can't work! I can't work!
Oh I can't work!
Of all things, how could she
want hodduk?! Really?!
I wonder if her stomach actually hurts!
So Weol! Give me a cup of coffee.
Unni! Can't you see that
I'm kneading the dough?!
It's ready, so just pour it for yourself!
Uh.. alright.
But why are you kneading dough?
Are you making kalgooksoo*?
(*flour noodles in vegetable-egg broth)
Ahem. Your daughter-in-law says that
she wants to have some homemade hodduk.
Hodduk?! That sounds delicious!
Of course.. everyone wants to have
some so of course I need to make it.
You know..
So Weol, I have a friend of a friend..
Whom a younger man confessed his love to!
Really?! At that age?
That woman must have saved
a country in a past life.
But how old is the man?
Oh, I'm not quite sure,
but she said he's 12 years younger.
Oh my! Isn't that man crazy?
Unni, so your friend's friend..
what did she say?
Does she like him?
She's not sure if she likes him,
but she seems to be a little confused.
There are other things to be confused about!
A man who's 12 years younger...
Unni, tell your friend not to
associate with that woman.
That woman really has no conscience.
Wow, 12 years..
Hey, I'll go answer the door.
Okay.
Oh my... oh my.
He even has a bouquet of flowers!
This person must be crazy!
Really?
Unni! Who is it?
Why aren't you opening the door?
Uh, I'm opening it!
I'm opening it! It's Director Bong!
You'd better not say anything weird!
- Hello!
- Ah yes.
Oh my! Why do you have a bouquet of flowers?
Ah, this is a leftover prop from the movie.
I thought it'd be a waste
to throw it out so keep it!
And during a break while shooting,
it seemed like Writer Kim liked
walnut cookies so I bought some.
I'm busy so I'll be leaving now.
Do you at least want a
cup of tea before going?
No, it's fine! I just dropped by
while was scouting for possible
locations for shoots so..
Good-bye.
Oh dear... why is he acting like this??
Wow.. he says it's a prop,
but how can the flowers
be so fresh and pretty?
Why are you two home so early?
I stopped by the job resort
and it seemed like Father wasn't feeling
well so I accompanied him home early.
Honey, don't you have to go
to the hospital then?
It's nothing serious.
- Are you home?
- Yes.
What about Kang Ho?
He's not back yet. He hasn't called either.
But...
What about Daughter-in-law?
Daughter-in-law still isn't back yet?
Kang Ho's having such a rough time.
Daughter-in-law hasn't come home in days.
What are you all hiding from me?
- Oh my son, you're home?
- Yes, Mother.
How are you feeling?
I know you must be tired,
but sit here for a moment.
Mother, while I was away
on the business trip,
what happened at home?
Why isn't daughter-in-law coming home?
The truth is...
Kang Ho and daughter-in-law
fought for reasons unknown to me...
and granddaughter-in-law left the house.
What?
Daughter-in-law left the house?
But what did she fight with Kang Ho about?
We too have no idea.
If granddaughter-in-law were home,
Kang Ho wouldn't have things so rough..
Son... I'm so upset about so many things
going on I don't know what to do.
What in the world have
you been doing at home?
Our daughter-in-law has left the house, so
how can you just sit back and do nothing?!
What do you expect me to do about
something they fought about?
- Kang Ho!
- Oh, Kang Ho!
Kang Ho's home!
Oh Kang Ho!
Why did you come home just now?
Where were you?
Did you want to see me so upset I could die?
Kang Ho! Come and sit down.
That's right. Come and sit next
to your grandmother.
Do you see, Kang Ho?
Grandmother, your mom, your Hyung and me
were so worried about you last night
that we couldn't get any sleep.
Kang Ho...
Everything that has happened is your
grandma's and your dad's faults.
So Kang Ho,
please just don't say that you're
going to leave this house.
If you're going to leave,
then leave after your grandma dies. Please.
Alright.
Thank you, Kang Ho.
Also, I don't know why you
and your wife are fighting..
But hurry and bring your wife home, okay?
I have something I need to tell you all.
Okay, tell us.
Eun Nim and I have decided to get a divorce.
W- what? Divorce?
What's the reason?!
The reason?
I am unable to tell you the reason.
What do you mean?
Getting a divorce after you marry
someone isn't something
that's decided so easily, is it?
Father, please don't ask me anything else.
I just wanted you all to know.
Kang Ho!
Just leave him be.
He must have a reason for acting that way,
would he be like that for kicks?
They're not children
and they'll decide things as mature adults,
so just let them be.
Look at you. Huh?
It's not anything else,
but your son is saying he wants
a divorce and you're telling us to
not do anything about it?!
Can you really say that as a mother?
He doesn't want to try anymore
because you're being like this!
You could have at least met
with granddaughter-in-law.
And just like my son said,
ask her what the reason is!
Don't we at least have to
know about the situation?!
Isn't that so?!
Mother,
I'll go see Daughter-in-law
so don't worry too much.
No, why would you meet her?
It would be much more comfortable if
Yoo Bin's mother or I went to see her.
If you go see her,
do you think she'd comfortably be
able to talk about what's going on?
Father-in-law,
I'll go meet her.
That's right! Okay! That would be better.
Unni!
Why aren't you going inside?
Oh..
Unni..
where did you come from?
Is it true that you came back
from a trip with brother-in-law?
Eun Jung..
let's go inside.
She said she's coming so she
should be on her way! Please sit.
You're making me anxious as well.
Have some papaya tea.
You really don't listen to me.
Mom! Dad!
Eun Nim unni is here.
What? Really?
Mom... Dad.
Why are you in such a state?
Did you really leave that house?!
Divorce?!
Oh my, Nan Jung was right, honey.
- Do you have another man?
- Honey!
Does son-in-law Baek feel the same way?
Yes, Dad.
Why?
What could be the reason for bringing
up divorce in front of your dad?!
Dad.
There must be a reason for getting
a divorce! What is it?
Can you just be quiet?!
Did the in-laws say something to you?
Is that it?
What? Did you do something to upset them?
No, that's not it.
Then why would you divorce?
You two were happy and living
just fine! How did this happen??
Oh... Eun... Hey Eun Nim!
I don't think it's because of the in-laws.
Do you think there really is something
going on with son-in-law Baek?
How could this... I mean...
Go upstairs and tell Kang Ho to eat
even if he doesn't want to.
Yes ma'am.
Ahjumma, you don't need to.
Kang Ho's not here.
What? Kang Ho's not here?
Did you go up to his room?
Yes.
Where did he go without
eating breakfast first?
Do you think he left home again?
I don't think so.
Yesterday he said he wouldn't.
That's right.
If our Kang Ho said that he's not leaving,
then he won't.
Even if he goes, he would have told
me that he was leaving first.
Yoo Bin's mom,
go see daughter-in-law today.
Yes Sir.
Team Leader!
Yeol Nam! It's been a while.
I thought you were someone else
because your style has changed.
Nothing serious happened
while I was gone, right?
Yes. There was nothing going
on at the office, but..
Team Leader, what happened to you?
Is there something going on with Eun Nim?
Yes?
Father, Kang Ho's come in to work.
Really?
This is a design of young people
at the beach during summer time.
Don't you think it'd be uncomfortable if it
looks more of an underwear advertisement?
It's because the concept is
being healthy and sexy.
What I think is the model should be wearing
exercise clothes and jogging,
but if you get a glimpse of underwear
through her clothes,
it seems healthier and sexier.
Then it's the you see it
or you don't concept, isn't it?
What's next on the agenda?
Hello, it's me.
Yes, then I'll see you there.
Alright, please sit down.
I'm not sure if I should have asked to see you
when you are busy with work.
It's alright.
What happened... between you and Eun Nim?
Something must have happened..
Eun Nim keeps saying something strange..
That you two want a divorce.
It's not true, right?
That you want a divorce?
It's true.
Eun Nim and I have decided to get a divorce.
Why are you doing this all of a sudden? Huh?
You two were so happy together..
What in the world happened
to make you want to-
Fine,
if you definitely want a divorce,
what's the reason?
Eun Nim's not saying anything..
So can you at least tell me what it is?
I don't love Eun Nim anymore.
I dislike her now.
What... what did you...
That's why I said I wanted a divorce.
Because you dislike...
Because you don't love...
That's why you said you wanted a divorce?!
Huh?
How difficult was it for you
two to get married?!
My Eun Nim...
my Eun Nim cried so much tears because
she wanted to marry you!
But because of that lousy reason..
How can you say you want
a divorce so easily?!
Is marriage some kind of joke?!
I have another woman.
I just wanted to let you know that.
You no-good bastard.
Fine. Get a divorce then!
Get a divorce.
So Weol, I'm going out
and will be back soon.
Where are you going?
There's a practice reading today.
Why don't you have one more
hodduk before you go?
I already had one, why would
I eat another one? I'll be back!
Mom, are you going out?
- Yep, I'll be back, my son!
- Okay, see you later!
- Aunt!
- Your mom's going to a practice reading.
She ate those five hodduks already?!
Oh, Nan Jung, no, our baby in her stomach
must think the hodduks are delicious.
I only ate one, but Nan Jung
ate the rest by herself.
Aunt, are the other hodduks done?
Oh yes, just wait a little longer,
they'll be ready soon.
Okay Aunt!
She said that her stomach was hurting
a little bit like she has lactic acid.
How can she eat those hodduks
without any problems like that?
What's wrong, Aunt?
Oh, it's nothing. Nothing at all.
Nan Jung!
Nan Jung, what are you doing?
I was just laying here.
I made some more hodduks. Do you want some?
Yes, Aunt!
There you go!
Oh.. oh my... Chul!
I think we should take Nan Jung
to the hospital.
Oh no.. look at her face! It's so pale.
Is Nan Jung's face pale?
Hey, get dressed so we can go to the OB-GYN.
If your stomach keeps hurting like that,
it's because you have lactic acid.
No, it's okay!
They said I was fine last time.
Your stomach hurts when you're fine?
It's because you're not okay
that your stomach hurts!
That's... Aunt, you have a point.
Honey, let's hurry and go.
My stomach doesn't hurt!
You said it hurts! Let's go!
Let's go! You shouldn't eat hodduk
because you're hurting.
Ah, quickly!
The mother and the baby are
both very healthy.
Is there no lactic acid?
Yes! When I looked before,
there weren't any problems either.
Really? Thank you!
Thank you!
Then why did you say that your stomach
hurt so much you couldn't do anything??
Aunt, that... that was probably
because I had an upset stomach!
What?
Oh dear..
My money... My money...
My money!!!
Yes. I asked for a renegotiation before.
I just wanted to know if
the contract closing was done.
What did you say?
That company isn't able
to do a transaction?!
What?
It went over to a management company?
And what's that?
What does that even mean?!
The shares became worthless?!
Then that means that money became worthless!!!
Oh my...
this can't be! This can't!
I'm so dead now.
What do I do now?!
I'm completely ruined!
Mom, what's wrong?
Yeon Hee!
You've been like this for a few days now.
You need to tell me what it is.
It's nothing. Nothing at all.
What should I do about Yeon Hee?
What do I do about this?
If Yeon Hee finds out, she'll go crazy.
Mom, get up. I made some porridge
so you should have some.
No, no.
There's no point if I eat
that and keep living.
Mom, what's wrong?
What- why are you like that?
Are you not feeling well?
Oh, yeah, I guess I'm not.
I must have indigestion because I ate
my kimbap too quickly at lunch.
You go ahead and eat, Mom.
Oh.. is our Yeon Hee.. pregnant?
If our Yeon Hee has a
child for that household..
Wait a second.
Then what happens?
Then that means that my Yeon Hee can
become the Baek family's daughter-in-law.
Money won't be a problem then, will it?
Mom, what are you thinking
about so seriously?
Yeon Hee, I think you're pregnant.
Mom!
Now that I see it,
I really think you are pregnant.
Is your stomach not well?
I'm not, Mom.
Let's go to the hospital.
I said I'm not!
Mom, why are you being like this?
You're not?
Are you really not?
What's the problem if she's
not pregnant right now?
All we need is for her to get pregnant.
That household considers
offsprings so important.
Because of the need to have an offspring,
they even got a surrogate.
If my Yeon Hee gives birth to
a child for that household...
That's right. It isn't like the first son
doesn't have feelings for Yeon Hee.
If he divorces So Weol's niece,
then it's only a matter of time
until Yeon Hee has a chance.
I just spoke to your Father-in-law
and Kang Ho must have figured things out.
They said he came to work
and is working diligently.
You should put yourself at ease now,
nothing's going to happen.
Then will brother-in-law and that
woman really get a divorce?
They said they will, so they probably will.
Father-in-law told me to go see her..
what should I do?
Should I ask her if they're
definitely going to divorce
and try and see if she has
nothing else planned?
No. Just forget about it.
I'll take care of telling
your father-in-law.
If the girl says she won't come back to
this house because they want a divorce,
what can he do?
That's true, but..
Are you going out somewhere?
To pick up Yoo Bin.
Really?
I was about to leave for the gallery.
It's been a while since we've been out, why
don't we take Yoo Bin and go to the gallery?
Yes, Mother-in-law.
Alright, finish getting ready and come out.
Yes, it's me.
Do you want to come out
and meet me for dinner?
It's been so long since the three of us
including Yoo Bin have gone out for dinner.
Dinner tonight?
You came back home
and I couldn't even pay much attention to
you because of what happened to Kang Ho.
I'm going with Mother to pick up Yoo Bin
from his kindergarten and go to the gallery.
Then leave Yoo Bin with Mother
and just come out by yourself.
Alright.
There's still some time left
before school's out.
Really?
Mother-in-law,
do you want to go inside and
see Yoo Bin in school?
Can we really go see?
Of course. We can just look
through the window.
Yes, let's do that.
I'm so curious to see if
Yoo Bin in doing well.
Oh my.. who's this?
Come here.
Let go of me!
Mother-in-law..
Who's your mother-in-law? Who?!
Who do you think you're staring at?!
What have you done right?!
What exactly is it that
I've done wrong to deserve this?
What? You...
What right do you have to hang
around Yoo Bin's school?
You know the reason,
so why are you being like this?
- Oh my, oh my. How can this girl...?!
- Oh! Mother-in-law!
Let's go, it's time for Yoo Bin to come out.
If I were you, I would never
appear before Yoo Bin.
Think carefully about what I'm saying.
Mother-in-law, let's go.
Yoo Bin's about to come out.
Aren't you going to leave?!
What are you going to do
if Yoo Bin sees you?!
Mother-in-law, even if that woman
and brother-in-law divorce,
what's the use?
She won't even leave Yoo Bin alone.
Don't worry about anything.
She's not going to appear
in front of Yoo Bin again.
What right would she have to do so?
If that woman possibly...
Now if she and brother-in-law
are divorced-
What if she tries to take Yoo Bin from us?
Why are you thinking about such
a preposterous situation?
How could she do something like
that if she hasn't gone insane?
She has no right and no means to do that.
Mother-in-law, I did some research
and in situations like this,
if the surrogate mother
files for guardianship,
the child can go to the person who
gave birth, not the one who cared for it.
What? Is that really true?
Yes.
What kind of ridiculous situation is that?!
Oh my, that doesn't make any sense!
That's impossible.
Yes, it's me.
Is it Sae Hun?
I'm at home right now.
Mother-in-law had something she needed
to do so we didn't go to the gallery.
Yoo Bin's sleeping right now,
so I'll go alone.
Honey, what are you thinking about?
Are you still uncomfortable around me?
Should we leave here?
What do you mean leave?
Somewhere very far.
Let's take Yoo Bin and
live somewhere far away.
America, or Europe.
Somewhere else is fine too.
Why are you saying something
like that so suddenly?
I just don't like it here.
I just want to go somewhere abroad to live.
Alright, fine.
I was thinking that too.
If you and I went to live
abroad for a few years,
wouldn't we be able to forget
all the bad memories?
I thought of that too.
Then let's start thinking
about it seriously.
Alright.
Do you have to go?
I promised, so what can I do?
I'll just choose the interior design
quickly and be home soon.
It's just that being alone at home
with Aunt scares me.
So why did you lie like that?
You even used our baby as an excuse!
Anyway.
I don't know!
I really thought I was hurting.
Okay.
I'll be back soon.
Go on.
I'll just sleep until Chul comes back.
Oh Geum Ja unni! It's been so long.
Yes it has!
But what about Uunni?
Who? Oh, my sister?
Yeah.
Oh, Unni went to the broadcasting station.
Oh, really?
When is she coming back?
Why are you asking about Unni?
It's just that I heard
something so unbelievable..
So I wanted to tell your sister about it.
What is it?
Tell me! It's the same whether
you tell me or unni.
Well, you have a point.
It's just that your niece Seon Young..
No, no, I think it'd be better
if I didn't say anything.
Oh unni! What about our Seon Young?
I don't know if it's okay that
I tell you something like this.
What is it? Why are you being like that?
It's just that.. oh dear..
how could something like this happen?
I just heard it on the grapevine,
but you know Seon Young's son Yoo Bin?
Seon Young didn't give birth to him,
but a surrogate mother did!
What do you mean a surrogate mother?
What... what is that?
You don't even know what that is?
Your niece couldn't have children,
so she borrowed another woman's
womb to have one!
U... unni! Are you insane?
It's been so long since I saw you, and now
you come and say crazy things like that?
Oh my, oh my, look at you.
Do I look insane to you?
Why would I take valuable
time to come look for you?
How can she care for a child that
another woman had for her?
I heard that that mother-in-law
planned everything and set it up!
That's not all!
Your niece's husband cheated on her
and that woman even got pregnant!
Oh-oh my... oh my...
U- u-unnie! This- what- you...
W... what are you talking about now?!
If you're going to say things
like that, just go home!!!
Hey, you should tell your niece to
come out of that house this instant.
If I were you, I wouldn't let my daughter
live in a place like that.
What time is it?
Oh... oh no! Look at me.
I have somewhere I need to go.
Why do I keep forgetting things like this?
I'll be going now!
That unni must be crazy.
Aunt...
Aunt, what was that woman talking about?
Aunt, have some water and you'll be okay.
That unni.. she suddenly came
and why was she being like that?
She must have some sort
of grudge against our family.
Do you think what she said was true?
No. They were all lies.
So you can't ever tell anyone, okay?
Who would I tell something like this to?
Don't tell Chul either.
If she knows, my sister,
your mother-in-law will die.
Don't worry! I won't ever tell anyone!
I'll take it to the grave.
Oh my.. my sister-in-law had
a child through a surrogate?
How could this happen?
That's right.. I thought it was really weird
how she and Yoo Bin looked nothing alike.
Of course. Who would I tell this to?
I can't ever tell.
Where did you go?
I had something I needed to do.
Come sit here.
Tell me the truth.
What's the reason you want a divorce?
For various reasons.
What are the various reasons?
Mom,
can't I tell you later when
everything gets cleared up?
Mom!
Mom! Mom! Mom!
Hey! Why are you running so breathless?
No, no, it's nothing.
If I tell you, it'll cause huge problems.
What is it?
Eun Nim, you didn't know either?
What?
You know that child Yoo Bin?
I heard that my sister-in-law
didn't give birth to him!
What??
What?
If she didn't give birth to him,
did someone else?
It seems forged or something.
If someone else had him, then that's that.
What's forged mean?
Well you see, that...
No, I can't say.
I'm so curious now! Tell me, you brat!
Mom, so, you see, our sister-in-law
couldn't conceive,
so she used a surrogate to have him!
Oh... oh... oh my... oh my!
A surrogate?!
But, w... what is that?
Hey, this is a secret so don't
act like you know!
A rumor like this can't get out.
Just keep it to yourself!
Where are you going when you just got home?
Mom, why is she like that?
Her face looks like death.
Mom, is Eun Nim really getting a divorce?
Ah, I don't know! Your father's so upset
about her that he's on the brink of death.
But why is she getting a divorce?
They couldn't live without each other.
She won't say!
If I knew, I wouldn't feel so frustrated.
Ahjumma, it's me. Let's meet right now.
Why do you want to meet?
I have something to say.
Something to say?
Okay.
Fine, I'll meet her and try to
figure out what's happening.
Ohh.. my money..
My money...
Ahjumma, come with me.
W... why are you like this?
Where do you want to go?
Go with me to the police station.
What?
The police station?
Why the police station?
We'll just tell the police everything
and receive our punishment
so everything will be over.
What are you saying?
Ahjumma,
why are you going around
telling people about Yoo Bin?
What do you want to happen to Yoo Bin?
You keep saying we should
go to the police station..
But if we go and confess,
I'm not the only one who'll be punished.
You'll be punished too!
Ahjumma, I'm not scared at
all of getting punished.
I'm even getting a divorce.
I left that house as well.
You really...
Why are you doing this to me?!
What did I do wrong?
Ahjumma,
why are you going around
telling people about Yoo Bin?
Oh... oh my...
what I told So Weol at her house
must have gotten out.
How can it be out this quickly?
Ahjumma,
I'm begging you.
Just leave Yoo Bin alone.
I don't care what happens to me.
If Yoo Bin finds out about this..
Ahjumma,
I'm not joking around.
If you tell people about Yoo Bin
one more time, I won't sit still.
Oh... oh my... how could she have realized?
She seems like she's going to do something
about this immediately.
I was scared to death!
But why is nothing happening when
even Eun Nim found out that I told?
What are you doing here?
I have something I need to tell you.
Tomorrow if you have time,
let's meet at the lawyer's office
to finalize the divorce.
Okay.
But did you come all this
way just to tell me that?
You could've just told me over the phone.
Then I'll see you tomorrow.
Wait a second.
Here.
Where did your wedding band go?
You had it on before!
Hey! Are you really going to get a divorce?!
I told you to get out!!
Is it true that Seon Young didn't
give birth to Yoo Bin?
How did you...
I heard that the girl you were
seeing is pregnant!
Our Seon Young doesn't know anything.
Yoo Bin, are you drawing your mom's face?
Her hairstyle is different.
This is Aunt.
The homework topic is A Face I Miss.
Hey! Go Eun Nim!
I'm not going to divorce Eun Nim.
I can't.
Why do we have to?