What I appreciate about India
is that it is a democracy...
...with a transparent legal system.
If you buy a plot of land,
you can be sure it is yours.
Nobody will take it from you
tomorrow...
...by demanding new taxes
or trying to confiscate it otherwise.
These are the remnants
of the colonial era.
This legal system is
very important for me.
It's an important
investment criterion.
We are very satisfied with it.
My name is Mirko Kovats,
I am Austrian.
I built up one of the biggest
Austrian industrial groups...
...over the past ten years.
Nobody is calling for the state here.
You have to take care of yourself.
I am always astonished
to hear discussions at home...
...about the problems
we think we have.
They never stop discussing...
...how to take things away
from people by taxing them.
All that does not count here.
The only thing that counts here
is the economy.
My name is Sujatha Raaju.
I have completed commerce studies
from the Madras University.
We are here in Chennai,
one of the biggest cities in India.
It was formally known as Madras.
It is populated
with 8 million people.
One third of the population
lead a life like this.
That is, they live
on the banks of the rivers.
Some of them live
even a much poorer life...
...living on the pavements.
In Europe students are interested
in sociology.
Everybody wants
to become a teacher.
Here they are studying
engineering.
I ask myself who will be where
in 10 or 20 years.
Will they be richer?
Will we be poorer?
I hope not.
The people
who finance the company are...
- As always if you have a company
quoted on the stock market...
...investors from London,
who manage the money...
...in pension funds and insurances.
The factory is already too small.
We think about moving and
enlarging it to the fourfold size.
Competition forces us
to take measures...
...all very unpleasant.
But we are under pressure
from globalization.
We have to compete with people...
...who get very small wages...
...but have to earn their living.
Of course,
working hours will become longer.
I am sure that this overtime
will not be paid.
It is quite simple,
we have to work more.
We have no choice.
Very tidy.
Was this difficult to achieve?
I had to put a lot of effort into it.
But it works, as we see.
I am really astonished.
Are you having any discussions
with labour unions?
Fortunately not, up to now.
I try to take into account...
...our employees' social situation.
How much does a welder earn?
The equivalent of
200 euros a month on average.
That's what he earns?
Or what he costs?
That is what he earns.
He costs us about 25% more.
250.
What about an engineer?
Around 8-10 times more.
That makes 2500.
That is far below Europe...
...but not cheap any more.
You have to consider
the booming markets in India.
The price increase
will not only be 3-5%...
...but 10-15% in the next years.
That's something
to take into account in future.
That means we have to be efficient.
We can't afford to be generous.
The costs will increase.
I worked in order to minimize
the processes...
...and to reduce the additional costs.
We invested
in half automated production...
...in order to reduce the costs
or keep them low.
We have to buy it at any price.
It will only become more expensive.
The prices won't fall.
Indians pay their taxes.
Taxes are collected by the government
in form of sales tax...
...revenue tax, water tax,
electricity tax...
...property tax
and so many other taxes...
...that are collected
by the government.
But this revenue
is given to foreign investors...
...in the form of grants.
And the government lacks
the money...
...to take care of the social welfare
of the people.
Environmental and social standards
will not change for a long time.
The costs to raise these standards...
...cannot be paid by countries
like India or China.
This is reality - Like it or not.
The majority of people are poor.
And they will stay poor
for a long time.
They have to stay competitive
at any price.
Therefore, I think that, except
for soft declarations of good will...
...things won't change much
over the next decades...
...because people can't afford it.
Flourishing economic growth
has nothing to do...
...with the people or the society.
Economic growth is only for
the politician, for the investor...
...and for the middleman
who plays between them.
10 years ago,
in a middleclass family...
...if the income of the family
was around 10000...
...they were able to save
at least 2000 to 3000 rupees.
But those days are gone.
Today, even if they earn 20000...
...they are not able to save
a single penny.
There is a lot of foreign culture
in India...
...and people are getting
accustomed to it...
...following all the ways
to imitate the Western culture.
But poverty
has not been eradicated.
There are still poor people.
This can be eradicated only...
...if there is a good political system
in India.
My name is Kalaiselvan.
I am in the 7th class,
I am 12 years old.
I have been living in the slum
Gandhinagar since I was born.
When I am grown up,
I want to be a lawyer...
...and I want
to fight against corruption.
My name is Gerhard Schwarz.
For 14 years,
I have been chief editor...
...of the economic section
of Neue Zürcher Zeitung.
I also teach
at the University of Zurich.
Besides, I am President...
...of the Friedrich August
Hayek-Society.
Friedrich August von Hayek
was certainly...
...the most important liberal economist
of the 20th century.
He was born in Austria...
...and worked in England,
America and Germany.
We are on our way from vevey
on Lake Geneva...
...to Mont Pèlerin.
Meaning "Pilgrim's Mount".
It is a little village
with some big hotels.
In 1947 some of the most important...
European and American thinkers
met here...
...to reflect upon the future
of the Western World.
The Mont Pèlerin Society was founded
in this "Hotel du Parc".
The founders' goal was
to organize...
...an intellectual network.
They did not want to make politics...
...but wanted to influence politics
with their ideas.
The Mont Pèlerin Society
became famous in the 1980s...
...with Ronald Reagan.
In his government
and in his advisory team...
...there was a great number of members
of the Mont Pèlerin Society.
Sometimes 20 or even more members.
Approximately at the same time
Margaret Thatcher...
...drew on Hayek's ideas...
...and the ideas of British members...
...of the Mont Pèlerin Society.
Here we are at the entrance
of the Sahel.
All the soils are ruined.
There is total erosion,
even ravines.
This is the result
of the cotton monoculture.
The cotton is gone...
...the money for the cotton is gone.
The only thing left is this soil,
where you can't cultivate anything.
I am called Yves Delisle.
I am an agronomist by profession.
I studied
Development Studies in Geneva.
I have been working directly
with farmers for about 20 years.
20 years is quite a long time.
But up to now,
I have the impression...
...that the situation
has not improved.
These people earn
not even 50 euros a year.
We are anxious!
We are fed up.
Our children cultivate cotton,
but they don't get anything for it.
What shall we do?
We are reduced to doing nothing.
We hope for your help.
To improve our lives.
Go and tell those
who buy the cotton to help us...
...to buy the cotton at a fair price.
So that Burkina and we
get more money.
Old women like me work the whole
day long under the sun. For nothing.
But what can we do?
Try to understand us.
We beg you.
You see how tiring the work is.
If we managed to pay back
our loans, we would be glad.
The quality of cotton is the best
in the world.
The production costs
are the lowest.
The cotton is clean,
because all is done by hand.
Nevertheless, the price is very low
on the world market.
Every year, the USA subsidize
their cotton producers...
...with $3 billion.
If the Americans are liberal,
so be it!
But why do they subsidize
their cotton producers?
This isn't liberalism!
In reality,
they practise protectionism...
...and impose liberalism on us.
They apply two different standards!
It is like if you have a football field
and two teams.
Team A has the best shoes
and can also use their hands.
Team B - And these are the Africans,
and small countries like us...
...have to play
without shoes or hands.
Do you consider this
to be normal?
In the 1980s the World Bank imposed...
...restructuring programmes
on Burkina Faso.
What does this mean for the country?
Raw materials are exported...
...cotton in the form of raw cotton...
...without added value.
All the World Bank and the investors
are interested in...
...is sucking raw materials
out of the country.
Cotton, timber, coffee, cacao, gold,
and so on.
In the past, the colonialists forced us
to cultivate a certain product.
Now the World Bank
puts us under pressure...
...with money to plant cotton.
How can you buy medicine?
You need foreign currency.
The cotton can bring us
this foreign currency.
I told you that cotton makes the living
of two million people - Directly.
But if you calculate that in Africa...
...every person supports
another 15 people...
...multiply by 2 million...
...and you quickly realize that
the whole population lives off cotton.
If the USA did not subsidize
their cotton...
Burkina Faso would make profits...
...of at least 80 billion CFA a year.
The bilateral aid...
...the credits from the EU...
USA and Japan...
...represent altogether only
20 billion CFA.
You see, we would not need to get
into debt to develop our country!
The work of the farmers alone
would permit us...
...to construct schools and roads...
...in order to give a better future
to our children.
This is the dilemma we are facing
with the cotton production today.
Here you see women
sweeping the soil.
They sell the soil or pebbles...
...in order to earn
a little bit of money.
According to the
UN development program...
...there are only 3 poorer countries.
62% of the population...
...has less than 1 dollar per day
to live on.
Among these 62%, a large part...
...is living in destitution.
That is even worse than poverty.
40% of the children
don't go to school.
Out of those
who begin to go to school...
...only 1-2% reach university.
Life expectancy here is 42 years.
Speaking about misery,
you have to notice...
...that the most destitute social group
are women and children.
Some women go to the quarries.
In that way they can earn...
...about 50 euro cents per day.
We have many debts.
Every Burkinan born today
is already deeply in debt.
Even those who are born
in 25 years already debts.
If we don't produce cotton...
...every African living in Burkina...
...but also those living in Mali,
Benin and other countries...
...will emigrate to Europe.
We will have no choice but to go.
We will invade you, sure enough.
But if the West doesn't stop
subsidizing their cotton...
...we will be forced to go.
If we go...
...they can construct
walls 10 meters high...
...we will nevertheless come to Europe.
All liberals in the world think
that frontiers should be open...
...for goods...
...money and services.
It becomes more complicated
if people are concerned.
You have to think about...
...introducing
membership fees...
...as you demand membership fees
in a club.
If you become a member
of a tennis club...
...you have to pay membership fees...
...not only monthly...
...or annual fees like taxes.
This is because
the predecessors built...
...the club house
and prepared the place.
Otherwise
the newcomer would profit...
...from something
he did not contribute to.
20 years ago...
...the financial groups,
banks and investors...
...began to make a grab...
...for public goods.
Goods actually belonging
to the state...
...and to the citizens,
who have to regularly...
...pay their rent, water rates, etc.
That is the whole point
of privatization.
We are sitting in
a public transport tram in Vienna.
Every citizen assumes...
...that the trams belong
to the City of Vienna.
But this is not the case.
This tram belongs
to an American investor.
Some years ago, the City Council
of Vienna decided...
...to sell its trams
to American investors.
They got a lot of money for them...
...more than $1 billion.
But the City of Vienna
never received that money.
Instead, the money was transferred...
...to banks in England and elsewhere.
They took the money...
...and for years to come will pay...
...periodic leasing instalments
to the American investor...
...so that the City of Vienna
has the right...
...to use the trams.
Can you imagine that?
The state is the community
of all people living in that state.
We are the state.
This applies at least
to a democracy.
In order to organize
a functioning society...
...the state needs public goods...
Schools, universities...
...public transport, etc.
In this context,
it is interesting to see...
...what is going on
with privatization.
" Privatization" originates
from the Latin word "privare"
...which means "to deprive".
In the process
of privatization...
...public goods
are bought...
...by private investors.
Sometimes they even receive them
as a present.
This is nothing else...
...than depriving society
of public goods.
You could sum it up as follows:
Society is deprived of a certain good...
...that the private investor
is interested in...
...for reasons of profit.
This strange system called
"cross-border-leasing"
...has been widely applied...
...not only in the case
of the viennese trams.
The Austrian Federal Railways...
...sold their trains
to American investors.
The City of Innsbruck
sold its public utilities.
Since we live in the era
of globalization...
...this didn't only take place in Austria...
...but also in Germany, the Netherlands
and everywhere in Europe.
The fact that politicians sanction
a cross-border-system...
...is sometimes due to ignorance.
Those who understand...
...care only about the very
short period of their career.
They are not interested
in what happens after them.
This short-term attitude...
...the lack of a will to take
responsibility for the long term...
- Knowing it will be up to others
to resolve the problems later...
...is characteristic
of the neo-liberal era.
In the neo-liberal era...
...everything is reduced...
...to making the highest profits
immediately.
And this at any price.
Over the past 10-15 years...
...a dramatic change
in the distribution of incomes...
...took place due to globalization.
Millions of
blue and white collar workers...
...had their earnings under pressure.
They no longer got
the wages they demanded.
Globalization made them work for less.
That led to a considerable shift
of incomes...
...in favour of capital.
This huge quantity of money
had to be invested.
That led to a dramatic abortive
development.
A new industry emerged...
...financial services,:
...investment bankers,:
...private equity funds,:
hedge funds.
This new industry
is a phenomenon...
It earns piles of money,
not by staking its own money...
...but by staking foreign money.
For each dollar and euro
that is invested...
...they get a commission.
Cologne is in a privileged situation
on the Rhine.
My name is Anton Schneider.
I am partner in a small
private equity fund.
That means
we collect our investors' capital.
We invest it
together with our money...
...in enterprises we restructure
and sell afterwards.
The private equity industry
is at the centre of attention...
...because normally
we buy enterprises...
...with rather low equity capital.
The purchase price
is mainly financed by debts.
These debts are merged
with the enterprise.
That way, the enterprises
which have been bought...
...have to service huge debts.
They do not have much money
left for investments.
That works as long as
the economy is good...
...as long as there are high profits.
As long as there is
no economic downturn.
As long as the enterprises...
...have made enough
previous investments.
But in many cases,
it does not work out.
The purchase prices
have increased incredibly.
They were financed...
...with a huge amount
of outside capital.
The risk is that the enterprises...
...cannot pay back their debts.
In that case, the banks
must write off the credits.
The enterprises are fleeced of
their money for years.
So they can't do
what they are supposed to do:
Develop products, invest,
create new jobs.
That is why
they are called "Locusts".
Unfortunately, I think
this is precisely the right term.
The whole financial system
increased in importance.
And that happened for 2 reasons:
First, those who possess the capital
become ever greedier.
Second, the managers of the capital...
...get commissions.
The riskier
the investment forms are...
...the more they profit
from the operation.
Hello.
Welcome to the El Algarrobico Hotel.
We are in Spain, in Andalusia...
...in Almeria...
...in the village
of Carboneras.
The hotel is situated...
...in the National Park
of Cabo de Gata...
...beginning in the west over there.
This is an important marine
and terrestrial reserve.
We are fighting for the preservation
of the biosphere...
...of the climate and fresh air...
...and for the preservation
of the species...
...living on land and in the sea.
This hotel is an important project.
This hotel is the first
of seven hotels...
...foreseen for this region.
In addition to this,
we want to build a golf-course...
...and a limited number of flats.
In the first phase,
we will construct 500 flats.
Later there will be 1500 flats
and houses.
My name is Miguel Angel Torres.
I am a public servant
and cartographer.
For 18 years
I have been observing...
...the construction of buildings...
...on the "Costa del Sol".
This is the "Parque Victoria".
They are constructing 4000 flats.
Mostly, they are built
as capital investments.
That way the real estate societies...
...enterprises and European banks...
...can reckon with an annual profit...
...of about 20%.
A traditional investment in a bank
or at the stock exchange...
...brings a profit of only 5-6%.
Therefore the buildings here
and on the Spanish coast...
...are not built for living in...
...not even during the holidays.
They are just built in order
to launch an investment chain.
After the whole process...
...we will have thousands...
...of empty flats...
...which profited people
we don't know...
...and who don't even live here.
If you have a pension fund
at a European bank...
...it is likely that
the money is invested...
...in one of these housing estates
in Spain.
These flats,
which are already sold...
...are empty the whole year long.
Young Spanish people
can't buy these flats.
The cost of these apartments
are much higher...
...than anything they can afford.
The upkeep of these buildings...
...which are of very poor quality...
...the water and the utilities...
...are paid by the Spanish state.
We have no advantage whatsoever...
...from the 800000 flats
built every year in Spain.
Spain is one of the countries
in the world...
...where the bubble
in the real estate market...
...became most apparent
over the past five years.
A real storm of urbanization...
...a "cement-tsunami" is ruining
the Spanish coasts and islands.
Here we can see one
of the housing estates...
...all of them are connected
to golf courses.
There are hundreds
of such estates in Spain...
...a country where...
...only very few people
play golf, a tiny minority.
How is this possible?
This is due to the big
foreign investments...
...in products of this type.
The value of these real estate
buildings is higher...
...if they are located
beside a golf course.
This is absolutely artificial.
We are creating a green space...
...in the midst of the desert.
To do so,
we need a huge quantity of water.
A golf course of this type...
...consumes the same quantity
of water...
...as a town of 20000 inhabitants.
7 of the 11 most important
construction companies...
...in the world are Spanish.
Some of them are linked
to big soccer clubs.
The biggest Spanish
construction company ACS
...is directed by the former president
of Real Madrid.
The extent of construction
has reached its limits.
Of the first kilometer
of the whole Spanish coastline...
80% is covered with buildings.
They are beginning to occupy
the last natural spaces.
At the moment...
...the construction works
are temporarily halted...
...because our activities
have been reported...
...to the authorities
by an ecological group...
...claiming that we don't have...
...the necessary permits.
I hope and I wish that the judge...
...after having confirmed the legality
of the construction...
...will soon allow us
to finish building this hotel...
...for which we already have...
...reservations from all over Europe.
The building sector
recruits its workers...
...mainly among immigrants.
The people coming from
Africa or South America...
...work for the lowest wages.
This way, the people
in the construction sector...
...spend their black money...
...on paying
their construction workers.
Why doesn't anybody do something...
...about this abortive development
of the financial system?
This question is difficult to answer...
...since many are suffering from it...
...including the national economy,
because there is the risk...
...of a new global economic crisis.
Despite of all this,
nothing is happening.
Even now, one year
after the financial crisis...
...there aren't any new regulations.
That way, these financial excesses
are permitted.
On the contrary,
they allocated public money...
...from the bank of issue to the system...
...so that the system won't collapse.
That means they use
ordinary people's money...
...to cover the bets.
In order to provide a basis
for the gamblers...
...who bleed the system...
...so that their institutes
don't go bankrupt.
It seems that time after time...
...catastrophes overtake humanity.
After each catastrophe...
...the rules are newly defined...
...in order to avoid such catastrophes.
After the world economic crisis...
...completely new rules for banks
were introduced.
The whole banking system
was highly regulated...
...to avoid something like
the world economic crisis.
Over the past years, a new
attitude has become established...
...purporting that we don't need
to regulate anything...
...because that the market
regulates everything.
So the public control authorities
have tolerated...
...that for the financial system
regulations no longer exist.
Everything has been
completely liberalized.
The sort of financial industry
we have today...
...is completely senseless
and directed against people.
It's the media...
...that choose today's leaders.
They give thumbs up or down.
So people are eager
to please the media...
...they try to be in the limelight.
They are elected less and less...
...due to serious political concepts.
This capacity to please the media...
...has become a crucial criterion
for a political leader...
...although it is the exact opposite
of the qualities...
...you need to be
a good political leader.
So we have
more and more dummies...
...who take crucial political decisions...
...and who very quickly
become compliant puppets...
...of developments determined
by other people.
Our opinion
in Switzerland...
...is that it is
of the utmost importance...
...to protect a person's privacy.
This protection is part
of a liberal economy.
This protection
may only be suspended...
...in the case
of major legal infractions.
Tax avoidance is considered
an infraction...
...but not serious enough...
...to suspend privacy.
Neither that of our own citizens,
nor that of foreign citizens.
Switzerland would never
exclusively protect...
...its own citizens
from tax authorities...
...but on the slightest suspicion...
...of tax evasion...
...or tax avoidance...
...suspend foreign citizens' privacy.
The Universal Declaration
of Human Rights stipulates...
"All human beings are born free
and equal in dignity and rights. "
If we want to stick to
this humanitarian principle...
...the distribution of wealth
has to be different.
Distribution should be in favour
of our whole society...
...and not in favour
of a few individuals.
Only then can you preserve
the humanitarian principle.
If we do not change the system...
...there will be
new selection mechanisms:
...selection mechanisms
between states...
...between races...
...between religions...
...between people entitled
to use resources...
...and those not entitled...
...between valuable people
and those who are not valuable.
In this case, the monetary value
of a human being will prevail...
...and a new barbarian era will begin.
This is ineluctable.
In the end...
...the average citizen will pay for it.
The so-called " little man".
Or the "little women" - People...
...who have no influence whatsoever
on the process...
...unless they get organized...
...unless they find someone
to represent their interests...
...strong enough to stop this process.
We are now at the Reichstag...
...the seat of the German Parliament.
Here we see traces of World War I...
...which ended
with the capture of the Reichstag...
...by Russian soldiers...
...who wrote their greetings
to their homeland.
This should remind us of the fact...
...that without a new form
of distribution of wealth...
...without a solution for the question
of the environment...
...by using renewable instead
of non-renewable resources...
...which will not be sufficient
for all of us...
...all things that ended here
with World War II
...will repeat themselves
in a different form.
DVD Subtitling: CNST, Montreal...