2
00:02:48,085 --> 00:02:49,544
Zeus.

3
00:02:54,591 --> 00:02:56,259
Poseidon.

4
00:02:56,760 --> 00:02:58,427
It's been many years.

5
00:03:02,391 --> 00:03:04,267
What do you see?

6
00:03:08,397 --> 00:03:09,939
Thunderclouds.

7
00:03:12,234 --> 00:03:14,068
But no lightning.

8
00:03:16,947 --> 00:03:18,573
Stolen.

9
00:03:21,618 --> 00:03:24,412
What?
You think I took it?

10
00:03:25,289 --> 00:03:28,374
Omnipotence has
blinded you, brother.

11
00:03:28,458 --> 00:03:31,127
We are forbidden
from stealing
each other's powers.

12
00:03:32,880 --> 00:03:35,131
But our children aren't.

13
00:03:35,757 --> 00:03:37,967
You're accusing my son?

14
00:03:39,136 --> 00:03:41,888
I haven't seen him
since he was a baby.
He doesn't know me

15
00:03:41,972 --> 00:03:43,931
or even know who he is
because of you.

16
00:03:44,308 --> 00:03:46,225
If your son
is the thief,

17
00:03:47,144 --> 00:03:49,478
I will send him
to the depths
of Tartarus.

18
00:03:50,480 --> 00:03:54,817
If you touch him,
you will have
the fight of your life.

19
00:03:58,989 --> 00:04:03,576
He must return
the bolt to me
in 14 days,

20
00:04:03,660 --> 00:04:06,078
by midnight
on the summer
solstice,

21
00:04:13,253 --> 00:04:15,087
or there will be war.

22
00:05:54,980 --> 00:05:57,064
- And he's alive!

23
00:05:59,818 --> 00:06:04,447
Percy Jackson is a beast!
You're a beast, man!
Give me some.

24
00:06:05,949 --> 00:06:06,991
How long was that?

25
00:06:07,075 --> 00:06:08,034
Seven minutes.

26
00:06:08,118 --> 00:06:09,368
Seven minutes?
Mmm-hmm.

27
00:06:09,453 --> 00:06:10,536
Oh.

28
00:06:10,620 --> 00:06:13,539
That's crazy, man.
That's ridiculous.
How do you do it?

29
00:06:13,623 --> 00:06:15,458
I just like
being in water.

30
00:06:16,626 --> 00:06:18,669
It's the one place
I can think.

31
00:06:18,795 --> 00:06:20,129
Mmm-hmm.

32
00:06:32,267 --> 00:06:34,685
I wish I could spend
all day underwater
instead of this place.

33
00:06:34,811 --> 00:06:38,105
Right.
It's like high school
without the musical.

34
00:06:38,774 --> 00:06:41,650
Every day
it's the same thing.
Look at this.

35
00:06:49,826 --> 00:06:51,118
Good morning.

36
00:06:51,203 --> 00:06:54,371
I'm Mrs. Dodds,
your substitute
English teacher.

37
00:06:55,165 --> 00:06:56,415
Would someone
please explain

38
00:06:56,500 --> 00:07:00,669
what Shakespeare
was trying to convey
in this line from Othello?

39
00:07:03,673 --> 00:07:05,174
Percy Jackson?

40
00:07:10,013 --> 00:07:11,180
Well?

41
00:07:19,815 --> 00:07:21,857
I'm sorry, I don't know.

42
00:07:23,401 --> 00:07:24,902
Anybody else?

43
00:07:45,215 --> 00:07:46,882
Hey, Mom,
I'm home!

44
00:07:47,008 --> 00:07:48,717
I'm up here, honey!

45
00:07:50,679 --> 00:07:52,012
Hi.
Hey, Mom.

46
00:07:52,097 --> 00:07:53,347
How was school today?

47
00:07:53,515 --> 00:07:54,765
The usual.

48
00:07:55,767 --> 00:08:00,062
I think this
dyslexia thing
is getting worse.

49
00:08:00,188 --> 00:08:02,273
Oh! Why do you
think that?

50
00:08:03,608 --> 00:08:06,777
- I don't know.
- Maybe it's the ADHD.

51
00:08:08,446 --> 00:08:09,488
You know,
I thought this school

52
00:08:09,573 --> 00:08:11,657
was supposed to
make things better.

53
00:08:11,741 --> 00:08:14,535
Percy,
I know how hard
this is for you.

54
00:08:15,036 --> 00:08:16,412
But someday
it'll all make sense.

55
00:08:17,205 --> 00:08:18,581
Really?

56
00:08:19,207 --> 00:08:20,791
When? Hmm?

57
00:08:21,751 --> 00:08:23,794
Tonight? Tomorrow? When?

58
00:08:25,463 --> 00:08:26,714
Woman!

59
00:08:27,966 --> 00:08:29,383
Hi, Gabe.

60
00:08:30,093 --> 00:08:31,927
Where's my beer?

61
00:08:32,053 --> 00:08:33,971
It's in the fridge.
So, what,

62
00:08:34,055 --> 00:08:35,681
it's supposed to
magically float

63
00:08:35,765 --> 00:08:37,808
from the icebox
and into my hand?

64
00:08:39,436 --> 00:08:40,728
Hustle.

65
00:08:41,605 --> 00:08:43,939
Come on, man.
You have to do
that right here?

66
00:08:44,065 --> 00:08:46,650
It's disgusting.
We're in a kitchen.

67
00:08:48,945 --> 00:08:51,739
Yeah, real charmer
you got there. Really.

68
00:08:51,823 --> 00:08:53,532
Show some respect,
all right?

69
00:08:53,617 --> 00:08:55,451
That's my mom
right there.

70
00:09:04,169 --> 00:09:05,669
This is my house.

71
00:09:07,797 --> 00:09:09,673
You show some respect.

72
00:09:10,175 --> 00:09:11,634
Oh, come on.

73
00:09:13,803 --> 00:09:17,306
Why do you stay
with that pig?
He smells like a sewer.

74
00:09:17,432 --> 00:09:20,309
He sleeps till noon every day
and he can't even hold a job.

75
00:09:20,435 --> 00:09:22,478
Why do you
stay with him?

76
00:09:25,106 --> 00:09:28,859
He's been good to us, Percy,
in ways you don't understand.

77
00:09:30,195 --> 00:09:33,489
You're right.
I don't understand.
I don't get it.

78
00:10:01,184 --> 00:10:06,021
Be prepared.
Everything is about
to change, Percy.

79
00:10:06,481 --> 00:10:09,316
Everything is
about to change.

80
00:10:18,493 --> 00:10:20,661
There are 12
Olympian gods.

81
00:10:21,830 --> 00:10:26,542
The big three
are the brothers
Zeus, Poseidon and Hades.

82
00:10:27,210 --> 00:10:32,006
They attained power
by overthrowing
their father, Kronos,

83
00:10:32,882 --> 00:10:35,342
chopping him
into little pieces.

84
00:10:36,678 --> 00:10:39,596
The three gods
have been rivals
ever since,

85
00:10:40,223 --> 00:10:44,059
always arguing,
always threatening war.

86
00:10:45,270 --> 00:10:49,273
On several occasions,
they would come down
to Earth and, um...

87
00:10:50,775 --> 00:10:52,318
How shall I put this?

88
00:10:52,402 --> 00:10:53,444
Hook up?

89
00:10:55,405 --> 00:10:57,948
They would hook up
with mortals.

90
00:10:58,074 --> 00:11:02,453
The children
of these unions were
half god, half human.

91
00:11:03,580 --> 00:11:06,540
Can anyone tell me
what they were called?

92
00:11:06,624 --> 00:11:09,710
Percy.

93
00:11:11,046 --> 00:11:13,756
Oh, I'm sorry. What?
What, Mr. Brunner?

94
00:11:15,091 --> 00:11:19,720
What is the proper name
of the offspring of
a human and a god?

95
00:11:22,307 --> 00:11:23,349
Demigod.

96
00:11:23,433 --> 00:11:24,433
Exactly.

97
00:11:25,143 --> 00:11:27,436
And many became
great heroes,

98
00:11:28,271 --> 00:11:30,773
like Hercules
and Achilles.

99
00:11:31,441 --> 00:11:34,943
Can you name another?

100
00:11:37,906 --> 00:11:40,074
I'll give you a hint.

101
00:11:40,158 --> 00:11:42,451
You have something
in common.

102
00:11:52,629 --> 00:11:53,962
Percy...

103
00:11:56,299 --> 00:11:57,591
Perseus?

104
00:12:00,512 --> 00:12:01,804
Correct.

105
00:12:03,973 --> 00:12:05,933
Now, over here,
we have a depiction

106
00:12:06,017 --> 00:12:08,602
of Hercules defeating
the Nemean lion.

107
00:12:10,146 --> 00:12:13,524
Hercules killed the beast
with his bare hands

108
00:12:13,650 --> 00:12:15,818
and took the skin
as a trophy.

109
00:12:16,611 --> 00:12:17,653
Percy?

110
00:12:18,655 --> 00:12:19,988
Yes, Mrs. Dodds?

111
00:12:20,532 --> 00:12:21,824
We need to talk.

112
00:12:23,701 --> 00:12:24,868
Okay.

113
00:12:25,370 --> 00:12:26,662
The next 11 labors

114
00:12:26,746 --> 00:12:29,123
would become
increasingly difficult.

115
00:12:29,207 --> 00:12:32,000
It would take Hercules
three months...

116
00:12:39,968 --> 00:12:42,219
So, did I do
something wrong?

117
00:12:44,347 --> 00:12:45,722
Mrs. Dodds?

118
00:12:46,641 --> 00:12:47,850
Hello?

119
00:12:48,852 --> 00:12:50,185
Where is it?

120
00:12:50,687 --> 00:12:55,315
Oh, whoa! Hey! Hey.
How did you get up there?

121
00:12:59,487 --> 00:13:00,863
Whoa, whoa, whoa!

122
00:13:04,701 --> 00:13:06,368
You stole
the lightning bolt!

123
00:13:06,536 --> 00:13:08,203
I don't know what
you're talking about!

124
00:13:08,329 --> 00:13:10,080
Give it to me!

125
00:13:11,374 --> 00:13:14,501
Give it to me! Now!

126
00:13:14,586 --> 00:13:17,212
Or I will bite
your heart out!

127
00:13:17,338 --> 00:13:18,714
Percy!

128
00:13:19,883 --> 00:13:21,091
Release him!

129
00:13:21,384 --> 00:13:22,468
You!

130
00:13:22,552 --> 00:13:26,680
Release him or I swear
I'll tear you to pieces!

131
00:13:39,068 --> 00:13:42,154
I'm going crazy!
Oh! I should be
on medication.

132
00:13:42,238 --> 00:13:44,114
Percy, calm down, okay?
Everything's gonna be okay!

133
00:13:44,240 --> 00:13:49,286
Oh, God, wait!
Did that really
just happen?

134
00:13:49,412 --> 00:13:50,704
She just turned
into that thing?

135
00:13:50,788 --> 00:13:55,167
A Fury
concealed in our school.
I should have known.

136
00:13:55,251 --> 00:13:57,920
Wait, a Fury?
What's a Fury?

137
00:13:58,046 --> 00:14:00,422
And why did you say
you could tear her
to pieces?

138
00:14:00,548 --> 00:14:02,341
What did she
want from you?

139
00:14:02,425 --> 00:14:04,885
She said something

140
00:14:05,970 --> 00:14:09,139
about me stealing
a lightning bolt.

141
00:14:10,642 --> 00:14:12,267
They found him.

142
00:14:15,313 --> 00:14:16,813
He's in danger.
Who found me?

143
00:14:18,107 --> 00:14:19,942
He's no longer
secure here.
Where should we move him?

144
00:14:20,068 --> 00:14:21,443
We have no choice.
The Camp.

145
00:14:21,569 --> 00:14:24,196
Huh? What camp?
Look, I'm standing
right here.

146
00:14:24,280 --> 00:14:26,031
If they think
he's the thief,

147
00:14:26,115 --> 00:14:28,283
there's nowhere safe
on heaven and Earth
for him now.

148
00:14:28,409 --> 00:14:31,995
Percy, take this
to defend yourself.

149
00:14:32,121 --> 00:14:35,832
It's a powerful weapon.
Guard it well.

150
00:14:35,959 --> 00:14:39,461
Only use it in times
of severe distress.

151
00:14:41,297 --> 00:14:44,258
This is a pen.
This is a pen!

152
00:14:44,342 --> 00:14:47,386
Take him to his mother,
and don't let him
out of your sight.

153
00:14:47,470 --> 00:14:50,556
Okay. Percy, come on.
Come on, man. Come on!

154
00:14:50,640 --> 00:14:51,807
Are you guys crazy?
Let's go!

155
00:14:51,933 --> 00:14:53,433
This is a pen, man.

156
00:14:53,518 --> 00:14:54,518
What do you want me
to do with this?

157
00:14:54,602 --> 00:14:55,686
Come on!

158
00:14:56,271 --> 00:14:57,521
Look, man,
what's going on?

159
00:14:57,605 --> 00:14:58,772
Look,

160
00:14:58,856 --> 00:15:02,317
don't trust anyone, okay?
Don't look at anybody,
just keep walking!

161
00:15:02,402 --> 00:15:04,861
Why did Mr. Brunner
ask you to watch me?

162
00:15:04,988 --> 00:15:06,613
Because I'm
your protector.
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on.

163
00:15:06,698 --> 00:15:09,116
My protector?
Are you kidding?

164
00:15:09,200 --> 00:15:10,450
What,
you think because
I'm like this,

165
00:15:10,535 --> 00:15:12,119
I'm not capable of
keeping you safe?

166
00:15:12,203 --> 00:15:15,289
Maybe you're not seeing
what I'm seeing.
You have crutches!

167
00:15:15,373 --> 00:15:17,374
Look, I would give
my life to secure
your well-being.

168
00:15:17,500 --> 00:15:19,418
What are you
talking about?
What's going on?

169
00:15:19,502 --> 00:15:22,588
We got to
warn your mom.
Come on, Perce.

170
00:15:22,672 --> 00:15:24,006
Come on!

171
00:15:25,258 --> 00:15:27,050
Sally! More beer!

172
00:15:27,135 --> 00:15:28,343
Mom!

173
00:15:28,511 --> 00:15:31,388
Hey, Mom. Mom! Mom!
Look, we gotta talk, okay?

174
00:15:31,514 --> 00:15:32,931
Hey!

175
00:15:33,016 --> 00:15:35,309
Can't you see
she's servicing me
and my friends?

176
00:15:35,393 --> 00:15:37,603
Hey. Hey!
Don't talk about
my mom like that,

177
00:15:37,687 --> 00:15:39,104
you bald-headed freak.

178
00:15:39,188 --> 00:15:40,814
No, Gabe! Gabe!

179
00:15:40,898 --> 00:15:42,357
Calm down!

180
00:15:45,361 --> 00:15:46,653
Whoa!

181
00:15:46,738 --> 00:15:47,863
Hey, nice one.

182
00:15:47,947 --> 00:15:49,990
Like I said,
I'm your protector.

183
00:15:50,867 --> 00:15:52,034
Yeah.

184
00:15:52,702 --> 00:15:56,121
Sally,
Percy has to leave now.
Like, right now.

185
00:15:56,539 --> 00:15:57,706
Okay.

186
00:16:03,296 --> 00:16:07,299
Look, what is happening?
Okay, I swear,
I didn't steal anything!

187
00:16:07,383 --> 00:16:10,052
Honey, I believe you.
I believe you.

188
00:16:11,220 --> 00:16:13,055
Where are you taking me?
What is this camp?

189
00:16:13,139 --> 00:16:15,932
It's a camp for really
special people,

190
00:16:16,059 --> 00:16:17,809
like you.
"Special people"?

191
00:16:17,894 --> 00:16:20,187
What, am I crazy
or something?

192
00:16:20,271 --> 00:16:22,439
No, honey, no.

193
00:16:23,232 --> 00:16:25,317
Percy, this is
about your father.

194
00:16:29,947 --> 00:16:31,031
I was just
out of school

195
00:16:31,115 --> 00:16:32,324
and working at
the Jersey shore

196
00:16:32,408 --> 00:16:34,117
when we first met.

197
00:16:36,496 --> 00:16:38,997
Your father was unlike
any guy I'd ever seen.

198
00:16:39,082 --> 00:16:41,166
He was just dazzling.

199
00:16:41,250 --> 00:16:43,669
Mmm. They're always dazzling.

200
00:16:43,753 --> 00:16:46,088
We were really
in love, Percy.

201
00:16:47,256 --> 00:16:50,801
And then you came along,
and then it was just perfect.

202
00:16:51,260 --> 00:16:53,095
But he had to leave.

203
00:16:54,138 --> 00:16:56,181
So he did abandon us.

204
00:16:56,766 --> 00:16:59,851
No, honey,
he was forced to.
He loved you.

205
00:17:00,853 --> 00:17:05,107
Leaving you,
it was probably the most
difficult thing he ever did.

206
00:17:15,827 --> 00:17:17,786
Why did he have to go?

207
00:17:18,871 --> 00:17:19,871
Because he's...

208
00:17:19,956 --> 00:17:21,039
Sally, watch out!

209
00:17:21,708 --> 00:17:23,709
- Whoa!
- Mom! Go straight!

210
00:17:31,467 --> 00:17:32,467
Percy?

211
00:17:32,552 --> 00:17:33,552
Mom, you all right?

212
00:17:33,636 --> 00:17:34,720
Yeah, yeah.

213
00:17:34,846 --> 00:17:35,971
Grover, you all right?

214
00:17:37,974 --> 00:17:40,392
Is it me or is it
raining cows?

215
00:17:44,814 --> 00:17:46,398
What is that?

216
00:17:46,482 --> 00:17:49,943
- Get out!
- Come on! Come on!

217
00:17:50,027 --> 00:17:52,320
Why are you
taking your pants off?
What are you doing?

218
00:17:52,405 --> 00:17:53,405
My job!

219
00:17:53,489 --> 00:17:54,489
Whoa! Whoa!

220
00:17:54,574 --> 00:17:55,824
You're half donkey?

221
00:17:55,908 --> 00:17:57,242
I'm half goat.

222
00:18:02,874 --> 00:18:04,499
Go, Grover!

223
00:18:04,584 --> 00:18:06,376
Guys, watch out,
there's glass!

224
00:18:07,420 --> 00:18:10,213
Come on, get out of the car!
That thing's getting closer!

225
00:18:10,339 --> 00:18:11,548
You don't even
need these.

226
00:18:11,632 --> 00:18:13,300
Look, man,
those are just
for show.

227
00:18:13,384 --> 00:18:15,093
Follow me!
Whoa!

228
00:18:19,348 --> 00:18:25,645
This way, guys! This way!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, run! Run!

229
00:18:39,952 --> 00:18:41,620
Come on! Come on!

230
00:18:46,209 --> 00:18:47,793
We're here!

231
00:18:58,763 --> 00:19:00,388
Mom! What are you doing?

232
00:19:00,473 --> 00:19:01,640
This is as far
as I can go.

233
00:19:01,724 --> 00:19:05,060
Come on!
I can't go through!
I'm not like you!

234
00:19:05,144 --> 00:19:06,770
Look, I'm not leaving
without you.

235
00:19:06,854 --> 00:19:08,647
You have to!

236
00:19:08,731 --> 00:19:10,023
You're meant to!

237
00:19:17,156 --> 00:19:18,990
Put my mother down!

238
00:19:19,075 --> 00:19:21,868
Percy, go!
You're safe
inside the gate!

239
00:19:21,953 --> 00:19:23,787
What can I do?
Listen, use the pen!

240
00:19:23,913 --> 00:19:26,122
What?
Use Brunner's pen
and click it!

241
00:19:27,583 --> 00:19:28,792
Whoa!

242
00:19:50,022 --> 00:19:51,690
Perce, are you okay?

243
00:20:03,369 --> 00:20:05,287
Percy,
behind you!

244
00:20:19,552 --> 00:20:20,552
Perce, you okay?

245
00:20:20,636 --> 00:20:21,720
I'm not feeling...

246
00:20:21,804 --> 00:20:23,054
Percy!

247
00:20:49,832 --> 00:20:52,500
Perce,
I'm sure glad
you're alive.

248
00:20:56,339 --> 00:20:57,672
Ow!

249
00:21:05,932 --> 00:21:07,933
Where am I?
What is this place?

250
00:21:08,517 --> 00:21:09,809
The infirmary.

251
00:21:09,894 --> 00:21:11,561
You've been unconscious
for three days.

252
00:21:11,729 --> 00:21:13,438
Three days?

253
00:21:14,273 --> 00:21:17,859
So, Perce,
what do you remember?

254
00:21:19,528 --> 00:21:22,489
Some crazy dream.
I don't know.

255
00:21:22,615 --> 00:21:25,575
There was a monster.
My mom was there.

256
00:21:25,701 --> 00:21:29,704
You were there, too,
but you were some
weird hybrid man-goat

257
00:21:29,789 --> 00:21:30,956
thing! Whoa!

258
00:21:34,126 --> 00:21:37,212
Yeah. The politically
correct term is Satyr.

259
00:21:38,297 --> 00:21:39,381
No.

260
00:21:40,216 --> 00:21:43,051
No, no, no, no!

261
00:21:43,719 --> 00:21:46,888
All of it was real?
My mom's gone?

262
00:21:48,891 --> 00:21:51,810
I'm sorry, Percy.
I try, man, I really do.

263
00:21:53,771 --> 00:21:57,315
But, frankly,
I'm just a junior protector.
I don't have my horns yet.

264
00:21:58,609 --> 00:22:01,736
It was my fault.
It was my job
to protect you.

265
00:22:02,738 --> 00:22:04,155
Both of you.

266
00:22:14,583 --> 00:22:17,919
So this is
Camp Half Blood.

267
00:22:18,421 --> 00:22:19,671
"Half" meaning what?

268
00:22:19,755 --> 00:22:21,256
I think you know.

269
00:22:21,340 --> 00:22:23,174
"Half" meaning
"half mortal,
half god."

270
00:22:23,259 --> 00:22:26,636
Fire!
Whoa! Guys!
Watch the arrows!

271
00:22:26,762 --> 00:22:29,889
Newcomer! Hello! Gosh!

272
00:22:29,974 --> 00:22:31,850
Look, man,
remember all the myths

273
00:22:31,934 --> 00:22:34,019
about Greek gods
and goddesses?

274
00:22:34,103 --> 00:22:38,106
Well, they're not myths.
Look, remember
what Mr. Brunner said?

275
00:22:38,190 --> 00:22:39,357
Sometimes they
come down to Earth

276
00:22:39,442 --> 00:22:41,026
and they fall in love
with mortals?

277
00:22:41,110 --> 00:22:43,153
And then
they have kids?

278
00:22:43,946 --> 00:22:44,904
No way.

279
00:22:44,989 --> 00:22:46,031
Yes way.

280
00:22:46,782 --> 00:22:51,202
Yep, you're a demigod!
Two points for Percy Jackson!

281
00:22:52,788 --> 00:22:54,289
Look, don't worry.
But you're not alone.

282
00:22:54,457 --> 00:22:55,957
There's hundreds
in the world.

283
00:22:56,042 --> 00:22:57,584
Some lead normal lives,

284
00:22:57,668 --> 00:23:00,587
and some,
I'm not allowed to divulge
their names, are very famous.

285
00:23:00,671 --> 00:23:03,131
I'm talking about, like,
White House famous.

286
00:23:04,133 --> 00:23:05,592
See, man,
this place right here,

287
00:23:05,676 --> 00:23:07,886
this is the place
where you'll learn to
harness your powers.

288
00:23:07,970 --> 00:23:11,806
You'll train to
become leaders,
warriors and heroes.

289
00:23:11,891 --> 00:23:15,268
I think you have
the wrong guy, all right?
I'm not a hero.

290
00:23:15,352 --> 00:23:18,438
I'm a loser.
I have dyslexia,
ADHD.

291
00:23:18,522 --> 00:23:20,690
And those are
your greatest gifts.

292
00:23:21,317 --> 00:23:23,943
When you try to read,
the words float
off the page, right?

293
00:23:24,028 --> 00:23:25,361
That's because your
brain is hardwired

294
00:23:25,446 --> 00:23:27,405
for Ancient Greek,
not English.

295
00:23:27,490 --> 00:23:30,200
Like at the museum,
I could read.

296
00:23:30,326 --> 00:23:32,535
Yeah. And your ADHD?

297
00:23:34,580 --> 00:23:38,208
You're impulsive, Percy.
You can't be still!

298
00:23:38,334 --> 00:23:40,877
Those are your natural
battle reflexes, man.

299
00:23:41,003 --> 00:23:43,338
They kept you alive
in your fight.

300
00:23:43,422 --> 00:23:46,841
Look, no pitiful loser
can defeat a Minotaur.

301
00:23:48,010 --> 00:23:49,886
Your blood is special.

302
00:23:50,346 --> 00:23:51,930
It's the blood of a god.

303
00:23:53,057 --> 00:23:55,391
This is a lot to process.

304
00:23:55,518 --> 00:23:57,685
Yeah, a lot. A lot.

305
00:24:01,732 --> 00:24:04,859
This is where
you'll do most of
your battle training.

306
00:24:19,208 --> 00:24:20,625
What's her name?

307
00:24:22,753 --> 00:24:24,546
She will squash you
like a bug.

308
00:24:24,672 --> 00:24:26,422
Her name.

309
00:24:26,549 --> 00:24:29,968
Annabeth.
Daughter of Athena,
the goddess of wisdom.

310
00:24:35,141 --> 00:24:37,142
Hey, no staring.
Keep it moving.

311
00:24:37,226 --> 00:24:38,268
Keep it moving.
Come on.

312
00:24:38,352 --> 00:24:39,394
Uh-huh.

313
00:24:42,356 --> 00:24:45,400
There's someone
I want you to see.
Check this out.

314
00:24:54,160 --> 00:24:56,161
Oh, wow!

315
00:24:59,582 --> 00:25:01,374
What are those things?

316
00:25:01,458 --> 00:25:02,876
They're Centaurs.

317
00:25:04,962 --> 00:25:07,255
Wait a minute.
ls that Mr. Brunner?

318
00:25:07,506 --> 00:25:09,174
Come on.

319
00:25:10,342 --> 00:25:13,386
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.

320
00:25:15,890 --> 00:25:17,724
Mr. Brunner?

321
00:25:17,808 --> 00:25:21,060
In my world,
I'm known as Chiron.

322
00:25:22,271 --> 00:25:23,605
Are you recovered?

323
00:25:23,689 --> 00:25:25,106
Am I recovered?

324
00:25:25,191 --> 00:25:28,902
You, you're not in
a wheelchair. You have...

325
00:25:29,987 --> 00:25:31,863
A real horse's ass.

326
00:25:32,573 --> 00:25:34,365
I apologize for
hiding my true form,

327
00:25:34,450 --> 00:25:38,411
but I needed to
keep an eye on you.
I hope you'll forgive me.

328
00:25:39,079 --> 00:25:40,246
Come.

329
00:25:54,094 --> 00:25:55,553
Hey, Grover!

330
00:25:57,306 --> 00:26:00,558
Ooh. The daughters
of Aphrodite.

331
00:26:00,643 --> 00:26:03,561
Okay. All right, guys.
You guys got a lot
of catching up to do.

332
00:26:03,646 --> 00:26:06,522
Their mother is
the goddess of love,
so you know where that leads.

333
00:26:06,607 --> 00:26:09,150
Hey, baby! Whoo!

334
00:26:09,235 --> 00:26:10,485
Satyrs.

335
00:26:13,489 --> 00:26:14,989
What is this place?

336
00:26:16,116 --> 00:26:17,784
Welcome home.

337
00:26:17,868 --> 00:26:20,662
Your father
built this for you.

338
00:26:23,666 --> 00:26:24,999
Wow.

339
00:26:32,883 --> 00:26:34,968
This whole place
is mine?

340
00:26:50,401 --> 00:26:52,527
This thing's got
some weight to it.

341
00:26:58,909 --> 00:27:01,119
My father is Poseidon!

342
00:27:01,203 --> 00:27:02,870
God of the seas.

343
00:27:03,497 --> 00:27:05,748
Why didn't anybody
tell me?

344
00:27:05,833 --> 00:27:08,001
It was for
your own safety.

345
00:27:09,378 --> 00:27:11,629
It's exceedingly rare
for a child to be born

346
00:27:11,714 --> 00:27:13,840
to one of
the big three.

347
00:27:16,218 --> 00:27:18,094
You're very powerful.

348
00:27:18,679 --> 00:27:20,221
A threat.

349
00:27:20,306 --> 00:27:22,682
A threat?
Who am I threatening?

350
00:27:24,184 --> 00:27:28,354
Poseidon's brothers,
Zeus and Hades.

351
00:27:30,691 --> 00:27:33,568
That's why your mother
married your stepfather.

352
00:27:33,652 --> 00:27:37,030
His pungent odor
masked the smell
of your blood

353
00:27:38,032 --> 00:27:43,995
and hid you from anything
or anyone the gods
would send to kill you.

354
00:27:45,789 --> 00:27:48,416
My mother put up
with that creep
to protect me?

355
00:27:48,500 --> 00:27:50,001
Mmm-hmm.

356
00:27:53,255 --> 00:27:54,964
I wish I'd known.

357
00:27:55,758 --> 00:27:58,092
She sacrificed
so much for me.

358
00:28:02,097 --> 00:28:03,681
Now she's gone.

359
00:28:11,398 --> 00:28:12,815
Why am I even here?

360
00:28:12,900 --> 00:28:15,485
You're here because
you're in jeopardy.

361
00:28:15,569 --> 00:28:18,196
Everyone thinks you're
the lightning thief.

362
00:28:18,280 --> 00:28:20,323
Look, I didn't steal it.

363
00:28:24,745 --> 00:28:28,206
Zeus' bolt is the most
powerful weapon ever created.

364
00:28:29,416 --> 00:28:32,335
And if it's not returned
by the summer solstice,
in 10 days,

365
00:28:32,419 --> 00:28:33,419
there will be a war.

366
00:28:33,504 --> 00:28:35,671
This is your problem,
all right? Not mine.

367
00:28:35,756 --> 00:28:37,548
This is about
your world, not mine.

368
00:28:37,633 --> 00:28:39,592
This is about
all worlds!

369
00:28:41,303 --> 00:28:43,262
Olympians would be forced
to choose sides.

370
00:28:43,347 --> 00:28:45,139
Earth would become
a battleground.

371
00:28:45,224 --> 00:28:48,476
Mountains erupted,
earthquakes,
raging fires!

372
00:28:49,353 --> 00:28:51,729
The end of life
as you know it.

373
00:28:57,653 --> 00:28:59,278
What can we do?

374
00:28:59,363 --> 00:29:01,406
I want to take you
to Olympus,

375
00:29:01,490 --> 00:29:03,449
convince Zeus of
your innocence.

376
00:29:04,243 --> 00:29:06,828
Someone's using you
to start a war.

377
00:29:08,872 --> 00:29:10,748
What are we doing here?
Let's go now.

378
00:29:10,833 --> 00:29:14,335
Your boldness is commendable,
but outside those gates

379
00:29:15,337 --> 00:29:17,964
you would be in danger
at all times.

380
00:29:18,674 --> 00:29:22,009
The Fury and the Minotaur
were only the beginning.

381
00:29:22,511 --> 00:29:26,139
First, we must train.

382
00:29:31,353 --> 00:29:34,355
This is always
a fun game to watch.

383
00:29:35,023 --> 00:29:38,151
Ow! God, how do you guys
wear this stuff?
It weighs more than me.

384
00:29:38,235 --> 00:29:40,528
Look, trust me.
Wear it or you'll
get killed.

385
00:29:40,612 --> 00:29:42,488
Wait. What?
What? Wait...

386
00:29:42,573 --> 00:29:46,701
Heroes! Warriors!

387
00:29:46,785 --> 00:29:48,077
Fall in!

388
00:29:53,959 --> 00:29:56,043
Hustle, hustle!

389
00:29:56,128 --> 00:29:59,255
Dylan, Paris,
stop lollygagging!

390
00:30:00,966 --> 00:30:03,801
Percy. Step forward.

391
00:30:07,890 --> 00:30:11,684
This is Percy Jackson!

392
00:30:13,187 --> 00:30:15,521
And he's going
to need a team.

393
00:30:16,064 --> 00:30:17,648
We'll take him.

394
00:30:21,653 --> 00:30:24,989
I'm Luke.
Son of Hermes
and camp leader.

395
00:30:25,574 --> 00:30:27,742
Not necessarily
in that order.

396
00:30:27,826 --> 00:30:29,660
Where's your helmet?

397
00:30:29,870 --> 00:30:31,662
No one gave me one.

398
00:30:33,499 --> 00:30:37,543
Chiron, you still
got your wheelchair?
Kid's gonna need it.

399
00:30:37,628 --> 00:30:39,462
You're a goner, man.

400
00:30:40,464 --> 00:30:43,925
I'm messing with you.
Smile a little bit.
It's good for you, kid.

401
00:30:44,009 --> 00:30:47,178
Anybody got
an extra helmet?
Please pass it up.

402
00:30:51,266 --> 00:30:52,642
Try it on.

403
00:30:53,602 --> 00:30:56,395
That'll protect you.
So will all of us.

404
00:30:56,980 --> 00:30:59,440
Welcome to
the Blue Soldiers,
my friend.

405
00:30:59,525 --> 00:31:03,486
All right!
Everyone in position
for Capture the Flag!

406
00:31:03,570 --> 00:31:06,906
First team to capture
the enemy's banner wins.

407
00:31:07,824 --> 00:31:09,200
Dismissed!

408
00:31:10,661 --> 00:31:13,412
Steady, steady!

409
00:31:13,830 --> 00:31:14,956
Now!

410
00:31:33,684 --> 00:31:35,935
Percy, I know where
the flag's at. Come on!

411
00:31:40,774 --> 00:31:43,526
Keep your eyes open.
Don't get killed.

412
00:31:43,694 --> 00:31:45,236
Whoa! Whoa,
whoa, whoa!

413
00:31:57,958 --> 00:32:00,751
I'm coming, buddy,
I'm coming!
Sons of Ares. Watch out!

414
00:32:00,836 --> 00:32:03,004
Whoa, that's a sword!
That's a sword!

415
00:32:06,550 --> 00:32:09,176
Oh, you guys take camp
way too seriously.

416
00:32:10,053 --> 00:32:11,304
Go!

417
00:32:24,067 --> 00:32:27,653
Percy, get out of here!
Go look for the flag!

418
00:32:27,738 --> 00:32:29,739
How did I just do that?

419
00:32:49,009 --> 00:32:50,092
No.

420
00:33:01,563 --> 00:33:02,772
I won.

421
00:33:04,024 --> 00:33:05,650
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!

422
00:33:05,734 --> 00:33:08,069
Did you really think
it would be that easy?

423
00:33:13,075 --> 00:33:16,202
My mother is
goddess of wisdom
and battle strategy.

424
00:33:16,787 --> 00:33:19,163
Do you know
what that means?

425
00:33:19,247 --> 00:33:21,207
I always win.

426
00:33:22,000 --> 00:33:25,378
I always lose.
Maybe we're both wrong.

427
00:33:27,964 --> 00:33:29,173
Ow!

428
00:33:36,098 --> 00:33:39,100
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!

429
00:33:44,481 --> 00:33:46,190
Okay, Chiron,
shouldn't we get in there
and stop them?

430
00:33:46,274 --> 00:33:47,358
She's killing him, man.

431
00:33:47,442 --> 00:33:48,776
You've got
to be kidding.

432
00:33:48,860 --> 00:33:50,486
This is the best part!

433
00:33:57,744 --> 00:33:59,537
Stand up and fight,

434
00:34:01,456 --> 00:34:02,707
hero.

435
00:34:17,556 --> 00:34:19,181
Come on, Perce.
Come on, Perce.

436
00:34:26,398 --> 00:34:28,065
Go to the water.

437
00:34:36,491 --> 00:34:38,826
The water will
give you power.

438
00:37:04,139 --> 00:37:05,764
Yeah, Perce!

439
00:37:25,243 --> 00:37:26,744
Get up there.

440
00:37:26,870 --> 00:37:28,412
All right! Yeah!

441
00:37:28,830 --> 00:37:30,205
- Excuse me!
- Excuse me!

442
00:37:30,290 --> 00:37:33,208
Ladies and gentlemen,
the son of Poseidon
is coming through.

443
00:37:33,293 --> 00:37:35,753
A hero is
coming through!
Move it!

444
00:37:35,837 --> 00:37:38,088
Hey, no dirty looks.
Stop that.

445
00:37:38,173 --> 00:37:39,298
Sorry, I'm trying...

446
00:37:39,382 --> 00:37:40,925
Hey, Percy?

447
00:37:41,009 --> 00:37:43,344
We're having a party
at our place later.

448
00:37:43,428 --> 00:37:45,304
And we would
really love it
if you came.

449
00:37:45,388 --> 00:37:46,764
I'd love to come.
That'd be great.

450
00:37:46,848 --> 00:37:48,307
That would be amazing!
Awesome.

451
00:37:48,391 --> 00:37:50,684
I would love to come,
too, to the party.

452
00:37:50,769 --> 00:37:52,603
You know? Thanks for
inviting me, ladies.

453
00:37:52,687 --> 00:37:54,271
Beat it, nymphs.

454
00:37:54,356 --> 00:37:57,358
Wait, don't leave.
Ladies... I'm available.

455
00:37:58,026 --> 00:38:01,403
Wait, come on, don't leave.
I'm available!
What time's the party?

456
00:38:01,488 --> 00:38:02,780
Feeling like a hero?

457
00:38:02,864 --> 00:38:04,657
More like a mutant.

458
00:38:04,741 --> 00:38:07,660
I'm not gonna grow
a fish tail or gills
or anything like that, am I?

459
00:38:07,744 --> 00:38:09,161
Not likely.

460
00:38:09,746 --> 00:38:12,456
Although a huge ego
isn't out
of the question.

461
00:38:15,669 --> 00:38:17,878
You know you could have
killed me out there?

462
00:38:17,963 --> 00:38:20,297
I could have died,
if I was normal.

463
00:38:20,382 --> 00:38:21,966
But you aren't.

464
00:38:23,051 --> 00:38:25,761
I get the sense
that you don't
like me very much.

465
00:38:25,845 --> 00:38:29,431
It's possible.
I mean, our parents
hate each other.

466
00:38:29,516 --> 00:38:30,641
Wait. They do?

467
00:38:30,725 --> 00:38:31,725
Mmm-hmm.

468
00:38:32,227 --> 00:38:34,770
I definitely have
strong feelings for you.

469
00:38:35,897 --> 00:38:38,983
I just haven't decided
if they're positive
or negative yet.

470
00:38:40,151 --> 00:38:43,237
Well, you let me know
when you figure it out.

471
00:38:44,364 --> 00:38:46,198
You'll be the first.

472
00:39:07,095 --> 00:39:09,680
Percy Jackson,
show yourself!

473
00:39:29,492 --> 00:39:32,202
Hades! Stay back!

474
00:39:34,247 --> 00:39:38,167
Percy Jackson,
bring me the bolt!

475
00:39:41,546 --> 00:39:43,464
Be a good boy.

476
00:39:43,548 --> 00:39:47,968
Hand it to me
and I will exchange
it for your mother.

477
00:39:49,262 --> 00:39:52,181
Percy!
Don't listen, Percy!

478
00:39:55,685 --> 00:39:57,603
My mother's gone!

479
00:39:58,772 --> 00:40:02,483
No, your mother
is still alive.

480
00:40:02,567 --> 00:40:05,527
I sent the Minotaur
to abduct her.

481
00:40:05,612 --> 00:40:08,447
She is here with me
in the Underworld.

482
00:40:15,371 --> 00:40:16,455
Mom?

483
00:40:17,373 --> 00:40:18,665
Percy?

484
00:40:25,006 --> 00:40:26,632
What have you done
with my mother?

485
00:40:26,716 --> 00:40:31,053
If you ever want to
see your mother again,
you will bring me the bolt!

486
00:40:37,519 --> 00:40:38,977
Chiron, I have
to go get her.

487
00:40:39,062 --> 00:40:41,980
Percy, you don't
have the bolt.

488
00:40:42,065 --> 00:40:43,649
Look, I'll tell
him the truth!

489
00:40:43,733 --> 00:40:46,819
When he realizes
I'm not the thief,
he'll release her.

490
00:40:46,903 --> 00:40:49,613
No. You cannot
negotiate with Hades.

491
00:40:49,781 --> 00:40:52,491
When he finds out
you don't have the bolt,

492
00:40:53,201 --> 00:40:55,035
he'll kill you
and your mother.

493
00:40:55,120 --> 00:40:56,620
This is her only chance.

494
00:40:56,871 --> 00:40:58,038
No.

495
00:40:58,289 --> 00:41:00,040
Stick to our plan.

496
00:41:00,583 --> 00:41:04,336
Travel to Olympus,
bargain with Zeus.

497
00:41:04,671 --> 00:41:06,296
Once you convince him
of your innocence,

498
00:41:06,381 --> 00:41:10,342
we will do
everything in our power
to bring back your mother.

499
00:41:12,804 --> 00:41:13,971
Okay.

500
00:41:30,947 --> 00:41:32,656
Going somewhere?

501
00:41:33,575 --> 00:41:35,617
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm going for a walk.

502
00:41:35,702 --> 00:41:37,035
Oh, for a walk?
I'm coming with you.

503
00:41:37,120 --> 00:41:38,662
No, no,
I'm going alone.

504
00:41:38,746 --> 00:41:39,788
No, I'm coming
with you.

505
00:41:39,873 --> 00:41:40,873
No!

506
00:41:40,957 --> 00:41:42,875
You're being followed.

507
00:41:46,546 --> 00:41:48,213
- You're stressing me out.
- Leave me alone.

508
00:41:48,298 --> 00:41:49,548
We got a 1:00
demigod curfew,
okay?

509
00:41:49,632 --> 00:41:51,592
Leave me alone.
Go to sleep
or something.

510
00:41:51,676 --> 00:41:52,801
No.

511
00:41:53,511 --> 00:41:54,845
- Come on.
- One small victory

512
00:41:54,929 --> 00:41:56,013
and you're ready
to fight Hades?

513
00:41:56,097 --> 00:41:57,055
Ooh, double team.

514
00:41:57,140 --> 00:41:58,223
Really? You, too?

515
00:41:58,308 --> 00:42:01,185
Look, I just found out
my mother is still alive.

516
00:42:01,269 --> 00:42:02,352
I'm gonna get her back.

517
00:42:02,437 --> 00:42:03,437
From the Underworld?

518
00:42:03,521 --> 00:42:04,730
Whatever it takes.

519
00:42:04,814 --> 00:42:06,398
Huh. Yeah, well,
maybe you'll
outsmart Hades.

520
00:42:06,482 --> 00:42:07,816
Maybe I will.
Look, man,

521
00:42:07,901 --> 00:42:09,067
I can't let you
do this, okay?

522
00:42:09,152 --> 00:42:12,279
Look, I'm not asking
for your permission.

523
00:42:12,363 --> 00:42:15,324
Okay. Well, according
to regulations,

524
00:42:15,408 --> 00:42:17,409
if I can't stop you,
I must accompany you,

525
00:42:17,493 --> 00:42:19,953
'cause I'm your best friend
and your protector.

526
00:42:20,038 --> 00:42:21,246
Junior protector.

527
00:42:21,331 --> 00:42:23,790
Is that
really necessary?

528
00:42:23,875 --> 00:42:26,001
I don't need
your help. Okay?

529
00:42:26,085 --> 00:42:27,294
This is something
I have to do
on my own.

530
00:42:27,378 --> 00:42:29,379
Yeah, well,
we weren't asking
for your permission.

531
00:42:29,464 --> 00:42:32,466
Come on, all right?
Today you tried
to kill me.

532
00:42:32,550 --> 00:42:33,926
Now you want
to defend me?

533
00:42:34,010 --> 00:42:35,177
That wasn't real.

534
00:42:35,261 --> 00:42:37,095
That was just training.
Yeah.

535
00:42:37,180 --> 00:42:38,555
Percy, that's all
I've ever done,

536
00:42:38,640 --> 00:42:40,641
is train and train
and train.

537
00:42:40,725 --> 00:42:44,353
I've grown up here.
I've only been in the outside
world a couple of times.

538
00:42:44,437 --> 00:42:47,522
And I've never
had the chance to go
on an actual quest.

539
00:42:47,607 --> 00:42:51,652
Besides,
you've won one battle
and I've won hundreds.

540
00:42:52,070 --> 00:42:53,403
You're gonna need
my experience.

541
00:42:54,155 --> 00:42:55,197
Good point.

542
00:42:57,367 --> 00:42:59,368
You two really
want to come?

543
00:42:59,452 --> 00:43:00,869
Yes!
Yeah!

544
00:43:01,746 --> 00:43:04,248
Okay. I guess
we're all going.

545
00:43:04,332 --> 00:43:07,251
So who knows
how to get to
the Underworld?

546
00:43:08,586 --> 00:43:10,837
I did not think
of that one.

547
00:43:12,382 --> 00:43:14,341
I think I know
someone who might.

548
00:43:15,593 --> 00:43:17,469
Friendly Harriers inbound!

549
00:43:21,349 --> 00:43:22,724
Luke?
Hmm?

550
00:43:24,686 --> 00:43:26,270
Hey, guys.

551
00:43:27,021 --> 00:43:30,565
Percy.
I figured you'd stop by
sooner or later.

552
00:43:30,650 --> 00:43:34,569
Everybody does,
just to get away
from all that

553
00:43:34,654 --> 00:43:37,739
Renaissance fair
stuff out there,
you know?

554
00:43:39,117 --> 00:43:43,829
But welcome to
the modern world.

555
00:43:45,123 --> 00:43:46,790
Cool. New stuff.

556
00:43:50,044 --> 00:43:51,628
What are you
guys up to?

557
00:43:51,879 --> 00:43:53,839
We're going to
get my mom back.

558
00:43:54,632 --> 00:43:55,716
Oh!

559
00:43:55,800 --> 00:43:58,010
Your dad is
the messenger of the gods,

560
00:43:58,094 --> 00:44:01,972
one of the only ones
who's gotten in and out
of the Underworld.

561
00:44:02,056 --> 00:44:03,765
Do you have any idea how?

562
00:44:03,850 --> 00:44:08,145
Mmm. My dad's a jerk.
I've never met him.

563
00:44:08,229 --> 00:44:09,563
You, too?

564
00:44:09,647 --> 00:44:11,356
Guess we all got
Daddy issues, huh?

565
00:44:12,358 --> 00:44:15,652
That's because all gods
are the same. Selfish.

566
00:44:15,737 --> 00:44:18,155
They only care
about themselves.

567
00:44:19,198 --> 00:44:22,993
But I once broke
into my dad's house.
Got some cool stuff.

568
00:44:35,340 --> 00:44:36,673
For you.

569
00:44:45,558 --> 00:44:46,767
Whoa!

570
00:44:47,852 --> 00:44:49,770
Flying shoes?

571
00:44:49,854 --> 00:44:51,021
Mmm-hmm.

572
00:44:51,939 --> 00:44:53,148
They're my dad's.

573
00:44:54,192 --> 00:44:56,902
He has hundreds of
these little guys.

574
00:44:59,572 --> 00:45:01,198
He won't even miss them.

575
00:45:01,866 --> 00:45:03,700
Look underneath
the other one.

576
00:45:08,247 --> 00:45:10,582
You see, people have gone
to the Underworld before

577
00:45:10,666 --> 00:45:12,209
without having to be dead.

578
00:45:12,293 --> 00:45:13,710
Hercules did it.
Orpheus did it.

579
00:45:13,795 --> 00:45:15,545
My dad does it
all the time.

580
00:45:15,630 --> 00:45:17,464
Getting in's the easy part.

581
00:45:17,548 --> 00:45:19,508
Getting out,
now that's tricky.

582
00:45:20,718 --> 00:45:23,136
This is a map to
Persephone's pearls.

583
00:45:23,221 --> 00:45:26,181
Persephone?
You mean Hades' wife?

584
00:45:26,265 --> 00:45:29,768
Yeah, he forced her
to marry him.
Keeps her prisoner.

585
00:45:29,852 --> 00:45:33,688
Needless to say,
she hates it there.
It's hot, he's a weirdo.

586
00:45:33,773 --> 00:45:37,067
So she has, um,
secret visitors.

587
00:45:37,402 --> 00:45:38,902
- Hmm!
- Mmm!

588
00:45:39,445 --> 00:45:41,613
She keeps pearls
hidden for them
all over the world,

589
00:45:41,697 --> 00:45:42,739
and these pearls,

590
00:45:42,824 --> 00:45:44,783
they provide a quick escape
from the Underworld.

591
00:45:45,827 --> 00:45:47,577
You could use them
to get out.

592
00:45:47,662 --> 00:45:49,329
So, how do
the pearls work?

593
00:45:49,414 --> 00:45:50,789
Easy.

594
00:45:50,873 --> 00:45:53,667
You take a pearl,
you step on it,
you crush it,

595
00:45:53,751 --> 00:45:55,836
visualize where you
want to be taken.

596
00:45:55,920 --> 00:45:57,921
Right now,
there's three pearls
in the United States.

597
00:45:58,005 --> 00:45:59,256
This map will
guide you there.

598
00:45:59,340 --> 00:46:01,133
Right here is
your first location.

599
00:46:04,178 --> 00:46:06,513
"Auntie Em's
Garden Emporium."

600
00:46:06,848 --> 00:46:08,265
Once you find
the first pearl,

601
00:46:08,349 --> 00:46:09,724
the map will show
you the next one,

602
00:46:09,809 --> 00:46:12,394
and the next one,
and then you're off
to Hades.

603
00:46:12,979 --> 00:46:16,064
Which reminds me.
You guys

604
00:46:17,191 --> 00:46:19,693
might need some
extra protection, so...

605
00:46:22,738 --> 00:46:26,366
My favorite shield.
You might want to
take a step back.

606
00:46:33,875 --> 00:46:35,000
Mmm.

607
00:46:36,836 --> 00:46:38,211
Hey. Thanks, Luke.

608
00:46:38,296 --> 00:46:40,213
Ah, don't mention it.

609
00:46:40,298 --> 00:46:43,800
But you're gonna have to
promise me one thing.

610
00:46:44,677 --> 00:46:46,887
If you see my dad on
the highway to hell...

611
00:46:46,971 --> 00:46:48,096
Yeah?

612
00:46:48,181 --> 00:46:49,222
Kick his ass for me.

613
00:46:52,518 --> 00:46:55,896
I'm on the highway to hell

614
00:46:55,980 --> 00:46:59,274
Highway to hell

615
00:46:59,358 --> 00:47:02,611
I'm on the highway to hell

616
00:47:04,238 --> 00:47:07,324
Highway to hell

617
00:47:10,745 --> 00:47:12,913
Don't stop me

618
00:47:20,171 --> 00:47:23,423
This place
definitely needs
an extreme makeover.

619
00:47:28,012 --> 00:47:29,221
Hello!

620
00:47:31,516 --> 00:47:34,851
Hello?
Anybody home
in Auntieville?

621
00:47:34,936 --> 00:47:37,896
- Check this out.
- They got free sodas.

622
00:47:42,735 --> 00:47:44,528
Okay. That's nasty.

623
00:47:45,071 --> 00:47:48,156
The Health Department
needs to give
this place an F.

624
00:47:51,452 --> 00:47:53,912
Hey, guys,
check this out.

625
00:48:03,172 --> 00:48:04,506
Look at this.

626
00:48:06,133 --> 00:48:07,300
Nice.

627
00:48:08,427 --> 00:48:10,095
Gold drachmas.

628
00:48:10,221 --> 00:48:11,930
That means we're on
the right track.

629
00:48:12,598 --> 00:48:13,807
Here.

630
00:48:15,017 --> 00:48:16,851
How are we gonna find
the pearl in this place?

631
00:48:16,936 --> 00:48:18,395
That's a good question.

632
00:48:19,230 --> 00:48:21,398
Okay, let's split up.
Check everything.

633
00:48:21,482 --> 00:48:22,607
Good idea.
Yeah.

634
00:48:22,692 --> 00:48:24,109
I'm gonna go this way.

635
00:48:28,698 --> 00:48:29,906
Hello?

636
00:48:46,173 --> 00:48:47,632
Get out!
She's coming!

637
00:48:47,717 --> 00:48:49,175
What? Who?

638
00:48:49,260 --> 00:48:53,179
We stopped... Directions...
My poor husband! Help me!

639
00:48:53,306 --> 00:48:54,681
Please, help me!

640
00:49:05,026 --> 00:49:08,612
Check this out.
He looks just like
my Uncle Ferdinand.

641
00:49:10,698 --> 00:49:12,198
That's crazy.

642
00:49:12,867 --> 00:49:15,285
He got the mole
in the same place.

643
00:49:16,495 --> 00:49:18,580
No. It's not
my Uncle Ferdinand,

644
00:49:18,664 --> 00:49:20,915
because Uncle Ferdinand
was killed by

645
00:49:22,376 --> 00:49:23,668
Medusa.

646
00:49:25,546 --> 00:49:28,298
Percy! Annabeth!

647
00:49:28,382 --> 00:49:29,466
We're in trouble!

648
00:49:29,550 --> 00:49:30,634
Grover?

649
00:49:34,555 --> 00:49:37,223
Please!
We have to leave
before she finds us!

650
00:49:37,308 --> 00:49:38,350
Who?

651
00:49:38,434 --> 00:49:39,726
She's turned
my husband to stone!

652
00:49:39,810 --> 00:49:41,728
Grover! Where are you?

653
00:49:42,897 --> 00:49:46,066
Percy! Annabeth!

654
00:49:47,234 --> 00:49:48,443
Annabeth, where are you?

655
00:49:48,569 --> 00:49:49,861
Grover!

656
00:49:53,574 --> 00:49:55,325
Come on, man,
watch where you're going!

657
00:49:55,409 --> 00:49:56,743
Perce! Listen.

658
00:49:56,827 --> 00:49:58,995
Where are we?
We're in Medusa's lair.

659
00:49:59,914 --> 00:50:01,331
Annabeth!
Annie!

660
00:50:01,415 --> 00:50:03,750
We're lost!
We'll never leave!

661
00:50:04,377 --> 00:50:05,418
Don't move.

662
00:50:09,840 --> 00:50:13,510
Well, this is
a fabulous surprise.

663
00:50:14,095 --> 00:50:19,182
It's so heartening
to have such
young visitors.

664
00:50:20,351 --> 00:50:22,268
We get so lonely here.

665
00:50:23,771 --> 00:50:25,105
Don't we?

666
00:50:26,565 --> 00:50:30,110
That's why I create
my statues.

667
00:50:32,446 --> 00:50:34,447
They're my only company,

668
00:50:37,076 --> 00:50:38,952
daughter of Athena.

669
00:50:39,036 --> 00:50:40,537
How do you know me?

670
00:50:40,621 --> 00:50:44,124
You have such
beautiful hair.

671
00:50:45,876 --> 00:50:48,920
I once had hair
like that.

672
00:50:50,297 --> 00:50:51,798
I was courted,

673
00:50:53,426 --> 00:50:56,261
desired by
many suitors.

674
00:50:57,596 --> 00:50:59,806
But that all changed

675
00:51:01,225 --> 00:51:03,226
because of your mother,

676
00:51:03,978 --> 00:51:06,312
the woman who cursed me.

677
00:51:07,565 --> 00:51:09,232
Who turned me...

678
00:51:11,986 --> 00:51:13,027
Don't look!

679
00:51:13,112 --> 00:51:14,904
...Into this!

680
00:51:17,241 --> 00:51:20,827
They say the eyes
are windows to the soul.

681
00:51:21,829 --> 00:51:25,331
I hope you find my eyes

682
00:51:28,252 --> 00:51:29,836
attractive.

683
00:51:31,922 --> 00:51:36,676
So rude, not looking
people in the eyes.

684
00:51:38,596 --> 00:51:40,096
Come on.

685
00:51:41,182 --> 00:51:45,143
Sneak a peek.

686
00:52:04,705 --> 00:52:06,539
How are we supposed
to fight something
we can't look at?

687
00:52:06,665 --> 00:52:08,958
We can look
at a reflection.

688
00:52:09,043 --> 00:52:11,294
Okay, wait.
Check this out.

689
00:52:11,378 --> 00:52:14,047
All right. Good idea.
I'm gonna go get Annabeth.

690
00:52:14,173 --> 00:52:15,215
Okay, I'm gonna
take care of Medusa.

691
00:52:15,382 --> 00:52:16,466
Okay.

692
00:52:16,550 --> 00:52:20,678
You'll make a wonderful
addition to my collection.

693
00:52:21,555 --> 00:52:24,224
We'll be
friends forever.

694
00:52:24,725 --> 00:52:26,226
Do you mind?

695
00:52:30,064 --> 00:52:31,231
Oh, no, no.

696
00:52:35,402 --> 00:52:41,825
Sooner or later
you will open
those eyes.

697
00:52:43,577 --> 00:52:49,082
The temptation
to look at me
is too hard to resist.

698
00:52:49,416 --> 00:52:51,751
Don't look, Annabeth!
Don't open your eyes!

699
00:52:53,712 --> 00:52:55,255
Who's that?

700
00:52:56,173 --> 00:52:57,924
Another demigod?

701
00:53:04,515 --> 00:53:05,723
Mmm.

702
00:53:07,059 --> 00:53:08,768
I can sense you.

703
00:53:11,605 --> 00:53:13,231
Whoa, whoa, whoa.

704
00:53:25,619 --> 00:53:26,870
Whoa!

705
00:53:27,413 --> 00:53:28,621
Mmm.

706
00:53:29,623 --> 00:53:31,374
Son of Poseidon.

707
00:53:33,627 --> 00:53:36,296
I used to date
your daddy.

708
00:53:48,642 --> 00:53:49,934
Need a hand?

709
00:53:50,019 --> 00:53:51,644
Grover. Help.

710
00:53:54,315 --> 00:53:56,816
Thanks. Okay.
Come on. Let's go.

711
00:54:04,283 --> 00:54:07,493
I hear you have
the lightning bolt.

712
00:54:07,995 --> 00:54:09,829
May I see it?

713
00:54:10,456 --> 00:54:12,123
I don't have it!

714
00:54:14,668 --> 00:54:17,921
Let me see your eyes.

715
00:54:18,005 --> 00:54:21,841
I hear they're bluer
than the Circassian Sea.

716
00:54:23,010 --> 00:54:24,844
Open them,

717
00:54:24,970 --> 00:54:30,433
or my hungry babies
will have to
open them for you.

718
00:54:33,187 --> 00:54:36,272
But it would be
such a pity

719
00:54:36,357 --> 00:54:41,611
to destroy
such a young
and handsome face.

720
00:54:44,156 --> 00:54:47,784
Stay with me, Percy.

721
00:54:48,285 --> 00:54:54,040
All you have
to do is look.

722
00:55:10,808 --> 00:55:12,141
Are you okay?

723
00:55:15,229 --> 00:55:16,813
Yeah, I'm okay.

724
00:55:23,070 --> 00:55:25,738
Son of Poseidon!

725
00:55:39,920 --> 00:55:41,546
Heads up.

726
00:55:45,592 --> 00:55:48,761
Hey, guys! It's cool
to open up your eyes!

727
00:55:49,763 --> 00:55:55,101
Annabeth, that was great,
great demigod driving.

728
00:55:55,227 --> 00:55:56,602
Thanks.

729
00:55:59,732 --> 00:56:00,982
We should
take it with us.

730
00:56:01,066 --> 00:56:03,026
The head?
Oh, no. That's sick.

731
00:56:03,110 --> 00:56:06,779
If you open the eyes,
they still work,
dead or alive.

732
00:56:06,864 --> 00:56:08,948
You never know when
something like that
might come in handy.

733
00:56:09,033 --> 00:56:11,117
Yeah, you're right.
But I'm not touching it.

734
00:56:11,243 --> 00:56:12,827
Come on, man,
just take off
your jacket.

735
00:56:12,911 --> 00:56:15,204
We'll wrap it up
until we get some ice.

736
00:56:15,289 --> 00:56:17,373
Why do I got to
take off my jacket?

737
00:56:17,458 --> 00:56:19,250
Because you're
the protector.

738
00:56:19,960 --> 00:56:21,878
Yeah, you're right.
I am the protector.

739
00:56:21,962 --> 00:56:25,631
So I'm gonna
give you my hoodie,
not my jacket. Okay?

740
00:56:26,383 --> 00:56:28,134
Come on, you baby.

741
00:56:30,554 --> 00:56:31,804
Disgusting.

742
00:56:31,889 --> 00:56:33,973
- Yeah, just toss it up.
- Come on, don't...

743
00:56:35,309 --> 00:56:38,394
Hey. Hey. Guys, wait.

744
00:56:39,396 --> 00:56:40,938
The pearl.

745
00:56:46,403 --> 00:56:48,237
One down, two to go.

746
00:56:50,824 --> 00:56:54,077
Would have been nice
if Luke had warned us
about Medusa.

747
00:56:54,161 --> 00:56:56,662
Maybe he just
didn't know.

748
00:56:56,747 --> 00:56:59,290
GPS from the gods.
Where to next?

749
00:57:00,417 --> 00:57:01,834
Let's see.

750
00:57:07,633 --> 00:57:09,342
The Parthenon
in Nashville.

751
00:57:09,426 --> 00:57:14,180
Nashville? Oh, great.
Home of my least
favorite music.

752
00:57:14,515 --> 00:57:16,099
Yee-haw!

753
00:57:21,146 --> 00:57:23,856
I make believe

754
00:57:23,941 --> 00:57:27,860
that the sight of her
in my head's seldom seen

755
00:57:36,620 --> 00:57:39,497
Let's stop
for the night!
Yeah.

756
00:57:40,124 --> 00:57:41,124
Good idea.

757
00:57:41,208 --> 00:57:42,208
Oh, my God.

758
00:58:01,019 --> 00:58:02,228
Percy.

759
00:58:19,663 --> 00:58:21,263
Hey.

760
00:58:26,295 --> 00:58:29,046
Nice work today.
Thanks.

761
00:58:31,758 --> 00:58:33,342
What happened to you?

762
00:58:33,427 --> 00:58:37,513
Oh, that poor lady
who turned to stone,
she...

763
00:58:38,515 --> 00:58:40,391
She had a tight grip.

764
00:58:42,436 --> 00:58:44,020
Check this out.

765
00:58:56,909 --> 00:58:59,911
Cool. Very cool.

766
00:59:02,456 --> 00:59:03,623
So,

767
00:59:04,791 --> 00:59:06,709
why do our parents
hate each other?

768
00:59:06,793 --> 00:59:09,795
They both wanted to be
patron god of Athens.

769
00:59:10,297 --> 00:59:13,466
And the people
chose Athena.

770
00:59:14,218 --> 00:59:17,470
And our parents
have hated each other
ever since.

771
00:59:18,472 --> 00:59:19,680
What's your mom like?

772
00:59:19,765 --> 00:59:21,349
I don't know.

773
00:59:21,433 --> 00:59:22,475
I never met her.

774
00:59:22,559 --> 00:59:26,520
What? ls it like
this for everybody?

775
00:59:27,147 --> 00:59:29,565
Don't any gods
see their kids?

776
00:59:29,650 --> 00:59:31,484
It's forbidden.

777
00:59:32,069 --> 00:59:34,237
Right after
we were born,
Zeus decreed

778
00:59:34,321 --> 00:59:38,407
that the gods
couldn't have physical contact
with their mortal offspring.

779
00:59:38,492 --> 00:59:40,493
Oh, that's a stupid law.

780
00:59:40,577 --> 00:59:42,245
I agree.

781
00:59:43,747 --> 00:59:47,458
Although, between us,

782
00:59:49,253 --> 00:59:52,505
I think my mother
speaks to me sometimes.

783
00:59:52,589 --> 00:59:55,258
In times of trouble,
I hear her voice

784
00:59:55,342 --> 00:59:56,759
giving me advice.

785
00:59:56,885 --> 00:59:58,344
That's happened to me!

786
00:59:58,428 --> 01:00:01,305
Yeah.
That's your father
talking to you.

787
01:00:02,683 --> 01:00:05,768
Yo, Percy!
Get in here, man!
This is ugly!

788
01:00:08,021 --> 01:00:09,272
Right.

789
01:00:09,856 --> 01:00:11,357
Hey, hurry up!

790
01:00:11,942 --> 01:00:14,318
Perce, check this out, man.

791
01:00:15,112 --> 01:00:16,279
You're on TV.

792
01:00:16,363 --> 01:00:18,698
...Surrounding
the missing boy,
Percy Jackson,

793
01:00:18,782 --> 01:00:20,700
and his mother,
Sally Ugliano.

794
01:00:20,826 --> 01:00:23,869
But their relatives have
some interesting theories.

795
01:00:23,996 --> 01:00:26,622
So, Mr. Ugliano,
talk to me about
your son, Percy Jackson.

796
01:00:26,707 --> 01:00:29,041
No, he's not my son.
He's a stepson.

797
01:00:29,209 --> 01:00:31,544
He did not come
from these loins.

798
01:00:31,670 --> 01:00:34,088
Ever since he started
with the drugs
and the alcohol,

799
01:00:34,214 --> 01:00:35,464
he's never been
the same.
Oh, no.

800
01:00:35,549 --> 01:00:37,008
Five nights ago,
he tried to kill me

801
01:00:37,092 --> 01:00:38,551
and he threw his mother
on the ground.

802
01:00:38,635 --> 01:00:41,012
And his cripple friend
then attacked me

803
01:00:41,096 --> 01:00:43,389
from behind
and knocked me out.

804
01:00:43,473 --> 01:00:47,560
When I woke up,
Sally was gone.
She was kidnapped by Percy.

805
01:00:47,644 --> 01:00:48,644
She would never
leave with that...

806
01:00:48,770 --> 01:00:49,812
Oh, shut up, Gabe.

807
01:00:49,896 --> 01:00:52,648
Great.
Now I'm a fugitive.

808
01:00:52,733 --> 01:00:54,650
See? That's what
I'm talking about, man.

809
01:00:54,735 --> 01:00:56,652
Gabe's always
running his mouth.

810
01:00:56,737 --> 01:00:59,655
He's just mad
because I busted him up
with my crutches.

811
01:01:01,491 --> 01:01:02,658
Guys,

812
01:01:04,077 --> 01:01:06,579
I can't pee
with her watching me.

813
01:01:18,925 --> 01:01:21,344
Sorry, guys.
I messed up.

814
01:01:21,428 --> 01:01:23,012
I should have
closed the curtains.

815
01:01:23,096 --> 01:01:24,430
Come on, guys.

816
01:01:24,514 --> 01:01:26,974
Let's hit the road
before Homeland
Security shows up.

817
01:02:01,718 --> 01:02:04,720
Wow, that's amazing.

818
01:02:04,805 --> 01:02:07,807
A complete replica
of the Parthenon
in Nashville.

819
01:02:07,891 --> 01:02:10,142
All right, guys.
Let's go get the pearl.

820
01:02:22,781 --> 01:02:24,115
Wow.

821
01:02:34,251 --> 01:02:36,627
Hey. That's your mom.

822
01:02:38,130 --> 01:02:40,423
I wonder if
she really looks
like that.

823
01:02:43,927 --> 01:02:45,511
We'll find out.

824
01:02:48,807 --> 01:02:53,102
Guys, check this out.
Oh, man.

825
01:02:55,355 --> 01:02:56,647
It's the pearl.

826
01:03:02,320 --> 01:03:03,279
That was easy.

827
01:03:03,363 --> 01:03:04,947
Easy?

828
01:03:05,031 --> 01:03:08,617
It's 30 feet in the air
and this place is
filled with tourists.

829
01:03:10,662 --> 01:03:12,204
I got an idea.

830
01:03:12,706 --> 01:03:15,708
We'll come back
after the place closes.
Come on, follow me.

831
01:03:15,792 --> 01:03:18,085
Or I can just throw
my crutch up there.

832
01:03:18,211 --> 01:03:19,795
I'm saying, the pearl
would fall out...
Grover!

833
01:03:19,880 --> 01:03:22,798
Perce, I'm saying...
It's not a bad idea!

834
01:03:37,022 --> 01:03:40,232
The park's been
closed for an hour.
Let's move.

835
01:03:40,358 --> 01:03:41,692
Yes, sir!

836
01:03:43,069 --> 01:03:44,820
All right,
this will be easy.
Okay.

837
01:03:44,905 --> 01:03:47,239
I'm gonna fly up.
I'm gonna use
Luke's flying shoes.

838
01:03:47,365 --> 01:03:48,908
I'm gonna grab
the pearl, and...
Cool.

839
01:03:48,992 --> 01:03:50,075
Oh!

840
01:03:57,334 --> 01:03:59,835
Okay, so what are
we going to do?

841
01:04:01,213 --> 01:04:02,880
All right, guys.

842
01:04:04,257 --> 01:04:05,341
I got this.

843
01:04:05,425 --> 01:04:07,760
- You got what?
- Hey, yo, hey, listen!

844
01:04:07,886 --> 01:04:08,928
You're going to
kill the janitors?

845
01:04:09,012 --> 01:04:10,012
Chill.

846
01:04:10,096 --> 01:04:12,181
Those are
working-class
Americans!

847
01:04:18,063 --> 01:04:19,230
Oh, man.

848
01:04:26,613 --> 01:04:28,239
Oh. Why did
you do that?

849
01:04:28,490 --> 01:04:30,032
They're not dead,
they're unconscious.

850
01:04:30,116 --> 01:04:31,492
Now, we have 30 minutes.
Come on!

851
01:04:31,826 --> 01:04:33,118
Cool.

852
01:04:46,299 --> 01:04:47,800
Y'all, what's cracking?

853
01:04:47,884 --> 01:04:48,968
Hey.

854
01:04:49,636 --> 01:04:50,636
Luke!

855
01:04:50,720 --> 01:04:51,845
Annabeth!

856
01:04:51,930 --> 01:04:53,556
How do you
turn on the shoes?

857
01:04:53,640 --> 01:04:55,724
Tell Percy
he's got to break
into a run, okay?

858
01:04:55,809 --> 01:05:00,646
He's got to build up speed,
kind of like
a jet on a runway.

859
01:05:00,772 --> 01:05:02,815
It's gonna take
some practice.

860
01:05:03,149 --> 01:05:04,316
Okay.

861
01:05:05,235 --> 01:05:06,652
I got this.

862
01:05:07,487 --> 01:05:08,988
Whoa... Whoa!

863
01:05:09,072 --> 01:05:10,823
It's gonna take
some practice!

864
01:05:11,783 --> 01:05:13,659
Whoa!

865
01:05:15,579 --> 01:05:19,081
Oh! Whoa. Whoa.

866
01:05:41,521 --> 01:05:42,605
I got it!
Yes!

867
01:05:42,689 --> 01:05:44,356
- Yeah, Percy!
- There we go!

868
01:05:49,029 --> 01:05:50,112
There it is.

869
01:05:50,196 --> 01:05:51,280
Yeah!

870
01:05:51,781 --> 01:05:52,781
That's what
I'm talking about.

871
01:05:52,866 --> 01:05:53,824
Way to go.

872
01:05:53,908 --> 01:05:55,075
All right,
let's grab everything...

873
01:05:55,160 --> 01:05:56,368
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.

874
01:05:58,955 --> 01:06:00,205
Oh, man.

875
01:06:06,630 --> 01:06:08,130
Look, I got this, okay?

876
01:06:08,214 --> 01:06:10,883
Hey, guys, I'm with
Park Recreational Services.

877
01:06:10,967 --> 01:06:13,385
You guys have been
caught sleeping on the job.
You better be happy

878
01:06:13,470 --> 01:06:15,554
I'm not writing
you guys up, okay?
This is the last time.

879
01:06:15,639 --> 01:06:18,390
We've been expecting you,
Mr. Jackson.

880
01:06:18,516 --> 01:06:20,726
Not again.

881
01:06:20,810 --> 01:06:24,063
Just give us
the lightning bolt
and we'll let you go.

882
01:06:24,147 --> 01:06:26,732
Look, I don't have
the lightning bolt.

883
01:06:28,068 --> 01:06:30,194
Okay. This is bad.

884
01:06:49,089 --> 01:06:50,589
Hydra!

885
01:06:50,715 --> 01:06:53,842
Guys, watch out!
The middle one
spews fire!

886
01:06:56,012 --> 01:06:57,262
Whoa!

887
01:07:18,118 --> 01:07:21,954
Oh, you got a sweet tooth?
All right! Try that!

888
01:07:39,931 --> 01:07:44,143
Whoa!
Percy, stop! No!

889
01:07:46,229 --> 01:07:47,479
Whoa!

890
01:07:57,157 --> 01:07:58,490
How flipping
awesome was that?

891
01:07:58,575 --> 01:07:59,575
I just killed
that thing!

892
01:07:59,659 --> 01:08:01,994
Killed it?
You only made it worse.

893
01:08:02,078 --> 01:08:03,287
What are you
talking about?

894
01:08:03,371 --> 01:08:05,581
Percy, when you cut
off one Hydra head,

895
01:08:05,665 --> 01:08:07,249
two more grow back.

896
01:08:15,133 --> 01:08:16,633
Get back!

897
01:08:19,304 --> 01:08:21,513
Distract that thing!
I'll get the pearl!

898
01:09:00,053 --> 01:09:01,887
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!

899
01:09:30,208 --> 01:09:31,667
Let's go!

900
01:09:31,751 --> 01:09:33,585
Let's go! Come on!

901
01:09:35,672 --> 01:09:37,339
- Go!
- Open the door!

902
01:09:37,423 --> 01:09:39,258
The door won't open!

903
01:09:39,884 --> 01:09:41,093
Grover!

904
01:10:18,840 --> 01:10:20,340
That's nasty.

905
01:10:23,678 --> 01:10:26,054
We interrupt our regularly
scheduled programming

906
01:10:26,139 --> 01:10:28,181
for this special report.

907
01:10:28,308 --> 01:10:30,809
Scientists are baffled
by what now appears to be

908
01:10:30,935 --> 01:10:35,105
a single storm cloud
that is expanding over
much of Europe and Asia,

909
01:10:35,189 --> 01:10:37,190
moving towards
the United States.

910
01:10:37,317 --> 01:10:39,484
Savage winds,
rain and mammoth waves

911
01:10:39,569 --> 01:10:41,278
are being reported
along the coastlines

912
01:10:41,362 --> 01:10:42,738
of several continents.

913
01:10:42,822 --> 01:10:47,409
So far, no casualties,
but countries everywhere
are preparing for the worst.

914
01:10:47,493 --> 01:10:49,453
The gods are angry.

915
01:10:50,204 --> 01:10:51,288
We need to get
the last pearl.

916
01:10:51,372 --> 01:10:52,539
Where's the next location?

917
01:10:52,624 --> 01:10:53,790
Yeah.

918
01:10:54,667 --> 01:10:56,335
Well, let's see.

919
01:10:57,712 --> 01:11:00,714
Well, guys,
we got ourselves
a good one.

920
01:11:01,507 --> 01:11:03,008
We're going to Vegas!

921
01:11:31,162 --> 01:11:32,204
Yo!

922
01:11:38,336 --> 01:11:40,504
Oh. There it is.

923
01:11:41,881 --> 01:11:43,256
Lotus Casino.

924
01:12:00,400 --> 01:12:01,942
I've been
looking forward to this!

925
01:12:02,026 --> 01:12:05,153
Look, guys, remember,
always split the eights,
never the tens, okay?

926
01:12:05,238 --> 01:12:06,822
We're not here to
gamble, remember?

927
01:12:06,906 --> 01:12:09,157
We got poker,
we got blackjack...

928
01:12:09,283 --> 01:12:11,493
Grover,
we're not here
to have fun.

929
01:12:11,577 --> 01:12:13,203
We just need to
grab the pearl
and go, okay?

930
01:12:13,287 --> 01:12:14,579
All right.

931
01:12:17,709 --> 01:12:19,418
This is nice!

932
01:12:28,094 --> 01:12:32,055
A little less conversation,
a little more action, please

933
01:12:32,140 --> 01:12:35,308
All this aggravation
ain't satisfactioning me

934
01:12:35,935 --> 01:12:38,770
Okay, this place
is officially dope.

935
01:12:38,896 --> 01:12:40,814
Here's your complimentary
Lotus Fun Book.

936
01:12:40,940 --> 01:12:42,691
Thanks,
but we're not staying.

937
01:12:42,775 --> 01:12:45,986
Please, I insist.
It's good for everything
in the hotel and casino.

938
01:12:46,112 --> 01:12:48,655
Don't comp us.
We're not checking in.

939
01:12:48,781 --> 01:12:50,532
Okay, that guy
was persistent.

940
01:12:50,616 --> 01:12:52,075
Yeah!

941
01:12:52,910 --> 01:12:56,413
Yeah, we're here
for one thing
and one thing only.

942
01:12:56,956 --> 01:12:57,914
Wow.

943
01:12:57,999 --> 01:12:59,207
That is really
awesome.

944
01:13:01,753 --> 01:13:04,963
Where would we
find a green pearl
in this place?

945
01:13:06,174 --> 01:13:08,467
Maybe on
a cocktail waitress
or a showgirl.

946
01:13:08,593 --> 01:13:10,260
We should start there.

947
01:13:13,639 --> 01:13:17,726
Can I get you something?
Try a lotus flower.
They're so good.

948
01:13:17,810 --> 01:13:19,061
It's our signature dish.

949
01:13:19,145 --> 01:13:21,646
Oh. Really?
Signature?

950
01:13:22,648 --> 01:13:24,024
Is it good?

951
01:13:24,984 --> 01:13:26,401
Thank you.

952
01:13:26,486 --> 01:13:27,903
Yo, do we have to
pay for this?

953
01:13:28,946 --> 01:13:31,198
I guess we don't.
It's free.

954
01:13:34,535 --> 01:13:36,328
Mmm. That's really good.

955
01:13:40,500 --> 01:13:45,837
Mmm. Wow. This is
the most delicious thing
I've ever consumed!

956
01:13:57,558 --> 01:13:59,976
I wanna hold 'em
like they do in Texas, please

957
01:14:01,896 --> 01:14:03,021
Wow.

958
01:14:03,147 --> 01:14:04,731
Fold 'em let 'em
hit me, raise it,
baby, stay with me

959
01:14:04,857 --> 01:14:05,857
I love it

960
01:14:05,983 --> 01:14:07,484
Love, game, intuition,
play the cards

961
01:14:07,568 --> 01:14:09,319
Guys, why don't we
stay here for a while?

962
01:14:09,403 --> 01:14:10,529
Yeah!

963
01:14:10,613 --> 01:14:12,114
That sounds like
an amazing idea.

964
01:14:15,034 --> 01:14:19,204
But we're on
a time-sensitive
mission right now.

965
01:14:21,332 --> 01:14:22,457
Aren't we...

966
01:14:22,542 --> 01:14:23,959
I can't remember.

967
01:14:24,043 --> 01:14:26,169
I totally forgot
what I was gonna say.

968
01:14:27,046 --> 01:14:29,923
I think I figured it out.
I think I know why
we're here.

969
01:14:30,049 --> 01:14:31,299
Why are we here?

970
01:14:31,384 --> 01:14:32,551
To have fun.

971
01:14:33,261 --> 01:14:35,595
Okay. Let's never leave!

972
01:14:35,721 --> 01:14:37,889
- Yeah!
- Let's stay here!

973
01:14:39,725 --> 01:14:41,685
Can't read my
Can't read my

974
01:14:41,769 --> 01:14:45,397
No, he can't read
my poker face

975
01:14:45,523 --> 01:14:47,440
She's got to love nobody

976
01:14:47,567 --> 01:14:49,776
Can't read my
Can't read my

977
01:14:49,902 --> 01:14:52,612
No, he can't read
my poker face

978
01:14:52,738 --> 01:14:53,905
Whoa!

979
01:14:55,366 --> 01:14:56,616
Yeah!

980
01:14:57,076 --> 01:15:03,081
Poker face, poker face

981
01:15:07,879 --> 01:15:18,180
I'll get him hot,
show him what I got

982
01:15:18,264 --> 01:15:19,848
You're awesome!

983
01:15:19,932 --> 01:15:22,017
Can't read my
Can't read my

984
01:15:22,101 --> 01:15:25,645
No, he can't read
my poker face

985
01:15:25,771 --> 01:15:27,981
She's got to love nobody

986
01:15:28,107 --> 01:15:29,983
Can't read my
Can't read my

987
01:15:30,109 --> 01:15:33,528
No, he can't read
my poker face

988
01:15:33,613 --> 01:15:35,488
Ooh! Ooh!
Ooh!

989
01:15:35,615 --> 01:15:37,949
Thanks.
Thank you! Thanks.

990
01:15:39,160 --> 01:15:42,287
- No, Percy.
- Don't eat the flower.

991
01:15:43,164 --> 01:15:47,292
It dulls the senses,
keeps you prisoner here.

992
01:15:49,086 --> 01:15:50,921
Hey, I think
I'm gonna go get some air.
I'll be right back.

993
01:15:51,005 --> 01:15:52,297
Okay.

994
01:15:57,094 --> 01:15:58,220
Another lotus flower?

995
01:15:58,304 --> 01:16:00,138
- No, I'm good.
- Thank you.

996
01:16:03,476 --> 01:16:07,270
- Look around you.
- Focus. Focus!

997
01:16:07,355 --> 01:16:08,355
Another lotus flower?

998
01:16:08,439 --> 01:16:09,481
No, thank you.

999
01:16:11,150 --> 01:16:13,944
Would you like
another one?
I'm fine.

1000
01:16:20,368 --> 01:16:22,202
The French Connection, huh?

1001
01:16:22,495 --> 01:16:24,329
- Yeah.
- You seen it yet?

1002
01:16:25,289 --> 01:16:27,666
Yeah, yeah,
I think so, on DVD.

1003
01:16:28,334 --> 01:16:29,834
What's DVD?

1004
01:16:31,462 --> 01:16:32,837
Seriously?

1005
01:16:33,506 --> 01:16:35,924
Whatever. I think
it's the best movie
of the year.

1006
01:16:36,008 --> 01:16:38,969
What? Wait.
This year?

1007
01:16:40,221 --> 01:16:43,348
Yeah, this year. 1971.

1008
01:16:50,815 --> 01:16:52,524
Percy, wake up.

1009
01:16:53,526 --> 01:16:55,235
You need to escape.

1010
01:16:55,361 --> 01:16:56,361
Wake up!

1011
01:16:56,445 --> 01:16:57,445
You could really use
a lotus flower.

1012
01:16:57,530 --> 01:16:58,697
I really
don't want one.

1013
01:16:58,823 --> 01:16:59,864
Thank you.
Just one.

1014
01:16:59,991 --> 01:17:01,199
No!

1015
01:17:16,173 --> 01:17:17,340
Another lotus flower?

1016
01:17:17,425 --> 01:17:18,466
No.
We insist.

1017
01:17:18,551 --> 01:17:21,219
I really don't want
another lotus flower,
so please, leave me alone.

1018
01:17:21,345 --> 01:17:23,555
Is there a problem,
Mr. Jackson?

1019
01:17:25,558 --> 01:17:27,559
No. Thank you.

1020
01:17:33,065 --> 01:17:35,025
Percy Jackson's awake.

1021
01:17:39,071 --> 01:17:40,196
Excuse me.
Annabeth. Annabeth!

1022
01:17:40,281 --> 01:17:42,198
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What're you doing with that?
Don't eat that.

1023
01:17:42,283 --> 01:17:43,450
What?
We have to go. Now.

1024
01:17:43,576 --> 01:17:44,784
What do you mean?
We're having so much fun!

1025
01:17:44,910 --> 01:17:47,954
No, no, no,
we're not having fun.
Grover! Grover! Wake up!

1026
01:17:48,080 --> 01:17:49,956
Grover! Come on,
we got to go!

1027
01:17:50,082 --> 01:17:52,959
What? Look, Perce,
your timing
is terrible, okay?

1028
01:17:53,085 --> 01:17:56,087
Dude, we're heading
to the chapel.
We're getting married!

1029
01:17:56,213 --> 01:17:57,756
How romantic!
No, no, no, no, no.

1030
01:17:57,882 --> 01:17:59,758
Hey, which of y'all
did I propose to?

1031
01:18:01,927 --> 01:18:03,428
Wake up!

1032
01:18:03,888 --> 01:18:06,222
Yo, man,
you're such
a buzz kill.

1033
01:18:06,307 --> 01:18:08,141
Percy,
what's wrong with you?
Why are you doing this?

1034
01:18:08,267 --> 01:18:09,768
Both of you need
to wake up, now!

1035
01:18:09,894 --> 01:18:13,063
Look at me. Look at me.
You're in a trance, okay?
We're trapped!

1036
01:18:13,147 --> 01:18:14,939
Listen to me.
If you eat the flowers,

1037
01:18:15,024 --> 01:18:16,983
you're never gonna
want to leave. Okay?

1038
01:18:17,068 --> 01:18:18,943
We're gonna be
stuck here forever!

1039
01:18:19,320 --> 01:18:20,653
Oh.

1040
01:18:21,781 --> 01:18:23,531
Oh, no.
We got to go.

1041
01:18:23,616 --> 01:18:24,866
Okay, I see
your point! Okay.

1042
01:18:24,950 --> 01:18:26,159
Let's get
the green pearl!

1043
01:18:32,083 --> 01:18:35,168
- Hold it right there!
- Stop right where you are.

1044
01:18:55,314 --> 01:18:59,609
Move, James Dean!
Out of the way!
Let's go, guys! Car! Car!

1045
01:19:00,111 --> 01:19:02,153
Come on, guys! Car!

1046
01:19:03,322 --> 01:19:04,572
Get in!

1047
01:19:04,657 --> 01:19:06,866
Come on, come on!
In the car, in the car!
Let's go!

1048
01:19:06,992 --> 01:19:07,992
Keys! Got the keys.

1049
01:19:08,119 --> 01:19:09,077
Come on! Go!

1050
01:19:09,161 --> 01:19:10,286
Drive! Drive!

1051
01:19:10,371 --> 01:19:11,454
- They're coming!
- They're coming!

1052
01:19:11,539 --> 01:19:13,081
Come on, start driving!
I got this.

1053
01:19:13,165 --> 01:19:14,374
Go!

1054
01:19:35,688 --> 01:19:39,149
Now, that's how you
get out of a casino!
That's how you drive!

1055
01:19:39,233 --> 01:19:41,359
Of course.
Now that all makes sense.

1056
01:19:41,485 --> 01:19:42,444
What?

1057
01:19:42,528 --> 01:19:43,820
That was the lair
of the lotus eaters.

1058
01:19:43,904 --> 01:19:46,656
They've been luring people
into their trap
since ancient times.

1059
01:19:46,740 --> 01:19:49,492
Guys, look.
Tomorrow is June 21 st.

1060
01:19:49,994 --> 01:19:52,328
No. No, no.
It can't be.
Today's the 15th.

1061
01:19:52,413 --> 01:19:56,458
No, tomorrow is the 21 st.
We were in there
for five days.

1062
01:19:56,542 --> 01:19:57,667
It felt like hours.

1063
01:19:57,751 --> 01:19:59,002
Then tomorrow's
the solstice.

1064
01:19:59,086 --> 01:20:00,962
Our deadline is
tomorrow at midnight.

1065
01:20:01,046 --> 01:20:03,715
Okay, look,
we've got to move it.
Where's Hades?

1066
01:20:10,514 --> 01:20:12,849
It's in Hollywood.

1067
01:20:12,933 --> 01:20:16,186
All right.
I can get us there
in four hours.

1068
01:20:16,562 --> 01:20:17,770
Maybe three.

1069
01:20:46,217 --> 01:20:49,093
And now, the latest
breaking news from KZLY.

1070
01:20:49,220 --> 01:20:53,181
An unprecedented storm cloud
has grown to cover most
of North America.

1071
01:20:53,265 --> 01:20:56,059
Authorities in several states
are ordering evacuations,

1072
01:20:56,143 --> 01:20:58,061
reporting severe
weather conditions.

1073
01:21:05,736 --> 01:21:07,445
- Don't slip.
- Watch your step.

1074
01:21:08,572 --> 01:21:10,990
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait, wait. Hold it.

1075
01:21:16,455 --> 01:21:19,165
"Woe to all
depraved souls."

1076
01:21:50,656 --> 01:21:53,741
Well, I guess
there ain't no
turning back now.

1077
01:21:53,826 --> 01:21:56,369
Yep. Looks like
we're stuck in here.

1078
01:21:56,453 --> 01:21:58,037
Yeah.

1079
01:22:08,841 --> 01:22:11,968
Hey, Perce,
who's that creepy guy
with the hoodie?

1080
01:22:12,052 --> 01:22:14,345
I don't know.
Let's find out.

1081
01:22:19,226 --> 01:22:20,977
Who are you?

1082
01:22:21,061 --> 01:22:22,770
We need to see Hades.

1083
01:22:22,855 --> 01:22:24,856
The living are
not permitted here.

1084
01:22:25,691 --> 01:22:27,692
Die and come back.

1085
01:22:28,986 --> 01:22:32,155
Okay, we won't die
and come back, but...

1086
01:22:33,198 --> 01:22:36,868
- You know what?
- I think I know what he wants.

1087
01:22:36,994 --> 01:22:38,286
What?

1088
01:22:38,370 --> 01:22:40,455
You got to pay
the ferryman.

1089
01:22:40,539 --> 01:22:41,706
Watch this.

1090
01:22:42,416 --> 01:22:45,043
Yo, my friend!
What up?

1091
01:22:47,046 --> 01:22:49,714
Okay, guess not.
Look, you like
dead people, right?

1092
01:22:49,840 --> 01:22:52,592
I got a few dead people
you might recognize.

1093
01:22:52,718 --> 01:22:55,094
Check this out.
Jackson, Grant.

1094
01:22:55,220 --> 01:22:58,681
And look who's
joining the party.
Benjamin Franklin.

1095
01:22:58,766 --> 01:22:59,974
Yeah, you like that,
don't you?

1096
01:23:00,059 --> 01:23:02,727
Look,
you give us a boat ride,
you take the money

1097
01:23:02,853 --> 01:23:04,145
and you get
an interior decorator,

1098
01:23:04,229 --> 01:23:05,480
'cause it is too
depressing in here.

1099
01:23:05,564 --> 01:23:07,440
All right?
Here you go.

1100
01:23:15,240 --> 01:23:17,033
That was $170!

1101
01:23:17,409 --> 01:23:20,745
Wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
The drachma. The drachma!

1102
01:23:30,923 --> 01:23:32,131
Climb aboard.

1103
01:23:32,257 --> 01:23:34,634
Thanks for telling me, man,
you're burning money.
We're in a recession.

1104
01:23:34,760 --> 01:23:37,220
That's treason.
Just shut up.
Shut up, man. Go on.

1105
01:23:55,823 --> 01:23:57,949
Welcome to
the Underworld.

1106
01:24:02,788 --> 01:24:04,288
What is all this?

1107
01:24:06,166 --> 01:24:08,501
The scrapheap
of human misery.

1108
01:24:09,962 --> 01:24:11,838
Lost hopes and dreams.

1109
01:24:13,966 --> 01:24:16,259
Wishes that never
came true.

1110
01:24:30,816 --> 01:24:34,152
All lives end
in suffering
and tragedy.

1111
01:25:02,389 --> 01:25:04,682
This is as
far as I go.

1112
01:25:24,870 --> 01:25:26,412
Guys, do you
hear that?

1113
01:25:26,538 --> 01:25:27,497
Yeah, what is that?

1114
01:25:27,581 --> 01:25:28,623
I don't know.

1115
01:25:34,671 --> 01:25:35,922
Annie, stab that thing!

1116
01:25:36,006 --> 01:25:37,215
What are we gonna do?

1117
01:25:39,051 --> 01:25:40,384
Back!

1118
01:25:44,348 --> 01:25:45,640
What were those things?

1119
01:25:45,933 --> 01:25:47,099
Hellhounds.

1120
01:25:47,184 --> 01:25:50,102
Yeah, well,
maybe you should
feed them.

1121
01:25:50,938 --> 01:25:53,231
They sensed the presence
of another animal.

1122
01:25:54,066 --> 01:25:55,149
Great, they smell goat.

1123
01:25:55,234 --> 01:25:56,943
Hmm. A Satyr.

1124
01:26:00,572 --> 01:26:02,448
I haven't had a Satyr

1125
01:26:04,952 --> 01:26:06,077
visit before.

1126
01:26:06,161 --> 01:26:07,870
Persephone!

1127
01:26:07,955 --> 01:26:10,456
What could possibly
be taking so long?

1128
01:26:10,958 --> 01:26:12,625
Don't ignore me!

1129
01:26:12,751 --> 01:26:16,295
Or what?
What will you do?

1130
01:26:16,922 --> 01:26:18,756
I'm already in Hell.

1131
01:26:39,444 --> 01:26:41,112
We have visitors.

1132
01:26:44,283 --> 01:26:45,491
Nephew.

1133
01:26:57,296 --> 01:26:58,629
Welcome.

1134
01:27:00,299 --> 01:27:02,633
You have your
father's looks.

1135
01:27:03,635 --> 01:27:07,054
Always the lucky
side of the family.

1136
01:27:07,139 --> 01:27:10,474
Wait. Wait a minute,
wait a minute.

1137
01:27:10,601 --> 01:27:11,684
You're Hades?

1138
01:27:11,768 --> 01:27:12,935
Yes.

1139
01:27:13,020 --> 01:27:17,064
Sorry.
I just didn't expect you
to look like this, man.

1140
01:27:17,149 --> 01:27:19,150
Kind of stylish.
I like it.

1141
01:27:19,276 --> 01:27:22,528
Would you prefer
that I looked like this?

1142
01:27:25,824 --> 01:27:30,995
No! No! Look, stick to
the Mick Jagger thing!
It works for you!

1143
01:27:40,172 --> 01:27:42,506
You're very
brave coming here.

1144
01:27:43,550 --> 01:27:45,009
Come closer.

1145
01:27:47,512 --> 01:27:49,388
Hey. Perce.

1146
01:27:49,514 --> 01:27:51,390
I can see
the look of disgust
in your eyes,

1147
01:27:51,516 --> 01:27:53,809
but this existence
was not of my choosing.

1148
01:27:53,894 --> 01:27:58,564
I was banished here
by Zeus and your father.
I am damned.

1149
01:27:59,191 --> 01:28:01,567
My only chance
of getting out
of this place

1150
01:28:01,693 --> 01:28:05,363
is to defeat my brothers
and take control of Olympus.
But, of course,

1151
01:28:06,406 --> 01:28:07,865
I'll need the bolt.

1152
01:28:08,909 --> 01:28:10,326
And I need my mother.

1153
01:28:10,452 --> 01:28:11,869
Then we have
an understanding.

1154
01:28:11,995 --> 01:28:14,664
You give me the bolt
and I'll give you
your mother.

1155
01:28:19,836 --> 01:28:21,045
I need to tell
you the truth.

1156
01:28:21,171 --> 01:28:25,257
I'm not
the lightning thief.
I don't have the bolt.

1157
01:28:25,384 --> 01:28:26,842
I never did.

1158
01:28:28,345 --> 01:28:30,221
Why did you
come here, then?

1159
01:28:32,516 --> 01:28:34,225
Well, I was hoping

1160
01:28:35,185 --> 01:28:38,479
that when you saw
that I wasn't the thief,
you'd let my mother go.

1161
01:28:38,563 --> 01:28:41,440
Yes. Yes,
but do you think
I'm an idiot?

1162
01:28:42,859 --> 01:28:44,652
I'm Hades!

1163
01:28:44,736 --> 01:28:48,280
Now, give me the bolt,
or say goodbye to your mother!

1164
01:29:13,056 --> 01:29:14,265
Percy!

1165
01:29:22,274 --> 01:29:24,692
I thought
I'd lost you forever.

1166
01:29:24,776 --> 01:29:25,901
No.

1167
01:29:49,801 --> 01:29:51,969
Zeus' master bolt.

1168
01:29:56,600 --> 01:29:57,767
Liar.

1169
01:29:58,477 --> 01:30:00,644
I swear,
I don't know how
that got there.

1170
01:30:00,771 --> 01:30:02,063
That's not even
my shield!

1171
01:30:02,147 --> 01:30:03,230
No!

1172
01:30:03,315 --> 01:30:04,523
Luke rigged it!

1173
01:30:04,649 --> 01:30:06,984
He put the bolt
in his shield
and used us.

1174
01:30:07,110 --> 01:30:08,819
Luke stole
the lightning bolt.

1175
01:30:09,321 --> 01:30:11,197
I think we're done here.

1176
01:30:12,449 --> 01:30:14,158
Feed them to the souls.

1177
01:30:27,547 --> 01:30:29,048
Whoa! Whoa!

1178
01:30:29,174 --> 01:30:32,927
We had a deal, all right?
You have the bolt!
Just let us go!

1179
01:30:33,011 --> 01:30:34,762
Summon the hounds.

1180
01:30:36,223 --> 01:30:38,015
Ella tho!

1181
01:30:38,183 --> 01:30:39,975
No. No ella tho.

1182
01:30:43,188 --> 01:30:45,022
Lassie, sit! Sit!

1183
01:30:48,193 --> 01:30:49,527
No! No!

1184
01:30:51,363 --> 01:30:54,657
I am going to be
king of the gods.

1185
01:30:55,492 --> 01:30:58,160
Stay back! Stay!

1186
01:30:58,495 --> 01:30:59,870
Stay!

1187
01:31:08,338 --> 01:31:10,214
All right, come on.

1188
01:31:11,216 --> 01:31:12,550
Go on, give it back.

1189
01:31:29,901 --> 01:31:31,193
Bad dog!

1190
01:31:34,739 --> 01:31:36,907
He won't
remember a thing!

1191
01:31:39,119 --> 01:31:40,911
Why did you do that?

1192
01:31:41,037 --> 01:31:45,249
Because he's cruel
and abusive!

1193
01:31:46,418 --> 01:31:47,835
The only thing
I look forward to

1194
01:31:47,919 --> 01:31:50,921
is my allotted time
away from this hellhole.

1195
01:31:51,047 --> 01:31:54,425
A war of the gods
would put an end to that.

1196
01:31:55,218 --> 01:31:58,554
And I'd be alone,
with only him,

1197
01:31:59,556 --> 01:32:00,806
forever.

1198
01:32:03,393 --> 01:32:06,562
Go. Take the bolt,
and your mother.

1199
01:32:17,782 --> 01:32:19,116
Only three?

1200
01:32:21,453 --> 01:32:22,661
Oh, no.

1201
01:32:23,121 --> 01:32:24,830
There are four of you.

1202
01:32:24,956 --> 01:32:27,917
Each pearl transports
only a single person.

1203
01:32:28,960 --> 01:32:31,253
One of you
will have to stay.

1204
01:32:31,838 --> 01:32:34,673
All right, I'll stay.
You three go.
What? No.

1205
01:32:34,799 --> 01:32:36,550
No, no, no.
I've achieved

1206
01:32:36,635 --> 01:32:38,260
my quest.
I'm staying here.
No. No!

1207
01:32:38,345 --> 01:32:40,179
I've trained for
situations like this.

1208
01:32:40,305 --> 01:32:42,348
Guys! Guys.
Knock it off.

1209
01:32:42,974 --> 01:32:44,725
I'm staying, because
I'm the protector.

1210
01:32:44,809 --> 01:32:46,268
Grover, come on.

1211
01:32:46,353 --> 01:32:48,896
Look, man,
I don't want to
hear it. Just go.

1212
01:32:48,980 --> 01:32:50,481
It's my duty.

1213
01:32:51,650 --> 01:32:53,150
It's what I'm meant for.

1214
01:32:53,860 --> 01:32:55,444
We'll come back
for you.

1215
01:32:56,488 --> 01:32:59,490
I'll take very
good care of him.

1216
01:33:01,159 --> 01:33:02,743
All right.
Now move it, guys!

1217
01:33:02,827 --> 01:33:05,788
Each of you, step on a pearl
and concentrate on
where you want to go.

1218
01:33:05,872 --> 01:33:07,289
Take this.

1219
01:33:08,500 --> 01:33:09,875
To Olympus.

1220
01:33:41,408 --> 01:33:42,533
Ooh!

1221
01:34:10,729 --> 01:34:12,604
Hey. Look.

1222
01:34:18,611 --> 01:34:21,196
Zeus and Poseidon
preparing for battle.

1223
01:34:21,448 --> 01:34:24,325
Oh, no, no.
This isn't the right place.

1224
01:34:24,409 --> 01:34:26,285
This isn't Olympus.
This is...

1225
01:34:26,369 --> 01:34:27,619
This is the
Empire State Building!

1226
01:34:27,746 --> 01:34:30,414
Percy! The entrance
to Olympus is there!

1227
01:34:30,540 --> 01:34:32,833
Well, there's 10 minutes
till midnight. Let's move.

1228
01:34:32,917 --> 01:34:34,710
Percy Jackson!

1229
01:34:41,926 --> 01:34:44,928
Well, you weren't supposed
to make it out alive.

1230
01:34:45,930 --> 01:34:48,932
I can't let you take
that bolt to Olympus.

1231
01:34:49,434 --> 01:34:51,477
I'm the lightning thief.

1232
01:34:52,103 --> 01:34:54,980
You hid the bolt
in my shield. Why?

1233
01:34:55,106 --> 01:34:59,193
Well, when you said
you were going to
the Underworld, it hit me.

1234
01:34:59,277 --> 01:35:02,821
"That is the perfect
opportunity to get
the bolt to Hades."

1235
01:35:02,947 --> 01:35:04,531
Why would you do that?

1236
01:35:04,616 --> 01:35:07,076
To bring Olympus
crumbling down.

1237
01:35:07,786 --> 01:35:09,661
Percy, let's go.

1238
01:35:10,288 --> 01:35:11,997
Let's go!

1239
01:35:12,123 --> 01:35:15,709
Well, it's too late,
'cause I'm returning
the bolt to Zeus right now.

1240
01:35:15,794 --> 01:35:17,628
Not before midnight.

1241
01:35:52,163 --> 01:35:53,789
You all right?
Yeah.

1242
01:35:55,834 --> 01:35:58,710
Luke! Why do you want
a war of the gods?

1243
01:36:00,130 --> 01:36:01,380
Control.

1244
01:36:02,340 --> 01:36:05,175
They've been in power
for too long.

1245
01:36:05,301 --> 01:36:08,387
I say it's time
for our generation
to take over.

1246
01:36:08,513 --> 01:36:11,014
Remold the world
in our image.

1247
01:36:11,141 --> 01:36:12,933
A world of new heroes.

1248
01:36:13,017 --> 01:36:14,435
You're no hero.

1249
01:36:23,069 --> 01:36:24,361
Huh!

1250
01:36:31,286 --> 01:36:33,036
- Mom, are you all right?
- Yeah.

1251
01:36:34,956 --> 01:36:36,123
Stay here.

1252
01:36:58,438 --> 01:36:59,563
Luke!

1253
01:38:41,207 --> 01:38:43,166
Maybe they were wrong.

1254
01:38:44,544 --> 01:38:47,004
Maybe you're
no son of Poseidon.

1255
01:40:11,923 --> 01:40:15,759
Yeah. I think I am
the son of Poseidon.

1256
01:40:38,658 --> 01:40:42,786
He's got the bolt!
Come on! Let's move!
We've got two minutes!

1257
01:41:24,829 --> 01:41:26,079
Olympus.

1258
01:41:32,670 --> 01:41:35,881
Percy,
I can't get through.
You've got to go!

1259
01:41:52,982 --> 01:41:54,274
Silence!

1260
01:42:08,206 --> 01:42:09,831
It is almost midnight.

1261
01:42:09,957 --> 01:42:11,541
This was predestined!

1262
01:42:11,626 --> 01:42:13,376
You wanted this battle!

1263
01:42:13,503 --> 01:42:15,253
You have only
yourself to blame!

1264
01:42:15,338 --> 01:42:19,966
Please! Let's be rational.
War is not the answer!

1265
01:42:23,471 --> 01:42:25,138
Time has run out.

1266
01:42:25,223 --> 01:42:26,389
Wait!

1267
01:42:26,974 --> 01:42:28,975
Wait! Wait!

1268
01:42:30,520 --> 01:42:31,561
Wow.

1269
01:42:38,277 --> 01:42:42,989
My name is Percy Jackson,
and I think you might be
looking for this.

1270
01:42:59,924 --> 01:43:02,467
Give me the bolt,
lightning thief.

1271
01:43:14,689 --> 01:43:16,940
You're wise to
betray your father.

1272
01:43:17,024 --> 01:43:21,736
I didn't steal it.
And I have no
connection to Poseidon.

1273
01:43:22,321 --> 01:43:27,033
But tell me,
if you didn't steal it,
then who did?

1274
01:43:27,118 --> 01:43:29,953
Luke, son of Hermes.

1275
01:43:34,000 --> 01:43:36,001
You see,
he was angry at you.

1276
01:43:36,085 --> 01:43:37,919
All of you.

1277
01:43:38,004 --> 01:43:40,881
He wanted you to
destroy yourselves.

1278
01:43:51,934 --> 01:43:53,727
You have done well.

1279
01:44:06,574 --> 01:44:08,366
Let there be peace.

1280
01:44:13,331 --> 01:44:14,456
Hi, Mom.

1281
01:44:15,166 --> 01:44:19,085
Annabeth,
I am so proud of you.

1282
01:44:22,214 --> 01:44:25,383
Zeus, I have
a good friend.

1283
01:44:25,927 --> 01:44:29,220
He's a Satyr
named Grover.

1284
01:44:29,722 --> 01:44:30,805
He's my protector,

1285
01:44:30,890 --> 01:44:33,266
and the only reason
why we escaped
the Underworld

1286
01:44:33,351 --> 01:44:35,894
is because
he stayed behind.

1287
01:44:37,438 --> 01:44:40,357
And now you expect me
to bring him back.

1288
01:44:43,444 --> 01:44:44,819
Very well.

1289
01:44:47,740 --> 01:44:51,409
I believe this assembly's
business here is finished.

1290
01:44:52,620 --> 01:44:56,665
Brother, please.
I need to speak
with him.

1291
01:45:00,544 --> 01:45:02,253
Just this once.

1292
01:45:14,266 --> 01:45:16,059
I'll meet you outside.

1293
01:45:26,570 --> 01:45:29,197
I'm not expecting you
to forgive me.

1294
01:45:30,366 --> 01:45:33,118
But I want you to know
that I'm grateful.

1295
01:45:33,202 --> 01:45:35,203
I didn't do it for you.

1296
01:45:35,955 --> 01:45:37,831
I did it to save Mom.

1297
01:45:45,089 --> 01:45:48,133
Please.
We don't have
much time.

1298
01:45:51,053 --> 01:45:54,347
How old was I
when you left?

1299
01:45:55,433 --> 01:45:56,683
Seven months.

1300
01:45:58,269 --> 01:46:01,730
Look, I didn't need you
there all the time, but...

1301
01:46:03,774 --> 01:46:06,443
I would have liked to
have seen you just once.

1302
01:46:09,864 --> 01:46:11,698
Why didn't you
ever come back?

1303
01:46:17,455 --> 01:46:18,913
I wanted to.

1304
01:46:21,375 --> 01:46:22,542
When I was with you
and your mother,

1305
01:46:22,626 --> 01:46:25,920
I became less concerned
with my responsibilities.

1306
01:46:26,630 --> 01:46:28,506
I was becoming human.

1307
01:46:30,676 --> 01:46:32,218
And that's a bad thing?

1308
01:46:32,303 --> 01:46:34,471
For a god?
Zeus thought so.

1309
01:46:35,222 --> 01:46:36,222
That's why
he passed the law

1310
01:46:36,307 --> 01:46:39,809
preventing gods from
ever having contact
with their children.

1311
01:46:41,604 --> 01:46:43,271
That was because of you?

1312
01:46:47,610 --> 01:46:49,736
But I was always
watching over you.

1313
01:46:51,739 --> 01:46:52,989
Just because
you didn't see me

1314
01:46:53,074 --> 01:46:55,533
doesn't mean that
I wasn't there.

1315
01:46:56,285 --> 01:46:59,162
When you were troubled,
I tried to help.

1316
01:47:00,831 --> 01:47:02,290
I heard you.

1317
01:47:03,209 --> 01:47:05,585
I know I'm not the father
you always wanted,

1318
01:47:06,629 --> 01:47:09,923
but if you ever need me,
I'll be there for you,

1319
01:47:10,007 --> 01:47:12,300
in your thoughts

1320
01:47:12,384 --> 01:47:14,177
and in your dreams.

1321
01:47:16,263 --> 01:47:18,181
I'll stand by you, Percy.

1322
01:47:19,391 --> 01:47:20,642
Always.

1323
01:47:46,919 --> 01:47:49,087
You can come
visit me anytime.

1324
01:47:49,171 --> 01:47:52,382
Just promise me
that I don't have to see
that loser Gabe ever again.

1325
01:47:52,466 --> 01:47:53,883
I kicked him out.

1326
01:47:54,009 --> 01:47:57,720
Yeah, he's gone.
He's out of
our lives forever.

1327
01:47:59,223 --> 01:48:00,223
Finally.

1328
01:48:06,063 --> 01:48:07,147
Oh!

1329
01:48:07,231 --> 01:48:08,690
I'm going to
miss you.

1330
01:48:08,774 --> 01:48:09,858
Me, too.

1331
01:48:17,867 --> 01:48:19,075
Percy?

1332
01:48:20,870 --> 01:48:22,704
This is where you belong.

1333
01:48:33,591 --> 01:48:35,508
Good job, man.
Thanks, Perce.

1334
01:48:36,385 --> 01:48:39,012
Ready! Aim!

1335
01:48:39,096 --> 01:48:41,014
Hey, whoa, Perce...
Watch it!
Hey!

1336
01:48:41,098 --> 01:48:42,599
You guys
gonna kill the man
who saved the world?

1337
01:48:42,683 --> 01:48:45,435
Great job. All you guys,
take a lunch break.
Thank you!

1338
01:48:45,561 --> 01:48:48,688
So,
the conquering hero
returns, triumphant.

1339
01:48:48,772 --> 01:48:50,607
Grover.
Hey!

1340
01:48:50,691 --> 01:48:52,275
You notice anything
different about me?

1341
01:48:52,359 --> 01:48:53,693
No.

1342
01:48:54,612 --> 01:48:58,114
You sure?
Anything that's
improved about me?

1343
01:48:59,033 --> 01:49:00,950
No. What,
you've been working out?

1344
01:49:01,035 --> 01:49:03,036
What, you get
a new cologne?
You smell good.

1345
01:49:03,120 --> 01:49:04,787
Look, man.
I got my horns!

1346
01:49:04,955 --> 01:49:06,623
Oh! I was seeing them
the whole time.

1347
01:49:06,749 --> 01:49:09,209
I mean, look at that thing.
You got little horns
in your head.

1348
01:49:09,293 --> 01:49:10,460
Right?
Crazy.

1349
01:49:10,544 --> 01:49:11,961
Zeus came through,

1350
01:49:12,046 --> 01:49:14,214
and now
I'm Senior Protector,
First Class, baby.

1351
01:49:14,298 --> 01:49:16,799
Congratulations.
Definitely earned them.

1352
01:49:16,926 --> 01:49:18,134
Thank you, man.

1353
01:49:20,137 --> 01:49:23,640
- Keep moving, keep moving!
- Don't lose interest!

1354
01:49:23,766 --> 01:49:25,225
One foot in front
of the other,

1355
01:49:25,309 --> 01:49:27,268
and the next thing
you know,
you're running!

1356
01:49:29,647 --> 01:49:30,897
Percy.

1357
01:49:34,151 --> 01:49:37,320
You left the camp.
You disobeyed
my orders.

1358
01:49:38,656 --> 01:49:40,657
Yeah, about that.

1359
01:49:40,783 --> 01:49:42,242
Which is why

1360
01:49:43,619 --> 01:49:45,245
you're my
favorite student.

1361
01:49:46,622 --> 01:49:50,083
You can receive all
the training in the world,
but ultimately,

1362
01:49:50,167 --> 01:49:52,418
you have to follow
your instincts.

1363
01:49:52,753 --> 01:49:54,337
Grace under pressure.

1364
01:49:58,092 --> 01:50:01,135
All right.
Time to train.
Go suit up.

1365
01:50:01,679 --> 01:50:03,179
You might be
a big shot on Olympus,

1366
01:50:03,305 --> 01:50:06,432
but down here,
you're still just
one of my students.

1367
01:50:06,517 --> 01:50:07,809
Move it.

1368
01:50:10,479 --> 01:50:12,355
Nice horns, Grover.

1369
01:50:12,439 --> 01:50:15,775
I'm serious, man.
We talked,
we wooed, we dined,

1370
01:50:15,859 --> 01:50:16,818
we had a great time!

1371
01:50:16,902 --> 01:50:17,902
Well, I'm happy
for you, you know?

1372
01:50:17,987 --> 01:50:20,530
Persephone might
really like me.
I'm serious.

1373
01:50:26,370 --> 01:50:28,621
I think you can handle
this one on your own.

1374
01:50:28,706 --> 01:50:30,206
Uh-huh.

1375
01:50:30,332 --> 01:50:31,874
All right, Perce.

1376
01:50:34,878 --> 01:50:36,296
Hey, Perce,
awesome job, man.
Hey, thanks.

1377
01:50:36,380 --> 01:50:37,547
Good job.
Thanks.

1378
01:50:41,051 --> 01:50:42,385
Good job.

1379
01:50:51,520 --> 01:50:52,812
Who's next?

1380
01:50:59,028 --> 01:51:01,154
I think I'd like
to give it a shot.

1381
01:51:13,042 --> 01:51:14,542
Welcome home.

1382
01:51:20,841 --> 01:51:22,508
Whoa! Whoa! Wait!

1383
01:51:23,761 --> 01:51:26,095
First rule of
battle strategy.

1384
01:51:26,597 --> 01:51:29,223
Don't ever let your
opponent distract you.

1385
01:53:10,242 --> 01:53:12,160
Sally, open the door!

1386
01:53:13,162 --> 01:53:14,412
Open up!

1387
01:53:18,333 --> 01:53:19,333
You changed the locks?

1388
01:53:19,418 --> 01:53:20,501
Yes.

1389
01:53:21,211 --> 01:53:23,212
So, here's your junk.

1390
01:53:23,338 --> 01:53:24,297
You can
let yourself out.

1391
01:53:24,381 --> 01:53:25,423
Well...

1392
01:53:26,341 --> 01:53:29,260
How am I supposed to
move all this stuff
by myself?

1393
01:53:29,928 --> 01:53:31,429
Deal with it.

1394
01:53:36,268 --> 01:53:37,852
I need a beer.

1395
01:53:41,773 --> 01:53:44,066
What? "Do not open..."

1396
01:53:48,447 --> 01:53:50,198
That little brat.

1397
01:53:51,408 --> 01:53:53,576
Well, I may not
live here any more,

1398
01:53:54,536 --> 01:53:56,746
but I'm still the king
of this castle.