Mexico was awesome,
thanks for asking.
You're late.
Yeah, speaking of late,
you're a couple payments behind.
I got to send my
brother more money.
Hurry up.
Seriously, he needs the dough.
Why? Huh?
Best thing about jail is
everything's taken care of--
Three squares, man.
Mexican jail.
They have to buy their
own toilet paper.
Come on, man, he's there
because of you and your--
- Jesus.
- Oh!
Come on, already.
Ah!
Ah! Ahh.
Send him my best the
next time you write.
Hey, I'm just the middleman.
You got a problem with the product,
you talk to Manny.
I already did.
Manny said it was good
when it left his hands.
I got to be honest,
I trust him a hell of a
lot more than I trust you.
hey, man.
I swear, I had no idea--
'Father figure' is a phrase
as potent as 'Mother Nature'.
Say it outloud and the images fly
From having a catch on the side of the yard
to the screen door slamming
exit of the dead-beat Dad.
For every 'Father Knows Best' in Atticus Finch
there's a Great Santini bouncing a ball off the head
of his teenaged son
One thing's for sure --
The 'Father Figure' -- in
your face or out the door --
will make his presence felt
like it or not.
Look, all I care
about is my brother.
I-I can send him money, right?
A percentage of the
stipend is yours to spend
However you want.
You'll have to send
it through our office,
So it isn't traceable to you.
And your brother Sam
gets out of prison
In only seven years.
That didn't serve as a
cautionary tale to you?
Kirk always looked after us.
What else was I gonna do?
That is one of the great
questions of our age, isn't it?
What to do when faced
with circumstances
Beyond our control,
which are most circumstances.
Look, Billy,
This is a chance for you.
From this moment on,
your life can be anything you want.
why?
'cause I'm living in Albuquerque
with a different name?
Because you're alive.
You're safe.
You're going to school.
Yeah, some up-nose,
d-bag private school
Where nobody will talk to me.
One of the best boarding schools
In the southwest,
Where 99% of the students
go on to college.
What do you care?
Seriously?
I'm here. I'm gonna testify.
You did your job.
No, trust me,
My job with you
has barely begun.
So who's gonna pay for all this?
I convinced d.O.J.
That since you're taking down
A major drug cartel,
the least they could do
Is foot the bill for
a decent education.
And what if I don't like it?
Can I leave? - Sure.
Wait.
Seriously? - Absolutely.
In which case,
you'll end up back on street
Needing money with no
discernable skill set,
As you gravitate to the
easy money of crime--
Recidivism defined.
Or you could try something new.
Scary maybe,
but a different life
You can make for yourself.
I don't know.
Billy, I'm not just
dumping you here.
Anytime, day or night,
you can call me.
We can talk.
I can come down here,
and we can figure things out.
So this is really what
you do for a living?
It is.
It's weird.
It's many things,
weird among them.
You think where I go to
school actually matters?
Let me give you one
last piece of advice
That I heard growing up a lot.
Everything matters.
Everything you think,
feel, but most of all,
Everything you do...
It all counts.
Ahh.
Okay.
Well, welcome back.
I got a busy day
and a crazy week,
So I will see you
when I see you.
You know, uh, the stony silence
The entire way home
from the airport
Is a subtle sign that
you're pissed at me.
And look, it's okay. I get it.
I get that whatever I say
about whatever I've been doing
And where I've been is
just gonna sound like,
"blah, blah, blah, blah,
more lies," whatever.
But I feel like I've
turned a corner,
A real corner in my life,
And I'm gonna prove
that to you...
Soon, okay?
Okay, well, that's suitably
vague and unsettling,
And on that note,
which basically defines your life,
I'm off to work.
- Look these over.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Excuse me.
- Good.
- Yeah.
- So that's him?
- That's him.
Is it true he guarded hinkley?
Rumor has it.
Sat and read magazines with
Jodi foster on the cover
Just to bait him?
- That's the story.
- Wow.
So, Charlie, have you ever
been on an operation falcon?
No, sir--Stan.
No, I haven't.
I've heard about it.
Yeah, but you got the
basic drill, right?
Us, other feds, state, local
Chasing down every
open warrant, right?
Anything else?
Well, it always stirs
things up a little.
Some inspectors here love it.
Some, well...
I find your almost girlish
delight disturbing
On many levels.
Come on, it's five days
without your standard,
Whiny, mopey witnessrap.
It's back to basics-- hunt,
bust, cuff, haul.
Then there's the
icing on the cake...
him.
You've now crossed
over to sadistic glee.
- You nervous?
- No.
Well, you should be.
I'm about to find out
so many embarrassing,
Hilarious you-secrets,
I'm gonna have to
alphabetize them.
I honestly fear for the
state of your soul.
Marshall.
Dad.
Heaven.
Since 1970, the federal
Witness Protection program
Has relocated thousands
of witnesses,
Some criminal, some not,
to neighborhoods
All across the country.
Every one of those individuals
shares a unique attribute,
Distinguishing
them from the rest
Of the general population.
And that is somebody
wants them dead.
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
- So.
So.
Oh.
Here we are.
Yeah, we're here.
You must be Mary. How do you do?
Seth Mann. - Wow.
What a pleasure to meet you.
Really looking forward
to working with you,
Talking to you...
About everything.
- Good.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Stan, just want to say thanks
For giving me a desk out
there and letting me squat.
They're short of real estate
at the falcon command center.
My pleasure, Seth.
So you want to get us started?
Kid, did you put these together?
- Uh, yes, sir.
- All right.
Mug shots ought to be
clipped on the inside
And the outside.
Oh, okay. I mean, that matters?
- Here it comes.
- What?
What's your name?
Charlie.
Well, Charlie,
if you were one of my boys,
You'd know two words by heart--
"everything matters."
Okay, great, so guess Mary
and I should get out there.
Well, actually,
I'd like to work with you,
If you don't mind.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
I thought-- I don't know.
I thought maybe it'd
be good for both of us.
Yeah. Well, it's Stan's call
Whether he wants to
split up Mary and me.
I don't know.
How about the three of us?
Double our caseloads.
We could clear this
operation in no time, right?
That's a great idea.
Well, be safe.
Bring back some bad guys.
Thanks, Stan. Thanks, Mary.
Oh, you bet.
Okay, what do we got?
So you seeing anyone?
There are a few prospects.
Mary doesn't know about them,
Because I try not to
subject people I care about
To what I
euphemistically refer to
As her "winning abrasiveness."
Look, Seth,
Marshall's social life
Is a contradiction in terms,
Unless you count putting
a bookstore clerk
In a headlock and telling her
About nietzschean themes
in Wagnerian opera.
- She was interested.
- Shh.
There's so much I want to know.
Who was Marshall's
first celebrity crush?
How old was he when he went to his
first star trek convention?
And when did he start
using a curling iron?
Fortunately, you're dealing
with a man of few words.
Uh-huh. Well, give my best
to your wishful thinking.
Okay, here we go.
Hands in the air,
boys! - Don't move!
Don't move! Don't move!
Turn around slowly.
God, that felt good.
What is that?
Triumphing over others makes
you feel better about yourself.
And now you have
a brother-in-arms
Who likes the sound of
shackles clamping on flesh
Even more than you, if possible.
Okay, seriously,
what is it with you two?
I mean, other than feeling
completely exposed
In my presence,
which I'm really enjoying--
I mean, you guys
are close, right?
You see each other
every Christmas,
Talk every Sunday?
Christmas, we discuss the
best way to brine poultry.
Sunday, it's mom's
latest yarn-based hobby.
We assiduously avoid
any topic of substance,
And I get the feeling--
Nah. - What?
He's here to study me.
Study you?
He's retiring this year.
This is his last
operation falcon,
Maybe his last major manhunt.
So?
Making it his last opportunity
To assess my worth
for final judgment.
Final judgment?
You got to lighten up.
You make him sound
like Darth Vader.
Look, don't you think you're
being just a little paranoid?
When I was a kid,
He carried two things
in his briefcase--
My best report
card and my worst.
He would remove
them at key moments
To illustrate whatever
point was on his mind.
Trust me,
judgment day is coming.
Hey.
Who's here?
His name is Scott.
You drinking again?
Wasn't aware a.A.
Gave time off for nerd behavior.
While it's true,
At times this house
severely strains my resolve,
This is for you.
Something tells me
you're gonna need it.
Mary, awesome-- you're home.
This is Scott Griffin.
Hi.
It's so nice to
finally meet you.
Our brother.
Wow.
You look so much like Lauren.
Even her shoulders-- it's weird.
I know, right? I told you.
Okay, I'm sorry.
What the hell's going on here?
Well, Scott and I got in touch
a few months back and...
And?
The $20,000?
I loaned it to Scott.
Okay, I've had a long day,
and I'm tired,
And I'm trying to catch
up here and actually care.
But honestly, Brandi,
for somebody who's such a good liar,
You are unbelievably gullible.
I mean, is there anything ever
you don't take at face value?
So what about lending
this guy $20,000
Puts you in Florida
for six weeks?
And what about
borrowing 20 grand
Puts you in my living room?
- Because Scott needed money-
- help with his business.
I hit a bad patch,
And I was gonna lose
basically everything.
- Oh.
- I work in Miami.
Anyway, Brandi flew out.
She loaned me the money.
She got interested
in the business.
Oh, my God. What business?
- Day trading.
- Perfect.
I just sort of helped
out in the office--
Drove some clients around,
but it was really fun.
That sounds really fun.
Come here.
Jesus.
Honestly...
Are you retarded? -
- You lend a total stranger--
- our brother!
- So he says!
- Oh, my God!
$20,000 and then go off the
grid for a month and a half,
Dodge my calls,
leave mom hanging, and Peter.
I mean, my God. Why?
Because I knew that this is
exactly how you would react.
You'd treat me like
some kind of idiot,
Like some failure-in-waiting,
stupid little squish.
That's not true.
Don't put words in--
I'm a good person, Mary!
I'm smart, and you know what?
I didn't just pay Peter back.
I made $10,000--
Me, working for Scott,
my own money, me.
Good. Congrats.
That sounds real legit.
and you wonder why I avoid you.
'cause you know what?
You don't trust anybody.
You don't even like anyone.
Okay, so I get it.
So your being a liar,
that's on me now?
- Because you're so honest?
- Yeah.
All those letters from dad
that you didn't tell us about?
That is completely different--
No! No, it's not!
You wanted dad all to yourself.
And you know what?
Our brother, I wanted him to
be my brother for a second,
Just once, to have
something in this family
That was mine before you and mom
Can tell me how
to feel about it.
You know what?
I'm happy for you.
Kudos on the fantastic
relationship
You've got blossoming here.
You want something just for you?
Take the Scott
side of the family.
They're all yours.
Send me a God damn
Christmas card.
So then?
I went to bed,
got up before Brandi,
And came to work.
And Scott?
- Don't know, don't care.
- Really?
Look, if we do
have the same dad,
He's at least half-crazy,
fully troubled,
And I've got plenty of both,
inside and out.
I don't want to think about it.
Liam Sykes...
Wanted for multiple
home invasions
Across three States.
Rolls into town,
pulls together a local crew,
Does enough jobs to
lay low for a while,
Then resurfaces in a new
town when the money runs out.
Last week he assaulted a
cop who pulled him over.
Abq p.D. Has a tip from a
confidential informant.
Let's get him.
That's Liam.
And he came here for?
Consignment sales.
Really?
Do we have to do
this old chestnut,
Where you pretend
you have no idea
What we're talking about,
and we pretend
We're not gonna haul your ass
in if you don't cooperate?
You know what? That sounds good.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say--
Guys, dial it down.
As you can see,
June, my partners
Are a bit adrenalized--
Too much red bull and sanka.
Thing is, I can yank
on their leashes
For only so long,
and then I've got to let go.
So...
Liam?
Couldn't tell you where he is.
It would be breaking
a confidence.
Okay.
Amy, tell these nice
people where Liam is.
Um...
7400 don Diego street.
We should call sog
and wait for backup.
I'm not gonna risk losing him.
Tactical protocol dictates--
That the team leader make
the call on approach.
- That's an interpretation.
- Which is the point of command.
To quote from the manual--
Okay, when you have to
quote from the manual,
It means debate done-
winner, dad.
So, what?
You don't want to
work for me anymore?
Billy says I should--
"Billy says"?
What do you say?
I want out, okay? I just--
No.
Sorry. Not happening.
Come on, Liam.
You can't just keep
me here forever.
Don't move!
Turn around!
Hands on your head!
I got Liam!
- Put your hands on your head!
- Don't move!
Don't move!
- Marshall!
- Stop!
Don't move, asshole.
Hey!
Billy?
Billy!
Dad, don't! - What
do you mean, "don't"?
He was--
He's gone!
What's wrong with you?
He's all yours.
So...
You guys lost Liam
And the girl? Wow.
You guys team up full-time,
this'll be fugitive Disneyland.
Billy Nevins was here.
Billy? "boarding school" Billy?
In a car.
My dad was gonna fire.
I stopped him.
I'm sure he was
aiming for the tires.
I'm sure if I'd let him,
we'd have Billy now,
Which I'm equally
sure I'll be hearing
A lot about in a second.
The kid in the car--
How Long's he been in
Witness Protection?
Son, you and I talk
around a lot of things.
That doesn't make me dumb.
You're a WITSEC inspector.
He was yours.
Now he's mine. - Ours.
And we don't know
what he's done--
And we don't care...
Long as we get him.
How old were you when
you first wondered
If you were adopted?
Four.
Did the saliva strip
test at eight.
Sadly...
Anything you want to
tell me about this kid?
There's a lot I can't
till we really know
What's going on.
What I can say is
he was adjusting--
Making friends, good grades.
He was a model witness.
Whatever that means.
Here we go.
Amber.
No last name.
Great.
I'll forward this to the office,
Have them try to find an I.
P. Address.
Oh!
Smart.
He left his cell phone,
'cause he knows you'd
use it to track him.
Looks like you
trained him well...
For whatever it is he's up to.
Three more fun-filled
days of operation falcon.
Yep.
Tomorrow I'll bring popcorn.
Hello?
Slow down. Slow down.
It's Billy.
Jesus. Tell him to come in.
Give me a second.
Where the hell are you?
Did you arrest Amber?
Tell me where you are.
Is she okay?
I'll tell you when I see you.
Great.
Oh, yeah, this is gonna go well.
I started all this.
I got to do this myself.
Started what?
Do what? - I think
she's in trouble.
I think it's my fault.
I was just trying to help.
Help Amber?
- That your witness?
- I got this.
- Give me the phone.
- No.
Look, look,
Marshall can talk him in.
The phone, now.
- Man, who is that?
- Nobody.
You tell your boy he can come in
Or get dragged in,
dead or alive.
Hello?
Dad, that was the
antithesis of helpful.
We'd have him if you
hadn't stopped me.
We'd have all of them if
you followed protocol.
And we can all see
where this is going,
So why don't we hit pause,
pick it up on father's day,
And go find the kid?
Come on.
Liam...
So good to see you.
Yeah.
You hear anything about
Amber and that Billy kid?
They ran off this morning,
Along with my entire take
for the last four months.
Ah, young love--
Nothing makes you
quite as stupid.
If I hear anything,
I'll give you a call.
Who else you gonna call?
The cops all of a
sudden know where I live
Right after I start
doing business with you.
Coincidence?
Did am say anything
That might illuminate
his motive?
He knew she was
talking to the cops,
But that's not why he was here.
He was asking about
Amber and Billy.
So you've met Billy?
He's been here?
I just heard Amber
talk about him.
He's her boyfriend, I guess.
She's-- she was--
She works for Liam?
Doing what?
Uh, she helps him set up scores.
I don't know how exactly.
Something to do
with where s works.
Do you know Amber's last name?
No.
Just to be clear,
Liam said they stole a
bunch of money from him?
Both of them? - Both of them.
That's--that's what he said.
Uh-huh.
Okay, so the girl
is Amber Whitman.
She's a student at four hills.
Hasn't been home or to
her job at the u-move
In two days.
Let me guess-- Ms.
Whitman's got a record?
Possession, shoplifting.
Thanks, Stan. Uh, hey,listen.
Feel free not to
mention this to my dad.
Oh, yeah.
No problem.
Thanks.
So we talk to classmates,
coworkers,
Try to get a line
on where she is,
Hope she can lead us to Billy.
Listen, I like your dad.
Call it a soft spot for guys who
don't bail on their families,
Rob banks,
and start new families,
But I will admit, to find Amber,
he's got the wrong style.
If by "style,
" you mean all the subtlety
Of an armor-piercing Shell,
then, yes, agreed.
You got to look for
her without him.
If we peel off, then he'll
know we're ditching him,
Which means he'll be hunting us.
And trust me, even as a kid,
Hide-and-seek with that man
gave me stomach cramps.
Hey, p.D.'s tagged a
van belonging to Liam.
I could stake it
out with your dad,
Tell him you had a
WITSEC emergency.
Good enough?
I wish I'd had you
in High School.
High School me would have
eaten High School you alive.
So why'd you name
him "Marshall"?
It was his mom's idea.
She took one look at
him in the hospital...
Those eyes and that face.
She knew right away
he was gonna grow up
To be maybe a writer,
a philosopher...
Anything but a marshal.
So she named him "Marshall"
In order to try
to seal the deal.
Yeah, 'cause who'd
ever want a job
Where they're marshal Marshall?
Little did you know
he'd consider it a perk.
Well, that's him.
Came into this world
with a mind of his own.
Marshall has this crazy idea
You're here to assess him,
judge,
Or even grade him
on what he does.
He's right.
Oh.
Huh.
That's very... Parental?
Well, look, I don't
claim to get WITSEC.
I mean, I spent a few months
working it back in '89.
I never saw anybody
get transformed
Or get in touch with
their true selves
Or any of that crap.
And I always worry that this
just isn't right for Marshall,
That what we do...
He just isn't built for it.
He's a sensitive kid.
He always was.
Which is why he's really
good at what he does.
It's just not the same as-
here we go.
Support team, we're
approaching the vehicle.
Stop right there!
You, down on your knees!
Down on the ground!
On your knees!
Clear!
- Where'd you get the van?
- I bought it last week.
What's wrong?
This the guy you bought it from?
Aren't you a little old
for the kids' park?
Hey. I knew you'd come.
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
- Are you stupid? The-
-the police are chasing us.
Liam is after us.
Nothing is fine.
Hey, look, whatever you did,
I know a guy.
He can help.
He's kind of a cop.
This is not just about the cops.
Well, I know Liam's mad that
you're gonna maybe quit,
But this guy can help.
During the raid, I just--
I kind of grabbed the money.
Wait. Liam's money?
He just-- he got so
mad right before,
And he just started
saying things about you,
And I thought if
we had the money,
We could just get out of here,
you know, go someplace.
Oh, amb.
- I know.
- Amb.
I know it was stupid. I just--
Look, it's done,
okay? Can we just--
Can we just go,
okay? I have the car.
Let's just get the money and
get out of here, please.
All right, where is it?
The money, Amber, where is it?
She was here yesterday.
Said she needed to
hide for a while.
I've never seen anyone
so scared in my life.
Did she give any indication
to where she was going?
No.
But I did let her borrow my car.
Charlie, hunter
green Toyota Camry--
I just emailed you
the license and Vin.
The car has safety connect,
so call abq p.D.
To get the real-time
tracking on its location.
What are we looking for,
a green Toyota Camry?
Yeah.
Where's my dad now?
He's getting the report
on the van Liam sold.
He thinks I clocked out,
and you're still with a witness.
I owe you forever.
Good.
He is here to judge you,
by the way.
And to his credit, he was
completely up front about it,
But he is a full-body, soul,
and brain scan with a gun.
Well put.
That's the one.
Amber?
Don't be afraid.
I'm a friend of Billy's.
I need to talk to you.
Can you come out for a second?
I just want to talk.
Hey, you guys were at the house.
Do you know where Billy is?
Amber Whitman,
you're under arrest.
Seth, Seth, we got it.
Put your hands behind your back.
Seth!
Son, did you really think
you could put out a search
For a car, and I
wouldn't know about it?
I just need to ask
her a few questions.
Me too. Playtime's over.
I'm taking her downtown.
Come on.
I know Billy was
there at Liam's.
I know about the money you took.
Where is Billy...
And where is that money?
He could at least try
to relate to her.
Trust me, that's him trying.
Okay, let's talk about the fence,
June rorchek.
She's dead.
Your buddy Liam
looks good for it.
You know where he is?
Young lady, this is now
a murder investigation,
And you are an accomplice.
Just how much jail
time do you want to do?
Because every minute of silence
Piles on the time!
I want you to think about that.
she'll talk.
No, dad, she won't.
Yeah, a few hours more,
and she'll break.
"break"? She's not a terrorist.
She's a teenager.
She's not scared of you.
She hates you, because
you're not talking to her.
You're threatening her.
So unless you're willing
to pull out pliers
And a blowtorch,
she's not telling you anything.
Oh, so get her a frappuccino
And a copy of one of those
twilight books.
You two can brush
each other's hair.
Sir...
With all due respect,
you're just wrong.
Let Marshall do this.
Amber, Billy is out there
Because of you.
He told me that.
He wants to...
Fix something with you and Liam.
Trust me...
If he does that,
it will get him killed.
All I want to do
Is find Billy and get him safe.
But to do that,
I need to know more
about Liam and you.
Liam, uh, came into
u-move one day.
He said he could
tell I was smart,
Said I could make some money
And get out of my dad's house.
So what'd you do for Liam?
He just wanted me to,
uh, tell him
Which moving vans had the
highest insurance rates,
Which people had the best stuff,
You know, just who
was new to town--
That sort of thing.
Then what?
Then I met Billy.
Billy's...
Not like anyone else.
He told me I had to quit.
And he kept on me about it,
But he was gentle,
Not, like, all judgmental and--
Just telling me that it
was gonna be bad for me.
And I fought him on it.
I said, "who cares, you know,
if I work for Liam?
And none of it matters.
It's all pointless anyway."
Then Billy goes...
"everything matters."
You know, like,
everything adds up.
Little, big-- it all counts.
He really believes that.
Made me believe it.
So I...
I called Billy,
told him I was out.
And he came to pick me up.
And that's when you
guys showed up.
Do you know where Billy is now?
I gave him the keys
to the u-move office
To get the money
out of my locker.
Not bad. So now what?
We know Billy's
headed for the money.
Let's make sure Liam's not.
Yeah?
Hi, Liam. It's Amber.
Look, uh, I'm sorry
I took the money.
It was stupid.
I guess I ju- I just got scared.
All right, take it easy.
Tell me where it is.
Well, I've still got it.
I can meet you at the
bowling alley on central
In 15 minutes.
Okay.
15 minutes.
I'll take the sog team
to the bowling alley.
You cover the moving place.
Wait for the boy.
Yeah?
Liam, it's Billy.
I get the money.
Really?
Okay, so where are you?
U-move.
Amber with you?
No.
And I'll only give you the money
If you swear you'll
leave us alone.
Take your money.
Stay out of our lives.
Cross my heart and everything.
See you soon.
You check the office.
I'll go out back.
Look, you got your money.
She's done, okay?
I'm not telling
you where she is.
Oh, I think you're
gonna tell me, Billy.
Drop your weapon now!
Aah!
I need an ambulance.
Liam went that way!
I'm on second and Woodward.
You're gonna be all right.
Who's got the trace
on Liam's cell?
Still near central,
still not moving.
Stay here.
Face down.
One way or the other.
How you feeling?
Uh, not too bad.
They say it'll leave
a pretty gnarly scar.
What the hell were you thinking?
She needed help.
Well, next time you decide
to help a criminal, don't.
This is far from okay
And far from over.
But in the meantime,
You have a visitor.
Hey.
Oh, my God. - Are you okay?
Yeah.
Oh.
- Yeah, you okay?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
No, it's okay.
hey.
Hey.
With all the hullabaloo,
I forgot to acknowledge the fact
That you probably
saved my dad's life.
Come on...
We both know he could have
caught that bullet in his teeth.
How does a guy like
that have a son
Who says "hullabaloo," anyway?
I feel like as much as
my father annoys, judges,
And generally fails to get me...
He's here.
So...
Go.
Hey, dad.
Hey.
What you doing?
Ah, just going over a few
things in my briefcase--
Lucky tokens I
carry on the road.
Is this the failure
report card or the...?
When did you start
carrying this around?
The day you gave it to me.
That and a few snapshots
of you and your mom,
Your brothers.
But that...
Is the only piece of art I own.
I, um...
Worried about you growing up.
It's a rough world.
You're not a rough guy.
But I think maybe
that's a good thing...
A real good thing.
- Thanks for coming over.
- No sweat.
Hi. - Hi.
So I looked you up.
You're a licensed broker...
That I am.
With a record.
Three arrests,
one suspended sentence--
Illegal gambling, bookmaking.
Did you know that?
We've pretty much told each
other everything, so...
If it makes any difference...
It's my two-year chip--
Gambler's anonymous.
Shannon blood.
Or griffin-- same thing.
Anyway, now I just
bet on the market.
Do you know where our father is?
No.
He just walked out one day.
I'll say this,
the man's consistent.
So you haven't been in touch?
Are you kidding me? Like,
I wouldn't--
I'm asking him.
Our father's a wanted fugitive.
If you're in touch with him,
either of you,
And I find out--
Mary, that's not
what this is about.
Then what is it,
okay? 'cause money can be wired.
So again, I got to ask...
Why are you in my living room?
I feel like he's just...
He's my Er, you know,
and all of a sudden...
He's not the man
I thought he was.
Brandi told me he
wrote you letters.
Those are private.
Well, then anything,
his life before--
Can you tell me
anything about him?
'cause I'm happy to tell
you anything you want.
Please.
For most kids, the scariest
thing you can hear
is "wait till your
father gets home."
For some there's no fear
of that or hope for it.
I'm still waiting.
Not like a puppy
head tilting at footfalls on the porch
or a key in the lock
I go about my days
every so often aware of his absence.
and telling myself that the heart,
old adage aside, does not grow fonder
except, it does.
It really, really does.
Re-Sync and Edited
by Word Faery
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com