Subs created by: David Coleman.
One week till our sweet 16.
After four years of being apart, we
are finally together on our birthday.
Yaysies!
I know! We get to blow out
our candles together again.
The three Rooney girls,
together again and ready to...
♪Party! Woo woo woo,
party! I said now party!
Don't turn around. You don't want
to know what Mom's doing behind you.
I don't need to. I can feel the
desperation on the back of my neck.
All right, fine. Guess I'll just
save my moves for the par-tay!
Back that party up over here, Care Bear.
Here we go.
♪Left left left, to
the right right right...
Anyway.
So for our party, I had a few thoughts.
I had...
A thought.
Ahem, okay, so I'm thinking
red carpet, designer gowns,
we enter cirque-du-soleil
style, spiraling in on silks.
I'm thinking peanut shells on the
floor, steaks the size of our heads,
we enter hungry-man style
in our casual eating pants.
Ahem. Maddie, this is our
big 1-6. It needs to be epic.
I know! And I'm thinking epic.
There's this new Cowboy-jail-themed
restaurant, The Hoosegow...
Wow! Ha ha.
We have very different ideas of epic.
You know what's epic?
Mini-golf birthday parties!
They worked for years for you two.
- Ages six to 11, done!
- Yes yes, Dad's right.
Maddie, you loved it
because it was sporty.
And, Liv, there was a Castle, so
you could dress up like a Princess.
And I loved it because you two were
together celebrating your birthday.
So, Rooney girls, let's get ready to...
♪Par-tay! Woo woo woo,
party! I said now party!
Mom! Mom, Mom.
Stop.
Hater.
As fun as mini-golf was,
we are turning 16 now, so...
We can plan our own party.
So let's just talk this out
because nothing's been set in stone.
Liv, I picked up the silks
for your epic party entrance.
Epically bad decision to
bring them home on my bike.
The silks have already been ordered?
You've already planned our
entire party, haven't you?
Well, it's not like I
could leave it up to you!
I mean, casual eating pants?!
Spiraling in on silks?!
You're being impossible!
Ugh, I wish we could just
have separate birthdays!
- Ugh!
A little help?
♪Better in stereo.
♪B... b... better in stereo.
- ♪ I'm up with the sunshine.
- Let's go.
- ♪I lace up my high tops.
- Oh no.
- ♪ Slam dunk.
- Ready or not.
♪Yeah, show me what you got.
- ♪ I'm under the spotlight.
- Holler.
♪I dare you, come on and follow.
♪You dance to your own
beat. I'll sing the melody.
♪When you say yea-ah-ah.
♪I say no-oh-oh.
♪When you say stop.
♪All I want to do is go, go, go.
♪You, you, the other half of me, me.
♪The half I'll never be.
♪The half that drives me crazy.
♪You, you, the better half of me, me.
♪The half I'll always need.
♪But we both know.
♪We're better in stereo...
My twins can't have separate
parties on their sweet 16th.
So while you two were at
Maddie's basketball game...
I came up with a "mompromise".
So take a look.
Dazzleberry!
Awesome!
Hold on, you haven't seen
the best part. Turn around.
Two themes, one party.
It's a red carpet rodeo!
Hey, why isn't this thing working?
So, Maddie honey, you
wanted to go to The Hoosegow.
So we're gonna have a Western
barbecue right here in the house.
- Joey.
- Mom, I don't want to say it.
Oh, come on, say it.
Yee-haw.
And, Liv, you wanted a
cirque-du-soleil, red carpet gala.
I bring you Parker-azzi!
Liv Rooney, Liv Rooney!
Who are you wearing?
Boom boom boom!
Send.
Mom, this is great! And I
think we're halfway there.
The half that doesn't
look like a barn. So...
I think we should clear out these hay bales
and, uh, ooh, all the barbecuey stuff.
And I just really want to, you
know, class this place up, you know?
I think we're gonna bring in
some French Contortionists...
Liv, why are you throwing
out everything that I like?
I thought this was our party.
Honey, it's time to come clean.
We've kept the secret for too long.
No, Pete! I'm not telling them...
They were born on separate days.
♪Camptown ladies sing
that song, doo-dah doo-dah.
This karaoke thing works great.
Who's next?
- What did you just say?
- We have different birthdays?
Girls, your Mother and I
have something to tell you.
Go ahead.
Liv and Maddie, the day you were born
was truly the greatest day of my life.
Well, that feels nice.
But it was actually the
"days" you were born.
You see, Liv, you were born
on the fifth at 11:56 P.M.
But, Maddie honey, you were born...
At 12:02 on the...
Sixth.
But the whole reason that five is my lucky
number is because I was born on the fifth.
I'm a five.
Apparently I'm a zero.
Wait, so Maddie's never
celebrated on her actual birthday?
What kind of parents are you?
This is preposterous. I
say again preposterous.
If they can do this to her, what
does that mean for everybody else?
Am I six? Am I 11?
I could be nine!
- Hey.
Maddie honey, I am so sorry.
Every year your birthday would roll
around and I would just get so excited
at the two of you sitting
together blowing out your candles.
Then why did you use those trick
candles that didn't blow out?
We wanted the moment to last forever.
Plus a joint birthday
party is double the fun.
It's also half the work.
See, I'm trying to be completely
honest with you from now on.
Don't try and be funny. I'm
still trying to be mad at you.
Oh, honey, I'm so sorry. I thought
I was doing the right thing.
You know, when you and Liv were
little, you were inseparable.
As your Mother, it just felt wrong
to take that special day away.
Are you seriously trying to take credit
for being a good Mother right now?
Yes, I tried to slip that in.
Now just tell me what you
want to do for your birthday
and your Father and I will make
it happen... sky's the limit.
Okay, there is a budget. See,
I'm trying to be totally honest.
Thanks, Mom, but...
Honestly the last thing I feel like doing
right now is celebrating my birthday.
I don't even think I want to
have a party at all this year.
And I'm sure Liv feels
the exact same way.
Well, think about it.
In the meantime I made your
favorite dinner; Chicken pot pie.
Okay, I didn't make it.
It was frozen from a box.
Woo, the truth really will set you free!
Okay, everyone find a seat.
Maddie's off on a jog,
but I bought us some time.
She always jogs till the end of
her play list so I added six songs.
Hey, Joey!
I got a spot for you right here.
I am going to say yes
because I am scared to say no.
Okay, you are all here because you
are Maddie's best friends and family
and I want you to help me to
throw a surprise party for her.
You have to keep it a secret.
I know that won't be
a problem for you two.
Mom said Maddie doesn't
even want a party this year.
Also I cannot feel my ribs.
I can!
Maddie says she doesn't want a
party, but I know my sister better.
This birthday shocker has knocked her
for a loop and we are going to fix it.
- That's very sweet.
- We'll do anything to help.
Of course you will. You're
totally on the hook for this.
Well, I'm in. I want Maddie's sweet
16 to be as amazing as it can be.
- Careful.
- Right, sorry.
Willow, Diggie, Stains, I want you to
take Maddie to The Hoosegow Saturday night
while the rest of us get the
house ready for the party.
Don't bring her home
until midnight though,
because that's when her
actual birthday begins.
Oh, midnight? Isn't that
awfully late for a party?
You mean like...
16 years late, Mom?
Midnight party... fun.
Hey, Mads, what are you doing?
I am turning all my
lucky fives into sixes.
Turns out the first 15 years of
my life I stuck fives everywhere.
Everywhere.
Identity crisis... I can relate.
I remember the tough transition
from Joseph to Joe to Joey...
With a brief stint as baby "J".
Then ultimately back to Joey.
- Wasn't there a J-Dog in there somewhere?
- Do not bring that up!
Okay.
Maddie and Joey Rooney?
Character from my nightmares?
Delivery.
"You are cordially invited
to the cirque-du-soleil
red carpet gala celebrating
the sweet 16 of Liv Rooney".
Liv's throwing a party for herself?!
The invitations
pretzel-butt was handing out
were for a fake party to
throw Maddie off the scent.
My job was to twist the
knife ever so delicately.
I have a gentle touch.
Wow.
Liv took this whole birthday
scandal a lot better than you did.
A lot better.
A... lot.
I can't believe she just
dumped me to do her own thing!
Yeah. Does that make you mad?
I bet I'd be mad.
I'd be, like, really mad.
You know what?
If Liv's throwing a party for herself,
I'm throwing a party for myself.
I'm going to The Hoosegow.
Oh okay, here comes Maddie.
Remember we have plans on Sunday.
Hey, guys, do you want
to go out for my birthday?
Hoosegow on Sunday, what do you say?
Can't, we have plans on Sunday.
What plans?
I... I've got a, um,
uh... a drum circle.
Washing my ferret.
Book Club?
You're in a Book Club?
Sure. Yeah, you know, every
month we pick a book and then...
We watch the movie and talk about it.
Well, we're available Saturday.
Saturday? Aren't you
guys going to Liv's party?
Not invited. Guess we
didn't make the cut.
Liv's loss... we're the cool kids.
Liv's throwing a party for herself
and she didn't even invite my friends.
You know what?
I am free Saturday. I'm
going to The Hoosegow.
Yes!
Snap! The jaws of my
traptastic plan had closed.
Maddie hated me, hello...
♪Best sister... ever!
There you go, little lady.
Now you are welcome to
as many return visits
to the salad bar as you
want at The Hoosegow.
But only under the
watchful eye of the law.
"Watchful eye"? Hardly! I filled
my whole purse with baby corn.
Don't mess with Sheriff Tim, Willow.
He's packing ketchup and mustard.
Dude, whatever Liv is doing
at her stupid red carpet party
cannot be nearly as cool as this.
I mean I'd much rather
be at a place where you
can throw your peanut
shells on the floor.
And rib bones.
Am I not supposed to do that?
Always the lady, Stains.
Always the lady.
Ooh, guys, they're gonna
arrest someone again.
You are under arrest!
Cattle rustling, stagecoach robbery!
And spitting in the presence of a lady.
Ooh!
- Lock him up!
Oh, I gotta take this.
This is jailhouse one. Over.
- Diggie, how's it going?
- It's great.
We're just about to order dessert.
She doesn't suspect a thing.
Dessert?! You can't be on dessert
already. It's barely 10:00!
You need to keep her out
of the house until midnight.
I mean, yeah, I'll do what
I can, but I didn't expect
service to be this fantastic
at a restaurant like this.
Diggie, I am trying to do
something nice for my sister.
Do not make me regret trusting you.
The fate of my plan rests
on someone named Diggie.
- We gotta stall for time.
- Not a prob.
Stains is doing the rotisserie
chicken stockade challenge.
If you can eat a whole chicken in
under an hour, you get a free T-shirt.
Come on, come on, come on!
Wipe.
Uh, you know what? Let's just
hose you off when this is over.
A one-layer cake? Really?
You think that's gonna make up
for 16 years of fibs and fraud?
I was going to put little purple
frosting flowers on the corners.
That will impress... no one.
Well, I suppose I could
do a few more layers.
Oh yeah! Maybe one
for each year you lied.
Wow, this mini-golf course
actually looks pretty good.
I'm glad someone's paying attention
to what Liv's trying to pull off.
- Let's see the windmill spin.
- Oh, it doesn't actually spin.
Yeah, no, it's decorative, like the
treadmill in Mom and Dad's bedroom.
Are you kidding me?
A crummy cake and a
non-spinning windmill?
Liv is trying is recreate the
mini-golf parties of Maddie's youth.
And if we're gonna do this,
we're gonna do this right.
I guess we could take apart
one of my remote-controlled cars
and use the motor from
that to make it spin.
Yeah, we could do that. We can
also play duck, duck, goose.
Am I the only one that cares?
We could take apart the riding mower
and use the motor from that bad boy.
Now we're talking.
Birthday magic, monkeys.
Let's go, let's go!
Where are you going?
It's already two hours past my bedtime.
If I don't take a nap before the party,
I'm going to be a real cranky-pants.
Good job, Stains.
I have never been more
impressed or disgusted.
And you know you didn't have to eat
the bones to win the shirt, right?
When I commit, I commit, man.
We hear it's your birthday, little lady.
Uh, it's not my actual
birthday till midnight.
Well, blow out the candle.
It's somebody's birthday.
Go ahead, Maddie, make a wish.
Guys, I can't.
Sheriff Tim was right.
It is somebody's birthday.
It's Liv's.
And the only wish that popped
into my head was that...
I wish we were blowing out
our candles together, so.
That's so sweet. Let's
get you home right now.
Uh...
Get up.
Well, are you sure? We've...
Barely been here for four hours.
You are under arrest... cattle rustling.
Wait! You're arresting the wrong bandit.
This girl here, she's
the cattle rustler.
Yeah, man, lock her up!
Lock her up, lock her up!
- Lock her up!
- Guys!
Guys, let me out! I need to get
to Liv's party before it's over!
Good move, Diggie.
I'm smooth under pressure.
There's a new Sheriff in town and his name
is Diggie and he's the meanest Sheriff on..
We're outta here.
Well... go! Maddie, wait.
Mr. & Mrs. Joey and Willow Rooney.
It's midnight! Seriously,
Diggie, 16 wrong turns?
And I've never heard of that law that
says you have to go 5mph past a graveyard?
That's just showing respect, man.
Wait a second, I don't hear music.
And the red carpet is
rolled up. You guys!
I missed Liv's birthday!
Su...
Upper was really great at The Hoosegow.
Where is everybody?
Surprise!
We missed saying surprise.
Are you kidding me?
Happy sweet 16, Maddie.
Wait, this is all for me?
- Where is your red carpet party?
- Oh.
There was no party.
I totally played you.
Don't feel bad though, I am a day older.
Ahem.
Hey, remember us, the
people you were screaming
at the whole way past the graveyard?
You guys were all in on this?
Liv, mini-golf?
It's just like old times.
We got so wrapped up in which kind
of party we each wanted that...
We forgot the best part
is doing it together.
♪Someone made you a cake!
Guys, a basketball cake?
This is amazing.
16 layers of butter-cream and guilt.
Mama's done her time. We're moving on.
Now the Rooney girls
are ready to get their...
♪A-party on, a-party on.
♪Whoop whoop, their party on.
♪Party on, whoop whoop...
Ahem! Mom, Mom.
We've forgiven you. You
can stop punishing us.
Maddie, we even got
you a number six jersey,
because we figured you'd
want to change your number.
Actually I've decided to
stick with the number five.
That's the day my best friend was born.
So, Liv, come over here. Help
me blow out all these candles.
Uh, okay, one sec. I want
to get a video of this.
I think I left my phone in the garage
when I was grabbing decorations.
Video? Then we've gotta
have the windmill going.
Dad, turn it on.
- Guys, I love it.
- We did a good thing today, boys.
See what happens when
you listen to Parker?
That thing kicks up quite a breeze.
Oh no, the cake!
We have to turn this thing off!
Don't worry, birthday
girl, your hero is here.
Hey, superhero...
The plug's right here.
Whoa.
Oh, nice work on the cake, Mom!
Oh, hey Parker, check it out.
Liv got us a present for
helping out with the party.
It's nice to be appreciated.
Surprise!
Dude, that was awesome.
Nice work, pretzel-butt.
Up top!
Yeah!
Hey, can you fit in my underwear
drawer? I want to freak out my Mom.
Follow me!
Sync & corrections by P2Pfiend.
Www.Addic7ed.Com.