Is it 15 minutes already?
20 minutes, actually.
I want you to become Khun Jane’s assistant.
And don’t come to work late again.
Ok.
Sanrak,
If you have any queries about work,
please ask Khun Jane.
But if you feel uneasy,
you can come to me.
I leave her to you, Khun Jane.
Yes. I will.
Well, excuse me, then.
I suggest you to lock the door next time.
It was me who forgot to lock it.
Don’t blame him.
Like what he said.
From now, you are my assistant.
Just observe me today.
And I let you do some work tomorrow.
So, the first rule you have to keep in mind is…
try to catch up with me.
Please sum this up for me by 10 am tomorrow.
This is for our special feature. Please edit as this brief.
So many typos, please recheck.
Please print this out 5 more copies.
Hey,
how come you got home this late?
And look at you.
Have you been to a military training or something?
The military training may wear out your body.
But the work training wears out my mind.
My girl, Sanrak can do it.
Right?
That’s right.
I can do it.
I’m talented.
Su! (Fight on)
Su!
I’m exhausted.
Where’s everyone?
It’s really quiet.
There.
She’s right there.
Sandee?
Pete, you asshole.
You will sure get some piece of me tomorrow!
What are you doing?
Are you tired today?
A bit.
Don’t forget to eat. You are so thin.
Hello, Thew?
What’s up?
Come again?
What are you saying?
The signal at my place is not so good.
What?
Hello?
Hello. Hello.
Thew, I can’t hear you?
Let’s text instead.
Hello. Hello.
What? I can’t hear you well.
Helloooo.
Listen, my neighbors.
Hey, uncle!
Look at my sister.
She is finally asked out by a guy.
She talked so sweetly to her guy.
Enough.
Are you crazy?
No one is asking me out.
Could that guy be Thada?
You also told me that Thada came to pick her up the other day.
Wait a minute.
P’Chacha.
Why did you tell her about Thada?
Huh?
I didn’t know you treat that as a secret.
Oh?
Isn’t he just a friend.
A friend and a secret…
A secret and a friend…
Yeah?
How can they be together?
I’m confused.
Gosh!
Nothing is going on.
This is so annoying.
Stop talking nonsense.
Her world looks pink, don’t you think?
Why does she feel annoyed?
Did I say something wrong?
She is annoyed because there must be something going on.
Hey, Uncle.
My sister finally got asked out.
I mean it!
A guy is hitting on her.
Gosh, I’m happy.
Let’s eavesdrop her on the phone together.
Let’s come in.
Excuse me.
Omo, so premium.
You are like Belgium chocolate, you know?
Good morning.
I’m here to see Sandee.
Are you the guy who called her last night?
Did Sandee mention me to you?
Something like that, dear.
Hey, Sandee.
You seem to have premium guys picking you up every day, dear.
What is going on?
This man is gorgeous.
He’s handsome like an angel.
Thew.
Why are you here?
Well, yesterday…
you haven’t given me your answer.
So I’m here to get it.
What if my answer is “No, you can’t pick me up.”?
Then, you would become a very mean person, you know?
Hey, Sandee.
Sandee, listen.
How come it can be this coincident?
Don’t worry. Sandee is not a mean person.
Go on…