Subtitles by KBS World
Yuto!
They always play with our emotions.
Hey.
- Hello. / - You've grown a lot.
Hello.
Everything works out for him.
They make us laugh with their comments.
Are you happy?
Sunghoon, you watching this?
They make every moment shine.
Strawberry, may I pick you?
Can I eat you?
They're like the spring in our hearts.
What kind of spring will the Supermen
spend with their children
in the 48 hours they have without mom?
The Return of Superman. Episode 19.
"You Are My Spring."
It's already the second spring of their lives
for the twins.
They look like some kind of
Mongolian tribe dressed in this.
Are you going somewhere today?
Are you going to herd sheep? Seoeon?
Going to herd some sheep?
Daddy.
- Honey. / - What's this?
This is for Seojun...
When you take him outside.
Please dress him in this.
They've never tried this on before.
Seojun's going to wear it.
- Honey! / - It'll be too hard to wear this.
- You only have one baby today. / - I know. Okay.
- I know. / - It's just one today.
Seoeon, let's go on a date with mommy.
We've always thought lightly of Seojun.
We just thought he had a good personality
and wasn't shy and was good with everyone.
But when I think about how Seojun must've felt,
I feel so sorry. So...
Why am I crying?
In the psychological test last episode,
Seojun showed that
he was a little unstable compared to his brother.
They just thought he was gentle.
But he would've wanted just as much attention.
Why couldn't they see that earlier?
Daddy's here.
We didn't pay enough attention as parents.
But we couldn't help it since we have twins.
I know it won't be easy for my wife but...
This time we decided to take care of one kid each.
And if this succeeds, we'll maintain this format.
- Honey. Honey? / - Yes?
You've been away from the kids
2 days at a time.
But this is my first time.
I feel really sad all of a sudden.
Why? You always said it'd be nice with just one.
I know but...
It's a first for me. Not seeing them for a day.
I'm getting really emotional...
You'll realize that having both is the best, right?
You'll never say you wish you only had one.
Since you've always felt bad to Seojun,
you shouldn't feel sad today.
Make sure you have heaps of fun today.
- Of course... / - Daddy!
Once you take Seoeon, I'll get really happy again.
That's right. We've always wanted to try this.
We should do it.
Can I leave it to you and get ready?
- Get ready for what? / - To go out.
Of course. But aren't you finished?
Your makeup looks ready.
No, I have more to do.
And these are home clothes. I have to get changed.
That's home clothes?
I've never seen them before.
I wore this dress in the past.
I've seen the dress but I've never seen that top.
You bought this for me. We went together.
Seoeon, come here. Seoeon!
Lee Seoeon!
- Mama! / - Hello.
- Mommy. Just wait. / - Hello.
Just a minute.
What was that? I think I just saw a cheetah run by.
Seoeon, I think I saw a cheetah race by.
Do I look hot?
Oh, it was mommy.
I'm going on a date with my Seoeon.
Seoeon and I are going on a nice date.
You like that?
You like it?
Seoeon?
Let's go now.
How exciting.
Goodbye. See you tomorrow.
Your outfit...
- Is it hot? / - It looks like my aunt's clothes.
Fashion comes back around.
My aunt used to wear that.
Say bye bye.
You know how to wave goodbye. Bye bye.
- Bye bye. / - Seojun, say bye.
See you.
Let's sleep!
Seojun, let's get some sleep.
I can't believe I'm having a shower in the day.
There are so many things.
First, brunch on a fine day.
Wearing sunglasses.
And going to the amusement park.
Seeing Sunghoon dress up so nicely...
I wondered how that was possible.
But now I have that chance too.
Hollywood!
The sun's up!
The sun is up!
The sun is up...
It's up...
The sun is up!
Sunghoon, you watching this?
I can dress up too.
Are you watching from Tokyo?
Your baby's really cute.
Say thank you.
Thank you
Bye bye.
Where's Seoeon?
I'm only taking care of one today.
You really work hard on the show.
Thank you!
Bow. Thank you.
If you have a baby chair...
What's this? It's the menu.
Menu!
He's not normally like this.
Seojun, don't do that.
I was wondering why I couldn't see properly.
It was these sunglasses.
Oh, goodness me.
Excuse me.
What's the most popular salad these days?
- How's the avocado salad? / - It's good.
It's good? Then I'll take that.
And an iced Americano.
- That'll do for now. / - Okay.
Excuse me.
Do you have any fashion magazines
or a newspaper?
- Would you like to read it? / - Yes.
- Just anything please. / - Just a minute.
I just hope a fashion magazine reporter
happens to pass by and takes some photos.
Lee Hwijae's 100 out 100, perfect fashion.
It's New York!
This is New York.
Please make "Empire State of Mind"
the background music.
Wonderful.
Wonderful tonight.
Wonderful weather, I mean.
This is close to what I pictured.
How nice.
This is great.
Meanwhile...
What's happening in Sarang's city of Tokyo?
Camera.
Hello!
Hello.
Don't do that. Don't harass Buru.
The entire city has become frozen
by the untimely snow storm.
Tokyo has become a winter kingdom.
It's become rain.
It's raining right now.
Sunghoon.
The dog food is outside.
So give feed them this when it's time to eat.
And please take good care of Sarang again.
And you must clean. Clean!
And I know I'm repeating myself,
but Sarang's getting very stubborn these days...
You go too easy on her
and do whatever she asks.
She's becoming more and more spoilt.
Since she understands everything we say now...
- Isn't that right, Sarang? / - Yeah!
Really?
Sunghoon! Please listen!
Please ask how she feels before you act.
Really?
It's cold!
Sarang, do you want rice porridge?
Or would you like rice and soup?
Do you want rice balls?
Rice balls please.
Really? Really?
Really.
Here! Eat this. Is it good?
You should eat too.
Wait, don't feed her the rice over there!
- She needs to eat. / - No, don't do that.
Is she going to come back and eat here?
Yes. If we sit down she'll come and eat.
I'm pretty sure she won't sit back down here.
She will.
You turned on the TV, right? That's why.
She wanted to watch TV.
That's why I asked you earlier.
You can't just do whatever she asks.
Then you come and make her eat here.
That's not it. She can eat first and watch later.
I want to eat here.
Eat here first and watch later, Sarang.
Let's eat first, Sarang.
Let's eat first then watch TV.
I just need to eat this?
I'm really sorry about this.
But the babysitter can't make it today
because of the snow storm.
I'm really sorry about this.
But do you think you could watch Yuto today?
Oh, Yuto?
Yuto wants to meet Sarang.
Sarang, Yuto's coming!
That means I have to watch two kids alone!
Sarang, Yuto's coming.
- Sarang, are you in a good mood? / - Yeah.
I really want to see him.
Sarang's starting to get excited.
You're okay to look after Yuto, right?
What do I do about lunch?
How long do I have to watch him?
Until 6:30 or 7 p.m.?
Until she finishes work.
Just think it's till the evening.
What do I do about their baths?
Can they go in at the same time?
You should ask and see if she wants you to.
I think bathing will be too hard.
Sarang and Yuto have kissed before.
What if Sarang and Yuto kiss again?
I'm going to kiss Yuto!
What did you say?
She says she's going to kiss him.
Oh, really?
I've never seen that before.
Totally!
Oh, my. Where is this? Korea?
That's the first time I've seen that.
I'll have to stop them if they do it in front of me.
If he tries to kiss her in front of me, I'll stop him.
Why didn't the cameraman tell me this earlier?
You want my headband. There you go.
You could simulate raising a son with him!
Which chopsticks do you want to use?
Mickey Mouse.
Mickey Mouse!
This is that thing...
What Junu's father used to do.
Junu's really clever.
He read books from a very young age.
And I don't think they let him watch much TV.
"You're not allowed to eat that cake."
Tinker Bell stopped him but Peter Pan didn't listen.
Yuto!
It's just the delivery man.
It's Yuto, right?
It's not Yuto. It's the delivery man.
Do you like Yuto?
- Do you like Yuto? / - Yes.
Yuto!
Mom, look at this.
What is that?
Look, it's a huge booger!
It's Yuto!
Yuto!
She looks so happy.
Yuto.
- Do you like Yuto? / - Yes!
Who do you like more? Daddy or Yuto?
Yuto!
She answers so quickly.
Haru, check this out.
Look.
Close your eyes.
Keep them closed.
Abra...
Cadabra!
No, wait.
Abracadabra. Ta-da!
- What is it? / - How did it get so big?
Giraffe!
Want me to make it small again?
Abra...
- Cadabra. / - Abra...
Abracadabra. Ta-da!
Should we make it big again?
- Again? / - Yeah.
Abra...
Abracadabra. Ta-da!
What's for breakfast?
Oh, wow. Pork belly?
It's the shoulder meat that Haru likes.
Pork shoulder?
Haru, mom's making your favorite.
Hurry up and cook already!
Why didn't I press the button? I thought I did...
Who are you talking to?
I didn't press the cook button for the rice.
Were you talking to the rice cooker?
I was raging at the rice cooker.
Nemo has big eyes.
Do you have big or small eyes, Haru?
- Big eyes. / - Let's see.
Open them real big.
As big as you can.
What is that?
Then what about mom?
Let's make mom be the shark.
No, they're scary.
That's why, because she's scary.
Daddy's a little scared of mom.
How am I scary?
In a good way.
Thank you for the meal.
Let's dig in.
This soup is so delicious.
Haru, this is what you call mom's bean paste stew.
Eat up.
Let's go!
Rice gives you the energy to raise kids.
That camera...
It's shooting me on extreme close up.
I only realized now.
You said yourself that you look like Kim Soohyun.
Haru, does daddy look like Do Minjun?
Will you be okay with daddy?
Want to stay with mommy?
Haru, what song do you want to listen to?
"Let It Go."
Aren't you sick of "Let It Go?"
Where?
You're asking where we are?
It's a strawberry farm.
Big and pretty strawberries
that have ripened with the warmth of spring.
Will Haru be able to take these strawberries
safely home?
The ones that have this green part
pointing to the sky, are well-ripe.
And this is how you pick them.
You twist your wrist like this.
As if you're waving. Then you can pick them easily.
Okay, let's go in and pick some strawberries.
Mom said to pick lots of strawberries.
This isn't it.
Here it is. Red one.
Hello, strawberries.
Can you get picked for me?
I can't pick this one.
You can't? You asked and they said no?
Haru, there's a family of 5 red friends there.
Hello.
Can I pick you?
Can I? There we go.
Wow, that's pretty.
A big strawberry!
Big strawberry.
- This one's really red. / - Let's say cheers.
Cheers.
Big strawberry!
Haru, big strawberry!
Can I pick you?
"Yeah."
It said yes.
Did you hear it? Did you hear its voice?
Can I eat you? "Yes!"
They really talk!
Was that the strawberry talking?
Yes.
Wow.
The strawberries talk.
Right?
Haru, even just a few years ago...
I never imagined I'd be picking strawberries like this.
I get to do lots of fun things thanks to you.
Haru and Hyejeong are like the spring to me.
When I'm lonely and feel like I'm trapped in winter...
Just looking at them makes it seem like it's spring,
even if it's for an instant.
That's what they're like to me.
Strawberry, may I pick you?
Can I eat you?
Haru!
There's a garden growing in your head.
Bee, come have some honey.
Haru, Haru!
Don't call the bees.
Daddy's scared of bees.
Bee, eat this.
- Hey. / - Haru!
- Eat this. / - Haru, don't call the bees.
Why not?
- Don't call the bees. / - Why not?
Did you call them?
You called them, right?
It's on me, right?
- It's on me, right? / - Oh, let's go, daddy.
- Did you call them? / - No.
You called them, right?
- It's on me, right? / - Oh, let's go, daddy.
Daddy, let's get out of here.
Okay...
But you called the bee...
Daddy! I said let's get out of here!
- Okay! / - Hold me!
I'm sorry.
But you called the bee over.
- Are you scared of bees? / - Yes.
When I was sending Junu to school,
I didn't really worry that much.
But now that I'm sending Junseo to school...
I'm pretty worried.
He doesn't even know
to raise his pants all the way up
after going to the toilet.
I'd like to send him to kindergarten
for another year or so.
- Junseo. / - Yeah?
Since you're going to school now,
you have to use these chopsticks.
When you eat...
Let's practice with this from today.
Okay?
Got it?
Give me the training chopsticks first.
Why?
So you can get a feel for it?
Get a good feel for it.
Remember how to do it and try.
You're going to match it to that?
I can't do this.
You can't give up after just one try.
You have to keep trying.
You can't use these chopsticks at school.
That's embarrassing.
Are you going to always give up at school?
Junseo's good at it.
He just has to fix this one thing.
Junseo, watch this.
Do it like this.
It's hard to do it on the inside.
That's the way.
When school starts, dad will...
To your mouth!
You really are amazing!
Try this one.
Mom!
- Get a little piece of kimchi... / - Did you get it?
Just a bit more.
You really are amazing!
Just what is going on here?
He got the bean.
He has to learn to tie his shoelaces.
Junseo has to get his vaccinations today.
Practice your addition just a little more...
Junseo, you're pretty good at addition now, right?
- Are you good? / - Yeah.
Show me.
1 plus 1 is cutie.
- Junseo. / - Yeah?
Do some study with dad.
1 plus 1 is...
Study with dad when I'm not here.
5 plus 7 is?
12.
Wow, you're amazing!
You're good.
I calculated it with my toes and fingers.
I'm suffering here with study
and Junu gets to read in peace.
Junu did all this once too.
Junu will teach you how to write
grandma and grandpa's names.
So he can write it out. Okay?
Get to it then.
Go on and memorize this.
This is grandpa's name on mom's side.
Grandma's name on mom's side.
Grandpa's name on dad's side.
Grandma's name on dad's side.
Gong Okja.
Jang Anyeong.
Yang Taekjo.
Memorizing this is so much work.
Jang Anyeong. Gong Okja.
Yang Hyeonseong. Lee Unseon.
Hey!
Yang, dot, Taek, dot, Jo, dot.
Jang. An. Yeong.
You add "dot" after each character to show respect.
Got that?
Yeah...
Think you're so good.
Yang. Taek. Jo.
Jang. An. Yeong.
Gong. Ok...
Grandpa's name on mom's side.
How do you write Taek again?
In 3 seconds...
How do I?
Taek! Taek! Taek! Taek!
You don't know?
No!
Then memorize it again from the start.
Yang. Taek. Jo.
Lee. Eun...
I've memorized it.
What will you do if you get it wrong?
What's your punishment?
Why must there be a punishment?
Why must you be like this?
What did I do wrong?
You're taking a test right now.
To see if you've memorized it or not.
My brother!
He was like...
He glared at me like this.
He was totally...
So annoying.
I've finished.
You got it all right.
- Dad, he's memorized it all. / - Oh, really?
Well done.
They met some amazing actors
as they followed dad to work.
Reply Superman, Uncle Kim Sungkyun.
Everything works out for him.
Uncle Cho Jinwoong who knows what's up.
And...
The king of charisma that's
hard to see on TV.
Uncle Kim Yunseok.
You've grown a lot.
Is it more fun to hang out with dad than mom?
What did you say?
A fun time with three uncles that
aren't easy to meet.
Don't miss out.
Yuto's coming, Sarang!
Who do you like better? Dad or Yuto?
Yuto!
I'm going to kiss Yuto!
Totally!
I'll have to stop them if they do it in front of me.
Yuto is here!
Yuto.
Sarang!
Thank... Huh?
She's been going on about
how much she wants to see him...
Look, it's Yuto!
Leave the umbrella.
Yuto, you look cool.
Check this out!
Wow, that's cute. What is this castle?
Yuto, what is this?
Yuto's been stressing about
whether to hug Sarang or kiss her.
Really? This is dangerous.
Sarang said she'd kiss him too.
Sarang, do you like this?
This is it.
Did Sarang turn on the music?
She wanted to play it for Sarang
and said, "This is it."
Say, "Can I borrow it please?"
Can I borrow it?
I think you'll have it easy today, Sunghoon.
You might get lonely if they play by themselves.
If they play by themselves.
I want to eat this.
Please open this. Yuto can't do it.
Give it to Yuto.
What are you doing, Yuto?
Don't give that to Sarang.
That was in your mouth.
What time did Yuto have breakfast?
I think around 8 o'clock.
You're not going to eat this?
Move. Yuto can't see.
Look!
Watch this.
Look! Sarang's on TV.
What's going on?
She normally hates brushing her teeth.
She's not coming out of the bathroom.
I want to have a bath.
What? A bath?
Are you going to bath?
Let's do it later.
Will you have a bath together?
I will.
Should we do it after we go outside?
We'll do it later.
I want to bath.
I said I want to bath.
Later.
I've put rice balls in your bags.
Will we bath after we eat rice balls?
Okay, let's bath after eating rice balls.
No, we'll bath after we go out.
He keeps going on about bathing.
They want to bath together.
Sunghoon, make sure you bath them both.
Bye bye.
Let's go eat.
We're here to have lunch.
Yuto, what do you want to eat?
This.
I'll call the goblin.
No.
I want to dance to heavy beats.
You want to dance?
One more time.
After we eat.
Let's do it after we eat.
The goblin is coming.
Sarang, it's scary. Will you be okay?
Hello!
I'm scared.
Are they being naughty again?
See? Make sure you behave.
Yuto and Sarang are behaving now.
Okay, talk to you later.
It's done. It's okay.
It's okay now.
You're alright.
Sarang, it's okay now.
- Sit down. / - Sarang, I'm scared.
It's scary.
Here are your toys.
Wow!
- Open this. / - Just one.
Oh, gosh.
- Oh, gosh. / - Oh, gosh...
I'm dying with you two.
That hurts, right?
Come here.
Oh, gosh.
It hurts!
Come over here.
That's because you were being greedy.
Come here.
Sarang, come here.
Come over here.
Where does it hurt?
Just a wait a bit.
Sarang, here!
It's a present.
This is great.
Very good. Is it tasty?
Open wide.
Sarang, you have some too.
Is it good? Oh, gosh.
Oh, Yuto.
You ate it all.
Look how full you are.
1, 2...
Want to kiss?
No kissing allowed.
Later.
I want to dance.
Stand up please.
She's so clueless about how much
her daddy's burning up inside.
Sarang's busy on her date with Yuto.
However...
Who said that love is like delicate glass?
Sarang!
That's Yuto's.
See?
Meanwhile, Haru's immersed in the sweetness
of the strawberries she picked herself.
Delicious.
Are they good?
You think they're good too, right?
They're good.
You put these gloves on...
And we're going to mush them together like this.
- There. / - There we go.
Watch this.
Come and do it with me.
Do it like this. Watch.
Like this.
If we do this then mom can't have any.
We're going to take those for mom to have.
And these are for making strawberry jam.
Then I'll give mom this strawberry jam.
Haru, do it like this.
Like this, with both hands. Squeeze them like this.
That's the way.
Taekwondo!
Finished.
I'll do it.
- You'll do it? / - Yes.
Since the fire is on, is this hot or cold?
- Hot. / - Right?
- So make sure you don't touch. / - Okay.
- Be careful. / - You can stir it, Haru.
What is this black stuff?
That's sugar.
Stir well.
Is it black sugar?
Haru, should I buy us something to drink.
No thanks.
There's the camera. Hello, camera.
You try.
You want me to do it? Okay, which camera?
The one on the ground?
- Yeah. / - Okay. 1, 2, 3.
There we go.
Haru, let's do one for the cameraman.
1, 2... What is that?
Catch my kiss.
Haru, I'm going to throw it high.
This kiss is going high.
You're good at eating kisses.
Haru, let's come with our friends next time.
It looks nice to see them all together like that.
Haru, come here.
Come over here.
You have to scoop this and put it in here.
Careful.
That's the way.
It's a horse.
Where is it?
Look at its hair.
It looks like when I wake up in the morning, huh?
There are geese.
We have geese and turkeys.
You keep them with the goats?
They don't know where to pee and poop.
- That's why we put them in there. / - Wait...
Haru loves donkeys.
Feed him.
Here, baby.
He looks just like the donkey we have at home, right?
Right.
Give him some bread.
She must be hungry.
Doggy! Doggy!
Can't you help me out?
I'll do it.
I can hold it too.
Haru, where are you taking him?
Haru!
Should we go on the swing?
Say baa.
Goat?
Should we put him on the swing?
No...
I'll hold him.
You can't poop here.
You'll get my pants dirty.
She seems so at home with the puppy.
That dog must like her. He's just sitting still.
Haru, Haru!
Doesn't she look like a kid
that's lived here for like 10 years?
She seems to fit in well.
Can I sit here?
So cute.
What's his name?
- Snowball. / - Snowball?
Is that his name?
Yes.
But that black one over there...
That's his mother!
- Really? / - Yes.
It's strange.
But they're totally different colors.
Haru! Haru!
You're like a dog.
I am, right?
Haru, Snowball doesn't look too happy.
But they're totally different colors.
Hold him like this.
That's it.
Rooster.
She really likes that dog.
- Check out this puppy. / - Haru, you can take a puppy.
No, it's alright.
The grandpa next door won't like it.
I want to take him.
- Okay, take him. / - No, no.
Haru!
Haru, we sent off the dog we had at home.
You can take good care of him, right?
Yes!
Okay then.
Haru...
Let's go and get our strawberry jam.
With him?
- Snowball? / - Yes.
Haru...
We had to give away our other dog...
No!
Haru, his parents will cry if we take him.
They won't.
Let's ask Snowball's family.
Mommy, can we take him?
No!
Yes!
She said no.
No, she said yes.
Haru, he has to live with his family.
It's okay to take fish and bugs home...
But we're not in the position to take dogs home.
Let's do this then.
You can live here.
Okay? You live here with Snowball.
I'll go home.
Do you want to live here with Snowball?
Let's say bye.
Goodbye, Snowball.
He likes you because you were good to him.
Bye!
Bye.
It was winter in my heart for a very long time.
There was a time I just sat in my room and cried.
I was crying and Haru came in...
"Daddy, why are you crying?"
She wipes my tears for me too.
It's really fascinating.
To have such a beautiful and cute friend
that looks out for me...
I think to myself that I have no reason to be sad.
After enjoying the Hollywood lunch of his dreams
with Seojun...
Hwijae's returned home.
What's he planning to do now?
He's so good by himself.
Seojun, you like baths.
Is this for 10 babies?
You can't come in now.
But you can look.
Do I fill the whole thing?
Seojun, you try.
Push it forward. That's the way.
So it's supposed to rise up like this.
Oh, my head.
Hello?
It's Hwijae.
Hi, Hwijae.
Are you home?
Yes, I'm home.
Can you come over for just a sec?
Where? Are you home?
Yes, I'm home.
- Okay then. / - Okay.
Seojun, let's open the door.
You can do it.
Open the door.
Kang In!
Heechul!
Hello, baby!
Hello!
Hi, Seojun.
Hi, it's Uncle Kang In.
Let's see if he goes to Heechul.
Come to me.
Come on.
He's shy.
Hey, blow some air into this.
Shouldn't you do that?
We have to fill this with water.
- You can do it. / - I haven't done this in a while.
You have to blow well and make it really tight.
That'll make sure the water doesn't leak.
Come to me.
It's Seojun.
Seojun, let's play with uncle.
Hello, Seojun.
Sorry for making you do that, Heechul
It's me.
- It can't be helped. / - Want to go to dad?
I'm too tired.
To daddy?
Seojun, these uncles...
They're world stars.
Hey, give him some of your energy.
Take my energy.
- Okay... / - Just hold him.
Seojun...
Seojun!
You're making me do this...
- Good work, Heechul. / - You need to blow more.
Heechul!
You can use this.
Yeah, use the pump.
I'm so dizzy.
- I'm dizzy. / - Heechul, give him a hug.
- Good boy. / - Give him your energy.
Seojun, these are world stars.
You need to get energized by them.
Sorry.
We haven't seen you in a while.
- We have the next mission. / - Okay.
Heechul can look after the baby...
- He can walk, right? / - No, not yet.
I think he'll like you, Heechul,
if you play with his toys.
- Come to me. / - Kang In.
- Kang In! / - Yes.
Come here.
- Don't worry about the baby. / - Okay.
Do you have to bathe the baby?
Bubble bath.
- You're going to fill the pool? / - Yeah.
Wait. This won't leak, right?
It can't leak.
So cute.
Want to go for a swim?
"I want to swim."
Seojun...
"Fill it up with water quick."
Heechul, it's not leaking, right?
- No. / - No.
Take a look.
He's so cute.
I love babies...
When will we fill all of this?
Don't you have a hose?
Of course not. Who has a hose inside the house?
Want to swim?
Do you want to swim?
How cute will they be when I have babies too?
Right?
How come he's not crying with you?
- You know I used to be scared of kids? / - Yeah.
But I love babies now.
Hello!
That's fascinating.
- What's your name? / - He's really behaving.
That's not good for your body.
Seojun, just wait.
Kang In's been tricked.
Oh, you're excited?
Hooray!
Look at you!
You're so cute.
Take your clothes off...
You have such a cute body.
How can he be so small?
Go in now.
Wow!
This is fun!
Oh, my!
It's so nice and warm.
How exciting.
Oh, hot. Oh, hot.
Let's get a bit of water on him.
You have such a pretty forehead.
Can't I quickly get married and star in
The Return of Superman Season 5 or so?
You need to be on Season 2 not 5.
How do I use this?
You don't put it on his body, right?
You get soap bubbles when you pour it in
as the tap is running.
Don't you pour it in water?
You do it with the tap on.
That's how you get bubbles.
Just pour it in.
- You don't use this on his body. / - You don't?
It's okay, just pour it in.
You can't just pour it in.
Then?
You have to do it in the bath tub.
No, no.
Just do this.
Are you sure?
You can't make bubbles like this?
- No, you can't. / - Then what do you do?
I know how to do it. I'll make them.
- You'll make the bubbles? / - Yes.
You have to make them in the bath tub.
Just play, I'll make some.
You'll make bubbles and bring them here?
You have to do it while the tap is on.
He knows a lot about bubbles.
- How fun. / - There are some bubbles.
There are. How fun!
He likes the water.
Oh, yeah! Dancing!
He likes it?
- Hey, Kang In. / - Yes?
- Is it working? / - Yes, we have bubbles.
Something doesn't sound right.
Is he doing something strange?
Are you doing something weird?
I'll scoop this over.
You're going to scoop that up and pour it in?
Help me.
It's okay. You do it.
Seojun will love you for it.
- He likes you. / - Look at him smile!
You smiled!
I think babies like me because I'm so immature.
No, my kids...
So it works that way.
You're getting it all over the floor.
How do you know this?
This guy...
I love taking baths.
- Wipe the floor. / - Yeah.
Can you wash hair with this?
I think so.
Oh, my goodness!
Look at your forehead.
Oh, that stings.
- I'm sorry. / - Oh, that stings.
- I'm sorry. / - Water!
It's okay.
Oh, that stings.
But he won't cry.
Seojun doesn't cry.
Seojun... How can he be so gentle?
This one is gentle.
As I told you before,
he could live out on his own.
That's how good he is.
He won't do anything dangerous.
- Oh, really? / - Yeah.
He'll never go behind there.
He only does it if something's there.
He never does anything dangerous.
Can't I be casted in Season 2 or 3?
You could right now.
- Right now? / - Now?
I haven't made anything public yet.
No?
Seojun, come here.
Do you have to wash again after a bubble bath?
Can't I just dry...
You have to rinse with water.
I have to rinse again with clean water?
- Yes. / - No way.
You have to.
If you watch the movies, they just come out.
They just wipe off the soap.
No way.
You have to rinse this.
Won't this be good for you?
No, you have to rinse.
This is edible... Where's the bottle?
Then have a glass, I'll pour some for you.
- Do you like that? / - Give me the bottle.
I'm not going to rinse.
I won't even if you're supposed to.
Okay, this is what it says on the instructions.
Bubble bath.
Here it is.
Made in Canada.
It's okay.
Hold on...
I think this every time I see him,
but I think Seojun takes after you more.
Oh, no.
You like that?
You like that, Seojun?
Why do you think he looks like me?
He's more active. How do I put it?
But he can't be like you when he grows up.
Why not?
He's a great guy for guys.
What about his nappy?
- Nappy? / - It's diaper.
Hey, just go home.
They are taking my energy.
You guys try too hard to be funny.
See, he says you're too noisy.
Okay, we'll be quiet then.
He wants to play more.
- You like the water. / - No more.
Seojun, you can't play too much.
He'll catch a cold.
No, Seojun.
Seojun must be a swimmer.
I just learned today that he likes swimming.
- Make him a swimmer. / - Wait here. I'll dry his hair.
Pororo!
No!
Put his clothes on.
Can't have water go in!
Kang In and Heechul...
This is your last mission. Put his clothes on.
Seojun. Jump!
Jump!
He knows how to put pants on.
Seojun...
- Put your arm in here. / - Just wait.
Just put that on.
Where is Seojun's hand? It's here.
He's really strong.
- Seojun's hand! / - I like Super Junior.
- It's okay. / - I'm sorry.
Hey, you shouldn't be like that.
I'll postpone having a baby for now.
Seojun! You're all dressed.
- Applause! / - Applause.
Okay, rock, paper, scissors.
- How do we decide? / - Just do it with this.
To clean up?
If you don't play, you lose. Rock, paper, scissors.
- You do it. / - Why?
Okay then. If you don't play...
No, you're going to make one person do it?
Both of you should.
Let's do it together.
Okay then.
You're going to take all the water out again?
You have to pour out a bit.
Be careful not to drop any water.
We should put a towel on the floor.
We can clean that later.
Super Junior are great.
Choi Hongman, Lee Hyundo...
Just forget them.
The uncles are cleaning up.
That's enough for today.
We can bath again next time. Don't be sad...
Where are the Jangs headed
on this sunny spring day?
Oh, and who do we have here?
Who is this?
Hello!
- Hello. / - Jihwon!
Junu, is it fun being with dad these days?
Yes!
Where are you headed?
- To get Junseo vaccinated. / - Yeah, vaccinations.
- Junseo! / - Yes?
Don't cry.
Yes, I'm going to sleep so I don't cry.
I told you not to sleep.
Why not?
You're too heavy for dad to carry.
Then anesthesia.
It'll just be a short prick.
Only just a few months ago...
Junseo caused such a fuss at the dentist.
Which is worse? The dentist or an injection?
Both are just as bad.
Junseo, don't worry too much.
You can be manly and not cry today.
- I'm scared. / - Sit down.
Hello. Let's take a look.
I'm scared.
Is he starting school this year?
- Yes, this year. / - Okay.
We have a few things to do before then.
Today, DTaP, polio and MMR.
Let's get those three injections.
Needle!
There we go.
Just take out your arm.
Not your head. No, no...
Just his arm?
Just need your arm.
We haven't started yet.
- You can cry when it hurts. / - I'm scared.
- You can cry if it hurts. / - I'm scared.
Can you do this?
- I'm scared. / - Hold his body. Hold him down...
It'll be over real quick.
Hold him so he can't move.
- I'm scared. / - It'll be over in 3 seconds.
You don't have to look. Look at me.
Let's do the polio shot first.
Look at me.
This will sting a little.
Good boy.
- You're amazing. / - That's a relief.
You're as brave as your brother.
Wow, you're amazing, Junseo.
It hurts so much.
Can't you stop now?
It's the last one now.
Junseo, you're really brave.
Wow, you're amazing.
Wow.
All over.
It's all over.
Oh, that hurts.
Dad! That hurts.
- Does it? / - Gosh, it hurts.
- Well done. / - It hurts.
You've become really brave.
Please give me a band aid.
You already have one.
But it still hurts.
Is the family here?
They've never seen it.
I won't be filming this time.
They're making a DVD for the movie I was in.
And I took them to see how it works.
It's the first actors the Jun brothers will meet.
Who is the first actor?
It'd be really scary if all this falls down.
Hey, Sungkyun.
The man that cooks seaweed soup with mushrooms.
That's right.
The magician.
It's not only seaweed soup.
- Say hello to Uncle Sungkyun. / - Hello.
- Junseo. / - Hello.
You know who I am, right?
Don't you know how popular I am?
We don't get cable at home.
Are you the driver?
No. The driver will be here soon.
Are you the cleaner?
He'll be here soon too.
- Then the one who stabs with a knife? / - Yeah.
I'm the smiling one.
He's really cute once you get to know him.
You said you liked that commercial, right?
- Which one? / - The one with the kid...
"Dad, can you get me a sibling?"
That one.
You said you liked that. He's that guy.
That's me.
Oh, really?
- The cocoa? / - Yeah.
That's him.
- For real? / - Yeah.
- You can communicate with them. / - Of course.
I can't converse at home.
- It won't take long. / - It's just one-sided.
What stage is he at?
- Now? He's an outlaw. / - Outlaw?
Where they knock things over and break them?
I say this to my kids.
Oh, my runt.
Then he goes...
Dad, you runt.
That's what he calls me.
It feels like he's cursing at me.
I bet he doesn't know what he's saying.
You just have to laugh.
More uncles have arrived.
Really?
Who is it now?
Hello, Junseo and Junu.
Hey.
Hello...
- Hello. / - Say hello, Junseo.
- Say hello. / - Hello.
Hey.
You've grown a lot.
Do you remember him?
The man with the bone in "The Yellow Sea."
Do you remember him, Junseo?
No!
You saw him when you were too young.
We've known each other for ages.
He's virtually my brother now.
Back from when we really struggled
as theater actors.
We've known each other since
before we were married.
Our families get together many times too.
So the kids have to wait for 2 hours?
That's right.
But you'll be bored.
Junseo, is it more fun to be with dad than mom?
What?
Is it more fun with dad than mom?
What did you say?
Now that you hang out with me,
is it more fun than being with mom?
It is a little tough too.
Why? What's tough about it?
Because mom might be sad.
Is that why?
But I make it much more fun.
Dad, what's your weapon?
Dad does the strategizing.
Right?
Then you're the smartest in "Hwayi."
He is the smartest guy.
In "Hwayi?"
Yeah.
But you're not as smart in real life?
What? Do you think I'm smart or not?
You're not as smart.
Why do you say that?
You really go easy on them.
Yeah...
- I'm bored. / - Okay then...
Hello.
Hey, Jinwoong.
Happy New Year.
Boys, say hello.
Hello.
- It's the driving uncle. / - Yeah.
You're really handsome.
Thank you.
I'm your fan.
- Say thank you. / - Thank you.
When you look at me now...
Everything works out for him.
No matter what he does.
For some guys things just don't work
when they're with a girl.
And there are others when everything just works.
Even things that didn't work before.
- Especially when there's a girl present. / - Right.
How can it work out so well?
So funny.
Oh, you're in a drama.
Yes.
"Beyond the Clouds."
- You're shooting that right now? / - Yes.
KBS 2TV "Beyond the Clouds."
That's a great title. "Beyond the Clouds."
Please tune in.
Isn't there a playroom around here?
No...
No one normally brings kids here.
Then what do we do?
You guys?
Play with your toys.
Next episode.
Hello.
The man they've been waiting for is here.
But he gets shocked by Junseo's questions.
And the Jangs head off to Busan.
Who is this cute baby they meet there?
So cute.
Meanwhile, Sarang becomes more and more drawn in
by her boyfriend's charms.
Haru and Tablo's late night date.
They have their sweet time together.
The Return of Superman. Episode 20.
"Dating Rather Than Babysitting." Don't miss out!