I will see you later
Look at a person when you greet them
And you call yourself a man?
Why, you brat!
Mom, do you have some money?
I'm supposed to go to
the movies with a friend...
Damn. I just Wanna see
a movie, dammit.
HEY, hey, Chang-Guk!
Whatcha looking at?
I Want playboy, you got it?
I got it
9 dollar, 9 dollar
Why are you so late!
What are you doing?
Looks about 30 pounds, 30
Load it up
Oh, give me one more!
After I bone it. It'll only be 20 pounds
I'm being generous, as it is
Move your ass over
Pull! Pull it you dumb-ass!
Pull it you dumb-ass!
Hey, you do it!
Fucking moron!
Light the burner and bring it in!
Enjoy your stew!
Oh, you're here?
How much?
What do you mean, how much?
Just give me the usual
Okay
Look! It does mean pleasure
Hey, then look up this one
0.r.g.a.i.z.e
What are you doing?
Squeeze some more yellow paint
It got returned again
It's not like you've sent one or two
Why not stop sending them now?
Welcome
Where are the canned mackerels?
What?
Canned mackerels... where are they?
There aren't any!
Not for sale!
Why not?
This is Korea! Speak in Korean!
I'll be in the U.S. soon enough!
Where are they?
Hurry up and give it!
Get out!
I won't sell to you!
Get out! Get out! Not for sale!
Get out already!
You pushing me?
Don't you be twisting your tongue around here!
You gonna get out?
You bitch!
Of all the rotten... rotten luck!
Bastard...
You weren' t like this
when you were a boy
You learned English Well...
listened to your mom...
Shut up, you whore!
Before I stomp you to death!
Told you to stop this craziness!
Damn bastard!
I was wrong! Stop it!
Please stop! Chang-Guk!
He hit you again?
The rotten bastard!
Don't you call my son a bastard!
You're probably the only woman
who gets beat up by her brat...
I told you I'd make sure it
never happened again!
You hit my son
and I'll kill you!
Let me see...
Dammit!
You, you wanna become like me, too?
[Ma.
an]!
Here's your monthly pension
Please give me your stamp
You' re lucky to have
such an honorable father...
Did your father die
in the Baekma-Goji Battle?
Doesn't that bother you?
Your brother shot you
with a toy gun, right?
Let me see
Let' s see how bad it is
It's not enough to take my eye
you gotta cripple my dog, too?
Why do you leave it anywhere?
And! Why is your eye my fault?
We were both playing!
Who said to move?
And you can still see
fine out of one eye!
You two fight all the time!
Dammit
Where did your husband die?
At the Fight of Nakdong River?
Many died there too...
I don' t know
They' cl have to find the body first!
Whew! What are you going to do
about your daughter's eye?
They could fix it
at the American Military Hospital...
If you're finished, leave!
I feel bad for your daughter that' s all.
She has her whole life ahead of her...
Whenever I hold an arrow
I remember the War
At the Battle of Nakdong River
We fought with a North squadron
I shot three of them dead!
So why didn't you get a medal?
Exactly
That's why the government's
screwed up!
They don't give to them who deserve it. But
them cowards at the rear they get one!
Take a look at this!
For this service all
I get is a measly
30 dollars a month
That' s disgusting!
Pull it down, quick!
What' s wrong?
This is as good as a medal...
Fuck!
You think anyone gets a medal?
Arrogant asshole!
You who come from licking
Yankee asses...
Still, I've never killed anyone!
Whenever you open
your mouth it's the War
Are you so proud of killing
three men of our same blood? Tell me!
Sergeant Kim!
Are you so proud of shooting
three men dead?
Bastard, don't even know who's
on top and who's at the bottom!
That's why you always
have dog blood on your hands!
Sure! Let's see
if you don't sell your mutt to me!
Care to lay some money down?
Who's betting at this
sacred archery field?
You're talking shit!
In the old clays, a butcher like you
wouldn't be allowed to shoot arrows!
Only wealthy farmers could!
Times have gotten better...
even a meat-hacking bastard
gets to shoot arrows...
God-dammit! A meat-hacker!
You clone talking?
You guys have to fight
every time you meet?
That's enough, people
You want to see me grab
a dog right now?
Patience, got to be patient
Just let him be
He's asking for it! Shit!
All he's got is that dingy pride of his
You gonna play a game?
You go first!
Really?
Yes
Will you be quiet!
What are you doing undressed?
Crazy bitch!
Mom! Did you see my puppy?
Don't know!
Hey, Jihum
About this big... its fur is white
with some black mixed in...
Little shmucks, at it already!
Go home now!
Anyone here?
Welcome
We're hereto sell this dog
We found it on the street
I don't need such young...
I don't take puppies
Take it away
Students
Shit! Even if it's a puppy it's still dog meat
why won't she buy it?
Let's kill it ourselves
and then sell it
Then she won't know it's a puppy!
Get over here!
What... dammit!
Who said to look at girls?
It's because of guys like you
we soldiers get a bum wrap!
That's right, asshole! I can't get used to it
here I think I'll go crazy Without a woman!
Yeah
I got a problem with that
There is a problem
You think I Want to be here?
I'm doing my part for World peace
World peace?
Who thinks like that?
Probably just us Americans
Hey, come over here
If you don't come
I'll kill you
Do you like coke?
Hey, you do it!
You click!
You think I like doing this?
Why'd you hit
my girlfriend yesterday?
That bastard! Hey!
Don't you run!
Asshole! See if you don't come back!
What are you doing?
Get back to Work, now!
What the hell? Get out of here!
Get out of here!
Get back to Work, now!
Get out of here! Bastard
I won't use the likes of you!
Hey, that's enough!
You're going to hurt the meat!
Come here!
Stupid moron, that's the way
you should have done it!
Then I wouldn't have hit you so much!
Here, have a swig
To be a dog dealer
you gotta outstare them!
When a dog looks straight at you
it's scary, right?
You know What the scariest
eyeball of them all is?
It's the human eye
You know why the dogs
look away from me?
Because there's fire in my eyes
Here look!
Hey, you Want to go to your
father's land, don't you?
Answer in English...
You bastard, your mother taught you English
by beating it into you, didn't she?
To speak good English
no good thing
You gotta do everything those
Yankees tell you to, everything
Everything!
You hit my girlfriend one more time
She's your mom but
she's my girlfriend!
From before you were born!
Look at me like Dog-Eye!
Stop looking at me!
My eye's about to explode!
Hey
come over here, stupid
You hear what I'm saying?
If I Went to school
I'd be two grades ahead of you
But you don't, moron!
What do you know better than us?
Okay, I'll ask you in English
so answer back in English
You want to go to school, too, huh?
He asked if you wanted
to go to school!
What's your dream?
What do you want to be in the future?
This is for being so dumb, got it?
Answer!
Got it?
Uh-huh
With respect!
Yes
We' re not taking your money we're exchanging
it with an English textbook!
Give me some more!
What did you do?
Tell me! fuckin' I outta...
What are you guys doing?
Oh, hey, cross-breed!
Say it again!
If they do that again, tell me
What's this?
Have you ever seen
a naked girl in person?
This is boring!
She's not undressing!
Are you okay?
Look at me!
It's okay. Look, you got
a little cut, that's all
How could she poke me
with a pencil? Oh, it hurts
Does it hurt a lot?
Shit! I'm going home
Having fun?
I guess you saw me naked
like these pictures... even
playing... with my puppy
You saw what the puppy did...
I felt weird
Just like dogs, right?
Get up, you bastard!
It's a gun!
Shoot it!
Do it! You don't have the guts
Shoot it! Let see you!
Hey!
You going home?
Yes
Do you want something to eat?
Eat?
Eat UP!
Can you pull your hair back once?
I'm not making fun of you
I just want to see if it can be fixed
Pull your hair back
Why did you run?
Who ran away?
I needed to take a leak!
You think We American soldiers are dogs, sir?
To take a leak anywhere?
Something's fishy here
I exercise the right to inspect your things
Inspect? What did I do?
We're on alert these days because of drugs
Please cooperate
Drugs? Sure. Go ahead
I'm sorry
How old are you?
Eighteen
Go home
You bastard!
Go! Now!
Wait!
Eighteen is still
underage in Korea!
Don't soil the honor of the world's greatest
American army
What the hell?
Wait!
Eunoj, walk straight!
Eunok, what's wrong with you?
Have you been drinking?
Eunok!
What's wrong with you?
Why you brat...
35 pounds!
Is that all?
He's at least 40 pounds
Try weighing him again
Forget it! You should be thankful
I'm buying your mutt
Uh, okay. What a temper...
Load it up!
What are you doing, stupid!
Get it in the noose!
Um... could We maybe let this one live?
He' s my friend's dog...
Talking dog-shit, you bastard
Hurry up with that noose, you dick!
Go!
Why that bastard!
Get over here, you bastard!
You got any sense in ya, dickhead?
You! Stop right there!
Hey, Dog-Eye!
The dog's here lying dead
in our yard. Hurry over!
Where did you bury it
you moron?
Where did you bury it?
Tell me now, you moron!
I don't have the money
to pay it back
so where is it buried? Dammit!
Hey!
What are you looking at?
You're in training! move ahead
Shit!
That crazy bastard...
Good work
Do some work! Some work!
What are you doing?
Get back to work?
Dammit! You think being manager
makes you God?
What!
Move!
Do some Work! Some Work!
No trouble, okay?
Hey!
Hi
There's one missing
Did you take it?
How'd you like it?
Felt good, huh?
Hey!
You want a lift?
It's okay. Come on!
That bastard, you rotten son of a bitch!
Where are you going, with a baby? Bastard
What? We're just riding a bike
What's the matter?
You think I don't know
What you are?
Pretend to be nice and
then eat her up!
I served three years
at Camp Carol
Eunok. do you want to
end up like Chang-Guys's morn?
Hurry up and go home!
What are you saying now?
You can't give me our pension?
By any chance, have you heard
from Mr. Wonil Jang?
How can I hear from
a dead person?
You see... actually they say
Wonil Jang didn't die in the war
that he's alive in North Korea
It's been confirmed that Wonil Jang
voluntarily went to the North..
Voluntarily went to the North?!
So whet we're saying is if Wonil Jang
comes here quickly report it to this men
And in the future, if you leave the village even for a day
please report to us Your children, too
Are you keeping an eye on us? The family of
a soldier who received a medal of merit?
You're no longer a family of a merited soldier but
a soldier who defected to the North
It's 180 degrees different
keep this in mind...
we're always watching you...
Please return the medal and certificate
of merit by tomorrow, please
Don't cry
They say father's alive!
What use is he alive now?
What are we going to live on?
Damn! Why take it out on me?
You... what's wrong with you?
What's wrong?
Who's the bastard?
Tell me now!
Look at me!
Come here, bastard!
You, you, you...
Hey, asshole, get up
Go in. Go in, now
Do you have some money?
Hey! They're hiring over in the next village female factory workers
to make underwear for American soldiers
Watcha gonna do at home?
You got kicked out of school anyway
Oh! Get out! Get out and die
you worthless-!
Dammit!
They're commie bastards
who got executed during the War!
They're small, small commies
These bastards
these bastards did this to my leg!
Is there anything else?
Look here
Look here, shouldn't you
report that to the police?
Report whatever... this rusty thing?
Take the bones already and
bury them by the river!
I thought the water
in our well was tasty...
You know They say rotting corpses
make the water taste good!
- Clean this up!
- yeah
I bet it'll shoot.
It's been a long time since. I've heard a gunshot
Makes me think of the War
How many commies
did your father kill?
Three
That's right, three commies!
But no medal! Dammit!
You can't tell anyone
about the gun
It's okay. Let me see
Look at me, like this
Wow! With a normal eye
you'd be a shoo-in for Miss America
Do you want eye surgery?
That's easy enough for the American
Military Hospital to take care of
If I help you, will you be
my sweetheart?
Can you fix my eye?
really?
I... I'm getting eye surgery today
It's that American soldier, right?
No! Don't get the surgery!
You... you want me to spend
the rest of my life only half living?
Hold me
Hold me... hold me
No! I like you the way you are!
Does this look okay to you?
Tell me the truth!
Can you smile at this confidently
for the rest of your life?
Can you?
Can you see me?
You got paid today, right?
You got paid today
You haven't studied!
I'll ask you again, an easy one
Why can't we be friends?
My name...?
Who asked you your name?
Let's try it again with me!
If you can't answer me then
you take five blows from me!
You're a mix-blooded bastard, right?
Yeah! That's right, asshole!
Your mom was a western princess who sold
herself to American soldiers, right?
Yeah, my morn was
a western princess
You fuckin' piece of shits!
It' s clicks like you who are so english hungry that'll
go abroad and come back to sell off our country!
Hurry up and answer!
The rest, you hit him!
Go ahead!
You said only five blows!
How do you like that?
You like the ring?
Now you can wear your hair back
You happy?
Yes
It's LSD Some doctor discovered it by
mistake trying to make some painkiller
If I didn't have you and this
I'd go crazy right now
Here
One's okay
You won't get addicted
I'm sorry!
Don't take it if you don't want to
I just wanted to let
you know how I feel
I'm suffocating
My home has no mountains just flat
plains as far as the eye can see
not like Korea
So I have a hard time here being
blocked in by mountains
If it weren't for you, I'd be
AWOL already. Believe me...
You'll feel good in a second
Let me see your eye
You see alright?
Do you want to go to
the States with me?
I could take you...
Come here
where are dog-eye?
What a surprise!
What brings you to the butcher's?
Don't get your hands bloody
use that
Dammit! My hands are bloody
just the same!
No!
- I have a question!
- No!
My husband name is michel!
Please make me in the camp
I want to my husband's address
Please tell me the address
of my husband's camp
Fuck!
Who is it?
Hey! Who is it?!
What?
All the wallets are gone!
Someone went through our clothes!
You went into the shed for
some water before, right?
I just had some water, that's all!
Liar! You stealing
mix-blooded bastard!
What did you say?
You bastard!
What are you doing right now?
This bastard stole our wallets
and is trying to back out of it!
I didn't do it!
I saw you going in there, too...
What? You think being the
owner is everything?
You're more suspicious!
Where are your things?
What! This is ridiculous!
Honey! Look at that!
Hey, why are you stealing our stuff?
Weren't you gonna throw this out?
What?
The bitch has a lot to say
being a thief!
So I'll give it back!
A big fuss over
a few cabbages!
What gibberish is that coming from
your thieving bitchy mouth?
Picking ones that aren't
even fully grown!
Go plant them back!
What? Thieving bitch?
Bitch!
It's because you're so shameless
your life's a mess!
What!
Crazy bitch!
Why am I a crazy bitch?
Bye-bye
Damn people...
That bastard!
You son of a bitch! Why do you keep hitting her? Why?
Don't you have any pity for your mom?
The bastard
He won't hit you again
I kicked the living shit out of him
You bastard
who are you to hit my son!
He's already such a poor boy...
Fuck!
What the hell am I supposed to do?
Shoot! Go ahead!
Ah!
That bastard!
Rotten son of a bitch!
What are you doing right now?
Chang-Guk, what's
going on with you today?
Mom! Just bear it for
a minute! Please! Mom!
Mom!
I was wrong all this time!
Please forgive me!
I want to live happily
with you, too!
Killed dogs and killed like a dog
Is that a thing to say
in front of the dead?
Chang-Guk...
Where is your son?
Your son killed the dog butcher!
Get out! Get out!
Chang-Guk!
...the Ministry of National Defense is now searching
for soldiers heroes who participated in the War
who weren't awarded their medals due to administrative mistakes
Soldiers whose commanding officer put
in a request for a medal during
the War, please report to the Ministry
of National Defense
Civil Office by the 27th...
Serial Number 72281444 Sergeant Jungho Kim!
Division Commander
Major General Junghak Lee! Regiment Commander
Lieutenant Colonel Ulsung Jang Commander Kidong Kim
At the Battle of Nakdong River
I killed 3 enemy soldiers
You have it?
Here. Now do you believe me? Look
Who didn't believe you?
We were just having our fun with you
Is it made out of platinum?
Oh, careful
Whether it's platinum or bronze,
who cares?
It's all about the honor, right?
Huh? It's nice. Beautiful!
Dammit!
Hey! Give me some money!
Do you really like American
soldiers that much?
You whoring bitch!
Shit!
Let go
you son of a bitch!
Shameless bastard! Playing
with my younger sister like
that and being stingy
with some dollars!
You're better off without
a brother like that
Chang-Guk!
Hey!
You didn't forget the last
time, did ya when you hit me?
Whatcha looking at?
You bastard! Lower your eyes!
Hey! You know
you look really scary...
Shit! I've had it with this crap!
You think I'm your henchman?
Have you gone crazy?
Arrows are not to be
shot like that
Here! Give it here
You've got to first hold
the bow correctly...
Look straight at the target
and hold your breath
It's to empty your mind
Now pull it straight back like this
Got it?
Try it once
Hold it good
If you're excited
you'll miss the target
That's good!
It's that bastard who didn't
want you to get the surgery!
What's he to you?
Look me in the eye and tell me!
Now that your eye is fixed
you're just going to dump me, huh?
Just like you people, sucking all the sweet juices
and then spitting it out You think I don't know?
Go! Get out!
You're all like that!
You forget already what I've done for you?
Get out of here!
Fucking whore!
I don't need you!
Mom!
Chang-Guk!
- Chang-Guk!
- Go away!
Lower! The enemy can spot you!
You listening to me? I said, lower you
fucking moron! You'll be spotted!
Damn it!
Where's the enemy?
Son of a bitch!
That's an order! Crawl!
What the hell are we doing here
in someone else's backyard?
You like war that much?
You lost your mind?
Shoot! The enemy's right here!
So shoot! Why can't you?
What the hell!
From this moment
I'm outta of here!
No! No!
I'm not a soldier anymore
You want another?
Come lie down! Now!
Stay still!
I'll carve my name real pretty!
- Eunok!
- Mom
bitch!
Kill me! Do it!
There's no hope for me anyway...
Freeze!
Come and get me!
Put the gun down! You're under arrest for
being AWOL and for the possession of drugs!
Come and get me!
Send me back to the U.S.!
I'm sick of it here! If you don't, I'll...
Are you really not going to talk?
Whose arrow is this?
You shoot with each other
so you would know!
We shot at the same time!
If you don't talk
all three of you are going to jail!
It's mine!
This is really your arrow, correct?
That's right. So go ahead...
Hey, Officer Lee
He got a medal from the war
can't you go easy on him?
It's not like the arrow killed him
He's an American soldier!
An American!
Take him away
Let my father go!
I shot him!
You brat! Stop your crap!
Hurry up and go home, you brat!
- What's going on here? Did you really shoot him?
- Yes
You small twit!
Have you no fear
shooting an American soldier!
Why are you hitting someone else's son?
This bastard's really asking for it!
Hey, What do we have here?
Open your mouth!
OK!
Huh? What are you doing here?
This bastard...
You did it, too, right?
The girl's eye may be whacked but
her body was something else!
You saw her perky breasts!
Pressing really close...
What the hell
Office sir!
Hey! What are you doing?
Let go, you son of a bitch!
Hey, snap out of it
Get it loose!
Breathe. Are you OK?
Anyone home?
I have a letter for you!
Stop... Stop!
This bastard... Stop wha, punk?
Stop! St-op!
Stop! Stop the car!
Dear chang-guk's mom
How are you?
My name is Clinton
and I own a small deli
in California