Loving You a Thousand Times
Episode 54
Kang Ho, did anything happen?
Why are you in such a hurry?
Father-in-law, Mother-in-law, where is Eun Nim?
Why are you like this?
Father-in-law, Mother-in-law, our
Eun Nim is sick, please save her.
What do you mean?
You said our Eun Nim is sick,
why did you ask to save her?
What's wrong with our Eun Nim?
You... really make people wonder.
Why are you not speaking out?
How is our Eun Nim sick?
She was talking about writing her resume
and looking for job just yesterday.
Eun Nim... Eun Nim...
Father-in-law, it's...
Speak out quickly, this fella.
Father-in-law...
Eun Nim has gastric cancer!
Gastric cancer... gastric cancer!
What are you talking about?
Eun Nim should go to the hospital, get treatment
from the hospital, but she disappeared.
You... what are you talking about right now?
Father-in-law, please help me find Eun Nim.
Once I find Eun Nim, we need to take her
to the hospital. She needs the treatment now.
Honey, you need to eat
some even if you don't feel like it.
Only after you regain your strength
will you be able to look for Eun Nim.
All right.
Why are you sitting like that, sit more comfortably.
Aigoo, my God, we have to find her.
She is so good,
why did she get such an illness?
All right, why not tell us the details?
After we understand the details then
we should find the solution.
You went to the hospital with Eun Nim, didn't you?
What did the hospital say?
I'm all right, this is a matter of life and death.
I'm not a weakling, tell us now.
Yes, tell us the truth.
The hospital said she had one year at most.
What!? They said she could only live for one year?
Are they saying our Eun Nim only has one year?
Oh my goodness...
honey, what should we do?
First, Son-in-law Baek...
I would like to know, is there any
alternative for our Eun Nim?
Is there any way to keep her alive?
Tell me! I will do anything.
That... even if it takes my life,
as long as it'll save Eun Nim's...
Right now, the only choice is operation.
Yes, right, let her be operated then.
She must have the operation, the operation.
Will she really be fine after an operation?
Although we will only find out afterward, Father-in-law...
Eun Nim will survive.
That's right. One of my friends had the operation
for his gastric cancer five years ago.
He is still alive right now.
Even if the hospital said only one year to live,
one could survive three, five years or longer once after the operation.
Dear. Let's find Eun Nim quickly
and bring her to the hospital.
All right.
Eun Nim... This is Dad. I heard
everything from Son-in-law Baek.
Um... once you receive this message,
please come home quickly. Do you hear?
Eun Nim! Do as he says.
Although I might be a mother that is nothing to you,
you must take treatment when you are sick.
If you still consider me as your mother,
please come back home soon, right now.
Do you hear me?
You! You! What are you doing like this?
It's snowing!
You! This person! How can you play with food?
Who is going to clean up the mess you created?
Grandma, let her do as she likes; we can clean it later.
Mother, you do whatever you like.
Aigoo.
Aigoo, my God.
Leave his crazy mother like this...
Where did our Kang Ho travel to?
He hasn't called back home either.
This would work.
We have to call him and ask him to come back home.
Aigoo, I can't even have one quiet meal now.
About that... Grandma...
What's wrong?
Do you have something to tell me?
I have something I haven't told you yet.
What? What is it?
In truth...
Grandma! It's me.
Where are you right now?
You told me, your grandma, such a lie as you travelled.
What are you really doing over there?
Grandma.
You're even stranger after divorcing, Stranger.
Leaving your unstable mother behind and going
after your ex-wife. What were you thinking?
Grandma, I'll tell you later, I'm hanging up now.
Hello.
I'm...
You know who I am?
Yes.
How could such things happen in this world?
I have never heard of such things before.
I'm very sorry to hear that your daughter is sick.
But, how could you let her ex-husband
Kang Ho take her to the hospital?
This doesn't make any sense.
It can't be like this.
About that, Grandmother...
I'm sorry, it's not convenient for me to take calls now.
I'll call you back later.
Who is it?
You should go home now.
Your grandmother is complaining of this and that already.
Do we have to take such calls under this condition?
Yes, let's do this.
We will contact you once we find Eun Nim.
Go on now! What are we going to do
if they come over here looking for you again?
Ah! Look here, it's packed.
That's right. There are different tricks to be successful.
Over here. Please give me one sauced fried chicken and
one marinated fried chicken to go.
Darling! Darling, have a seat here, quick.
What is this?
Why did you bring fried chicken?
This is the fried chicken from that famous store.
Why did you bring these?
What do you mean why?
We need to study carefully so we can develop
new recipes to compete with that store.
That is so, but the real trouble isn't that.
Then where is the trouble?
The problem is that my mom hasn't
answered any calls since she went to study.
What?
Are you behaving like this because you're afraid
your mom is going to meet with the PD again?
I can't just do nothing while my mother meets with guys.
Aigoo! Really! After seeing how you are,
I really hope to have a daughter than a son.
Others can live happily meeting with men,
why can't your mother?
What?
So you mean my mom is going over to her in-law's
house after she gets married again?
Really, how could you interpret my words like that?
That's not what I meant.
What I mean is... look at my parents,
they both are remarried.
Look how well they live together
and how happy they are.
What I'm saying is, if she meets with a man
matching her, would I be this way?
Nan Jung, think about it; what if your
father-in-law was PD Bong.
Would you feel it's fine?
Father-in-law?
That's right! Treating PD Bong as father-in-law
doesn't sounds quite right.
Not just a little, but totally out of the question.
If she doesn't answer again...
- You worked hard.
- Yes.
You worked hard.
Goodbye.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
- You worked hard.
Yes. It's me...
Mother, where are you?
Script discussion ended. We finished just now.
If it's donem come home soon. What are you doing there?
Mother, you should not treat PD bong like that,
do you understand what I mean?
Chul, really, how could you speak
to Mother without respect?
What did Chul say?
That... I'm hanging up.
I don't know. That's why...
you shouldn't make things so complicated.
Writer Kim, there are no difficulties in
this world that could stop us.
Wild... you're still doing wild things even now.
Really, you really want to continue saying that?
What wild thing did I do?
You worked hard all this time, I'm leaving first.
Wait! Where are you going? Let's go together.
Where are we going?
Outside.
I'm tired, I want to take a rest at home.
If you keep on doing this then
I'm going to take some action.
Right here?
So what? Bet I won't do it?
I got it. Let's go. Let's go.
Didn't I say...
Why are we here at a coffee shop?
Over here, here...
Who is he?
Let's go over there first.
You are here.
Gosh, you bring the mother-in-law.
How are you? I'm PD Bong's mother.
What?
Why is only the mother here, where is the daughter?
Aigoo. Aigoo.
That... that... Mother.
She is the one I am dating.
What?
Mother. Mother.
Mother, it's going to burn your mouth.
My gosh, because he said
it's the writer of my favorite TV show,
I was very excited.
This is the writer?
It won't work even if Grandpa knelt down in front of me.
Won Seo, let's go.
Mother.
I said let's go.
That... Mother, please listen to me first.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
My poor child, my poor child.
Her heart must be so hurt.
Don't cry! Nothing will happen to our Eun Nim.
Why are you crying so hard?!
Our Eun Nim... our Eun Nim will be fine.
Of course, our Eun Nim hasn't had a good life yet.
But nothing bad will happen to her.
So stop crying, do you understand?
Hello? Yes, Eun Nim... it's Dad. Eun Nim...
Father, I'm sorry.
I made you worried.
No, don't worry, you will come back home, right?
Yes, Father, I'm coming back home.
So Father, don't worry.
I understand.
I won't worry, and you should come home now.
Yes, come home soon.
Eun Nim says she is coming back?
Yes, she is coming back.
Turn on the heater in Eun Nim's room.
I already turned on the heater in her room a while back.
I should make some cabbage soup for Eun Nim.
Where were you?
Why are you hurting my feelings like this?
You didn't read my letter?
I read it.
Then why are you like this?
If you read it then you should not be like this.
Why aren't you listening?
I'm really all right with it.
If you feel sorry for me, all you
need to do is take the treatment at the hospital.
You heard what the doctor said and you're still like this?
I... only need some quiet...
Quiet for what?
Quiet to die?
I'll take care of my own business.
You can survive.
Did you read through the books I gave you?
There are many survivors in a later term of cancer than you.
Why are you giving up before ever trying?
Eun Nim! Eun Nim!
You haven't left yet?
Eun Nim, let's go inside.
Father, Mother, please ask Kang Ho to leave.
All right, why don't you leave first?
Quick, have a seat, it's very cold outside.
How were you raised? You have parents.
So, are you thinking of dying outside by yourself?
Why aren't you considering your parents?
That's enough.
Why are you saying nothing? Talk to her.
Eun Nim, we heard everything from Kang Ho today.
But it's strange, your father...
I never thought that you would have any problems.
Eun Nim, first of all, you need to take it easy.
Everything is dependent on how you think of it.
There are many incredible things in this world.
Besides, the doctor never said it's impossible.
Is that so?
So... you should think about your father and your mother.
If something happened to you,
more than one or two people will be hurt.
So you should never think of bad things.
Do you understand?
Good, that is enough.
That's enough.
It's me. Father!
Where are you? Come back home right now.
All right, I understand.
Aigoo.
Oh, you came home so soon?
Come over here, have a seat here.
Mother, I'm home.
Mother, what are you doing?
Aigoo.
I told you to sit quickly.
You told your elders at home that you're going for a trip?
What's really going on?
Grandmother, I already said, he went there to...
But this matter is a little bit difficult...
Sae Hun, don't say anything for now.
If it's hard to speak out, why are you still doing it? Huh?
Who asked you to take care of your ex-wife?
You didn't go to work, you have that much time?
We also feel sorry for Youngest Daughter-in-law's condition.
But she is no longer related to us.
That's right.
If you feel pity for her, we can check the hospital
and also pay for her medical bills.
But Kang Ho, you should not get involved directly.
I did not stay by Eun Nim's side out of pity for her.
If it wasn't pity for her, then what?
I... I couldn't stay beside my maternal
mother when she passed away.
This will be a great stone in my heart
that presses on me until I die.
But you should know that I did not divorce
Eun Nim out of dislike for her.
I'm going to stay by Eun Nim's side.
And I must save her, I will never
separate from her again.
You are not separating from her-
then are you going to marry her after you save her?
It's so noisy!
Do as Kang Ho Oppa wants, don't interfere with it.
It's me.
It's me. Eun Nim.
Why are you not talking? Hello?
Mother-in-law! I am very sorry to call so late
Something isn't right with Eun Nim.
Eun Nim?
What's wrong with Eun Nim?
Kang Ho says we should go check out Eun Nim's room.
What?
Yes, we understand.
If something happens we will call you, don't worry.
Eun Nim! Eun Nim! Eun Nim!
Wake up, Eun Nim!
Eun Nim!
My God, what happened to Eun Nim?
What are you doing? Call 119!
Call for the ambulance, hurry up!
Eun Nim! Wake up! Eun Nim!
Eun Nim! Eun Nim!
It's me, Mother-in-law.
I understand, I'll head directly to the hospital.
Does this mean she fainted due to so much pain?
So much pain?
How could it be? How could it be?
It would be extremely painful to make a person faint.
Even though I had pain before, suffered before...
Doctor, please gives her some pain killer.
Please don't let my child suffer the pain.
It would be better for me to bear the pain.
How can I let my Eun Nim, who is as
beautiful as flowers, bear the pain?
Eun Nim.
Aigoo! Eun Nim!
You told me not to cry, how could you cry like this?
We agreed not cry in front of Eun Nim!
Grandma, what is it?
Kang Ho isn't here! Kang Ho...
Looks like last night he went out again.
He probably went to her house again.
What should we do about him?
If in fact Sister-in-law is not doing well,
he probably went there for that.
Her illness is her business.
They are strangers now, why is he going over there?
This won't do, I need to visit their family.
Grandma.
If you go there under your current mood,
you are going to hurt each other's feeling.
I'll stop by there on my way to work and take a look
and ask Kang Ho what's going on with him too.
Would you?
I think it's better that way.
Then you better hurry up and take a look there.
Give me a call after that.
Yes.
Father?
Oh, he went to work.
You go eat something before coming back.
It's all right, I'm doing fine.
How can it be all right?
I won't run away with Eun Nim.
So hurry up and go eat something, hurry up.
In that case, call me if Eun Nim
wakes up or needs anything.
I understand, go ahead.
Eun Nim!
Mother.
Yes.
Son-in-law Baek went to get something to eat.
You better not scold him anymore when he returns.
It's not right.
Although you're like this,
it's not Son-in-law Baek's fault.
Do you understand?
What's your plan for the future?
Hyung, I must save her life.
Hyung, please help me.
Help me persuade Father and Grandma.
I understand, but would it be possible?
We could create the possibility.
I'll do everything that can be done.
Have her take the treatment and the operation.
Where are planning to stay during the treatment?
Her family house is a little bit inconvenient.
I'm not too sure about that,
I'm still thinking.
Hyung, I'll head back in first.
That's fine.
Such youth, such blooming age.
I think of all the neglect I did.
I didn't take care of you,
that's why you are like this now.
Mother, what are you doing?
Why do you think of such useless matters?
You should blame Mother, there is
one or two more people you should blame.
Mother didn't do anything wrong,
it's my own illness.
But Mother, I really want to live.
I really want to live.
Eun Nim...
I'm not scared of death, but I'm worried about what
to do about Kang Ho and Father if I die.
So I really want to live, Mother, I really want to.
If I ended like this, what would
my Kang Ho do? Mother!
If you want to live, then live well.
Why are you having such weak thoughts?
Didn't your father say before,
"As long as you have faith,
you will make it work?"
Would it? Mother.
Would it really work?
Mother, I really want to live.
I really want to live with Kang Ho, Mother.
Yes, you two should live together.
Eun Nim, live on, Eun Nim, Eun Nim.
Why are you so pitiful? Eun Nim, Eun Nim.
Mom!
Who is there?
I'm PD Bong's mother.
Is this the house of Writer Kim Chung Ja?
Yes.
Who is it?
Unni, Unni, PD Bong's mother is here.
How are you?
Yes, why did you come here?
I have something to say.
Are you not going to ask me to sit?
Yes, please have a seat.
So Weol. Tea, please.
Yes, Unni.
PD Bong's mother looks like a tough person.
But what has she come here for?
Please have some tea.
I'm... really thinking of drinking
myself into the sea.
But I need to take care of
this one matter before I die.
I withheld my death thought and came here.
Why is that?
My son wants to marry you, Writer.
Are you going to marry?
What? Marry?
Ah, I suffered a lot to raise him,
selling rice cakes in the market.
How do I describe with just words
the hardship we suffered?
But the son I raised with such hardship wants
to marry a woman that is twelve years older.
What kind of feeling is that?
That... that... there might be
some misunderstanding.
To you, the writer: if your son wanted
to marry some woman twelve years older,
would you agree?
My son is married.
But what if?!
Of course, not allowed.
That's why... I think
I can communicate with you.
This is very expensive sesame seed oil.
I'm asking you a favor.
Have a safe trip.
What is this? What...
Unni, do you really like PD Bong?
I don't know. I don't know, what is this?
Unni.
Is that so? Thank you.
Let's meet again when we have time, all right?
This just arrived by express delivery.
Did it?
Yes.
What is this?
My friend's vacation house,
I borrowed it for you.
You and Eun Nim can stay there together.
Hyung...
Cancer treatment might take longer than we imagine.
The environment is important too.
Take Eun Nim and stay there comfortably.
There is the address, it's very easy to find.
Hyung...
I packed it myself.
I'm not sure if everything needed is in there.
There are stores nearby, so it should be
very convenient. Don't worry.
I worry most about food.
There is no one to prepare the meals.
I can handle most things.
If I can't do something, I can
always ask Eun Nim. Don't worry.
Mother, don't worry.
I'll eat a lot of good things.
Hey, what's going on? Huh?
Unni, your tummy is getting big.
Is it time to talk about that right now?
That's enough, don't yell.
When I see you I feel sorry and pitiful.
Nan Jung...
Eun Nim, I plan to tell Eun Jung later.
All right, Mother, it's nothing good anyway.
She is still studying,
don't disrupt her concentration.
I'll call her later to tell her myself.
All right.
Grandma...
Eun Nim... I need to use the bathroom.
Don't worry, I'll go check.
Why did you check out so soon?
Shouldn't she stay in hospital for shots or such?
There is no need to stay in the hospital
until she starts the chemical treatments.
I would like to take Eun Nim to someplace
nice with fresh air for some rest.
Would you like that?
Grandma, I'll get well,
so don't worry and don't cry.
We are leaving.
Be careful driving.
Eun Nim, I'm sorry.
This girl, is it the time to say that kind of thing?
You should leave first.
Son-in-law Lee, please take her away.
Yes, fighting. Nan Jung, let's go.
Eun Nim, I'm sorry. Sorry.
Hurry up. Go.
I'm leaving. Mother, I'm leaving.
All right, go ahead.
Father...
Go.
Please take care of her, go.
Aigoo. Aigoo, my precious...
Why is Eun Nim's life so hard?
I can't bear to live for Eun Nim's sake.
Mother-in-law, please take care of yourself.
Eun Nim...
Eun Nim.
Is this it?
Yes, looks like this is it. It is.
It's so pretty, is it okay to stay here?
Of course, otherwise why are we here?
Kang Ho, I can walk by myself.
I'm not carrying you because you can't walk.
My dear, did you lose weight? Why are you so light?
That won't do.
During this time, I will let you eat
good food and take good care of you.
Oh, you're home, have a seat over here.
Where is Mother?
Probably she got tired playing with
Yoo Bin all day and has fallen asleep by now.
So... did you meet Kang Ho?
What did you two talk about?
Kang Ho... it's better to leave him alone.
No, ridiculous, it's such an important matter.
They're together... nothing else can be done right now.
What else can't be done?
Can't they live without each other?
What's wrong with starting anew?
Really...
Children's Father, it can't be.
Send Kang Ho to an American subsidiary quickly.
That method won't work for Kang Ho.
True, there's not much time left anyway.
We just need to bear with it till then.
Mother...
What? Am I wrong? Only one year left.
If the child is like that, she won't recover.
Nothing would help now, useless is useless.
If you love me, please come out wearing this dress.
No, you must love me, come out quick.
You understand, right?
So pretty, Eun Nim is beautiful any time.
But, dressed like this, are we going somewhere?
Driving around, having a date.
Let's go.
That's right,
since we're already dressed up so nice like this,
why not make up a little bit too.
Should we?
This is a church!
Oh, it's all right.
Let's pray together.
Both of us are your children.
If it's good, please bless us.
What is this?
Just stay still.
Kang Ho...
We just married, in front of God.
Kang Ho.
Even if you don't want it, please bear with it.
We can't argue in front of the God.
Let's take some photos.
Photos?
Yes, today is our wedding day.
We should take some pictures.
One, two, three.
All done, both facial expressions were great.
Please take care of it.
Let's go.
Ahjussi, may I take some pictures alone?
Yes, come here.
Okay.
Why? More photos?
Yes.
Kang Ho, you go out first.
Could it be...
You are taking memorial photos now!