Think you'll win?
Why do you think I walked up
here in the snow?
- Cold as hell out there, right?
- Yeah, I can take it.
Oh, um, I need an ID for the wine cooler.
I'm clearly over 21...
- Cute picture.
- How much do I owe you?
Oh, ah, $11.36.
Here.
Good luck Wednesday! Root'n for ya.
Oh, hey! Wait up! Hey!
Hey, hey, gorgeous!
Leslie!
OK, I'm up... I'm up!
What time did he leave Kurt?
Hmm? Was it 4 or 5?
He is a big jerk and naughty
boy, Kurt. Yes he is!
Say hello to Momma, Kurt! "Hi Momma!"
"Hello Momma!"
Kurt, that man said you were gonna talk
and it has been almost a year.
No pressure! No pressure! I love you!
Excuse me!... Yeah, you. Sorry. Thanks.
Excuse me. Sorry. Yeah.
Whoops, sorry Mrs. Brands. "Koogler &
Brown," please hold.
"Koogler & Brown", please hold. "Koogler
& Brown", please hold.
"Koogler & Brown", can I help you?
- Hi, I'm trying to reach Steve Mason.
- Who's calling, please?
-"Wendy."
Do you know what this
is regarding, Wendy?
"Ah yeah, I would hope so."
One moment.
I am, so sorry, Wendy. He's not in the
office yet. Would you like his voice mail?
"Yes, fine."
I'll see you at 3 o'clock then.
Make sure Davidson isn't late.
You got it!
Ah, Mr. Mason!
Ms. St. Martin?
I got you a present.
You snuck out last night.
Oh, thanks.
So, if you can make sure all my calls
come directly to me...
...unless I'm away from my
desk. In which case...
Steve?...  Hang on!
- "Koogler & Brown", Can I help you?
-You're busy. You shouldn't...
- Lucy...
- Koogler...
I should be going.
Mr. Mason... "Koogler & Brown",
can I help you?
Who are you calling for? One moment
please, one moment please.
- Lucy.
- "Koogler & Brown", please hold... What?
Ah... ah... don't get upset, the
copy machine is busted.
-Mannn!!!
- It's ah...
...it's bad.
Ben, you cannot put stapled documents
into the sorter.
I didn't.
What's this?
(Phone ringing) Can you get that?
Oh, I don't know how to do that.
You just say "Koogler & Brown,
please hold..."
- ...and just hum a song.
- Oh, OK.
"Koogler & Brown, please hold."
And, I'll just do this from now on, it's
my job anyway.
Oh, no. I don't mind...
Who are you holding for?
Yeah, he's new...
Well then be more careful with it, OK?
Mrs. Brand doesn't need to know
you're doing my job.
She already thinks I'm an idiot.
Whooo...
Whoa... my lord it's cold!
Not that bad.
Umm, you smell good. Is that the
cologne I bought you?
Ummm...
What's the matter?
You sure you don't have
another tuna sandwich?
They go fast.
Tomorrow, I'll bring you two. I'll
set them aside, I promise.
You always say that.
Stop it!... STOP IT!
Lucy, I'm not going to let you
make me the bad guy.
It's not fair!
You don't fit in, Lucy!
Honey, it's 20 degrees and look
at what you're wearing!
You probably don't see it now...
but this is the best thing that
ever happened to you.
Aaaahhhh!!!
That's good. That's a good reaction.
Good for you.
- That's it!
- You'll thank me, really!
Jerk.
Ben?
There's only one tuna today. Do
you want to split it?
Lucy...
I love you, Bo.
I love you, Daisy Duke.
Lucy...
- What Ben?
- I love you.
What?
Eeewww!
Mom!
What, Ben?
Thanks for your help with
the copy machine.
- Are you OK?
- Every thing's fine, Ben, now leave...
Ben, it's your mother. She
says it's urgent.
I suggest you get that... At your desk!
It's me. What's up?
What?
Mom... mom, you're talking too fast.
Thank you, Tom, for taking care of those
contingency plans for us...
Now, let's move on to the
numbers we have...
I would like to continue looking into
that for next week's meeting...
and see where we are on those
totals and then we can look...
at projected numbers for next quarter...
Hi. We're in the middle of
something here...
- Hi, I just want to let everybody know...
- Yes?
That... one night after Steve fucked
me, he went into the bathroom...
...and when I woke up the next
morning, there was shit on the seat.
But I overlooked it, because I loved
him, and I thought he loved me.
Thank you. Have a great day.
Ow!
Oww.
(Car stalling)
Wait... Wait!
- What are you doing?
- I'm sorry, ah.. my Mom is in trouble...
And, my car is not working. It's
probably nothing, but I have to...
Can I...?
You're home.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
Mom!
OK, what's going on? Why
is the door locked?
Ben! Ben! Right here, right here...
Ben, what's the first thing
your gonna buy?
Where did you get that lottery ticket?
Mom?
Ben! Oh my God! Benjamin!
Oh my baby!
Oh honey, you know your
ticket? The lottery ticket?...
Well, I turned it around, and I called...
and then these people were
calling and calling.
And that TV producer over there? He
made me lie to you to get you home.
Oh, I'm so nervous. Oh, my God...
Oh, my heart!
- I'm gonna have...
- We're set for you, Ben.
Where? What? Mom...
Mrs. Keller, it was you who found it?
Yes, yes, yes. My son always takes me
Wednesday and Friday to the...
physical therapist, and uh, his car
is such a mess...
candy wrappers all over the place. So
I said to him...
if you want to waste your money...
Well, I hate to say this... but if it weren't
for good ole Mom, ha, ha, ha...
"You know, answer me one question.
"Why doesn't stuff like that
ever happen to me?
"Well, Ben Keller, I hope you deserve it.
"I don't know how how to out do
that one people,
"but let's see if Justin Timberlake
does the trick..."
Oh Heidi, I know... and me standing
there like screaming like a manic...
Oh, no, that was just a prop they
made for TV...
The real check comes in spurts...
Yeah...
What, it is already?
Ben, it's on again. Are you watching?
Channel 7!
"Report is there is a winner in the Iowa
State lottery.
"A new record of 36 million dollars.
"Won by a young man by the
name of Ben Keller.
- "Congratulations Ben."
-Ben!
Uncle Barry is on the telephone!
"In other news, police are for your help...
"in the disappearance of a young
woman named Leslie Singer.
"Police are not releasing any
information if...
"there is any link to the disappearance
of 2 other young women...
"...throughout the Council Bluff area."
Ben! What are you doing?
Don't you want to talk to Uncle Barry?
Uh, I'll talk to him later, alright? I'm
going to take a shower!
He said "congratulations" and that we
should get a lawyer.
Yeah, OK!
Are you hungry?
I'll be up in 15 minutes!
Okay, okay...
I think you won the lottery...
Try it now!
There you go...
It's fixed?
Yeah, just a loose battery connection.
You should be fine.
- Thank you!
- No problem.
Oh, Hi! What happened? Was your
mom, Pauline, okay?
Oh... She fine.
It just turned out to be, ah...
- ah... nothing. Did you...?
- Good, I was really worried.
I was going to try to call you, but I
don't have your number.
Plus, I wanted to say I'm sorry for
being rude in the car...
- They gave me my notice yesterday...
- You got fired?
You have every right to be mad at me.
You were trying to be nice, and
I was being all "grrr!!!"
So, I'll just say it now... Sorry.
- Thank God it's Friday, huh?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God, did you get a promotion?
Ah, no. I...
Thanks...
Oh, my!
Ben, you won the lottery! This is
so amazing!
- Ow!
- Oh, my God! Are you OK?
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean to hurt you.
Yeeaahh!
Hey! OK, OK, OK! You've got to come
back office Monday, and see me.
For seriously now..
...do not try to handle that money
yourself. I can help you.
Excuse me! Sorry! Can I ah...
Can I um, just get right in, yeah...
if you just...
Thank you.
Excuse me. Sorry.
- Lucy, you're on my foot.
- Sorry.
So, what did you do when you found out?
Did you just freak?
Well yeah, I had never bought
a ticket before.
Luck! I'm buying those dam
things every week.
Well, don't give up.
Oh, yeah. Two people from our
office is going to win
Yeah, really...
Kurt, I've gotta go. I need you
in your cage now.
(Door buzzes)
- Hello.
- Hi. I'm sorry to bother you...
I'm Detective Harold Waylon, and I'm
working on the Leslie Singer case.
- OK, the what?
- Leslie Singer...
Kurt!
- No, that's fine...
- Kurt, what are you thinking? C'mon
I'm so sorry, are you OK?
- That's fine. Besides, birds and I...
- He's usually a good bird. Usually.
- OK, she did what?
- She didn't do anything...
She disappeared and ah... she lives
kinda close to here.
Sorry. Yeah, I've never seen her
before. Sorry about that.
OK...
Well, you keep that picture, the
card is attached. And...
...you call me if you hear of anything...
- Should I be nervous?
- No. Stick with your attack bird there.
You're gonna... you're gonna be great.
OK. Bye!
Mom! C'mon, we can't be late for this!
Ben, I told you I need... Wait.
Mom...
Okay.
Do I look alright? I looked so bad on TV.
- I don't want to do it if I look that bad.
- You look great.
- Oh, I forgot my blusher.
- Mom, you can do that in the car...
Alright.
Thank you.
Did you take out the garbage?
Oh, I missed it.
Shit.
Lucy!
Hi!
Mrs. Keller, hi!
How are you? Hi, Ben!
Look who's here.
Hi.
How are you doing?
What are you doing?
Oh man... just been doing a little jogging.
On the weekends I jog. You
know, here and there....
Then here...
- Say something.
- What?
Well, enjoy. Keep up the ole
pace before I freeze to death.
Talk to you later!
Okay.
What?
Or...?
...how long?... You...? What
are you doing?
This is the newsroom. OK? Right.
- Hi Betsy.
- Hi Jeff.
Alright, and right in here is where we
do the show.
Yeah... OK.
Now your interview comes after the
weather, and before sports.
So let's get you both into make-up.
And then we're going to mic
you with microphones.
OK? And guys, let me tell you, this is
gonna be so much fun for you guys.
Are you ready?
Cause she's on the watch now.
Is she OK?
She's just really excited for the make-up.
City officials reiterate that there is
no hard evidence...
to relate the 3 disappearances.
Meanwhile the Singer family continues...
to hope their daughter
will return unharmed.
Awful, awful, awful story, Lance.
Coming up: Can a trip to the Doctor
be hazardous to your health?
And Josh Kincaid with the weather.
Where is she? Chip is freaking out.
- She's not doing it , Ben. She threw up.
- What?
Mom, we have to. Chip is gonna kill us.
Benjamin Keller, look at your mother.
Just do it without her, Ben.
I'm not doing it if she's not. I don't want
to do it either...
... but we told Chip we would.
- Fuck Chip!
- I'm with her.
But we said...
Hey, do you always do what other
people tell you to do?
That's no way for a millionaire
to behave.
Yeah!
Benjamin!
Don't you think I'm trying?
Shh!!!
Guys?
- They're ready for you.
- Bye, Chip!
You guys are crazy...
We should have gone out to dinner
tonight, and taken Lucy with us.
She's got better things to do, I'm sure.
It's just so funny seeing her again.
Do you remember how close you two
were when you were kids?
You were inseparable.
So cute.
It was a 100 years ago.
She did not have it easy, you know. I
would feel so bad...
You growing up without a father, and I
would look at her's.
Well...
And when her mother died, and
then to see you two together...
- I just...
- What are you saying?
Look, I don't want you to be afraid, OK?
Now that you have, you know...
What?
I don't know, I don't know. I don't know...
I just... a mommy gets tired.
I feel like I'm going to the loony bin.
My son, the millionaire.
No, I'm not.
It's all a dream.
Yeap...
Big changes are coming...
Are you ready?
No.
Yes, you are.
"Hello?"
You about ready?
"Ready and waiting. Where are you?"
- Greenleaf.
-"Did you make reservations?"
Yes, I did, I'll be there in a minute.
"You told them it's your birthday, right?
"Because they have that special cake
that they only give to you...
- "...if you tell them."
- I told them, I told them.
- "What time?"
- I told them about 6.
- "Ben, that's too early!"
- But that's all they had.
- "Did you tell them who you are?
- No.
"Ben, we've been together for 2 months
now.? Haven't I taught you anything?"
Oh... don't start now, OK.
I'm already here.
- Handsome man.
- Beautiful woman.
- Upper body, today?
- No, I skipped.
- I'll do it tomorrow.
- I put you on a schedule for a reason.
You can't skip, you'll screw it all up.
Perfection! Let's go shopping!
Let's go, Ben!
- Which one do you like?
- Is it me, or are they all just ugly?
Ben...
Ah, man, this is what Pauline wants.
She told me.
Well, last year, I got her a Whitman
sampler and she loved it.
That was last year.
It had a little map to find
all the chocolates.
I'm sure it did.
- Hey, listen to me a minute...
- Would you like to look at one?
Yes, the lady with the harp.
Alright then. How about the
mother and child?
Forgive me, but are you
Benjamin Keller?
- Ah...
- Yes he is.
Ohhh... my goodness!
- How exciting.
- Can you hold this for a second?
How about the mother and child?
You went to high school with my son,
Charlie Baton. I'm Sue Baton.
Nice to met you.
But I need your help. Ben, which one
do you like.
Any one of these is fine. Let's just make
a decision and go.
Do you remember Charlie? Because, he
remembers you quite well.
- Who?
- How about a unicorn?
This one's nice too, depending
on the occasion.
Oh, my God!
Oh my God!
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry! Ah...
Oh my God! We'll go... and we'll just
pay for it, and just go.
- Ben, relax.
- Here, do you take Mastercard?
That's fine, don't worry.
You can certainly...
It was an accident. We have another
one like it right here.
Would you... would you...?
No, no, just ah...
Alright, alright, I'll just
bring this back out.
No problem.
- I told you!
- What?
We should go. Let's just go.
Hey, Ben, she has your card.
Just hang on.
- What's wrong with you?
- Let's just get out of here.
Alright, we should go!
Hey Ben, you may not know who
you are, OK, but I do.
So you dropped a... a lady with
the harp. Who cares?
Hey!
You are Benjamin Keller, and you can
do whatever you want.
Do it.
Aaaahhh!!!
What are doing?
You see?
"BEAUTIFUL WORLD" by
Christoffer Hoyer begins...
"What a beautiful world..."
"Everywhere that I look on
down the road...
"You stir, my soul."
"Such a beautiful day...
"Life is smiling, and pushing me
the right way...
"...and then, on the way."
"Yesterday, when I was older...
"I was wise, but such a fool."
"Every page a new beginning...
"now I'm spinning...
"...in the sun."
(Whistling and then fades)
What do you think?
I've never seen anything like it.
- Your mom was so cute today.
- She's your mom too, now.
Yes, and now, it's just us...
I love you.
- I know.
- I mean, you've changed everything...
You know that, right?
Well...
Now, what do we do?
Ben... you know what comes next.
I do?
Wait here.
OK.
("HAPPY WHEN I'M WITH YOU"
by Jody Whitesides begins)
"Doesn't matter, the time...
"...or the place."
"Only know there's a smile,
taking over my face."
"Always seems to be in,
when you're there."
"Justing feeling it inside,
and it's in the air."
"I'm happy, when I'm with you!"
"It doesn't really even matter,
what we do!"
"I'm hap, I'm hap, I'm hap...
"I'm happy, when I'm with...
"Happy, when I'm with you!"
"I'm hap, I'm hap, I'm hap...
"I'm happy, when I'm with you!"
"It doesn't really even matter,
what we do!"
"I'm hap, I'm hap, I'm hap...
"I'm happy, when I'm with...
"Happy, when I'm with you!"
(Song fades)
Ah... You're going to have to
roll me home.
No, you are going to have to carry me.
Let's just get the hell out of here and go
back to the hotel.
OK, I'll just go grab the waiter.
Can you just go get the bill?
- Yes. Of course.
- Hurry.
- They didn't?
- No? Fantastic.
- Ah... Lucy...?
- Let's go.
- Do you have any cash?
- No.
Okay... um...
- Our credit card was declined.
- That's alright, we'll use our other card.
No, that's been dead for days.
No it's not, it comes right
out of your account.
I know...
- It's empty.
- No, Ben...
That's impossible.
Because it's "36 million". I mean, hello!
You know I don't get it all
at one time, right?
I mean, it comes... it's not important.
- The point is that...
- We don't have any money?
That's why I was asking you
if we had any cash.
At all?
Well... ah...
The wedding, the cars, this honeymoon,
remodeling mom's house...
...our new house. It adds up.
Our new house?
I bought us a house. It was
suppose to be a surprise.
How much?
The house?
How much money have you spent, total?
Uh... eight... ty... hund...
Speak up!
Eight hundred thousand.
- In 3 months?
- Don't get mad, alright?
Look, we have our plane tickets for
tomorrow, the hotel is taken care of...
And they'll mail me a new check in a
week or two. Everything will be fine.
- Trust me.
- Great.
How are we gonna get out of here?
14 dollars and 36 cents.
Well, that will be enough to get
us to the airport.
Okay, great. I don't have to eat.
Ohh, look! A black banana!
- Lucy...
- I cannot believe it.
Do you have any idea how
embarrassing that was?
I'll get you another bracelet.
No. From now on, I'm
handling the money.
When it feels good to actually do
something for yourself.
Why do I have to do everything
around here?
Could you please not yell at me?
You have been tipping people
a 100 bucks a pop.
What happens tomorrow when "Mr. Big
Man" can't give anybody, anything?
Please don't yell at me.
You threw away almost a million dollars!
Oh, so you married me for the money?
Is that it?
Dammit.
I'm sorry.
You are?
Is there a problem, Mr. Keller?
No, I'm not awake...
Allison.
Oh... thank you.
Bet you want a tip now.
Mr. Keller?...
Ugh!
Ben! Ben!
Ben, I'm sorry...
"Help!"
"Help me!"
"Stop it!"
Hello?
- "Whoo hoo...
- argh!"
Sorry about that.
Argh... argh... argh...
Gargh... argh... argh...
Shit!
Hello?
Lucy?
Can I come in?
Things to do in Hawaii... What!
Volcanoes.
We should pack.
Just tell me you don't hate me.
Please.
It will never happen again.
I just can't handle the idea of you
being mad at me, alright?...
You're right, you should
handle the money.
It's.. it's.. it's our first fight.
It's our first, and last.
OK?
You really... hurt me back there, Ben.
Oh, no, no, please, please,
don't say that.
You did, Ben.
Maybe, we rushed into all this.
No... I'll do anything. Anything.
Just please...
...Just give me a chance. Tell
me what to do.
I just need to know that you'll never...
...hurt me... like that... again.
Never.
Say it.
I will never hurt you. Never.
No matter what.
I would rather die.
How long have we know each other?
Hmm?
OK, Ben.
Really?
Thank you. Thank you...
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
I love you.
That's OK.
Heyyy!!!
Wow!
Welcome home. My goodness.
So good to see you!
How was it? Was it really great?
Oh.. I'm so happy to see you.
Lucy?
You look exhausted...
- Where's your cane?
- Carl tossed it. I don't need it any more.
- What? That is fantastic!
- Who's Carl?
Carl's my trainer. You know I'm really
worried about her.
- Oh, she is just tired. Honey, you OK?
I'm fine... I'm fine...
Where are we?
Well...
I know you're mad that I did this.
And we don't have to live here, it's
not definite, but...
I thought you might want to see it.
- Are you going to get the bags?
- No, leave it, leave it.
- Kurt!
- Oh, he missed you terribly.
We have to talk.
- Who are all these people?
- Mom, I told you...
I know, I know, but it was too late to
cancel the caterers.
and I thought what a wonderful way
to met you neighbors....
That's OK.
Hi!
Crowd: "Hi!"
I'm Lucy.
How are you all?
Your mother has been telling us about
all your adventures.
Grace and Jonathan live right next door.
I'm just so glad that somebody
bought this terrific house.
Gracie helped me with the guest list.
They know everybody in town.
- Now ask John about the country club.
- Yeah, do you play golf?
He would love that. And Lucy could
swim or play tennis.
Okay.
Girl, you look so cute, my goodness
we miss you. We really do.
Oh, well...
- Are you ever gonna come back?
- What do you think?
- Will you excuse me for a minute?
- Thanks for inviting us!
Hi.
Hello.
Want my drink? You can throw it in my
face. That won't be necessary.
That's strong, though.
- Great house.
- Thank you.
You know, I really have you to thank for
it. Because when we were together
...and you said that whole thing about
about holding each other back.
You know you were right.
OK...
No, really, because I have Ben,
and this house, and...
- You, are you partner yet?
- No, not yet.
- You didn't introduce us.
- I would like to know who did.
She grew up next door. She didn't need
to be introduced. She was just there.
Oh, stop it.
- Well, where is Lucy? Let's met her.
- Yeah, enough of the mystery.
Oh... I saw her around here,
somewhere. She's ah...
Well, she's talking to
somebody right now.
So, how's Hawaii?
Ah... uh... oh... uh... ah...
Ben?
Yeah... uh... No, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Just... uh?
Honey?
- Ben? What's wrong?
- I don't know...
I thought... I'm fine. I'm fine.
Met our neighbors. These
are our neighbors.
This is Lucy.
-Thank you so much!
-You're welcome!
Everything was delicious!
Honey, I'm going to get going.
Oh, Oh, don't wanna come in for
a cup of coffee?
No, no, no. I am so exhausted.
I'm fine...
Well, if you're so tired, maybe you
should spend the night.
Welcome home.
That was fun.
- Did you have fun?
- Yeah.
You scared me though... You
almost fainted.
Yeah?
Yeah, I should get some sleep.
Saw you talking to "Steve Mason".
- Yeah, he was here...
- He's an asshole.
I am well aware of that.
You're not jealous, are you, Ben?
- It's just he's sooo...
- Ben, shut up!
If anyone's gonna be jealous here,
it's gonna be me! OK?
I saw you talking to that neighbor! In
fact, get out of here!
Go sleep on the coach!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry...
I love you so much.
I know.
- But you...
(Blows on her neck)- Pppphhhttt!!!
Ben!
Oh... Uh.... Uh... Ah...
"Our latest victim, Leslie Singer, is
presumed dead...
"at this point, missing for 3 months.
The search goes on...
Ben.
"These are all the locations
where the girls were taken...
Oh, my God.
"...by Det. Waylon...
Oh, God.
"3 girls missing from the Council Buffs
area of Iowa.
"All of them have blond hair. They are
5'6" to 5'8" and weigh 110 to 135 lbs."
I decided it would be fun to dress up
one of the rooms with Ben's...
old toys and trophies from school.
I would hate to see what it
looks like down there!
Ah... this is really not an opportune time.
Thank you so much! It's gonna mean
so much to him...
- Oh, but I've been waiting for Carl.
- Carl?
- My trainer?
- OK, go ahead, and I'll lock myself out.
(Car honks horn)
- "Lucy?
- What, Ben?
"I love you."
Ben, why not just try meth
while you're at it.
Now you're showing me this?
I was here three months ago, I
asked if you knew her.
- I don't think it was me.
- No?
I forgot about it. She never came
back. I haven't...
I'm gonna need your surveillance tapes.
Copy of all your receipts.
We'll get that. Come on, Chris.
What can this be?
Did you slip on a banana peel too?
Door bell: "Ding Dong!"
- Hello.
- Hey!
I'm sorry to bother you on a
Sunday, Mr. Keller.
I'm Det. Waylon, and I'm working on...
... the Leslie Singer case.
- What?
- Leslie Singer.
She's the... well you may not
know. She's the young...
Whoa, Kurt!
- I'm sorry! Are you OK?
- I'm Fine.
- I know this bird.
- Oh!
We're gonna go for a ride, ladies.
Won't that be fun?
Sorry, but I had to dig you up
before the new owners did.
I'll come back for you guys.
Well, tons of people bought lottery
tickets that day.
- I bet even Leslie bought one.
- Why do you say that?
Oh... Oh, well...
Everybody wants to win the
lottery, don't they?
36 million?
You know what you should do?
You should find all the people that
bought lottery tickets that day...
- And ask if they saw her.
- That's a good idea.
Except, I can't do that.
People, for the most part, use
cash to buy tickets.
The only person I know who bought
a ticket that day, was you.
Why?
Because you won.
That's right.
Well... I'm sorry I couldn't
be of more help.
Don't hesitate to call if you
have any questions.
My card is on the picture there.
I will.
Ah, I gotta ask you something.
What?
What's it like?
Oh... ah... Well... ah...
You know how they say your
life totally changes?
Uh, huh.
They're not lying.
You're a lucky bastard.
God speed!
"I have 3 dead ladies, lying in my car...
"My husband killed 3..." Ahhh...
Hello?
Yes?
What?
OK... OK.
Will do, good bye!
"My husband killed..."
- Shannon, get Brentford out of the pool.
- Oh no, that's OK.
If I can wander around in my pajamas,
your dog can swim in my pool.
You can wander around in your
pajamas any time.
So Grace, what is it you do?
- I'm a family planner.
- I'm not sure what that is.
- John, are you doing OK on that drink?
- I'm fine, I must say.
I mostly work with inner city
families, single parents...
- Shannon... Is she home from college?
- Northwestern.
Oh... great!
That's really great.
"I've got 3 dead girls, in my car...
"3 young ladies, that look just like me...
"And I'm bringing him chicken..."
Who's hungry?
What happened?
Oh!...
Oh, my God...
Oh.
What a funny story...
Where did you go?
What?
Um...
Oh, you know...
- The Garden Center.
- The Garden Center...
Wait a minute!
So... I am... just
Leaning over looking at the Azalea's,
and I tripped and fell...
And landed in a pile of mulch...
Oh, you poor thing!.
Crazy.
All the flowers are dead. I mean
it's a terrible location.
I mean it's like... whoa!
Honey, I think that maybe
ah... you should...
maybe you should go inside
and get cleaned up.
Oh, no, no, no, no, I'm fine. Hi
Grace, How are you?
Hi, Grace... Oh! Sorry.
- And ah...
- Jonathan.
Jonathan!
I haven't seen you guys since...
You know, the... welcome home
party, right... that was...?
How long ago was that?
That was last night, wasn't it?
Was it?
And this is Shannon, our daughter.
Lucy honey, you're shaking like a leaf.
- Well that's a very pretty young girl.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
Shannon is a sophomore
at Northwestern.
Do you wanna think about maybe...
changing your hair color?
Do you wanna think doing about that?
Why?
Well, aren't you afraid of that
"Council Bluff Killer"?
Lucy!
Right, that is what they are
calling him now, right?
And you are exactly his type.
Right... am I right? Right?
- Am I wrong?
- Well, maybe you should, Shannon.
We can't let some lunatic govern
how we live our life, Grace.
- We can't?
- Lucy!
She's OK, she's OK. Honey? Honey??
- Sweetie, are you OK?
- She alright? Should I...
She's OK, she's OK. Honey?
Does anyone want chicken?
- I say that's dishonest.
- No, Lady bugs.
Are Lady bugs the one's that bite the
heads off their husbands?
No, that's the Preying Mantis.
- Hi.
Come on in, Lucy.
- Oh, no, you don't want me.
- Come on. Don't be shy.
Is it cold?
No.
It's great.
It is great.
Are any of you guys married?
- It's strange.
- What's it like?
- I don't know.
- They say communication is the key.
And honesty.
- Once the check comes, I'm outta here.
- Right, that will happen...
I am!
It's not that easy.
He can't hurt me. It's all about me.
- What are you doing?
- What?
You shouldn't be out here,
you need your rest.
I just wanted to try the pool.
Here.
It's fine...
You should come inside. I don't
want you to catch a cold.
I'm fine, every thing's fine.
Come to bed.
Let me swim some more.
I'll be in soon.
OK.
Just when I thought I made
some new friends.
I'm sorry you guys.
I really I'm.
I just... I know what I'm doing.
Well, you're up early.
- Gardening.
- Ah. I hope you're feeling better...
... you scared us to death.
Yeah. Very dramatic, I am.
This thing has everyone spooked.
You're not alone.
We just all have to keep a close
eye on each other.
You're right!
So, how are these famous Azaleas?
The what?
The... From the Garden Center?
Hey!
Hi.
Let's eat.
- Is it there?
- No.
Well, it will get here.
- Well?
- No.
- Is there someone we can call?
- I did, and it's a recording.
We're out of eggs.
Sorry.
That's OK.
You know that this will never
happen again...
now that you and I are... you know...
...really a team. I mean, together,
we'll make sure this never...
- I think I'm pregnant.
- What?
Maybe, I'm not... I don't...
I'm not really sure.
I guess it happened in Hawaii, if I
even am, I don't know...
Oh, God...
OK, well ah...
We gotta get one of those ah...
one of those test. Or...
Mom will know what to do.
No, Ben, hang on.
This is fantastic. This is great.
Ben, it's too early to...
Mom, guess what?...
You're just gonna get all worked...
It's probably nothing!
- Lucy's pregnant.
- Oh, God, no...
But we don't have any money for one
of those test. What should we...?
OK.
OK, OK.
Ben...
So mom is gonna go and buy
one of those test.
and you're gonna go over her house
and you're gonna take it...
I'm just asking you to calm down, OK?
We don't have to deal with
this right now.
Oh, my God! Where's the fucking check?
I mean you're eating for two now, and
all you have to eat is eggs?
Jesus Christ... That's it.
You're going to mom's, and I'm
going to call the lottery.
And I swear, where ever that check is,
I promise you, it will be here
when you get home. OK?
Now go.
- I gotta go get dressed...
- No, no, no, no, just go, OK? Go.
Now, Two lines, you're pregnant.
One line, you're not.
OK.
Are you OK? You look exhausted.
It's just been a rough week. How long
is this thing gonna take?
Oh...
I remember while I was waiting
to hear about Ben.
I just thought I was going crazy.
- Hear what about Ben?
- If I was pregnant.
You know, he loves you so much.
You just mean so, so, much to him.
At the wedding, you both
looked so beautiful.
And you! You looked like an angel
sent from heaven.
- Oh, well...
- You did!
Well then, I knew I could stop
worrying about Ben...
See, I'm his mother, and I worry.
I know, that you will give him a good
life. You've helped him so much already.
You know.
I know that... that you are the best
thing that ever happened to him.
You know what he does.
I know that he loves you,
and he needs you.
Why didn't you tell anyone?
There's nothing to tell. What
are you talking about?
Lucy, it's one line.
It's OK. Oh, honey you've got time...
Look, it will happen when
you least expect it.
I promise you!
Oh, honey...
Yes!
Rosemary is not having a baby!
Oh, my God! Finally a little luck!
- I don't understand.
- Nobody is buying that anymore.
The first year of marriage is the hardest.
I mean, that is what they always say...
Fuck you!
Oh, my God!
I'm so sorry. I can't believe I
just said that to you.
- No, it's my fault.
- No, it's not.
I try very hard, but you know,
when they grow up, and...
however, whatever, whatever you did...
Pauline, come with me. I have the car.
Let's just go. Don't pack, let's just go.
- Go where?
- So I don't get the money, right?...
- Who cares?
- What money?
Come on. Pauline...
- No, no, no, he's my boy. I can't...
- Pauline...
No.
I love you.
Benjamin. How are you
doing sweetheart?
No, she isn't.
Honey, I want you to listen
to mommy now.
(Cell phone ringing)
Hello?
"Hi."
Hi.
"Sorry, mom told me about the test."
Yeah, I'm not gonna have a baby.
"Yeah."
Ben, I'm really sorry, but I
can't do this anymore.
"I've got the check."
What?
"It came right after you left."
Oh?
"See you at home."
- Sorry about that.
- No problem.
- You're a busy guy.
- Yeah.
OK, Leslie... guy who bought condoms...
Mom with scouts... a dumb kid...
Guy buying cigarettes...
A mother and child...
Ben, I'm home!
Hello?
Ben?
Don't look at me like that, I wasn't
going to leave without you.
Ben!
Hello?
Come on, Kurt.
There you go. I know it smells
like dead bodies in here.
But you'll get use to it, Kurt. OK?
I did it, Kurt.
I did it.
It's not like I planned it. But
nobody can say I didn't do it.
I got my bird, and I got my check.
Your really gonna like Canada,
Kurt, they have...
Well, I actually don't know what
they have there but...
I just know that we're gonna love it.
I'm mad at you.
I don't know how to begin. I'm in shock.
- Ben, stop it!
- You know, I didn't believe her.
I said you were just upset because
you weren't pregnant.
Now that we are a team.
Do you have any idea how
disappointed I am?
I'm not gonna sit here and listen
to a lecture from you.
Yes, you will!
Ben, Ben, Ben.. Ben.. Ben.. Ben.. Ben...
You can't hurt me. Remember...
remember our little talk...OK?
So, let's just calm down.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm realistic. Now, I know that
marriage isn't easy and that...
I may not be experienced in the ways
of amore. But I know that.
Ben, listen...
I ah... might have married you
under false pretenses...
But, after spending time with
you, I came to really...
... you know, to really, really...
And then you started killing people,
Ben! And it's just too much!
Marriages take work.
This has been our biggest mistake. We
have just been sitting back...
Hoping for a miracle. Well, I've done
a lot of the work already.
Now, the first thing I did, was to
eliminate all distraction.
BEN!!!
That hurts!!
This hurts. Your...
When you kill people, you are hurting
me, and you can not hurt me!
OK, now you're just getting
me on a technicality.
Alright, come with me. I want to
show you something.
Help!
Lucy!
I really need you to be coherent.
I went to a lot of trouble here.
Ben!
Now, Grace here, is gonna help us get
through the rough spots.
I can't do this, I can't do this...
Leave, and she dies.
Lucy, honey, please sit down. Let's
try and act like adults.
OK.
Grace, scream, and I cut you.
OK, Grace... when you have gotten
yourself together.
I'd like for you to tell me and Lucy...
What it is we are doing wrong.
I  told you... I'm a family planner,
not a marriage counselor.
- I don't even have a degree.
- It's the same ballpark.
Ben, let her go!
Just say... something.
Is your marriage based on honesty,
and mutual respect?
Yes!
No, it is not, Ben. I married you for the
money, and you like to kill people.
No... like to kill people? What?
- They're burned in the yard?
- I don't put them there!
That was all you. I thought you
were trying to help me there!
Garden Center? Wink... wink. Here I
thought we were a team.
- A team?
- Who did you kill?
Grace, have you ever wanted
something, so much...
And when you couldn't have it
you had to argh...
- ...but you couldn't.
- You're insane!
- I'm not saying I'm proud of myself.
- You seemed like such nice people.
- Stop talking!
- Such nice people!
We are still nice people, but
we're also in love...
And love is scary, I'm starting
to realize that now.
I don't love you.
- Yes, you do..
- I want to go home.
Well, that depends on my partner here.
Ben, You have a long ways
ahead of you, OK?
Don't live it like this. I'm not worth
it. Not by a long shot.
- I love you.
- I don't love you.
I love you.
- Let me go!!
- Let me go too!
All I want is to be able to kiss, you...
and have you kiss me... And to feel
you mean it. That's all I want.
Ben, I don't know. Maybe if...
- ...I hadn't been so...
- Greedy.
- And you hadn't...
- Killed all those people?
- ...killed all those people.
- Maybe things...
- Would have been different?
- I  wish they were.
I really do.
Suddenly, the money doesn't seem
to matter much, does it?
Grace...
Lucy!
Lucy, we're not done talking!
Get back here!
Lucy!
Please, don't leave me, Lucy!
Look at what you did!
Lucy...
I can't take it anymore. I can't take it...
Just take something sharp, and stab
me with it, and kill me with it...
Bury me under the hedges with
the rest of them...
Excuse me.
No one answered at the front
door. Is everything OK?
Detective!
Mr. Keller, I need to ask you a few more
questions. Do you mind if we go inside?
- I ah, don't mean to be rude, but...
- But what?
Well, we're swimming here. So if you
could maybe come back, tomorrow?
Mr. Keller, I reviewed the surveillance
tape from the...
convenience store where you
bought the ticket.
Yeah?
You're not on them.
Excuse the mess. I'm still unpacking.
Fine. I understand.
So ah, you're asking me how I could
have bought my lottery ticket...
and still not be on the tape?
- On point.
- Well, you're obviously on the tape...
...he just looks different. He's been
working out. He's bigger.
Not that much bigger.
You're on the tape, don't be
stupid, you're drunk.
He's drunk, he's been swimming.
I know why I'm not on the tape.
You're on the tape! Detective, are
you accusing him of something?
Because if you are...
I snapped her neck in the parking lot.
I never even stepped foot in the store.
That's how I'm not on that tape.
Marriage is based on honesty. That
is what Grace said.
Sometimes the truth hurts. I'm sorry.
You couldn't hurt me even if
you wanted too.
Alright, I want you two to sit down.
We're gonna take this as
calmly as possible.
The more calmly we do this,
the better off we'll be.
- I want... the check.
- Well, you don't get anything.
- Unless, it's me.
- Nobody wants you.
You can have me.
Mr. Keller, tell your wife to
give me the gun.
- You don't win. I won't let you.
- Gimme the gun.
- It's not fair!
- Put that gun down, Mrs. Keller.
- Just admit it, Lucy.
- What?
- You love me.
- Shut up!
- Mrs. Keller, give me that gun.
- Just admit it, you love me.
- I don't want too!
- Give me the gun, Mrs. Keller.
Add it to the pile.
Can you turn that up, please?
"They were as nice as can be."
"He invited us to lunch, just
the week before."
"Looking back... looking back, she
doesn't remember that night at all."
"No, I hit my head, very hard..."
"What happened afterwards?"
"Well, after she was home
safe, everyone..."
Is this really "The Sunny Mart"?
Why would I lie?
- Kurt says "hello".
- What are you doing here?
- No, no, I mean he actually says "Hello"
- What do you want?
I ah...
I wanted to make that sure you're OK.
Lucy, I didn't think it was
gonna end this way.
You didn't?
I told them that it was me!
Those women under the hedge...
they had your DNA, or your
fibers, or whatever...
...all over them. I mean, you
shot Detective Waylon!
I know what I did. What about,
what you did?
Well... I think, we should just put the
past behind us...
I asked you a question.
How much does a jury cost nowadays?
Is it expensive? Jonathan and Grace,
they cost a lot of money,
...is there any money left? At all?
Mom says hello.
I'm gonna get out of here, and I'm
gonna set you on fire.
- Did you get any of my letters?
- I mean it... fire!
OK, OK, ah...
I love you anyway.
Wait, wait!
I know you, Ben.
And ah, pretty soon...
Tonight even...
You're gonna go home, and you're gonna
get to thinking about me...
How much you love me. How
we belong together, and...
How you still, don't really have me...
And when some 27 year old blond
woman, about 5'6", 125 lbs...
doesn't come back from
her aerobics class...
Everybody's gonna know, what's, what.
I don't expect to be here much longer.
Not long at all.
- I don't think that's gonna happen.
- And then I gonna set you on fire!
You may be right...ah you
normally are, but ah...
Since you've been here, I just...
...I haven't had that urge.
It's not that I like the idea of you
rotting away in here, I don't...
Get out.
- Get out! Get out...
- It just makes me feel.
...and don't ever come
back here! Ever! Guard!
Guard! Hello, I'm ready to go back.
Take me back!
- I love you, Lucy!
- I'm ready to go. Take me away!
- I love you!
- Screw you! Fuck you!
Goodbye, Lucy!
Ben, wait, wait! I have time,
I still have time left...
Ben. Ben!
Yes?
It's almost been a year now...
I know.
Would you like me to come back?
Yes.
Would you?
Of course.
Tomorrow?
I'll be here.
- Kurt spoke?
- Yeah, I was at the house...
...maybe Wednesday, or Thursday,
and ah...
What did he say?
"Hello"
"Hello", that's what he says. Just
"hello", all the time.
Around... around the clock.
Have you been working out?
Aaahhh....
Ben, no skipping. You're screw it all
up and turn puny again!
I know, it's just...
I really need someone to motivate
me. It's so boring.
Ben, what do you want? Somebody
to hold your hand?
You just have to get in there and do it!
OK...
Hey, just don't say "OK". Just do it!
- OK.
- Promise me.
I promise.
You gonna work that chest tomorrow?
If you find any problems with this sub...
please e-mail me at
xmorobertson@yahoo.com
and let me know.