1994 - Mumbai
sorry! that time this city called Bombay.
a lots of thing chage with the
city name.
name of raod and properties are changed.
fm called finence minester.
not FM radio.
one or two family get the color Television.
two channel and movies of amitab bachan.
we dont have anything else
for pass our time.
boy play cricket and street game
in the street instead of Xbox.
mobile phone is science
fiction for us.
and call rate of Mubai to dehli
is 90 rupees instead of 90 paisa.
police man get 10 or 20 rupees
and street bagger gets 50 paisa.
shoes till clothes and neil cutter till
car all important thing are selling on black prices.
only overseas employee go
to Mc donalds.
and not every one going to overseas.
but not our luch is good.
my brothers exams are finish.
now you will go to bangkock.
so what will i do
you are going to bangkock.
this is danzi. his father is in army
he was 10 years old when he come in Mumbai.
what is different bangkock neitheland.
all are same.. karan i will beat him.
don't say chineese also have feelings.
this is chandu his father is most senierjunier artist
and he is most rediclious.
how much you expect..hmmm 65-/0 how about
you.. l passed its much for me.
and karan you.
Why you asking him? he will do top.
l was no 1 in studies, no1 in sports
i was number one in all
except money.
which make me number one.
today we are going overseas.
without money.
even we are getting money
to going bangkock.
where is you smart guy
he will come.
flight get missed.
just shutup.
l told you to wear shoes
yes l dont have shoes.
take it in socks and you too.
this is the bundle of 5000$
and you be carefull and put in underwear.
underwear? do you have bra? No.
then put in underwear.
put it in karan. only 500$ is allow
you are taking it illegel.
l am too worry then you because
that money is mine.
why you giving me tension
put it in..
i don't want any tension anymore.
i will let you know all game.
now you take dollar and go to bangkock.
in bangkock you do shopping for me .
you take bag and come back mumbai.
i have setting in custome.
l will you give you 10000rs on each bag.
and all trip of bangkock and eating all free.
you understand any question?
Asif Bhai is wine free in flight.
you leave just.
where you see girl and stand over there.
bangkock is perfect palce for you all
you will never come Mumbai.
Madam! What is this?
you are not allow to take inside.
this is not dangerous.
its always in my bag.
l am telling you its not dangerous. Sorry!
meet with her! Bulbul
she is coming with us.
this is chandi, Karan, and
Singh. Hi. Hello Hey.
he mean to say that you are
also carying the dollar.
he definatly put dollar in his bra.
you are not from Mumbai right.
you are not seen like Mumbai girl.
you never say where are you
from? he is not talking.
you just see his expression.
Where are you all?
today is last day so packed good hurry.
then l will take chandu and zingu
to masagh.
l am ok here
come on boy with me.
lf l was boy
l defenatly go.
ok we will be meet after an hour
in hotel.
so you do MBA.
Yes.
although honestly l don't want
to do MBA.
actually my father wants me to
complete MBA and do job in company.
and what do you want
l want to start my won bussiness.
i want my complany is listed in
Stock exchange.
its not so easy to start bussiness
need money which i dont have.
so you do MBA because your father
want you to do it.
karan tell you father.
all fathers is not cool like you father.
you father send you alone to mumbai.
my father even send my sister
to his friend's home.
My father told me what you
wanted to do. and what are you doing?
Modeling l want to be top Mobel
and now Bulbul singh.
so Bulbul singh
so karan all the best.
may be it will come true.
my father always big bussiness is not
big because of money but with big idea.
with a big idea..
l will pay. Why? are you my boyfriend?
l always pay my own.
can l pay my own.
who is you boyfriend.
what l do no goodboy
in Mumbai.
if you kiss me then l will
burn all the clothes.
Father! have you try this shirt.
when you will become serious.
only two months are left for MBA interance.
Father l dont wanted to do MBA.
then what do you do?
Job as watchman.
l am asking the same
What do you wanted to do?
l am not bussinessman like your
Juss Uncle. l am not demanding anything.
sit here
come on.
What is the problem?
l am seeing you for 24 years.
you go out from home in early 7:30 pm
and come home in 9:00 am.
daily you sit beside
of the same desk daily.
you work saturday for overtime
and in sunday you are too tired.
what you got doing all this.
he is right. you shutup.
next year office giving me award
of 25 years services.
l have security.
l won't live like you live.
if l even sale food on raod and l am good
in it then l will be rich man in it.
l only get the revange of
my all efforts.
man should be practicle in life.
practicle that why l am saying
that l don't want to do job.
when you need you dont know.
i will not live like this.
you think l live scare living.
so do what you want.
l wont tell you anything agian.
he loose his carrier and
you are worry about presents.
your father is on the phone.
Father, No... Hi Bulbul.
my father is here.
give me you car.
don't have petrol.
l will fill it.
i am going will bulbul.
i will full the tank.
this is my line.
want chips, refreshment.. No
want condom.. condom.. getout.
you have to run out
look back police is coming.
Where have you been
What happen doctor.
they shift in the room.
They are saying insurance is only 50-/0
how much?
50 to 60 thousand.
l will be back
i give you maney for money.
My man is standing in red channel
so what will i do.
how do i know. last year
lisen! you left the bag there
do as i am saying.
bhai is any problem.
no problem.
its rutine problem.
after getting money he is not
releasing the bag. l have solution.
if he seas the bag
no problem
after one month they oction
and l get setting in oction department.
which l call like 19000
he say sold.
l am trying shoes.
all is yours.
what happen with you.
l wanted to trip more.
do as much as you want
if your mother and father then call him.
ok i will am fix you on flight.
you like this yes that one rebock.
there is only one shoes other one is inside.
why shelf is in only one shoes.
why it is.
only shoes never steal.
shoes is the only its usefull when its pair.
how much duty of it
120-/0.
you remember you told a big bussiness
is with big idea not money.
my client meet with me personaly.
l am think that if we contact
bulbul for five years.
l am staying in hetel holiday inn
come on evening want to talk.
we are giving you contact of 5 years.
instead of it l want
your only five minute.
tiger will kill me
Chandu! yes father l am coming.
Tiger is chandu's father
and chandu really scear with him
l want big money for big idea
That's why l want Jazz Uncle.
so you wanted to important
shoes. Yes Uncle.. 2000 shoes.
how much money you need
two million.
no problem
just bussiness be a good
with the help ofjazz uncle
we are going again bangkock.
this is our first dealing
with a big shoes company. Reebock.
three months.
helf of good send to calcata and
half of the goods send madrass.
karan its call for you
from madarass.
chandu you do madarass. bulbul you
and me go to calcuta. you stay here.
for bussiness you have to
seems like bussinessman
even you don't have money
but you seen richman.
here you cartons.
please open one of it.
can l try
Ofcourse.
give me right one.
i wear left one give me the right one.
these both are left one ..
lts complete consignment.
-yes
how is it possible
All are left.
there is lSD phone
Of Course.
Come in
Hey give me back my money.
Hey You....
what now
i am ruined
Totally Ruined.
and this paper work.
hell thsi paper work
i dont want more loss after claim.
its not enough for you..
please
-dont talk with me.
Go to hell
did you see carefully.
all are right legs.
okay no problem
we send himself left legs shoes to calcutta.
and right leg shoes in madras.
and both way we didnt get return.
and now 1000 right leg shoes in madras customs.
and 1000 in calcutta customs.
his value is zero.
shoes is that item
if its 2 then full if not then zero.
and now its a time to wait.
wait of that time
when customs give tender notice in news paper.
hey stop
stop.
chandu its your calcutta ticket.
you auction is after 4 days.
and your day after tomorrow.
zing i'll call you where you meet me.
old house
if they know then we caught.
i'll get a tiger mocahe and beard.
what happen?
deal is begin with 80thousad.
1 .20 lac
1 .25 lac
2 lac 5000
2 lac 10000
but there is just right legs
not left legs.
auction start from 20thousand
20 thousand
son what you did with this.
its just one side.
our bussiness is scrap.
are you sure you want to bet.
chandu out with 1000shoes from calcutta
and i am from madras
with 1000 right legs shoes.
and we are reached
at old house that is our godown.s
are you like fool
finally shoes are with eachother and
it become a zero value to full value.
now we have 2000 rebook shoes
without paid custom clear duty.
that shoe who have with the money cost of 2000rs
now we have just in 1000rs
where you get me
are you planned to killing me.
where is shoes?
he didnt believe on me.
we are yesterday boys
hwo we given original reebook shoes in less amount.
i just smelling
no need to see any thing.
so laod it
-Zing Come on.
dont worry darling
when you want.
payment at this time.
payment must come
because he know in this rate it must sold
you are tough in bussiness.
from which name
friends and company.
wow friends and company
it good name
and first profit of friends and compnay
10lac rupees.
you import a shoes
where you get a money.
from jazz uncle
yes
my fight with you not with jazz uncle
bussiness with whom.
he is not smuggler
he have a shop
now you exlaining me who is smuggler and who is not.
do know what calling
that the man who work with smuggler.
smuggler
-daddy he is not smuggler and i didnt do any bad work
now till you never meet with zing and chandu
now stop meet with him and bussiness also.
you ruturn back money of smuggler and jazz uncle
no mean
now i am young what i want i know better.
look my son if you want to live in my house
then you did that what i want.
understand.
so i want to leave your house.
-you leave house mean ?
so go now
get out from my house.
what are you doing?
-i am serious
if he want to live in my house
then live like me.
otheriwise go away from here
-dad i am anot live like you i'll be die.
Son please you swear of me.
he is going really stop him.
-Karan
karan
your father give you one advice.
god give you powerfull mind
and problem is that
you know that
if you use this mind right
then life is going good.
if you use this mind wrong
then you'll be ruined.
now your turn.
problem is that i am did
right.
but you already decide
i am wrong.
alright
Go
i leave my house
i dont know how to cook.
what they are talking?
how is it possible it all right leg shoes.
look you check himself
it not complete consignment.
no sir its complete consignemt
what are you saying
now what ever here its front of you.
now do one work you bet all consignemnt on his head.
understand
-return him
how can i return
so you know how much i bared
yes
you are in calcutta also
sir thsi chinese person cheat me second time.
really.
look if i want then i must go to customs.
but i didnt go.
so now you tell me what we did?
we are commision agent
we are happy with small commision.
how much
not more just 15-/0
impossible
so less the 10 -/0
no
so you are kidding
-7-/0
no 3 -/0
5 -/0
-4-/0
its not matter
because you are like genteleman
after this small distance
back to bussiness
bulbul is right
big bussine gro up with big idean not with money.
now our bussiness runiing in whole india.
but tiem is good or bad one day it will be change.
but what happen?
there is change a import policy
-what are you talking.
Tv News]
if he down duty then we are ruined.
dont worry nothing will happen
i am scared
TV News]
how come to 120 to 20-/0
oh shit
duty theft is our bussiness.
now if there is no duty then how we run bussienss.
leave it chandu there is not any thing
what do you mean
now mean bussiness is finished
so now we can open bar
scondral all you drunk
we make a picture.
we sign madhuri on my opposite.
we are bored sitting here
can we go any other way
bangkok
you tell me.
america
Hey scoundral
-Welcome To Mika Usa.
l am too much happy
-what happen you are too handsome.
Uncle who is she?
she is your aunty.
Greetings
Oh She is not blessed aunty
she is casual aunty.
No problem
He is Chandu
You make me jagat uncle
i am jazz just call me jazz
And uncle she is bulbul
-hello jazz.
Hello son welcome to america
Usa
Come lets Go
i told you before if brother in law know
that you get money from me then it will be create problem.
You are right
bro you dont want to leave house.
how much create problem
dont leave house after all family is family
leave it uncle please
No Problem
lts also your house.
Uncle i mean Jazz
where we are Going.
Queens
i booked apartment for you.
i tell him live with me
but know he have a diffrent style.
aunty also live with you
But you are first travel to america in start
No uncle
what is that mean earn in rupees and expence in dollars
we enjoye that time when we earn in dollars.
what is import from india
too many things.
diamonds, handy crafts ,leather goods.
many things
basmati is too much.
Spices , they are like
-uncle can you arrange leather gloves list.
Yes Of Course
Now we are in usa and
ruined all english people.
Thats why new country
New Change.
Style is same
just bussiness is change
First we fix aappointement with biggest
impoters of gloves in new york.
what she did?
Charlie know that in thae rate of 8$
no body earn profit.
but till that he didnt face like us
We Say Yes.
we made thiis order for his same supplier
atleast they like quality.
if he like our things
after that part 2
charlie give us order 1 lac gloves
mean he caught.
Now just bined time.
like shoes we packed left hand
gloves and right hand gloves.
Chandu left hand man and i am righthand man.
We keep this in diffrent godowns.
now we just want to wait.
Now
give wait.
Karan i dont understand about this wait.
Now its right time.
charlies waitjust one reason
he didnt check any one gloves.
before he know he have just 1 lac left hand glove
we want to cash his cheque.
we are disappeared
with charlies money and he just live with 1 hand gloves.
hsi value just 0
But till that we didnt earn money.
we buy in 8$ and sale in 8 $
profit is remain.
we purchase charlies gloves with his cheap rates.
becasue of Zing there is no doubt option.
Finally left hand gloves meet with right hand gloves.
and its become a value of 0 to full value.
now this 1 lac gloves we sale in any amount
that was out profit.
and we sale to whom.
charlie again buy 1 lac glove from us.
that time in 10$
in america friends and compnay first profit 1 million$
now its time to expence.
for enjoy.
What asre you thinking?
l thought we forgot lord.
Today whatever i want i do it
One day i become a very big person.
How much you want to big.
lts Just Start
What are you doing.
if we cant take a risk in life
so what you did?
Karan now lets Go.
Wait i am coming.
Karan i am telling you its enough.
What happen with you?
They dont have respect
where he come from.
What do you think
i dont know hindi?
This chinese are talk in hindi.
- can i abuse you.
he is mad
-where are you going coming back.
why he drink too much?
10 times in 4th week.
Take him inside the room.
-why i take him inside.
you go i want to play more.
i want also.
-hey who is Boss.
what?
Chandu there is running my luck.
please.
lts all play.
hey lets go
why insulting in front of girl.
Hey uncle how are you?
-hey where are you?
We are in aiport we are coming back.
you ruined me.
why what happen?
cops are asking about you.
you supply leather glove to any company.
yes.
they telling you supply wrong things.
really they talk like this.
so uncle ask him why they paid me.
any buyer before buying
he must check.
his things are not sold then
they are blaming on me.
you are right.
lts mean gloves bussiness closed.
yes
every one know about us in market.
if you are hurry then go himself.
hey are you gone mad
why you trat her like that
we are worried and you are worried
about linda.
i am telling go back
its enough.
she is right
movie launched in 50 lac
you have any better idea
i have an idea
but its different
first we buy 1 house
not costly just 1 lac $
and we get a loan from bank.
and after soem month we are selling.
you sold this house to zin in 2 lac dollars.
how come money for buy.
Relax excatly from there
where coem before.
1 more loan from bank.
there is no problem in bank loan.
becase bank manager get his share.
like that when bulbul sold house to zing
we earn 1 lac $ profit.
now zing sold me this house me
into 4lac $
and once again bank loan and we are in profit of 2lac $
like that we are
but one day we must paid money to bank.
not to be paid.
Chapter 1 1 bank have procedure
if no body paid then he get his property.
and one person are less
and bank didnt have any option.
just our property.
his actuall value
just 1 lac $
we expence other money
exactly.
Life is going fast
and we are enjoying
but we forgot we are going on lions.
its too hard going down.
Hey out from here.
dont you slap to linda
she beat me you didnt tell him any thing.
Zing your wine intoxicate
is too much i am not all of them telling.
now a days you didnt leave bottle.
i am drinking
whats your problem.
there is problem zing.
when you play in casinos and publci places
it embarassing for us.
i am embarssed you.
you are too big isnt.
you getting wrong
-you look himself.
you are too big.
you forgot everything.
you always want rent of auto.
you wear my cloths and go to parties.
you said zing my brother my friend.
now today i embarassed you.
you are big man
- yes i am.
yes i am big man.
because i am also want to more big
because i think big.
i am big man you are street boy okay.
oen we did for him
and they are talking on me.
yes i am big man you are poor
whatever you want do it with me.
now you are big and i am small.
and there is no friendship continue in
small and big.
and if there is no friendsship
then what need in freinds and compnay.
dont talk more
-dont you touch me.
its because of you.
you threating me this company
not running without you.
i dont want your company
keep your company withyou.
first send me then talk.
what you did
-i am doing are you gone mad.
bank calling me and ask me
how you know chandu.
from when
karan is there any problem.
uncle chandu getting loss
that y he didnt paid payment.
maybe bank takeover his property.
why they talk about my loan.
i am your sponsored
thats why i think i am with you
l'll take care of this.
Okay Bye Bye
Greetings
-Will you call to karan
is he leave any cheque for me.
there is a cheques
what name? Ms Sahani
i think karan made name of pamela kapoor.
leave it if you didnt get
then - one minute.
i am sorry i thought you know that.
what?
Karan was marry with one girl Pammi.
in the court
for green card
This marriage just contract for green card.
lts fast style every one did it
-why you didnt tell me karan.
becasue i dont want to hurt you.
-today you did too much hurt me.
if you come to me then
i give you permission himself.
you planned all thing and not ask me.
why i am asking with you.
what i ask with you and why?
l did big mistake.
i am not in with your any releation.
there is no space for me in your future plan.
i did all thing for our future plan.
you know how much this bussiness is risky.
as you know.
any time we are going back india.
and now i never go back to india.
you know that.
our future is here
after getting green card
i'll marry with you and settled here.
what is wrong?
everything is wrong damn it.
its just paper never ever any thing change.
everything is change kara because you
are change.
so what every person change
whats a big del.
please karan i want to back my sweet karan.
-you know that sweet karan who agreed with you everytime.
she leave the house and you leave.
is any one stop her.
leave her.
you want to talk with her.
Linda and me decided to live together.
we are opening a video libarary
in jackson heights.
Linda and me thinking..
we wanted to seteled
l don't want to hurt you.
l will not do work with you anymore.
and lisen you also left this work.
why don't say that time when you want
new house and new car.
l purchase you a Benz.
now you get much
so l am doing bed work.
we are not partner anymore
but when you need my help l will available.
you will help me.
can l say something.
this is my idea
and only my investment.
who take you to america
so l help you not you did mine.
you are are rascals
you just leave.
lisen! can i say something
what you all did this all.
you did this all with you because you want
be rich so you need us.
you only trust us we are
partners only partners.
without us you are nothing
don't think you did help us.
we are friend and we will be
the friends ever.
hello! hello!
karan.
you are lisning my voice
my child karan!.
what happen my child
why are you crying.
let me know first where are you
talk to me my child.
My all which l earn in my
whold life is in this room.
even l say l am the richest man
in this world.
because i have my
bueatifull sufering wife Maya,
My bueatifull daughter Hannu,
and my son in law Rohat is with me.
with them all which l earn my respect
in my whole life is made me rich.
l have to get this award with
a humble feels.
but l will not get with humble feel
but get it with Proudly feel.
my worth of my 25 life is
not earn form wrong way.
thanks for make my ordinery
life into extra ordinery life.
you have to correct you mistake.
Mr Karan kapoor we have
arrest warrant of yours.
lisen that's mean if you return
70-/0 of bank's money.
then they drop the crimnal case of yours
and you only have civil case.
you will be priosner only for 6 to 8 month
we are four partners
l don't have even 25-/0.
l am not here alone. l am here
for all three partners.
you take out friend from the company
now we were only partners.
there is only company left which
is yours.
you not only did this all
we all with you.
we were so this is stickly bussiness.
Mine, Chindu and singaniya.
you will get your 70-/0
after then all is clear.
we are free and quit.
you give the order l will
back after use washroom.
if you are paying the bill then
give my bill.
l know you only earn 10-/0 a day
but althought you take a coffee for me.
you only of yours boyfriend or husband.
l call you and l try to contact you
l don't want that type of father of my child.
l know that's why l am here
for you.
l will be best father and best
husband in the world.
you will also proud when you see me
like when i see my father.
lisen! will you marry me.
that's my line.
they reject all the consigment.
see them its it dry
all the color is blitting.
color are changed after washing.
They are saying to case in party.
party is belong to madrass
l case on him in lndia.
l didn't tell you bed news yet.
how split this news in stock market.
shares are go down 30-/0 more.
be relex uncle. how can l be
you know how is 30-/0.
you just leave
you did something worng.
you made another problem
for me.
l didn't do wrong.
will do right.
what will you do.
let me know the names of your big custoers.
and give me 7 shirts in your consigment.
what you will do?
l have again a big idea.
but l wanted to correct my old mistake.
l have to get friend in circle from
friends and company.
thank you.
Karan! that's all right but linda
do dancing in show. she won't do this.
l won't do with you all.
i need you all.
help me my friend.
you are saying this.
Yes.
l will handle linda.
can you take a wine for me.
l am big fool.. l know man.
l am big....
are you kidding me karan.
this all is not your but its
because of you.
can l say something
l just fedup with all this.
you. l never use wine anymore.
and there is no chinesse girl in india.
l never respect her.
and l am glad that she is with you
karan share percent is down 40-/0
its mean 12 $. l know.
you purchse not much
but buy small small quantity..
is it important to wish them seperatly.
no bilit the colors of shirt to another.
what? 1 1$ purchase more.
not this.
first shirt wash one time.
second two time and seveth one is seven time.
colors are change after
every wash.
so in the price of one shirt a
single man get seven shirt.
they think this is not normal shirt.
they give me trail order of 5000 shirts.
if they sold l will get big order.
they didn't call so fast
they take time for sale those shirts.
look that news in front page.
this is the senier dancer of mickal jackson
belong to india we have to take profit from it.
how much l say you to wait for while
call him.
hello my friends
how many more pieces do you have.
load all the shirt and send.
now purchase how much you
wanted to much.
at last they give me
big orders.
when that news reach to stock market
uncle compnay shaires gone again high.
before the selling of shirt we have to
purchase all the shaires.
and that zingu and chandu doing
l loose my all money to purchse those shaires.
if it not happen then you see
go wallmart and check.
chigao party need 2 Million shirts more.
shaires are got high.
now time to sale the shaires
and earn money for friends and company.
which the loose because of me
that time to return them all.
we four and jazz uncle are partners
of friends and compnay.
our compnay is also public and
its registered in stock exchange.
that was my dream
new office new house new car
all are new but somthing are never change.
now l have all like father.
good friends.
and very important is my father
today he feel proud on me.
father told me if l use my brain
in right direction then l will be succesfull.
He was right.