[RADIO CHATTER]
Give 'em room!
Hold the line, gentlemen! Look left, look right!
Hold the line!
It's here. It's here.
Calm down, buddy!
Let him go!
Let him go! Let him go!
Easy. Easy. Let him go! Let him go!
Here!
Here! It's here!
It's here!
I've gone over the charts you've sent...
... and consulted another neurologist, who works with me here. We are alarmed by two things.
The deificiency in lipid metabolism and severely diminished enzyme output.
Right. That's exactly right.
Both indicate Lysosomal Storage Illness
Are you the boy's primary physician, Doctor...?
Scully. Dana Scully.
And you tested his lysosome function?
I think you have all my results there, doctor.
My fear is that it's a Type-2 degenerative brain disease like...
...Sandhoff Disease. That his enzymes aren't clearing the lypids from his brain, causing atrophy.
If you suspect Sandhoff Disease, I'd test the boy's levels of hexasaminidase.
I've done that. What I am looking for here, doctor, is a course of treatment.
There is no treatment for Sandhoff.
If there were, I'm sure you'd tell me.
Hi, Christian. How are you feeling?
Okay, Dr. Scully. How about you?
Me? I'm doing just fine, thank you
You get some outside opinions?
Yes.
We're gonna do some more tests.
Dana Scully?
Doctor Scully, I'm looking for Fox Mulder.
- Special Agent Drummer. I'm with...
- I can guess who you're with.
The FBI urgently needs to speak with Fox Mulder.
I don't work with Fox Mulder any longer. I don't work with the FBI...
If you could contact him...
... it might just save the life of an FBI agent.
What's up, Doc?
You've become awfully trusting, Mulder...
... for a man wanted by the FBI.
Eyes in the back of my head, Scully. "Auf einer Wellenlange" the Germans say.
It's a precognitive state often confused with simple human intuition...
... in which the brain perceives deep logic, underlying transitory human existence, unaided by the conscious mind,...
... materializing much as you did just now.
Although if you'd actually materialized, you'd be rapidly dematerializing.
But who believes that crap anymore?
Well, they do at the FBI, apparently. I had a visitor today, Mulder.
THE FBI wants your help finding a missing agent.
I hope you told them to go screw themselves?
They say 'all is forgiven'.
That they'll drop all charges against you if you come in and help them solve this case.
The FBI will forgive me?
They put me on trial on bogus charges and tried to discredit ...
... a decade of my work. They should be asking me for my forgiveness, Scully.
I think they are. Desperately.
How can I possibly help these people?
Someone's come forward with some promising evidence.
A psychic, he claims.
It's a trick, Scully, to smoke me out.
If the FBI wanted to get you, I've no doubt that they could.
I think they'd just be happy to have you out of their hair.
Good, because I'd be just as happy having them out of mine.
A young agent's life is at stake.
Mulder, I know I don't have to say this, but it could have been you once.
Or me.
You know, the truth is, I worry about you...
... and the effects of long-term isolation.
I'm fine here.
I'm happy as a clam.
I'll tell them your answer.
(Whispers) Shit.
Okay, I'll go...
... under one condition.
Thanks for the lift!
Don't thank me! I didn't send it!
Wait here.
Come in.
Excuse me. They're here.
Thanks for making this happen. I am special agent in charge Whitney.
Dana Scully
87.
Fox Mulder, I believe?
I know this is awkward, but welcome back. My team and I appreciate your trust.
Well, trust being what it is, what if I can't help you? Or your agent turns up dead?
The past is the past.
I know your work on X-Files cases here and believe you to be the best chance Monica Bannan has now.
How long has she been missing?
Since Sunday evening.
Almost three days.
I know you know this, but, after 72 hours, there's slim chance she's still alive.
We have some reason to believe that she is.
There so far, we have no evidence to the contrary. And the facts give us hope.
Soon after she goes missing, we find this. A severed arm.
- Where?
- About ten miles from her home.
I don't understand. It's a man's arm.
It's a match for evidence found at or near the crime scene. Blood or tissue?
Blood. Found in her garage and on the tool that matches the wound.
- I take it you were led to it?
- Like a needle in a haystack.
By someone claiming psychic powers.
Joseph Fitzpatrick Crissman.
- And you think he's full of shit.
- What makes you say that?
I'm psychic!
- Father Joe was...
- Father?
- he was a priest?
- Catholic.
He cold-called six hours after Monica Bannan was reported missing...
... claiming a vision of her. A psychic connection.
- And she tells you she's alive?
- That's right.
Have you found any other connection?
- To Monica Bannan?
- No. That's why I sent for you.
I need to know we're not wasting time.
Well, he's a religious man, clearly. Educated man.
He took right action. Said nothing to cast doubt upon himself. He has no material connection to the crime.
You are wasting time, only it's mine and your agents.
There is a question of credibility.
If you have no reason to doubt the man, why doubt the man's visions?
Can he lead us to Monica Bannan? He gave us a man's bloody arm in the snow.
This is not an exact science. If it were me, I'd be on the guy 24/7. I'd be in bed with him...
... kissing his holy ass.
Father Joe is a convicted paedophile.
Maybe I'd stay out of bed with him.
What is this?
Dorms for habitual sex offenders.
Dorms?
They manage the complex and police themselves.
Father Joe lives here voluntarily with his room-mate.
Just avoid the Activities Room.
Joe?
- Tell them to come in.
Father Joe?
Excuse the mess. I haven't been sleeping.
- Father Joe, this is Fox Mulder.
- Okay.
He'd like to ask some questions.
Actually, I'd like to ask something.
What was it you were praying for in there, sir?
For the salvation of my immortal soul.
And do you think God hears your prayers?
- Do you think He hears yours?
- I didn't bugger thirty-seven altar boys.
That's a colorful way of putting it.
- I have another word, if you'd like.
- I'm sure you do.
I have to believe He does hear me. Or why would He send these visions?
Maybe it's not God doing the sending.
You call them visions.
Do you see them?
With what you might call 'my mind's eye'.
What do you see?
I see the poor girl being assaulted.
I see her putting up a fight.
I hear dogs barking.
Where?
Can't tell.
But you see her alive?
No, but I...
... I feel that she is.
Can you show us how you do it?
I don't know if I can do this right now.
Maybe it would be better if she wasn't here.
Maybe what you see is a way to try to make people forget what it is you really are.
Jesus, Mulder!
So much for kissing his holy ass.
I'm sorry.
I've been too long away from this business, or not long enough.
No, you were good in there.
All I had were questions.
But you pushed him, challenged him. Like old times.
Well, he's a creep and a liar.
He knows who did this, and they're supplying him with information. Look where he lives!
And this arm they found?
This wasn't severed in any fight. It was cut cleanly, chopped off.
And tell me how he's been able to lead them straight to it...
... and not even muster a guess as to where the victim is.
And two things you're gonna find in the next 24 hours:
A dead agent and that this Father Joe is a big, fat fraud.
You could be right, Scully.
You could be right.
But what if you're wrong?
What are you doing?
Gonna take him for a ride. See just how psychic this Father Joe really is.
Yeah, well, have some fun.
Scully, it's gonna be me sitting next to him.
Thanks, but I've already been taken for a ride. Anyway, he doesn't want me there.
I want you here.
This isn't my life any more, Mulder.
I'm done chasing monsters in the dark. I think you've done all they've asked of you here too.
You know, no-one says you have to stay here.
These people need my help.
And I could really use yours.
Are we getting warm?
You tell us.
I don't have a clue where we are.
That's all right. Everybody works differently.
Are you the Good Cop?
I'm a non-cop.
This girl...
... this agent Bannan of yours...
... I haven't a clue of the connection.
There's always something, however small.
And who made you the expert?
I once investigated a series of cases involving unexplained phenomena for the FBI.
So you believe in these sort of things?
Let's just say I want to believe.
And his sister was abducted by E.T.
Is that true?
It was a long time ago.
She's dead...
... Isn't she? Your sister.
This is where she was taken.
Your agent.
This is where she was attacked.
I want him to see the crime scene.
No, it's...
This isn't right.
You've brought me to the wrong house.
Pulled that right out of his ass.
There were news crews out here, covering the scene. Maybe he recognized it from TV.
Yes, but why?
- Why?
- Why do it?
Why go to such great lengths to create such an elaborate fiction?
Expiation. Forgiveness of his sins.
He's written dozens of letters to the Vatican pleading re-engagement with the Church.
It's an odd way to impress the Holy See.
Voice of God speaking through a man? I think that's been a winner a few times.
So you think he's guilty too, huh?
We have to consider him a suspect.
But you've found no connection to the crime.
Don't think my guys have stopped looking. And they think they're gonna find one.
Yeah, but you don't, or I wouldn't be here.
I'm not the most popular girl in the FBI right now for pulling you in here, believe me.
I wasn't exactly Miss Popularity at the FBI myself.
But you've dealt with psychics before.
Luther Lee Boggs, Clyde Bruckman, Gerald Schnauzer.
I went through those cases. That work was extremely impressive.
Yeah well, I'm only half the team.
But it's your insights I need.
She ran way. She tried to escape.
There were two men. But she couldn't... He pushed her down.
It was here. It was right here.
And then they put her in. In the back.
- Where?
- The car. No!
It was a truck, a truck with something on.
We have to find her!
She's in pain, great, great pain.
- Tell me Where!
- I don't know. I can't see!
We need to find her!
I can't see!
'Cause he's pulling it out of his ass.
Father Joe?
Hi, Christian.
You're looking very bright-eyed this morning.
I was thinking.
Yeah? What were you thinking?
How I'm going to get out of here.
Well, you know, I'm thinking exactly the same thing.
Can I get out of here soon?
What's wrong? Has something scared you?
The way the man is looking at me.
What man?
Don't be afraid.
I was just looking for those.
I wanted to go over them myself and the results of new tests that you ordered.
That isn't really your purview, father. It's his primary physician's.
It is in my purview to see that all of my physicians are making the right choices.
For their patients and for the hospital.
Can I have the test results, please?
We are here to heal the sick...
... not prolong the ordeal of the dying.
There are other, better facilities for the boy.
I'm okay!
I'm fine.
I can feel you thinking.
Sorry. I can't sleep.
I think I have a little something for that.
Just a little something?
Thank you.
What's the matter?
I have a patient. A young boy with a rare brain disease.
And he's very, very sick
Why haven't you told me about this before?
I thought there was something I could do.
There's not?
There's radical treatments, but nobody wants to talk about those.
Even the experts say that nothing to be done.
Nothing, but...
Nothing, but let him die.
So I'm lying here, cursing God for all His cruelties.
Do you think God is losing any sleep?
Why bring a kid into the world just to make him suffer?
I don't know, Mulder. I've got such a connection with this boy.
How old is he?
You think it's because of William?
I think our son left us both with an emptiness that can't be filled.
Just go to sleep.
Let me curse God for a while.
Thank you.
Scratchy beard.
- Oh, there was something weird on the toxicology report of the severed arm.
- What?
I looked over the FBI evidence reports again.
In the tissue there were traces of a drug ...
... that's commonly given to patients who've been injured by radiation...
... and traces of a drug called acepromazine.
Why is that weird?
Acepromazine is an animal tranquilizer.
Now I can't sleep.
Mulder?
What is animal tranquilizer doing in the tissue sample of a man's severed arm?
I can't even begin to speculate.
He said he heard barking dogs.
Who?
Father Joe.
Mulder, what are you doing?
Is this a tranquilizer you might give a dog?
He's a phoney, Mulder.
He pulls these so-called visions out of thin air and now he's got you straining to connect them.
When I see a man cry tears of blood at a crime scene he recognises without ever having visited...
... I need to go out on a limb. You know what I'm saying?
Tears of blood?
Some trick, huh? How do you fake that?
- Hello?
- Doctor Scully?
I have Dakota Whitney for you.
Can you hold on a second?
I'm sorry to call at this hour.
- Has there been a break?
- Dod they find her?
We're pursuing another lead.
The same source?
Same source, new news.
It's here.
It's here. Turn up ahead. At the barn.
One more time. Ten minutes!
- Did you find her?
- No.
What did you do?
You said there was news.
The news is our psychic led us the exact same site he led us to before.
We're gonna find it.
That's what you keep saying.
We're going to find the body.
- You keep telling us she's alive.
- She is.
We can do this all night.
These guys are running on empty.
I'm sorry for bringing you out here.
Hey! Let's go fellas!
Bring it in! Let's go! Bring it in, gentlemen!
It's time to go home!
Tell me.
Tell me what you see.
I see a face.
I see eyes staring out.
Who?
Who is it?
It's unclear.
Like through dirty glass.
It's out there.
I know it.
Scully, what does he mean "like through dirty glass"?
- Mulder
- What?
Stop!
Okay, just feel free to give up like everybody else.
This is not my job any more, Mulder.
That's right. You're just like my booking agent now. Right?
You're right.
This is my fault.
What do you mean, it's your fault?
For getting you involved in this.
No. No. It was the right thing to do, Scully.
This is not about finding an FBI agent.
This is about you trying to save your sister.
My sister is dead
it hasn't stopped you from looking for her.
Mulder, I have been through this too many years with you believing you can save her.
You can not save her, not now, not ever.
I'm gonna need those men back!
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to ignore you.
This it! here it is!
This is it.
We need shovels.
It's solid ice.
No. It's dirty glass.
Flashlight?
You're gonna need resources.
We need equipment! Concrete stays and a back hoe!
You two get on the line. You two, come with me.
Don't give up.
Please!
Get me out of here!
Help!
Let me out of here!
Please. I won't tell anyone.
I won't tell anybody. Just let me go.
I just want to go home.
I did not mean to hit his truck.
I didn't mean to do it. I didn.t mean to hit your truck.
Wait, wait!
Where? Wait! No!
What is this place? Who are you?
Please! Just get me outta here.
Get up.
I can help you get outta here.
HELP!
I think we can resolve, then, in good conscience and without objection...
... to relocate the patient to a facility suited and more...
... humane to his condition.
As you and I discussed, Doctor Scully...
... I was just informing the staff and doctors of the hospital's decision on Christian Fearon.
I'm sorry? What decision?
To relocate the patient to a hospice who will manage his palliative care.
That was a discussion, not a decision.
Well, it's been discussed here at length with no objection from your colleagues.
I have an objection.
You, Doctor Scully, have a patient with an untreatable condition.
Now that's very sad and unfortunate and nobody disagrees with that.
But he is my patient.
Unless you've come here today with a cure for Sandhoff Disease...
... we all ask that you let the boy go in peace.
Thank you.
I'd like to wrap up, so that we can get on to today's good work.
We have the final matter of a patient in intensive care, Doctor Willar's patient, I believe.
Admitted after suffering myocardial infarction.
There is a treatment.
The matter is resolved, Doctor Scully.
No, it's not.
The disease can be treated with interthecal stem cell therapy.
You're not serious? Don't put the boy through hell.
Would you do it if it was your son?
It's not her son and he's not yours.
And it's not an decision for hospital administration. It's his doctor's.
If you want to challenge that, you can take up the matter with a higher authority.
I have taken it up with the highest authority, Doctor Scully.
As should you.
Come on, pick up.
Come on!
Come on, answer!
"This Dana Scully. Please leave a message."
Hey Scully, it's me. I keep leaving you messages. Here's what I wanna tell you.
The woman's head in the ice, it's not the agent's. It's not Monica Bannan's.
We don't know who she is or why she's there, but so far...
... we have pulled eleven discrete human limbs from the ice and we're not even done yet.
Each one a clean cut, too. An exact match to the previous amputation you noted, Scully.
It looks like somebody's been dumping body parts in the ice for months, possibly years.
And there appears to be no pattern to the limbs. Men and women, all with healthy, undiseased tissue...
... according to forensics.
Which suggests to me that they are victims.
But here's the thing. What I need you to know.
We found more traces of your animal tranquilizer.
I do not know what the hell that means, but hopefully you cam make sense of it.
- Anything?
- No, I can't reach her, but this is going to make sense, this is a break. I can feel it.
Your feeling it, Father Joe's feeling it. All I'm feeling is my head spinning.
It is a serial case you've uncovered. You're gonna solve a dozen murders here.
Yes, but I'm no closer to finding my agent.
We're gonna find her. I know it.
Well, she may have to stand in line.
I see a woman's face.
Another woman, taken from a car.
She's being held...
... in a box, I think.
Is she with Monica Bannan?
I don't know.
Is it the same men that took her?
I think so.
Yes, it's the same men.
Do you see this or are you just telling these people what they want to hear?
- No!
- No, you don't see it?
No, it's the same men.
I want a car ready.
- To go where?
- I don't know yet.
- I don't believe this.
- That's been your problem from the start.
I can get you a car.
And a list of missing persons in the greater area for the last 48 to 72 hours.
- Hi.
Cheryl Cunningham, 34, never made it to work last night, no-show at home either.
There's no blood on the air bags. Driver's side window knocked out.
Keys in the ignition. Surviveable crash with a seat belt.
She sets off, take a shortcut.
Gets tired. Sits down and falls asleep. Happens all the time.
Pretty hard left turn for such a long, straight stretch of country road, don't you think?
But why settle for my opinion?
I'm sorry. I'm not getting anything.
What a  surprise!
What a  surprise.
I think we're done with Father Joe.
- We're not quite finished.
- What is that?
It's a medical ID bracelet. I noticed your missing agent wore one too.
- What are you thinking?
- Pop the trunk.
This isn't gonna do her much good.
Gym bag.
It's a bathing suit. It's frozen stiff.
- Chlorine
- Where's the nearest public pool?
Hi. We're hoping you can help us.
Would y'all like lockers?
No, we're with the FBI. We'd like to show you a photo, sir, if you don't mind.
Why would I mind?
Do you know this person?
Let me see.
These young people look so much the same.
- Do you have a sign-in register?
- Yes, I keep one every day.
- I'd like to see yesterday's. - I threw yesterday's away.
Excuse me. sir.
Doesn't he know that's the women's side?
Hi Christian.
You've got a whole bunch of people taking really good care of you today, okay?
What?
Now you look scared.
People say I went underground!
I'm sorry, Mulder.
I've got to keep my focus here.
It's the boy, isn't it?
Yeah.
I thought there was nothing to be done.
I'm taking a big chance on something.
A radical and extremely painful new procedure.
Last night you said that wasn't an option.
It wasn't last night.
What changed your mind?
When will you know if it's working?
- There's a series of these procedures and I won't know until they're all done.
But that's not what you came to talk about.
- There's another woman missing.
She and the missing agent swam at the same pool.
We found that the agent kept a locker there. We think they were stalked there, both of them.
The women had medical ID bracelets and they both had the same rare blood type, AB negative.
Organs harvested for transplant. That's how they were targeted.
Donors and recipients need match types. Someone using that pool knows that.
Black market. Somebody filling orders.
Would they have access, recipients, hospitals?
That's your world, Scully. Your knowledge of it will save time and time is our enemy.
You can start with the transporters. Call the Richmond DA.
No. I need you on this with me.
No. No, Mulder.
You asked for me to get involved, Scully. Now I'm asking for you to stay involved.
Oh, Mulder.
You helped them already. You broke the case for them. Why don't you just let the FBI pursue it?
We are so close now.
- I'm asking you to let it go.
- It is not that simple.
No. It's complicated.
What's this supposed to mean?
Something that I knew would happen, that I've been afraid of and haven't had to face until now.
What? Just say it.
I am a doctor, Mulder.
- That's not my life any more.
- I know that.
You're not understanding me.
I can't look into the darkness with you any more, Mulder.
I cannot stand what it does to you or to me.
I'm fine with it. Scully, I'm actually okay. I'm good.
Yeah. That's what scares me.
Where else would you want me to look of you want me to find these women alive?
I'm asking you that you look at yourself.
Why?
I don't think I'm the one who has changed.
We're not FBI any more, Mulder.
We are two people who come home at night.
To a home now.
I don't want that darkness in my home.
Scully, this is who I am.
It's who I've always been. This is who I was before I met you. It's what I do. It's everything I know.
Write it down. Put it in a book.
Are you asking me to give up?
No.
I can't tell you to do that, Mulder.
But I can tell you that...
... I won't be coming home.
Scully.
Mulder, I've got my own battles to fight.
Don't do this.
- Please don't argue with me.
- Don't do this now.
I don't know what else to do.
Good luck, then.
You too.
Doctor Scully?
We would like to speak with you if we may...
... about Christian.
- Have you been in to see him?
- Yes. He was sleeping.
But...
We've change our minds -  about going forward with this new treatment.
But you don't even know if it's working yet.
We think Christian's been through enough.
We want to put our faith in God now.
I see.
- It's nothing against you.
- No.
If you were a mother, you'd understand.
Have you spoken to Father Ybarra?
Yes. But the decision is ours.
What if it did work?
What if we found we'd made the wrong choice by stopping?
Are you saying you can save my son?
I'm saying I don't want to give up now.
All of a sudden, the plane gears up and we're back up in  the air again.
I say, "Honey, isn't this fantastic? We're gonna die together."
It turns out that there was a plane on the tarmac...
... and we missed colliding with it by seconds.
We were in love and it was romantic.
Sir? Excuse me, sir. Can we talk with you a minute?
I'm transporting vital organ.
That's what we'd like to talk to you about.
This is my job. I move very quickly. I don't have much time.
Please, sir. Step over here.
My name is Robert Koell, I'm with the District Attorney's office in Richmond. May I see your paperwork and license?
I have green card.
- What are you transporting?
- human liver for transplantation.
Paperwork and license, please.
Where are you delivering it?
Willow's Memorial Hospital.
There is patient wait for it.
Have you ever procured or delivered an organ outside of normal or lawful channels?
No.
You're an employee of this company. How would your employer answer this question?
Is sick, has cancer.
That's not what I asked you..
Am I under some kind of suspicion?
A vision if ever I had one.
Can I speak with you?
Would you like to come in?
Make yourself comfortable.
I won't be staying long.
Have you come here by yourself?
Yes.
Sit.
Please, I insist.
Now, you came to ask me something.
We are alone. Free to speak in confidence.
You said something to me the other night in the snow.
Yes, I said, "Don't give up."
I need to know why you said that.
I haven't the faintest idea.
Were you hoping for another answer?
Do you know anything about me?
Other than that you loathe me?
Do you know what it is that I do?
No. I can see that you are a woman of faith.
- But not in the same things as your husband.
- he's not my husband.
- Do you care to tell me about yourself?
- No!
Do you care to offer a confession?
- I don't think you're...
- What?
In a position to judge? And yet you've judged me, haven't you?
You deserve to be judged!
Do you know why we live here, the men who call this vile box of monsters home?
Because we hate each even as we hate ourselves. For our sickening appetites.
That doesn't make it any less sickening.
And where do they come from, these sickening appetites, these uncontrollable urges?
Not from God!
Not from me. I castrated myself when I was 26.
And the visions weren't my idea either.
Proverbs 25:2.
"God's glory to conceal a thing...
... but the honor of kings to search out a matter."
Don't you quote Scripture to me!
What are you doing here? What are you afraid of?
"Don't give up!" What was that for?
- I don't Know.
- I don't believe you!
I'm telling you the truth!
- They were your words!
- I don;t know why I said them!
You said them to my face!
All I ever wanted was to serve Him. All I've ever wanted was to serve God.
Ask for His pity, but don't expect mine.
You can stop the act any time!
Look at me!
The paramedics have been in with him for about seven minutes.
He has stabilized. Blood pressure's normal.
- They are loading him in now.
- What happened?
He had a seizure.
- Who called you?
- No-one.
What are you doing here?
We need to talk to Father Joe?
Well, that's not going to happen.
We've got a suspect. A Russian immigrant working as an organ transporter.
In custody?
No. The Richmond DA questioned him about trafficking black market human organs this afternoon, but he was released.
They had no evidence to hold him.
We've got a fairly credible witneses who says he swam with the women at the pool.
ASAC Whitney?
What's that got to do with Father Joe?
- He's the man in his visions, Scully.
- Who?
The suspect. The man in this photo.
Mulder, now you're wasting their time.
Tell me again what you're doing here.
Here's a vision for you. A couple of my guys just had it.
Who's this?
That's our suspect's employer. An old friend of Father Joe's, we just learned.
- Known him for over twenty years.
- Known him how?
That's one of his 37 altar boys.
Three guesses who he's married to in the state of Massachusetts?
Our suspect.
We got a warrant to search their offices.
Mulder.
It's over.
Why don't you hold up?
Let these men do their jobs.
Clear this bottom floor.
We were all fooled on this. I wanted to believe as bad as anyone.
Look, I don't need the sweet-talk.
- You led us here.
- Father Joe led us here.
This is Special Agent Drummy with the FBI. We have warrants to search these offices.
Anyone inside, identify yourself and unlock the door now.
I called you because I thought I could help with this case. Because I valued your belief in these phenomena.
And now what do you think?
I think that this is a longer conversation.
Down on the floor! Everybody in here I want down on the floor.
Somebody find the lights.
We were at a complete standstill and you pushed us forward in a direction or two.
What are you, nuts?
Stop him!
Hey! You can't go there.
- Which way did they go?
- That way.
Mulder!
Up here!
He's coming at you!
Mulder.
- Where are you?
- Right here.
Where?
Fox?
Where is he? Do you have gim?
No, I lost him.
- I saw him.
- Where?
They're both dead.
Monica Bannan and Dakota Whitney.
I heard.
I'm sorry.
I thought we were winning, Scully.
I know you did, Mulder.
I'm here to see Father Joe.
I want to show him these photographs. These men.
You still want to believe him.
I think you should know that he's been diagnosed with a terminal illness.
He has advanced stage lung cancer.
I just want to be sure.
Then let me ask him.
You wouldn't believe...
... I was thinking of you.
I had a vision...
... you might find interesting.
Of a man speaking in a foreign language.
Did he happen to look like this?
Yeah, that's the man.
How did you know?
We think he's the man that abducted the FBI agent...
... and the second woman you say you saw and possibly many more.
And we think that he was helped...
... by this man.
I don't know who that is.
Are you sure?
I'm failry certain. I don't know him.
I'm fairly certain that you do.
And that you've known him since he was a boy.
Oh, no.
It cannot be true.
I don't believe this.
He was my connection to the girl.
My visions were to save her from him.
This is God's work.
Let me ask one more question, Father Joe.
The FBI agent...
... the first woman that you saw, Monica Bannnan.
Is she still alive?
I feel her.
Yes.
She's still alive.
That second victim may be alive. Everybody's given up on her, but I'm not going to.
Mulder, you think that I don't understand but I do.
This stubbornness of yours.
It's why I fell in love with you.
It's like you said.
It's why we can't be together.
Hold on.
- I'm sorry to bother you.
- I'm closed
I just need a moment of your time.
We got some bad weather coming in. You'd better get where you're goin' fast.
So, what do you need?
Is was wondering if you carry an animal tranquilizer called acepromazine?
You got a prescription for it?
No, I don't.
Well, I can't sell it to you then.
can you tell me if you've ever sold any to this man?
I am never getting out of here.
- Nutter's Feed.
Yep, I was just closing up and I'm gonna pick him up.
Yes, goodbye.
What happened to the othe guy?
Who?
The guy who was standing right here.
- I need to refill this now.
- Okay.
"... in laboratory animals, particularly dogs."
"... fused at the neck."
"... survive for periods of several weeks."
Yeah, it's me.
I must be busy right now. Leave a message.
Mulder, I just found something in my stem cell research.
Experiments being done in Russia on dogs. I think that's what...
... your suspects have been doing, only on humans.
Those women who have been abducted. You've got to call me.
Mulder, the FBI agent's alive.
FBI, Special Agent In Charge Fosse speaking.
It's for you.
This is Special Agent Drummy.
I've been trying to find you for hours.
I can't reach Mulder.
- Is this Doctor Scully?
- Yes, it's Doctor Scully!.
- Where is he?
- If I knew that I wouldn't be calling.
Doctor Scully, I'm gonna suggest that you call the police. This is not an FBI matter.
Listen to me!
I need your help!
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
Then let me talk to somebody there with some balls who can!
Don't touch me!
You're going to be right.
I take care of you. You no longer need this body.
Look at me. You are going to live.
You are going to have a fine, strong body.
Excuse me.
I'm Dana Scully and that's my car.
I talked to some bigwig down at the FBI. He called from Washington.
Yeah, that's him. Walter Skinner.
Is there indication what happened? Any footprints?
Nothing. This snow's pretty heavy. But we did find this.
Might want to give it to him. Excuse me.
It's his cellphone. It's got blood on it.
Calm down. Stop and think. He's okay. He climbed out of there somehow...
...and if he climbed out he probably climbed up.
Stop!
Back off!
Back away!
Do you speak English? Does anybody speak English?
I want her out of here! I want those tubes out of her neck and I want her neck sewn up!
Do it!
We will find him.
I know Mulder. He'll get to a phone and he'll call first.
He wouldn't do anything crazy.
Relatively crazy.
Wait a minute. Back up.
What is it?
Proverbs, 25:2.
"The Glory of God to hide a thing."
I've got it. An invoice for medical supplies to a Dr. Uroff-Koltoft.
An address in Bellflower Road.
- Listen
- What?
Dogs. Dogs!
Mulder!
Can you hear me?
Sorry about your car.
The girl. Still inside.
Show me your hands!
Put the scalpel down! Put that scalpel down!
Put that scalpel down or I'll blow your goddamn head off!
Get over there!
My God! What have you done?
What have you done?
Mulder needs warm clothes and fluids.
Oh God.
I've got work to do here.
Get in! Get in!
The girl ... inside ...
Scully's got her. She's in good hands.
Skinner?
I'm cold.
I gotcha.
Mulder?
What's up, Doc?
Father Joe is dead.
He was clearly a very sick man.
Did you see this story?
The FBI is claiming that Father Joe was an accomplice.
Not a word about his psychic connection.
He's dead, Mulder.
We'll never know.
I know, Scully, and I can prove it.
Father Joe died of lung cancer, right?
The same as that man that Doctor Frankenstein tried to give a new body.
What time did you pull those tubes from that woman's neck?
What time did you cut off the blood supply to that man's head? That's when Father Joe died.
Get me his death certificate and I'll show it to you and I'll take it to the FBI and I'll show them.
Do you really think they're gonna take your call?
It's an injustice to the man's name.
Well, considering his crimes against those young boys...
... Who is really going to care?
I thought you believed him too?
I wanted to believe him.
I did believe him! I acted on that belief!
Why don't you just tell me what he said to you?
He told me:
"Don't give up."
And I didn't. And it saved your life.
But I put that boy through hell.
And I have another surgery scheduled for this morning ...
... because I believed that God was telling me to.
Through a paedophile priest, no less!
What if Father Joe's prayers were answered after all?
What if he were forgiven?
Because he didn't give up.
Try proving that one, Mulder.
I'm due at the hospital.
Scully?
Why would he say that?
"Don't gibe up." Why would he say such a thing to you?
I think that was clearly meant for you, Mulder.
He didn't say it to me. He said it to you.
If Father Joe were the Devil, why would he say the opposite of what the Devil might say?
Maybe that's the answer.
The larger answer.
What do you mean?
Don't give up.
Please don't make this any harder than it already is.
Okay.
If you have doubts...
... any doubts at all...
... just call off that surgery this morning.
And then we'll get out of here.
Just me and you.
As far away from the darkness as we can get?
I'm not sure it works that way.
I think maybe the darkness finds you...
... and me.
I know it does.
But let it try.
Are you ready to begin, Doctor Scully?
Yes.