[Ah...this humiliation.]
[Ah...this disgrace...]
[I didn't forget it...]
We should do that.
Do what?
- We should take revenge.- Why the revenge?
[What is that?]All the members come out!
What is this?[Time for revenge. All of you come out now]
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The So! Pink Team @ Viki
All of you wanted it
So I acquired it.
- Yes!- So I am gonna take my revenge.
- What are you talking about?- What is this?- Bye Bye...
Want to try it right everyone?
Please don't do that. Please do not play, "let's catch a fish" or anything like that.
- No way! - Ahh...
- Why are you doing that? - Why, why, why?- Hey guys...
- I will give you chance.- Oh.
I will give you.
You are gonna give it.
Stop right there. Just give it to us.
What is that flashlight?
- What is that really? - Go, go, go.
Giving it?
We hid it somewhere.
Try it.
We have a gift certificate for raw fish (sushi).
There's a piece of paper. How do we find a piece of paper?
- Pardon?- Within 15 minutes.
- We have to go all the way there within 15 minutes.- Is there a flashlight?
Flashlight is behind you there.
There is... this one?
- Yes that's all there is. - This is a mini me, so tiny.
So then when we arrive it's 15 minutes?
- It's a mini me. This flashlight it too tiny. - It's easy, I have walked there before.
You can go there in 5 minutes.
So then..
So you are staying here Mr. Producer?
Yes Yes, I will be staying here.
- Wait what the heck?- Once you get there everything will be ready for you.
But wait, you should give us enough time to go look for it too. Give us 15 minutes once we get there as well.
So?If Somin acts all cute then...I will give you 20 minutes.
*Boing Boing* [Launching because of her cuteness]
That's so not adorable.
I think...
It's 7:05 right now. I will give you exactly 20 minutes.
My head is starting to hurt.
It's really scary. Can we just not go?
You see what I have here now.
This is show twinkling and shiny.Oh yeah, flashlight.
You should give us one more.
It's 7h18 right now.
We will give you 20 minutes.
Okay now go!
Flashlight...you take the lead. Please move out of the way.
I can't see anything that's in front of me.
Wait, what the heck...What is it?!
I can't see anything! I can't see here either.
- It looks fun. It looks like a ghost will come from here. - Aish...
I don't think we really need flashlights here.
- We can't see here you know.- Wait, this here..
I can't see.
I can't see the way.
This is...
- There is raw fish? - Please give it to us. - What?
- What are we doing? Aren't we gonna go in?- Go through there.
- WHAT?! I don't want to.- No!- We can all hold hands and go in there.
- I really don't want to.- It's okay It's okay.
We could hold hands and go together.
Let's hurry up and go in.
Hold on a minute.
- Just hold my hand. - Come this way.
Gonna get scare it.
- It's so scary. - OOOHHH~~~
What in the world!
We have to go inside in there.
I just discovered a grasshopper.
I think we have to go inside in there.
- Keep on going straight in there. Inside of there?- Yeah...
You guys..no wait!
This place is so creepy.
- Bye Bye.- Let's all gather. - They are all gathering there.
You are not scared right?
This way...
Mr. Camera Director.
- Mr.Camera Director. Which way do we go? - I think there will be something over here.
Don't do that!
- What! Get out!- Look here..
Where do we go Camera Director?
What did you say was there now?
- Don't use the flash!- Ahh!
Calm down and be quiet.
Mr. Camera Director, where do we go?
Please don't wiggle around like that.
Don't wiggle around.
Who are you? WHO ARE YOU?!
- Oh...It's Director Young Jin..- I could see it all. I could see it all.
- Seriously, don't do that. Please come over here. - Please come.
Seriously, why are you doing this.
Don't move. You guys...
Why are you doing this?
Why do you this? I am really okay.
I know...
Hey, take me too.
Don't come over. Please take me along.
- WHAT THE HELL!!!- This totally sucks!
- I am so sorry for speaking out informally.- Take your unnie too. Let's go together.
Unnie, take me too. Unnie, take me too.
What the heck is this? Is it a piece of string?This is a piece of string.
- Unnie, take me too. - There is a piece of string here.
Oh no there isn't. That string is totally worthless.
Paper!I think that string looks like something we need.
Hey, Yena, take your unnie too. There isn't anything here.
What the hell are you?Isn't that it?!
- What is it?- Don't do that~!
Why do you do this to me for?!
Huh?
- You have to find number 3. - This is number 2.
- There is no number 3.- They said that this is number 2.
Where is this going to, Mr. Director?
Director, director... Are you not there Mr. Director?
Director, Director?
Over here? Keep on following it?
- Have to keep on following it. - Hello there.
Please give us a hint here.
Give us another flashlight.
It's really okay.
So scary...
I came here before. What is that over there?
Hey Yena.. Don't tease me.
Really, what is that?
Oh...
- I know there is that thing here for sure. - Should we go inside of there?
- This is not it.- I didn't see that.
You don't have to do that.
- Don't do that.- Unnie, I will try to look for it quickly.
Where is it at?
- It won't be here.- Here, here.
Go in there.
Number 3! Caught it... Catch it!
It's going out.
Let's go out.
- Please take the lead.- Hurry up and follow.
- Finally...- This was all you got huh?
Hey...
Hurry up Hurry up.
Let's hurry up and leave now.
- Hello.- Unnie, smile.
That thing.
Smile. Hello.
- Hurry up girls. - Maybe we should go down.
We're found it.
Ta Da..Hehe..
- Is it number three?- Yes.- It's number 3.
- What it is this spider for? Seriously.- We found it!
- What the heck man.- It's 7:16pm now.
You have to hurry up and go now in order for you to pass.
- It's so dark- Careful now.
Go up, go up.
Which way is it?
This is too much.
It's over here! It's over here!
- What?- It's over here! It's over here!
[Sorry Mr. Director]
[Are you a spy or an X-men?- Wait up!
Oh crap.
We don't have much time.
[They are running towards the sashimi with their strong tenacity.]
♫ Please open up my heart ♫
♫ Please come towards me gently ♫
♫ Cmon Cmon ♫
We're almost there.
Ah...so tired!
How was it?
It was okay. We barely made it. What the heck is this?
We're you trying to scare us now?
Your hair is messed up a lot.
Sorry about that.
- How about you Jinsol? - I thought I was gonna die in there.
It was so scary that I couldn't even scream properly.
- How was it for you Chaewon?- Me?
For me...I was able to find it.
Show it to us.
It's a spider. What is this spider for? What is this huh? Seriously.
You came right one time.
You brought the number three sashimi gift certificate.
- So it was a success!- Woow!
- There were cards from 1-6.- Really?
I was able to find number 3 foreals.
I don't want to play anymore.
I was able to hear you girls yell all the way to here.
No not really.It was kinda easy.
WHO ARE YOU?
Who yelled the most?
Oh My Goodness~~!
Because it was fun.It was quite scary. Be quiet.
Who screamed then? AAACKK~
Sit Down. Stop it. Stay Still. That's Right. That's Right That's right.
Yay! So then , just like we promised we will prepare some sashimi for you girls. WoW~~~
You girls can go there and rest for a bit.Thank you very much.Thank You..
[Idols that are into cleanliness.][Cool and crisp skin with lots of energy.]
[AQUTOP]*Let's put the fresh mask pack on that's full of collagen. *
Hello there.
What is all this?
Today is dinner is sent by your mother because you all have been working so hard.
She wanted to feed you delicious food so your mother cooked them especially for you girls.
This is so awesome! Yay!Thank You~She has something else to bring later as well.So please stick around kay?
What else is there?
There is something.
Pardon? You girls can look forward to it. This is good enough actually.
OOOOHHHHHHH~~~
[Hey girls, you won't be starving today.]Wow~~~
This is so amazing..
Enjoy.This is so awesome.
Thank You so much.
I feel like we are at an actual countryside.
Thank you...
Your mother brought them for you girls.
This one This one.
This is so cold.Thank you so much.
Yes,,,
Thank you for the food.
This looks so good.
When are we gonna eat it all?
*Yummy*
This is so delicious.
This is so tasty.
Have a bite of this.
Eat it all.
This is like the LAST SUPPER so eat it all.
Eat to your heart's content.
We've been eating nothing but instant food so this is awesome.
Since we came here we've been eating nothing but good food and so we feel healthy.
I totally messed up the Japche (Clear noodle stir fried dish)So yummy.
I messed up the Japche.
It's okay. It's hard to do.
*Music* "Wish everything will go your way*
*Shout it out* Shout it out loud.*
*Do it as if your heart will explode*
There's a bone here.
You're talking as if you have a short tongue?You said..There ish a bone..
When someone talks in an adorable voice you just want to protect them.
To Who?I am just saying..
Mother, we really enjoyed your food, thank you. Did you guys eat a lot?
I didn't make that much.
You made so much. Thank you.
I am happy that you enjoyed the food.Yes, thank you.
Can we come here again?
Of course. Come during the summer, it's really nice there then.
That would be great.
We will come again in the summer. We will come again.
I have my corn here in the summer. Wow~~
Thank for coming.Thank you so much.
[Already]HERE GOES APRIL
[Already]HERE GOES APRIL[Next Story]
I still can't believe it yet...