(Emilie Simon)
"All is white"
All is white
I think it snowed
in the night
Everything is cold
So cold outside
I listen to the wind
All alone
I know it means
the storm will come
I want to live in paradise
I want to live in the South
At the south of the earth tonight
All is white
I know it snowed in the night
Everything is cold
So cold outside
I try to be calm
It's a lonely trip
Listen to my eyes
Listen to my lips
I want to live in paradise
I want to live in the South
At the south of the earth tonight
Once upon a time a garden
A fertile world where life was a given
A long time ago - before winter
But one day, everything was blanked
plants, animals
Those who could flee
did so, but our ancestors
decided to stay.
At any cost
And to resist tothis frost
which was taking everything
Time has passed
100 times, Earth has changed its face
We are still there
We stand, light sentinels.
Here is our story.
Where are the others?
I feel dizzy
leaving the Ocean.
Here we are, our two feets
in the snow,
in this country
too large for us.
Are we all here?
Everybody's here?
A day passes,
and another...
and the third day...
We gathered all here today,
from the straightest to the
hunchbakcs, all of us
Waiting for the signal
The signal...
...comes at last.
In this great day,
One third into the year,
when the moon and the sun
meet at half day,
we, swimmers, stand up
and start to walk.
Our kind is forever shared between
the ocean which feeds us
and on the other side
beyond the great plain
the ice covered ocean,
...a meeting.
We've got a rendez vous.
Now standing up
we walk, like nomads,
we walk one day,
two days
ten days, twenty days.
The same number of nights
the same number of cold nights
Here comes the time
of the first walk
The walk of the long caravans
Above us, the sky's
paths are shining
The sun, the stars draw
eternal maps
Under our feets, Earth's
heart humms...
Humms its beautiful
magnetic fields
Each year,
our trek takes a new turn
Icebergs are like giant tramps
They sleep wherever winter catches
up with them!
Sometimes we have to make long detours
Going around the sleeping titans.
But even the oldest amongst us
cannot remember ever being lost
Despite the cold
engulfing the plain
despite the dreamy mountains' walls
caravans from all 4 corners of the horizon
are gathering - nearly
the same day
at the same time, at the same place.
As if by magic.
10 days pass
and thousands of steps
And another 10 days
another thousands of steps
...and one morning
Our people gets
to the end of the trip
Here are the stone doors
that witnessed our birth
Since the dawn of times
It's here, on the Oamock (river?)
that we meet
every year to give life.
No place is safer
Protected by granite walls
and the ice beneath our feet
will not break until summer.
No more order, no more steps
we all freely roam the crowd
...looking for our soulmate.
Love songs cover the Oamock
We marry for the whole year
to a single partner.
Every yearit's the same.
As soon as we arrive...
...it's slapping time.
More females than males!
Females fierciously fight for us :-)
A new couple?
They intervene.
A married male is a lost male...
So they dive in,
push their way in.
Other couples wait.
Those who, like us
have already found
each other...
...isolate themselves in the intimacy
of songs and parades.
Our nuptial dance
is opening the big winter's bal
(Emilie Simon)
"The Frozen World"
Won't you open for me
The door to your ice world
To your white desert
I just want to stare
Out over these snowfields
Until we are one again
We belong to
the frozen world
When the ice
begins to thaw
Becomes the sea
You will see
How beautiful we can be
How beautiful we
can be
Everything is cold
At the end of the planet
In our white desert
The sun kissed the ice
It glistens for me
And we are one again
We belong to the frozen world
When the ice
begins to thaw
Becomes the sea
You will see
How beautiful we
can be
We are going to dance
for the longest of winters
We'll lose and find
each other for 9 months
If our ballet is harmonious,
we shall survive
Too bad for those who
couldn't follow
those who are erring, lost,
those who are late or weak.
At the desert's mercy,
far from the Oamock's granite walls
Without the groups' strength,
the solitary is condemned.
Those the march forgot slowly fade.
Here, white reigns -
what dies
...is erased.
Already, winter's first tears come.
Soft tears, like
souvenirs from the sea
Love was proclaimed,
Love was made,
all those around us keep quiet.
In the warmth of our bodies,
a promise of life starts
A moon passes
and we wait.
Another moon
Comes the 3rd moon,
the time has come.
With our feathers, we have to cover life
the moment it appears
...hide it.
Cold is everywhere
This mini heart's tremor,
hidden in its shell
is so vulnerable in
this huge ice land.
Here, you need much more life
to create life.
From now on, each of our move
aims at one single thing:
keep him alive.
I'm worn out.
I need to go back to the sea,
eat to keep
my body awake.
Yet, before, I need to
give the egg to his father.
Life contained in the egg
won't resist the frost's bite
No more than a few seconds
Some couples, like this one
- they must be young -
are too nervous
Frost bites and breaks
the treasure of the hurried,
the clumsy, the unlukcy.
Their dance is over,
their year is lost.
Now without an aim,
they'll go,
in an errand towards the ocean.
100 times, we patiently repeat
the dance...
...before passing the egg.
Again and again,
we repeat the litany
of our songs,
of our charms.
Again and again,
we repeat the litany
of our songs,
of our charms.
In our dance's balancing act
lies the perfect movement
This little step, this little step.
I'm leaving,
I have to walk to the ocean.
I'll stay with our egg,
I will cover it.
My belly's warmth will
protect until your return.
Go back to the ocean
and its food feasts.
And make sure you're back in time,
too feed our soon-to-born baby.
We'll wait for you.
It's time for the 2nd walk,
the march at dawn.
For the first time,
dancers separate.
I'm starving.
Our food is over there,
beyond the desert.
Yet only here,
on the Oamock's solid ice...
can our baby be born.
We'll go to the sea,
they'll stay here.
They'll walk,
we'll wait.
Two month...
of misery,
and fight to try to...
...preserve life.
For the last few days,
the sky above darkens.
The sun, the mountains,
the settings change.
It's like hearing winter
preparing its first blow.
We look like circus artists
with this egg on our feet.
We're now a single body
rolling itself
like a storm roll.
We'll hold.
Same winter -
we walk again and again
Cruel irony, on the ocean's back
we're looking for the door.
Here, under the ice, fishes swim.
Here, on the ice, the storm blows.
The starving walkers suffer.
The smell of water...
We can smell the water.
The entrance isn't far.
Here we are.
The ocean at last!
Caress of the water,
everywhere, the light shows
the way to the abyss.
Over there, past the blue
gateway to the deep,
...the table is ready.
"Song of the sea"
See
how I fly
In the sea
Like in the sky
You set me free
Sometimes, the wind leaves a bit
of fresh snow for us
...it quenches our thirst.
3 months without any food!
We defy winter and reach
life's limits.
Some pass the border,
they fall asleep, slowly.
White spreads little by little
over their body,
which disappear forever.
Nightime
...we crawl under the storms,
cold rules.
It has no name.
We hold without failing, under
the mother of all blizzards
melded together, a single body,
like the scale
...of turltes are fitted.
Night's daughters wear their
best veils.
They run
...under the stars,
dance to the wind's song.
Be courageous, enslaved people,
this dance is going
To the sky's limit,
looking for the sun who forgot us.
How soft is
the sea's water!
We enjoy the ocean
as long as we can.
But on the Oamock, life
will soon need us.
With a single jawbite,
the monster erased two lives
...the life of the trapped mother
and that of her baby
who will never be fed.
We are still petrified
by terror.
Around us, the night
has the smell of frost
we remember the ice's noise
so different from the ocean's songs
It's time for the return
time for the 3rd march,
the walk of the moon.
In the endless night,
we find our way to our land of cold.
We bring back lots of food
to feed our babies.
People are waiting for us.
We have to hurry.
Our gaping night takes forever
...and get bogged,
a 100 days long night,
filled with cold
and turmoil.
Yet... this morning...
something...
...sparkles in the air.
The light is back.
We have vainquished winter.
Life...
so small, so beautiful, unreal
in this cold that erodes us.
We reached
the summit of our torment.
From now on, each day
will bring a stronger sun,
which frees the youngs
from their shells.
Where are they?
But where are they?
How long have we
been going around like that?
Dawn's first glow has
awaken winter.
It enrages, it increases.
Cold is so strong that it finally...
...froze the wind.
It tighten its grip on us,
locks us stronger,
...clenches stronger.
So we turn, so as not
to be too exposed to the cold
...our back to the cold.
Heat exists, at the turtle's hearth,
hidden under the heads.
At our feet, babies appear,
always more plentiful.
Where are they?
As soon as they hatch out,
the babies are hungry.
The mothers have to
come back!
In this cold,
their energy fades so quickly.
And I am exhaused,
4 months without any food.
I am empty.
Barely enough to walk
another 20 days.
20 days... the eternity
that separates us from the ocean.
So this evening, if his mother
hasn't come back,
...I'll have to go,
abandon my child.
But before we give up,
there's still a chance.
The hidden part,
a few crumbles...
...preserved deep inside my body,
...despite these months of starvation.
A few more hours of life.
I had kept them...
...for you,
in expecation of this moment.
Who will win?
Life or winter?
For some,
it's already too late.
We walk, and in us,
life shrieks:
Hurry up!
He, she, is born, needing you,
He, she will not hold for long, now.
Frightened for no reason,
a lot of wasted time.
We push our speed.
The wind brings puffs
of familiar scents.
The colony's not far,
faster!
The Oamock, at last!
Who will I find?
Is my baby dead?
Is he or she still alive?
Where in this crowd are you?
Where are you?
This voice...
This chant coming towards me...
This baby calling,
is he or she mine?
Come on, sing!
You did hold!
You came back in time!
You are still here.
And you, I only meet you now,
my marvelous son of the winter,
...my little baby.
Do you remember the dance,
our songs in the times of love?
Here they are again...
...renewed to celebrate
your return.
I must take our child,
and you must leave hastilly.
A short moment,
a precious moment.
Within one step, we'll be separated,
...Soon we'll be 1 000 winters apart,
let's make the most of it!
Another instant.
Youngster, listen carefully
to my voice
...thanks to my voice
you'll recognise me one day.
I'd like to be able to
promise I'll come back.
It's my turn to leave.
My strength desert me,
I have to complete...
...the most dangerous
part of the trip:
the march of the starved ones.
The ultimate march,
the march which decimates us
every year.
Here it comes at last - renewal.
Slowly, light blossoms
on the Oamock.
Like the sun, our youngs
grow stronger day by day.
But summer is still far.
No way we'll let our youngs out.
They are so frail,
They need...
our warmth.
Around us,
frost lurks.
10 days pass by
then 10 more days.
And one beautiful morning...
I am going for my first walk
by myself!
Oh, it's like a nettle...
under the paw (clawed feet)!
I'm cold!
It's funny, it tickles!
Here, my first walk,
the march of the free chick!
Cold is bringing them back
under our paws.
But they made...
...the great jump.
A page of their life has been turned.
We haven't seen snow running like that.
Adults sqeeze together,
they are worrying.
This wind is no bearer of good news.
The dying winter is kicking us...
...with it last blizzard.
We think cold lost
its arrogance,
...but our youngs think otherwise.
They'll have to be strong.
The time of their initiation has come.
It's the dreaded moment of
their first turmoil.
Can't you hear my storm coming
Stones falling on to you
Can't you feel the earth shaking
Big dark clouds forming now
And I hope you're satisfied
I hope you're satisfied
To see the wind
blow over me
Can't you hear my sky shouting
Close, chasing after you
Deep, dark fear building up
It's too strong for you
And I hope you're satisfied
I hope you're satisfied
To see the wind
Blow
over me
Can't you hear my storm coming
Stones falling
Big dark clouds
forming now
The wind leaves, on its trail,
mothers looking for their child.
Trembling lost chicks.
And a harvest of lost lives,
swept away by the cold.
All these efforts broken
by a gust of wind.
Some find it unbearable.
They need a child, at any price.
Life has to keep on growing
on their feet.
So, they perpetrate the most
inconceivable act.
In a moment of crazyness,
the steal...
...someone else's child.
That was just! I thought they
would crush me!
You saved me!
It feels good to be close to you.
Happy birthday, short legs!
One month ago...
...we were hatching out of our shells,
now we run.
Not bad, innit?
We don't even need our mothers
to get warm.
Sometimes, we'd really like to...
...go under the warm duvet.
There's always one or two
who slouch in the pockets.
They pretend to be cold,
but for them, same system:
Stand up, your two paws
on the ice, and walk!
When time's up,
time is up!
Now, we are
in-de-pen-dent!
When we are cold,
there's the child care centre.
Not bad, we aggregate
and keep warm.
A bit like our fathers
making a big turtle.
But it's hard to stay in place.
I'm going to have to leave you alone,
I'll be back quickly.
I need to go and fish
to nourish you.
You'll stay here,
your father should be there soon.
You'll recognise his chant.
He'll recognise yours.
I'm not too fond of
staying alone.
Wait! I'm a little bit afraid.
Alert!
The long wings are coming!
Hurry, to the day care centre!
Oh! What about those ones,
left alone over there!
It's over for that one.
She'll never see the sea.
Here they come!
The fathers are back!
Is my father with them?
Yes, it's him, I'm know it.
Yes, it's you, I know it.
Adults keep on going and coming back.
They have two sides:
The white one, it's the full bellies
coming back.
The black one, empty bellies leaving.
As for us, front or back,
we are grey.
We are always hungry!
Sometimes come days
we can't even dream of.
For weeks, we have
fed our kid...
...separated, never meeting up.
And here we are, reunited
by the finest of all hasards.
Our kid is strong,
our kid is lovely.
On the wake of the last march,
let's promise to meet
for next season...
...to dance again,
maybe tie the knot...
...for another winter.
It's been a few days,
it's always sunny...
...and there's no night.
The icefield groans,
...it looks like it wants to leave.
It's time to depart.
The ocean calls me,
it will call you soon.
To life, little son of winter,
to life!
There ends our last march.
The separation march,
that of the return...
...to the sea. We leave
the Oamock for this year.
The time of the couples has passed away,
the dance is finished.
The dancers leave their separate way.
We return to...
the water for the year's most
beautiful moons.
Three months of ocean,
Three months of summer,
...of swimming and pleasure!
These last few days,
we feel strange.
We don't even want to eat,
maybe...
...we are becoming adults?
Time for us to answer the call.
Like our parents came
from the sea,
...it's our turn
to walk towards the ocean.
We leave the Oamock
to join our people...
...in the gentle deep.
Little ice walkers,
here comes the time...
...of metamorphosis,
we became...
...children of the ocean,
amongst children of the ocean.
One day, far away,
this famous day of 1/3 of the year
...when the sun and the moon
meet in the sky,
...we'll have to jump...
...out of the sea and become
walkers again.
Faithfull to our forefathers' oath,
...we'll come back here
to dance for life...
...during the biggest winter,
and perpetuate...
...the march of the Emperor.
Subs CEDRA PRODUCTlONS
Translated by Patrick