Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
Main Translators: ripgal, kiki08, ai*
Spot Translator: purpletiger86
Timer: ltrang
Editor/QC: theedqueen
Final QC: ay_link
Coordinators: ay_link, mily2
This is a FREE fan sub. Not for sale!
Get it for free @ d-addicts.com
Jang Chul Soo.
Did you think I left?
You were no where to be found
since this morning. I thought you left.
What’s with your expression?
I thought you’d be happy if I’m gone.
I was happy.
I’m disappointed now.
I’m sorry to disappoint you.
I have no plans to leave yet.
Although I might be
bugging you like that,
I can only depend on you now.
The dog went missing so
I went out to look for it.
Na Sang Shil.
When you really want to leave,
Don’t leave without a word.
Tell me that you’re
leaving, or leave a note.
What difference does it make?
If you leave a note, I wouldn’t
have to waste time looking for you.
You…
were looking for me?
If Ggot Soon went missing,
you’d look for her too right?
Me too. If you went missing,
of course I’d look for you too.
So you meant,
you’d search for me as if
you’re searching for a dog?
That’s right.
Some more, about Ggot Soon...
she occasionally goes looking
for the neighbor’s dog.
You don’t have to bother looking for her.
Hey...dog!
Did you go out to date?
How can a dog not guard the
house and instead go off on a date?
Don’t wander off. Guard the house properly!
Got worried for nothing.
I should be worried that she’s not leaving.
Why am I worried now that she’s leaving?
It’s normal for her to leave.
Of course she has to leave.
I’m going to see Anna today.
Not bad.
Right.. that’s better.
I told you to adjust it better.
Oh that’s right.
2 times will do.
Oh yes.
The last weapon to
attract Anna’s attention…
Princess…
There’s something wrong with my mobile phone.
What is it again?
It was still functioning well at home.
But the ring tone volume went down as I came out.
It’s noisier outside. Nothing’s wrong.
If you call again for no reason,
I’d have to confiscate your phone.
That’s it.
A wretched phone.
How about I use it to
order for jjajangmyun?
Unni!
Long time no see.
Unni.
You got a mobile phone?
Kang Ja, do you know how to make calls?
Yeah. What’s your number?
Tell me.
Kang Ja.
You have a phone too?
Jang Chul Soo.
Even Kang Ja has a phone, why
did you only get me one now?
I’m the only one who doesn’t
have a phone all this time.
Petty fella..
What is she talking about again?
Sang Shil’s really troublesome.
Then don’t answer her calls.
Or else, just switch off your phone.
I’m the only one she can call,
how can I switch off my phone?
I’d have to answer anyway.
Ha Duk Gu-ssi.
What’s the matter?
Your phone was switched off. I
was worried so I came to see you.
What are you doing?
Working.
Duk Gu why are you
doing these kind of jobs?
It’s my hobby.
Alright?
Really…
I didn’t get it wrong..
It really is his interest.
He has 100 cows!
Ha Duk Gu-ssi!
The toilet in my house
is broken again.
Sang Shil, alright it’s done.
How do I store numbers?
Let me help you.
Kang Ja. Like this.
Can we take pictures with this?
Yea. We can even play
games and watch videos.
Games?
Let me see.
Here.
Yours is bigger than mine.
Bingo!
If I go in abruptly like this,
something bad might happen again.
I will have to pretend to
meet her up coincidentally.
When Anna comes…
I will leave Princess here.
You helped me find Princess again!
Let me treat you to dinner as
an appreciation for your help.
Princess.
Princess…what’s wrong?
Princess! Princess!
Princess!
You helped me find Princess again.
As an appreciation…
You’re bleeding.
It’s okay.
It’s bleeding there too.
It’s alright.
You’re looking for her again?
It seems that she likes to wander off.
As an appreciation…
You look familiar.
I’ve seen you before several
times… you look familiar.
Na Sang Shil.. again?
Yes Hyung?
I’m very busy.
How could I have time for fishing?
What?
You know which yacht is it?
Didn’t you say it was a very big yacht?
Didn’t Young Bok just go to Seoul?
He has worked on a similar yacht before.
Young Bok?
I think I know the person.
It should be my high school senior.
He got fired for a small matter.
I even remember him
being furious back then.
Well just give me his
contact number now.
She’s not getting off me.
Yeah.
It’s as if you’re her owner.
This cat,
and also you…
are very familiar.
Because we’re family.
Your bruises, do they hurt?
If they hurt, plasters work well.
Do you want me to get you one?
Can you?
Anna’s worried about me.
It means she still
remembers me sub-consciously.
Where’s the plaster now?
Jang Chul Soo. What is it?
Come to the office. I will
treat you something delicious.
Right.
It’s the last time.
Treating me to something delicious.
He wants me to do something again.
Stick it here?
No… stick it on both sides.
Buy the plaster yourself.
I’m busy.
See ya.
Eat a lot.
Sorry for making you eat
jjajangmyun all the time.
I don’t it eat just because
you buy them for me.
I eat them because I like them.
I don’t eat food that
does not suit my taste.
That’s right.
You’ve stayed here long enough.
You’ve gotten used to it huh?
You didn’t like to eat
jjajangmyun in the past.
No.
Although I have lost my memory,
it’s impossible to like something
that I disliked in the past.
I like it now because
I liked it in the past.
That’s why, Jang Chul
Soo.. a person like you…
Since I liked you in the
past…so naturally now I…
won’t hate you.
Even if I remember everything in the future,
I will still like the
things I that I like now.
Till then you will know,
whether you will still like them or not.
Eat a lot.
But why is it only the two
of us eating good food?
What about the kids?
You’ve become caring for others
now huh?
It’s alright for today.
Let’s come again next time.
With the kids.
“Mom says she doesn’t like jjajangmyun.”
“Ahh.. we’re so in love.”
This mother is really strange.
Why doesn’t she like jjajangmyun?
It’s not that she doesn’t like it.
Didn’t she say that she doesn’t like it?
It’s not because she doesn’t like it.
She doesn’t like it for
the sake of her children.
Why?
Forget about it.
A mother’s great love and sacrifice...
how can Na Sang Shil
understand a thing like that?
The mother is so choosy.
She likes it yet she pretends not to.
I don’t like to be pretentious.
Sang Shil.
If someone lies to you…
Only those who don’t know
anything can live happily.
Live your life the way you want.
She just left like that? After telling
me that she would help me get a plaster?
How long would it take
to stick a plaster?
It must be Jang Chul Soo
who asked her to leave.
Hateful Jang Chul Soo!
I’m going to Seoul.
I will come back by tomorrow night at the latest.
What’s the matter?
I will tell you everything
after I come back.
When I come back,
I will really tell you everything.
Take care of the kids.
I love you?
The title of the book sounds awkward.
The main characters are
Young Gu and Kyu Joo?
It’s not them.
Bang Gu you’re so cute.
It’s my sincere gift to you.
It’s a comic book. It’s more
convenient like this then.
The main guy’s name is Chul Soo.
I also know a person
by the name of Chul Soo.
I’m going to Seoul today,
with my son and Chul Soo.
There’s a wedding to attend.
Right, I can read the comic in the car.
Thank you Bang Gu.
Let’s go.
Noonim..
Why don’t you let me send you to Seoul?
Why?
I’m going with my son.
Oh it's just that...
I want to chat with you.
And have a nice meal
together at the resting place.
Nevermind.
Bang Gu.
Yes?
You’re really very cute.
Of course, I’m Young Gu.
Am I really cute?
But why is Jang Chul Soo going to Seoul?
Assistant Gong,
where have you been lately
with your phone switched off?
Were you looking for me, Chairman?
Mr. Gong...
is there anyone called Bang Gu in our resort?
What?
That Bang Gu guy seemed to have
badmouthed me behind my back.
Spreading rumors about me going
after my dead wife’s property.
Now Anna knows about it.
Bang Gu.
It doesn’t sound like a formal name.
Could it be a nick name?
Check out this Bang Gu guy for me.
Everything’s going berserk
now. I’m going crazy.
I am Bang Gu.
Chairman.
I’m sorry.
Are you sure you have
worked on the yacht before?
Of course.
The owner’s a wealthy foreigner’s wife.
She has a disgusting character.
Aren't all wealthy people the same?
She’s the owner of the yacht right?
We’re home.
What’ wrong?
Are you guys sick?
I think we got a cold.
Cold?
What do I have to do?
Bring us to the hospital.
Alright.
Let’s go now.
So you don’t know this woman?
The yacht that I had worked on...
is this one.
It looks the same,
but it’s not this one.
There are not many big
yachts in the country.
I will help you ask around,
but I’m not sure if
this can really help.
Please do it for us.
Alright.
What do we do now?
Since we’re in Seoul now,
we’ll just go check at the
Missing Person’s Center then.
Let’s go.
According to your situation,
it’d be quite difficult if
nobody comes to look for her here.
If anyone contacts you, give me a call.
Did you take in someone unrelated?
Do you want any information on
homes which take in such people?
Jang Chul Soo.
I beg you…please abandon Anna.
If you abandon her, then
only I can take her back.
Abandon her.
They’re back from their cold shots
already. They’re sleeping now.
You’re not coming home today?
I still have some things to handle.
Thanks a lot for taking care of them.
I will go home early tomorrow morning.
Thank you for doing this.
Ahjumma… Ahjumma…
What is it?
Geun Suk’s is feeling really sick.
They got their shots already
and took their medicine.
Why are they still like this?
Don’t cry.
What are their body temperatures?
I don’t know.
How am I supposed to know?
I have a thermometer in my drawer.
It’s not very serious.
Did you give them fever medicine?
They took the medicine given
by the hospital already.
But they’re still vomiting.
It’s normal when
they’re down with fevers.
You know the cooling method right?
The fever has resided.
Then it’s alright now.
I will rush home as soon as possible.
Thank you Sang Shil.
Come home quickly.
I’m tired.
I really hate being sick.
Kids…
Why did you all fall sick together?
My child…
I feel very sick..
I’m dying soon.
No.
I don’t like to be sick.
And I don’t like death too.
Mom and Dad died already,
Grandma, you don’t have to die either.
My poor child.
I will hold onto your hand.
Don’t go.
You won’t have any family
to hold onto in future.
Poor child.
What dream was that?
I will let you be, since you’re sick.
Did something happen?
Kids…
It’s time to eat.
Ahjumma, we’re unable to eat rice.
You have to eat to gain energy.
Only then you will recover fast.
Our throats are sore.
It’s painful.
But you still have to eat.
Will you have to eat porridge?
It’s burnt.
And there’s only little rice left.
Do I have to add more?
Jang Chul Soo.
Oppa is not in?
No, he’s not.
He’s not in his office.
I was worried so I came.
Since he’s not in,
then I will just leave.
Flower girl.
You know how to cook porridge right?
They must have sweated a lot.
Did you help them change their clothes?
No, I didn’t.
They must have felt thirsty?
Did you give them any water to drink?
No.
So I just give them water?
How can you let them drink
cold water when they’re sick?
Do you have barley tea?
No.
Then go buy some barley tea.
Alright.
The house is in a mess.
What did they do?
Sang Shil.
Na Sang Shil.
Oppa.
Yu Kyeong.
Why are you here?
Where is Sang Shil?
She went out to buy something.
I cooked porridge for the kids already.
The fever has gone down. Don’t worry.
Kids…
Are you guys alright?
We’re fine now.
We were really sick.
Uncle...
Alright. Everything’s fine now.
Flower girl.
You came at the right
moment. You’re clever enough.
Well..
For the sick kids,
Flower Girl would come
more useful than me.
I hate being sick the most.
Just leave that. I’ll do it.
With the kids sick,
why didn’t you call me?
Without any proper care,
they have been suffering.
Sang Shil is taking care of the kids.
What’s the use of having her around?
When I got here, she was even
going to give them cold soup!
Don’t know if she spilled
it, their beds were all wet.
Their clothes were soaked in sweat
and she didn't even get them changed.
Also, she’s been out
till now and not back yet.
Leaving these sick kids, can
she still be in the mood for fun?
Yu Kyeong.
Sang Shil may not be
experienced in the household,
But for the kids, she
has tried her best.
So don’t say that anymore.
I only said that because I
was worried for the kids.
Then I’ll be going.
Oppa.
You’re still hanging onto this?
Can you give this to me?
I’d like to have it.
If you like it, just take it.
Have the kids eaten the porridge?
Yes. It’s all done.
Get on it.
Whatever the case, thank you!
I didn’t do it for you.
Just the kids alone, they’re
already a big burden on oppa.
Even if you can’t help him,
You should not become his burden, too.
Why does Flower Bouquet keep saying the
right things these days? So upsetting.
Don’t give up.
If I give up then I can’t
stick with him any longer.
I have no where else to go too.
Just a short period and
everything’s in a mess.
Uncle, I’m so sick.
It’s alright. You’ve taken the medicine.
Sleep some more.
What’s this?
Joon Suk, how are you feeling?
I’m not sick anymore, I’m well already.
Uncle, I’m hungry.
Hungry?
Oh, because you only ate porridge.
I’m sorry I couldn’t be around.
Let’s eat something nice.
Yes.
What do you feel like eating?
I’d like pizza.
Pizza?
Is that interesting?
Sang Shil.
What should I do with you?
Someone’s looking for the yacht?
Yes. Who?
Yes.
Please give me the
contact of that person.
Yes.
What is it?
Someone in Seoul is looking for the
yacht that was sold to Hong Kong.
Seoul?
Oh yes. Yesterday, Jang
Chul Soo went to Seoul.
Why did you say so only now?
Quickly get on a plane to
Seoul to solve this problem!
Jang Chul Soo.
I think it’s impossible
to find that yacht.
Those are all high-ranking folks,
really hard to get in touch with.
I’m so sorry I can’t help you.
It’s alright.
Yes, I understand.
What you looking at?
What’s wrong?
Nothing, you eat.
I’m leaving.
Jang Chul Soo.
Didn’t you say when you got back
from Seoul, you’ll tell me everything?
Is something going on?
Let me think through it carefully
before I tell you.
You thought you could send her back
immediately, you must be disappointed.
Duk Gu.
Don’t you think it’s strange?
The yacht….the call log too.
It’s like someone doesn’t
want Sang Shil to be found.
What?
That can’t be.
We can’t find the yacht, I’m feeling
down so I’m just saying that’s all.
You did well, Mr. Gong
Are you sure he will
not leak any information?
I can’t let any of this be out there.
Jang Chul Soo has thoughts
of sending Anna away.
As this goes on, if he
feels tired of it all,
Naturally, he will abandon Anna.
There’s a limit to playing Mr. Nice Guy.
He didn’t bring his phone out huh?
Who is this?
This is the Missing Persons
Center. Is this Jang Chul Soo?
The Missing Persons
Center? You can tell me.
We wanted to suggest welfare facilities for
the person that Jang Chul Soo is taking care of.
Although he said it’s not necessary…
But since the person
is unrelated to him,
We thought it would be better for him
if that person was sent to a facility.
Jang Chul Soo.
Playing Mr. Nice Guy.
Stupid retard.
What's this?
Now it’s Flower Bouquet?
I'm telling you straightforward.
I’m… not going to America anymore.
I will meet oppa and tell him this.
What?
Didn’t you leave Jang Chul Soo
and run to some other man?
I couldn't go.
I don't think I can leave oppa.
You...
Really...Jang Chul Soo…
I love him.
This feeling I have is for real.
And yours...it’s not love, is it?
That watch....
He gave it back to you?
Yes.
This watch....
You already know the significance
of this between me and oppa, right?
Both ends are coming at me so fiercely.
I don’t have staying power anymore.
What is it, Kang Ja?
Unni, where are you?
On my way home.
I’m not in the mood now, hanging up.
Unni.
Unni, this time you call me.
You’re right here, why
do we need the phone?
There’s not a call on my phone.
There’s no snow and no call.
It’s all over.
What an ‘act cool’ song!
Hello? Long time no see.
I’ve called. That’s it, right?
Of course, I’m familiar with that area. Yes.
I’ve gone with my dad many times.
I can’t go.
Yes.
Kang Ja,
Do you know why mothers say
they don’t like jjajangmyun?
My mum likes jjajangmyun very much.
Yes.
Mothers do like jjajangmyun.
But there are times
when they say they don’t.
That’s what they call
love and sacrifice.
That’s what Jung Chul Soo said.
Then, unni doesn’t like jjajangmyun?
Yea.
From now on,
I will say I don’t like it.
You’re here just to pass this to me?
Yes.
I’ve been calling you. You’re getting
irritated so you didn’t bring it out?
Yes, you’re irritating.
I thought so too.
Jang Chul Soo.
I feel like drinking
today. Give me a treat.
What?
Jjajangmyun with makgulee*,
how is that? (*Korean rice wine)
Jjajangmyun with makgulee,
do they go together?
What’s the problem with that?
Today, I’ll eat whatever
I feel like eating.
Today we’ll drink makgulee,
tomorrow we’ll go for jjajangmyun.
No.
Today, we’ll eat both.
Who ordered jjajangmyun?
Here.
Hyungnim, only today, never again.
Na Sang Shil,
Drinking makgulee like
this is really weird.
But it’s not bad too.
Of course it’s not bad.
That’s what I like.
Yes.
The two things that you like are
both here. Of course you’re happy.
No, it’s 3 things.
There’s Jang Chul Soo here too, right?
It’s my honor.
To be listed with
jjajangmyun and makgulee.
Don’t think too much about it.
I like you because you buy me food.
Yes, I’ll buy and into the future too.
Eat a lot, Na Sang Shil.
Jang Chul Soo, what is that?
That? That’s BungMakPan?
You want some?
BungMakPan? See how awful it looks.
Awful looks aside, it tastes good.
Jang Chul Soo,
What is a JimDaeBang?
Don’t you like it when it’s heated up?
When we next have a chance,
let’s go. You’ll like it.
Heated up?
I like that.
Jang Chul Soo, what is this?
This is a doll machine.
You seem to have come from another
world. Everything is new to you!
It’s true I’ve come from
another world, isn’t it?
My memory is at another
world I don’t know of.
Want to try getting a toy?
How can there be a machine like this?
A whole money-eating machine!
It’s a friend, your friend.
I would never eat money so shamelessly.
Give me more money.
I must get that toy no matter what.
If you go on your way, the
house will not be ours anymore.
Shove aside.
It’s all about technique.
You did well, Jang Chul Soo!
A cat doll, huh?
Just nice. You like cats very much.
Is that so?
I knew that.
I’m going to take it away with me.
What?
Huh? I said let’s go.
Why is she so happy today?
You’re coming along with me.
That’s good.
Sleeping again!
She’s not Na Sang Shil,
Jang Chul Soo!
Don’t get confused.
We’re off to school.
Yes, go well children.
I’m off.
Jang Chul Soo.
What?
If you’re very bored
by yourself, call me.
Jang Chul Soo.
What?
Thank you.
Take care.
Goodbye.
Dog,
Take care.
Go often and see your beloved.
Na Sang Shil is very quiet today.
Did she lose interest in
the hand phone so quickly?
Chul Soo, are you really going
to let Miss Na earn her own money?
What?
Miss Na looked me up,
She asked if she could make money by being
good at English and playing the piano.
Did Sang Shil ask you that?
Yes.
Hello?
This is the Missing Persons Center.
We’re checking if you received
the information we sent to you.
What information?
Some woman called, asking for
information on the welfare facilities.
[Sang Shil]
Jang Chul Soo.
Thank you.
Hyung, where are you off to?
In the middle of eating!
Where are you going, Chul Soo?
Sang Shil!
Jang Chul Soo,
I’ve regained my memory.
As you requested, I wrote
you a note before I left.
[Seoul  NamHae]
I’m leaving.
I’ll take care of myself,
so you live well too.
The money I took from the envelope,
I’ll try to repay as quick as possible.
Na Sang Shil.
Got to figure out where she’s headed.
Just a minute.
This is the woman Chul Soo is
looking for, everyone take a look.
[Subject: Looking for Na
Sang Shil. Attachments: One]
This is the woman,
Chul Soo is looking for her.
[Saw her on the bus
headed for the city.]
[Saw her at the bus terminal.]
[Saw her at the highway bus terminal.
I got so far away from Chul Soo's house so quickly.
Jang Chul Soo,
Why are you here?
Just come with me,
everyone’s looking for you.
No need.
It’s time for me to go anyway.
So you’ve regained your memory?
Yes.
That’s why I’m not
related to you anymore.
The money I borrowed I’ll pay
you back later, don’t worry.
Regained your memory?
Yes!
That’s fine, right?
Don’t tell lies.
If you did regain your memory, how
is it you’re still Na Sang Shil?
What…do you mean?
You...
You’re not Na Sang Shil!
Stealing a dog from the
kids, aren’t you ashamed?
Who was the one who first
sold somebody else’s cat?
Didn’t I mention?
Our relationship is
already very “special”.
The butterfly knot is
as big as a watermelon,
No, looks good, looks good.
Just like a gift wrap box.
I’m starving and you’re still eating?
You have food so you’re happy?
Buy you jjajangmyun?
That plaster,
Get over here.
- No.
– Get that plaster off.
It feels warm.
Feels like it’s effective.
Jang Chul Soo, I found money!
Really?