Attention projectionist,
adjust the lens,
so that your picture
will be focused properly
before the show starts.
Flying Saucers have
invaded our planet,
Washington, London,
Paris, Moscow are
key targets, the whole
world is under attack!
People of Earth, attention!
(Narrator) In 1952 the
Central Intelligence Agency,
faced with a huge public
interest in flying saucers,
brought in a
panel of scientists,
very senior scientists,
we know it now as
the Robertson Panel.
They concluded that
there was nothing
to these flying saucer reports
as objective devices
of some kind
but that, nevertheless,
the government had to
exercise great care
to debunk the stories
and individual civilians
who expressed an interest in
flying saucers ought to be
carefully watched,
said the Robertson panel.
And I believe that to be
the founding document,
the document giving the
long range strategy
that has been followed
by the US government.
The general feeling
amongst people
who have devoted a big
chunk of their life
to studying UFOs, I think,
is fear that they have
been taken for a ride,
that these cases are hoaxes,
but sophisticated hoaxes carried
out by their own government.
What do you want with me?
(Narrator) Let's take
one step at a time,
you're looking at Richard Doty,
the professional
disinformer, trained to lie.
I'm Richard Doty.
There's probably about
80% of false information
being presented and about
20% of factual information.
Unfortunately the
UFO community
doesn't know which is which.
(Interviewer)
And that's your job,
to keep it that way?
(Richard Doty)
That was my job before,
I'm a private citizen now.
But back in the early
eighties it was my job
to confuse the UFO community.
Doty was representing
himself, as I recall,
as basically this
sort of Deep Throat.
Doty had this wonderful
way to sell it,
I'm with the government
you cooperate with us,
and I'm going to
tell you what the
government really
knows about UFOs.
Doty found a lot
of gullible people
in the UFO community,
that would easily believe
what he said without
any type of scrutiny.
My commander told me,
"Well there's this guy
Special Agent Doty,
and you've got to be careful
because he kinda made the..."
The impression I got was that
he had made the Air
Force a little nervous.
Maybe... they didn't say egg
on their face or anything,
but they were just
very cautious.
The main reason that
we in the UFO field
recognize the name Richard Doty
is that a man named
Paul Bennewitz
a self-made man,
a very successful businessman
was systematically driven insane
wound up in an insane
asylum under treatment
for a long time,
lost his business
had to turn it over
to his family,
and was destroyed
by the efforts of
Richard Doty.
You hear about the ones that
something goes wrong.
You hear about the ones
where there was an
unfortunate incident
or in some cases
there are failures.
It was unfortunate
what happened to Mr. Bennewitz
but they were
supposed to protect
something and they
did their job.
That's the part
of the base that
Paul Bennewitz could see.
You can see the
Manzano mountain here
where all the nuclear
weapons were stored.
Kirtland Air Force Base,
the perimeter fence,
Paul Bennewitz's house
is right over here,
and his excellent view was
afforded from this
exclusive area of Albuquerque.
You basically have
a front row seat.
August, September of 1979,
Paul was standing
up on his deck
and looking up over the
roofs towards the base
and these lights he
saw would probably be
about half a mile away,
there was always two of them,
they'd lift up from the
ground rather quickly
and then very
quickly go around,
shoot that way around
the side of the mountain
and then drop down behind it.
And they did the same
thing every time.
For anybody that would
peak your interest,
"What the hell is that?"
He had an interest
in the UFO subject.
It was about the only
thing he was interested in
besides his business.
He had a company called
Thunder Scientific
they designed instruments for
high profile people like NASA
and even the Air Force.
A lot of people said
he was a genius
with electronics and
he decided that he was
going to listen in
on what was going on
at the base, maybe he
could pick up some
radio signals about
what this thing was
and he knew about
where to start looking
and he started picking up
these bursts of information,
when he started
to decode the signals
he thought that it
had a connection to whatever
these lights were.
He decided it was
something to do with
technology that wasn't ours.
He was a good American,
so he called up
the Air Force base,
they connected him with
Richard Doty eventually.
Paul didn't know
initially what he got,
he didn't analyze it.
And when he had got
the first series
of transmissions,
he recorded them,
and then he contacted the
security officer for Kirtland.
I began
a dialogue with Paul,
trying to find out
everything he had
and as I did then I
learned that a lot
of the information he had
wasn't anything to do
with a Soviet threat or
some kind of hostile
threat against Kirtland
it was information
that he had gathered -
because of the fact
that he was a scientist,
and because he had sensitive
and sophisticated equipment
he was collecting emissions
coming from the base.
And we had to decide what we
were going to do then,
were we going to
allow this to happen?
Or were we going to try
and convince him otherwise?
The more he had contact
with me and others
within the intelligence
community,
the more he started analyzing
the information.
So, we kinda planted
the seed in Paul that
what he was seeing and
what he was hearing
and what he was
collecting was in fact
probably, maybe, UFOs!
It was very easy
to convince Paul.
Paul was a
World War II veteran,
he was very patriotic,
he always flew his flag.
Those type of people
you can convince that,
"Listen", just tell him
"Paul, you can't tell
anyone else about this,
because it could get
into the wrong hands"
so immediately Paul became
a cooperating source
he held everything
that he had gotten
in secrecy.
(Bob Durant)
Doty was feeding this man
all kinds of lies
about UFOs and aliens
being kept underneath
a mountain nearby, and
so on and so forth,
and Bennewitz, of course,
was believing all of this.
He had two films,
of an object flying,
one picture depicted an object
that looked like it was
flying out of the mountain
and it looked like some kind
of saucer-shaped object.
He immediately then
though that there
were UFOs coming
out of Manzano.
The second film
was of an object
that was something
that was experimental
that the
government was doing.
When he filmed that, then
again the flag went up that
he just filmed a
classified project.
Paul made a presentation to
the Air Force officials,
on what he had been doing
and about what he had
been collecting.
He showed some of his film, he
showed some of his pictures,
he had a audio recorder
that was playing
the sounds that he had
collected from the base.
The highest ranking
person in the room
who was a Brigadier
General said
"You have some very
convincing information Paul."
And that kind of set
everything in motion with
Paul to let him think
that, yup, he does.
From the point he came
in and gave that meeting
they decided all his perceptions
were going to be directed
exactly the way the intelligence
organizations wanted.
(Richard Doty)
We briefed everybody
in the room.
So they knew what we
were doing, basically.
And so after the meeting there
was a number of
questions asked to him,
"What do you want the
Air Force to do?"
And Paul says "I'd like
a grant to investigate
UFOs on the base" and a
grant to continue
this contact that he claimed he
had with some of these aliens,
which... now that's
a different story!
At one point another
agency was conducting
an investigation and they
set up a surveillance
across the street from him
and Paul's son contacted
me and said
"Leave my father alone,
you guys are across
the street and you're
bothering my father,
he's getting to the point
that he's being paranoid."
Well, I knew it wasn't us.
(Greg Bishop)
He said he saw people coming
in and out of the house
and looking out
from the curtains
and things like
that and as it turns out
the NSA had some
people in this house,
they were watching
him and actually
beaming messages straight
across the street
into his antenna set up.
He'd started picking up
these signals
and the NSA was scared
that anybody could
figure that out.
They decided to just
take complete control
of what he was seeing
and give him exactly
what he thought he
should be getting.
They replaced his
computer with
their own computer.
The computer had software
that would decode
the messages that he
was getting in the way
that they wanted
him to see them.
And if you look at
the transcript of it,
it seems like almost
gibberish but because
people want to pull out
content from a random
order it starts to make
some kind of sense.
They said that they
were from a planet with
no water and they were
trying to find a new
place to live and they
wanted to take over
the Earth and that they
can only trust Paul.
They were going to have some
kind of agreement with him
but he said you can't
trust anything they say,
these aliens are evil
and it served to make him
look silly which was
exactly what they
were trying to do.
Paul actually thought
that these UFOs had
to be coming
from some other place.
So Paul on his own went
up to Archuleta Peak,
which is in northern New
Mexico, around Dulce, New Mexico
and he did his own
investigation basically.
Dulce and the
Archuleta Peak area
had a superstition
for many years,
way, way before we
were ever involved.
There were strange lights
and strange stories
about that area coming from
the Indian tribe that
lives up there.
(Greg Bishop)
If somebody wanted to hide
something here
it would be pretty
easy, it's very remote.
It's supposedly the site of
an underground alien base.
That rumor got started
in the early 1980s
because of what was
told to Paul Bennewitz
by the Air Force Office
of Special Investigation.
Paul was a pilot,
and he had a plane,
and he flew around those
areas and he saw things
and he filmed things
up there that, again,
presented a
problem for us because
what he was filming up
there was actually
a secretive military
installation
that was training commandos.
So then we had to convince Paul
that what he was seeing up there
was again, UFOs.
(Greg Bishop)
The Air Force actually put him
in a helicopter
with Rick Doty the first time
and flew him up to a
place above Dulce,
called the Archuleta Mesa
and before they
took him up there,
they dumped a bunch
of props up there.
They flew him up there, flew
him over the mesa and said,
"You're right
Paul, look there's stuff here,
there's some evidence
of what's going on,
why don't you check
this out for us?"
(Richard Doty) So I would
go with Paul up there
and we actually
camped out there a couple times
and we actually saw some
things that startled me,
which were fully
explained later,
but one of the things that
was kind of interesting
were these lights coming
out of the ground,
but the way the
lights, these beams,
were coming out of the ground
in a pulse kind of manner,
that it looked like they were
saucers flying out
of these mountains, and I
actually saw this
and I was somewhat
concerned that maybe
Paul had stumbled
onto something.
Paul was flying what
he called his missions
around Archuleta Mesa
and would send back
fascinating letters,
five, six, seven,
eight pages long,
hand written with pencil
sketches of what he'd seen.
And finally he started
sending large format
eight by ten photographs taken
with his Hasselblad
in which he'd say,
"Well, here's the black
atomic powered ship that
crashed last week" and
he'd circle it, and, oh,
I'd look at that
and, bless his heart,
I couldn't see anything that
resembled a crashed anything.
(Greg Bishop) Something
actually did crash near Dulce
on the mesa
in the late 1980s.
Bennewitz just happened
to be flying over it
and took pictures of it and so
the disinformation campaign
had to be ratcheted
up even more.
The Air Force, they knew
it was something
they were testing up in
this area and that it
had gone off course
and crashed.
Of course they told Paul
Bennewitz that it was
some sort of alien
craft that had been
given to the humans
to use and that they
had shot it out of the sky
as some sort of a lesson.
What probably crashed there was
some sort of unmanned
aerial vehicle and now they're
over in the Middle East,
remote controlled,
killing people in cars
as they drive
across the desert.
But in 1985 they didn't
really want anybody to
have any knowledge of
this kind of thing.
They took great pains to
explain to him that it
was this atomic powered aircraft
that the aliens had helped us
with and bring down
that laughter curtain
again so people
just wouldn't pay attention.
They'd just think it
was another UFO nut.
Somebody gave him a
satellite picture
of the landing area.
In '83 he went up
there with me
and the chief of police for
the Jicarilla Apache tribe.
They had made a landing pad
and he took us
right to the spot.
They were giving
him disinformation,
some of it was true,
some of it wasn't, see.
I think that was the
biggest problem he had,
coping with, why this,
why not the other thing?
He thought that
this was the place
where the aliens were
getting together
to take over the world
and he wanted to trap
them all there, kill them
all in one fell swoop
and save the Earth.
By the mid eighties he
was getting to the point
where he had written
all of these
letters to congressmen,
senators, TV stations,
even President Reagan
saying this is what's
going on, the Air Force
is cooperating with me,
these are the people
who are cooperating
with me and giving
me this information,
Earnest Edwards,
Richard Doty, all this,
he would put their
names in these letters.
He'd get answers back saying
"We're not interested
in the UFO subject,"
and there was this kind of
cognitive dissonance,
here are people in the
government telling him
"Yes, you're right,
this is going on,
let's keep an eye on it."
And then elected
officials and other people
in the media saying,
"We don't know what
you're talking about,
this isn't very important."
And nobody seemed to
care what he was talking about
except the Air Force.
So many people knew
ultimately about
Paul Bennewitz and that
sad, strange,
horrible story that it got
way out of the realm
of just a cute
flying saucer story.
Paul was convinced
that everything
he was doing was UFO related.
I actually sat down
with Paul and told Paul,
"Listen Paul, I think you
ought to stop doing this.
I think you've gone
as far as you can go,
and this is a friend, this
is Richard Doty a friend."
It wasn't Richard
Doty a Special Agent
with OSI talking to him, I said
"This is a friend
talking to you, Paul."
Because I became a
friend with him,
he was a very wonderful person
and I didn't want to see
him harmed and I said
"Paul, stop it!
Listen to your son,
listen to your wife, end it.
Get rid of the equipment,
lock this stuff
away, go on with your life,
go back to your
work at your business
and stop this".
Paul listened to me and
I thought maybe he was
going to take my
advice, but he didn't.
He continued and continued
and continued
and at that point we ended
the investigation,
we ended every
involvement with Paul Bennewitz.
(Greg Bishop) By 1988
things were so bad that
his family decided to
take him to a psychiatric
facility and see if they
could try and save his life.
He said that aliens would
come at night through
his wall and inject
him with something
that would make him get
in his car and drive out
into the desert and
he didn't remember
what he was doing
or why he went.
The scary thing was
there actually were
injection marks on his arm.
(distorted voice) This is a
friend talking to you...
Years later, I sat
down with Paul,
at dinner and told Paul,
exactly, that everything we did
was a sanctioned counter
intelligence operation
to convince him that
what he was seeing
was UFOs and that what
we didn't want him
to know was that he had
tapped into something
on the base, and
we didn't want him
to ever disclose that.
Paul looked at me and said,
"You don't have to
lie to me, Rick,
I know it UFOs related".
If it hadn't been for Paul
Bennewitz I would have
never known 70% of the
stuff that was going on.
(Greg Bishop) What kind of
stuff did you find that
would make you think
that there was
something underground there?
(Gabe Valdez )
Well, the entrance to...
(Greg Bishop)
A big enough entrance to get
a truck or a plane or
something through?
(Gabe Valdez) Yes.
(Greg Bishop) You saw this?
(Gabe Valdez) Uh-hum.
(Greg Bishop) But it wasn't
where Paul said it was?
(Gabe Valdez) No.
Well, the first case of
the cattle mutilation in Dulce,
it was June 14th 1974.
People do kill animals
and steal the meat,
and it's different,
it was different.
Why did they just
take the udder,
the lymph nodes and the tongue
at the base of the
throat with the tonsils?
And we're finding the
evidence at the mutilations,
gas masks that were
made by the military,
radar chaff,
and the tranquillizers
they were using -- atropine,
they were injecting
them with atropine.
I was up front
with the ranchers,
they were losing cattle and
nobody was compensating them.
I wasn't hiding
anything, I never did.
I'm established as
somebody who is doing
all of this news
and documentary.
So I start getting
newspapers, people are saying,
"Linda, what is the answer?"
Ok, this is what I'm
going to do next.
I'm going to get to the bottom
of this animal
mutilation mystery.
And finally in October
of '79 Lou Girodo,
who was the head of
the district attorneys office
in Trinidad says,
with our cameras running,
finally, "Well,
investigators and I
have come to the conclusion
we're dealing with creatures
not from this planet,"
is the way he put it,
which is in my film,
A Strange Harvest.
And said all the reasons why,
the orange light that
he and a deputy had seen
go into the ground,
come out, split in two,
in pastures where they had
mutilated animals.
(Gabe Valdez)
We did follow one
and it stayed there,
it was hovering on
top of the cattle,
Manuel Gomez's cattle,
and when I was going to try and
intercept it myself
it flew over me.
But this looked like a
saucer type, yeah, aircraft.
(Greg Bishop) Ah ha.
(Gabe Valdez) You could
see lights in it blinking.
Why do they put lights if
they're from outer space?
They don't need any
guidance with lights!
I was an analyst in the
agency responsible
for chemical weapons
analysis
so the embassy would
always give me
a security escort and bodyguard.
Special Forces guy
came, and I said,
"Hey, what do you know about
these crazy stories
about the helicopters that
are taking mutilated cattle?"
"Oh," he says, "my real job,
I'm in a special
group in New Mexico.
We've been doing something that
is really, really interesting."
He said, "It just blows my mind,
I just...we got these
helicopters that I'm flying."
He says, "These helicopters
are all fixed up.
First of all they got
no markings on 'em.
Second of all
they're really fast.
Third, they're really quiet,
and they got a lot of lights.
We got red lights,
we got white lights,
we got strobe lights."
I said, "What are
you talking about?"
He says, "We pretend
we're UFO's."
What the hell is that?
(Greg Bishop) Do you know
anything about this?
Where did all that
information come from?
Why do you listen to
those people, they lie?
It's like, yes but they talk.
And if they talk, once in
a while you're gonna get
a piece of something
in that huge pile of crap
that will actually
connect to what you want,
and if you don't
let them take you somewhere
like they did with Paul,
kind of keep an even keel,
I think you're ok.
You just have to listen,
that's the thing.
(Man at conference)
So are you saying
the Dulce base,
or the Dulce architecture,
let's call it, ah,
exists or doesn't exist?
Have you investigated
the RAND Corporation's
involvement in
tunneling in that area
in the 50's and 60's?
(Greg Bishop) Oh yeah, yeah,
I actually put some
of that in the book...
(Man at conference)
...nuclear waste facility
there...
(Greg Bishop)
Not waste, but they
exploded an atomic bomb
underneath
about ten miles from Dulce
to try and get
gas out of the ground.
Stupidest idea! They
couldn't use the gas
'cause it was radioactive.
(ARCHIVE) New programs
of the Atomic Energy Commission
and other
agencies are designed
to expand the usefulness
of nuclear energy.
Before work is begun on
any of these programs.
The government thoroughly
evaluates the health
and safety factors,
often for several years.
Project Gasbuggy was
an underground nuclear
detonation that
took place in 1967
in Dulce, New Mexico.
It was an attempt to release
natural gas reserves
from the subterranean
environment
in a sort of early version
of what we would
now recognize as fracking.
Some people have
suggested that the cattle
mutilation program
was actually a covert
monitoring program for
assessing the radiation
leakage levels into
the environment,
into the ecosystem and
into the food chain.
(Gabe Valdez)
Senator Harrison Schmitt
had a conference here in
1980, 'cause the ranchers
were asking for help,
and I met Paul Bennewitz there.
He was taking a bunch of
pictures of the aircraft
coming out of the
Kirkland area,
but we were watching
the same aircraft
flying in the Dulce area, see.
Everybody's looking at these
sophisticated aircraft
and kind of saying,
"Well, they're the
one's that are
mutilating the cattle."
One agency was doing
the cattle mutilations,
but the people that
were doing the research
on the aircraft used the
cattle mutilations to test
their aircraft so that
people think it was UFO's...
and it helped the cattle
mutilation thing, see!
It's a wonder they didn't crash
into each other, you know!
(Linda Howe) Doty and
others would probably
defend their
counter-intelligence efforts
as being patriotic.
They are carrying out
work assigned by people
who have decided
that there must be
a policy of denial in the
interests of national security.
They're working
for my government.
They're working in
agencies of the government
that is supposed
to be protecting
of the people by the
people for the people.
How did it all
turn upside down?
(Tracy Tormé) At the core
there is something
that they want to keep
people away from.
A real truth.
I'm Richard Doty.
I'm here at the UFO
Congress at Laughlin, Nevada,
as a private citizen,
just enjoying the
sights and sounds.
Disinformation is
designed to appeal
to the person that
it's operating on.
The more dramatic you
can be appealing to that
prejudice, the better
you're gonna get
your hooks into the person
you're trying to get.
In Paul Bennewitz's case,
he was taking about
UFOs and so if the Air Force
wanted his full
and undivided attention, they
would talk UFOs with him
which is exactly
what they did.
It became seen as
necessary to create
an active disinformation
program in the late
1970's and early 1980's
and the reason for this
is twofold.
One was the American
Freedom of Information Act.
(Archive Voice)
"It's curtain time.
An ingenious printing
element that works faster
than the eye can see.
Watch it in action."
(Richard Dolan)
Thousands of pages of documents
were released from places
like the CIA, the FBI,
all the
military agencies.
Documents proving the
lie that agencies
across the board were
interested and were tracking
the UFO phenomenon.
During the late 1970's
a variety of leaks
started to occur.
Now they're just
stories right?
But the problem is
there were many of them
and they seemed to have
a coherence about them.
Researchers at the time were
in a very optimistic mode.
I wouldn't say there
were giddy so much
as just hopeful, that if
they got the right leak,
or the right document,
that they just might be able
to smash the
wall of secrecy.
Then what happens?
Then we get entrants into
the field by individuals
who start leaking
documents of dubious origin
whose provenance
was basically unknown,
that caused now twenty
five year's
worth of dissension
in the research field.
And it's the same within
the mainstream media.
Serious media never in
their news coverage
truly, seriously promoted the
extraterrestrial hypothesis,
what they
did do was move that
to the realm of entertainment.
Any time someone
brings such ideas up seriously,
what you find is the serious
media says well,
you've been watching
too many movies.
So in a sense you could
argue that the movies
are used to inoculate the
public against these truths.
So these demonstrably
false UFO stories
become inoculations.
When the doctor inoculates
you from a disease,
he gives you a little
bit of it,
and then your body's immune
system recovers,
deals with it and now you're
kind of immune to it.
(George Hansen off camera)
Look at the UFO conferences,
where are they held?
Usually in small dingy
hotels with rather limited
numbers of people participating.
(James Carrion off camera)
I mean there has to be
a reason why
it's perpetuating.
You don't see conferences
on leprechauns,
so why do we still have
conferences on UFOs?
James Carrion (off camera)
One of the keys to a
disinformation campaign
is to have a feedback loop,
and you need people
on the inside to feed back
to you the results
of the operation.
Probably Doty's first
success in rounding up
a useful asset as they say in
the intelligence field,
or a useful idiot as they also
say in the intelligence field,
was his recruitment of a
man named William Moore.
Now William Moore I think
very significantly was
the co-author of the
first book about Roswell.
(Rick Doty) I was given
the task of making contact
with Bill Moore
and basically finding out
what he knew and who he knew.
Bill was a little reluctant
to disclose everything to me,
for obvious reasons.
Here I am a government
agent coming in
and introducing myself and
wanting to know what he knew.
But there's techniques
that we use,
that we're trained
to use in gaining
that person's confidence,
and I used those techniques
against Bill Moore
and they worked and Bill Moore
took me into his confidence
and we had a professional
relationship as far as him
providing us information about
the UFO community and agreeing
to say things we wanted said
regarding the UFO community
or within the UFO community.
The process of studying
this phenomena
and the people involved with it,
of assessing the claims
and the counter-claims,
and of dealing with the question
of how we as
Earthlings will react to
the discovery of a race of
extraterrestrial visitors
and how they will react to
us, all of this and more
when finally looked at
in perspective leads
us to the inescapable
recognition that in studying
the UFO phenomenon we
are at the same time
becoming more
aware of ourselves
as individuals.
(Robert Durant)
Moore was singled out
because he had
achieved considerable
celebrity within the
UFO field and a certain
authenticity that
would recommend him to
politicians and journalists,
and remember
it's the politicians and the
journalists who are
the ultimate target of all
of this disinformation.
I went to visit Bill, he
had a bad back,
he was lying flat on his back,
he couldn't move,
he was in traction and I
remember him very dramatically
saying to me, "Aliens do
exist, UFO's are real,
I know that now for a fact."
Just seems kind of
almost like a bad
science fiction movie,
but that's kind of
what was going on at the time.
He was invested in
maintaining these contacts
that he had supposedly
inside the government.
At one point Bill
Moore had played me
an early tape recording
of a conversation he had
with Doty, and Moore was
telling me, you know,
this is a huge breakthrough,
and this guy is like
on the inside and he's gonna
give a lot of stuff away.
I just remember even
back then that I was
kind of suspicious that
it sounded a little too
good to be true, but I
was kind of curious as to
why somebody who
supposedly was in
Air Force intelligence
was speaking so openly
about some of these
incredible things.
(Robert Durant)
William Moore was
using his position
as an executive
of an outfit that was called
the Aerial Phenomena
Research Organization.
And in fact Moore admitted
that he paid off the secretary
of that organization
to send him reports
at once when they came in
and they went directly to Doty.
Bill didn't believe
everything I was telling him
and obviously he's
a very smart person
and a lot of the information
I was telling him
wasn't factual.
If you were a UFO
researcher and you were offered
documents that
nobody had ever seen,
that pointed the way
to what the government
might know about UFO's
and in exchange you
basically had to report
on what people were thinking,
what rumors
were making the rounds,
that's what he was
offered and in exchange
he was offered something
that nobody else had
gotten up to that point,
pure unadulterated
information
that would lead him to
the center of the answer,
the answer to the
question, you know,
what does the government know
and are there actually some
sort of non-human intelligences
interacting with the human race?
(Robert Durant)
Moore later was
part of the series
of break-ins into
the Bennewitz house,
and the psychological
warfare program.
Again, self-admitted by Moore.
Moore was not working alone.
Others, I'm convinced
went for the same deal,
and the deal was very simple.
You cooperate with us,
and, we will give you
the information that
the U.S. government has
deep down in those vaults.
Now, this is the
Faustian bargain
that William Moore went for
and he came up short on it.
It became apparent to
me that my supplying
information to the
government through Doty
on the activities of
Paul Bennewitz, APRO,
and to a lesser extent,
several other individuals
was to be a
part of this equation.
I also discovered that
whatever it was that
Bennewitz was involved
with, he was the
subject of considerable
interest on the part of
not one but several
government agencies,
and that they were actively
trying to defuse him
by pumping as much
mis, dis-information
through him as he
could possibly absorb.
Being a very small part
of that process gave me
I thought something
of an advantage.
It became my intention
to play that advantage
for all the information
I could get out of it.
Bennewitz for his part...
Frankly I'm a
little ashamed of some
people in this audience,
regardless of what you
believe what you hear or not.
(Greg Bishop) They had
to stop the talk about
4 or 5 times just because
of all the yelling.
People got mad ran out
of there, I saw a woman
start crying and leave,
people kept saying,
"Where'd you get all
that crap from, Bill?"
And one guy said, "I'm
gonna get a firehose!"
And ran out the back.
Very dramatic.
Bill's admission to
working with government agents
was the first
acknowledgement to the degree
which our government would
go in an attempt to keep
the cover-up going, and I
think people were angry,
maybe not so much at Bill,
but at themselves
for their own
naiveté as allowing
that to happen,
and refusing to
acknowledge that they
could have been just
as easily duped,
it's scary to think,
gee somebody I trusted
might be playing
me for the fool.
Bill Moore I think
probably believed
what he was preaching.
I think he was one of
these people that wanted
to believe that he was
one of the chosen few
to spread this information,
to be the Moses of
mythology, UFO mythology.
(Robert Durant)
Moore's book was well received
and in my opinion,
well done research,
but very troubling because
the thesis was
that Roswell was a real
spaceship that crashed
and that the U.S.
government has the parts.
I believe that he was
singled out precisely to
ultimately discredit him
and Roswell,
to keep the press and the
politicians off of Roswell.
(ARCHIVE) July 8th 1947.
The Army air forces has
announced that a flying
disk has been found
and is now in the
possession of the Army.
Army officers say the
missile found sometime
last week has been
inspected at Roswell,
New Mexico and sent
to Wright Field, Ohio
for further inspection.
(Mark Pilkington)
The key thing to remember
about the alleged crash
of a UFO at Roswell
in 1947 is that by the
time of Paul Bennewitz's
involvement in the UFO
field it had been entirely
forgotten by the UFO
community, and it was only
with the publication in 1980
of the Roswell Incident
by William Moore
and Charles Berlitz
that the elements
of the Roswell story,
the crashed spacecraft,
the recovered alien
bodies, the pact between
the American government
and the extraterrestrials
to back engineer
their technology.
All of these things have
eventually become the core story
of the American UFO mythology.
Their craft crashed
somewhere after coming all
these 50 light
years, they crashed
and then they sent
another one that crashed again,
and sent another
one that crashed.
About nine crashes
in the Southwest
in the late 40's and
that would indicate
to me or at least suggest
to me that we were
testing something
that was crashing.
Roswell happened.
Two crashes, one in
Roswell and one west.
They didn't find the craft
for a couple of years,
it was all one crash
but it took them
a couple of years to find
the second crash site.
(Conference voice)
Things are getting weird, man.
Now Doty played a
massive role
in the perpetuation
of the Roswell myth,
many of the ideas prominent
in the UFO subculture
for two decades and it was
completely avoided.
Rick Doty is certainly
a fascinating character
and clearly a trickster.
(Robert Durant) A man
who probably has trouble
figuring out whether he's
lying or not these days.
(George Hansen)
It would not surprise me
if people were selected
to sow disinformation.
It would also not surprise
me if some of the people
were selected because
they were not very bright,
they lacked
certain critical judgement
but were very
energetic in putting
out certain messages,
and I do often think
that some of the people
in the government agencies
who have been involved
in the UFO field
were kind of pushed or
nudged in that direction.
They'd just go
into the field
and muck it up automatically
by themselves
without any external controls.
Rick is not the
man you're after,
it's the person in the control
position that's important here.
In my opinion he was
just simply a pawn
in a much larger game.
Just as I was.
What we are hearing
today about malevolent aliens,
underground bases, secret
treaties with the US government,
has its roots firmly planted
in the Bennewitz affair.
The entire story of a
secret treaty between
the US government
and the aliens,
of exchanges of technology
between us and the aliens,
of battles between the aliens
and American armed forces,
and of aliens allegedly having
implanted hundreds of thousands,
if not millions, of human beings
for the purpose of
taking over the world,
and using us as
cattle, or slaves,
came about as a result of
the disinformation process.
I know, because I was in
a position to observe
much of this process
as it unfolded,
and I was providing regular
reports on its effectiveness
to some of the very people
who were doing it to Paul.
It wasn't a whole
lot that we did.
It was just a simple,
really, really, simple,
nod and statement to
Paul that what
he was seeing was probably UFOs.
It's generally assumed that the
counter intelligence operation
conducted against
Paul Bennewitz was designed
to throw him off the
scent of some kind of
classified experimental
technology
that he was accidentally
filming over Kirtland AFB,
but when you stop
to think about it
this doesn't make
a whole lot of sense.
If the Kirtland base
personnel really had wanted
him to stop his
investigations
they could have ordered
him to do so,
instead they encouraged
him to continue his
research and indeed
facilitated his
growing delusions about an
extraterrestrial invasion.
What this suggests is
that rather than a
campaign directed against
Paul Bennewitz,
this was an information war on
the American UFO community.
And there are a
number of reasons why
Air Force Intelligence
might have wanted to use
Bennewitz as a conduit
for disinformation.
The UFOlogists were
constantly seeking evidence
for the extraterrestrial
conspiracy and the UFO cover-up.
They were digging
through documents,
they were hanging
around secret air bases
and quite likely stumbling
upon genuine military secrets.
And a more serious possibility
is that Soviet intelligence
agents may have been
infiltrating the UFO field
in order to extract
this kind of information
about new technologies.
I think it's no coincidence
that the timing
of the operation
against Paul Bennewitz
dovetails with the development
of the Stealth program,
and at the time this was the
absolute pinnacle of
global aviation technology and
that's exactly the sort of thing
that Soviet agents would
be looking for.
If you guys are
doing a film... I...
I do not want to do an
interview in a film
in which you're going
to try to communicate
that there's nothing to UFOs,
that advance technologies
are being used to cover...
I mean... (Mark Pilkington
off camera) No. No.
That's not what it is.
(Linda Howe) It's just playing
into the government's...
absolutely what
they want people to do...
(John L. and Mark P. off camera)
That's absolutely not
what we're doing.
(Greg Bishop )
People trying to put out
documentaries about
UFOs seemed to be
teased over and over
and have the rug pulled
out from under them
at the last minute.
In the late '70s a rumor
started circulating
that there was a film of
a UFO landing at
Holloman Air Force
Base, in New Mexico.
And apparently a UFO came and
landed at the Air Force base,
on the tarmac, a group of
people went up to meet him,
there was a sort of
exchange of information
then the alien got back in
his ship and took off.
(Richard Dolan)
I have wondered,
that that film - I think as
many people have wondered -
was an abortive attempt at
some kind of disclosure.
We began with an
invitation and met with
Paul Shardle, who was head of
security for the Depository,
where all the films by the
military are sent,
all out at Norton.
We talked about possible
programs such as
three-dimensional
moving holography,
atomic fission, a dog
program where they
trained Shepherds to
do reconnaissance,
and a lot of laser work
at Wright Patterson.
Then he said, "I want
you to come with me
into this studio."
We went into a studio,
which was a clean room.
He said, "What would you
think if we told you
that in the early '70s
there was a landing
of an alien craft at
Holloman Air Force Base,
and our TDY, temporary
duty guys, had filmed it?"
And I was just
sort of scratching my head
thinking, UFOS?!
What are we talking about?
So he said, "Look, if
you're interested,
you should bury that under
the other projects,
because UFO sends
up a red flag."
He said,"If you're interested,
go talk to Captain somebody,
and he'll start a liaison
with the Pentagon."
Which we did.
I was told that
there was footage
and that was sort
of like a carrot.
Where you'll be
provided with a film
that we have, 900
feet of Ektachrome,
and off we began our project.
We had a legal contract
with the Pentagon
and an agreement on
everything that we were
going to be doing and their
total cooperation.
They fulfilled every
one of our requests,
they vetted our information,
gave sanction to it,
they really did not influence
the content at all.
I was quite surprised.
Even the people at
Holloman did not say,
"What are you doing? What
are you talking about?"
They seemed to confirm that
something had happened.
And the film was
not forthcoming,
but I knew where it was
and what it was
and was told by one of the
people we worked with
that it was confiscated
at the last minute
because it didn't
seem appropriate.
So we ended up having
to go to animation.
But everything else
was documented
as I recall it happening.
It was a daylight shot
of a light ascending
on Holloman Air Force Base.
And with that little clip,
that's all I can tell you,
that it's genuine.
A landing of a craft
at Holloman...
it was... film... very
brief... that's all...
you know... I can tell
you it's genuine...
(Mark P) Just that
snippet that you saw?
Just a light coming
down from above...
it was really not
that distinguishable
it was just among
other footage,
that's all I can tell you...
(Mark P) And just to
say on camera that you
never saw the Holloman
landing footage?
Not really...
(Mark P) Oh... OK!
Can you elaborate?
(sound recordist off-camera)
Can we just wait for that car?
Saved by the car.
I'm trying to think
how to answer that.
I knew what the film was
about, all the details of it.
But I never saw a real
projected version.
(Mark P off-camera)
You saw a still of it?
Yes.
(Linda Howe)
What is your bottom line?
Beginning, middle and end?
(Mark P off-camera)
Our bottom line is that
there is a UFO
phenomenon that's
genuine and needs to be
studied, and seriously,
and one of the things
that makes that
difficult is the muddying
of the waters by
people like Rick Doty,
Walter Bosely
and others who are
working for OSI, FBI,
who ever else
they're working for,
CIA, NSA, and they are
making the work of
people like yourself,
and us, and others
who want to understand
what's really going on
very, very difficult.
OK, and thank you
for your attention.
We're ready to roll
here just momentarily.
(Chris Green off-camera)
If you believe that it's true
then you have to buy in
to this phantasmagorical,
conspiratorial, bizarre,
nonsensical,
ridiculous story,
and when I've sat down with
Rick, his response to me is,
you know, it's
really all true.
(Bill Ryan off-camera)
Rick's great strength is
that he's a wonderful
storyteller.
He's a very friendly guy,
he builds relationships easily.
My immediate instinct
is to trust him.
(Tracy Tormé off camera)
I think it's very easy
to mislead people in
the UFO community.
You get them going
down a certain trail..
you give them certain
leads and you just
watch people chase
their tails over
and over again,
looking for the truth.
I was living and working
in New York when
Linda Howe actually came
to stay with me for a few days
and it was right in the midst of
her working on this HBO project.
Linda was sort of, I
believe, on the track
at the time, of thinking
that this was the film
that was gonna
again, expose everything,
and I believe she was
in touch with Doty at the time,
in fact I think she had even
gone to see him face to face.
And that was very
curious to me because
I'd known about this guy
through Bill, you know,
Bill Moore, and
I thought, hmm,
now he's sort of hooking
Linda in the same way.
Doty said that he has names
of people who are witnesses.
A security guard has a gun
melted in his hand,
there's a disc, beings.
I want to investigate
that story.
The original plan
with Linda Howe
was to obtain
everything she knew,
as much
information as she knew,
and to find out what
she was going to air
in this documentary for HBO,
and whether we wanted
it aired or not.
So I drove her out to
Kirtland, to the OSI office.
I took her into
a special room,
I told her it was the
Commander's office,
which wasn't really,
necessarily true...
The first thing that
shifted this from what I
thought was going to be
a five minute meeting -
get these names,and addresses
and phone numbers and go on -
I had already set up
other things to do...
"That documentary that you did
broadsided the government."
"How do you mean?"
"Nobody ever expected that
a credible journalist
would ever take on the
animal mutilation story."
It was like something was
shifting in the air...
Where is this going?
What is happening here?
He never gave me a list
of names or phone numbers.
Instead, he said,
"My superiors have asked me
to show you something."
Pulled out this
manila envelope,
pulled out these pages,
and as he's handing
them to me, he says,
"You can read these but
you cannot take notes.
You can ask me questions,
but I want you to
move from that chair
you are sitting in
to that chair."
Everything that was done
there was being filmed
by other agents
in another room,
and there was a
two way mirror.
And I'm looking at the top
page,and it's all caps.
Briefing Paper
for the President
of the United States of America
on Unidentified
Aerial Vehicles.
And I'm trying to
read what is the most
remarkable series of
letters and words that
probably has ever been
handed to me,
because this was
new, I was innocent.
And it started out about
all of these places
in the United States
that the government had
retrieved discs that
were identified
as extraterrestrial.
I knew some names,
like Roswell.
There was Aztec, Magdalena,
south of Laredo,
down in Arizona.
There were... my mind
was kind of reeling
at how many places
this is saying,
because all of us had only
heard of Roswell, really.
And eventually it came
to paragraphs that are
as indelibly emblazed
on my mind sitting
here today as they were then.
And the one that is probably
worth sharing from all of this:
"These extraterrestrials
manipulated DNA
in already evolving primates
to create homo sapiens."
And I remember
reading that sentence
over several times,
trying to absorb
the implication of its meaning.
Because if homo sapiens
is a genetically
constructed species by
extraterrestrials,
we are then, by definition,
a planet of six and a
half billion androids.
If we are androids,
what purpose are we serving?
All of that hit me,
reading that sentence.
Then, on the last page:
Paragraph, paragraph,
paragraph, paragraph.
PROJECT GARNET, all caps.
All questions and
mysteries about
the evolution of homo
sapiens on this planet
have been answered and
this project is closed.
The documents
that I showed her
came from our special
office in Washington,
with the operational plan and
what I was supposed to do.
And the plans to
show her these.
And I'd read them, and
I knew what was in them,
and I realized that
some of the information
contained in them was real.
But then I realized
that you have to give
real information in order
for a person to think
you're credible.
So I knew what was in there,
and I gave them to her
and it was sanctioned.
I did what I was told to do.
When you look back at it,
they must have had
meetings about,
"How do we stop a persistent
and dogged reporter
who has already demonstrated
that she's going to go after
a really, really
difficult subject.
How do we stop her?"
When you look back,
it all makes sense.
She wanted me to
tell her things
that I couldn't tell her,
and at one point she
went public with my name,
and she did what Paul Bennewitz
and Bill Moore didn't do
and she publicized the
fact that she was deceived
by a government agency,
namely OSI
and although there
were many other people
involved with that operation,
she named my name,
and so then I became
a public figure.
We actually played
a trick on Linda that,
er, kind of paid
her back so to speak.
Not anything that
harmed her in any way,
or anything like that.
We kind of planted something
that she ran with
which wasn't factual,
and I think she realized that
maybe she should keep her
mouth shut after that.
(Mark P off-camera)
The forged documents
shown to Linda Moulton Howe
by Richard Doty would
form the basis
for the Majestic 12 papers
which expanded upon the story
of the Roswell UFO crash
and provided the foundations
for the future
UFO mythology in America.
And over three decades later,
these documents
are still dividing
the international
UFO community.
Before it had always
been inferred
that a cover-up was underway.
There was talk about
who was involved and so forth,
but there was never
any paperwork.
Here's the paperwork.
A package showed up at the
home of Jamie Shandera,
who was Bill's sort of
writing and research partner.
What it contained was a
canister of 35mm film.
They developed it,
and what was on it was
photographs of this
document, saying that there
was a group that had been
controlling UFO information,
how it was released in public
and how the government
should deal with it.
Regarding the MJ-12
documents that were released
to Jamie Shandera
and Bill Moore,
I had absolutely nothing
to do with that.
The document could be real,
and because of the nature of it,
it made a perfect perception
management device.
People have to realize
that these things
may not be to cover up the
truth about flying saucers
it may be more to
gather information
about how the public
responds to manipulation.
When I print off the sum total
of all those documents -
you get a stack
about this thick.
When you read them through,
as one day I decided
this is what I am going to do,
it's very impressive.
To have faked it would
have required a team,
a high level team, of very,
very expert individuals
who know everything
about document creation,
science and technology
in the 1940s and '50s
and a whole bunch
of other things.
I looked at them, and
initially I thought
they were good
forgeries, but over time
my opinion of their quality
has gone down hill.
The use of a zero
in front of a date,
the use of an extraneous comma,
the obviously
photocopied signature...
they just keep getting
worse and worse.
If they were faked, the only
thing that one can say is,
the UFO topic was
considered important enough
by these people to create
the most elaborate,
incredible, detailed
series of papers,
and one would have to
ask, if they're faked,
"Why?"
There were some
investigations conducted by FBI,
OSI, regarding
the MJ-12 documents,
extensive investigations,
just to determine
whether these things
were legitimate,
whether they contained
classified information
and then who released them.
I was interviewed as a
suspect, did I do these?
It was proven that
I didn't do 'em.
But somebody outside the
government created it.
And in that particular instance
I don't know if the government
would prosecute them.
Doing that would lend
credence to the document itself
and then they would have to
disclose the information
and so the best thing
to do is just say...
we did an investigation
and not tell anybody
what the outcome was.
(Mark P Off-Camera)
I like to think of UFOs
as weapons of mass deception,
and the role of the
intelligence organizations
and the military,
in propagating UFO mythology,
as somewhat analogous
to what evolutionary
biologists call
a punctuated equilibrium.
The UFO mythology develops
of its own accord
and the Mirage Men
will just drop a new
piece of data, a new meme,
some new faked documents
into the mix as and when it is
expedient for them to do so.
And so there's no real
need for a sustained
UFO deception campaign
because the folklore
is just perfectly capable
of sustaining itself.
The US government
had a once-secret program
in which 12 astronauts were
sent to an alien home world,
Serpo, thirty eight point
four light years away
from the years
1965 through 1978.
When the returning
astronauts came back
I believe there were seven,
that report was finalized
into a report called
Project Serpo in 1980.
Rumors about this
kind of thing had been
flying around since
the 1960s or '70s,
so it's got some kind of
historical provenance.
(Victor Martinez)
In November of 2005
Project Serpo was sent
to my UFO thread list.
I received an
email from someone,
he requested to be anonymous.
When I first read
that bombshell email
it was far different
from anything
I'd ever received
and even though it was
a version that was
different than what
I was familiar with
it had the ring of truth.
Somebody within the
government would have
to be cooperating
because I can tell you
that a lot of information,
not all of the
particular details,
but a lot of the
information is factual.
I believe it is a
disinformation campaign
to lead people astray.
That said, a good
disinformation campaign
a good perception
management campaign
will always includes nuggets
of fact and truth
and some of those
nuggets of facts and truth
should be, if you're
going to do it effectively,
should be some of the more
extreme facts or truths.
They brought back
thousands of soil samples.
Samples from the Eben
civilization,
and I believe all
these artifacts
are now at Bolling
Air Force Base.
And photographs, too.
There's always a possibility
that the Serpo story
was created for
disinformation to
present to the Soviets
back during the Cold War
and somebody stumbled on to it.
There's always
that possibility,
but I don't think so.
It's not a professional job.
Myself and three
others were working
as a research team looking
into the Serpo story.
We really wanted to
get to the bottom
of Rick's involvement in it.
People within the UFO
community immediately said
"Hey, is Richard Doty
involved in this?
Did Richard Doty do this?"
I never had anything to
do with the Serpo story.
We were adamant at this
time that Rick Doty
was the person sending
the information.
But we didn't have any
proof and the only way
we could get that proof
was if we could see
an actual copy of
the original emails
that the anonymous source
had been sending Victor.
Unless Rick Doty is one
the greatest novelists
and writers of
the 21st century,
it's not him.
We came up with a plan.
We'll use the same name
and just contact Victor
and let him think
his anonymous source
was back in
touch with him.
We asked Victor to send
us copies of the emails
that we, allegedly, had
sent him which meant
we could look at the
headers of these emails
to determine where they
actually came from.
And it was from looking
at those headers
and having emails from
Rick Doty to compare against,
that it was indeed
Rick Doty's IP address
on the Request
Anonymous emails,
and, as it turned out
later, he was also
several other people
in the story.
All contacting Victor
and Victor thinking
he's been contacted by a
multitude of different people
when in fact
it was all one person,
it was all Rick Doty.
I didn't create
it, I didn't, err,
conspire with anybody
else to create it.
It was created by
somebody else and,
those people, I don't know.
(Bill Ryan) How do we
ever know what we know?
Apart from Victor
Martinez who really
started this thing off,
I'm the only name who's known.
We've got this
anonymous storyteller
'round this giant camp fire
who's entertaining us
with this incredible tale,
and we're sitting here
with bright eyes with
the flickering flames
thinking "Wow, tell
us some more."
The idea of
disinformation is that
it's meant to be believed.
With Serpo, the
first response is,
"Well, this is fascinating,
but it's ridiculous."
Of course there's
an aspect of me
that wants to believe this
wonderful story.
I had no idea where this
would be leading...
(Greg Bishop) Well, when
I first met Bill Ryan
at the Laughlin
conference in 2006
he presented himself
as somebody being
given information to
reveal to the public.
He didn't quite know why but
thought it was very important.
What's strange about
the Serpo thing
and Richard Doty was that
he denied, you know,
continually and
vociferously that he had
anything to do with
it, yet he came to
the Laughlin UFO convention
to see what was going on there,
to hear Bill Ryan talk and
announce this to the world
in person rather than
just on the radio
and basically had his hands in a
lot of things that were going on
or at least looked like
an interested bystander.
Why should he be interested
in this silly story?
Wonderful question.
We don't know whether Anonymous
got this from the movie
or whether Spielberg
had the tip-off
that this was one of the ways,
as many people in
this community suspect,
over the years, the public
have been gradually
acclimatized to the
possibility of this contact
with an extraterrestrial race.
By seeding little
parts of the truth
here and there in
movies, it's the best way
to get ideas through to
the general population.
This might have been one
of the ways of doing it.
I think the
information should be
brought out to the public.
Let the public decide
whether this is real or not.
(Bill Ryan) Whether you think
the information is real or not,
or whatever the proportion
of that might be the case
this is a government operation.
If it's a government operation
these guys wouldn't
be doing their job
if they weren't following
me every step of the way.
Ever since the
middle of November,
I've been assuming that
I'm being monitored.
If they're not doing that,
they're not doing their job.
And it's like I'm
one part of a team
but I don't even know who
the other team members are.
And I have to assume
that I'm being bugged.
I mean, this may be paranoid,
but whatever's going
on, it's happening
at a government level,
and therefore everything I do
is being watched.
I have to assume
I'm being tested.
-- You know the whole
Bill Moore stuff?
(Mark P) Yeah, yeah.
(Bill Ryan)
I wasn't around then,
but they were running
around ragged just to see
whether he would
make a good spook...
just to see whether he was
willing to obey orders...
I have to assume that's there's
something more at stake.
(John Lundberg)
You also need a really good
bull [bleep] detector.
(Bill Ryan) Yes, I know.
Since 1985 I've
talked to 18 people
at the cabinet
level or above
including four presidents.
About a third of them
have said, "It's true,"
about a third have said "I heard
it, and I think it's true,"
and about a third of them have
said "I don't have a clue.
I do think though,
Doctor Green,
that this is important for
you to investigate."
Turn it off for a minute.
The trouble with
the whole UFO thing
is there are so many
people who make up
BS stories that
no one can check.
Somebody can step
forward and say,
"I'll tell you what's
going on in UFOs,"
and they can say, "I've
briefed the President."
"I've done this, I
know what's going on."
I don't know ...
I think there's
too much BS in that field.
Part of the problem
that UFOs created
was that there were
people within government
within the Air Force,
within the CIA,
who really believed that
flying saucers existed.
And because they had stature,
because they had rank,
their opinion was
considered proof.
(ARCHIVE) Unless we understand
and work effectively
for the principles
on which our
American way of life
is founded the
structure will crumble.
Well, before going to
Norton Air Force Base,
going into a clean
room and being told
we had a landing by somebody
who seemed to be respectable,
his name
was all over the wall
as head of security, and his
boss and everything agreeing...
I didn't believe it then,
but then when confronted
with the information
I now realize
after working with
intelligence people
that it's a reality.
And they stand
behind the idea that
they don't disbelieve it,
it's just so far it's not
proven to be a threat to
our national security
and that's the way they
got out from under it.
In the intelligence
community there are
definitely people that
are interested in
extraordinary phenomena,
particularly UFOs.
Definitely believers in that,
because you don't work
in that profession
and it's not just a profession,
it's a world unto itself,
without learning some things.
How many pictures do you
need, how many eye witnesses,
how do you study
something that controls,
possibly, even this program?
What is known of
the truth of 'them' -
these other beings?
What if the truth
is bad? Could be.
What if we're their
farm animals?
What if they eat
us psychically?
Yeah, I don't know. There's
a lot of possibilities
there that are not good.
I think we are surfing
on the wave of a huge
adventure of the
opportunity of humankind
rolling into a totally new era
and that wave might
break one of these days.
Even the Vatican
recently has come out
in preparation saying
"Hey, listen, you know,
if there is anybody out
there, they're all
God's creations and
they're our brothers
and sisters really."
I mean, what a set-up
that is for what
might be coming next.
We're really a by-product of
extraterrestrial intervention.
We're really - I
mean, this is my view -
that we're... we've been
genetically altered by,
maybe not one, maybe
perhaps several
extraterrestrial races.
The government obviously
doesn't want to tell us,
otherwise they'd disclose
everything they knew.
And the most
important players,
the aliens, don't
want disclosure
because they could
disclose any time.
I mean, they control
most of the cards.
I don't have any files,
any photographs,
anything to show you,
I just have a lot of
personal research, I
have my professional
experiences and I have
the bona fides,
the tested bona fides
of the sources
and I have my intuition.
And those things
all fit together
and you kind of get a picture.
There is a planet,
that orbits Sirius
the Dog Star system,
they are human
they are very much
interested in us
and they have been
key to our survival
and they are capable
of coming here
certainly others
have come here.
Um, now... could that be
part of disinformation?
Absolutely.
I read things even
today that we fed to
Paul Bennewitz or
to Linda Howe
or to Bill Moore
that I fed to them.
And I see that today and
it's surprising that
that stuff's still
there but it just shows
we were a professional
organization
and we did our job
and that information
is still out there.
People whose job it was
to make the subject
look ridiculous over
the last 50 or 60 years
have done a very good job.
I don't know where they're
from, I don't know.
I don't know where
they're from.
I know that they're not,
like, from Detroit, you know.
That's as far as
I can take it.
So again, when
somebody starts saying,
"Well, here's who they are."
"Here's why they're here,"
they lose me almost
immediately.
I was selected to participate
in a special access program
within the counter
intelligence community.
My supervisor
selected me and said,
"You're going to be
briefed into a program
and you're going to be
responsible for investigating
everything associated
with this program."
The first part of the
briefing dealt with
how the United States Air
Force were countering
unauthorized disclosure
of technology
to the public by using the
UFO phenomena as a cover.
And then the second part
of the briefing
was where we were actually
shown and briefed about
the United States
government involvement
with extraterrestrials
since the late 1940s,
which was obviously the most
interesting part
of the briefing.
Well, they showed us
a lot of things.
They showed us a film
which was a late '40s
or early '50s film of a
recovery operation
which they talked about
as being in Roswell.
They showed crash debris, they
showed extraterrestrial bodies
and then there was also
a briefing showing
a live alien sitting in a
room talking to people.
And then the narrator of
this film talked about
the continuation of a
connection between
the United States government and
extraterrestrial civilizations.
After viewing this I was
not sure if it was real,
if it was... they
presented it to us for
some reason, maybe
some kind of
psychological conditioning,
I don't think
I initially
believed any of it.
But after the film
was over with
an Air Force Colonel
in uniform then started
talking about the
operation, the program,
how the United States
government,
and it was always the
United States government,
it wasn't Air Force or Army
it was the United States
government,
how they progressed
from the early days,
meaning the crash
retrieval operations
in the late '40s until now,
which was the late '70s.
And then the more he
spoke, the more I realized
that what I saw was real.
I mean this guy wouldn't
be sitting here,
standing here talking to
us with the people in the room
briefing into
this high-level program
if it was a hoax.
A fractured hall of mirrors
with a quicksand floor
that nobody knows
exactly what
the truths are and everybody
has found themselves
completely suspicious
of the motives of any
human being because
counter-intelligence
in England and the United
States and a lot of
other countries have
worked overtime
to misinform and to
tell the public
and the media there is nothing
to the UFO phenomenon.
It's a lie - I have no
question about it -
and my work is to try
to shed some light on
what could be so threatening
out of some other
intelligence from some
other part of the universe
or it's been here for
two billion years
and it's not
extraterrestrial but
we're the new ones on the block.
What is it that is
considered so threatening
that governments
will kill people
to keep it silent?
They can't come forth and say,
"Yeah, OK, we had
contact in 1947,
all this is real."
What would that do?
That would open up
a Pandora's Box,
because there would be
millions and millions
and millions of people
asking questions
that somebody has to answer.
The easiest thing for
the government to do
is just to say "no comment"
or "No, it I didn't happen."
But there are so many
people, so many people
within the government
that have come forth
with information saying,
"It did happen,
it's real," and the
reason I'm doing it
is because I asked the
government a long time ago,
"Hey, what am I
supposed to say?"
And they're going to say,
"You stick to the
fact it's not real."
But when the government
tried to discredit me
on something then I
went to them and said,
"Listen, you're telling
everybody it's not real,
and I know it's real,
and you know it's real
and all these other
people know it's real,
so I'm going to
tell the public
what I know about it."
And the government
basically said,
"Do what you gotta do."
(Robert Durant off-camera)
Let's take one step at a time.
You're looking
at Richard Doty,
and by looking at
him, you're taking
a glimpse into a whole machine
that now has a life of its own.