Strike_Back_2011 - S02 - E10 Project_Dawn_#10
Re-Sync & Edit
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha
Step aside, Major.
We'd all understand
if you pulled that trigger.
But the lives of thousands of people
are at stake.
Secure him.
Dress his wound.
PORTER: John Porter,
confess to the crime...
(ECHOING SPEECH)
Blood.
SCOTT: Sit forward.
Enjoy your stay at the organ farm?
Actually, I thought the food was shit,
so I discharged myself.
- (TIGHTENS ZIP TIE)
- (GROANS)
We're secure.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Careful.
SCOTT: He's clean.
Sergeant Richmond.
All your training to do this.
Woman's work.
(GROANS)
MAN: Are we the transport as well?
Sergeant, we have a hit.
MALE AGENT: Target two,
purchasing train ticket.
Where?
SINCLAIR: Big screen.
Kobánya Station, southeast suburb.
FEMALE AGENT: Satellite lock-on Kobánya.
Target's carrying a case.
Right, he's on the train.
Where is it going?
Arrives Nyugati main station
in 12 minutes.
SINCLAIR: If there is a bomb
in that case,
he'll need a trigger mechanism.
Something like a cell phone.
Remember, we're dealing with VX.
You will shoot to kill.
- Copy that.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Is it just me?
- What?
Sinclair.
You gotta wonder about a guy who's gonna
step between a bullet and Latif.
(TRACKING DEVICE BEEPING)
MALE REPORTER: General Ramiz's
announcement is
expected to be
welcomed by western leaders
attending the world Security Summit
in Budapest.
The stability of Pakistan,
which has nuclear weapons,
is high in the summit's agenda.
For us there,
Jessica, what's the latest?
FEMALE REPORTER: I report to you live
from outside Buda Palace,
as behind me, more of the delegates
from the world's most powerful countries
arrive to discuss security issues
in the Middle East and elsewhere.
- Now, although confidential...
- (MURMURS IN HUNGARIAN)
...we suspect that Pakistan will be high
up there on the agenda,
along with the staggered withdrawal
of Western troops from Afghanistan.
Now, as you can see,
a large crowd has formed...
Anything on the other target?
Nothing yet.
Whatever transport he's using
is coming in under the radar.
(MOUTHING)
And all the main delegates,
they understand the need
for absolute secrecy?
Yes, sir. A discreet meeting room
has been arranged
- just as you requested.
- Good.
About time, Colonel.
Recognise it?
Should I be invoking my human rights?
Well, for that you need to be human.
Terrorising a peaceful city
makes you something else.
How does a civilised, intelligent man
become what you are?
You know better than anyone, Colonel.
How many deaths have you sanctioned?
GRANT: Hmm.
As you can see,
we're tracking your bomber.
We have face recognition software
on every CCTV camera in the city.
(SMIRKS)
Impressive.
He will be caught
and he will be neutralised.
But if you thought there was only one,
you would have killed me already.
MALE AGENT: Target has disembarked.
We have visual.
Suspect getting off train
at Nyugati Station.
STONEBRIDGE: Yeah, copy that.
We're approaching the station now.
See anything?
SCOTT: Got no visual.
Repeat, no visual.
Found him.
Target's boarding a westbound subway.
It's rush hour.
If he detonates down there,
he could kill tens of thousands.
- He's heading under the river.
- (MONITOR BEEPING)
You need to intercept
further down the line.
Copy that.
SINCLAIR: We have you on visual.
RICHMOND: Target still on train.
Next stop, Batthyány tér.
You're thinking about Delhi, aren't you?
When we shook hands.
(ECHOING) When we shook hands.
And you gave me Mahmood.
You must long for that moment again.
It would have saved her life.
She had forfeited her life.
And what about Sergeant John Porter?
Captain Kate Marshall?
Are they just pawns in your game?
Pawns that you pushed
into the centre of the board.
This will end today.
Finally, something we can agree on.
Target's off. Batthyány Station.
STONEBRIDGE: Yeah, copy that,
we're en route.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
He's going down. Go.
SCOTT: I think I got a visual on target.
Looks like he's coming up
the riverside exit.
Target visual. In pursuit.
(TRAM BELL RINGS)
If you get a headshot, take it.
Negative. I got no clear shot.
It's a fucking sardine can in here.
Where's that tram heading?
Due south. Towards the palace.
Moving closer. I might have a chance.
Excuse me. Coming through. Excuse me.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
SCOTT: Hey, hey, hey. Shh.
Calm down. Calm down.
Fuck off. Fuck off. Fuck off.
Move! Move! Move!
Get the fuck back!
Get the fuck out of my way!
STONEBRIDGE: He's got a phone!
Drop it! Drop it!
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
SCOTT: Move, move, move.
(ALL CLAMOURING)
Lay down! Move! Move! Get off!
Give me the fucking phone!
- What's happening?
- SCOTT: Fuck! Get out!
- Scott, Stonebridge, report.
- Fuck.
- SCOTT: I think he's armed it. Fuck!
- Oh, shit.
Get the fuck up!
Fucker, stay there! Stay there.
Everyone get off the tram! Now!
STONEBRIDGE: I'm opening the briefcase.
(EXHALES)
(UNLOCKS BRIEFCASE)
- How you doing, Michael?
- (STONEBRIDGE EXHALES)
Careful, Michael.
- It's fucking empty!
- Where's the fucking bomb?
Where's the fucking... Where's the bomb?
Tell me! Where's the fucking bomb?
Huh? Where is it? Where is it?
What the fuck is that?
STONEBRIDGE: What?
SCOTT: Jesus. The bomb's in him.
SCOTT: Get off the train!
STONEBRIDGE! Get the doors, move!
Move away! Move back! Move!
(FIRING GUN) Everybody get back!
STONEBRIDGE: Now! Move!
SCOTT: Shit!
Back up! Back the fuck up!
STONEBRIDGE: Scott! Scott!
SCOTT: Everyone back!
STONEBRIDGE: Lady, back! Back!
STONE: Get away from the tram!
STONEBRIDGE: Get away from here!
Scott, report.
Yeah, the police are gonna need
decontamination units,
Hazmat suits, the works.
Is he using the VX?
Yeah. It's nasty shit.
And you're okay?
(CHUCKLES) Yeah. Thanks for asking.
The explosion was contained
within the tram.
No civilian casualties that I know of.
That shit is leaking out.
Hey, back up. Back up.
- Are you at a safe distance?
- STONE: Affirmative. We're upwind.
This entire area needs to be sealed off.
All right, Mike.
Looks like the cavalry's here. Let's go.
Scott, can you confirm
how the device was detonated?
You really want to know?
It was inside the son of a bitch.
Alert the Hungarians.
Let them know what we're dealing with.
- Got it.
- There's no keeping a lid on this now.
We need to find that other bomber,
and fucking quick.
(OFFICERS SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
(PROTESTORS CHATTERING)
(IN HUNGARIAN)
Colonel.
The bomber triggered a device
on board a tram.
Scott and Stonebridge managed
to get everyone clear
and contain most of the blast.
The device was carried
inside the bomber's body.
It's been a potential
terrorist M.O. For a while now.
A bomb in a cavity created
by the removal of the spleen.
It seems Major Sinclair appreciates
the measure of my achievement.
- It's an obscenity.
- Then it is just one of many.
- Thank you, Major.
- Colonel.
FEMALE REPORTER: We'vejust received
a report that there's been
a large explosion in the city.
Now, we're all the way up here
at the Buda Palace,
and we heard a really loud bang.
There is still no indication
as to what has caused that explosion.
But as you can see behind me,
the riot police have been drafted in.
And they were quite calm,
but now they are starting
to get very, very anxious indeed.
Exposing innocent people
to this poison is meaningless slaughter.
I'm not a nihilist, Colonel.
Everything I do has a purpose.
And what is that purpose?
If word of my presence here gets out,
our enemies at home will
undermine my presidential campaign.
And with it, our chances for peace.
- (SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
- (MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
- AIDE: Yes?
- (CHATTER OVER PHONE)
- I'm sorry, sir, we have to turn around.
- Why?
AIDE: We've been given a new location.
Well, what is happening?
Some incident at the summit.
- Incident?
- (TYRES SCREECHING)
(SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
(AUTOMATIC GUNS FIRING)
- (MAN SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
- (GUN FIRES)
No, please...
So what are you hoping to achieve?
Becoming the poster boy
for Islamist jihad?
- A new bin Laden?
- Oh, please.
You insult me by comparing me
to these religious fanatics.
- Oh, and you're not?
- I'm a pragmatist.
- A Pakistani patriot.
- You disgrace your country.
I honour my country, as I always have.
I have no regrets.
Can you say the same?
I'm not going to let this happen.
My will is greater than yours.
Then you know nothing of my will.
Mr Laszlo, this is Major Sinclair.
SCOTT: Come on, guys.
What the fuck are we waiting for?
Return to base. Still awaiting
intel on the second target.
That was not our intention.
...running scans
on every subway station...
Mr Laszlo,
Colonel Grant cannot come to the phone.
Tell me.
Have you told Sergeant Scott
that you framed him?
Does he know
of your role in Trojan Horse?
FEMALE REPORTER: We understand
that an order has been given
to evacuate all of the world leaders.
What's more worrying
is that the entire area surrounding
the explosion has been sealed off,
and Hazmat decontamination teams
have been called to the site.
Emergency services are asking people
to stay inside,
to close their doors and...
We intercepted
a local police radio call.
Mmm-hmm?
A VIP convoy was ambushed
en route from the airport.
Ambushed?
(GRUNTING)
Strange. I thought
all the leaders had arrived.
- They have.
- So who's this?
- Lost power on bank one.
- Lost comms.
Everybody down!
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
- Shit, you okay?
- Give me my gun.
- Julia, look, you're injured...
- I'm not dying without my fucking gun!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNFIRE STOPS)
SINCLAIR: (WHISPERING) One, two, three.
(GRUNTING)
(RICHMOND YELLS)
Fuck!
Clear! Fuck.
Sinclair, Richmond, you all right?
SINCLAIR: Here.
Julia, you all right? What happened?
Colonel.
Colonel!
They've gone.
STONEBRIDGE: Oh, shit.
(PROTESTORS CLAMOURING)
Thank you.
- How the fuck did they find us?
- I don't know.
You don't know? How convenient.
(GRUNTS)
SINCLAIR: Enough!
I haven't betrayed anyone.
I haven't compromised anyone.
So if you want to beat
some kind of confession out of me,
you're gonna have to wait
until there are no more
terrorists running around the city
with chemical bombs
stitched inside their fucking bodies.
Fine.
SINCLAIR: Good.
What have we got?
Well, the mainframe's fucked.
With a laptop, we should be able
to hook up to London.
Let me help you.
The first terrorist only tried
to detonate when he was confronted.
If it was just about killing people,
he would have done it on the subway.
(SIREN BLARING)
Laszlo.
STONEBRIDGE: That train
was headed towards the palace.
Major Sinclair, I demand to speak
with your superior right now.
She's not here.
As you can see,
our unit came under attack.
Your unit has no mandate
or authorisation...
With respect, we have already stopped
one suicide bomber in this town.
We saved the lives
of God knows how many people.
We think there's another.
And he's on his way to the palace.
So please, either help us,
or get out of our way.
- LASZLO: Is this your suspect?
- Yes, sir.
Do you think you can recognise
this man in a crowd?
Yes, I could.
WOMAN: Is struggling,
but his condition is critical.
(SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
My officers will escort you
back to the palace.
We'll have tactical support.
Thank you.
Major, what about the Colonel?
The terrorist threat first.
Besides, we have no idea where she is.
We do if she's with Latif.
- How?
- I put a tracker in his dressing.
Nice work.
RICHMOND: Just getting a signal now.
Tura, 38 kilometres from here.
Okay. Michael, you take the bomber.
Scott, you take the Colonel.
What the hell happened here?
Carnage.
By the way, Sinclair,
you hit like a girl.
I don't know. He kind of
hit you pretty good, didn't he?
Fucking hurt, but don't tell him.
- Let's go.
- SCOTT: Yeah.
- STONEBRIDGE: Bring her back.
- Shall do, buddy.
(GRANT CRIES OUT)
So what can you tell me
about this man right here?
- RICHMOND: Thank you.
- We know that he's Chechen.
But we have no name, no date of birth.
Major, I'm sorry to interrupt.
Just before she was killed,
Sally intercepted a communication
between Hungarian security
and Pakistani intelligence.
It refers to the VIP convoy
that was ambushed.
(GRUNTS)
SINCLAIR: The car that was ambushed.
He was in it.
General Akmal Ramiz.
Akmal.
RICHMOND: The Pakistani
presidential candidate?
And our best hope for peace in Pakistan.
Latif.
Your invitation to the summit was not
as secret as you thought, General.
You have John Allen to thank.
You endanger the lives of thousands
with chemical weapons for one man.
As ever, Colonel,
you see things so one-dimensionally.
General Ramiz is a liar and a charlatan.
But this is not a mere abduction.
You are witness to a moment in history.
And I'm honoured
to have such distinguished guests.
As the two principal architects
of Operation Trojan Horse.
Trojan Horse was only ever supposed
to be an intelligence operation.
Falsifying evidence of WMDs in Iraq
made the case for war.
But the road to hell
is paved with good intentions,
isn't that right, Colonel?
Intelligence wasn't enough.
Which is where ATAT and the
Pakistani military proved so helpful.
So the weapons were made and transported
to be placed inside Iraq.
SINCLAIR: Sergeant, the comms
are back on.
- LASZLO: Thank you.
- Sir.
RICHMOND: Scott, what's your position?
(TRACKING DEVICE BEEPING)
- ETA in 10.
- RICHMOND: Copy that.
Trojan Horse was necessary at the time.
We had to justify the action of our
Western allies to our own people.
This is ancient history.
But its relics survive.
It is those relics
that I have sought and obtained.
The very cache of VX that you intended
to plant inside Iraq.
They were supposed to be destroyed.
The temptation to keep them
was too strong.
However, ATAT didn't
hide them well enough.
So today, I deployed them.
While the future of my nation
is casually sealed over lunch
by foreign imperialists,
and you grovel at their feet.
I came here to save Pakistan.
You want a craven Pakistan.
A Pakistan laden with American bases.
A Pakistan that will give away
its nuclear weapons...
I'm trying to preserve my country
against extremist traitors
who would tear it apart!
Traitors?
Like you.
(BEEPING)
(ALL CLAMOURING)
(SIREN BLARING)
STONEBRIDGE: I need you
to get me inside this crowd.
SCOTT: Right.
(IN HUNGARIAN)
You're going to confess to Trojan Horse.
(SCOFFS)
Let the people of our country see you
for the hypocrite you really are.
What do you hope to achieve?
The truth about these weapons
will shatter your credibility,
awakening a new Pakistan,
a strong Pakistan,
unafraid to use its nuclear weapons
against its enemies in the West.
And why should I do your bidding?
(REPORTER CHATTERING)
LATIF: In that crowd,
a martyr is ready to detonate a bomb
containing your VX gas.
He is awaiting my order to proceed.
Or if you comply, I can call him off.
You have to release this crowd.
Do you hear me?
I can't. Not until
all the delegates are evacuated.
They are my absolute priority.
Somebody's gonna get crushed to death!
You have to let them out now!
I'm sorry.
You will kill those people
whether I talk or not.
GRANT: Akmal.
My men will intercept him.
We've already stopped one bomber.
You can take that chance, General.
But the questions remains.
How do you weigh up
the lives of thousands
against your cherished reputation?
(SMIRKS)
What, you feel sympathy
for this man, Colonel?
Placed in this terrible position
by a monster like me?
The man who killed John Porter?
(PORTER GRUNTS)
I, John Porter,
confess to the crime
of being a British spy.
(GUN FIRES)
But you must have asked the question,
who betrayed John Porter to me?
Why don't you tell her?
I would not lie to you, Eleanor.
His handler reported to me.
Porter was getting too close.
He learnt that the weapons were
a hangover from the operation.
Knowledge of Trojan Horse
would have torn Pakistan in half.
You gave him to Latif?
I...
allowed certain elements within ISI
to let his whereabouts be known.
A politician's answer.
But perhaps we shouldn't
be too quick to judge.
I saw Porter's last report from Lahore.
He told you he stumbled across
Trojan Horse, didn't he, Eleanor?
But did you tell him what you knew?
Let's be frank.
Mahmood, ATAT.
You suspected the connection
- right from the start.
- I...
But you hid it from your own section.
I tried to stop you.
But you only succeeded in helping me.
You didn't share your suspicions with
the people who trusted you the most.
For what?
Your own ambition?
My only ambition
has been to serve my country.
- For the sake of your career?
- Career!
- Reputation?
- Not my reputation.
- Then why?
- Because I was ashamed!
I was ashamed of what I'd done.
Then your shame killed Porter.
And the others, as if you'd
blown their brains out yourself.
Your silence meant the sabotage
of your own mission.
And with it, you were my greatest ally.
(SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
Come on. Move through.
STONEBRIDGE: I see him!
Get down! Down! Get down!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Get down!
- Don't shoot!
- (YELLING IN CHECHEN)
LATIF: Look into the camera and confess.
Never.
I will not do your bidding.
(LATIF COCKS GUN)
- I'll do it, I'll do it. I'll confess.
- No.
- It doesn't matter who says it.
- No, Eleanor, you cannot confess.
If you confess to Trojan Horse,
you will destroy...
(GRANT CRYING)
(CRYING) Oh, fuck you.
(SPEAKING CHECHEN)
No, no. Don't look at them.
Don't look at them! No, don't shoot!
Don't shoot! You look at me.
(SPEAKING CHECHEN)
It's okay.
We're gonna let
some of these people go, all right?
Go. Go.
Now it's just you and me.
I need you to think.
It's a child.
It's a life.
(GIRL WHIMPERING)
Just give it to me.
It should have been my brother.
SCOTT: Put the phone down.
Give her here.
(INAUDIBLE)
(SPEAKING CHECHEN)
(WOMAN PANTING)
LATIF: Seems for you, the lies have been
difficult to live with, Colonel.
So why don't you unburden yourself?
- (STABS)
- (GUARD GRUNTING)
(RADIO EMITTING STATIC)
I am Colonel Eleanor Grant,
British military intelligence.
(GROANS)
Thank you, Colonel.
There's something else I'd like to say.
To my colleagues in Section 20.
Very well.
(BEEPS)
(GIRL SOBBING)
- Shit. Run! Get out of here! Run! Run!
- (SPEAKING HUNGARIAN)
Mike.
Fuck. Someone's armed the bomb!
Get these people out of here!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Okay. Sinclair. Talk to me.
I'm going to pull out the detonator.
No. Don't touch the det, it's on a trip.
Okay. Okay. Then what do I do?
Which wire do I cut?
You have to cut the earth.
Which colour is the earth wire,
Sinclair, which one?
It's the one that leads to the battery.
- The brown one? The brown one?
- Um... I'm not sure.
Which colour is the earth wire,
Sinclair, which one?
Wait.
(CHOKING)
Sinclair, the green? The brown? Tell me.
Sinclair.
- Fuck.
- Green.
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
(KNIFE CLANGS ON FLOOR)
LATIF: Finished?
That's very touching.
But I'll probably just edit that out.
(GRUNTING)
GRANT: Hey!
Colonel!
Damien, forgive me!
(GRUNTS)
Latif!
(INAUDIBLE)
Secrets are
an occupational hazard in this job.
But I have kept too many for too long.
Perhaps the burden
led to my mistakes.
But everything I have done,
I have done for my country.
For my involvement in Trojan Horse,
my failure to admit it,
and my part in John Porter's death,
I have nothing but regret.
To Major Sinclair,
if you are still alive,
I wish you every success
your doggedness and intellect deserve.
To Sergeant Richmond, for your
camaraderie and your courage,
I thank you.
Damien Scott, amongst my effects,
there is a blue file.
I tried to tell you.
And to Michael Stonebridge,
you are the finest soldier
I have ever known.
Serving with you all
has been a privilege and an honour.
Colonel Grant.
- Colonel Grant.
What are you gonna do?
She did give me a second chance.
Guess I should be thankful for that.
You gotta make
a decision, too, buddy boy.
Yeah, I know.
And?
I've already made it.
Well, fuck me. (CHUCKLES)
Who's gonna make me look good now?
Shit.
- Daddy Stonebridge.
- Yeah, I know.
- Up all night.
- Yeah.
Not for the good reasons.
- (STONEBRIDGE LAUGHS)
- Fuck.
Strike_Back_2011 - S02 - E10 Project_Dawn_#10
Re-Sync & Edit
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha