Stop, Howl! It's a trap!
Hold on!
Sophie, sit up here!
Did you have to bring those two with you?
Nice doggie.
I can't believe you work for Suliman.
I guess it's too late to toss him.
Sophie, take the wheel!
What?! I can't fly, are you kidding?!
They're gaining on us.
I'll distract them. Then, you can fly this thing
back to my castle in the Wastes.
How? I don't know the way!
Hey, don't worry.
The ring that I gave you will guide you back home.
All you have to do, is summon Calcifer with your heart.
Calcifer?
It's glowing.
Just keep following that light
and you should be there before dark.
I can't do this!
Why did you make me come here, if you were coming yourself?
Knowing you'd be there gave me the courage to show up.
That woman terrifies me,
I can't face her on my own.
You've saved me, Sophie.
I was in big trouble back there.
Don't let go!
- Wow, you're good.
- Are you nuts?!
We've got a good lead now.
I can give you 5 minutes of invisibility,
so use it wisely.
Howl!
Good luck!
No, not now.
Thank you.
That was the most fun I've had in ages.
I suppose Howl thinks he's evaded me.
I bet his "mother" can help me find him.
Almost there,
that's my hometown below us!
Don't try to be cute, dog,
I'm still not going to trust you.
The castle is coming to meet us.
Sophie! Here!
Markl, help me!
How am I supposed to land this thing?!
Sophie.
Nice doggie.
Markl.
I'm home.
Are you hurt?
I missed you!
I missed you too,
thanks for coming to meet us.
Oh, this is bad, you've gone too far, Howl.
I wonder if Howl's back home.
Howl?
Howl? Is that you?
Are you in pain?
Tell me what's happening.
Go away.
No, I'm not going away.
I'm going to help you break
the spell that you're under.
You... you can't even break your own spell.
- But you don't understand, I love you!
- You're too late.
Howl! No!
Calcifer, did Howl just get in?
Yeah, and he looks terrible.
You better figure out, how to break the spell on us, quick.
Howl is running out of time,
I hope you realize that.
You mean he'll become a monster, is that it?
I can't tell you the details of the curse, lady,
you should know that by now, c'mon.
Do you know what madam Suliman said?
She said that Howl's heart was stolen by a demon.
- Tell me now, what do you know?
- I'm so sorry, but that would be confidential information.
What if I dump a bucket of water on you?
If you drown me,
then Howl will die too.
Hi Turnip-head.
This isn't gonna be easy.
'Kay! Ready!
All right! Calcifer, open it wider.
Here we go!
I said move...
If I just hang a little curtain here,
maybe Howl won't notice.
Come on in, it's time to eat!
Here, want some more?
Don't feed her, that's the Witch of the Waste.
Oh, she's all right.
She keeps staring at me,
it's freaking me out...
What a pretty fire.
- Howl, hello.
- Good morning, everyone.
- Glad you're home.
- Master Howl, we can keep this dog, can't we?
The Witch of the Waste and Suliman's dog at my table?
What possessed you to let them in my house, Calcifer?
I didn't let them in!
Sophie crash landed her plane into my face!
I knew she'd make a great pilot.
Looks like we have yet another addition to the family.
You've got a quite nasty spell on you too, huh?
Seems everyone in this family's got problems...
What a handsome man.
So! We've got a lot of work to do.
We're moving!
Moving?
That's good. I'm sick of being stuck out here,
in the middle of nowhere.
Madam Suliman is hot on our trail,
so we're gonna have to hurry.
I'm afraid your spell is too strong for this move.
You're gonna have to stay behind.
There, all done.
All right, Calcifer, line her up!
There, that should do it.
Sit tight for a second.
Be gentle with me, please...
On my mark.
Moving's done,
you can get down now.
This is great, master Howl,
it's huge.
Oh, what a pretty fire.
But this is...
I added on a bathroom,
since our family seems to keep growing.
Come over here, Sophie!
I added another bedroom, too.
Have a look.
Why'd you... do this?
So we'd have a room that suited you.
Do you like it?
Of course.
It's perfect for a cleaning lady.
I got you some new clothes, too,
but you can open them later.
Come on, Sophie!
Look at this!
All Right! A courtyard!
That shop's ours, too.
Heen, c'mon!
See that new colour on the dial?
There's a new portal.
It's a present for you.
Come see.
You like it?
It's my secret garden.
It's incredible.
Did you use your magic to make this?
Only a little, just to help the flowers grow.
This place is gorgeous, Howl!
It's like a dream.
Sophie?
It all seems so familiar,
yet I know I've never been her before.
I feel so at home.
- Come with me.
- 'Kay
Look there!
- What a cute cottage.
- That was my secret hideaway.
I spent a lot of time here, by myself,
when I was young.
You were alone?
My uncle, who was a wizard,
gave me this place as my private study.
And now you can come here whenever you like.
What's the matter?
It's...
You're scareing me,
I have this weird feeling that you're going to leave.
Howl, tell me what's going on.
Please, I don't care if you're a monster.
I'm just setting things up,
so that all of you can live a comfortable life, Sophie.
With all the flowers you've got in this valley,
you could easily open up a flower shop.
Right? I'm sure you'd be good at it.
So you are going away...
Please, Howl, I know I can be of help to you.
Even though I'm not pretty
and all I'm good at is cleaning...
Sophie! Sophie, you're beautiful!
Well, the nice thing about being old
is you've nothing much to lose...
What is that thing doing out here?
- A battleship?
- Still looking for more cities to burn...
- Is it the enemy's or one of ours?
- What difference does it make?
Those stupid murderers...
We can't just let them fly off with all those bombs.
What's happening?
What did you do?
Just messed with it,
it won't crash though.
Howl!
Uh-oh... Here they come.
Those things are Suliman's henchmen.
Let's go!
Faster, we need to take off!
All right, you're going in!
No! Don't let go!
Sophie? What happened?
I'm too old to be treated like this!
Good night, Sophie.
Good night, Markl.
Don't worry about Master Howl, Sophie.
Sometimes, he likes to go away for days on end.
Thank you, that's good to know.
- Need anything else?
- No, I'm fine.
Well, good night then.
You're in love.
Don't deny it,
you've been sighing all day.
Just as I thought.
Have you ever in love before?
Of course I have.
I'm still in love.
Strapping, young men are so difficult to deal with,
but their hearts I just adore.
You're terrible.
And they're so cute, too.
What's that?
It's an air raid siren.
Air raid?
It's a long way's off,
but you better not go outside tonight, dear.
I'm sure Suliman's henchmen are looking
everywhere for this place.
What a good fire.
He keeps this house so well hidden.
Sophie, there's a strange lady in here!
Mother?
Sophie!
Thank goodness you're here!
I searched everywhere for you!
Oh my, look at your face, you're so old!
Everyone’s saying it's my fault that you left.
You'll forgive me, oh won't you?
Oh, Sophie.
Mother...
I barely recognize the place.
Who is that woman?
Huh? The landlady?
Oh, I forgot to tell you,
I got married again.
He's such a nice man and he's filthy rich, too,
so we can all live together again.
You won't have to work as a cleaning lady anymore.
That's all right, mother,
I actually like living here.
Really?
I forgot.
I've got a car waiting,
I've got to run.
Sophie, I'm so glad I found you.
A peeping-bug?
Can't Suliman do better than that?
Open wide, Cal.
I hope you and your new husband will be very happy.
- Thank you, Sophie. Bye.
- Bye, mother.
I did what I was told,
now take me to my husband.
Yes ma'am, I'm sure Madam Suliman
will be very pleased with your.
Forgive me, Sophie...
Oh, look at all of them.
If they keep leaving at this rate,
the town will soon be empty.
- Do you want to leave, too, Sophie?
- What?
That lady said she wants you to live with her now.
Yes, well...
At least she cared enough to visit.
Don't leave, Sophie!
I love you,
you have to stay...
I love you, too, Markl.
I'll stay.
Really?
'Cause we're a family now.
Yes, we're a family.
Thank you, Sophie.
I will never let Suliman
get a hold of Howl.
But the newspaper says we won.
Only idiots believe what they read in the paper.
That's so strange,
I can't get Calcifer going.
Do you have to keep smoking that?
It smells terrible.
Don't deny an old witch her pleasures, young lady.
Markl, will you crack a window, please?
I wouldn't open that window if I were you, dear.
Calcifer's too weak right now
to protect this place.
Suliman's henchmen could get in.
Markl!
Markl, get back inside,
I'm gonna check on the shop.
There are bombs falling on us,
why won't you put out some fires instead?
Howl, no!
This is exciting.
Howl!
I'm sorry, Sophie,
I should've gotten here sooner.
You're alive.
Oh, thank goodness.
Master Howl! Sophie!
You're okay!
Calcifer, you hang in there now!
Tell me... Was that cigar a gift from Madam Suliman,
by any chance?
Howl, she fed me something gross, I feel sick.
Why, if it isn't Howl.
I think you and I need to have a nice,
long, heart-to-heart chat.
There's nothing I'd like more than that,
but right now there's a war going on.
How unlike you, Howl,
not running away anymore.
Until later, then.
Stay here,
Calcifer will protect you from the henchmen.
I'll stand guard out front.
No, wait, Howl!
Don't go out there!
It's too dangerous.
Another wave's coming
and Calcifer is too weak to stop the bombs.
Let's run,
don't fight them, Howl.
Sorry, I've had enough of running away, Sophie.
And now, I've got something I wanna protect.
It's you.
Come back!
There's where we are at the shop.
Looks like Howl's in trouble.
Howl, look out!
What's going on?!
Turnip!
Markl, I need your help!
Are you crazy?
I can't move the portals without Howl's help.
You have to try, if we don't break away,
Howl will keep protecting the hat shop.
I preferred him as a coward.
Okay, we have to go now.
Are we going for a stroll?
We can't do that,
it'll make us too vulnerable.
We already are! And if we don't move quick,
Howl doesn't have a chance.
Sophie!
They're about to bomb the hat shop!
Quick! Help her get outside, okay?
You coming with us,
hop on.
I can't! It's impossible,
no one, but Howl, can take me out of this hearth.
There's no time to lose, Calcifer,
we have to try something.
Don't do this!
No! No! No! Help! Help! Help! Help!
Crazy lady with a shovel! Don't!
If you take me out that door,
the castle could collapse!
Good!
- We're ready!
- Okay, step back.
Make sure I go out last, Sophie.
I don't know what's gonna happen...
but I'm sure it won't be good.
I told you it would collapse.
Rain! Rain! Rain!
That ship's headed for town!
Markl, look after her, okay?
Turnip-head, help me find a way back in.
Don't you worry now, ma'am,
I'm gonna take good care of you.
Markl, here's a way in.
Please, oh ple-, uh, watch, the roof is leaking,
don't make it wet.
- Please, don't make it wet.
- Hold on for a second.
It's wet here, Sophie!
Too damp, too damp, damp, very damp here,
hu-hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, please.
Markl, hurry, get inside.
The castle's a wreck.
Told you we should have stayed put,
Howl and I could've handled it.
We have to tell Howl,
we're not attached to the hat shop now.
Move the castle and take us to Howl.
What?
I know you can do it,
I've never seen a fire with more spark.
But there's no chim-,
but there's no chimney here,
and I keep getting dripped on
and the wood's all damp...
They say that the best blaze brightest
when circumstances are at their worst.
Yeah, but no one really believes that...
Come on, let's be honest...
Uh, what a pretty fire.
Why don't you have a seat?
All right, I need something of yours, Sophie.
Why is that?
I can't do it by myself.
How about your eyes?
Huh?
How about this?
Thanks, Calcifer!
You're fantastic!
Imagine what I could have done with
your eyes or your heart.
That's it! You've got Howl's heart!
I found it!
I can see Howl down there.
Looks like he's trapped.
Calcifer, hurry!
No!
Put it back!
Let go!
Howl's heart, it's mine!
Put it back, now!
- It's hot, hot! Burning me!
- Let go!
You're catching on fire!
No, it's mine! It's mine!
It's mine!
Sophie!
Sophie ruined it.
My heart's ruined.
Heen, what've I done?
I poured water on Calcifer.
What if I've killed Howl, too?
It's moving...
Is Howl still alive?
Can you lead me to him?
The front door...
Heen?
That's Howl...
I know where I am,
I'm in Howl's childhood.
Howl!
Calcifer!
It's me, Sophie!
I know how to help you now!
Find me in the future!
Sorry, Heen,
I'm trying to hurry.
I just can't seem to stop crying.
Howl.
I'm sorry...
Did I come too late?
I didn't mean to make you wait this long.
I need you to take me to Calcifer, if you can.
He's dead?
No, Markl.
Howl needs that back now.
Don't look at me, I don't have it,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Please.
Please give it back.
You really want it that badly?
Yes.
- All right then. You'd better take good care of it.
- 'Kay.
Here, dear.
Thank you, you have a big heart.
Calcifer.
Sophie, I'm so tired...
If I give Howl back his heart,
what will happen to you?
I'd be okay, if you do it, I think...
I mean, you dumped water on me
and Howl and I both survived.
I'd better try then.
It’s so warm and fluttering like a bird.
It's still just the heart of a child.
Please... Help Calcifer live.
And please help Howl take back his heart.
I'm alive!
I'm alive! Look! I'm free! Free!
I'm alive, I tell you!
He moved! See?
I can't steer without Calcifer!
Turnip!
His pole snapped.
Are you all right?
We'll get you a new pole, okay?
You saved us, Turnip.
Thank you, Sophie.
I'm the prince,
who's been missing from the neighbouring kingdom.
Somehow, I got that blasted spell put on me.
I know that spell.
A kiss, from your true love, breaks it.
That's right.
If it weren't for Sophie, I would've been
a scarecrow for the rest of my life!
My, what a stunning, young man, you are.
What's going on?
What am I doing here?
I feel terrible,
like there's a weight on my chest.
A heart's a heavy burden.
Wow, Sophie, your hair looks
just like starlight.
It's beautiful.
You think so?
So do I!
Looks like your true love
is in love with someone else.
You should go home anyway,
and tell your king to stop this dumb war.
Yes, that's exactly what I'll do.
One thing you can always count on,
is that hearts change.
So as soon as this war is over,
I shall return.
I love it, when you talk like that.
I'll look forward to your return, big boy.
There you are.
You should've checked in earlier.
What on earth were you up to?
Howl found his true love.
You little traitor.
The game is over.
Get me the Prime Minister and
the Minister of Defence.
- It's time to put an end to this idiotic war.
- Yes, ma'am
Hey, it's Calcifer!
You didn't have to come back, Calcifer.
I kind of missed you guys,
and it looks like it's gonna rain...
I missed you too, Calcifer.
Subtitles by: Hecko X
Member of: DKSubs
For Danish subtitles, please visit:
http://dksubs.rdwsubs.com
DKSubs are sponsored by:
www.rdwsubs.com
Thank you for watching :)
The End