I guess not every girl in the world
has to wait in the hot sun...
for her father to get out of jail.
But I didn't care about that.
I just wanted us
to be together again.
I used to be pretty angry
at him. Eddie was, too.
We figured he kinda dumped us.
But it wasn't that simple.
We've all done a lot of growing up
since the bad old days.
You see,
the thing aboutJack...
I don't know,
he kinda grows on ya.
Where is he?
Are you sure this is the day?
I don't think this is the day.
He's comin'.
- There he is!
- Where?
Come on!
Dad!
Look at us. The perfect,
happy family, right?
Well, trust me.
It wasn't always like this.
You can run for cover
You can run for help
You can run to your lover
But you can't ever run
from yourself
No, no, no
- How many times
have I told you about this?
- You're hurting me!
- I am not going to tell you again.
- Let me go!
- Shut up!
- I didn't do it. It wasn't my fault!
No matter how far you go
No matter how long you stay
You can run forever
But, darlin'you will never
Never find true happiness that way
- You're going on a trip.
- You're kidding me!
I-I've got this big deal goin'
down and I'm outta here, I rea--
Far away. Not alone.
Yeah, New Orleans. I mean,
it ain't no hop, skip and a jump.
So I mean, this is,
this is real good, right?
Wh-Wh--
Uh, uh, over all, I mean, y-y--
Please, Celeste, don't be tellin' me
no negative stuff.
I mean, I can't be havin'
nothin' draining my energy right now.
Draw another.
Just gotta think positive.
Now, come on! He's got a couple of kids
and no wife to look after them.
Now don't that
mean anything to you?
Well, yeah--
He, he got a fo--
All right, all right, all right!
I'll talk to my client.
Don't be using her
for your games.
Jack, if you hadn't put
your kids in foster care...
they would've knocked
six months off your sentence.
I didn't put 'em nowhere.
Linda died and the State took 'em.
Now I ain't happy about that, but they're doin' just fine and so am I.
Now, what's the deal?
Well, considering everything,
we did pretty well.
The D.A. says we can plea bargain it
down to two years.
Two years for what?
I robbed drug dealers.
That's right, until you robbed an
undercover cop posing as a drug dealer.
Look, I'm gonna tell you something.
I ain't goin' to jail.
I am this close to doin' a deal where I'm
gonna see more money than you can imagine.
And I ain't lettin' nothin'
mess it up. You got me?
Jack, this is so easy.
If we do go to trial, I call
the kids in. We put them on--
Leave the kids out
of it, all right?
The best thing I ever did for them
was keepin' out of their lives...
and keeping them outta mine.
Okay!
We see the judge in two days.
Now, you think you can stay
out of trouble for two days?
Of course!
How sweet it is
to be loved by you
Yes, baby
Ooh-ooh-ooh
How sweet it is
to be loved by you
Ooh, baby
I needed the shelter
of someone's arms
And there you were
- Who is it?
- Kelly.
- Kelly who?
- Very funny!Just open the door.
Hi, Daddy.
- Oh, you've changed.
- Yeah, well, you haven't!
And I'm runnin', right?
And then the alarm's going off.
I'm like, ''Kelly, you better
get over this fence, man.''
Do you know what they do to kids who try
and get outta that place? Bigelow Hall.
Well, I'll tell you what. You oughta
look at it a little more positively...
like, uh, a little bit like,
um, prep school.
It's really sick in there.
Kids are getting hit
all the time.
I mean, hit really hard.
You do one thing wrong, and someone's
comin' after you with something...
or, or slammin' you
up against a wall.
And Lazzaro, the guy
who runs the place?
He never uses his hands, but he knows
what's goin' on and he just lets it happen.
You are outta here,
little girl.
'Cause this is gonna be the first place they look for you.
- Then get me transferred.
- I can't do that.
Yes, you can! They have
to listen to you,Jack. It's the law.
Finish your pizza
and you're gone.
What about Eddie?
Remember Eddie?
- What about Eddie?
- They're putting him in Bigelow tomorrow.
No. No, ma'am.
He is in Humboldt
with that foster family.
No, he's not! They're putting him
in Bigelow tomorrow like a prisoner.
He has never done one thing wrong
except to have you as a father.
- See you smile
- God!
Little girl,
you back off now.
You know, when they put him
in Bigelow...
they'll put him in handcuffs.
Just get into that, why don't you?
Your own little boy in handcuffs.
-Seven years old!
-I thought he was five.
- Yo, hello.
- Hey,Jack, is that you?
- Hey, hey,Jerry.
- Did I wake you up, man? You sound like--
No, man, I've been up for hours.
What's the deal?
- Are you in there?
- Don't call him.
I'm in. You sure it's
a quarter of a million?
Just sittin' there waitin' for us. Come on!
Baby. Okay, well,
sit tight, stay cool...
and I will be in New Orleans
before your rice begins to boil.
Okay, later.
You know, we could go pick up Eddie.
I mean, then it just wouldn't be the two of us.
And, I don't know, we could
all have a lot of fun.
True love, baby
that's what you give to me
Your love
Where are we going?
This is the way to Bigelow.
You can't do this to me,Jack.
You're my father!
Look, face facts!
I was never your father.
You understand me?
I hate all this family crap.
- I'm gonna jump out of this car.
- Be my guest!
- Fine!
- What are you doin'? Get in here!
- Get in here! You'll get me killed.
- I don't care, all right?
Are you crazy?
Look, I'm gonna tell you something.
I am outta here. You got me?
Why can't you just
get me transferred?
I mean, what about Eddie?
Um, are you even gonna talk to them?
- You're just gonna let 'em
throw him in Bigelow?
- Hell yes!
All right. If I get them
to put you someplace else...
will you stay put
and stop hassling me, huh?
You give me something, baby
I can't forget
You give me your love
Your love
Stay put and don't touch--
Ohh!
I need another day in court
like a hole in the head.
So, since his mother died, I have been very
concerned about, you know, their welfare.
And that's the reason
we gotta do something about it...
at least until we can come
together again as a family.
'Cause as far as I'm concerned, there ain't
nothing more important than a man's family.
- You're the boy's father?
- Well, uh, we never did
blood tests, but yeah.
Mr. Charles, do you know
what these are?
Uh, I believe those
are folders, Your Honor.
No. These are lives,
very young lives.
And it's my job to make
a hundred judgments a day...
about what would be best
for each of these lives.
Well, excuse me, Your Honor, but, you know,
I know a little bit about young lives, too.
All right? Because
I grew up in these places.
And what I Know is I can't have them running around trying to find me all the
time.
And that's the reason I want them out
of this Bigelow place and into this--
Weel, Bigelow happens to be one of the finest institutions of its Kind in the
country.
Pardon me, Your Honor. Uh, not that I want
to get into this here with you right now...
because, you know,
I'm a very positive kind of person.
But this Bigelow place, man,
I'm tellin' you.
The-They're abusing the kids,
they got 'em running away and
I'll tell you one more thing.
-Well, I can hardly wait.
-They're handcuffing these children.
I'm tellin' you. Little Kids in handcuffs. They're cuffing these Kids.
I'm serious.
Mr. Lazzaro, would you
approach the bench, please?
- Your Honor.
- Mr. Lazzaro, would
you please tell the court...
a-and Mr. Charles...
is it the policy of the
Youth Services Administration...
to use handcuffs or any other
form of restraint on children?
-No, of course not, Your Honor.
-They're handcuffin' these Kids.
- Then they got 'em starvin'.
- Mr. Charles!
- Their wrists are scarred.
- Mr. Charles?
- Sorry.
- May I remind you you're in a courtroom?
Yes, ma'am, I'm sorry, but
th-th-this Lasagna dude's lyin'.
-Just look at him.
- Your Honor, Kelly Charles has been missing...
from our facility since last night.
Mr. Charles, although he has abandoned
her, may be giving her safe haven.
- Is this true?
- Your Honor, all I'm tryin' to ask...
- is this San Diego place any good?
- Mr. Charles, if you don't mind.
Young Edward Charles,
who is right now in our van, he--
- Yeah, probably in handcuffs, no doubt.
- Mr. Charles!
I am sorry, Your Honor.
Look, can I at least see the kid?
As a reward for your exemplary
behavior in my courtroom?
I said I was sorry.
I mean, if this dude can see him,
I can see him. I demand to see him now!
Please.
I say get down,yeah
Edward, this is your father.
Yo, uh, Eddie, what's happenin'?
- You, uh, doin' all right?
- Dad!
Yo, hey! Yo, hey,
be, be cool, kid.
- You come to take me home?
- Well, you know, um--
Uh, you eatin' enough? Uh, looks
like you'd be bigger or somethin'.
Dad, please, you gotta take
me home. I hate it in there.
All right, that's it.
You're upsetting the child.
Hey, hey, wait!
I'm still talkin' to the kid.
Your Honor, I cannot stand idly by
while Mr. Charles agitates the child.
This visit is detrimental
to the child's welfare.
Hey, what do you know
about it? He's my kid.
Correction, Mr. Charles, it's my kid.
You gave him to me two years ago.
- No!
- Keep your hands off of him,jerk.
Please!
You asked to see your son.
Nobody, nobody messes or takes
with Jack Charles, you get me?
You get me?
I'll seal your fate, baby.
That boy just messed
with the wrong guy.
- What happened?
- Why'd you lie to me about the handcuffs?
I am not lying! I mean, who are you
gonna believe, them or me?
There he is.
That son-of-a-- He lied to me.
He lied to me!
- See? I told you.
- Oh, shut up.
All right, baby,
cover your face.
All right.
Put on your seat belt now!
Hey!
- What the hell is this about?
- Hello, baby, get in there!
- What is this?
- This is visiting hours.
- Dad!
- Hello, class. I'm your substitute teacher.
And our first lesson today is how to mess with a real scumbag.
Sit down!
- Unlock him.
- Dad, I knew you'd come for me.
- Yeah, sure.
- Dad, the driver!
Unless you wanna get hurt,
I'd sit down and shut up now.
- Okay, all right, all right.
- Sit down!
Mister, I don't wanna have
my baby in this place.
- What do I look like, a halfway house?
- Take her,Jack, she's a friend.
- You get in the car now!
- Please!
All right, unlock her, too.
Hurry up!
- Thanks.
- Poor little civil servant,
just tryin' to do his job, huh?
- Come on, let's go!
- Well, it's your turn in the barrel.
Pucker up, sweetheart.
Eat it.
- Huh?
- Right now! Eat it.
Yeah. Yeah!
Now swallow it.
Mmm-mmm, good.
And so good for you.
- Good boy.
Did you see that sucker?
- Whoa!
- Who is this guy?
- He's my dad!
- In your dreams, kid.
- Hey, Dad!
- Hey,Jack, we got company.
Uh-oh. Hang on!
-Jack, he's right behind us.
- Here we go!
Watch out! Watch out!
That sucker ain't
following us now!
- Radical, Dad!
- Don't call me that.
So, where can I dump you,
whatever your name is?
Whatever happens, I am
never going back to that place.
Just wait a minute, okay?
-You're gonna be fine.
-I Know.
- I love you.
- Come on, we ain't got all day.
- You take care, all right.
- Bye.
- Hurry up!
Geez, Mr. Impatient!
What are we in such a hurry for?
So, are you taking us
with you?
They're never gonna transfer us
now that you kidnapped us,Jack.
Yeah, Dad,
what are we gonna do?
We're goin' to Grandma's house.
- Now what?
- Your Grandma likes to play here.
Stay put and don't move.
I'll be back.
Ladies and gentlemen in the gambling hall
area, please place your bets right now.
- Place your bets now.
- I learned how to shake
these dice playin' Parcheesi.
That's right,
playin' Parcheesi.
- Now I win if I get a seven?
- Yeah.
- That's right, ma'am.
- Oh!
- How are ya?
- Okay, I'm gonna roll.
Now you might win, young man.
- It's good to see you, Aunt Gladys.
- Okay, here we go!
- Come on.
- Come on, seven!
- Here we go.
- Way to go, yeah! Take them chips.
- Yeah, you won! You won, sweetheart.
- My God! Land sakes alive!
If Henry could see me now!
- Mom, I've gotta talk to you. Now.
- Not now.
- Now, I gotta talk to you--
- I gotta put these little winnings in here.
- And, yeah, put these
right here on the number.
- Yep, beginner's luck...
-is amazin', isn't it?
-Wait. On the field?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, on the field.
Ye, yep, yep.
Yep, nope, nope.
Man, she's got it down, doesn't she?
- A little backup there. All right!
- Clear all bets...
- 'cause the shooters comin' out.
- Okay, now blow, blow!
- All right, here we go.
- Okay, go, baby.
- All right, here we go!
- Yeah!
- Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
- Come on, baby!
- Come on, baby, yeah-ho!
- Lady pulls a nine.
Oh, you chip off
the old block you. Hey!
Lady. Excuse me, lady.
I need to talk to you.
Oh, no, she's on
a winnin' streak, man.
- What's wrong?
- I got a pain here. It hurts.
It hurts. Oh, God! Oh!
- Somebody help the la-la--
G-G-Get somebody to help her.
- Oh, God! Oh! Oh!
- Oh, oh, oh, oh!
- La-Lady, lady, lady. Help!
- Call 91 1 .
-John, get 91 1 .
What in the hell did you think you were
doin' in there? Didn't I teach you nothin'?
Comin' in there dressed like some hood
when I had those suckers...
set up this close to
gettin' me some serious money.
This close? I'll tell you what you were
this close to: goin' to jail, sweetheart.
- I rescued your butt just like I always do.
- Oh-ho, oh-ho. Rescued my butt?
- Yes, ma'am. You know I did.
- Goin' to jail? Please don't tell me...
-you're goin' to jail again.
- I got something much more
important to talk to you about.
- Okay?
- Important?
I brought your grandchildren
to see you.
- I thought they were in foster.
- Nope. They're here to see their Grandma.
- Say hi to your Grandma.
- Hi, Grandma. I'm Eddie.
- Grandma.
- Deal with it.
Sugar!
Gimme some sugar.
- How are you, you cute thing?
- So, how 'bout it?
- One night.
- Deal.
Yeah. Ha-ha. Let's go!
- Let's rock. We're goin' to Grandma's house.
- Hi, Grandma.
Hi, guys.
You're gonna love my place.
So, what do you think?
Not a lot.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Are you coloring
in your sideburns?
So what if I am?
I got a image to keep up.
And I got gaps.
Yeah, well, where
are you goin' anyway?
- It's late.
- So what am I supposed to do, baby-sit?
Yeah, well, if you spend all our money
on a hooker, I'm gonna kill you, okay?
You are treadin'
on thin water, sweetheart.
It's thin ice,Jack.
I mean, you are coming back, right?
You're not just gonna leave us here.
Now how can I eave somebody when I ain't with ' em in the first place?
Go to bed!
You're not my mom.
Will you--
Will you move?
- Aha!
- What is your problem?
I knew it! You were going to run off
and leave me with your kids.
- Weren't you? Admit it!
- I was not!
I'm in major party mode.
I'm goin' out playin'.
You are not going to lay your
responsibilities on Mother's shoulders.
You gotta take these kids, Mama,
just for a little while, please?
Hello!
I got a major deal goin' down
in New Orleans.
This briefcase comes in once a month and it is filled with cash.
Just a minute,Jack. This is the first time in my life that I can think about me.
- It is my turn!
- This is my big chance, Mama.
If I don't get outta here,
I go to jail.
You are going
to work this out yourself.
I give up. I can't talk to you.
I can never talk to you.
- Whoa!
-Jack, wake up. Get your backside outta bed.
Jack, I said wake up.
- What now?
- I want you to look at this!
- Read this.
- Um, ah--
Well, look at it!
- Oh, my!
- You see it?
Hey, Dad, did you know
we're close to the Hoover Dam?
- So what?
- So, I'd like to see it?
Where did they get this picture of me?
I look like a total geek.
Let's see.
Mine ain't bad.
Hey,Jack, this says
you've been in jail three times.
I thought you only did time twice.
- They don't know nothing.
- Dad, I'm hungry.
Listen to this,
''Charles terrorized the children
on the Youth Services bus. He then--''
That's not true.
Those kids liked ya, Dad.
Does, does anybody here like Egg McMuffins?
- ''Armed with an M-1 6
automatic assault rifle--''
- M-1 6? Let me see that!
God! They're
gonna get me killed!
Now they're gonna shoot to kill,
they're gonna bring out the helicopters.
These jerks will do anything
for a headline.
- Who's writin' that crap?
- Um, Kathleen Mercer.
Ha. I'm gonna handle her case.
- First thing I gotta do is dump this car.
- Oh, no, I like this car.
- Oh, shut up!
- Well, at least they got one thing right.
''The mental state of this individual
is highly unpredictable.''
- Let me see that.
- That's cute.
- It's my turn!
- Get off of me!
- You've had it for a long time.
Give it to me!
- Oh, back off.
I'm not finished yet, all right?
- Get off of me!
- It's my turn. You've had it a long time.
Oh, give it a rest!
-I7m not finished with it, all right?
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
You stay on your side of the car.
You stay on yours.
You mess with each other again,
I'm gonna mess with you, all right?
I'm sick of you!
I can't take this!
Well, I hope we get caught
so I can get rid of you.
Look what you made me do.
I was speeding!
- You guys are bad luck.
- Well, maybe he's just
gonna give us a warning.
A warning? Girlfriend,
our picture's in the paper.
Now sit that thing under
the seat so he, he doesn't see it.
Well, I didn't tell you
to speed, did I?
Maybe, maybe he didn't see
the paper today.
Okay, dude, let's play, baby.
C'mon up here.
C'mon! C'mon!
Let's rock!
Well, the news of the saucer's
been flyin'around
He was havin'a walk
seein'over the ground
First at the scene
he was soarin'and then
Got drunk and started a band
Flyin'saucer rock n'roll
I couldn't understand
a thing they said
It was a crazy beat
just a-knockin'me dead, huh
- So, we havin' fun yet?
- Yeah, Dad. Floor it!
Well, them little green men
they knew that cat
Rockin'and a-rollin'
to the lazy cats
Faster, Dad!
Brought out the drums
and he started to roll
Flyin'saucer rock n'roll
I couldn't understand
a thing that they said
Get off me, sucker.
He's still comin'!
- Dad, go in a zigzag or something.
- Don't tell me what to do.
Yeah!
Okay, sucker,
now it's my turn!
Flyin'saucer rock n'roll
Flyin'saucer
Holy shit!
I couldn't understand
a thing they said
It was a crazy beat
just a-knockin'me dead
We did it! We did it!
I haven't seen Jackie in say,
oh, I guess it's been two years.
Uh,Jackie? Does he go
by any other name than Jackie?
He gets so upset
when I call him Jackie.
But you know how boys are.
You know what I mean?
Get off my side. Get-- Stop it!
Dad, she's on my side of the line again.
-Just sit down, please. I'm asking.
- I am not.
You're always on my side of the line.
Why don't you get off me?
-Jack, would you please
make him stop jiggling his foot?
- I'm not jiggling!
- Yes, you are. You jiggle all the time.
- You're jiggling!
- You're so stupid!
- At least I have the sixth grade reading level.
- Get off my side!
-Jack, I'm hungry.
Ju-- Too bad. Too bad.
- I have low blood sugar.
- Mom had that, too.
- I do, too.
- You don't remember her.
- Dad, I gotta take a piss!
- Will you shut up?
If I don't eat,
I'm gonna pass out.
- Shut up, shut up.
- Dad, Dad, I have to go to the bathroom.
- Shut up. Time--
- Would you please get over...
-Just shut up!
- and stop jiggling your feet!
- Get out, get out. Get out. Get out.
- Get off my side!
- What are you--
- Get up. Get out!
Get out of my car now!
- Dad, what are you doing? Are you nuts?
- I can't take you!
- Dad, where are you going?
- I'm not your father!
- Where are you going?
- Snotty little dirt bags!
You jerks are gonna get me killed.
You're drivin' me crazy!
- Oh, great! What are we gonna do now?
- I don't know.
They deserve to be in that
juvenile home. They're animals!
Little jerks.
Good riddance!
Shit!
I don't like you
But I love you
Seems that I'm always
Thinkin'of you
Though-whoa-whoa
you treat me bad, babe
I love ya madly
You really got a hold on me
- Dad?
- Don't even think about it.
Oh, we're so close to the Hoover Dam.
Please, Dad,just once? I wanna see it.
Come on,Jack,just stop.
He's never gonna shut up.
We could get a car there.
I was already planning
on doin' that.
Don't wanna kiss you
but I need you
Though-whoa-whoa
you do me wrong
- Kelly, check this out!
- What for?
It's amazing!
Dad, do you have
any more quarters?
Yeah, can I speak
to a Kathleen Mercer, please?
-Jimmy, I need that copy!
- Okay, I got it!
Kathleen, you have
a Jack Charles on one.
-Jack who?
- He says it's important.
Oh! Right.
- Kathleen Mercer speaking.
- So, what are you tryin' to do?
Get me killed?
What is this crap
you're writin', sweetheart?
- What do you have to tell me, Mr. Charles?
- What do I have to tell you?
Okay, point number one:
I didn't have no M-1 6!
Point number two:
these are my kids!
You got me kidnaping my own kids
when I'm tryin' to save the little jerks.
Mm-hmm. Hold on for a second.
City desk. Mercer speaking.
H-Ho-- What?
I don't believe this.
- Saving them from what, Mr. Charles?
- What is your problem?
What do you think,
I'm some nobody to put me on hold?
You call yourself a reporter?
Let me ask you something.
Where did you get this rubbish?
Did you just make this junk up?
Look, do you have anything in the form
of information that you'd like to tell me?
Yeah, I got something to say.
I am tryin' to save my kids.
You are not helping.
- So the blood is gonna be
on your hands, sweetheart.
- Oh!
But I'd like to ask you
one thing. Now you got kids?
Ah, come off it, Mr. Charles. You abandoned
those kids and you didn't visit 'em once.
And now you're facing
ten to 1 2 years in jail.
And because of you,
it's gonna be 50!
Look, if you've got something
real to say, then say it.
Real? Let me ask you something.
What is real to you?
I have been tryin' to bust this
foster care racket for over a year now.
But it's against the law for a journalist
to talk to a minor. So here's something real.
Ask your daughter if she's ever taken a field trip to Yosemite National Park.
And then ask her how many
times a week she ate meat.
What? Wh-Wh-What are you talkin' about?
Are you tryin' to give me
some kind of runaround?
Just get me some details, all right?
That's how you get a story like this.
You follow the money.
- Back off. Let's go. Back off.
- jack? Jack?
Are you listenin'to me,Jack?
Jack!
Get over here. Get over here. Get over here.
Hurry up. Get over here. Fast, fast!
- What's goin' on?
- Look behind you.
Now you guys, stay here, don't move.
I'll be back. I'm gonna get a car.
The sooner we do this, the sooner you
people can go. So, please, everybody out.
How is he gonna get a car
with all those cops there?
I don't know!
It's your stupid idea to come here in the first place.
Leave me alone.
Dad!
Psst! Yo!
-Jack!
- Dad!
- Shut up!
- But you're alive.
- Come on, let's go. Let's party.
- Come on.
Those suckers are so stupid!
I hate foreign cars!
Did you see that sucker?
Dra-kaboom!
What? What is the crybaby crap?
- He thought you were dead, okay?
- Dead? Dead?
It was the coolest thing I ever
saw in my life. Did you see it?
It was like Schwarzenegger.
It was like TV.
- It was amazing!
- Yeah, it was real great!
Now instead of a couple cops after us,
there's probably gonna be a hundred!
You guys are wet blankets.
I can't take it.
I gotta be around
somethin' more positive.
This is Andrea of unit five.
We're in pursuit.
We'll notify on contact.
Unit five out.
- Please,just leave me alone.
- Shh. Hey, hey, hey.
You know, I looked for you
last night.
- Don't you disappoint me again, sweetheart.
- MacDougall.
- Mr. MacDougall?
- Go on, get out.
- May I have a word with you?
- What's up, Chief?
I got a call from the L.A. Post.
-Jack Charles phoned in.
- And?
This woman reporter has been trying
to smear our facility for a year.
She's totally irresponsible.
Sometimes I just don't understand
what makes people so vindictive.
You know, I'd love to say to her...
''Miss Mercer, if you think you can do
a better job with these children...
you are welcome to take several
of them home with you.''
Well, in the meantime,
Mr. MacDougall, uh...
just try to keep everything
shipshape around here.
Did you love Mom?
Dad, what are we gonna do
past Flagstaff?
Well, uh, they'll figure Mexico.
but we're gonna go east
and fool 'em all.
So, did you?
What are you tryin' to do,
make conversation?
- Forget it.
- We can take the 1 80 right into Texas, okay?
Yep.
So, Kelly, when you were
at Bigelow, did, um--
Did you ever go to
Yosemite National Park?
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
Steak, what about steak?
You ever eat steak?
You'll talk about anything except
what I want to talk about, won't you?
-Just answer me!
- We never went anywhere.
I don't want to go to
Yosemite National Park anyway.
The only time I ever saw a steak was when
I had to clean up the custodians' dining room.
Okay? Happy?
Now answer my question.
Did you love her?
She was a
good-looking woman.
We'd walk down the streets of Reno,
and every head would turn to look at her.
She was a tough cookie though. And legs,
girlfriend, she had legs up to her chin.
Actually, you look a lot like her.
Well, who could tell though,
with those dumb-looking
high-water pants and army boots.
The problem was...
her legs were a little too long.
She sure liked the good life.
Good morning! I'm Chad Carter, and here's what's happening.
Here's Tony Mosdy
with News 9 1.
- Stop it!
- The search for L.A. mobster
jack Charles continues.
- Uh-oh, not again.
- The search has widened
to include six states...
- Shut up!
- and personnel from over
30 local police forces...
as well as the FBI.
- On the weather front,
morning patchy clouds--
- The FBI?
- Cool! The whole world's looking for us.
- Damn.
Gangster. Mobster. The way these
squirrel-peckered, numb nuts
use the damn English language...
makes me wanna puke!
I gotta pull in
and make a call.
Hey, Dad, could you grab me
something to eat? I'm starving.
Girlfriend, you ain't doin'jack
about gettin' 'em off my trail.
Well, you're not exactly doin'jack
about doin' anything to help me, either.
Okay. Okay.
She ain't never been to
no Yosemite National Park...
and she ain't never ate a steak.
Well, now, isn't that interesting.
I've got reimbursement sheets,
and Lazzaro's charged the State...
for two trips to Yosemite
this past year.
And he was given money
for steak dinners...
on Tuesdays and Saturdays
for the past three years.
That's another $30,000.
So now, are you gonna change your
stories and get 'em off my butt or what?
- He's been in there a long time.
- He probably snuck out the back.
Cut it out, Kelly.
He's our dad.
- He took us.
- He didn't take us! We took him.
I don't care. I love him.
You don't know what love is.
I mean, you'd love a dog
if it licked your hand.
- So?
- Who's that?
- A friend in New Orleans.
Ooh! Kelly's got a boyfriend!
You better not say anything!
And you better not tell him
I know he's goin' to New Orleans, okay?
Now look, I told you
about the trips...
and the meat, right?
That is the information
that you really needed to know.
So, you got it!
Go with it!
Jack, was your daughter...
abused in Bigelow Hall?
Oh, yeah. Absolutely!
You're her father,Jack.
You can ask her that.
What do you know about
being a father in today's world?
You're a, y-y-y-you're, you're
a scrawny little Irish chick...
who pushes pencils and lives
alone and, an-and eats take-out
and has a cat named Ginger.
How'd you know that?
Well, y-y-you live on the streets,
you pick shit up.
One thing.
I'm allergic to cats.
Hey, I know, I know, I know!
When I rescued these little sh--
When I rescued my kids...
I rescued a little girl
named Dolores.
You talk to her, she'll back up
everything I'm sayin'.
- Dolores what?
- Wha-- How should I know?
You're the-- Dolores!
You're th--
You're the reporter. Find it!
Uh-uh! I'm in no mood
for cowboys and Indians.
Now,just put it
on the counter, sir.
I don't--
I don't want any trouble.
I knew that. I really did.
There you go. Thank you, sir.
Now, let's do a little negotiatin'.
Here, wrap these around you.
Whoa! How much did these cost?
- Nothing. He robbed the guy.
- No, I didn't!
- Kelly,just give him a break.
- You're always so negative.
Lou, is that you?
Hey, listen, man.
That outlaw from Los Angeles,
the one that took the kids?
Yeah, he was here
in my place, man.
Yeah, I'm sure it was him.
Come on, give me
one more dance
Before this night is through
I'd love to watch
the sunrise with you
I got time on my hands
I got a pocketful of money
I got no plans but I--
Hey, Kelly, wake up.
- Kelly!
- What?
- Get up! Take over.
- Take over what?
Drivin'.
I can't drive. I'm a kid.
Everybody in our family
can drive.
There's nothing to it.
Get out.
...on K-l0l FM,your favorite
all-night station in Santa Fe.
There's the wheel, there's the brake,
there's the gas, there's the road.
Just don't overload.
Nighty-night, sweetheart.
Here we go.
Above is a summer moon
Children will be sleeping soon
This is cool.
We drink by the fire's glow
I'm definitely driving next.
Not a chance.
The stories will all be told
and we'll dream
- No! Leave me alone!
- You can't do that! Don't do that!
- You better get in the house, lady.
- No! For God's sake! Please.
- Step back!
- Don't do that! Don't do that!
- Don't do that! She's just a little girl.
- Get in the house, lady!
- She's just a little girl.
- Don't let her scratch you, boy.
- Don't let her scratch you.
- Don't, please!
- Step back.
- I got a wild one. Get in!
Get in the house!
- Hey, Dad, we just crossed into Texas!
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, Dad, after New Orleans,
we're gonna have plenty of money, right?
Yeah, we're gonna have lots of--
What do you know about it?
Who said anything about New Orleans?
I did! I heard you say it
back in L.A., okay?
Well, it doesn't make one bit of difference,
'cause as soon as we get there...
you're both goin' back into foster.
Look! Look, let's not fight, okay?I'm sorry.
-Who's fightin'? Who's fighting'?
-What Kind of a way is that to talk?
- He is a human being. He is your son.
- Oh, shut up!
No, you shut up!
You're mad at me, not him.
Kelly! Kelly, look out!
I didn't see him, I swear.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I've banged up a hundred of'em.
That's it? That's her punishment
for wrecking a BMW...
and I get yelled at every time I have
to go to the goddarned bathroom?
- Come on!
- Will you lay off of her and be cool?
-You folks all right?
-We're fine.
- I put a call out on my CB for some help.
- You did what?
I-I put a call out
for help on my CB.
Uh, could you please call them back
and tell them not to come?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
Jack, it won't start.
Forget it. We're outta here.
Let's jam.
What is happenin' to my luck?
I'm sick of this.
Stupid kids!
Where is Dolores,
Mrs. Carter?
It's very important
that I speak with her.
Did she ever speak to you
about Bigelow Hall?
No.
They took her.
Where?
I don't know.
You are her aunt,
aren't you, Mrs. Carter?
I'm not her aunt.
She liked to call me that,
you know, but--
You see, Dolores was
my foster child years ago.
And then they took her
away from me.
How come they did that?
Didn't you try to adopt her?
Yes, I did.
I most certainly did.
But it's hard with kids
in foster. It--
You know how it is.
I mean,
they wanna keep them.
Once they get their hands on them,
they wanna keep them forever.
It's all-- It's all money
to those people.
It's all money.
Car 7252 to dispatch.
We found the car stolen
by the kidnapper from California. Over.
This is like the most fun
I've ever had.
Yeah, yeah.
Thought this was Texas,
the land of the wide-open spaces.
Oh, Lord. I just wish
I knew where I was.
Wow!
Man.
- Cool. Look at that!
- C'mon, kid. I ain't got--
I ain't got time for this.
- Wait a min--
- I got a day and a half,
and we ain't stoppin' to breathe.
Hurry up!
Stay here.
One of life's sweet moments: when
you're just about to take what you want.
- In the car.
- I'm goin' in that cave.
You ain't goin'--
Get in the car or I'll kill you, kid.
- The third largest in America.
I'm goin'! Goin'.
- Look! Look!
My life is runnin' away from me before
my eyes like a cockroach up the wall...
and you wanna go in a cave.
Get in the--
Out of the car. Out of the car now. Get outta
the car now, now. Go that way. Go, go, go.
The more we know
about caves...
the more we can tell
about geological history.
And also, the more we see
what nature has done...
and the time involved,
the smaller we seem.
- It's awesome, Dad! Can we live here?
- Oh, shut up!
...of silt mud and shale
on the bottom of the sea.
The police are here, and they want
all the people back upstairs. That's it.
Folks, I'm sorry.
We gotta cut it short today.
The police want us upstairs.
Okay.
C'mon, folks. Let's move it out.
Come on out, folks.
Leave very carefully
and watch your step.
Watch your step, folks.
Very good, folks. Watch your step.
Be very careful.
Watch your step
and move to the left.
Turn on your flashlight!
Got any bright ideas,
O Fearless One?
Ah, Kelly, please, not now.
I-I ain't in no mood.
Move. Go, go!
Hurry.
Jack Charles!
We know you're down here!
Come out and
you won't get hurt.
You wanna try and calm down, Bill?
He's got kids with him!
- Get goin'. Go.
- C'mon, guys. This way.
- Where are we going?
- Shh.
- Hurry up!
- I'm hurrying.
C'mon, guys!
This way.
Look, you guys.
I found a door.
Go.
C'mon, now. Hurry up.
- Oh, no!
- Oh, yes!
I can't deal with this.
I'm afraid of heights.
- C'mon,just follow me.
- Oh, God! Okay, you go on.
- C'mon, Dad.
- Yeah, yeah. I'm comin'. Oh, God!
- You're doing great,Jack.
- Oh, my God!
- C'mon.
- Oh, no! My flashlight!
Forget about it unless you
wanna get shot in the butt. Go!
Let's go.
- They're everywhere.
- There's millions of'em!
There, there, there. Go, go!
What are we gonna do?
- You guys get seasick?
- What?
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Shh, shh.
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon.
Get up.
- I'm on! I'm on!
- Okay, shut up!
Whoa! Mm-hmm.
Let's see here.
Mm-mmm! We're gonna have ourselves
a little Thanksgiving dinner.
This is good.
To the good life.
- To the good life.
- Whatever that means.
Hey, Dad, tug it with me.
No way.
Somebody made that up.
- Come on, Dad, please?
- Uh-uh.
Come on, please?
Just tug it with me.
- Oh, I knew it! I knew it!
- Yes, I won!
I can't get a break.
Doesn't mean anything.
Forget it. Keep eatin'.
I remember the last time
we had Thanksgiving.
No, you don't!
You were two years old.
Yes, I do!
You know what?
I remember one Thanksgiving.
I think it was Thanks-- Well, it was
a turkey, so I g-- It had to be Thanksgiving.
Um, Rita and my old man were fightin' again, as usual...
this time about the turkey
not being ready.
Rita couldn't cook it anyway
'cause she was drunk on her behind.
And so, my old man says-- Slams her
against the wall and he says...
''I'm goin' out to get
take-out chicken.''
And I know. Right then I know.
He's gone. He ain't never comin' back.
Uh, I decided to play hero. I run out the back
of the house, run around the house...
jump in the trunk, and I decide to wait
for him because I'm gonna bust him...
when he tries to split.
So I'm waitin',
and nobody comes.
I'm waitin', and waitin' and waitin'
and still, nobody comes.
I wound up havin' to stay in that trunk
all night long. I peed all over myself.
And I had to wait, you know, 'til the cops
came and found me the next morning.
- That's sort of depressing.
- No, it ain't depressing.
Everything that's ever happened to me
in my life has taught me something.
You just gotta remember
to think positive.
You could use a little of that.
Eddie, go up and check.
Make sure we're headed east.
Okay.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, wait!
Sit down.
Now what?
Um--
You know that Bigelow place
you were in?
Did anybody, you know,
ever touch you?
Touch me?
Why would I ever
tell you something like that?
Why don't you stop asking me questions, okay?
Just stop pretending you're my father!
Yo, yo, yo!
I told you something.
- Y-You're drunk.
- What's-- I am not drunk.
Anyway, I didn't want to know.
It was this reporter that wanted--
Look, no one ever touched me,
okay? No one touches me.
They wouldn't dare.
No one!
- Kathleen Mercer.
- Yeah. Yo, it's me.
Jack, they caught Dolores
and put her back in Bigelow.
I'm gonna try to get by there to see her,
but they probably won't let me.
Listen, I think they abused
my daughter in there, okay?
Jack...
what would you say if I
asked you to come back here...
bring yourself, bring your kids
and tell your story?
-You're crazy!
They ain't gonna believe my st--
-Oh, no, no, Jack.Really.
- Really. I think I can cut a deal for you.
- Deal? Deal?
I'll tell you about my last deal
somebody tried to make for me.
I was lookin' at
a lot of hard time.
Well, this deal is
gonna be different, okay?
Hey, hey, hey. What was I doin'?
I was robbing drug dealers.
What's he doing?
- He's still talking on the phone.
- Well, make him hurry up.
- Make the guy stop! Make him stop! Dad!
- Huh?
-Jack!
-They're pulling away! Hey, I'm comin'.
- Hurry up!Jack!
- Hang on.
- Dad, come on!
- Hurry up!
- You can do it. I know you can.
-Jack, hurry up!
Come on, run!
Hurry up!
Okay.
He stopped running.
Not even Jack
can catch a car, Eddie.
Uh, who owns the truck
with the antlers on it?
I'm tellin' you, man. This is
the greatest watch I've ever seen.
- Are these diamonds real?
- Yeah.
It's just a great watch, man. I mean, I don't
normally wear watches, but I'm gonna--
- Why do you paint yourself like that?
- Oh, it's just to get women.
They're good luck symbols.
My mother does 'em.
All right, when we get up here,
I want you to jam on his tail...
and stay right behind him so
he don't see you in his mirror, okay?
I-I just gotta tell ya, you look real familiar
to me. I'm real good with faces.
And I know that I know you from somewhere.
I mean, I know that I don't know you, but...
but I know you,
you know what I mean?
- Uh, do you do television or something?
- No.
Okay, it's just that you remind me
of a guy I know on television.
Well, I mean, I don't know him,
but I, I know him from television.
There! There it is!
Go, go, go! Move it!
- Get up behind him.
Don't let him see you. Go!
- I got it! I got it!
Get behind him
and stay behind him.
- Okay, closer.
- Okay.
- Closer.
- I'm gettin' it. Okay.
I got it. I got it. I got it.
- Easy, easy.
- What do you got on this boat anyway?
My kids are on that boat.
Easy, easy.
Wait a minute. Hey, I know
who you are! You're the hit guy!
You're the guy from California!
I know you! You're the hit guy!
I know you!
Shotgun boogie
All right!
Give 'em hell,Jack!
Look out, big boy
He's loaded all the time
Ta-da! I'm back!
- Dad!
- How could you do that to us?
You're just blabbing away on the phone!
Are you crazy? I-I thought you were--
I'm gonna tell you somethin'.
I lived through a bar full of rednecks.
I jump off the front of a truck onto a boat.
I risk my life! I mean, let me ask you somethin'.
Are you perfect? You ain't never missed
a busted appointment or nothin'?
Look at your son!Just look
at what you're doing to him!
What am I doin' to him? I ain't even talked
to the kid. I ain't even been nice to him.
You're making him
fall in love with you.
It isn't fair,Jack.
You're gonna break his heart.
Stop it! You're gonna make him
go away again!
Where are we?
Let me see your map.
- Where are we?
- We're right there.
This is takin' a lot longer
than I planned.
Well, at least we're on the right road.
It kinda feels like my luck is back!
You really believe in that
luck junk, don't you,Jack?
In my business, you better believe
in somethin', sweetheart.
- I believe in luck!
- Only because he does.
No, I've always believed
in luck ever since I was a kid.
I believe in luck,
and I believe in Mom.
You believe in Mom?
You believe in a dead woman?
Yo, back off!
That's what believin' is.
If it's staring you right in the face,
you ain't gotta believe in it.
It's about believin' in the stuff
you can't see that you gotta believe in.
It was a good idea,
gettin' that map.
So, can I ask you somethin'?
- What?
- Why ain't you ever called me dad?
What's happening?
Son-of-a-bitch
just launched us.
- Bull, gimme a hand?
- Yeah, I'd be glad to.
- Can you unhook that?
- Yeah.
- Thanks, buddy.
- There you go.
- Have a good day.
- What the hell!
Hey!
Hey! Stop!
That's my boat!
What do you think you're doin'?
Come back!
That's my boat!
You are so wonderful
Being near you
Is all that I'm living for
You've shown me more kindness
in little ways
Than I've ever known
in all my days
Tell me we'll stay together
Let me love you forever
'Cause you're a wonderful one
You're a wonderful one
Ooh, And you--
This is great, isn't it, Dad?
Yeah.
- Can I steer?
- No, man. If I'm late, I--
- Yeah, come on.
- Yeah!
Get over here. Got it?
Hey, look. No, look.
No hands!
...in return
Wonderful one
You're really more
than I deserve
From my heart
I mean these words
'Cause you're a wonderful one
You're a wonderful one
Oh,you're a wonderful one
Baby,you're a wonderful one
Sweetheart,you're a wonderful one
My darlin; you're a wonderful one
Baby,you're a wonderful one
Look!
Shut off your engine!
This is the Louisiana State Police.
- It's party time!
- Stop the boat!
You're ordered to turn around
and follow us.
He's gonna kill us, Dad!
Be cool, kid.
They can't even land.
Stop the boat!
If you don't comply, we will open fire.
Shut off your engines
immediately!
- Maybe we should stop, Dad.
- No, don't stop!Just go faster.
What do you want to do,
get us killed?
- Dad, they're gonna shoot us!
- Turn off your engines now!
- Shut off your engines.
- He's right on top of us.
Look!
Check it out!
It's the news dudes!
Whoo, yeah!
I told you to be positive.
Ain't no way they're gonna shoot us
on national TV. We're gonna be famous!
You havin' fun yet?
- Hey, look what I found.
- What the-- Put that down.
- No, no, no, no.
- Let it go, Kelly!
- Lay your weapon down!
- Let it go! Let it go!
You're gonna get us killed, you st--
You're gonna get us killed,
girlfriend. Drop it.
-Jump!
- Whoa!
- We could've died.
- Yeah, but you didn't. Swim.
- This is gettin' ridiculous.
- Did you see 'em?
They had guns!
We could've been killed.
Why do you have
to be like this?
- Why can't we be just like a regular family?
- Oh, shut up!
Why do you have to be like this?
Why can't you be like other people?
What do you-- What do you think,
I want this? You think this is my idea?
- This has been one big screwup.
- You're the one who took me off the van.
You said you wanted
to go home, kid.
That's when I thought
you were my father!
Will you just shut up, all right?
We're gonna get caught.
God!
What are you gonna do
when I'm gone
Whose shoulder
are you gonna cry on
What are you gonna do
on the day
When I turn my head
andjust walk away
Now, what are you gonna say
to your friends
When the talk
around town begins
Will you tell them
how you treated me bad
how you made me so sad
'Cause you make some people
Think that you love me a lot
But theyjust don't know you
And what they see
isn't what we've got
We're happy
in the public's eye
They think you're such
a wonderful guy
But they don't know--
Whoa. Okay, everybody out.
C'mon, hurry. Let's go.
Thanks, man.
- Which way?
- This way.
- C'mon, Eddie.
- C'mon!
Jerry?
- Yo,Jerry!
- What is this place?
- Shut up.
- Whoa! Look at that!
Shh!
Jerry!
Anybody home?
Yo!
Hello?
- Freeze!
- Damn! Fuck!
- What are you doin'?
-Jack, it's you.
- Yeah, it's me, you stupid--
- I-- I mean, you made it.
- Oh! Oh, God!
- I'm here, man.
I told ya! You've been
all over the news.
Yeah, I'm famous. I'm famous.
Ah! What are they doin' here?
Haven't you dumped them yet?
- I'm workin' on it.
- Don't touch that!
Sorry.
You guys go find somethin' to do and don't touch anything. Okay?
Come on.
And I don't need grief
from you, all right?
What I need is a shower
and some whiskey. You got?
- Aye.
- That's my man. C'mon.
-Hello.
- Collect call from Jack Charles.
Will you accept?
Yes, operator. I will.Jack,
I just talked to your lawyer.
You're never gonna believe this.
We managed to make a deal for you.
You did what? Oh, my God! That guy
couldn't deal his way out of a paper bag!
You gotta understand somethin'.
I am this close to gettin' what I want.
You, you, you,Jack! I'm sick
and tired of hearing about you!
For once in your life, why don't you
do something for somebody else...
and come back here and
do something about this.
- Something about what?
- Lazzaro and this whole foster care system.
That's your job, girlfriend!
Well, I can't do it alone,Jack.
Now, I need someone to come forward.
Look, get somebody else.
If I come back...
it's gonna be ten years plus whatever
else I've racked up on this little trip.
- I need you,Jack!
- Yeah, I can see it now.
''Stickup man turns self in
to expose foster care system.''
- Yeah, something like that.
- Look, what's in it for me?
Tell me this. I don't have a life like you
with major medical and pension plans.
What's in it for me?
Please tell me.
All right, look. They're
offering you a reduced sentence.
Two years and you're out.
Good behavior, 1 8 months.
Get outta town, girlfriend.
Jack, I know you think
the system is totally--
What do you know about the system?
You live in an insulated...
middle-class little dream world.
You write about the system.
I live the system, sweetheart.
-And in case nobody's told you...
- I--
the system is broken, so I can't
believe you're asking me to do this.
- I thought you were a friend
or at least understood.
- I am totally--
What are you packing?
.38 snub-nosed, same as always.
My baby.
- That's not a gun.
- Get outta my face, that's not a gun.
This is my baby.
- Ta-da!
- Whoa!
Whoa! What are you gonna do,
start a war?
- That, uh, automatic will get you killed.
- What?
- What about one of those
revolvers over there?
- Look!
The black one there. Is that a .3 57?
What is that, a two-inch barrel?
Let me see it.
Yeah, that's my kind of gun.
Now, nine times out of ten...
the last ferry from Algiers
is always empty.
- So it's just us and them?
- Absolutely.
It's gonna be easy, right?
Easy pickings.
I wanna rob Guzman.
I want a new passport.
And I want to live the life of ease
in Belize, where the ladies are lovely...
the beer is cold, and they ain't got no
extradition treaty with the U.S. of A.
- That's what I want.
- Yeah.
Don't worry.
It's gonna be okay.
Yeah. I sure hope so.
Yo, Eddie.
Yo, Eddie!
- Eddie!
- Yeah?
- Where is your sister?
- Out.
What'd you say?
- She's out.
- Out?
What do you mean out?
Where'd she go?
She-- She went to see
her boyfriend.
Boyfriend?
She ain't got no boyfriend.
Yes, she does. That's why
she wanted to come here.
Let me tell you something. We are hot
in this town! People know we're here.
It's very dangerous for her to be walkin'
on the street! Now, tell me where she went!
So...
I've been readin' about you,
anyhow, and I saw you on TV.
Weird.
- Andy?
- Yeah?
Back at the Bigs,
you were my best friend.
- You were the best friend I ever had.
- Yeah.
That was pretty weird there,
wasn't it?
I saw your picture
in the paper, you know?
You're in a lot of trouble.
You know...
when my dad told me that
he was comin' to New Orleans...
I made him take me with him.
I really wanted to see you.
Kelly, look.
I was only trying
to be nice to you.
I mean, come on. Hasn't anyone
ever been nice to you before?
Thanks.
- Yo, hey.
- What are you doing here?
Do you want me
to break his legs?
This is none of your business, okay?
This is my life, so just leave me alone!
Yes. Yeah!
Baby, baby, sweetheart.
- Who are you calling?
- Horoscope.
- Did ya get a good one?
- I sure did. Absolutely.
What if the guy you're robbing
has the same horoscope as you?
I told you to
think positive, kid.
Yeah. Famous last words.
You know, I wish you weren't goin'.
Well, this is who I am.
This is what I do.
I ain't got no other profession.
We could run around the country
all we want and play little games
and have funny times...
but that sure as hell
don't make us a family.
Yeah, well what if
you don't come back?
Bad vibes, sweetheart.
I told UncleJerry
to give you my take.
UncleJerry? He's worse than you are. He'll
keep the money and throw us to the gators.
Probably will.
Yeah, and what if UncleJerry
don't come back?
Well...
then I guess
you're on your own.
I never made you no promises.
That money
ain't gonna wait,Jack!
I'll see ya.
- C'mon.
- I'm comin'!
- He's not comin' back, you know.
- Yeah, I know.
Let's go!
- Did you get gas?
- Yeah, of course.
- Tank full.
- Well, that's a start.
Look. What'd I tell ya, huh?
It's just sittin' waitin' for us.
It's so close, I can taste it.
- Huh?
- Well, be cool, man, 'cause it ain't over yet.
Belize, here we come!
Yeah.
This is it, baby.
- What's that?
- What? I don't hear nothin'.
- Where's it coming from?
- What is it?
- It's coming from back there.
- No, no, no! Be cool, man. Be cool!
- Dad!
- Ah! What is he doing here, huh?
- Oh, my God! Stupid little--
- Let us outta here, Dad!
I gotta get 'em outta there.
You gotta just pop the trunk, man.
- Pop the trunk? Are you crazy? No, man, no!
- Pop the trunk.
- I'll be cool.Just pop it.
- If they see you, it's all over.
Hey, listen to me, man.
Just pop the trunk. I gotta get--
- No! It's a quarter of a million
dollars, man. It's on the table.
- I'm callin' off the whole deal.
-Just keep your mind on the money, man.
- I ain't blowin' nothin'.
- I ain't blowin' nothin'. It's my deal, too.
- No! No! No!
Listen, pop the trunk,Jerry!
Do it now.
I can't leave the kid in there.
Your priorities
are all screwed up,Jack.
I ain't got nothin' screwed up.
Pop it now!
- Be cool.
- Yeah.
- Oh! My, that was a stupid idea.
- It was your idea!
- Get outta the car.
Get outta the car now! Now!
- I gotta go pee!
- Come on. Come on!
- It wasn't my fault.
- Listen. Listen to me.
What do you think this is? Listen.
- It was Kelly's idea.
- Don't blame it on me.
- What the hell is goin' on back there?
I don't know.
Something's wrong! Go! Go!
I knew it! I knew it! I knew it!
- C'mon.
- This way. Let's go. C'mon. Let's--
Look out!
Dad!
- Get the other guy! Get that bastard! Hey!
- C'mon!
- Get that son-of-a-bitch!
- C'mon, let's go! Let's go! Run! Run!
- Get him!
- Let's go!
Get up!
Right behind ya.
- Let's try the topside.
- All right. Let's go!
Over here!
Cover me.
- You wait here.
- Where're you going?
Forget about him! We're docking!
Let's just get outta here.
We didn't get him, though.
What have you two done to me?
So, where's the money?
Oh, shut up!
No. No. I know those
charges have been made.
But, ladies and gentlemen,
I want to assure you that nothing
of that sort has ever happened.
Kelly Charles was a runaway.
Her reason for running away,
it's come to our attention...
is that she developed an obsession
for a young summer intern--
Geez, will you come on! This Lazzaro
has been doin' his razzle-dazzle...
- I got this Lazzaro dude's number, okay?
- on some panel committee for--
- No, no, no. This is no joke,Jack.
- Let me ask you something.
- How many deals have you made for me,
and how many worked?
- Now, don't bring it up now.
-Just answer the question.
- We've been workin' our chops off for this.
- This is a dumb idea.
- This is not a dumb idea.
Jack! You're late.
Kathleen Mercer,
the world-famous Jack Charles.
- You're not Irish.
- So I lied.
What else did you lie about?
Is this deal goin' down or what?
Absolutely,Jack,
as long as you tell the truth--
the plain, simple truth.
I always tell the truth.
Let's do it, girlfriend.
You better tell the truth.
Just keep it straight,Jack.
You see, this whole thing finds its origins in the fantasies of a disturbed child...
the arrogance
of a career criminal...
and a media circus ringmastered
by an irresponsible reporter.
Jack, she's right.
Just tell them the truth, huh?
Don't worry about it, man.
Relax. I got it down.
So, there I was tryin'
to get my life straight...
tryin' to do the right thing, and put
my kids someplace decent, you know.
But I always
was thinkin' of the kids.
I never thought about anything else,
and then they're ripped from my arms.
So, naturally, like
any good father, I was upset.
But then like magic,
they come back into my life.
And we're forced to try to cram
years into a few days, but we managed.
We got to go to Vegas.
We got to go to Hoover Dam.
The desert, some caves,
the mighty Mississippi.
You've, uh, had your difficulties with the law, isn't that right, Mr. Charles?
- Uh, Madam Chairman, if I may--
- You may not!
Yo, yo, back. Sit down, man.
I got it under control. I'm cool.
Uh, Your Hon--
Uh, Madam...
at least one of those convictions
was highly questionable.
But what about them? What did they
do wrong? Where's their crime?
The man kidnapped his children. Doesn't
that mean anything to anyone here?
You know, now look.
I don't know...
anything about the other homes
for kids around this city...
but I do know that in Bigelow Hall
these kids are being hurt.
Madam Chairman,
Bigelow is not on trial here.
- Mr. Lazzaro, please!
- Maybe Bigelow Hall should be on trial here.
- Madam Chairman, I've got evidence.
- What evidence?
Gleaned from the minds
of disturbed children?
Look, these kids
did not hurt anybody...
and you had them
locked up like criminals.
Where's the justice in that?
I gotta ask you that.
I mean, handcuffin' ' em, abusin' 'em, makin' money off of' em.
There were no handcuffs.
There was no abuse!
What about Dolores and her baby?
What about Eddie?
Have you forgotten
about your friend Travis?
Whatever might have happened
with my staff, happened without
my consent and knowledge.
That is a lie!
What about me?
You were there. You saw it!
You just walked away.
Can I ask you somethin', sir?
What did she do
that was so wrong?
Tell me, please.
Being a kid is not a crime, man.
You can't get punished
for just being little.
And she c-- She can be sassy. K-Kids think
they know everything, but they don't.
And, i-- It's scary because
you gotta watch 'em, man.
You gotta, you gotta
talk to 'em!
You g-- You--
You gotta raise 'em.
You can't just
throw 'em away because...
if you do...
this is what you get.
Oh, please! The man has no idea
how to raise children!
Look, maybe I wasn't worth beans
as a father...
and actually, maybe, I probably...
was the worst father
that ever hit the planet.
And I didn't know my kids.
And I didn't never
do nothin' for 'em.
And maybe, I've, I-I don't know,
know-- Maybe I--
Maybe I should stop
the excuses, huh?
It all comes down to this:
I didn't know you.
I didn't know I had a son.
I didn't know I had a daughter.
But now I do. Now I do.
I ju--
I just wish that
I could be your father.
This is outrageous!
He is not their father!
According to transfer form 33-1 1 ...
these children still belong to me.
- Could we have some order here.
- Leave me alone!
- Get your hands off my children now!
- Could we please...
have some order here?
You touch my kids again,
I'll kill you. Sorry.
I pray that when
they put you away...
they put you where I am,
because we're gonna dance.
I love you, Kelly.
I love you, too, Daddy.
- Be good to yourself, okay?
- Sure.
Come here, little fella.
Gimme a hug.
- I love you, Dad.
- I love you, too.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Think of it this way:
I'll get to make the license plates for your first car.
Jack? Jack!
I'm sorry. Come on.
We've gotta get goin'.
Will ya check in on 'em
every once in a while?
You know I will.
- I'm proud of you,Jack.
- Thanks for everything.
Anytime.
- Deal, my ass!
- Oh, hey. Don't start.
I did the best I could,
and you know that.
Wa-wa-wa-- Why, why do I feel
like I've been here before?
- Because you have.
- Yeah.
You know what?
There's a difference.
-What?
-Now I Know where to find you.
You're a funny man.
Ah! You'll be out in no time.
- Dad!
- What?
You are so wonderful
Being near you
is all that I'm living for
You've shown me more kindness
in little ways
Than I've ever known
In all my days
Tell me we'll stay together
Let me love you forever
'Cause you're a wonderful one
You're a wonderful one
In you there is a rare quality
Your love, baby
It means the world to me
For me you're always concerned
And you ask nothin; baby
In return
You're really more than I deserve
From my heart
I mean these words
You're a wonderful one
Oh,you're a wonderful one
Baby,you're a wonderful one
Sweetheart,you're a wonderful one
My darlin; you're a wonderful one
Oh,you're a wonderful one
Ooh,you're a wonderful one
Mm-mmm,you're a wonderful one
Baby,you're a wonderful one
You're really more than I deserve
From my heart
I mean these words
You're a wonderful one
Sometimes I'm up
Oh, sometimes I'm down
But your love
You're always around
Words of confidence you speak to me?
Baby, then you place
a tender kiss
On my cheek
It makes my burden
a little bit lighter
Makes my life
a little bit brighter
'Cause you're a wonderful one
You're a wonderful one
Oh,you're a wonderful one
Baby,you're a wonderful one
You're really more than I deserve
From my heart
I mean these words
You're a wonderful one
Oh,you're a wonderful one
Baby,you're a wonderful one
Wonderful baby