- Did I miss breakfast?
- Sorry, I just switched over to lunch.
Could I have breakfast anyway?
No. If I start serving
breakfast at lunch time,
- it could lead to...
- Brunch?
- Fine. I will get you a breakfast menu.
- Thank you.
Miss brekky, huh?
Got to sleep in?
No, I just had to go pray.
Oh! Pray-time. Right, yeah.
Pray-time instead of playtime.
Yup. Guilty as charged.
Five times a day.
Like clockwork.
Certainly keeps you types busy.
Well, it's an important
part of our faith, except...
Can't eat pork.
No booze.
You sure got a lot of rules.
Well, they're not rules as much as...
Plus you gotta wear the babushka
thing on your noggin there.
- It's another one...
- Hijab.
Call it whatever you want
you still gotta wear it. Right?
I don't know how you keep
your hijabs from your jihads.
Hey, did I miss anything?
Yes. You missed me missing breakfast.
Rayyan and I were just talking about
all the rules you people gotta go through.
Yeah, it's terrible.
Like we have to pray five times a day,
and I have to wear a
babushka, apparently.
Yeah, not to mention we gotta
brush our teeth three times a day.
And we have to drink
eight glasses of water.
- That's true.
- Those are Muslim rules too?
Yeah, that's right, Fred.
We gotta brush our teeth...
- facing Mecca.
- Really?
And we have to eat
5 to 9 pieces of fruit a day.
- Facing Damascus.
- You learn something new every day. Huh?
Anyhoo, have a good one, huh?
Damascus?
You don't think he believed us, do you?
Nnnnoooo!?
Everyone has to to eat
5 to 9 pieces of fruit a day.
That's what it says in the book.
The "Canada Food Guide".
Season 3 Episode 5
Rules R Rules
- Salaam alaikum.
- Walaikum assalaam. Brother.
- What's up?
- Just working. Busy.
- You know, time is money.
- If that were true, I'd be rich.
But I'm not.
No sir.
I see.
Well, don't let me keep you.
Yo, it's okay.
I'm just headed to the post office to
mail some things before
the postage goes up.
- Two cents, per item.
- That's um...
- really interesting?
- Every little bit counts.
The imam business is not a lucrative one.
It's like no business I know.
- Isn't that show business?
- I don't know show business.
Just a shot in the dark,
but, um,
- are you short on cash?
- Oh, perpetually.
- I don't have much on me, but I...
- No, Yasir,
you're a good friend to say that,
but I don't want a loan,
- I want to vent.
- Ah.
Yeah...
Vent.
Venting.
- Because I'd rather give you a loan.
- Not necessary.
You know what bugs me about
being short on cash is that it...
distracts me from spiritual matters.
I was walking by the town hall
yesterday and uh...
I noticed a really interesting thing
about Mercy, I actually never notice...
- So, stockin' up on fruit, huh?
- Yeah.
Takin' the old Muslim fruit train,
to vitamin station.
Fred, you know the thing we said
before about Muslims and fruit...
it's not a real rule, right?
We were just joking.
- Sure, sure. I know you're just joking.
- Good.
Just like I know you guys
don't have secret rules
you don't want the rest
of us to find out about, uh?
And when those real rules do slip out,
and now you guys wouldn't
say you were just joking
- to try to make me look stupid.
- Nobody's trying to make you look stupid.
- It's just sort of happening.
- Sure, sure, sure.
Anyhoo, you better pick up
some gooseberries
before some other Muslims
swamp in and grab 'em all.
- Ohhh... no gooseberries.
- What?
Now what's the matter?
What? They forbidden?
Yes. Gooseberries are forbidden.
If it were raining,
we could have them, but,
we can't have them now
because it's not raining.
Until we're married.
Yes! At which point we could have them...
- unless it were raining.
- And then we eat raisins.
- Yes!
- Huh. Interesting.
I knew you guys had some wacky rituals,
but these, I had no idea.
- Fred! It's a joke.
- Rrrrright.
You sound like you don't believe us.
Well, maybe I just sound that way
because I'm joking.
[ They laugh uncertainly ]
- Are you?
- More gooseberries for me.
Suckers!
That guy took my gooseberries.
- Good riddance.
- What?
I don't like gooseberries.
Yasir: I wasted the whole day today.
I'm sorry to hear that, darling.
Amaar was in my office all day
complaining about money.
- What money? He doesn't make any.
- That was the complaint.
Complain, complain, complain.
I couldn't get a thing done.
I can't imagine what that must be like.
And here's the worst thing...
He didn't want any advice.
No. He just wanted to complain.
- Well, you know what you need to do...
- I couldn't even get a word in edgewise.
It was terrible.
Darling, do you want advice,
or are you just complaining?
I'd hope to just complain.
If he needs money,
why don't you give him a job?
- Yeah, good one, mom.
- Now, that's funny.
You always know what to say
to lighten the mood.
I was being serious.
He could do construction.
- Classic.
- You know why that's funny?
Because she plays it small.
You are joking, right, mom?
Well, he's short on cash,
and you're short-staffed
on that deck you're building. So?
I don't know if Amaar has what
we contractors call "it".
He's building a deck. He's not becoming
an astronaut. Anyone can do it.
- Hey, that's what I do for a living.
- And you do it very well.
I just don't think it's a good idea.
- He'd probably work for cheap.
- Then again, I might give him a chance.
He could have what it
takes to be a carpenter.
Well, his sermons are certainly wooden.
[ Laughs ]
She should played it big that time.
Didn't work.
Yeah!
Just come on, please.
No, I have been too lenient,
too many times.
- It is eleven o'clock!
- My stomach doesn't care what time it is.
- It just want some pancakes.
- There are three meals in a day,
- and brunch is not one of them.
- You're being unreasonable.
I do not believe in brunch.
- Whoa.
- Hi.
No brunch for you folks either, huh?
The list goes on.
- We have to do something about Fred.
- Why? What happened?
- I told him I don't eat gooseberries.
- You don't.
You see, we might have given Fred the wrong
impression about some of the rules of Islam.
He might think we eat 5 to 9 fruits a day.
Well, that's not such a bad rule.
- And we brush our teeth...
- I hope you brush your teeth.
- Facing Mecca.
- Okay, that one's a little bit weird.
You can't engage Fred
when he's being paranoid.
It's better just to let
this sort itself out.
Better how?
This way he just goes on the radio and
says bad things about Muslims all the time.
- Okay, not better. Just easier.
- Yeah.
Look, I know I'm not from here...
but maybe that gives me a perspective
on things that you two lack.
- Yes. The wrong perspective.
- Bad, bad perspective.
- I'm going to go talk to him.
- You'll regret it.
- Out-of-towners.
- Tell me about it.
I dunno.
A carpenter?
I don't know if it's really for me.
I'm a spiritual leader.
Well, I can think of an example
of a very famous man
who was a carpenter,
even though he had a higher calling.
- Jesus?
- I was going to say Harrison Ford.
But both work.
Well thanks, Yasir.
But you don't have to worry.
I'm a master of saving money.
For instance, did you know that
a single teabag can last two days?
- Is this oleo?
- Yup.
I thought they stopped
making it after world war II.
Sure, but it has amazing shelf life.
- Why don't you just buy some butter?
- Do I look like a millionaire?
Yasir, thanks for the offer,
but as you can see, I'm doing fine.
- I can pay you in advance.
- Three A's in "Amaar".
What you're saying is
Muslims can't wear gloves.
No, that's not what I said...
And you have to turn your socks
inside out every day at two o'clock?
- No!
- That's weird.
- Though it makes sense in some ways.
- That's not what I said at all.
Those are examples of crazy rules
that I could make up, as a joke.
What's the matter?
Can't keep your lies straight, there, J.J?
J squared?
The J's so nice they named him twice.
If that's your real name.
Well. it's not actually.
It's Juanaid Jafer,
- J.J's just a...
- Just got shiftier and shiftier.
Well, you're not pulling the wool
over my eyes, buddy boy.
Wait a minute, why am I leavin'?
This is my booth.
Beat it.
Now, these clients, the Wispinskis,
are very difficult people.
- They want their deck built just right.
- Of course. It's their home.
Yes, but they have no idea what
goes into the construction of a deck.
- I've re-done the plan three times.
- Uh, everybody's an expert.
By the way,
I'm an expert.
I got the "Carpentry for Dummies" book.
Amaar, construction isn't
something you learn from a book.
- You learn by doing.
- Ah! I knew that.
Because it said so in the book.
- Hamoudi!
- Eh!
- Here come the clients.
- Okay. I'll head to work.
No, wait, I haven't shown you how to...
Mr and Mrs Wispinski.
What a surprise to see you here.
- We live here.
- Your arrival was a surprise...
because you walk quietly.
We are appalled by the state of that deck.
Well, "appalled" or uh,
might be a little strong...
We are appalled!
When we came to you, we thought
we were getting the best in town.
Well, it is a small town.
And yet after all these weeks,
I don't have a place to put my barbecue.
My husband doesn't have a place
to put his barbecue.
- You have two barbecues?
- Don't judge us!
Look. I understand your frustration.
And that is why I hired additional staff.
Amaar: I'm okay!
- That's your additional staff?
- Very eager, isn't he?
[ More stuff crashes down ]
Amaar: No problem!
Gettin' it done!
[ Lumber crashes ]
Amaar: Can I get a little help here?
Okay, you were right.
It was better to let it be.
Let what be?
Fred has got some
misunderstandings about Islam.
- You are just realizing this now?
- Oh, these are new misunderstandings.
We were telling some jokes,
and Fred took it the wrong way.
- You were making jokes about Islam?
- No, no! Not about Islam.
- These were just jokes.
- Hey funny's funny right?
No, funny is not funny.
I think by definition it is.
It is important that
infidels understand our faith.
We sit them down,
we explain to them:
Allah is the one true way,
and what they believe is wrong.
And does that work?
No, usually they get
very mad for some reason.
Baber, believe me.
Rayyan's right.
When it comes to Fred, it's better
to let sleeping dogs lie.
This thing is going to go away by itself.
Fred on radio: Well, listen up, sports fans.
Fred: We all know your Muslims control the
world's oil, and wanna do the rest of us in,
Fred: but it gets worse...
You see, we always hoped that
underneath all our differences,
we shared a few essential sames,
that we all put our socks on one at a time
or brushed our teeth the same way.
But yours truly has discovered
some troubling Muslim rules
that make it clear our sames are more
different than our differences ever were,
from a hatred of brunch to an
unnatural love of fruit.
What is it with your Muslims and fibre?
Makes 'em more explosive, I guess.
Fred: Anyway, guard your berries, folks,
Fred: hang on to your honeydew
with both hands
Fred: because your Muslim menace is out there,
and they are hungry.
It's just Fred, right?
No one's going to listen to Fred, right?
- Don't even think about it.
- Uh-oh.
[ Yasir moans in pain ]
Amaar is terrible at construction.
He actually set our schedule back a week.
Well, it's no help saying he's terrible.
Give him some specific, useful criticism.
Now what's he bad at?
- Anything involving wood.
- Uh huh.
And nails. And concrete.
- And other construction materials.
- Okay, well...
And the tools involved in construction.
And the methods involved in the
transport of construction materials.
- Well, maybe...
- And the methods involved
in the transport of tools used in
dealing with construction materials.
Does he have any strengths?
He's good at first aid.
This is bad.
Maybe they're all whispering
about something else.
And staring at people just behind us.
Of course. How is the weather
in your fantasy world, huh?
- Joe.
- You got a lot of nerve.
- I do?
- Yeah. Hoarding all our fruit.
Let me tell you something.
My dad was a cherry farmer. And uh...
life was no bowl of cherries.
- In fact it was...
- The pits?
Hey, that's pretty clever.
But I'm still mad at you.
I will not have Fred Tupper
telling ridiculous lies about us.
Not allowed to eat gooseberries?
I love gooseberries.
Really?
They're so tart.
- I know what we must do.
- I'm not going to like this, am I?
Amaar: I'm sorry about your hand.
But accidents happen, right?
Yes, well...
we need to talk.
And, again,
it's a good thing I knew first aid.
Amaar, but I'm under some pressure here.
Okay hold that thought.
I want to show you something.
Now, Frank's doin' the deck.
But look! Ta da!
I did the stairs.
Amaar. Well done.
I am impressed.
You said I couldn't learn
construction from a book.
Obviously, I was wrong.
Is it up to code?
What type of screws did you use?
- I didn't use any.
- What?
The wood is so beautiful,
I didn't want to put holes in it.
- So I just used glue.
- Glue?
Well, wood glue.
I'm not an idiot.
- Why, is there a problem?
- Depends...
Maybe.
So I think our conversation
may have left you with some
misconceptions about Islam.
Really?
I knew it!
You don't have to wear
that thing on your head.
No, that one's real.
Stop this nonsense about
brushing your teeth and eating fruit.
- You have been led astray.
- What do you mean?
We may have misspoke.
- Ahem.
- Okay.
There may have been
a misunderstanding.
- Okay. We were joking.
- You see? It has all been a mistake.
And I promise you she
is very, very sorry.
Huh! No, no, no!
I didn't get out of bed yesterday.
- You didn't?
- Or off the boat, however that go.
Nice try toots, but you gotta get up
pretty early to be up earlier than me.
Look. If you don't believe me,
just go online. Type in "Muslim".
You won't find anything about
socks or teeth or gloves.
If I type in the word "Muslim",
what I'll find is my name on
a government watch list.
Okay, this is getting out of hand.
A woman at the store today
called me a "glove hater".
Fred's really got a hold of
something this time.
After all the things he's said,
you'd think these little things
wouldn't bother people so much.
Oh, people take the little things seriously.
It's the little things that count.
That's why they say:
"Sweat the small stuff".
No, they say:
"Don't sweat the small stuff".
Left out one little word, darling,
don't sweat it.
This is all my fault.
If I hadn't wound Fred up,
he wouldn't be saying these things.
I misrepresented my faith.
I have to set it right.
But how do I do that?
- Talk to him.
- I tried that. It didn't work.
It just made things worse.
I even took Baber with me.
- Well that's your trouble.
- What?
Well, Baber is a guy
who no one listens to,
and Fred is a guy that
doesn't listen to anyone.
I thought those two things would
cancel each other out.
No. It will all blow over, darling.
It's true.
People are smart.
I mean no matter how many lies Fred tells,
eventually the truth will win out.
Maybe you're right.
Thanks, guys.
Truth and honesty,
always good!
Can you help me think of a way out
to trick Amaar into quitting?
- Yasir, sorry I'm late.
- Are you late?
- Well, it's almost noon.
- Oh! So it is!
We've gotten so much done,
with so little injury.
I would have been here sooner,
but I thought you were gonna me up.
Ah! I must have forgot.
It's completely my fault.
That's strange, because...
I got a message from you
telling me to keep waiting.
Well, that must be an old message.
My cell phone has been acting strangely.
Accidents can happen.
- There's been another accident?!
- No, no. It's all fine.
Anyway, where do you want me?
Cos'...
- I don't want to waste any more time.
- Of course. Lunch!
Let's go to Fatima's.
I'll drive.
- As long as you promise to bring me back.
- Oh! Ah, ah, ah!
- Hamoudi!
- Excuse me.
Hello, my friends.
- Careful.
- Yeah.
Well, We've been doing
some soul searching.
Ah! Excellent!
It's always in the last place you look.
You know, we appreciate all
the work you've done, uh...
- up to this point.
- Excellent.
If there's no "but" in that sentence,
I'll get back to work.
But... we're moving in
another direction with the deck.
Oh, you're not changing the plans again.
- No, we're keeping the plans.
- Good!
- We're changing the contractor.
- Oh.
Raisins for crying,
them Muslims.
And that's when it rains.
Fred: You should hear what
they do on a clear day...
Fred: Everyday, if you can say that...
Sarah. I was just listening to Fred's show.
I know. He's crazy.
He really is. Certifiable.
A wacko.
- What's this?
- Our new ad campaign.
We have a new ad campaign?
- Why wouldn't you tell me?
- I want to surprise you.
You know, I haven't always
supported your Muslim ways.
But things have gotten out of hand.
And I will not let people bad mouth you.
Wow. Thank you.
I think.
So you can't wear gloves.
And you can only eat
raisins on a rainy day,
and during a full moon you
believe a half man - half wolf
- is going to steal your children.
- Okay, that's new.
No matter what you believe,
we have all got to get along.
And I think the best way to stem
these "anti-Muslim" thoughts
is to head them off at the pass.
- So...
- Oh boy!
- "Brushing Apart, Smiling Together".
- What do you think?
I think this is out of control.
- We have a contract.
- A contract, yes.
- A deck, not so much.
- Excuse me.
If I may.
Mr and Mrs Wispinski. Hi.
Of course, this deck is important to you.
It's a part of your home.
- It's for your family.
- Please don't tell us how to use our deck.
My point is, you've made a lot of
last-minute changes. And...
Yasir's had to roll with that.
Well, I'm not going to apologize for
wanting the deck that I want.
- Good for you, honey.
- Oh shut up, George.
Yasir has shown flexibility
on his side of the bargain.
Maybe you could do the same?
No!
Well, if you terminate now,
Mr. Hamoudi could argue
that you violated the agreement
when you changed the construction plans.
You forfeit any rights to
further work on the deck,
but you still would have to
pay for it in full.
That's black letter law.
You know, maybe this guy's a...
you better keep talking.
I'm sure we can all agree on a
reasonable cooling off period
and then Yasir can redouble his efforts
to complete the construction.
- Yasir?
- Yeah. Certainly.
I can finish this deck in two days.
- Yasir.
- Three days.
If not, we revisit the
question of who's at fault.
All right. That seems...
reasonable.
You're lucky you've got
this guy on your crew.
Talks like a lawyer.
- I am a lawyer.
- Ha, ha, ha. Good one!
- He plays it small.
- Yeah. Okay, that's enough, George, c'mon.
Fred on radio: It's a cover-up, people.
That's what it is.
For the last few days yours truly
has been repeatedly cornered by
members of your so-called
Muslim community.
The message: Keep my mouth shut.
Think before I speak.
Well, that's not Freddy Tupper's way.
No, you can take this microphone
Fred: from me when you pry it
from my cold, dead fingers.
Fred: Or when we go to sports at six.
Darling, I wanted to hear
the sports at six.
- What are we going to do?
- Listen, people are smart.
- They will see through this.
- Yeah. Tried that.
- Have you tried talking to him?
- Several times. That doesn't work.
It only makes things worse.
- I'll go and see him.
- Are you sure?
But I'm on a roll.
I just talked Yasir's crazy clients down.
He was amazing.
He got me four extra days to finish.
- Three.
- That's what I said.
So what are you going to do?
You know what?
We just have to connect
with Fred on his level.
Fred: "Islam for Dummies"?
I love these books.
- I based my entire life on these books.
- That's not surprising.
Now, I challenge you to find something
in there that talks about socks, or
brushing your teeth or whatever it is
you think you might have heard.
Well, you know,
I might've been a little
quick to jump to conclusions there,
you know.
Multiple times, yeah.
You've changed, Amaar.
You used to be a little too
slick for your own good, but
now you're kind of folksy.
I've been getting my hands dirty.
Doing a little... carpentry.
You know, in my culture
there's a great man that
revered by everyone,
who started out as a carpenter.
I know.
Harrison Ford.
Yeah, love that guy.
[ Makes whipping sound ]
That's good.
Subtitle by: Kiasuseven