No!
Lady.
Detective... The culprit...
Lady, are you okay?
Let's get out of here. Now.
Detective, the culprit is over there...
That's not important right now.
Detective... I...
Lady, don't worry.
- It's just...
- Don't worry.
I'll save you. Trust me. Just trust me.
Ms. Yoo will be okay, right?
Hang in there, lady. You're a strong woman.
You'll be fine.
Hang in there.
- Seol Ok!
- Get out of the way!
- Goodness.
- What happened to her?
What happened? How bad is it?
- Please move.
- Goodness.
It's not serious, is it?
No, Seol Ok.
Wake up. Please, Seol Ok.
Wake up.
What did you do? What happened to Seol Ok?
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
Sorry isn't going to cut it!
What are you doing? Mom's going to faint!
- Goodness.
- Doctor.
Mother.
Seol Ok.
Goodness, Seol Ok.
(Episode 16)
Sit down.
I'll give you some tea.
Welcome back. You're in your place again.
Is Hyun Soo...
dead?
I'm sick of this.
Stop bringing this up.
I've waited 17 years for her.
I'm all worn out.
I want to know if she's dead.
Did you make them do it?
The statute of limitation already ran out.
Even if you speak the truth...
It'll be of no use.
Is Ms. Yoo Seol Ok's guardian here?
How is my child?
We removed the bullet.
It was right next to her aorta.
If it was a millimeter closer,
it would've been bad.
Is she over the worst condition?
She bled quite a lot,
so we'll have to wait and see.
Oh my goodness.
Mom.
Lady.
Don't be mistaken just
because I'm staring at you.
It's not because I like you.
It's because this is our last time.
I won't be able to see you again.
I don't care about the truth anymore.
I want to break free from my past.
So you should forget about me too.
I can't sit around seeing you in danger.
And I'm sorry...
about your parents.
I really wanted to catch
the culprit for you.
This is as far as I'll go.
Have a great life.
Goodbye.
Seol Ok.
It's me.
Ms. Yoo.
Ms. Yoo, it's me.
Where's Detective Ha?
Wan Seung is too busy to come.
I know he's busy, but
how can he not stop by?
She got hurt while trying
to clear his accusation.
I have no idea. I can't
get a hold of him either.
(Director Ha Wan Seung)
(Report of cases taken in 2017)
(Signed by Director Ha Wan Seung)
You're working hard.
I quit being a detective.
Of course, I'll work hard.
Wow, is this really the Wan Seung I knew?
I realized I needed power to protect...
the things I like.
Is that why you're going
on an arranged date...
with the daughter of Minister of Justice?
Why? Do you still have
feelings left for me?
Excuse me. I have a meeting coming up.
My gosh, that's too heavy for you to carry.
You should've called me.
No, it's okay. I can do that much.
Be careful.
Don't make me stand by your sickbed.
Gosh, did you know how much older I got...
from running this lunchbox place,
making porridge, and bringing
it to your hospital?
All right. I'll never get sick again.
You should sit and rest.
I'll carry this in. Goodness.
Hey, how's your new house?
It looked too small.
That's all the space I
need to live by myself.
I don't care what it is,
but don't get divorced.
Just spend some time
away from each other...
and move back in later.
Right, I should help Captain Bae.
That's a lot to do by himself.
Whatever.
Did you two fight?
But you were always so lovey-dovey.
Lovey-dovey?
Hey.
He's not my type.
I was just being nice because...
he helps me out in the
kitchen with heavy stuff.
Don't try to fool me. What is it?
I'm belittled by his actions.
I think he's playing hard to get.
He completely drew a line to me.
It's like he's saying,
"Don't come any further."
Wait, that was him and not you?
Whatever.
I don't want him either.
Come on, you're going to hurt your hand.
Just get the cabbages ready.
What's going on with you and Gyung Mi?
I thought you two liked each other.
You always came to visit me together.
I'm sure you know this as her friend.
She's very popular among guys.
Yes, of course.
She's smart, cool,
a good cook, and a great businesswoman.
She's an all-round player.
Yes, of course.
I am...
a man who has nothing,
a detective who never gets promoted,
old, and I even have a kid.
I shouldn't even think about it.
You do like her.
I'm glad I can stay next
to her like I'm doing now.
What if someone else takes her?
I can't ruin her future.
I'll leave you two alone.
You're quick at picking things up.
I'm quick at learning how to cook too.
I don't think so.
Goodness, I can hardly read this.
What is it?
I got a text from Mrs.
Kim, but I can't read it.
Let me see.
There.
Make the font the biggest size.
(Make the font the biggest size.)
(The font size has been reset.)
- Goodness.
- You should make the screen brighter.
You said your vision's blurry these days.
Make the screen brighter.
(Make the screen brighter.)
(The screen is now brighter.)
What? I can do this myself.
Thanks.
Then I don't have to clean anymore, right?
Then I don't have to give
you allowance, right?
All right, I'll clean.
If you won't do your laundry,
don't wear something like that.
That one is hard to wash.
Whatever. I like this shirt.
Hi, Seol Ok.
I bought a TV.
I'll send it to you.
Give me your address.
Mother, it's okay.
I can watch things on my laptop.
It's not okay.
I miss you, you know.
The house feels empty without you.
Ho Soon is no fun,
so I'm bored.
I also...
miss your bad cooking.
Mother, do you have a lot
of leftover side dishes?
Thank you, Mother.
Ho Cheol.
Hi, Seol Ok.
When did you get in? Mother
doesn't know you're here.
I was just on the phone with her.
You talk with my mom, but
you never pick up my calls.
I didn't tell her because...
I have to get back right away.
I see.
How is Jeju Island?
Well... It's all right.
Ho Cheol.
- I...
- Don't make your decision yet.
It's all right.
You need some time, don't you?
Now that I'm with Jeju Prosecutor's Office,
I regret not solving the
Shinim-dong case...
when I was with Ansan Prosecutor's Office.
I should've solved the
case and quit my job.
Would I have been a great husband to you...
if I had done that?
You said you'd become an
international lawyer.
Why are you back so early?
I think Korean law school would be better.
The US schools weren't impressive.
Then what did you do in the US?
Well, this and that. I
looked into MBA programs...
and traveled.
How is Wan Seung these days?
He exercises in the morning...
and comes to work at Ha And Jung on time.
He doesn't see his former
colleagues from the police.
He often goes drinking...
with his new judiciary acquaintances.
Anything unusual?
Recently he bought very
expensive handmade...
Swiss watches with his company credit card.
Find out why he has been to the US.
(7080 Live Pub)
You said you'd be an international lawyer.
Why are you back so soon?
Come on, I'm too old to study.
I just went there for fun.
And to find someone.
Find who?
I already find the person.
The US is great.
Private detectives are
quicker than the police.
As long as you give them money.
Who did you find?
You'll be surprised.
Hyun Soo.
See? I told you you'd be surprised.
Seo Hyun Soo?
Was she really in the US?
I only saw her in pictures.
She's gotten old.
She was very different...
from how I imagined her to be.
How did she end up in the US?
The private detective said...
she was chased out to Japan.
She met a Korean-American there...
Did she get married?
She did and got divorced.
I misunderstood my dad all along.
What will you do now?
I'll make her come back.
Jang Do Jang is dead now.
As long as I'm with Ha And Jung,
nobody can hurt Hyun Soo.
Will you get back together with Hyun Soo?
What? Seo Hyun Soo?
Seo Hyun Soo?
You're crazy.
Seo Hyun Soo is dead.
(Comics)
Are you sure Seo Hyun Soo is dead?
Mr. Ha is being suspicious.
I buried her with Do Jang.
Jang Do Jang is already dead.
Who's going to prove it?
You didn't...
let Seo Hyun Soo run off,
did you?
You know I don't have the nerves.
What's all that?
Hyun Soo.
I don't want her to stay in a hotel.
I wonder if she only wears
pants like she used to.
When will she be here?
On the 29th.
I already sent her the flight ticket.
She's not doing well financially.
The 29th?
It's a good thing I moved in here.
Hyun Soo doesn't have a
place to stay in Korea.
There will be a welcome back party...
on the 30th. Do you want to come?
You've been curious about Hyun Soo.
Who's this?
What are you trying to do?
Seo Hyun Soo is dead.
I buried her myself.
She isn't dead.
I carried her to the hospital myself.
Hyun Soo.
Excuse me. Could you please help?
You need to help her.
She bled a lot, so she fell unconscious.
However, the doctor said the
wound itself wasn't deep.
Hyun Soo...
walked out of the hospital alive.
I checked the security footage too.
Did she walk out of the hospital?
Do you know why?
It's because of you.
The moment he walks into
this hospital room,
I'm going to fire.
You need to leave before he walks in.
There's a car waiting for you
in front of the hospital.
Can you do that?
Then I can ask Hyun Soo myself.
It'll be an interesting story.
I knew it was odd for you
to work for Ha And Jung.
I know you.
You're scheming something, right?
But I won't fall for it so easily.
You look busy. I'll leave.
Will you? I thought you had a question.
It's nothing. I'll see
you at work tomorrow.
Mr. Ha, this is Jung Ji Won.
Wan Seung saw a video of Ms.
Seo walking out.
We'll find the video too.
That's when there weren't many cameras.
I didn't know.
They just put one up in
the entrance for a test.
Why did she have to be on the footage?
Is that your excuse?
Mr. Ha has the video footage.
He's suspicious of you.
Once Mr. Ha turns his back on you,
I can't help you anymore.
I clearly buried her deep.
Then...
you must be sure that her body is there.
I saw a video...
of Hyun Soo walking out of the hospital...
with my own two eyes.
She died right after that.
How could I believe that?
You hid the fact that she was hospitalized.
He remembers the place where he buried her.
Detective Ko, I mean.
Are you having...
any other ideas by any chance?
Do you think I hid her away?
Were you really unable to find...
that thing she had?
Mr. Ha, I'm very disappointed.
I'm the one who is desperate to find that.
Then would you like to see
her body with your eyes?
How would I recognize her
body after 17 years?
We'll know for sure after a DNA test.
We will...
collect her DNA on our side.
As you wish.
All right.
Give me a call when you have the date.
I'm here.
Have a great life.
Goodbye.
We can catch him.
The culprit.
Lady.
Lady, are you okay?
We can...
catch him.
It's no use. The statute
of limitation ran out.
Wait, did you hear everything I said?
Do you know what time it is?
Then why did we set up
a time for a meeting?
Did you look into a similar
case in Shinim-dong?
Yes.
Was it wrapped up after the
victim, Yoo In Sang, died?
Wow, there is your superhuman sense again.
How did you know?
They covered up Hyun Soo's
case with Shinim-dong case.
Ms. Seo's name wasn't on the will,
but it was odd how you
knew about the two cases.
That means the person who
gave you the case file knows.
That taxi driver killed Ms. Seo.
If they covered up one case with the other,
there must be another designer
other than Detective Ko.
The statute of limitation
doesn't apply anymore.
We just have to get the culprit.
Oh, gosh, what's wrong with this?
I'm sorry. Something else was on my mind.
Goodness.
You have an expensive watch,
but you're always late.
The surveillance is harsher than ever.
Wow, that's a good sign.
And this watch is a fake.
I'm paying for this place
by selling those watches.
All of my watches are fake now.
You're here.
Wait, are you coming just now?
Then why did we set up
a time for a meeting?
I got here first.
I was in the bathroom.
Take a seat.
My gosh, why isn't he coming?
Captain Bae.
Goodness.
Hey. You're here.
If you're going to sleep, why
did we set up this time?
I'm sorry, man.
I was on a stakeout yesterday.
Gosh, darn it.
There's no use in catching
just Detective Ko.
He's chased after for Jang
Do Jang's murder anyway.
We need the murder instigator.
Murder instigation gives you...
the same sentence as committing a murder.
But...
would that be all right?
What is?
He's your dad.
Have you been seeing Ho Cheol again?
It looked like you are.
It looked like you're often
on the phone with Ms. Jung.
That's work-related.
Wait, are you jealous?
I mean, Ms. Jung is on Ha And Jung's side.
I'm suspicious that you
might be spying on us.
You just got out of the hospital.
Stop drinking.
You should take care of your health.
It's because I made these meatballs.
You can't eat that without alcohol.
You cooked something inedible again.
My cooking got much better.
You never tasted any of it.
According to Officer Lee
from Shinim Police Station,
the other detectives seem to be...
looking out for Detective Ko.
Of course, Ha And Jung's behind them.
Where do you think he is?
Here you go.
Because of that,
Ha And Jung can't really
cut Detective Ko loose.
Everyone's connected.
Detective Ko's been quite active.
He uses the public phone
next to his hideout often.
Did you drop enough hints
that Hyun Soo's alive?
Everyone should've heard by now.
I call her every day.
Secretary Pyo even pulled my call records.
The client didn't see her
die and can't be sure.
I don't know about the rest...
but Lawyer Jung fell for it.
Seo Hyun Soo's alive.
It can't be.
It's a groundless rumor.
He mentioned her to a Mr. Kim.
Like he was reporting back.
Mr. Kim?
I heard at a private club that...
everyone's trying to get his number.
He's great at cleaning up.
Mr. Kim changes his number every month.
No one knows his name or face but...
he knows more than the
National Intelligence Service.
Do you think Hyun Soo died...
because she knew something she shouldn't?
I'm positive that this Mr.
Kim works for my dad.
Detective Ko works for that Mr. Kim.
Mr. Ha agreed to a DNA test.
So, where did you bury the body?
I will tell you on the day.
We need to check first to...
I will take you there myself.
Do you not trust me?
You're the one who doesn't trust me.
Mr. Ha's leaving to Hangook Hospital.
Dad's really busy.
He went to a hospital.
He's way too healthy.
The DNA test.
How do you know where your father is?
I bought his people with his money.
We should get ready.
It's almost time to wrap up.
Go, go.
I thought he was exercising too much.
A tangsuyuk and noodles, right?
Leave it there.
Enjoy.
(Comics)
Okay, perfect.
To Hangook Hospital?
Yes.
Mr. Ha.
Do you want to strike a deal...
with information on Wan Seung?
Whatever it is,
he will come back in due time.
You are so foolish.
Have you forgotten the accident?
Do not forget.
It doesn't end with me.
There's something bigger than our law firm.
Have you eaten yet?
Are we close enough to ask each other that?
A lot has happened...
between us.
Get to the point.
Did serving Mr. Ha...
make your life any better?
The point, please.
Work with me.
Let's take the law firm.
Why should you bow to Mr. Ha?
What do you have on Wan Seung?
Why did he come back?
It's something you can't handle.
This is the last time.
Get creative again and you're
banned from the kitchen.
Stick to the recipe.
I'm doing as it says.
That's enough.
I almost added too much again.
Not bad.
Now let it simmer.
Okay.
That must be a customer.
Keep stirring so it doesn't stick.
Okay.
Stir.
Right.
Detective?
He's on the move.
What happened?
Seol Ok.
You're banned from the kitchen!
Why are you suddenly refusing to be there?
If I were to be at the scene,
you might suspect me of...
switching the DNA samples.
What if you suspect me
because I am there alone?
What are you talking about?
I trust you completely.
Very well.
I'll tell you the results
as soon as I have them.
Lawyer Jung.
You gave me information.
I'll give you what you want.
What do you want?
Ha And Jung.
What? Get in.
You still believe Hyun
Soo's alive, don't you?
I know there's no possibility.
If you don't think you can see the corpse,
we can go without you.
It might not be her.
Right.
We shouldn't be biased.
Let's go and check.
Keep stirring so it doesn't stick.
Stir.
What?
Were you really scared to get in?
You're different today.
You get scared?
This is it.
Let's go.
See? I told you I'd buried her.
The test results will
tell us whether it's her.
Go and get a sample.
Get it from a femur and the
cartilage from a right rib.
Okay.
The test will take 24 hours.
No one else can find out about this.
Yes, sir.
We shall...
run some tests on this ourselves.
Our results...
should correspond, shouldn't they?
Of course, they should and will.
If that's all, we can go.
Cover it back up carefully.
What are you doing here?
I heard you found Hyun Soo.
I came to see if she's really dead.
What are you doing here?
To set up a murder for hire?
Are you here to check...
if you killed her the first time?
Was it a trap?
You set for me?
I will tell you everything that I know.
Why Wan Seung joined Ha And Jung...
and what's he's up to now.
You're under arrest for...
murder and the disposal of a body.
You don't know what you've done.
Everyone should pay the price
for what they've done.
Hyun Soo.
I said I'd find you.
That I wouldn't die before I do.
It's so pretty.
Thank you.
I love you.
Me too.
The CEO of Ha And Jung,
Korea's largest law firm...
was questioned for instigating a murder.
17 years ago, Mr. Ha Jae Ho...
instructed a Shinim-dong detective...
to kill a young Ms. Seo.
(Mr. Ha)
You...
know nothing about Seo Hyun Soo.
She's not the woman you think she is.
So you had her killed?
Or...
did she see something she shouldn't have?
It was all because of you.
You started to look into her death...
and to save your life...
I got involved.
If only you hadn't joined the police...
and reported her missing...
in order to find her,
I could have...
lived the rest of my life
not knowing about her.
Why are you taking the fall?
There's more, isn't there?
I will...
get out soon enough.
You have solved nothing.
It's so nice and clean.
Those windows are so high
up, so I can't reach them.
You should've told me sooner.
I love a good arm workout.
- Did you get those?
- Yes.
- It's hot, I'll open the window.
- Okay.
This feels great.
Oh, right.
Seol Ok will be here alone tomorrow.
I'm off to see Dong Ho.
Shall I come along?
Kids can't get enough of a policeman.
I'll show him my handcuffs and police car.
Shall I show up in my uniform?
Forget it, you're too busy.
Boys don't like to hang
out with their moms.
They need physical playtime.
Is that why he gets bored
when he's with me?
He's full of energy at that age.
What can he do with you?
There's something on your face.
- What's this?
- Where?
What's this here?
She's been living by herself now.
Let's not get on her nerves.
Hey.
You get more on my nerves when you do that.
You can stick together, all right?
She became sulky.
We should be careful.
I'm telling you, that's not the case.
Please, go on.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
- Goodness.
- I'm sorry.
Me too.
Why are you here again? I
heard you were reinstated.
My sixth sense tends to work when I'm here.
To be honest, I'm in charge
of a difficult case.
Stop luring me into it..
My exam is coming up.
I'm only going to study for a while.
You're like Sherlock.
Of course, you'll pass.
And you're fast, so you'll
pass the fitness test.
I'm bad at pushups and sit-ups.
And I don't know anything
about criminal procedure law.
Open the page. I'll teach you.
Go and catch your criminals.
You're so cheap.
I hope you fail the police employment test.
What is it?
What is the case anyway?
I'm so curious.
Gosh, he never helps.
Detective Ha.
What's the case?
Detective Ko died.
He was killed.
And Hyun Soo's DNA...
was illegible.
They even did mitochondria DNA test,
but five testing labs
said it was illegible.
The case...
isn't over yet.
I have a feeling about this.
Something smells fishy.
There's something bigger.
I'm not sure how big this is,
but if you have sinned,
you must pay for it.
Mr. Kim?
I heard you've been looking for me.
Who are you?
It's me, Hyun Soo.
Seo Hyun Soo.
We should go to the
detention center first...
to catch the one who killed Detective Ko.
Lady, even a police officer
can't go in there.
- I have a way around.
- A way around?
Aren't you going to take the
police employment test?
I'll take it again next year.
You always say that.
You should come work for me.
I'll take a good care.
Why would I go work for you?
Wait, there's an age limit to the test.
How old are you again?
I still have more time.
- I think this is your last year.
- No, it's not.
- My gosh.
- Let's just go get some coffee.
(Thank you for watching Queen of Mystery.)
("Queen for Seven Days"
will be aired next week.)