Subtitles by DramaFever
Madam, please get in.
Madam.
A fax came for you.
Joo Da Hae, I'm getting
out in seven days.
Wait for me. Ha Ryu.
Thank you.
A fax came for you here, too.
- I have one here.
- Me too.
Is someone playing a prank?
Someone sent the same fax to all of us.
It's nothing.
It seems that someone is
playing a practical joke.
Just go back to your seat.
- Checkmate!
- What is this?
She should have received the fax by now.
Taek Bae said he would
send it today as planned.
It should be there.
Make sure your stomach is always full.
Once you are hungry, you become soft.
Mister, how much for the faxes?
Did any fax come for me?
No, there is one addressed
to Manager Joo.
It must have been sent here by mistake.
Manager Joo?
What is it?
It looks like someone's playing a joke.
Give it to me.
Find out more about this fax.
And also who Ha Ryu is.
Yum Sam Do, you are being released
next week, right?
Yes.
About your life after this
a lawyer will be assigned
to you pro bono.
Would you be willing to try?
I'm okay.
I see.
It's not mandatory, but...
this lawyer is very beautiful.
Oh, is that right?
I must have come to the wrong room.
I came to see a female lawyer.
I'm sorry about being a male lawyer.
Please have a seat.
What?
I'll do my best.
- It's just that...
- Please have a seat.
- Is your name Yum Sam Do?
- Yes.
By the way...
Is there someone who looks
exactly like you?
Someone who looks like me?
You look like someone I know.
He looks exactly like you.
Are you saying that he looks just like me?
Yes.
- Do you know the man who looks like me?
- Yes.
He's in here! In this prison.
In here?
Ha Ryu!
What is it?
- Thank you.
- Sure.
What is going on?
Ha Ryu, you have a brother.
- You have a brother.
- What nonsense!
You have a brother, twin brother!
Man, why are you doing this?
Your picture in your pocketbook...
the picture from your first birthday.
Have a seat.
Are you my brother?
It would be odd if we weren't twins.
We look exactly alike.
That's what I thought.
The pictures were switched.
Because I don't have that spot on me.
That's right.
I have that spot on my arm.
This is me and this is you.
Now the picture has found the real owner.
It's finally found.
Who else is there?
Do we have a mother and father?
There is only our father.
- Do we have any other siblings?
- We are the only ones.
I'm sorry to have met you like this.
I'm sorry.
I'm the one who is sorry.
What took you so long?
- You should have come sooner.
- We were looking for you.
We've been looking for you.
If I had a father...
if I had a brother...
I wouldn't have lived like this.
Do you have any idea
what I went through?
I'm sorry.
Have you been alone all these years?
I... had a daughter and everything.
I had a beautiful daughter...
Brother.
This is so unfair.
This is so very unfair.
- Happy?
- Yes.
We look exactly alike.
What did you say?
In prison?
Did you really meet your
brother in a prison?
Yes.
Whew... what do we do?
Why is he in prison?
I didn't ask him the details.
What do we do?
If we tell your father that
your brother is in prison
he'll have a heart attack.
We should tell him that we haven't
found your brother yet.
I think so too.
I wonder what he did to end up in prison.
You had your father
growing up, but...
it must have been very hard
for your brother.
I feel sorry for him.
Tisk, as if you weren't a cry baby...
Stop crying.
This is a picture from my first birthday.
Mine and my brother's pictures
were switched.
Look at the spot here.
Wow, you didn't have this birthmark
on the picture you had.
Can I see your birthmark?
It's amazing.
You've had that mark since your birth.
When he gets out of prison,
let's be good to him.
Of course, I will.
He's my brother-in-law.
I'm his sister-in-law.
Wait, should I just talk down to him then?
What do you mean talk down, huh?
Should I not?
Talk casually or not?
Get your facts straight.
Address each other formally.
He will call you 'Sister-in-law' and
you'll call him 'Brother-in-law' politely.
But you are my honey.
Gosh, that's enough.
How did you manage to pass the first
bar exam, when you are this clueless?
Well, that would be my charm.
Ha Ryu.
I'm getting out first.
- We will see each other outside.
- You've made it.
Get some rest until I get out.
When I get out, things will get tough.
- There will be a plenty of things to do.
- Okay.
I understand.
I will go now.
Please be well.
Master!
Thank you.
Take care.
I will see you when I get out.
Sam Do!
Yum Sam Do, good to see you.
You've made it!
Sir, you've made it.
- Good to see you, sir.
- It's been a while, guys.
You guys all look good.
Introduce yourself.
You know who he is.
He's the infamous Master Yum.
He's the best strategist in Korea.
Sam Do, let's first go to a barbecue
restaurant and talk it over.
Are you planning something again?
Wait.
In plain language, I should
say 'commit a fraud'.
I told you I quit.
Sam Do.
Without a strategist
even the best operators in Korea
can't do anything.
Draw up a scheme for us one last time.
Please.
I'm sorry.
I'm... done with it.
Keep up the good work.
Don't get caught, okay?
Sir.
I didn't like riding at first.
But it became a good exercise.
If you like riding
you will get close to my sister quickly.
It may seem like I'm kissing up to her.
I'm not good at doing things
to please someone.
Please give me a break.
When you and my sister argue
I get nervous and frustrated.
Let's just pretend that we rode
and go back to Seoul. Please?
Come this way.
I have something to show you.
This is Lisa.
She's the one my sister cares
for like her own child.
Is that so?
I thought you were the one
she cared for the most.
Lisa is the best.
I'm about here?
Then I would be... this much.
Nonsense.
If Lisa coughs
my sister would cancel her business
trip from New York City
and be on the plane home.
Shocking, isn't it?
I'm jealous.
Here.
Touch her to get close.
You are such a chicken.
It's okay, here.
Why are you doing that?
Madam.
- I got the report on Ha Ryu as you asked.
- Did you?
Ha Ryu is in prison for the remains found
at Baek Hak Town site three years ago.
What did you say?
Then 'be out in seven days' on
the fax means that?
Yes. He's scheduled to be
released in three days.
Alright. Good work.
Joo Da Hae...
Again there is something she's hiding.
Do Kyung!
I'm sorry I'm late.
Let's go now.
I'm going to hurt you if you lied
about buying me a mink coat today.
What are you looking at?
Auntie, I'm sorry but let's
go shopping next time.
I need to go somewhere in a hurry.
Hey, you said you'd buy me a mink coat!
Do Kyung!
Why is she acting that way?
Ha Ryu... Joo Da Hae?
- Mommy!
- Wow.
- Do I look pretty?
- You look so pretty.
I wish I had something like this.
Who is this guy?
Did she find the child's father?
This is too soon.
It can't happen already.
So, how was it? It's easier and more
fun than expected, right?
Yes, it was refreshing.
Next time, let's come with my sister.
Okay.
Sir, there is someone who
wants to see you.
Okay.
Be right back.
Hi auntie.
I'm at the riding club with Do Hoon.
I'm at Do Kyung's office right now.
I wanted to go shopping with you,
but I guess you are too busy too.
By the way, do you know
anyone named Ha Ryu?
Pardon?
On Do Kyung's desk,
there is a fax from him, and...
a report on Ha Ryu, so I just got curious.
I came here to go shopping with Do Kyung.
Was it Mi Ah Dong or something?
She grabbed the address
and left in a hurry.
- Mi Ah Dong?
- Yes, it was Mi Ah Dong.
Anyway...
have a good time and I
will see you next time.
When the riding club is three hours away
can she stop Do Kyung in time?
Let's see who this guy is.
Ha Ryu will be out soon.
How much his heart will ache again...
Hello? Yes.
Lisa did what?
Okay, I'll be right there.
It's okay.
Da Hae.
What is it?
What happened?
How could Lisa get out when I wasn't here?
How could she get out?
I'm sorry.
Was that you?
You did that?
She looked stressed,
so I took her out for a walk.
She suddenly jumped and got loose.
I couldn't do anything.
Who the hell are you to take her out?
- Who the hell are you?
- Sis.
Calm down.
The staff is looking for her.
- Lisa will be back.
- Do Hoon, you!
Shut up.
You are here.
They've found Lisa.
Have they?
Where is she?
See, what did I tell you?
But it's just that...
there was an accident with
a truck on the road.
What accident?
What happened?
I'm asking you what happened!
On the spot...
she was killed.
Sis, what are you doing?
You are the one who killed Lisa!
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
I don't need your sorry.
Should I say sorry after I kill you?
Sis!
A truck with Lisa has arrived.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
I'm okay.
What did you say?
You've found him?
- You just said you've found him?
- Yes, we have.
- We're going to see him tomorrow.
- We've finally found him.
Ever since I let go of his hand
I haven't been able to sleep well at night.
Now I can die without regrets.
Father, this is so great.
Wait a minute, shouldn't we
throw a party or something?
Of course, I will prepare a huge party.
Alright then.
You should get ready for a big party.
In looking for my brother...
you've done most of the work.
Thanks.
Wow, I'm so happy.
Aren't you?
Soo Jung.
Jae Woong.
Will you marry me?
Soo Jung, are you crying?
Don't cry.
What is this?
Jae Woong.
In a court, in front of brutal criminals
you show nerves of steel.
Why are you trembling like that now?
That was cute.
I'm getting married to Cha Jae Woong!
Hooray!
Jae Woong, I love you.
I love you.
You scared me!
Why are you still up drinking?
I didn't think you were back.
Did something happen?
Lisa...
is dead.
- What?
- Joo Da Hae...
killed Lisa.
Joo Da Hae...
Why would she kill Lisa?
She knew what would hurt me.
That's who she is.
Joo Da Hae...
I will never forgive her.
You are drunk now.
Stop drinking.
Joo Da Hae...
She killed a horse for that?
- I will see you when I get back.
- All right.
Be careful.
Jae Woong.
Drive carefully.
Don't worry.
I will be back soon.
Soo Jung, take care of him.
I will.
Father.
- Please go in.
- Alright.
Jae Woong.
Soo Jung, I can hear everything.
What do I do?
I'll go in. See you later.
- Hello?
- This is Yum Sam Do.
When are you coming?
How can you keep me waiting
when I found you your long-lost brother?
Yes, I'm on my way.
Hello? Da Hae, it's me.
I'm on my way to the prison.
Don't worry.
I will fix Ha Ryu once and for all.
Okay.
Please don't let him show up in front of me.
Alright. Bye.
Gosh, I forgot to buy tofu.
I will go get some.
It's okay. He can have
it when he gets home.
What are you talking about?
As soon as he's out, you have
to put the tofu in his mouth.
That's how it works.
I forgot my wallet.
- How much would it be?
- Ten thousand won will do.
- I will be right back.
- Sure.
Attorney Cha!
Sam Do!
Ha Ryu, your brother...
- Someone just kidnapped him.
- What?
Who took him?
Who?
We will talk in the car.
Get in the car, hurry!
You drive!
We have to find him before
something happens to him.
Start the car!
Hello? Officer Bang.
It's me, Yum Sam Do.
We can talk later.
I'm in a hurry.
Can you look up a license plate for me?
Who the hell are you
to threaten her?
After you killed my father,
you dare to threaten her?
What are you talking about?
Are you going to continue to play dumb?
You murderer!
Who the hell did I kill?
Ha Ryu!
You killed my father, you son of a bitch!
Ha Ryu.
Get up!
Hey!
Ha Ryu!
Wake up!
Wake up.
So, did you see Ha Ryu?
Did you talk some sense into him?
He...
Ha Ryu is dead.
What?
I said Ha Ryu died.
Let me see, it's 2334.
It's registered to the address near here.
Isn't that the car?
That's it.
Let's get out of the car first.
The car is registered to this night club.
Is he really dead?
I asked if he is really dead.
Are you crazy?
Why did he die?
How could you kill him?
You think I wanted to kill him?
It was just bad luck.
I was only trying to scare him off.
He died on me.
That's right. That's the guy
who took your brother.
- That son of a bitch!
- Hold on!
Ha Ryu paid for his crime.
He even threatened you.
Did anyone see it?
Where is the body?
I handled it.
We won't be caught.
I have to go.
Don't contact me for a while.
What would you do after
you attack him here?
Do you want to die too?
Calm down, Ha Ryu.
Brother!
Joo Da Hae...
That son of a bitch...
Ha Ryu is dead.
It's too late to go back.
Even if I stop here
I know that I won't be forgiven.
I'm sorry, Ha Ryu.
I'm sorry.
If we analyze what happened
Joo Da Hae asked him to murder you.
Joo Yang Hyun mistook your
brother for you and killed him.
Ha Ryu.
Let's call the police.
What's the matter?
They won't find a way out
with the evidence.
Joo Da Hae will find a way out.
Just like how she was able
to do so in the past.
She will find a way out again.
That woman killed my daughter
and my brother.
I will kill her with my own hands,
no matter what.
[Jae Woong, how come you're
not answering?]
[Your father might faint while he's
waiting for you and your brother.]
I don't know what's going on.
We got a text back from Jae Woong.
It would take three to four more days
to handle the matters with his brother.
You've been waiting all this time...
Can't you wait for three to four more days?
It's because I'm being anxious.
Please go inside.
I will go now.
Alright.
If there is anything, call right away.
Yes, I will do that.
Ha Ryu.
Ha Ryu, come over here.
I'm going to work on a scheme again.
- Sam Do.
- I know.
I told you I quit.
Please stick to your original plan.
You have to think about your
late daughter, So Young.
That's why I'm going to do
one last big one.
4974 Sam Do.
Before I grab you by the collar
and drag you to the police station
I want you to stop.
Ha Ryu.
As I take an x-ray scan
through this office...
I can see the whole picture right away.
Sam Do.
- What?
- Ha Ryu.
From this moment, you...
are not Ha Ryu, but
Attorney Cha Jae Woong.
What?
Ha Ryu died.
He's not alive anymore.
Ha Ryu was killed by Joo Da Hae.
That's right.
I'm my brother,
Attorney Cha Jae Woong.
That's right.
Acting like Attorney Cha Jae Woong
I'm going to follow the scheme
to send Joo Da Hae to hell.
Coming up with the scheme
will be done by Sam Do.
Bingo.
That will be the very last scheme of my life.
Sam Do.
I'd appreciate it, but I still
want you to go your way.
It will be dangerous.
There is no scheme that's not dangerous.
It won't be beneficial to you at all.
Just stick to your original plan.
Don't you want to ask me the reason
why I'm trying to do this with you?
My answer is simple.
It's just that I like you, man.
Plus, a scheme like this...
To my daughter
So Young, who is in heaven,
I won't be ashamed.
Who knows?
Your daughter, Eun Byul
and mine, So Young...
might be friends up there.
Sam Do.
We are going to proceed with the
scheme starting tomorrow.
Sam Do.
Sam Do, wake up.
Wake up.
Guys, when Director Joo buys us lunch
forget kimchi stew or soft tofu stew.
It's polite to choose something expensive.
Madam, can we have tuna sashimi?
Shall we?
Manager Yum, shall we go to
that place from last time?
Yes, Madam.
I will call that restaurant to let
them know that we are coming.
Okay.
Madam, aren't you coming?
Yes, go ahead.
Da Hae, what's the matter?
Yang Hyun, what happened to Ha Ryu?
Ha Ryu is alive.
What are you talking about?
He's dead.
That's not true.
He's alive.
I saw him with my own
eyes a few minutes ago.
Da Hae, pull it together.
He is dead.
How can a dead man be
walking around like that?
Are you saying I saw
a ghost or something?
I wish he was alive too.
I'm telling you that he's dead.
Come in.
Did you ask for me, ma'am?
- Have a seat.
- Yes.
Manager Yum.
Weren't your colleagues already
promoted to a higher position?
Among my colleagues
I'm at the lowest position, ma'am.
Manager Yum, you should
be promoted too.
Pardon?
I'm thinking about giving you some work.
Yes, ma'am. If there is any
work you want me to do...
I will offer whatever service I can.
About Director Joo
report her every move to me.
Can you do that?
Yes, ma'am.
I'm shaking now.
First project of the scheme.
Make Joo Da Hae sit in front of you.
Will she come to me willingly?
Well, she's coming to see
Attorney Cha, but...
She will definitely show
herself in front of you.
For that, we will need some actors.
We will start casting first.
About Baek Do Hoon's schedule
if you call the secretary's office for an
interview, they will tell you everything.
Tonight, Baek Do Hoon...
is scheduled to have a meeting
with an outdoor designer at a cafe.
I'm dying.
While he's waiting for the designer
the designer gets involved in a car
accident fraud and is stuck for three hours.
Obviously, the designer can't
find his cell phone.
Redirecting calls...
To keep Baek Do Hoon entertained
while he's waiting
we will send a female
con artist into the scene.
Excuse me.
Are you by any chance,
Director Baek Do Hoon?
Yes, I am.
Hello, I'm an employee at
Sae Han Design House.
I came to run an errand
for President Chung.
I see.
How come he's not coming?
He's not answering his cell.
Is everything okay?
He says he's very sorry.
He's running late, so...
he asked me to proceed with the meeting.
Okay.
What an honor!
You are the heir to Baek Hak Group.
Is it okay to take a picture
before the meeting?
No, thank you.
I'm not too comfortable...
Don't do that.
Please take one picture.
One, two, three!
When she takes a picture,
her work is done.
Excuse me.
About Baek Do Kyung
her favorite horse that she cared for
like her own child recently died.
She's been going to Montvert
riding club every day.
Hello.
Oh yes, hello.
It's been a while.
We have an announcement.
Attorney Cha Jae Woong, there is
someone to see you at the club house.
It sounds like there is someone to see me.
Excuse me then.
- Are you on your way to Seoul?
- Yes.
Is something wrong with the car?
I got two flat tires at once.
There must have been something
sharp on the road.
I only have one spare tire.
I may need to call someone.
- There is a garage further down.
- Is there?
I'm sorry, but do you mind taking me there?
Of course.
Thank you.
Hold on please.
Excuse me.
I have dirt all over my hands.
I don't want to make your seat dirty.
It's okay.
Didn't you have a horse named Lisa?
I haven't seen her.
Has she gone to a different
ranch for relaxation?
She recently died.
What? Died?
How did that happen?
She was such a good horse.
That's too bad.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have asked that
when it must be still hard for you.
It's okay.
- You are a lawyer?
- Yes.
While I was working at the riding club
I was studying for the bar.
I got lucky and passed the bar.
You must have worked hard.
I'm really sorry about Lisa.
Thank you for saying that.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
When Director Baek Do Kyung gets
back to the office from the riding club
the female con artist from
last night pays her a visit.
Ma'am, there is someone who wants to
see you regarding Director Baek Do Hoon.
Regarding Do Hoon?
Who is it?
How do you do?
Are you Baek Do Hoon's older sister?
Yes, and?
Why don't you sit first?
The female con artist will insist
that Baek Do Hoon assaulted her.
When she sees the picture
she will go insane.
It's so embarrassing that she
cannot say anything to anybody.
How come Director Baek Do
Kyung isn't calling me?
4573, how many instant
noodles did you put in?
Are you sure you dropped
your wallet in her car?
I'm positive.
I put it on the seat when I was getting out.
Are you really going to eat it all?
Why don't you make one for yourself?
You put a name card with the
phone number in your wallet, right?
I put a lot of them in there.
Let me have one bite.
No way!
I would let you have one of my kidneys,
but I can't let you have my food.
Why isn't she calling yet?
What if she took it to the police?
Don't you dare touch my noodles.
I'm not kidding.
Am I interrupting your lunch?
No, that's okay.
Have a seat here.
You surprised me.
What brings you here?
You left this in my car last time.
Oh, did I?
I thought I dropped it while
changing the tire on the road.
Thank you.
I'm okay, so please continue.
It's okay. I'm finished.
But...
you came all the way to drop this off?
I had to take one name card for
your address out of your wallet.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't mention it.
I wanted to give back your wallet, and...
I thought I would consult you about a case.
Bring a case?
- A case?
- Yes.
Would it be okay if I asked you on the case?
Go ahead.
What is the case about?
It's about my younger brother.
He might have done something shameful.
I want this to be kept confidential.
Is it possible?
We have a duty to protect
our client's privacy.
Go ahead.
The female con artist is saying
to Baek Do Hoon that...
she will reveal the fact he assaulted
her on the Internet and press.
Baek Do Hoon is in a state of panic.
Hello, Attorney Cha.
How did it go?
Of course, it is resolved well.
Why? The female con artist is on our side.
Is that true, Attorney Cha?
It was completely resolved?
Thank you very much, Attorney Cha.
Don't mention it.
I didn't do much.
What do you mean?
You have no idea what I went through.
Although I didn't do anything
I felt like I did something wrong
to my girlfriend.
I was afraid that my girlfriend
would find out.
Are you afraid of your
girlfriend or something?
Yes, very afraid.
Attorney Cha, let me take
you out to dinner.
Let's go.
It's my treat.
Wait, shall I have my girlfriend join us?
Do you want to see how scary she can be?
To dinner?
Ha Ryu.
It's time for Joo Da Hae to
show up in front of you.
Da Hae, here.
- She's here.
- Okay.
Say hi.
This is Attorney Cha Jae Woong.
How do you do?
Nice to meet you.
Subtitles by DramaFever