Prof. Yoshiyama...
Here's the research data you asked for.
Thank you.
Don't forget the conference at 14:00.
Immersing yourself in
your own research is fine...
but don't be late this time.
TIM E TRAVELLER
- The Girl Who Leapt Through Time -
Here's one from 1972.
Why do you collect coins
from so long ago?
I'm not sure myself.
"1972"
Original novel by Yasutaka Tsutsui
"The Girl Who Leapt Through Time"
"Shotoku Univ. Entrance Exam
Results for 2010"
No way!
Here it is.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
"Department of Pharmacy"
Directed by Masaaki Taniguchi
Miracle happens!
Congratulations!
Congratulations on passing the exam.
Thanks.
We always celebrate here.
Yeah.
This boat feels smaller each time.
I wonder when we'll come next.
Mom ...
What kind of person was Dad?
Why ask now?
I was just wondering.
I barely remember him
so I'm curious.
He's different.
He's back in Japan
shooting movies again.
He's in the mountains right now.
You keep in touch?
He emails me sometimes.
Why didn't you tell me?
You never asked.
That's why?
For you, ducky.
"Misonou High: Archery Club"
"Today is the seniors'
last day of practice"
I knew it.
Your form was cool though.
Shut up.
Just take them home
a little by little.
I'm glad you're here.
Thanks from me too.
Well, it's nice being
around young people.
You know that song?
Of course. Takuro Yoshida is my idol.
He's a strange kid.
- What's this song?
- "It was Spring"
Correct.
Our voices disappeared...
It was spring...
My throat hurts.
Too much singing.
You're such a big help.
Mom always says it's great
to have you around.
She says that?
She says that.
Is she still busy?
She's a workaholic.
I hope she doesn't get sick.
Thank you for helping.
See ya.
Goro!
Sorry to bother you.
You have something for me?
A photo of you.
Of me?
Remember my neighbor
Granny Fukamachi? It's from her.
She found it in her attic.
She doesn't know why it was there...
but wants you to have it.
Was this guy in our class though?
She grows them
in her greenhouse.
She knows you like lavender.
Saturday. Science lab.
Yoshiyama...
I have to go.
Sorry to keep you.
Sorry.
Yoshiyama.
Fukamachi...
Hello.
My name's Yoshiyama.
The daughter?
Yes.
She has no serious external injuries...
and they'll heal completely
in two weeks.
But she hit her head hard
and is still unconscious.
We don't know when
she'll come around.
Talk to her as much as you can.
I'll be back later.
Mom ...
Wake up!
You haven't slept.
You should lie down.
No.
You have to stay strong for
your mom when she wakes up.
Today, let's travel back
in time to Mar. 3, 1974.
The Noshiro night bus accident.
The bus, full of passengers,
departed Shinjuku
on the night of Mar. 2.
It traveled northbound
on Route 4 until...
36 years ago
I was supposed to be on this bus.
It fell off a cliff killing
38 people onboard...
I was going on a ski trip.
But I forgot my bus ticket at home.
"A Night Bus Accident
Kills All Passengers"
A friend of mine...
died in this accident.
But...
I'm alive.
It was fate.
Fate is on your mom's side.
So she'll wake up.
I'm sure of it.
Thanks.
"Birth of Akari Hasegawa"
"Masamichi Hasegawa"
"I'll be filming in the
mountains for 4 months."
"This is Akari. Mom had an accident...
and is in the hospital."
"If..."
Mom ...
It's...
my birthday today.
I'm 18.
Sort of...
sounds grown-up, huh?
Mom?
Mom!
Akari...
It's me.
I have to go.
No! Lie still.
What?
To see him.
Kazuo Fukamachi.
Kazuo Fukamachi?
The photo and key...
in my bag.
Bag?
The photo...
This?
I have to go.
No, Mom!
I'll go, okay?
I'll go.
Where is he?
Saturday, April 1972.
The junior high science lab.
1972?
The key to my desk...
There's a liquid...
It'll take you to the past.
Drink it and wish hard.
Tell him that...
Okay.
I'll go tell him.
So you have to...
Mom ... Wake up!
"Showa Era 47"
That's 1972.
Saturday, April 1972.
Science lab.
What am I doing?
This is crazy.
Was it...
February 1974?
Saturday, February 1974.
Science lab.
What the heck?
She came falling.
Out of thin air.
I'm sorry.
Who are you?
I'm Ryota and
this is my apartment.
Remember yesterday?
Yesterday...
Kazuo Fukamachi?!
You're...
Not.
Is this the Setagaya
Jr. High science lab?
Shotoku University.
Oh, no!
I couldn't just leave you there.
So I brought you here.
What's today's date?
Sunday, Feb. 17, 1974.
1974...
February 1974.
April 1972.
I'm 2 years too late.
Your bag!
Where's Setagaya Jr. High?
Uh, the station's that way.
I'm completely lost.
Come with me.
"Setagaya Junior High School"
Excuse me... I'm looking for someone.
This guy.
That's Kazuko Yoshiyama
next to him, isn't it?
That's right.
But I'm looking for the guy.
I've never seen him.
Stop loafing around and go home.
Fresh off the grill.
Thank you.
It really is February 1974.
What's your name?
Akari Yoshiyama.
Your home?
Go home when you finish eating.
Your parents must be worried.
You ran away, right?
I ...
came from 2010.
I came from the future
to meet someone.
You hit your head hard.
I'm serious. I appeared
out of nowhere, didn't I?
Yeah, but...
Okay, proof.
My wallet.
A 500-yen coin and...
What's this era?
This is technology of 2010.
A small radio?
A mobile.
Mobile?
It's mainly a phone.
No signals, of course.
It's also...
a camera. Cool, huh?
A multiple communication device.
I use this in my SF movie.
You can transmit and record
messages from anywhere.
My invention, right in my hands...
It hit the spot.
So you believe me?
You're an SF geek, right?
Geek?
You.
Ryota, let me stay with you.
"Ryota"? ... No way.
I'll clean, wash, and cook.
I won't get in the way, so please.
Wait.
I have to do this.
Give a message to Kazuo...
and go back to my mom.
If I find him ...
and give him the message.
she might wake up again.
So, please.
Help me find him.
I'm sorry.
Come in.
What are you doing?
See.
What's up?
You tell us.
- Hello. - Hello.
She's cute.
Your type, huh?
No...
I'm his cousin Akari.
Yeah... my cousin.
She's here visiting colleges.
Great! Do you have a boyfriend?
He's Kadoi. I'm Natsuko.
We're in Ryota's movie.
We're just across the hall.
Come if you want.
Natsuko...
I think...
Here.
Natsuko Ichise.
"The actress most likely
to hold a grudge"
That's her.
He should be in high school.
Which one though...?
Is there a famous director
called Ryota Mizorogi?
I don't know about movies.
His address?
I don't know.
Using a red towel as a scarf.
What's that?
A hit song, "Kanda River".
Let's walk from the bathhouse.
I want a bath.
There isn't one.
No bath?
Then let's go to the bathhouse.
No bathing for another 2 days.
You don't bathe everyday?
That's a waste.
Plus, it's winter.
The season matters?
Use the communal sink.
In the hallway?
Forget it.
Sleep under the kotatsu.
It's heated.
Sorry.
"Setagaya Junior High School"
We're clear.
Class 3C...
Here it is.
Kazuko Yoshiyama...
Here.
Your mom?
Yeah.
Where's Kazuo Fukamachi?
He's not here.
Let me see.
Nope.
But look.
They're both wearing 3C class badges.
Weird...
He's not a ghost, is he?
I have an idea.
Let's go ask my mom.
Here's her address.
Hello.
Is anyone there?
Uncle Goro?!
Uncle?
So you're Kazuko's cousin.
Yeah...
You're the big brother.
Yes...
You don't look alike.
You surprised me when
you called me "uncle."
Sorry.
Kazuko always talks about you
so I feel like I know you.
She talks about me?!
It seems like nobody's
home right now.
They moved to Yokohama.
When?
When she entered high school.
You didn't know?
We haven't been in touch.
Oh yeah...
Do you know him?
Never seen him but
he's wearing our uniform.
Oh...
What's Kazuko's school and address?
I have them at home.
I'll be off work tonight
so call me.
Asakura Liquor Shop.
Dial "D-R-I-N-K-U-P."
See ya.
"Drink up"?
We have some time.
Can I take you somewhere?
"Moving Picture Club"
What is it?
A flying car of the future
in year 2011.
Start.
The Planet of Light.
The earth began spinning off its axis,
losing its field of gravity.
Fundamental changes occurred
in the earth's crust.
The artist, Hiro, painted a cherry tree
with 100 buds on the wall.
When these buds blossom,
help will arrive.
They waited, believing it was so.
And...
"Bathhouse"
I go this way.
I'll transform myself
into a girl of the 70s.
Feels wonderful...
Paradise...
Right there.
Feels great.
Hey.
It felt so good.
You took too long.
I'm all warmed up.
I'm cold.
How do I look?
Beautimus, don't you think?
Beautimus?
What language is that?
Beautimus.
It's totally 70s!
Just like that song.
What?
You were staring at me.
No, I wasn't.
Let's go. It's cold.
It's too hard to pick her out.
But she's here for sure.
Let's find her.
Your mom?
Excuse me...
I'm looking for someone.
A guy named Kazuo Fukamachi.
Kazuo Fukamachi?
Your classmate in junior high.
That's me?
You know him, right?
No. I'm sorry.
I don't remember taking this photo either.
But... you're in it with him.
Same class badge...
I'm sorry.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Maybe you'll remember something.
Goodbye.
Your mom doesn't even
know him. We're stumped.
He really might be a ghost.
Absolutely not.
She made the liquid to
come see him herself.
You're right.
Can we go visit someone?
Gotetsu... It's Ryota.
Oh, you were here.
Hi.
Does everybody do this?
Your girlfriend?
No. My cousin Akari.
Hello.
Akari... "Light"... Nice name.
Light is essential to good shots.
Please get dressed.
This is Gotetsu, the cameraman.
Gotetsu?
His nickname for staying up
five straight nights gambling.
Hey there.
Well drawn.
Good, huh?
You okay?
Don't you get it?
My dick won't get hard
with a drawing like this.
Make it hard.
It'll get hard.
Gimme a hard-on.
Shit! My camera!
Get a rag.
Wipe it.
Ryota...
Do you remember anything?
I'm sorry I can't help you.
Is there something between
me and him in the photo?
Rather a lot...
So, why a school in Yokohama?
I want to go into pharmacy studies,
and this school has
a strong science course.
When did you decide that?
At the end of junior high.
I suddenly felt compelled
to study pharmacy.
From way back then...
There's something else
I want to ask you.
This was at a friend's house.
Hasegawa took this.
He's my friend's tutor.
Do you know him?
Hasegawa?
Masamichi Hasegawa.
Gotetsu... That's what
everybody calls him.
"Masamichi Hasegawa"
What're you doing here?
What's your family like?
My family?
Mom, Dad, and a little sister.
Dad runs a printing factory in Akita.
He's not making you
take over the business?
I'm sure he wants me to.
But he's letting you live your own life.
A good father does.
What about you?
My family?
I ...
What?
Well...
I barely remember my dad.
When I was small...
he left me and my mom.
Mom took good care of me...
and I never knew him anyway...
so I never felt lonely.
But still, I always imagined...
what having a dad would be like.
That was a stupid story.
Can I have one?
Sure.
41 ,200 yen.
"Ways to look for Fukamachi"
How should we spend it?
How about this?
He might see it.
"Personal Ads"
It'll stay printed
in the future too.
Maybe he's also from the future.
What if he doesn't exist now?
That could be.
That couldn't be.
No way.
But you're here.
"Yomiuri Newspaper"
Please, we only have 40,000 yen.
It's 50,000 yen per frame.
That's our rate.
But you see, it's an emergency.
Her future depends on it.
Yes... my future.
My future?
In a sense.
We beg you.
Please.
All right. 40,000 then.
Don't tell anyone else.
Thank you!
Don't say it loud.
Looks good.
Mix and eat.
Yum.
Noodles...
Tomi, are you all right?
I'm scared shitless.
Just don't drop the equipment.
You're weightless, remember?
Like you're floating on air.
I think... you should move slower.
How many should I take?
What roll is it?
Five.
Let's do it.
Camera rolling.
Ready... Action!
Ryota...
Thanks.
I'll take this.
You're not his cousin.
How do you know?
I can tell.
When we finish this movie,
I'm going to the US.
To study photography.
Look after him while I'm gone.
Do you have to go?
What if she asks you not to go?
She'll never say that.
But what if?
She'd tell me to go.
She's strong-minded.
She won't stop me.
She'll force me to go.
Gotetsu, come here!
Let's move the camera
instead of zooming in.
Which cut?
Cut 1.
I have to get out there and
connect the transmitter.
Are you serious?
It's better than just
waiting here to die.
Are we going to die?
Cut!
Haru...
Goodbye.
Cut!
OK!
Are we wrapping up?
We're finished!
Good job!
Kazuko...
If...
Gotetsu is going faraway,
what would you do?
Another strange question.
You mean, to the US.
Or other places.
I'll wish him luck.
I want him to do what he wants.
But I'm not as strong as I sound.
You like him.
Where are you going?
To return the equipment.
Can I go with you?
Yeah, if you want.
Then I will.
70s men are so complicated.
The ad will be run tomorrow.
I hope he shows.
They're waiting for you
in the future, right?
Yeah.
This song...
Takuro.
It's from this decade, huh.
Why did you let me stay?
Just because...
I suppose nobody would reject...
a pretty girl like me.
Ryota...
You're gonna be a famous director...
and marry a beautiful actress...
and have cute kids.
But...
At that time...
I'll be...
a person of the past.
Weird.
'Cuz I'm from the future.
I gotta go out.
Ryota...
Gotetsu.
I need a favor.
What happened?
Can I borrow your camera?
The last scene...
What?
I want to shoot it myself.
Say yes.
You owe me one.
Thanks.
Here.
"Awaiting Kazuo Fukamachi
Mar. 2 in the science lab"
I'm playing the part?
Ready.
Action.
These cherry blossoms
36 years from now...
They're still blooming.
Nothing changes here.
When it's your time...
Wouldn't it be nice if
we could view them together?
Yes.
You sure? I'll be 56.
Dig that.
What?
It means "I accept."
You dig... accept.
Yeah, "dig"...
Ken, look at this.
"Awaiting Kazuo Fukamachi
Mar. 2 in the science lab"
This is...
Yes.
Hold on.
Ryota, it's from your mother.
Hello.
Hi.
Did you go to the photoshop?
The film's being developed?
I'm really excited so
I was just wondering...
Ryota?
My dad collapsed.
A stroke.
He overworked himself.
Business wasn't that great
when I left home...
but the factory nearly went
bankrupt because of the oil shock.
He struggled to rebuild the business.
I knew that, but I didn't go back.
I pretended not to notice.
I deserted my family.
Don't blame yourself for your father.
He wanted you to live your own life.
I was playing around making a movie.
I was selfish.
You don't have to rush.
Give it time.
You can complete your film.
It's not like the future.
Are you the one?
Are you...
Kazuo Fukamachi?
Who are you?
Akari.
Akari Yoshiyama.
Kazuko's daughter.
Kazuko Yoshiyama.
Who made the time-leap liquid?
My mother.
She did?
Yes, to see you.
But...
she was in an accident.
She's in the hospital.
So I came instead.
Her condition?
I see.
The plan was...
to leap to April 1972.
But I made a mistake.
So, why?
You're not in high school?
I came from 2698.
2698?!
I received information that
someone from 2010...
leapt through time
looking for Kazuo Fukamachi.
To confirm that, I traced
you through time-space.
What information?
My old name was in the newspaper.
My real name is Ken Sogoru.
Ken Sogoru...
So the ad reached...
2698, huh...
Sogoru.
What a name.
Oh, this...
I failed to erase this...
What's her message?
"I remember the promise."
What did you promise my mom?
I came here in 1972...
with the time-leap liquid
we were testing.
I misplaced the dose
for the return.
So I became Fukamachi
for the time being.
That's when I met her.
She accidentally inhaled the fumes...
and became able to leap
short spans of time.
The scent was lavender.
Then I fell in love with her.
But I had to return to the future
and erase her memory of me.
Will you come see me again?
Yes.
Only I won't be Kazuo Fukamachi,
but someone else.
But I will come visit the future you.
My memory might disappear but
my heart will remember the promise.
You accomplished your mission.
You must go back now.
My mission is...
to erase everyone's memory
that you were here.
Wait.
There's someone I have to see.
After I see him,
I'll go back to the future.
Fine. I'll wait until tonight.
"I'm waiting for you in
the science lab - Akari"
I gave it to him.
My mother's message.
I wish I met him too.
You'd be surprised.
He was so different.
More so, then.
I'm going back...
to Akita on tonight's bus.
I'll call you tomorrow when I arrive.
Tomorrow...
It's my birthday.
I just remembered.
Seriously?
I want you to keep this.
What is it?
The film, but with no sound.
I'll be back soon.
This movie...
I'll complete it.
When I come back...
let's watch it together.
It'll be your birthday present.
When you come back...
I won't be here.
Thank you.
The film ...
Don't lose it.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Akari?
Unc... Goro.
What are you carrying?
Ski things, but I forgot
my bus ticket at home.
It leaves in 20 minutes.
From where?
Shinjuku.
Where's your house?
Futako.
You'll never make it.
I was so looking forward to it.
Where were you going?
Noshiro in Akita.
Akita...
I'm going back...
to Akita on tonight's bus.
The Noshiro night bus accident.
The bus was traveling
northbound on Route 4...
when it fell off a cliff...
killing 38 people onboard.
I was supposed to be on this bus.
I'll call you tomorrow when I arrive.
I'll be back soon.
Is something wrong?
Ryota...
Where are you going?!
Excuse me.
Where's the bus to Akita?
Over there.
"For Akita"
Ticket, please!
Ryota!
You have to get off.
Isn't this the bus to Akita?
Yes, but that one goes to Noshiro.
"Noshiro"
Ryota!
Let me go!
You mustn't change the past.
Then I'm not going back to the future!
I'm going to stay.
Ryota!
Wait!
Let me go!
It's cruel but it's history.
Stop the time.
Ryota!
I'm sorry...
I'm erasing your memory.
Today, let's travel back
in time to Mar. 3, 1974.
The Noshiro night bus accident.
You got the message.
Yes.
You came as Kazuo Fukamachi.
Thank you.
She's a lot like you.
We'll meet again...
in the future.
Mom ...
Mom.
My mother woke up.
It's me, Mom!
Akari...
We'll take an M RI but
I'm sure she'll be fine.
Thank you.
Akari.
I smell a familiar scent.
Familiar scent?
This?
It's lavender.
Who brought it?
It smells nice.
"The Planet of Light"
Hello.
This is Hasegawa.
Akari?
Yeah.
How's your mom?
She's gonna be fine.
Good.
Can I ask you something?
Doing good?
You watch 8mm, huh?
Who's the director?
The title?
"The Planet of Light."
What's the matter?
I guess it's a common title.
The same title of one
I shot with an old friend.
This is the projector, right?
Can you carry it?
Yeah. My friend's in the car.
Okay.
See ya.
Thanks.
You really know how to use that?
I got it.
Lights off.
Ready?
"The Planet of Light"
What is this?
"Don't paint the last cherry blossom"
"Directed by Ryota Mizorogi"
That was too bizarre.
Why are you crying?
I don't know.
Why am I?
This was inside.
"For you viewing the cherry
blossoms of the future"