The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies
Subtitles by:Salman, Shayan & Sahar.
I warned you.
Did I not warn you what would come of dealing with dwarves.
Now they've done it.
They've woken the dragon.
They've brought an apocalypse upon our heads.
Come on. Quickly!Quickly!
Faster now. I'm trying to evacuate myself here.
Careful men.
- Never mind the books.Get on!Get in the boats.
But Sire, should we not try to save the town.
- The town is lost, save the gold.
Come on. Let's go.
Pile 'em up.
We have no time.
We must leave.
Get him up.
- Come on. Let's go!
It's fine. I can walk.
- So as you can. We're not leaving.
Not without our father.
You stay here, your sisters will die.
Is that what your father would want?
Open this door.
Do you hear me?
Down here. Go!
- Give me your hand.
Come on, we're good to go.
- Quickly now.
Hurry!
- Kili, come on.
Keep on going.
Dragon.
Come on.
Come on, Faster!
If only we could take more people with us to bear...
...But they're hardly worth it.I agree.
Oh!Ow!
Look out.
Move it. Move it!
Come on. Faster!
My gold. My gold!
We can't. It's too much weight.
We need to dump something.
Quiet right, Alfrid.
Faster.
Poor souls.
Da. Da!
He hit it. He hit the dragon.
- No.
He did. He hit its mark, I saw.
These arrows can not peirce its hide.
I fear nothing will.
What are you doing?
Bain?
Leave him.
We can not go back.
Bain.
Da.
Bain, what are you doing?
Why didn't you leave? You were supposed to leave.
I'm here to help you.
- No.
No, nothing can stop him now.
- This might.
Bain, you go back.
You get out of here now.
Da.
Bain.
- Da.
Stop, stop, halt, halt!!!
Who are you,
that would stand against me?
Oh, that is a pity.
What will you do now, bowman?
You are foresaken.
No help will come.
On my mark.
Go! Go!
Head for the open water.
Is that your child?
You can not save him from the fire.
He will burn.
Stay still, son.
Stay still.
Tell me.
Wretch, how now do you challenge me?
You have nothing.
But your death.
Bain, look at me. Look at me.
A little to your left.
That's it.
Bain. Hold on.
What was that?
What happened?
- It fell, I saw it.
He's dead.
Smaug is dead.
Why my beard, I think he's right.
Look there.
The ravens of Erebor are returning to the mountain.
Aye, word will spread.
Before long, every soul in middle earth will know,
the dragon is dead.
The Battle of Five Armies
You are not alone.
Mithrandir.
Ilealidon
Intulitun
Somebody help me.
Help.
- I'm right Here.
Da, Da!
Why me?
Tauriel.
Kili, come on.
We're leaving.
They are your people.
You must go.
Come with me.
I know how I feel, I'm not afraid.
You make me feel alive.
I can't.
- Tauriel.
I would feel honored.
I don't know what that means.
I think you do.
My lord Legolas.
Take your leave of the dwarf.
You are needed elsewhere.
Keep it.
As a promise.
These are dry. You need them.
- Thank you.
Give me one.
I'll be caught by death in this cold.
Find your own.
You have no charge now, Alfrid.
That is where you are wrong.
In the absence of the master
the power goes over to his deputy...
which in this instance is my goodself.
Now give me that blanket.
Master's Deputy.
Don't make me laugh.
You're a creep, I would rather die
before I answered the likes of you.
I think that can be arranged.
You wouldn't go turning on your own, Alfrid.
Not now.
Da.
- Come here.
You're alive.
- Its fine.
It was Bard, he killed the dragon.
I saw him with me own eyes.
He brought the beast down.
Shot him dead with a black arrow.
He saved us.
All hail to the dragon slayer.
All hail King Bard.
I have said many times.
This is a man of noble stock.
A born leader.
- Do not call me that.
I am not the master of this town.
Where is he?
Where's the master?
- Halfway down the lake
- With all our coin.
I don't doubt.
You know.
You helped him to empty the treasury.
- No, I tried to stop him.
I begged him.
- I pleaded.
I said, master, no.
Think of the children.
Would nobody think of the children?
Enough.
Let him go.
Look around you.
Have you not had your fill of death?
Winter is upon us.
We must look to our own.
To the sick and the helpless.
Those who can stand,
tend the wounded.
And those who have strength left, follow me.
We must salvage what we can.
And what then
- What do we do then?
We find shelter.
Hello?
Bombur?
Bifur?
Anybody?
Wait, wait.
It is Bilbo.
- He is alive.
Stop, stop, stop.
We all need to leave.
- We only just got here.
I tried talking to him,
but he won't listen.
What do you mean laddie?
- Thorin.
Thorin, Thorin
- He's been down there for days.
He barely eats.
He's not been himself at all.
It's this place.
I think a sickness lies on him.
Sickness? What kind of sickness?
Fili.
Gold.
Gold beyond measure.
Beyond sorrow and grief.
Behold, the great treasure hoard of Thror.
Welcome, my sister's sons.
To the kingdom of Erebor.
Balin.
Any sign of it?
- Nothing yet.
Nothing here.
- Keep searching.
That jewel could be anywhere.
The Arkenstone is in these halls.
Find it.
Keep looking.
- All of you.
No one rests until it is found.
I am almost tempted to let you take it
If only to see Oakenshield suffer
Watch it destroy him .
Watch it corrupt his heart
And drive him mad
Take only what you need.
We have a long march ahead.
- Where will you go?
There is only one place.
The Mountain.
You are a genius, Sire.
We can seek refuge inside the mountain.
It must smell a bit of dragon.
Women can clean that up.
It'll be safe, warm and dry.
Full of stores.
Bedding and clothing.
And a bit of gold.
What gold is in that mountain is cursed.
We will take only what was promised to us.
Only what we need to rebuild our lives .
Here, pull your weight.
News of the death of Smaug
will spread through the lands.
Aye.
Others will now look to the mountain.
For its wealth
- For its position.
What is it you know?
- Nothing for certain.
It's what I fear may come.
Woodland Elves.
The king's son and the she-elf,
They tracked us to Lake-town.
And you killed them?
They fled and squealing like cowards.
You fool! They will return
with an army of elves at their backs!
Ride to Gundabad.
Let the Legions come forth.
Elves.
Men.
Dwarves.
The mountain will be their tomb.
To war.
You saw something out there?
The Orc I persued near Lake town,
I know who he is.
Bolg, spawn of Azog the Defiler.
A warg pack was waiting for him in the outskirts of Esgaroth.
They fled into the north.
These Orcs were different from the others.
They wore a mark that I have not seen for a long time.
The mark of Gundabad.
- Gundabad?
An Orc stronghold in the far north
of the Misty Mountains.
My lord Legolas.
I bring word from your father.
You are to return to him immediately.
Come, Tauriel.
My lord, Tauriel is banished.
Banished?
You may tell my father,
if there is no place for Tauriel,
there is no place for me.
Legolas.
This is your King's command.
- Yes, he is my king...
but he does not command my heart.
I ride north.
Will you come with me?
To where?
- To Gundabad.
Spells will not save you, old man.
This is my master's domain...
Die now, Wizard.
Three rings for the elven-kings
under the sky.
Seven for the dwarf-lords in their halls of stone
.
Nine for mortal men who are doomed to die.
You can not fight the shadow.
Even now you fade.
One light alone in the darkness.
I am not alone.
Are you in need of assistance, my Lady?
You should have stayed dead.
Mithrandir.
Come back.
He is here.
Yes, the darkness has returned.
Gandalf, climb on.
He is weak, he can not remain here.
It is draining his life.
Go, quickly.
Come with me, my Lady.
Go.
It has begun.
The East will fall.
So shall the kingdom of Angmar rise.
The time of the elves is over.
The Age of the Orc has come.
You have no power here.
Servant of Mordor.
You are nameless.
Faceless.
Shapeless.
Go back to the void.
From whence you came.
We were deceived.
The spirit of Sauron endured.
And has been banished.
He will flee into the east.
Gondor should be warned.
Set a watch on the walls of Mordor.
No, look after the Lady Galadriel.
She has spent much of her power.
Her strength is fading.
Take her to Lothlórien.
My lord Saruman,
he must be hunted down and destroyed once and for all.
Without the ring of power.
Sauron can never hold dominion over Middle-earth.
Go now and leave Sauron to me.
I need a horse.
- What?
Gandalf, where are you going?
To warn Erebor,
they've no idea of what is coming.
I saw them with my own eyes.
Rank upon rank of Moria orcs.
You must summon our friends,
bird and beast...
the battle for the mountain is about to begin.
It is here in these halls, I know it.
- We have searched and searched.
Not well enough.
- Thorin, we all want to see the stone returned.
And yet it's still not found.
Do you doubt the loyalty of anyone here?
The Arkenstone is the birthright of our people.
It is the King's jewel.
Am I not the king?
Know this.
If anyone should find it
and withold it from me...
I will be avenged.
Dragon sickness.
I've seen it before.
That look, the terrible need...
is a fierce and jealous love, Bilbo.
It sent his grandfather mad.
Thorin,
- if Thorin had the Arkenstone.
What if it is found.
Would it help?
That stone crowns all.
It is the summit of this great wealth.
The stone,
- bestowing power upon he who held...
But withstay his madness
No, laddie.
I fear that would make it worse.
Perhaps it is best,
if it remains lost.
What is that?
In your hand?
- It's... It's nothing.
Show me.
It...
I picked it up in Beorn's garden.
You've carried it all this way.
I'm going to plant it in my garden.
In Bag-end.
Its a poor price to take back to the Shire.
One day it'll grow
and every time I look at it I'll remember.
I'll remember everything that happened, the good, the bad
and how lucky I am that I made it home.
Thorin.
Thorin, survivors, from Lake-town.
They're streaming into Dale.
There's hundreds of them .
Call everyone to the gate.
To the gate, now.
Come on, keep moving.
Sire, Sire, up here.
Look Sire, the braziers(torches) are lit.
So, the company of Thorin Oakenshield survived.
Survived?
You mean there's a bunch of dwarves in there
with all that gold?
you shouldn't worry, Alfrid.
- There's gold enough in that mountain for all.
Make camp here tonight.
Find what shelter you can.
Get some fires going.
Alfrid, you take the night watch.
This fortress must be safe by sunrise.
This mountain was ours once,
I will not see it be taken again.
The people of Lake-town have nothing.
They came to us in need.
They have lost everything.
Do not tell me what they have lost.
I know well enough their hardships.
Those who have less than dragon fire,
should rejoice.
They have much to be grateful for.
More stone.
More stone to the gate.
These children are starving.
We need food.
We won't last three days.
Bard, we don't have enough.
- Do what you can, Percy.
We need more water.
The children, the wounded and women come first.
Yeah.
Morning, Alfrid.
What news from the night watch?
A little quiet Sire,
nothing to report.
Nothing gets past me.
Except an army of elves
That would seem.
My lord Thranduil.
We did not look to see you here.
- I heard you needed aid.
Here.
You have saved us.
I do not know how to thank you.
- Your gratitude is misplaced.
I did not come on your behalf.
I came to reclaim something of mine.
There are gems in the mountain that I too desire.
White gems,
of pure starlight
White gems of Esgaroth.
I know an Elf lord who would pay
a pretty price for these.
Wait.
Please wait.
You would go to war for a handful of gems?
The heirlooms of my people are not likely foresaken.
We are allies in this.
My people also have a claim upn the riches in that mountain.
Let me speak with Thorin.
You would try to reason with a dwarf?
- To avoid war, yes.
Nice work.
Come on.
Hail Thorin, son of Thrain.
We are glad to find you alive beyond hope.
Why do you come to the gates of
king under the mountain armed for war?
Why does the king under the mountain
fence himself in?
Like a robber in his hole.
Perhaps it is because I am
expecting to be robbed.
My lord.
We have not come to rob you.
But to seek fair settlement.
Will you not speak with me?
I 'm listening.
On behalf of the people of Lake-town,
I ask that you honour your pledge.
A share of the treasure,
so they might rebuild their lives.
I will not treat with any man,
While an armed host lies before my door.
That armed host will attack this mountain,
if we do not come to terms.
Your threats do not sway me.
What of your conscience?
Does it not tell you our cause is just?
My people offered you help.
And in return you brought upon them only ruin and death.
When did the men of Lake-town come to our aid
before the promise of rich reward?
A bargain was struck.
- A bargain?
What choice do we have but to barter our birthright
for blankets and food?
To ransom our future
in exchange for our freedom.
You call that a fair trade?
Tell me, Bard the dragon slayer.
Why should I honor such terms?
Because you gave us your word.
Does that mean nothing?
Be gone, let the arrows fly.
What are you doing?
You can not go to war.
This does not concern you.
Excuse me, but in case you haven't noticed
there is an army of elves out there.
Not to mention several hundred angry fishermen.
We are in fact outnumbered.
Not for much longer.
What does that mean?
That means, master Baggins...
You should never underestimate dwarves.
We have reclaimed Erebor.
Now we defend it.
He will give us nothing.
Such a pity.
But still, you tried.
I do not understand.
Why, why would he risk war?
It is fruitless to reason with them.
They understand only one thing.
We attack at dawn.
Support us you?
Master Baggins, come here.
You are going need this.
Put it on.
This vest is made of silver steel.
Mithril.
It was called by my forebearers.
No blade can pierce it.
I look absurd.
I'm not a warrior, I'm a hobbit.
It is a gift.
A token of our friendship.
True friends are hard to come by.
I have been blind.
But now I am able to see.
I am betrayed.
- Betrayed?
The Arkenstone.
One of them has taken it.
One of them is false.
Thorin.
The quest is fulfilled.
You've won the mountain. Is that not enough?
Betrayed by my own kin.
No, you made a promise to the people of Lake-town.
Is this treasure truly worth more than your honor?
Our honor. Thorin, I was also there,
I gave my word.
For that I am grateful.
It was nobly done. But the treasure of the mountain
does not belong to the people of Lake-town.
This gold...
is ours.
And ours alone.
All my life,
I will not...
...part with a single coin.
Not one piece of it.
Gundabad.
What lies beyond?
- An old enemy.
The ancient kingdom of Angmar.
This fortress was once its stronghold.
It is where they kept their great armouries.
Forged their weapons of war.
Light, I saw movement.
We wait for the cover of night.
It is a fell place, Tauriel.
In another age,
our people waged war on those lands.
My mother died there.
My father does not speak of it.
There is no grave.
No memory.
Nothing.
Let me through.
Make way.
No, no, oye, You.
Pointy hat.
Yes, you.
We don't want no drunks, beggars, no vagabonds
around here.
We've got enough trouble without the likes of you.
Off you go. On your ****
- Who's incharge here?
Who's asking?
You must set aside your petty grievances
with the dwarves.
War is coming.
The segments of Dol Guldur have been emptied.
You're all in mortal danger.
What are you talking about?
I can see you know nothing of wizards.
They are like winter thunder on a wild wind
rolling in from a distance
breaking hard in a long...
But sometimes, a storm is just a storm.
Not this time.
Armies of orcs are on the move.
These are fighters, they have been bred for war.
Our enemy has summoned his full strength.
Why show his hand now?
- Because we forced him.
We forced him when the company of
Thorin Oakenshield set out to reclaim their homeland.
The dwarves were never meant to reach Erebor.
Azog the Defiler was sent to kill them.
His master seeks control of the mountain.
Not just for the treasure within.
But for where it lies,
its strategic position.
This is the gateway to reclaiming the lands of Angmar
in the north.
If that fell kingdom should rise again...
Rivendell, Lorien, The Shire,
even Gondor itself will fall.
These orc armies you speak of, Mithrandir.
Where are they?
Our army will be in position by dawn.
The attack will be sudden and swift.
The fools.
They have forgotten what lives beneath these lands.
They have forgotten the great Earth-eaters.
If we are going in
-we should move now.
They are swarming.
These bats are bred for one  purpose.
- For what?
For war.
We must warn the others.
- We may be too late. Hurry!
Since when has my counsel counted for so little?
What do you think I am trying to do?
I think you're trying to save your Dwarvish friends.
And I admire your loyalty to them.
But it does not disuade me from my course.
You started this, Mithrandir.
You will forgive me if I finish it.
Are the archers in position?
- Yes, my lord.
Give the order.
If anything moves on that mountain, kill it.
The dwarves are out of time.
You, Bowman, did you agree with this?
Is gold so important to you?
Would you buy it with the blood of dwarves?
It will not come to that. This is a fight they can not win.
- That won't stop them.
You think, the dwarves will surrender...
They won't, they will fight to the death to defend their own.
Bilbo Baggins.
If I'm not mistaken...
This is the halfling who stole the keys
to my dungeons from under the noses of my guards.
Yes. Sorry about that.
I came... to give you this.
The heart of the mountain.
The king's jewel.
And worth a King's ransom.
How is this yours to give?
- I took it as my 14th share of the treasure.
Why would you do this? Where is your loyalty?
- I'm not doing it for you.
I know that dwarves can be obstinate...
And ***headed and difficult
suspicious and secretive...
with the worst manners you can possibly imagine.
But they are also brave and kind...
and loyal to a fault.
I have grown very fond of them
and I would save them if I can.
But Thorin values this stone
above all else.
In exchange for its return,
I believe he will give you what you are owed.
There will be no need for war.
Rest up tonight.
You must leave on the morrow.
Get as far away from here as possible.
- I'm not leaving.
You picked me as the 14th man.
I am not about to leave the company now.
There is no company. Not any more.
I don't like to think what Thorin would do,
if he finds out what you have done.
I'm not afraid of Thorin.
- But you should be.
Don't underestimate the evil of gold.
Gold of which a serpent has long brooded.
Dragon sickness
seeps into the hearts of all who come to this mountain.
Almost all.
You there, find this hobbit a bed.
And fill his bed with hot food.
He's earned it.
Keep an eye on him.
If he should try to leave, you tell me.
Move it.
Wakey Wakey, Hobbit up you...get.
I will put the next one
in between your eyes.
We have come to tell you...
Payment of your debt
has been offered and accepted.
What payment? I gave you nothing.
- You have nothing.
We have this.
They have the Arkenstone.
Thieves. How can you buy the heirloom of our house?
That stone belongs to the king.
The king may have it.
With our goodwill...
But first, he must honor his word.
They are taking us for fools. It is a ruse.
A filthy lie.
The Arkenstone is in this mountain.
It is a trick.
Its no trick. The stone is real.
I gave it to them.
You...
I took it as my 14th share.
You'd steal from me.
Steal from you? No. I may be a burglar, but
I'd like to think I'm an honest one.
I am willing to let it stand against my claim.
Against your claim?
Your claim.
You have no claim over me,
you miserable ***.
I was going to give it to you.
Many times I wanted to but,
- But what thief?
You are changed, Thorin.
The dwarf I met in Bag-end would
never have gone back on his word...
would never have doubted the loyalty of his kin.
Do not speak to me of loyalty...
Throw him from the rampart.
Did you not hear me?
I will do it myself.
I curse you.
Cursed be the wizard who put you in this company.
You give back my burglar, but please don't damage him.
Return him to me.
You're not making a very splendid figure
as king under the mountain, are you ...
Thorin, son of Thrain.
Never again will I have dealings with wizards...
Go.
- ... Or Shire ****.
Are we resolved?
The return of the Arkenstone for what was promised.
Give us your answer.
Will you have peace or war?
I will have war.
Iron Front.
Stand by.
Who is that? He doesn't look very happy.
This is Dain, Lord of the Iron Hills.
Thorin's cousin.
Are they alike?
- I've always found Thorin the more reasonable of the two.
Good morning. How are we all?
I have a wee proposition,if you wouldn't mind
giving me a few moments of your time?
Would you consider...
Just starting off?
All of you, right now.
- Stand fast.
Come now, lord Dain.
- Gandalf the Grey.
Tell this rabble to leave,
or I'll water the ground with their blood.
There is no need for war between
dwarves, men and elves.
A legion of Orcs march on the mountain.
Stand your army down.
I will not stand down before any elf.
Not least this faithless woodland *****.
He wishes nothing but ill upon my people.
If he chooses to stand between me and my kin...
I'll split his pretty head open.
See if he's still smirking ****.
He's clearly mad, like his cousin.
- You hear that lads?
Come on.
Let's give these ******** a good hammering.
Come on, children of Durin.
Prepare.
- Ready.
Were-Worms.
Oh! Come on.
Come forth my armies!
The hordes of hell are upon us.
Fight, Sons of Durin.
I'm going over the wall. Who's coming with me?
Come on.
- Stand down.
Are we to do nothing?
- I said, "Stand down."
The Elves,
will they not fight?
Thranduil, this is madness.
Ready!
Charge.
Hit me and you're dead.
Gandalf, is this a good place to stand?
Send in the war beasts .
Ready to attack.
They cannot fight on two fronts...
Now we make our move.
Attack the city.
Attack.
Azog.
He is trying to cut us off.
Everyone, fall back to Dale.
To the city. Bilbo, this way.
My children. Where are my children?
I saw them,
they were down in the old market.
The Market? Where are they now?
Tilda. Sigrid.
- Bard, the Orcs are storming over the causeway.
Get the bowmen to the Eastern parapet.
Hold them off for as long as you can.
Archers, this way.
The Orcs have taken stone street.
The market's over-run.
The rest of you, follow me.
Charge. Onwards, until they're dead.
Da, Da. Right Here.
We're down here.
Bain, Sigrid, get down.
Listen, I need you to gather the women and children.
Take them to the Great Hall and
barricade the door. You understand?
You must not come out for any reason.
- I want to stay with you.
Show your father some respect.
You leave it to me, Sire.
You heard him, we make to the Great Hall.
Alfrid, women and children only,
I need every man fighting. See that you return.
I'll get them to safety, Sire.
My sword is yours to command.
Get Up.
Look after them.
- I will.
Shift it, granny.
Make for the Great Hall.
Out of my way, we make for the Great Hall.
They cannot hold the city.
The dwarves are almost spent.
You *******.
Where's Thorin?
We need him. Where is he?
Let these lands run with blood!
Slaughter them all.
Fall back.
Since when do we forsake our own people?
Thorin, they are dying out there.
There are holes beneath holes
within this mountain.
Places we can fortify.
Shore up, make safe.
Yes!Yes!That is it.
We must move the gold further underground
for safety.
Did you not hear me. Daine is surrounded.
They're being slaughtered, Thorin.
Many die in war.
Life is cheap.
But a treasure such as this
can not be counted in lives lost.
It is worth all the blood, that we spend.
You sit here in these vast halls
with a crown upon your head.
And yet you are lesser now than you will ever be.
Do not speak to me...
as if I were some lonely dwarf lord.
As if I were still...
Thorin Oakenshield.
I am your king.
- You were always my king.
I used to know that once, but...
you cannot see what you have become.
Go.
Get out.
Before I kill you.
You sit here with a crown upon your head...
You're lesser now than you were ever be...
A treasure such as this
can not be counted in lives lost
A sickness lies upon that treasure.
- Blind ambition of a mountain king
Am I not a king.?
- It is ours
Only from us
I will not part... With a single coin...
He cannot see beyond his own desire
- I'm not some lonely dwarf lord...Thorin Oakenshield
Look at yourself.
- The same disease as your grandfather
Oakenshield
- This is Thorin...
son of Thrain, son of Thror...
- I'm not like my grandfather
You are the heir to the throne of Durin..
- They are dying out there
Take back Erebor..
- Daine is surrounded
Surrounded...
- Take back your homeland...
You are changed, Thorin.
- I'm not my grandfather
Is this treasure truly worth more than your honor.?
This treasure will be your death...
Fall back,
fall back to the mountain..fall back.
Now comes their end.
Prepare for the final assault.
I will not hide behind a wall of stone
while others fight our battles for us.
It is not in my blood, Thorin.
No, that is not.
We are sons of Durin.
And Durin's folk do not flee from a fight.
I have no right to ask this of any of you...
but will you follow me one last time?
Get ready.
Not yet. Wait...wait...
attack...now!
To the king...To the king.
To the towers.
The dwarves... They're rallying.
Rallying to their king.
Any man who wants to give his life, follow me.
I say we stand with our men
in life and in death. Arm yourselves.
Come with us.
- No,no, leave an old woman...
Do not be afraid.
- I say, "Let them."
Alfrid lickspittle, you're a coward.
- Coward?
Not every man's brave enough to wear a corset.
- You're not a man, you're a weasel.
Dain!
- Thorin! hold on, I'm coming.
Hey, cousin,
why did it take so long?
There are too many of these buggers, Thorin.
Hope you got a plan.
Aye!
We go to take off their leader.
I'm going to kill that piece of filth.
- Come on.
We may yet survive this.
- Gandalf.
It's Thorin.
Fili, Kili, and Dwalin.
He's taking his best warriors.
To do what?
- To cut the head of the snake.
Gandalf.
- Legolas.
There's a second army.
Bolg leads this force of Gundabad Orcs, they're almost upon us.
Gundabad? This was their plan all along.
Azog engages our forces and Bolg sweeps in from the north.
...The North?... And where is the North exactly?
- Ravenhill.
Ravenhill? But Thorin is up there, and Fili and Kili,
They're all up there.
Where is he?
Looks empty. I think Azog fled.
I don't think so.
Fili, take your brother.
Scou all the towers.
Keep low and out of sight. If you see something,
report back. Do not engage, do you understand?
We have company, goblin mercenaries.
Not more than a hundred.
- We'll take care of them. Go. Go.
Fili. Come.
Recall your company.
My lord, dispatch this force to Ravenhill.
The dwarves are about to be overrun.
Thorin must be warned.
- By all means warn him.
I've spent much blood in the defence
of this accursed land.No more.
Thranduil?
I'll go.
- Don't br meticulous.
You would never make it.
- Why not?
Because they would see you coming and kill you.
- No they won't.
They won't see me.
- It's out of the question.
I wouldn't allow it.
I am not asking you to allow it, Gandalf.
You will go no further.
You will not turn away.
Not this time.
- Get out of my way.
The dwarfs will be slaughtered.
- Yes, they will die.
Today, tomorrow...
Only hence a hundred years from now.
What does it matter?
They are mortals.
You think your life is worth more than theirs...
while there is no love in it.
There is no love in you.
What do you know of love? Nothing.
What you feel for that dwarf, is not real.
You think it is love?
Are you ready to die for it?
If you harm her, you will have to kill me.
I will go with you.
Get up.
- Get away from me.
I don't take orders from you.
The people trusted you, they listen to you.
Master's mantle was there for the taking.
And you threw it all away. For what?
Alfrid, your slip is showing.
Stay here, search the lower levels.
I've got this.
Where is that Orc filth?
Thorin!Bilbo!
- You have to leave here now. Azog has
another army attacking from the north.
This watchtower will be completely surrounded,
there'll be no way out.
We are so close, that Orc scum is in there.
I say we go show him...
No, that's what he wants.
He wants to draw us in.
This is a trap.
Find Fili and Kili, call them back.
Thorin, are you sure about this?
- Do it.
We will get to fight another day.
This one dies first.
Then the brother.
Then you, Oakenshield.
You will die last.
- Go.
Run.
Here ends your filthy bloodline.
Slay them all.
Go in for the kill.
Finish him.
The Eagles are coming.
Bilbo!
- Don't move. Lie still.
I'm glad you're here.
I wish to part from you in friendship.
You're not going anywhere, Thorin.
You're going to live.
I want to take back my words,
of what I said at the gate.
You did what only a true friend would do.
Forgive me.
I was too blind to see.
I am so sorry.
For I have led you to such peril.
I'm glad to sharing with you the experience, Thorin.
Each and everyone of them.
It's far more than any baggins deserves.
Farewell, Master Burglar.
Go back to your books.
And your armchair.
If you plant your trees, watch them grow.
If more people...
valued help above gold...
...this world would be a merrier place.
No, Thorin. Don't you dare.
Thorin, hang on.
Eagles are here.
I can not go back.
Where will you go?
I do not know.
Go north,
find the Dúnadain.
There is a young ranger amongst them. Meet him.
His father, Arathorn, was a good man.
His son might grow to be a greater one.
What is his name?
- He's known in the wild as Strider.
His true name you must discover for yourself.
Legolas!
Your mother loved you.
More than anything. More than life.
I want to bury him.
If this is love, I do not want it.
Take it from me, please.
Why does it hurt so much?
Because it was real.
There's to be a great feast tonight.
Songs will be sung, tales will be told...
And Thorin Oakenshield will pass into legend.
Balin, I know you sound that you must honour him.
But for me it was never that-
He was... Until he...
He was...
I think, I will slip quietly. You tell the
others, I said Goodbye. You can tell them yourself.
If any of you are ever passing Bag-end...
Tea is at four.
There's plenty of it.
You are welcome any time.
Don't bother knocking.
The Borders of the Shire.
T'is here I must leave you.
That's a shame.
I quite like having a wizard
around.
Seems they bring good luck.
You don't really suppose, do you that all your
adventures and escapes were managed by meer luck.
Magic rings should not be used lightly, Bilbo.
Don't take me for a fool.
I know you've found one in the goblin tunnels.
And I've kept my eye on you ever since.
Well, thank goodness.
Farewell, Gandalf.
Farewell.
You needn't worry about that ring.
It fell out of my pocket during the battle.
I lost it.
You're a very fine person, Mr. Baggins.
I'm very fond of you.
But you're only quite a little fellow,
in a wide world afterall.
That's my mother's closet.
And that's my dining chair...
Put that poof down. What is going on?
Hello, Mr. Bilbo? You're not supposed to be here.
What do you mean?
- I mean, you're kind of presumed dead and all.
I'm not dead.
Presumed otherwise.
I am not sure that's permitted.
Mr. Bilbo!
21, who offers it 21?
AUCTION SALE PROPERTY MR Bilbo Baggins
- Sold to Mrs. Walker. Fine for the feet.
And here I am beautiful...
- Stop.
There has been a mistake.
- Who are you?
Why? You know very well who I am,
Lobelia Sackville-Baggins.
This is my home,
and those are my spoons, thank you very much.
Highly illegal. There are
thirteen months passed since your disappearance.
If you are infact Bilbo Baggins and undeceased,
can you prove it? What?
Something official with your name on it will be sufficient.
- Right.
A contract of employment as a...
Never mind.
There, my signature.
Seems to be in order.
Seems there can be no doubt.
Who is this person you
placed your service to? Thorin Oakenshield?
He was my friend.
No, thank you.
We don't want anymore visitors,
well-wishers or distant relations.
And what about very old friends
Gandalf. Bilbo Baggins.
- Good to see you
113 years old.. Who could believe it?
Enter