Movie And Subtitles Encoded By Nexus Wolf
Negative. No sign.
Wait a second.
I think I got him.
You know,
You could put somebody's
eye out with that thing.
We airlifted out the
last passengers, ace.
We're heading out.
What about
the animal cargo?
It's just one
little raccoon.
If I were you,
I'd turn back.
Yeah?
Well, if you were me,
then I'd be you,
And I'd uyour    body
to get to the top.
You can't stop me,
no matter who you are.
Hoo hoo hoo!
Loser.
Lo-ser.
[cheep cheep cheep]
Hungry, fella?
[burping]
That ought to hold you
for a while.
[chattering]
That's ok, spike.
There's nothing more
we can do.
Look, spike.
[screeching]
Do not fret,
my little woodland friend,
For your life
is in the hands
Of ace ventura...
Pet detective.
[screeching]
Whatever you do...
Don't look down.
[squeaking]
Hang on!
Hang on,
little buddy!
I got you.
I think I got you.
Uh, maybe not.
You're slipping.
[screech]
Don't let go!
No!
Oh.
My goodness.
Ah!
Well, hello. Yes.
Well, now, that was
quite a shock.
It's, um...
It's extremely nice
to meet you.
Now, my name
is fulton greenwall,
And I am looking
for an ace ventura.
No man here
Carries with him
a label.
What?
Oh, yes. No names.
How silly of me.
Well, um,
he's an american.
We are all
children
Of the same
life force.
Yes, of course
we are.
Well, he bends over,
And he speaks
from his rear.
Oh, him.
Right this way.
He came to us
a broken man.
He had lost the will
to sustain his existence.
I heard about that
unfortunate accident
With the raccoon.
It was terrible
for him,
But the life force
once again smiled upon him.
He's now at peace.
[sheep bleating]
I will wait here.
[growl]
Aah!
Oh! Oh!
I must apologize.
Quite. Well, um,
ah, no harm done.
Let me
introduce myself.
My name is
fulton greenwall.
I'm sent here to
employ your services
In the retrieval
of a lost animal.
Can you help us?
Your request is not unlike
your lower intestine--
Stinky and loaded
with danger.
We can pay you
handsomely.
I am now
a child of light.
Your earthly money
holds no appeal to me.
$20,000.
Re-e-e-e-e-ally?
No.
I cannot,
for I am sorely needed
Here...
At the ashram.
If I may interject!
We are short of space,
And it's important
for you
To use your talents.
Let me help you pack.
But I am yet
to attain
Omnipresent
supergalactic oneness.
No.
Wait.
There it is.
You have just
attained it.
I have?
Yes. Just now.
You are one.
I can see it
in your eyes.
You're more one
than anyone.
What about
my medallion
Of spiritual
accomplishment?
Take mine.
This took you
80 years to achieve.
That's ok.
I don't like it
anymore. Really.
In the light of this
personal sacrifice
You've made...
I have no choice...
But to take
the case.
Great! I'll go
tell the others!
Master...
Break it to them
gently.
[cork pops]
Ha ha ha!
[cheering]
I've never seen them
Act like that
before.
Denial can be
an ugly thing.
Well, we should go,
mr. Ventura.
I've arranged a plane.
I'll meet you
at the bottom.
There's still
one more thing
I must do
before I go.
Isn't this incredible?
It's going to be
some kind of a record.
¶ everyone
loves a slinky ¶
¶ you got to
get a slinky ¶
¶ slinky, slinky ¶
¶ go, slinky, go! ¶
Oh, man!
Can you believe it?
It was right there!
Can I do it
one more time?
Please forgive me,
but if we don't hurry,
We might
miss the plane.
Of course.
How selfish of me.
Let's do
all the things
That you want to do.
[ace moaning]
Canadian moose
During
mating season.
And now...
A yak.
[moaning]
Peanuts?
Yes. I have one
right here.
It's bulky,
But I consider it
carry-on.
Peanuts.
Oh, I see.
Ha ha ha!
If we can get back
to business, mr. Ventura?
The wachati are
a peaceful tribe.
Since their sacred animal
has vanished,
They believe that
there is a curse
Fallen
on their village.
It all started
some time ago...
So the daughter
of the wachati chief
Is set to wed
the first son
Of the wachootoo tribe,
And the sacred animal
was offered as dowry
For the marriage.
But if it
is not recovered,
The result will be
The merciless slaughter
of the wachatis.
Uh, mr. Ventura?
Mr. Ventura!
[imitating
william shatner]
There's someone
on the wing--
Some...Thing.
[normal voice]
I'm sorry.
What were you
saying?
The daughter
of the wachati chief
Is set to wed
the first son
Of the wachootoo tribe.
[singing in native language]
Spectacular.
This land holds
great beauty.
How far
to the crime scene?
Well, I've been
instructed
To bring you first
to the consulate,
Which should be
beyond those trees
On the other side
of the jungle.
We'll have to
circle around...
Ha ha ha!
Oh, no!
Steering's
a little loose.
Ah!
Alignment's off,
too.
Mr. Ventura!
Aah!
¶ oh, you pretty
chitty bang bang ¶
¶ chitty chitty
bang bang, we love you ¶
¶ and our pretty
chitty bang bang ¶
¶ chitty chitty
bang bang loves us, too ¶
¶ hi ho ¶
¶ everywhere we go ¶
¶ on chitty chitty
we depend ¶
¶ bang bang chitty
chitty bang bang ¶
¶ our fine,
four-fendered friend ¶
¶ bang bang chitty
chitty bang bang ¶
¶ our fine,
four-fendered ¶
¶ chitty bang bang ¶
¶ chitty chitty
bang bang ¶
¶ chitty bang bang,
yeah! ¶
¶ chitty ¶
Oh, there's
the consulate.
Oh, thank god.
If I can just find
a parking spot.
Perhaps we should
slow down
Just a teensy-weensy
bit.
Nonsense,
poopy pants.
We're going
a bit fast!
Ha ha ha!
Really! Look out!
Like a glove.
You might want
to think
About getting
this baby detailed.
Oh, no.
The consul general's car.
[man]
down, boba.
That's it. Down.
[trumpets]
Yes. Good.
[nicker]
[ace]
come on, man.
[horse grunts]
Whoa.
Mr. Ventura,
So looking forward
to your arrival.
Uh!
Funny. It didn't
seem that painful
When you were doing it
to the horse.
Ha ha! Uh, sir,
mr. Ventura
Has an affinity
for animals.
Shall we?
Shalln't we?
Tell me,
mr. Ventura,
Just how good
are you?
You're an extreme
workaholic.
You recently returned
from a short trip to gotan.
Upon your return,
you more than likely
Took a nasty spill
because of some...
Shoddy masonry work.
Very impressive.
Might one ask how?
Surely.
[inhales]
The abrasion on the palm
of your left hand
Is sustained breaking
a 3- to 5-foot fall.
The small plaster
on the tip of your shoe
Pointed to a careless mason
being the culprit.
Your new watch,
a forgery of a cartier,
Was purchased through
the north african black market,
Known to reside
in gotan.
[inhales]
And my work habits?
Yes. A workaholic.
The urine stain
on your pants
Would signify
that you're
A single-shake man,
Far too busy
for the follow-up jiggle.
Brilliant,
mr. Ventura.
Simply brilliant.
[ace]
spank you, greenwall.
Spank you
very much.
Mr. Ventura,
we've been coexisting
Quite nicely
with the native cultures
For the past
200 years.
They're almost
like family.
Are they?
It is imperative
That we recover
the sacred animal.
If not, the
peaceable wachatis
Will assuredly
be obliterated.
The wachootoos
are bloodthirsty.
They consider
its disappearance
Both an insult
and a curse.
[babbling]
Do I have something
in my teeth?
[man]
ah, cadby!
Lovely brunch,
I must say.
Quinn.
I'd like you
to meet
Ace ventura.
This is burton quinn.
He owns and operates
quinnland safari park.
Most call me quinn.
Say hello, tinky.
Pleasure, tinky.
Corvus corax.
Common raven.
The smartest of all birds.
Rare these parts.
[gasp]
Excuse me.
That's quite a wrap
you're wearing.
Perhaps
I could get you
Some fluffy
new slippers
Made from the heads
of innocent
And defenseless
baby seals.
Who is
this ghastly man?
Ace ventura,
pet detective.
And...You must be
The monopoly guy.
Hey...
Thanks for
the free parking.
Another activist,
maguire.
Activist. Yes.
Ha ha ha!
Mr. Ventura,
There's
nothing wrong
With enjoying
The fruits
of nature.
You should
try it sometime.
Alrighty, then.
You know something?
You're right.
[inhales]
¶ la da da ¶
¶ da da da da ¶
¶ la da da da ¶
¶ da ¶
¶ da da da da
da da da da da da ¶
¶ da da ¶
¶ mm-hmm mmm hey ¶
[gasps]
¶ la da ¶
Do not pass go.
Do not collect $200.
[woman]
oh!
Oh!
It's lovely,
But I fancy myself
an autumn.
[murmuring]
If you've quite finished,
mr. Ventura,
We might make
for the projection room,
Greenwall.
Kooky.
Mr. Ventura,
I'd like you
to meet hitu,
Chief of tribal security
in the province.
Please!
Don't...Get up.
At this point,
We don't have
any leads,
But we've had
similar problems
In the past.
Oh.
Sorry.
[imitates gunshot]
[cadby]
this is derrick mccane.
Spotted several times
in the province
In the past year,
Mr. Mccane makes
a handsome living
From rare
and endangered species.
Hitu.
[cadby] now, these two
are australians.
The bald one
is mick katie.
The other is said
to have been raised
By aborigine...
Aborigines.
The natives call him--
[ace snarling]
Call him gahjii
the hunter.
[ace snarling]
Both are known poachers.
And have been seen
in the area!
Mr. Ventura!
This wedding ceremony
will take place
In four days.
I cannot have
bloodshed in my province!
We're counting on you!
[ace]
ewooh! Ewooh!
Honk honk!
Honk honk honk honk!
Hi ho, silver! Away!
I've assigned greenwall
to assist you.
Before you go,
mr. Ventura,
There's something
I'd like to show you--
Something
you might enjoy--
As one animal lover
to another.
Errr...
Aah!
[ace laughing
maniacally]
Something wrong,
mr. Ventura?
Ah ah ah ah
ah ah ah ah!
[inhales]
Of course not.
This is a lovely
room of death.
Take care, now.
Bye-bye, then.
[trumpets]
Down, boba.
Oh! Oh!
Aah!
Mr. Ventura,
how could you?
Oh!
Ch-ch. Pick. Pow!
Now, mr. Ventura,
I think the village
Is roughly
about a mile ahead.
Excellent.
Flat tire.
Ha ha ha!
I think this joke
has run its course,
Don't you?
Certainly.
I prostrate
myself before you
And beg
your forgiveness.
Don't get me wrong.
I do enjoy the
occasional prank.
My heel is getting
rather raw.
We love you,
dark continent!
Good night!
[animal growling]
Listen.
The majestic song of the
male silverback gorilla.
I think we should
move along.
It's their
mating season,
And they can get
rather hostile.
¶ dee dee dee dee dee dee
dee dee dee dee ¶
¶ dee, owimoweh ¶
¶ owimoweh, owimoweh,
owimoweh, owimoweh ¶
¶ owimoweh, owimoweh... ¶
Oh. Oh, excuse me,
mr. Ventura.
I have to rest.
Of course you do.
The wachatis believe
They draw
their power
From these caves,
But they now
live in fear
Since the vanishing
of their sacred bat.
Bat?
What...Bat?
The one we're here
to find,
Mr. Ventura.
You didn't say anything
about a bat.
What's
the difference?
What's the difference?
Have you ever seen a bat?
They're hideous.
Lifeless, beady eyes,
clawed feet,
Huge, grotesque
wings, even fangs.
[shrieking]
They give you
rabies, you know.
Yes. Quite.
I see your point.
But are you saying that
you won't take the case?
No. As a being
of light,
I must
show compassion
For all the living
things of nature.
Good.
I'm not
touching it, though.
No, spank you.
[singing in native language]
[greenwall] the wachati
are a peaceful people.
They find all forms
of life sacred.
I like them already.
Bumbawae atuna.
Hi there.
Nice to see you.
Bumble bee tuna.
Ooh!
Ace ventura,
pet detective.
How are you
this afternoon?
Alrighty, then.
Excuse me.
Your balls
are showing.
Bumble bee tuna.
[greenwall] they've lived
in the same state
For thousands
of years.
They did not know
about disease
Until
the white man came.
[ah-choo]
[ace]
ahh.
[sniffle]
What's going on
over here?
Oh, yes.
Now, all young
wachati warriors
Must face five days
of balance and concentration.
[greenwall] should he
lose his focus and fall,
He must start
all over again.
Earthquake test.
He's good.
With my help,
he could be the best.
Maybe we should
see the chief,
Mr. Ventura.
This way.
Neato!
[speaking
native language]
The chief says
he knew you would come.
Libby libby wa!
Chim chiminy
chim chim cher-oo!
Hey!
[arf]
The chief says he has not
understood your dialect.
Tell him I'm happy
to meet him
And that
his sacred...
Bat is as good
as found.
[speaking
native language]
Oh, my goodness.
The chief really
seems to like you.
That is a great sign
of affection
In the wachati tribe.
Re-e-e-e-e-ally?
Oh, this is
the chief's son, ouda.
The missionaries
came through
And taught him
some english.
I like you.
[ptooey]
Ha ha ha!
My...
Aren't I
the popular one?
Allow me to display
affection.
[snorting]
[laughter]
It is the mucus
that binds us.
Ha ha ha!
A bubo obe.
The chief says
That the sacred hut
is over there.
How did they
get past the guard?
[greenwall]
uh, well, I'm afraid
He was found shortly
after...Sleeping.
At ease, soldier.
We all make
mistakes.
Quite an auspicious
dwelling
For a filthy
flying weasel.
Alla shikaka!
[greenwall]
please, mr. Ventura.
That is sacred ground.
I'm sorry.
But only the wachati
are allowed to step there.
Hey...
Take it easy.
I'm the loogie guy,
remember?
[speaking
native language]
Y-yes, yes, chief.
Thank you.
Dalu.
The chief says unless
the sacred bat is returned
Before the marriage
of the princess,
The entire wachati tribe
will meet their death.
What type of bat
Are we talking
about here?
The great white bat,
of course.
Corpus
kilochiroptera?
Yes,
but to the natives...
Shikaka.
[gasp]
Shikaka?
Shikaka!
Ha ha ha!
Shikasha!
Ahh!
Shh...
Shish kebab.
Shawshank redemption.
Chicago!
You're...
Out of there!
Go on. You're gone.
Go on!
[drums playing]
[wachatis chanting]
[grunting]
Were you going to
eat these?
Ha ha ha ha!
Ace.
Oh.
I've got to
inspect that cage.
Mmm!
My, my, my.
This fruit paste
is delicious...
And the pottery
is lovely.
It's made
from guano.
Guano?
That sounds
so familiar.
Bat droppings.
[gagging]
Guano is the wachatis'
chief resource.
They use it to make
many things in the village.
Yummy.
[greenwall] oh, now,
this is really fascinating.
This is a great wachati
tradition--
The virgin's dance
of seduction.
[ace]
I am now a holy man.
I think of women
Only as the mothers
of our children.
They are a sanctuary
for the reproductive organs,
A temple to house
the miracle of procreation.
Do you have a dollar?
[music speeds up]
Oh! Ha ha!
Thank you so much.
I've not danced
in years.
Hi.
Don't mind me.
Sleep.
[yawning]
Fee...Fi...
Fo...Fum!
I smell...
The fingerprints
of scum!
Better dust the place.
Totally clean.
Not one damn clue.
Unless...
[thunk]
Here she comes.
Oh, boy.
Holy, holy, holy,
holy.
Good thoughts in,
bad thoughts out.
Good, bad, good,
bad, good, good--
You have come
to help us.
We are
in great appreciation.
You...
Speak english.
Yes. Ha ha!
The missionaries,
they come with books.
Ah.
Oh. Ha ha ha!
You are very good
with that. Ha ha!
It's incredibly
accurate.
Care to try?
Not bad.
Try again.
Relax
your shoulders...
Breathe...
And release.
Mmgh!
There you go.
You make me smile.
And yet...
I am troubled.
You see...
The man my father
wants me to marry--
I am worried
I will not please him.
I...
I've never known a man.
I would love
to help,
But you see,
I have vowed
To take a life
of celibacy.
Well...
Perhaps this will assist
your decision.
Those are very nice,
But I'm a child
of light--
A pure spirit.
I am no longer
encumbered
By the appetites
of the flesh.
Oh.
[ace]
oh, mamma.
Oh, mamma.
Oh, mamma. Ooh, mamma.
Ooh, mamma.
I'm so sorry,
mr. Ventura--
Aah!
I...
[panting]
That's ok.
I was just...
Practicing
my mantra.
Oh, uh, yes.
I thought you wanted
to visit the sacred caves.
I do. Could you
meet me outside
In 10 minutes?
Mm-hmm.
If I don't finish
my meditation...
I tend to get
a little cranky.
Take care, now.
Bye-bye, then.
Bye-bye.
Well, everything here
seems good!
Big load off my mind.
Oh, god, you can speculate
all you want,
But unless you check it out
for yourself,
You never know.
We should
head back now.
Don't you think
You should
investigate?
There's no reason to go
in there...Ever.
I sense it
as a holy man.
But I thought
you said--
[ace]
it's dark!
I could fall
into a precipice.
Here. Take this.
Spank you,
helpy helperton.
Hah!
I'm not afraid.
I am not afraid.
[grunting]
I really like it here.
Hmm!
[screech]
My medallion.
I will fear
no living creature
As long as I keep this
near me.
[screech]
Take that,
you winged spawn of satan!
[medallion hits rock]
Oh!
Urgh...
That's ok.
All I really need
is my torch.
[screech]
Die, devil bird!
Aah!
[torch hits rock]
I'm ok.
[screech]
Aah!
[grunting]
They're in my hair!
Agh! Oh!
Oh, god in heaven,
help me!
Ace.
There is nothing
in your hair.
Exactly.
I was merely running
a drill.
Just as I suspected.
Quinn.
What?
We met him
at cadby's soiree.
His bird is a raven
named tinky.
I found that
inside the cave.
Ace, now, you don't
understand.
Burton quinn is
a very powerful man.
Worry not,
my brother...
For I...
Am a master...
Of disguises.
[caw]
[screeching]
¶ there's a man who leads
a life of danger ¶
¶ to everyone he meets,
he stays a stranger ¶
¶ oh, with every move he makes,
another chance he takes ¶
¶ odds are he won't live
to see tomorrow ¶
¶ secret agent man,
secret agent man ¶
¶ they've given you a number
and taken away your name ¶
Eat up, guys.
None of this animal
goes to waste.
[chomp]
¶ be careful
what you say ¶
¶ or you'll give yourself away ¶
¶ odds are you won't live
to see tomorrow ¶
¶ secret agent man,
secret agent man ¶
¶ they've given you a number
and taken away your name ¶
Ah, mr. Mccane.
How are you doing?
I'm--I'm--I'm doing well,
thank you.
[whirring]
[grunt]
Don't mind me,
mr. Quinn.
I'm just
a curious little rhino.
I appreciate
your...
Agreeing
to undertake this.
[whirring and beeping]
Meeting secretly
with sinister types much?
Ah, not too much,
amuch    too much.
[fan stops]
[circuitry
sizzles]
[sighing]
I'll pay your fee--
The sum
we've agreed upon.
Kind of hot
in these rhinos.
Uh...
Warm!
I had a dog,
And his name
was...Bingo!
Oh, time to get
some oxygen.
Oh, no.
Come on!
[snap]
[grunting]
Aah!
Mayday!
[hissing]
Must...Have...
Air!
[groaning]
[cars approaching]
Come on, girls.
Quiet, quiet, quiet, quiet.
Look. Take a look.
[ace groaning]
[woman]
oh, look.
The mother rhino
is giving birth.
Oh, god...
Mommy!
Cool!
Oh, we have to
get out of here!
Get in the jeep!
Quick, girls! Get in!
Welcome
to quinnland.
[roar]
And you, too,
my friend.
Ha ha ha!
Ah, yes. Ah, yes.
I know you'll be
happy here.
[growl]
Huh!
Ah!
Well, how did you
get out, little fella?
Ha ha ha!
You're a cute little
devil, aren't you?
What's that
you got there?
[screeching]
Aah!
[groaning]
[ace]
where's the bat?
What is this about?
Who are you?
[german accent]
where is the bat?
I know who you are.
I met you
at cadby's!
You're that...
Ventura fella!
Last chance!
Where is that darn bat?
What are you
going to do?
Whatever I have to
to get some answers.
[quinn gasping]
[scraping]
Aah! Oh!
Aah! Oh! Ooh!
Stop that!
Stop it! Stop that!
You'd like me
to stop that,
Wouldn't you, hmm?
Getting to you, hmm?
I'll never tell you
anything.
[stops scraping]
Ooh...
A tough guy, huh?
I know what to do
with tough guys.
Wheee!
Ugh!
Eww...
No!
My brother used to
do that to me!
Oh, you're sadistic!
Stop it! Stop it!
All right,
I'll talk!
Spill it!
I paid
derrick mccane
To find the bat.
[groan]
I thought it could
be an attraction.
Business has been
a bit off lately.
So...
You don't know
who...
Took the bat?
Neither does
mccane!
Ok.
I'm going to
untie you now...
But before I do,
I want you to know
That I'm really,
truly very...
Sorry!
Ugh!
Appreciate
the lift!
We'll walk
from here.
Shikaka!
Ok, quinn is
out of the picture.
We have no more
suspects or clues,
But I have
instincts, spike,
And my instincts tell me
we're getting closer.
I can feel it.
I can feel it
like it's right...
In my neck!
Run!
[whimpering]
Aah!
It's starting
to get numb!
[panting]
[grunting]
Three darts
is too much.
I think I lost them.
Hey!
[imitating blanche dubois]
flowers...
For me?
I do declare,
mr. Beauregard.
You are my hero.
Was I...
Talking in my sleep?
You've been suffering
hysteria.
It's a natural reaction
to these poisoned darts.
Water.
Guano bowls.
Collect
the whole set.
Ace, did you see
the shooter?
Only their feet.
Not enough
for a positive I.D.
That is the dart
Of the wachootoo
shaman.
The whaty whatan?
The wachootoo shaman,
or medicine man,
Has openly protested
Against the intertribal
wedding.
Has he?
But you do not speak
wachootoo.
I go with you.
Yes. Ouda will be
my interpreter.
Ace!
Now, please
take care.
The wachootoo are
a savage tribe.
If they catch you,
they'll show no mercy.
Worry not,
my brother.
I will be as a
fly on the wall,
A grain of salt
in the ocean.
I will slip
amongst them
Like
a transparent...
Thing.
[chanting]
[drums playing]
[ace] the sacred bat
has to be in a hut.
We'll never know
Until I can walk
freely among them.
"wunderbar!"
He exclaimed
with great relish.
Aah!
[making
flatulent noises]
[grunting]
Come on, girls!
Show them
what you got!
Oh! Big finish!
[shouting]
[drums and chanting stop]
I'm sure it's fine.
Ouda is probably
going for help right now.
Hello, ace!
They found me.
No sweat!
Don't beat yourself up.
Aah!
You know,
gingivitis
Is the
number-one cause
Of all
tooth decay.
Equinsu ocha!
What does
equinsu ocha mean?
White devil.
Well, tell them
I'm not.
I've only
met you.
How do I know?
Equinsu ocha!
He said--
Let me guess.
"white devil,
white devil"?
Yes. You speak
wachootoo?
Tell them
what I'm saying.
I come in peace!
Equinsu ocha
Uza inkosazana.
I couldn't help but notice
that equinsu ocha part.
Did you just refer
to me as white devil?
This how
they know you.
Leave that part out
from now on.
I represent
the princess!
[whispering]
War...
Is hell.
The last thing
we want...
Is a fight.
[shouting]
[speaking
native language]
[ouda]
the chief said,
If you pass
all wachootoo tests,
You do not die.
Kooky.
¶ ooh, abba wah,
ay bay abba wah ¶
¶ abba wah,
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ bay abba wah ¶
[cheering]
Yeah!
¶ you can make me out
to be a fool ¶
¶ even say
I lost my mind ¶
¶ I know in my heart ¶
¶ there's no room ¶
¶ you're the one
I need to find ¶
¶ sometimes at night,
I feel alone ¶
¶ and I know
I need someone ¶
[grunting]
¶ to hold my hand
and carry me home ¶
¶ my ancestor,
I'm lost in the storm ¶
¶ abba,
I'm what you need ¶
¶ abba, I lean on you ¶
¶ I have my faith
in you ¶
¶ abba, let me
call your name ¶
¶ abba,
I'm what you need ¶
¶ abba, let me
see your face ¶
¶ abba,
take me to your place ¶
¶ abba ¶
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ bay abba wah ¶
Yiyiyiyi...
Ahh...
My entrance
to the winner's circle.
Your admiration
is well-founded,
But I'm merely
a servant.
Do not worship me!
Aah!
Oof!
[speaking
native language]
Chief says
you have passed
All tests
but one.
Only left is
Wachootoo circle
of death.
Funny...
That's my specialty.
[growling]
This is it?
I have to
beat him?
Ha ha ha!
[growling]
[shrieking]
Ya ya ya ya!
Alrighty, then.
I must tell you...
I do not wish
to fight you.
Rrrrr.
Violence is no longer
in my nature,
But if you want it,
you got it, sister!
Aah!
Biting, I see.
I was unaware
that the wachootoos
Were biters!
Well, why don't you
try this on
And see how it fits?
Aah!
Oh!
Ace...
He much better
fighter than you.
Doii!
Ya! Ooh ooh!
Ha ha! Hee hee!
Equinsu ocha!
[crowd cheering]
All right!
This white devil thing
has gone far enough.
Nobody messes
with the 'do!
[cough]
Equinsu ocha...
[speaking
native language]
He said sorry,
white devil,
But he must
kill you now.
I'll have you know
I have the reflexes of a cat
And the speed
of a mongoose.
Throw it.
I dare you!
Aah!
Oh-oh-oh!
[crowd laughing]
Ouda, don't just
stand there.
Throw me a spear!
Aah!
[laughter]
Oh!
Ha ha ha!
It's in the bone.
Oh! Aah!
[speaking
native language]
Chief says you
make him laugh.
You are like
sissy girl.
[laughter]
Sissy girl.
Ha ha!
[speaking
native language]
Wachootoo chief say
you friend to wachootoo.
Ha!
[speaking
native language]
But if curse shikaka
not lifted
By tomorrow's sun
at top of sky,
Wachootoo kill
all wachati
And smash your head
on a rock.
Super. Take care, now.
Bye-bye, then.
Ok. Take care. Super.
Are your legs
sore?
Do you want me
to carry you?
That won't be necessary,
my friend.
I have
an incredibly high
Threshold for pain.
Holy monkey!
[crowd laughing]
Ace,
why you stopped?
The wachootoo
didn't tashikaka.
Hi. Welcome back.
What would you say
this is?
Dart of
wachootoo shaman.
Precisely.
And when compared
To one of the darts
that hit me before?
Same.
Only to
the untrained eye.
You see,
the wachootoo dart
Is made of wood
from a mimosa tree,
While the other dart
is carved
From a red
fungus-bearing acalla.
And there's only
one area of the jungle
With red
fungus-bearing acallas.
Go back to the village.
Tell them the wachootoos
attack tomorrow at noon.
Ok.
This little hound dog
just picked up a scent.
[inhales]
Won't be long now, katie.
Big night tonight.
You're going to meet
your new owner.
G'day.
Disgusting rat.
[hiss]
Ha ha!
[screeching]
Gravy.
[roar]
Did you
hear that?
What is it?
Silverback.
[roaring]
Female. Big.
Yeah?
About 200 meters south.
We'd get $5,000
for one of those.
What about the rat?
Don't worry
about the rat.
We'll be back
in no time.
[gahjii]
stay downwind.
Bleah! You're even uglier
than I thought.
[screeching]
[gahjii] she's a big one,
isn't she?
[blow dart]
Uh!
Huh?
[monkey screeching]
Oh, boy. Deciduous trees
lining the riverbank.
Suman shrubs with
extreme protococcus.
Steadily increasing
water current.
Spike, I think
we can assume
The stream gets
pretty rough up ahead.
As soon as I get
you loose, spike,
You can chew
through my ropes.
That's it!
[eee]
Yes! Your turn.
All right! Yes!
[eee]
Hey!
Spike! Spike!
Spike!
[ee ee]
Spiiii...
[gurgling]
iiiike!
[gasping]
I'm alive.
Ha ha ha!
I'm alive!
Yee haw! Yee haw!
Say "uncle"!
Oh, no.
Don't start what
you can't finish!
Uh!
Quit hitting yourself.
Oh, water
tastes good, yes.
Glub, glub!
Ar ar ar ar ar.
This isn't over yet.
There's something
I've missed,
Some clue I've overlooked,
some motive,
And that motive is...
Pluh!
Think!
Somebody wants these two tribes
to destroy each other.
There must be
something valuable
In this equation.
Perhaps we should meditate
upon it, spike,
For it is said
that when seeking answers,
One must quiet the soul
in order to hear them.
What is it
the wachatis possess
That is of great value
to other men...
Besides the princess
with the amazing rack.
[inhales]
¶ aa aa aa aa
aa aa aa aa ¶
¶ alrighty, then ¶
[chanting continues]
¶ om mani padme hum ¶
¶ om mani pad-- ¶
Oh, ace. You're back?
You can dispense
with the smallpox,
All-knowing one.
I'm here on business,
And time is
of the essence.
Very well.
What answer
do you seek?
I need to know what it is
the wachatis possess
That is of great value
to civilized man.
The medallion will
lead you to the answer.
You do still have the
medallion, don't you?
Medallion? Why...Surely.
I left it back,
uh...With my body.
Your aura is weakening.
Ok, I threw it
in the cave!
What do you want from me?
What are you--
mr. Perfect?
You want to know
where it is?
It's probably lying
in a big pile of...
[gasp]
Guano!
They have guano!
Like...A glove.
Hi, chief.
Appreciate your
meeting me here.
Let's go kick
some...
Consulate butt.
Hello, ace.
You've come
for your money?
Wrong again,
sweeney toad.
I've come
for the sacred bat.
Where is it?
Why, ace,
Whatever can you mean?
Guano. Hello.
Does "poo"
ring a bell?
"guano mines as
a source of nitrate,
"producing 84% of
the world's supply
"of fertilizer,
A $1.4 billion
industry."
That's what this war
is all about.
You can't legally
Take possession
of the caves
As long as the wachatis
inhabit the area,
And you want
that dookie so bad,
You can taste it.
But, sir,
I thought that--
Yes. Thank you, fulton.
That's a fine theory,
mr. Ventura.
What has it
got to do with me?
I thought
you'd never ask.
[inhales]
There was
a white substance
On your shoe
That I mistook
for plaster.
Yesterday, I saw
the same white substance
Outside the hut
where the bat was kept.
The great white bat
has great white guano.
That's what
you slipped in!
was on your shoe!
And that explains
The abrasion
on your palm!
Let me run that
back for you.
[speaking backwards]
That's what
you slipped in!
That's what was
on your shoe!
And that explains
The abrasion
on your palm!
Damn, I'm good!
Can you feel that,
huh?
Can you feel it,
Captain compost?
The day of redemption
is at hand!
[imitating
charlton heston]
Repent! And thou
shall be saved.
Very good, mr. Ventura.
Very good.
I believe
you've solved the case.
One thing I still
don't understand,
Mr. Belvedere.
If you are the slime
Behind this
little flimflam,
Why, oh, why did you
hire me?
I'm afraid
there's going to be
A horrendous investigation
after the war.
You were my alibi
To prove I'd done
Everything I could
to stop it.
Arrest him.
Arrest him!
Please arrest him.
Simon says,
"arrest him."
[chuckling]
[door opens]
[bat screeches]
[shudders]
I thought you loved
all animals, mr. Ventura.
[mimicking cadby]
I thought you loved
All animals, mr. Ventura.
Shall I stick him
on the wall?
No. I don't think
it'll be necessary, gahjii.
Mr. Ventura here
has very cleverly stolen
The sacred bat
of the wachati.
Unfortunately,
we were unable
To recover it in time
to stop the war.
Greenwall,
hit the lights!
The switch on the wall
beside you--go for it!
Flick it, quick!
Alrighty, then.
Shall we go to jail?
Hey, what are you--
h.R. Shove-n-stuff?
Get in!
Just one more thing--
[speaking gibberish]
What are you doing?
[trumpets]
[ace speaking gibberish]
Stop it!
I said stop it!
[trumpets]
Aah!
To the jungle, boba.
Friends, rodents,
quadrupeds,
Lend me your ears!
[tarzan yell]
Imbecile!
You let him
get away.
Sir, you don't seem
to understand.
The entire tribe
will be killed.
Remind me to send
a sympathy card.
We'll go and get
the bastard.
Doesn't matter, gahjii.
There's nothing he can do now.
We've got the bat,
and it's nearly noon.
[rumbling]
[lion roars]
[zebra brays]
[water buffalo bellows]
What the hell
is going on?
[trumpets]
Aah!
[hiccup]
[belch]
You see?
Humans and animals
can live in harmony.
Wow.
Sorry for
the delay, ace.
[cough]
[with cuban accent]
hey, poachers!
Say hello to my
stinky little friend.
No!
[bat screeching]
[monkeys screeching]
Get off, get off,
get off.
Not so fast, sally.
Oh! Get it away!
Shikaka!
Ha ha ha!
Aah ha ha ha!
Aw, he wants
to go off-road.
Duh, nobody wants
to play with me.
[imitating truck engine]
loser!
Cadby! From the consulate,
right?
This is weird.
[whistling]
Ow! Ooh! Ah!
Ow! Ow!
Ha ha!
Aah!
[engine revs]
[lion roars]
Bleah.
Noon.
The wachati.
[screech]
The spirit
will overcome.
Shikaka!
Aah!
Uh!
Shikaka!
Hey, hey!
[gasp]
Headhunters!
[shouting
in native language]
Wachootoo!
Shikaka! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Pet detective
coming through.
Clear a path,
people!
Shikaka!
Equinsu ocha!
[bat screeching]
Yuck!
Ha ha ha!
[growl]
Huh?
¶ wee dee dee dee
dee dee dee dee dee ¶
¶ dee, owimoweh ¶
¶ owimoweh, owimoweh,
owimoweh, owimoweh ¶
owimoweh, owimoweh... ¶
[speaking
native language]
[crowd cheering]
[ee ee]
They will now
consummate the marriage
Under the witness
of the tribe.
Well done, ace.
You must be extremely proud.
Pride is
an abomination.
One must forgo
the self
To attain total
spiritual creaminess
And avoid
the chewy chunks
Of degradation.
Aah!
[shouting
in native language]
What's that
he's saying?
Well, I think he's saying
she's not a virgin.
They can tell that?
Shikaka!
[shouting
in native language]
Captioning made possible by
warner bros.
Captioned by the national
captioning institute
--www.Ncicap.Org--
Shikaka!
¶ there is
no political solution ¶
¶ to our troubled evolution ¶
¶ I have no faith
in constitution ¶
¶ no, no ¶
¶ just check
this reggae revolution ¶
¶ we are spirits
in the material world ¶
¶ are spirits
¶ our so-called leaders speak ¶
¶ with words
they try to jail you ¶
¶ what's the right? ¶
¶ they subjugate the meek ¶
¶ ooh, yeah ¶
¶ but it's the rhetoric
of failure ¶
¶ we are spirits
in the material world ¶
¶ are spirits
¶ watch this ¶
¶ so come, come, come,
every posse, come, come, come ¶
¶ come, come listen
to the words ¶
¶ of mr. P-a-t-o banton ¶
¶ I must be a real gentleman
in this material land ¶
¶ spreading peace and love
to each and every one ¶
¶ so pato is your one
from the radio station ¶
¶ unlock the ill winds
with positive vibration ¶
¶ do you need
spiritual education? ¶
¶ that's the only way they'll
ever know their destination ¶
¶ we are spiritual, material ¶
¶ yes, we are spiritual
in this material world ¶
¶ oh, oh, my, my ¶
¶ how easy I go ¶
¶ watch this ¶
¶ where does
the answer lie? ¶
¶ living from day to day ¶
¶ and for something
we can buy ¶
¶ ooh, yeah ¶
¶ there must be
another way ¶
¶ we are spirits
in the material world ¶
¶ are spirits
¶ we are spirits
in the material world ¶
¶ are spirits
¶ get down ¶
¶ let me tell you
about a friend of mine ¶
¶ his name's boll weevil,
check him out ¶
¶ he spends all day
on his big butt ¶
¶ and he don't ever,
ever get outside ¶
¶ I come to visit ¶
¶ I bring
some sunshine ¶
¶ and I just spread it
all over the fire ¶
¶ he's stuck
on his big couch ¶
¶ stuck in his big shell ¶
¶ he looks at the tv,
and he's all right ¶
¶ I come from the drug lord,
the local drugstore ¶
¶ bug is a fly,
baby, he's never uptight ¶
¶ and I wonder ¶
¶ boll weevil, why don't you
get out of your home? ¶
¶ he said,
"I'm comfortable here" ¶
¶ "I don't want to move,
I don't want to leave" ¶
¶ I said, "boll weevil,
get right out of your home" ¶
¶ "good-bye, I got to stay,
I'll move some other day" ¶
¶ "bye-bye, I got to
go to sleep" ¶
¶ and let the tube shine ¶
¶ let the tube shine ¶
¶ now I would tell you
about boll weevil ¶
¶ but that bug is
just too scary ¶
¶ he's sitting there
all alone ¶
¶ I try to coach him out
with chocolate pie ¶
¶ but he would not
move a muscle ¶
¶ and I tried ¶
¶ to make him see that the sun
is shining outside ¶
¶ check it out ¶
[humming]
¶ boll weevil, get right out
of your home ¶
¶ now I would tell you
about boll weevil ¶
¶ but that bug is
just too scary ¶
¶ he's sitting there
all alone ¶
¶ I try to coach him out
with chocolate pie ¶
¶ but he would not
move a muscle ¶
¶ and I tried ¶
¶ to make him see that the sun
is shining outside ¶
is shining out ¶
¶ make him see the sun
is shining outside ¶
¶ make him see the sun,
make him see the sun ¶
¶ make him see
the goddamn sun ¶
Come on, little buggy.
There's a little bug.