Previously on
Necessary Roughness...
I'm sorry
about your father.
Daddy left me the team.
Community service, huh?
Been there.
Nico, you keep that girl
away from my son.
I'm having trouble
restarting my practice.
It's a good idea
that you see me.
You ever think
she's hitting it
with somebody
in the organization?
My money's on Nico.
Toes should be the guy
on the sidelines
trying to get in the game,
not me.
Rip and dip.
You're gonna
tell me how to play football.
All it took was
a little dip, a little rip,
get that extra step I needed,
and the rest is history.
Game on, dawg.
Game on.
Ladies and gentlemen,
together for the first time
in over a decade,
please welcome Von Dozer!
♪ The day we met,
there was no denying ♪
The myth of the rock God --
edgy, glamorous,
larger-than-life.
♪ You looked so sweet,
like a cherry soda ♪
The fact is whether
we've chosen them or not,
we all have our own myths
to live up to.
The question is, is it possible
to shatter a myth,
especially when you've started
to believe it yourself?
♪ I knew that you
would drive me crazy ♪
♪ You taste like
♪ bitter sugar
♪ We do it all night
♪ Just like bitter sugar
Whoa!
Ohh.
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ the day we met,
there was no denying ♪
♪ I had to have you,
i just couldn't resist ♪
♪ you looked so sweet,
like a cherry soda ♪
♪ in high heels
and a baby-doll dress ♪
Oh! Oh.
Oh, yeah. What's up?
What's that racket,
Mom?
Von Dozer --
the best band...
♪ Ever!
Where are you off to
so nicey-nicey?
It's the first day
of my new community service.
You need a sports coat and a tie
to pick up trash?
Actually, I'm working for
a charity now -- Hawks Cares.
Since when?
Since...Juliette Pittman
hooked me up.
Say what now?
It's a great organization.
Do you know
how many of these kids
get a solid meal every day
because of them?
Mom, I'll be gaining
invaluable corporate experience
in an air-conditioned
environment.
With Juliette Pittman.
When are you gonna start
trusting me?
When you stop
getting arrested!
Gentlemen, our season
is off to a great start,
and as such, I've taken it
upon myself to create
an image worthy
of that success.
I give you...
the new Hawk uniform,
designed by Michael Kors.
Bold, isn't it?
The Oregon Ducks
went fashion-forward,
and they're making a statement,
getting noticed,
and moving merchandise
in a big way.
I also set up a photo shoot
for the cover of a magazine
that shall remain nameless,
but let's just say it's big.
I sold them on my idea to make
football not just cool, but hot.
She's like
the freaking Weather channel.
Everything's "hot."
I think I quit.
This wasn't
supposed to happen.
You promised
is wouldn't happen.
What -- you're not a fan
of the red, white, and bling?
Oh, come on.
The league is never
gonna approve those uniforms.
And the photo shoot --
Nico,
you and I both know
that this is just
the tip of the iceberg.
This is just gonna
play itself out. Trust me.
She's gonna find
something more exciting to do --
get bored.
Why?
'Cause
that's what women do?
No, that's
what Juliette does.
Look, I am trying to
run a team.
She just
lost her father.
Have some compassion.
So, Von Dozer.
David, Paul, welcome.
Tell me
why you are here today.
I think
Paul reminds me of my dad,
and I'm transferring
the resentment I have
for dear old dickhead
on to him.
No, the problem is
you drink too much.
You're
chronically late.
When you do show up,
you're distracted, hung over,
and more concerned about
getting laid than playing music.
Sounds like rock 'n' roll,
don't you think, Dr. Santino?
Here's what I know --
uh, you two grew up together,
formed Von Dozer
while still in high school,
four platinum records,
sold-out stadiums.
And while other band members
have come and gone,
you two have been
the ones to stay together,
until 10 years ago,
when you broke up.
And if I understand correctly,
you haven't spoken much since.
Do I smell a Doze-head?
Let's just say that I am...
familiar with your work.
What made you decide
to do this reunion tour?
The cash -- we need it.
Yeah, well, after what
you pulled last week,
two other venues
already canceled,
not to mention
the three pending lawsuits.
So we're losing cash,
not making it.
Ruh-roh!
I have two children at home.
I don't need another one --
who's out of control! --
as my business partner.
Let me
tell you something.
People come to see our band
because I'm out of control!
I am the show, dude.
They come in spite of you, dude,
for the music --
most of which,
I've written.
Okay, obviously
there is some unresolved anger
between you,
but are you both committed
to doing this tour
and to working
on the relationship?
I'm here, aren't I?
Dr. Santino, please help us
get through this tour
without killing each other.
♪ Baby, work your magic on me
♪ Necessary Roughness 2x13 ♪
Hits and Myths
Original Air Date on January 30, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Oh!
Aah! Nico.
I thought we were done
with that move.
Sorry. No.
We need to talk.
Uh, is it T.K.?
No.
About us.
Oh.
Well,
I thought that, um --
I thought we were done
with that move, too.
Not quite.
Wha...?
So, I am
officially defrosted.
I gave little dude
a proper fish burial,
office back up and running --
smooth sailing, yep, yep, yep.
And yet here you are.
Yep.
That little foot
just twitching away,
indicating you would like to
talk to me about something.
But you're...
stalling.
Yeah.
I have been having dreams
about a co-worker.
Matt or Nico?
I happen to
have a lot of co-workers,
so I don't know
what would make you --
Nico.
And the nature
of these dreams?
Sexual.
Were they
satisfying or not?
They were
pretty darn satisfying.
Okay.
I realize that sex dreams
are not about...sex,
but I can't figure out
what the connection is
between all of them.
The last one
was actually a scene
from a little movie
called "Titanic."
You know, when they're
in the cargo hold
and they're in the car and
it's super-steamy and the --
Was Kate Kinslet in it?
Hmm?
DiCaprio?
Everybody dies
or you die?
No.
Dr. Gunner, it, uh --
it was just the sex.
It was just
the sex with a man
that I should never,
ever have sex with.
Juliette.
Wherefore art thou,
Juliette?
I think somebody boo-booed.
Oh, no,
that's the right costume.
You'll understand
when you see the whole layout.
I'm in a onesie.
It looks fantastic.
Uh, it's all good 'cause I was
thinking we could, you know,
just crop it
right here anyway
'cause this is
where the money is, you know?
Oh!
Well, I hope you
brought extra cameras
'cause that mug's
apt to crack some lenses.
Hey.
Hi.
Hey, there.
Tell me Toes is lost.
No,
it's all three of us --
me and my two
star wide receivers.
Come here.
Step into my office.
Why does
Toes get pinstripes,
and I get pen stripes?
Well,
everyone has an image.
Toes is our gentleman,
and you're our bad boy.
And I'm the girl
caught in the middle.
Okay, I smell
what you're cooking,
but I'm ordering
off the menu, okay?
The bad-boy myth --
not my bag anymore.
Oh, okay.
I understand.
I don't want you to do anything
that makes you uncomfortable.
That's cool. All right,
what are my options?
Your options are...
to leave.
Excuse me.
I thought you -- you...
I want to
stomp a hole in his face.
I want to put my toes
up Toes' ass.
Okay,
but what you should do is...
I know --
breathe, relax,
work diligently
to regain my spot.
Yeah.
Don't let Toes or Juliette
distract you from that.
That's great in theory.
It's just that
I'm trying to fly --
trying to reinvent myself,
and Juliette Pittman
is literally holding me back
with a ball and chain.
God,
grant me the serenity
to accept
the things I cannot change...
...the courage
to change the things that I can,
and the wisdom
to know the difference.
Yeah, I'm thinking about
getting it tattooed
across my forehead.
Terrence, don't tell everybody
what a new man you are.
Show them.
Hello.
Ohh!
What do you got to be
so sneaky for all the time?
When I was a kid, I was always
the best at hide-and-seek.
I'll bet you were.
Are you aware
that Juliette Pittman
has offered
Ray Jay a position
at Hawks Cares
for his community service?
Hmm. I am now.
I take it
you don't like this.
Juliette Pittman
isn't exactly Mother Teresa.
Dani, she has a good heart.
She's just young.
Well, it's not her heart
that I'm worried about.
I'll keep an eye on him.
I promise.
Thank you.
Place looks
a lot smaller now.
Maybe you just got bigger.
Yeah.
So you brought us here
because...
Well, if my fan-club memory
serves me,
the Round About is where
it all began for Von Dozer.
Sometimes it's good
to remember where you came from
in order to figure out
where you're going.
Oh!
I cannot believe this!
Is that David Blaize
all grown up?
Hey, Paul,
how you doing?
Good.
Yeah?
Holy hell, dirty Doug.
How's it hanging, man?
Well, it ain't --
not without medication.
What's it been --
15 years now?
So,
what the hell you doing here?
I mean,
you should have called.
I could have packed the place.
There's only 25 people here.
Well,
it's about 25 more
than when we gigged here
the first time, right?
You here to jam?
Hey, Doc, how you feel about
your own private concert?
Me? Awesome!
A bottle of
your finest bubbly, please.
Make that two.
Actually, I-I'll
have bubbly...water.
Oh,
you're doing that?
Yeah.
Fresh out of rehab.
I went to rehab.
You get the best drugs there.
Kidding. Sort of.
Yeah, I'm just trying to
stick with the program,
you know, uh,
reinvent myself.
So you
didn't bring me here
to get me drunk, naked,
and X-rated?
Unfortunately, no.
Um...
The first year of the program,
you know,
you have to lock the booze away,
put the booty on layaway.
Good.
I have
such a terrible habit
of just jumping
into bed with guys
and having wild,
orgazmo, toe-curling,
make-you-want-to-cry sex.
Frankly, I'm relieved.
To being friends.
Amigos.
So, why are we here?
First of all,
I just wanted to apologize
for overreacting
at the shoot.
I have a certain persona,
and I know that you were
just rolling with that.
But I'm trying to get rid of
the myth of T.K. the terrible,
you know?
Emerge from the chrysalis
a new butterfly, if you will.
Oh, right.
Well, I'm trying to emerge
from the hot mess of this
to the triumphant
team owner.
Prove to the old guys
that I can do it.
Tell you what --
you support my metamorphosis,
I'll support yours,
to the team and anybody else
who dares question you.
I scratch your back,
you scratch mine?
All those hard-to-reach places.
But with clothes on.
♪ You taste like
♪ bitter sugar
♪ We're doing all right
♪ just like bitter suga-a-a-r
come on!
♪ Let me fix ya
All right!
Thank you.
It's great to be back
where it all started for us.
Von Dozer! Whoo!
Thank you. I will, uh,
add these to my collection.
Do you know
"You Should Be Mine"?
Oh, yeah.
E-flat.
Now we'd like to do a song
that's probably won us
more awards than any other,
but one
we very rarely play live.
There's a time
for everything.
David.
What are you doing?
Don't do this, man.
There's like nine people here,
bro. Play the song.
♪ I keep looking for my life
♪ in my eyes,
it has been stolen ♪
♪ all the days that pass me by
♪ keep my sight
♪ clear as the light
♪ sometimes it's hard
to find the meaning ♪
♪ in a world
that's running out of time ♪
Screw you, David!
♪ give me a sign
♪ 'cause I may lose my way
♪ but I'm standing here to say
♪ that you should be mi-i-i-ne
Here we are...
just the two of us.
Romantic music playing.
Dr. Santino...
Are you
trying to seduce me?
I-I hadn't thought of it.
I wish you would.
Really?
Oh!
You know
this isn't a sex dream, right?
I do know,
and I don't care.
What's happening right now
between the two of you
is not about sex.
It won't be
if you keep interrupting.
My point is...
there's more meaning
behind this whole thing.
Why?
Why can't I just have fun?
Why does everything
have to mean something?
Why can't my sex dream
just be about sex?!
Fine.
What's it about?
About wanting
what you can't have.
Ooh! No, no, no, no, no!
Don't go!
That doesn't mean go!
No!
I...
Okay.
But...where'd everybody go?
How am I supposed to
have a sex dream with no sex?!
O-o-okay,
so in the latest dream,
the sex was with Matt
in "The Graduate."
No. No, no, no.
It -- it was still
with Nico, but...
that's the point.
I...was Mrs. Robinson, and Nico
represented what I can't have,
or shouldn't have.
And Matt...
Well, I can't have Matt
anymore anyway.
Or shouldn't have,
right?
It was Matt who told you
this was about wanting
what you can't have, correct?
Damn it!
And since you are
the author of your dreams,
who did Matt represent?
Me.
So you think it's all about
wanting what you can't have.
So, Danielle, what is it
you feel you can't have?
Break!
Break! Break!
Hello, coach.
Hey.
Um, so, I've made a decision,
and I would like...
First you take my advice,
then you take
credit for my advice,
and then
you take my spotlight.
Got to learn
how to give, son.
You give,
and you shall receive.
Well, seeing as that
I'm the number-one receiver
on this team,
I don't think
I'm the one that needs lessons.
Thank you.
First-team offense,
let's go!
Not you, son.
Uh,
I need T.K. out there.
Uh, what the hell?
Our illustrious owner
has moved T.K. to number one.
All right, come on, come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
Hey, Mr. Harper.
Yeah, this is Ray Jay Santino
here from Hawks Cares.
How you doing today?
Yeah, I'm doing well,
thank you.
Yeah, we were
just hoping to count on you
to match last year's
donation of $1,000.
Mr. Harper?
Hello, Ray Jay.
You enjoying the job?
My mom sent you here
to check up on me, didn't she?
What should I tell her?
Tell her
everything's going great
and that I have
a real future here.
And that
Juliette's teaching me
a ton of things
that I didn't know about.
Yeah,
leave out that last part.
Smart.
♪ But I'm standing here
to say ♪
♪ that you should
be mi-i-i-i-ne ♪
Tell me about this song.
There's all types of myths
about it --
that you wouldn't
play it live
because it was
about David's ex-fiancée.
Which one?
Or David's drug problem?
Whoa,
I didn't have a problem.
I did drugs,
like every other rocker, um,
including
someone else in this room,
who's suddenly
a freaking monk.
I'm not a monk.
I'm a parent with
responsibilities now, David.
I'm sorry
if that pisses you off!
David...uh,
this was the only song
that you wrote solo, right?
You really are a fan.
Tell me
what this song's about.
It's about Willa, my wife.
Ah.
Paul, brother,
we've been over this.
It's not about her,
you narcissistic --
Me?!
You haven't changed
since you were 17!
When are
you gonna grow up?!
So I can be a...
soccer dad like you?!
Uh,
sport some sweet Dockers
and maybe do a little backyard
composting with the kids?!
Okay, hey, guys.
No amount of money
is worth this.
Uh, so, are you gonna bail
like you did the first time?
I didn't
bail on the band!
You gave me no choice!
You were high and drunk
all the time,
and we couldn't write a song
to save our lives!
So I decided to save my life
and get out before it got sad.
But you know what?
It got sad anyway.
What did you do --
clean her dog's dingleberries?
With tweezers.
You know,
I didn't know I had to
learn how to play football
on a mattress.
Oh, wow.
You might need to
learn how to play football,
period, there,
turf toe.
'Cause then you could see
that speed is deadly.
Check this out.
So fast, you didn't see me
bitch-slap you.
Spin it however you want.
We all know you didn't earn it.
You can't just switch positions
like you're changing clothes.
It undermines front office
and coaching staff.
Not to mention
it damages team morale.
Especially when you
do it on the field, publicly.
Look,
we'd respectfully ask you
not to mingle
with the personnel.
They're my personnel.
I will mingle with them
however I see fit.
I own this team.
I'm sorry if you don't agree
with my decisions.
Perhaps this isn't the place
for you --
any of you.
Compassion, was it?
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe she
just needs a hug.
"I keep looking for my life.
In my eyes,
it has been stolen."
David.
What is it that you think
was stolen from you?
Okay.
You want real?
Here it is.
The song isn't about Willa,
his wife.
It's about his son,
Dillon.
Except...
I think Dillon's my son.
I didn't want to
destroy their happiness,
so I never said a word.
And yet,
every day since...
you have destroyed
your own.
You're not surprised
by any of this?
One thing
I can tell you...
Paul sure as hell will be
when I finally tell him.
Oh! T.K.!
You made it!
Listen, uh,
you didn't return my texts.
What --
I hit you back.
To tell me
to meet you at a bar,
which is the last place
I'm trying to be right now.
Okay, you can't keep
doing what you're doing
because my team thinks
I'm kissing your ass.
And what's wrong
with that?
You got what you wanted, right?
Back on the field.
I want it the right way.
Hard work
is so overrated.
Maybe for you,
but I wasn't born with
a silver spoon in my mouth.
I'm just trying to get you
to relax, have some fun.
I'm having fun!
I'm -- this is me having fun.
I'm the conductor
on the fun train.
Whoo-whoo!
Uh-huh. Right, T.K.
Do you want some advice
from someone who's been there?
I know you're trying to
change your image,
but don't throw the old T.K.
out with the bathwater.
You are a extremely dynamic
and...
Really sexy.
...really sexy man.
And you don't want to trade
that in for a lesser model.
Just fine-tune it a bit.
Rotate the tires.
Put a little oil
in your engine.
Vroom!
And take your foot
off the emergency brake.
You're like me, T.K. --
passionate, intense.
If we don't
blow off some steam,
we'll go
insane in the membrane.
You know what --
screw it, yeah.
Who wants to
do shots off my abs?
Whoo! It's spring break
up in here! Yeah, yeah!
I know you think
this song is about Willa and me.
But...it isn't.
I think Dillon is mine.
No. He's not.
Dude.
I know it must be hard
for you to hear,
but basic math tells me --
David.
You're right.
Dillon is not my son.
But he's not yours,
either.
You know, I knew you
slept with Willa, so I checked.
I did an online DNA test.
It wasn't hard.
You're like a big damn dog.
You shed your hair
all over the place.
Then whose son is he?
Some roadie.
He split.
Look, I raised him.
I'm his dad.
So...
where do we go from here,
gentlemen?
This is basural.
I'm cleaner
than a Brazilian bikini wax.
Well, then,
it shouldn't be a problem.
It's a problem
'cause I'm offended.
Were you out partying
last night?
Somebody told you that?
Were you or were you not
out in a club
with Juliette Pittman?
Juliette Pittman
told you that?
It wasn't Juliette.
This foot-fungus-having
mother...
Toes is a liar!
Well, then,
take the test,
which you're contractually
obligated to do.
Take it. Pass it.
Let's get out of here.
You shouldn't listen to rumors,
Matty "D."
Come on.
Rumors
can be helpful, "T."
Lets you know what's going on
behind your back.
You got something to ask me,
Matt?
You have something
to tell me, Nico?
No.
Hey.
Is David here?
No. Come in.
He didn't
show up for sound check.
Concert's tomorrow.
I have no idea where the guy is.
What happened
after you left here?
He got real quiet.
Didn't want to talk.
So I-I just let it be.
And then an hour ago,
get this message.
Hey, buddy.
How's it going?
Personally,
I'm going to hell.
Don't think
I'll make it over.
I just want you to know
I'm sorry, Paul.
I'm so damn sorry.
He's never done that before --
apologized.
Do you have
a way of tracking him down?
Let's start with the obvious.
Come on.
What's up, Terrence?
You have a good time
last night, bro?
You scared?
What -- of you?
Hmm?
That's why you snitched.
This isn't the hood, T.K.
I didn't snitch.
I went to the management about
a concern regarding a co-worker.
Just being a gentleman.
No,
you're being a liar.
Ah, see, if you see
an addict falling off the wagon,
it's not really lying.
It is when you know
I didn't touch a sip of alcohol
last night.
Look, I get it.
Being an addict,
that is not your fault.
It's --
it's hereditary, right?
So, we should just blame
your crackhead mama.
Oh, man, don't be mad at me,
T.K.
Be mad at your mama, man!
She the one that left your ass
in the trash!
Stay by the car,
and I'll check inside.
Yo!
Jesus.
Did somebody lose
a middle-aged rock star?
Come on, man!
It's gonna be all right.
Just come down.
Whoopsie!
Whoo!
That would have hurt.
David, look,
I know you're upset.
Just come down,
and let's talk.
Less talk,
more rock, baby.
Whoa!
Come on, buddy.
Just --
just come on down.
Okay.
I'm coming down.
Oh, my God!
Oh, crap. That hurts.
Ohh!
You crazy son of a bitch!
I thought
you were dead.
Unfortunately, no.
That --
that was a bad idea.
Not your first one.
Don't move, okay, because you
might have broken something.
Go call 911.
I'm fine.
Oh, oh, oh.
Sort of.
David,
what were you thinking?
I wanted to...to go out
in a David Blaize of glory,
like Hendrix and Morrison
and Joplin.
I can't
even do that right.
All these years...
I told myself
this story --
that Dillon was my kid,
that Paul stole my life.
Thinking
I had a kid out there
made me feel
like I had something.
After all these years,
I got nothing.
But, David,
you are still wildly talented.
You are still
filled with possibilities.
And it's time for you
to invest in that story.
Paramedics
are on their way.
I'm fine.
Oh, oh, oh.
Yeah, maybe I should
kick your ass!
You scared
the hell out of me!
You couldn't kick my ass
if you tried.
I can and I have.
Senior year -- after prom.
That whole thing
with Deb Florentine.
Oh, yeah, she was wearing
that smoking-hot dress.
Yeah,
she was also my date.
You're such
a son of a bitch.
I know.
Matt, please,
please take me with you.
No.
I'm going to my office,
where I can find some peace.
Can't you understand that?
No!
I only know
that I love you!
Well,
that's your problem.
Matt, Matt!
But, Matt,
where will I go?
What will I do?
Frankly, my dear,
I don't give a damn.
My dreams --
they're all movie reenactments.
What the heck
is that about?
Um, you know, movies
are the modern-day myth.
They're the campfires we gather
around to pass along legends.
But tell me this.
What do these particular movies
all have in common --
"Titanic," "Graduate,"
"Gone With the Wind"?
They're all...
love stories.
Yeah, and?
They're all
tragic love stories.
So, Danielle, do you believe
in happily ever after?
For me?
I'm not so sure.
What the hell happened
to the serenity prayer?
I had the courage
to rearrange Toe's face.
Serious question.
How many chances do you
expect me to keep giving you?
Look, I'm sorry --
Yeah, you sure
as hell are sorry.
Toes calls my mother
a crack whore.
I'm just supposed to
smile and take that?
You punched him
in the face.
You know,
if you want people
to stop treating you
like a problem child,
stop causing problems.
And stop being a child.
Then where would I be?
You'd be
playing this Sunday!
Instead,
you're benched, again.
I see it really doesn't matter
what I say or what I do.
You're just gonna keep seeing me
for the person that I was,
not the guy I'm trying
really hard to be.
What are we celebrating?
Tuesday.
Oh.
I feel a lecture
coming on.
I'm gonna be brief.
Yes.
Definitely a lecture.
Just a little something
about your dad --
the uber-competitive
Marshall Pittman.
It didn't matter whether
he was watching or playing,
he loved games.
More than humans.
Perhaps, but what
he came to realize was...
Football may be a game,
but managing people --
real people --
that definitely is not.
Is this about T.K.
going Ali on Toes?
Look, football players
need aggression.
Happy players
don't win games.
Juliette, if you want to
destroy your own life,
that's your choice.
But being the owner of a team,
people depend on you.
You think about that
next time you make a decision.
Think hard.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Grow up.
You're not my father,
Nico!
All these years --
acting like my great protector.
I know
about you and my mother.
I had a very complicated
relationship with your parents.
I cared about both of them.
And I care
very much about you.
Now you work for me.
Maybe you need to
think hard about that.
Hey, whose ready to rock!
You want to come out there
with us -- sing some backup?
Oh!
You clearly
know all the songs.
You guys don't
want to hear me sing.
Dude,
you smell like whiskey.
Cologne, man!
Okay, one drink.
One.
Rome wasn't
built in a day.
Shall we rock the house,
my good man?
We shall!
Ladies and gentlemen,
Von Dozer!
♪ oh
♪ Go
♪ go on
♪ take me
♪ for a ride
You're here kind of late.
And dressed to rock.
I was at a concert.
Hmm.
And, uh,
Ray Jay texted me,
said that he was working late,
and I was curious.
He is...working late.
So I don't have
anything to worry about?
I didn't say that.
He has a crush on her.
But does she have
a crush on him back?
Only in his dreams.
As long as
they stay there.
♪ Yeah, I believe
♪ in the other
Anything going on?
Nothing's going on,
Donnally...
with Dani and me.
And Juliette?
She's got to go.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==