On the first Tuesday
of each month,
a military police pick-up
and 3 patrol cars
leave Suburbana Ave.,
in Rio de Janeiro,
where the Narcotics Division's
headquarters are located.
They come to this junkyard in Caju.
The convoy transports drugs
confiscated during that month.
The amount may vary between
200 kilos and 3 or 4 tons.
In less than 2 hours,
everything will be incinerated
in a high temperature oven.
The rise in drug dealing after
the mid 1980s is responsible
for a sharp rise
in the number of homicides.
One person dies every
half-hour in Rio de Janeiro,
90% shot by large caliber guns.
Federal Police estimates that,
today, drug trafficking
employs 100,000 people in Rio.
It's the same number of people
the city has in its payroll.
Not all of them live in the slums,
called "favelas",
but police action is mainly
concentrated in these areas.
This program,
filmed during 1997 and 1998,
listened to the people closely
involved in the confrontation:
the policeman,
the drug dealer,
and, caught in the crossfire,
the slum dweller.
''NEWS FROM A PERSONAL WAR''
THE POLICEMAN
CAP. PIMENTEL - SPECIAL POLICE
OPERATIONS BATTALION-BOPE
When you are 5 or 6 years old,
you wanna be a policeman.
Then, we change our mind.
I never did.
I always wanted to be a policeman.
Sometimes,
I arrive here in the morning,
put on my uniform,
and I feel invincible.
I feel like going
into the favela.
Sometimes, I get here in
the morning and I'm scared.
But I always wanted the opportunity
to be in a real combat operation.
I ended up being
in hundreds of them.
Maybe I wouldn't have that
opportunity in the armed forces.
Do you miss never
having been in a war?
I am in a war.
I'm in the middle of a war.
The only difference is that
l get to go home every day.
THE DEALER
There's no way
to invade Bairro do Jockey.
We'll have fun with the cops.
Because, at Jockey
I'll tell you how it goes.
Things are hard
even for the "narcs".
To climb the Jockey
even the BOPE trembles.
The police have a hard time.
Just like the Feds.
I respect all bad criminals.
Now I'll show you how
it goes at Bairro do Jockey.
FRANCISCO -16 YEARS OLD
One holds an AR-15
The other holds a 12-gauge
There's another with a pistol
escorting the police pick-up
This rap is cool
l tell you this
Who are those guys?
They carry M-16s
The cops are jerks
They bring old guns
Shoot twice and run out of here
If you don't bring a revolver
Maybe you'll scream
Bring a .50 or a .30
In general, we don't want anyone
to suffer like I did when I was little.
I could have been
a poor person,
ADRIANO - 29 YEARS OLD
but I wouldn't be
running from the police.
I wouldn't have to live
in the favela sometimes.
I could've been holding
a modest job,
but I could also have been
living a better life.
I didn't have that chance.
If I steal,
if I've ever stolen anything,
it wasn't to buy cocaine.
If I did it, the motivation
was, first, to buy food.
I can't die of hunger.
Second, to help my family.
Third, to keep my appearance.
I don't think about doing
bad things to people.
I don't think about
being mean to people.
I think about living my life.
THE DWELLER
I wake up at 2:30 a.m. every day.
I go to my job.
I deliver newspapers.
At 7 a.m.,
I have to rush back to take
my two younger kids to school.
Then, I rush up the favela
again to do my housework.
My son works at noon,
so I have to be home.
He says: "Mom, I want lunch.
Lunch must be ready. ''
Then, it's time to rush
back down to pick up
the little ones and run
my girl to ballet school.
By then,
the day is almost over.
It's time for dinner.
Everyone is tired.
Sometimes, I go to sleep at 10 p.m.,
when my husband
comes home from work.
I have to give him dinner.
At 10 p.m., I go to sleep.
I collapse, really. Then...
I wake up at 2:30 a.m.
This happens every day of the week.
Rain or shine, I have to get
out of bed and face the day.
I'm content with this because
I think of my kids' future.
I see a lot of things
happening to other kids.
and I hope these things never,
ever, happen to my kids.
VALÉRIA
HILDA'S DAUGHTER
LUANDA
JANETE'S DAUGHTER
Luanda is the wind she is the sea
She is Xangô 's daughter
and Iemanjá's granddaughter
THE HOME OF
LUANDA, JANETE AND ADÃO
The drug traffic has a good
and a bad side.
Because before there were dealers,
the police entered the favela
breaking down your door.
They'd come in and brake it all.
When these guns entered
our community, because of the drugs,
they forced the police
to come in more cautiously.
-They walk around in fear.
-They know the new generation...
-This might lead to death.
This new generation, this youth,
is in a suicidal spirit.
-They don't care if they'll die or kill.
-They have no fear.
All they want to do
is protect the community
from this kind of violent
police invasion.
It's the good side of the guns.
Now, the negative side,
the cruel side of the guns
is that, when they come
to collect a debt,
from people down
in the city or in our community,
they don't care
if that person is a minor or not.
If they can kill,
cut the person up,
and display the pieces
as an example,
to show that any mistake with them
means death, they are capable of this.
THE BEGINNING
1950 - 1980
NORTH SIDE
The dealers were
old people, old ladies.
Drug dealing was not very intense.
Cocaine didn't use
to get here back then.
There was only marijuana.
PAULO LINS - WRITER
Cocaine was a rich people's thing.
The poor didn't use it.
They would only touch marijuana.
There was a time, in the favela,
when people who snorted coke
were considered rich.
It was a status drug.
When it left the rich people's
arena and reached the poor,
things got more violent.
When it became lucrative,
it got violent.
There was a lot of money involved
and too many people trying to sell it.
They had to establish
their territory,
to defend their selling point.
People have always died in the favela,
but the press didn't take notice.
The morgue would pick up the body.
It was normal.
It happened within the favela.
It never got to here to
the rich people's area.
The media discovered the violence
when it left the favela,
when kidnapping started,
along with
Comando Vermelho,
drug trafficking, stray bullets.
There was a great transformation
after the popularization of cocaine.
Then, stealing from your neighbor,
stealing money in buses
wouldn't take you anywhere.
The person wouldn't prosper.
There had to be some kind of unity,
so everybody could make money.
There couldn't be this war
in which blacks would kill blacks,
the poor would kill the poor.
The enemy, let 's put it this way,
would be the middle class,
the government,
the businessmen,
people from outside
the favela environment.
This was born with
the dictatorship.
It grew because of the political
prisoners at Ilha Grande.
They locked up
5 or 6 political prisoners
with around 60 common prisoners
thinking these 60 would dilute the 5.
It was the opposite.
Those 5 dominated the 60 others.
They froze the war by teaching
them to form one command.
They organized crime.
CARLOS GREGÓRIO, ''GORDO'' - THE
FOUNDATION OF ORGANIZED CRIME
If a political prisoner
had a banana, he would share it.
If one could eat,
everybody could eat too.
If 10 of us couldn't eat,
nobody would eat.
That's where the idea was born.
We began to think collectively.
We started to get organized
inside the prison to fight the crimes
committed against inmates by guards
and by inmates who liked
26th Pct ENCANTADO NEIGHBORHOOD
to prey on other inmates.
The project was
"Peace, Justice and Freedom".
Peace: we wanted to live
in peace inside the prison.
Justice: we wanted justice
for all, a social justice.
The idea was to take all the
holes left by the government
and fill them with the
Comando Vermelho.
What would it do?
The idea was to do everything
the government doesn't do.
Freedom: as everybody knows,
is getting out
of prison at any cost.
We're with Comando Vermelho.
KLEBER - 23 YEARS OLD
Have you heard about it?
Talk about it.
It's an organization of our own.
It's organized crime.
On the streets, all we do is for
our population, for our society.
We do it for our people,
a suffering and humble people.
I was born in the favela.
I'd be lying if I said a resident
doesn't help me once in a while.
I'd be lying if I said we don't help
them. We also help them.
This is an obligation we have.
If my daughter gets sick
in the middle of the night,
...or I or Adão does...
-She's been helped many times.
Sometimes,
I go to the drugstore.
I bring money to buy medicine,
but it costs 3 times
the amount I have.
then I go over
to the dealers and say:
''My daughter is sick.
I need to buy...''
They say: ''Where's the prescription?
Give it to me.''
In a half-hour,
her medicine is here.
We supply the needs
they have once in a while.
Sometimes, they need
butane gas, medicine.
They have to ask for our help.
Their shanty might be falling apart.
They ask us for some money
to buy construction material,
to buy cookies,
to buy cigarettes even,
toilet paper, soap.
When Christmas comes,
they throw toys for us to catch.
-You'd die to get one.
-It's a lie!
-I wouldn't wanna die!
-I think most people here
are on the dealers' side.
If a dweller dies,
we pay for the burial.
THE COMBAT
On April 20, I was able
to get early to headquarters.
1st MILITARY POLICE BATTALION
l was on the building's veranda
GUN TRAINING RANGE
I was looking at the favelas.
I noticed the tracer rounds
from one favela to the other.
It was a war between dealers,
who were using tracer ammo.
I thought:
"In which other capital in the world,
which is not at war,
can you see something like that?"
Rio de Janeiro is
not in a civil war.
There's a war in the favelas,
between dealers and policemen,
or between dealers
and other dealers.
BOPE'S TRAINING FIELD
FAVELA COMBAT DRILL
During the last 6 months,
100°% of our missions were in favelas.
There were 156 operations
involving confrontation
and maybe the same number
without confrontation.
During confrontations,
we exchanged fire
with heavily armed dealers.
We've acquired an experience
in favela combat
that can't be matched in Brazil.
This has made us
one of the most efficient
urban combat units in the world.
We are certainly better
than any American soldier.
Our confrontations happen
within 10 meters, 15 meters.
SOLDIER MILTON BOPE
Our combat is real.
In the favela,
there are very narrow alleys.
It's rare to find a spot
where 2 shooters
can work side by side.
The 1st man shoots kneeling down.
The second shoots over him,
using his back as support.
Attention!
Fire!
If I see the police, I try to run.
If I can't, I shoot.
For instance,
I'm here selling dope.
If I see the police,
I try to escape.
If I can't, I'll shoot.
I won't let them shoot me first.
I'll get them first.
I won't let them hit me.
They'd kill me.
When we kill the enemy,
we use fireworks.
We celebrate and everything.
We have a party.
It's a victory.
Isn't that worth celebrating?
To kill the enemy is a victory.
Terceiro Comando, for example.
As a minor, I escaped 14 times,
just from one detention
home called Padre Severino.
From another one,
I escaped another 7 times.
When I turned 18,
I was arrested by the 10th Precinct.
I stayed in jail for 9 months
and escaped.
I was free for a month
and got arrested again.
I stayed in jail for another
6 months and escaped again.
Then, I was arrested and
sentenced to 9 years in prison.
They sent me to Polinter,
Água Santa, and so on.
Then, I finally reached
the top security prison in Ilha Grande
I could only achieve
freedom by my own means,
and God's help,
this is by escaping again.
I escaped for the 3rd time.
I was free for only a month.
I was arrested again
under other charges.
I went to jail and suffered
all of that again.
I spent another 2 years
or so in prison.
I was even angrier.
I wanted to lose my life.
I tried to regain my freedom
and here I am, thank God.
What do you do
when you are working?
LICO - 13 YEARS OLD
I watch for the cops.
-Do you carry guns?
-What?
-Have you carried guns?
-Yes.
How about you?
How far did you get in school?
LEANDRO - 14 YEARS OLD
I quit after the 3rd grade.
Can you read?
Not really. I get by.
How was your first mission?
It was cool.
-What did you do?
-I sold drugs.
My first mission was robbery
on the streets.
What do you feel
when you do that?
I feel the desire to steal
from the person.
-Are you afraid you'll die young?
-What?
-We're all going to die someday, right?
What makes a young
person go into that?
This generation,
born in the favela,
which is a third generation,
wants to prove itself
for the entire city.
I think the organization
offers that to them.
ITAMAR SILVA - COMMUNITY LEADER
It offers to the boy the respect he
doesn't get when he chooses to be
a delivery boy for a drugstore.
When he opens the paper
and reads that, at a certain favela,
a young man faced the police,
armed and wearing a ski mask.
This feeds the pride,
the power he believes he has
over a society that doesn't
recognize his true worth.
The heart beats stronger, right?
POLICE HEADQUARTERS
Somebody says he is a success
HÉLIO LUZ CHIEF OF POLICE - RIO
''Finally, one of us is somebody.
One of us can buy
an expensive car.
One of us is able to have
5 women.
One of our own made it in life."
I felt like I was
the king of the world.
When was that?
At the favela when I held
my first gun, I felt like that.
Was it a good feeling?
Yeah, sort of...
Women look at you.
They flirt with you.
Women, especially
from down in the city,
seem to be attracted by young men
with heavy guns.
They go nuts!
They enter even the poorest shacks
to go to bed with them.
Only men with guns are
entitled to go out
with city girls.
If you don't carry a gun...
-They don't even look at you.
-They ignore you.
They are all blond and beautiful.
The bigger the gun, the more
they want to get near them,
the more they want to participate.
I don't starve.
My family doesn't starve.
I walk around with good clothes
because, in this line of business
you have to look good.
-Which jeans do you wear?
-Toulon, Company.
T-shirt?
TCK, Cyclone,
Toulon or Company.
What kind of tennis shoe
do you choose?
I choose Nike.
-Which one?
-Nike, Reebok.
If you had been born in the favela,
what would you be today?
What options would I have?
If I got a job,
I would have to work
12 or 8 hours a day
to make U$ 60 a month.
If I was to get into drug dealing,
I'd make U$ 150 a week.
So it's a good deal.
Don't you think so?
For anybody.
It's not an option if you've never gone
hungry. But if you have, it's a job.
For the social outcast,
it is a good deal.
People line up to get a job.
You might say it's not a job,
but it is.
It's not an option, it's a job.
They make more money
then their fathers do.
They're suicidal.
He watches his brother die,
his cousin die
because they were involved,
but he wants to get involved!
Do you know why?
Because nobody wants this
meager salary anymore.
Drug dealing is a business,
an illegal business.
They occupy an area
left vacant by the government.
The government makes the favela
an area for outcasts.
The minimal wage is
U$ 60 a month?
The drug dealers pay
the kid U$ 150 a week
and that kid goes to work for them.
They will choose it, of course.
PADRE SEVERINO INSTITUTE - FOR
JUVENILE DELINQUENTS 12 TO 18
Hands.
Turn them.
Lift your arms.
Lift your balls.
Lift one leg.
Now, the other.
-Turn around.
-Open your hand.
-Down.
-Turn. Open your mouth.
-Get up. Open your mouth.
-Lift your tongue.
Hands towards
the ground and down.
Get you clothes
and come to this side.
FÁBIO - 16 YEARS OLD
I was arrested because of marijuana.
-Do you work for the dealers?
-No. I just got in trouble.
Is this your first time in here?
Where do you live?
I live at Nova Holanda.
VINÍCIUS - 17 YEARS OLD
Who me? I was selling cocaine.
-Do you work for the dealers?
-No.
I got into this less
than 3 days ago.
-Where did you sell it?
-At Morrinho.
Is this your 1st time?
NELSON 14 YEARS OLD
Yes, sir.
-Why were you arrested?
-I was stealing.
-Where do you live?
-On the streets.
When you are 18 and have a
clean rap sheet, will you stop?
I intend to stay in the favela.
Would you like to get a job?
I want a job dealing drugs.
-Only dealing?
-I like the life.
Why did you get into this?
I saw a lot of suffering.
The police always wants
to beat people up. They have
no respect. They don't care
if they come after the dealer
and get the worker.
They can't do their job well.
LAW ENFORCEMENT
MAURINHO 16 YEARS OLD
The policemen arrested me.
They booked me and said
they were going to kill me.
They shot me in the leg.
I was squatting down.
The policeman came
and said: ''Get up.''
He pointed at my leg and shot it.
MAURO 15 YEARS OLD
When they get us, they take our money
and give us trouble on top of it.
Everybody knows the biggest
crooks are not the criminals,
but the cops.
If a cop arrests me, for instance,
he'll try to get money
not to take me to jail.
He's not making only his salary.
If you had a good television
set or a good VCR,
they would take it away.
They wouldn't even ask
if you had proof that
you've bought it in a store.
They'd say that it was stolen,
even when the owner
was an honest person.
I'll say to myself
The police are corrupt.
The institution was designed
to be violent and corrupt.
And people think that's odd.
Why do I say it was
designed that way?
Because it was created
to protect the State
and the elite.
I practice law enforcement
to protect and serve the status quo
No beating around the bush.
It keeps the favela under control.
How do you keep 2 million
people under control,
people who make US$ 60 a month,
when they make any?
How do you keep all
the underprivileged
...under control and calm?
-With with repression?
Of course!
How else would it be?
When the policeman
climbs up to the favela,
he's prepared to be
aggressive with everybody:
old people, kids...
Once, I was inside my home
and the cop said:
''Listen, I don't care if people
are crippled, blind or old;
I'll just beat the
heck out of them.
And I don't want anyone
to say anything.''
Sometimes, when a kid from
the community is arrested,
instead of going back down
to take the kid to jail
they climb the favela's hill
even higher.
The women, mother, cousins,
sisters, have to follow
to stop anything from happening.
By then, everybody thinks
the boy is facing
some form of aggression
or even execution.
We follow them, we fight, we cry.
They push us around
and ask us to step back.
We don't, because we know
what will happen.
Then, we stick to them.
That way, they can't have
a moment alone with the boy
and nothing will happen to him.
They end upcoming
down with the boy,
taking him to the precinct
to see if he's really guilty.
Sometimes, cops don't come
to arrest. They come to kill.
It's a political police.
This is an unfair society.
We are here to protect
this unfair society.
The underprivileged is under control.
He'll pay if he gets uncontrollable.
At the favela,
things are very sophisticated.
In South Africa, they put up
barbed wire. Here, we don't.
"Don't complain.
Pay your taxes."
People are used to it.
They conform to it.
The poor have TV sets
and watch them.
When the soap opera is over,
they turn it off,
and look at the favela
What are they supposed
to reproduce?
There are not violent.
They stay inside.
They are so stupid
they just stay inside.
When they do come out,
they are told to go back,
and they do.
I like to stay at the São Conrado
Fashion Mall's veranda. Why?
There's a country club and
the largest favela in Rio side by side.
If this country was a violent
place, how could that be?
Would that be possible?
This is a tranquil country.
The safety policy adopted is efficient.
Now, the question is:
does the society
want a police without corruption?
It's easy.
I'm not speaking theoretically.
I've worked in the interior
with squads of 30 men
who wouldn't touch bribes.
The first 2 months were great.
The chief warden controlled
the town's drug deal operation.
The town was in a state of panic.
We got there with 30 honest men.
We were cheered for 2 months.
On the 3rd. month, the supermarket
owner's bodyguard
slapped a kid who was
stealing a bottle of liquor.
The kid and the bodyguard
were arrested.
The supermarket owner said:
''Sir, he is a thief.''
We said: ''But the bodyguard
can't hit a thief.''
They were both booked.
Then, social clubs
wouldn't invite me anymore
for the Wednesday
night dinners.
They stopped doing that...
Then, a rich farmer
committed a murder.
He was booked.
End of story.
There was trouble.
What was seen as nice
Was no more.
We pose a question to society:
is there a real interest
in an honest police?
An honest police will act
like in other countries.
You don't park in a forbidden area,
because you'll get a ticket.
You don't drive through a red light
or draw a graffiti.
You don't do anything wrong.
Let's say we operate both in the
favela and in the rich neighborhoods.
People will have to stop
sniffing coke at their chic parties.
There would be search warrants
and doors getting kicked down
at the beachfront condos.
Isn't that right?
This is an honest police.
It doesn't have limits.
Will the society handle it?
It's people who can pay
US$ 500 for coke who are making
our profit. Most of them are
from the upper class. Poor people
can't spend US$ 500 in cocaine,
because his kid will
starve the next day.
Rich people spend it,
because they can afford it.
The middle class
supplies the money.
With that money,
the dealers buy more guns.
It's a vicious circle.
-The middle class...
-The are also the enemy.
In a later date,
they scream against the violence.
THE GUNS
This is the armament
BOPE utilizes to fight crime.
This is a German
military rifle, H&K 7.62.
It has been found
with the dealers also.
This is a 9 mm
H&K submachine gun.
This is the most sophisticated
submachine gun in the world.
We have a 5.7x28 caliber
P-90 submachine gun.
We also have a 5.56 caliber
MD-2 military rifle.
This is the same caliber
as an AR-15,
but it weighs almost
twice as much.
This gun...
The only police in the world
using this gun is in Rio de Janeiro's.
In many occasions,
this gun has saved our team.
It's a gun you won't find on
European or American policemen.
It's a military gun, designed
to give support under fire.
In Rio de Janeiro,
it's instrumental,
because of the intense
confrontations we have with dealers.
This is a .30,
made in Brazil.
This is an AK-47, Russian.
This is a grenade
launching AR-15. American.
This is a 9 mm PT-92.
It has been made in Israel.
Do policemen sell you guns?
We don't sell them guns,
but they...
You know.
Sometimes, they come
in a police pick-up,
open the back,
and tell us to choose.
But those are cops we know.
-What kind of gun do you use?
-G-3, rifles,
CARLINHOS 16 YEARS OLD
9 mm pistols, .45,
PT, .38 caliber... It depends
on the guns they give us.
Today,Rio de Janeiro
dealers use AK-47,
which is Russian,
it's a guerrilla rifle.
They use AR-15, grenades,
rocket launchers...
Recently, we've noticed they're
using night vision equipment,
something even
our platoon doesn't have.
POLICE WAREHOUSE FOR
CONFISCATED WEAPONS
When it comes to drug dealing,
we must mention gun smuggling.
The profit from drugs
and gun selling are related.
Look at the guns they make
by the end of the century.
Why produce a rifle
that shoots 700 bullets a minute
by the end of the century?
Isn't the Berlin Wall down?
What 's the issue?
Are there frontiers
to be drawn?
There is no real interest in this.
Then, why do they make those?
The gun made in Switzerland
won't be sold in Libya, will it?
If it's offered to the lRA,
It won't be bought.
The lRA doesn't have Sig-Sauers.
We have modern armament
that even Libya doesn't have.
The makers know that it comes
to this country. Why?
Because they can sell it
for the highest price.
OK, then. We have to close
gun factories in Switzerland,
in the US... Colt is American,
and the AR-15 is made by Colt.
I want to close Colt 's factory.
This is how they handle
The drug war,
and I thing it's fair.
It should be the same for us.
They want to interfere in Colombia.
They come into plantations,
and they want to control production
in Colombia and in Peru. I want to
have control, to close Colt, in the US,
and Sig-Sauer, in Switzerland.
What is the real issue?
There are favelas
with 100 armed men.
They carry sophisticated armament.
The day they realize
the status quo,
and they decide to come
down in an organized manner,
they'll take over.
DISRUPTION
The brains behind drug dealing
and kidnapping are in prison.
They're all in prison.
ERNALDO MEDEIROS ''UÊ''
ARRESTED IN MARCH, 96
About 15 men were arrested.
ROBERTINHO ''DE LUCAS''
ARRESTED IN JANUARY, 97
They were gang leaders.
MARCIO NEPOMUCENO ''VP''
ARRESTED IN OCTOBER, 96
JORGE LUÍS ''DE ACARI''
ARRESTED IN MARCH, 96
All dealers that left prison died.
There are no powerful Comando
Vermelho leader on the streets.
-Who killed them?
-The criminals themselves.
Either them or the police.
The link between the prison
and the community is over.
APOLINARIO DE SOUZA ''NANAI''
KILLED IN APRIL, 81.
People who lived the era
KILLED IN MAY, 92.
they usually say:
"It was born and died.
It lived for one minute."
KILLED IN JUNE, 94.
Some people died
in their first mission.
KILLED IN AUGUST, 87.
Others were arrested. The whole
thing fell apart.
It got all disorganized.
The consequence is
that people dropped out of it.
Things changed a great deal
and all that was left was the myth,
the name Comando Vermelho.
Now, we have the frightening
myth of the Comando Vermelho.
They tried to reorganize
in prison.
It didn't work.
Fortunately for us,
it didn't work.
It didn't sparkle.
It went bad because they'd
deviate from it, using drugs and so on.
-I'm a criminal, all right!
-Why?
Why?
Because I like good things.
I was never into being
oppressed by society.
There's no way society
will oppress me.
What I have was not given
to me by society.
-I got on my own.
-What did you get?
With about 3 bank robberies,
I got my own house,
thank God,
and some other things.
We don't want to take people's lives,
we want our own money.
I won't work for US$ 50 a month.
My grandmother is over 70 years old.
She worked her whole life.
What did she get?
She doesn't have anything.
What kind of society is this?
I want a Mizuno tennis shoe.
It costs over US$ 100.
If I work,
I'll never buy a Mizuno.
I'll rob money then.
I'm not scorning the workers,
but I'll rob from people
who have money.
They don't amount to nothing.
They are the tip of the system.
They're excluded from society.
When they're alive,
they control all of that.
When they die, it's over.
Jorge Luiz's son has no
guarantee that he'll become
Acari's drug lord.
They don't even have that.
It's a retail operation.
A favela leader like UÊ is
nothing but a retail manager.
He doesn't even know
how to manage profits.
How is UÊ going
to manage US$ 5 million?
He's just the guy
who handles the tent.
That's all he is.
He handles 50 street market tents.
It's basic, isn't it?
No criminal got rich,
bought land and stuff.
They don't stay on
the media spot light either.
Actually, if we analyze it,
we'll see that
the dealer sell drugs
for a clientele in his own community.
Do you understand?
Drug dealing doesn't
bring any transformation
dealers don't change anything,
they are lost in the middle
of the whole thing.
Their inconformity grows and
fades in 24 hours. It's short-lived.
If you check the history of
either the Terceiro Comando
or the Comando Vermelho,
you'll see that neither
had a social background.
They defend their
own interests.
They don't have
a political view of society.
They are like wild animals
fighting to see who is stronger.
Drug dealing does not
replace the State in the favela.
They might help people,
but they don't have the structure
to replace the State.
This is a lie.
There might be some kind
of rudimentary structure.
They're stupid.
Uê stayed in 5-star hotels.
It's stupid! Is there anything
easier than catching Uê
at a 5-star hotel?
It's stupid.
He could stay in a 3-star
hotel and remain unnoticed.
He goes to a 5-star hotel.
We don't even have to ask who he is.
This is the deal.
It's chaos. We live in chaos here.
15-year-old kids have no
idea of who is the leader.
One shoots the other.
It's a crazy situation.
Kids with Sig-Sauers, AR-15...
CHAOS
The dealer is escaping
through the window!
MANCHETE TV STOCKSHOT
The police keeps shooting!
There's another dealer trying to
escape. He's gonna jump! Look!
You put the squeeze on this
favela and they go to the next.
You go to the next, they move
again. It's an endless war.
Even if you go over...
For 2 weeks,
almost every night, the BOPE
would kill a dealer over there.
It'd confiscate a pistol
or a rifle and kill a dealer.
Did it solve a thing?
It didn't. It didn't solve anything.
For the young people there...
There are dozens of young
men who are not part of it,
but are waiting in line
to get in on it.
Maybe, the new leader,
because he's even younger...
We have just witnessed
the formation
of the youth's organization,
Comando Vermelho Jovem, CVJ.
Being younger, they are
even more prone to violence.
If we have a shoot-out
with the police,
many times they back away
and leave 1 or 2 soldiers behind.
If we get the soldier,
we tie him up, beat him,
shoot him, put him in
a barrel and set fire to it.
When did you get into this life?
When I was 11 years old.
What was your 1st mission?
My first mission was
to kill an informant.
At 11 years old...
What did he do?
What did you do?
He told the police we pack
cocaine and marihuana.
He told it to the ''worms'',
the policemen.
Then, I set him on fire.
I got 7 car tires,
I mean, 7 truck tires.
I got 5 liters of gasoline.
I lit a match
and set him on fire.
Who asked you to do that?
It was my boss.
How did you feel
after doing that?
I felt normal,
like I feel right now.
If I have to kill again,
I'll do it.
When I kill?
The only feeling I have is
that I've fulfilled my duty.
If I say I got home
and couldn't sleep, I'd be lying.
Have you ever killed
a policeman?
No, I haven't had
that opportunity.
I stay on a roof at
the top of the favela
with a 9 mm pistol
that has a laser beam.
I point the beam at their
chest or head, and they run.
The beam marks the place
where the bullet will enter.
If it's on your forehead,
the bullet will hit it.
I intend to go back on the streets
and do it all over again.
-This time it will be worst.
-What will you do?
I'll rob more banks,
more armored cars.
I'll raise millions,
and help the needy.
The police fights a personal war.
If we kill a dealer,
other dealers will hate the police.
They kill a policeman,
and then we hate them.
It develops at that level.
The war is almost personal now.
JOÃO LUIS ALVES REFORM SCHOOL
FOR JUVENILE DELINQUENTS
12 YEARS OLD AND UNDER
All I know is that
I want to have a family.
I want a new life.
My mother couldn't raise
my brothers and sisters
ZINHO- 1O YEARS OLD
because she was kind of nervous.
She couldn't raise them.
What did she do?
She had the kids...
I don't know what happened.
She sold her kids.
-What did you do at the favela?
-I was a''fireworks kid''.
What does a''fireworks kid'' do?
I used to make money
at the favela.
But what exactly does
a''fireworks kid'' do?
When the ''heat'' came,
I'd use fireworks.
It works just like an alarm.
People have time to hide.
The policemen did this.
I want money for this.
I don't see an end to it.
There's no light
at the end of the tunnel.
I see no solution.
WEARINESS
POLICEMAN ROGÉRIO DE OLIVEIRA
SANTOS' BURIAL
HE WAS KILLED
FIGHTING DEALERS
MINOR EDMAR DOS
SANTOS' BURIAL
HE WAS KILLED
FIGHTING POLICEMEN
JARDIM DA SAUDADE
CEMETERY
SÃO JOÃO BATISTA
I lost many friends:
Cidinho, Nininho,
Orlando Jogador,
Dição, Siri...
I lost a lot of people.
Sergeant Renato died here,
at Morro da Mineira,
in the middle of the night,
shot in the head.
There's Lieutenant Vega,
Sergeant Brazuna...
It will never end.
The war will never end.
I'll lead this kind
of life until I die.
-Why?
-Because this is my destiny.
I made it my destiny.
If the problem of the drug
trafficking is serious,
the good guys have lost the war.
They have been at it for a long time,
and accomplished nothing.
The only government agency that
goes into the favela is the police.
The police alone is not
going to solve anything.
I took over prisons with guns:
machine guns, grenades,
pistols, revolvers.
I attacked police stations
and police cars.
What for?
What history have I written?
Is crime history?
No, it isn't.
I come home from a difficuIt mission,
in which one of us
has been shot,
in which a dealer
was killed,
our famiIy doesn't even ask:
''How was your day?
How was the mission?
What did you do?''
They don't ask anything anymore.
I'm tired of this
kind of work.
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
''PIMPOLHO''
HOMELESS CHILD - 1981-1993
HÉLIO DE SOUZA SANTOS
METALWORKER - 1965-1993
LIEUTENANT JOSÉ AREAS
AZEVEDO JUNIOR - 1973-1997
''FORMIGÃO''
DEALER - 198O-1998
''GAMBAZINHO''
HOMELESS CHILD - 1977-1993
LUÍS CLÁUDIO FELICIANO
OFFICE WORKER - 1969-1993
SOLDIER RONALDO ALVES
DA CRUZ - 198O-1998
THREE MONTHS AFTER
THIS INTERVIEW, HÉLIO LUZ
RESIGNED HIS POST AS CHIEF
OF POLICE. TODAY,
HE IS STATE REPRESENTATIVE
FOR RIO DE JANEIRO.
ADRIANO WAS ARRESTED
IN JANUARY 1999.
IN MARCH, HE ESCAPED
ONCE MORE FROM PRISON
AND WAS KILLED ON JUNE 22, 1999.