Neckbone finds out about Sleep...
he's coming for our families.
Where is Neckbone?!
I just wanted to tell you I'm sorry.
I got a better offer.
(GUNFIRE)
JEREMY: It's important you get
this stuff with your mom resolved.
You're gonna have to get closure.
We're throwing a net over the cop gangs.
We'll drop paper on the
Vipers, Berserkers and Ravens.
It's over. I'm coming home.
Call me when you land, okay?
They're bringing you in.
- SAC will get some time off your sentence.
- No! To hell with this!
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- Cover!
Okay, guns on the ground.
I need to know everything you
gave the Feds about my bosses.
LOURDES: Something happened to Pete.
- You told us we were gonna be safe!
- Calm down, baby.
Tell me exactly what happened.
I've got video.
The kind that'll prove you
knew all about the WMD.
- What the hell?
- Get out.
You give me the damn flash drive.
Now!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- I shouldn't have done that.
- Payback's a bitch.
You are going to tell me exactly
what FBI know about my employers.
- HAMMOND: That's enough!
- (BONE CRUNCHES)
- (BYRD SCREAMS)
- (GUNFIRE)
- HAMMOND: Who are you?
- You're free to go.
HAMMOND: No!
GRANDFATHER ASSASSIN:
You shot him, not us.
The man you killed was my friend.
I got a guy I need you to look into.
I've got bigger problems.
(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
NECKBONE: Took a minute...
but here we are.
I swear to God, man...
I had no choice, man.
- Them Colombians were gonna come in and...
- Had...
a better deal?
You already told me that, remember?
It ain't like that, man.
There's more to the story.
I'm sure there is.
But all that's in the past.
I mean, what's done is done.
Today's a new day.
I'ma make this right, Bone.
- I promise.
- No.
You won't.
I will.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYS)
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
♪ ♪
(SOBS)
My name's Aria and I
worked with your dad.
He was very proud of you.
Round up Hammond and the others.
And put this damn thing
to bed once and for all.
Come on.
♪ We don't ever fall out
over money, that's loyalty ♪
♪ Got product moving fast, keep
'em coming, that's loyalty ♪
♪ No one got left behind,
I brought 'em with, that's loyalty ♪
♪ If there's ever a problem ♪
♪ And I need a hit, that's loyalty ♪
Lourdes!
Veronica! We gotta go!
Lourdes?
Shit.
(PHONE BEEPING)
LOURDES (ON VOICEMAIL):
Hi! Leave a message!
Where'd you go?
Babe, I need to talk to
you. It's important, alright?
Call me back.
Where is she?
I have no idea.
Listen, I'm sorry about what happened.
It was uglier than I
thought it would be.
- He was an FBI agent.
- I know.
One that was going to
eventually testify against you.
From now on, I want you to
stay the hell out of my life.
And my family's life, you hear me?
You fucking just don't get it, do you?
It's you she's running away from,
not me.
(GUNSHOT)
Where you been?
Getting patched up.
Long story.
What's going on?
Byrd's dead.
And Price is gunning for us.
Dead?
Yeah.
How?
Steve?
I don't want to talk about it.
This is my burner's number.
Get yourself one.
And then what?
You get out of town and wait
until I get this under control.
And how you gonna do that?
I'm gonna turn myself in.
Try and work out a deal for all of us.
That is a shit plan.
As a matter of fact, that is the
king of shit plans and you know it.
It could work.
The Feds love a headline.
And the leader of a cop
gang pleading guilty?
That's a great one.
I brought this on us.
We robbed that bank to
pay for Tom's lawyer.
What's that?
"Get Out of Jail Free" card.
For all of us.
Heads up. Some suits just
pulled up to the curb.
Shit.
(DOOR JIGGLES)
- FBI! Open the door!
- Kick it!
Don't kick my door.
Hey, easy, man.
Place is clear.
CARL: Of course it is.
Hey, y'all hear that one
about the confused bitch
that walked into an empty bar?
Hook him up.
I don't know. It's a great joke.
Look, I can offer you the
exact same deal I gave Winters.
PRICE: Winters is a street cop.
I'm a federal agent.
I can provide cover for
you in ways that she can't.
So you're just gonna have to do a
little bit better on those numbers
to make it worth my while.
Jesus.
- Seen enough?
- Yeah, kill it.
This is big.
Like I said,
"Get Out of Jail Free" card.
Only if we play it right.
So what now?
Get a few copies of that flash
drive made and wait for my call.
How long am I waiting?
Hours? Days?
If you don't hear from me in 24 hours,
take a copy of the flash
drive straight to the DOJ.
It has to be far enough
above Price's head
that she can't squash it.
- And what are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna reach out to Price.
Negotiate terms face to face.
(PHONE RINGING)
What?
Hello to you, too.
What is it, Mom?
ABIGAIL (ON PHONE): You know
I hate calling like this,
but, um...
But what?
I got a problem.
Goddamn Stanley, he, uh...
What about him?
He, um...
We had an argument.
And?
Shit.
He hit you?
And he locked me out of my damn house.
I'm sitting here like a fool.
Call the cops.
Mom? Mom!
Did you hear what I
said? Call the police.
It's not right what he did.
Alright, for Christ's sake.
I'm coming over. Don't move.
♪ ♪
Shit.
Hey! Hey! What's going on?
- Hey!
- Ma'am, put your weapon down!
- Okay, okay, relax, relax.
- Put it down!
Ma'am, lay the weapon
down on the ground now!
Okay, just... I'm putting it.
I'm doing it.
There. It's there.
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- FBI AGENT #2: FBI! We have a warrant!
♪ ♪
Mom?
(KNOCKING)
The hell's going on?
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(OBJECT CLATTERS)
Officer Beach, let me see your hands!
Put your hands on your head!
Lace your fingers! Do it!
Let's go!
Spread your legs. Spread them!
You know the drill.
Karen Beach, I'm
placing you under arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be provided
to you by the courts.
Do you understand these rights?
Better than you do, bitch.
ABIGAIL: She dropped
something over here.
In the bushes.
Right here.
That mother of yours
is a real piece of work.
Nothing to say? No smart-ass comment?
Get her out of here.
(CRUNCH)
RAMOS: Hey!
They almost got me at the house.
They hit up Carl's as well.
Shit.
So what are we gonna do?
We can't keep running like this.
We don't have the cash for it.
We're meeting with Tom in a few hours.
- Why?
- 'Cause he's family, that's why.
He's leading the Ravens now.
And we got to hear him out.
Okay.
How long are we gonna
be in this shit hole?
Until we ain't.
Hey, hey! Dump that
before it brings us heat.
It's a burner, too.
They ain't up on it yet.
- Did you use it to call your wife?
- Yeah, once.
Alright, maybe two or three
times, but she didn't answer.
What if they're tracking
her phone looking for you?
They can ping the location
of incoming calls, man.
Give me your phone.
- Come on, Hamm.
- Don't take chances, Pete.
She's not gonna know what
number to call me back at.
I know you're hurting right now...
but if you call her on that phone,
you're putting us all at risk.
COLE: Gimme the damn phone.
(GROANS)
COLE: You okay, Steve?
Yeah. It's just with all
this shit going on, my
stomach's killing me.
Look, you need some food up in ya.
All of us do.
- I'll be back.
- HAMMOND: Okay.
(BELL RINGS)
(SIZZLING)
(BEEPING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
We've got company.
Get out of there right now. Go!
Sir, stop where you are
and show me your hands.
What's all this, man?
Why y'all sweating me, huh?
Put your hands in the air.
Y'all see this shit, right?!
Look, my hands are up.
They can't get no higher.
Y'all always looking for a
reason to shoot a brother.
BYSTANDER: Yeah, what's
up with that, man?
You can all see he ain't got no gun.
- What did he do?
- Yeah, what did I do, Officer, huh? Tell me!
What did I do?!
Say it! Can't even tell me.
Too black for you?
- Come here.
- Is being black a crime?!
Is that what I did? Huh?!
Man, take your hands off me!
Bullshit!
Where's Cole?
- They got him.
- Huh?
Listen, why don't you check
with your guy at division.
- See if knows anything about him.
- Copy.
You're serious?
Your job is to keep your brother safe.
Don't lecture me about
being there for someone else.
If I could've done
something, I would've.
- (TOM SCOFFS)
- Got it. Thanks.
Cole hasn't been brought
in for processing yet,
but Beach has.
Goddammit!
Yeah, so much for your plan, huh?
Let's be honest,
your ideas never
really pan out, do they?
(CHUCKLES)
This is coming from the
guy who brought us heat
when he went to jail in
the fucking first place.
- RAMOS: Enough with this shit.
- TOM: Listen.
You two assholes, you killed Sleep,
so I'm not really the one...
who caused your mother
to be killed, am I?
I loved her more than you ever could.
Yeah, you watch your fucking mouth!
- Take a shot!
- Chill the hell out, the both of you!
- Come on!
- RAMOS: Hey, listen to me!
Listen to me.
We're gonna get that piece of shit.
But first, we gotta beat this.
When I first got into
this, you both made me swear
that the Ravens came before anything.
Whether it was the department, family,
- or revenge!
- Yeah, nice speech.
But the both of you,
you stopped being Ravens
the second you started
working with the Feds.
The man showed up at my office!
I know who it is!
And I have it under control.
No, if you had it under control,
none of this would be happening.
I destroyed the flash drive.
And as far as that man
that tried to blackmail you,
it's only a matter of
time before I arrest him.
No. Look, this is too crazy.
That mom showing up
at the press conference
accusing me of murder in front
of everybody and now this.
You do what you need to do,
but until this settles, I am
waiting this out in France.
Running away is not a good idea.
It shows consciousness of guilt.
(SIGHS) I will handle this. Trust me.
I know what I'm talking about.
Fine, but if any of
this blows back on me,
I'm taking you down with me.
Yeah, good. Give me the phone.
Now get back in the trunk.
No. No, no, I... I did
exactly what you told me to do.
You said you were gonna let me go.
What? With the company
you've been keeping?
Not a chance.
Now get your sorry ass
back in the fucking trunk.
- Come on, come on, get in.
- Easy.
That's it. Good boy.
Goddammit.
(PHONE DIALING)
(LINE RINGING)
911 OPERATOR: 911, what's
the nature of your emergency?
There's a man with a gun at
the corner of 7th and Chase.
Listen, Tom's gone.
You're all I got.
I really don't want to do this.
I don't have a solution for that,
but I admire the problem.
Very funny.
Listen, brother, let's fix this shit.
'Cause if not, we're all screwed.
Come here, bro.
I love you, man.
Get outta here.
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(GUNFIRE)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Everyone else is on the run,
but you turned yourself in.
I'm delivering a message for Hammond.
He has a copy of the flash drive.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Maybe the Department of Justice will.
They took a burner off me
when they put the cuffs on.
You're gonna want to get it back.
Keep it close.
Hammond's gonna call you
with the terms of our deal.
If Hammond actually had a copy,
Beach wouldn't have tried so hard
to dump the one she had on her.
(DOOR BANGS OPEN)
FBI! Hands where I can see them!
Who the hell are you?
Who the hell am I? I'm the
guy that's doing exactly
what the guy with the
gun is telling him to do.
Search him.
Frank Albanese. What are you doing here?
I'm the GM of a casino.
Ms. Beach has a line of credit with us.
One which is now delinquent.
What's in your hand?
The door was open.
I thought I'd leave my card.
Put your hands behind your back.
Come on, is this really necessary?
Do it! Now!
(PHONE RINGING)
HAMMOND (ON PHONE):
I want to make a deal.
Whatever you're trying
to do, it won't work.
I have a copy of the flash drive
Beach kept in her apartment.
No, you don't.
Your friend Frank just
got caught looking for it.
So, you're bluffing.
Frank was just a distraction.
I knew you'd have people
at Beach's apartment.
That's why I sent him in there.
- Bullshit.
- Is it?
As soon as your guys
walked Frank to the car,
I went in and got the other flash drive.
(SIGHS)
(CAR APPROACHING)
If this is some kinda
game you're running,
- or an attempt...
- It's not a game.
It's not a set-up.
I'm not wired.
A wire can be anywhere.
- Feels like you're looking for more than a wire.
- I am.
Where's the flash drive?
- Where is it!
- It's not here.
If you want it, you're
gonna have to make a deal.
You better prove you have
it, or that's not happening.
Don't be an idiot, son. She's
not gonna keep her end of it.
HAMMOND: What are you doing here, Tom?
What are you doing here?
Whatever this bitch promised you,
it's all lies.
It's all lies!
Only way to fix it, that's why I'm here!
HAMMOND: Don't!
He's just looking for a reason.
- Drop the gun.
- Put it down, son.
Or I'll drop you where you stand.
Everybody calm down!
That deal you wanted,
I will make it happen.
- (GUN COCKS)
- I want more than that.
I want retribution.
Her and Shankman are making millions!
HAMMOND: This ain't about money!
This is about our guys.
Now get the hell outta here!
I ain't going anywhere!
Question is...
are you capable of pulling that trigger?
If I have to, yeah.
Shankman's given me
stock in his company!
I'll split it down the
middle with both of you!
What about the Ravens?
We can say that the case was tainted.
That Byrd was dirty and that
everything that he wrote in his report
was fabricated and embellished.
Every one of your people will walk free.
How do we know you're
not playing us, huh? Huh?!
I'll prove it.
I'm gonna call Shankman right now.
(PHONE BEEPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
RYDER: We have Shankman in custody.
I heard everything, Aria.
Even your phone call.
(SOBBING)
RYDER: You have the
right to remain silent.
And I'd use that if I were you.
- Let's go.
- PRICE: No, no!
- Get off of me!
- RYDER: Get her gun.
Relax, Aria.
It's over. It's over.
(SOBBING)
RYDER: It's over.
When you approached me with this,
we never specified the exact terms.
We didn't have to.
The terms are obvious.
My guys walk, every one of them.
I can't do that.
I'm willing to drop charges on you two
as long as I have your
word that the both of you
will testify against the other Ravens.
- Kiss my ass.
- We just proved Price is dirty.
That means everything she
touched is compromised.
Not everything.
Some of it's salvageable.
You're an idiot if you press this.
I don't need legal advice from you.
How about some career advice?
Yours is over unless you walk away.
Every lawyer that reps my guys
will file a discovery motion.
What Price did will be national news
unless you contain the damage on this.
It's addition through subtraction.
You lose a few cases,
but you keep your job.
I can't just ignore the fact
that there are gangs
inside the police force.
You don't have to.
Listen, you catch us riding dirty,
you make a fresh case.
All we're asking for is
to wake up tomorrow morning
with a clean slate.
Is it a deal?
(LIGHT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ON TV)
(PHONE VIBRATING)
Hello?
Princesa?
Are you okay? Where's your mom?
Mom, it's Dad.
What do you want, Pete?
- Where are you?
- I'm not telling you.
Listen, I need to see you.
That's the only way to
make things right again.
I wish we could.
We're not coming back. I'm
not gonna raise my daughter
around men like you or my father.
Don't say that.
Listen to me, it's all behind me now.
The Feds are out of my life.
We can go back to the way things were.
The way things were? Living a lie?
You're a gang member, Pete.
The badge doesn't change that.
Just...
for the sake of our daughter,
be a man. Stay out of our lives.
Here. Say goodbye to your father.
Mom says I have to say goodbye.
It's okay, princesa.
I love you.
I love you so much.
You know that, right?
Love you too, Dad.
Bye.
Bye, baby.
Give me the phone.
(PHONE BEEPS)
You're gonna be staying
with your dad from now on.
What I did is wrong,
but I want you to know
that everything I did,
I did for you, okay?
Can you put your sister on the phone?
(SIGHS SHAKILY)
Okay, I understand.
Tell her I will talk to her soon, okay?
I love you.
I have given my life to this bureau.
And now I am losing my pension, too.
Can't I just resign?
You'll serve less than three years.
And then what am I gonna do?
That's for you to decide.
Not me.
(DOOR CLOSES)
JEREMY: I appreciate the
confidence you have in me.
But this isn't really what I do.
You're the only one I trust.
Why?
Because it's delicate, and...
complicated.
But you said yourself that
I couldn't give you closure
when it came to your mother.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, well.
She gave me all the closure I needed.
So, now...
I want to focus on the future.
And that means, you have to fix us.
If you think she's messed up,
wait till you get inside my head.
♪ ♪
Hey, Pearl.
Hi.
Um, I made some pasta for you,
and I put it by the door.
You don't have to eat
it if you don't want to.
Thanks.
But I need the Tupperware back.
How's the neighborhood?
Are you sure you want to know?
Yeah, I really want to know.
Um, okay.
So there was this suspicious car
parked down the street earlier.
I saw it when I came to put
the pasta on your doorstep.
You got a plate or something?
I'll run it for you tomorrow.
Didn't have any plates.
But the three men that were
in it were up to no good.
I'm sure about that.
There were three men?
Latino guys in suits.
They could've been family.
It was an old man and
the others were younger.
(GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING)
VICTOR: So next week sounds good to you?
- MAN: Works for me.
- VICTOR: Perfect.
Set up a meeting.
Get some papers ready.
And then...
Excuse me. Something has come up.
Could I have a few minutes
with my friend here?
MAN: Certainly.
_
Gracias.
There's a debt to be paid.
But it isn't yours.
The Ravens aren't under the
control of the FBI anymore.
They're resourceful.
And to my boss,
that makes them more valuable than you.
(SCOFFS)
That was not part of our agreement.
Agreements change.
Scared.
Where's Neckbone?!
(HONKY TONK MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ You can run on for a long time ♪
♪ Run on for a long time ♪
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
Oh, hell no.
This shit is whack, man.
It's garbage.
TOM: Oh, I don't know.
Something about it feels right.
You've been playing it real smart, man.
Rolling without a crew has made it
a hell of a lot harder to find you.
But find you we did.
♪ Tell the rambler, the
gambler, the back biter ♪
♪ Tell 'em that God's
gonna cut 'em down ♪
You ain't running!
Not this time.
You wanna get away, your
best bet is to man up.
Pull that gun.
Man, y'all ain't shit.
Yeah, I see what's up.
There's too many witnesses out
there so you need an excuse.
And I damn sure ain't giving you one.
So I surrender, assholes.
Arrest me, Officers.
That's a real smart play.
You know...
I wish your little brother
would've done the same.
I can't lie though.
Would've been kinda
poetic to use this on you.
Right here.
Come on!
(GUNFIRE)
(NECKBONE COUGHING)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
♪ I got the animal animal ambition ♪
(UPBEAT IRISH MUSIC PLAYS)
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -