We didn't take a single step
outside during the month of June.
The moment I came to believe all
the things that he went through,
my heart felt strangely at ease.
That feeling that I had
touched fate with my hands...
The fact that a world that
I did not know existed...
That the world I could see with
my eyes was not all there was...
It felt like an epiphany, very unfamiliar,
but it also strangely made me
feel relaxed, and gave me peace.
♪ On an early spring day ♪
♪ Like a dream ♪
♪ You came to me ♪
♪ I knew that I would love you forever ♪
Let's...
listen to this song until
we're a hundred years old.
♪ On a summer beach ♪
♪ that happy sand castle ♪
Are you embarrassed?
♪ By the waves ♪
I don't have the right to boast,
and I have the desire to boast.
So a small concert is fitting.
Whoa, you are very modest.
Please say something to our viewers.
Ah, what should I say?
I live thanks to you, everyone.
Thank you so much.
Let's be happy. Go, go, go. Fighting!
We finally left our home and
emerged outside when June ended.
So this is the person you've been
seeing in your visions, all this time?
Nice to meet you.
My name is Park Soon Taek.
It's all... true.
It's possible to see the future, but it
doesn't mean it happens exactly that way.
It can be similar to the vision,
or it can be completely different.
In the middle, if something changes,
the future is bound to change.
Are you still seeing visions?
No, I see nothing at all now.
Then, it's all over, right?
We should consider nothing to be completely
over, as long as we live, right?
- Don't say it so vaguely, please.
- What am I saying that sounds vague?
So...
we don't have to worry about
death, or such things anymore?
Well, everyone's going to die at some
point. It's not as if we are phoenixes.
Did I say something wrong?
Let's live together. I
can't leave you alone.
Thinking about how you couldn't tell anyone and
just trembled alone, it makes me feel so bad.
- Let's live together.
- I've never trembled, once.
And I've never been afraid.
I'm grateful that you liked me first,
but don't say such things first.
I'll be the one to propose to you.
- Hold on, just a moment.
- We're almost done. - Hey, Park Hoon.
Help us carry this. Come on.
Help us. Hold this, it's heavy.
Where are you going? Aish! Really!
Go, go, go.
Yeah, we're all done.
I got it.
Hand it to me too. Here, here.
The seizure order has been cleared.
Really? Is that true?
Hey!
Move everything back out.
I wish he'd told us earlier. Now you tell
us, after we've moved everything in?
Look at my hand trembling. My hands have never
trembled in my whole life from being tired.
Park Do Kyung, this guy. I know
he's hiding somewhere watching us.
He knew we just moved everything in, and
that is why he's calling right now.
Is he looking at us through binoculars?
I'm 100% sure. That pervert.
Should we start moving it back, then?
No! Call movers!
Seizure Notice Stickers
You did nothing wrong. Live comfortably.
Stay far away from Chairman Jang.
Just consider the funds you spent
buying that debt as a loss.
Then, I'll be going.
You shouldn't do business. You won't do.
Aigoo. All they do is talk
but they never do anything.
- Move!
- You can't go in.
- Don't you know who I am?
- Madam Heo, you can't go in.
- Just move!
- You can't!
- If you do this, it's troubling.
- You stupid humans. Out of my way!
Madam Heo, you must not do this.
Ah! That hurts!
So I heard about it. You played
around with my Do Kyung.
Why do you live this way, you sad human?
Hey!
Move! Let go!
Hey! What is the use having a lot of money?
You can't even go outside.
All you ever do is stay inside your
house all day playing board games
and making young guys fight each other!
Hey! Don't mess with a bitch
who has nothing to lose.
You, if you ever even look like you're
going to do anything to my Do Kyung...
Then! Just!
I will set my body on fire
and you and I will both die!
Let go!
Indeed, Ji Yah, you are filled with fighting
spirit! This is why I like you, Ji Yah.
You make me laugh. Do you
dare say that to me now?
You! You are scared, aren't you?
The day that I come back here...
You know what day that will be, right?
Don't make me come here again! You got it?
Yes, ma'am.
If had married her, I wouldn't
have survived a week.
Right?
- Yes?
- I'm sorry,
but can you give me your seat?
Me?
I'm pregnant.
Ah, yes. I'm sorry.
- Thanks.
- Yes.
♪ Wonder ♪
♪ The taste of things and people's taste ♪
♪ A flower on the sidewalk
and some smiling friends ♪
♪ The evening light ♪
♪ Wonder ♪
♪ Before rain, before the good weather ♪
Should I carry your bag?
No, it's fine.
Give it to me.
You heard that Do Kyung's recording
studio seizure has been cleared?
- I heard.
- Ah, you heard.
♪ Wonder ♪
Your ankles are pretty.
I am pretty in other places, too.
Wow, the stars are really twinkling.
Oh, so pretty.
When did they change the boardwalk?
I think the wall changed, too.
- Jin Sang.
- Yeah?
Um... Where can I grab onto?
You can just grab onto anything.
Here?
Yeah.
Here.
Ah, it tickles.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
- It's not difficult?
- No, it's okay.
Ahh. It feels kinda weird.
I think you can let go now.
Ohh, okay. We'll let go
on the count of three.
One, two, three.
Sleep well.
You too.
Noona.
- Sleep well, I said.
- Of course.
- Bonne nuit.
What am I feeling that I'm
having such a hard time?
Ah, really.
I told you to have a good night!
Go to sleep!
Aish.
Mom, I want to get married.
I just want to live with him. I
want to live with him in his house.
Live with him. Get out.
- Get up.
- Mom.
Get out.
♪ Your gaze towards me is heavy ♪
♪ My footsteps that
circle round and round ♪
♪ As always, I miss you ♪
♪ I need your mind ♪
♪ I remember that cold day ♪
♪ I was afraid that my trembling
heart would cry alone ♪
♪ Like a dream that fades when
I open my eyes, let me go. ♪
♪ If that's not true, then stay with me. ♪
♪ There is nothing good about crying ♪
You have to tell him...
that you gave permission.
If I just go by myself, he
will tell me to go back home.
So let's go together, and
please tell him. Please.
I cannot leave him alone.
Please Mom, please.
- Get up. Let's go.
- Okay.
♪ like a dream, let me go ♪
♪ If that's not true, then stay with me ♪
Give it to me.
Yes, Dad.
♪ Now ♪
I finally realized how I
feel about Noona today.
It turns out, I respect her.
Respect is something I should
feel for General Lee Soon Shin.
So it's like I'm dating someone like that.
So what can I do to General Lee Soon Shin? Put
my arm around his shoulder or hold his hand?
Crazy bastard. You still
haven't come to your senses?
To a woman who wants to live
together before marriage,
you tell her to wait until you propose to her, and you
will bring her home officially after the wedding?
You want to embrace her and sleep with
her and wake up with her every day.
You're saying things you don't mean,
pretending that you are thinking of her.
How many times do you have to die and come
alive for you to come to your senses?
Me?
Me!
♪ I can hurt this much is shocking ♪
What the heck are you saying?
♪ it hurts even to dream about it ♪
Don't be angry. Smile.
Like you're being sincere. Please?
Like your heart is at ease.
Please smile.
As I live,
I'm seeing the end of you, you brat.
I'm really abandoning you today.
Don't talk like that.
♪ The pain that is full of you,
enough to burst my heart ♪
♪ and how much I still want you ♪
♪ If I were you, I would
just love me back ♪
Hey. Look here.
Oppa!
Relax your face. Be nice, okay?
I want to marry Hae Young.
Please, give me your blessing.
I'm grateful that you came first.
We already approved. Right?
We approved.
Just live together from now on.
You guys can't live without each other. When
are you going to set the date and get married?
Just live together from now on.
I'm being sincere.
Get up.
Get up!
Live well.
Let's go back.
Driver, the trunk, please.
We'll leave. Hurry up and go in.
Yes. Please get home safe.
Pull your car out.
Please look at me, Mom.
That boy, he is sick somewhere.
All the more reason to send her to him.
♪ Smiling to myself about
the happy memories ♪
I told you we should go somewhere better.
I love it here the best.
While I was living there,
I thought my insides were
going to burst, every night.
You knew for sure that I liked you,
so how could you never come over?
Should I have jumped your bones? But if you
had refused, I would have been so humiliated.
I would get so worked
up every single night.
Whoa. But
how could this guy sleep?
Could I have slept?
♪ Dream a dream of you, a
dream I'm kissing you ♪
When should we get married?
Anytime.
Let's do it soon.
3 minutes earlier.
Whoa, what's going on...?
Friend. I'm behind the sofa. Can
you help me leave quietly, please?
- You got a message.
- It's fine. Just leave it.
Who is that?
- It's me.
- Oh, what to do?
What do you mean what should you do? Just tell her that we're getting
married and that your parents approved of us living together.
Let's tell her tomorrow, okay?
Officially, during the day. Right now, it
feels like we got caught or something.
Today, let's just act like I'm
going home and tell her tomorrow.
Alright. Take the car key with you.
My leg.
Hello.
- It's late, isn't it?
- Oh yes.
I'm about to leave right now.
Why? I was about take her home right now.
Is Jin Sang here?
- He's not.
- But his shoes are here.
Over there.
Let's go for a walk.
I couldn't digest very well.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Oh!
Congratulations.
For what?
Oh. Starting today— No, starting
tomorrow, they're going to do something.
- What?
- They said they got permission.
- For what?
- They'll tell you tomorrow but it's definitely not today.
I dare you to sneak into my room again.
I didn't sneak in. I've
been here since you left.
Well, it's not as if I saw
everything from the start...
I did see it, though.
I saw everything from the beginning! They were everywhere!
Rolling around. Noona, they were spinning around and everything.
And they were sitting down, and squealing, and
pecking at each other like chickens. Whoa!
Let's go! I saw everything!
Anyway, thanks for saving me. Wow,
I thought I would sweat to death.
I understand. Next time
something like this happens,
you have to say it right away. There
is no impact when you hesitate.
You have to say it within
three seconds. Got it?
Oh, Jin Sang. Stay here for a moment.
Oh, what's wrong with me. Hold on.
Oh, you held on well.
Lean back a little bit.
Ah, wait a minute.
Ah, Noona. Oh!
- Ah, that's nice. That's what I'm talking about.
- I don't think this is good for you!
- I think this is dangerous.
- It's not.
He's here.
Espresso con panna. The cream must be
whipped by hand and not a machine. Right?
Okay.
You're good.
Quickly run over here. Quickly!
Take the tissue off your face.
It makes you look pathetic.
There's more remaining.
When would I have the time to read this?
Explain it to me. I want to see if you have
the skills to transfix me with your words.
What?
With words?
Okay. Then with words...
Number 3 had a woman he loved,
but this bumpkin went on
his first trip abroad.
To commemorate his trip, he bought an Eiffel Tower-shaped
bottle opener, the kind you stick on your fridge.
And he gave that as a gift to his woman.
But one day,
he went to Number 1's house,
and that bottle opener
was in his house.
The moment that he sees that bottle opener
he gave to his woman in Number 1's house,
he goes crazy.
He was exploding with betrayal and fury. But the truth
is, he wanted most to get his bottle opener back...
This petty man's... noir...
It sounds fun. Let's do it.
I choose work based on energy and your
energy is good. So is your girlfriend's.
Tell PD Kim Hee Ran that
I said I would do it.
She does good work, as you know.
Thank you. You are the nobleman of my life.
Nobleman, geez. Who knows?
Maybe you will become the
nobleman of my life.
I am humbled.
I know.
I'm off.
Bye!
We decided to meet his mom tomorrow.
Do you have time?
I threw you away. Why concern
myself with a girl I threw away?
- You told him to live well.
- You told me to say that.
Can't you be more tender?
Have you and I ever spoken
tenderly to each other?
Be tender from now on.
From now on, if we fight on the phone, it's not
as if we'll both return home to face each other.
So if you speak to me
like that, it bothers me.
Did that guy give you a
ride to work this morning?
Of course, he gave me a ride.
But why do you keep calling him
"that guy?" Stop calling him that.
Then what should I call him?
Son-in-law Park.
Ridiculous.
Delete the first and the second one,
and then try to re sync the first one.
Alright.
- Yes?
- It's me.
I'm now... your father-in-law.
Oh yes.
Write this down.
Yes, please speak.
Um... milk vetch root.
Milk vetch root.
White...
balloon flower.
Jerusalem artichoke.
Boil and eat them. They say
it's great for your health.
Milk vetch root - calms body down / White balloon flower -
regulates breathing / Jerusalem artichoke - prevents diabetes
As soon as Oh Man Seok (actor) came in, I
thought, "Okay, I will work on him for a week."
Flirt with him every day, just enough
so he's refreshed, but not burdened.
Then say, "My oppa has
a killer screenplay."
You really have yourself a
good girlfriend, there.
Aiyoo.
I... uh... little bit...
I'm going to say something
that makes me blush.
It's really making me blush.
I... I love you.
♪ Softly, I'm melting now ♪
I love you, too.
♪ I melt you too. My heart
is a small and cute ♪
♪ Little Miss Sunshine ♪
Anna!
Park Hoon!
♪ Suddenly, it is dawn ♪
Hey!
Cheers!
We decided to get married.
We decided to meet with
our mothers tomorrow.
Congratulations. Congrats.
Thank you.
And, isn't there anything else?
Before we get married, we're
going to live together.
Starting from today?
Don't over do it. I will make you scream.
I'm your elder brother-in-law. Should you
treat your elder brother-in-law that way?
The two of us... are dating.
Dating is all you're doing?
Control your little brother, please.
I...
am pregnant.
It's okay.
We're going to be one family soon,
so she's going to find out anyway.
That's why you couldn't come inside
and lingered outside, every day.
Did you get permission to live
together before you get married?
Yes.
How nice.
You two live together already.
Uh... We... We haven't got
our own place... Yet...
You two. As difficult as it
was for you to get together,
be just as happy.
Bonne sante!
We've reached the love level!
What are you saying?
Oppa said he loves me. Since we reached the
love level, when we reach the fart level
we become a real couple!
I can already fart in front of her.
Do things in order. Love
level, then fart level.
You two still haven't said
"I love you" to each other?
- Have you said it?
- Of course. Would we be living together if we haven't?
I thought you couldn't say
that your whole life.
Why haven't you said it yet?
Well, it's not that hard. I
can just say it right now.
You should say "I love you"
when you really mean it.
You can't just spit it out at any time.
If you do, you're dead.
You still have many levels left.
The speaking level, too.
They are going to live together.
- What?
- Huh?
We're getting married.
They started living together yesterday.
Let's go upstairs.
We'll be going up first.
Bonne nuit.
That guy, he's become bolder lately.
Are they really living together?
AHHH!
Oh, so cool. You're so cool, Honey.
Did you see those veins?
What is this?
It was at the front door.
To Son-in-law Park
We need to eat together a few more times for me to know what
side dishes you like, to know what I could make for you.
But we've only eaten together twice, so I didn't
know what you like. So I made some guesses.
I think of marriage as something you
do with loyalty rather than love.
Marriage is what you do when you are prepared
to cut off a finger when you break up.
So please live together for a long time.
Did you know that your daughter
is living in my Do Kyung's house?
I brought her there.
Surprisingly, it seems as if
you have American-style mind.
How different from the way you look.
The two of them love each other so much, it
seems that they can't live without each other.
In our lives, how many days do we have, when we
feel like we could jump up and down for love?
Also, how many people can fulfill
that desire as they live?
"Don't be concerned with
the judgments of others,
and be as happy as you can,
to your hearts' content."
That is why I brought her to his house.
But still, that's a bit... You know?
Everyone who is concerned already knows
all about the messy circumstances
around how these two met, so
they should observe all decorum
and get married carefully. Even then,
they may barely escape scrutiny.
I'm the one who asked to live together.`
But still, a woman shouldn't
just say yes to that right away.
It's not sitting right with me.
That my child is living with
someone else before marriage
is something I didn't even dream of.
There's an order to everything...
Noona is pregnant.
Say something that actually makes sense.
She's not even married, how
could she be pregnant?
It's true.
Congratulations.
Then...
Yes.
Your mother-in-law is prickly on the
outside, but you don't need to be scared.
She's like bland soup on the inside.
Women like that are easier to handle.
Go.
I'll call you.
How can you say that, then?
How does that make me look?
I'm sorry.
Is it really true?
Soo Kyung is really pregnant?
She really is.
Who's the father?
Jin Sang.
She did something good, my Soo Kyung.
What?
Is the toilet clogged?
Is it big?
Then unclog it!
- I can't do it.
- I can't do it, either! Call someone!
Don't do it.
Then are we just going
to leave it like that?
Let's move! No one can touch this!
You should just do it, punk.
Are you crazy? Unclogging someone else'e poop,
when I can't even do it with my own poop?
Ah, really. Sheesh.
I'm telling you it's okay. I'll do it.
Then are we really going to move?
I can do this.
I can do this neatly!
Are you done?
Clean the toilet, too.
It's okay now. I'm done.
You don't even know how
cool I was when I did it.
You should have seen it.
It's really okay. We are having a baby together.
Could I not even unclog a toilet for you?
Isn't that true?
No, that's not what I'm saying!
You came?
Thank you for coming. This
is our Sound Director.
Nice to meet you.
Sit down.
- Okay.
- Please sit.
- Our movie barely has any dialogue.
- That's right.
So the sounds needs to tell the story,
and the audience must really feel it.
My friend over there did the sound effects.
- Is that right?
- Wow, great job.
- Right?
- Yeah.
I'm craving pork belly. Let's
eat that for dinner, okay?
Oh, right. You said you
had dinner plans, right?
Then let's eat pork belly another time.
It's no fun to eat it alone.
Eat a lot of delicious
things and come home.
Hey, it's been a long time.
Good to see you.
Ah, say your greetings.
This is the sound director.
Wow, his sound effects were really good.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yes.
Director, I'll be heading back.
- Already?
- Yes.
- I'm sorry.
- Going already?
I'm sorry.
Go home safely.
You said you'd be late.
It ended early.
Pork belly. I'll go change clothes.
As expected, eating pork belly
when you crave it tastes the best.
Next.
Again, something that
I've never done before,
I will do it now.
- Just let me feed you once.
- No, thanks.
Eat it! It's not hard.
Just accept this from me. All you
have to do is open your mouth.
It's not a big deal, right?
I heard you're pregnant.
Congratulations. Out of all
the things you've done,
I think this is the best one.
I wanted you to be the
first person I told, Mom.
Guys like Jin Sang, who played
around a lot when they were young,
will have good marriages and are
less likely to cause trouble.
Guys who want to play around after they
get married—there's no solution for them.
So... Don't worry, and be good to him.
But, we can't be romantic at all.
We can't even hold hands
properly, but we still did that.
- It's a mess.
- Hey!
You're looking for romance at your age?
You have a child together, game over.
Romance. What bull crap.
Even so,
we still haven't even said "I
love you" to each other, yet.
We even even held hands properly.
But how can... How can... How can...
What?
How?!?
How can... poop... be first?
Thank you for the food.
How nice to have a sister-in-law. We even
get to eat such delicious side dishes now.
Your mother's cooking skills
are really a work of art.
- Then...
- Yes.
Did something happen? I heard you left
early from the gathering tonight.
To be invited to a gathering of such important
directors means that they appreciate you that much.
Give him a call. It seemed like
Director Ahn was a little upset.
- Please rest.
- Yes, go ahead.
Why'd you come? You should
have stayed a little longer.
You said you wanted to eat pork belly.
Should I download a movie?
Sure.
♪ As much as I waited for you ♪
♪ I can wait even more ♪
♪ Oh oh. But somehow ♪
♪ This moment for us ♪
♪ feels like our last ♪
Your concert went well. What's wrong, now?
Did you come so late to keep an eye on me,
just in case I did something bad again?
Are you doing this because you want to save
me, or because you want to save that guy?
Both.
- Did your day go well?
Yes, I was a little busy recording
for the weekend, ahead of time.
What about you?
I was crazy busy in the morning. There are
a lot of patients because it's wintertime.
So I just ordered black bean noodles
and ate it at the hospital.
When I meet a woman later
on, how honest should I be?
There's only one thing you
shouldn't say to a woman.
I got it.
I'm sorry.
That those words came out of my
mouth must have been your fate,
so that you would meet an even better man.
The exam results came out. ♪ You
pretend to be okay, smiling ♪
Ah. ♪ But in those eyes ♪
Be happy. ♪ There is sadness, always ♪
I'm being sincere. Really.
♪ Because I know your scars ♪
♪ better than anyone else ♪
Tae Jin!
It was the truth when I said that you're a
good guy. ♪ Because I can’t say anything ♪
♪ It starts to ache ♪
Thanks.
♪ What should I do with
this heart of mine ♪
♪ You, like the breeze, ♪
♪ you scatter my heart ♪
♪ It may be that I, for a very long time ♪
♪ have been waiting ♪
♪ for you ♪
The exam results came out.
Ah. It came out quicker than expected.
Yeah.
You unplugged the toilet for her?
Be quiet.
The man who unplugs the toilet that
I plugged up is my man forever.
But how can you unplug the toilet
even before you say, "I love you"?
That's almost the final level
between a man and woman.
- This couple is going in reverse order. They started their relationship by making a baby.
- What?!
A baby?!
Is this couple going backwards?
Wow.
So cool.
How is that cool?
It's so cool. Normally you begin
with love, then you speak freely.
You fart freely, then you unplug the
toilet. After that, you make a baby.
But it's backwards. Have a child together, then unplug
the toilet for her. Then you fart in front of her.
You've seen all the good and
bad already, and finally,
you say, "I love you."
The words, "I love you," will
probably explode so amazingly.
Oh, reverse order! It's totally cool!
Totally cool.
Is that so?
Of course. The, "I love you"
that comes out in reverse order,
is a real, "I love you."
I'm so jealous!
Let's eat.
Okay.
She really thinks it's cool.
My noona is so simple-minded.
Wasn't I really good at acting surprised?
"What?! A baby?!"
"A baby?!"
Here.
I wrote the script. "A love that goes
in reverse order." It's killer, right?
Ah, it was killer. Hey, my acting
was pretty good also, right?
"Be quiet."
Yes, very natural.
But the thing is, for some reason, going
in reverse order does seem really cool.
You must be joking.
No, no, wait a minute. No baby.
No baby. No baby.
Hey, I thought we should be laughing
loudly when I drank with you.
I didn't want to drink while
pretending to be okay when I wasn't.
My heart is at ease now.
- You hate me, don't you?
- Yeah.
Hey, you were hateful too, during the
entire three years of high school.
And even up until recently.
But still, you're the winner.
Let's not call winners and losers
because of a man. It's embarrassing.
I won't go to your wedding.
I think that's the right thing to do. I'm
also transferring to another company.
A better company.
Let's meet occasionally
at alumni gatherings.
And you two, live happily
together for a long time.
I mean that sincerely.
Thank you.
♪ Where are we? ♪
You have to be happy!
You must be happy!
♪ We are standing at the end of
this road that no one can find ♪
Mom
Yes, Mom.
♪ then fall black and come down ♪
Where are you? I'll come to pick you up.
Don't come. Today, I think
it's right that I go alone.
I'll see you at home.
Jin Sang.
Hold on, my knee.
My knee. Ouch.
Rooftop party. Rooftop party.
Rooftop party.
It's not like that. Rooftop party.
I really look forward to
what our child will be like.
Since the video is going
to be projected there,
the bride will sit here, and
the groom will sit here.
Just hold the cup like this to
signal us to start the video.
Okay.
Just a moment.
Yes. Where are you?
I'm walking. I'll arrive
within ten minutes.
I don't know why I'm nervous when
I already know what will happen.
You can just give me the ring,
so don't be too cheesy, okay?
I mean, I know that's not your thing, so
you don't have to exert yourself, okay?
Okay.
Me, someone who lived with my heart firmly
closed, as if determined to remain miserable.
And her, the woman who flew into that me.
As she said, I was emotionally defective.
I lived without even knowing
whether I was happy or miserable.
I was emotionally defective.
I was so severely damaged that
it wasn't easy to change me.
So I think I had to see
the moment of my death.
At the moment of death, what
I regretted the most...
Even after being hurt so badly, and still
shouting, "Love again! Love again!"
Seeing her, running
towards me fearlessly...
That the heart has no shape, and can
become new again at any time...
And seeing her open her heart
fearlessly and run towards me...
It comforted me, and I
wanted to be by her side
in hopes that some of her energy
would be transferred to me.
Now, it's my turn to fill her up.
Breaking News: Death of
Singer Lee Byung Joon
I was careless. In the end,
I am lying down like this. What has changed
is that the sky is blue, instead
of the black night sky.
And instead of her cold, stoic face,
I now think of her smiling face.
♪ Was I the only one who felt this bliss? ♪
Please hurry and come, and hold my hand.
♪ My footsteps that
circle round and round ♪
Before death, trying to
hold each other's hand,
using all their strength to crawl
towards each other. This scene...
This scene that appears in countless
movies, I could never understand it.
But now, I know
why they struggled so arduously to hold
each other's hands.
Because it felt like they
would go somewhere soon.
That fear that they didn't
know where they were going.
That fear that they would
become completely alone soon.
In that moment of fear, you
long desperately for that hand.
That hand that gives you reassurance
that you are not alone.
♪ Showing me your shoulders
that have become heavy ♪
If you would only hold my
hand, that fear disappears.
The power of that hand that
makes all fears disappear...
Perhaps that is because it is your hand.
It's all right. I'll come to you soon.
Just hold on for a moment. It's all right.
This is nothing.
♪ I remember that cold day ♪
♪ I was afraid that my trembling
heart would cry alone ♪
♪ Like a dream that fades when
I open my eyes, let me go ♪
It's all right. It's all right.
♪ stay with me ♪
♪ There is nothing good about crying ♪
Now... I can relax.
♪ Who knows? Maybe you will return ♪
♪ I remember that day
when you looked so sad ♪
Operating Room
♪ I was afraid that you would
see my trembling shoulders ♪
♪ Like a dream that fades when
I open my eyes, let me go ♪
♪ If that's not true,
then stay with me. Now ♪
Let's set the date. September 3rd.
We will be cursed for having a wedding
the week before Thanksgiving.
The week after Thanksgiving is too late.
So let's have the wedding on September 3rd.
September 3rd is still too warm.
Let's do it in October.
Sorry, but we have to get married in
October. Her belly will start showing.
I have to make sure my dress fits.
Then, September 3rd it is.
Let's make the dowry gifts simple.
Dowry gifts, my ass.
What would you like to
receive, Madam In-law?
An alligator purse and a mink coat.
What?
- Mother, don't be like this.
- No, no.
What did the alligator and the mink do wrong
that we have to kill them when those two marry?
Why are you getting angry?
How can I not yell? Come to your senses.
- Dowry gifts, my ass.
- Then you won't give me dowry gifts?
Dowry gifts? My Hae Young is your dowry gift. She
is as precious as gold. What more could you want?
Excuse me. We will sing the wedding song.
Are you in your right mind?
Should I say that the
mood that day was crazy?
Or funny? No one seemed to
be in their right mind,
but it was a moment when I felt
very relieved and comforted.
Skipping over prayers to let him live,
rendering his survival a fait accompli,
and just moving onto the
next thing—my shameless mom.
And reading her intentions correctly,
all of you who went with
the flow of her energy.
I was swept away by all your energy, too.
I better wear a very pretty wedding gown.
Lee Byung Joon Recovers
Consciousness, Saved by CPR
♪ I've never expected anything ♪
(♪ When you show me your
sunlight-filled beautiful smile ♪)
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
♪ I become speechless and
just counted the stars ♪
- Go! Fighting!- Good job!
♪ and softly ♪
♪ I melt you, too ♪
♪ My heart is a small and cute ♪
Someone who died and lives again
lives his life differently,
because he learned what the most
important thing in life is.
The heart. The happy heart.
That is everything.
At this moment, I could not be
more comfortable and happy.
I am grateful to everyone.
The times we spent together, the times we laughed
and cried. The times that were bitter and sweet.
The times we collapsed and got back
up again. On the last day of my life,
I will look back on those times,
and I think that I will say this:
"Everything was perfect."
♪ As I conjure your face ♪
Please live. We are grateful
that you are alive.
Oh Hae Young Again
♪ When the lazy sunshine comes in ♪
♪ I stare out the window in a daze ♪
♪ I think about you, who've
been buried in my thoughts ♪
♪ Wondering where you are
and what you're doing ♪
♪ Smiling to myself about
the happy memories ♪
♪ Scared to be hurt by the sad memories ♪
♪ I try to not care, but I
can't help but be found out ♪
♪ My heart, why is my heart doing this? ♪
♪ What about love? ♪
♪ Why is my heart doing this? ♪
♪ Every day, it makes me
shed tears and snot ♪
♪ What about love? ♪
♪ My heart is racing, racing! ♪
♪ I want to lay my heart
onto your sweet lips ♪
♪ dream a dream of you, a
dream I'm kissing you ♪
♪ The pink flower petals are scattering ♪
♪ and I whistle in the warm wind ♪
♪ as I ponder whether to call you or not ♪
♪ Since when did I fall for you? ♪
♪ I confessed my love to you
in my dream last night ♪
♪ And I stare at the phone all day long ♪
♪ I try to not care, but I
can't help but be found out ♪
♪ Why do I feel this way? ♪
♪ What about love? Why is
my heart doing this? ♪
Thanks to all the viewers who loved "Oh
Hae Young Again," not just 89% but 100%.
♪ What about love? My heart
is racing, racing! ♪