He who merits,
through qualification and virtue,
the highest ranks
is, however, not counted
among the members
of our Central Committee.
And so
we only can explain it
by reading this letter
from the hand and word
of Comrade Ernesto Guevara.
A self-explanatory letter.
It says the following:
"Havana, Year of Agriculture.
Fidel, at this moment
I remember many things:
When I met you at María Antonia's house,
when you proposed that I come along,
all the tension
involved in the preparations.
One day they came by
asking who to notify in case of death,
and the real possibility of it
struck us all.
Later we knew it was true
that in a real revolution,
one either wins or dies.
I feel that I have completed
the part of my duty
that tied me to the Cuban
revolution in its territory,
and I say farewell to you,
to the comrades, to your people,
who now are mine.
I formally resign my positions
in the leadership of the party,
my post as minister,
my rank of comandante,
and my Cuban citizenship.
Other nations of the world summon
my modest efforts of assistance.
I can do what is denied to you
by your responsibility as Cuba's leader,
and the time has come for us to part.
If my last hour
arrives beneath other skies,
my last thought will be for this people,
and especially for you."
Let me see you without the hat.
You're the living portrait of your father.
You have the money?
Yes.
We could wait until things settle down.
If we don't do it now,
we'll have to wait another 50 years.
One more.
One, two,
three.
Aleidita, remember Mom and Dad
sit at the head of the table.
But since Dad's not here,
we'll give his friend Ramón the seat.
Here it is. Four and five.
What is he doing?
I don't know.
Go see what your brother is doing.
Special representative from the OAS?
Yes, the Organization of American States.
Just a second, please.
There's a man who is
a special OAS representative.
Organization of American States?
Yes, let him in.
- Please, come in.
- Thank you.
Mister, may I help you with your suitcase?
No need.
No. No.
I'm worried about Monje.
Why?
When I asked him about the 20 men he promised,
he said, "Which men?"
as if I had never talked to him.
It's okay.
Apolinar.
Serapio.
- How old are you, Serapio?
- Sixteen.
At 16, a man already knows what he wants.
Hello. I'm Camba.
Ramón.
Do you know who that man is?
He came with you.
The man you just shook hands with
is Che Guevara.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Could I shake his hand again?
- Ramón.
- Ricardo.
- This is Coco, Inti's brother.
- I know, I know.
- The farm is under his name.
- Braulio.
- How are you doing, bro?
- How are you?
- Miguel!
- What's up?
- Urbano, how was the trip?
- Quite tough.
Rolando.
You're Inti?
- It's an honor to meet you.
- The honor is mine. I'm Ramón.
This is Dr. Ernesto Maymura.
He's in the Bolivian Communist Party
and studied medicine in Havana.
- Where did you do your residency?
- At Calixto García.
And so we fell asleep.
Do you know where we woke up?
- In the United States.
- In New York.
We went right in with our Panamanian passports.
Everything was going smoothly
until we almost screwed it up
because we were so hungry!
Braulio says, "Let's go over there,
they have hot dogs."
So we got there and, of course,
the vendor was Dominican.
The first thing he says is,
"Oh, but you're Cuban."
Braulio just looks at him.
He served us the hot dogs without another word.
I made a mistake and took the wrong flight.
You didn't make a mistake,
you discovered something.
What did we discover?
If you dress an elephant as a man,
it would still make it into Bolivia.
Good one!
To Bolivia or anywhere else!
Brother!
Let's go.
Hello.
- Eustaquio.
- Welcome, Eustaquio. I'm Ramón.
- Salustio.
- Ramón.
- I'm Pedro.
Paco.
- Aniceto.
- Tuma, this is Aniceto.
Carlos.
Tuma.
- Willy.
- I'm Chapaco.
I'll need a few days to learn all your names.
In the last conversation I had with Monje,
I made it clear that if we really
want to change this society,
we are the ones most capable of doing it.
That's why the party
has to support the guerrilla.
Monje expressed his doubts about
the armed struggle.
He began to talk about his love for his family.
And here people also have children
and women that they have left behind.
That is why, with all due respect, Ramón,
I don't think the party
will support an armed struggle,
much less Mario Monje.
So I want to ask for permission
to go back to La Paz
and recruit the best people from the party
to join the group.
First we have to meet
Mario Monje as we agreed to.
Not doing so would be inappropriate.
Conditions are not right for
the kind of struggle you propose.
Mario, anywhere in the world where men
are being exploited by men,
conditions are right.
When children work in mines
and 50 percent of miners
don't reach 30 years of age...
When these same miners go on strike
to improve their wages,
and they are massacred by the army,
are those conditions right or not?
If infant mortality rates
are the highest in Latin America
because of lack of hospitals and medical care,
the situation is right for me.
If we learned something in Cuba,
it's that a popular uprising
that isn't backed by armed struggle
has no chance of taking power.
When people learn that
this movement is led by a foreigner,
they will turn their backs on you.
You will die heroically,
but you have no hope of achieving victory.
Then let's change the name of Bolivia.
After all, Simón Bolívar
was a Venezuelan, right?
Comrade Monje,
your job and the party's job is to
make it clear to the people that Che,
that Ramón, is a revolutionary
from the continent, not a foreigner.
It's true. Ramón is like Simón Bolívar.
The party does not endorse armed struggle.
You are free to abandon it.
And you will have our support if you do.
If you stay, the party will no longer
pay your stipends.
As the head of the Communist Party here,
I advise you to leave with me.
With a mojito, you cannot grind up the leaves.
I know about mojitos.
So you know you can't grind them up.
You cannot grind the leaves.
How are you?
Come over.
Just a second, I'm finishing here.
Then you have to cover it.
Half an hour in the oven
with the correct temperature.
No, I forgot something.
On top of the cream, put cheese.
Cheese.
Excuse us for a second.
We need to talk.
Go ahead.
- Everything good?
- Yes, good.
Why did Che change the location of the camp?
I think he wanted to be closer to Argentina.
He had contacts waiting for him in Alto Beni.
The mines are there.
Miners are more politicized.
They support us.
Che needed somewhere to train for six months
where he wouldn't be bothered.
How is that Ñancahuazú region?
It's a very remote place.
Life is hard there.
In fact, the few peasants who live there
don't trust foreigners.
The Soviets won't allow Monje to make a deal.
No.
We have some money
that we want you to take to Bolivia.
And we need to find out if there's
anything else that we need to send.
We also found a cave which could be useful.
Good morning.
I told the men that I'm going back
to La Paz today.
I'm resigning from the party.
My mission is over.
- Okay.
- The jeep arrives this afternoon.
Why don't you stay in the camp
until the jeep arrives?
I would like to be alone.
I'll wait at the zinc house.
Fine.
I'll return on January 10th,
with my decision made.
Okay. Monje, we'll be here.
Coco, find Moisés Guevara.
Tell him I want to talk to him.
We're leaving in a few days on a training march
for about 20, 25 days.
I'll go to the mines.
I'll be back between
the 4th and 14th of February.
I'd like to come back earlier,
but it's Carnival season,
La Diablada in Oruro.
My men will be all spread out,
it'll be difficult to gather them.
You are our primary connection to the outside.
Your cover needs to remain intact.
You can't come back to the camp.
There may be a strike at Siglo XX.
And your husband?
How are things?
Did you get the trip straightened out?
I arranged everything so that
he could go study in Bulgaria.
What about Barrientos?
What happened there?
We've been in contact.
- What happened?
- I think he likes me.
I know he likes me.
- Should I try to see him again?
- Yes.
Tania, when this thing heats up,
your job will make the difference.
Here are provisions:
Sugar, eggs, flour, what's needed.
The new employee, is he Bolivian?
Yes.
- How much do I owe you?
- No, keep your money.
- No, keep it.
- We are neighbors now.
- Take it.
- I'm not doing this for the money.
I want to take part in your project.
I have relatives in transportation.
You can rely on me for everything.
Okay?
Go with Tuma to see our neighbor
and tell him we need his help.
Involve him without offering much.
Tell him that we'll pay for
what he carries in the jeep
and nothing else.
Tumaini.
Put a little fear in him.
And explain to him that if he betrays us
he'll pay with his life.
You can drive back and forth
to town in your jeep
so you can buy the food we need,
and we'll pay you well.
Yes, sure, whatever you want.
- Good.
- I have to tell you something.
In private, because it's something
I would only say to a friend.
Okay, fine.
You want some more?
There were two little birds who lived in a tree.
One was quiet, the other liked to
fluff his feathers and sing and sing.
One day a hunter came by.
He heard him sing,
then put him in his sights and shot.
But the other bird, the quiet one,
nothing happened to him.
He saved his own life.
It's a nice story.
- It's good.
- It's good. I liked it.
I really liked it. I know what you mean.
You junkie son of a bitch.
We'll see.
Good morning.
- How are you?
- Good morning.
This looks beautiful!
I see the factory is doing well.
- Good morning.
- Come with me.
Can we come in? Show me the house.
I see you are really busy.
Soon.
I don't know when, but soon
we will confront the enemy.
Our contact with the outside will be limited.
Some of us will die,
and it's sad to see your comrades die
because you can't help them
with your limited resources.
Food will be scarce.
Sometimes we won't have anything to eat.
And if all of this weren't enough,
we'll have to endure the harsh weather.
By the end,
we will have become human waste.
That's all I can promise you.
Think it over.
You still have time to go back home.
Afterwards it will be too late.
In closing,
I would like to repeat
what I said to Monje.
Me? I'm already here.
They would have to kill me
to get me out of here.
I will be at the side
of those who stay, until victory.
How much corn can you sell us right now?
There's not even enough for us, sir.
At least sell us a pig.
They're piglets, just little ones.
How am I going to sell them?
Besides, they belong to the missus.
How much is your pig, madam?
I can't sell them, they're only sucklings.
I'll pay you 30,000 bolivianos.
I'm not sure.
How about 40,000?
Should we sell or not?
Make it 50,000, okay?
Okay.
What conditions do they live in?
Very bad.
Do they have children?
They have six kids.
Barefoot, all full of ticks.
One of the little boys has a badly infected eye.
How old is the peasant?
About 40, 50 years old.
I think he's a bit older, you know?
And when you offered the money,
how did he react?
His eyes sparkled when he saw the money.
Hello.
Good day, Honorato.
Come, I want to talk to you.
We want there to be schools for your children,
and hospitals to take care of them,
and roads to be built
so trucks can reach here,
and you can sell your products.
Don't you want all these things?
Well, yes, that would be nice.
But in order to do this, we need your help.
Two and three.
Look.
You are a big man.
May God repay you.
- It's all right.
- May God repay you.
Okay.
- See you.
- Bye, madam.
- Goodbye.
- May God repay you.
What are you doing?
That's communal food.
No one helps themselves
without being given permission to do so.
Understood?
I'll let you off this one time
because you don't know the rules yet.
- Everything belongs to the group.
- But we're hungry.
We're all hungry, Darío.
But one can feeds six for breakfast.
There's one missing.
I have no radio coverage with
the main camp, so I'm going back.
No, big guy. You're not going anywhere.
Stay with us until 6, then you can
tell Ramón how far we've gone.
No, I'm going now while it's still light out.
Hey, I'm giving you an order!
Stay here until 6.
- I'm leaving now.
- You're not leaving, can't you hear?
You listen to me, I'm fucking going!
You'll have to go through my machete first!
- Hey!
- What's wrong with you?
Hey, Miguel!
What's going on here?
Listen, listen!
Miguel, look at me!
Hey, you're comrades.
- For what? He has to follow orders!
- That's enough!
Miguel, you have to control yourself
and give orders with respect
like a boss.
You cannot threaten or hit anyone here.
That's not permitted by the guerrilla.
And you know that better than anyone.
And you
lied.
Miguel never hit you with the machete
handle. He didn't even touch you.
The one thing I won't tolerate here
is a liar.
One more incident like that, Pacho,
and I'll send you back to Cuba
with a dishonorable discharge.
Incidents like this destroy group morale
and our readiness for combat,
not only of you or you,
but of the entire group.
If anyone feels weak or discouraged,
he shouldn't resort to such methods,
but should speak to the political commissaries,
to Inti or Rolando or to me,
and we will peacefully discharge him
from the group.
I didn't come here to work.
We should have a rifle.
Listen to me.
Ramón could be back now in Cuba with his family,
with many cars, enjoying comfort
everywhere he goes.
But he is here because he wants you
to have a better life,
so your kids can learn to read and write.
I'm just a baker, I've been a slave all my life,
but someday I'll be free.
Rest, because we'll be leaving at sunrise.
- We're not staying here?
- No, we need to be patient.
We are taking you to another camp
where you'll be safer.
Have you had any problems?
There's a neighbor that thinks
we're making cocaine.
The police have been here twice already.
When's the last time you heard from Ramón?
Over a week ago.
We lost contact with the whole group.
Moisés, hello!
Who did you bring?
Contacts from Argentina and France.
Chino is from Perú.
Are you going back to Camiri?
I need to talk to Ramón first.
Monje and the party
are interfering with everything.
They even convinced the last Bolivians
that were trained in Cuba
not to come here and join us.
Hey, listen.
Hey. Everyone keep away
from her hammock.
Whoever touches her will be severely punished.
Listen to me, Arturo.
They are Bolivian, and they have come to fight.
You must not disrespect them.
I need two volunteers to go hunt,
and I thought about you.
Bring something good
because supplies are running low.
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
We'll get money for this!
Hey, that sounds like a plane.
Airplane!
Come on, Ramón.
Get down, Ramón.
They caught two of Moisés' men who deserted,
and they talked like parrots.
Soldiers went into the zinc house.
They seized Tania's jeep and a mule.
- Who gave orders to move camp?
- Antonio did.
Tell him we'll win the war with bullets.
- Bring back all to the camp.
- Okay.
Rolando.
Prepare an ambush.
Was there anything in the jeep?
I had some recordings of Fidel's speeches.
They're going to search the jeep
which will lead them to the hotel,
and the hotel will lead them to your apartment,
and your apartment will lead them to everything.
I couldn't trust anyone.
Every time I called
they hung up the phone on me.
- That's why I decided to bring--
- You had strict orders not to return.
That's five years of lost work.
Tania, five!
Give me your rifle.
You and the visitors will leave
as soon as we prepare your trip.
Hold your fire!
We surrender! We surrender!
My superiors are cowards
and don't tell us anything.
I didn't want to be here. I swear.
Calm down.
- Please don't kill me, please.
- Calm down.
I suffer from rheumatism, I swear.
- No one is going to hurt you.
- And I have a bad heart.
Don't believe a word Major Plata says.
He's a liar and he's abusive.
He sells our food to the stores
and keeps the money for himself.
He hits people.
Look how he's crying. He's a coward.
So, what should we do with him?
Kill him.
Yes, kill him.
Put him on his side.
- Did you give him a painkiller?
- Not yet.
Give him some morphine.
We have committed ourselves
to a struggle in which,
whether we like it or not, we may have to kill
or be killed,
because we are fighting for Bolivia's freedom.
You can do it now.
I won't be returning.
I'm quitting the army.
We hope to see you soon.
Because we could use more
of your ammunitions and weapons.
Long live a free Bolivia!
Long live the National Liberation Army!
No one wanted to stay.
That takes time.
This is a national emergency.
Is the United States going to sit back
and let Castro create another
Communist revolution in Bolivia,
in the heart of South America?
Mr. President,
the threat has three components.
One, the actions of the guerillas themselves.
Two, the lack of anti-guerilla capability
at all levels in the field,
including your high command.
Three, the potential for the various
elements in the population
to become indifferent to the situation.
That's my point.
What if Che Guevara is here?
I can't have that information made public.
Mr. President, our latest intelligence
indicates Guevara did not get out of the Congo.
Guevara is irrelevant
if you're controlling the press
and winning the hearts of the peasants.
They're your source of information.
If anyone's going to know
where the guerrillas are, it's them.
We believe you should train
a small, specially equipped force
to deal directly with the existing threat.
These men should be recruited
from existing Bolivian forces
and their area of operation
should be restricted to the combat zone.
And who is going to train these men?
We have men supervising
similar operations in Vietnam.
They can work with your people.
No, if you leave now you could be arrested.
I think you should wait until
we start our march northward.
- You're going north?
- Yes.
Then we can let you off on the Cochabamba road.
No, I don't think that's right.
That could take two or three months.
Ciro, we're at war.
Give me a guide.
Give me a guide, and I'll make the arrangements.
I can't break up the group
under these circumstances.
I'll think about an alternative.
But any move we make will be made
with the group as a whole.
Ramón, your books are soaked.
Put them on those rocks to dry.
Arturo.
Water got in the radio, everything is rusted.
What are you saying, that it doesn't work?
It still receives, but it doesn't send.
Shit. Now we're really screwed.
Not quite. We still have
the visitors to relay messages.
The army says that you are here
to practice Communism.
That you have no God,
that you all work for the state.
That you rape women and destroy families.
You kill those who refuse to serve you
and want to make us slaves.
And what kind of freedom do you have?
The kind where I can do whatever I want.
Listen to me.
None of what they said is true.
We haven't come to harm anybody.
We just want to buy
some food from you, that's all.
But I have nothing, only this.
How much do you want for this?
Whatever you have. Take it.
I'll stay if you need me.
What I need now are peasants.
It's better if you go to France and make
a network to promote our cause,
so they can send us money, medicine and radios.
I'd also need you to take some messages to Cuba.
I'll write Sartre and Bertrand Russell
to organize a worldwide fund
on behalf of the Bolivian revolution.
Don't worry.
We'll take you out of here when you recover.
I'm not worried.
Tumaini.
Here, it's yours.
To protect you.
I'll move southward with the vanguard
and take the visitors out by Muyupampa.
I want you to stay with the sick
until we come back.
How long will you be gone?
About three days.
Rolando.
Go with Loro to replace Benigno and Miguel.
Ramón.
There's no one in the house.
So leave the money with a note.
Pick up everything, we're leaving.
Ramón.
There's no sign of Loro.
That's what they've given me, captain.
What good is this for?
Are there any shops here?
They took my pigs and my corn.
You helped them, and they gave you money.
Now you are going to help us
eliminate them, otherwise...
And now you are stealing my chickens, captain.
Listen to me closely, smartass,
really pay attention.
Let me know immediately
if the guerrillas come back again.
You have a good heart.
You'll do it.
- Alejandro.
- Hey.
This is Captain Mitchell, in charge of training.
Nice to meet you.
By the time we're through,
we'll turn the Bolivians
- into U.S.-grade special forces.
- We'll train them in the following areas:
Weapons, communications,
demolition and intelligence.
Also educate them politically,
so they understand the moral
component of the operation.
We also have one of the best
chopper pilots in Nam.
- So how much time do you need?
- Five months.
Good morning.
I'm just here to write an article
on the guerrilla movement in Bolivia.
Trying to confirm the Bolivian army's rumors
that Che Guevara is the leader of the group,
and there is a woman with him.
This guy is a Trojan horse.
I don't want any Cubans talking to him.
- What's up, Darío?
- Food is ready.
Start serving. Children first.
Are you from Paraguay?
Paraguay? No way, I'm from Oruro.
Okay, kids.
Once you are done you have to leave, right?
We can't leave, because that gringo
owes us money.
How much does he owe you?
Fifty pesos.
I spoke with the Englishman about the way out.
He says the army knows him in Camiri.
We could get out that way.
You are the ones to make that decision.
We could use our papers
to pass as reporters, no problem.
Inti will take you up the road to Camiri.
Try not to go through Muyupampa.
Don't get yourselves captured.
If that happens, remember
to always deny my presence
and the presence of all Cubans here
at each moment and at all costs.
- Do you have a cigarette?
- No, I don't.
Goddamn it!
Why don't you smoke?
Smoking's great.
- But I do have some tobacco.
- Oh.
Thanks, brother.
Where are the Cubans?
- Well, they should be--
- Darío, come here!
I told you not to talk to that guy.
What did he say?
He didn't say anything, brother.
I asked him for a cigarette.
You're going to the back.
Freeze! Stop right there!
Drop your backpacks
and show us your papers, shitheads!
Throw them on the ground.
The Frenchman's name is Régis Debray.
Masquerades as a radical author,
a Marxist journalist.
Spends a lot of time in Cuba,
and is a good friend of Fidel Castro.
The Argentine's name is Ciro Bustos.
A painter and also a writer.
This character collected money in 1963
for a local guerrilla movement
led by Jorge Massetti.
Massetti was killed
by the police in Argentina in 1964.
Two mercenaries, a
Frenchman and an Argentine, were killed
when confronted by the army
in the area known as Vaca Guzmán.
The Guzmán region, that's in Muyupampa.
If that's true, those bastards
are going to pay for it, bigtime.
The three of them were arrested.
They were taken to Camiri.
Who told you that?
We stopped a van that came from Muyupampa
with a German priest and a man.
They gave all the information.
They want to talk to the boss.
They gave us some sweets and stuff.
- Inti, have those people seen you?
- No.
Many of your men are not Bolivian.
That's why no one trusts you.
But they trust you.
They asked us to talk to you.
Then tell them that our army
is open to anyone who wants to fight.
They should be here with us.
No, they reject everything
that has to do with violence.
So people in power can use
violence to oppress us,
but we can't use it to free ourselves?
They don't want to join you,
and they don't want you here.
You don't have the right to ruin their lives.
You are going to have peace today in Muyupampa
on the condition that you bring us
a truck of food and medical goods
by 6 p.m. on this watch.
We'll meet at Nemesio's farm.
We'll pay for everything.
Then we'll go, you have my word.
Okay.
Open your mouth.
They will torture Bustos and Debray.
They'll learn everything.
Ramón.
I think you should change your name.
That's not a bad idea.
Plane! Get everyone out of the house.
- Run!
- Cover yourselves!
Quickly, under the tree!
Get out of here!
Most of these men are Cubans.
Don't be mistaken.
This is an invasion promoted by Castro.
A Communist plot to remove a peaceful,
democratically elected government.
President Barrientos, what about the Americans?
Are there U.S. military advisors?
The United States has sent
planes, helicopters and nothing more.
That's their response to the guerrilla threat?
Our military is entirely capable
of handling this situation.
The guerrilla forces are on their last legs.
Is Che Guevara leading this group?
I'll say it once.
Che Guevara is not in Bolivia.
- Fernando. Fernando.
- Hm.
The miners are threatening to go on strike.
Where?
In Catavi, Siglo XX.
The miners are going on strike!
Fernando. Miners have pledged 50
bolivianos of their paychecks to our cause.
For them, that's a fortune.
Arturo, report to Miguel at the ambush
and replace Pablito.
I'll go through all of Bolivia
without firing a single shot.
Okay.
Sir, the situation is slipping
through our fingers.
The pope and de Gaulle
are pressuring us about Debray.
Some members of your coalition
are expressing support for the strike
and sympathy for the rebel cause.
We need to take control of this thing.
What do you have in mind?
Tell people about Guevara.
Declare a state of emergency
and crack down on the Siglo XX miners,
the iron fist.
Seal the borders and declare
a national state of war.
And the rebels?
Your main problem, Mr. President,
is the lack of coordination
among your deployed forces.
I couldn't agree more, sir.
What do you suggest?
Divide the region in three zones.
Surround each zone,
cut off its source of supply,
and liquidate any guerrilla forces.
A few minutes ago,
Radio Argentina reported
the sad news about the Siglo XX massacre,
which resulted in the deaths
of 87 miners.
The families and fellow miners
mourn their loss.
What are they saying on Bolivian stations?
The same.
They confirm the battle in the mines,
but they are silent about the death toll.
They hit Pombo.
They almost got us, man.
Pour me some water.
Come on, breathe.
The worst is over.
He asked that you hold
his watch until you can give it to his son.
Joaquín.
We can't circle it forever.
This place is crawling with troops.
Ramón told us not to move out of the area.
That was before the army overran our camp.
We have no food left, nothing.
If Ramón were coming back, he'd be here by now.
If we leave, how are we going to meet him?
If Ramón is not here it's because
the army is preventing him.
I say we find our way to the Rio Grande.
We've got as much chance
finding Ramón across the river
as we do here.
Good morning, miss.
Can you sell me a can of milk?
Ricardo, what's up?
- Shut up and give me your canteen.
- Moron!
Breathe! Now hold it.
- Fuck!
- Calm down.
Hold it!
Breathe.
How long are we going to look for these people?
Until we find them.
I agree, but I think
we're moving away from them.
We should try to make contact
with the capital again.
We're at an impasse.
How many more of us have to die
to find the other group?
Chapaco, if you were lost,
we'd do the same thing.
No one abandons anyone in the group.
Is that clear?
Let's go.
Excuse me, Fernando,
but the men are starving,
and we have nothing to give them.
We also have nothing for the animals.
They're eating the bark off the trees.
- What do you want me to do?
- Kill a horse.
I'm giving you another shot.
Fernando, with your permission.
I think I could
make it back to the camp
to look for your medicines.
What do you want?
Do you want me to divide the group again?
I'm not doing it.
And even less, risk anyone's life
for the sake of my own well-being.
We are in a difficult situation.
The truth is, all of us
have made mistakes.
But I made the worst mistake
when I didn't bring my medicines along.
This struggle gives us
the opportunity to become
true revolutionaries,
the highest level of humanity.
To become men
in the purest sense of the word.
Too old to learn.
If the wheel rolls downhill,
let it go.
Come on, let's go up.
Let's go!
- Let's go!
- No, I can hold them!
Go!
You bastards!
They're reporting three hours
of intense combat in Monteagudo
between a group of guerrillas
and the 3rd division.
The army didn't suffer any casualties.
Here's Monteagudo.
They are talking about one dead guerrilla
named Antonio Fernández from Tarata.
Pombo, sounds like it was Pedro.
He's from Tarata.
Monteagudo is here.
- Where exactly?
- Here, south of Ñancahuazú.
This is where Joaquín
and his group are operating.
- So, what we're hearing makes sense.
- We're not far off.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- Good afternoon.
With your permission,
I need to check your house.
- Good afternoon.
Hello, madam.
Good afternoon.
Don't worry, madam, we won't do you any harm.
Who's that man over there?
- Sit down.
- No, thanks.
- Who is that man?
- Oh, he's a friend...
Is he all right?
Have you seen the army around here?
He's a neighbor. He has a fever.
We have a doctor with us.
We'll bring him to see you when we come back.
Do you understand me?
But what about the army?
We need to find a way across the river, a ford.
You live here and you know
this area well. You can help us.
Get us some food.
There, have some money.
You are seven people, right?
And eight with the woman.
How do you know that we're seven?
I'm slowing everyone down.
I don't know if I'll be able to go on.
Of course you can, Tania.
We'll be back in two days.
Remember, sir, find us an easy place
to cross the river.
Pombo, I've got to talk to Fernando.
Fernando is sleeping.
He's recovering from an asthma attack.
Don't you think he's had
enough worries for today?
Let him rest.
Inti, what's the matter?
Okay, go and tell him.
I think you should speak to Camba and Chapaco.
Camba says his physical condition
prevents him from continuing.
I think he no longer sees
the point of the struggle.
I talked to Inti already.
Fernando, I am a bit sick.
- I don't believe--
- Camba.
I can't let you go
until we meet Joaquín's group,
because if they capture you,
you not only risk your own life,
but you also put the whole group at risk.
Look, Camba.
To survive here, to win,
you have to live as if you've already died.
I never said to Inti that I wanted to quit.
Quitting is for cowards.
What I told Inti is that in six months
to a year, I want to return home.
Let's see.
Tell me
exactly where you said to cross.
Just about here is where
I will make them cross, captain.
Now,
put this white shirt on
so we don't shoot at you.
Now go home and don't move
until the guerrillas arrive,
or they'll suspect something.
Fire!
Today, the Bolivian army
reported a rebel clash
at Vado del Yeso.
Ten rebels were reported killed.
The group's one survivor,
José Carrillo, is a local miner
who was under the command
of a Cuban named Joaquín Acuña.
That's bullshit from the army.
They can't all be dead,
unless they were walking in their sleep.
José Carrillo is Paco.
Maybe he was caught and is talking.
Let's go.
It's already 5:00.
- What happened to her face?
- The piranhas ate it.
I requested a coffin.
There's a cemetery in town.
Mr. President,
with your permission, sir.
What do you plan to do with Che
if he is captured alive?
Personally, I think
the biggest mistake Batista made
was not killing Fidel when he had the chance.
Thanks.
Fernando, they say the truck comes
every day, and the deputy--
- What's his name?
- Vidal Aguilar.
--left yesterday for Vallegrande
to warn the army about us.
It's a two-day-old telegram
sent by the army to the deputy.
It says, "Any expenses incurred will be
reimbursed by the army."
Inti is already talking to the wife.
They own a store.
Tell Inti that in reprisal for that,
we will take all that we need from the store.
Take 10 cans of sardines and those tomatoes.
This is for my children!
Madam, madam.
Dear comrades, we've been here
fighting the army for six months now.
You may wonder why.
We want to end injustice
in this country.
To end neglect and misery
to which the government subjects
its own people.
For example,
where is the nearest hospital?
About 100 kilometers away, right?
What if you get sick?
First you have to pay
to take a truck to Vallegrande,
and then you pay for the stay.
So you go to a hospital,
which they say is public,
but to see a doctor,
you must pay first.
Isn't this the way it is?
And the medicine? They won't even
give you aspirin for free.
In other words,
if your kid gets sick or dies because
you have no money for the hospital,
who is going to care?
That is the reason why your luck
changing for the better
depends on the triumph of our struggle...
Yes?
Is there going to be fighting
here in the village?
We have no intention of
fighting in the villages.
Nothing.
Two pigs and a mule.
- Weird, isn't it?
- You're telling me.
- Where is Miguel?
- He should already be here.
Hey.
Madam, madam!
Madam!
I don't see anything.
Absolute silence.
Smells like soldiers to me.
It's completely deserted.
I talked to an old woman who said
that her grandson saw soldiers yesterday.
Miguel.
Get the vanguard ready to go
to Jagüey at 1300 hours.
You heard it.
The vanguard, get ready.
Miguel, stay on guard.
Take all security measures.
Understood.
- Tell me.
- Fernando.
I think it's better that I stay here.
I can't stand up or pee.
We aren't going to leave you here.
When we get to Jagüey, we'll make a decision.
Good afternoon.
I met him on the way to Jagüey.
He says he comes from Vallegrande.
Where are you going with these goods?
To Picacho, sir.
I have jerky and cheese to sell to
Pombo, Pombo.
support my family, sir.
- Have you seen the army around?
- No, sir. I haven't seen the army.
Fernando, he looks too nervous to me.
Maintain vigilance.
Fall into line. Everyone, stay alert.
Are you sure you haven't seen the army?
No, sir. I haven't seen the army.
Good.
Pombo, walk with him
to the outskirts of the village.
Thank you, sir.
You have a pebble factory in your shoe.
It's the second time
you've stopped for the same shit.
Pacho, that way.
Darío, go over there.
Willy, go with them.
- Antonio.
- Chapaco, let's go.
Urbano, go over by the fence.
Arturo, over there.
Keep going, Darío.
Retreat!
Everybody run down the hill!
I'm covering you!
Downhill, everyone!
- Chino, what's wrong?
- I lost my glasses!
They'll kill you. Here they are!
They killed Coco, Julio and Miguel.
Camba, this way. Camba!
Camba! What are you doing?
Come on!
What happened?
They killed Miguel, Julio and your brother.
I tried to get them out,
but I couldn't.
I'm sorry.
This is Che's vanguard.
You think he's close?
I think you should bring in
the 2nd Ranger division.
They haven't finished training.
You're going to need every man you can get.
Benigno.
Benigno, Fernando is asking you to stop.
Hold on.
Benigno, let me see your wound.
It's okay. It's nothing.
Take it.
Tell me, Fernando.
Go with Benigno to explore.
Let's see if we can find a place
to spend the day without being seen.
Captain, a message from Lieutenant Huerta.
A peasant saw some rebels
heading toward Yuro Ravine.
Tell him we're on our way.
Look.
Must be a peasant
on his way to Pucará. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
- How many are there?
- More than a battalion.
- Are they together?
- Two or three meters from each other.
Willy, go look for Ñato and Urbano, immediately.
Arturo, bring Darío and Aniceto.
Fernando, the left ravine ends in a house
that's taken by the army.
- You can't get out of the middle one.
- This is the steepest ravine.
It's 500 meters to the hill.
And there's also a tree I think
would be good as a lookout.
- Then go there immediately.
- Okay.
Benigno, be vigilant, find a place
where we can leave during the night.
Okay.
Take care.
We'll wait there until 9 at night.
Those who don't arrive by then
should make their way down
the ravine to Rio Grande,
and from there to the mouth of Santa Elena.
We'll wait there for two days.
Pacho and Willy.
You will take this position here.
Antonio and Arturo,
into this ravine.
No one shoots until they shoot.
If you hear gunfire,
first, find out for sure
that they know about you
and that they're not just sweeping the area.
Do you understand? Go now.
Go with Darío and reinforce Benigno's position.
Don't let him fall asleep from exhaustion.
Fernando.
We've been in worse situations than this.
There are three ravines:
La Tusca, San Antonio and Yuro.
The guerrillas could be in any one of them.
Search all three.
Start in the upper canyons
and make your way down.
What if they try to escape?
I'll set up a command post
where the three ravines meet.
Ñato.
Get Aniceto.
Go with Ñato and take over for Pombo and Urbano.
Make them both come back.
Wait a moment.
What's that?
Hey, Urbano.
Ñato is making signs I don't understand.
Either he's saying Fernando wants us
to retreat or move toward him.
- Antonio, do we move?
- No, we stay here.
Pablito, prepare the wounded to leave.
Go now.
Fuck! We have to leave now, Urbano.
Pombo, go now! I can cover you!
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait! Now move!
There they are.
Pombo and Urbano are there.
How do you feel?
Fine.
The lieutenant bandaged it for me.
Where have you taken Willy and Chino?
They're next door.
How many guerrillas are left out there?
I don't know.
What was your rendezvous point?
We didn't have one.
What's your rendezvous point?
- I told you we didn't have one.
- You didn't have one?
Why did you come here
to La Higuera during the day?
Does it matter?
Nothing matters anymore.
Listen to me.
You are no longer in Cuba, sir.
And you should know that
I am a colonel in the Bolivian army.
You escaped the Congo, Venezuela,
but I assure you, not Bolivia.
This is where your adventures end,
you foreign piece of shit.
All right. Get some rest.
Tomorrow we'll go to Vallegrande
to have your wound examined.
Put on your best face.
A lot of people will want a photograph of you.
Maybe we should shave you.
Piece of shit!
Bring me the dead, and leave them here, quickly!
That's not right.
They shouldn't do that with the dead.
Do you want to smoke?
Yes.
Thanks.
How is Cuba?
Cuba is progressing.
Do they have religion there?
Yes, there are religions.
I thought Communists didn't believe in God.
Well,
in Cuba there's no official religion,
but many people believe in God.
You don't believe in anything?
Yes, I believe in mankind.
- Are you married?
- No, no.
- How about you?
- Yes.
Do you have children?
- I have five.
- Five!
Three girls and two boys.
You want some more?
Yes.
What's your name?
Eduardo.
Would you untie me, Eduardo?
Hey.
- Che asked me to free him.
- What?
He asked me to untie him.
No, you're crazy. They'd kill both of us.
I don't want to go back in.
You take the next shift.
What are you thinking about, comandante?
Where are you from?
From Cuba.
I don't talk to traitors.
Okay, so you don't want to talk to traitors.
But listen to what I have to say.
You executed my uncle.
Must be hard, comandante?
You, here, in the jungle,
and Fidel in Havana having lunch at El Nacional.
Can you imagine?
What made you think the Bolivians
would be receptive to your ideas?
We already had our revolution.
Didn't you hear about the land reform in 1952?
Yes, and Barrientos sold out.
Now you have a military dictatorship.
Have you seen how your peasants live?
If the peasants are so bad off,
why did they turn you in?
Maybe they believed your lies.
Or maybe, they never wanted you here.
Yes, maybe.
Or maybe our failure will wake them up.
Captain.
- Tell me.
- A call for Colonel Zenteno.
I told them he had left, but they
asked for the senior officer.
Bravo 1.
This is Captain Ramírez.
Repeat, please.
Order 600. I will tell the colonel.
Put him there.
Take a picture.
You just have to press here.
So that you can smoke, comandante.
Say cheese.
Stop there.
I have a message for you from the
high command. They ordered a 600.
Fine. I have to leave for Vallegrande.
I'll send a helicopter back at 1400 hours.
Have the body ready.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
You can shoot from here down.
Nothing more.
Listen to me closely.
I need two volunteers.
Someone else?
Sergeant. Let me do it.
Shoot him below the neck.
Come.
Come with me.
Sit down!
Shoot. Do it.