[One Percent of Something]
KoreanDramaX.com
[Episode 2: Match Point.
I Don't Play Losing Games]
- Goodbye!
Is Ms. Kim Da Hyun here, by any chance?
She left not too long ago.
I can get in touch with her
if it's something urgent.
Um, no. You don't need to do that.
It's not urgent.
Grandpa, I've come all the way here.
Thus, I've done all that I could.
This just goes to show
that we're not meant to be.
Oh, my wallet!
Darn it!
Man, not again!
This... is just a coincidence.
It's not fate.
My grandpa wants us to get married.
That doesn't seem like it
has anything to do with me.
Yes, it does.
Because you're the one
that my grandfather chose.
In our family,
whatever that man says is law.
Then you and your grandpa
should talk it over
instead of burdening others
with your family problems!
You shouldn't be acting
as if this isn't your problem
since he wants us to get married.
You. And me. This marriage
will involve the two of us.
What do you mean, this marriage?
I told you!
I have no idea who your grandpa is!
Your grandpa and you
have nothing to do with me!
I just can't bring myself
to believe that!
Don't believe me, then.
Whatever.
What are you doing?
I'm not done talking.
- Let's go.
- Where?
I want the three of us to talk.
What?
You said that you can't bring yourself
to believe what I'm saying.
But you see, I feel the exact same way.
I have no interest in your grandfather,
or in your money, either.
So let's talk.
All three of us.
Will that really be okay?
I'd like to ask you the same thing.
Hey, Ms. Kim!
Um, thank you.
You're not getting in?
Just tell me the address.
I'll take a cab there.
What's the point? We're going to see
the same person, anyway.
It's a dangerous world, you know.
How am I supposed to trust you?
Who knows what you'll do?
What are you doing?
Aren't you going to call?
Call?
Call who?
Your grandpa, of course!
Even if he may be an
accomplice in your scam.
Scam?
Sorry. I shouldn't just say
things like that outright, should I?
Where are you right now?
Why do you care?
The woman you introduced me to wants
to have a three-way conversation.
A three-way conversation?
Why would I need to participate in that?
Who else would she want to talk to?
She says she doesn't know who you are!
You take care of it.
That's your mission.
Hello?
What the...
Lee Jae In.
It's your turn to suffer.
Not everything in the world will
always go your way, you know.
What is it? He freaked out when
you said that I was coming, right?
You should do some pre-planning
if you want to pull off a scam!
Why do you keep going on about a scam?
Why can't you believe me?
You don't believe me at all,
so why should I believe you?
Go and ask anyone on the street if this
kind of situation sounds normal to them.
Are you implying that I'm crazy?
At least you understand that much.
Wait, what are you doing?
I'm not done talking to you!
I'm done talking to you, though!
Do you want me to wrap my arms
around you and force you inside?
I'll seriously call the cops!
What are you doing?
I feel like we need
a real heart-to-heart.
I have nothing to discuss
with the likes of you.
What's this?
[Lee Jae In - Businessman CEO
of SH Alpegia Hotel]
Do you believe me now?
Wait, what?
I'll admit that you two
do look a bit similar.
It's not that we look alike!
That's really me!
Geez.
Was the person calling you... the CEO?
Yeah.
But, um, do you really have
a debt to repay to that teacher?
I told you, yes!
I'm not exactly sure what kind
of debt that may be, but...
can't you repay her in another way?
Throwing CEO Lee at her
isn't paying back her kindness.
You're making her into your enemy.
- Is my grandson really that bad?
- Um, of course not!
The fact that he's not
lacking at all is the problem!
In assholeish-ness, anyway.
That's why he needs Da Hyun.
You're well aware of the fact that
Jae In is a real piece of work, right?
And the women he dated
are all just like him!
All he cares about is money.
I can't let him live like that forever.
And I'm running out of time.
So that chairman left me his fortune,
but I have to marry you to get it.
That's what you're telling me, right?
More or less.
Yeah.
Um, I mean, yes.
I don't particularly like
this condition.
Do you know how much our
company's shares cost right now?
The dividends you'd get per year
that you're apparently not interested in
are more than what you'd make on your
salary in the next ten years, Teach!
Teach-er.
You've been calling me "Teach" or "Woman"
all this time. Call me "Teacher."
Teach, Teacher, whatever.
It's all just a way of referring to you.
It'd be much better if we didn't
waste time talking about that
and talked about what to
do about all of this, instead.
That's your opinion.
I'm starting to wonder which
one of us is the crazy one here.
There's so much money at stake here!
But you don't care?
Look here!
Um... what was your name, again?
- Lee Jae In.
- Yes, Mr. Lee Jae In.
It's not like my house is getting
knocked down tomorrow, or I'm starving.
I'm getting by just fine even without
this nuisance of an inheritance
so why would I need to get married?
And to you, of all people?
Because if you don't marry me,
it'll get really annoying.
Do you think that you'll
be able to handle that?
What... do you mean by that?
You'll get incredible power at SH Group,
as long as you just marry someone.
Tons of people will try to seize this
chance, and swarm over like flies.
It'd be fine to just choose
someone among that crowd, I guess, but--
Oh, that doesn't sound bad.
But you know, you definitely
won't be the one I choose to marry.
Your grandfather sure is strong-willed.
It'll take more than his wealth
to cover up your nasty temper.
That's why he's going out of his way like
this to try and give you a chance at it.
By adding you into the deal
as a free gift.
Some cold water, please.
With ice.
And please put some ice in it.
Yes, sir.
Stop stomping around.
It's driving me crazy.
Are things not going well
with the teacher, or something?
Is she too much to handle?
That doesn't even begin to cover it.
She's literally pouring bucketloads
of salt into my wound!
She's a real pro at pissing people off!
She's really cunning, sly,
and is super brazen.
So in other words, she's smart,
clever, and fearless?
Hey!
Thank you.
Sheesh.
Do you know what
that wily fox said to me?
No, what'd she say?
She called me a "free gift."
Free gift!
Wait, so what happened in the end?
She said I can do whatever,
but she doesn't want any part in it.
She's not interested
in marriage or money.
Wait, then...
what are you going to do?
What else? Just keep pressuring her
until she crumbles!
Have you ever seen me lose to anyone?
[Talking About Management
by Lee Gyu Chul]
Do you know me?
Why did you do this to me?
Why didn't you just give me money,
instead? That would've been better.
Why'd you have to throw
your grandson into the deal, too?
Oh my gosh!
What brings you here?
Why aren't you wearing a hat?
I'm not famous enough to be doing that.
Nobody recognizes me.
No, you're definitely famous!
You're starting to be talked
about on the web now, too!
Hurry up and put a hat on.
You're the only one who
thinks that, Teacher.
No, no.
Put this on.
And I told you, don't call me "teacher."
I'm the president of your fanclub!
Keep it down!
You read all the books
from last time, right?
The GED exam is coming up,
so let's finish these up by then.
Don't worry. I'm diligently
listening to online lectures, too.
Good!
Let's go.
Oh yeah. As the president, I'll buy you
something yummy on behalf of your fans.
Let's go!
Sorry, but I don't play losing games.
That's it for today!
Don't make your parents worry by
studying too much at home, okay?
And make sure to listen
to a lot of classical music!
And to those taking the special class,
make your way to the other classroom.
And, to all my friends in
the third grade Green class...
Today, you all did a...
- Great job!
Great job!
Clean up after yourselves, and let's go!
Is he not here yet?
- No, I am.
- Oh my gosh!
Geez, he scared me!
Thank you.
Why do you keep calling me out?
I told you last time, but I really have
no interest in you, or the SH Group.
Deal with that mess among yourselves.
That's not possible.
Do you know what a three-legged race is?
You and I have been tied
together by my grandpa.
With what?
Marriage.
I thought you said that
you wouldn't go through with it!
Do you want to do it, Teach?
- Are you joking?
- That's a relief.
Thankfully, Grandpa has backed off
from the idea of marriage.
He said that he'd rewrite
his will in six months
if the two of us consort with
one another, for real.
Consort with one another?
What do I have to gain from that?
I told you already! This is the best way
for both of us to escape this mess.
I barely managed to get
him to agree to this, as is!
So, am I supposed to be
thankful about that?
Are you saying that you'll
get married after all, then?
Want to?
This is a joke, right?
You don't need to glare at me like that.
I don't want to marry you, either.
But, why do you keep asking to see me?
He said that he'll be okay with it
even if we don't get married.
However, we must really date,
as a man and woman
- for the next six months--
- Excuse me.
I don't know what your
grandfather's thoughts may be
but I have no intention of dating you.
Want me to tell you how much SH Group
makes in sales every year?
Do you want me to tell you
how much my monthly salary is?
- Why would I?
- Exactly.
Why should I care about
SH Group's yearly profits
when I get confused
about my own yearly salary?
You have the potential to
inherit a huge fortune, here.
You really don't care?
If I really am inheriting a
huge fortune, I am interested.
But if I have to marry you to get
that money, I'll have to refuse.
It's not like I'm starving, here.
I don't really want to get married just
to inherit someone else's fortune.
And I don't want to twist up my
life over something like this, either.
So talk it over with
your grandfather nicely.
And tell him that I'm
completely opposed to this.
So you really do mean it.
Yes. I've really meant it
since the start.
It kind of is a shame, but it's not
like I'd get all that money anyway.
Those people seem super wicked.
Who knows what they're planning?
Yeah, Mom?
All right, all right.
Wow, I'm going to end up meeting all
the herbalists in Korea, at this rate!
No, no. I'm just saying that I'll
definitely end up marrying an herbalist.
Yeah.
And I don't want to twist up my
life over something like this, either.
So talk it over with
your grandfather nicely.
And tell him that I'm
completely opposed to this.
Then SH Group will become Tae Ha's.
Of course, that includes SH Mall.
There's no reason why I have to
make you my successor.
Listen, Teacher.
You're making things complicated
for me by acting like this.
Jae In is quiet, right?
Yes, sir.
So he got rejected.
What a relief. I knew that would happen.
No way.
The CEO, rejected?
I'm growing to hate him
more and more, too.
So I'm sure Da Hyun thinks
even less of him than I do.
All right then, when should
I tell Tae Ha about this?
Call Attorney Park.
N-now, sir?
This is bad.
Dongyang Hotel's restaurant.
Noh Hyun Woo.
Aw man, I hate this so much.
It's the weekend, and
the weather is so nice, too.
And yet, I have to waste it by going to a
marriage meeting with some stranger.
All right, then.
Let's go.
- Did I keep you waiting?
- No, I just got here.
Wow, it sure is hard to see my son!
I heard your grandpa called you over.
How did he blackmail you this time?
Nothing much.
I can figure it out.
Are you... keeping in touch with
your father's sister, in Canada?
- Um, Mr. Noh?
- Oh, yes!
- Hello, Ms. Da Hyun.
- Yes, hello.
Yes. I called her once last week.
She seems to be much healthier now.
I see.
- There wasn't any traffic?
- No. It was great.
Oh, really? It seemed like
there was some unexpected traffic.
Do you know them?
Are they your friends?
Um, yes.
Somewhat.
- I heard that you're an herbalist.
- Oh, yes.
Looks like it's a marriage meeting.
They look good together.
You're not going to get married?
I'm getting tired of waiting
for you to get married!
I'll get to it when the time comes.
Hurry up and come back to
SH Group, already.
You're the Chairman's eldest grandson.
I know that.
But I don't want to pop in there just
because I'm the chairman's grandson.
I'll go back to SH Group
when the time comes.
You're not just Chairman Lee's grandson.
My father is the Chairman
of Daehan Electric.
Your grandfather and I would
provide you with anything you need.
- Please, eat.
- You know that, right?
Um, Mother.
I think I'll have to go.
Is there a problem?
Yes.
A huge problem.
All right, then.
I'll go see Madam Kang, since I'm here.
Take care of your problem, then.
Are you really close with that PD
from the broadcasting company?
Yes. We went to school together,
so we keep in touch.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
Ms. Kim Da Hyun?
Oh my! Huh?
Mr. Lee?
What are you doing here?
I thought that you and I still
had some loose ends to tie up.
So isn't it cheating for you
to be here, doing this?
Cheating?
What are you talking about?
We talked about this
more than enough last time!
- I told you, I don't want to marry--
- Exactly!
Let's push back our wedding
for now, just as you said.
I'd be fine with us getting
married tomorrow, but...
Oh, yes.
I'm sorry.
When you date someone,
tiny misunderstandings pile up, and...
Well, at any rate,
dating sure is tough.
Um, we're not like that at all.
What are you doing?
What do you mean? Do you want
to get married, then, like Grandpa said?
I thought we didn't have to!
I thought we just had to date--
I don't think I should be here.
- Wait!
- Have a safe trip home!
Shall we start over, then?
Oh, I'll move over there.
Oh my. He didn't touch his food at all.
Do you want to finish that
before we start talking?
Are you out of your mind?
Why did you do that?
No, I'm not.
Like I said, I want to start over.
Start what over?
When did we ever start anything?
Well, we can just get started
right now, then.
Hey, wait!
Wait!
You were dating someone? Why didn't
you bring him over sooner, then?
I told you, no! I don't know!
I don't even know the guy!
Well, it's not true
that you don't know me.
Well, um, a guy who's slightly crazy--
No way!
Well, no, he's not dangerous.
All right. All right. I'll go on
another marriage meeting next week.
There. Happy now?
I'm telling you, it's not true!
Okay. Bye.
Think of an excuse
that'll make me forgive you.
I have no intention of doing that.
Why do you have to go out of
your way to date another man?
And you're even going on
marriage meetings to find someone!
You can just solve everything
by going out with me.
Because that's complicated!
And it's weird!
I'll make it uncomplicated!
And what's so weird about it?
You need a man, and I need you.
Teach...er.
Don't people say that that
you're insanely stubborn?
- Sometimes.
- That's not a compliment!
Fine.
Let's give it a shot.
He wants me to give Tae Ha
a copy of the will, too?
By when?
Like, yesterday.
Right now.
Hey, Deputy Han. What did the
American Chamber of Commerce say?
The CEO?
Well, um, the situation is... um.
You know the phrase,
"hopeless endeavor?" Like that.
I feel like I'm going to go insane.
Okay. Call me later, okay?
I'll say this again.
What my grandpa wants is for us
to see each other for six months.
This is the best way.
And it's the most ideal option we have.
In my opinion, it's not the
most ideal option "we" have.
It seems like this benefits you
more than anyone else.
You'll inherit the fortune
just for dating me.
I have to give up on
getting stocks and a husband.
And to make matters worse,
I have to tolerate you for six months.
You're quite clever.
Well, I haven't ever had
someone tell me that I'm dumb.
You said that you had no
interest in the fortune, though!
And I'm not that interested
in a husband, either.
Also, a deal is supposed
to be fair for both parties!
Well, you know, you're not
losing out in any way.
If everything gets
resolved well in six months
I'll give you a sum equivalent to three
years worth of dividends, in cash.
It'll be much easier for you to date me
than to get tangled up with
stocks and director meetings.
Oh, and you won't have to go on marriage
meetings to meet weird men, either.
Really, now?
I feel like this option is actually a lot
more complicated than the first one.
If I get married, I don't need
to accept cash from you.
And the people who get tangled up with me
because of my shares will be nice to me.
I'll have tons of money, and have a lot
of shares. And I'll have a husband, too.
So why should I choose the difficult
path instead of this easy path?
Oh. As for that man from earlier,
he wasn't a weird person.
Fine. What do you want, then, Teach?
Let me make this clear now.
I'm not marrying you.
Thanks. I feel exactly the same way.
- Firstly--
- "Firstly?"
You have multiple things that you want?
Aren't you being too greedy?
Firstly, call me Ms. Kim Da Hyun,
or Teacher.
I've mentioned this
several times already.
That's easy enough, right?
Damn it.
And please watch your language.
Fine, Ms. Kim Da Hyun.
Teacher Kim Da Hyun.
This is Lee Jae In.
Negotiate with AmCham Korea
regarding the meeting, first!
If you miss this chance, you'd better
have a letter of resignation for me.
What is it?
He... told me to write
my letter of resignation.
Did he finally realize that you're
working for the chairman, too?
Wait. Were you the one
who told him about that?
Are you out of your mind?
Who knows what'll happen if he finds out?
You know, I'm his friend and all,
but he's super scary.
Me too.
Why is it that everyone in his family
is such an asshole?
I know, right?
I'm genuinely curious.
So, what do you want?
Money? SH Group?
Or something else? Just name it.
You have to tell me for us to negotiate.
You can give me anything I want?
Looks like you're loaded, then.
Just how much can you offer me?
Hmm, it's much easier to talk to
you now that you're being frank.
Well, then, tell me.
What is it that you want?
A brand new technology system
for my school's library.
There were a lot of budget cuts
from the Board of Education this year.
And it'd be nice if you threw in
a lot of nice books, to boot.
And a nice indoor gym, so the kids
can play in there on rainy days.
And it'd be nice to have
a school bus, too.
Oh, and it'd be nice to have a big
mirror in the multipurpose room, too.
I'm the academic adviser for
the dance club, you see.
Anything else?
Can you get me some stars from the sky,
so we can make the science room brighter?
That'll be hard, since I think
that the SH Space Program
hasn't broken ground yet.
- Anything else?
- Um, excuse me.
That was a joke.
Well, I'm not joking.
Is that all you want?
The school will take care of everything
else, so I don't need anything.
But can you get my Ji Su
a better management company?
What?
Who?
He's a fantastic singer, and actor!
On top of that, he's so handsome!
If you just help him out a little,
he'll definitely become a star.
His management company
is kind of crappy--
I mean, um, it's pretty tyrannical.
He's pretty much stuck in a slave
contract, so he can't even leave.
It might even take a lawsuit.
I mean, how could they ask him for 300
million won for breaking the contract?
Isn't that ridiculous?
Um, does your attorney know
how to handle cases like these?
Is that really all you want?
- You mean it?
- Yes!
I'm not joking this time.
This is a lot more important to me
than some capricious will.
A young kid's life depends on this.
That's what you think,
Teach...
er.
What else?
Is that all?
No. If you'd just do that for me,
I can agree to anything you want.
Not including getting married
to you, though, just like you said.
Okay.
The contract is in place.
Don't change your mind later.
Fine.
Let's write up a contract.
What?
Goodbye.
Teacher!
Oh!
- Are you doing this on purpose?
- What?
Why do you always leave things behind?
KoreanDramaX.com
If I just date him, Ji Su's issue
with his company will be solved.
She's a fox.
And a cunning one, at that.
Don't make a copy of that last page.
You were three minutes late.
I guess you really do
have a lot of money.
You forgot about all of that overnight.
I'm not sure.
It's my first time seeing them.
Does Jae In have a girlfriend?
Don't act like you know me.
Don't even look my way.
I thought you said that you weren't
embarrassed of me, at the very least.
Close your eyes.
And I will kiss you.
[One Percent of Something]