(Episode 8)
How dare she talk about your mother?
Who does she think she is?
Don't worry, Jae Yi.
We'll just deny everything if something goes wrong.
I'll go find the reporter and sue her.
I'll find a solution no matter what.
Reputation is very important for an actress.
You went through a lot to hide your identity.
It's because of that jerk.
You get hurt again.
(Is Han Jae Yi Jee Hye Won's daughter?)
(She's the only one to survive.)
(Is it really true?)
(Han Jae Yi is found...)
(Han Jae Yi is found to be Jee Hye Won's daughter.)
It's what the inmates wait for the most.
Time to exercise.
It's the most free time to the inmates.
In case of emergency,
guards are placed everywhere.
After the exercise,
we count the number of inmates.
The counting...
is similarly conducted as in the military.
- Count. - 1, 2, 3, 4.
5, 6 present.
Count.
- 1, 2. - 3, 4.
5, 6 present.
- Count. - 1, 2, 3, 4.
Most inmates are put into work.
Only death row inmates...
have a choice to participate or not.
Goodness.
Do it gently.
Clean this up.
Do it properly.
Let's move on.
Do it gently.
Number 2837, where are you going?
Come back to your place.
I heard you.
Do they think we're monkeys in a cage? Darn it.
(I never sold my daughter's death.)
Don't buy it.
Don't ever buy it.
(Yoon Hui Jae's family agrees to share profits...)
(Yoon Hui Jae's family agrees to share profits from the book.)
Welcome.
What's good here?
- "What's good here?" - Yes.
Is it your first time here?
Yes.
Everything is good here.
Today around 3pm, Kim Sang Chul, the representative...
for the victims' families of serial killer Yoon Hui Jae,
- What are you doing? Hurry up. - applied for an injunction...
- Are you distracted again? - to prohibit sales.
- Hey. - Regarding his autobiography,
Reporter Park...
acts as a proxy for Yoon's rights for sales.
And she claims that details of his criminal acts...
and his victims were already announced in public.
- What kind of reporter is that? - He denied the victims' opinions.
- She must be insane. - Also Reporter Park...
still intends to give copies of his autobiography...
to his family and the victims' families.
She hasn't changed her plan.
Many people...
are still interested by Yoon's autobiography.
As he applied for an injunction to prohibit sales,
- we expect a conflict between... - Hello.
the publishing company and the victims' families.
This is Han Ji Yoo from MBS News.
What's wrong? Who called?
It's nothing. Someone called the wrong number.
- Hello? - Who do you think you are?
- How dare she hang up on me? - Just hang up.
Who is this?
How dare you curse at us?
Are you Yoon Hui Jae's wife?
Do you make profit from that autobiography?
You piece of trash.
Is it nice to earn money as his family?
Are you happy...
that you make money off of the victims?
Chugae Island?
Did you think no one would find you hiding on that island?
I'll find you on behalf of the victims' families.
I'll burn your house down.
- Fine, go ahead. - What?
Neither my son nor I...
earned a cent from that book written by that crazy man.
Go ahead and burn our house.
What on earth?
Stop cursing.
Who are you to curse at me?
Or curse at my children?
My children did nothing wrong, you punk!
Mom.
Are you okay?
So Jin.
Your brother.
Call Do Jin right now.
If anyone visits him before his graduation,
he shouldn't see them.
Tell him not to pick up calls from unknown numbers.
Okay?
- Do it now. - Okay.
Hey, did something happen?
You look pale.
Of course not.
It's nothing.
Why would I look pale?
I'm completely fine.
No...
He's not picking up.
What do we do?
Today around 3pm,
Kim Sang Chul, the representative for the victims' families...
- of serial killer Yoon Hui Jae... - He wrote an autobiography?
applied for an injunction...
to prohibit the sales...
of Yoon Hui Jae's autobiography from being sold.
This autobiography outlines...
the details of his crimes against the victims,
so there was a lot of controversy even before its publication.
The victim families found...
the autobiography to be misusing...
the deaths of the victims,
and have performed a protest against the sale of the book.
Until the court decides on the verdict...
of the injunction,
the victim families say they will continue their protest.
The details of his crimes were distorted in favor of him...
Yes, sir. I can't get through...
What about Nak Won?
I'll be there right away.
Do Jin.
I thought you weren't coming.
You're early.
Let's go inside.
Wait.
Actually,
I'm not feeling well today.
Could we take today off?
I'm sorry. You made your way here.
Sure.
I'm sorry.
Don't die.
Stay alive.
You must stay alive...
no matter what.
It's not your fault.
So please don't die. Never.
If you die,
I won't ever forgive you.
So...
promise me.
Promise me.
Promise me...
that you will stay alive.
Tell me you will endure it...
just like your name.
Tell me...
that you will keep this promise.
Answer me, Na Moo.
The air in here...
feels different today.
Did we have a visitor?
There were a few visitors earlier.
I haven't watched a movie like this in a while.
I miss my family more than ever today.
I'm not sure if I can say it's fortunate,
but at least your oldest son is here with you.
That punk is just like me.
He gets hot easily, so he doesn't wear a jacket...
even in the winter.
However, my wife...
has cold hands and feet. It's because she works a lot.
My daughter...
won't have breakfast if there isn't a hot soup on the table.
Also,
my youngest...
My youngest...
My son Na Moo...
wouldn't go to bed...
if I wasn't around.
He was worried about me whenever I came home late.
He would stay up all night studying while waiting for me.
Once he heard the gates,
he would sneak over quietly...
without waking up the family.
He would tip toe to the door...
while rubbing his eyes...
to welcome me home.
"Father."
"You're late."
That's what he would say.
I miss that sweet face.
Just because I wanted to see that face,
I went home late on purpose at times.
What do you think?
My youngest kid...
is a good son, isn't he?
Please stop.
Stop it!
I wonder if he eats regularly.
When he gets fixated,
he forgets to eat, you see.
You should quit smoking. It's bad for you for health.
You should live for a long time.
Isn't life...
just great?
Actress Jee Hye Won who was killed...
in 2006 by serial killer Yoon Hui Jae...
has been one of the most-searched names in the past few hours.
That's because Yoon Hui Jae revealed that...
Jee's daughter followed in her mother's footsteps...
to become an actress, in an interview...
with a weekly current affairs magazine.
People are trying to find out who she is...
- by looking online. - It's too cold for March.
Where the tow truck?
I'm getting really sick of you lot.
- Will you just go to bed? - Sir.
I'll do it. You get some rest.
No, you have to film tomorrow.
I can't let an actress do this.
I'll deal with tomorrow when tomorrow comes.
Do as I say.
I can't do that.
You only just left the hospital.
I'm an expert at this so get in the car.
I can't let you do this.
Your hands are freezing cold.
It's March and look at you.
I said I'm okay.
No, no.
Use the blanket in there.
Are you okay?
Do you need help?
No, it's okay.
Our car's just old.
The tow truck is on its way.
It's quite cold. Will you be okay?
Yes, I'm well wrapped up.
Thank you.
Take care then.
- We will. Thank you. - Let's go.
Good girl.
Nak Won.
Hey.
Moo Won.
How come you're here?
What about training?
Are you okay?
You bet. Whose sister am I?
(Reporter Kim Sang Ho)
I put my name...
on the injunction against the book.
Kim Ji Young's father called me last week.
I see.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you sooner.
But...
You were worried for me.
It's okay. You did it and that works with me.
We knew this would happen...
when you started acting.
Right?
Yes.
I'm just annoyed that...
he talked about Mom and me.
That's all.
That's really all there is to it.
Why did you come all the way here over that?
What if you're expelled?
I'll have to support you then.
To be honest,
today was a really, really long day.
It felt so long,
as if I was dreaming.
Seeing you brought me back to reality.
I'm so glad you came over.
I didn't have a nice day at all.
Moo Won.
What?
Do you think...
we did what we should?
We got out alive.
(From Yoon Hui Jae)
(To my darling Ok Hee)
We survived,
so we have to go on...
living each day as it comes.
(To Na Moo. Are you okay?)
(I miss you.)
I miss you.
Na Moo.
I want to see you.
We all...
survived the fiery pit.
(Forest)
What's this?
You're mean to the end, Yoon Na Moo.
Do you still...
like me that much?
You'll feel sorry for me...
for the rest of your life.
You'll feel so guilty that...
you'll be hurt whenever you see me.
You'll suffer like crazy on your own.
What more do you want?
What about you?
How about you?
Nak Won.
Can you...
still...
smile at me?
Just to survive,
we go on living.
(Come and Hug Me)
You have a visitor today. The one who visits often.
Your father wants to see you a lot.
Will you come with me?
How dare you publish a book like this?
- Who are you? - I'm his son.
Everything in my father's autobiography is a lie.
There's no truth in that book.
Who is he? He fell in love with a girl.
He destroyed our family.
It seems like...
there's a secret love story between you two.
Graduated with honors? You're a police officer?
You wanted to be with her knowing that your father is a monster.
That's your fault.