One Direction
You And I
Hope u liked it
I figured it out,
I figured it out, from black and white
Seconds and hours
Maybe they had to take some time
I know how it goes
I know how it goes, from wrong and right
Silence and sound
Did they ever hold each other, tight
Like us, did they ever fight,
Like us?
You And I
We don’t want to be like them
We can make it till the end
Nothing can come between
You And I
Not even the gods above (There's Only One GOD)
Can separate the two of us
No nothing can come between
You And I
Ohh.. You And I
I figured it out
Saw the mistakes of up and down
Meet in the middle
There’s always room for common ground
I see what is like
I see what is like, for day and night
Never together
Cause they see things in a different light
Like us, they never tried
Like us
You And I
We don’t want to be like them
We can make it till the end
Nothing can come between
You And I
Not even the gods above
Can separate the two of us
Cause You And I ... haa..
We don’t want to be like them
We can make it till the end
Nothing can come between
You And I
Not even the gods above
Can separate the two of us
No nothing can come between
You And I
You And I ...haaa...
ohhhh You And I
You And I
We can make it .if we try
ohhhh You And I