Orderly or Disorderly?
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 1, take 1.
Come!
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Disorderly, scene 1, take 1.
Come, children!
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Disorderly, scene 2, take 1.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 2, take 1.
That's fine.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 3, take 1.
That's fine.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Disorderly, scene 3, take 1.
- How long has it been?
- One minute.
It's even past one minute.
It's taking a very long time.
- Well it's supposed to take time.
That's what we're trying to show.
Disorderly, it takes time.
- Yes, but you can't see
what they're doing.
- Well, they're getting on,
what else would they be doing?
We'll take one scene from inside,
it'll show better. It takes time.
They're pushing, it shows.
Yes.
How long has it been?
- It's even past two minutes.
It's taken very long. I should
continue filming, no?
- The longer it takes, the better.
That's what we're saying with this
film. We want to say it takes time.
It's an experiment, we're
not cheating are we.
There are 40 kids, 1 bus and
they're getting on little by little.
- More! They're 60 to 70 kids!
- 60, whatever. Anyway, they're...
- Before it was orderly, now...
It'll show when we go shoot
from inside. They're pushing.
So let's go inside now. Shoot from
inside, and see how it is.
Cut.
Fine. Now let's shoot one take
with an orderly fasion too.
Camera.
That's enough.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 4, take 1.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Disorderly, scene 4, take 1.
Fine.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Disorderly, scene 6, take 1.
Fine.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 6, take 1.
Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 5, take 1.
- He crossed.
He went.
Well, it's orderly.
... in the middle of the street.
- It's didn't go well.
- They ruined it.
That man, damn. Look he's
going straight in the...
Where's is he passing?
- He's gone in the center.
- Cut.
Sound. Camera.
Orderly, scene 5, take 2.
- Let's see how this one goes.
- These ones are going,
that side.
- Cut.
... had asked this...
- Yes.
- ... controlled. - ... stopped.
- That's why he stands there.
- ... they'd stop so we can shoot.
- She went!
- She went.
- It's ruined.
- Cut. Cut.
Camera.
Yes, it begins.
- Reprising...
- Cut.
Camera.
Where's this man going?
What the...
He can't controle this place.
I say, ask him to just controle
this place for just a minute.
We have one take. If we could
just take one orderly...
- It won't work.
- But why won't it?
... make it somehow, so that we could
If we could just shoot one take.
- They're not listening to him. You can
see that. They're not listening to him.
Well, let's at least do one thing.
Let's take disorderly.
Disorderly, scene 5, take 1.
...
- Where should we shoot the orderly?
- Orderly, I don't know. Let's ask
and see where it can be shot.
- ...
Subs by hirvi14