Subtitles by the Team By Your Side @ Viki
♫ When you're speeding up, the horsepower flies into your arms ♫
♫ I’ll deliver the view beneath the clouds high in the air ♫
♫ The city is impenetrable ♫
♫ In this microcosmic world, we feel touched ♫
♫ This is the dream that belongs to us ♫
♫ Every move is a dance and it's a spectacle ♫
♫ A conductor's hand so respectable ♫
♫ This feeling's so indescribable ♫
♫ Go rambo go rambo ♫
♫ We're going wild wild wild ♫
♫ Leaving the physical realm yeah ♫
♫ Till all the chaos turn so calm ♫
♫ And we light years ahead and now that we gone ♫
♫ Time makes a record of us ♫
♫ With creativity and dialogue,  ♫
♫ we format love ♫
♫ And take control of the heart ♫
♫ Putting forth our summer, ♫
♫ the tears on our journey now evaporate ♫
♫ Begin with signals and reflections ♫
♫ Right now, start flying ♫
[Only Side by Side with You]
[Episode 38]
Who is Chang Jianxiong?
If you tell him, he doesn't get it.
If you don't, he is even more clueless.
His acuity when it comes to relationship is really one where he would neither listen to reason nor bow to force.
He is the classical model of an egg without any cracks.
Do you still want your salary and bonus?
I can't communicate with people like you who don't understand women.
Looks like the greatest enemy to a woman
is not aging or a sixteen year old girl.
It's the brain of a straight man.
Qiao, can I go after Chang Jianxiong?
Chang Jianxiong doesn't belong to me. You shouldn't be asking me this.
- You should ask...
- Who?
Yourself.
Shi Yue, you are using the guitar pretending to be Casanova again.
Thinking about when we were in training camp, you gave the female instructor...
It's a birthday cake. You need to eat it while it's hot.
It's bad for your health when it's cold.
Do you still remember what you said to the female instructor to cause me to run five kilometers less?
What female instructor?
- I didn't. I know that every night, you were with...
- What female instructor?
No, you are my female instructor.
This alcohol's after effects are pretty strong.
Why did you drink so much?
You can't puke here.
I can't take it anymore. I'm dizzy.
Why are you here?
Aunt.
What are you doing? You...
Dad, what brings you here?
My daughter's home is small. Raising dogs
it'll make them too grumpy.
It's also not convenient for anyone to live here too.
It so happens that I have a big house.
Let's do this. I will take care of them for you for a few days.
What are the names of your dogs?
This is Eldest, Second, and Third.
Come, Eldest. Get up.
Let's go.
Give that to me.
Grandpa. They haven't agreed yet and you are taking the dogs along with you.
This is not what I meant.
They have ready-made meals here. They haven't finished eating yet. Let's leave after the meal.
His cooking skill is really not bad.
When did you had it?
Why do you raise German Shepherds?
A military dog with lasting affection.
I will open the door for you.
- Be good.
- Let's go.
Over here.
Let's go.
What should we do?
Are you worried about the dogs?
I'm worried about you.
What are you worried about?
Once my father extended his hand, there will definitely be no way out.
Why do I feel that your father is an extremely loyal person?
The first time we met, he took our dogs along with him.
I feel that, in the future, there wouldn't be any barriers in our communication.
We can also be good friends.
So thick skinned. Just wait and see.
- Just wait and see.
- You think that I'm a bit like your father.
What?
I'm a bit like your father.
It was clearly supposed to be mars colliding with earth kind of fighting event.
How come it became a heart-warming Chinese opera of finding joy in helping others?
Grandpa, are you afraid?
You don't understand. We are here today
not to protest. It's intimidation.
What's the difference?
A show of force relies on fists.
Intimidation relies on wisdom to advance.
To add further, your Aunt was there.
Even if I ask questions, he will give you false answers.
You are really an expert. So, these dogs are actually human hostages?
No, they are dog hostages.
That's right, dog hostages. Let's go.
Director Wen.
Sister Wen Di, you are not loyal.
Yesterday was CEO Shi's birthday. Why didn't you take me along with you?
He has a host with him. Why would you go there?
There were many good men in Lucid Dream who had hosts too?
No, there were just the four of us.
Does Brother Chang has a host too?
If Chang Jianxiong were to have a relationship with a woman,
all the sows will be able to climb trees too.
Zhen Hao told me that the best method in love is to take advantage of the situation.
It's the best opportunity for Brother Chang who is single and lonely now.
I say, this Chang Jianxiong,
is not only stupid. During critical times, he becomes a loser.
He distinctly has muscles.
The more muscles a person has, the smaller his brain is.
The time, place and environment was perfect last night...
Last night? Both of you were in a situation?
What happened? Tell me.
Xiao An, I'm warning you. Don't ever be deceived by men's outer appearances.
But not only does he has a good outer appearance, he has a good father too.
What's the relationship?
Who knows? His good father may become his weakness.
When there is money, there is less affections. When there is power, there is less loyalty.
What's so great about rich heirs?
Are things going smoothly on your end?
I think there seems to be some problems here.
Listen to me.  I'm here...
I'll call you later.
Sorry. Please wait for a moment.
Is Chang Jianxiong really that bad?
You are...
I'm the Chang Jianxiong's weakness that you were referring to.
Yes, his good father.
Uncle, I wasn't talking bad about you just now.
Yes, I did talk bad about Chang Jianxiong just now.
But you should also know that...
sometimes when one likes that person, she would say...
Don't panic.
I'm on your side.
Do you know that Chang Jianxiong's father took the initiative to visit me?
Why did he look for you?
The both of you are not even together yet and the elder of the family has jumped out to oppose it?
Daddy Chang is an assistant that will help me fulfill the impossible.
His style is totally different from your Chief in the family.
Moreover, do you know?
He even volunteered to be my planted agent and
asked me to get his foolish son as soon as possible.
I envy you.
How are things going at your end?
After your father took away his dogs, have there been any new movements?
None at all.
It has been a few days and there were no movements at all. It's too scary.
I think this is definitely the first step for a son-in-law by the old people.
No, you don't know my father.
I think this is the calm before the storm.
On my end, everything is ready. It's only short of Chang Jianxiong.
On your end, both of you are willing. It's just that there is a father who comes in-between.
Look at how carefree Hao Jie and Ouyang Qi's lives are.
They have been away for fun for a long time and still not back yet.
Should I learn from Hao Jie and be tyrannical?
I will give you my support.
With someone like Chang Jianxiong who is so slow-paced, you should use strong tactics.
Dad?
I see.
What's going on?
My father wants to see Shi Yue.
This is a good thing. Your father has taken the initiative to attack.
What do you plan to do?
I can't be tyrannical anymore.
I... I should try to outwit him instead.
You've already delivered dog food for three days.
But, you were unable to scout out any signs of activity.
What are you doing?
I just came back from Uncle Nan's house yesterday.
How did it go?
I have never seen Uncle Nan in such a tight predicament.
He chased your three dogs around the entire yard.
His entire life of military training was defeated at the hands of your dogs.
This isn't some good omen.
That is too perfect. I only need three dogs
to test out my father-in-law's true feelings towards me.
What the heck? Do you know how much misfortune your three dogs have brought onto the Nan Family?
So much misfortune,
yet he still has not returned the dogs to me.  Do you know what this means?
Returning grudges with kindness?
Love me, love my dog. Even my dogs could enter and garrison.
How hard could it be for a human?
You are too naive.
I can now confirm this little bit.
The dogs have already entered the house. How far can you be?
Of course... Our first meeting was plainly unexpected.
But do you know that being unexpected has its advantage.
This is giving both of us some space, some time.
Letting us have some mental preparation on our second meeting.
What's the result of your first testing?
Very good. I really like this old man.
Kind. A good person.
I actually feel that he's quite like me, isn't it?
Then...I wish you good luck.
- Don't worry. It will surely be fine.
- I'm going now.
Hey! Hey... Wait! Wait!
Oh, right. I still have to give you an advice.
Better prepare yourself well.
No... She texted me earlier...
How come he suddenly wants to see me. Did some major thing happened?
Aren't you constantly been thinking of how to get my father?
But I still am not mentally prepared now.
- I hope that we can...
- My father hates people who run away midway the most.
He is actually easy to amuse.
He kept saying that...
Men should be bold and frank and not one that keeps bowing low to others.
Continue saying. Give me more suggestions.
He likes my brother-in-law a lot. Why is that?
Oh, my brother-in-law submit to his commander. Easy, right?
What did your brother-in-law wear during their first meeting then?
I've also called my sister about that.
Won't this be too hot?
It surely will work. Fighting! Go change your clothes.
What if I perspire in front of your father?
I'll help wipe it for you.
Let's drink.
Dad.
- Uncle Chang, you're here too.
- Oh, you're here.
Uncle.
I brought you some gifts. Are my dogs obedient?
We see each other again.
Do you know how to play 'shuang sheng (double lift)'?
A little bit.
Let's go.
Let's go!
A little bit? You have the nerve to say 'a little bit'?
Old Chang.
- You sit there.
- Okay.
- You sit in front of me.
There's no use sitting by his side. I'll still scold him if he plays the wrong cards.
You were in a hurry to tell us to come here just to play cards with you?
A person observing a card game shouldn't talk. That's the rule.
Jianxiong, deal the cards.
Okay!
Blood is thicker than water. Tacit understanding.
Hey, with your speed, it doesn't look good for you two.
Royal Flush
Just get from the deck.
We have tacit understanding.
Don't you know to help me?
Old Chang,
it is the one laughing in the end that's considered the victor.
Jeez, just move faster.
How did you know that my father has 2 Kings?
Although the face of your father earlier was so tensed (poker face),
you didn't see that his eyes were shining.
How then did you know that he needs diamonds?
This is based on the pattern that he takes his card.
From lower to top, the order was always spade, club, and diamond.
In this round, it takes him the longest to get a diamond card. That's why, I gave him a diamond.
Do you know what this is called?
What?
Intelligence can change our lives. Details can get you your father-in-law.
You think that you've passed his test already, is that it?
Not only passed, I've completely won him over.
You didn't pay attention to how he looked at me.
One eye is doting.
The other eye is liking.
But do you know what if it's both eyes?
Love.
Since I did so well, shouldn't you give me some reward?
Just focus on driving. You kept talking.
Stop sulking alone.
Look at you. You now have a grandchild and a joyous and harmonious family.
Look at me. Look at my stupid son.
No career achievement. No marriage.
And kept mixing in with those two.
I really don't know what his brain is thinking.
You're just sitting here and awaiting death.
Even if you develop hypertension, it won't solve the problem.
If you continue saying it, I indeed will get sick from anger already.
Hey, you should learn from me. Attacking proactively.
How?
Catch his key point. Attack his weakness. Test him.
What you did is called testing?
You clearly gave that lad a position in your family.
In looking for a son-in-law, I only have one requirement.
What?
Knows how to play cards.
Hey, didn't you say you're going to invite those old guys over?
Attack him until not a single armor remains.
[Future Up]
- Look, here.
- Director Wen.
The development of our electronic speed regulator has almost
reached the previous estimate.
The flight panel will also be 80% complete by this week.
Old Qin, what about yours?
The design proposals for the brushless motor and propellers have been submitted to the factory.
They said that deliver the sample product, at the latest, by Friday.
Not bad. Based on our progress rate, Hunter can soon start production.
With us working this hard,
should we not worry about our year-end bonus already?
Year-end bonus...
Let me award you a little gold medal first. It has an inspiring nature.
Only mental reward?
Isn't health the most precious material award?
What time is it already?
Beijing time...
11 sharp.
How come Xiao Qiao is not yet here?
Miss me already?
The timely rain is here.
Come...it's time for you to relieve me from my shift.
Now that you're here, I can go out and resolve some personal problem.
What personal problem? If it's marriage-related, I'll let you go.
It's marriage matters concerning Chang Jianxiong.
Hurry and go. Don't rush to come back.
Boss, let me report my work to you.
Boss, see mine first!
Look.
Uncle Chang.
Xiao Wen, hurry and sit down.
Wow! You have ordered so many food.
Look and tell me what you think of my strategy.
Is there anything special about these?
There is.
This is about my son.
This is a strategy on how to get my son.
Look at this steak.
80% cooked. It's just like the relationship between you two.
You two are very familiar with each other already. But if you want it to progress further,
you still lack 20%.
What you mean is the timing isn't right?
A 80% cooked steak has the best flavor.
Now is the best time to gobble it up with one move and it's a chance that must not be missed.
But if you are to wait for it to be 100% cooked
before turning from friends to lovers...
it will be too late.
Look at this plate next.
This is the breakout point in making my son yield to you.
Macaroni?
He likes to eat that?
His heart is empty.
But before, he was like this.
Have a one-track mind.
Because that time, his heart only has Nan Qiao.
But don't worry. Based on my observations,
he has now completely put down his thoughts on being Nan Qiao.
Right now, whoever is able to fill up his empty heart,
she'll then be able to eat him.
This person is you, Wen Di.
I understand now.
For the meantime, I should give him more warmth and show up more.
Let his eyes have only me.
Slowly, his eyes wiill also have only me.
Get him return to this very fine and long Italian spaghetti.
Being a tactician to an intelligent person is really fun.
Uncle Chang, what strategy does this salad represents?
This...
I understand already. What you mean is to make Chang Jianxiong jealous.
Right. Right.
That is indeed what I want to say.
If he gets jealous because of you,
doesn't that mean he cares about you?
If he even made some moves, we can be sure
that he likes you already.
We've set the strategy. How then are we going to do the deployment for this operation?
Don't worry about that. Don't forget that I'm exactly in the PR field.
Just wait to see how I
catch Jianxiong while he's inside the jar. (confident to catch him)
Okay. I'll have one advice.
You must not hold back.
Come.
Yogurt drink paired with Wester cuisine, what strategy is this?
Looking to be in disharmony, but they actually are very compatible.
This is like you and Chang Jianxiong.
I like this mix and match.
Welcome!
Take a look.
Thanks.
Hey. What do you think about this?
It doesn't seem to be your style.
Is changing my style not good?
What about this?
This is indeed your style.
But the white pants are too large. Not good.
- Drink some juice.
- Thanks.
We have a few dresses in our shop that fits your aura.
Wait a minute. I'll look for it.
Your service here is quite thorough.
I have guessed that you must like drinking juices for your skin is so good.
It's penetratingly rosy and bright.
Look. This dress really fits your figure.
It is indeed quite beautiful, but...it seems to be too long. Quite inconvenient.
If you wear this dress, you'll be like a princess.
Any man who sees you wearing this will not bear to let you work anymore.
Hey. What do you think?
I don't know.
- I'll look at others first.
- Okay.
This one was totally created for you.
Only your figure can carry this.
We have a dressing room here. Do you want to try this on?
It suits you so perfectly.
How about it?
This dress indeed suits you very well.
But the back is too revealing. It's easy to catch a cold.
It's also good this way.
Go out then.
Go out.
I'll pay with my card.
This way please.
Thanks.
I really feel that this dress suits you very well, that's why, I gifted it to you.
But covering up a dress with such good design,
do you understand aesthetics?
Of course, I do.
We've already understand your abilities and experiences.
Do you still have other questions?
It's okay already.
Then, let's end here for today. We'll inform you once we have a decision. Thanks.
Thanks.
Oh, my.
There is one more person who submitted his resume online. He's here.
[Jerry Hao  (Hao Jie)]
Hi.
Why are you imitating them and making trouble here?
Since you two are already in the middle of a job interview,
then interview me too in passing.
I'll leave this one to you.
Bye-bye.
Did you have fun?
My name is Hao Jie. Just like my name, I have good looks (hao kan) and an outstanding (jie chu) brain.
You're so annoying. Come then. Height, weight, age.
Just right to be grouped, to protect, and to pester Ouyang Qi.
This job that you're applying into is not something that I can give.
Nan Qiao, say some fair words with me. I have a fine body, right?
In terms of looks, I can pass, right? For intelligence, let's not even talk about it anymore.
Just casually placing me in the marriage market and I'll be a hot product.
How come when it comes to Ouyang Qi, I've become a defective good?
I've also courted a lot of girls before.
But how come I just can't pick up this tyrannical flower?
Why?
Because...looks, body, and brain are not the basic requirement
in this job that you're applying into.
If you want to apply as Ouyang Qi's fiancé, you actually just need to do well on
preparing to never leave her.
I'm already ready to be with her forever.
I even proposed marriage to her...
You proposed already?
Did she accept it?
Of course not. She actually feels that only a trained dog
is suitable to find a lifetime partner.
A high level animal like humans
is best to just live alone.
After living for so long, I can't even compare to a dog.
She totally have rejected me.
She actually isn't rejecting you.
I can see that you really like Ouyang Qi.
I also hope that she can quickly go back to living her life.
I feel that Xiao Qi does like you.
She might just not know how to put down Nan Si.
I can wait for her. I have the patience. No matter how long, I can wait for her.
This isn't a time problem. Enough already. Your interview is done.
As for if you can be hired or not, go back and put on some more effort.
Okay.
Thanks!
Did you had fun?
It was great.
It's good that you are here. I brought you a gift from my travel.
I actually planned to deliver it to you.
What would you like to drink?
Water.
Xiao Qiao, what are you doing?
Last night, I dreamed that I saw my older brother.
He said these should be returned to its original owner.
It can't be.
You also know that it can't be? You think that if you think about it everyday, it will become possible?
Shouldn't you think for yourself?
Without these, how can it be proven that he existed?
Don't take these away. Leave them with me.
Go with me to a place.
Nothing has changed here.
Look carefully. It has changed.
When you first came to our home, was that tree that tall?
We have already replaced the trash bins in our home.
What are you trying to say?
Didn't you learn that motion and stillness are relative?
Changes are absolute.
Everything that are around us will change.
I know what you are worried about. Frankly, you have changed too.
You are just trying to maintain a relative stillness with Nan Si.
I have already experienced firsthand.
Enduring it psychologically has already reached my limit.
You are afraid of being hurt and you closed yourself up forever.
Will you be happy?
Rather than living a lifetime of always being on the edge,
why not just forget each other?
What you should forget now is my older brother.
Come in.
Nan Si, all those years, I'm still used to writing letters to you.
I had them posted to your Team Unit.
Because they couldn't find the recipient, they returned  them.
I knew it would end up like this
but I still insisted on doing it.
Because it would make me think that
you are still somewhere else in this world.
I won't write to you anymore.
I heard you went to Nan Qiao's place for an interview.
That's right.
Which post were you applying for?
You know the answer to that.
Tell me.
As your fiance.
Did you think carefully about this?
Yes, I did. I really thought carefully about this.
I can accept the probation. Furthermore, if I get hired,
I will never resign. If I become disloyal, you can do whatever you want with me.
What else?
Also... your dogs and cats.
And everything in your life. Leave them to me.
Okay?
Fiance? Just only this post?
There is still more. I do want to get promoted to being the official husband.
Let's go.
Where are we going? To celebrate?
Back to the shop. That's what you said. We are giving the dogs and cats a bath.
Okay.
Come here now.
Wear your helmet.
The streamlining of this aircraft body...
it's really not bad when you touch it.
Director Wen, the streamlining you just mentioned,
it was designed by me.
As for the limbs, they are very slim.
Don't look at it as being slim, but its strength and toughness
will definitely exceed your expectations. I'm the one who chose this carbon fiber material.
Move aside.
Director Wen,  the design of my camera is not bad.
Look. This camera lens is so good and has great depth.
Let me tell you that its field of view when flying is as wide as that of a hawk's eye.
Tell me. If this Hunter is human,
wouldn't he be a perfect male god?
Idiot.
Boss, don't you think I'm right?
Of course, Boss would think so too.
I even know who the male god that Boss is thinking of.
He is the source of the inspiration for the design.
Subtitles by the Team By Your Side @ Viki
♫ Come closer ♫
♫ Let me listen to your heartbeat as I lay awake ♫
♫ As your scent fills this night air, ♫
♫ My passion lights up for you ♫
♫ It doesn't matter ♫
♫ My world crumbles for you ♫
♫ Innocent eyes turned out to be the most dangerous ♫
♫ Little by little, I fell for you ♫
♫ I fell in love with you without realizing it ♫
♫ I love you, I love everything about you ♫
♫ Even if you're headstrong and unruly, controlling how I feel ♫
♫ On the edge of dreamland and reality, ♫
♫ I'll give you warmth and stay by your side ♫
♫ I love you, everything about you ♫
♫ Even if no one can understand my attachment to you ♫
♫ When the final page of the story is written, I'll be by your side ♫
♫ I fell in love with everything about you ♫
♫ Even if you're headstrong and unruly, controlling how I feel ♫
♫ On the edge of dreamland and reality, ♫
♫ I'll give you warmth and stay by your side ♫
♫ I love you, everything about you ♫
♫ Even if no one can understand my attachment to you ♫
♫ As the final page of the story is written, I'll forever be by your side ♫