Shochiku Films
Late Spring
Based on the novel
by Kazuo Hirotsu
Screenplay by
Kogo Noda and Yasujiro Ozu
Cinematography by
Yuharu Atsuta
Produced by
Takeshi Yamamoto
Cast:
Chishu Ryu as Professor Somiya
Setsuko Hara as Noriko
Yumeji Tsukioka as Aya Kitagawa,
Haruko Sugimura as Masa Taguchi
Hohi Aoki as Katsuyoshi,
Jun Usami as Shoichi Hattori
Kuniko Miyake as Akiko Miwa,
Masao Mishima as Yuzuru Onodera
Yoshiko Tsubouchi as Kiku,
Yoko Katsuragi as Misako
Directed by Yasujiro Ozu
- Did you arrive early, Auntie?
- No, I just arrived
- What's your father doing?
- Working
He didn't meet
his deadline yesterday
Moths have just ruined
your uncle's striped trousers
- Could you mend them for Katsuyoshi?
- Wouldn't he look odd in such trousers?
It doesn't matter.
You could just snip the legs off
- I can probably mend them
- Have a go
- Here
- You brought them with you?
Don't spend too long on them.
They won't last long anyway
But reinforce the seat
Good to see you
I was expecting to see you
at Shimbashi Station so I waited
I missed my train
Thank you for waiting.
We will now proceed
Pass me a pencil rubber
Can't you find it?
Found it
"Friedrich List..."
It's spelt without a 'z'
"L-I-S-T"
I thought so.
Liszt with a 'z' was the musician
1811 to 1886...
I'm from the electricity company.
I'm here to check your meter
Please come in
May I borrow a stool to stand on?
- Yes...
- Where is it?
In the corridor, under the stairs
- Thanks
- Not at all'
Thanks
Professor, was List really
a self-made man?
Yes, and he became
an excellent economist
He detested bureaucracy...
- It's 3 kilowatts over!
- Thanks
How many pages do we have so far?
- 12 or 13 pages
- I see
That means 6 or 7 more to go
I'm home
- Hello, Mr. Hattori
- Hello
Making copies?
Thank you.
That saves me the trouble
- How was your aunt?
- She went straight home
- Make us some tea, will you?
- Yes
- Can you stay this evening, Mr. Hattori?
- No, I have to rush off
Why? I can go to Tokyo
with you tomorrow
Tokyo? What for?
To the hospital
And I need to buy you a shirt collar
By the way, Professor...
...that last mah-jong game we had,
we did over-calculate
Did we?
- You mean 8 and 16?
- So I won after all
Say, Noriko!
Noriko!
- Is Sei at home?
- Why?
Go and ask. We'll have a game
- Have you finished?
- Well, almost
No game till then
What about our tea?
- Did you bring the manuscript?
- Yes, it's fine
Do you want to sit down?
No, I'm fine
Will you be home at the usual time?
Yes, unless there's a faculty meeting
Take care
Uncle!
- Have you just got here?
- No, yesterday morning
- You've put on weight, Nori?
- Have I?
- Where are you off to?
- Shopping
- May I join you?
- But aren't you busy?
- No, I've finished
- Really?
Oh, an art exhibition is on.
Shall we go?
- I need sewing machine needles
- Very well, let's go
Art Group Exhibition in Ueno
Sponsored by The Mainichi Newspaper
Takigawa Restaurant
You must be tired, Nori
I really enjoyed it.
I haven't been to Ueno for ages
But you know, things have changed
Did you see the boy aiming
at the pigeon on the statue?
Just like William Hart!
Here you go
Professor Shigeno was here yesterday
Oh? Is he still in town?
- He said he was leaving today
- I see...
By the way, this is Somiya's daughter
Really? And so grown up!
- That little girl with the fringe?
- The very same
Fancy that.
Your father comes here often
Welcome!
Do you want sake?
Nori, do you want some?
- No, I don't drink
- Do you want something else?
- Or do you want something to eat?
- I'm fine for now
- Let me pour you a drink
- All right
- Shall we order something?
- Be right with you!
You know, Uncle...
I heard that...
What is it?
- ...that you got remarried
- Yes, I have
- I feel sorry for  Isako
- Why?
Well...it's a bit strange, isn't it?
It doesn't seem so.
They're getting on quite well
I wonder.
- I'd find it distasteful
- What, my new wife?
- No, you, Uncle
- Why?
It seems...impure
- Impure?
- It's dirty
Dirty? Now I'm really in trouble
I'm dirty, uh?
- Any better?
- Not at all
No good, eh? What am I going to do?
Here you go
- So I'm impure, am I?
- Yes, you are
I'm in serious trouble, then!
I'm home
- I'm back. And we have a guest
- Who?
I wasn't planning on coming round
but I ran into Nori in Ginza
What was it this time?
I was at the Ministry
of Education again
A present for you, Father
Oh... Where did you find these?
No wonder we couldn't find them
in the house
- Here
- Oh, the Takigawa! Did you go there?
I made her keep me company
- Would you like more sake, Uncle?
- Sounds good
- Do we have any?
- I'll have it hot
- How was your blood test?
- It went down to 15
That's good
She looks well
It was all because of forced labour
during the war, wasn't it?
And she had to run around
to get food on her day off
What an awful time.
No wonder she suffered
- We don't have anything special
- Thank you, Nori
All your family's well in Kyoto?
- Yes, but it seems I've sinned
- What do you mean?
Nori said I was impure
- Who was?
- Me
She said I'm dirty. s that right, Nori?
I don't know!
s   Isako well?
She's going around saying that
marriage is life's graveyard
She's 25 but refusing to get married
Come to think of it, she might be right
Nothing I can do about it, though.
How about Nori?
I suppose it's time for her
to start thinking about it
She's 27, right?
- It's only lukewarm
- Oh, I'll...
- Make the next one hotter
- I will
- s the ocean near here?
- About a 15-minute walk
That far?
- s it that way?
- No, this way
- s the shrine over this way?
- No, that way
- Which way is Tokyo?
- Tokyo's that way
- So that means east is that way
- No, east is that way
- Oh? Has it always been that way?
- Of course it has!
No wonder ancient warlords
liked this area
It's a real labyrinth!
Are you all right? You're not tired?
I'm fine
So which type do you think I am?
Well, you're not the jealous type
- On the contrary, I am
- I wonder
Whenever I slice pickles, they stick
together. That means I'm jealous
That's just the way you use the knife
and the chopping board
There's no connection
between pickles and jealousy
So you prefer pickles stuck together?
I don't mind if my pickles
are stuck together
Really?
Young people today are
so different from our day
Take the bride last night.
She's from a nice family...
...but she ate everything on her plate
and even drank sake!
Eating sashimi with lips
covered in lipstick! I was so shocked
Don't blame her. We haven't been
able to get it for a long time
But at my wedding,
I was too nervous to touch any food
But you'd eat it now, though
Never! Anyway, it's difficult to say
- You'd eat it!
- I wonder
- You would
- You think so?
But not sashimi
- Yes, you would
- Would I?
You would
I don't like weeping brides...
...but behaving like that
just shows the parents up
Can't be helped nowadays
How about Nori?
She wouldn't weep
No, I'm talking about
her getting married
- She's recovered, hasn't she?
- Yes, she has
She should've been married
a long time ago
- What about that fellow?
- Who?
- That assistant of yours
- Oh, Hattori?
Well, how about him?
He's nice, but I don't know
what Noriko thinks
They get along,
but there's nothing between them
But you can't tell
how she feels inside
- Can't I?
- No, you can't
- They're the young generation
- So?
- Why don't you ask?
- Who?
- Nori, of course
- Ask what?
- Ask her how she feels about him
- I see. Perhaps I should try
Yes, or we'll never know
One can never tell
I'm home!
Welcome home. You're early
- Was the train busy?
- No, I got a seat
Your aunt gave us some pickles.
They're in the bag
This says the PEN club meeting
is on the 28th
- At the country club this time
- It's this Saturday
Mr. Hattori was here
- When?
- Around noon
Do you want dinner now?
We went out cycling together
- You and Hattori?
- It was really nice by the beach
- What did Hattori want?
- Nothing in particular
Noriko! A towel!
Here
- You rode together on his bike?
- Of course not! I borrowed a bicycle
- We're running out of soap
- Really?
- My sash
- Here
The beach must've been nice today
- Yes, we went as far as Chigasaki
- Really?
I've added something to your rice
What do you think of Hattori?
- What do you mean?
- I mean, Hattori...
He's quite nice
Would he make a good husband?
I'm sure he would
Would he?
- He's very gentle
- Yes, you're right
I like his type
Your aunt was wondering...
About what?
About you and Hattori...
- What is it?
- Tea! Some tea, please!
What's so funny?
He's already been engaged
for some time
A very pretty girl
- Three years below me at school
- Really?
He'll tell you all about it soon.
I know the girl very well
s that so?
I was wondering
what to get for a wedding gift
I see...
So Hattori is getting married?
What would be a nice gift?
- So he's already engaged...
- Yes
Tell me. What would you like?
- Well...
- What kind of gift?
As it's from the professor,
I'd like something to keep
Anything from 2,000 to 3,000 yen
- I wonder...
- Any good ideas?
I'll think about it
- With your fiancée?
- I will do
Noriko, Mari Iwamoto's playing
in concert. Want to come?
- When?
- Tonight. I've got tickets
How nice!
Did you buy it for me?
- Yes, I did
- Really?
- Of course
- I wonder...
But I can't
- I don't want to cause trouble
- It'll be fine. Let's go
- No...
- She wouldn't mind
I'd rather not
Are the pickles all stuck together?
Yes, and my knife isn't very sharp
Mari Iwamoto - Solo Violin in Concert
Tokyo Theatre
Good evening!
- Who is it?
- Uncle?
- Is that you, Aya?
- Yes
- Good evening
- Come in
- Is Nori in?
- She'll be home soon. Come in
Please sit down
I was just on my way
back from Hayama
I see
I've been hearing good things
about you
- About what?
- That you're very busy
Not that busy
There's a great demand
now for typists
Don't call me a typist.
I'm a stenographer
I beg your pardon
- And you can do English shorthand?
- Yes, I can
- That's great
- Not really
It's great
- So you're not short of money
- Well, I do all right
I see
- Did your parents say anything?
- About what?
- About you remarrying
- No, not recently, thank goodness
- Once was enough?
- Do you mean, marriage?
I wouldn't say that
- What was his name?
- Who?
- Your ex
- Ah, Ken
Kenkichi, wasn't it?
- Have you seen him since?
- Not once
- What would you do if you did?
- I'd glare at him
- You hate him that much?
- I'd run away. I really detest him
Really?
- I'm back!
- Welcome back
- What is it?
- My legs have gone numb
You're here, Aya!
- Evening
- Welcome back
- We've just been chatting
- Are you staying?
- Yes
- Let's go upstairs
- What about dinner?
- I already had some. Have you?
- Yes, I've eaten
- Let's go
- Why didn't you come to the reunion?
- Were there many people?
About 15 people,
including Miss Camellia
And Professor Murase?
Was he frothing at the mouth as usual?
Yes, he spat all over the place.
Even in our tea!
No one near him touched their tea.
I was fine, I was sitting far away
- Did she come?
- Who?
- She married after school
- Miss Ikegami?
She was there,
but she was being a bit sly
When Camellia asked her how many
children she had, she said three
But she actually has four.
She's hiding one!
- Four, already?
- Yes, that's right
- And you remember 'Pollack'?
- Ah, Miss Shinoda
She's leaving her broadcasting job
to get married
- To whom?
- A notable family in Mikawashima
- Really?
- Well, that's my guess
- Oh, thanks
- Some bread and tea
- Thank you, Uncle
- Will this do?
- Oh, there's no sugar
- No?
- It's fine, Father, I'll get it
- All right, I'm off to bed, then
- Night, Aya
- Goodnight
- Do you want some bread?
- Later
- He forgot the spoons, as well
- I know
Was she there? Miss Watanabe?
Kuro? No, she wasn't
She's pregnant now.
A big one. Seven months
- When did she get married?
- She hasn't yet
How awful!
These things happen.
Divine providence, you know
That leaves only you and
Miss Hirokawa unmarried
- Really?
- When will you get married?
- I won't
- Hurry and get married
- No way
- Go on!
Look who's talking.
You don't have the right to say that
I do. And with authority!
No, you don't. You're a divorcee
I do! It was my first innings!
I'll get it right next time
So you're still playing the game?
Of course! I chose the wrong ball
in the first round
I'll hit the right one next time
So, come on and get married
What's so funny? I'm being serious
Don't you want to eat some bread?
- Later!
- I'm starving
- I'm fine
- I'll eat by myself, then
- Actually, I will have some
- I'll go and prepare some
- Do you have any jam?
- Yes
Just a little bit
- But you mean a lot really
- Yes!
Bu-chan?
Why aren't you playing baseball?
Have you had a fight?
Bu-chan! Why are you so angry?
It's not dry yet, the enamel
- What enamel?
- On my bat
- Oh, did you paint it red?
- Yes, I did
So you splashed the paint everywhere.
Your mother will be so cross
- She already is cross
- And you cried?
I did not! Go away, Noriko!
Big talk coming from a crybaby
What? I'll get you with this!
Go away, Nori!
Shut up, Bu!
- Noriko!
- Has your guest gone?
She's leaving. Please come down
You're not allowed out today!
This is Somiya's daughter, Noriko.
This is Mrs. Miwa
I'm Miwa.
I often see you in Kita-kamakura
- Forgive me for staying so long
- Not at all
- Goodbye
- Thank you for coming
Noriko, come with me
Sit down there
What is it, Auntie?
Well...
Isn't it time you got married?
Oh, that? Please, Auntie, it's fine
It's not fine. Now sit down
I've found a nice fellow.
Won't you at least meet him?
Mr. Satake's a science graduate
from Tokyo University...
...and from an old family
in Matsuyama
He works for Nitto Chemicals
His father used to be
the director there before the war
He's 34. Just right for you
And his office speaks very highly
of him. What do you think?
Hey, who was that American actor...
...in that baseball film recently?
- Gary Cooper?
- Cooper, that's him
He looks just like him
Especially around his mouth
But not the top half
Listen, how about it?
Won't you meet him?
He's a fine man, really
Won't you?
I don't want to get married yet
Not yet? Why ever not?
Well, there'll be problems
if I get married
Like what?
My father
It's fine, I'm used to it...
...but he can be very difficult
If I leave him, he'll be in trouble
But you can't help that
But I'm the one
who understands him the best
Leave your father out of this.
What about yourself?
- I don't want to do it like that
- Then you can never get married
That's fine with me
Listen, Nori...you know
that Mrs. Miwa you just met?
Think she'd suit your father?
What do you mean?
Your father will need someone
if you’re no longer there
I was wondering
if she would suit him
Come here and sit with me
She had a good husband...
...but he died, leaving the poor woman
with no children.
What do you think of her?
She's a sound woman with good taste
- Does father know about this?
- I did mention it to him recently
What did he say?
He was polishing his pipe,
but he didn't object to the idea
Then why do you need my opinion?
But I need to know
how you feel about it
It's up to him, isn't it?
Welcome home.
How was it at your aunt's?
Nothing special
The bath's ready.
The temperature's just right
Hey...
- What?
- What happened at your aunt's?
What is it?
Is anything wrong?
Where are you going? Hey!
Shopping
Excuse me?
- Hello
- Oh, hello. No one's home today
- They went out this morning
- Oh, I see
They told me they were going
to see a Noh play
Then would you give them this
when they get back?
- Yes, of course I will
- Tell them I came to thank them
Certainly. Sorry for your trouble
Goodbye, sir
I'll go and chop some wood
Hey, come and look at this
That's Mr. Hattori, isn't it?
- I thought he was marrying Noriko
- Me, too
sn’t it an amazing photo?
It looks just like him
And the bride looks so beautiful
Today's Noh was really quite good
Shall we go to the Takigawa to eat?
What shall we do?
I have to go somewhere
- Where?
- It's nothing
- Will you be home late?
- I don't know
Sorry for keeping you waiting, Noriko
I've been busy baking shortcake
I put in too much vanilla,
but they're delicious
Let's go to the other room
Goodness, your hands are cold
Fumi, bring the cakes
to that room, will you?
What gave you that idea?
Tell me, why?
No special reason
Will you try some?
- Is it very difficult?
- What?
- Becoming a stenographer
- No, it's not that difficult
I can manage, after all
Come on, try some. It's delicious
But why are you doing it now?
What are you trying to do?
I told you, no particular reason
You can't work for no reason
I wouldn't be doing it,
if Ken had been a decent man
I only started work
because I got divorced
- Someone like you should get married
- Save your advice
- I'll advise you anyway
- I don't want such advice
Just get married for no reason!
- Aren't you going to eat it?
- I don't want it
- Have some!
- I don't want to
- It's delicious
- I've had enough
Just a little piece.
I made it. Try some!
- I don't want to
- Eat it. I'll make you
- I don't want it!
- No need for hysterics. Fine, then!
This is why you should marry
- Where are you going?
- Home
Home? Are you really leaving?
I thought you'd stay over!
Stay overnight!
I'm home
Where have you been?
At Aya's
I got a letter from your aunt
She wants you to visit her on Saturday.
The day after tomorrow
She's mentioned it to you, then,
hasn't she?
Go and meet him.
He'll be there as well
- Can't I refuse?
- Just go and meet him once
If you don't like him,
you can turn him down
Noriko!
Come here
Sit down
Your aunt must've told you already,
but his name is Satake
I've met him,
and he seemed like a nice fellow
I'm quite sure you'll like him
Just go and see for yourself
You can't remain like this forever...
...you have to get married some time
I think it's the perfect time
What do you think?
Your aunt's been concerned about you
- You know?
- But I...
I just want to be with you
That's impossible
It would be most convenient
for me if you stayed, but...
- Then why not...?
- No, that won't do
I've been using you
for far too long
I couldn't let you go,
and I must apologise for that
It'll be a huge worry to me
if you don't get married soon
But if I marry,
what are you going to do?
I'll manage
- How?
- I'll get by
- That's not good enough for me
- Why not?
Your shirts and collars...
you'd leave them dirty
And you wouldn't shave in the morning
Well, I'll shave in the evening
If I wasn't here to clean up,
your desk would be a mess
You'd end up eating burnt rice,
like that last time you tried to cook
I can see you'd be in trouble
But...what if I were to release you
from these worries?
For instance, if someone else
were to look after me?
- Which someone?
- It's only an idea
So, you're going to do
what Uncle Onodera did...
...and take a wife?
Will you remarry?
The woman we saw today?
You've decided?
Honestly?
Really?
Stay away, Father.
Go downstairs. Please!
Anyway, go and visit your aunt
on Saturday
We're all so worried about you
You will go, won't you?
Please
It'll be sunny again tomorrow
What did Nori say?
She's not said anything about it
Nothing? It's been a week
since I introduced him
I have to give his family an answer
I realize that
I don't want to push her
and complicate things
His family has approved of her
Noriko shouldn't find
anything bad about him
Nori likes him.
I think she really likes him
Why did Nori go to Tokyo today?
You're too easy-going on her, Brother
I must have her answer today
- When is she back tonight?
- I don't know
Look, I found a purse
It's a good omen!
The wedding will go ahead
Shouldn't you turn it in?
I will, but it's such a good omen.
Let's go
So what was he like?
What type was he?
- Was he fat?
- No
- Skinny, then?
Then which was he?
He used to play basketball
when he was a student
Is he good looking? What's he like?
My aunt thinks
he looks like Gary Cooper
Amazing!
You always liked Gary Cooper
But I think he looks more
like our local electrician
Does he look like Gary Cooper?
Yes, very much so
What? Then they both
look like Gary Cooper?
I'll give you a slap!
But well done to you
for going to the introduction
It sounds good
Don't think too much about it,
just get married!
There aren't many good men around.
Grab him while you can
- I can't bear it...
- What?
- Arranged marriages
- Don't ask for too much
You'll never get married
unless it's arranged
- But...
- But what?
If you liked someone,
could you go up and propose to him?
You don't have the courage.
You'd just squirm and blush
- That's true
- An arranged marriage suits you fine
I proposed, though...
...and look what happened to me.
It didn't work out.
Men are sly and can't be trusted
They show only their good side
before marriage...
...but once they're married,
their bad side comes out
Love doesn't always mean
a happy marriage
- I wonder...
- It's true, it's the same
If you don't like marriage,
you can always leave him
Of course you can, don't worry
All you need to do is smile at him
He'll fall for you,
then you take control
- Surely not
- Yes, that's how it works
- Do you think I'm joking?
- I wonder!
Yes, that's the smile!
Try that. I guarantee it'll work
Nori's late
Shall I come another time?
Wait a little longer.
She should be on the next train
Really?
I hope she approves
- She will. I know she likes him
- You think so?
She's shy. She's old-fashioned
for her generation
You think so?
Think she might be bothered
by something trivial?
- Like what?
- Mr. Satake's first name
- Kumataro Satake?
- "Bear Boy"
It's a fine name. Sounds strong
You're much more old-fashioned.
She wouldn't mind such a thing
Doesn't it make you think
he might have a thick, hairy chest?
These things do bother young girls
If she marries him,
what should I call him?
"Kumataro-san" sounds so crude...
..."Kuma-san" is too common,
but "Kuma-chan" is even worse!
But we've got to call him something
That's my point!
I'm thinking of calling him "Ku-chan"
- Ku-chan?
- What do you think?
Oh, she's back!
- I'm home
- She's coming
Well, that was definitely when...
- I'm home
- Welcome back
Welcome home
- I'll go and ask her how she is
- Hey...
- What?
- Be tactful
Don't worry!
Oh, welcome home, Nori-chan
Hello
About that meeting...
...have you thought
any more about it?
What do you think?
I think it's a splendid arrangement,
don't you?
Well, say something.
What do you think?
- Yes
- You will?
- You will! Really? You will marry?
Thank you. I'll notify them
That's all right, then?
Oh, how wonderful. I'm so relieved!
- How did it go?
- She'll marry. Just as I thought
Really? That's good
Listen, I have to run now.
What a relief
- I'll tell them immediately
- Yes. Thank you
- I can still catch the 9:35
- Yes, but you'd better hurry
Now my worries are over.
I'll sleep soundly tonight
I'll come again to discuss
the date and other things
- Drop by to see me some time
- I will
- I told you that purse was a good omen!
- You'd better report it
Of course I will
- I won't lock it. Goodnight
- Thanks. Take care!
- Bye!
- Ah, bye!
- Your aunt just left
- Did she?
She was really happy
Are you sure about your answer?
Yes
You're not just giving in, are you?
No
You're not reluctant to go, are you?
- No, I'm not
- I see. That's all right, then
- Did you sleep well on the train?
- Yes
So did I. When I woke up,
we were already at Seta
I completely missed
Nagoya to Mawbara
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I feel refreshed
- Are you tired, Nori-chan?
- No, not really
Really?
I'm glad you came
- Noriko's getting married soon
- Really?
- This is our last trip together
- Congratulations! That's wonderful news
Congratulations, Nori-chan
Hey, Nori-chan, what's he like
compared to me?
There's no comparison
- Who's better?
- Of course, you're much nicer, Uncle
Oh, is that true?
Shall I treat you?
How about lunch today?
- Shall we go to Hyotei?
- That'd be nice
- Misako wants to meet Nori
- Really? I'd like to meet her, too
But the "Impure One" is coming, too
Is that all right?
Kyoto is very nice. It's so relaxing
There's nothing like this in Tokyo.
It's so dusty there
Do you come to Kyoto often,
Professor?
Not for years. This is my first time
since the war ended
I see
Uncle!
Nori, how do you feel
about the "Impure One"?
You're so mean
Tell me what you think
What's this "Impure One", Father?
Hmm? I'm filthy, right, Noriko?
We walked a lot today
- Aren't you tired?
- No
Last time I was here, the bush clover
was in magnificent bloom
What are you going to do tomorrow?
Misako's coming to see me
around 10:00
Where are you going?
You should go to the museum
- Shall we get some sleep?
- Yes
I'll turn the light off
I'm afraid I was very rude
to Uncle Onodera
What about?
His wife is such a nice person
They make a wonderful couple
I shouldn't have called him "impure"
Don't let it worry you
- It was an awful thing to say
- He didn't take it seriously
- Do you think so?
- It's fine
It's fine
Father...
...I was feeling angry
towards you, but...
I'm glad Nori decided to get married
She'll certainly make a good wife
Having a son is better.
Daughters are no good
Once you've raised her,
she leaves and gets married
If they don't get married,
you only worry...
...and when they do get married,
you feel let down
Can't be helped.
It was the same when we got married
That's true
Father, hand me those
How time flies
We just arrived,
and now we're already leaving
But I've really enjoyed Kyoto
I'm glad we came
One can't have everything,
but I wish we'd had a day in Nara, too
Oh, this...
I wish we'd done this
more often together
This will be our last trip together
Once we get home, you'll be so busy.
Your aunt will be waiting
I hope we get seats on the train
I couldn't take you to visit many places,
but your husband will
He'll take good care of you
What is it?
What's wrong?
I...
I just want to be with you, like this
I don't want to go anywhere.
I'm happy being with you like this
I'm happy just as I am
Marriage couldn't make me
any happier
I'm happy the way things are now
But, you see...
No, no. You can remarry, Father
I just want to be at your side
I love you dearly, Father
My greatest happiness
is to be with you
Please, Father...
Why can't we stay as we are?
I don't believe that marriage
will make me any happier
That's not true
It's nothing like that
I'm already 56
My life is nearing its end
Yours is just beginning.
A new life is just about to start
A life which you and Satake
will build together
A life apart from me
That's how both life and history
progress
Marriage may not bring you
happiness from the start
It's wrong to think that marriage
will instantly make you happy
Happiness is not
something to expect...
...but something you create
Happiness isn't about getting married
Happiness lies in the couple
creating a new life together
It may take a year or two...
...or even five or ten years' work
to create that happiness
Only then can you claim
to have become a true, married couple
Your mother wasn't happy
in the beginning
We had our troubles for years
So many times I found her weeping
in a corner in the kitchen
But your mother put up with me
You must have faith in each other
You must have love for each other
Show Satake all the warmth
and affection you've shown me
All right?
Then your new, true happiness
will emerge
Understand?
You understand, don't you?
- Sorry for being so selfish
- You understand, then
- It was very selfish of me
- Well, I'm glad you understand
I didn't want you to get married
feeling the way you did
Marry him
and I'm sure you'll be happy
It's not difficult
I'm sure you'll make a great couple
I'm looking forward to it
Soon we'll laugh about this talk
we're having tonight
I'm sorry...
...for worrying you all the time
So...just be happy.
All right?
- I'm sure I'll be happy
- Of course you will
I know you can do it,
I have no worries
Be happy
I got worried
when it started raining last night
I'm glad it cleared up
- Rain would've ruined the day
- Yes
- Where did you go on your honeymoon?
- Yugawara
Noriko's going there, too.
Are there buses only from the station?
- No, you can get a cab
- Oh, there are taxis?
- Professor, you're wanted upstairs
- Very well
Your daughter's such a beautiful bride
- Go upstairs and have a peek
- Very well...
She makes a wonderful bride
- Oh, she's ready now, Brother
- I see
- Is the car ready?
- It's arrived
Thank you. Thank you all
All ready, eh?
- We'll go on ahead
- Please do
- I'll take this along
- Thank you
Nori-chan, do you have your fan?
You're such a beautiful bride
I wish your mother could see you
Well, shall we get going?
We don't want to be rushed
Do you have anything
to say to Nori?
- No, I have nothing more to say
- Really?
Nori-chan, let's go, then
Father...
These many long years...
...thank you for everything
Be happy, and be a good wife
Be happy
Remember, be a good wife
Shall we go, then?
Aya-chan, want some?
This is my third
I can handle five
- Once I drank six and I fell down
- Did you?
Here you go
Professor Onodera came here
with your daughter recently
- That's right
- I was amazed
So grown up.
She's not with you today?
We just saw her off at Tokyo Station.
She got married
Did she? And you saw her off?
- Many congratulations
- Thank you
Thank you!
Uncle...
- Where will she be by now?
- I'd say around Ofuna
Probably.
You'll be lonely from now on
Not too much
I'll get used to it
Ready for your fourth?
Listen, Uncle...
- Are you really going to remarry?
- Why?
It worried Noriko. That's what
seemed to bother her the most
Don't do it. Why would you
do it again? You mustn't
All right? I mean it
But if I'd said otherwise,
she'd never have got married
You're wonderful. Amazing!
I'm so impressed
Don't worry, you won't be lonely.
I'll visit you often. Really
Please do, Aya-chan
I certainly will
I feel wonderful
I'll take my fifth!
That's my fill
Remember to visit me.
I'll be expecting you
Of course, I promised.
I don't tell lies like you do
What?
Or at least not so convincingly
It couldn't be helped.
It was the biggest lie of my life
- Welcome home
- Evening
- Did she get off all right?
- Yes, thank you
That's good.
I offer you my congratulations
- I'm indebted to you
- Not at all
Goodnight
Give my regards to Sei
Goodnight, then
'Night