Deanie, please.
Bud, I'm afraid.
Oh, Bud.
Don't, Bud.
No.
We mustn't, Bud.
No. No.
Bud, don't be mad.
I'd better take you home.
We've had enough kissing for tonight.
Has Bud left?
Yes, Mom.
There's wonderful news tonight.
The Stamper Oil stocks, drink your milk,
went up 14 points today.
Think of it, honey.
That means if we sold those stocks,
we'd make $15,000.
Maybe we can even send you away
to college next year.
Well, we're not going to sell.
Your father says that everyone
at the Elks says...
...that the stocks are going up even higher.
Didn't Bud say anything about it tonight?
He doesn't know anything
about his father's business, Mom.
He doesn't care about that.
What were you and Bud doing all this time,
for heaven's sake?
We were studying together.
I'm going to bed, Mom. I'm awfully tired.
Now, Wilma Dean....
I want to talk to you.
Now, Wilma Dean, Bud Stamper could
get you into a whole lot of trouble.
And you know how I mean.
Boys don't respect a girl
they can go all the way with.
Boys want a nice girl for a wife.
Wilma Dean, you and Bud haven't gone
too far already, have you?
No, Mother.
Tell me the truth, Wilma Dean!
No, Mom, we haven't gone too far.
That's a relief.
Mom?
Is it so terrible to have those feelings
about a boy?
No nice girl does.
Doesn't she?
No. No nice girl.
But, Mom...
...didn't you ever....
Didn't you ever feel that way about Dad?
Your father never laid a hand on me
until we were married.
And then...
...I just gave in because a wife has to.
A woman doesn't enjoy those things
the way a man does.
She just lets her husband...
...come near her in order to have children.
Deanie, what's troubling you?
Oh, nothing, Mom.
I'm just tired.
I want to go to bed now.
Now, Deanie...
...you tell Bud Stamper to bring you home
earlier after this...
...especially on school nights.
"Good night, sleep tight,
don't let the bedbugs bite."
'Night.
"Our Father which art in heaven,
Hallowed be thy name...."
Something wrong?
Wilma Dean and the Stamper boy
are in love.
They're in love, I tell you, Del!
Go back to sleep, Mama.
He'd be the catch of a lifetime, Del.
I hope we bring in a gusher
every day, Boss!
Hold it! Hold it!
Boss, Bud's here. Here's Bud!
Come on in here, my boy.
Your old man will get us in trouble
with our wives...
...'cause we'll go home smelling
like home brew and they'll wonder why.
They'll want some, too.
-Get something to eat, Son.
-I gotta go up to bed now.
Wait a minute, Son. I want to talk to you.
You go on entertaining yourselves.
I'll have a few words with my boy here.
Have more of this venison.
You don't get meat like that anymore.
They don't make home brew
like that anymore.
It's pretty late for a boy
keeping football training, isn't it?
Come here. I want to talk to you, Son.
You're the captain of the team, Son.
Those other boys look up to you.
You gotta run with the ball.
I wasn't much older than you, Bud,
when I fell off that crown block...
...and I hit that rig floor.
And my running days was long gone.
So, you're doing the running
for both of us now, boy.
Listen, I brought in a well today.
She's flowing over 100 barrels an hour,
and our stocks are going way up.
Those big Eastern companies are beginning
to take notice of us.
Them people really beginning
-That's great.
-You been out with the Loomis girl?
-Yes, sir.
-Are you watching yourself with her?
You're not doing anything
you'll be ashamed of, are you?
No, sir.
She's a nice kid, Son. She's a good looker.
I've known her folks ever since
old Del and I were boys together.
I got nothing against them
'cause they're poor.
I'm not a snob or anything like that.
The only difference between me and Del
is that I got ambition.
Hey, Dad, l--
But if anything was to happen,
you'd have to marry her.
You'd have to marry her, Son.
You realize that, don't you?
You get a girl in trouble
and you gotta take the consequences.
-Dad, I'm not--
-Sit down.
-I want to talk to you--
-I want to talk to you about that.
-All right.
All right, lay it on me. Come on.
Lay it on me. That a boy.
There we go, lay it on me.
Lay it on now. Lick like a bear.
We got a future, boy.
You and me, we got a future.
First, we'll get you an education.
The best. Four years at Yale.
Did I tell you a secret?
-I'll tell you a secret.
-What?
Come here.
My company is gonna merge
with one of those big Eastern companies.
I'm gonna put you in there, boy.
I'm lining up a future for you, boy.
I've been thinking about--
There ain't nothing in this world
that I wouldn't do for you, boy.
I know.
There's nothing I wouldn't do
if you do right.
If you do right, Bud!
Now, don't disappoint me, Son.
Don't disappoint me, boy.
God knows I've had
one disappointment already.
-She asleep?
-Yes, finally.
-Is Sis back?
-Hello, Bud, darling.
Mother brought her home
from Chicago a little while ago.
Welcome home, Mom.
It was a miserable trip, just miserable.
How's Deanie?
I don't know.
I'm gonna go to bed, Dad.
I'm going to bed, too,
but I'm afraid I won't sleep a wink.
Yeah, you go to bed, Son.
You got a football game to win tomorrow.
I got all my hopes pinned on you now.
How're you men getting on in there?
Well, you certainly spoiled that girl.
First you send her off to finishing school.
She breaks all the rules
and they kick her out.
Then you send her off to university.
She goes hog wild
and flunks all her courses.
Then you had to learn your lesson
all over again, didn't you?
Let her go off to art school
in a wild place like Chicago.
She gets tied up with some cake-eater who
gets her into trouble so he can marry her.
Your lawyer got it annulled.
Damn right I got it annulled.
When I made it clear to "Mr. Cake-Eater"
that I'd cut off her allowance...
...he backed out in a hurry.
She's just a headstrong little flapper...
...but I'll keep her home
and teach her a little discipline.
Yes, sir.
I'm gonna keep that young lady home,
teach her a little discipline.
If you think I'll stay
in this God-forsaken town...
...and have people gossip about me,
you've got another think coming.
I'll really give them something
to gossip about.
Why, Sister, you're up so early!
I can't sleep in this house.
I'm going to California and live
with Aunt Blossom and study art.
Art who?
Welcome home, Miss Virginia.
Phoebe.
I hate it here. I'm a freak in this town.
Everybody stares at me
like I'm something out of a carnival.
'Cause you peroxide your hair
and paint your face like an Indian.
Good morning, everybody.
-Hey, how are you?
-Just great.
He's gonna make me stay home
a whole year just to punish me.
There aren't any more schools left
that'll have you.
There's nothing so distasteful--
This is the ugliest place
in the whole world.
Everywhere you look is an oil well,
even on the front lawn.
I'll bet you'd drill right here
in the dining room.
Damn right I would, if I thought
there was any oil in there.
I'll see you later.
How do you want your eggs, Bud darling?
Come back here
and eat a decent breakfast!
I'm late.
Come back! You can't play a football game
on a breakfast like that!
Neither of my children gets
any real nourishment.
Hey, you want a peach?
What?
Don't! Bud, don't!
Pardonnez-moi.
Wilma Dean, hereafter,
I shall count you tardy...
...if you are not in your seat
when the bell rings.
I'm sorry, Miss Metcalf.
Alan, please.
All right.
For the first few weeks,
we've been reading...
...the stories of King Arthur
and the Knights of the Round Table.
The literature of the age
was characterized by....
All right, Alan?
"By high ideals."
True. And by what else?
You going with us to the football game?
All right, Carolyn?
They were very religious.
Religion was an important part of the lives
of the Knights and their fair ladies.
What else?
I'm going with you, but I'm waiting
for Bud after the game.
We knew that, crazy.
The Knights of the Round Table....
-Just because his father's got money--
-That's not true.
Well, they were very brave
and things like that.
Bud Stamper isn't stuck on himself at all.
What in the world do you mean
by "things like that" exactly?
Well, I don't know exactly.
Let us learn to express ourselves
with as much precision as possible.
Juanita, you had your hand up?
The Knights of the Round Table
had a very high regard for women.
In what way, Juanita?
They looked on women as very pure.
They wouldn't look on her as very pure.
All right now, I want it quiet
in this classroom!
The next time there is talking
while this class is in session...
...I am going to send the culprit
to the principal's office.
Yes, Juanita, you're quite right.
The Knights did have a very high regard
for womanhood.
In fact, they put women on a pedestal.
Some people say that chivalry is not dead.
Well, how about it, girls?
Do any of you feel
that you're on a pedestal?
That's unnecessary roughness.
Fifteen yards.
Come on, you've been on me all day!
You're out! You're out of the game!
Who you taking out, Toots?
Never mind who.
Okay, okay, what's so funny about that?
She's the only girl who knows
what it's all about.
You can say that again.
I'll never look twice at those other girls.
They expect you to be satisfied
if they even kiss you good night.
Hi, Bud.
Hi, Juanita.
Did you see Toots in there?
Yeah, yeah. He should be right out.
You played a wonderful game.
Thank you.
He should be right out.
Hi, sweetheart.
I suppose you wish I were more
like Juanita Howard, don't you?
What?
I saw the way you were looking at her.
I think she's disgraceful.
The way she stands
waiting for one of the players--
Wait a minute.
There isn't any reason in the world
why I shouldn't speak to her.
You were more than speaking to her.
I'm supposed to not notice her?
Is that what you expect out of me?
I'm not even supposed to know
girls like that exist, huh?
Bud, I'm sorry.
-I'm sorry, Bud, honest.
-All right, you're sorry.
Mr. Loomis, a customer for meat.
Bud, please don't be mad.
I'm not mad, Deanie.
Hi, Bud. Deanie.
-Hi, Mr. Loomis.
-Hi, Dad.
I just can't stand it
when you're mad at me.
I don't know what's the matter
with me lately.
I'm always losing my temper.
You're the only girl in the world for me,
you know that?
I want to be.
If it weren't for you....
If it weren't for you, Deanie, I'd....
I don't know!
Bud, it's broad daylight.
-Who cares?
-Stop it. Stop it.
Come on now. Bud! People can see us.
I don't care.
Bud, stop it. Come on now.
Mom?
She's not here.
-Mom?
-"Mom? "
Nobody's here.
Stop that.
Yes, Mrs. Harper, here's your change.
Stop it. I have to pull down
the shade to the store.
Bud, stop it.
You're nuts about me, aren't you?
You're nuts about me.
I've got your ten-pound sack
in the back of the store, Mrs. Thatcher.
At my feet, slave!
-Bud, don't.
-Tell me you love me.
-You're hurting me.
-Say you can't live without me.
-Say it!
-I do.
-Do what?
-I do love you.
And you can't live without me.
You'd be everything I ever ask you to be.
I'd do anything for you.
Deanie, I didn't mean to hurt you.
Deanie, I was just kidding.
I'm the one; I should go down
on my knees to you.
I was just kidding.
I thought you knew that.
I can't kid about these things...
...because I am nuts about you.
And I would go down on my knees
to worship you if you really wanted me to.
Bud, I can't get along without you.
And I would do anything you'd ask me to.
I would.
Anything.
-Let's speak of it at the next meeting.
-I certainly will, if you will.
I'm going in to fix supper now.
-Bye-bye, Nell.
-'Bye, Frieda.
Hi, Mom.
The coast is clear.
Are we going to the victory dance?
I can think of things I'd rather do.
I'll be ready.
I'll pick you up right after dinner then.
Did he tell you about his sister Ginny?
No.
Ginny Stamper is too low
for the dogs to bite.
Come here.
She met some man in Chicago,
put her in the family way.
Mrs. Stamper had to go out there
and get her, take her to a doctor.
Store's all locked up.
Good.
To have one of those
awful operations performed.
Mom, that's gossip.
Every word is true.
I was at the DAR and heard all about it.
Mrs. Whitcomb lives across the street
from the Stampers...
...and she knows everything
that goes on in their house.
That's what happens to girls
who go wild and boy-crazy.
Well, congratulations, Son!
The game, boy, the game.
Thank you.
I'll run along upstairs and....
Dad, I have to talk to you.
I've just about had all the nonsense
I intend to take out of you.
Get out of here, young lady.
I'm gonna have a talk with my boy.
All right, Son.
All right, go ahead.
Dad, I'm gonna marry Deanie.
Whoa now, Son.
You see, I don't really wanna go to Yale.
I'm not a very good student.
What do you mean
you're not a good student?
Boy, you can do anything
you set your mind to do.
I'd like to go to a good agricultural college
for a couple of years.
I'd really like to do that.
I could come right back here...
...and take over your ranch
just south of town.
Ranching's no life.
I could marry Deanie,
take her to college with me.
That's what I really want.
She'd be a big help to me, Dad.
I spent my life trying to create a place
of importance for you in this world...
...then you come home telling me
you want to marry some little girl!
It's what I want that counts.
Son, a boy your age doesn't even know
what he wants.
After you've had a college education,
you might change your mind.
A college education
will take me four years.
-Trust me.
-I do trust you, but--
-Trust me this time, Son.
-I trust you, Dad.
I do trust you, but four years--
Listen to me now.
But, Dad....
Son, all I'm asking you to do is
to finish Yale.
Then if you still want to marry her,
return and marry her with my blessing.
I'll send you both off to Europe
for a honeymoon.
Bud, please wait, Son.
I just don't know if I can, Dad.
I feel like I'm going nuts sometimes.
I understand, Son.
Your old man understands, Son.
What you need for the time being is...
...a different kind of girl.
When I was a boy, Son,
there was always two kinds of girls.
Us boys, we'd never even mention them
in the same breath...
...but every now and then one of us boys
would sneak off with a girl...
...and we'd get a little steam
out of our system.
No girl looks good to me except Deanie.
I know, Son.
I know.
I love her, Dad.
I know, Son, I know.
See, I don't want to do that.
Okay, I'll go to Yale.
But I want to tell you now,
I'll marry her as soon as I get out.
That's a promise.
-I want you to remember that.
-It's a promise.
It's a promise, Son. I'll send you both
off to Europe on a honeymoon.
-That's a promise.
-Okay.
Bud, I'll wait for you.
I'll wait for you forever.
I'll do anything you want, Bud.
Yes, it's a time of great prosperity
for us all, and we must give thanks.
But let us not forget Christ's warning
to the multitude.
"Lay not up treasures for yourselves
on earth...
"...where moth and rust doth corrupt...
"...and where thieves break through
and steal:
"But lay up for yourselves treasures
in heaven...
"...where neither moth nor rust
doth corrupt...
"...and where thieves do not
break through and steal:
"For where your treasure is,
there will your heart be also."
Fine sermon. Fine sermon.
Let us pray.
Take my advice, Del.
Hang onto those stocks of yours.
This comedian said,
"You ain't seen nothing yet."
We're hanging on.
Fine sermon, Reverend, fine sermon.
Wonderful passage.
Don't light a cigarette
in front of all these church people!
Do you want me to be a hypocrite?
Who would've thought that one day
our kids would be, well, engaged sort of?
I'm mighty proud
of my son's choice, Frieda.
I'm mighty proud of your boy, too.
Excuse us, honey.
I'll see you at dinner tonight. Don't forget.
Dad, I'm no spy.
All I'm asking you to do is keep an eye
on her while I'm in New York.
She likes you, Son. She won't do
anything crazy when you're around.
Virginia, I told you, your father has
the key to that cabinet...
...and he's on the train to New York.
That's him all over. He keeps it locked.
He doesn't think
anybody should drink but him.
You may be shocking Glenn.
Virginia, after all,
we do have prohibition, you know.
Maybe Glenn doesn't approve of drinking.
Quick, Henry, the flit.
Has your family lived long in town?
They just moved here from Oklahoma.
Oh, I see.
Is your father engaged
in some business in town?
His father is looking for work
and Glenn works at the filling station...
...on the corner of Sycamore and Main.
Anything else you'd like to know?
Ginny, I see no reason at all
for your bad nature.
Bud, you're not eating a thing.
I'm bored!
Come on, let's go.
There's a lovely dessert coming.
I don't want a lovely dessert.
Glenn and I are going for a ride.
Come on.
Deanie and I'll go with you and Glenn.
Wake up.
Hey, Buddy boy, you're a Boy Scout.
Run in and build us a nice, hot fire.
My hair's a mess.
Where?
Here.
Stop it. Stop it.
"Everybody's wild about Mabel
"She's the talk of the town
"Mabel's willing and able
"To show a guy around
"She's a tease, she's a flirt
"You better watch out or you'll get hurt"
Good, Buddy boy.
Now, how about a drink?
I forgot, Buddy boy's in training.
What about you, Deanie girl?
You want a drink?
Come on, Deanie.
Come on, have a little drink. Come on.
Or is Deanie girl in training, too?
Lay off, Ginny.
Why don't you relax?
You're just standing around
like a chaperone.
Is that what you came out here for,
just to chaperone Glenn and me?
Ain't he pretty, Deanie, huh?
My handsome filling-station attendant.
Fill me up, please, I'm empty.
Come on, honey, let's go for a walk.
All right.
Yeah, why don't you go
for a walk upstairs?
Why don't you quit trying to pretend
you're so pure and righteous?
If you weren't my sister--
If I weren't your sister,
you wouldn't do anything.
You never do anything
except what Dad tells you.
Isn't that right, Deanie?
You been finding that out, haven't you?
He just lets things torment him inside
and make him miserable...
...and he never does anything about them.
He never does anything.
'Bye.
All this is gonna be ours someday.
This is the most wonderful Christmas
I've ever had.
Isn't it beautiful? Oh, Dad,
it's the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
I wonder what Bud paid for it?
Why do you always think about the cost?
If you want to know,
I wish it was a lot less and was a ring.
-Don't, Mom, don't.
-Four years, you'll be....
All right, all right.
I just wish that Bud Stamper
had a little more gumption.
Always drink plenty of milk, Deanie.
Still.
One, two. There.
Thank you.
One more, please.
I don't know why I couldn't have had a car.
Why should I buy you a car?
You got your mother's coupe.
That coupe is a wreck.
-What have you done with your hair?
-I just put a henna rinse in it.
Still.
I'll get it.
One. Two. There.
Thank God that's over.
-Hi, Ginny.
-Oh, Brian.
My parents are in there.
-Perfume?
-Arpege.
It's my favorite.
I just have to slip on my dress.
Come meet the folks. Come on.
They're kind of dull,
but you can stand them for a few minutes.
Go on!
-Hello. I'm Ace Stamper.
-I'm Brian Stacey.
-What can I do for you?
-I'm waiting for Ginny.
She may take forever. Come on in.
This is my son, Bud.
Come here, Son.
The boy's captain of the football team.
You heard about him?
I don't get to many games.
-Merry Christmas.
This is my wife, Mrs. Stamper.
Won't you come in?
Ginny, I want to talk to you.
Come on in.
Ginny, I know who that guy is.
That guy's a bootlegger.
Is he? Here, do me up.
He's married. Do you know that?
How do you know so much about him,
sweetie-pie?
-You're not going out with him.
-Is that so?
-Try to stop me.
-This is Christmas Day.
You'll stay home and you'll be decent
to your mother.
-You're not leaving!
-Get out of my way!
If you want to listen to Dad, go ahead.
One of these days you'll find out.
You'll find out and then God help you.
All right, calm down, everybody.
Come on now, just calm down!
All right, boys, give me a fanfare.
Give me a fanfare.
You people, shut up in there!
Let's crowd around here,
crowd around here.
We'll bring this New Year in right.
For Joe!
Happy New Year!
You look lovely, boy!
You're the prettiest baby here!
Shake that jelly.
Look, Daddy. Happy New Year!
Shake that jelly. Shake it! Shake it!
Daddy, look at us.
Daddy, look!
Come on, move aside.
Hey, let me through there.
Hey, Smokey boy,
let me ring your doorbell.
Happy New Year, Daddy.
You cut that out!
You behave yourself.
You behave yourself, you hear me?
Mr. Stamper, the perfume is coming in.
Yeah, perfume for all the ladies.
Line up, ladies.
Line up to get your perfume.
Come on, get your perfume,
all you ladies.
Happy New Year, Son.
Go on, get in line. There's some for you.
It will be a great year for both of us.
-Dance with me, Dick?
-No thanks, Ginny.
Boy, oh boy, she's really plastered.
Hello, Bill.
She's disgraceful.
It's all she can do to walk.
Why don't her folks
do something about her?
What did she do to her hair?
Charley, will you dance with me?
Not right now, Ginny.
I didn't know you were married.
Hey, look out!
What do you think you're doing?
Happy New Year, Joe!
Go get your sister, Son,
and take her on home.
-Hey, Sis.
-Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
-What's happy about it?
You want to dance?
Where are you taking me?
-Where are you taking me?
-Sis, let me take you home.
No!
No, I'm not going home.
-Can I do your dress up?
-No.
You're all unsnapped here.
Get away. I'm not going home.
And you don't have to dance with me.
Ginny, I like to dance
with a good-looking girl once in a while.
If you weren't my brother
you wouldn't even come near me.
You're a nice boy! You're nice!
I know what you nice boys are like.
I know, you only talk to me in the dark!
In the dark!
You talk to me then, don't you?
You talk to me in the dark, in automobiles!
You talk to me!
You're very familiar then, aren't you?
Get away from me!
Joe, where have you been?
-Where's Joe?
-Here I am.
Come on, Joe. Let's go.
Where?
Anywhere!
Let's go, honey.
Happy New Year!
Hey, come on.
Leave me alone. Leave me alone.
I'm dizzy.
No!
Did you see where Arnold went?
-You get stood up, Kay?
-It looks like it.
Bud, would you be an angel, huh?
-I'll love you for the rest of my life.
-I'll go look for him.
Cut it out, it's his sister!
Now lay off, Bill!
Cut it out, I tell you, she's his sister.
He's gone mad.
Stop this fight! Stop this fight!
It wasn't his fault. No one's to blame.
Let's go.
Come on inside a minute. Okay?
-Do you wanna come inside?
-No.
We gotta stop all this kissing
and fooling around, Deanie.
Tell me what's happened.
I just don't think we'd better
see each other for a while.
I have to go. Goodbye.
We planned the whole play around you.
You're supposed to be there.
What's the matter?
-I'm sorry.
-Sorry, my foot!
-You keep training?
-Yes, sir.
-Hours? Diet?
All right, let's try it again.
I said, let's try it again.
I want very much to say this:
I want to give most of you
a high compliment on your term paper.
They're the best set of papers
I've ever received.
Bud?
Just a minute.
There's something I've got to tell you.
Your term paper was not very good.
Well, I guess so.
Remember, you've got to do much better...
...if you're going to get into Yale in the fall.
Hi.
I miss you, Bud.
I just wanted to wish you good luck
on the game.
Thanks.
Dr. Smiley.
-Doc?
-Yes, Bud.
-What happened?
-You tell me.
What do you want? What is it?
What's wrong with him?
He just had a fall.
There's nothing to worry about at all.
104°. I recommend the hospital.
There's a lot of pneumonia around.
-Pneumonia?
-My God!
Yes, I know.
I've signed my name to this check.
Pull my boy through
and I'm willing to give you a bonus.
You just fill out the amount,
$5,000, $10,000--
I'm doing everything that can be done.
You just fill out the amount.
I think the boy's going to be all right,
but if he isn't....
What do you mean, "if he isn't"?
Ace, I'm not a very religious man,
but I know what every doctor knows.
You can't reckon with the will of God.
Just say whatever is in your heart,
Wilma Dean.
All I can think of is, "Dear God,
make him well, make him well."
Then that's your prayer.
But aren't there some words I should say
out of the Bible?
I can't think of any that would be better
than your own.
Oh, please, God, make him well.
Make him well.
Well, Bud, in another week or so
you'll be feeling yourself again.
Then spring will be here.
You know what happens
to a young man's fancy in the springtime.
-You go with Del Loomis' girl, don't you?
-Yeah.
Mighty attractive girl.
She sure is.
-I'm pretty nuts about Deanie Loomis.
-I don't blame you.
I mean, I love her.
And she loves me.
But it's no fun to be in love. It hurts.
Every time that we're together...
...I have to...
...remember things.
You know what I mean?
Oh, yes.
I just can't go back to seeing her again.
Not like the way we were doing.
We'd go out every night and...
...I'd hold her and I'd kiss her and...
...I'd just go home.
I mean, a guy can go nuts that way.
I don't know how to advise you, Bud.
My dad said...
...that I should get another kind of a girl.
No.
But when you don't really want
another girl....
No.
I don't know.
Come in again Friday, Bud.
I'll give you another shot of iron...
...and another sun-lamp treatment.
Okay, Doc.
So long.
Hi, Deanie.
And that was the surest way to lose him.
What did you say?
-He's an animal.
-He is not.
-Yes, he is. I met him.
-You don't know him.
Who's an animal?
-You're out.
-I am not.
Yes, you are.
-I hurt my finger.
-I'll kiss it and make it better.
"What though the radiance
which was once so bright
"Is now for ever taken from my sight...
"Though nothing can bring back the hour
Of splendor in the grass...
"...of glory in the flower;
"We will grieve not, rather find
"Strength in what remains behind...."
What do you suppose the poet means
by these lines?
Deanie Loomis?
I'm sorry, Miss Metcalf.
I didn't hear the question.
I know it's spring but I must ask you
to pay more attention.
I'm sorry.
I quoted some lines from Wordsworth's
Ode on Intimations of Immortality.
Did you hear them?
I'm afraid not, Miss Metcalf.
Then I must ask you to turn your text
to Page 380.
Yes, l....
You read the lines to me.
Yes.
Stand please.
"Though nothing can bring back the hour
"Of splendor in the grass...
"...of glory in the flower;
"We will grieve not, rather find
"Strength in what remains behind...."
Perhaps you can tell me
exactly what the poet means...
...by such expressions as
"splendor in the grass"...
...and "glory in the flower."
I think it has some....
Yes?
Well, when we're young...
...we look at things very idealistically,
I guess.
And I think Wordsworth means...
...that when we grow up...
...that we have to forget
the ideals of youth...
...and find strength....
Miss Metcalf...
...may I please be....
Children!
I'll go see what's the matter.
-Hi, June.
-Hi.
I just gave her a sedative.
-I'm not sick.
-She'll be all right in a little while.
Now lie down.
I'm all right. I'm perfectly all right.
Stop that.
I'm all right.
I don't care if his father is making
my folks rich. I hate Bud Stamper.
-You'd take a date if he asked you.
-I would not.
-You know you would.
-I absolutely would not.
Here he comes.
Hi.
All right.
Why aren't you going out
for track this year?
Got all that work to make up
from when I was sick.
You going to Yale? You going to Yale?
Yeah, if my grades are good enough.
How come you're not dating Deanie
anymore?
I'm just not.
I guess I'll just go to cow college.
I'm only a farmer and I know it.
Hot dog! Now it's my chance.
Any objections?
I can't stop you.
Deanie! Come on, honey, supper's ready.
Deanie! Come on, honey.
Deanie, come on! Supper's getting cold!
Veal roast, mashed potatoes
and succotash for my girl.
Eat a good meal, Deanie.
Make you feel better.
Always drink plenty of milk, Deanie.
Eat your dinner.
Seventy-six and three-eighths!
What do you know about that, huh?
Seventy-six and three-eighths! Oh, Del!
Did you hear that, Deanie?
We are rich! We are rich!
I'll bet the Stampers are feeling good
these days.
Honey, we'll send you to college.
We'll get a new car. That I promise.
Saw young Stamper driving this afternoon.
Crowd of boys in the car.
Brand new car his father got him.
Deanie, stop it! Stop carrying on this way!
Mom, I can't eat. I can't study.
I can't even face my friends anymore.
I wanna die. I wanna die.
Do you feel better, dear?
Oh, yes.
Nothing like a good soak.
Deanie, tell me,
what's been the matter the past few days?
I'm sorry I've troubled you.
I don't want to worry you.
I don't want to worry anyone.
Is it all on account of...because of Bud?
Because he doesn't call for you anymore?
I don't know.
I don't know, Mom.
I want to call him and tell him--
Don't you dare! Don't you dare, Mom!
Don't you dare!
I won't!
Mother, you do something like that,
I'll do something desperate!
I will! I will, Mom! I will!
Deanie, how serious have
you and Bud become?
I mean....
You know what I mean.
Had anything serious happened?
Did he spoil you?
Spoil?
Did he spoil me? No!
No, Mom! I'm not spoiled!
I'm not spoiled, Mom!
I'm just as fresh and virginal
like the day I was born, Mom!
Stop it! Stop it!
I'm a virgin who wouldn't think
of being spoiled!
-Stop it, please!
-I've been a good little girl!
A good little, good little girl!
I've always done everything
Daddy and Mommy told me!
I've obeyed every word!
I hate you! I hate you! I hate you!
-Help me.
-What's wrong? People can hear her.
What will we do?
Leave me alone!
What'll we do with her?
Give her some of that medicine.
I hate to give it to her so often.
I'm not spoiled! I'm not spoiled!
What else can we do?
Open this door, dear.
Deanie, open the door.
What are you doing?
Maybe we should take her to Wichita
like Doc Smiley suggested.
A psychiatrist?
It'll take money,
but I'll sell the stocks if I must.
I can't believe it's that serious.
She's bound to get over it in time.
There's never been any mental trouble
in either of our families.
Who's this?
Probably one of her school friends.
How do you do, folks?
My name is Alan Tuttle.
They call me Toots.
Yes, I've heard Deanie speak of you.
How do you do?
I thought I'd drop in
and say hello to Deanie.
Hi, Deanie.
Hi, Toots.
How are you feeling, Deanie?
I feel all right.
If you two young folks will pardon us....
It's almost time for supper.
Very nice to have met you, folks.
What have you done to your hair?
Enjoyed meeting you, too, Toots.
I've been meaning to come for a long time
to see how you were getting along.
Thanks, Toots.
You look fine.
But she's out there in her robe.
Thank you, Toots.
So I was wondering if maybe...
...you would like to go to the dance.
I'd probably be an awful drip
at the dance, Toots.
Why don't you say you'll go?
And if anything happens, you change
your mind or you don't feel like it....
Have a wonderful time.
-I'll take good care of her, Mrs. Loomis.
-Thank you.
Good night, Deanie.
Good night.
I'll leave the door open.
And, Deanie, don't stay out too late.
"Don't stay out too late."
Did you hear her?
She's been saying that
ever since I was knee high.
I used to think it meant something,
but it doesn't. Doesn't mean a thing.
Hello, Deanie. Glad to see you.
-Hello, Toots.
-Hello, Coach.
You look just beautiful. Look at your hair.
-Your dress is beautiful.
-You look gorgeous.
He's here. And guess who with? Kay.
Would you dance with me, Toots?
All right with you, Deanie?
Sure.
Sure, go ahead.
Come on.
How are you, Deanie?
All right, I guess. I don't know.
How are you?
All right, I guess.
You like?
Come on outside for a cigarette.
Okay.
When did you start smoking?
The past few weeks.
I had to do something.
Mom had a fit, but she doesn't
say anything anymore.
I know why you quit coming by.
-Let's not talk about it.
-I've got to talk about it.
All I've done the past couple of months
is just sit home...
...and think about it.
Hey, get out of there.
You said you wouldn't see him anymore,
and here you are in his car.
Deanie, I want to tell you something.
Every night after dinner I force myself
from going to the telephone and calling.
Deanie, I think about you all the time.
Where's your car?
Come on.
Please, Bud. Please.
Deanie, cut it out.
Now, Bud.
Deanie, you're a nice girl.
I'm not.
I'm not a nice girl.
Come on, cut it out.
I just can't go on like this anymore.
Now come on, we're gonna go back inside.
No, I don't want to go back inside.
I want to stay here with you. I want you!
-This isn't the way it should be.
-Why not?
-Why not? Why don't you want it?
-You're not yourself.
Deanie, where's your pride?
My pride? My pride?
-I don't care about my pride!
-Deanie, stop it!
Stop it, Deanie! Deanie, stop!
Go on, go on! I haven't any pride!
I haven't any pride!
Oh, God! What am I gonna do with you?
I don't care what you do.
I don't care what happens!
I haven't any pride!
I just want to die! I just want to die!
Take me away from here. Take me away.
It's okay. Come on.
I put some bread on to set.
We'll have homemade bread for a few days.
What are you thinking about, Del?
I'm worrying about our little girl.
She's all right now. She's at the dance.
I'll bet you she's having the time of her life.
Drink your milk.
Stop it!
Don't, Bud, don't!
Bud?
Deanie, come back here!
Where are you going?
Deanie, come back!
Stop it!
Deanie, come back here!
Hey, you can't go up there!
Hey, you, come back here!
Isn't that Deanie Loomis?
What's the matter with you? Come here!
She dove in. What's wrong with that girl?
Get away! Leave me alone!
She hasn't spoken a word of sense
since they brought her in here.
Stay close to her.
-Any word?
-No, not yet.
Not yet.
My baby. Why did she do it?
I don't want to see you ever again.
Mama, quit talking like that.
I don't care. He's the cause
of all her trouble.
He's the cause.
-What did you do to her tonight?
-No, Mama!
I want him to answer me.
She doesn't mean what she says.
I do, too.
My little girl. I want my little girl.
Mama, quit getting all worked up.
How can I help getting worked up...
...when my baby, my baby lies there
fighting for her life?
Frieda, I'm sorry.
By george, Del,
I'm sorry to hear about this.
-Is she all right?
-They don't know what's the matter yet.
Your daughter is
in a very nervous condition.
-Can I see my baby?
-No, not now. Perhaps tomorrow.
Have you thought about
what I suggested to you?
Yes. I'm going through with it.
I'll sell those stocks and send her off
to Wichita as soon as she's ready to leave.
Good. I'll make the arrangements for you.
It's time you and I were home in bed.
I'm gonna marry Deanie.
I don't care what he says, Doc.
-Good night, Bud.
-Good night, Mr. Loomis.
I'm of legal age. I don't care what he says,
I'm gonna marry her.
Bud, do you want to help Deanie?
Then stay away from her.
-For how long?
-I don't know.
I don't know now. No one does.
Who's that?
Who's there? Who's there?
There's nobody. Nobody.
There was somebody here.
Somebody was here.
You have another letter from your father.
I'm beginning to think you want
to be thrown out of school.
Angelina, do you think I could have...
...another one of these home brew?
Mister, you drink! You're gonna get sick.
Let me bring you some food.
Would you like something to eat?
My mother's making some pizza.
Would you like some pizza?
What is pizza?
You don't know what pizza is?
Where are you from?
From Kansas.
Where is that?
It's right in the middle of the USA.
So that's where your home is.
Is it nice out there in Kansas?
Yep.
It's very friendly.
That's what it's like, it's friendly.
Everybody knows your name
and they know who you are and....
Why don't you go back?
You must have a sweetheart out there.
I did.
Come in the kitchen with me.
Mama will give you some pizza.
Have some pizza.
Come on.
That's fine, you're up.
You all right?
What?
Are you all right, mister?
Sure you are.
Sit on that bench.
I'll be right with you. All right?
No, that's for Mr. Mangialomino.
What do you think about that?
Squint your eyes a bit.
What would Cézanne say to that?
That's swell, Deanie.
I never thought I could do this well, really.
It looks better with one eye closed.
Oh, you!
I like metalwork, though. You can
get rid of a lot of hostilities this way.
Watch.
Every time I pound,
I tell myself it's my old man.
My old man had his heart set on
my being a surgeon.
Well, not just a surgeon
but the greatest surgeon who ever lived.
So, anyway, I couldn't make that first cut.
That first cut into the flesh
of another man's body.
I shook. I couldn't keep my hands steady.
You can still be an M.D.
when you get out, though.
If I ever get out.
Johnny, don't talk like that.
I'm kidding, I hope.
Deanie, your parents are
in the waiting room.
Mother and Dad are here?
My folks are here. I haven't seen them
for six months. Not since I've been here.
I hope these people know
what they're doing.
How much longer are they going
to keep her here?
Here she comes.
Don't let Deanie see you looking this way.
-My baby! My little baby!
-Hi, Mother. It's good to see you.
Daddy! It's so good to see you.
Doesn't she look just fine, Del?
They can't tell me there's anything wrong
with my little baby.
She's just as sound and normal
as the next one--
I brought our little girl a box of candy.
Thank you, Daddy.
All the girls in your old gang
wanted to tell you hello.
Your father had to go
and tell everyone where you are.
I'm not ashamed, Mom.
Sit down.
Well, now lets see.
Kay's gone off to Miss Finch's school.
Very elegant.
Her folks are very wealthy now, you know.
And June. June calls about you
every week or so.
-I guess you know she married Bob.
-Yes.
Carolyn and June are off at the university.
Now Carolyn pledged Pi Phi.
Hazel pledged Kappa. Which is better?
-I don't know.
-The university isn't far from here.
Maybe you'd like them to come
and see you some Saturday.
I don't think so, Mom.
No, no, I guess not.
I guess it wouldn't be...suitable.
There's nothing the matter with you,
you just remember that.
You are perfectly all right.
Just as well off as Kay or June or Hazel
or any of those girls.
Maybe....
Deanie, would you like to have dinner
with us tonight down at the hotel?
Deanie's had a very trying day,
she's too tired.
Yes, I'm awfully....
We're not gonna see any more of you?
This is all we get to see of you?
Mom, I'm sorry.
We drove all the way up here
just to be with our baby.
Now they tell us we can't be
with her tonight.
You want what's best for your daughter,
don't you, Mrs. Loomis?
Yes.
Yes, I want what's best for my daughter.
We'll take our little girl out to dinner...
I'm sorry.
...the next time we come up, Mama.
Mom kept calling me her baby...
...and Dad kept calling me his little girl.
Dr. Judd, don't they realize I'm me?
You're the one that's got to change.
They can't.
I don't think I could ever go
back home again.
I don't think I can feel the same way
I used to feel about them.
You'll just have to accept them as people,
with a lot of faults maybe...
...but not as Mama and Papa.
As people?
You know, we blame our parents
for everything these days.
You've gotta remember
they had parents, too.
I suppose.
You had a mama and a papa, too?
Oh, yes, most assuredly.
That'll be all, Deanie. You can go now.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Have you heard from that young man?
What was his name?
Bud?
No.
No, we've given up writing.
I guess he's probably away at school.
I don't know. No one ever writes me
anything about him.
I guess they're afraid it would upset me.
Would it?
Maybe you'll feel a little stronger
about it in time.
I hope so.
I'll bet they've been practicing
some of that Freud on her.
I've read about him.
All he's concerned about is sex.
And it's costing us every blessed penny
we made on our stocks.
If we could've held onto those stocks,
we would've made a fortune.
I don't think it's very polite of you to turn
on the radio when I'm talking to you.
Stock prices crashed today...
...in the most disastrous trading ever
on the New York Stock Exchange.
$14 billion was lost
in the nation-wide attempt to unload.
Sell out? What do you mean, sell out?
You're getting panicky like everybody else.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Now just don't get panicky, Jack.
Don't lose your courage.
Come in.
Hang on, Jack, just hang on.
Just hang in there.
No, I can't go on with this right now, Jack.
Sit down, friend, I'll be right with you.
I'm in New Haven.
My kid's in school up here.
Oh, hell, he's doing just fine.
Flunking every course, but otherwise fine.
He'll be all right.
I got an idea what's wrong with him.
Yeah, I'll be calling you.
-What'd you find out?
-You were right.
-Who is she?
-She's a waitress.
Waitress?
In a pizza place. It's all right here.
Do you want a drink?
Bud, suppose you tell us--
He hasn't been applying himself.
I know my boy.
He could pass any course you offer here.
Flying colors, straight A's.
Thank you.
Suppose you tell us
what you think is the matter, Bud.
Have you really been interested
in your work here at Yale?
What difference does that make?
I sent you here to graduate.
I'm sorry to disappoint you, Dad, but--
Now why don't we just talk turkey, Son?
Tell us what's been on your mind.
What's been eating your time and energy?
A long-distance call from New York
for Mr. Stamper.
-Where can I take it?
-Urgent. Right this way, sir.
Is there anything you'd rather
be doing now than going to school here?
To tell you the truth, Dean Pollard,
I never wanted to do a thing but ranch.
But, Dad....
I've never had the belief
that everybody should go to college.
Well, maybe you could talk to him.
He isn't a very good listener really, is he?
I gotta get back to New York right away.
Bud, suppose you let me talk
to your father.
Yeah, sure. Thank you.
I'll see you back in your room, Son.
Dean Pollard, what's the matter
with people?
What do you mean?
The whole town of New York
is jumping out of windows.
I mean, they're quitting.
And things are gonna get back to normal
in a couple of days.
-You really think so?
-I know so! I know so!
They've got to! They've got to!
Now, about the boy....
I'm gonna take him to New York with me.
I'll have him back here Monday morning
ready to settle down and go to work.
I must say, Mr. Stamper, I do not feel
that the boy should remain in school here.
Please don't give up on him.
Don't give up on him, Dean Pollard.
I had to go through something like this
with him once before.
He falls for some little girl
and then that's all he can think about.
-I don't think that's it, Mr. Stamper.
-I think that's it! I think that's it!
I think I've known him a little bit longer
and a little bit better than you have!
I had to break something like this before!
I'll break it up again!
I'll have him Monday morning
ready to go to work!
Kewpie dolls.
Would you like a Kewpie doll
for your cutie-pie?
-Yeah. How much are they?
-$50.
All right, you fish $50 out of there
and you give me the rest back.
Thank you.
'Bye.
They all look the same in this town.
The newlyweds. Stand up.
Give the little girl a hand.
Hello, suckers.
I think I smell fresh money tonight.
I'm glad the stock market crash
didn't keep you from coming out tonight.
Tonight as I was walking
down Park Avenue to get a taxi...
...I had to dodge the bodies
jumping out of the windows.
But let's not be morbid.
-Same all around?
-No, no more for me.
Same all around.
Lay one on me. Lay one on.
Doggone.
Dad, let's go.
Wait, Bud, wait a minute.
The point I'm trying to make, Bud....
I never have been able to make
this one point with you, Son.
Bud, listen....
I may not be around
too much longer and....
What are you talking about?
Wait now. Don't act so worried.
I got no intention of kicking off for a while.
What are you leading up to?
It may be that I haven't always done
the right thing by you, boy...
...and I'm sorry.
There may be things
I might have taken away.
I'd like to make it up to you.
Forget it, Dad.
Look up there.
Look up there on that stage.
Deanie.
Yeah, she does look a little like Deanie.
Little, hell! Hell, a little! Exactly!
Same damn thing! Exactly!
Same damn thing! Just as pretty!
Just as pretty!
You never been fair to me on that.
I did that for your own good.
How'd you like to be married to her now?
Did you ever think about that?
Ever think of how you'd like to be married
to Deanie with her in that institute?
Did you ever think about it?
How'd you like that?
Her in that institution?
What the hell difference does it make?
That's the same thing!
That's the same thing exactly!
And just as pretty! Just as pretty!
You look up there, just as pretty!
You want that? Do you want it, Son?
Son, you want it, you can have it!
You can have it, boy. I'll get it for you.
You can have anything you want.
Anything you want, boy!
This world is your oyster!
You sit here, I'll show you.
You sit there, I'll show you.
Yeah?
Are you Bud?
Yes, ma'am.
Aren't you gonna invite me in?
I'm sorry, but...
...I think you must've got the wrong room.
Mr. Stamper?
Mr. Stamper!
That's him.
What do you want to do with...?
I'll take him home.
I'll be home in a few hours.
The first time in....
Two years and six months
almost to the day.
How do you feel about going home?
Like going to a foreign country.
John has asked me to marry him.
You waited until now to tell me?
Well.
Are you going to accept?
I don't know.
Do you love John?
I think so.
It's different from the way
that I felt about...
...Bud.
But, l...
...I love him.
Well, I see no reason why both of you
shouldn't have a very happy future.
John's back in Cincinnati now,
practicing medicine, doing very well.
I know.
I hear from him every day.
My taxi.
Taxi's here.
Will you see Bud when you're home?
I don't know.
Do you think you'll be happy
married to John if...
...you still don't know how you feel
about the other young man?
When we face these fears
they sometimes turn into nothing.
All right, Dr. Judd.
I'll see him.
I'll write to you.
Bye-bye.
Why couldn't you marry a boy from here?
You won't be much company for me,
living back East in Cincinnati.
What do you know about
this young man you're marrying?
After all, you met him in a mental hospital.
Are you sure he's all right?
I was in the hospital, too.
Well, with you it was different.
You were just run down.
That was the only thing
the matter with you.
Is he a New Dealer?
I don't know.
I could cry, just cry, when I think
I'm going to lose my little girl.
How much did this cost?
I don't know, Mother.
Did those doctors at the hospital...
...say your mother had raised you wrong
or something?
Did they blame your father...
...and me in any way?
I don't blame anyone, Mother.
I raised you the only way I knew how.
The only way I knew how.
The way my mother raised me...
...and I suppose the way
her mother raised her.
If I brought you up wrong, Deanie,
I don't think you should hate me.
I know I used to hate my mother at times...
...but I always believed she was right
about things. Maybe she wasn't...
...but I loved her.
I love you, Mother.
I hope so, Deanie.
You know it would be nice if children
could be born into this world...
...with an absolute guarantee they'd have
just the right kind of bringing up...
...and all lead happy, normal lives, but....
Well, I guess when we get born
we just all have to take our chances.
Mom?
Is he married?
Who?
To tell you the truth, Deanie,
I don't really know.
Don't be afraid of running into him.
Maybe he's living with his mother in Tulsa.
She joined her folks there
after old Ace killed himself.
They say she's as poor as a church mouse.
And that girl Ginny?
Got killed in a car accident.
We all knew something like that
would happen the way she carried on.
Now the Stampers are almost extinct
in this town.
You know their home's been turned
into a funeral parlor?
Some of the old gang's here
to see you, Deanie.
-I can't wait to see her.
-It seems simply ages.
How is she, Mr. Loomis?
She's fine.
Come on, come for a ride with us.
All right, but give me two minutes
to wash the train off.
Just one thing:
Keep her away from Bud Stamper.
Mrs. Loomis, she's forgotten about all that.
No, she hasn't. Have some fudge.
The very first thing she did
was ask about him.
And then she laid on the bed
and cried and cried.
I thought that the years away
she'd forget about him but....
Now I want you to promise me.
The doctors say she's perfectly all right,
but there's no use in asking for trouble.
Keep her away from him.
Well, here's our girl.
I want to see Bud now.
Now, honey, you just forget about him.
I'm not even sure where he is now, Deanie.
I mean, no one ever sees him.
Do you know where he is, Hazel?
He's staying out at his father's old ranch.
-It's a long way out there.
-I want to go, please.
Clear out of there!
You want me to go looking for Bud?
Oh, Hazel, would you?
He's around back.
I know.
Hi, Bud. Jeepers, you're a mess.
Yeah, I've been working.
We have 40 head of cattle now.
Bud, Deanie's out there in the car.
-I hate to see Deanie when I'm so dirty.
-She won't mind, Bud.
How is she?
She seems just fine.
Well, I'm glad.
Hi, Bud.
Long time no see.
Long time.
It's good to see you.
Thanks, Bud.
You want to meet my family?
Of course.
Come on.
She didn't even know he was married.
You're her best friend.
Why didn't you tell her?
I just couldn't.
Come here, honey,
I want you to meet somebody.
Hello.
Angelina, this is Deanie,
an old friend of mine.
How do you do?
How do you do, Angelina?
Would you like to come in?
Please.
Come in.
Hungry?
The house, it doesn't look like much.
-Maybe I can offer you some wine.
-Thank you, but I really can't stay.
This is Bud Junior.
The one without the feathers.
Oh, sure.
Hello, Bud Junior. Hello.
What a fine boy you are!
So now we're expecting another child.
I hope it's a girl this time.
You're a fine boy.
Well, I have to go now.
You will come back again sometime?
Will you come back for dinner?
Thank you, Angelina.
I married Angie when I left New Haven.
You know I didn't even finish
my first year there?
She's real nice.
She was wonderful to me
when things started to go wrong.
You're happy, Bud?
I guess so.
I don't ask myself that question
very often now.
How about you?
I'm getting married next month.
Are you, Deanie?
A boy from Cincinnati.
I think you might like him.
Things work out awful funny sometimes,
don't they?
Yes, they do.
Hope you're gonna be awful happy.
Like you, Bud, I don't think too much
about happiness either.
What's the point?
You gotta take what comes.
Yes.
I'm awful glad to see you again.
Thanks, Bud.
Goodbye.
'Bye.
So long, Bud.
Hello.
-You girls have to come again sometime.
-You might ask us.
I will. I promise. Angie and I got
a little more money coming in now.
We'll have a big beer party. She'll call you.
-It's a date.
-Great.
Goodbye.
When do we eat?
Deanie, honey, do you think
you still love him?
"Though nothing can bring back the hour
Of splendor in the grass...
"...of glory in the flower;
"We will grieve not, rather find
Strength in what remains behind.... "