The nuclear industry is a death industry.
It's a cancer industry.
It's a bomb industry.
It's killing people
and will for the rest of time.
Well, why doesn't
President Obama know this?
He's an intelligent man.
He's got 2 little girls he loves.
What the hell does he think he's up to,
supporting the nuclear industry?
It's wicked.
Do you mind if I use
the "F" word?
Can I use the "F" word?
We can get rid of all these
fucking nuclear plants right away
because we can switch to solar, wind,
tidal, geothermal, ocean thermal...
all that energy is available
to do today.
We can shut all the
nuclear plants
and all the coal, all the oil
and all the gas plants.
We can shut them down.
We have the technology.
It's called "Solartopia."
As a life-long environmentalist,
I'm against nuclear.
But what if what I have
been thinking all this time
and what my friends have been thinking
all this time, is wrong?
STEWART BRAND
Founder and Editor of Whole Earth Catalogue
It's been interesting to see
how people respond to
my pro-nuclear power position.
Because they respect me for my books
about nuclear weapons,
they know that I'm a liberal Democrat
and they are puzzled.
RICHARD RHODES Pulitzer Prize winner
for "The Making of the Atomic Bomb"
I was against nuclear power.
All I had to say was
Three Mile Island, Chernobyl,
atomic bombs, atomic weapons.
My mind was made up, definitely.
So I needed a lot of input.
The research I did, and the
scientists I interviewed, and so on.
Going and visiting,
and seeing for myself.
GWYNETH CRAVENS
author, "Power to Save the World"
I was under no doubt
that my whole career
and my whole reputation
as an environmental activist, communicator
was at risk if I talked
publicly about
having changed my mind
about nuclear power.
I'd have been much better if I
had only just keep my mouth shut.
But I couldn't do that.
MARK LYNAS
Environmental Activist
Whenever you change your mind
so radically,
like those of us that have
become pro-nuclear have changed our minds,
you start to wonder
what you were thinking.
I mean, what exactly
was going on?
MICHAEL SHELLENBERGER - President and
Co-founder, The Breakthrough Institute
You know, the more you peel that onion,
the more strange things you've figured out.
...a top radiation issue in Tokyo...
from the nuclear power plant Ai
at Fukushima Daiichi.
Now today, 4 of the 6 reactors there
remain in states of danger.
A nuclear accident is one of the biggest
media stories it's possible to have.
...reactor number 3, this is the one
whose fuel contains a mix of plutonium...
In my first blog entry, within the
first 2 or 3 days of it happening,
I didn't know what the scale
of the radiation release was going to be,
I didn't know whether people
were going to be injured.
The fact that this was happening live
on TV and that there were explosions,
you know, this was
a nuclear power station blowing up.
Clearly, this situation was
out of control.
The Chief Cabinet Secretary
has asked the residents of Tokyo
not to hoard bottled water.
So you have these awful images
of total devastation from a tsunami,
and the story was a nuclear power accident.
It all got muddled together.
Some people on the West Coast
of the United States worry
- that the radiation could travel 5,000 miles...
- I hadn't been pro-nuclear all that long
before the Fukushima plant
started to melt-down.
It's hard to watch that happening
and not insert the question of
whether or not this is an energy source
that is really safe.
Radioactive isotopes
will likely reach California...
but experts say those levels are so low,
they certainly fall within safe limits.
Now, a large network of radio monitors
is keeping close tabs on all of this.
The long-term effects of all of this,
obviously, still to be determined.
I thought:
"I've got to keep my head, you know,
"I could really lose it here,
and I could just panic."
JAPAN
A year later
What do you think, Mark?
- I feel like a bit of an idiot, actually.
- Why?
I don't know,
because it's sort of...
I'm wearing radiation clothing.
It shouldn't be necessary.
SPECIAL SECURITY ZONE
FUKUSHIMA POLICE DEPARTMENT
It must be absolutely awful
to have your town wiped out by a tsunami
and earthquake, and you can't even
come back and rebuild,
because the whole place
is contaminated by radiation.
Even if it's not massively contaminated,
it's contaminated enough
that it scares the shit out of you.
And I think that's...
you know, nobody can look you in the eye
and say: "You shouldn't be worried."
Um, you know, there's no other
energy source that does this,
that leaves huge areas contaminated
by this strange invisible presence
which, you know,
is potentially deadly, you know.
Everything has it's drawbacks,
everything has it's risks
but this is something that is
unique to nuclear.
I guess I can understand why people are
scared of nuclear power as a whole.
You know, it's um...
it's kind of eerie.
So, um, yeah, I would say
I'm having a wobble.
I can see why we'd want to do
without nuclear power, I really can.
FUTABA
2 kilometres from Fukushima Daiichi
This parking lot is the hottest spot
in the whole exclusion zone.
This place got some serious
fallout, I think.
So, are you still pro-nuclear?
Um, am I still pro-nuclear?
Ask me in a few days, when I've had
a chance to get my head around it, alright?
Are you still pro-nuclear?
To start the chain reaction, all we need
is one neutron.
I think you can see
what is going to happen.
Watch.
My first introduction to nuclear power
was quite nice.
It was a Disney movie called:
"Our Friend the Atom".
The atom was going to
bring about a wonderful revolution
in the way we got our energy.
And, there was a nuclear powered
submarine called the Nautilus...
that went under the North Pole and us kids
were really enthusiastic about that.
And then, when I was in my early teens,
Admiral Rickover came to give a speech.
And, my dad knew I was interested
in science, so he took me.
Watch the control rods come out.
As the control rods come out,
the reactor starts.
And water starts
encirculating through here.
He was a wonderful speaker and
he was very inspiring
about American technology
and about the future
and he talked about nuclear energy
being used to light up cities,
not just run submarines.
So, it was a generally positive notion.
I got into the nuclear business
in early 1948.
Prior to that I was working on engines
for the Tucker automobile.
Everything we had done, up until that time,
that produced energy
was by burning something.
The enticement in the nuclear business
was the fact that it was a new
LEN KOCH
Engineer and Nuclear Pioneer
source of energy,
a new way to generate heat.
But the equivalence is huge.
One pound of uranium,
which is the size of my fingertip,
if you could release all of the energy,
has the equivalent of about
5,000 barrels of oil.
And that, to me, is amazing.
I worked at
Argonne National Laboratory, in Idaho.
Which really was the headquarters in the
world for nuclear power at the time.
We were building this first in the world
experimental breeder reactor.
EBR-I was an experiment just to prove that
the concept made sense, scientifically.
Everything happened
just like we expected it to.
The reactors went critical.
Critical means that you have enough
uranium so that it generates heat.
All the reactor does is generate heat.
The end product is steam,
and then once you have steam, it's the same
whether you generate the electricity
with oil, or coal, or gas, or...
just as long as you have a source of heat.
So, we generated electricity
and then we hooked-up 4 light bulbs.
And we lit the light bulbs
from atomic energy.
December 20, 1951
Nobody else had done it before.
But the fact that
the whole nuclear business,
atomic energy, was started
for a bomb, and used as a bomb...
and I think that put the
negative side on it.
SAN ANTONIO, NEW MEXICO
July 16, 1945
I'm just old enough to have
conscious memory of World War II,
and the ending of World War II.
MONUMENT AT TRINITY SITE
White Sands, New Mexico
First nuclear test site
Nuclear bombs were not just a weapon.
They were a little window
into some kind of Armageddon.
The photographs and the films
and the stories
that came out of Hiroshima and Nagasaki...
those things cut pretty deep.
So, you had this
very strong residue of
this is not primarily an energy source,
this is primarily a weapon,
uh, that we feel very badly about.
And then the testing went on and on.
We're hearing about the radiation
from strontium-90.
And then the Russians were doing tests.
Ah, the Chinese were doing tests.
And before it really slowed down,
there were over 2000 tests
with nuclear weapons.
I grew up having nightmares
that my home town was bombed into oblivion
and I was the only survivor.
Those kids were in school doing
duck-and-cover routines under the desks
and the back yard fallout shelters
and all that stuff,
made it all pretty personal.
I grew up in an
anti-nuclear family.
You know, my parents were
children of the '60s.
They were liberals and environmentalists.
To actually believe in nuclear power was,
by definition to be a dupe.
Every step along the way,
measures will be taken
to guarantee that
our plant at Connecticut Yankee
contributes to the beneficial
and harmonious development
of the Connecticut Valley.
The Haddam Neck site
will be artfully landscaped
so that the buildings harmonize
with its wooded background.
Plans even call for an information
and educational centre
for those wishing
to visit the Haddam Neck project.
I actually visited the nuclear power plant
with my buddies in high school.
And we knew enough
to have a very sarcastic attitude
toward the tour they gave us.
They would say:
"It's this clean source of energy,
"it's really safe, it doesn't have
anything to do with nuclear weapons."
And we would just laugh,
we thought they were all "tools,"
stooges of the nuclear industry
and its propaganda campaign.
Of course, that gets reinforced for people
in my generation with The Simpsons.
Warning: problem in sector 7-G.
7-G? Good God,
who's the safety inspector there?
Where the evil character is the C.E.O.
of the nuclear power company.
Simpson, eh?
Good man? Intelligent?
And Homer Simpson is bumbling
while the whole thing is melting down.
Doh! Whoever thought that
a nuclear reactor would be so complicated?
You just always had the sense that
nuclear power was something sinister,
something that was a lurking danger.
I was against nuclear power
because I was an environmentalist.
I am an environmentalist...
and the two things go together.
Certainly, that always
seemed to be the case.
Looking back, I suppose you could say
that I was a hard-core activist.
It's almost like being in a battle-zone.
It's the kind of experience
that most people never have.
Where you're battling the forces of evil
almost on a day to day basis.
"Evil" being the big corporations,
those who are making profit out of
Earth's destruction;
and "good" being us.
The slogan was:
"No compromise in defence of Mother Earth."
That was the original
Earth First slogan.
And it's one I still subscribe to,
on a very deep level I think.
Well, I mean,
nuclear power was evil.
No doubt about it.
Who are the criminals?
I was writing for national magazines
many years ago.
Writing articles about the dangers
of nuclear power.
And I had the standard point-of-view
that I think, many journalists still have:
that it must be bad.
I came to realize
they basically avoided
looking at the whole picture
and only looked at the questions that
seemed to prove to them
that nuclear power was dangerous...
as I had too.
The only reason I changed my mind is
that I talked to experts, physicists
in particular,
who were the pioneers of nuclear energy.
And who carefully, one by one,
explained to me
again and again,
until it finally got through my head
why it wasn't what the anti-nuclear
activists felt it was...
believed it was.
I was right there
at the beginning of this.
It was my chance to
do something for humankind.
This, after all,
was an unlimited source of energy.
I assumed that all electrical power,
if we were successful,
would be generated by nuclear means.
In the '50s there were essentially
two kinds of reactors being developed.
The breeder reactor, which EBR-1
was a prototype for,
and the light water reactor.
The breeder reactor breeds plutonium
and can recycle it over and over again
It's a very good fuel.
The light water reactor is
a much simpler reactor,
but it produces much more waste.
It was chosen by Admiral Rickover
to be the reactor for the submarine.
CHARLES TILL
Nuclear Physics Pioneer
There are many things to be said
for light water reactors,
and there are some to be said against.
But, with Rickover's influence,
the light water reactor
became the principal commercial reactor
around the world.
We developed water reactors,
but we looked upon that as sort of a
near-term, short-range stepping stone
to real nuclear power:
the breeder reactor.
That's what we considered to be
the most likely,
real long-range
future for nuclear power.
But, the water reactor
got marketed first.
This was partly a commercial move
on our part.
In the early 1950's we were concerned
that the Soviet Union,
which had kept pace with us
in the development
of nuclear reactors for power,
would steal a march on us and
get the commercial business in Europe.
So, President Eisenhower decided
to share the benefits
of nuclear energy with other countries.
It's called: Atoms for Peace.
We've had 50 years now
of water reactors,
400 of them, roughly,
all over the world.
And they've produced a hell-of-a-lot
of waste that we didn't anticipate.
You know, you've mentioned a
100,000 years of stuff
that you gotta keep isolated
from the rest of the world,
it's enough to scare a lot of people.
There was perhaps a price we paid
for commercialization,
in the sense that we didn't look ahead.
Nuclear power was developed
as a kind of a boutique energy source
by utilities executives
who really didn't know much about it.
I talked to people who said,
"Well, I heard about it on the golf course
"from the guy who
runs the plant down the road.
"He's going to build one,
and so I thought I should too."
The first commercial nuclear power plant,
that was built in the United States,
was built in
Shippingport, Pennsylvania.
It was a modified version
of a large submarine reactor.
One of the major reasons
the power company wanted it,
was because there was a lot of
coal pollution in Pittsburgh.
And nuclear energy looked to people to be,
as it is, a clean form of energy.
The first power reactors were fairly small.
But the push by the
power and light companies of America
was to scale them up as
quickly as possible.
Safety, instead of being inherent in
the design of the reactor itself,
had to be engineered around it,
as it were.
You had to have
multiple core-cooling systems
that had to be added on
to anticipate possible break-downs
of various kinds.
The odds of "X" happening or "Y" happening
were very small.
But unlike the smaller reactors,
they really couldn't say it was impossible.
March 28, 1979
Late today, officials here in Washington summarized
briefly what seems to have caused the problem.
First, a pump in the generator system
broke down at 4:00 a.m. yesterday.
The reactor immediately shut down.
Reactor operators decided to
open the valves
and release radioactive water
from the reactor.
That, apparently, may have been
the wrong thing to do.
When the emergency core-cooling system
came on automatically,
an operator turned it off.
That too, apparently was a mistake.
For then, high levels of radiation were
released inside the containment building.
And not until 3 hours later
was it realized
that radiation was being released; and
in fact, was penetrating to the outside.
Three Mile Island happened.
And, the first thing I thought of is:
are those rays
coming out of Three Mile Island
gonna come to New York and
harm my daughter?
I remember standing in my
apartment and thinking:
"What can," you know, "what can we do?"
This is Jack Godell,
we have a serious condition.
You get everybody into safety areas,
and you make sure that they stay there.
Of course, 2 weeks earlier,
The China Syndrome had come out.
So I was already prepared to be
terrorized by this event.
The China Syndrome.
The what?
If the core is exposed, for whatever
reason, the fuel heats the...
The idea behind
The China Syndrome
is that the nuclear power plant
would melt down and it would
burrow a hole
all the way to China.
Never mind that China is not actually
on the other side of the Earth
as the United States, but,
that was the idea.
That, the worst-case scenario
would be apocalyptic.
...the number of the people killed would
depend upon which way the wind is blowing...
...render an area the size of Pennsylvania,
permanently uninhabitable.
Not to mention the cancer that
would show up later.
That's when I think I began to conflate
nuclear power with nuclear weapons.
...from a leaking nuclear plant.
We don't want a radioactive wasteland,
whether it's from a bomb or a nuclear plant.
That kind of... that's probably the
sort of thing I would have answered.
It just seemed like, okay,
nuclear anything is a bad idea.
WASHINGTON, D.C.
May, 1979
I want to just say a few words
about The China Syndrome.
My movie, The China Syndrome.
Because, we continue to place
our health and safety
in the hands of utility executives
whose main goal in life
is to maximize profits,
then we will see more Harrisburgs,
we will see more leaks
and we will see an
increase in the cancer epidemic
that is already running rampant
in this country.
No more nukes! No more nukes!
No more nukes!
NEW YORK September, 1979
Stopping atomic energy is
practising patriotism.
fighting cancer.
Stopping atomic energy is
fighting inflation.
saving this country.
♪ Just give me the restless power
Of the wind ♪
♪ Give me the comforting glow
Of a wood fire ♪
♪ But please take all your atomic
Poison power away ♪
In the 1980's, my husband and I were living
in the east end of Long Island.
And, um, word gets out that
this nuclear plant is going to start-up.
And this is, of course,
right after Three Mile Island.
That was very much in people's minds.
The local-grown
environmental people...
and I would be one of those,
ah, just said:
"Yeah, we've gotta stop Shoreham,
however we can."
- No nukes!
- No one will survive!
Every day the plant operates
radiation will be
coming out of the plant, right?
And it will get into the food.
Women may be hard-wired
to protect our families.
Stay clear of the bus.
And it's just a natural impulse.
Stop the fraud!
If something looks like it's bad,
we're holding up our hand and saying: "No,
no, pl... please, we... we can't have that."
I remember these
big scare ads in the papers.
Getting people to organize
rallies against Shoreham.
There were many things that I didn't know
at that time, that I've learned since.
For one thing, it turns out, the ads were
placed by the oil delivery industry.
You know, the companies that deliver
fuel to people on Long Island.
And sure, the oil companies can say:
"Go solar!"
Because they know that it's never going
to replace oil heat.
You cannot turn on the sun in the winter
and hope to warm-up your house.
Good luck.
- Solar, not nuclear.
- Sponsored by the Oil Heat Institute.
- Yeah. Yeah, no problem.
Yeah, you don't need a furnace,
just have solar panels.
I mean, this is the cynicism
of the fossil fuel industry.
Shoreham was actually finished
and started-up,
when it immediately got shut-down
by the Governor of the State
and basically, moth-balled.
It was this immense investment,
billions of Dollars,
in a reactor that would have been
of great use to New York City.
But people were so afraid of it,
that they simply said:
"Shut it down."
And, today it's a mausoleum.
Those of us who were worried
about nuclear power,
perceived that nuclear power
wasn't really needed.
And this, I think, was one of the fundamental
tragedies of the anti-nuclear movement.
To be anti-nuclear, is basically, to be
in favour of burning fossil fuels.
I had, finally, to change my mind.
And, I have seen friends of mine
change their minds.
One of them being, Gwyneth Cravens,
who started out rather anti-nuclear,
as I did,
and ended up writing a book
about the benefits of nuclear power.
November 8, 1989
United Nations, New York
The difference now, is in the scale
of the damage we are doing.
We are seeing a vast increase
in the amount of carbon dioxide
reaching the atmosphere.
It is mankind, and his activities
which are changing the
the environment of our planet
in damaging and dangerous ways.
Change to the sea around us.
Change to the atmosphere above.
Leading, in turn,
to change in the world's climate,
which could alter the way we live, in the
most fundamental way of all.
That prospect is a new factor
in human affairs.
It's comparable in its implications,
to the discovery of how to split the atom.
Indeed its results,
could be even more far-reaching.
We can't just do nothing.
One of the key arguments that the
climate-deniers use is:
"Oh look, climate is a huge thing.
"You mean were affecting the weather?
It's just us, we're just little people."
But we are.
October, 2012
We are beginning to see the kind of
destabilization and chaos that you get
actually, when you see this transition to
much warmer global temperatures.
HURRICANE SANDY
And that process of change,
very very rapid climate change
is going to wreak havoc
on human society.
Having children has made me
even more concerned about the future.
So, it's deep in my commitment
to tackling global warming.
Loving your children is about
loving the future
and loving the world
that they're going to inherit.
And so, you've got to make
sure that that's right.
You know, I had a sneaking suspicion that nuclear
was going to have to be part of the solution,
simply because it doesn't produce
carbon dioxide.
But, I didn't want to go there.
- Why?
- I was too scared.
I mean, it's pathetic really,
but, looking back, but you know, yeah,
you don't want to make enemies
of your main allies in
the environmental movement
by tackling something
which is difficult, controversial.
Ted and I spent basically the
entirety of our professional careers
working for the
big environmental groups.
I mean, you name it: Sierra Club, NRDC,
even worked with Earth First
on a campaign to save
the last ancient redwoods in California.
We were movement guys. I mean, we were
consultants to the big green groups.
We really accepted most of the basic ideas
of the environmental movement,
and I think over time we,
you know, became gradually disillusioned
with the traditional environmental
approaches to climate change.
It is my assessment that
we have no consensus here for Article 10.
Then, we are going to
delete Article 10 from the Protocol.
It is so decided.
THE KYOTO PROTOCOLS ASSEMBLY
People would tell you that:
"Oh, everything is going to change.
"The world is going to implement
the Kyoto Treaty on global warming.
"We're all going to start
using solar and wind for our energy."
It was a very seductive narrative.
Then, Part A is adopted.
There is agreement on
paragraph C of this article.
Paragraph C is adopted.
We understand that there is
agreement on Paragraphs D, E, F & G.
The idea was that the U.S. was
going to sign Kyoto
and then all the countries in the world
were just going to start
ratcheting-down their emissions year after year.
Just like they did on their Excel spreadsheets.
We continue with the revision of Part B.
The problem is, these were
all proposals based on
making fossil fuels more expensive.
I think it's pretty safe to say,
that is not going to happen.
The adoption of this Protocol
to the conference is by unanimity.
There is not going to be a
global treaty on climate change.
The United Nations treaty process
is basically run aground.
We just walked away being like:
"Nobody has a clue
as to how to do this."
So, we wrote this essay:
"Death of Environmentalism"
that argued that, if environmentalism
is that kind of small bore,
then we need something beyond
environmentalism.
Modern environmentalism, with all of its
unexamined assumptions,
outdated concepts
and exhausted strategies
must die,
so that something new can live.
I would suggest that it will take more
than dead penguins and melting ice caps
to get Americans to
fundamentally get involved
in its political transformation
of our energy economy.
We still didn't think we needed
nuclear power.
It really took us getting clear about
how big the gap was,
between fossil fuels and renewables
for us to take a second look at nuclear.
Part of the problem is intermittency.
And that hasn't been solved.
It's not always sunny and it's
not always windy
and there a long periods of time
when renewables would deliver
no power at all into a grid.
You have to have natural gas backup.
So, what you end up getting with renewables
is a pretty big expansion of natural gas.
You know, I'm sure people had told me that
and I didn't believe them.
We're building these all over the country
and one of the questions we ask,
we need about 3,000 foot in altitude,
we need flat land,
we need 300 days of sunlight
and we need to be near a gas plant.
Because, you know, for all of these
big utility scale power plants,
whether it's wind or solar,
everybody is looking at gas as the
supplementary fuel.
The plants that we are building, the wind
plants and the solar plants are gas plants.
I end up feeling like a sucker.
I... I ended up feeling like
I was a sucker.
The idea that we're gonna replace
oil and coal and natural gas
with solar and wind and nothing else
is an hallucinatory delusion.
You know, you find yourself feeling...
I found myself quite
disappointed in myself and...
and honestly, quite angry at others
who were propagating that myth.
This light bulb, when everybody's got them,
will quadruple the efficiency of bulbs
and that will displace
two dozen power plants.
This thing for florescent lights
will displace 60 big power plants.
This motor controller chip
and about 10 other things you do to motors
will save 70 big power plants.
Just these 3 things:
there goes every nuclear plant we have.
I had gotten the religion about
energy efficiency and renewables
in college,
when I first read Amory Lovins.
Amory Lovins is still taught
in maybe every liberal arts
environmental states class in America.
In his article after article,
explaining why solar and wind are
cheaper than fossil fuels
and why you don't need to
build nuclear plants
because we can use energy efficiency...
It's a very appealing, seductive message.
Ah, they're getting smaller, here's
a little Osram 11, replacing a 50.
And I bought it,
my parents and my family bought it,
really, everybody I know believed this.
The standards of green
environmentalist narrative
has been that we can all use less energy;
so we can be renewable,
we can go for energy efficiency.
The idea that humankind is simply wasting
and using too much.
Now, I have a lot of
time for that argument.
But you can't keep using
less energy forever.
Most people kind of think
that, somehow we're going to be reducing
our energy consumption.
Actually, we just find more and more
uses for it.
If you look at all the energy
that is used by an iPhone,
not just to make it
and to power it,
but also to power all the servers,
all of the stuff you don't see,
that the iPhone is connected to:
it uses as much energy as a refrigerator.
There is a direct correlation
between the amount of energy
available to a civilization
and that civilization's quality of life.
Unless you want to condemn
more than half the population of the Earth
to poverty and sickness
and short lives.
We're going to have
to produce more energy.
In regions that don't have electricity,
or very little electricity,
the life span is much shorter.
Clinics, schools, refrigeration,
all of these things rely on electricity.
And just a few watts make
a big difference.
As soon as you get electricity,
you improve people's lives.
Well, that's human life.
First of all, we're talking
about human, just quality of life.
And if you look at the countries
with the best quality of life,
they are the countries
that consume the most electricity.
Rain or shine, 24 hours a day,
a steady stream of power.
The global south is pretty warm, they would
like air conditioning.
And, up till now, they've not been
able to afford it. But now they can.
They're getting out of poverty
and they need grid electricity to
run their air conditioners.
Of course, various environmentalists
freak out at that point.
But, on the other hand,
if you could have vast quantities
of really, really clean energy,
in the developing world
in the next decade or so.
That is such an improved world,
it takes your breath away.
Assuming that the world
continues to develop,
and that China and India and Brazil
become rich countries,
over the next half-century
or century,
how much energy
is the world gonna use?
When you start running
those numbers, it's a sobering exercise.
And you may not be able
to get that number exactly right,
but you realize that we're gonna basically double
the amount of energy we consume by 2050.
We're probably going to triple it
or quadruple it by the end of the century.
And meanwhile, if you want to stabilize
emissions at some reasonable level,
almost all of that energy
has to be clean energy.
You know you've got only, you know, create
a clean energy infrastructure
to replace the fossil fuel infrastructure
we have,
but we have to create
yet another one, or maybe two of 'em
between now and 2050 or 2100;
in order to reduce our emissions,
to stabilize the climate.
And, that is just nothing that anybody
has really been talking about
or dealing with
over the last 20 years.
It comes as a shock
to a lot of environmentalists to hear this,
but coal is not only the most
widely-used source of energy in the world,
it's also the fastest growing
source of energy.
It's use is accelerating world-wide...
faster than natural gas,
faster than renewables,
faster than anything else.
When I have spoken to women's groups,
none of them knew how bad coal was.
They didn't know it killed people.
If you add up all fossil fuel combustion
in the United States,
just from power plants,
the fine particulates alone,
kill 13,000 people a year.
World wide, 3 million people die a year,
from air pollution from fossil fuel plants.
One of the big surprises for me, when I
started looking into the mortality data:
the death rates associated with each
energy technology
per, the amount of energy they make,
is that nuclear is the second-safest
after wind.
And in fact,
to add to the irony of it,
nuclear power is even safer than
solar panels.
Making solar panels is
an incredibly toxic process.
But, I thought people died
at Three Mile Island.
I thought that hundreds of thousands
of people died at Chernobyl.
I thought that there was nuclear waste
scattered all around the country
and that it was seeping into
our water systems.
I believed all that stuff and I... and I thought,
even if maybe it was getting a little bit better,
or maybe if the problems with it
were exaggerated,
a little bit by my
fellow environmentalists,
that it was still a risk
that we didn't need to take.
There hasn't been a single death
from the operation of commercial
nuclear reactors in the United States.
Not one death in the history
of nuclear power in this country.
At Vermont Yankee, which anti-nuclear
people are trying to shut down,
protesters keep saying,
it's causing public health problems.
- It's not.
- But it's leaking tritium.
It's leaking tritium, that's true.
- Banana break?
- Oh, I'd love one.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- If you ate one banana...
- Banana Breaks?
which have a potassium isotope
that's a little hot,
you would get more radiation exposure
than you would if you drank all the water
that comes out of the plant in one day.
Banana Break!
Tritium is a naturally
occurring hydrogen isotope.
I'm going to ask that all those people
who are willing to risk arrest
remain in this safety zone,
until the rest of the people have moved...
Vermont, 2012
In New Mexico, where I grew up,
there's Radium Springs.
And, um, I had a friend who went
with his Geiger counter,
and these hippies were there
soaking in the baths
and he got out his Geiger counter and said,
"You know, this is radioactive."
and they said,
"Yeah man, but it's natural."
It is true to say that we are
all bathed in natural radioactivity.
It's affecting all of us all the time.
It comes from the rocks and the air,
and even from space.
It's in our food and our water
and in our teeth.
So, radiation isn't dangerous
in an everyday sense.
And there's enormous variation in
different parts of the world.
Do you have any numbers
just to put that in a kind of a context?
Well the numbers, I mean the units are difficult:
it's grays and millirems and all this kind of thing...
Right.
You know, so the numbers are not familiar
to people in any way, shape, or form.
If I say to you: "The radioactivity:
Oh, it's only another 4 microsieverts."
Are you going to feel better about that? Of course you're
not, because you don't know what on Earth I'm talking about.
Iodine 131.
They were reporting those radiation levels, and
it was as confusing as they could possibly be.
...has just about zero point seven rem...
You have to get up to 50 to 75 rem
to get to...
We hear about rems,
and millirems and microrems
and then, oh now there's sieverts.
We hear a lot about sieverts,
microsieverts, millisieverts.
And you're looking and squinting,
and okay, that looks like large numbers.
Is that a number I should worry about?
And compared to what?
What's the background radiation level
relative to all this?
LOS ANGELES
0.09 microsieverts per hour
LONDON
0.10 microsieverts per hour
I didn't even know that there was such a thing
as natural background radiation, actually.
I had assumed that radiation was
something which humans
had artificially introduced into the environment;
which was doing us harm.
NEW YORK
0.13 microsieverts per hour
There's background radioactivity
affecting all of us, all the time,
which is many many times
more powerful than artificial radioactivity
in terms of how we are affected.
TOKYO
0.14 microsieverts per hour
So, zero tolerance of radiation
doesn't make any sense.
Radiation increases with altitude.
NEW HAMPSHIRE
0.30 microsieverts per hour
People who live at a higher altitude
get a higher dose
than people who live in low-lying areas.
ON THE PACIFIC OCEAN
2.20 microsieverts per hour
And, if you are travelling on an aeroplane,
say, you're going from New York to Tokyo,
you will get 20 times the average
background level during that flight.
For example,
in Guarapari Beach, in Brazil,
the natural background radiation is
way above permitted levels
in terms of what the
public can be exposed to.
GUARAPARI BRAZIL
30.81 microsieverts per hour
And that's what is coming out of
the soil that's on the beach.
Can you ask him why he does this?
Eh, he has, ah, body pains, you know?
And this helps?
Ele ajuda. Ajuda. Ajuda.
It helps.
And, what's really striking,
is that there is no correlation
between background levels of radioactivity
which vary by such enormous amounts
and high levels of cancer.
Cancer is something which is the greatest
fear of most people in rich countries.
And, because it kills 20%
of people anyway.
We all know people who've died of cancer...
and so this idea that radioactivity
is a cause of cancer
is probably the number one reason
why people are scared of it.
EXCLUSION ZONE
Chernobyl, Ukraine
You can't go to Chernobyl
and not re-examine your core beliefs
about nuclear power.
I mean, you would have to be
really thick-headed.
Not... not to look at that
and the damage that was done and say:
"Alright, when it goes wrong...
"you know that we do everything we can
to make it go right,
"but when it goes wrong:
it can go really very wrong indeed."
Chernobyl was a...
a real-world experiment
of what happens when you irradiate
a very large population.
But, 1986 was a long time ago.
So, we've gotten the perspective
and the distance
to be able to assess
what the real impacts of that were.
And they were nothing,
nothing like what was expected.
CHERNOBYL
0.92 microsieverts per hour
You will soon feel...
The reactor that exploded in Chernobyl
in April, 1986,
was actually number 4, reactor number 4
of a whole set of them.
No one really realizes it,
the 3 other units
which are in the same building,
carried-on operating and generating
electricity, right up until the mid-'90s.
CHERNOBYL REACTOR Unit One
And people just
went to work there every day.
Isn't that amazing?
Outside of the old Soviet Union,
we didn't use the reactor design
that Chernobyl had.
Among other things, the Chernobyl reactor
had no containment building.
It was in, virtually a quonset hut.
So, when there was a fire and an explosion,
there was nothing to contain it.
Chernobyl was a different kind of reactor.
It was inherently unsafe.
It was primarily designed to make
plutonium for bombs.
No Chernobyl-style reactors were
ever built in the West.
But, if you could then point to
other nuclear power stations and say:
"Each of those could be a Chernobyl..."
then, you've got a pretty powerful argument
against nuclear power.
The city nearby, called Pripyat,
the entire place was evacuated
when Chernobyl blew up.
It's just fascinating to see
some place which is frozen in time
at the very end of the era
of the Soviet Union.
It's an extraordinary place.
I really can't even describe it.
It's a bit like the Fukushima thing,
in the sense that
you're tramping around on this, debris
of broken glass and broken everything;
and it's almost as if the explosion
at Chernobyl had somehow caused this.
Of course it didn't, it's just the decay
of time and things have been broken.
Obviously, what people are concerned about
at Chernobyl is the radioactivity.
I never knew, until I went to Chernobyl,
that there were places full of people
that just decided to
ignore the restrictions
and they just moved back to their houses.
And, you can go to this old
church and you can meet them.
PRIPYAT, UKRAINE
0.20 microsieverts per hour
Just ask him when and why did
he decide to come back
and um, how many... how many people
came with him?
This is our Chernobyl.
It is where we have always lived.
Nobody wanted to leave here.
By the spring of 1987,
people were already beginning to return.
Of course, nobody let us come back,
we just came through the woods on our own.
People returned to their homes a few at a
time. They just came back and re-settled.
I have lived here in
Chernobyl for 25 years.
And I'm perfectly healthy.
Among those who have returned,
no one has died of cancer
or any other disease.
OUTSIDE CHERNOBYL REACTOR BUILDING
3.74 microsieverts per hour
The explosion of the reactor at Chernobyl
had enormous consequences.
But not the ones, I think,
many people expect.
I've followed the studies that have been
done by the international experts
in radiation and oncology
that followed the damage at Chernobyl
for all the years since.
The damage that was
caused to people by the fallout
from that worst-of-all
nuclear power accidents
has been remarkably limited.
You can look at the evidence,
it's all been published.
It's been certified by the United Nations
and the World Health Organization.
What's so striking is just to go read the
original World Health Organization documents
then read the public health reports.
- Was that a shock to you?
- It was a complete shock to me.
I mean I... there was a period when I'm
reading all the Chernobyl stuff,
and I... I, I kind of am not believing it.
Because, it was so out of sync
with what I had come to believe.
Literally hundreds of thousands of people
were involved in the clear-off operation.
They're known as liquidators. And they got
some really significant doses of radiation.
Their doses are known and their
health has been studied ever since.
And even in that large number of people
who were very heavily irradiated
40 or 50 people have died so far
and a few thousand may have shortened life
spans due to cancer in future decades.
And there have never been any children
born deformed from Chernobyl,
according to the best authoritative science
we've got from the United Nations.
So, people have substantially been fed
an urban myth, really, about what the impacts
of Chernobyl actually were.
I mean I've got books full of it.
A million people dying right now, or
have died because of Chernobyl
and it was only 25 years ago.
How many millions more
will Chernobyl kill?
40% of the European landmass
is radioactive.
It will be for hundreds of years...
In order to believe that more than
56 people were killed at Chernobyl,
or more than the maybe 4,000 who would
eventually die of cancer;
in order to believe that a million people
were killed by Chernobyl
which is what Greenpeace and Helen Caldicott
and a number of other people claim,
you have to believe there was a cover-up
of just massive proportions
by the World Health Organization,
by the United Nations,
by literally hundreds of the world's
top public health experts.
It's so absurd of an idea.
And it is exactly the same thing
global warming deniers think.
Helen, what do you think is
the motivation for the United Nations,
to perpetuate
such an appalling cover-up?
I don't know,
I'm not... privy to their motivations.
But the difference between 50 people
and a million people is so extreme.
I think people are confused
about what to think.
Well, they should
look at the literature.
This is the most important study, almost,
that's ever been done.
How do you explain it?
This is the biggest cover-up in
the history of medicine.
Many of the tactics and the arguments
that have been used by the environmental
groups against nuclear power
are exactly the same tactics and arguments
that are used by climate sceptics.
The United Nations,
that's where all of this started.
Senator James Inhofe R-Oklahoma
It was the IPCC in the United Nations, said
that the world was going to come to an end
because of the emissions of CO2.
So, the cherry-picking of scientific data,
the nurturing of... of scientists
who happen to believe
your ideological position
and the production of reports which
apparently are authoritative and scientific
but actually are
ideological propaganda, basically
41% of the people believe that
global warming claims are exaggerated
Climate change deniers are idiots.
- But they're saying the same thing.
- I don't care about them.
They, they are denying science.
- We're going back into the Dark Ages.
- But they're saying the same thing.
How dare...
how dare they deny science?
Not to understand science
and medicine in this day and age
is more than irresponsible.
- How do you square these two conflicts?
- I can't.
You know, we think of Japan,
we think of Hiroshima, those pictures,
horrible after the event that happened...
No radiation is safe.
But, generally speaking, Americans don't
have anything to worry about.
We have this map here, and we're showing
obviously, the path of 5,000 miles.
First to the Aleution Islands,
this is where they expect...
You can't reassure people. People are
so terrified that anything you say,
because they don't
have that background context,
that understanding of what radiation is
and what it means,
they can't actually
decide for themselves what's safe
and what risk they want to bear.
REFUGEE HOUSING
Fukushima Prefecture
And I think that's one of
the real problems at Fukushima.
There's no way for the experts
to actually communicate what s safe
to the general public.
FUKUSHIMA HOUSING
0.18 microsieverts per hour
I don't let my children play outside
for very long.
At most, one or two hours, not more.
If you are exposed to the
fallout from Fukushima
and according to the World Health
Organization and the U.N. generally,
the increased risk of getting cancer
is estimated to be
so infinitesimally small,
given the large population,
that you will never be able
to identify this impact epidemiologically.
I just won the bet.
This particular weed here is more
radioactive than Guarapari Beach in Brazil.
So we got, what did we get, 44?
Now we've seen what
the worst is that can happen
with a 1960's era Western design reactor,
which does have a containment
structure, which Chernobyl didn't.
But, this isn't something you can
just brush away.
This was not supposed to happen
to a reactor.
IDAHO, U.S.A.
Back in the '80s, it was clear to me
that something had to be done.
Something better than
present day,
about safety.
And, it wasn't only in safety.
It was in matters
of waste as well
and in proliferation matters.
And over all of those things,
the matter of economics.
You can't make the plant impossibly
expensive by making it too complicated.
Go ahead and go up to the
main parking lot there, Mac.
All right, thanks very much.
So, in 1980, I was given the job of
directing the entire program
of advanced reactor development
at Argonne National Laboratory.
Our goal was to design a
new type of reactor.
Where the very physics of it
would be such
that it could withstand
almost any type of accident
that nuclear plants can be subject to.
EBR-II
CENTRAL REACTOR
It was called the IFR.
The Integral Fast Reactor.
The budget was about $100 million a year.
1,500 people,
scientists, engineers, supporting staff.
This was a very big development program.
But you've got to test it.
Calculations don't tell you everything.
You've got to have the big facilities
and say:
"If we have an accident of this kind,
what will happen?"
We're now going to set-up the test...
April, 1986
We did two experiments to demonstrate
some unique safety features
that that reactor has, that
others don't have,
and invited people from all over the world
to come and witness it;
T minus 2 minutes.
Station black-out is a term
that is used by N.R.C., the safety folks,
to describe the situation where one
loses all bulk AC power.
You assume that you lose all site power.
You assume that you are getting no AC power
from your own turbogenerator.
You assume that your first diesel
started up and it failed to start up.
The second one started to start
and it also failed.
So, you end up dead in the water
with no AC power.
This experiment was almost
a direct parallel
to what happened at Fukushima.
- It was eerily similar.
- Mark.
We ran the reactor at full power,
disabled the shut-down system
so that the operators had
no ability to shut the reactor down.
And we shut-off the cooling system,
didn't extract the heat,
so we just let things get hotter.
In most reactors,
you can't do it.
No reactor that I know of, could
survive that accident.
You have a melt-down.
The international audience were
watching the temperature
going up like that, straight up.
They turned around like so,
to see if I was,
or if the Argonne guys were running.
By the time they looked up again,
the trace had turned
like so, and it was on its way down,
and the reactor just quietly shut
itself down.
No action required of the operators,
no action required of the safety systems,
nothing.
You could just stand back like this,
watched the dials if you wished,
and the reactor shut itself down.
- 30 seconds.
- 30 seconds to test time.
Well, in the afternoon
we started the reactor up again,
and carried out the conditions
responsible for the accident
at Three Mile Island.
5, 4...
We shut off the pumps.
Just shut off the pumps.
All major reactor accidents
CHERNOBYL
happen because of one thing:
inadequate cooling.
The IFR type reactor,
which EBR-II was a prototype for,
if you cut it off from the steam systems
so it cannot reject its heat,
it will just shut itself down.
So it can't melt down?
No, it can't melt down.
REPROCESSING FACILITY
Idaho National Laboratory
We are now in the facility that completes
the circle, if you like,
of the Integral Fast Reactor.
We've come out of the reactor building,
we're now in the fuel-cycle part.
The intimate part of it was
that every part of a
complete nuclear reactor system,
not the reactor itself, but also
the facilities for treating the spent fuel,
for treating the waste,
would all be an integral part
of the same system.
Ready for the transfer.
Bring it over to me...
What this enables you to do is
you can take the spent fuel
chop it up,
and back it goes into the reactor.
You can recycle the fuel again and again
until the end of plant life.
Ready to receive fuel.
The other thing that needs to be said
about all of this technology
is that this is not... a dream.
This is not somebody's calculations
on a piece of paper.
This is real. We know how
to do these things.
Now, let me frame this debate, if I may,
by reading a letter from
the President of the United States,
sent to me yesterday.
"Thank you for your letter
"supporting our decision to terminate the
Department of Energy's
"Advanced Liquid Metal Reactor
program
"including the Integral Fast Reactor.
"I want to assure you that
this administration
"does not support the IFR
"and will oppose any efforts to continue
the funding for this reactor project..."
Democrats have gotten themselves
on the wrong side,
in my opinion, in this issue.
Being opposed to nuclear power,
for, I think, no good reason
other than it's very high on the list
of what Republicans like.
We know
that nuclear energy is clean.
We know that it
doesn't pollute the air.
We know that
it doesn't damage the ozone.
We know that it is a tremendous producer
of energy in a clean sense
and our only problem is that
we can not come to political terms
on how to handle the waste stream.
We're talking about what it's gonna cost.
If we go that far and continue
our obsession with nuclear power.
IFR waste streams
lose their radioactivity to background
level in about 800 years.
Light water reactor,
in nearly 10,000.
I share with my colleagues
some of the public opinion on this.
The Washington Post:
"The Wrong Reactor."
The Oregonian:
"Give Up Nuclear Breeder Dream."
The San Francisco Chronicle:
"Saying No to Nuclear Pork."
The IFR program was shut down.
And the project went down the black hole
of Government politics.
It was by chance,
about the year 2000, I think,
I wound up in the desert,
on a visit to Yucca Mountain.
America's planned nuclear waste
repository
100 miles north of Las Vegas.
A hole in the ground
where 10-plus billion dollars were spent
on vastly expensive experiments.
Trying to prove that this place is
going to be absolutely safe
over the next 10,000 years.
So, I just felt like, wait a minute!
This is nuts!
Among other things,
have you even thought:
No, we are professional futurists,
many of us who are on this trip,
what exactly is this world 10,000 years
from now that we are trying to protect?
Science Fiction
is what we are playing out,
at vast expense, at Yucca Mountain.
The kinds of experiments they were
doing at that mountain,
it's not a mountain, it's just a ridge,
certainly didn't persuade anybody.
For political reasons,
Yucca Mountain was not opened,
and will probably never be opened.
Then, I started to look at,
well, what actually is
the amount of hazard that comes
from nuclear waste?
The first thing I found out is what people
are actually doing with the nuclear waste
which is being generated
all this time
by every nuclear power plant.
Turns out to be pretty good.
They put it in this, pretty simple,
but very workable dry-cask storage.
And they park it out at
the back of the parking lot.
And you can go there and see it.
There's the nation's nuclear waste.
Is it causing any problems?
No.
OUTSIDE WASTE CANISTER
0.10 microsieverts per hour.
The other realization for me,
and it took a while to get through,
is that by not putting it in the ground,
you've got the option to use it as fuel
in 4th generation reactors.
Wow! We can take this waste
from the nuclear plant
and recycle it into fuel
either by reprocessing, or by having a
new kind of reactor that uses this fuel.
That looks very much like
a renewable resource.
People are always talking
about nuclear waste,
the accumulation of nuclear waste,
and I did too.
I think it's around 70,000 tons
have accumulated, of
used fuel in the United States.
I thought the quantity was staggering.
In fact, all the spent
nuclear fuel
from commercial nuclear plants
in the United States
could fit in a single football field,
if you stacked the fuel rods to
a height of about 3 meters.
That's it.
But of that,
only a very small fraction,
mainly plutonium, is long-lived.
By long-lived, I mean that it would
still be "hot" thousands of years from now,
still be highly radioactive.
Volumetrically, nuclear produces
tiny amounts of waste.
The entire waste production from
France's 50 nuclear power stations,
which produce 80% of the
country's electricity
are under the floor in one room.
Compare that with the
billions of tons of waste
produced by coal-fired
power stations.
It completely blows away
most of the anti-nuclear arguments.
So it's... it's not...
Nuclear waste is not
an environmental issue.
It's not something which, as an
environmentalist, I'm concerned about.
One of the most inspiring stories anywhere,
is the story of France.
Here was a country, in the early '70s
that was burning oil for electricity.
It doesn't have coal reserves,
it doesn't want to be dependent on gas
coming from Northern Europe and Russia.
But, when the oil shocks happened and
the prices went up dramatically,
the French realized that
they needed to get serious
about a different source of energy.
They said this was serious
and it has to do with national security.
So, they focused on making sure
they had the best nuclear engineers
and the standard design for the reactors,
and they just rolled it out.
What's so significant
about what the French did,
is that they did it so quickly.
They scaled up almost exactly
at the pace
that we need to scale up
nuclear power globally.
They now have 80% of their electricity
coming from nuclear.
The trains are electric powered.
They have clean air.
They have the cheapest energy in Europe.
They're selling it to everybody else.
And they are greener than
Green Denmark,
greener than Green Germany.
I didn't know what French per capita
carbon dioxide emissions were,
which is actually the most important
question to ask.
The answer is they are about 5 tons
per person per year.
Germany is about 10 tons per year.
So, Germany has much, much higher per
person emissions of carbon dioxide
than neighbouring France because
France is nuclear
and Germany is trying to
get out of nuclear.
When we look at nuclear
we have to understand that
we are making a long-term investment.
Now, it's a big up-front
capital cost.
But these are plants that are going to last
60, 80, maybe even 100 years.
And much of the other infrastructure that's
being built will last far longer than that.
And, when you really look at it that way,
there's just really no question,
it's a much more economical alternative
to very expensive solar panels,
or very expensive wind turbines
that require back-up power.
The current generation of reactors
we're building now,
are third generation reactors.
This technology is much safer.
But fourth generation reactors,
like the Integral Fast Reactors
can use the waste from the first
three generations as fuel.
The great philanthropist, Bill Gates
has put money and time into
a Travelling Wave Reactor,
that you basically stick in the ground
and it goes through its body of fuel
over a period of 60 years.
You don't need to refuel it.
There's a thorium reactor
that the same group is working on.
Other fourth generation,
coming along with a small modular reactor.
They look exactly like the kind of
local power source
that environmentalists are increasingly
saying we should have.
So, there's a renaissance
in reactor design,
that those are just the
first glimpses of.
For some people, who perhaps
accept most of these arguments,
in favour of nuclear power,
the ultimate argument is:
"But knowledge of this technology
"is also the kind of knowledge you
can use to make nuclear weapons."
And that's quite true. It is.
There are, by the CIA's estimate,
about 37 countries in the world today,
that if they wanted to,
could develop nuclear weapons.
They have the technical and scientific
infrastructure to be able to do that.
How many countries
actually have nuclear weapons?
Nine.
Which, I think, begins to point out
the fundamental flaw in the concern.
We won't get rid of nuclear weapons
by forgetting how to make them.
We will get rid of nuclear weapons
by deciding we don't want
them around anymore.
It turns out that the United States
has been buying up nuclear warheads
from the Russians
for over 10 years now.
16,000 nuclear warheads.
And we're recycling all of these
nuclear warheads
into energy,
electricity, nuclear power.
And so, nuclear power is doing more
to de-nuclear-weaponise the world
than any other thing we do.
Poetically, it's rather beautiful.
The very things that were designed
to blow up our cities
are now lighting up our cities.
And, basically, 10% of
American electricity,
half of our nuclear power
comes from reprocessed
Russian warheads.
Ideally, every single nuclear
weapon in the world
eventually, can get turned
into electricity.
I believe that while much
of the environmental movement
that came of age in the '60s
will never change,
I feel very confident
that the next generation will.
They're going to understand the challenges
they face in an energy hungry world.
And, they're going to put nuclear
in its proper context.
We can have a world
of 7, 8, 9, 10 billion people
that are living high-energy,
resource intensive modern lives,
without killing the climate.
And that's exciting.
I have the sense that this is the
beginning of something really beautiful.
You actually do feel like
this is the beginning of a movement.