We're ready, boss.
You can go.
Move, let's move the cars.
Let's go.
Let's go!
- Mum?
-Hello!
- Can you hear me?
-Is it you, my son?
- Yes, it's me!
-I can't hear you.
- Now you hear me?
-Yes, yes! Now it's better.
I want to pray with you.
You do the introduction.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Tomorrow I'll go to jail
and I'm scared
you'll abandon me, my Lord.
And that you might not understand
my actions.
I just want to remind you
that everything I do,
I do out of love of my family,
to protect them
from all evil and danger.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now, and in the hour of our death.
Amen.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now, and in the hour of our death.
Amen.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now, and in the hour of our death.
Amen.
- Good evening.
-Good evening, Pablo.
We are all family, right?
Have a seat.
Nico, sit over there.
Well...
I've made a deal with the Government.
Tomorrow,
I'll surrender to the authorities.
I'll be in jail... for a while.
Till things get quiet again.
I've called you all in person
because I need the help...
of the people I trust the most.
Our job is to hide our economic power
from our enemies.
And this treasure is the life
and the future
of our families and children.
And we'll be the only ones to know
where it's hidden.
So...
the question is:
are you ready to help me?
- I am, Pablo.
-We're family.
- Till death, patron.
-Whatever may come.
And you, Nico?
Me too.
Very good.
Reach hands.
One, two, three! Let's do!
Lights!
Heavy metal, the workers can come out.
Come on, people!
Pepito,
you're gonna be in the first car.
Alfonso,
you're gonna be in the second car.
Nico, the third one.
Ricardo, in the fourth.
Felipe, you're in the fifth.
And Juan, in the sixth.
Group One,
load the trucks as fast as possible.
- Take these. Water too.
-Thank you
Boy, take care.
May God be with you.
I see you've got two sandwiches.
Yes.
And you will say setenta y dos.
Setenta y dos...
Good luck.
- That's for all:
-20,000 pesos for transport.
In this car.
Guys, when I will tell you,
pull at the same time.
The truck don't go.
Good, Ricardo.
Eso. That's good.
Go with him.
Let it down!
Take that shit down.
Wake up! Get up!
- Get up, get up, get up! Everybody up!
-Get up.
Wake up! Wake up!
Come here.
Nothing's gonna happen to you.
You think you can come to my woods
and do as you like, or what?
They told me
that this doesn't belong to anyone.
What?
This place is mine.
Everything around here is mine.
If you want to do something here...
Business...
Come to the village.
Ask for the Rolando brothers.
Everyone knows who we are.
All right.
Move forward, sissy!
Let's move.
Thank you.
Special greeting
for the young people of this town.
I'm thankful
to all the people
who have helped
renovating this clinic.
This hospital...
This hospital
is but one small step
towards the life you deserve.
I'm proud
of my humble origins.
My family never had great means.
And we experienced
the same problems most Colombian
families are faced with daily.
I promise you...
I promise you
that if I can do anything
I'll keep fighting for your rights.
Civismo en marcha
will provide you with a shield
that will protect you from all evil.
Thank you very much!
People from Turbo,
once more let's thank
Pablo Escobar Gaviria.
Come on!
Why didn't you come over?
This jacket... with these pants.
- If it fits big, I'll fix it.
-Thank you.
Can I help you, Sir?
No, you can't.
Gringo,
get out.
Come here.
Stop it! Please stop it,
it's going to kill him!
Stop it, it's going to kill him!
- Hi!
-What's up, bonita?
Juanita! Your dress is beautiful!
This is Nick.
Nice meeting you.
Maria's spoken so much about you.
So nice to see you!
- You're so elegant!
-How are you?
Now I need your attention.
This is my boyfriend Nick.
See you later.
Aunt!
- Aunt!
-I was looking for you.
- This is Nick.
-Nice meeting you. You've had lunch?
- Yes. Where is Pablo?
-Over here, in the water.
Can we go say hi?
I'll ask him. I'll be right back.
Pablo, go get dressed.
Maria wants to introduce
her boyfriend to you.
Come over, Maria love, come!
- Hi Maria!
-Hi prince, how are you?
OK.
- Did you have a good flight?
-Very good.
- Happy birthday, uncle Pablo!
-Thank you.
At last, Pablo, this is Nick.
- Hi. Welcome, Nick.
-Thank you.
- Does he speak Colombian?
-No. No, English.
Maria, show him around the house
and introduce him to Grandma.
- Go, go see Grandma.
-We're going to now, Pablo.
We are so proud that Maria
opened up a clinic for the poor.
She's adorable.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday to you,
Hey to Pablo!
A Speech!
In the sky
fly the clouds
going toward the sea.
God, how I love you.
I cannot...
embrace...
so much happiness,
True love.
- Good night.
-Good night.
Light, camera, action!
Now a big round of applause
to the new member
of the Escobar Gaviria family.
Come on.
- Good morning, Carmen.
-Good morning, Nick.
- Daniela.
Nico, come!
He's dead, Luis.
Luis, get ready!
What are you doing? It's sunday.
Nick,
there's no one there to help you!
Watch out!
- Who's that?
-Nick. Maria's boyfriend.
Finish it off.
At last we meet, Nick.
It's a pleasure.
I know Maria
since she was a little kid.
Bambi, get me the boss.
We have a problem.
No fear, Nico, no fear.
Feind hiort mit.
Please be careful with those frames,
put them here.
It's the biggest corruption scandal
in the history of Congress.
Senator Pablo Escobar has been found
to have a criminal record
as a drug dealer.
This operation
is having significant results
so we need to have the national
public and armed forces support it.
This will give you
an idea of the magnitude
of the narco trafficking problem
we have in this country.
First, the Minister of Justice
lied when he said that...
Pablo Escobar had a criminal record
in the United States.
- Hello, Nick.
-Hello.
Hello, Nico.
- Are you done with the cash?
-lt's all done boss.
Let's go! Let's go, chiquitin!
The assassination of the Minister
of Justice, Rodrigo Lara Bonilia
has Colombia
on the verge of a civil war.
These are chilling words
from Pablo Escobar's last interview.
The Minister of Justice
lied to the country six times.
He said he wasn't going to resign.
Let's see what happens
in the next few days.
Everyone who opposes Pablo Escobar
is a potential target
of his assassins.
The epidemic of violence
is unprecedented.
Innocent people
are getting caught
in the crossfire.
American forces have now joined
the biggest manhunt
in Colombia's history
for the drug Lord.
Escobar,
confronting this new threat,
responds with
a brutal wave of terror.
The cartel will soon pay
for their crimes.
Escobar and his allies
are an enemy of the state.
Dad!
Boys, try these delicious beans
that Maria made for patron.
It's Ramirez.
Dursi, how are you?
All set.
Boys, we have to get going.
I'll call you later.
This son of a bitch.
It's because
they're hitting like goats.
Camillo,
can you come help me with this?
Sure.
Nick, we forgot the salt.
You want melons?
- Take some.
-No, thank you.
Two for 80 pesos.
Take them, they're delicious.
Take them.
Take them, take them. Take them.
Take them. They're delicious.
No, no, no, thank you.
Ok then.
Melons!
Let's go! Come on! Start the car.
Start the car, brother.
What are you waiting for?
I'm Martin.
He can't come. I'm Martin.
Don't look. Don't look!
Don't move, understand?
It's not working.
This phone never worked.
If you have another one,
it's very important.
Follow me. It's here.
- This way.
-Thank you.
Everything okay?
The number is 72.
We have to go this way. 72. That's it.
Let's go.
If I had been driving, we would have
been here like an hour ago.
But you're driving
like you're scared or something.
Well whatever, there's your cave.
But I know these mountains
like the back of my hand
and you're driving like one or two
kilometers per hour, you feel me?
Hey, here it is, 72.
It's nicely done.
Brother, it's almost time to eat.
Es que hay hungry.
Mi wife prepare very good food.
Yes, of course.
Of course, brother.
This is my wife, Estrella.
And my son, Martin Junior.
They're heavy, no?
All right.
I'm going to set the dynamite
and the cable.
Come on, let's go.
Why?
This... is a lot of money.
A lot of money for you
and your family.
I knew it, brother.
There's treasure in those boxes, huh?
How am I supposed to forget this?
This is a treasure.
Why do you want me to leave ltuango?
I don't want to leave ltuango.
No, I can't leave here.
I can't leave ltuango.
Thanks, but there's no way.
Keep them.
Thank you.
With this,
I'll buy my son
some really nice clothes.
And for my wife,
I'm going to buy her a huge bed.
So she'll feel like a princess.
Thank you.
You sure?
Alright.
Finally I'm going to drive.
With this,
I'll even get myself a gift.
Maybe even buy myself a car one day.
Left.
Let's
Right.
- Where is your house?
-This is my house.
- Do you have a phone?
-No, but there's one in the hotel.
Yeah, I found him on the street
and you know
how his wife is really sick.
Yeah, his wife is real sick
and he's real sad.
Yes.
- Yes, please.
-Well then, I'll call you later.
You can use the phone.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Martin de la Pena Vasquez.
At last we meet. A pleasure.
Where's the gringo?
If you tell me, I'll let you live.
So you can give your family
a decent funeral.
If you don't, I'll kill you.
"They decided to take Mowgli
to the men immediately.
From here on out,
you'll take care of yourself.
As Mowgli got up
and left the jungle..."
Hello. Who's there?
"When Mowgli stopped to rest,
a happy bear wandered over,
named Baloo.
Baloo figured that the elephant
-had much to learn..."
-Excuse me, patron.
There's a little problem
with the Canadian.
He never made it to the restaurant.
Darling, you know who's calling?
Nick, Maria's boyfriend.
Do you want to talk to him?
Ask him where he is. And tell him
we thought we lost him in the jungle,
like Mowgli.
where are you? You got lost
in the jungle lost like Mowgli?
No. I'm not lost.
Can I speak with your dad, please?
We're drawing
the animal from the hacienda
And I'm going to draw you too.
What's up, Nico? Everything good?
Yes.
The man is not coming
to the restaurant.
He's somewhere outside.
Cap y, Drago.
Get out of there and come over here.
- Please, help me.
-The way out is back there.
- Open.
-The exit is back there.
Where the hell are you going?
There's no exit over there.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
- Have you seen the gringo?
-Yes.
- How long ago?
-He left this way a minute ago.
Sit down and don't move.
The man is nearby.
Go check the houses over there.
Allo? Patron.
He escaped
when I was about to catch him.
I'm going to ask the police for help.
Don't worry, patron. Trust us.
He's not going to escape us.
Don't worry.
I've already checked the car.
Go check the hotel,
the houses on the block.
Get going!
Captain, this is Drago Gutierrez.
I need a few men here
to close a perimeter around ltuango.
Send quite a few men. To return
the favor to the boss, is that clear?
We're looking for a gringo!
He's dangerous!
This gringo is an enemy
of Pablo Escobar!
Don't hide him!
Don't help the gringo!
If he gets into your house,
get him out.
This gringo is an enemy
of Pablo Escobar!
Come on, let's go!
Good afternoon, captain.
He's hiding out somewhere around here.
We'll look for him.
- We have to find him, and kill him.
-Ok, we'll kill him.
Look in that house over there.
Over here, and up there.
Hurry before he escapes.
You are the man of the family.
Your priority is to take care
of your mom
-and your little sister.
-Yes, sir.
For you, Papa-
Take care of yourself.
You know that we need you.
Don't worry, my love.
The hard part is over.
I'll be safe, don't worry.
You look nice in that.
I'll call you when I'm inside.
Please do.
Chiquitin. Come.
What is it, patron?
What happened to Bambi
when he crossed the street?
- He got run over.
-Affirmative.
Let's PW-
Go and get it.
Go, go.
Colombia News.
Greetings to our audience
from Colombia News.
The whole country is on hold.
The top drug trafficking capo
in Colombia
and boss of the dangerous
Medellin cartel,
Pablo Emilio Escobar Gaviria,
should surrender to the authorities
on a soccer field in Envigado
ending a war that has brought
the country to its knees.
A huge crowd have already gathered
here, calling out his name.
This confirms the controversy
about this criminal
who is loved and feared
in equal proportion.
Today is a great day for Colombia,
because Pablo Escobar
agreed to put an end
to this violence
which had spread
all over the country.
Don't move!
Don't kill me. Please, don't kill me.
Hurry up, hurry HP!
Attention.
We are looking for a white male
from the age of 25 to 30.
Suspect may be impersonating
a police officer.
Suspect is wanted in connection
with the slaying of a family
of five in ltuango,
including a five month old baby.
He is armed and very dangerous.
To all units in the ltuago area:
The subject has a police officer
as hostage.
Today is a very important day
for Colombia.
Pablo Escobar has turned himself
in to the demand of Justice
in a deal that will end the violence
that has gripped the country.
The authorities
who will escort him to prison
will rendezvous with Escobar
at the Evigado soccer field,
where thousands of his supporters
are waiting for his arrival...
Make sure everyone
gets a little bit of money.
Come on.
Make sure everyone
gets a little bit of money.
Why?
- Tell me, patron.
-Get Maria out of here.
- Why?
-Get her out here.
Where is she? I don't see her.
Drago, what happened with Nico?
Pablo, it's time to go.
You made a deal, Pablo.
You have to go.
Did you want the blessing?
Affirmative.
May the strength of God Almighty
and the Holy Spirit guide you
in the decision you made.
I will ask the Lord
to keep an eye on you.
When you talk to God,
the Almighty,
remind Him how much I do
for His church...
and for the poor of Medellin.
And tell Him
that today I saw my family
for the first time
after months of solitude and distress.
And I probably won't see them
for a long time.
He seems a bit distracted lately.
You tell Him, Father,
that I'll have a powerful telescope...
pointed to the sky.
And from time to time,
when I'll remember His existence,
I, Pablo Emilio Escobar Gaviria,
will keep my eye on Him.
Forgive me, Father.
And God bless you.
Help!
Help, please!
There is wounded man!