Nail Shop Paris
You decide...
who you're going to believe.
Me or him?
I... I...
I love you.
Run!
What did you do?
You didn't have to do that!
Do you still trust him?
What he said to you was all lies.
How do you know?
All of your friends that got killed and the
other Gumiho! What else do I need for proof?
Stop there.
If you come any closer, I'm going
to shoot your heart this time.
Do whatever you want.
If this heart couldn't earn the trust of
the woman I love
it doesn't even deserve to beat.
No!
The show is over now.
Wait.
Are you going to let Alex
get killed like that?
Wasn't he the main character?
He was.
Yeo Joo, did something
happen to you and Alex?
Did you really kiss him?
Did you really?
I don't know why I did that either.
I must be crazy.
How did he respond?
He must think I'm some kind of freak.
Yesterday...
I need to know how to do that for my
skill test but I'm not good at it yet.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I have to do something now.
Jin, if you aren't busy,
can you finish her nails?
I didn't know he would act like that.
He's such a coward.
In his position, he got kissed by a guy.
I'm just glad he didn't spread a rumor
that I'm gay and kick me out.
Don't bother.
At least you know how he feels about you.
Does your stomach hurt again?
Yeah. It's been hurting since yesterday.
Shouldn't you go see a doctor?
It's okay. I'll just take digestives
and go to sleep.
I'm going to bed.
- Hey, Beanie.
- Kay.
Can we talk?
Jin! Hi.
What is it?
What's this?
Now put this ring on my finger.
Kay...
There. Now nobody can get in the way
of our relationship. Okay?
I'm not going to let anybody
take you from me. Never.
- Kay...
- Hey...
What are you guys doing
so early in the morning?
What's this?
Is this a couple ring?
That guy is so anxious about you.
What are you talking about?
You had feelings for Alex so Kay gave you
this ring so you can't go anywhere.
So be good to him. I've never
seen Kay do something like that.
Let's go.
The boss wants to see all of us.
I gathered all of you because I want to tell
you that Alex will be on vacation for a week.
It might be hard for you
to cover Alex's work.
But please understand.
And Bunny, you should help out a lot.
Okay.
Then get back to work.
And Alex, I'll see you after a week.
What is it, Alex? Is everything okay?
No. I just want a break.
I'm sorry, guys.
Good luck on studying for the exam.
Bye, guys.
He's acting so weird.
- You're all set.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
- A vacation?
- Yeah.
All of a sudden without notice?
I think he's doing that because of me.
Because he doesn't even want to see me.
No way.
I must've been crazy.
Why did I do that to him?
Don't stress out so much. It might be good
for you, if he's not around.
Just focus on Kay.
I heard from Jin that Kay
really worries about you.
Okay.
I'll see you at home.
Bye.
You're a makeup artist, right?
Our makeup artist hasn't come in yet.
Can you put makeup on someone?
He just needs a touch-up.
- Sure.
- This way.
Come have a seat here.
- Are you here for a talk show?
- Yeah.
My adviser academic...
I mean my academic adviser was supposed to
do this but something urgent came up.
- You look so nervous.
- Yes. This is my first time.
Then try to sing a song.
It will make you less nervous.
Sing?
Should I dance too?
- Why?
- Nothing.
Don't you feel better now?
- I think so...
- Keep going.
How's your leg?
I'm doing remedial exercises.
The doctor said by fall, I might have
to walk on crutches but I can stand up.
- That's great.
- So you can stop coming here.
Come to think of it, it was my fault that
I asked you to treat me at the hospital.
But as a doctor, I was the
one who made the decision.
I think after that accident, not just me, but
you also lost something that meant a lot.
Like passion, spirit, ambition...
something like that.
Am I wrong?
Life is like fishing.
Unless you try to throw a fishing
rod to catch something
all the precious things will be missed.
Isn't that a waste?
- I have to go now.
- Oh, sure.
When we meet again,
I hope we're both a little different.
Jin won't be mad because only you and
I are having lunch together, right?
Who cares if that guy gets mad or not?
But still...
There's ice cream!
Can we buy some for Jin?
It's ridiculous. How did I think
that you were a guy?
What?
You're crazy! People might see us.
What's wrong with you?
Are you okay?
Did you get hurt?
I'm okay.
I'm sorry. If you start feeling sick or
something, please call this number.
Okay?
I'm sorry.
Come in.
Here it is.
What took you so long to
just run an errand?
Bring some tea.
Never mind. Tell Ms. Seo to bring the tea.
Yes, sir.
Why can't she bring the tea?
I don't want to see that ugly face
while drinking tea.
You're right about that.
You know how it is...
- Excuse me...
- What?
The boss wants you to bring
some tea for him.
Come on...
Can't you do it?
He told me to ask you to do it.
You are so useless.
Must be nice.
Nobody asks you to do
anything or comes on to you.
You're studying so hard.
Lasers might come out from your eyes.
The exam is coming up.
Let me see.
- This part is contorted a bit.
- That's...
If it's dried, its shape keeps changing.
Gel polish usually shrinks.
Try this.
The color comes out nicer
and it doesn't shrink. It'll work better.
I just gave you very important information.
Don't I get anything for that?
What?
What if somebody sees us?
Why do I love you hugging you so much?
Do you not like it?
Well... it's not that I don't like it...
What are you doing?
Put me down!
You hugged me like this too.
Beanie, did you gain weight?
You're heavy.
Go away. I'm gonna fail the exam like this.
You're so cold. Fine, I'll leave.
Don't get lost on your way home.
Wanna die?
Isn't this delicious?
I was so worried that you lost your appetite.
Let's fry some rice after this.
Yeah.
Here.
Ji Soo, should we get couple rings too?
What?
Come to think of it, there's nothing
that I bought for you while dating.
It's okay.
What the? What was that response?
Are you worried that I'll never let you go?
- No, it's not that.
- Then why don't you want couple rings?
I want get couple rings with
someone I like...
One second...
What happened?
I don't know. We were just having
some stir-fried chicken then suddenly...
Stir-fried chicken?
I won't be sure until she gets checked up.
But I think she has Crohn's disease.
Crohn's disease?
It means she has an infection
on her digestive organs.
Lately, a lot of people in their 20s
have gotten that disease.
She needs to stay at the
hospital and get treated.
Doctor Jo, help her go through
the admission process.
You're Mr. Nobody.
Don't you think so Bunny? That intern guy
looks like a player. Very suspicious.
You saw him touching Ji Soo's hand
when taking her pulse, right?
He's not a real doctor.
He's just an intern.
Bunny, say something.
You think he's suspicious too, right?
- Aren't you going to work?
- I'm going to but...
You went to the hospital this morning, right?
Did you see that guy again?
Jin, are you...
Do you have a delusional jealousy of her?
No, it's not that.
You told me the other day that Ji Soo
can't refuse guys who have a crush on her.
But you're over thinking.
You're being so petty.
Petty? Every guy is the same.
Hyun Bin, Rain, and Kang Dong Won...
You think they wouldn't be like this?
You said you like Ji Soo.
Then you should trust her.
You trust somebody because you love him?
That's cool.
But I'm still mad.
You can't do anything about being mad at your
girlfriend for being close to another guy.
Look at Kay.
Welcome, are you here for a manicure?
I would like him to do it.
Hi. We met on the street the other day.
Hello.
I'm sorry. I can't do it yet
because I'm still learning.
Instead, I can give you a hand massage.
And you can get the manicure from him.
He looks like a playboy but he's good.
You said your name is Woo Jeong Ah, right?
Your hands are so pretty.
Everybody said my hands are
ugly because it's so skinny.
That's not true. Maybe because you
don't take care of your hands.
But I can tell you're very
honest and have a soft heart.
You can tell all that from my hands?
Yes. This guy I know said hands can tell
you more than the mouth can.
Kim Ji Soo.
You came...
I'll see you later then.
What did you guys talk about?
Nothing.
I didn't tell you how I met him, did I?
A few days ago, he came to the
broadcasting station for a talk show.
But he looked so nervous.
So I told him to sing a song
to make him calm down.
And he stood up right away and
started singing and dancing.
You didn't ask why Jin didn't come here.
He worried about you all day.
Did Jin go somewhere?
He was asked to do some interview
for this pin-up boy nail artist show.
He told me to tell you how sorry he is.
Thank you.
Did the picture come out well? That was
my first time. I felt so awkward.
What do you mean? The picture came
out like something in a magazine.
I'm... pretty hot, huh?
It's kind of strange to hear
that a guy can be a nail artist.
But what's a good thing about
being a male nail artist?
How do you feel now?
Well...
I feel kind of nervous.
That's it!
You can feel stability and warmth through
touch while getting a manicure from a guy.
And you can also have a good feeling
of nervousness from the opposite sex.
It's like the icing on the cake.
The more I talk to you, the
more I think you're attractive.
- Do you have a girlfriend?
- Of course, I...
If I say I do, would girls not like me?
Well...
I'll leave that up to you.
What do you think?
Doesn't this picture look great?
I should've worn a brighter shirt.
Hey, what's that?
'He doesn't have a girlfriend.'
I said that for my fans, you know.
You don't deserve to complain
about that intern guy.
This is why she's...
What?
- Ji Soo's what?
- Never mind.
What is it?
Bunny, you know how sensitive
I am about that, right?
Is there something between
Ji Soo and that intern guy?
- No, I didn't say that.
- I knew it.
That damn guy.
That's it. I'm going to keep my eye on
Kim Ji Soo 24/7 from today.
- Excuse me.
- Hello.
I came here to get a hand
massage from Bunny again.
Can you do that?
Sure, I can.
Have a seat.
- You changed your hairstyle?
- You noticed?
Of course.
You look better with that hair.
That customer... I think she
has a crush on Bunny.
It must be so hard for you to
protect Bunny from guys and girls.
Oh my. Did you get a manicure?
It's pretty but it doesn't really suit you.
- Don't you think so?
- Just let her be.
I think she paid a lot for that.
Let's just go have lunch.
Yeo... Yeo Joo.
You can keep talking to him.
I'll be in your room.
Is there anything else you need?
No.
What about Jin?
Did he leave already?
No. He went out to buy something
that tastes better than rice porridge.
Yeo Joo, nothing happened between me and
Doctor Jeong. He just wanted to talk.
Do you...
- Do you like him?
- What? No!
Kim Ji Soo.
I've known you for years.
Well... I know it's hard to
control somebody's feelings.
But just don't be so harsh to him.
You know he's a nice guy.
Bye.
What happened to her? I thought she
would yell at me to straighten up.
- Jeong Ah.
- Bunny.
Did you get hurt?
No.
I got burned.
Let's go.
I'll walk you home.
It's okay. You don't have to do that.
It's okay. Jin told me that I
should be nice to you
since you became my regular even
though I'm not an official nail artist.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
Come in.
I can just go home.
You walked all the way here for me.
I should treat you to some tea.
No. Do you want to have
dinner with me here?
It's okay.
Please. Actually, it's so lonely
to have dinner by myself every day.
Okay, then.
- Thank you.
- Have a seat.
Do you like spaghetti?
Yes, I do.
Actually, I make delicious spaghetti.
Jin.
Aren't you tired?
You can't hang out with people
on the weekends because of me.
What are you talking about?
Staying with you is fun and relaxing.
- Do you want me to leave the hospital?
- Why?
Are you worried about something?
No, it's not that.
I'm kind of worried about the hospital bill.
And I'm not sick anymore.
- Are you really okay?
- Yeah.
Alright!
Honesty, I don't like that
Doctor Jeong or Jang or whatever.
The way he looks at you makes me so mad.
Anyway, you better not get sick again.
- Okay.
- What a darling.
- Do you like it?
- Yes. It's so good.
Excuse me.
Hello?
- Why aren't you calling me?
- Sorry. Something came up.
I told you to come when I called you.
Okay. I'm near the salon now.
I'll be there soon. Bye.
- I'm sorry.
- Was that your girlfriend?
Kind of like that.
Anyway, thank you for the food.
I have to go now.
Can you stay a little bit longer with me?
It's already late.
Please. I'm begging you. Can you stay
here with me for 10 minutes, no, 5 minutes?
Please?
Bunny.
Um...I think you're
misunderstanding something.
I am...
- What are you doing?
- You hate me because I'm ugly, don't you?
You hate me because I'm
fat and ugly, don't you?
What are you talking about, Jeong Ah?
This isn't right. I have to go.
Beanie.
Did you see a ghost or something?
What's with that look?
Nothing.
By the way, how did you know I was here?
I was going to go to the
salon but then I got lost.
You're so weird. How can you get
lost on the way to your work place?
I've never been in this neighborhood.
- Let's go.
- Wait.
Try this one.
What's the occasion?
You don't like to see me drinking.
It's okay if it's just you and me.
It'll be better if you get drunk.
You pervert.
What are you two doing here?
Jin is with his girlfriend
and Alex is on vacation now.
By the way, what happened to
him and the girl he likes?
- What?
- You didn't know?
Shoot.
It should be a secret but
I'll tell only you two.
There's this girl that Alex likes.
But another guy took her already.
Isn't the girl our boss?
No, no. She's mine.
Nobody can take her, you know.
But she and Alex seemed so
close so I asked her about it.
Me and Alex?
No. You know he studied
Oriental medicine, right?
I have severe anemia so
I get dizzy sometimes.
He helps me when I get sick. That's it.
He likes somebody else.
Are you okay?
Is your hand okay?
Follow me.
Hey, hey!
What's wrong with them? Did I say
something that I shouldn't have?
Let go.
What are you doing?
Why are you having feelings for Alex again?
Why do you keep going back and forth?
I didn't know how Alex felt about me.
I didn't know what his relationship
was with the boss.
I misunderstood him, my heart
fluttered, and I blamed him.
The guy in front of you is me.
Can't you just focus on me?
What's the use of these couple rings?
What are you doing here this late?
Who's the girl?
The girl that's taken which is why
you're in pain. Who is she?
It's late. Let's talk tomorrow.
Is the girl Bunny?
You probably won't say you didn't know.
There is nothing manly about Bunny.
You probably knew she wasn't a guy.
It doesn't make sense if you didn't know.
What are you going to do
if the girl is Bunny?
Let go, Kay.
How could you do this to me?
When you know full well
what she means to me.
- You know how much I care about her.
- What did I do wrong?
It's hard for me too, Kay.
So don't make things harder.
There's nothing for you to worry about.
To Bunny, I'm just a co-worker
who doesn't know she's a girl
and has feelings for another girl.
We'll leave it at that.
So don't worry.
What if I don't want that?
What you're saying is you're
backing down just because of me.
Since when did I become that pathetic?
Kay.
I don't want you to pity me.
And I don't want to be afraid of you.
That's not how I live my life.
So, if you don't want to make
me look so pathetic, be brave.
Let's fight and see who will win.
Are you  getting carried away by bravado or
are you just overconfident about this?
Whatever. It's Bunny that will
decide who she's going to choose.
- How are you, Bunny?
- What happened, Alex?
You said you were gonna take a week off.
- I guess not.
- I'm glad you came back sooner.
You can't take another vacation now.
Yes, ma'am.
I have a nail artist meeting to attend.
I'll be back later.
Get back to work, guys.
Ji Soo, are you leaving the hospital?
Yeah, I'm about to leave now.
Yeah.
I'm okay!
Can you give me Patient Kim
Ji Soo's number and address?
Kay, can we talk?
I'm sorry about last night.
I was so shocked and flustered.
I won't do it again.
You can keep it for now.
I don't want to keep this relationship vague.
Keep it for now.
And if you're ready to give all of your heart
to me and focus on me, then give it back.
Kay.
- Excuse me.
- We're not open yet. What's going on?
We're from the police station. Who is Bunny?
It's me.
What's going on?
Sexual harassment?
Wait, officer. There must be
some misunderstanding here.
There she is.
Woo Jeong Ah, is he the one you were
talking about? He keeps saying no.
That's him. He came to my house
and had dinner.
And after that he tried to take
off my clothes and grab me.
He ran away because I grabbed a
knife and made him go away.
This is a scar from getting cut yesterday.
What are you saying, Jeong Ah?
Why are you lying all of a sudden?
We can see if she's lying or
not by investigating you.
Do you admit to going to her house?
Yes, I did go there but...
Take him.
Wait.
This is not right.
- I didn't do that.
- Wait, officer.
There's something off here.
Woo Jeong Ah, so you're saying
Bunny was trying to rape you, right?
How can you be so sure?
Because he touched my body.
The you probably felt or touched
Bunny's body. Correct?
Wait, this is sexual harassment.
Then why do you still think
that Bunny is a guy?
This person is....
a girl.
Alex.
If you can't believe me, check her ID.
What's wrong with you?
This can't be right.
This isn't right.
I'm so sorry about that.
You can leave now.
Let's go.
I can't believe he fooled me.
I liked him so much.
Alex!
How can you lie to me? Apologize!
Let me go!
Can you give us a moment?
Jeong Ah...
Alex is okay.
He didn't get hurt that much.
Just in case you're worried.
- If you don't want to talk to me, then...
- I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to do all this.
Bunny, you're the first person to smile at me
and actually call my name with warmth.
But I thought even you hated me because I'm
fat and ugly. I just couldn't stand that thought.
I couldn't control myself.
Jeong Ah, the reason why I could make eye
contact with you and say your name warmly
is because you did the same to me.
Don't you get it?
I may not become your boyfriend
but I want to become your friend.
Can I?
Since when?
Since when did you know I'm a girl?
When Kay asked you out.
And when I realized you're more
than just a little brother to me.
Then why did you pretend
you didn't know anything?
Kay is as dear to me as you are.
I'm sorry for being so cranky to you.
I couldn't control my feelings around you.
Then...
Are you okay with that now?
If it's something I can't
suppress, then I'll let it free.
I like you, Bunny.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Boss, I'm quitting Paris.
Beanie.
What are you doing?
I said you can tell her how you
feel about her, not kick her out!
Kay, promise me one thing.
Whoever she chooses, let's
not hate or blame the other.
Bunny.
Kay.