Subtitles by DramaFever
Episode 5
Bunny.
How's Alex?
He's sleeping. The doctor said he should
stay in the hospital for a couple of days.
He let the disease grow.
By the way, isn't Kay with you?
I didn't see him.
Didn't you leave with him?
Kay.
The aura around you
is so depressingly gray.
It means there's something you're worrying about.
Am I right?
What?
Pick one.
Come on.
Fortune's wheel.
It means life altering, luck
or a fateful meeting.
Kay, did you get a girlfriend?
Shut up.
A fateful meeting?
I hate her so much.
She looks bad on the screen
because her skin is so bad.
Why does she take it out on me?
She's a chain smoker
and has a bad temper.
And she's foul-mouthed.
She swears a lot.
You shouldn't hear any swear words.
Your pretty ears will get dirty.
My eyes are about to get dirty.
What the heck is this?
You think I can even buy
gum with this money?
Don't play with me like this.
Prepare more money. Understand?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Excuse me, can I get a bill?
How can she smile like
that in this situation?
I see. I should go see Alex later.
- Jin, take care of Alex's customers too.
- Okay. Don't worry.
- Why isn't Kay here yet?
- He must be late.
Bunny, take this.
Nail class?
Alex asked me for that. You should go there
and take the class 3 times a week. Good luck.
- Okay.
- Get to work, guys.
Why?
Are you impressed by Alex?
No.
You got a new haircut, Kay.
Yeah.
You look good.
What's wrong with him?
Just ask me why Pororo wears stupid glasses.
Why does he wear that?
Because he wants to.
Excuse me, can I sit here?
Sure.
- What's wrong?
- No. Nothing.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Jeong Mi Ae.
I'm Hong...
Just call me Bunny.
Now, you're going to practice with
someone who's sitting next you.
I'll do it first.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Boss.
You brought a lot of stuff.
Comic books?
I thought he would be bored.
Bunny is better than me.
I'll leave you two alone.
I have to make a call.
Have a seat.
How's the class?
Do you like it?
Yeah.
Alex, do you remember Tae Hee?
You said you noticed Tae Hee got the blues
by seeing red lines on her nails or something.
Anyway, is that right?
Yeah. Why do you ask?
There's this girl that has
red lines on her nails.
But an interesting thing is that she doesn't
seem like a person with depression.
She always smiles like a robot.
Maybe she did become a robot.
What?
There are some people like her.
They have to smile everyday for
their job and it becomes a habit.
So even if they want to cry and be angry,
they just smile like a machine.
Bunny.
You're sharp.
Take care of her.
She might need some help.
Okay.
Don't worry.
You study so hard.
Are you not going to write
your novel anymore?
It's good to become a nail artist but think
about the people who are waiting for your novel.
Are you not meeting Jin tonight?
One of my co-workers told me
not to meet him too often.
Why not?
She said if I meet him too much,
he will get tired of me.
That doesn't make sense at all.
You're right.
Jin, it's me.
Why is she so happy?
- What are you doing?
- Stay still. I'm an expert, you know.
If a person has clean nails, she is
beloved by many people around her.
You're one of them.
Nice.
Give me a second.
What's that?
It's couple's nails.
I'll buy couple's rings for us.
Just wait.
How are you feeling?
Good.
Are you going somewhere?
Yeah.
It won't take long.
Do you love that man?
He can make you become a human,
but he might be a hunter.
Since you know how to assimilate with humans
you don't have to risk your life like this.
And that might put other
Gumihos into danger.
I'm sorry.
Good bye.
Let's go.
You're such a bad brat.
You made me stay up all night.
Hey, don't be sloppy!
What's wrong, Kay?
There are customers here.
Don't worry, Bunny.
Kay must be in a bad mood today.
Okay.
Smile.
Smile!
Stop.
- You're like a goldfish.
- Dude!
What's wrong with me?
Bye.
That man extorted you of your money,
didn't he?
You saw it?
Are you smiling?
Actually, I saw him at the
restaurant the other day.
You shouldn't be smiling like this now.
I'm sorry.
I've been working at a mall and
dealing with customers for a long time.
Smiling became my habit.
Look. Do you see these
red lines on your nail?
This means that you're depressed.
You might not feel it but your mind is
suffering because of that damn man.
You need to stay away from
that bastard right now.
If you can't do it, I'll help you.
Who is this little brat?
Don't contact Mi Ae every again.
Don't even come near her.
What is this load of bollocks?
You think she likes you because
she doesn't get mad at you?
Hey.
You don't know who you're messing with.
I'm done talking.
Bye.
Excuse me.
You can't do this here.
If you bother her one more
time, I'm not letting it go.
Don't forget.
Let's go.
You're so brave. Weren't you scared?
You should've called me.
Why?
So you could help me?
No. So I can tell Kay to help you.
Anyway, people like him should get punished.
Why does he exploit people like her?
I told you she's changed.
By the way, did you read a fan
fiction that our fans wrote?
A fan fiction?
It's so funny. You and I are dating
and Kay has a crush on you.
So it becomes a love triangle.
It's kind of erotic too.
Kay bullies me all the time.
That's not possible.
You know, if somebody likes you, they want
to bully you so they can get your attention.
It's like that.
Not possible.
You read this fan fiction, too?
Isn't it so funny?
Hey, Jin.
The way I treated Beanie...
was that weird?
Of course, it was.
What's the matter with you?
You acted like you have feelings for him.
Where is he now?
In the hospital.
What's wrong?
Does he really have feelings
for Bunny?
- Bunny.
- There you are.
Are you going somewhere?
He's about to get examined.
Have a seat while you wait.
Okay.
Are you not done yet?
Bunny, is everything okay?
What?
Yeah.
Why are you zoning out?
Jin, what's the relationship
between Boss and Alex?
Relationship?
Employer and employee.
No, no. How did they meet?
I heard that when Alex was
wandering after he quit his job...
Boss was the one who led him
to become a nail artist.
So she was like his savior.
Come to think of it, everyone
here had hard times.
The same goes for me and Kay.
By the way, I'm going to Club with Ji Soo.
Do you want to come with us?
I'm not interested in that.
You're only interested in Alex,
aren't you?
You're a stalker.
Dude!
Didn't you go home yet?
No.
I left something here.
- Bye, Kay.
- Bye.
Why do I have to lie because
of Beanie?
Excuse me.
Is Bunny here?
I'm not going to worry about him.
Beanie.
Let go.
Where are we going?
Why? You turned on me in a fury
the other day. Do it again.
You think I can't do that?
Just wait there.
Guys, look at this brat.
Get him!
My phone.
There are you are, you little rat.
What are you doing here?
How are you feeling?
I'm okay.
What's wrong?
Are you worried about something?
You're not the type of guy who'd come
visit me just because you're worried.
- Kay.
- Yes?
Check my hand.
You said you know everything
if you check a hand.
Check if I'm crazy or mentally ill.
What the heck are you saying?
Jin.
What's up?
Kay, did you see Bunny?
Why are you asking me that?
You were the last
person at the salon.
Ji Soo wanted Bunny to join us so I called
him but he's not answering the phone.
Ask him if Bunny said where
he's going.
Kay, did he say where
he was going?
No. He was with this man...
Is Bunny here?
I have to go.
Kay.
You know a man with a
scar on his face, don't you?
Where's that bastard?
You little brat.
What do you care about the
business between me and Mi Ae?
Hey, do you really have
a crush on her?
- He looks like a girl.
- Why would two girls be together?
Yeah, he looks so pretty.
Why don't we strip him and check?
Let me go.
Stop!
You shouldn't have been rude to me.
What the hell?
- Kay.
- If you want to keep walking with two legs...
Bring my shoe back and
get out of here.
Look at that son of a bitch.
Go kill him.
Watch out.
Kay.
Bro, your arm is bleeding.
Don't you have a brain?
You don't know how to think?
Why did you follow him?
You don't even know how to fight.
Did you want to kill yourself
or something?
I didn't follow him. He forced me.
What was I supposed to do?
You are...
You should've taken your
phone with you.
I didn't have time for that.
Bunny.
Are you okay?
- Did you get hurt?
- Yeo... Ki Joo.
You must be so shocked.
If this happens one more time,
I'm not going to worry about it.
- Understand?
- What's wrong with you? He's shocked.
Damn bastard.
You made me so worried.
Are you Jeong Mi Ae?
I see.
Bunny must have been so scared.
- Is that all?
- Pardon?
I thought you would worry
about him more than that.
I feel so sorry.
He was in trouble because of me.
You can report it to the police or whatever.
It's not my business.
I have to leave now.
Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Is she a psycho by any chance?
I mean a psychopath.
She doesn't seem like one.
Kay, you think you can
find Hyung Shik again?
Why? Are you really
reporting him to the police?
No, I'm not.
Bunny, you said they've known
each other for a long time, right?
Yes. She told me she has
known him since high school.
He might know what her problem is.
What do you mean?
She doesn't feel emotions and she
suffers from severe migraines.
I think she has alexithymia.
Alexi...what?
Alexithymia.
It's like you can't feel
nor express your emotions.
Of course, it's impossible to
notice how other people feel.
Then what's going to happen to her?
It might lead her to premature dementia
in the worst case.
Isn't that a serious disease?
It might be because of a
congenital handicap.
But I think it's because
of some kind of trauma.
It's like her old wounds from the
past blocked her emotions.
So to cure her disease, we need
to dig up her old wounds.
Wouldn't Hyung Shik know
about something?
Park Hyung Shik.
Can I talk to you for a second?
What?
Trauma?
I'm too stupid to know what
that word means.
But I know that bitch isn't
a normal girl.
Do you know why she has
to pay money to me?
Her classmates didn't talk to her since
she always looked depressed.
She ended up getting bullied.
I figured out that she was
raped by her stepfather.
She was going to kill herself.
She was 16 years old at the time.
Since that incident,
she has been like that.
She doesn't get mad nor sad,
like a robot.
Well... after she got a job at the
mall, she smiles all the time.
But do you know why her smile
drives me nuts?
But you've been watching her because you
have feelings for her. Am I wrong?
I followed her to get money from
her because she owed me her life.
Let's go.
Thank you, anyway.
Hey.
I know I'm a hopeless man.
But please help that girl.
If you let her go, she might
try to kill herself again.
I never thought she had that kind of past.
What do we do now?
The best thing is get her to see a doctor.
But she needs to be able to
admit her problem first.
It won't be easy.
You have to use a little mysticism for this kind of problem.
I mean I assume that people like
her are possessed by a ghost.
So she was probably possessed
by a furious ghost.
- You're talking nonsense again.
- No, I'm not.
The best cure for this is to use a
person with pure and honest energy.
The best treatment for her is a person
who has clear and fresh energy.
Whatever. Can you make us pork cutlet please?
Dude, it's real.
Hey, make one pork cutlet.
He might be right.
Don't say that.
I'm not sure about everything he said,
but a person's heart can be
healed by another person.
Bunny, you started this.
So you need to help her until the end.
- Can you do that?
- Yes.
Good job today.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bye.
Let's go.
You go ahead, Jin.
I'm going to go see Ji Soo.
Kay.
You walk so fast.
Your legs are short.
Thank you for what you did on that day.
I didn't get to say thank you so...
Is your arm okay now?
Why do you care?
How can I not care?
Your arm got hurt because of me.
- That's it?
- What?
Never mind.
You think I can help her?
I'm talking about Mi Ae.
I told the boss I can help her.
But I honestly don't know.
Maybe I should never have gotten involved.
There's no such thing as a single
right answer in the real world.
Pick anything and make that your answer.
Then that becomes the answer.
You're so cool, Kay.
I understand why you have fans.
Are you crazy?
Kay, where are you going?
Diamond Nail
Hello.
Bunny.
Are you okay now?
Yeah.
But did you really worry about me?
Well...
Do you want to go out on a date with me?
You're free on this weekend?
What?
You're mad, aren't you?
Don't you get mad?
I'm sorry.
I acted a little crazy, didn't I?
I wanted to see the real you,
not that smile today.
But it's not working.
Alex said you're sick now.
Because of the deep wound in your heart,
this thing that connects your
brain and heart is broken.
So you don't feel mad, happy, and sad.
You don't try to feel those emotions.
But I thought if I tried,
you would open your mind.
Maybe I was wrong.
Bunny, if you're done talking, can I go home?
I'm tired.
Sure.
Hey Bunny,
How did it go?
It didn't work at all.
Maybe I can't help her.
Don't be disappointed.
It's hard to cure that disease.
Is there really no way to fix her?
Come in.
Bunny, we could've practiced in class.
We should practice like it's for real.
Have a seat.
What is he trying to do?
He's trying to figure it out.
She's his first customer.
We're supposed to practice glue-on nails, right?
I'll begin.
Do you like this place?
I like it.
Do you know why this place is called Paris?
When I first started working
here, my boss told me why.
Just like the myth of Paris,
our goal is to comfort and
cure customers' wounds.
To help our customers, my co-workers
sometimes have to fight and get hurt.
They even get cursed at.
Seeing all that, I realized what
my boss was talking about.
So this time, I'm going to give it a shot.
You're my customer.
I don't have a mother.
On top of that, I was from the countryside.
So people made fun of me.
They even bullied me.
So as time went by and I got
older, I never left my house.
I got a job that I could do alone.
And I had only one friend, my roommate.
I thought I was happy at that time.
But I wasn't.
Because of other people,
Sometimes, I feel happy, sad...
mad, angry...
annoyed, disappointed...
and scared.
Without having those feelings,
I wasn't really living a life.
So I decided not to let
Mi Ae's life to be my old life.
Bunny.
I heard from Hyung Shik what had
happened to you in the past.
I understand why you closed your mind.
But I really want to teach you how
it is to feel those emotions.
Just like this, I'm never going to let you go.
So?
Do you like your the diamond glue-on nails?
Mi Ae...
What's wrong with me?
Your body does feel.
Even if your brain doesn't feel
anything, your body and heart can feel.
They feel hurt and sad.
Help me, Bunny.
What do I do now?
So what's she going to do?
I went to see a doctor with her and
got her admitted for treatment.
The doctor said it's not
an easy disease to cure.
But since Mi Ae has the will to get better,
she's going to be fine.
Wow!  You did a great job
with your first customer.
I guess so.
Anyways, congratulations for becoming a
member of our Paris family officially.
Hello.
Sure.
I'll go now.
Bye.
I'm sorry.
I have to leave now.
Who was it?
Your girlfriend?
Have fun, guys.
- I'm leaving too.
- Kay.
Kay!
What's wrong with them?
Bunny, how about we go to a club?
No.
Bunny, I couldn't even enjoy the club
last time because of you.
I knew it would be like this.
Where did she go?
Call her.
Yeo Joo, where are you?
- I'm going home.
- Why didn't you tell us?
You guy were having fun without me anyway.
Just have fun, guys.
Bye.
What's wrong with her?
Yeo Joo...
Jin!
- I didn't look! I swear!
- What?
Where am I anyway?
Should I get a taxi?
That car...
- What are you doing?
- What the heck?
Are you okay, Jin?
You're such a mess.
Why are you being so nice to me?
What's wrong Yeo Joo?
Are you crying?
Ji Soo, I'm so sad.
I'm so sad, Ji soo!