Misha!
Aah!
Superman's mother:
listen carefully,my son.
By now, Kal-El,
you are entering
The atmosphere of
the planet known as earth.
I pray you have made
a safe journey.
The yellow sun
of your new home
Will give you
great physical powers,
But it cannot
console your spirit.
Placed aboard this vessel
is an energy module,
All that remains of
a once powerful civilization--
Krypton,
your mother planet.
It is my last gift
to you.
Once removed,
The ship will grow
cold and silent,
And you will
be finally alone.
The power in the module
can be used but once.
Use it wisely, my son.
Clark, you out here?
Clark Kent!
Hi, Mr. Hornsby.
Over here.
Ah, there you are.
How are you,sir?
Oh, I'm fine, Clark,
how are you?
Nice to see you.
It's been a long time.
A long time.
I was just tidying up
for when you show the place.
Yeah, well,
didn't I mention
There's an offer
to buy sight unseen?
I won't sell
to a big developer.
Anybody who buys it
has to want a real farm.
I don't think we need
another shopping center.
Darn it, Clark,
why are you so stubborn?
Today,
nobody wants a farm.
You blink your eye,
and they'll all be gone.
That's progress.
Oh, my gosh,
look at this.
Oh, what a joker
old jonathan Kent was.
I asked him what happened
to the baby's crib,
And he said...
"Little Clark must have
had a bad dream and kicked it."
Yeah, dad liked
a good joke.
I was wondering,
Mr. Hornsby,
Maybe you'd like
to keep these
For your
grandchildren.
Why, thank you
very much, Clark.
Here. Batter up.
Come on,
let's hit a few.
Watch out, now.
These will come in
pretty fast.
Ha!
You never could
hit a curve ball.
Ha ha ha!
That's my final decision
about the place.
I'm going to hold out
for a real farmer.
You are?
You're just as obstinate
as your father was, too.
I'm sorry.
That's just how it is.
You be careful
when you get back
To Metropolis, Clark.
It's a long, long way
From where
you were born.
Yes, sir.
I never
forget that, sir.
Bye.
Bye, Clark!
What is that god-awful
noise you're making?
Mozart,
my low-forehead friend.
Even this wretched pit
can't diminish
The spirit of true genius.
Life itself started
in a murky pit much like this.
A true genius like myself
learns to seize the moment.
You're the first to know
That I now have plans
to recreate life itself.
Hey, Luthor, you better
start breakin' a sweat,
Or we'll throw you
to the wolves!
Let's get
them duds dirty!
Move it, meathead.
Let's see
a little sweat.
What's that car
doing out here?
?? She ain't fakin'??
?? Whole lotta shakin'
goin' on...??
Hey, stop!
Hold it there, son!
Yo, dudes,
where the hell is this,
And how the hell
do I get to cedar city?
You're on the wrong
side of the state, boy!
No chance.
Oh, no.
Ooh, you got
a fine, fine,
Super-fine sound system
here, son.
I guess you dudes
have never seen
One of these sensurround
100s, have you?
I seen one
in a magazine.
Come on, get in.
Really?
Only way to hear it.
Come on.
All right!
Hop in, Bubba.
Let's give it a listen.
Hey, this is groovy.
Doors.
What's going on?
Windows.
Whoa!
The top.
Seats.
Whoa! All right!
All right!
Drive away.
Y'all come back
and see us now, hear?
Launch.
Whoa-oh-oh!
Boom.
All right!
Did I do OK
or what, uncle lex?
Lenny, I've always
considered you
The Dutch elm disease
in my family tree,
But this time, nephew,
you did fine.
You skipping
the country?
You pathetic product
of public schools,
I've had nothing
on my awesome mind
Since incarceration
except one thing...
Both: destroy Superman.
Rock!
Sorry.
Bon jour, Monsieur.
Comment a va aujourd'hui?
Clark!
Oh.
Pardon, Monsieur.
Ou est la gare pour...
The metropolitan station?
Arghh!
Help!
Help! Somebody get help!
Superman!
He'll be all right.
I think he needs a doctor.
Superman!
Gentlemen, one moment.
I'D like all the people
back there to know
That our subway system
is still the safest
And most reliable means
of public transportation.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You're late, Kent!
Sorry.
Won't happen again.
Ha!
Where is everybody?
Boring.
Tedious.
Abominable!
Regardez.
Voila, Monsieur
David Warfield.
That tycoon who owns
those sleazy tabloids?
Au contraire,
mon ami.
He owns those
sleazy tabloids
Both:and The Daily Planet.
Tedious.
Don't tell me
you only read pictures.
The fact is, Mr. White,
that I only read the ledger,
A ledger which
the previous owners
Paid so little
attention to,
I bought the paper
out from under them.
It hasn't made any money
in three years!
And the name of the game
is making money.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my daughter,
Lacy Warfield.
Thanks, daddy.
It's very nice
to meet you, ma'am.
Mr. White,
lacy will be helping you.
Helping me?
Helping me what?
I have some mock copies
Of our new layout.
Super, isn't it?
The suit's not right,
but we'll change it.
Excuse me, Mr. Warfield,
But the world isn't
really on the brink.
Isn't that headline
irresponsible?
Maybe, but it'll sell
a lot of newspapers.
Don't do anything rash.
I won't let you turn
this grand old lady
Into one of your bimbos!
Mr. White.
May I point out that daddy
holds all your contracts,
Which you will
have to honor.
Excusez-moi...
Your spoiledness.
Why is lois trying
to speak french?
I'm flying to Paris
For the emergency
ministers conference--
Not so fast.
All trips are canceled.
My trip to Paris
is canceled?
Mr. White,
show me your books.
Everybody else,
get back to work.
We're being
treated unfairly.
I'll speak
to miss Warfield.
Me, too.
Excuse me,
miss Warfield?
Yes?
I think I speak for
all of us when I say
That we'll all do
our best to cooperate.
Thank you.
But a reporter's
first allegiance
Is to the truth.
This city's people
depend on us.
We can't
let them down.
Thank you.
Is he for real?
100%, And I like
him that way, OK?
You have
a thing for him?
For Clark?
No! Ha ha ha!
He's kind of cute.
Uh, look,
miss Warfield...
Clark is the oldest
living boy scout, OK?
He's trustworthy,
he's helpful,
He's loyal,
he's obedient,
He...
I don't know how
to tell you this.
I just don't think he'd be
attracted to somebody like you.
Don't be silly.
All men like me.
I'm very, very rich.
Why don't you have
air travel expenses?
I usually
get air sick,
Especially
when it's bumpy.
Lois, get in here!
Lois, explain this
column of figures.
Chief, the president's
coming on live.
Oh, he is? Oh.
I doubt
it's good news.
It won't be
that terrible.
Hopefully,
very terrible, miss lane.
We could double
our circulation
With a good
international crisis.
And because
the summit has failed,
We have no choice
But to strive
to be second to none
In the nuclear arms race.
Therefore, I am announcing
the following measures--
I know you're all upset
by the crisis.
The best thing we can do
is think positively.
Now, is there
anything we can do?
Doesn't anyone
have a suggestion?
All right.
I'll make a suggestion.
Let's write
our congressmen.
That'll do
a lot of good.
Somebody has to be
an optimist.
Jeremy?
What can we do
about the crisis?
He doesn't know
what's happening.
I'D write a letter to someone
that would do some good.
Who, Santa Claus?
No! Superman!
Superman, the subject
of our newest exhibit,
Has graciously donated a strand
of his hair to the museum,
So we can see how strong
he really is.
Here you can see
a 1,000-pound load
Easily suspended
by his single hair.
The museum will
be closing soon,
So we should
hurry a little.
You know what
I can do with that hair?
You can make
a toupee that flies.
That hair is a sample
Of Superman's
genetic material,
The building blocks
of his body.
With enough nuclear power
to mutate the genes,
I can create a being who's
more powerful than him,
Who has total
allegiance to me.
You better
stand back.
Keep your eye out.
You wanted
to see me?
Yeah, hi, Clark.
Please, come in.
I've come up with
a brilliant idea.
Oh...really?
Well, daddy thinks
it's brilliant.
You'll write this new series
Called Metropolis after hours.
Who, me? I...
It's wonderful.
It's great,
isn't it?
I'm not
right for this.
You're perfect
for it.
You're young,
You're single,
you're successful.
I'm usually
in bed by 10:30.
That's just it.
You don't flaunt it.
You're no slave
to fashion, although...
Have you considered
using contacts?
Uh, they, uh,
make my eyes itch.
Listen, I thought we
could do this together.
I know all
the right places.
I belong
to the right clubs.
We'll start tonight
at the metro club.
Oh, tonight?
Yeah. It's a date.
A date?
Uh, well, it's just
business, actually.
I've got a letter
for Superman, care of me.
Superman
gets mail here?
It's probably just
a picture request.
I could look after
it for you, lois.
I think it's more
than a fan letter.
I think you
should read it.
"Dear Superman,
my teacher is speaking
"About the president's
speech on the arms race.
"We're all
very unhappy about it,
"And I said
we should get Superman
"To rid the world
of nuclear arms
Because only
he could do it."
"Everybody thinks
I'm a space cadet.
"Once you've destroyed
all nuclear missiles,
"They'll see
I was right.
"Superman can make sure
"We don't blow
ourselves up.
"Thanks a lot. I know
you'll come through.
Your friend, jeremy."
Poor kid.
I'll get back to work.
There's an angle
in this.
An angle?
He's just a kid!
Daddy loves whipping
up campaigns,
And the public
loves it!
Lacy!
We're going to make
this kid a celebrity.
Everybody in the world
will wonder
What Superman's
reply is.
Welcome to
Metropolis, jeremy.
I'm Mr. Warfield,
And this is
my daughter lacy.
Hi, jeremy.
Now come along
and meet the press.
Have a good trip?
Car had a flat.
Oh, I'm sorry
to hear that.
Here, let everybody
get a picture of you.
That's it, everyone.
Jeremy, over here.
What a boy!
Now, come along,
And tell the American public
what you told me.
I said I wish Superman
would've said yes!
Did you get that?
Man: no, we didn't.
Say it again...
Loudly.
I said I wish Superman
would've said yes.
Miss lane. Miss lane.
Take a look at this.
Hot off the press.
Oh, my god!
This time, he's
gone too far.
Look, Clark.
Can't wait for
the chief's reaction.
I'm through
taking it lying down!
Anybody wants me,
I'll be downtown!
Chief look
different to you?
He looks like my father
asking for a loan.
I'll make sure
he's all right.
Look, Clark,
There's nothing
we can do about it.
It's Superman's
decision now.
I'm sure he'll do
the right thing.
May the elders
watch over you, my son.
Their wisdom
is all that is left
Of a once powerful
and enlightened planet.
You must listen
to them, Kal-El.
Listen.
I know I'm forbidden
to interfere,
And yet the earth
is threatened
By the same fate
as Krypton's.
The earth
is too primitive.
You can flee
to new worlds
Where war is
long forgotten.
If you teach
the earth
To put its fate
in any one man,
Even yourself,
You're teaching them
to be betrayed.
Betrayed.
Betrayed!
And because
the summit has failed,
We have no choice
But to strive
to be second to none
In the nuclear arms race.
To that end,
This administration
has pursued,
And will continue
to pursue...
Therefore--
Just a minute.
Lois.
There you are!
What happened?
What do you mean?
"Meet me at 6:00 for
the press awards.
Wear something
really nice
And don't be late."
Were we discussing
some other lois?
I'm sorry.
I completely forgot.
OK, get dressed,
and we'll go.
I'D rather not,
if you don't mind.
I've got thinking to do,
But you go ahead, OK?
Clark...
Something's wrong,
isn't it?
Hmm?
Is there anything
I can do?
Yes, as a matter
of fact.
Could we get
some fresh air?
Fresh air?
Fresh air.
Fresh air! Sure!
Sure, Clark. Sure.
Who needs rubber chicken
and speeches anyway?
Come on, let's get
some fresh air.
Breathe really deep.
Breathe.
Do you feel better?
Clark? Clark! Clark!
Things aren't that bad!
Clark, stop!
Oh, Clark!
Clark! Clark!
Superman!
You OK?
Great.
Hey, look at that.
Ready? There you
go! Bye-bye!
How'd you like
going solo?
I loved it...
But not as much
as being with you.
I needed to be
with you, too.
You make me laugh.
You're the only one
I can talk to.
Sometimes, I don't know
what I'm supposed to do.
I'm always
here for you.
You know that.
You'll do
the right thing,
No matter
what it is.
You always have.
Thank you.
You know something?
What?
You don't even
know my name.
Kal-El.
You remember,
don't you?
I remember
everything.
"Never set one of them
above the rest.
Love all humanity
instead."
That's not fair.
Lois.
Time to go.
We'll be late.
Huh?
What am I doing out here
freezing my butt off?
Oh, you wanted
some fresh air.
That's OK.
I don't want
to catch a cold.
I feel kind of weird.
I feel like
I have jet lag.
Jeepers.
Isn't that crazy?
Yeah.
How about you?
You still down?
Nope. Things are
pretty clear.
Good. Too much thinking
wears down your batteries.
Clark, you got to
go with your gut.
Mmm.
Come on.
OK, here you go,
jeremy.
Mr. Warfield
wants shots of you
With lots
of local color.
I can't find
anything special.
Hi, jeremy.
Superman!
Jimmy.
What a scoop!
Want to take
a walk with me?
Sure! OK!
Jimmy, come on.
You can't!
You'll get towed!
Do you know what
a ticket costs here?
Lacy, it's only money!
Wait for me upstairs
in the gallery.
Sure. OK.
Good luck,
Superman.
Thanks.
I saved you a seat.
Yay!
All right, Superman!
Madame secretary, I don't
represent any country,
But I'd like
to address the delegates.
In that case,
you will need a sponsor.
I believe that will do.
Please.
Thank you.
What's he going to say?
Something wonderful.
Madam secretary,
Honorable delegates,
Ladies and gentlemen.
For many years now,
I've lived among you
as a visitor.
I've seen the beauty
of your many cultures.
I've felt great joy in your
magnificent accomplishments.
I've also seen
the folly of your wars.
As of today, I'm not
a visitor anymore
Because the earth
is my home, too.
We can't live in fear.
I can't stand idly by
and watch us
Stumble into the madness
of possible nuclear destruction.
And so,
I've come to a decision.
I'll do what our governments
haven't done.
Effective immediately,
I'll rid our planet
of all nuclear weapons.
Yay!
Yay, Superman.
Way to go, Superman!
Superman!
Missile test alpha.
All systems go.
4, 3, 2, 1.
Oh! Hello!
Nice to see you guys!
Why don't you
just relax there?
I'll get on with
the introductions.
Dixie...
And Trixie.
From the land of the free
and the great cost overrun,
Harry howler,
nuclear strategist
From America's
top think tank
And a great warmonger
in his own right.
A hearty bienvenue
to Jean Pierre Dubois,
Nuclear warhead dealer
to the world.
His motto is,
"If you didn't
buy it from Jean Pierre,
You didn't buy it
on ze black market."
General Romoff.
A lot of people think of you
as the mad Russian.
I like to think of you
as just madly eccentric.
Please, be seated.
I know you guys
are overcome with joy
Now that Superman
has ended the arms race,
But if we work together,
We can make
the world safe...
For war profits.
Make your point.
I, Lex Luthor,
The greatest criminal mind
of the modern era,
Have discovered a way
to destroy Superman.
Behold,
my unscrupulous friends.
Shut those blinds!
The sun is
hurting my eyes!
Exactly.
You know what the sun is?
It's a huge nuclear bomb
With so much
radiation in it,
It could incinerate
the average man like that!
Yes, but Superman
is no average man.
Aha! Right.
What is your plan?
Boys, old lex here has
kind of a secret recipe,
A genetic stew
in this dish, if you will.
If you'll put this
on one of your missiles,
Superman will have the biggest
surprise of his life.
I'll introduce him
to his first nightmare--
A nuclear man.
He'll pierce his skin.
He'll make him mortal.
He'll become sick.
We'll dance on his grave.
Why should we deal
with a scoundrel like you?
Remember my motto,
"The more fear you make,
the more loot you take,"
And the more missiles
you guys sell.
Yes,
but what's in it for you?
A tiny commission.
Something appropriate.
A number...
With a lot of zeros
behind it.
Lenny.
The new
genetic material.
And now, leonard...
Your uncle lex,
with this protoplasm
That I've grown from
Superman's hair cells...
Will duplicate
creation itself.
Ow.
Now the fabric.
Uncle lex, this ain't
gonna cover him.
The computer inside will
weave enough material
To maintain
the high moral standards
That I've always
subscribed to.
You know what
this means, uncle lex?
What?
We're going to
be parents!
What's your name,
sergeant?
York, sir!
At ease.
Launch control.
Yes, sir?
Yes, sir.
There's a weather problem.
We got a hold.
Hold?
What's your name, son?
Gorrham.
Gorrham, sir.
You know your code book?
Of course, sir.
It's a 2706,
inclement override.
On my command, fire.
Yes, sir.
Standby to launch.
10, 9--
Missed us.
Reach out!
Come on!
Down!
Reach out!
And stretch!
Down!
Up!
Oww! Ahh!
Clark,
are you OK?
I'll sit
this one out.
Oh, are you sure?
But it's great
for your series.
Let's try it again.
Come on, let's start.
2...
3, 4...
1, 2, 3...
I don't think so.
Clark, are you OK?
48.
49.
23...Done.
OK, you try it now.
OK.
Let's set it
a little higher for you.
Just push down.
Are you OK?
Need some help?
Just step down.
Thank you.
Your friend doesn't
know his own strength.
Clark,
this is Paul.
He's a trainer
here.
I got just
the thing for you.
Over here, Clarkey.
Clarkey?
It's nice of him
to help me out.
Here, try this one.
Oh, Clark,
are you OK?
Yeah.
Sorry.
No pain, no gain.
Jeez, what a jerk.
I never
realized it before.
I guess a lot of
people I know are jerks.
Maybe you think I'm one,
so you avoid me.
No, I don't think that.
I've just been really
busy, that's all.
You know lois is doing
that interview with Superman
About his peace mission?
Maybe the four of us
could meet for high tea.
It's very chic.
Paul: could you hand me
those weights, Clark?
Uh, excuse me.
Wait a minute,
lacy.
Come early.
The view is so romantic
from my balcony.
See ya.
Oh, sure. Here.
Not those!
The other one!
Uh...no pain, no gain?
What was that?
Uncle lex,
you're spooking me out.
There.
Madam...
Thank you
very much.
Oui, Monsieur.
Au revoir.
I'm incredible.
Uncle lex, he's like...
He's beautiful.
He's perfect.
Welcome home,
nuclear man.
Your father's
happy to see you.
The sun has given him
internally generated heat.
I'm, uh...
You are...
I'm...what?
I'm a genius?
I'm incredible!
I'm...
You are nothing!
I am the father now.
You have my voice.
No, you have my voice.
Just remember,
I made you.
You're just
an experiment, freako.
What's that?
Oh, no.
I'm an experiment?
I'm freako?
I was just kidding!
If anyone's freako here,
it's got to be me!
Oh, wow!
I'm break dancing! Hey!
This rocks!
Hey! Oh! Whoa...
I made you.
I can destroy you.
Destroy.
Destroy Superman now.
You sweet thing!
But not quite yet.
Come here.
We'll discuss
when the proper time is.
Uncle lex.
Oh, no!
He's, like...
He's, like, cold.
Of course he is.
That's
his vulnerability.
That's the only way
he can be stopped.
What?
Lenny,
my loud-mouth nephew,
He gets his energy
from the sun.
Without it, he's
like you at night...
Useless.
Nobody's perfect.
You know, I never had
a double date before.
This is fun.
How do I look?
Illegal...
Like the last six
dresses you tried on.
Uh, listen, lacy,
I don't want
to burst your bubble,
But Clark won't notice
what you're wearing.
Yes, he will.
Oh, there's Clark.
You look great.
Oh, maybe it's
just Superman.
No.
No, Superman makes
a different kind of entrance.
Hi, lacy.
Hi, Clark.
Could you break a 20?
Driver didn't
have any change.
Yeah, sure.
Let me get my purse.
Hi, lois.
Hi, Clark.
You won't believe
these questions
Mr. Warfield gave me
to ask Superman.
"Are you part of a plot to
weaken our national defense?"
It's his gray matter
that's weakened.
How can I ask Superman
these questions?
Uh, well,
politely, I guess.
Let's see,
I have $18 and...
Clark, she really
likes you,
So notice the dress.
My American express card.
Dress.
Oh, hey! Neat dress!
Thanks. Be right back.
Hey, what's that?
Now, there's a different
kind of entrance.
Hi, lois.
Hello, Superman.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Oh! Um, Superman,
meet lacy Warfield.
She's the boss'
daughter.
How do you do?
That's a very
attractive outfit.
I think we better
start our interview.
Two's company.
Oh, right! Yeah!
I'll go get Clark.
He's probably helping
the cab driver change a flat
Or some other good deed.
Something
smells wonderful.
Oh, thank you.
I'm cooking some
scallops and duck
In this wonderful
mushroom sauce with champagne,
In case we got
hungry afterwards.
Uh...I mean, later.
You shouldn't have gone
to all that trouble.
Should we get on
with the interview?
Yes, let's get on with it.
Um...
Have...have you had
any trouble
Confiscating
the missiles?
There always was
the possibility
That some warped
individuals
Would take advantage
Of the world's
good will, but--
Is there
something wrong?
Oh, my dinner!
Um, I'll be
right back!
Hi.
I missed you, Clark.
It's so boring up there
with lois and Superman.
Let's go do
something wild.
That wouldn't
be polite.
Yeah, you're right.
How can one man
be so square
And so delicious?
All right. Let's go.
If I have to
face Superman,
So do you.
Ooomph! Uh...lacy.
Oh, Clark.
Uh...uh...stop.
I don't believe it!
I've never had a duck
turn out so perfectly!
I'm out here, lois.
Oh.
Isn't it beautiful?
The city's beautiful.
The whole world
is beautiful.
I've always felt moments
like this should be shared
With someone you
care a lot about.
Isn't that
the doorbell?
Yes.
Lacy.
Where's Clark?
Well, the elevator--
Never mind.
It's a long story.
It always is
with Clark.
Oh, great,
that's him!
Clark?
Hi. Those bellboys should
look where they're going.
Superman?
Is dinner ready?
Can we eat?
Yeah.
Let's go sit down.
Oh, great.
Ohhh! Sorry!
Oh, dear.
Oh, no, that's OK.
Just leave it
there, Clark.
Let me
just get a rag.
Be right back.
Where's Clark?
Lex:?? Hello, dolly??
?? Hello, dolly??
?? It's so nice to have
me back where I belong??
Don't be concerned,
blue boy.
Only you can hear me.
It's my own
private frequency.
You might
call this lex TV.
Look to your left,
tall, dark, and handsome.
I'll blow 20 stories
off that building...
Give or take
a floor or two. Peace.
Men.
I hope Clark's OK.
I better look.
OK.
I'm sorry.
An emergency's
come up.
My apologies
to miss Warfield.
Oh, but--
Superman!
Take me with you!
I could
cover the story!
Have you seen Clark?
Huh?
Guess who.
It's your old friend lex.
If you'd
planted a bomb,
You'd be miles
from here by now.
This is my nephew Lenny.
He worships me.
The dude of steel.
Boy, are you
gonna get it!
Silly me, thinking
I could fool the super guy.
You're right. No bomb.
It's just
that you're so involved
In this world peace bit,
You don't have time
for social calls.
I confess.
I tricked you.
You look great.
Enough small talk.
What are you up to?
You know,
you're a workaholic.
You're playing a good guy
24 hours a day.
Why don't you stop
and smell the roses?
Get yourself a pet--
a kitten, a puppy.
You hate children
and animals.
Why are you
in Metropolis?
I want to introduce you
to the new kid on the block.
Look closely at
the cell structure.
You see
anything familiar?
You've already broken
all the laws of man.
Now you've broken
the laws of nature, too.
You must have
hidden a device
On a missile
I hurled into the sun.
You know, Mr. Muscle,
I'll miss our chats.
You're the only one
that could keep up with me.
Lenny!
What?
I want to
propose a toast.
To a nice guy...
Who's about
to finish last.
Arrr!
Destroy Superman!
Later.
He's a little bit
anxious.
Can you blame him?
Not one of
your great thinkers.
But I, in all modesty, am.
The touching thing
about this plan
Is you helped me devise it.
Prison twisted your mind
into a delusionary state.
No, no, no. Listen.
I escaped from prison
with one thing on my mind--
The end of Superman.
So there I was,
the first time ever
That I didn't
have a long-range,
Truly devious
criminal scheme.
And then
I came up with it.
With this guy
And you gone,
I'll make a fortune
rearming the world.
You'd risk nuclear war
for your financial gain?
Nobody wants war.
I just want to keep
the threat alive.
Nifty, huh?
Good night,
sweet prince.
Parting is...
Inevitable.
Destroy Superman!
First, I have fun.
Aah!
Help me!
Thank you, Superman.
Santa Maria...
Oh!
Un gran miracolo.
Grazie.
Eeyi! Hah!
Aah!
Oh!
Arrrgh!
Aah!
Yaaa!
I said I'd get you
To run one
of our papers yourself,
And I meant it.
Congratulations,
miss publisher.
Thank you, daddy.
That's very nice.
Step into
your office.
Where'd this
come from?
Oh, somebody
brought it in.
We bought it cheap.
OK. This time you have
both gone too far.
You can print your rag
without lois lane.
And you certainly have
no right to this.
Lois, I'm sorry.
Oh, let her go,
darling.
I mean,
she's useless.
And while you're at it,
fire that Clark Kent.
He hasn't been around
or even telephoned.
I know. I'm worried.
Oh, kitten,
Didn't we have
our little talk
About personal
involvement
With the help?
Now that you're
the publisher--
Daddy...
Yes, darling?
Stuff it!
Lois?
Lois, I'm sorry.
I promise you I had
nothing to do with that.
Have you heard
from Clark?
No.
Just a minute.
Oh, lois. What are
you doing here?
I knew it.
Oh, I've just,
Uh...just got
a really bad flu.
What do you mean
you knew it?
How'd you know?
You haven't been to work.
You haven't called
the office.
You haven't even
called me back.
How could you not
call me back?
Whatever it is,
I guess you've
got your reasons,
But I knew you
were here, you know?
Somehow...
Somehow something
pulled me here.
I always know when
Superman's in trouble.
Ha ha! Superman?
Something's happened to him?
Everybody's saying
he's dead, but...
It can't be true.
I just know it.
I feel it in my heart.
I think
he just needs help.
Well, wherever he is, lois,
I'm sure he'll manage.
Well, if he can't...
Manage...
And he really is...
In trouble,
Then there's, uh...
There's a few things
I'd like to tell him.
I'D tell him...
That I will always
cherish the time
We spent together,
And I never expected
anything in return
And no matter how few
minutes I saw him for,
It always made me happy.
And I would tell him...
That I love him,
And that
I'll always love him,
And that...whatever...
Happens to the world, I...
I know that...
That he's doing his best
to make sure
That it'll be all right
for the rest of us.
Well, wherever he is,
lois,
I know that...
He would want
to thank you.
Listen, I'm, um...
I'm pretty tired,
you know,
So I think I'll
just rest here
For a while, OK?
I'll be fine.
It's OK.
Please?
Well, I hope you
feel better, Clark.
Thanks.
Um...
If...if you do
see him,
Um...or--or--or
hear from him,
He might need this.
Oh, lex,
we're all very pleased
At all the nuclear missiles
and arms you've helped us sell,
And, uh, we've decided
to increase your commission.
Oh, guys, really,
that's great.
It's the least
we could do.
Well, I have
another idea.
Gentlemen, I've decided
To assume control
of the company.
My first official act
is to say, "you're fired!"
You're mad.
Oh, really?
Look at this.
If you want
a reference for work,
Forget it!
That was a good bit.
You know,
with my brains
And your...
Frankly, your brawn,
The possibilities
are absolutely staggering.
I could be president,
emperor, king.
Did you see how scared
those guys were?
And what
do you fear?
What? Now?
With Superman dead,
and you're on my team?
It's like I'm the coach,
And you're the best
power forward ever.
What's to fear?
All that remains
of Krypton's energy
Is yours.
After it is gone,
You will belong solely
to your new home.
If our dying planet
can save your life, my son,
We have not died
in vain.
Rrraaarr!
Where is the woman?
You'll never find her.
If you will not tell me,
I will hurt people.
Rooaarr!
Yaaaah!
Stop! Don't do it!
The people!
Aah!
Yaaahh!
Ohhh!
Easy, now, easy.
Slow, slow, slow.
Stop! That's enough!
That's enough.
You win.
I'll take you to her.
Raaarrgh!
Yaahh!
Rooaarr!
Where is she?
Far away from here
and safe.
Don't go in there.
She's not in there.
Ah...aahh...
Errr!
Errrr!
Raarrr!
Grrrrr!
Aah!
Uugh!
Aaaahhh!
Aaarrrrgh!
Rrrarrrr!
We've got to tone down
these headlines.
Tone down our headlines?
Lacy, that's all
the common man reads.
We could do with
less sensationalism.
Less sensational papers
go broke.
I taught you long ago
That the business of
newspapers is business.
No, daddy.
Our business
is journalism.
We can't be
so irresponsible.
Otherwise,
We'll lead everyone
into a disaster.
Don't be overdramatic.
What kind of disaster
Could we possibly
bring about?
Raaaarr!
Lacy!
Aaahh...
Oh!
What's going on?
Are you sure
you know
What you're doing,
Mr. White?
Well...
Uh...ahem.
Here comes
Mr. Warfield.
You'd better have
an explanation, white,
Or you'll talk
to your lawyers from jail.
You know, I'm not a tycoon.
I'm just
an old reporter,
But I've read enough
in my own newspaper
About hostile takeovers
of big companies,
And you, Mr. Warfield,
Must have been
asleep at the wheel,
Because I convinced
the bankers of this city
That our Daily Planet
should be treated
Like a natural resource,
protected from predators,
So I convinced them
to lend me the money.
I bought up
the outstanding shares,
And you, Mr. Warfield, are
now a minority shareholder.
Everyone back to work.
Way to go,
chief!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Yay!
I'm sorry.
You win some,
you lose some.
Now, this is what
I call a newspaper.
Compliments of
the Daily Planet.
Have a nice day!
We did it!
We're back!
Hi, everybody.
Am I late?
Hey, Mr. Kent.
No, he's not here yet.
It must have been
an effort for you
To drag yourself
out of bed this morning.
I'm feeling better.
Had a visit from
a good nurse.
It must have been some
pretty good medicine,
Because miss lane said
you were really ill.
Jimmy, sometimes
all you need
Is some
loving attention
From the right
person.
Glad you're back,
Clark...
And remember...
I am covering
Superman's press conference.
You just tape
crowd reactions.
Reactions, OK.
Oh, dear.
Guess I'll need
a tape recorder.
Be right back.
Clark.
Same old Mr. Kent.
He'll never change.
I hope not.
Whoo!
Hi, Superman.
Lois, good
to see you again.
Good to see you, too.
Morning, gentlemen.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
We've survived
the threat of war
And found
a fragile peace.
I thought I could give
you freedom from war.
I was wrong.
It's not mine to give.
We're still
a young planet.
There are galaxies
out there,
Other civilizations
for us to meet,
To learn from.
What a brilliant future
we could have.
And there will be peace
When the world's people
want it so badly
That their governments will
have to give it to them.
I wish you could see
the earth as I do.
When you really see it,
it's just one world.
Think he'll find us?
Never. We'll lay low
for a while,
Couple of years.
I'll come up
with a new plan.
Whoa. Good thing
I brought my drums.
Oh, no!
Uncle lex,
you won't believe this,
But it's...
Superman.
Oh, wow!
Hey, this rocks! Hey!
Morning, father.
Lenny's been under
a bad influence.
Think you can help him?
Every boy
can be helped.
I think you're right.
Good luck, son.
Come with me,
my friend.
Do you have
a drum set?
Hey! Mozart's back!
Dwayne,
mozart's back!
I see him, Bubba!
Shut up!
Marshal,
take him away.
Thank you kindly,
Superman.
Come on, Luthor.
One thing--
how'd you beat him?
High school physics.
I figured
that if your creature
Was born from the sun,
That was
his energy source.
Will the world
be vaporized?
No, Luthor.
As always,
it's on the brink,
With good fighting evil.
See you in 20.