(Episode 19)
I'm Shim Jae Bok. I called earlier.
As I told you, Lee Eun Hee is doing well.
Still, I'd like to see her.
Visiting hours are over.
Let me see her. Please.
See? She's fine.
Eun Hee.
Eun Hee. It's me, Jae Bok.
That's Hae Wook's doll.
Did she take it?
Eun Hee. Eun Hee!
I knew it.
She isn't Lee Eun Hee. Where is she?
When did you switch her?
Guys.
Why are you here?
Eun Hee.
Get your hands off them.
Get your hands off. Jin Wook! Hae Wook!
No. No!
No. Don't go.
No.
Hae Wook. No.
Mommy. Are you dreaming?
- Mommy.
- No!
Hae Wook.
Jin Wook.
Darn it. You're so loud.
What is it?
Jin Wook.
- Jin Wook. Come here.
- Mommy.
Were you dreaming?
Was it a bad dream?
Yes, I guess so.
You're sweating.
You must be growing.
You said a scary dream
means you're growing.
I guess.
I guess...
I'm getting tall.
Why would an adult get taller?
It's possible.
- They don't.
- They do.
She's already all grown up.
Come here, guys. Let me hold you.
Why are you being corny this morning?
Mommy.
Jung Hee, wear this one.
How could you do this to me?
Let go!
Let go, you jerks! Let go!
Jung Hee.
You...
How did you get out?
- What are you saying?
Jung Hee.
Mom.
Gosh, your face is so pale.
What are you doing here so early?
What? I was worried about you.
Eun Kyung is at the
hospital, so you're alone.
You didn't have breakfast, right?
I'll make it quickly.
It's okay. I have to go to work.
I better go.
Hey.
Are you sure Eun Kyung is at a hospital?
Yes, I went and checked.
My poor baby.
Now...
will Jung Hee and I live here alone?
Mr. Kim, where are you?
I quit.
Mr. Kim? Hello? Hello?
What are you doing?
Yes, ma'am. It's all cleared.
Mr. Oh, what happened here?
Your department has been terminated.
Mr. Koo. You're fired as of today.
What?
What is this?
There were so many projects
I was in charge of.
How can you do this?
What are you doing? You're being rude.
Mr. Koo, you're nothing now.
Mr. Oh. Mr. Oh!
(Chief Director Koo Jung Hee)
You're sure?
Is Lee Eun Hee in the hospital?
Yes. Thank you.
If something happens,
please give me a call.
I'll really appreciate it.
Is she doing well?
- Yes.
- She should be.
She needs treatment and get well...
in order to get proper questioning done.
Whenever I call,
the person in charge always says the same.
Jae Bok, don't worry too much.
I looked into it, and
she's getting treatment.
Do you think it's true?
Is she really getting better?
For some reason, I don't
think she'll be there.
I keep dreaming of it.
You've become really sensitive.
You need to take it easy.
Let's go.
- Where?
- To see Eun Hee.
I feel like you'll get sick
at this rate. Come on.
I went there last time,
and she refused to meet.
Let's go anyway. Come on.
Yes. Go in there somehow,
and check with your eyes.
I feel bad just looking at you.
- Go. Hurry.
- Okay. Let's go.
- Mom. Mom!
- Yes?
What's going on?
What is all this?
Our stuff.
That man told us to leave.
Who are you?
Bryan is on the line.
You punk. What do you think you're doing?
It's just as you see it.
Vacant the house.
My sister is gone.
You have no right to live there.
How can you kick someone out so suddenly?
I was engaged to your sister.
Engaged?
You were disgusted by her.
You called her crazy.
Isn't it funny that you're
bringing that up now?
Fine, we'll leave.
I'll leave.
- Mom, let's go.
- Where to?
To your house.
Jung Hee.
What? So we don't have anywhere to live?
No. Your brother Jung Bae
wanted to open a business,
so he took my lease deposit and ran away.
Why did you give him all of that?
Jung Bae, that jerk.
Mom, what about the place...
Eun Hee bought for you?
He took it all.
If you give him all of
that, where do we live?
Ms. Lee Eun Hee is coming.
I heard you came to visit me last time,
but I couldn't see you.
I wasn't ready to meet you then.
I'm sorry.
Are you ready now?
I feel a bit lighter.
Have you been well?
You don't look so good.
Eun Hee, you look good.
Yes. I'm doing well.
I'm taking my pills and getting treatment.
You're doing bad because of me, aren't you?
Actually,
I've been anxious.
People told me that you were here,
but I couldn't believe it.
That's why I came.
Of course.
I've wronged you so many times.
I can't even apologize to you.
Still,
I'm really sorry.
Are you really repenting?
Are you sure this isn't a show?
I regret what happened...
with Na Mi as well.
You must have been in sorrow.
I'm sorry.
After coming here, I
thought about what I did.
I think I made a lot of people get hurt.
Why did I do such a thing?
I really regret it.
Right.
It was because of your mental illness,
but it can't give you a pardon.
You made all of us suffer.
I'm sorry.
I have a question to ask you.
Please answer me in all honesty.
What happened with Na Mi...
Was it really not your doing?
What are you doing?
Do not stimulate the patient.
What are you talking about? What did we do?
The visit is over.
Please leave.
Ms. Lee.
I'm okay.
They came from far away. I
don't mind talking longer.
It's time for your music therapy.
Okay.
Jae Bok, don't be nervous.
I'm no longer...
the Eun Hee you know.
You're comforting me?
How funny.
Is it because the treatment is going well?
We'll come back another time.
We'll talk later.
Even when somewhere pleasant.
Calls for me.
The only place for rest is the small house.
Eun Hee didn't change at all.
She's only acting.
If she hasn't changed,
it'll show on the tests.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. I have to be...
if I want to face Eun Hee.
My love, my house.
(Ms. Perfect)
Gosh, this is perfect for Won Jae.
Let's see.
All right.
Why is it so expensive? Are they crazy?
I'll pay.
I can buy everything.
You don't have to feel pressured.
No.
I'm a man.
I'll buy you even if I have
to sell my golden tooth.
Sam Kyu.
You're buying me dinner at a
romantic place like here?
I just want to crumble.
Won Jae.
Are we having dinner here?
Are you buying?
What's this? Sam Kyu?
Hey, are you setting the two of us up?
Yes. Have a great time.
- I'll get going.
- Hey, Won Jae.
What do you think you're doing?
If you hand him over like
you're volunteering,
did you think I'll thank you and take him?
Forget it. You keep him all you want.
What are you doing? I thought
you wanted him again.
You should date him.
Friendship comes first to me.
- Go.
- No. Do you think I have no pride?
- I have a lot of men.
- I said I'm okay.
- You should go in.
- Gosh, are you serious?
- You go in.
- My goodness.
Gosh.
Won Jae. Won Jae.
Ouch. Wait. Wait.
Do you still get nightmares?
Eun Hee either chases me...
or my kids disappear.
I can't sleep deeply, so I'm always tired.
Come here.
- Sit down.
- Why?
- What is it?
- Sleep here for 10 minutes.
I'll sleep at home.
You just said you can't sleep at home.
Just sleep for 10 minutes.
It'll feel refreshing if you
sleep well for 10 minutes.
I'll count 10 minutes from now, okay?
Here, okay. Sleep now.
Sleep.
All right. Then just 10 minutes.
How can you sleep like that?
You can't sleep like that.
No. Go like this.
Come here.
Now you're sleepy, right?
This is what you should do.
You know,
my parents separated early...
so I lived alone since I
was in middle school.
I thought there wasn't much to life.
I went around with my nose up high.
But it's scary sleeping alone
in a basement apartment.
I used to get paralyzing nightmares.
These days, you're going through...
such hard times. It feels...
It really feels bad to hear about it.
I wish I could go into your dreams...
and fight in it for you.
Why aren't you sleeping?
How can I sleep when
you're talking so much?
Okay, sleep. Sleep. I'm sorry.
Dad...
Dad.
I wonder if Jung Hee is okay.
(Jung Hee)
(Jae Bok)
Try drawing your face as well.
Eun Hee.
- A tree and a house?
- A house.
That's right.
(One month later)
Mister, watch it!
Yes, sir. I'm sorry.
- Did you watch it yesterday?
- Yes, I did.
- You look kind of like him.
- Totally.
- Stop it.
- Let's go to the internet cafe.
Okay. Internet cafe.
- Let's go.
Jin Wook. Jin Wook...
- Noodles.
- Black.
Bee.
- Bee?
- No, no. Bean.
Jin Wook.
In Ho.
- Dad.
- Hello.
Your dad's car is awesome.
Isn't it amazing?
They're so childish.
That's his dad's car, not his.
- Hey, isn't that your dad?
- What?
What? Dad!
Dad! Dad!
- Maybe it's not.
- I'm sure it was.
No way. My dad isn't that grungy.
He dresses super well.
Good for you. You have a dad.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
It's okay. Let's go.
Okay.
I'm going to get you.
What's wrong with you?
Jin Wook.
I'm sorry.
Our housekeeper does all
the grocery shopping.
Still. I wanted to come with you.
My cute Che Ri. So cute.
You found your way.
Che Ri.
This is our shopping list.
Thank you.
Don't you worry, Little Miss.
I'll get your groceries without mistake.
I'll go now, Mom. I have my cello lesson.
Che Ri. What are you...
Mom. They say love is about timing.
Don't miss it.
Che Ri!
Che Ri, see you later.
Won Jae, I'll push the cart.
(Motel)
Jae Bok.
Why are you here?
Gosh. It's a long story.
Come in.
Sit down.
I heard Jung Hee quit the company.
He didn't quit. He was fired.
Since Eun Kyung or Eun Hee,
what's her name is gone,
we've been thrown into the dumpster.
We were kicked out of that nice house too.
You've been here since back then?
Where is Jung Hee working?
Just... Here and there.
He's a good worker, so
he'll get a job soon.
But anyway...
I've been short on cash lately.
Do you have any money you can lend me?
Is that why you called?
Once Jung Hee gets a nice job,
I'll pay you right back.
This is all the cash I have.
- Jae Bok.
- Jung Hee.
You got out early today.
Why did she have to call you?
How are the kids?
Hae Wook must've grown a lot, right?
Do you want to see them?
Should we have dinner together?
You didn't let me see them before.
Do you feel sorry for me?
That was because of Eun Hee.
Because she was too dangerous for the kids.
The kids miss you too.
When are you free?
Forget it.
How can I see them like this?
I'll go visit once I'm settled.
I heard you're doing well.
There's a rumor that your firm will expand.
Yes. So I've been very busy lately.
That's great.
You'll fulfill your dreams. I'm sure of it.
You...
resented me a lot, didn't you?
You lost everything because...
I had Eun Hee locked up.
To be honest, I did at first.
But none of it was mine anyway.
I must've lost my mind for a while.
What an idiot.
Jae Bok. I'm sorry.
You don't have to forgive me.
I'm sorry to you and to the kids.
I just...
wanted to do well.
I wanted to be a cool dad.
Go back.
I'll walk you a little farther.
This is good enough. Go back.
Rest up. Go see a doctor
if your back hurts a lot.
I will.
- Bye.
How did this happen to us?
How?
Hello?
Where are you?
I'm on my way to the office. Why?
Eun Hee was discharged from the hospital.
What?
When?
Just now. I had been checking.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
Jae Bok. What's wrong?
Eun Hee's been discharged.
What will you do?
Will you see her again?
No. Just thinking about her scares me.
Are you okay?
You have to be careful.
She may get back at you.
I'm fine.
I'm not afraid of anything.
Be careful.
The kids too.
I'm home, Mom.
I did it.
She doesn't know anything.
Please calm down.
How can I be calm? That
scary psycho is back.
Eun Hee changed a lot. You saw last time.
Do you believe that? Be honest.
Do you believe that?
You're saying that to calm me down.
I need to see Eun Hee's brother.
We need to send her back to the hospital.
That's absurd.
Even if his daughter is precious,
how could he take her out of the hospital?
The hospital said her results were good...
and that she was safe to be discharged.
You punk. How could she
have been cured already?
She was in there for a month.
I'll check on her.
- Rest assured.
- No.
I can't rest assured as
long as she's out there.
You take responsibility and make sure...
to keep a close eye on her.
Okay. I will.
This is huge. A scary person
is free to roam around.
It's a big problem.
Do you remember this? I used
to make this for you...
when we were young.
I suddenly remembered this in the hospital.
And that I hadn't made
it for you in a while.
After taking the beating from Mom for me,
you made this for me...
although you were in pain...
to tell me to smile.
Bryan.
Don't worry too much.
I'm really completely cured now.
Really?
Are you really all better?
I'm really sorry...
for always making you worry.
Bryan.
I love you more than anyone.
Go visit Mom.
She misses you a lot.
I should.
I should make up with her.
I'll forgive her now.
I think that's the only way to find peace.
Eun Hee.
I won't go back there again.
Will you live like this,
- looking like this?
- What's wrong with this?
I'm happy right now because
my heart is at peace.
It may be tiring,
but I'll rise again from here.
I know just how badly I annoyed you.
I know how hard I made it for you.
I repented a lot while
I was in the hospital.
I really regretted it.
I'm all better now.
I'm not the old Eun Hee.
There you go again.
You've said that all before.
I mean it.
I won't make it hard for you...
because of my obsessions.
I'll be a good wife.
Are you really completely better?
Then you start a new life too.
Forget me,
and live a happy, good life.
Please.
How could I be happy...
without you there?
Goodbye.
- What?
- She's back?
The kids will hear.
Is she back home then?
Probably.
I wonder if Jung Hee is okay.
I'm more worried about you.
You look terrible.
Hey. You have us. Don't worry.
Should I...
just immigrate?
What?
I'm too worried to live here with Eun Hee.
It I were alone, I'd make it work somehow,
but for Jin Wook and Hae Wook's sake...
Bong Goo said you seemed
nervous and insisted...
We'll stay here for a few days.
We'll guard the door, so you sleep.
You can't survive with no
sleep and so much fear.
You don't have to do this.
How can you live here?
We'll come at night just to sleep.
During that time, trust us and sleep well.
Will you be okay?
Of course. I've slept
outdoors for 30 years.
It'll be uncomfortable.
No, no.
Push me.
Hae Wook. Hae Wook!
Hae Wook. No! It's dangerous!
Hae Wook!
Hae Wook.
Hae Wook! No!
No! Hae Wook!
Hae Wook!
- No!
- Mom.
- Hae Wook!
- What's wrong?
Hae Wook!
- It's okay.
- Hae Wook!
- Jae Bok!
No!
- Jae Bok.
- Mommy.
It's okay.
It was just a dream.
Jae Bok.
- Oh my gosh.
- Are you okay?
Oh, no.
- Mommy.
- It's okay. It's just a dream.
- Mom.
- A dream.
- Calm down.
- Are you okay?
Mommy.
Are you okay?
Jae Bok.
Come here.
- Mommy's okay.
- Mom.
Oh my gosh. What should we do?
Mom.
It's okay.
Jae Bok. Are you okay now?
Yes.
Sorry for waking you.
What do you mean?
We're just sad that we
can't share your burden.
Eun Hee being all calm and quiet...
scares me more.
This means she got worse, right?
Yes. It's better for her
to show her true self.
It'd only get worse since
she's suppressing it.
Just watch over Jung Hee.
Who knows what she'll do?
I plan to.
Even if he refuses, I'll keep watching.
I have to. He's the kids' dad.
What? What did you just say?
How dare you?
Do you know who I was just
until a few days ago?
I was the madam of a wealthy family.
You just have to act so cool, don't you?
You can't even do the work right.
Why this woman...
- Oh my gosh.
- Just hit me. Hit me.
- Hit me.
- Why you...
Mother.
You...
I'm really cured now.
I'll be good to you now.
Get away.
Mother. You used to be so refined.
What's wrong with you? I have to work. Go.
- Mother. I'll do it.
- Well...
I can't leave when you're
working hard like this.
You don't have to go home with me.
Just let me help you a little.
Mom. Did you really go back there?
Yes.
Turns out Eun Kyung...
I mean, Eun Hee is all better.
She was crying so much while apologizing.
A person needs to know how to forgive.
Get out of there! Now!
You know she's dangerous!
No! Don't come if you don't want to.
I'm going to live here.
Where's Eun Hee?
I don't know. I think she went out.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
- Wipe this here.
- Yes, ma'am.
Yes. I'll prepare the
documents and send them over.
Okay.
Jae Bok.
You...
Why are you here?
Jae Bok...
What's your deal?
This is where you were?
I thought...
it would be only right
for me to come first.
Last time,
you seemed so nervous because of me.
You must be roaming around
as you think you're well,
but you're not. I don't believe you.
I'm sorry.
You used to be so strong.
It's all my fault.
I feel so bad.
Eun Hee. Stop pretending
to be a nice person.
Are you really all better?
I'm sure you wouldn't believe it,
- but I...
- Then let the police investigate you.
Na...
Na Mi's case...
was framed on your mom,
but you have several cases
to answer questions about.
Here are the cases the police
will investigate on you.
Take a look.
I'll go for investigation.
If I must be punished,
I'll accept that as well.
I apologize once again.
Jae Bok. I won't hurt Jin Wook...
and Hae Wook.
I'm sorry for suddenly popping in.
Bye.
Wait.
You haven't changed.
I know.
I'll keep a close eye on you.
Are you okay?
You can tell if you see her...
when she is alone.
She does look like she has changed.
No.
She hasn't changed. Eun Hee.
She's still a crazy woman.
This woman...
won't change.
I know.
She'll never change.
I...
Jae Bok.
She's been too nervous and not sleeping.
She finally fainted.
Everything is because of Eun Hee.
Jae Bok was always so strong before.
It's all my fault.
It's all my fault...
for Jae Bok to suffer like that.
I'm the only person...
who can correct this.
If I want to protect Jae Bok and the kids,
I need to step up. I must stop Eun Kyung.
Even if I become the sacrificial
lamb and disappear,
I must act like a real dad if I want...
to protect my family.
Jung Hee.
Eun Kyung.
Are you moving back in?
You couldn't trust me.
I was worried about you.
Jung Hee.
I'll stay...
by your side.
Thank you, Jung Hee.
Thank you.
I love you.
(SI Construction)
Mr. Koo! I made a huge mistake!
I only did as they told me to from above.
I'm sure you did.
You lead a difficult life too.
(Chief Director Koo Jung Hee)
I won't spy on you anymore.
I got rid of them all.
I fired Mr. Ha too.
And I won't have you tailed.
I won't put a GPS tracker on you.
Whatever you do, I'll trust you.
Because I love you.
Thank you, Eun Kyung, for trusting me.
I'm going to cut all ties with Jae Bok now.
I won't see the kids anymore either.
I'll live only for you, Eun Kyung.
Jung Hee.
Let the two of us...
be happy now.
Okay, Jung Hee.
Okay. Lets...
live happily ever after.
I love you.
It's June 15. I'm starting
a secret diary from today.
This is my confession diary as well as...
What is all of this?
When will you ever learn how to keep house?
It will become...
- my observation log on Eun Kyung.
- Yes, Mother.
- Did you sleep well?
- Yes.
Have a nice day at work.
Did you sleep well, Mother?
Why is my room so dry? My throat's all dry.
Get me an air purifier.
- Mother.
- I can't tell if her mental illness...
is cured.
I'll go buy one right away. I'm sorry.
The most I can do for Jae Bok,
Jin Wook and Hae Wook...
is to keep monitoring Eun Kyung...
and stop her madness.
(Jae Bok)
Hello?
Jung Hee. Did you move
back into Eun Hee's house?
Are you insane?
Eun Hee improved a lot.
- She's not like before.
- You hope she's better.
She didn't get better.
You're in danger. Move out right away.
Are you doing okay?
I'm not okay, but your doing this...
is driving me insane.
What if something happens
while living with Eun Kyung?
What about the kids?
Even if something happens,
- there's nothing I can do.
- What?
Jung Hee. Are you still unable...
to forfeit your greed?
Is living in luxury that important?
Enough to live on edge with that woman?
Yes, I guess so.
Jae Bok.
Jung Hee.
How did this happen to you?
You won't listen to anything I say anymore.
I think you've gone crazy too.
That's right.
I may have been crazy from a long time ago.
That's why I ended up here.
Jae Bok. Why did you come
here without telling me?
I heard you moved into Eun Hee's house.
Yes. I did.
You really are incredible.
Jung Hee.
I can't...
do anything with you anymore.
Still...
You're still my friend.
Call me if anything happens.
Always be careful.
- Jae Bok.
- Bong Goo.
Take good care of her.
I know I'm shameless, but our kids too.
You won't even call anymore?
No. That's the plan.
So don't contact me again.
What's this?
Jae Bok.
They say Jung Hee has
been careless with work,
and that he has no drive anymore.
I'm worried he's thinking
of doing something drastic.
Did he say anything?
Even if something happens,
there's nothing I can do.
Why do you think something happened?
Call him.
(Jae Bok)
He isn't answering?
He's such a pain.
I'll ring the doorbell then. Okay?
I'll ring the bell.
(Jae Bok)