I am Sakuma Manabu,
of Kaio Academy.
I am here to play table tennis
against Tsukimoto!
Aren't you worried about Sakuma?
He knows non-competition games
are against club rules.
If he plays one and loses,
he's off the team.
I'll play, but you'll lose.
Listen to this!
He'll lose.
What did you say?
Sakuma's going to lose.
Tsukimoto's in there!
Not now!
But he's so cool!
What's happening?
Yuck! It's Hoshino!
Want some sour chips?
They're excellent.
'Suppamucho'.
I thought you quit ping-pong.
I didn't quit living.
Well?
Give this to Tsukimoto for me.
Roger.
After I check it.
Why?!
'Do you have a girlfriend?...
No!
Hattori Mako, Grade 10C!
'Mako Hattori'!
Change serve!
To Kaio Academy.
Damn it!!
Where did I go wrong?
I can't watch this!
Sorry.
Demon! Leave Smile alone!
But he's lousy!
He'll get better with practice.
Practice won't help him!
I don't care.
21-7. Game, Tsukimoto.
Aw, shit!
Why?!
Why is it you and not me?!
I've tried!
Ten, a hundred, ten thousand
times harder than you have!
To impress Mr Kazama...
to beat Peco...
I've lived and breathed
table tennis!
So why is it you?!
You just don't have the talent.
What?!
That's all it is. It's nothing to
start screaming over.
You can go now.
Bye-bye.
Hey!
Where do you think
you're going?
you're going I said!
Wherever the hell I want to!
Where am I going, huh?
Tell me!
Kazama
Rise to Buddha, old buddy.
Home it!
We were just warming up.
I asked for some better balls
to practise with, didn't I?
Oh, yeah... they're on order.
You said that last week.
Look, we can't spend the whole
club budget on you.
What else are we buying?
Hey wait! Tsukimoto!
There's Peco!
Why don't you come any more?
Come and teach us!
Girls don't go for ping-pong players.
There's a guy
there who chops!
A chopper?
The guy with the glasses.
Smile?
Nope.
But an old friend's an old friend.
There!
Gee!
Idiot!
That chop wouldn't cut tofu.
You're right.
See? I'm teaching myself.
I'm totally impressed.
I had to drop out of school but
I want to give it my best shot.
But this watch-and-wait
kind of game...
...just doesn't suit me.
Some birds can't fly.
Keep playing.
You've got the gift.
I'm talking about you, Peco.
Do I know you?
You've got an instinct
for the game.
Bullshit.
The fact is that you beat me
and Smile beat you.
So do something about it.
Go screw yourself.
There are things
only a hack player knows.
I'll say this once.
Run till you puke blood.
Practise till you piss blood.
You'll feel better.
If you don't...
...you'll let down the ones
who've always admired you...
...me and Smile.
Haven't seen him.
Coaching is more than just
teaching technique.
Aw, shuddup.
It's trial and error.
I've bust my ass over him.
That's why he took off.
If there's no love in it,
you'd better leave him alone.
Young man!
Don't do it, son.
It's not worth it.
I had a bad day at the track.
All I've got is Y60...
...but I'm not giving up.
What'll your parents think
if you die?
Die?
Yeah. You'll never amount
to anything if you're dead.
I'm not going to die.
No?
I'm going to fly.
Yeah? Great!
I can touch the moon
no problem!
That's the spirit!
Did I make you do that?!
Are you strong?
...taste iron in blood.
Hey, Peco...
... do you believe in heroes?
You're still here?
A coach isn't a coach...
...without a player.
Next time I'll kick your ass.
Now I remember...
...the one time...
...that Smile smiled.
This isn't a barber shop.
Show me again, will you?
Right from how you grip the racket.
5:04...no good! Do it again!
Granny!
What?
I said from how you grip
the racket, didn't I?
Yep.
When do I start hitting?
I've been running for two weeks.
Until you beat three minutes.
Do it again.
Nice day.
Don't you have...
...someone to pack you a lunch
on a sunny day like this?
I've got a girlfriend.
Just kidding. You don't have to
be surprised like that.
Wanna go out?
Tsukimoto!
Hey, Tsukimoto! Hi!
Isn't this fun, Mr Tsukimoto?
Are you having fun?
If you're having fun, smile!
I would if I was.
You would, huh?
Damn right!
Stop puking!
You'll hurt my feelings!
I'm your honey! Get up here
and put your arms around me.
Stop puking!
Butterfly Joe?
Yep. 30 years ago,
he was one of the best.
Was he really good?
Not just good.
He was beautiful to watch.
No one could touch him. He was
the king of Japanese table tennis.
He was a shoo-in
for the national team...
But...
...I had a friend I'd hit against
ever since I could remember.
He was really good...
...but if we were both
in good shape...
...I'd beat him.
A knee injury...
They said to take
six months off.
So you defaulted?
I would have.
But it was my friend
who had the bad knee.
I don't get it.
You could've played him deep
then hit to his backhand.
Could you do that?
Would you take advantage
of a friend's injury...
...and risk ending his career?
Could you do that?
That was my last game.
Let's go.
Coach...
...I've always wanted
to ride that thing.
Well? Did I do it?
I did? I didn't?
Back to the dojo!
I did it!
Three minutes!
Am I awesome or what!
You're great.
We make a great couple!
I love you a whole bunch!
Here...
What you've been waiting for.
You're losing it, Granny.
There's rubber on the back, too.
I'm not losing it. That means
you can turn it over to hit.
I thought you'd forgotten.
We'd just come to the end of
last year's budget.
Plus I didn't know
where to order them.
Will you hit against me
for a bit?
You'd better ask Coach Koizumi.
The Inter-High's getting close.
I'll go easy.
These are good.
It's not the same.
Now for some spin...
Damn!
That's enough!
No!
Tsukimoto! Shouldn't you
be warming up?
Is he listening?
You'll be late!
Who's my first game?
Don't leave on me
when you find out.
Why do I have to draw China first?
I seriously want to go home!
I'm not losing it.
Placement, control, speed...
...Tsukimoto's in another league.
Hmm?
Oh, Kong Wenge...
He's gotten better this year, too.
He's headed for the top.
I wonder...
He could lose here.
16-20.
Yes!
Alright!
You remember?
The first time we played,
you didn't win a point.
Thanks, Kong.
I learned something from you.
You taught me how to fly.
There!
The back side!
Game! Hoshino!
That's my boy!
Check it out, China.
You might catch me in 300 years!
Hey! You're in a game.
Sorry.
Get a move on, will you?!
Hurry up, Muko,
or I'll leave you here!
Hey, Manabu...there's
a swimming tournament, too.
You can go jump in
with them, then.
What's the matter?
I just said there's swimming.
Swimmers have meets,
not tournaments!
I should've gone to Europe.
Sweden, or Germany...
But I chose Japan...
Say hello to Kazama.
Hoshino
Kong
I could cry...
What?
Did your friend win?
Hello, Mr Kazama.
It's Sakuma.
Sakuma Manabu.
I'm not going to let you...
...show up my school!
How have you been, Sakuma?
What?
I'm doing alright.
Mr Sanada never quits, does he?
If there's one guy he doesn't
want to lose to, it's Tsukimoto.
Sakuma...
...competition is there to show
who's best.
If you say so.
It doesn't matter who says so.
Now that I've quit table tennis,
I finally understand...
...why you shut yourself away
in here.
Funny, huh?
Who do you play for anyway?
Myself, of course.
You're kidding, of course.
If you mean that...
...I was wasting my time.
Be seeing you.
Sakuma!
Do you feel betrayed?
I sympathize.
What's the matter?
Have you got diarrhea?
There's more than diarrhea
that drives a man to the toilet.
What do you mean?
Stay there.
I need to cry a little.
Game, set! Hoshino,
Katase High School.
Semi-final Round
Game, set! Tsukimoto,
Katase High School.
You're in the final!
Way to go, Smile!
Uh...'Tsukimoto'.
Where's Peco?
In the medical room.
His knee's pretty bad.
Aren't you worried about him?
The man's a machine!
I like it... how cool he is.
No problem, baby. Check it out.
I had it retaped, and I got a
shot of pain-killer.
You don't know what
a bad knee can do.
Excuse me... it's time for
your semi-final.
I'm coming.
No, he's not.
Listen, Peco... I know how bad
you want to play Kazama.
But if you want to be the best
in the world someday...
...you've got to have the guts
to raise the white flag.
Smile's calling me.
He's been waiting
for a long time.
For ages and ages...
...he's believed in me.
I knew it,
but I pretended I didn't.
It scared me.
I covered my ears against it.
But he's waiting for me.
Peco...
...I love you, kid.
Stand back! Stand back!
Competitor coming through!
Stand back, stand back! There's
a player coming through.
Do you believe in heroes?
Heroes?
You OK?
Your knee...
I don't know if it'll hold up.
But you're a high-flier.
Way high up there.
So I'll just climb your back,
stand on your shoulders and...
...fly.
A hero shows up in the clutch...
...and saves me, no matter
how deep a hole I'm in.
That's a hero.
Here goes!
After I beat you,
go out and get...
...a haircut.
Go get some hair.
I really need to take a piss!
He jumped over to his backhand.
He won't admit that Hoshino's good.
Amazing!
Nice shot.
But...
...you won't be there forever
looking down at everyone.
'Enter the hero.'
I'm the hero.
It's me.
He comes back.
My name is...
...Hoshino...
...Yutaka!
Remember that!
15-2.
What's wrong...
...'hero'?
What's wrong?
Aren't you the hero?
Can't you fly?!
He thinks he's fated to win.
Maybe for Kazama...
...table tennis is pain.
There's a strength in that.
Looks like Peco made him mad.
The back!
Use the back!
Right!
Kid!
Don't go pulling
those cheap trick shots on me!
It sucks!
First game's yours, Dragon boy.
Love you, man.
Game, Kazama!
Does it hurt?
You're a nice guy.
So why not give me this game?
Clown!
You asked!
Right?
Left?
Stop thinking, Peco!
Not that way!
I can't keep this up!!
Oh, man...
...here we go again!
Ow!
Shit!
Help me!
Please!
Enter the hero!
Is he good?
Yeah.
Table tennis incarnate.
You can have fun here.
Your knee's no problem.
Listen to it.
Can you fly?
What's going on?
Don't ask me.
Hey!
I'm ready to roll!
What?
The speed of sound!!
The speed of light!!
Yes!
And beyond.
Faster!
Back!!
I get it...
The hero...
Game, Hoshino!
Kazama's in trouble.
Maybe.
Don't fall back.
Play up!
Shut up!
You bother me!
Kazama's smiling!
Hoshino's not sticking to one pattern.
It's like he's playing
for the sheer joy of it.
Yeah.
Playing someone like that...
...is fantastic.
Match point, Dragon.
You're going to win?
What the hell.
It was fun.
I like it here.
Bring me here again...
...'hero'.
You guys haven't
changed a bit!
You sure have.
That kid with
the bangs was cool!
Yeah.
You're not jealous?
You're no fun!
Final:
Tsukimoto vs. Hoshino
And now, the 2001 Inter-High
Men's Table Tennis Final.
Captain Ota...
...is Hoshino's knee OK?
He's coming.
I see.
So who should we cheer for?
Both of them of course!
You cheer whenever there's a point.
But...
You can yell, Ota.
Tsukimoto!
What's with you?
Tsukimoto... I probably
don't have to say this...
I'll play to win.
I'm not like you, 'Butterfly Joe'.
You're the best player
I've ever seen.
Stand aside! Stand aside!
Competitor coming through!
Viva!
You're late.
Don't be like that.
I'm here to kick your ass.
The final match!
Hoshino, Katase High,
vs. Tsukimoto, Katase High!
I'm getting too old
to stand and watch.
Yeah.
And it doesn't matter
who wins.
Get Hoshino to a hospital
when this is over, OK?
I know.
Go, go, Hoshino!
Push, push, Hoshino!
Go, go, Tsukimoto!
Push, push, Tsukimoto!
Let's go, buddy!
Welcome back, hero.
Smile...
...don't squeeze the ball
when you serve.
And hold it up
above the table.
It has to bounce here first.
Try it.
OK.
I'll try it.
Don't swing so far.
Take the ball, gently...
Bring your arm down, and hit.
Hit it well forward...
...as it's rising.
OK? Can you do that?
You try it.
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
Thank you, Peco.
'Mr Peco', please.
Enter the hero!