And don't worry about the prompter.
- You got a lot of lights in here, I'm just--
- Recording.
Let's go. Okay, right down the lens.
He was scoring--
Tell us the story. ESPN.
- Recording.
- Now?
Yeah. Recording. Okay, loosen up.
Just go for it.
Just go for it, George.
The Los Angeles Galaxy came into
Washington today and beat DC United.
Gotta say, whats going on
with DC United nowadays?
Danny Allsopp brought his A-game,
scoring a bicycle kick goal off the corner...
...but he and the rest of
the black and red...
...couldn't put a stop to a particularly
ferocious and unstoppable Galaxy attack:
Landon Donovan, the Galaxy captain
and lean, mean scoring machine.
Landon, you went to sleep
after the World Cup for a few months...
...but you're out of bed now
and I gotta say you go, Landon.
Go on with your bad striker self.
And that's it for tonight.
Back to you, Denise.
Yes.
Look at you, huh? How good was that?
I enjoyed that.
That was fun.
You enjoyed it?
I really enjoyed that, George.
- Really, and you looked great.
- Thank you.
So how different was that
from coaching soccer?
That's a good question.
I mean, looking after 13 kids
is not exactly a piece of cake.
Well, they say the parents require
the most work. What do you think?
I guess I would take that
on a parent-by-parent basis.
And the moms?
A single dad like yourself...
...do you find that a distraction
or inspiration?
I would have to take that
on a mom-by-mom basis.
And what about me?
Distraction or inspiration?
Listen, it's getting late.
I gotta go pick up Lewis.
- We should get going.
- Yeah.
Listen to me, I gotta-- I can't.
It's not as if I'm not leaving my family,
George.
I'm just looking for laughs.
We're back. Hi. Hi, sweetie.
Hey, buddy. Hey, champ.
Sorry we ran on a little long.
You ready to go?
Yeah, okay? All right.
- Bye, George.
- Bye. Bye, Samantha.
Come on, it's late. Let's go.
- Wonderful. it's 11:15, George.
- I know.
But we had fun, didn't we, champ?
Yeah.
Yeah,
I got that audition as a sportscaster...
...but it was just a little bit last minute.
That's good. That's good.
I'm glad for you.
It's all right. No one got hurt.
Everyone's home safe.
Okay. Good night, George.
- All right. Good night, Matt.
- Good night.
You're gonna have to explain to me
what you saw in that guy.
Mr. George, can you explain how you
drive a fancy car and still owe money?
Yeah. No, I can't actually.
The thing is...
No, there is no thing. There is only rent.
If I don't have by tomorrow--
Shit. I'm so sorry.
Sorry, one second.
- Hello?
- Hi, George.
-It's Pam.
- Patti, Mrs. King Patti?
Yes, yes, George. It's Mrs. King.
Listen, can I call you back?
You can talk to me when you get home.
I'm in your bed, George.
I'm sorry. Where are you?
I'm in your bed.
This is quite some room.
It's a little Mid Eastern for my taste,
but I must say your closets are fabulous.
Wait, wait, Patti, wait. Wait, Param!
Don't-- Param, come here a second.
- I don't think that you're in my bedroom.
- What?
No, you think that you're in my bedroom,
but you're in my landlord's bedroom.
Oh, my God.
- Where are you?
- In the guest house across the driveway.
Patti, just get out of there now, okay?
Mr. George.
Param? Okay, yeah.
I'm sorry I didn't sort you out before,
but I forgot I left the cash in my Ferrari.
- So how much is it?
-900.
-900? Cash is good, yeah?
- Yeah.
That's 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6--
- It's a beautiful night, huh? 7, 8.
- Yeah.
- How much did you say?
-900.
9-- 900. There you go.
All right, buddy.
I'll probably see you around,
maybe tomorrow or something.
- Okay, no, no, no. Out.
- In.
- You know that I can't do this.
- Oh, stop it.
He lent you his Ferrari.
He's more possessive of that than of me.
Whatever it is you got going on with
your husband, I want you to know...
...I consider him a friend.
I need you to put your clothes back on
and just leave.
- You're gonna tell him, aren't you?
- No. God, no. I'm not gonna tell him.
Okay, if you go now, just go home,
there's nothing to tell.
- Mrs. King, you're not moving.
- I'm starting to feel a bit foolish.
Oh, no, no. No reason to feel foolish.
Just go.
You have no idea what he might do.
He's very vindictive, George.
That's the point I'm trying to make here.
He's gonna ask me where I was
and I'm not a very good liar.
I think I just need one drink.
Okay. One drink.
There you go.
Well, aren't you gonna have one?
Just leave.
I need to use the bathroom.
You don't know how many times
he's cheated on me.
And I can't even do unfaithful right.
Mrs. King? You are a smart...
...a strong, beautiful woman.
And I personally think...
...that you shouldn't stay in a marriage
that you're not happy in.
Oh, shit. That's probably Carl.
What? Carl knows you're here?
- Yeah. Sometimes he has me followed.
- What?
He thinks I might cheat on him.
Okay, okay. Stay in there, okay?
And don't come out.
Par-am'?
Mr. George"...
...you gave me an extra hundred.
Yeah, thanks.
Mr. George, how do you meet
all these beautiful women?
Well, maybe it's the accent.
I have an accent too.
- George. George, I was looking for you.
- Oh, hey, how's it going?
Well, it turns out I'm not the only person
who thought you had style.
My old station manager edited your tape.
He's gonna send it to Bristol.
He thinks you have a shot.
- Wait, you serious?
- I'm serious.
- Bristol, Connecticut?
- Yeah.
- Just don't forget the girl who said it first.
- No, no, I won't.
Oh, George?
When you're out there today
and you see me tug my ear like this.
That means I'm imagining you
on top of me.
ORE?
Well, I better get back to the game,
all right'?
- Well, you have a great game.
- Okay.
Hey. Hey, what's going on?
- What's going on? You all right?
- Nothing.
All right, Lewis. Here, your bag.
Move forward, Scott.
- Yeah, take it in.
- Come on, Cyclones.
Use the mind, use the wing.
Nice one. Watch your man.
Nice play, Lewis. There you go.
- Hey, hey.
- Hi, coach, it's me.
I'm kind of busy.
I'd say everything's great
except for this silly grin...
...I can't seem to get off of my face
since the other night.
Listen, I can't really talk.
I hope that it's not awkward between us.
We're both adults, single.
And if it happens, great.
If not ifs really only what's best
for the kids, right?
I'm a little busy right now,
but, I mean, we could...
- It was Lewis!
- Yes!
Well done, kiddo.
Lewis, well done, champ.
Well done.
- That was great.
- Didn't even see it!
All right, come on, Cyclones.
Let's go, let's get another one.
All right, come on.
Let's get another one.
Come on, Cyclones.
Nine.
What the hell was that?
What are you playing at?
Is this about last night?
- What's the matter?
- Leave me alone!
I hate soccer, and I hate you!
- Hello'?
- He doesn't hate me, right?
No, of course he doesn't hate you.
But he does want to quit the team,
George. Do you know that?
You know, I'm a bit lost at sea here,
Stace.
I was thinking maybe you could
give me some parenting tips.
Basic dos and don'ts.
Don't let your 10-year-old son
drive a Ferrari, that kind of thing?
- My son has a big mouth, you know.
- Honest. He gets that from me.
I'm serious.
Can we meet for a drink maybe?
No. Absolutely not.
We can meet for coffee, though.
- Dinner.
- Lunch.
- Early dinner.
- Late lunch.
- I'm not budging on dinner.
- I'm not the one asking for advice.
Are you sure, no beer?
Well, so I read about this place online.
The true Virginia experience, it says.
Apparently, you have to really like,
you know, beat the stuffing out of it...
...you know, to get to the good stuff.
All right, okay, you get it. Good?
According to the Internet,
there's a real kick to the seasoning.
I don't know,
maybe the Internet was wrong.
Oh, here, here.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
Waitress, two beers, please.
Three more beers, please.
So I fall down the stairs, I stubbed my toe,
and I scream, "Shit."
And then the next five days...
...Lewis is going around the house
going, "Shit, shit, shit."
I get it. Okay.
Even when it's hard, even when
you want to be anywhere but there...
...even when you feel like he doesn't
need you, trust me, he does.
Here.
What? Where?
- You have some crab on your cheek.
- Crap?
- Crab. Crab, on your cheek.
- Crab. Okay.
- Crab lips.
- Gross.
You're the only woman I ever really loved.
- Stop it.
- No, I'm serious. I'm serious.
You know what I miss the most?
In the early years, when I used to play
and you were in the stands watching me.
After every game, I would look for you
and I would wave to you. Remember?
And no matter how badly I played
how massively I screwed up...
...I always knew when you waved
back at me, everything would be all right.
I mean, I felt like the most special person
in the world when you did that.
Until I'd look behind and six other women
were all waving back along with me.
I was young then.
You know, I'm different now.
Okay, so prove that to Lewis.
- He hates me, remember?
- He doesn't hate you.
He just hates being disappointed,
and you've done that a lot, okay?
I mean, he was 4 when you left,
remember?
You weren't even there before that.
It was easier when you were an absentee
daddy sending gifts, but now you're here.
And I'm sorry
if you take offense to this...
...but you're a time bomb
with a charming accent...
...and when you explode, it's like:
You know, boom. Chaos.
I hope you came back for him.
I really do.
Nothing would make me happier.
But if you came back for me...
...you're wasting our time, and you're
gonna break his heart in the process.
- I gotta go.
- All right.
Hey, thanks for lunch.
Hey, kiddo.
So your mom was saying you were
thinking of quitting the team.
I just want to say, I think that would be...
I think that would be a big mistake.
What's the point? I'm not good anyway.
No, see, I don't agree with that.
You may have your mom's looks
and her smarts...
...but you're a Dryer kid
and you play soccer.
It's in your blood.
I was thinking maybe we'd go
down to the park now...
...and gel a practice session in
before the big game.
What do you say?
Okay.
Dad, ifs raining.
It's just a sprinkle.
It'll be over before you know it.
-It's just typical.
- What do you mean, "typical"?
Nothing ever works out for our family.
What are you talking about?
Plenty of stuff works out.
This is the best time
to learn how to play soccer.
Because in the rain, like this...
...if you can play in this,
you can play in anything, right?
There you go.
Don't worry, Stace,
I'm sure they'll be fine.
I'm just gonna see if they're all right.
- Do you want me to come? I can drive.
- No. I'm fine.
All right, one, two.
And you're gonna do this one now.
Like this.
- Okay.
- Okay? There you go.
That's it.
I think I finally got all of that mud
out of my ear.
What about you?
Lewis?
You had a big day.
- Another good result, buddy, huh?
- Yeah.
A great goal coming in from the left.
He?
He?'
How was the game?
- Mom, I scored a goal.
- You did?
- We won again.
- Nice work, kiddo.
- How was last night?
- Yeah, it was really good.
- Good.
- Hey, Dad?
Me and Mom are going to the arcade
today. Wanna come?
- No, I'm gonna let you guys go on with it.
- Mom, can he come?
Well, yeah, I mean,
you're welcome to come if you want.
Okay.
Yeah! Yeah!
- You're playing like a baby.
- You're hitting like a girl.
Young Dryer.
Two shots? Accident.
Let's get rid of him.
Oh, yes!
Hey, Mom, did you know that Dad
once took the ball off of Beckham?
Oh, yeah, I know, actually.
I was there.
I wanna play like Beckham.
Hey.
What, you don't want to play like me?
Yes!
God, it seems like so long ago,
doesn't it?
Yeah.
So the big day's coming up, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
- Are you excited?
- Yeah. Yeah, of course I am.
It's just crazy.
I just never thought
I'd be doing this again.
Stacie's getting married.
- Hey, Dad?
- Yeah?
Can I have a sleepover
at your house again tonight?
It's not my night, buddy.
It's your mom's.
Yeah. Sure. Fine with me.
You wanna see my room?
Yeah.
Yeah, of course I want to see your room.
It's not as big as my room at home,
but I like it.
Yeah.
It is way cooler than I thought.
You know that's me, Mom.
Yeah, I know that's you.
- You see this?
- That? Who's that?
- You.
- Me?
- And me.
- You.
Dad.
And Dad, huh? You, me, and Dad.
- He okay?
- Yeah. Fast asleep.
Some wine?
Oh, no, no.
I should probably get going.
- Fun day though, huh?
- Yeah. Yeah.
So who gets the teddy bear?
Does he make you laugh, Stace?
Like really make you laugh?
Yeah.
It's so weird...
...but sometimes I just...
I look at you and it feels like
nothing ever changed.
Like we're still together.
I look at your face, and I--
I realize how lucky I was
to ever have you.
And it kills me that I can't just
reach out and talk to you anymore.
L-- I can't. I can't do this.
Stacie. Stacie, hold on a second.
Hey, hey. Stacie.
You don't have to go.
- Hey.
- Hey, I thought you'd be home later.
No, I grabbed an earlier flight.
Where were you?
I was just dropping Lewis off at his dad's.
Oh, it's not his night, is it?
No. But he wanted to go,
and I thought it was fine.
Who's that?
My mom. Last-minute invites.
Hey, hey, hey. You okay?
- I'm fine.
- You are?
You hungry?
Hey, Denise. What's up?
I am. So you want some good news?
I could certainly
do with some right now.
Okay, good news coming at you
in three, two...
- I like the look, George.
- Yeah?
So, what did you want to tell me?
Well, you gonna some closer?
No, no, no. The last time I came closer
I got myself in trouble.
Which was just fine.
ESPN liked your tape.
They did?
Liked as in liked?
They want to fly you up there
to see you personally.
ESPN? ESP-bloody-N?
- You did it, George.
- That's amazing.
You're on your way.
Thank you so much.
All right. Okay, okay.
I gotta get--
I gotta get back inside.
So that's all I get? That's it?
I help you out,
you just leave me hanging?
I just can't.
I just can't do this anymore.
I gotta grow up.
I got a boy in there
who needs me to start being a father.
Well...
...you have no idea
what you're missing.
I think I do,
which is why I gotta go back inside.
All right.
That's it?
Lewis?
Hey, buddy.
Hey.
You Okay?
Hey, what's the matter?
- You having a bad dream?
- No.
I just want to sleep in here.
Yeah?
Okay.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
I love you.
Come here.
Please don't leave again.
- Mr. Dryer?
- Yeah, I'm George.
I'm Ellen. I work with Mr. Minion.
You ready?
Yeah, I'm ready.
All right.
They're waiting for you in the studio.
- Right this way.
- Okay.
- Hey. George Dryer. How's it going?
- Good, nice to meet you.
I heard you were coming.
I know you're gonna kill it.
Get out there and make it happen.
Thank you, buddy.
I appreciate it.
In Group E, Cameroon went down
2-1 to the Netherlands.
The Dutch team are appearing as strong
contenders, taking 9 points out of 9...
...and moving on past the group phase
to face Slovakia.
Not moving on are the French...
The French.
What happened to the French?
They came, they saw, they bitched,
they fought, half the management quit.
The rest of the team went on strike,
lost, and went home.
I may be giving the French a hard time,
but it does lead to a point.
Now I've been honored and lucky enough
to play for both club and country...
...and I can tell you
that to stand on a field...
...and score a goal in front of
50-, 70-, 100,000 fans...
...to feel the ground shake beneath you.
It's unbeatable.
And whether you're on that field
or whether you're part of that crowd...
...there's no feeling like it,
and that to me is soccer.
George Dryer...
...welcome to ESPN.
- Hello?
- Oh, hey, Matt.
I was looking for Stacie. Is she there?
Oh, hey, George. No, she's actually--
Went to get fitted for her wedding dress.
Okay, buddy. Thanks.
- Hi, can I help you?
- No, I'm okay. I'll just be a minute.
Hi.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm sorry. It's not cool.
It's not.
You can't come in here like this-
I know, I know. Stacie, the timing's
always off with me. I mean--
-ls everything okay?
- Yeah. it's fine. Just give us a minute.
I'm either too early, or I'm too late.
That's why I came.
In a couple of weeks,
I'm gonna be too late again.
Stop, George, stop.
Why are you doing this to me?
I'm moving to Connecticut.
I got that job.
- You got the job?
- I did, yeah.
You know, and they gave me this book
on things to do in Connecticut.
And I'm looking at the chapter
on family life and parks and schools...
...and I'm thinking, what's the point?
What is the point if I don't have my family
with me, if I don't have you with me?
Stacie...
...I want you and Lewis to come with me.
No.
I can't just pick up and go to Connecticut.
I can't, not with a 9-year-old.
- Yes, you can. Yes, you can.
- No. No.
I know that I haven't given you
any good reason to trust me.
But I swear to God
everything's gonna be all right.
I'm gonna make a life for us there.
God, I love you so much.
Oh, George, if you love me...
...let me go.
Let me go.
Excuse me?
I think the lady's waiting for you outside.
Oh, damn you, George.
I know. I know, I know.
I meant everything I said.
Please, don't touch me.
Please don't.
If I want to be touched, I'll tell you.
Okay, my hands are here.
This is on my pace.
This cannot be on your pace.
- Okay, this is not all about you.
- Okay.
Okay. On your pace.
Whatever you say.
ORE?
Why couldn't you have just come back
two months later?
Because my timing's always bad.
You know that.
That's a couple that can really talk.
I really don't think he's the groom.
- Hello?
- Hey.
Mom, we should've left already.
I know, I know. I'm sorry.
Two minutes, okay?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Buddy, let's go get your bag
and get ready.
We should probably
have been there already.
I know. I know. Sorry. Okay.
- So do we have a wedding dress?
- It zips. That's as much as I can tell you.
A bride to soccer mom in two seconds.
All right, beautiful.
Hey, coach.
Looks like we have a friend in common.
It's the accent.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey, champ.
- You doing all right?
- Yeah.
I looked up my horoscope,
and it said “You're gonna be victorious."
Well, we should be okay, huh?
- Hey, coach.
- Hey. Hi, everybody.
Hi. Hi, everybody.
Hey, coach.
Let's get the show on the road.
Okay, so it's the final game
of the season, okay?
- If we win this, we win the championship.
- Yeah.
Yeah?
And no matter what happens today...
...I want you to know
you've made me proud.
But we're gonna get out there
and win this game, yeah?
Yeah!
Let's give it everything we've got
and get these wankers.
Yeah!
One, two, three...
Go, Cyclones!
Yeah!
Well done, Ally.
Cyclones. Cyclones. Cyclones.
Yeah!
Good job, Hunter.
Don't let them play like this.
- Don't worry about it.
- Now we got a game on.
Now we can concentrate.
All right, let's go. Keep it together.
Go, go, go. Don't let them--
Okay, not a problem.
Let's move it forward.
Close them down.
Samantha, let's see some playing,
okay?
Just keep pushing forward.
Come on, guys.
Let's talk to each other.
Lewis, make a difference.
Push it down the line.
Go, Lewis. Take the shot.
Come on, Lewis.
That's it, go ahead, take it to the goal.
There you go, Lewis.
Go, Lewis!
Yes. Yes, Lewis.
Yes!
Cyclones. Cyclones. Cyclones.
Two minutes, Cyclones.
Let's finish this off.
Hey, Carl.
I was wondering where you got to.
Let's push forward, Cyclones.
Come on.
Hey, I got a little gift for you.
- Postcards from a great season.
- That's thoughtful. Thank you.
- Open it up. Take a look.
- No, after the game.
Why don't you look at it now, George?
Come on, folks. One minute left.
Now that is my divorce attorney's
favorite.
George, I thought I had mentioned
that I hire people to keep tabs on Patti.
- That slipped your mind?
- Buddy, you know what, I may be a shit.
I'm a bigger shit
than even you dreamed of.
But you don't know me.
I wouldn't sleep with your wife.
Go, go, go!
Dog pile!
It's not what it looks like.
It never is.
Good luck in Connecticut.
He?
He?'
So I thought I'd come say goodbye.
Okay.
Well, good luck, George.
Hey, Dad.
Hey.
I thought maybe you and I could
take a walk. What do you say'? Yeah?
Okay.
So I'm not gonna see you anymore?
You're gonna see me.
Of course you're gonna see me.
We're onna have weekends.
I'm gonna come back...
...and you can come and visit me
in Connecticut.
Hey, I got something for you.
Remember this?
That's the first medal I ever won
with Celtic.
Yeah.
You're gonna win your own someday,
but you can keep that warm for me.
- I'll miss you, son.
- I'm gonna miss you, too, Dad.
Come here.
- We're gonna talk on the phone, okay?
- Okay.
You're gonna call.
And you're gonna write me.
Okay.
Okay, I gotta go.
All right, buddy.
- He'll be okay.
- Yeah.
Stace? Hey. Hey.
Look, I'm not stupid.
We've been together three years,
so I think that you owe me the truth.
Do you still love him?
I've never stopped loving him.
Dad.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was on my way...
...and I suddenly thought
what if I wake up tomorrow morning...
...and I want to take another walk
with you? You know?
Yeah, but what about your job?
Well, I don't have it all worked out...
...but I figure if I'm good enough for them,
gotta be good enough for someone here.
You're really here to stay this time?
Yeah. I'm really hereto stay.
Come on.
Let's go play some soccer, all right?
Okay.
All right, come on.
Come on, here you go.
Mom, Dad came home.
You gave up the job?
Someone very smart once told me
you just have to be there.
I called off the wedding.
Why?
Because someone kind of stupid
got in my head.
I can live with that.
Wanna play?
- Yeah. Wanna play?
- Yeah. I wanna play.
Okay. Let's go.
All right, Lewis. Come on.
Here you go.
--And speaking of time, we are out of it.
We'll see you tomorrow night
with the next George and Chip show.
And he means
the Chip and George show.
I thought we agreed it sounded better if
we called it the George then Chip show?
But that was before we had the logo.
Logo says Chip and George.
Yeah, the Chip and George and Chip.