This film is based on historic events
The Hague, 1945
shortly after World War II
Mr. H.A.M.T. Kolfschoten,
Minister of Justice (Catholic party)
The case Oss.
Oss.
A conflict between the MP,
the priests, the mayor.
Corruption, abuse of power,
excessive crime.
Minister Goseling took some
peculiar measures at the time...
and the entire cabinet resigned, just
before the invasion of the Germans.
Am I supposed to read all of this?
We could also throw it away.
Fine.
The Gang of Oss
They call them the Gang of Oss,
but they're just a bunch of misfits.
They steal from the rich
and give to the poor. Sometimes.
Wim de Kuiper thinks he's the boss.
Harry den Brock, his counsellor,
is the only one who can read.
Van Schijndel, a local cop,
looks the other way.
If you pay him, that is. And why not?
Everybody here is corrupt.
Father De Roos sins
while taking confession.
Father Bakker does the altar boys
and washes his hands in innocence.
In Oss the fires of purgatory are lit
to rip off the insurance company.
The government, based in the north...
sent the MP to us in the south,
to set things right.
Protestants.
It's not as if we're such devout
Catholics, but we hate Protestants.
Most of us here work for the meat Jew.
Sal Hedeman doesn't talk to male staff.
But he talks to the women
in packaging. I work there too.
At night I work behind the bar.
We don't have a license,
but they drink anyway.
I'm Black Mien's daughter
and a half sister of Trees.
Mum isn't really sure
about who our fathers are.
I learned a lot from my mum.
They don't call me
Johanna the Tramp for nothing.
- 100 guilders?
- For bodily injury it's 100 guilders.
You need to make sacrifices
for a new bike.
No, like you had it before.
Like that, like that.
We needed that as evidence.
I'll take care of it with the doctor.
I get out in two weeks.
For good behaviour.
You wouldn't have thought, huh?
- We're going to do things differently.
- Sure.
I'm going to quit drinking,
fighting and burglary.
I'm going to get a regular job
with the meat Jew.
I'm only sticking my knife
in a cow or a pig.
- New or did it belong to your wife?
- Put it on.
I want you to have it.
I'm pregnant.
I think it's yours.
Now what?
Do you want money?
Or do you want to get married?
Don't touch. Your hands are dirty.
I'm married already.
Why don't you finish the job?
Then I took it in my hand...
and made slow movements.
Then I passed over it
with my tongue...
and I had to take it in my mouth.
Until he...
- Should I go on?
- If you have more to confess.
Ties and I
are going to do things differently.
I don't need to confess
for the time being.
That would be a pity.
Say two 'Our Fathers'
en ten 'Hail Marys'.
The Lord has forgiven you
for your sins.
- But are you pregnant?
- No, of course I'm not.
I just wanted to give him a fright.
Hi, Wim.
- I heard that you left Hedeman.
- Yes, and what about it?
- Why are you giving me that?
- What tone of voice is that?
Ties is my cousin.
You need to support your family.
And he kept his mouth shut, of course.
This is enough to rebuild the pub.
Put a pool table in it.
Then I can meet up
with the group there.
We'll manage without it.
Yes, I don't want to have anything
to do with it anymore.
Not with Hedeman
and not with Wim de Kuiper.
We're going to do things differently.
- And what about Trees?
- She can help me.
We're no longer welcome. She's going
to turn it into a restaurant, she said.
She's never eaten out before
and she wants to open a restaurant?
Could you write something down?
Soup, bread, coffee.
Surprising menu.
Ties is back.
Are you that happy?
- Had a lot of customers?
- Word needs to get around first.
Last week was our fourth
wedding anniversary.
You owe me something.
I need to report.
- Right now?
- Yes, I'm out on probation.
Come with me.
Hi.
How did you enjoy "the guest house"?
See lots of friends? Relatives?
Let's hope you learned from it.
I'm here for the note.
- I want to work for Hedeman.
- Give me names.
If you don't talk, no note.
And no note, no work.
I served my sentence.
I'm starting with a clean slate.
Two years, dammit.
Who were there two years ago?
You can read it, Van Heesch.
The light is not very good.
Ellie can read in the dark very well.
Can't you, Ellie?
I'm too dumb to read,
but smart enough to shut up.
Sergeant Kramer sends his regards
to Mr Hedeman.
Tell Kramer that I said hello too,
Van Heesch.
We don't need Hedeman's pennies.
When all of Oss eats at our place,
even if he begs, he's not coming in.
Welcome home, son.
- Hey, Wim.
- Was it hard in their "Pleasure Garden"?
It was okay.
- Let's celebrate. I'm buying.
- We were just going home.
- It's been so long. Let's go home first.
- There's plenty of time for that later on.
I know what you've been
thinking about, boy.
What?
A big glass of cold, frothing beer.
- Ties doesn't drink anymore.
- But I do. Come.
- Hey, Ties. Are you sure?
- Yes.
- One is okay, isn't it?
- Thanks, Uncle Wim.
- Damn.
- You know what it is?
The damn MPs decide who gets to
work around here and who doesn't.
The Northerners
are running the shots in Oss.
Last week they arrested 12 guys.
Eight of them are still in jail.
Van der Heijden
was practically beaten to death.
But enough is enough.
On Palm Sunday we're going
to show them who's boss in Oss.
Are you in?
I'm...
Yes, never mind. I can tell.
It's fine.
What?
I promised your father on his death bed
that I'd take care of you.
Here.
You can rebuild the pub with that.
Put a pool table in there
and a real tap.
- Go and see Den Brock for a license.
- I can't take that.
Johanna and I want to start
a restaurant.
It's your damn place.
You inherited it.
We want to start all over again.
Restaurant van Heesch. Food,
drink and a good fuck for dessert.
It's not working.
Sure it is.
Just stop it.
Are you burying your mother-in-law?
A Webley. It didn't suffer
from being buried for 28 months.
That wouldn't be the same
for your mother-in-law.
Nice bike.
Yes, I got it
from the insurance company.
You should chop off your hand
so you can buy a car.
Sell it to Wim de Kuiper.
Ten guilders, 2.50 for you.
- We need to eat.
- You have a restaurant, don't you?
Johanna has a restaurant.
I hope you have a license?
- A license?
- A restaurant license.
- Regulations.
- We've only just opened up.
We'll get one as soon as
business picks up. Of course.
- Are you hungry?
- No, I've already eaten.
But perhaps we could make
another arrangement?
- I didn't make a reservation but...
- I've got a table here.
Alright. I'll see how it goes.
Van Schijndel.
What's the daily special?
Soup.
Nice.
Just one.
To wash away the coffee.
I'm going to help Mum for an hour.
- You shouldn't walk that way.
- I'll walk wherever I want.
I'll be at your place in ten minutes.
You can either pay off
or shoot a witness.
This is the third time.
There's not going to be a fourth.
As soon as Kramer has been buried,
we're going to party.
Drinks are on me
and I'll take care of the music.
A party, goddamn.
- Just shoot them. All of them.
- Anything else?
That's what we all want.
- Is there any more soup left?
- We're out.
Finished.
Time to close.
Everybody go home.
You go home. To The Hague
or wherever you're from.
Or do you want to stay in Oss and join
Sergeant Kramer at the cemetery?
Enough, enough.
Their shift is over.
These gentlemen need to go to bed.
Tomorrow morning at nine
you're the first.
Tally it all up and I'll pay tomorrow.
Can you put this away?
Welcome back.
On Palm Sunday we're going
to shoot him, De Kuiper said.
First the procession and then dead.
Like Jesus. That's how it went, right?
- But he won't be resurrected.
- What if we help him along?
Van der Heijden, you're drunk.
Go home. Party's over.
It's not over by a long shot.
Get some beer, dammit.
- Where are you going?
- With them.
- Ties, don't.
- What?
We were going to start all over.
I can already hear him.
Go ahead and be resurrected.
Van der Heijden, take it easy
or you'll drop him again.
Stand him up. Stand him up.
Ties, baptise him.
- How is that again?
- Father, Son, Holy Ghost...
Now he's a Catholic.
Let's have another drink
at the Korenbeurs.
Don't lecture me.
I'll do as I please.
I'm still my own master.
And yours.
Got it?
Stop it. That will never work.
- It will work.
- No, it won't.
- Just take out the window.
- Harry, don't be so stubborn, man.
Stubborn? It simply doesn't fit.
- He's the next one we're going to shoot.
- We?
He's afraid of his own wife.
You shoot one and get 15 in return.
- I warned you.
- Yes, yes.
- Bye.
- Wijnen.
Put it on my tab.
I didn't know you could write.
Jo Wijnen has a cane.
I put notches behind it.
- How do you know who drank what?
- I remember.
Jo Wijnen, gin. Gerrit van der
Heijden, beer. Coffee for you.
Gerrit van der Heijden, Wim de Kuiper.
Smart.
- What's my symbol?
- I'm not showing.
I'll teach you to read and write.
You're strange.
You want to teach me
how to read and write...
but you never paid me
to go upstairs with you.
Ain't I worth a few pennies?
I never felt that I could buy you.
Oh, Harry. That's the sweetest thing
anyone has ever said to me.
- Verstegen.
- I put 2.50 on Jan Greven.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I am.
The new commander.
He's not bad looking.
Yes, get close to him.
Then we can bury you next week.
Here's Jan the Champion.
Congratulations? Beer?
If they send 100 of them,
I'll blow them all to bits.
Really? Are you sure?
What?
- What?
- Do you know what I heard?
- What did you hear?
- You're putting down the MPs...
but when it mattered
you shat your trousers.
Tell me if I'm wrong.
Goddamn, Gerrit. How could you?
Your own cousin.
- I was dazed...
- Outside. Beat it.
Clean up. You lot keep your
mouths shut, understood?
Verhoef wants us to drink
to the victory.
He's buying.
Shouldn't you be partying?
The heart has friends,
the brain is alone.
It's not mine.
Ah, the police.
Do the MPs let you go out
on your own?
- I heard there was a fight.
- Not that I know of.
- So, what's that?
- Spilled some coffee. A shame, isn't it?
It was brand-new too.
Somebody reported a crime.
But of course such a report
could get lost.
A drink?
Your change.
I'll be back some other time.
Champion.
I heard the MPs
are investigating the mayor.
Fraud, taking bribes.
The Northerners are imagining things.
We don't have that in Oss.
I, uh...
I already paid Ties.
- Are you crying?
- It has nothing to do with you.
Come with me.
Away from here.
I'll be a pro in Italy.
Listen to him. He won one race.
You have to go or he'll think
you're staying too long.
Think about it.
I will.
At least two months.
- Is it...
- Yes.
Does Ties know?
You can't keep it hidden
for much longer.
Where were you?
I had two customers.
I sent them away.
You could have served them.
They weren't here for drinks.
You should be here, dammit.
Where were you?
At the doctor's.
Are you ill?
You're not pregnant, are you?
That's not a bad thing, is it?
For how long?
- How long?
- One month.
Perhaps five weeks.
- It can't be mine.
- It doesn't matter.
We can take care of it together.
You're going to get rid of it.
Can't you tell?
Who? Ties?
- I don't know who.
- Sounds familiar.
Did somebody hit you?
Duck sooner.
You're going to be an aunt.
- How long?
- About two months.
Does Ties know?
Two things have changed.
He drinks more and hits harder.
He's fighting with everybody.
Until he runs into the wrong guy.
He'll get shot dead.
That would be something.
Then I'm moving in with you.
You can stop working
and we can get married.
Don't you want that?
Are you here to drink or to fuck?
- Ties.
- What Ties?
Friday we're going to Geffen.
- Why?
There's a woman who can help us.
No.
No? What do you mean no?
Maybe it's yours.
Ties, listen. I'm keeping it.
I'll take care of it on my own.
If you don't get rid of it,
then I'll kick it out.
Are you going to say
something about it?
Come on.
Cowards. They're the worst.
Where's your hero now, huh?
Where's your hero now?
Get out of here.
You got what you came for.
What?
I'm going to lie down.
I'm exhausted.
Are you okay? Come on. Come.
I won't let him kill my baby.
I'd rather kill him.
Don't do it yourself.
You lost some blood.
Nothing to worry about.
I'll give you something...
to stop the cramps.
But don't fall again, okay?
How did Ties take it?
- Fine. He's looking forward to it.
- Good.
Next.
I'll wait here.
I'm sorry that I...
Violence isn't my thing.
I don't have the stomach for it.
I'd never ask you.
But I can help you.
We can take out an insurance.
If it has to be done...
we can take out an insurance
on Ties' life.
That way you can pay
whoever does the job.
And you'll have a little something
for yourself.
It cuts both ways, so to speak.
I have to go back.
Think about it.
Wait a minute. Hurry up.
Verstraete is upstairs already.
You're not supposed to be here.
We keep business and pleasure apart.
I'm here for business.
A life insurance.
Is he home?
I'll get my coat.
Dora, I'm out for a while.
What are Ties's initials?
That's probably him.
We can go ahead and ask him.
Damn, Greef, it's you.
Our champion.
I heard that you and Johanna agreed
about Ties?
Tell him that you know a place
in the next village with a lot of money.
The brewery. That checks out
when he asks about it.
Johanna will take care of the gun.
You shoot him
when he's out on the heath.
You collect half
of the insurance money.
Don't stay at the brewery to drink,
mind you.
Come on.
- Are you cold, Greef?
- No. Yes.
No, yes.
Or are you scared?
I asked you if you're scared.
What are you doing, Greef?
Sergeant Roelofse,
divisional commander.
Can we talk quietly somewhere?
I have bad news.
Your husband has been shot.
Is he dead?
I'm sorry.
Did your husband have enemies?
- Can you give me names?
- It's faster to list his friends.
You celebrated after my predecessor's
death. Don't expect sympathy from us.
I'll talk to you later.
You didn't run your mouth?
It looks good on you.
What are you doing here?
- The MPs were quick.
- What did you do with the gun?
Damn you.
- He has to get out of here.
- He can't go out like that.
Upstairs.
Come.
Get in.
Go.
Nobody in Oss gets shot
without my permission.
Least of all my cousin.
My condolences.
A counsellor who doesn't talk
is of no use to me.
What have I done?
Come with me. You too.
Get out.
Turn around.
We all fuck around...
but going so far
as to shoot your own people...
- I didn't...
- Harry den Brock told me everything.
Should we take out an insurance
on you too and kill you?
The new commander doesn't beat up
people but has them investigated.
That's much more dangerous.
I said that nobody
was going to get killed anymore.
Just burglaries.
How could you be so stupid, man?
On your knees. On your knees.
What have you done?
I shot Ties.
It's just like church.
If you confess, we can forgive you.
Then we never talk about it again.
We keep our mouths shut.
He shat his trousers.
In the back of the car.
The enemy are the MP,
the Northerners.
We're fighting them.
Not each other.
Know your enemy.
Only then will you know your friends.
Dismissed.
Clean him up.
You're walking home, right?
And no contact with Johanna
or the MPs will figure it out in no time.
I don't know how,
but you're going to pay for this.
- I didn't...
- You had it done.
That's the same thing.
And I can even respect that.
I told him.
Abortion is a mortal sin.
Half of the insurance money is ours.
For keeping quiet.
Since you've lost your man,
I will protect you.
Here, for the funeral.
If you do as I say, you'll be fine.
Go.
Van Schijndel wants to talk to you.
I'll take care of it.
My condolences
on your cousin's death.
The municipal police will do what it
takes to solve this cowardly murder.
Harry, it'll be fine.
Why did you betray us?
- I didn't betray anybody.
- To Wim.
Wim's with us.
No need to worry about him.
Can I have some coffee?
I hold no secrets for you.
Everything is in here.
Transactions with the municipality,
church, insurance, burglaries, the works.
If the MPs get a hold of this,
all of Oss goes down. Including Wim.
What about the life insurance money?
The MP won't issue a statement
while the investigation is ongoing.
Without that the insurance company
won't pay. It will come.
Be patient.
What are you going to do with it?
I may go away from here.
Where to?
Do you hold secrets for me?
This is where I want to go.
America.
Nobody over there
knows the Van Heesch family.
It's a long way from here.
I can't stand being at home.
I can't stand being on my bike.
I need to know what I'm up against.
I'll be a pro in Italy. Come with me.
We can get married over there.
What makes you think
I want to marry you?
It's not yours.
There's a woman who says
she has an appointment.
Where's the mayor?
And Father Bakker?
And Hedeman?
You persecute people
who have nothing...
and protect those
who have everything.
We investigate everybody.
Me too?
What can I do for you?
I'm here to get a statement saying
I'm innocent of my husband's death.
Then the insurance company can pay.
- Your husband had a life insurance?
- Yes.
Who is your insurer?
For how long?
I don't know.
Ties took care of his own business.
- Do you know who's the agent?
- Harry den Brock.
He needs the statement.
Of course I want to be of service,
but I want something in return.
What can you tell us
about Wim de Kuiper?
We don't blow the gaff on each other.
Then you'll have to wait
until the investigation is closed.
Are you ill?
Move over.
Are you sad?
Soon I'll have money.
I'll take you with me to America.
Then we'll open a restaurant.
We'll succeed over there.
How's your English?
Van Schijndel.
The MPs have over 140 addresses.
- Something is going down.
- What do they want, dammit?
- Arrest all of Oss?
- Kramer was one of them.
They're not going to stand for that.
There are people in Oss
who are saying...
that they saw who shot Kramer.
Anyway,
people talk rubbish all the time.
Perhaps we should help the MP
along a bit?
We found a gun on the heath
where Ties van Heesch was killed.
We have the prints of three fingers
and a thumb.
- That's impossible.
- Wait and see.
I haven't slept for weeks.
I keep seeing him before me.
And I hear him say:
'What are you doing, Greef? '
I'm glad I confessed.
I'll do ten years
and then start all over again.
With a clean slate.
You confessed to the murder
of Ties van Heesch.
You're also charged
with the murder of Kramer.
Ties van Heesch and Kramer
were shot with the same gun.
A Webley.
Yes, but I didn't shoot him.
Not Kramer.
I didn't kill Kramer.
Then who did?
If you help us, you'll get a reduced
sentence for killing Van Heesch.
I'm not saying anything.
- Thank you for coming.
- You're welcome.
Jan Greven confessed
to killing your husband.
I assume you already knew that?
That he confessed
or that he did it?
If you confess now,
you may get a reduced sentence.
If you wait for the investigation,
you face the consequences.
Is that all?
Mrs Van Heesch,
we're going to clean up Oss...
and we won't stop
with the little guys.
Has Hedeman ever
approached you indecently?
No.
And has Father De Roos
ever engaged in particular acts?
What do you care
what the priest does?
You Protestants aren't going
to do the bishop's job, are you?
This girl is a minor. She works
at Hedeman's packaging department.
You worked there too.
Did you hear or see anything?
I wouldn't tell you.
I understand your position.
We don't like you Northerners.
Just accept that.
Piet van der Heijden got arrested,
Jo Manders. It's all coming down.
Can I put this upstairs at your place?
I don't want it at home now.
I have to get out of here.
- Are you coming with me?
- Where to?
You wanted to go to America.
I'll come with you.
The two of us? I'm pregnant.
I've always wanted a baby.
I don't care.
We need to get out of here.
I managed to free up some cash.
- Dora can have the house and the rest.
- Is that what you want?
You learn fast.
What if I left Oss?
Far away.
To America.
When everything is sorted out,
I'll send you money.
And you can come over too.
Where's Trees anyway?
Hedeman's driver
came to pick her up.
What did you say?
Hedeman's driver came.
We have to eat as well.
You only think of yourself.
And Trees didn't mind.
- This is private property. Get lost.
- I'm here to get Trees.
She's not here. Get lost.
Then tell Hedeman
I'm going straight to the MPs.
It was an accident.
You have to believe me. It was a game.
But suddenly she pulled away.
Easy, easy.
Good.
She has to go to hospital.
She might go into a coma.
No, out of the question.
That would raise too many questions.
She has to.
Put her in my car.
I'll take her to Den Bosch.
Where's Trees?
Now you listen to me.
Trees has had an accident.
- I'm going to the MPs.
- They can't do anything.
Hedeman and his associates
are powerful.
Why do you think
I never got arrested?
And you're not going
to ruin that for me.
The MPs won't be here much longer.
They have to leave Oss.
That's being arranged in The Hague.
By Hedeman.
The Minister of Justice
is a good Catholic.
Keep your mouth shut and Hedeman
will take care of you from now on.
This is your stop.
- I'm staying with her.
- One patient is enough.
- I'm going to the hospital.
- Get out. Come on.
Johanna,
we're losing precious time, okay?
I'll come as soon as I can.
Come on.
You see?
You can hardly stand up.
And keep your mouth shut,
understood?
May the mercy of the Lord
lighten your heart so you may repent...
and experience God's mercy.
I killed Ties.
And Jan is taking the blame.
That's my confession.
And what do you have to confess?
Johanna, we need to help each other.
The MPs are the enemy.
They're all fascists. They're all
following Rost van Tonningen...
and he hates Catholics.
We're your friends.
The thing with Trees was an accident.
I honestly confess.
- What use is that to Trees?
- Trees will be all right.
Our Lord will take care of that.
I abide by the secret of
the confessional. You do the same.
Our Lord doesn't punish people.
The justice department does.
I'm counting on your silence.
Silence.
That's what made Oss great, isn't it?
Goddamn.
I'm not leaving before I know
that Trees is fine.
They'll take good care of her
in hospital.
Take me to Den Bosch.
- It's not visiting hours yet.
- Please.
I just want to make sure she's okay.
- What was her name again?
- Trees Biemans.
She was admitted last night.
I have nobody here by that name.
Please check again.
Maybe he took her to another hospital.
Veghel, Nijmegen.
We need to find Wim.
My condolences.
I couldn't help it.
She jumped out of my car
when I had to stop.
You drowned her.
Watch what you're saying.
Talk to her, Harry.
- I did my best to find Trees.
- Well, she has been found.
Don't think the municipal police
is going to get you out of this one.
I'm going to see Roelofse.
- Like hell you are.
- Are you on his side?
Do you know what they did to Trees?
No, and I don't want to know.
It's not going to bring Trees back.
There's no point in stirring things up.
Let bygones be bygones.
Mayor Megens.
This is the Bishop of Den Bosch.
Shall we?
Holland America line. Tomorrow
evening at 7, Waalhaven Rotterdam.
- Can you get there on your own?
- I'll take the train.
I'll take a suitcase.
You can't walk on the street with it.
Here you have the main documents.
You need to keep them with you.
Those too.
Diocese of Den Bosch
For Trees.
Tomorrow we'll be sleeping
in a suite on a boat.
We'll have nothing to do
with Oss anymore.
Are you leaving?
- To the midwife.
- That can wait.
The kid isn't going to pop out like that.
First you're going to visit Jan Greven.
Why?
He needs to confess to killing Kramer.
He's going to hang anyway.
Why would he?
Tell him that I'll stab you if he doesn't.
Whether you're pregnant or not.
Oss' coat of arms, so they always
know where you're from.
Now De Greef will know
I mean business.
Are you coming, Johanna?
Come, come.
Here. Alum, that will stop the bleeding.
It's a keepsake
Wim de Kuiper gave me.
I'm here to tell you that you
shouldn't listen to anybody.
You need to think of yourself.
If you can get a reduced sentence
by talking, you should.
It's my fault. I put you here.
I pulled the trigger.
We're all responsible
for our own actions.
Without me you might have become
a famous racing cyclist.
What am I going to do in Italy?
I don't even like spaghetti.
You don't have to keep quiet
for my sake.
I'm leaving Oss tomorrow.
You're right to leave.
With Harry.
Don't wait for me.
By the time I get out,
you'll be an old hag.
Take care of our baby.
And?
- And?
- He got the message.
We look alike, don't you think?
I used to bang your mum all the time.
Now we look even more alike.
Turn left here.
Nobody will suspect me
if they find you dead.
- Anybody could have done it.
- Why would you?
- Haven't I been good to you?
- You killed Trees.
Even if that's true,
and I'm not saying it is...
you have no right to speak.
A life for a life, Johanna.
You killed Ties
and you're paying with Trees.
Get out.
Strip.
Throw it on the back seat.
I let you live
and you leave me alone.
Deal?
You think you're quite something.
You don't have the nerve to shoot.
You're walking back, right?
The Holland America Line just called
about two tickets for New York.
- That's right.
- Why wasn't I told?
I don't want people in Oss
to know we're leaving.
That's why I didn't tell you.
So you wouldn't tell anybody.
- It had to be a secret.
- Even for Johanna van Heesch?
I called Sergeant Roelofse
and told him about your books.
If you cooperate, they will consider
reducing your sentence.
I don't know what you got yourself into,
but you need to straighten things out.
They're waiting in the room.
These documents will convict
all of Oss.
It contains everything.
About everybody.
Blue, Hedeman. Orange, the priests.
Yellow, De Kuiper.
In exchange you let me go.
We picked up 60 people yesterday.
Today there will be 40 more.
And we should let you go?
We're taking down Hedeman,
the priests, the mayor.
And thanks to your books
we'll get them convicted.
I didn't do anything.
Instigating burglary, arson, forgery.
I don't call that not doing anything.
I can't go to jail.
They'll think I betrayed them.
Can I grab some of my things?
I won't come looking for you.
You can come to me, damn you.
I did everything for you.
And what do I get in return?
You know what? I'll smoke you out.
The Attorney General has arrived.
I took care of you from the time
you were a little girl.
Who gave you the best present
for your Communion?
Do you remember? Goddamn.
And who paid for your wedding,
everything included?
Well?
You'd rather die than admit it, huh?
Goddamn. You're really one of mine.
Trees wasn't, but you definitely are.
A life for a life.
Wim...
Was he my father?
It had nothing to do with love. If was
'one good turn deserves another'.
And I certainly didn't hate him.
But the thing with Trees...
You need to leave Oss.
Just go.
Silence.
Member Rost van Tonningen
of the National Socialist Movement...
will now speak.
Oss is a crime-ridden
den of thieves.
The MPs are putting things in order
and suddenly they're dissolved...
by the Roman Catholic
Minister of Justice.
The MPs have exposed
atrocious vice crimes.
Crimes committed by Roman clergy
and Jewish businessmen.
The Roman clique
is covering for the Jews.
Oss is ruled by papists and yids.
Mr Rost van Tonningen, this is
inappropriate. You are closured.
Traitor to the country.
You should have arrested me in Oss,
to keep us from going to Rotterdam.
Harry den Bronk is dead.
He hanged himself.
- When?
- This morning.
A little over 40,000 guilders,
if I got it right.
The ministry closed the case today.
The MPs have left Oss.
If the mayor and the priests go free,
then so does Johanna van Heesch.
You'll miss the boat.
Harry's papers.
Everything is in them.
I'll make sure they get used well.
I don't want to keep quiet any longer.
This is your suitcase.
It was in Den Brock's car.
The case Oss
became a national scandal
the Catholic Minister of Justice
had to resign
this led to the fall
of the last pre-war cabinet
many military policemen
joined the National Socialist Movement
many gang members spent the war in
prison and became resistance heroes
the Capital kept growing
Oss's slaughterhouses grew
into multinationals
like Organon and Unilever
resistance also continued
a small municipal socialist party
from Oss evolved into a national party
against authority,
church and capital