Timing and subtitles brought to
you by The Ugly Ducklings@Viki
Episode 15
Everything's in there. Who I
am, why I lived this way.
Please listen to it, write an article, and
incorporate it to your 20th anniversary issue.
So... you're saying that you're the
famous anonymous novel author Ten,
and that you'll reveal it all to the world
through an interview with The Most. Is that it?
Bingo!
It's possible that you wouldn't believe me.
You've seen it a lot
somewhere, haven't you?
The handwriting and mechanical
pencil are the same.
Shouldn't that much evidence suffice?
What else should I show you...
Then, are you the one who stopped
the binding of the magazine?
You can write the article
by listening to that.
Take some pictures.
There have to be several
pictures to make an impact.
- Feature Director Kim...
- Please take a good one.
I even shaved to look good for the picture.
Smile.
What's your reason for
revealing who you are?
Is it to keep the Most
from being discontinued?
Hey... just take a picture. Jeez.
I'll take a selfie.
Sheesh, I look better in person.
Photoshop it for me, so
that it looks Most-like.
There has to be a reason why you
kept it a secret for so long.
Nothing stays a secret
forever in this world.
If it's going to be revealed, I wish for
it to be revealed in a Most-like way.
I also wonder if there'll ever be
a better timing than this one.
- But still, why are you going to this extent...
Weren't you an exact person when it came to business?
If you're like this, then it takes away
the reason why I asked you to come.
I was going to ask Jackson at first.
Oh, when you listen to it,
you might feel a bit upset.
I recorded it thinking I was talking
to Jackson, so I spoke informally.
I'd hate for other people
to chat about my story.
But if it were Jackson... No, Hye
Jin, I thought it'd be okay.
But as you know, she's just too nice.
It was obvious that she wouldn't be able to
reveal it, and would be suffering on her own.
So I called you.
- Feature Director Kim.
- Please write an article.
Let's be number one.
Let's save the Most. Then nobody...
will have a reason to cry.
If I reveal it...
what will happen to you?
What you're doing, won't
it change your life?
Well, it will be quite a fuss for a while
at first, but that will die down quickly.
I don't mind it. I'm okay.
Still, this...
I'll count on you.
I absolutely wish the first article
about me to be done by The Most.
Absolutely.
Feature Director Kim.
Wow.
No but this, this...
Does this make sense? Does
this situation make sense?
How is it that I'm not feeling bad at all?
Sunbae Poong Ho is the
vice president? Heol.
- What's going on? - It doesn't make sense.
Earlier, I thought I was seeing a ghost.
Me too. This doesn't make any sense.
Ciao!
You... you... I mean, Vice-President...
So... that is...
- What are you doing, Sunbae, seriously?
- How could you do this to us?
- I doesn't make sense. - You traitor.
Attenzione. You all...
You probably have lots of
things you're curious about.
O sole mio.
Yes, Aunt.
Officially exchange your greetings
with your team members.
Okay.
Hello. I'm Jin Sung's new
Vice-President, Kim Poong Ho.
Hey, Kim Poong Ho, how could
you lie to us?! How could you!
You should have told us!
You're too much!
Did you ask me? You didn't ask.
Also, how could you not know.
I give off such a noble air.
Noble air, my butt.
I am the Vice-President, after all, so
you should be responding properly to me.
That's not important. Instead, can't you talk
to your father and ask him to save our team?
That's true.
I already asked but...
The decision has come from headquarters,
so there's nothing we can do.
But why did you work here as a reporter?
Well, I should check out how the company's
coming around, you know, so I can manage it.
Seeing that, I'm a highly capable person.
- I could kill you— - Control
yourself, control yourself, Sunbae.
Yes, Hye Jin.
Where are you?
I just... had a meeting...
With whom?
Just... someone.
You don't know that there's a big
commotion in our team, do you?
Don't be startled. The Vice-President
who got inaugurated today...
It's Sunbae Poong Ho! He's
a son of Jin Sung group!
How could that be? There really are lots of
surprising things in the world, aren't there?
I know right. There are
lots of surprising things.
Okay, let's talk later.
Hi, Jackson!
From here on, I'll tell you everything
about me. Listen carefully.
Korean name: Kim Shin Hyeok. Pen name: Ten.
Well, up to here, you probably
already know everything.
Yes, Crew Chief. As for the article that was to
be added to the special 20th anniversary issue,
there is none.
Don't put the binding on hold and just
proceed with the normal schedule.
Yes.
What, what, what is it?
I'm going crazy.
Why?
You know I took that aptitude test?
The results came out, but...
It came out?
I mean, I quit being a hotelier
because it was embarrassing.
How could I be so well
suited to be a hotelier?
It wasn't even worth quitting.
What is that?
But what you felt embarassed about was
that you got the job thanks to your dad.
Not the fact that you worked in a hotel.
I think you actually liked working there.
Well... I didn't hate it.
Hey, you say that everything
else seems pathetic.
Then, doesn't that mean you
really liked that job?
Is that so?
- I'm sure it is. - Is it?
It is.
Hello.
Exclusive interview with the author Ten
This...
Crew Chief, I told you that there
was no additional article.
What happened?
How much has been circulated right now?
Wow, Ten did an interview.
Oh? There's an interview with Ten in it.
I guess they really did interview him.
Oh, it's Ten!
Reporter Kim personally came and said there
was an article to be added in a rush.
I told him I would confirm with the Deputy Chief
Editor, but he said it was already discussed.
He said he would take full responsibility.
That 20th anniversary issue that made
our insides boil actually did come out.
W-w-what is this?
An exclusive interview with Ten?
- What?- What, Unni?
Isn't that Sunbae Shin Hyeok?
W-what's up with this?
Oh my God. There's no way!
Wait, what's going on?
Sunbae Shin Hyeok is Ten?
What are you...
Wait, why is Feature Director Kim...
Because today is a special day.
What's so special about today?
You'll find out tomorrow.
No way...
Yes, this is Ara Hotel.
Yes, please connect me to room 2024.
- That room number is vacant.- What?
Isn't there someone named Kim Shin Hyeok?
He cleared his room and
checked out this morning.
Are you okay? You were really
surprised, weren't you?
I'm sorry.
See, you should have revealed it sooner. You
made me have to do it with my own hands.
Don't do something useless
like running over to my hotel.
I won't be there anyway.
Alright, I'm leaving.
Bye!
Oh, my my.
The mechanical pencil was
sufficient as a gift.
It would have been fine even if you hadn't given us
such an overwhelming gift, Feature Director Kim.
Wow, this guy is a born idiot.
Wow, I'm so bored.
What is this?
[World-renowned Novelist Ten
Finally Reveals His identity]
Oh! Th-this... 2024 is...
I'm not seeing things, right?
It really is Feature Director Kim!
Wow, did you really read
Sunbae Shin Hyeok's (book)?
This is totally unexpected!
It doesn't seem like Sunbae Shin Hyeok.
Up to this...
Idiot Reporter
Oh, Ha Ri. I'm in the middle of something.
Hey, what's with this idiot reporter?
How do you know the idiot reporter?
He's the person that I was talking about.
The one who lives in a suite room.
He told me he didn't want me to tell you because
he had some personal circumstances, so I didn't.
He thought about you a lot.
Oh, Seong Joon! Feature Director Kim is...
I know.
This issue has been distributed to all the
bookstores, right? What should we do now?
First, I think I need to meet with Reporter
Kim. He's in a suite at Ha Ri's hotel-
He said he already left. I looked into it.
But I want to try going at least once.
I think I need to try.
What is this?
I think it's the last words that Feature
Director Kim was planning on leaving to you.
Hey, Jackson! I'm going to talk about
myself from now on, so listen well.
My korean name is Kim Shin Hyeok.
My pen name is Ten.
Well, you'll already know this by now.
I have another name, David Joseph.
That is my American name.
I was adopted when I was twelve years old.
At this time, "Ah, that's how it was."
That's probably the kind
of expression you have.
Although you may have noticed,
I have a good personality,
and I had good parents, and grew
up receiving a lot of love.
So happily that I want to brag about it.
Oh my gosh! Ma, you look
even greater than before!
Really? Well, you look so handsome!
Yeah, I'm still sexy.
Dad, are you okay? What's happened to you
these days? You better gain some weight.
Well David, I'll put on some
weight if you slow down
and stop drinking so much soju.
How have you been, Son?
I'm good. Everything's okay here.
We love you.
- We miss you.- I miss you.
Dear loving parents,
I really became a fiction writer
at the spur of the moment.
In high school, I uploaded my writing on the web
as a hobby, and a publisher showed interest.
They wanted to release it as a book,
and I thought it wasn't a bad idea.
But strangely, the focus went
in an unexpected direction.
To them, being an adopted Asian teenager
must have been a charming gimmick.
I just wanted to make
the things I liked fun,
but the number of people who wanted to change my
writing to suit their own taste kept growing.
Then, at some point, it seemed like what was mine
was turning into something that was not mine.
I thought that I could keep having
fun if I gave up revealing myself,
so I kept my gender, age and
my birth origin a secret
and created the name Ten.
The only way that I could
show myself the way I am
and my writing the way it was
without judgment was, ironically,
by hiding myself.
So I chose this lifestyle,
so that I could have fun doing
the work that I enjoy 100%.
Jackson, you know my life motto, right?
"Let me do what's fun for me now."
I thought that making magazines
was fun for a while,
so I came to Most.
With this, you should be able
to write an article, right?
Okay, then that's it.
Please write a good article, Jackson.
You thought it was over, didn't you?
I thought that I should sing you a
song since I'm already recording.
One, two, one, two.
That was a joke. You were fooled again,
right? I know. I see everything.
How could he just leave without
saying goodbye? Seriously, Sunbae.
Hm? What is this?
Hey, I told you not to mess with my
stuff, and here you are messing with it.
Who was it? I'm thinking
it was probably Joon Woo.
I thought that you guys would be mad at
me, if I left without saying goodbye.
I want to say my farewell. You
know that I have good manners.
Sunbae Cha, I really don't
need a lot of words for you.
You're seriously the best. Really the best.
Ah Reum, I sincerely congratulate
you on your marriage.
I don't know who he is, but he's
really blessed. Look under your chair.
Omo!
Sunbae Poong Ho,
you're dirty. You stink.
Hurry up and wash yourself.
- Poong Ho is the vice-president now.-
Do something with that hair too.
I'll relay it to him.
And Joon Woo and Han Seol,
stop making it so obvious
that you're dating!
You make it way too obvious!
It gives me goosebumps.
And to our Beautiful Trio,
I hope that you hang in there until
the end and become great editors.
- Strength!- Strength!
Our Deputy Chief Editor who loves 525,
you were really surprised, weren't you?
I'm sorry.
You regret it, don't you! If you would
have known it would turn out like this,
you would have given me
several pairs of underwear!
I'm even wearing them right now
because they feel so good. Underwear.
Okay. Then I'll be leaving now.
Everyone, live well
and be healthy. Fighting, Editorial Team.
He didn't say anything to Unni Hye Jin.
Aigoo, I forgot someone!
Ah, how could I make this kind of mistake?
That's right, that's right.
Editor-In-Chief, how was my last present?
The Most, in a really Most-like fashion,
please protect it well.
Okay.
Then I'll really be leaving now.
Everyone be healthy and happy, okay?
Okay!
I'm leaving. God bless.
But he didn't leave a
farewell to Noona Hye Jin.
She Was Pretty
Congratulations to Most Korea on the
highest circulation and sales rank
Why am I not happy at all even
though we made first place?
I know, right?
Did Sunbae Shin Hyeok leave Korea? Even
his phone number is completely gone.
Kim Shin Hyeok.
Bad guy. Seriously.
Unni Hye Jin, didn't you say that you were
going back to the management team now?
Yes, I'm going back tomorrow.
What's this? Why is everyone leaving
at the same time? Feels so empty.
Ah, that's so upsetting.
If you're feeling down, why
don't we have a farewell party?
That's right!- Let's
have a farewell party.
Let's have a farewell party.
Oh!
Sunbae, when did you get here?
I mean... Vice-President.
Vice President's office isn't even a jail
cell but it's so suffocating, I almost died.
So, I'm going to work back
here again starting today.
What kind of Vice-President does that? Would
our company work well if you did that?
Geesh! I'm just going to peel all
the keratin off of your head!
- Leave, hurry up and leave.-
Get out of here. Go!
I'll throw a farewell
party for Hye Jin today
with this gold card...
- Unni!- Woah!
What about a buffet?
- Lobster! It has to be lobster!- No,
let's get the full course set menu.
Full course menu!
Lobster. King crab.
What's with that hair?
Back to number one. Really good work.
You can expect a reward.
Now, get ready to return.
Okay, I got it.
December Issue Fashion Magazine
Score GraphFirst place: The Most
Are you okay? You drank
everything that was offered.
They were throwing a farewell party for
me, so I should at least drink that much.
And I'm pretty good with alcohol.
Like that's something to brag about!
Let's talk for a while before we go. I'll
go buy something warm, so you go ahead.
Where did she go?
Oh, you startled me!
The moon is really bright.
Deputy Chief Editor?
The moon is pretty bright.
This seems really familiar, doesn't it?
Let's go, slide-mania!
Ah, it's cold.
They called me to return to headquarters.
They even offered me a
much higher position.
Really? Oh, my boyfriend is so cool!
Is this a high-speed promotion?
It's probably a reward for
getting Most to first place.
But... I didn't do that
through my own power.
I wouldn't have been able to do
it without Feature Editor Kim.
That's why I
am going to refuse that position.
What?
I told you that I would propose to
you if we made it to first place
and that I wanted to be
with you at my best moment,
but this isn't the moment that I imagined.
I have to go back for now.
I may have to go back and
take care of everything,
then start again from the very beginning.
I may not be able to show you the best
moment that I was thinking of right away.
But Hye Jin... Will you still ♪
You were the one at my side. ♪
Be able to stay by my side?♪ Let's
not do that a second time. ♪
Go with me. ♪As much as we love
we should not hurt each other. ♪
Okay. Let's go together. ♪ Let's
do that from this moment on ♪
Let's stay together. ♪ Let's not ever let go of each
other's hand which was grasped with difficulty♪
♪ Let's not ever let go of each other's
hand which was grasped with difficulty♪
♪ All of the time remaining
for you and me ♪
♪ I want to use every moment for us ♪
Ah, I'm just saying this, but
you can't misunderstand me.
What?
This isn't my real proposal. ♪ Until we
close our eyes for the last time forever, ♪
I'm going to do it right, so wait for it.
♪ Just as you are now. ♪
Oh yeah? I'm going to anticipate
it.♪ I will love you ♪
But, the moon is really bright, isn't it?
I told you not to joke around.
I'm going to go down the slide!
That one's mine!
It's mine! It's mine!
I'm really thankful to
you for all this time.
Unni, do you really have to leave?
It's so sad, Unni.
Unni, don't go.
Do you really have to leave?
- Do you really have to?- Noona.
- Goodbye.- Bye.
I think it would be best if
you left now, Kim Hye Jin.
- You worked hard.- Yes, sir.
I'll come hang out with you guys often!
You went through a lot, Hye Jin.
Sunbae Cha.
When I think of how you were
when you first came here,
I think you've become a totally
different person. It's nice to see.
Thank you so much, Sunbaenim.
I really, really learned a lot.
Ah, why do I feel like this?
It feels like I'm sending
my kid off somewhere.
Sunbaenim!
Omo, I was so mushy just now.
I take that back. Bye.
Ah, yes!
I'm here.
- Hye Jin!- It's Hye Jin!
Wow, do you know how much I
was looking forward to today?
I'm glad that you came. Let's
give a round of applause.
Welcome!
So I'm back.
Team Manager, should I do anything?
What do you mean, what should you do?
It's 6 o'clock. You should go home.
Wow, I feel flustered from
ending work so early.
Feature Director Kim?
Feature Director! Feature Director Kim!
Sorry.
He definitely looked like
Feature Director Kim.
I think it is him.
Was it not him?
Hey, Jackson. Have you been well?
Feature Director!
What happened to you?
How could you just suddenly
disappear without a word?
How could you, seriously?
Why am I the only one...
Why am I the only one
you didn't say bye to?
That's why I came to say goodbye like this.
Do you know how worried everyone was?
Where are you staying?
Are you eating? Are you really alright?
Why did you go so far...
♪ To me it's like the first time
I cautiously said how I feel ♪
♪ My awkward confessions
that are too late ♪
♪ Keep on making you go far away from me ♪
♪ Because I love you more
than I love myself. ♪
♪ You are the only one for me ♪
♪ Yes, you are the only one for me. ♪
Jackson, good morning! You want a bite?
♪ I'm lonesome to the point of tears.♪
What's wrong?
My front tooth.
I think my front tooth fell out.
My front tooth. I think
my front tooth fell out.
♪ Yes, you're the only one for me.
I still feel so alone ♪
Oh yeah! It got crushed well.
Jackson, what are you doing?
♪ At the place where someday you can
see me and come to me I will stay ♪
♪ Yes, you're the only one for me ♪
Jackson.
♪ Someday you can come back to me. ♪
♪ I will wait for you just as I am now ♪
Oh my goodness! Who spent all my money?
What have you been typing so much?
The thing is, there are so many things to
spend money on, and it's obvious what I have.
I don't have anything else to sell!
You can sell that.
No, I can't. I bought this fair
and square with my own money.
Oh, is that so?
But, I'm really happy that we spend
time together on the weekends.
If you were still on the editing team, you
would have had to work even on the weekends.
You don't have any overtime or night
shifts. You're happy about it too, right?
Of course! I'm totally happy!
But how do I get an educational loan?
Why?
I want to go to graduate
school for hotel management.
Really?
Yeah.
Now that I thought about what you said,
it seems I really liked that work.
That's why I'm going to
study properly this time.
There, there. Such a good girl.
You thought well.
I'm an expert in tuitions
and loans, so don't worry.
Hello, Writer.
Have you been doing well?
Yes. You've been well too, right?
I called the journalist who wrote the
article to thank for writing it so well.
Ah, I'm not a journalist.
I was just moved to the editing team for a little while
and I've returned back to the management team now.
Oh, really?
If you have some time, come over here
to take a break and get some air.
Yes, ma'am. I will. Yes, goodbye.
Wait, Hye Jin!
Yes?
Where are you? At home?
I'm in Ha-il right now to see the
children's book writer I met last time.
Really? If I would have known you were going
there, I would have taken you in my car.
No, what do you mean?
Later,
you can eat dinner with me, right?
Yeah. Okay, see you later.
Huh? Is this it?
But at this point, shouldn't
a tiger come out roaring?
- That would be really good!- I don't know.
You're here, Hye Jin?
Hello!
I was just watching because I was
worried I might be interrupting them.
No, let's go in.
- No.- Let's go in.
That's right.- No. That cute bear...
What's cute about a bear?
Attention, everyone.
Say hello. These are my colleagues
who work together with me here.
- Hello.- Hello!
Nice to meet you!
Ah, this is that journalist who wrote
that interview article before?
No, I'm not a journalist.
Your workplace is so pretty.
But were there originally
this many authors?
No, we got together not too long ago.
We're going to be working on a
collaborative creative project together.
For about a year, they're all
trapped here, unable to move.
Wow, that sounds so fun! I'm so jealous!
That's so cool.
Why don't you try it instead of
just being envious? - Pardon?
Maybe it's because I heard that it was your
childhood dream to become a children's book writer,
I'm really sad to hear that
you don't write anymore.
I just went back to where I originally was.
The place you originally were could be
like a mold that you create for yourself.
I am thinking where you want to
be is the right place to be.
That's why I'm saying this. We're looking for a person who could be the
youngest (junior in experience, not in age) story writer in our team.
Hye Jin, would you consider it?
Me?
I know it was the writing of a reporter, but
I really liked your writing and feeling.
Oh, you're too kind.
And, I'm going to America soon.
I think that I'm going to get married.
Really? Congratulations!
Thank you.
The workplace there is so pretty.
It's so cute and
it feels like your heart warms
up just by being in there.
- You know what that
feeling is, right?- Yeah.
I don't know if it's because
they write children's stories,
but the writers' impressions were
really nice and lovely. And...
Wait a second, wait a second.
Drink some water.
You're going to run out of breath.
And they were sitting around a table
about this big having a story meeting.
Thank you.
It's delicious.
That writer's dream was for people who are
like-minded to gather and write collaboratively.
So this time she really made a creative
fairy tale village. Isn't that so cool?
Don't you want to do that too?
You look extremely fired
up and excited right now.
Your dream was to be a writer of
children's books when you were younger.
But I'm going to be
leaving with you anyway.
That's right, we were going to talk about
language schools today. What do I need to do?
First, you need to look
at these and choose.
In about a year, will I be
able to speak English too?
This is so cool!
Where should I go?
It's so hard to choose.
Why are you already up on a Sunday?
Well, for me, everyday is like Sunday.
These are potential questions for my graduate
school interview. Ask me some questions.
Interview questions?
Let's see... Four P's are?
The four key elements required
for effective marketing.
Product, price, place, promotion!
Woah! Then, what is promotion?
Advertising, PR, direct marketing, sales marketing,
and so forth. Meaning, communication with customers.
Woah, Min Ha Ri! You studied hard!
I'm pretty awesome, aren't I?
I mean, was studying always this fun?
Product, service, design, quality...
Ha Ri, you look really pretty right now.
So out of the blue...
Just today?
Not your face, but your expression.
You look really excited.
Really?
In any case, I am really
excited these days.
Are we going to differentiate the products?
You don't look pretty.
You don't look excited at all.
So this time she really made a creative
fairy tale village. Isn't that so cool?
Don't you want to do that, too?
You look really fired up
and excited right now.
I hope that you will always keep
on dreaming, Hye Jin.. -Lee Yi Eun
I am thinking where you want to
be is the right place to be.
Do you want to eat dinner
together at home later?
Golden Dew
You're here, come in.
- Let's get married,
Seong Joon.- Huh? What?!
So, what' I'm saying is...
We're getting married,
but I'm going to marry you no
matter what happens anyway.
So, of course I should do it with you.
I'm going to, but... Oh.
I got rings ready too. This one is
mine, and... Give me your hand.
This one is yours.
I'm proposing to you right now, you know.
But I'm not saying we
should do it right away.
You're asking me to give
you about a year, right?
How did you know?
So, the thing is, if you want
to know why I need time...
It's because you want to try doing the childrens'
stories job that was proposed to you, right?
How did you know that?
Thank you for being honest with me.
I saw that you want to do that.
I was a little worried that you were
giving it up because of me, too.
So you knew.
If you would have stayed silent about it and just gone to
America with me, you definitely would have had some regrets.
You definitely would have had some regrets.
You would have stewed over it by yourself
and I wouldn't have known it
and would have felt sorry and upset
when I found out about it later.
You told me because you trust me, right?
I wanted to look beautiful to myself.
When someone is doing something
that they really want to do,
they look the most beautiful.
I also wanted to look truly beautiful
as I do the work that I really want to do.
Not to someone else,
but to myself.
That's right. You thought well.
Thank you, and sorry.
But I feel kind of wronged! I was planning
on going all out for my proposal.
Really?
How were you planning on doing it?
It's too late now. It's
fine if you don't know.
Let's do a puzzle together for
the first time in a long time.
- Why? How were planning on doing it?
What is it?- Shh!
But seriously, how were you going to do it?
Just tell me a little bit
of how you were going to.
Why are you asking me now?
I told you it's fine.
Bring the peeking sister puzzle
next time so we can fit that piece.
But where did that one piece go?
Ah, you really can't tell me? I'm curious!
How were you going to propose?!
It's over there. Go get it.
I was planning on proposing like this.
And
I was planning on saying this too.
Before I met you, I didn't know
that it was possible to live
so happily in this world.
I want to make you feel the
happiness that you made me feel
for the rest of our lives.
Hye Jin,
will you...
♪ You don't look or sound unfamiliar ♪
In one year, will you marry me?
♪ Maybe it's ♪
Give me your hand.♪ because I didn't know ♪
♪ love ♪
♪ That I couldn't say anything ♪
We both have two rings.
♪ I'm looking at you ♪
Well, it's unique so it's good.
♪ I think you're still unaware ♪
What?
Do you really have to go?
Well, I mean... It's late,
I didn't put my laundry away... and...
I need to separate my trash.
Alright, let's go. I'll take you home.
Ah, my car key! I must have left it.
Stay here, I'll go get it real quick.
- Hey, I can just ride this taxi.-
Just stay here. I'll take you.
It only takes 10 minutes to get there anyway.
I'm going! I'll call you when I get there. Bye!
Who is it?
Hye Jin.
Well, now that I think about it, I don't
really have to fold my laundry today,
I was thinking that I don't have
to separate my trash today either.
Do you have to live and eat there? Can't
you go back and forth from this house?
It's a collaborative work.
Until the final product comes
out, all the writers stay there,
I have to stay there as well.
Even yesterday, it didn't feel real
that you are leaving this house.
Now that you're packing, I'm
getting the real sense of it.
You're right.
Except when my family was
in Japan, for you and me,
this is our first time
separating like this, right?
Are you crying?
Crying? Why would I cry?
Why would you cry?
Because you're about to
cry, so it's making me cry!
I almost went to America but I'm going to Haeil,
which is way closer, so why are you crying?
It'll only take 2 hours to get
there if you're determined.
Even when I wasn't determined, we saw each
other everyday for the last ten years...
But now we can only see each
other when we're determined.
Why are you saying stuff
like that and making me cry?
If you're not here, who'll cry
and blow their nose with me?
If you cry, I'll run over
to blow my nose with you.
Will you really come and
blow your nose with me?
Of course!
- Hye Jin. - Ha Ri.
For Kim Hye Jin's new beginning, and...
To Min Ha Ri's graduate school acceptance!
Cheers! Love shot!
♪ I ain't fakin', I ain't fakin' this ♪
♪ I ain't fakin', I ain't fakin'
this, shut up and let me go. Hey! ♪
Do you remember when we
first moved into here?
The boiler broke and everything.
You mean the day when our lips
almost got twisted when we got up?
Do you remember that?
While you were in the middle of taking a shower,
suddenly, there was a shortage of water.
- So while washing your hair... Yes, of course, I remember.
I was shampooing and the water stopped so suddenly!
Oh my gosh! Oh my gosh!
- Don't go, Hye Jin. - No.
- I will go. - No, don't.
- You don't even do cleaning.
- No, don't go. - No.
Hey, Min Ha Ri, you want to die?!
That's the office over there.
Oh, that looks great.
I might just live here
and not go to New York.
When do I go to the airport tomorrow?
When's your flight?
Hye Jin.
Should we not do something like
crying and separate at the airport?
Why? I still need to go
there and see you off.
I might not see you for a whole year.
I'm worried that it wouldn't
work out well because of me.
I was pretending to be cool when I said okay
to your choice, but if I see you there,
I'm worried that I might beg you to
come with me and cry and whatnot.
Then you're saying we should separate here?
Keep your guard up. You never know
when I'll suddenly show up here.
I will call you ten times a day,
and send you emails every day.
Like in the past, let's write
letters to each other often.
Let's do that.
Go in.
You go first, I'll go
in after I see you off.
Okay.
I'm going.
I love you.
I love you, Hye Jin.
Me too.
♪ All of the time that's left ♪
I love you, too.♪ to you and me ♪
♪ I want to use every moment on us ♪
♪ Until the last time that
we close our eyes forever ♪
♪ Just as I do now, ♪
♪ I'm only going to love you ♪
Hye Jin, where are you going?
Someone's come here! I'll be back!
♪ I'm ugly. I'm too ugly to have you ♪
Hello.
♪ Listen to it gently go 'La la la' ♪
♪ I'll tell you now. I'll protect you ♪
♪ I'll love you for life ♪