The mysterious music show, King of Mask Singer.
Last week.
With a dreamlike performance, he left everyone satisfied.
The 45th King of Mask Singer...
who won three consecutive times is...
Tin Man with a Burning Heart.
(He dressed up like Santa today.)
(You look adorable.)
(Park Wan Kyu)
If you open your mind, you can experience...
a Christmas miracle.
Today's show is the Christmas Special.
The mysterious music show, King of Mask Singer.
Hello, I am your unbiased show host, Kim Seong Ju.
(Niel from Teen Top)
(Na Ra of Hellovenus)
I wish you a merry Christmas
I wish you a merry Christmas and a happy new year
Merry Christmas, everyone.
I wish all of you a merry Christmas.
On Christmas day,
Tin Man with a Burning Heart is...
performing a miracle.
He is seeking his fourth successive victory now.
Tin Man, please say hello to our viewers.
Dashing through the snow
In a one-horse open sleigh
Shall we go or not?
Marry Christmas, everyone!
Merry Christmas to you, too!
For Tin Man...
who is looking for his fourth successive victory,
one of the panelists prepared a little gift for him.
As you know, Christmas is all about sharing.
So here, we have Gianna Jun of King of Mask Singer.
- He is Gianna Jun... - Officially,
- of King of Mask Singer. - he is.
His hair is shinier than...
- than Gianna Jun's. - I agree.
Wan Kyu prepared a song for Tin Man.
(Excited)
It is a Christmas gift for Tin Man.
This is for the beautiful king, Tin Man.
(What song is the legendary singer going to sing for Tin Man?)
(Tin Man)
(I really like you)
(Wan Kyu sang the song to Seung Woo before.)
(I love you)
(Acting cute)
I love you!
(A 43-year-old man acts charming for the King of Mask Singer.)
- That was a nice gift. - He is cuter than Gianna Jun.
(She bursts into laughter.)
He is the youngest of his family.
(Shy)
The mysterious music show, King of Mask Singer.
Let's begin the matches in earnest.
Who will be the King of Mask Singer...
for the last episode of 2016...
and the beginning of 2017?
The first step to become the 46th King of Mask Singer.
Let's begin...
the first match of Round One.
(King of Mask Singer)
The first match of Round One.
A voice of sharing on the street.
We Are the Salvation Army.
(We Are the Salvation Army)
(Winter is the time...)
(to put sharing into action.)
(I will warm your heart.)
(He is hot.)
Is he in the army? He must be a man.
I think he'll be quite old.
His opponent is...
a woman with a clear voice like white snow.
Our Town Is in Snow District,
White City.
(Our Town Is in Snow District, White City)
(Do you want to know where our town is?)
(Any place where we have snow is our town.)
(Hello, everyone?)
(Joy to the world, Our Town has come!)
(We have two masked singers for the winter.)
(What song did they prepare for Christmas?)
("Grass Leaf Love" by Choi Sung Soo)
- Is it "Grass Leaf Love"? - That's right.
I told you. He's old.
("Grass Leaf Love" is a refreshing song released in 1980s.)
(What will the duet song sound like?)
(He has a fine voice.)
(He has a low and deep voice.)
(Salvation Army's voice sounds sweet and gentle.)
(Surprised)
(Our Town's voice is...)
(as refreshing and clear as the song.)
(Between the low-pitch voice and the high-pitch falsetto,)
(Our Town's voice lovably rings in people's ears.)
(Dew)
(I'm sunshine)
(Sunshine)
(Two people with different singing styles are...)
(making the perfect harmony.)
(That's so sweet.)
(You are)
(My grass leaf love)
(I love you)
(I love you, too.)
(Salvation Army's deep voice and Our Town's clear voice)
(Who could they be?)
(Lively)
Her voice is so refreshing.
(Our Town's refreshing charm...)
(warms people's hearts like spring.)
(Salvation Army's unique voice...)
(has its own resonance.)
(I love you)
(Even her high-pitched voice sounds refreshing.)
(Great vibratos)
I'm sure she's a singer.
(They all feel happy.)
(It is a sweet confession of love.)
(Grass leaf love)
(A heartwarming and refreshing melody)
(Their performance turned the cold winter into a warm Christmas day.)
(Love is in the air.)
(It is fresh.)
That was very refreshing.
(Satisfied)
The first match of Round One is over.
It was the first match of Round One.
Kai seemed to enjoy the song very much.
He even danced to the song.
(Seong Ju talks to Kai.)
Hello, I'm Kai.
The song reminded me of a scene.
They looked like a couple pounding steamed rice into cake.
(They were perfect for each other.)
- With a rice-cake mallet? - The husband balanced the song...
with his deep voice as if he was pounding steamed rice,
while the wife made rice cakes from the dough...
with her clear and beautiful voice.
It was a perfect harmony...
that reminded me of soft, pretty, and delicious rice cakes.
- That's how I felt. - I see.
I think he has a talent for music.
- But I don't think he is a singer. - I see.
- He's not a singer? - No.
Meanwhile, Our Town has...
great vocal techniques to use falsetto and chest voices freely.
But I think...
she is an actress who sings very well.
- An actress? - Yes.
- That's my guess. - Okay.
Then we will hear Young Seok's opinion about the duet performance.
Salvation Army has an attractive voice.
- Does he? - Yes.
His voice is as heavy as a piggy bank full of coins.
It's so full that you won't be able to hear the sound of coins jingling.
- If we heard him reading his lines, - Yes.
we'd have noticed his voice immediately.
- Do you think he is an actor? - Yes, I think he is an actor.
- How old do you think he is? - He's about 39 years old.
39 years old? That's very specific.
I could tell Salvation Army is...
in his late 30s.
Salvation Army is in his late 30s.
- Or he might be in his 40s. - He might be in his 40s.
I think both of them are singers.
- Both of them? - Yes.
- Is Salvation Army a singer? - Yes.
What if he loses?
He may be an actor slash singer...
or something slash singer.
Whatever his real job is, he may also be a singer.
- He has his original job. - He probably sings at night.
- At night? - I think...
he sings in nightclubs or something.
- In nightclubs? - Yes.
I saw him wagging his legs...
on tiptoes while singing.
- Like this? - That's right.
That's what singers in nightclubs do.
- Singers in nightclubs? - Yes.
In fact, he distorted his voice.
- It was not his real voice. - I agree.
He was afraid of being caught...
with his real voice.
He needs a lot of strength to distort his voice...
by making it deep.
His voice is very deep by nature.
Also, take a look at his body. He has an athletic body.
That means he's strong enough...
to sing with a different voice.
- Really? - Otherwise, he can't do that.
We have...
Kim Hyun Jung here.
(What does she think about their identities?)
Hello. It's nice to meet you.
When I heard Salvation Army sing,
it sounded like talking rather than singing.
So I thought he was more like an actor in a historical drama...
than a singer.
She narrowed it down to an actor in a historical drama.
Meanwhile I noticed something about Our Town.
Compared to the size of her body, the outfit she is wearing...
seems too big.
- It's very spacious for her body. - Is it?
Most people would attempt to look slimmer.
Is she an idol singer?
I judge her to be an idol singer who recently learned...
how to sing professionally,
judging from the nervousness in her voice.
The panelists have many opinions about these two masked singers.
That's why they will show us their dancing skills.
(Will they dance?)
The dance Our Town prepared...
are the highlights of Kim Hyun Jung's hit songs.
She will show her dance skills...
in front of the original singer. Music, please.
(Kim Hyun Jung's Hit Songs Dance)
("Breakup with Her")
(Stretching)
- She is young. - There you go.
She is young.
(She is exactly like Hyun Jung 18 years ago.)
- She is bringing back memories. - She's young.
(It's "Bruise".)
"Turn everything back."
(Shaking her body)
(Dancing)
(Powerful)
That's right.
She is doing well.
(She is good.)
Her dance moves are on point.
She didn't make a single mistake.
(Stiff)
- She is old. - She seems old.
She is in her 30s or 40s.
She might be in her 40s.
(Pointing)
(Cute)
All right. Let's end it here.
She danced very well.
(Analyzing)
The dance confirmed my initial thought.
- Really? - Yes.
- She has to be an idol singer. - You are certain.
Yes. She couldn't dance perfectly due to the mask she is wearing.
If she shows us the dance of her own song,
I am sure we will see that she is a great dancer.
Let's see what the original dance is like.
Please show us the original dance.
Music, please.
(Expectant)
"Turn everything back."
(This is the original dance.)
You need to drag out the movement.
(Powerful)
That's right.
(Swaying)
(Turning)
(Here it comes.)
(It's a body roll with 18 years of experience.)
(His eyes widen.)
(Sexy)
(Their dance shows different charms.)
(Pointing)
(Charismatic)
(This is the class of the original singer.)
(Kim Hyun Jung is the best.)
The original singer is on a different level.
There was a big difference.
It was very different.
- There was a big difference. - Our Town must be much younger...
- than Hyun Jung. - Thank you.
Compared to Hyun Jung's, her dance looked very awkward.
Our panelists think he is a singer with a different profession...
who used to sing at nightclubs.
Salvation Army will show us his specialty.
He said he is very good at imitating action.
He will first imitate how Yoon Seok takes off his clothes at home.
That will be interesting.
Let's take a look. Show us your impression.
Yoon Seok arrives home. He begins to take off his clothes.
Yoon Seok took off his clothes.
He is taking off his clothes again.
(He hangs them neatly.)
He hung them up.
Okay.
(He takes off more clothes.)
He must have worn a lot of clothes.
He is taking off more clothes.
- He was wearing a lot of clothes. - I don't know why this is funny.
- He is good at this. - He is, right?
- I think he is a comedian. - A comedian?
He is taking off his clothes again.
- It's "So I went". - Heo Kyung Hwan.
- "So I went". - It's the same gesture.
"So I went".
- "So I went". - That's right.
- "So I went". - It's the same gesture.
- You can't fool us. - "So I went".
- You can't fool us. - I see.
The gestures come out.
- Look at that. - "So I went".
This time,
he will imitate how Gu Ra shaves.
It makes sense.
- An actor wouldn't imitate me. - He will imitate how Gu Ra shaves.
(Whirring)
He is starting at the chin. Oh, look at the chin.
(Laughing)
He is a comedian.
- It's Heo Kyung Hwan. - It has to be Heo Kyung Hwan.
He is very good at trifles like that.
Come on, Kyung Hwan.
They are certain he is Heo Kyung Hwan.
He has a nice body, too. He must be Heo Kyung Hwan.
Lastly, he will imitate how Park Wan Kyu runs in a hurry...
after receiving a call...
while he was eating instant noodles.
Wan Kyu is eating instant noodles.
He turned on the stove.
He is cooking instant noodles.
He adds seasoning and stirs.
The instant noodles are done, and he begins to eat.
(He is putting his hair to the other side.)
He begins to eat.
(Laughing)
(My hair must be treasured.)
He is having trouble because of his hair.
He needs to eat carefully.
(Careful)
He is Heo Kyung Hwan.
He got a call. They want him to come out.
- He needs to hurry up. - Look at the way he is running.
He is Heo Kyung Hwan.
- He is Heo Kyung Hwan. - He is tying his hair.
- He is tying his hair. - He is Heo Kyung Hwan.
- I think he is Heo Kyung Hwan. - He needs to tie his hair.
All right.
Let's end it here.
While Salvation Army reminds me of Heo Kyung Hwan,
he could be Yoo Sae Yoon.
(He is always cheerful and quick-witted.)
(He is a comedian through and through.)
- He could be Yoo Sae Yoon. - Yoo Sae Yoon.
All right. Now, I will announce...
the result of the first match of Round One.
You will be surprised by the result.
(Surprised)
Don't tease Salvation Army.
- Why would you tease him? - Okay.
Salvation Army had a nice voice,
and Our Town had a voice that was as pure as white snow.
I'll now reveal the winner...
who will move on to Round Two.
(With his deep voice,)
(Salvation Army showed power and sentimentality.)
(With her clear and fresh voice,)
(Our Town showed purity of a dewdrop.)
Who is the winner who will move on to Round Two?
The winner is...
(The winner is...)
Salvation Army! Salvation Army!
Our Town!
(Will the winner be Our Town?)
(Who will become the winner and make an appearance in 2017?)
Who is the first winner...
who will move on to Round Two? Please show the result.
The winner is...
Our Town.
(Our Town moved on to Round Two.)
(We will see Our Town next year as well.)
(The panelists are divided in their reactions.)
What was the final score?
Our Town won.
The final score was 69 to 30.
You received a surprisingly large amount of votes.
Our Town won.
Please return to your waiting room and prepare for the next round.
Please give her a big hand.
(The shocking identity of Salvation Army will be revealed.)
(My goodness.)
My legs went weak.
I am so nervous.
Please look forward to my performance in Round Two.
It seems like Salvation Army...
is devastated.
I prepared four songs.
- Did you prepare four songs? - Yes.
You even prepared an encore song.
I will sing the two remaining songs at a different program.
He is greatly devastated.
Who could Salvation Army be?
We will reveal his identity with a solo performance...
prepared for Round Two. Please give him a big hand.
(He has natural talent in singing.)
(His voice is weighty like a full piggy bank.)
(He has a unique tone of voice.)
(He is a singer with an additional profession.)
(Is he Heo Kyung Hwan, the comedian?)
(Is he Yoo Sae Yoon, the comedian?)
(He showed an impressive sense of humor.)
(Who could Salvation Army be?)
("Last Promise" by Kim Jung Min)
I know this song.
(The intro of this hit song made people's hearts flutter in the 90s.)
(Salvation Army's voice sounds familiar.)
(He is no longer trying to conceal his voice.)
(Everyone can tell who he is.)
(Salvation Army's performance is different from the duet.)
(He has a charming baritone.)
(Come back to me)
(We promised to stay together forever)
(His emotions go well with rock ballad.)
(Salvation Army sings a sad love song with all his heart.)
Now, Salvation Army, please take off your mask...
and reveal your face.
(Screaming)
He is...
Who are you? Who is he?
I think it's him.
That's strange.
(Who are you?)
He is...
Heo Kyung Hwan, a comedian with 11 years of experience.
(It was Kyung Hwan.)
(We knew it.)
(They recognized Kyung Hwan's familiar voice.)
(It's good to see you, Kyung Hwan.)
(Kyung Hwan looks more serious than ever.)
(He's the best.)
(He has a wild but soft voice.)
(It makes you concentrate on his singing.)
(He dances frivolously.)
(He imitates Kim Jung Min's voice.)
(It's a delightful stage where...)
(you can hear both Jung Min and Kyung Hwan's voice.)
(He finishes off with motioning Wan Kyu's trademark hair tying.)
(Laughing)
("Last Promise" by Kyung Hwan was a great performance to enjoy.)
That was great.
(You're the best.)
When he was singing, I didn't know.
He changed his voice. You couldn't have known.
You found out who I was too soon.
All right. Salvation Army was the handsome comedian,
Heo Kyung Hwan.
Please say hello to the viewers.
Hello. I'm Heo Kyung Hwan, a singer and comedian. Good to see you.
(He debuted as a comedian in 2007.)
("This is what I'm talking about.")
("No, no. You can't do that.")
("If you want to know, give me 50 cents.")
If you want to know, give me 50 cents.
(He has so many catchphrases.)
(He also released many songs like "Ing" "NAMJA" and "Precious Girl".)
(He's a famous comedian who is also a singer.)
(With his witty words...)
I was like this.
I survived. I should've collapsed.
(He draws a lot of attention on variety shows.)
Here is the bazooka.
(Kyung Hwan is a great entertainer.)
You prepared so many specialties for today,
but you made this hand gesture while imitating Yoon Seok.
I tried to hold it back,
but I realized that I was doing it.
- You went like this. - I knew I messed up.
He's wearing many layers.
- How many layers... - Look at that.
- Kyung Hwan does that. - It's Kyung Hwan.
(His hands stopped awkwardly.)
(I messed up.)
They caught it with sharp observations.
I'm so disappointed that you couldn't show us your specialties.
Can I pretend this never happened and come back next week?
You can't do that.
Kyung Hwan, you were a panelist here before.
Our staff repeatedly asked you to show us...
your singing ability here on stage, but you hesitated for a long time.
It's because it's not easy to perform on this stage.
Whenever I came here as a panelist,
I wasn't sure if I could sing here...
and touch people's hearts with my song.
It was very hard to decide to come and sing on this show.
I've been here as a panelist,
so I was worried that my singing would disappoint the audience.
It was so hard to decide,
but I was told I could be a panelist at the beginning of next year.
That's why I decided to come.
Is that so? All right.
Are you satisfied with your performance?
- Do you think it went well? - I've practiced for a month.
I think I sang like this on the first day of practice.
(Goodness.)
- Gosh, but I'm so relieved. - Why?
I couldn't sleep well...
for the past week.
If I had known I'd mess it up, I would've slept well.
(He's upset.)
I just couldn't sleep.
But you didn't mess up.
Seung Woo and I were talking.
- We think you did well. - The important thing is...
- Besides, - You were great.
you were even disguising your voice.
You're a grass leaf
- But it's... - You should've sung like that.
(Disappointed)
Today, as a comedian who loves music,
he touched our hearts with a heartwarming stage.
It was Heo Kyung Hwan. Please give him a big hand.
- Go, Kyung Hwan! - Thank you.
(Thanks to you, we had a delightful and pleasant time.)
Hello.
I didn't do well.
Let's start over again.
I'm so disappointed. I could've done better.
Being on King of Mask Singer was very meaningful to me.
Now that it has become 11 years since I debuted,
I no longer felt nervous or excited...
when I shoot TV shows or appear on events.
It's because I do it so often these days.
But in a long time, I felt nervous today.
I felt tense and thrilled...
(It made him excited and tense.)
I felt it in such a long time.
If there are celebrities who are tired of being on TV shows,
I'd recommend them to come to this show.
It'll make them feel excited again in a long time.
This is the result of Round One.
Our Town Is in Snow District, White City...
defeated Heo Kyung Hwan and moved on to Round Two.
The second match of Round One.
His sweet voice will save humanity.
Defense Corps Member, Dessert Man.
(Defense Corps Member, Dessert Man)
You'll soon hear my sweet voice.
(It's time for a sweet dessert.)
He says he has a sweet voice.
- Which will save humanity. - I know.
Let's meet his opponent.
His song will bring blessings and love...
on Christmas.
Tree to the World.
(Tree to the World)
Please look forward to a stage as fancy as a Christmas tree.
(I'm Tree in Santa's outfit.)
(He's handsome.)
It's Santa Clause.
He's tall.
Dessert Man...
seems too much like an idol singer.
- He reminds me of Seung Woo. - Yes.
Maybe he'll sing with a sweet voice.
(You must have dessert...)
(and a tree on Christmas.)
(What kind of stage did the sweet Dessert Man and manly Tree...)
(prepare to celebrate the Christmas night?)
("Old Love" by Lee Moon Sae)
He's so good.
(His sad voice pierces your heart.)
(He quietly calls...)
(the name of an old love.)
I love his voice.
(Tree has a beautiful voice like the sound of a Christmas bell.)
(This is great.)
(They sing about the pain of love in a delicate harmony.)
(When I long for something)
(I'll keep on longing for it)
(I know this voice.)
(It's heartwarming.)
(He has a voice as pure as white snow.)
(You can feel his heart throbbing as he thinks of for his old love.)
(The two men's beautiful harmony spreads...)
(on a silent Christmas night.)
(Their stage warms you up on a cold winter night.)
- They sound like choir singers. - They're great.
I love it.
(Tin Man's heart also warms up.)
(It sounds more sincere since he sings calmly.)
(If you come into my mind)
(I'll just leave it as it is)
(His lonesome voice expresses endless loneliness...)
(that people can't even think of loving someone.)
(Even when spring comes after winter days,)
(the one who I loved will be remembered forever.)
(It's amazing.)
I love it.
(Their harmony brightens up the Christmas night.)
(She's fascinated.)
(Their performance is like a long-waited Christmas present.)
(Warmth of the song lingers in their minds.)
It was excellent.
- It's wonderful. - Brilliant.
It's so lovely.
I love it.
Second match of Round One is over.
Let's start from Gu Ra's strategist,
- Seung Woo. - Strategist Yoo.
- Let's hear his opinion first. - He has a clue already.
You seemed very busy trying to guess their identities.
Since they both have amazing voices, it was really hard to choose one.
As for Tree, his singing style...
reminded me a lot of Shin Seung Hun.
- You mean Tree? - Yes. His pronunciation was...
very similar to that of Seung Hun.
- I see. - He sang like that.
I think he's...
- a big fan of Seung Hun. - Shin Seung Hun.
Or he could be a ballad singer...
of his era.
That's what I'm guessing.
- As for Dessert Man, - Yes.
- I'm sure he's a ballad singer. - I see.
If he moves on to Round 2 or Round 3,
I think he will be good at singing...
with high notes.
If he can manage his condition well,
I think he could become King of Mask Singer.
- You set a high value on him. - Also, he sounds like...
he is in his early 20s.
- His voice sounds young? - Right.
Jang Hyuk, you seemed very busy talking to Seung Woo.
Both of them have amazing voices.
As for Dessert Man,
his voice sounds so attractive...
that it makes people concentrate...
- so they can listen to him well. - I see.
He's born with that amazing voice.
Moreover, he almost didn't use any vibrato while singing.
Does that mean that...
he isn't that skillful at singing?
- It rather means he's confident. - No. Don't take it that way.
- Really? - It means he's confident.
He sang comfortably.
Without anyone knowing
(He sings calmly without using any vibrato.)
This kind of his singing style...
implies his confidence.
It means that he's good enough without any technique.
- His voice sounds confident. - Right.
- As for Tree to the World, - What do you think about him?
he breathes a lot while singing.
(He breathes out heavily.)
(He sings with deep breath.)
He breathes so deeply...
to express all his emotions.
This kind of breathing method is...
- used a lot by actors. - Is he an actor, then?
You mean someone who uses this kind of breathing technique is...
- more likely to be an actor, right? - Yes.
(Tree must be an actor.)
Eagle eye, Kai.
You're looking at them like a detective.
As for Dessert Man,
his physical appearance and voice...
seem very young.
Those young singers tend to...
- use many techniques while singing. - I see.
But he sang very calmly with all his heart,
and it sounded really nice. As for Tree to the World,
his first appearance caught my eyes...
because I could feel a sense of true modesty...
through every single gesture of his.
He folds his hands,
and he tends to...
- look down a lot. - Right.
I could feel his desperation...
towards this stage today.
It's something like a child...
wishing for Santa to come.
It's something like you're waiting for a Christmas present.
Yes. That kind of innocent sorrow was...
- expressed well through his voice. - Right.
I personally like him very much.
- He's appealing in that way. - Yes, he was amazing.
As for Tree, you've been folding your hands...
and looking down from the beginning until the end.
It's possible since he's the one who has experienced...
rumors or aroused criticisms.
- It's hard to fake it. - Who could he be?
- Who is it? - I'm afraid it's Tak Jae Hoon.
Tak Jae Hoon.
It's hard to fake it with thick clothes.
You mean it's hard to maintain those modest gestures.
- It was a minority opinion. - What an interesting view point.
- It's very interesting. - Someone's name has been mentioned.
I think he is...
one of the trendy singers.
I think a lot of viewers might know who he is.
As for Tree, this is what I think.
- There are many actors who are shy. - I see.
Some actors run away...
- when asked for an autograph. - Really?
- I think it's Park Hyuk Kwon. - Park Hyuk Kwon?
There is an actor called Park Hyuk Kwon.
(He runs away when asked for an autograph.)
(He's a shy actor, Park Hyuk Kwon.)
I feel sorry for that.
(He's shy.)
He's good at singing.
I saw it from "Radio Star".
I think I heard his real voice...
when he was singing.
I think he was a popular star among teenagers.
- Was he? - He's probably an actor.
You're guessing somebody, right?
- B. W. M. - B. W. M?
- Yes. - Who is B. W. M?
He told us initial letters of the star's name.
- Byeon Woo Min? - Right.
You're talking about Woo Min.
(He was very popular among teenage girls.)
(He's an actor, Byeon Woo Min who's been acting for 30 years.)
Right. It must be Byeon Woo Min.
Do you think it makes sense?
It does.
He used to be criticized and blamed a lot...
in many dramas.
He always stood like that...
- in those dramas. - In dramas?
- As for Dessert Man, - Yes.
he's really good at singing and his voice sounds amazing.
I listened carefully...
while he was singing in harmony.
He was singing freely between...
the 3rd and 5th chords.
(He sings in harmony freely.)
I think he's a member of a vocal group.
I think it's a group...
- which consists of 4 members. - A group of 4 members?
- The group's name starts with S. - Really?
- His name starts with S as well. - It does?
- In my opinion... - So You from Sistar?
He said So You from Sistar.
So You from Sistar.
- In my opinion... - So You from Sistar.
- Who is it, then? - So You from Sistar.
It's Sweet Sorrow.
- Sweet Sorrow. - Sweet Sorrow.
- It's Sung Jin Hwan. - Sung Jin Hwan.
(His specialty is singing in harmony.)
(It's a vocal group, Sweet Sorrow.)
You're guessing that he's Sung Jin Hwan from Sweet Sorrow.
Okay then. I'll give you a chance...
to hear their real voices.
Dessert Man is...
good at voice imitation.
First of all, he will imitate Bobby Kim's voice.
It's Bobby Kim's voice. Give it a go.
(Preparing)
I love you
I do love you
There's no answer
Stop it here.
You can stop whenever you want.
His voice imitation was pretty boring.
Many people tend to exaggerate when they imitate his voice.
- This time, - He's a very honest person.
- it's Lee So Ra's voice. - Lee So Ra?
It's a female singer Lee So Ra's voice.
(Remember only that)
(We)
(Keep going.)
We
Let's stop it here.
You can stop whenever you want.
Why did you laugh while you were singing?
- The lyrics were too sad. - He laughed since they're too sad.
Sorry for smirking.
Now,
it's time to see Tree's b-boying.
(Surprised)
- He'll be b-boying. - Byeon Woo Min is...
over 50 years old. Is that even possible for him?
He'll be b-boying. Music, please.
(It's Tree's b-boying.)
(He dances freely.)
Look at his restrained movements.
(Ready and shoot.)
His moves are so restrained.
B-boying, b-boying.
(He passionately makes splendid steps.)
Dance more lively.
More lively.
(He moves hurriedly.)
(He ends with a cute wave.)
That's enough.
- This is it. - I didn't expect that.
Make your own judgement based on his dance.
I doubt it's Byeon Woo Min.
- It's not Byeon Woo Min. - He does dance well.
- He really dances well. - Yes.
I'd like to ask Niel one question.
Are they from idol groups?
I don't think they are idols.
- What about Dessert Man? - Are you sure?
He's young, but he's not an idol.
I think he might be...
a solo singer-songwriter.
Aren't idols supposed to be funny?
- That's right. - Right?
- Of course. - Idols...
- try to be funny. - Yes.
Yes, that's right.
- I'll impersonate Bobby Kim. - Bobby Kim.
- It's the idol's impersonation. - Let's compare.
(He's getting ready.)
(I fill up today with drinks)
(He copies the way Bobby Kim rolls his eyes.)
(I can't stop thinking of you)
- That's how you should do it. - You should do it like that.
- That's how idols do it. - Right.
That's how you draw people's attention for your team.
- Yes. - You're right.
- You need to be funny. - Yes.
Now, I will announce the result...
of the second match of Round One.
Dessert Man has a sweet voice.
Tree to the World lightens the mood.
Among these two masked signers,
I'll now reveal the winner...
of this match.
Who is the winner?
(He expressed a solitude that makes our hearts ache.)
(Dessert Man's solitude is beautiful.)
(He expresses strong emotions.)
(Tree to the World showed his maturity.)
Who is the second winner...
who will move on...
to Round Two?
- The winner is... - The winner is...
- You never know. - Who could it be?
Who is it?
(Everyone is anxious to find out.)
(Both have different charms.)
(He fiddles with his fingers.)
(Her heart is pounding.)
Please show the result.
The winner is...
(Dessert Man won.)
Dessert Man.
(Dessert Man takes his sweet victory.)
(They show different responses to the result.)
(One's happy while the other is sad.)
He has a fantastic voice.
Tree to the World did well, too.
That's a pity.
Dessert Man is the winner.
With a final score of 61 to 38,
Dessert Man moved on to Round Two.
Please go back to your waiting room.
Please give him a big hand.
He moved on to Round Two.
Dessert Man moved on to Round Two.
He will compete against Our Town.
(He bows politely.)
I will do my best in Round Two. Please look forward to it.
Let's find out who Tree is.
Please give Tree a round of applause.
(This will be the last clue to figure out who Tree is.)
(He breathes a lot when he sings.)
(He must be an actor.)
(Could he be the actor Park Hyuk Kwon?)
(Or could he be the actor Byeon Woo Min?)
(Perhaps it's the singer Tak Jae Hoon.)
("I Love You" by Simply Sunday)
(Even if it's not glamorous,)
(his simple singing style catches people's ears.)
(Like the lights on a Christmas tree,)
(he has a soft and warm voice.)
(The audience is immersed in his song.)
(He sings from the bottom of his heart.)
(Reminiscing of an old love)
(Through Tree's voice, the past becomes a beautiful memory.)
Now, Tree, please take off your mask...
and reveal your face.
(Screaming)
Tree is...
Who are you?
The audience seems delighted.
Who is it?
Now, Tree, please take off your mask and reveal your face.
Tree is...
Byeon Woo Min, the actor with 30 years of experience.
(He's Byeon Woo Min.)
Byeon Woo Min. My goodness.
(He's Byeon Woo Min, indeed.)
He guessed it right.
How did he know?
(Hyun Chul was spot on.)
(They are happy to see his face.)
(It feels strange to see Byeon Woo Min singing.)
(He's emotional.)
(Perhaps it's because it's been a while since he performed.)
(His voice trembles.)
Oh, gosh. Don't cry.
(They can feel his sincerity.)
(The audience becomes teary-eyed as well.)
This is shocking.
(Good to see you, Byeon Woo Min!)
("I Love You" sung by Byeon Woo Min from the bottom of his heart)
(It was a heartwarming performance.)
(You're amazing.)
He has a heartwarming voice.
- He must be nervous. - I think he's emotional.
He seems happy.
Please say hello to the viewers.
Hello. It's good to see you.
I enjoyed spending time with you. Thank you.
I see.
(He was one of the biggest actors in the 80s and 90s.)
(With method acting that suited various roles,)
(he's been active as an actor.)
(In "Temptation of Wife", his wife who returned with a spot under...)
(her eye revenged on him. Back then, his acting career reached its peak.)
(After a blank, he returned.)
(He is a skillful actor.)
(Byeon Woo Min is an actor who has acted for more than 30 years.)
Actually, Byeon Woo Min...
was emotional during the rehearsal.
(The rehearsal was going well.)
(He couldn't continue singing.)
(He wiped his tears and dropped his head in the end.)
(He couldn't finish the song.)
It seems like you were emotional while singing.
Yes. I was thinking of the past.
After getting married and my child was born,
I spent all my time and effort...
for my kid and wife.
I didn't have time to go to a karaoke and sing like this.
Songs that I sang were like...
I like playing, so come play with me
(I never knew this children's song was so sorrowful.)
You probably know the song.
I didn't have time to spend...
even just one hour for myself to sing like this...
for the last seven years.
As he's been devoting himself to caring for his child,
- he felt that way, I guess. - That's right.
In fact, I'm very busy with the drama shooting.
But I didn't want to miss this chance to sing on stage.
- I see. - I was so excited to be here...
and got carried away.
Would your daughter recognize you on TV?
My daughter? I think so.
(Why is Gu Ra talking about his child?)
Your daughter might be watching you now.
Please say hello to your daughter.
Why should I do that?
She might recognize you on TV.
I just want today to be a special day for me.
- I see. - I won't care about anything else.
He doesn't want to care about anything but himself today.
Ha Eun, have fun...
with Mom today.
He wants some time for himself.
It's time for me now.
I know.
By the way, I was really startled by Hyun Chul.
He recognized you right away.
I've been a big fan of Woo Min for a long time.
- I see. - Wow.
I hope to see him more often...
in many dramas.
I'm a big fan of you.
Thank you.
- Me, too. - Thank you.
Thank you very much.
(He is an actor beloved by a lot of celebrities.)
Today, he forgot about being a father and came here...
as an actor who loves music.
And he showed his performances with all sincerity.
- Please give him a big hand. - Go, Woo Min!
(We look forward to your future endeavors.)
(He feels relieved as he leaves the stage.)
It feels so good.
Now I'm relieved.
It feels good.
You must be disappointed.
No, I'm not.
I'm so happy. I feel great.
It was an exciting breaking away from the daily routine.
This program gave me unforgettable memories.
I want you...
to try singing just for yourselves today.
All of you deserve...
to be happy as well.
He happy. I love you.
Merry Christmas.
Defense Corps Member, Dessert Man beat Byeon Woo Min...
and moved on to Round Two.
Right after this show ends, the online mobile survey...
on this week's masked singers by netizens will proceed.
Please participate in the survey.
We are having duet matches in Round One.
Let's begin the third match of Round One.
The third match of Round One.
Her burning voice will melt permanent snow.
Mrs. Kettle Has Boiled.
(Mrs. Kettle Has Boiled)
(A cup of tea during a busy day)
(Would you care for a cup of tea?)
(She looks pretty.)
Look at her. She's cute.
Her opponent is...
like a gift set of songs...
full of luck.
Sock Boy Says You Reap What You Sow.
(Sock Boy Says You Reap What You Sow)
(This is a gift...)
(for those who did good deeds this year.)
(Please stuff my Christmas stocking with gifts.)
He looks so dashing. I like him.
(Excited)
They are a good-looking couple.
We usually get to see good-looking singers in Round Three.
- I sang in Round Three. - Really?
- You are wrong. - You are good looking.
(In fact, I sang in Round Three.)
- He looks a bit playful. - He does.
Is he a comedian?
I acted like that when I came on stage, too.
He might be a great singer.
(They look like a nice couple.)
(As she has a very slender figure,)
(they are already guessing who she is.)
(The two masked singers are catching people's eyes.)
(What song are they going to sing in Round Three?)
("I Will Become Dust" by Lee Miki)
(With their delicate emotions,)
(they sing about the lonely winter.)
(Amazed)
(Surprised)
(Her husky voice sounds heartwarming.)
(His clear voice sounds like a little boy.)
(Amazed)
(Sock Boy's sweet voice...)
(and Mrs. Kettle's gentle voice...)
(make everyone sing along to the song.)
(His clear voice touches people's hearts.)
(The two great singers are...)
(making a beautiful harmony.)
(He's sure that they are singers,)
(but he doesn't know who they are.)
(She's making unique gestures,)
(but they have no idea who she is.)
I love her voice. It is beautiful.
Her voice reminds me of Okdal.
(She raises her clear voice gradually.)
(Sock Boy is just as good as her.)
(Moved with admiration)
(They sing "I Will Become Dust" together powerfully.)
(With their warm hearts and cool high-pitched voices,)
(they captivate people's hearts.)
(Who on earth are they?)
(They remade the old classic song into a new version.)
(Is he a rocker?)
(The more he shows his talent, the more it makes people confused.)
(They are two mysterious singers.)
(It was a beautiful harmony of two sentimental singers.)
(They are so good.)
(It was a heart-warming song.)
I love the harmony of a man and a woman.
The song sounds different as a man and a woman sing it together.
(Who are they?)
I guess they are singers.
I know. But I have no idea who they are.
(I don't want to say anything.)
The third match of Round One is over.
I saw him concentrate hard on watching their performance.
Let's hear Wan Kyu's opinion first.
How did you like it?
It is really difficult to say.
- What's so difficult? - While they sang,
the panelists were in a bit of a panic.
We didn't even know what was going on.
It is so hard to tell who they are.
When Sock Boy...
came on stage,
he looked very playful.
I was pretty sure he was a comedian.
But now I think he is a singer.
(Acting silly)
Or maybe not.
He's very suspicious.
Wan Kyu, just tell us what you think.
Don't be deceived by what he does.
- Mrs. Kettle seems... - Mrs. Kettle?
like a vocalist of a band.
I felt that way because...
a band's vocalist usually has a powerful voice.
And she sounded like a rocker.
- Maybe she's in a rock band. - If she was a rocker,
you'd have noticed her voice, right?
- I know. - Who would have...
such a voice?
Seung Woo, you seemed to enjoy their performance pretty much.
Yes. In fact, I like...
voices like Mrs. Kettle's.
She sounds like Marketa Irglova from the movie, "Once".
She sounds like a woman with a story to tell.
He's right.
A woman with a story to tell.
She sounds like a woman with a story to tell.
- Yes. So... - Look at that.
She looks very happy.
- She sang the song in high notes. - She's very excited.
But I think she can touch people's hearts...
even without the high notes.
That's why I think she is a singer...
in the indie music scene.
As for Sock Boy,
I think he is an idol singer...
who debuted many years ago.
I think he is in a second generation idol group...
such as Super Junior.
(Super Junior debuted 12 years ago.)
(The group has a variety of voices.)
I think he is an idol singer in a group such as Super Junior.
When Seung Woo said that Sock Boy is an idol singer,
Na Ra of Hellovenus...
- nodded enthusiastically. - Really?
- Yes, I did. - Do you agree with him?
- I think he is an idol singer. - Sock Boy.
- Yes. - You are certain.
When he entered the stage,
his steps and composure were full of swag.
I think he is an idol singer.
- I think Mrs. Kettle has... - Mrs. Kettle.
a beautiful body.
She is falling for the compliment again.
She loves compliments.
- Seriously. - She isn't an idol singer.
I don't think she is an idol singer. I think she is a solo artist...
who has a nice body and amazing singing skills.
- A solo artist. - Yes.
Here is what I noticed.
These days,
people don't cover their mouths when they laugh.
People in the older generations cover their mouths for two reasons.
It could be that their parents taught them to laugh that way.
It also could be that they cover their mouths...
- to hide their unruly teeth. - That's right.
I think she is from a generation before braces became popular.
She is on the older side.
She loves receiving compliments.
She shows signs of menopause.
- You saw signs of menopause. - Yes.
Those are the clues I got.
Kai seems to be confused.
- It's very difficult. - It's difficult.
- Everyone is confused. - I can't figure her out.
I focused on one thing about Mrs. Kettle.
She constantly used gestures.
She constantly shook her hand.
That's right.
(It's not a common gesture.)
Artists on the older side don't use such gestures.
The gesture tells me...
she could be an idol singer or a rapper.
- That's right. - They use such gestures.
Old people turn plates to regain their sense of balance.
- They do that. - A sense of balance?
- Is she old? - Perhaps she feels dizzy.
Old people do that.
The gesture she used...
seems like a hint but also confusing...
- at the same time. - I see.
Now, look at the way Sock Boy is standing.
- His legs are wide apart. - That's right.
- That's right. - He is a rocker.
- That's right. - Most people don't stand like this.
- His legs weren't that wide apart. - He sang in that position.
Most people don't stand like this.
He maintained that position when he sang.
I believe he is a singer...
with a know-how who feels comfortable on stage.
- That's right. - I believe Sock Boy's life...
is closely connected to rock.
Rock maniacs would love...
his L.A. style.
- You think he is from L.A. - It seems like it.
Is he Korean American?
(It's a secret.)
I am sure he is from the 90s.
He has amazing talent in singing.
- However... - However...
- Give us a name. - I have no idea.
- I have no idea. - This is frustrating.
- They should reflect on themselves. - Why do you say that?
Even though they sang passionately,
no one can figure out who they are.
Perhaps they have been away from the industry for a long time.
Do you have a sideline career?
We always say that voices are like fingerprints.
It's strange that no one knows who they are.
Now that we are talking about their identities,
Mrs. Kettle will show us her specialty.
It's Swing Dance. Music, please.
(Is she a rocker, rapper, or solo artist?)
It's Sistar's dance.
(Her dance is spot-on.)
My goodness.
I think she is a talented dancer.
(She does her best.)
She has a nice sense of rhythm.
"Shake It"!
(I am not an old woman.)
She has a nice sense of rhythm.
There you go.
(The next dance move is...)
(She shakes her bottom.)
My goodness, she didn't hold back.
Let's end it here. Let's end it at "Shake it."
Even though she has dancing skills, she is old.
You still think she is old.
Yes, she is old.
- She was probably a delinquent. - Delinquent?
She is a part of Generation X.
- She entered college in 1992. - She is a part of Generation X.
- She was probably a delinquent. - That means she is in her mid 40s.
She could be in her mid 40s.
You think she could be in her mid 40s.
This time,
you will hear Sock Boy's real voice.
He will imitate Yoo Hyun Sang of Baekdoosan.
- I told you he is a rocker. - Please say hello.
Please say hello in Yoo Hyun Sang's voice.
Do you know who we are?
We are Baekdoosan.
Let's end it here.
(It was similar, but funny.)
- That was cute. - Their specialties aren't special.
We still don't know who they are.
Would you use the same voice...
to sing "One and Only You" by Shim Shin?
Wait a minute. Why does it have to be Yoo Hyun Sang's voice?
Can't he imitate other voices?
Imitating Yoo Hyun Sang's voice conceals his true voice.
Let's hear "One and Only You".
Please sing "One and Only You".
Don't leave when I still miss you
When I am by myself, I feel lonely
I feel lonely!
You don't know who he is, do you?
You don't!
(Wow)
(The MC is even more excited.)
Gu Ra should know who he is.
- This time... - Don't listen to him.
He is saying that to throw us off. I have been fooled too many times.
Why should I know who he is?
Why should I know?
He will be disheartened.
I am completely certain that Sock Boy is...
a member of a rock band.
I see characteristics of a band.
- As for Mrs. Kettle, - Mrs. Kettle.
I think she was active at the same time as Hyun Jung.
Even though Hyun Jung has a voice...
of a rock vocalist,
she specialized in dance music. I think...
she is a dance singer...
with a voice of a rock vocalist.
That's my conclusion. Am I wrong?
Why are you laughing?
- Why are you laughing? - You have everything but the names.
- Did we get everything else right? - Yes, you did.
You have everything but the names.
Now, I will announce the result...
of the third match of Round One.
What will be the fate...
of these two masked singers?
I'll now reveal...
the winner of this match.
(She has a unique voice that is clear and husky.)
(Mrs. Kettle sings in a straightforward way.)
(He has a delicate voice of a boy.)
(Sock Boy has a sexy voice with irresistible charms.)
Let's find out who will move on to Round Two.
The winner is...
- I don't know who will win. - I have no clue.
Who is the third winner who will move on to Round Two?
Will it be Mrs. Kettle or Sock Boy?
Please show the result.
The winner is...
Mrs. Kettle won.
(I am glad Mrs. Kettle won.)
(Mrs. Kettle received a Christmas present.)
(Congratulations.)
(Those who rooted for Sock Boy are devastated.)
(Panelists show mixed reactions.)
Mrs. Kettle beat Sock Boy...
- with a score of 57 to 42. - It was a close match.
She won with a difference of 15 votes.
Mrs. Kettle, please go back to your waiting room.
Please give her a big hand.
She will compete in Round Two.
(Careful)
(Laughing)
I am happy.
No one figured out my identity.
So that my identity stays a mystery in Round Two,
I will sing harder. Please look forward to it.
From a first generation idol singer,
there were many guesses on his identity.
Who could Sock Boy be?
We will reveal his identity...
with a solo performance prepared for Round Two.
Please give him a big hand.
(His identity will be revealed with a solo performance.)
(Is he an experienced singer?)
(Is he an idol singer? Is he a member of Super Junior?)
(Has he returned to the stage after a long break?)
(Is his life connected to rock?)
(Is he a member of a rock band?)
("Honey" by Park Jin Young)
(His rock spirit booms from the start.)
All right. Here we go.
(He has a sharp voice that pierces our hearts.)
(His voice has changed from the duet performance.)
(He transformed into a rocker.)
(The cheerful rock and roll rhythm...)
(is brought to the next level with his energy.)
(Hey, you)
(His sexy voice that catches your ears...)
(will even make Santa Clause fall in love with him.)
(Sock Boy has charms like a black hole.)
(Everyone is fascinated by his stage.)
Now, Sock Boy, please take off your mask...
and reveal your face.
(Unbelievable)
(I love him.)
He is...
(Who are you, Sock Boy?)
Who is he? He's a rocker.
He is...
Kim Se Heon, the main vocalist of Eve with 21 years of experience.
- He's from Eve. - Oh, my.
(They get to see Eve on Christmas.)
(This is shocking.)
Yes! Go, Eve!
(He's still dashing after all these years.)
(He's handsome.)
(He can't hide his charms.)
(Now I recognize his voice.)
(He rules the stage with his rock spirit.)
(What is he doing?)
(It's his signature charismatic shouting.)
Scream!
(His energy turns the set into a concert hall in an instant.)
(Eve's rock vocalist has made an intense comeback stage.)
(It was "Honey" by Kim Se Heon, a stage full of his rock spirit.)
(You're so great.)
He's the king of rock and roll.
(Wow)
He looks so young.
Please say hello to the viewers.
Hello. It's good to see you.
I'm Kim Se Heon of Eve.
(He debuted in 1995 as a member of Girl.)
(Girl, a band of handsome men, made modern rock popular.)
(Se Heon became popular with his good looks and charming voice.)
(He formed Eve in 1998.)
(They made people go wild with glam rock.)
(As they made big hits with their songs,)
(Eve was one of the most influential rock bands in the 1990s.)
(Eve has been re-formed after 15 years.)
(Kim Se Heon of Eve has come to our show on Christmas.)
He hasn't been on TV shows in 10 years.
I want to know why you decided to be on our show instead of others.
Actually, most of my friends told me that people would...
recognize my voice immediately.
I wondered if they would really recognize my voice.
I got curious.
That's why I decided to come to this show.
I see. Actually, many people remember...
- your red hair. - Yes.
You wore quite thick makeup.
How is your real personality?
I'm easy-going and playful.
I'm just an ordinary person.
When my hair used to be red,
people were scared of me.
He's a really nice person.
- Se Heon. - Do you know him well?
Wan Kyu is younger than Se Heon.
- Is that right? - Yes.
I even had drinks with him a couple of times.
Did you? But Wan Kyu said someone else's name.
I said he may be an idol singer...
because people called him the idol of rock music...
when he was in Girl and Eve.
- That's right. - Yes.
That's why other rock musicians were jealous of him.
Eve was a visual style rock band.
Not every rock musician can try their looks.
Do you think Yoo Hyun Sang can try their looks?
It wasn't an easy thing to do.
- Eve tried glam rock... - That's right.
for the first time.
Their music and appearance were ahead of its time.
He's such an amazing singer.
He's also incredibly stylish.
That's right. It's been over 20 years, but he's still in style.
Yes. Our band, Eve, came back...
- with the original members... - That's right.
- and released an album. - Yes. Your band has been re-formed.
We came back in a very long time, so we prepared many things.
We released our album yesterday, so you'll be hearing our songs soon.
I see. It was so good to see you.
He ruled the stage with his unchanging charisma as a rocker.
It was Kim Se Heon of Eve. Please give him...
a big supportive round of applause.
Thank you. Thank you.
(We'll look forward to Eve's active performance.)
Thank you.
When I told the other members I have to dance and do voice imitations,
they were depressed.
They didn't want me to do things like that.
They didn't want me to do it.
But I think rock musicians shouldn't always be serious.
I think we should show our friendly side sometimes.
It's actually been three years since I got married.
We're going to have a baby soon.
I'm going to be a father next year.
I wanted to leave something for the baby.
It was fun. It was only possible here on King of Mask Singer.
Mrs. Kettle Has Boiled defeated Kim Se Heon of Eve...
and moved on to Round Two.
The last match of Round One.
Her beautiful heavenly voice spreads out to the whole world.
Mysticist Baby Angel.
(Mysticist Baby Angel)
(A baby angel has come down to the world.)
Tin Man. Do you want to know who I am?
Curiosity killed the cat.
(Hello)
(He's cute.)
(Wow)
He has wings.
They're pretty.
I think he's going to be amazing.
Let's meet his opponent.
Ring-ding-dong. She has a beautiful and blessed voice.
Please Jingle Bells.
(Ring the bells.)
If you don't vote for me...
That's mean, that's mean
(Jingling)
(It's a clear sound.)
Tofu sellers used to have that bell.
Tofu sellers had that.
How cute.
Both of them are quite short.
I think they'll be great.
Show us what you got.
(On Christmas evening,)
(their song will spread all over the world.)
(What kind of harmony...)
(will the cute Baby Angel...)
(and adorable Bells show us?)
("All For You" by Cool)
Is this "All For You"?
(I like this song.)
It's Cool's song.
(It's a clear and beautiful voice.)
- She's so cute. - How adorable.
(Bells sings as if she's whispering quietly.)
(He sings with a clear voice and smooth vibrato.)
(A mellow voice comes out of his small build.)
(Baby Angel's sophisticated voice...)
(and Bells' pure voice...)
(make a sweet love serenade together.)
(I want to be a person who is only for you.)
(It's so sweet.)
Bells sounds like a baby.
Maybe she's a child actress.
(He loves their stage.)
(Baby Angel's voice is soft and sweet,)
(so it warms people's hearts.)
(With a clear and vivid tone,)
(they add a spoonful of love.)
(They're cute.)
(They're adorable.)
(Wow)
(For you)
(They promise eternal love with one voice.)
(It's a sweet eternal whisper of love.)
(They're adorable.)
(They console the panelists with their pureness.)
It was such a pure performance.
They're like babies.
They're so cute.
Final match of Duet Song in Round One is over.
Number one is Baby Angel.
Number two is Bells.
Please press the button to cast a vote.
All votes are in.
I was surprised...
how the panelists stood up...
as soon as Baby Angel starts singing.
(Cute Baby Angel.)
(In fact, he's a man?)
- Is he a man? - What?
When he came out,
I saw he had narrow shoulders,
and he was very skinny.
Everyone thought of him as a woman.
We really did.
I was surprised to hear his beautiful voice.
Alright. It seems like you were shocked too, Jang Hyuk.
I really was.
Anyway, when I listened to him singing,
I noticed that he was brilliant at controlling his voice volume.
He harmonized very well with Bells' clear and pure voice.
He's such a great technician.
Listening to Bells' song...
made me feel so great.
Her singing style reflects her life.
Her voice was very pure and clear...
that it was so good to hear it and many people were smiling...
while listening to her song.
I was even more amazed.
I wish I could hear that once more.
I'm sorry to say this to Baby Angel,
but when I heard your song right after her song,
it felt like a fraud.
(Is Baby Angel's song a fraud?)
Really?
He used so many singing techniques.
Bells was too pure.
It felt as if...
he was showing off his muscle...
to a pure girl.
He overused techniques.
He was too good.
I talked about this with Bong Sun.
As for Please Jingle Bells,
she's so tiny, cute. She's like a baby.
So we're guessing that she's a child actress.
I was thinking the same thing earlier.
I think she was nervous and had a stomachache...
because she kept rubbing her belly.
- Are you talking about Bells? - Yes.
(In fact, as soon as she finished her first part...)
(Rubbing)
(Did her stomachache really hurt?)
Children don't have stomachaches that often.
Even though they get extra nervous,
children don't usually get stomachaches.
She could have an acute gastric ulcer.
I don't see her as a child.
Why did you do that?
(Is Bells a child or an adult?)
I was feeling too nervous.
- You were nervous. - See?
Children don't get stomachaches for that.
I think she's an adult actress with a small figure.
As for Baby Angel...
There are contestants in the past who were too good to leave.
It feels as if one of them...
came back to the show as an angel.
I felt that way.
Did he come back to life?
- That's it. - Okay.
Kai, what did you think about their performance?
When we were young, we used to go to church...
and little children would be all dressed up.
Then they'd sing together. Watching that would make you feel delighted,
which makes it so precious and beautiful.
Yes, indeed.
That's exactly how I felt when I saw these two singing today.
Just by listening to them sing, we were able to enjoy ourselves...
and clap all together as one.
I think that warmed up everyone's hearts.
- As for Jingle Bells, - It's Bells.
I thought it could be Moon Geun Young.
She sang an original sound track for a movie.
Since her voice sounds like a little girl,
she's loved by everyone with an image of younger sister.
I think she could be an actress.
- You think she's an actress? - Yes. She's someone widely known.
Isn't she Im Ye Jin?
Im Ye Jin?
You mean the nation's younger sister, Im Ye Jin?
Yes, her.
(She'll forever be the nation's younger sister.)
When she started singing,
someone came up in my mind straight away.
- She sang a song for a movie. - Who is she?
- Even though she's an actress? - It's an actress called...
Shim Eun Kyung.
(Will Shim Eun Kyung with a pure voice...)
(turn out to be Bells?)
What do you think, Wan Kyu?
As soon as I heard Bells' voice,
it reminded of Moon Geun Young.
She's was very confident on stage.
That made me think of her as an experienced actress.
Once she takes off her mask,
I feel like everybody will get shocked.
As for Baby Angel,
he's definitely a professional.
I'm sure he's not a solo artist.
When they were singing together,
he showed that cared about his partner by altering his voice.
He was able to control his voice.
He could be the main singer of a vocal group.
All right. We will now see...
Bells dancing.
The title of the dance is Popping Dance.
Let's see how much she's good at dancing.
It's Popping Dance. Music, please.
(She pops lightly in the beginning.)
(Popping)
(She pops her pelvis.)
(It's a must to open your legs wide.)
My goodness. Look at her popping.
(Where did the pureness go?)
I thought she was pure.
(It's a fatal temptation.)
My goodness. What's going on?
(She attracts men.)
She seems well experienced.
Her moves are exceptional.
She's popping.
(She attracts people.)
Let's stop here.
Her dance completely broke prejudices against her.
Who said that she's Moon Geun Young?
It's Park Na Rae.
I don't think she's a comedian.
Comedians won't get nervous here.
I think she's an actress.
Do you still have a stomachache? It's fine now, isn't it?
I'm still feeling nervous.
- She's still feeling nervous. - What did you have for lunch?
(He asks a daily question to make her feel more comfortable.)
I had a lunchbox that costs 14 dollars.
She's a top-class actress. Eating a 14 dollar lunchbox means...
she the top in her agency.
A 14 dollar lunchbox. She must be the...
most famous actress in the agency.
- That's true. - It's expensive.
How much does your lunchbox cost, Bong Sun?
- It costs three dollars. - What are you talking about?
She pays her own lunchbox.
Now, this time around, we will see Baby Angel dancing.
The title of this dance is Angel Dance.
It's just like how he's dressed. Music, please.
It's Angle Dance.
(He seems sulky.)
(He still seems embarrassed.)
(Should I start flapping my wings?)
He's being very shy.
He's touching his wings.
(He shoots his love to people.)
He's about to begin his dance.
He's being cute.
(I'm the cutest in this area.)
Like an angel.
(He spreads his cuteness.)
This is it.
He's good at dancing.
His body is totally like a girl.
- Niel. - Yes?
What do you think about his dance?
Is it good...
or bad?
I think he's really good at dancing.
- Baby Angel? - Yes. If he dances seriously,
I think he will be really good.
I saw that possibility through his moves.
(He couldn't hide his dance moves even if he was shy.)
(Wow)
What do you think about her?
How do you evaluate Bells' dance?
I also thought she was a child actress at first.
But her dance was a bit too lascivious...
- for a child actress. - Was it?
Yes.
(She seemed shy at first.)
(She bounced her pelvis without a hitch unlike a child actress.)
My goodness, she was innocent.
(She's fatal.)
(I can't believe what I'm watching.)
If children see her dance...
- They might be pretty frightened. - That's right.
I thought she was a child in a church choir,
but it turns out she was a deaconess.
(It turns out she was a deaconess.)
That's what it feels like.
- She looks relatively old. - That's right.
I see.
She has another surprising specialty for you.
Bells can..
lift up Baby Angel or me...
- quite easily. - She can?
(Can she really do that?)
No way.
I'm heavier than Baby Angel.
I want to lift Baby Angel.
She wants to lift Baby Angel.
Baby Angel.
(Go ahead.)
He welcomes her with open arms.
Can she really lift up Baby Angel?
You won't believe your eyes.
She is...
lifting Baby Angel.
(She easily lifts him up.)
Lift Baby Angel.
(Energetic)
She must be Ki Bo Bae.
(Baby Angel is just excited.)
That's enough. Stop it.
She's so strong.
Bells, can you lift me up?
I'm pretty heavy.
Are you sure? Will you be okay?
Can I throw myself into your arms?
You should be careful though. Please don't throw me down.
I have three children.
(He keeps saying that.)
I'm the breadwinner.
In 1, 2, 3.
(He's floating in the air.)
(Startled)
Gosh. That's enough.
(She is unbelievably strong for her figure.)
I'm sure she is an athlete.
I guess she is Jang Hye Jin, the archer who recently won a gold.
- Jang Hye Jin? - Yes.
- A gold medal winner? - Yes.
- She might be Park Se Ri. - Park Se Ri?
- The golfer who recently retired? - I don't think so.
Yoon Seok, what do you think?
She has a beautiful voice...
and a monstrous power.
I'm sure she's an athlete.
And it is Christmas season.
So they must've invited a very special guest.
- Who would that be? - Gwok Chae Yi, the inline skater.
- Gwok Chae Yi? - Gwok Chae Yi!
He doesn't think she is an actress.
Now, I will announce the result...
of the fourth match of Round One.
We have two masked singers here.
I'll now reveal the winner of this match.
(Her voice echoes so clearly.)
(Her voice glittered like precious stones.)
(Bells captivated the audience with her pure and clear voice.)
(He sang with his sweet and warm voice.)
(His gentle voice will melt the winter cold.)
(With his plain voice,)
(Baby Angel refreshed people's minds.)
Baby Angel or Bells?
Who is the last winner...
who will move on to Round Two?
The winner is...
(Please show the result.)
(Nervous)
(Who will be singing...)
(once again in Round Two?)
Who is the winner?
(The winner is...)
Who will move on to Round Two?
The winner is...
Baby Angel or Bells?
Who will be the winner?
The winner is...
Baby Angel.
(Letting out a sigh)
(Baby Angel wins!)
Baby Angel.
(Disappointed)
(She accepts the result.)
Baby Angel is the winner.
With a final score of 70 to 29, Baby Angel moved on to...
Round Two.
Please go back to your waiting room. Please give him a big hand.
Baby Angel moved on to Round Two.
I will make sure...
to spread my wings wider in Round Two.
(He flies to Round Two.)
Is she really an athlete?
We will reveal her identity with her solo performance.
Please give her a round of applause.
(Is she a child actress with a clear voice?)
(They thought she was an actress.)
(But she showed off her monstrous power.)
(Is she Jang Hye Jin or Gwok Chae Yi?)
(Who on earth is Bells?)
("Look Out the Window")
She's singing a carol.
(It is a special gift to celebrate the Christmas night.)
She's so cute.
(Her voice lights up people's hearts.)
(It is a clear and flawless voice.)
(What a heart-warming song!)
(Let's dance together.)
(Let's enjoy Christmas together.)
(Her snow-white voice will melt the winter cold.)
Now, Bells,
please take off your mask and reveal your face.
(Unbelievable)
Who is she?
I'm so curious.
I can't wait to see her face.
Reveal your face.
She is...
the first Korean female national soccer player...
to get into the European league, Ji So Yun.
She's Ji So Yun!
That's Ji So Yun.
(It is unbelievable.)
- She's Ji So Yun. - She's like Lionel Messi.
She is like the Lionel Messi of Korea.
(She's standing right in front of me.)
(She was picked for the national soccer team at the age of 16.)
(Ji So Yun currently plays for Chelsea Ladies F.C in the U.K.)
(With her winning score in the 2015 FA Cup,)
(she rapidly rose as the ace player of Chelsea Ladies.)
(The whole world is crazy about her.)
(Ji So Yun gets picked as the PFA Women's Play of the Year.)
(She won the Player of the Year Award by the PFA in 2015.)
(She is so-called the Messi of Korea.)
(Shy)
(I've come a long way from the U.K. to meet you for Christmas.)
(Her voice rings out clearly like the sound of bells.)
(She's cute.)
(Right now, she doesn't look like a soccer player at all.)
(No one expected her to have such a beautiful voice.)
(So Yun looks just like a little girl today.)
(It is a beautiful Christmas gift from the great soccer player.)
(Shy)
(That was very cute.)
(She looks like a little girl.)
(It's nice to see you.)
You are so pretty.
This is amazing. Isn't she cute?
She's so cute.
(They are mesmerized by her charm.)
She is the ace of our national soccer team.
It's Ji So Yun.
Hello. I'm Ji So Yun, a national soccer player. Nice to meet you.
(It's nice to meet you, too!)
(Excited)
- Were you nervous? - Yes.
I practiced singing very hard, but it didn't go well.
(Bashful)
Her voice was very lovely.
It was so clear.
I know. If you didn't show off your strength,
no one would have known you were an athlete.
She has such a youthful voice.
How do you appeal to the referee with such a sweet voice?
I'm a tough woman on the field.
So do you appeal to the referee...
with such a youthful voice?
I can talk in a rough manner...
- just like you, Gu Ra. - Like how?
- Show us. - It's not a foul.
(He smiles like her dad.)
(It sounds more like she's whining.)
- She's very lovely. - I know.
I'm told that I look like you.
Really?
- I am sorry. - Did it feel nice?
I felt good, but are you okay with that?
I feel great.
I feel good too.
(I found my sister.)
There is one thing that will surprise you.
She wore a skirt for the first time in her life today.
- Really? - Is that true?
- Yes. - Yes.
How do you feel?
It's uncomfortable. I can't spread my legs.
- I can't stand comfortably. - I see.
- I wanted to wear a training suit. - Okay.
But the crew suggested that I wear something girly.
It was the writers' idea.
Thank you.
(She's so charming.)
It's lovely.
There's a phrase that So Yun...
wants you to write on the banners that are made to cheer her on.
I heard you wanted to ask your fans for a favor.
- There are pretty athletes. - Okay.
The fans write "princess" or...
"cute" on those athletes' banners.
But for me, they write "Ji Messi, you are the best."
Isn't it nice that they think you're the best?
It feels good, but I'm a girl too. So I want to be cute too.
- What do you want then? - What do you want them to write?
"Princess So Yun".
That's not hard at all.
- "Princess So Yun". - "Beautiful So Yun".
- Yes. - "Cute So Yun".
- Yes. - Yes.
- Seung Woo is a big fan. - Is that right?
Seung Woo, do you like soccer?
- I am a soccer maniac. - Are you?
She plays for the world's best team.
That's right.
She's Princess So Yun.
(He calls her a princess.)
You have to keep your promise.
You said you will reveal...
your million-dollar heart calves after you reveal your face.
You said you want to show it to everyone as a national athlete.
All right. Our national athlete, So Yun, will reveal...
the traces of her hard work.
You can't see them when she's just standing.
All right. Her calves are already muscular.
Look at her calves.
So that is it.
We can see it.
She's amazing. We are all very proud of her.
She left the soccer field and...
showed her lovely charms on her heart-beating stage.
Princess So Yun. Please give it up for So Yun.
- Please give it up for her. - Thank you.
She's a cutie.
I didn't do well.
(She's still quite nervous.)
Thank you.
I got too nervous.
I was off-tune and off-beat.
I practiced really hard.
I am still nervous.
Bye. It was really fun.