You have somethin'?
Do you or do you not?
No, no...
Milka!
Don't you make a
monkey out of me.
Where are you going, you dirt?
Where?
Give me back my wallet,
you gangster.
Give it!
I'm gonna call the cops.
No, you're not.
-No?
-No.
Mrs. Milka, do you need any help?
-Go away, you faggot.
C'mon, give it to me.
Take 300, leave 200 for me.
-What do you need it for?
I'm gonna make pastry for supper.
-You're lyin'.
Milka, your nose is growin'.
Don't, Milka!
Better than nothing.
My name is Mirsa.
They call me ''The Late Mirsa''.
Actually, that is what I
nicknamed myself.
Up until 17 years ago
I had a band,
a Punk band.
We were No. 1 punks in the country.
Since then, I'm living on old glory.
And on ''chasing my own tale''
as my grandfather used to say,
God rest his soul.
At the time we were playn',
Skopje was a city.
A city that lives...
It is a grave now...
It lay dead, underneath that
Cross they built on Mt. Vodno.
Where did you get that shit?
I bought it.
My dealer's name is Gzim.
He's an Albanian.
Can you stop that?
We call him Jero.
The chicks say he's got
an irresistible childish smile.
I don't know... We don't like
each other much.
Turn left here.
But, that's not 'cause we're
an Albanian and a Macedonian,
enemies by default,
like, hate between Muslims
and Christians, that kind of stuff.
Well, I don't give
a flyin' fuck 'bout that.
I swear, during the fuckin' war
in 2001 between 'us and them'
I was so high,
so I had no idea who's
shooting and whom,
and what the hell is goin' on.
Hey, c'mon, we're late!
Hey, fag, they're waiting on us!
Jero and I,
we respect each other, sure.
I help him dealing;
I find clients for him.
Hey, you punk..
You know, kids that
are into the music thing.
Honk at him.
-He gives me a price cut.
Sometimes he doesn't
even charge me.
We divide the labor;
he works with Albanian kids,
I work with Macedonian kids.
But, he thinks I'm a surplus,
a simple excess.
I know that he's only
interested in cash.
Two different worlds, fuck it.
Take.
You're putting my ass
on the line, man.
And you're doing me a favor.
Jero remembers.
There's gonna be some
cash in for you guys, too.
I'm gonna wait on you until
the day after tomorrow,
until Wednesday.
Wednesday!
Believe it or not,
I got an offer for a gig.
He said it would totally
change my life.
It's a simple deal: I gather
my band and we hit the road.
I feel like playing so much,
I wanna cry.
We haven't performed
in 17 years.
They're diggin' us out of the grave.
Cool. Except, the gig is in Debar,
a town of fuckin' Albanians.
When this gets out in town,
I'm gonna find myself
in some serious shit.
Besides, it is
sponsored by some fucking NGO.
Anti-war vultures,
ethnic relaxation, bite my ass.
Take it or leave it.
Fuck it, at least Jero's honest.
None of our bands didn't want
to take them up on it,
so I'm their last chance.
Last chance, my ass.
Piss on it.
For me?
You bought it...
You've given money
for this stupid stuff.
And, as if this shit wasn't enough,
Milka started getting' on my ass
sayin' that I was just like
my old man - a man of doubts.
Maybe she's right.
And My dad I remember him or not.
I was very young when he left us.
He fled to Australia
with a new woman.
He hasn't called since.
Milka doesn't mention him,
and I don't ask about him.
I don't know
Probably, I don't give a shit.
Milka and I...
We live our own lives...
and it's working.
She lives on
chasing her own tail as well.
Where's the pastry, Milka?
-Who? What?
They ran out of flour at the grocery.
Gosh, you've been smoking
that shit again.
Go away, you stink. Go...
God will punish you.
I can't.
-Don't be such a wimper... c'mon.
Don't do this to me.
Can I help you, gentlemen?
-We're together with them.
Do you have an invihtion?
-It's OK, chief.
This is not the one, is he?
-I hope not.
A freakin' party with not
a living soul in it.
A fake glamour.
I used to enjoy watchin'
the system crashin' down.
Now, that's a bore to me.
Hi.
Mirsa...
himself.
The man is a punk legend in town.
Number one.
But, Gzim, darling, you know
what Debar's like.
Just try to picture this guy there.
Oh, you're gonna tell me
what Debar is like?
Fifteen bands have blown us off,
we're takin' a phony action.
Stop undermining me, please.
We are too deep in this shit.
Do you speak English?
-He's tired. He's tired.
Works all day and plays at night.
You know, your life style fits
like a glove in our program.
Jero!
DTY...
Democracy, Tolerance, Youth.
Be serious, darlin'
I'm 40. Next month.
It's OK. I'll cut the bull shit.
I know what Punk is like.
The event is in a week,
so, if you need anything,
Gzim will find it for you.
Instruments, equipment...
Are you in?
Actually, I'm still out.
I'm not sure.
Jero, come on...
-He's joking, of course.
Jero...
-The man is an anarchist.
He enjoys making drama.
I don't bite. You're so sweet.
You look like...
like Sid Vicious...
Give me that.
This is crazy, bro,
I swear. A gig? Hello!
What's he sayin'?
How much are we getting?
He's not saying anything.
Are we goin' to snatch
200 euros per person? Huh?
Bro, I really don't get your dilemma.
How long we haven't played? Huh?
You really helped me indeed.
Like a fucking expert!
Bro, I'm gonna say no to him.
Fuck him.
Do you have money for beer, bro?
No.
-Then say no to him.
Why are you lookin' at me?
'Cause you are so beautiful,
you fuckin' monkey-faced asshole.
Hey, stupid, think about it.
We're going to perform.
What else is important? Tell me.
We're gonna have to spit
on our whole image.
Spit on what? Our image?
-Yes.
Hey bro, have you seen
your self lately?
It's stupid.
That's all we have left.
Image?
-Yes.
We've an image left?
You are out of your mind.
You're out of your mind...
an image...
fool...
Shut up.
Ljak's been my best friend
since I can remember.
He's the drummer,
we've been playing together.
I know I am no better,
but he totally remained a kid inside.
A kid, a real little brat.
I really love him.
A lot.
Why are you lookin' at me?
Do I make you feel sick?
A lowlife?
Mind your business. Shame on you.
See what you look like.
Mirsa, bro, do you jerk off?
Say it I asked you if you spanked it.
I can't get a hard-on.
At least, tell me if you can get it
hard.
-Shut up, it's impolite.
There are cunts here.
Shame on you two.
I really can't get it up.
But I would really like to jerk off.
I would spank it
-What would you spank?
My dick, of course.
I would spank it hard
until it wears off.
But, it's not usable.
You idiot, you drove
out the cunts.
There you go.
It's looking good, relax.
-It's a little tight.
It's perfect. The way it should be.
I needed a bigger size.
-You're looking great.
You look like a prince.
-A prince? I'm a condom.
Nonsense!
You know, there aren't only
roles of princes in theatre.
A real condom.
-So what if you are a condom?
Somebody has to play
the part of a condom as well.
You're looking great.
Where is Gzim?
Jero -Hey, bro.
Remember, Sid?
I don't bite.
Jero, let's... -No problem.
The girls are friends.
So, you accept? -Not yet.
Look, the guys are asking
for some if you...
Just a moment. Excuse me.
You're bitchin' now, honey.
-No...
I told you the conditions.
Jero...
Look, Jero...
The guys are asking
300 euro's per person.
Plus, what me and
you agreed upon.
You really are a punk, man!
That's why you're goner.
You're a failure that walks, bro.
No bargaining with Jero.
The answer's... NO.
Fine, Jero...
I also feel funny about this...
I don't feel like doin' it.
To play in front of Albanians, huh?
But dealing for Albanian
doesn't make you feel funny.
Don't be pathetic.
Ok, fine. You persuaded me.
150 euros per person.
That's final. Think about it.
And? -Bad.
-What's bad?
150 euros.
-Per person?
Per person. -No way...
Motherfuckers!
These kinds of people
messed up Macedonia...
Stop shittin', please.
These kinds of people are
preventing our prosperity.
Die, mothefuckers.
-Please, Ljak, leave me alone!
Unplug everything.
Those assholes from
the electrical company are here.
Leave me alone, Milka.
I have things to do.
What things, you fag?
What, you think I can't see?
You're just sitting there,
staring like a bull.
We have 30 unpaid bills.
They gonna hunt us down
like rabbits.
Milka, we fixed ours.
Do you need any help?
It's done, Mirsa. Those hooligans
cut our power supply.
Motherfucking capitalists
-Don't worry. We can connect
a wire from my place,
and you will have a light.
Don't worry.
The coolest place in the world
for me is Buenos Aires.
I've never been there.
I've never been in Debar, as well.
Fuck Debar, and Jero, and both
Albanians and Macedonians
and those NGO's.
Motherfuckers, all of them
Nina...
Come in.
I hear you gonna play
for the Albanians.
Hey, don't you start that
shit, please.
Mirsa is a shithead.
Mirsa is slime.
Want some more of this?
-No.
You're being hard to swallow.
-Yeah.
You disappear for ten months
and you come here kissin' me
like you wanna take me out
of my pants.
You wanna be
together again?
Like a guy and a girl?
-Is there another way?
I don't know, like a
brother and sister?
I would never take you in
as a brother.
Never...
Do you want?
Yes.
I'm pregnant.
So am I...
-It's not funny.
Whose is it?
-I don't know.
It's not important.
It doesn't matter.
Listen
-What?
What, man?
Say it, man.
-We gonna play.
We'll get Blondie and Pasha.
Great.
You feel like playin'? -Damn,
I fell like fucking playin'.
Even in Debar?
Even for Eskimos,
as Ljak would say.
And me?
What about you?
Will I hang along?
Yeah. -Really?
-No.
I was supposed to start
gathering the band.
Like those cowboys
in ''The Wild Bunch''...
Blondie lives in some small
shitty place in southern Serbia.
Pasha is in Sarajevo.
Who knows where...
Minion imponible...
But my adrenaline started
rushing, I admit.
You really are a fag, you know?
Like a little pussy...
Fine, drown in this stink.
Who's not coming with us,
can take it up the ass.
Mirsa, bro, tell her.
Tell her I don't wanna go
to that blonde piece of shit!
Hello, what is it?
It's OK. -What else, man?
-I will play, but I am not going
after
that blonde jerk. -We'll find
somebody
else to come with us. Let's go.
You fat, nasty pig!
Who else are you gonna find?
Wait a little, Mirsa!
You like this? -Yeah, a lot.
And you?
Come on. -Stop it.
Nina's a real piece of work.
A shot of penicillin.
We were together
for seven years.
She wouldn't tell me
whose baby is she carrying.
I tried to persuade her
to have an abortion,
but not because I'm jealous,
I swear.
I even said that I will
claim the child as my own.
It's only a matter of ideology,
the reason
why I don't wanna have children.
She got on to me saying that
I became a nihilist cause I was weak.
A clash, from the very beginning.
Why don't you two go alone?
I don't feel comfortable
taking the days off.
-It's only two days, jackass.
Why the hell are we goin', anyway?
Can we just call'em?
They'll blow us off
over the phone easily.
Besides,
I haven't left this city
for 17 years, man.
I feel like travelin', bro.
Understand?
And, who's payin'?
Me? Again?
Jero's gonna give us
some cash out-front.
Great.
Scream now, if you've got the balls.
-Shut up.
You think I'm scared
of Albanians? -Hey...
Are you fucking with me?
Who is it?
Jero, it's Mirsa. - What do you
want?
Can I come in?
Didn't you say
you'll try to find somebody else
-I tried, buddy. -Like hell you did.
They're not Keith Richards
and Charlie Watts.
OK, man. We ain't playin' then.
Don't try that cheap shot
on me. -Well...
How in the world did I make
a deal with you.
And you guys also don't
have passports, right?
Mirsa, bro, shouldn't we
all go home now? -Huh?
Should we go home?
What else?
But the day started great.
-Really, why are you so down?
Mirsa, wait.
Let's have a beer, bro.
Look at this.
Should I hit you once instead?
Bro, it's just one beer.
-You better both fuck yourselves.
The three of us.
It wants a beer, too.
I made a promise to the man.
He took the money out
of his own pocket.
-Fine.
Since you made a promise...
Hey, amateurs...
Wait for my sign!
Let's see what you
know, you fuck.
Are we ready?
Ready? -Ready.
You cunts... pussy!
Common!
Ljak! Ljak!
Congratulations!
Long live Gzim, bro!
Time's on the run, but fuck.
I felt like havin' a beer.
As Ljak would say:
Fuck Jero, he'll have to wait.
After all, he needs us,
not the other way around.
Are you pissed off?
I am.
It's no big deal, I'll come
handy to you guys for the gig.
If there is one. -Why not?
You feel like playing, or what?
Those NGO vultures
don't give a fuck.
Big deal, it's important
that you guys are playing.
He's followin' your every step.
I'm here.
Cunt!
Hey, you cunt...
You crazy fool...
Be careful here, you steed!
-You be careful.
Mirsa... Mirsa!
You should've been a little
quieter last night.
They arranged a gig for us.
You goin' all over through
that stupid stuff again?
You shouldn't give a flying
fuck about what I'm doing.
Mirsa! -Bro, brother.
-Mirsa!
Take it easy, honey, you're
going to kill your dad.
Hold on, I'm going in.
You gonna kill your old man.
Mirsa, my old man was
pushy about coming here.
I'm leaving him in deposit with you,
deal with him.
OK, sweetie, daddy can
take it from here.
You go back to school.
Go now!
You fucked us all, jerk.
We should have been
on the road by now.
Where did you get this?
-Don't know.
Someone gave it to me.
Where did you get this, man?
-Why are you yelling at me?
Mirsa gave me the money.
That's where I got that.
Mirsa gave it to me.
Didn't you put cash in my hand?
Come on, say somethin'.
You told me to buy for everyone;
to do what I'm gonna do.
Fine, where is the
rest of the money?
I blew it all.
You should've stayed. Really.
You know, it was a bomb.
No, Nina. You know
what it was like?
We're so screwed.
Quiet, you asshole!
Look at him fucker.
-Let go, damn it.
He's a fucking idiot.
Go see what he's doin'
Careful, let me. I can handle it.
Done. Go, go...
This pig is heavy, faster.
Done.
I'm a Houdini.
You're not helping me any.
Fuck, I'm dyin' here.
Let this wasted animal help you.
This is it, boss.
Bundesliga fleisch.
Buddy, this is less
than a 100 euros.
See how big this beauty is.
If you wanna do it this way, fine.
If not, go somewhere else.
We want to.
Here, in Skopje, they're messin'
with us, callin' us dinosaurs,
like, the punk music
is dead which is a fact indeed.
But, the whole punk-idea is great.
We are I don't know
the biggest guerillas in the world.
Do or die! That's us.
Take.
And quit fuckin' around.
Clear?
Plus, you're running late.
-Yeah...
What the hell are you laughin' at?
Give me that.
So, what? A thing of beauty.
Wow, Turkish.
Jero.
You think he's going
to persuade him?
He will, my ass.
There's a problem.
What's the problem now?
-Wait.
I took 20 euros from my kids;
just in case...
You pig! -Quiet.
Look, Jero...
-What's up?
Don't get all pumped up right away.
Listen to me.
- What is it?
We need 250 euros...
-Are you out of your mind?
No, that's it.
Another 250 and that's the last.
It's a promise.
The end, that's the last
I mean, we're broke, bro.
OK, 100 Euros.
And this is the last time,
understand?
Jero, look...
I don't wanna hear a word.
Not a word. That's it!
Good job, boy.
Well done, Mirsa.
OK? Be back in three dam.
Understand? -Don't worry,
we are no adolescents.
Cause, if you're not back in three
days, then don't come back at all.
Fair deal.
And again, Jero was the one who
found Blondie's address.
He's got his sources.
When Yugoslavia crashed,
Blondie and his dad,
a Serbian officer in the Yugoslav
Army, went to Serbia.
It was like, temporary.
And this ''like temporary''
remained for 17 years.
And this?
-It's for the children.
What are we to do with you?
Suck my dick, you fuck!
-Look at her,
you motherfuckin' bitch.
Stop that,
you're getting' on my nerves.
I don't give a shit.
Pull him over.
Here, in Serbia,
people have a saying:
You can foresee the day
by the way the dawn looks.
We foresaw ourday
a long time ago.
Hey punks, going to Belgrade?
-No, to Leskovac.
Well, come on, why are you
standing there like monkeys?
Wow, we're saved.
I'm Tarzan... He's Chita.
Jane.
Where are you from?
-I'm Slovenian.
Can't you see that I'm beautiful?
-Oh, yeah...
Communism, communism...
-Fuck communism. Anarchism!
Take it...
What's that group that Blondie's in?
-I have no idea.
They're tryin' to get off the
''horse''.
Somethin' like love, nature,
understanding...
That kind of a shit ''feng-shui''.
Bite my ass.
Fuckin' pieces of shit.
Did you take a piss, you pig?
No, I took a shit.
Well, that's a bad sign.
For a while there, Blondie kept
calling from Serbia.
He even came once...
And, this was to be a band-reunion.
My ass, we busted like a soap-bubble.
On our first rehearsal.
I don't know why Ljak and Blondie
got into a fight.
They had the same girlfriend.
Mimi...
But that's not why.
They couldn't stand each other,
just like Jero and I...
Take it. Take it,
don't be a fag, motherfucker.
Do I look like a caddy to you?
It's important
to know that we are all one.
It's even more important to feel
that love's what spins the world.
Love! Remember that.
And we drain that love
from the Earth,
from ih depths
and ih roots.
Let us all...
hold hands.
And send a strong
message of Love.
Imagine that this message of ours
should reach the Universe,
the Gods,
Eternity.
Come on,
concentrate.
Breathe in...
Your body's here, but your spirit's
out there, with the spirit of Love.
Concentrate... there you go.
Travel go deeper.
Don't, stop it.
-Be still.
We gonna fly this
monkey into the Universe now.
As Leica did. -Leica was
a dog, not a monkey.
Didn't some monkeys fly
as well? -Yeah, they did.
Concentrate...
Mirsa, look.
Take a breath...
Not a monkey, nor a dog.
A grouse.
A primitive animal in love.
I'm proud to inform you that
this here is Eldorado.
Skopje ain't shit.
And now what?
You're not coming with us?
It's a gig, you fool.
And?
I'm glad you came.
I can't do it. -Yes you can,
but you don't want to.
A pussy brainwashed you?
Ljak, don't do that!
What are you doin'?
-What do you want?
What are you up to?
-What's with you?
What's with you, you piece of shit?
Stay down!
You blonde shit!
Blondie, stay down,
or I'll drown you, you shithead.
You blonde shit!
Stay down!
I'm gonna drown you,
motherfucker.
Are you crazy,
you motherfuckers?
I'll drown him. Shout at him!
-You fat pig! -Stop it!
The band split up because of him!
-Because of me?! -Enough!
Why do you say this shit, you junkie?
We split up because of you!
Are you out of your fucking
mind, you motherfuckers?
Everything's gone to hell!
I don't believe in the afterlife,
but when I die, at least during
the first 50 years,
I'd like to be able to take a peak
into this planet's dwelling.
After that,
I could disappear forever...
I won't be givin' a fuck about a
thing.
Fuckin' pussy! If it wasn't for me,
you would've got your an kicked.
Look how pretty it is.
-It's beautiful.
You know what we gonna call it?
Ferdinand...
Look at him.
Bro, How can something
so small be so smart?
Look how smart and
pretty he is.
But the bulls are big, yet you
can still mess with them
with a red cloth for days.
Do you think that frogs
have souls?
This one does.
Ferdinand has a soul.
-Isn't that right?
I knew it.
Do the fleas and mosquitoes
have souls? -Fuck...
I guess not.
What do you think?
-They have nothing to hold it.
And where is Ferdinand's?
-Soul?
Right here.
Here? -Yes.
Ferdo, Ferdo...
They say some frogs release drugs.
-This one doesn't.
I checked him.
He's straight, bro.
As straight as I have seen.
Look how clear his eyes are?
Look clearer than mine.
Yeah, unbelievable, isn't it?
C'mon.
Come on, Ferdinand,
screw this faggot.
Our brother,
Sai Baba has said:
Don't fight the evil.
Because the evil actually don't
exist.
Mirsa, give me your hand.
Give me your hand.
Hold him, hold him.
Hold him still.
Give me that.
You really are freaks.
Fuck me, but I gonna make
a junkie out of this God's creature.
If I don't,
you can call me ''Mohammed''.
Hey, blonde...
We were the champs...
And? What did I get from that?
Beating... ''horse''?
Everything you get and everything
you lose is here, bro, here.
If it wasn't for these people,
I would've never be clean, brother.
It's clear to you that
I cannot come with you guys.
You're not helping me any...
-What's with you?
I wanna teach him how to take
a ''shot''. Turn him around.
Come on, stop.
How can you torture
that animal?
And how can you
torture these people here?
Ilija!
You really are something.
There's no way out for you guys.
You'll remain like this
until the end.
Ilija a newborn,
enlightened...
That's what we are like,
Blondie. Fuck it.
You are so full of shit all the time.
I told you that this blonde
piece of shit's gonna screw us.
This is not his first time, right?
Give it back.
I'll drink your blood and piss on
your grave, you slut.
If you're not a woman,
I would beat the shit out of you.
I'm scared shitless. -Slut.
You are a hero...
you can handle this.
It's not some hippy catch.
It doesn't matter,
anarchistic.
There's a difference.
A big one. -Yeah, right.
Fine, I'm a moron, and I don't
give a shit about those differences.
Simply, this baby's mine,
and I'm gonna raise it.
Why did you stop?
Mirsa is going to
be the daddy, right?
As you wish.
That's your problem.
But Blondie's a fool.
-How can you say that shit?
Go on, keep defending him.
Nobody understands you, too.
Same as him.
Stop screwing with me.
-You poor thing.
Stop screwing with me,
you hear?
You know what I think?
Seriously...
Please, tell me, ''seriously''.
The problem is here.
-Where?
Here.
-You don't say...
And a bit here...
And here as well.
-Yeah? -Yeah.
And also,
there...
Absolutely.
(singing) old communist song
What you're doing it's awful.
-We're doin' it cause of his teeth.
It's very important for him to
have healthy teeth. -What?
But, frogs have no teeth.
-This one does. Come and see.
This one is from Macedonia.
It's a mutant breed that's been
around since the time of
Alexander the Great.
You blonde shit!
-Way to go, Blondie!
We nearly collapsed on the trip
to Sarajevo 18 hours.
We're runnin' late, but I'm OK with
it.
I got excited,
like a kid with a lollipop.
The only thing that bothered us is
that we ran out of food for
Ferdinand.
Fuck this famous meat-pie
from Sarajevo. It's awful.
Ours is 100 times better.
Yeah, this is a real scam.
-Why? I like this one better.
You like it better?
You're no patriot at all.
I'm not, it's a fact. Fuck it.
Now you come to see me,
you hoodlums.
Quit saying shit.
This is business.
Congratulations.
There no salt in this.
And it's really hot.
Don't do that, I'm eatin'!
Don't, I'm eatin', you fucking pig.
Guys, now I have
some bad news.
But, take it easy on me.
It's possible
...that I cannot come with you.
Just maybe.
Why didn't you say so,
you circumcised fag,
so we didn't have
to come all this way.
How else would you see me?
You swine, you think someone would
travel all the way from Skopje
to see an ugly face like yours?
Mirsa, brother...
Would you come?
-Never.
See, swine? -I rang you guys,
but you were already on the move.
Suck my dick, asshole.
-Don't act all nice on me, you Gipsy.
I know when you're lyin'.
Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
-Oh, yeah? Yeah?
You wanna eat?
Wanna try Pasha's nuts?
I have to pick up the kids
from the kindergarten.
Com' on, we'll talk
on the way. Come on.
You didn't become some manager,
did ya, buddy?
I'm my own manager, son.
I'm a mediator between
the foreign invaders
and domestic business.
God provideth for the youngsters.
It'd be a shame for me to complain.
It's only two days, Pasha.
Mirsa, I'm no longer
the same Pasha.
We can see that you're not.
Plus, I got a shit load
of things to do, a shit load.
Hey, bro, take this
Pick up the kids,
keep goin' straight.
I'll see ya.
Hey, Pasha, wait!
I've no idea what Pasha's
business is all about,
nor where he got that rotten
white jeep with SFOR plates.
I didn't even ask.
I know, he'd lie to me.
Here you go. They were out of the
yellow one. They only had the red.
He's makin' trouble again.
We know him well
it's Pasha, all right.
Come on, don't fuck with me.
-No.
What color are his eyes?
-Violet, like yours.
I don't have eyes like a frog.
-No, they're pretty, like yours.
Notice the way he's lookin' at you.
Look how much he loves you,
I swear.
Pasha was the strongest,
musically speaking.
He was schooled for it.
Notes, and stuff like that.
He went to Sarajevo a little
before hell broke loose.
His mother was a Muslim, and his
father was one of us, a Macedonian.
I guess they thought that they'd
save their asses easier there.
But after a while, it was
too late for them to come back.
I really hadn't hoped that
he'd let me down.
A traitor...
I thought that I'd see a lot more
traces of the war in Sarajevo.
A cataclysm.
My ass. They cleaned it up,
those NGO's Mariah and company.
I found just some poor girl's handbag
with condoms in it,
'Made in Yugoslavia'.
Fuck, it really blows.
Don't, it's a sin!
-What?
What? I didn't hear you.
-Not that kind of sin.
It's somebody's secret.
It's not OK.
Do you think I'm an idiot?
Yeah, I think you are.
What happened with my little
anarchist? He turned into a pussy?
Stop shittin', please.
Hey,
are you still mad?
Wasn't this cynical enough for you?
I mean, it's stupid, Nina!
Really stupid!
Where did you guys disappear?
-Oh, here...
You weren't gettin' ready to fuck,
were you?
We're done fucking.
Now, we're just a little pregnant.
Mirsa, bro.
We're going without Pasha,
huh? -Well, that's it.
Fucking little lizard.
Screw me, bro,
but I was sure that the blonde
shit is the one who gonna fuck us.
If you, too, had a business...
You said seven o'clock.
It's 15 after seven.
I'll do it. I will.
Don't lie to us!
-Sign the papers.
What happened?
They picked him up
from his bed. That's all.
I'll get it, I swear
Sign'em, motherfucker! Sign them!
Sign'em, motherfucker!
-I'll do it!
I'll do it. Take it easy.
Easy...
Are you OK?
No, I'm not.
Sorry, brothers, I got myself
into a situation.
Fine, fuck it, some other time.
When are you playing?
-Saturday.
I'm gonna keep
my fingers crossed.
Ferdinand got a diarrhea in Nish.
The chicks got scared
off their minds.
We're two days late.
Jero's gonna be really pined.
I don't give a shit.
Wait, wait.
Stop.
This's not right. -What's right then?
-This was not right.
Ljak, when did you start your part?
-I start on the fourth,
same as I have been my whole life.
The blonde shit behind you
starts on the third.
-Don't look at me.
You're the one who's
singing... nah, nuh, nah.
So the lyrics are the problem?
-Come on, it'll all come back to you.
I don't know the lyrics?
-You don't.
Mirsa!
Hey, Mirsa!
Hey, you eagles.
The whole hood's rocking.
Hi.
Glad to meet you, folks.
I'm Mariah, I'm Danish.
Hi. -Hello, Maria...
I am Ljak.
Can I kiss you?
No.
Come here.
Meet Besim.
He's talented musician.
He'll be playin' whith you guys.
Say what?
-I can't believe it.
Are these silly photos yours?
I adore you, Sid Vicious.
Jero. Jero!
What is this?
Don't look at me that way.
You got screwed by the Bosnian,
so he's gonna fill in for him
and help you
with the song in Albanian.
It's a must, bro. Understand?
Multi-culture, damn it.
Hey, friend, we're playing punk!
-What can I say, it's a must.
What?
-Guys, I don't wanna hear anything.
The band has to be mixed.
That's it.
Come again, man.
Fuck it.
Big deal.
We found ourselves in
a ''brotherhood and unity deal''
with those NGO fucks.
It's not like we don't know
they're screwing with us,
but fuck them move on.
Let uncle Ljak take
a photo of you and Ferdinand.
There you go...
I love him. He's so cute.
-Uncle Ljak's gonna
take a photo of you with ''acute''.
For real.
Say sex -Sex.
-Seeeex... Everybody, sex.
What do you mean a threesome?
-Easy.
Ljak, Blondie and Mimi,
together.
No way.
With fucking and sucking
and all that?
Like, I'm fucking you
while you blowing Blondie?
All that, fucking sucking.
-Don't be stupid.
They do it all the time in India.
There are a million combinations.
Really?
-Ljak's right.
You're not being concrete.
Like, he's here, you're there,
and I'm on the other side.
You sissies scared, huh?
-Yeah, sure thing.
You rotten fags... All I'm trying
is to bring you close again.
Both of you to be great
and play together again.
I knew the dude with Nina
- Borche Orbital.
He was one of us, then he became
a techno DJ in ''A-Quadro''.
Of all the people in this town,
she found him.
Chaos is my drive.
Do not have any rules.
When they build a wall
in front of you,
you'll have to pin on it
and do somethin' else.
You should never, never
be completely understood.
That's a full stop.
The end.
I don't like full stops.
Excuse me.
It's a day in Buenos Aires
at this moment,
and it's winter.
Let me in, Mirsa.
I'm gonna stay here, even
sleep here, until you let me in.
Please.
Please, Mirsa.
Are you listenin'?
The baby's his.
-You're so lying.
Maybe I'm lyin' to you.
I don't know.
I can't be... 100 percent sure.
He wants the same thing you want.
He's offering me cash
to have an abortion.
I'm not offering you cash! I'm not
making you have an abortion.
Change the fuckin' subject!
I'm telling you, we were only
sitting in the car.
I saw you.
You're shittin'.
You're full of it, boy.
My love...
Nina loses her grip when I tell
her that she's carrying just another
wretch on the face of the Earth.
It's a fact. That's what I think.
But, I made a promise to her
that I myself will pierce
the child's ear on his first
birthday.
(singing in Albanian)
Wait, stop. Stop!
What does it say here,
''zemra im'' or Ibrahim?
Blow me, Mirsa. What do I look like
to you? Why should I know
how to sing lousy Albanian song.
Sorry, brother. -No problem.
You don't need to know anything!
What does this say?
''Zemra im'' or Ibrahim?
Zemra im.
Then why do you sing Ibrahim,
you fucking retard.
Wait...
Because, that's how it comes to me.
-It comes to you? -Yes.
It comes to you to say Ibrahim?
-Yeah, it comes to me to say Ibrahim.
Fuck you, and fuck Ibrahim
Sorry, brother, really.
That's how it comes to me.
What's up,
you little fags from Skopje?
You wanted to play without me.
Hello, Mirsa.
I cannot believe this, man.
Look at this ugly Bosnian face.
People, you won't believe me.
You'll think that I'm a pussy.
You are a pussy
all right, big time pussy.
People, I was drivin' down the road
when I see this sign: ''Skopje''.
And then I started cryin'...
tears in my eyes.
Just like I was one of
those poor immigrant workers.
I swear.
It's the truth.
What's with you, people?
Why are you so quiet?
We're goin' to a game. ''Vardar'' is
playin. -Go away, you fool.
Ljak!
Pasha, you're a big man!
Why is the stadium so empty?
-That's how it is lately.
Mirsa! -Hey, there goes Fritz.
-Hey, you're the man! -Hello, Fritz.
You are the best. A legend!
Is that Blondie?
-It's Blondie.
And Pasha? Hello, Pasha.
You are going to perform, huh?
Let me know, do you hear?
What'ya doin' here?
Aren't you at the game?
The game's over.
It started at one o'clock.
We lost. -It's over?
-Take care.
You did this on purpose to me.
-Yeah, right.
You did it on purpose, I know.
There goes Vardar, see?
-Thanks, friends. Thanks.
He wanted to see
''Vardar'' play soccer.
Shitheads, I haven't seen a
football game in a long time.
Stop hittin' me.
You get on my nerves
with that football shit.
What's up, slackers?
I'm tired of waitin' damn it.
NGO! What's up?
What'ya doin' here?
Did you bring us some cash?
Very funny.
-Hey, Jero, this is Pasha.
This is Sali, a young trumpet
player. Gipsy. -Another one?
He'll come handy to you guys.
To hell with him, there are
already too many of us.
I'm living him here with you,
do whatever you want.
I'm not going to take
your bull shit talk.
Jero, aren't you being an
asshole a bit too much?
Ljak! Be still.
Jero, what was our deal,
huh? What was the deal?
Where did you guys
crawl up from? Damn it. Mirsa!
You stay here.
-You can't do this, Jero.
Hold on, you can't.
Hold on, dude!
Fine, fine...
-It's not working out.
Guys, we are going again.
Only the chorus.
Pasha, you're great.
-I know.
Hey, kid...
Come here.
Go stand over there,
next to Blondie.
A big band, hey Mirsa?
We can play at weddings now.
Are you done?
-Two more seconds.
Come on.
Wow...
That Milka did a great job.
This is awesome.
Look how she spelled ''dead''.
She's a sweetheart...
To Debar, to Debar, to Debar...
Macedonian folks...
How far is that Debar of yours?
-Two days of horseback riding.
We'll cut across through
the villages. It's faster.
And now what?
-Where are we going, Jero?
Pasha!
The granny here...
yeah, this granny...
Granny, Debar?
-Who are you?
Are you one of us or them?
-We're one of ours.
Then, what are you doing here?
-We got lost, granny. Lost...
To go to Debar, go straight
up the hill, then take a right.
May the Lord guard you, children.
Why in the world are you going there?
-We're in a hurry, granny.
A lot of their people are on this
path.
-Huh?
Thanks, thanks a lot, granny.
We'll be careful.
Turn the engine off.
We are screwed.
Nobody says a word.
Let me do the talkin'.
Good afternoon.
-Good afternoon.
Are you all one of ours?
-We are, we are...
Brother, we're in a rush.
Where?
-To a concert in Debar.
What do you have in there?
I'm asking what do you
have in there? -An accordion.
No passage allowed.
You can't go further.
Brother, we're in a rush.
I have to take the guys to a concert.
Plus, we are one of yours.
You can't go.
What's that?
What is that?
-Ljak -Ljak.
Hey, you, what
do you have in there?
Give it.
-No way. No way...
Give it to him, you imbecile.
Open it. Open it!
That was it...
Open... c'mon.
Hey, guys, come here!
Come and see this.
C'mon, start it!
Come on!
Have a nice time!
-And a safe trip!
Motherfuckers!
Hello, guys. Come with me,
I will explain everything.
Mariah?
What the fuck is this?
-What's this?
System break-down.
These are packin', bro.
-Well, they've already left, bro
Honey, you can't do this to me.
-I can, believe me.
And I am doing it right now.
It's crazy, and it's cruel.
Miss Rasmunen, please hurry up.
I'm very sorry, Gzim.
I regret very much.
But unfortunately this is not
the issue at the moment,
so we should all fuck off!
Motherfuckers.
Fuck the punks.
Tell them it's the swine flu.
And you know, we are late.
-Yeah.
Excuse me.
-Motherfucker.
Jero, what's the problem?
It's a shame we couldn't do this,
sweethearts. I love ya.
Gzim will explain it to you.
Take care.
Guys, it's from the highest level.
Believe me, it's not up to us.
-Then, to who is it up to, you fucks?
This is not right, you gangsters!
-Let me fuck the bitch in the
vehicle.
Mariah's multi-culti kept on bouncing
in my mind. Just like a mantra.
Motherfuckers, all of them
motherfuckers.
Everything is going to be OK.
Hi, little meety.
It's a frog. -Ferizai?
-Ferdinand.
Ferdinand.
You'll never walk alone, baby.
Mimi, sweetheart.
Drugs?
Blondie, sweetheart,
yeah.
Drugs.
Are you OK, brother?
Are you sure?
-Yeah, yeah...
I swear, Jero, everything is OK.
Jero, bro...
Wait for me, be right back.
Jeronimo!
And?
Tell us.
Tell us, really. -Say it.
What is it?
We're playing.
You're lying, bitch.
-You're lying...
Guys, we're playing!
-Stop shittin' us.
I made a deal!
A gig, bro!
Tonight, at the centre of culture.
I made a deal.
C'mon, Pasha.
Way to go.
Don't close the bottle.
We're starting in five minutes.
You guys, behave.
-Are there people out there?
They'll show up.
Questions?
OK? Fine.
Ladies and gentlemen, it's an
honor to present to you
the multi-culti band from Skopje
''Worker's therapy''.
Thank you for your presence.
Let's go. Are we ready?
You stay here now
Daddy has a little gig,
daddy has to work.
Be nice, don't get into trouble,
daddy have job to do.
Let's bust them, Ljak.
-That's right, we'll bust them.
Of course we'll bust'em.
Isn't that right, Ferdo?
What is this?
Be quiet, brother and
keep on rockin'.
Look at the bald one.
Fuck... ready?
Mirsa, follow me, bro!
C'mon.
Monkeys!
What kind of shitty music is this,
you motherfuckers?
Stop playing and come outside!
-Go home! Leave!
You fuckin' losers, get outside!
Are you showin' your dick to me?
What the fuck? To me?
Buddy, be careful. Be careful.
Look, there's a problem!
To whom is he showing
his dick, motherfucker?
Take'em outside!
-It's OK.
Do we understand each other?
Understood?
You sit down!
Bring in more guys,
there's a chaos in here.
Hurry! Hurry up!
There's gonna be trouble!
-Fuck'em, bro. Let'em come!
They came here and
they're toyin' with us!
Who the fuck are they?
I'm gonna take your soul,
you motherfucker!
Get'em outside!
-Throw them out!
Come outside, or
we'll kill you in here!
Go outside.
Calm down, brothers,
we're one of yours.
Go outside! -Calm down, please.
-Come outside.
Move, or I'll hit you.
Run, guys. Run now...
Move, I will bust your ass!
Run, you monkey! Run!
Screw the gig! Run!
I'll fuck your wife, asshole!
Let me get'em!
-You fucking cunt!
Run, you idiot.
Nina!
Run, run! Fast.
Ferdinand...
Hey, son.
Here you are.
Good.
What 'bout the instruments?
Run, bro, run!
Kid, c'mon!
Where'd they go?
-There!
If they catch us, we're fucked.
We're fucked!
Do something! Do something
Hello?!
What do you mean ten minutes?
Hurry up and get'em!
Hurry up, you idiot!
Take this.
Move, move!
Mirsa! -What is it, Sali?
C'mon, hurry up.
Keep hittin' the door, fucker.
Let's go from the other side.
-Where? -On the other side.
Catch her, Blondie.
Come on.
Come on, Mirsa.
Come on, bro.
-Come on, Mirsa
Drive!
Hold on, you shitheads!
We performed, bro.
We performed....
-We performed, yeah.
Despite the organizer's good
intentions, this concert of tolerance
turned into a violent incindent,
where serious consequences
were avoided by an inch...
The extradition of Lirim Jakupi
- The Nazi is uncertain.
Kosovo remains silent
on this matter.
Panic not, the price of
bread will not rise.
Hey, you junkie,
do I have to learn from the TV
that you're back?
How did you get the power
back on, Milka?
Kiki broke off the seal
and connected us.
Hey!
I saw on TV that it was rough, huh?
-It was great, until they threw us
out.
But...
It brought you luck, right?
Take it.
A little memento from Skopje.
It's nice.
Is it a male or a female?
A female. Her name is Elisabeth.
-Yeah?
Yes. She's Ferdinand's girlfriend.
You really are a fag because
you're splittin' them up.
Isn't that right, Ferdo? -''Little
fag..''
-See, you're a fag.
I have to, brother.
-Why do you have to?
It's Tuesday... it's bad luck.
It's a night.
Pasha, give us a minute, please.
Let's baptize the kid.
Hold the frog.
Come with us,
we wanna tell you somthin'.
Oh, no you're not.
Blondie, grab a hold of him.
That's good.
Now, you are one of us.
Let me have Ferdinand.
Fuck you, your daddy's
gonna make you a punk.
Where are you, champs?
You're going to sing
to the Albanians, huh?
You motherfucking sell-offs.
There are too many of them?
-Too many.
Should we run?
-We run.
Catch'em. Faster.
Catch'em.
Run to the left!
Run that way!
Stop. -What is it?
Ferdinand.
You motherfucker!
Ljak!
Where are you going,
you piece of shit.
I'm gonna cripple you,
you shit!
Motherfuckers.
Shitheads!
You're going to play
for the Albanians?
You motherfuckers. Mirsa!
Die, you piece of dirt.
Wow, man. Wait, stand up.
Real cunts, bro.
Cunts!
They screwed us good, huh?
Motherfuckers.. all of them.
We were all at the funeral.
Except Pasha.
They kept him at the hospihl.
He had severe injuries.
As my grandpa Kuzman used
to say: ''May dogs piss on
the graves of those who work
in the emergency rooms".
But, not only theirs.
And we decided to call this place:
''Ferdinand's grave''.
Brother, let me ask you somethin'.
Do you still jerk off?
All the time.
All the time?
-All the time.
Do you spank it?
-Yeah, the whole deal.
Do you jerk off?
-I jerk off.
When was the last time you did it?
-Yesterday.
How 'bout you?
-Me? Tonight.
Jero, what about you?
-How should I put this, bro?
Me too.
I don't wanna to lie to you.
Nina, brother, do you jerk off?
Wow!
Or does Mirsa do it by himself?