Eagle Releases Presents You:
Riot 2015
Translated by: The Unknowns and Snow White
Thesis delivery.
"Since no weapons allowed here."
Open 23.
Green. Come forward in the east wing.
I was looking for an uncomfortable place to take a nap ...
but the house was closed.
Where are you going?
The infirmary, organize the kitchen, and then a few more things.
Well, go on.
New eater.
New medication list for the prisoners. - Thanks.
'Fobidden territory'
Package for Balam.
Masks.
Good. Sounds fine. Thanks.
He is here.
Walk on, walk on.
Stay in line. Scrolling ... walking.
Wie is dat?
- Jack Stone.
Wie is Jack Stone?
An ex-police officer.
Not so fast, Slankie.
Come on, run.
Jack Stone.
First a cop. Then a killer cops.
Well, Stone, how long do you think you can last here?
It seems that Green has a new sweetheart.
These prisoners are beasts. And you've been there enough, right?
And so it begins.
And you are the center of everything.
If you want to talk, I listen well.
We are on the roof.
Does he know what is his place?
With so much money do you really think that he give a damn?
Three, two, one ...
Everyone is looking for coverage.
If you stay alive white let him lie.
Ren, ren, ren!
Over here, come!
We're here for the money from the bank, not yours.
Everyone on the ground. - On the ground.
Lie and not say a word.
The bank manager, hands on your head? Where is he?!
You have three seconds to open the safe. One two...
Move along.
Keys.
You hear that, Jack?
That sound in the distance, voices. That is of hungry prisoners, Jackie.
They smell fresh meat.
I do not know who to put my money. On the prisoners or guards.
I would go for the guards.
Everyone take cover.
Here they come! Motherfuckers!
Clark, Ashdown, follow me!
Everyone aside! On the ground.
Dirty whore!
Lay down! Everyone on the ground.
Ashdown you check this floor. Clark, you're coming with me.
Clark, you go left.
That's far enough. Hands up. Now!
I said hands up.
I thought I had to go to my cell because you ...
Jack, right? Would you like to the top or bottom?
I'll go at the bottom.
Call me Silva.
Semyon. Let me welcome you to your new home.
Once times a week, you pay me for protection ...
then you the money directly into my account transfer.
I do not need your protection.
Always use protection.
My friend, if there is someone here needs protection, then you will.
Take him and put him in a cell.
My name is Sem ...
Everthing allright.
Come on up.
Detective Jack Stone, your name for years ...
a constant irritation for my business.
You cost me guys, shipments, money. More times than I want to remember.
Do you feel guilty if you share a cell with me?
That's a bold move.
Unfortunately I have not met personally.
We can still change this?
I guess that would work out not good for me, Jack.
Have you ever heard of a king who gives tours of his kingdom?
No of course not. The king remains in his castle.
Do you know why? If the king leaves his castle he offers his enemies ...
a chance to climb up there.
I'm not here for your throne, Balam.
You know what price on my head?
A million dollars. That's what they think I'm worth.
What about you, Jack? What are you worth?
25, 50, 100,000 dollar?
What did you get out of my safe and to whom have you given?
As you wish, you go there as if your wife.
I heard she bled to death.
Agony stand out while you watched, without even do anything.
It's a shame that you're not dead.
Jack, you and I are at war.
Who are you, Jack Stone?
I said hands up.
I trusted you. - Jack?
She's dead because of you. - I had no choice, Jack. I have a family.
Did you again late shift, Timmy?
As punishment for the past week.
Fences do not jump for a car, Tim.
You should really behave like a retarded character to be touching one.
Were you ?? and sms while driving?
I sat back of a truck.
Thank you and goodbye.
How can I help you? - I'm Trisha Sinclair.
I have an appointment with prosecutor Johnson.
Sorry. But unfortunately I have no agreement with that name.
Unfortunately, I canceled that appointment.
Hallo, Miss Sinclair.
Mark Crane.
Mr. Johnson could not come so I had to cancel.
I do not call to cancel?
I'm sorry, if you're with me ... - Sorry, when he has time?
You can discuss it with me as well.
Then I can give that information to him if he is available.
I did not ask to speak with you. - Can you cancel my calls.
Ja, Mr Crane.
- Kom hier.
Listen, the information you gave to Mr. Johnson is very important to me.
Jack Stone is a closed case.
This is not just about Jack Stone.
If you have additional information I give it gladly.
If you give it to me I'll make sure he gets it.
But make a new appointment.
The head of the school is conducting an investigation.
Excuse me, prosecutor Johnson?
Excuse me, but I really need to talk to you.
En u bent...?
- Trisha Sinclair.
The reporter of 'The Post'.
George, I can still talk later? Thanks.
And Miss Sinclair what's so terribly important ...
that my conversation with the mayor had to pause?
Is that the mayor? - You're not him Recognized?
I was working for the other.
I'm sorry, I made an appointment with you, but your guard canceled it.
That was Mark, he does not long for me.
And he sometimes behaves what overprotective.
Shall we run?
What is this about? - Jack Stone and Balam Moglovich.
Balam? That's been years in prison.
The same as where Jack Stone is sent there.
And? - I think this was not purely coincidental.
They murdered his former partner. Jack Stone was part of a group of three
that robbed the Bank of Orleans?
What many believe that it was by the Russian mafia.
That was never confirmed. It's not that it's not true, but ...
Accusations without proof ...
I mean, how much evidence. Lots of it.
What if Jack and Balam work together?
A detective is involved with the Russian mafia?
It's more complicated than that, Miss Sinclair.
It would be good if you think about it! Why did Jack go to jail?
He killed a policeman.
It's not just Jack. I have a whole list of names.
Do not worry. Your name is not listed.
Police corruption is a fundamental threat.
Like any lifestyle and everything to protect our neighbors.
And judgments given in the courtroom.
If you have information, you should come with them for the day.
I wanted that too.
I wanted to make sure you understand everything before I come up with evidence.
Good. Let me know if I can do something to help.
This is my number.
You do not have to worry about Mark Crane.
Stone, you have a visitor.
Hallo, Mr. Stone.
Miss Sinclair. I have looked forward to your visit.
How do you know who I am?
What will you do with the information I sent you?
Was that yours?
What do you want?
Use the information, Miss Sinclair.
William, come on, you block the road.
On the side!
Congratulations.
Because you are my anchor, and no matter how hard the sea can be ...
and I know you are always there for me.
I love you.
Sorry, I did not bother. Are you Jack Stone?
Thanks for your help here.
What do you mean?
Does not matter.
I am William. I'm very important here.
If you need to clean floors in this block, they call me.
Can you imagine that I'm sometimes crowding.
Ken je Balam?
And.
His nephew Semyon put his face in the jelly.
I know who Semyon.
Are not you afraid of Balam?
Do you know where Balam his cell?
Nobody knows where it is. Nobody goes there ...
Even the guards ... also not good.
I like your necklace cute. Were you in the military?
It was a gift from my wife. She is dead.
That is sad. Sorry.
Stay away from me!
Wait. I take her over here. You are needed in Block D.
Come on, sweetheart.
Isolation is not the other way?
Shut up.
Cousin, why am I here? Everything is good.
There are three reasons why I chose a life in prison.
Protection of my many enemies.
It's like a blind spot to keep my business outside the government.
And ultimately, control.
Control means power, it means ranking.
Control means respect. - I know this already!
Nothing is happening this prison without my approval.
And if someone's like to work alone without consultation, I find it disrespectful.
I do not tolerate disrespect, not even my cousin.
I would never ...
A percentage taken without my permission.
Amiss.
Selling drugs, inside and outside these walls, behind my back?
Very disrespectful.
Try to murder Jack Stone and grab the honor.
That's very disrespectful.
What a shame. Your face is a mix of beauty and tragedy.
Like a beautiful painting.
Why risking damage to something so precious?
You must know that Katerina is one of my employees.
That means she's under my protection.
So if you fight with Katerina, you fight with me.
You want me to be your enemy?
Because when you're a little care there
For something so beautiful ...
Maybe you do not deserve this.
I grab it and put it on my wall.
Where it is not abused by you.
You represented me in everything you do, cousin.
Your failure to murder Jack Stone is my failure.
And in the eyes of the other prisoner show your weakness.
Weakness leads to difference and that can quickly turn into revolt.
Please, cousin. Give me a second chance. I will not disappoint you.
No. Jack Stones question can not go unanswered.
I want you to spread it.
One hundred thousand dollars to the one who brings the head of Jack Stone.
You're in trouble. Balam paid one hundred thousand dollars to the one who killed you.
This also applies to the guards. What are you going to do now?
I do not move so much more. It gives me more time. I'm not busy.
These guards are good. So stay at the bad guys away.
How do I know who the bad guys are?
Those are the ones you want to murder.
Everybody out!
Come on! Now!
Who are you?
A friend.
But how did she get all that information?
Come on, you have lists, names, contacts, buyers, sellers!
Remember who you're talking.
Come on, she's got proof! Paperwork, disks, USB sticks.
That is impossible. I was told that everything is burned.
Listen, I'm not perish!
Then it's simple. That woman must die.
Okay, I'll take care of it. What about with Stone?
He is dead at the end of the day.
Allison! - I'm at the airport.
I'll see you later tonight, okay?
Really? Think logically. With how many are you. Eight?
We are with z `nine.
Actually, eight and a half.
I know it's a lot of money but it's not as you think.
If you've got what you look for?
11,000 each?
Eleven thousand sounds good to me.
Not if you're risking the risks.
What is he talking about?
Are they worth 11 000 dollars you for a skull fracture, broken eardrum.
Maybe a broken femur, cracked ribs, collapsed lungs,
Half your nose beaten into your brain.
You look smarter than you are!
How are you doing? - Yes No. Jesus!
That must have been a visit ..
It was not what I expected. Alone...
What is going on?
I'm doing this all wrong.
I do not think I've ever seen you so passionate to have a story.
The whole time I try the connection between Jack Stone and corruption
so I came nowhere.
This is all about Balam.
His drug network, vendors, buyers ...
All of these names.
City officials, police officers, the list is long.
What will you do with it?
Please check everything, make sure I understand everything and then call.
What?
Balam says that I must apologize.
I wait.
The cat!
Let's go, princess!
Is all well with her? - Mind your own business.
Blood pressure 126/78. 65 heartbeat.
The pupils are dilated and unresponsive.
Another? - No, let her sleep. Be sure of it
that gets her next record.
Stone. Your girlfriend is back.
Jack, I read it with your wife. Sorry.
So you've figured out that I was not working for the Russian mafia
as it was on paper.
But I did find out who did.
I called my partner told what I had found, and he went to the Mafia.
She wanted a hit on me, but Elizabeth was killed.
And I killed him.
What will you do with the information I sent you?
I know why you're here. You're killing yourself even by doing this.
What happens to me does not matter. This is about the one who is responsible.
I'm allergic to peanuts `s ...
Onions? Onions are good.
Are you happy? You look happier.
I have a full time job ...
Excuse me, Doctor?
That's pretty flattering, William, but I'm just a nurse.
Just a nurse? Well, I heard that they do all the work
while the doctors are somewhere playing golf.
Okay, ladies' man, but told. What do you want?
I was hoping you could answer a medical question.
An embarrassing question.
How long have you been undercover?
You are still alive. I bet that you make passes around me.
Where are you from? FBI, CIA?
FBI.
This place has long been corrupt
but we did not know how deep the SAT.
If you tell me where is the proof that we need, the mystery disappears.
You know why I'm here?
Are you going to stand me in the way?
I am now six months here. I'll grab one while Balam here is boss.
He has too much information for the government.
Once I heard that you came here, and you have the missing piece
that makes a difference.
Here they come.
There's more what we need here.
Go back!
Sometimes I finish this fluent Russian.
How do you say '' Jack, you're so sexy. I need you. I want you''?
You need help.
I need a friend.
Why do not you hire a translator for this in?
The information is too sensitive.
As much of this is true, there are many people in prison.
When you were six months ago came here they told me two things:
One, you're not a good defender ... Two, I gave you a trusted status.
I never had a reason to answer that until today.
William, I must tell you that I am very disappointed in you.
Three prisoner saw you Losif picked up and tossed him over the rail.
I want to know why you're doing something.
It was 13-4. If I would do this terrible, I would be afraid and be useless
and then God would execute the rebels.
I'll be honest with you, William. The Bible came from the office.
If you want to stop your faith in God to save you is up to you.
But within these walls I'm the only savior that you need.
And believe me, boy, you need a rescue.
Losif Balam was one of his boys.
If I have to put back into block A or block any whatsoever
then you are to the end of the week death.
Can you help me?
It is not a question of whether I can, but more if I want it.
Will you do that?
Yes, paid.
I have no money.
Not you. But I'm sure you have friends there who can arrange something for you.
What you have hidden. If you do what you have blocked.
My brother has money.
See! Your brother is his love for you, say worth $ 1,000?
I do not know.
Why do not you go back to work and think about it, okay?
When you're ready to call your brother, let me know.
But you'd better think fast. You know how the communication works here.
Balam, there may already be behind what you did.
If my brother you paid $ 10,000 you will promise me that I will not be killed?
With my hand on the Bible.
I need Mr. Johnson speak, please.
Do you have an appointment?
No, but it's important. - It always is.
Is there a problem? - I need to talk to the prosecutor.
Another plot. Listen, Miss Sinclair, if you have a problem, call the FBI.
You go down with the rest.
What is happening?
You do not feel well, Princess?
On the side!
Stand still!
Get out of my way!
How are you doing? - Yes.
Let's lay it up.
Sure we can trust?
Balam is the force that I came here.
Jack wanted to bring this to an end.
Ready? Come on. We go.
Is it true?
Is this you?
Papa?
I lied to my whole life. I thought you were dead.
I went away to protect you.
I was told you were a national hero.
A life with your family sacrifice for the love of your country and I accepted it.
Mom knows that you wanted?
I do not know what you've been told and that it is not true.
Drugs, weapons, human trafficking?
I could not bear to read the rest. It was page after page.
Available.
I am inside.
Be a man for once and tell me the truth.
I want you to look me in the eye and tell
that everything I've read is not true.
These things are not true.
You're not man enough to admit it.
You made the choice long ago to be a part of my life.
So I now make the choice never to be a part of yours.
I want nothing to do with you make.
I do not know what you are, but I will never find out.
Olesya, you're not safe! They're coming for you!
I think this was the last time you see me.
I see Balam and his escort leaving the business area.
Semyon is in Blok A.
The rest of the group waiting for the return of Balam.
Jack is in isolation.
Okay, Jack, let's see if you now are so good again.
What are you to `t rumble? Answer!
Isolation, answer.
Will, take them on.
I assume this is not a social call.
I do the check and my partner sits on the surveillance cameras.
We help you to come to Balam.
Which way?
Turn right.
Go left.
Door 5B. - Good.
23-C.
There is a guard at my door.
Jack, we are running out of time.
They come closer, Jack.
I forgot my keys. Open it.
Open the door. I want to go home.
Open the door.
Eric, wake up!
Eric, wake up! I want to go home!
What is going on? - I'm sorry, sir.
I forgot my keys and my partner I guess is asleep.
What is going on? Come on, open it!
Open the door, come on!
Jack, we have to go.
To open!
We're screwed. They're here, Jack.
Make them all open.
What do you mean?
The hall, the cells, everything. Make them open!
I want you to do all the doors locked. Nobody is allowed in or out.
This is a large emergency!
Back in your cell!
10-34! 10-34! We need assistance!
I have the money already.
I want to just go on a search.
No, I want to Stone!
Hey? - It is time.
Amazing. I have been waiting a long time.
Remember to clean. You wait for your money.
I'm going down.
This job is finally done.
I want it all. I need the original files.
Allison?
- Disks, usb stick, alles.
Get up, now.
Stone!
Jack, do you start?
Nee.
Balam is nearby. Let him stop.
Get up now and give me everything I want, or I'll shoot you.
You're not gonna shoot me, Allison.
Trust me, I'll accept that.
What are you doing? You're my friend.
I was offered a lot of money.
You sit deeper in, Allison. Probably hired to observe.
But not to act.
You are wrong.
FBI, Miss Sinclair.
Wait! Or I'll blow your head off empty.
Move over, so we ...
I'm sorry, man. It's just my job, okay?
William?
No, wait.
I have money, I do drugs, I have everything you need!
Freedom. I can give you freedom! I can get you out of here.
Please, no! The Bible! You're a man of faith.
I remember that.
Free!
Look in the hall.
Cover me!
Stone!
What, Elizabeth? It was nothing personal, just business.
We met each other in person and you pulled my daughter herein.
I killed her because of you!
I was going to murder because of you!
On the ground! Lie down on the ground!
Free!
Jack? Do what you came to do?
I have done that.
Why did you do to me?
I lost my partner a few years ago, had him felted
cut him into pieces and sent it to his family.
You did what no one had the balls.
Meet my new partner, Agent Shiles.
How are you doing? - It sometimes got worse.
Let's go.
The director would like to thank you for what you did.
Disabling Balam and his men opened your doors.
One way to purify you, not here, but in the city.
I appreciate that but actually I should be thanking you.
I hope you do not mind.
We need you anyway arrest yet.
A big arrest today, including the government and police officers.
Attorney Johnson was also arrested.
There were rumors for months about Mr. Johnson.
Until the story came to light.
Rumors of embezzlement, tampering with the jury and attempted murder.
Under the motto of other prizes.
Translated by: The Unknowns and Snow White
Control: SideKick
Operation: Sendleech