(STATIC)
(BEEPS)
(CHIMES)
MAN: - Hey, buddy.
Space is great. Umm...
I miss you guys.
We're a long way away now.
I can't even see you...
I can't even see Earth anymore.
(CHUCKLES)
(BACKGROUND CHATTERING)
MAN: And, uh... it's peaceful.
You know?
Don't tell my mom this,
but I think
I actually sleep...
- better up here, away from her snoring.
(WOMAN SPEAKING)
- Over.
(CHIMES)
MAN 2: (OVER RADIO) Tanks
B-7 and B-9 are showing
early signs of freezing. Over.
MAN: What would you do
if you get out there
and you find nothing?
Well, even if we found nothing,
- it's in effect a discovery.
(STATIC)
MAN: It would make me very frustrated.
WOMAN: I know there's something there.
MAN 2: (ON RADIO) Check on
NAV bays 3 and 4.
(DISTORTED)
You might want to update...
(STATIC)
Mission Control,
repeat please. Over.
MISSION CONTROL: Come in, Europa One.
MAN 3: Do you want me
to show you how to beat 'em?
William, I've got some static
in the comm array feed up here.
- It looks like a radiation spike.
(ALARM BEEPING)
WILLIAM: Have you tried
recycling the system?
MISSION CONTROL: Rosa,
we've lost your feed.
Europa One, come in.
(STATIC)
- Europa One.
(DISTORTED VOICES)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(STATIC STOPS)
WOMAN: These were
the last images we received
from the Europa One craft.
At the time,
it had already gone farther
than any human being
had ever traveled before.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
For 16 long months I've been asked
the simple but loaded question:
"What happened?"
All... I'm sorry.
(CRYING)
(SWALLOWS)
WOMAN: We have to tell his family.
We can't.
The communication fix
was never completed.
MAN: The system is fried!
Last sync with Mission Control
was 19 hours ago.
We're all alone now.
So what happens?
Do we go on?
(SIGHS)
I was on a plane,
a transatlantic flight,
when the mission feed went dark.
When I landed,
Mission Control was still saying
"Maybe it's just
a transmission delay."
But, by the time I made it
into Mission Control,
we were looking
at over 15 hours of dead feed.
After James was lost,
the joy of the mission,
the exhilaration of it all just...
it just left.
I stopped feeling
like a kid on a family trip.
The mission has
stretched on ahead of us,
somehow longer
than it had been before.
MAN: No one at home knows we're alive.
(BEEPING)
We're doing the right thing, right?
Absolutely.
(BEEPING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKS)
WOMAN: Andrei, have you
looked out at Jupiter yet?
It's something to be excited about.
(HISSING, BEEPING)
- Are you okay?
- Mmm.
You haven't said
a word to me in a week.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
ROSA: - I woke up one morning...
- Okay.
(LAUGHS)
I woke up at some point and...
didn't recognize myself.
Objectively, I know it's the zero G
and the isolation that changes you.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
But that doesn't make it
any less strange.
It doesn't stop you
from slowly breaking.
(BEEPING)
SAMANTHA: I started living my life
in tune with the mission
that I hoped was still going on.
(WHIRRING)
(ANDREI BREATHING HEAVILY)
MAN: - That's good.
ANDREI: - Okay.
MAN: How's your appetite?
ANDREI: I'm fine.
MAN: And you're sleeping kind of...
ANDREI: I'm not.
WOMAN: It's been a year since we lost him.
(SCISSORS SNIPPING)
(BEEPING, STATIC)
(DISTORTED VOICES)
Tell me we can still...
(BEEPS)
(WHIRRING)
(CHATTERING)
- Good morning. I am very...
MAN: - Shh shh shh.
We are all very excited
to be here today.
It has certainly been a long road
and all of us up here
started with the shared dream
of space and possibility.
And this really is a new
first-step for mankind.
From one perspective,
you can say our mission
actually began 400 years ago.
- That's when Galileo first saw...
(LAUGHTER)
...Jupiter and its moons
through his telescope.
SAMANTHA: For something this big,
you get one shot.
An unmanned mission
simply wasn't going to cut it for us.
You put men and women into space
because they have strength
in the face of cosmic odds.
MISSION CONTROL: Europa One
is cleared for launch.
T-minus 10,
nine, eight,
- seven, six...
WILLIAM: - All vents open.
- ...five, four...
WILLIAM: - We're go for main engine.
...three, two, one.
WILLIAM: Ignition.
MISSION CONTROL: Liftoff!
On the trek to Europa.
WILLIAM: Our engines at 98% thrust.
Fuel rate is nominal.
MISSION CONTROL: Rolling right
in zero-point-six degrees.
Telemetry nominal.
Loft at 225 meters-per-second.
Altitude, 2.3 nautical miles.
And in three, two, one.
We have good booster separation.
WILLIAM: Vehicle is supersonic.
Command module jettison in three,
- two, one.
(WHIRS)
MISSION CONTROL: We have
a good shell separation.
WILLIAM: Initial burn is complete.
Staging in three,
two, one.
MISSION CONTROL: Copy. We
have good stage separation.
WOMAN: We have visual of command module.
Beginning turn for docking.
MISSION CONTROL: Trajectory is good.
Thrust is good.
SAMANTHA: We hadn't left
near-Earth orbit since 1972.
Our company was tasked
with moving forward
where the space programs
of the 20th century had left off.
WOMAN: - 10 meters to docking.
SAMANTHA: - I believe
if you have the scent
of a discovery this big...
- Five meters.
- ...you do not simply wait
and see what happens next.
(THUDS, HISSES)
- Contact.
SAMANTHA: You go after it.
MISSION CONTROL: Copy. We
are green on hard dock.
Locks B through D are green.
Connects are stable.
Repeat: We are green on dock.
(WHIRS, CLANGS)
Mission Control,
we are proud to report
that we are officially underway.
MISSION CONTROL: - Roger that.
(CHEERING OVER RADIO)
We'll be here for you
when you get back.
We've prepped some light
traveling music for you.
("ON THE BEAUTIFUL
BLUE DANUBE" PLAYING)
(CLICKS)
(ELECTRONIC HUMMING)
MISSION CONTROL: Internal
cam check is a go.
(CLICKS, BEEPING)
- Must be peaceful up there.
(ALARM CLOCK RINGING)
(RINGING STOPS)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
MISSION CONTROL: External
cam check is a go.
(CLASSICAL SCORE PLAYING)
♪ Come on in! ♪
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello.
Please don't vote me off.
There's a camera.
What do ya know?
Reality TV.
Okay, Jamie, this is your own
personal tour of Europa One.
Oh look, it's you, Jamie.
Hi, Jamie.
"Hi, Dad."
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, Dan. You still upset
that you got the bottom bunk?
How did you know
I was thinking about that?
- I really was thinking about it.
- The top is just so much better.
DAN: - I was supposed to have that.
- Look at that.
- Here's Daniel down here...
- I'm supposed to have...
..."I'm so cramped."
Look at my spacious bunk.
- Film me for a second.
- Okay.
Okay, so this is actually
one of two living quarters.
What they do is they rotate
around the core module
so this gives us simulated gravity.
But watch this.
We also get to experience
real gravity-free
space excitement.
Whoo!
- And the head rush that goes with it.
WILLIAM: - Crew meeting
- in one hour, guys.
- Okay.
Now the thing
about zero gravity is that
it makes our bones
and muscles really weak.
This is why we spend
as much time as possible
in these living modules.
Yeah, okay.
Just pass it up. I got it.
Okay.
And there's the lovely Katya.
Now these are some
of the science tools
that we're using to test
for life on Europa.
And your dad has to fix them
if any of them break.
When you're done playing tourist,
you can come over here
and help me.
If you're not afraid to chip a nail.
(CHUCKLES)
JAMES: - Now... whoa...
- this is the cockpit.
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
ROSA: Mission Control...
(DISTORTED) ...sync.
MISSION CONTROL: Copy, Rosa. We have sync.
MAN: And Rosa, our pilot, used to fly jets
before she started flying us around.
And what's she doing?
She's setting up the camera system
which monitors everything
that happens on the ship.
Smile for Jamie, Rosa.
(CHUCKLES)
And now...
last thing I want to show you...
have a look at this.
The view.
(CHUCKLES)
Kind of ironic, really.
So little space in here
and so much space out there.
Whoa.
SAMANTHA: As the ship passed the moon,
it had already gone farther
than any human being
had ever traveled before.
I mean, think about that.
Across all of human history,
that moment was the farthest
anyone had ever gone.
But they still had millions
upon millions of miles to go.
Our craft was heading
for a moon of Jupiter
known as Europa.
JAMES: This mission is riding
on the shoulders
of many great men and women.
And so if we have any legacy at all,
I would hope that it would be
that we would inspire
those who come after us
to keep exploring,
to keep questioning,
to keep pushing the boundaries,
to keep looking for the answers
to those really tough questions...
Who are we?
Why are we here?
Where do we come from?
And... are we alone?
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
- For a very long time,
Europa has seemed
to be just a solid sphere of ice.
But even just looking at its surface,
there are clues, you know?
There might be water
underneath the ice.
And then in the fall of 2011,
scientists realized...
they released data
showing the presence
of sub-surface lakes...
of liquid! And... wow!
(LAUGHTER)
- Wherever we have found water...
we have found life.
But what came next was, um...
even more startling.
NASA discovered heat signatures
under an area known
as the Conamara Chaos.
Well, they teased the idea that...
that simple mono-cellular life
in our solar system
might not just be possible,
it might be probable.
I wanna go to Europa
and go ice fishing.
Cut through the ice,
lower a submersible,
look around, see what's there.
See what swims up
to the camera lens and licks it.
If life exists on Europa,
it will be the single most profound
discovery in human history.
ROSA:
Dasque to Mission Control. Over.
MISSION CONTROL:
We read you, Rosa. Over.
ROSA:
Data sync is live.
MISSION CONTROL:
How's everyone holding up?
DANIEL:
I think it's potato soup.
- Get something to drink.
- Dude, why...
why would you put garlic
into a space dish?
(LAUGHTER, CHATTERING)
ANDREI: - It's very rich.
KATYA: - It's delicious.
WILLIAM: - I have to say, though...
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(ROSA PANTING)
Okay, look look...
I've got another mile to go.
(CHATTER)
ROSA: - Not bad, eh?
DANIEL:
What about after your run?
When are you gonna
actually call someone?
- None of your business.
(BEEPS)
- Hey. It's time.
(ANDREI SPEAKING CHINESE)
DANIEL: I should have learned
Mandarin before we left.
- He's probably talking about us.
ROSA: - Gun it.
- One, two, one, two, one, two, one...
(FAST-FORWARDS)
(BEEPING)
KATYA: - How did you feel?
WILLIAM: - I said yes
before the question had even sunk in.
(KATYA LAUGHS)
They had to ask me four times
before I could even respond.
MISSION CONTROL:
No trouble on the ping requests.
We see a sticking valve in V-Tech.
Are you seeing that too? Over.
(CLICKS)
- Andrei is already working on a fix.
If it leaks any more,
we'll isolate the manifold.
Oh, and we have series
of fuse events in Rosa's station.
Can you have the team
on duty investigate? Over.
MISSION CONTROL:
Copy that. But you might have it fixed
before we finish the review.
You're making us feel
two steps behind.
(WILLIAM CHUCKLES)
- Over.
(CLICKING)
- You'll make him blush. Over.
(FAST-FORWARDS)
(BEEPING)
(WARBLING)
- Mission Control, can you hear me?
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Andrei is in the shower right now,
so I want to take this opportunity
to tell you that your shower system
is totally inadequate.
And I don't buy your theories about
the body adjusting
to the new hygiene regime.
You know what I can't adjust to?
The drinking of the distilled urine.
Oh! James!
I'm just saying...
you're worried about my smell
and you're drinking my urine?
You know what I think
they're really pissed off about?
You guys only gave them
four outfits.
So sometimes they wake up
in the morning,
they find out they're wearing
the same thing the entire day.
They get totally pissed off.
(KATYA LAUGHS)
- And the shoes...
(WHISPERS)
you gave them two pairs of shoes.
For women. I'm just saying.
ANDREI:
Rosa, dinner! Where is she?
ROSA: - Coming.
DANIEL: - Who's the lasagna?
JAMES: - Yeah.
DANIEL: - That's you?
WILLIAM: - Oh God.
- Who's the pod macaroni and cheese-ish?
WILLIAM: - I guess I'll take that.
JAMES: - To six months!
KATYA: - Mmm.
ALL: - Cheers.
- Okay, eyes. Eyes.
KATYA: - Wait,
- you're not looking into my eyes.
- Oh, sorry.
(LAUGHS)
(CHATTERING)
KATYA: - Can I see?
ANDREI: - Did you see any polar bears?
- No, really.
(CHATTERING)
(BEEPING)
(ANDREI SCREAMS)
SAMANTHA: We...
(CLEARS THROAT)
we pulled our astronauts
from the very best space programs
across the globe.
Our captain is William Xu.
I think this mission
will show people that
we're still capable
of achieving impossible things.
SAMANTHA:
Dr. Daniel Luxembourg.
My entire adult life has been dedicated
to exploring extreme environments.
And I became an astronaut specifically
to have the opportunity
to do something like this.
SAMANTHA:
Dr. Katya Petrovna.
Life on Earth began in the ocean,
so in some ways
this mission will be like
taking a trip back in time.
My background is in marine biology
and oceanography.
To be honest,
sometimes I'm terrified of flying.
SAMANTHA:
Andrei Blok.
I think I have
349 days in outer space,
so I'm what you call a veteran.
The only thing I can't face is...
- the food.
(LAUGHTER)
SAMANTHA:
James Corrigan.
I remember watching
footage at school
of Neil Armstrong on the moon,
and just... just knowing
"I want to do this."
- Rosa Dasque.
- Call me immature, reckless, arrogant.
I just want to go faster and farther
than anyone has before.
We had to design a spacecraft
unlike any before it.
Of course, once the decision
was made to put people on board,
the requirements ballooned.
Human beings need food, shelter.
They need an environment
that is survivable
and has some level of comfort.
(STATIC)
(ANDREI SCREAMS)
(KATYA, DISTORTED)
It's cracking the ice.
(BEEPING)
DANIEL:
We're a month away, Andrei.
We're still concerned
about your recovery.
So how should I be
recovering, exactly?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Excuse me.
WILLIAM:
So what do you think?
I still wouldn't advise leaving him
in the orbiter alone for three weeks.
I'd rather not leave
our only engineer behind.
So we take him down
with us then.
Yeah.
ROSA: Jupiter.
Being so close to our destination
lifted our spirits.
It felt that everything
made sense again.
The thickness in the air cleared.
But what cleared it
was sheer adrenaline.
WILLIAM: (OVER RADIO)
Prep for orbital transfer.
We're gonna feel some Gs here.
(ENGINES WHINE)
(ENGINES IGNITE)
(ENGINES ROARING)
(SWITCHES CLICKING)
(RATTLING)
ROSA:
Pitch maneuver.
WILLIAM:
We are clear of Jupiter's orbit.
Beginning orbital transfer.
ROSA:
Pitching for power descent.
WILLIAM:
Daniel, can you keep Andrei abreast
of any of those changes
in the readouts, please?
DANIEL: - Roger that.
ROSA: - Orbit trajectory, clear.
Current speed
60 kilometers per second.
WILLIAM: - Ready?
ROSA: - Yeah.
WILLIAM:
Surface conditions in the IZ?
DANIEL: I've got heat plume
and radiation analysis incoming,
but the data is variable.
Heat is fluctuating.
ROSA:
Not far now.
ANDREI: All systems online.
Showing green light.
WILLIAM:
Landing gear armed and ready to deploy.
ROSA:
Ladies and gentlemen, hold on.
Here we go.
WILLIAM:
Trajectory and speed?
ROSA: Heading 270.3.
Coming in low across Thera Macula
at 458.4 meters per second.
Target site lining up.
Landing gear deployed.
WILLIAM:
20 seconds to...
(BANGS) (GASPS)
What was that?
DANIEL: It's like a thermal vent.
Sort of an eruptive feature.
- Can you stabilize us?
- I'm trying!
Andrei, I need an option
for emergency landing.
DANIEL: Vent's coming from the area
around our target site.
There's a low gradation of ice
just past the IZ, along Thrace Macula.
Okay. Land us long.
Get us past the vent area.
ROSA: - 100 meters to contact.
WILLIAM: - 10 seconds of fuel.
Back off the burners on approach
or we'll melt our landing site.
ROSA: Roger that. 10 meters.
- Five meters.
WILLIAM: - Contact lights.
ROSA: Shut down.
I think we've got it.
(ENGINE ROAR STOPS)
(THUDS)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(BEEPS)
(WHIRRING DOWN)
(CLICKS, WHIRRING)
WILLIAM:
Everything okay up here?
KATYA: Sorry.
I can't pull my eyes away from it.
It takes your breath away.
(SNIFFLES)
That night I went out
and found Jupiter
in the night sky and...
I spent a long time
looking at it, just...
hoping.
(BEEPING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
DANIEL: Surface temp in current position
is holding at absolute zero.
Prelim service data has us
on a bed of what looks like ice 11.
We should be there,
but we're here.
We flew 590 million kilometers
and then landed
100 meters off the mark.
(BEEPING)
- It seems insignificant,
but it will be difficult
to get useful surface analysis.
SOKOLOV: Ironically, what threw the ship
off course from the original target zone
was a reconfirmation
of what we had hoped for.
If such heat-plume eruptions were
escaping through the cracks in the ice,
it suggested strong underwater thermal
activity and the potential for life.
If they had landed on the target area,
which was ripe for surface analysis,
the mission would have begun
with extensive surface tests
using the ship's robotic arm,
followed by a few hours
of drilling through the ice
to deploy a remote underwater probe.
- So how will that affect procedure?
(SIGHS)
What it means is we won't get
the data we want very easily.
That's why I want to move back
Daniel's surface test
and start the drill immediately.
Our best hopes of success
lies under the ice.
Daniel, what do you think?
- I wanna argue...
- I'm sure you would.
(SIGHS) ...but with
our current position in the ice,
we won't get key data.
Let's go for a swim.
(CLANGING, WHIRRING)
(HISSING)
(ELECTRONIC HUM)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
(WHIRS)
- Drill head is locked and prepped.
Beginning extension.
(BEEPS)
KATYA: - Thermal is live.
(WHIRRING)
Entering ice layer now.
(THUDS)
(RUMBLING, CREAKING)
DANIEL: - Do you hear that?
- Uh-huh.
DANIEL: - Are you getting it?
KATYA: - Yeah.
DANIEL:
I think that's just the ice shifting.
Everything's all right.
KATYA: We can expect more of that
as the temperature drops.
(BEEPING)
(RATTLES)
(GRUNTS)
(BANGS, RATTLES)
(SILENCE)
(RATTLES)
DANIEL: That was stronger
than our data projected it.
WILLIAM: - Are we stable?
- Re-working the analysis now.
Katya, let's try the frequency
of these quakes.
KATYA:
The increased tidal activity means
there could be more heat
than we thought beneath the surface.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
DANIEL: - Are you recording this?
KATYA: - Yeah.
(RUMBLING)
(RATTLING)
Okay, let's run
some diagnostics here,
because it seems
to be escalating a little bit.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(GROANS)
DANIEL: Might be some subsurface
aftershocks, but up here we'll be fine.
(STATIC) (KATYA SPEAKING)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY) You saw it.
Huh.
(SWITCHES CLICK)
DANIEL:
You got to check out this activity.
- It's incredible.
KATYA: - Everything's fine here.
What about the ECS?
WILLIAM:
All clear?
- How about the hull and landing gear?
- You see this?
- Check out the activity. Incredible.
- Yeah, no deflection.
- ECS?
WILLIAM: - ECS okay.
No problems here.
ANDREI:
Guys, I saw something.
WILLIAM:
What do you mean?
Uh, umm...
I saw something outside the ship.
From up there
through the porthole.
Maybe 100 meters out.
I tried to get a video, but I missed it.
It was a light down the linea.
I was working one of the servers
when the ice shook.
And... it was there.
WILLIAM:
A light source outside the ship?
ANDREI:
I know that I saw it.
- It was flickering.
KATYA: - How strong was the light?
Well... (SIGHS)
it was like an LED,
but dull from refraction.
But the... oh, it happened so fast.
It was there and then it was gone.
You mean it moved?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, it moved.
DANIEL:
I can check the heat signatures.
(CLICKING)
WILLIAM:
Do you see anything?
ROSA:
I've checked this footage three times.
- There's nothing to see.
KATYA: - Yeah,
but that doesn't mean
there was nothing there.
If it was too dim, these cameras
wouldn't have caught it.
DANIEL: That's true.
A weak chemiluminescence maybe?
Triggered by shifts in the ice?
KATYA: A chemical iridescence
doesn't fit this description.
DANIEL: Maybe. When we prepare
the surface test, we'll know.
I find the idea of bacteria clinging
to the underside of the ice more likely.
Something that has a luminescent
response to radioactivity.
Yeah, but do you think
it actually moved?
KATYA:
Scientifically I doubt it.
(SIGHS)
But personally, I hope so.
(GASPS)
DANIEL: - Wait, did you notice that?
WILLIAM: What?
(STATIC)
DANIEL:
Radiation interference.
It's on all the cameras.
(BEEPS) (GASPS)
DANIEL:
Wait, let's take two steps back here.
I think there's another version
of this that we have to consider.
It's entirely possible
Andrei didn't see anything at all.
It's very dark out there and his mind
could be filling in the blanks.
But it could also be
our first indication
of exactly what
we came out here to find.
(CLICKS, HISSES)
(PEN CLICKS)
(WHISPERS) Is Andrei sleeping yet?
(WHISPERS) No.
(WHIRRING)
(BEEPING, CLICKING)
ROSA'S VOICE:
In those days there was a raw...
a raw mix of emotions.
We'd come so far,
weathered so much.
(KEYBOARD, SWITCHES CLICK)
I think we were all in a place where
excitement blended with awe...
and fear.
(STATIC, DISTORTION)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Okay, so Daniel is my witness.
You find a single microbe
up there and I win.
If you find a still-living microbe,
you win.
What? Evidence of extinction
doesn't win me the bet? (SCOFFS)
ANDREI: You always find
a technicality like that
- for winning.
JAMES: - No no. It's not a technicality.
It means that at some point
in time we were not alone.
ANDREI:
It is a technicality.
- Daniel.
- What?
What are you doing, buddy?
What's happening?
- You lost something?
- I lost my toothbrush.
- What?
- He's unpacking his entire bunk.
You lost your toothbrush?
What color is it, man?
Did you pack it?
ANDREI: - Oh no.
- Okay, where's my toothbrush?
ANDREI: - We have to return to Earth.
JAMES: - We better call housekeeping.
(STATIC)
DANIEL:
You should get some rest.
Not until I know
what I saw out there.
We're working on it.
- We'll figure it out.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
What if I can't believe
or trust my own eyes?
(SIGHS)
You need to sleep.
We need you to sleep.
There's pills, sedatives.
ANDREI:
No pills.
I need to stay alert.
I need to stay focused.
(BEEPING)
(DRILL WHIRRING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
KATYA: - How are you holding up?
Good.
(THUDS)
(BEEPS)
(CREAKING)
DANIEL:
We've broken through.
(WHISPERS) Water.
(BEEPS)
I'm patching in.
- Probe microphone live.
(CLICKS, BEEPS)
(BUBBLING)
(WHIRRING)
KATYA: Wow. This is a completely
untouched environment.
Just waiting.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(CHUCKLES)
KATYA:
We're so far from home, but...
it's like looking
at Lake Vostok right now.
(SIGHS) Radiation levels
down here are minimal.
And there's definitely a heat source
somewhere in our target zone.
122 meters to heat-plume area.
There's 100 kilometers
of water down there.
It puts the trench zones
back on Earth to shame.
I think we're seeing
some tectonic plates here.
The sulfur concentration is showing
that the thermal vents
are closer than expected.
(SIGHS) Creepy.
That's your scientific
assessment, is it?
DANIEL: - Yep.
- "Creepy"?
(DANIEL CHUCKLES)
- Is that the weathering of the ice?
KATYA: Maybe.
Could be a bacteria.
DANIEL:
Grabbing samples
and... moving on.
20 meters to target zone.
Look at how the sunlight
penetrates the ice here.
It must be much thinner
than we thought.
(REVERBERATING HUM)
You hear that?
It could be coming
from reverberations,
deeper caverns caught in currents.
It's almost like a male whale sound.
Hey, a little presumptuous,
don't you think?
(KATYA LAUGHS) Maybe.
- Oh yeah.
I've got some irregularities
in our data here.
KATYA:
I'm getting a radiation spike.
DANIEL:
Rosa, are you picking up on this?
ROSA:
There's something in the video feed too.
It's similar to what we saw
after the last ice shift.
DANIEL:
That doesn't make any sense.
The ice should be shielding
the probe from radiation.
KATYA:
It's not coming from above.
It's coming from deeper
into the target zone.
DANIEL: Yeah.
Let's adjust course
and depth to investigate.
KATYA:
Bringing us down.
(STATIC)
WILLIAM: - What was that?
DANIEL:
What's our temperature down here?
Get ready to expand the probe arm
- to get samples.
(ELECTRONIC SHRIEK)
DANIEL:
What was that? Oh shit.
(HIGH-PITCHED TONE)
(CLICKS)
(TONE STOPS)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
- Recycle power.
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
- All right, let's run some tests.
KATYA: There was an abnormal shift
in the velocity of the current.
DANIEL: - It's not reacting.
WILLIAM: - Is it a remote issue?
DANIEL: - I've lost control of it.
- Shit.
(BEEPING, CLICKING)
ANDREI:
Can you play back the video?
(STATIC)
(SHRIEKS)
(THUDS)
(STATIC)
WILLIAM:
Did something hit the probe?
- What data do we have?
DANIEL: - It'll take time to process,
- but I'll tell you right now, not much.
(SIGHS)
ROSA: It seemed like
it was right under the probe.
(WILLIAM, FADING)
What was the last piece of data it sent?
The heat surged to 50°,
but that couldn't have
caused a critical...
(VOICES FADE)
ROSA: - Shit!
(KATYA BREATHING HEAVILY)
SAMANTHA: A surface walk
was always heavily debated
at all stages of our mission planning.
And our main concern then
was the radiation from Jupiter.
KATYA:
I will walk to the target zone
and I'll get the body
of samples we need.
DANIEL: Katya, the radiation alone...
The radiation is fluctuating.
It was 200 ram last time I checked.
I'm willing to take that risk.
What about everything else
that could go wrong?
It's 100 meters!
SOKOLOV: Having lost the probe,
the only way to get the data
was to explore the chaos zones
where the ice had cracked
and re-cracked.
And this process would
expose any microorganisms
that have been trapped inside the ice.
(ARGUING)
- Somebody's gotta go out there!
DANIEL: - It's too risky.
- Enough! Enough!
JAMES: I feel like it's
a critical phase and I'm not there.
- I just...
(SOFT CHATTERING)
I just didn't realize
it would be this hard.
- Over. (CHUCKLES)
(COMPUTER CHIMES)
(KATYA CHUCKLES)
DANIEL: - Sounds like a car.
(CHIMES)
(SIGHS)
You know take him
to the game, if you want.
Umm...
I miss you guys. Love you.
Over.
(CHIMES)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
- You Okay?
Yeah, I am good.
I'm good.
(SNIFFLES)
Not so easy, is it?
(SIGHS) No.
No, it's not.
(SNIFFLING)
You know, my boy's gonna be
six when I see him again.
(SIGHS)
DANIEL:
He's gonna be proud of you.
(SNIFFLES)
(CLASSICAL SCORE PLAYING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
ANDREI: What would you do if you
get out there and you find nothing?
(CLICKS, CHIRPS)
Well, even if we found nothing,
it's in effect a discovery.
ANDREI:
It would make me very frustrated.
KATYA:
I know there's something there.
MISSION CONTROL:
Check on NAV bays 3 and 4.
(DISTORTED)
(STATIC)
Mission Control,
repeat please. Over.
Do you want me to show you
how to beat him?
ROSA: William, I've got some static
in the comm array feed up here.
It looks like a radiation spike.
WILLIAM:
Have you tried recycling the system?
MISSION CONTROL:
Europa One, come in.
(ALARM BEEPING)
- Rosa, we've lost your feed.
Come in, Europa One.
- Europa One, come in.
(STATIC)
Come in, Europa One.
Europa One, come in.
Europa One.
(ALARM BEEPING)
(STATIC)
(HISSES, CRACKLING)
MISSION CONTROL:
Europa One, Europa One, do you...
(STATIC)
SAMANTHA: Now try as you might
to prepare for everything,
there will always be
that unknown element.
(BEEPING)
(CLICKS)
SAMANTHA:
In this case a solar storm hit,
damaging key systems, including
communication with Mission Control.
ANDREI:
Are you ready?
(HISSING)
(JAMES BREATHING HEAVILY)
Okay. Oxygen is flowing.
We're good.
(BEEPS)
(WHIRS, CLANGS)
ANDREI:
This never gets old.
JAMES:
Okay, commencing egress.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
JAMES: William, I'm gonna
tether the EMUs once we're...
- on the hull.
WILLIAM: - Roger that.
SAMANTHA: Andrei and James had
to do an EVA to repair the system...
a bit like performing ballet
and rocket science
at 125,000 miles an hour.
JAMES: This reminds me
of the ISS thrust fix all over again.
WILLIAM:
5 hours, 13 minutes remaining on EVA.
JAMES:
You know what time it is back on Earth?
ANDREI:
Battery block D is non-functional.
WILLIAM:
2 hours 55 minutes.
All right, I've got green lights
on the fan arrays.
How are we doing
on the comm power supply?
JAMES:
So I said to the guy, "You know,
I can't just come along
and stay as long as you want."
"You have to tell me
how long it's gonna take."
WILLIAM: Okay, guys,
50 minutes remaining on EVA.
I can't keep you
out there much longer.
ANDREI:
Panels one through six are clear.
(CLICKS, BEEPS)
- Moving onto seven.
JAMES: We just need
a little more time, William.
I think it's a blown fuse
in the communication panel.
WILLIAM:
You've got 37 minutes.
If you don't find it,
we'll need to begin regress.
JAMES: Okay, we're at
the communication panel.
Opening up the door.
What do you got, Andrei?
James, get a look at this.
(JAMES CHUCKLES) Whoo.
ANDREI:
The receptors are shot.
JAMES:
Yeah, William, the whole board is fried.
I gotta take the pins out.
Okay.
Taking out the first pin.
(BEEPING)
- Come on.
And first pin is clear.
Going for number two.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Proceed.
JAMES:
Come on.
Shit.
It's not coming.
Okay.
William, we've got a frozen pin.
WILLIAM: Okay, guys,
leave that last panel for now.
What do you think?
ANDREI: We can't tell
how bad it is till we get in there.
You sure, man? You don't want
to put heat on there first?
- It just feels...
ANDREI: - The damage could spread.
(DISTORTED DIALOGUE)
JAMES: - Okay.
- What the hell is going on out there?
JAMES:
Okay. I'm set.
(BOTH GRUNT)
JAMES: - Come on.
Ah! Shit! It snapped.
- The panel snapped.
(ANDREI GROANS)
(HISSING)
ANDREI: - I ripped my glove.
(DISTORTED) I ripped...
JAMES:
It's okay. Andrei's okay.
- We're tethered.
- It's a tear of one inch.
- I've cut my skin.
JAMES: - I got him hooked to me.
ANDREI:
We're coming in.
Andrei, do not attempt
to climb back in on your own.
- James?
- I see him, I see him. I got him.
I'm going for him. Hang on.
ANDREI: - It's a small rip.
JAMES: - Take it easy.
- Just relax, big guy.
WILLIAM: - Keep calm, Andrei.
ANDREI: - I'm bleeding.
WILLIAM: - Save your oxygen.
He's losing air,
but he's got his hand on it.
I'm bringing him in.
(BEEPING) I got you.
Nice and easy.
Just relax, big guy.
- I got you.
- Oxygen pressure is dropping steadily.
- You don't have much time.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(JAMES BREATHING HEAVILY)
WILLIAM: James, listen to me.
His oxygen level is red-lighting.
Get him back inside the ship.
JAMES: Okay.
We're at the lock. I'm coming in.
ANDREI:
Stop, don't go in.
JAMES: - Why?
- There's something on your suit.
It's hydrazine.
Uh, guys, we've got a problem.
I've got hydrazine on my suit.
It must have hit me
when we popped the panel.
ANDREI:
He's covered in it.
It's in the seams.
It's... it's everywhere.
- What can we do to decontaminate?
- We can't.
If we bring him in,
the air in the ship will become toxic.
Come on. Shit.
We should get him in the lock,
get a v-cam reading.
We can't. There'd be too much risk
of lingering contamination.
We gotta figure out
a way to get the suit clean.
It's not coming out.
- I'm totally screwed.
WILLIAM: - Andrei, get in the lock.
We need to depressurize
your suit now.
Then we'll figure out
how to get James in.
Seriously?!
Come on, man, I got...
I've got 20 minutes of oxygen.
Is there no way to get it clean?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ALARM BLARING)
- Andrei.
ANDREI: - I'm not going in.
I'll get you out of the suit...
- What?
- ... Into the airlock.
You'll be out of the suit
less than two minutes.
- It's survivable.
ROSA: - Is that even possible?
ANDREI:
I'll get you out of this. I'll fix it.
No. Andrei,
you're gonna black out, man.
ANDREI: - No, I'm not.
- This isn't gonna work.
WILLIAM:
James, now you're bleeding oxygen.
- No. No.
ROSA: - We're going to lose them both.
WILLIAM: James, he's fading.
You have to get him in the lock.
(SOLID ALARM TONE)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Okay. Shit.
WILLIAM:
Rosa, close the airlock now!
James is no longer
attached to the hull.
- I said close the lock!
JAMES: - Rosa, close the lock!
(CLICKS, BEEPS)
(WHIRS)
(THUDS)
ROSA: - Airlock is closed.
Oxygen is flowing.
Repressurization in 10 minutes.
This is insane.
You gotta go get him.
We can't.
By the time we'd get there, he'd...
James?
Yeah yeah yeah, I'm here. Umm...
Oh, Christ, I can't...
(WHIMPERS) I'm gone.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Oh shit.
Is Andrei okay?
WILLIAM:
Yeah. He's okay.
I'm sorry, James.
Don't be sorry.
It was an accident, you know?
Um...
I... I don't have much time,
so tell Andrei...
tell Andrei he's a...
(DISTORTED)
he's a crazy son of a bitch, you know?
And I love him for trying
to save my life and...
Deb and Jamie, I...
I love you so much.
(CRYING)
Forgive me.
I thought I was trying to do
something great for mankind.
I always said it was
worth the risk but...
(SIGHS)
Forgive me for... for hurting you.
A part of me kinda wishes I could just
float out here forever, you know?
(WHEEZES)
JAMES: I can't s...
I can't see anything. I can't...
I can't see any...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BREATHING STOPS)
(BREATHING SOFTLY)
(SCREAMS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
It's stupid to argue like this.
Katya, no way you can go out there
without us behind you.
And, William, with all due respect,
I think we should all
decide together how to do this.
I know what you think, William.
What about you, Daniel?
It's ill-advised.
A surface walk was
always a question mark.
Well, we can do it.
I'll walk the equipment out
and you can run
the analysis from here.
We can get what we came for.
And if she goes out there
and we never see her again?
(ANDREI GRUNTS)
WILLIAM: - Think hard about that.
I think she should do it.
I'm sorry, William.
(DISGUSTED SIGH)
- Thank you.
- Andrei?
- It's too dangerous.
I vote no.
Absolutely.
So that's a tie then.
Rosa?
ROSA'S VOICE: Katya made
our complete cosmic insignificance
seem like a call to arms.
What can I say?
She was right.
She's still right.
WILLIAM:
Two hours of EVA.
210 meters out.
Search the top layer of ice
while Daniel runs analysis back here.
KATYA:
Copy that.
(BEEPS)
(WHIRRING)
(BOTH SPEAK RUSSIAN)
(HISSES)
Be careful.
(KATYA SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
Compared to the breadth
of knowledge yet to be known,
what does your life actually matter?
(HUMPHS)
(HIGH-FIVES)
(CLICKS, BEEPS)
(THUDS, HISSES)
WILLIAM:
30 minutes for depressurization.
(BEEPS)
(HISSING)
(HIGH-PITCHED TONE)
KATYA: - Batteries live.
WILLIAM:
Switching to battery power.
Pressure's at 30 kPa.
How's your prep?
30 seconds to egress.
Good luck.
KATYA: - I'm ready. (SIGHS)
(CLICKS, BEEPS)
(WHIRS)
(THUDS)
(WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
I can't believe I'm here.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
We're here.
This is incredible.
DANIEL:
Radiation is holding steady.
We're at 50 millisieverts per hour...
within acceptable limits.
ROSA: I'll check if I can
see her from upstairs.
KATYA:
It's so still out here.
It's so... I don't know what the word is.
- Creepy?
(KATYA LAUGHS)
KATYA: I was going to go
with "cosmically astounding."
I wish I could take one of these
gloves off and touch the ice.
- Really feel it.
- Please don't.
I have visual of her from here.
KATYA: I'm heading towards
the target zone now.
WILLIAM: We've got your back.
Life-support systems look good.
(CRACKLING, RUMBLING)
DANIEL:
Okay, Katya, you are crossing
into the target zone.
You see that?
Where the ice is less deteriorated?
Just set up in the middle of that.
- Here?
DANIEL: - Exactly.
She must have been
out there for an hour.
But it... it felt like an eternity.
Each minute seemed to
divide and divide again
into endless moments.
KATYA:
First sample ready for scan.
(BEEPING)
Sending data back to you now.
Are you reading?
DANIEL:
Running analysis, stand by.
(BEEPING)
DANIEL: We're negative for trace
carbon and chemotropic processes.
Can you try ice
with more trace rust?
ROSA:
You could feel...
every minute is somehow longer
than it had ever been before.
(RADIATION METER CLICKING)
KATYA: - Let's give it another shot.
DANIEL: - Why don't you take
the equipment down
the linea to zone three?
(CLICKING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
WILLIAM:
Radiation is trending upwards, Katya.
You've been out there 70 minutes.
KATYA:
We're so close.
How much time
can you give me, William?
WILLIAM: You've only got time
for a few more sample sets.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BEEPS, BUZZING)
(RAPID CLICKING)
WILLIAM: All right, Katya,
it's time to come back.
KATYA: Okay.
I'm digging out a sub-surface sample
that isn't radiation blasted.
Are you guys seeing this?
- Here.
(BEEPS)
I'm getting imaging... now.
(BEEPING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKS)
- It's a unicellular organism,
something akin to an algae.
I knew it.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
- What is it?
- I don't know for sure, but...
I mean, it's not like it has a name.
KATYA: It looks like
something Precambrian to me.
That's my first guess
on an Earth-based analogue.
I don't believe it.
We did it.
(CHUCKLES)
DANIEL: Okay, Katya,
let's get you back into the ship
- and sort out this data.
KATYA: - Packing up.
(CHUCKLES)
I hope the champagne's ready.
Look at that.
Do you guys read
that light in the distance?
WILLIAM:
We're not reading anything.
It looks like some kind
of chemical iridescence.
I'm going to get closer to investigate.
DANIEL: Reserve oxygen
will give her another 90 minutes.
WILLIAM: Okay, Katya.
Proceed with caution.
I can't see her.
She's moving farther out.
(BEEPING)
(KATYA BREATHING HEAVILY)
KATYA:
It's beautiful.
Andrei.
This looks like it could be
the light you were describing.
- I can see it again.
(SWITCHES CLICK)
Can you check on my readouts?
DANIEL: It's... it's...
it's... it's hard to say.
I mean maybe there's
other microbial organisms
out there that eat through the ice.
This is a much more complex
ecosystem
than we'd previously thought.
(STATIC, BEEPING)
I wanna see
if it's reacting to my lights.
I'm going to turn them off.
(CLICKS)
(KATYA BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm going to get closer.
WILLIAM:
Hold that action, Katya.
(BEEPING)
(THRUMMING)
(WILLIAM, DISTORTED)
Katya, do you read me?
We have severe
electromagnetic interference.
WILLIAM:
Did you see that?
She has to come back.
KATYA:
...have visual.
I'm going to try to get it back.
I'm seeing it through the ice.
I think it's some sort
of bioluminescence.
DANIEL:
We've got the data, Katya.
Heat and radiation levels
are moving with it.
I can't wrap my head around this.
It's... (DISTORTED)
KATYA:
Okay, the ice is thin here,
but it seems stable. If I get close,
- I should be able to get a better look.
WILLIAM: - Keep your line open.
I want to know
what's happening out there.
(STATIC)
KATYA: - The ground is not stable!
- The ice is breaking.
(CRACKING)
Katya, can you hear me?
Come back to the ship now!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
It's cracking the ice!
- My foot is... (DISTORTED)
(LOUD STATIC)
(SCREAMS)
- Katya, do you read me? Come in!
ANDREI: - Get her back in!
- Get her back in!
- Katya, come in. Do you read me?
- She's not listening.
- Rosa, do you see her out there?
ROSA:
Nothing. Just the ice.
(CLICKING)
- She's under the ice.
WILLIAM: - What?
Under the water.
(STATIC)
We've still got her helmet cam.
(STATIC, BEEPING)
(CHITTERING)
(FLATLINE)
(WILLIAM BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CLICKS SLOWING)
(CLICKING FADES)
DANIEL:
Whatever it was,
it was reacting
to the light on her helmet.
That's the behavior
of a complex organism.
ROSA:
The logs, the data...
they don't show
any proof of complex life.
We can't leave until we have that.
ANDREI: We don't know how long
we'll be stable here.
WILLIAM:
And we've lost two of our crew.
ANDREI:
If we never leave,
no one on Earth will ever
know what we discovered.
I agree.
We need to leave now.
When the next launch window opens,
we take off.
ANDREI: Mmm.
I want all the data secured
and double-checked...
- especially everything Katya found.
(ANDREI SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
(HISSING, IGNITES)
ROSA: - T-minus 32 seconds to liftoff.
Prepping for ascent ignition.
(ENGINES HUMMING)
Orbital sync is established.
Docking operation
in t-minus eight minutes.
(BEEPING)
WILLIAM: - Give me a systems check.
- Engine temperature's rising.
(WHIRRING)
WILLIAM: - Andrei?
ANDREI:
Booster 3 is stuck at 30%.
WILLIAM:
We've got to launch now.
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
(RATTLING)
(ENGINE HUMMING LOUDER)
ROSA:
Launch in three, two, one.
What the hell?
I can't keep it steady.
Our trajectory is way off course.
(GRUNTS) The injectors are melting!
(ALARM BEEPING)
We've got engine mixture ratio errors
in engines two and three.
DANIEL:
We're nowhere near orbital transfer!
ANDREI: Hey!
ROSA:
I can try to correct course at apogee.
- The vernier thrusters might do it!
DANIEL: - We need to shut
- the valves down!
- Get us back down on the surface.
- What?
- Don't engage the second burn.
You mean crash us?
ANDREI:
What's happening up there?
(DISTORTED SHOUTING)
ANDREI: - Valves dow...
(BEEPING)
(ENGINES STOP)
WILLIAM: 2,000 meters.
1900.
I can't keep it steady.
Computer's unable to rectify.
Still dropping!
Coming in too fast!
What are you doing? William!
- William!
- I'm going to slow us down.
(GRUNTS)
- I'm going to blow the water shielding.
(ROSA AND ANDREI SHOUT)
- It'll create... thrust!
(SHOUTING)
- Brace for impact!
DANIEL: - 200 meters!
(ROSA SHOUTING)
(CRASHES)
(THUDS)
(SHIP GROANING)
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(STATIC)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(SWITCHES CLICK)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ELECTRICAL HUMMING)
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
- Andrei? Andrei?
(GROANS)
- Huh?
- Wake up, wake up!
(ANDREI GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
ROSA: - William?
Okay.
(STATIC)
DANIEL:
He's dead.
ROSA:
He saved us.
(CRYING)
ROSA'S VOICE:
Europa wasn't ready to let us go yet.
It quickly became apparent that
we crashed
into the original landing zone.
Ironic, I suppose.
(BEEPING)
SOKOLOV: - This zone was much warmer,
much more active than
any previous data had suggested.
Underwater vents
had rendered the ice brittle
and unstable and constantly shifting
And then you add onto that
William had jettisoned
the water shielding
on descent and that had saved them,
but it also left them
dangerously exposed to radiation.
(HISSING)
ANDREI: - We're leaking oxygen.
And we're also losing heat...
three degrees
since I started checking.
If I would bet,
we'll freeze before we suffocate.
The exterior light should be working.
Daniel, can you check?
- Daniel?
DANIEL: - I am.
It's not good.
The ice is cracking under the ship.
You can almost see
the ice/water interface.
We're gonna be under the ice
in a matter of hours.
ROSA: Our last shot
is docking with the orbiter...
and using its back-up
life-support systems.
ANDREI: If the propulsion system
is still alive...
I can get us into orbit.
Come help me.
It's pointless.
(BEEPING)
ROSA: - Is this what you're looking for?
Yeah. Thank you.
(DISGUSTED SIGH)
(CLATTERS)
(THUDS)
(CLATTERING)
Shit!
(ANDREI GRUNTS)
(ROSA BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Are you all right?
DANIEL: - The ice broke through.
This is it. It's happening.
It's the end.
ROSA:
We'll find a way.
We have to.
ANDREI:
The fuel line is partially frozen.
That caused the loss of thrust.
DANIEL:
We're lodged in the ice.
Can we even take off properly?
ROSA:
If we time it right, maybe.
Two hours
is the fastest we can fix it,
but that is if...
two of us is working on it.
- You mean the three of us?
ANDREI: - No.
You have to stay inside,
prep engines.
The fix must happen
outside the ship.
(SHIP GROANING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
ROSA'S VOICE: - That was that.
Are you ready?
- Are you?
(ANDREI CHUCKLES)
ROSA'S VOICE:
Daniel and Andrei entered the airlock
for final de-pressurization.
(CLICKS, BEEPS)
- Here.
Two hours.
Then I'll see you both
back here. Yeah?
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
ROSA'S VOICE: - And that...
(THUDS)
(HISSING)
...brings us to now.
If we don't make it...
(CRYING)
this record...
one day...
Just in case.
(BEEPS)
(DANIEL EXHALES)
Depressurization complete.
ROSA:
Pressure is 25 kilopascals.
(CLICKS) (WHIRRING)
DANIEL:
I'll go first,
make sure the ice is stable.
(SHIVERS)
DANIEL: - Beginning egress.
Roger that.
(BEEPS, HUMMING)
ROSA:
System signals are strong.
(BEEPS, HISSES)
(WHIRS)
DANIEL: - The hatch is open.
(STATIC)
Oh shit.
The ladder is a bit skewed,
but I think I can make it.
The ice beneath the ship is cracked,
but it looks sturdy.
Taking my first step now.
(STATIC)
ROSA: - Be careful.
We're picking up
the same radiation signature.
Okay. Taking my first step now.
(CLICKING INCREASING)
- I am on the ice.
Oh God. I can feel it...
(RUMBLING)
ANDREI:
Daniel? Daniel?!
- Do you read me?
ANDREI: - Daniel?!
(RUMBLING STOPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Daniel? Andrei?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Talk to me!
(STATIC)
(DANIEL SHOUTS)
ANDREI:
Rosa, turn off the exterior lights.
- Turn off the exterior lights!
- Okay.
ROSA:
I'm getting nothing.
His mike is dead.
His camera is dead.
He just vanished.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you read me?
What the hell
is going on out there?
ANDREI:
I don't know.
What?
(CLICKING)
- I lost him. I lost him.
The ice cracked beneath him.
Daniel? Daniel?
He was surrounded by lights,
then he was gone.
Tell me...
tell me we can still
patch the fuel line.
(CLICKING)
Andrei?
Say something.
- Andrei?
- We can't.
There's one thing still worth trying.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
The communication array
is still salvageable.
I can fix it if I take parts
from the life support.
(EXHALES SHARPLY) I don't know.
ANDREI:
Can you still prep data sync?
(BEEPS) (CLICKS)
Rosa, we can do this.
How will I know when?
When I remove life-support batteries
you'll lose power
in the command module.
- Then data sync...
(STATIC)
ANDREI:
Keep talking to me.
Keep the line open.
(ANDREI, DISTORTED) It's dark.
It's not gonna be easy.
(CLICKING)
ROSA: - Andrei?
I've lost your camera again.
ANDREI: - Can you hear me?
- Uh-huh.
- Okay.
ANDREI: - It's not far.
(BEEPS)
ROSA: - Camera's back up.
ANDREI: - 10 paces...
(CLICKING)
(ICE CRACKING)
(RUMBLING)
Andrei?
(MMMM) Come on, come on.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(STATIC)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
Andrei, I can see the light behind you.
(DISTORTED SPEECH)
Hurry, please.
ANDREI:
I can see water under the ship.
Come on, hold on.
(POWER WHIRS DOWN)
ROSA:
Another malfunction.
I need to check the drives.
Work, please.
- It's just one more tweak and I'm done.
- Andrei?
Do you read me?
Do you read me?!
ANDREI:
There's a cabinet in the cockpit...
(WHIRRING DOWN)
- ...that I've been working with.
Join the wires...
and the systems will start.
Command module is just about dead.
We're losing cameras here.
I'm moving to the...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Andrei?
I'm connecting the wires.
Almost there. Almost there.
(DISTORTED) Rosa, it's working!
It's working!
ROSA: - Oh God.
(DISTORTED) Running out of time!
(BEEPING)
Communications are up.
- You did it!
(ICE CRACKING)
ANDREI: You need to see this!
Are you getting this?!
(DISTORTED SPEECH)
(STATIC)
The luminescence is
all around the ship now!
ROSA:
The exterior cameras are dying.
ANDREI:
Can you hear me?
Andrei?
(CRACKING)
ANDREI:
The ship is sinking into the ice! Oh!
(DISTORTED SCREAMING)
Andrei?
Do... do you read? Andrei?
Andrei, do you read?
Talk to me. Talk to me.
Andrei, talk to me!
(BUZZING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHIRRING)
ROSA'S VOICE: Compared to the breadth
of knowledge yet to be known...
(WHIRRING)
...what does your life
actually matter?
(STATIC, DISTORTION)
(BANGING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(CLANGS)
(SPLASHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHITTERING)
(ROARS)
SAMANTHA: In those final moments,
knowing communication
had been re-established,
Rosa chose to open the airlock.
I got the call at 3:00 a.m.
telling me that communication
had been re-established.
By the time I got
into our mission control
our servers were flooded
with images of our crew.
(CLASSICAL SCORE PLAYING)
Our mission
had finally come back to us.
We saw the sacrifices
they made for each other
to keep the mission alive,
to push the discovery further.
And that final image...
startling.
Terrifying. Completely beyond
our wildest theoretic models.
The discovery of this creature
is simply extraordinary.
We now know that our universe
is far stranger, far more alive
than we had ever imagined.
The crew of Europa One
changed the fundamental context
in which all of humanity
understands itself.
I don't know what
greater measure of success
- they could have achieved.
(ROSA CHUCKLES)
- Is this smiling? Smiling?
- Wet your lip.
- Yeah.
ROSA: - Uh-huh.
One, two...
U
Up
Upl
Uplo
Uploa
Upload
Uploade
Uploaded
Uploaded b
Uploaded by
Uploaded by n
Uploaded by ne
Uploaded by nec
Uploaded by necc
Uploaded by necco
Uploaded by necco.
Uploaded by necco.d
Uploaded by necco.du
Uploaded by necco.dur
Uploaded by necco.dura
Uploaded by necco.duran