I wake up in the
middle of the night
Every night ...
it's been 4 years
I hear a cry in my sleep
The voice of
a baby screaming
calling me for help
I wake up and look around
Erina is not here
Although I am a mother
Her warm embrace
cannot soothe my pain
Some said
"make another baby"
How can they
be so insensitive
Until she came back
I thought I would
go crazy
As a couple
Erina was our treasure
But the Erina
who came back
of course is our child
But
the little
4 year-old Erina
Does not see us
as her real parents
She thinks her abductor
is her real mother
She loves her
Do you know how painful
how sad this is?
That woman
Has robbed the whole family
The pain of our family
Even as Erina is back
still continues
That woman
Stole not only
Erina's body
But her heart also
One who takes a life
gets the death penalty
But she took the heart
of a whole family
And there is no death
penalty for her
This is why I say ...
Give us back
our happiness
Etsuko told me:
"You are bare like
a tree in winter"
"You got pregnant from Hiroshi
but terminated it"
"now it went bad and
you can't conceive anymore"
"That's the price you pay
for killing a baby"
When Etsuko got pregnant
I thought I had to take
a distance from Hiroshi
But I was too weak
I couldn't
Etsuko was calling
every day
Crying for her
husband to return
or the next day talking
about Hiroshi's sex life
taking pleasure in
an open discussion
an other day
verbally abusing me
she kept calling
every day
She seemed almost crazy
when I heard
the baby was born
I just wanted to take
a glance at the baby
one look and that
would be enough
then I would forget everything
change place and job
Start a new life with
my dad's inheritance
It was all set
in my heart
Kaoru ...
Little Kaoru
...protect this child
I will protect
this child
Her smile would
comfort me
would forgive that ...
I had killed my baby
in the womb
tried to steal
a married man
for all these
she would be
my forgiveness
this is ...
what I thought
"In a baby's most
tender years"
"the accused took her
away from her parents"
"at a time when a child
needs affection most"
"she dispossessed her"
"That little Erina's emotional
scars will remain"
"is also a concern"
"Despite the cruelty
of the crime"
"The accused doesn't
reconsider her act"
"or show any sign of regret"
"it is useless to expect
any sincere remorse"
"And in the view
of these facts"
"We apply the sentence
of 6 years imprisonment"
"We have given this penalty
due consideration"
Let the accused
come to the bar
This is the end
of the trial
Does the accused
want to say something?
If you do
please be concise
Until I was arrested
I would pray
every day of my life
and every day, all day
to live with Kaoru
And I lived praying
continuously
For four year
I was allowed to taste
the joy of motherhood
I would like to thank
Mr. and Mrs. Akiyama
Wouldn't you rather apologize
than thank them?
There is no word
of apology
Just die!
Why don't you die!
Please calm down
Rebirth
[The loneliness of
the 8th day cicada]
[John Mayer - Daughters]
I know a girl
she puts the color
inside of my world
But she's just
like a maze
Where all of the walls
all continually change
And I've done ...
Ms Akiyama
We're going out to karaoke
I work until
12 midnight
Oh, right
You're Erina Akiyama?
I'm Ando
a freelance writer
May we have
a little talk?
Are you a journalist?
You are little
Kaoru, right?
I'd like to ask you questions
about the abduction
I don't remember it
Here
If you remember anything
please tell me
I'll come again
Finished Work?
Be careful on the way back
Kishida
Mrs. Akiyama
congratulations !
Congratulations
It's a family reunion
How do you feel right now?
How do you feel
about the accused?
Do you feel she
is your own kid?
Erina found in Kagawa, Shodoshima
with 33-year-old abductor
Erina reunited with family
after an absence of 1342 days
Kazuo Nozomi, no regrets
expresses gratitude instead of apologies
Oh, Yasue!
Yeah ... Who is it?
Kiwako Nozomi
I'm sorry
Right now I'm in
your neighborhood
Close to your house
Alright, thank you
Little Kaoru
It's cold out there
So your Mom got married
and made you!?
Little Kaoru is so cute
Little Kaoru
Let's make a tea pot?
What?
Milk
What's her dosage?
About that, Yasue
I need your help
What kind of help?
I did not actually get married
I lived together
with this kid's father
but I ran away
Why?
He was hitting the baby
So I decided to take
the child and run
Tell me Kiwa, could
this person be ...?
No way! Of course not
So, help me please
I Broke with up with
that other guy long ago
He was so mean
Although he was married
He told you he'd leave
if you cheated on him
I thought of going
myself and yell at him
Yasue, typical
Remember our teacher
was smoking in class
You started getting
angry at him
I did?
You are the same
person I used to know
But there's
no going back
You don't need
to be so dramatic
I'll help you
You can ask me
anything you want
Next, the infant
abduction in Kanagawa
A 4 month old baby
disappeared yesterday
in Hiratsuka City
Kanagawa Prefecture
[Magazines:]
"Infant"
"Mom and Baby Everyday"
Erina daughter of
Mr. Hiroshi Akiyama
Is 4 months old
[Book:]
"My first Baby"
According to the police
yesterday around 8:30 am
Etsuko, wife of Mr. Akiyama
drove him to the station
When she came back home
Little Erina
had disappeared
She reported it
to the police
There was no
evidence of robbery
Police say it's highly probable
that in the couple's absence
little Erina has
been abducted
The investigation into a
minor's abduction has started
Please
Welcome
Hi!
It's OK at the counter?
What do you recommend?
Handmade tofu and
raw horse sashimi
And a beer please
Why the long face?
So you came
We never meet
so I came
- good evening
– good evening
Did you read
my document?
We don't need to drinking
but we could go to a place
Who's this?
Mr. Kishida
I had a previous appointment
with my friend, I'm sorry
What?
A Boyfriend?
A Stalker?
You want me to
walk you home?
We could bring
beers home instead
I think there was a
convenience store there
Tell me
The cicadas are
full of life
They're still singing
Cicadas wait in the
ground for years to hatch
Once they come out
they live 3 days
It's sad
It's not 3 days
it's 7 days
Oh, is that right?
Let's sit for
a while and drink
I was surprised
you came suddenly?
That's for sure
This time I want
to write about you
about that abduction
I got it, you don't
want to talk
I really don't remember
it's quite plain, I was
brought up by abductor
It's too particular
I came to listen to
that particular account
One more drink?
Let's drink
Let's buy side
dishes too
Ah, right
Can't you drink at home?
I want to go
back and sleep
I meant drinking
at your place
Where is it?
No time to daydream
let's go
Wow, you have no shame
I'm hungry
How was my document?
I read such prints
a long time ago
Oh, and where?
Mommy used to buy
them secretly
Hiding them from me
So you know everything
about the abductor
Kiwako Nonomiya
What did you think
about Kiwako Nonomiya?
the interview has
already begun?
Well it's just
small talk
What did you think the first time
you read such articles?
Such books or articles
tell so much
it's hard to know
it becomes confusing
Well ...
The writers purposefully
designs an entertaining
story, right?
Well ...
You have such wisdom
It's like reading
about someone else
as if it didn't
happen to me
I see ...
You know
inside you'll find
the trial record
read it again
you were four years old
it's great that you returned
safely to your family
The truth be told, we still
don't feel as a family
It took me long to realize
who my real mother was
My mother too
was embarrassed
Every time
she looks at me
All the memories
of the event come back
Embarrassed?
How is that?
It's not your fault
[Osaka Imperial Palace]
Yes
OK
I'm sorry ...
OK, OK!
Let's drink
You must be hungry
OK, OK
I decided to name it Kaoru
You remember we said
Kaoru sounds beautiful
Be it a boy or a girl
Kaoru is good
it's not possible
right now
In fact I'd like to
have dinner every night
watch TV with you
We'd have a normal life
get married like
normal people
Not a sordid affair
I'll tell everything to
my wife and leave her
so if this kid was born
It would ruin our
chances for a future
I want a child
Yet
when we make
a fresh start
I know you understand
It's not coming
I know
I'm sorry
It's not coming
"Everything he told
you was a lie"
"You thought
he'd Marry you?"
A person like you never
becomes a mother
Touch it
Can you feel
it move
Hey
It just kicked
You felt it, right?
You're bare as a tree in winter
You killed your own kid
You forced her out
to kill her, right?
How monstrous
Isn't your bareness
a just payback?
How old is the baby?
About 5 months?
A Girl? What's her name?
Kaoru
Cute name
Little Kaoru looks
like her Mom
The spitting image
You can have this
maybe a bit overcooked
It's delicious and organic
Ester!
Yes
Bye bye
House of Angel
Female shelter to set you
free from family problems
Women only
House of Angel
An ideal home in harmony
I don't need money
Stop seeing me in
secret from Mom
Please accept it
I'm fine, really
How about School?
It's Summer vacation
Are you eating enough?
How about you Dad?
You're eating properly?
Mom prepares meals
for you?
Well
Mom's in good health?
She finally got used
to you being away
Really
She's sad
you should call sometimes
You don't have to play
the father part on me
It does not suit you at all
Is that right
Maybe right
Yeah
See you
She says she's been taken
to a couple of
strangers place
So she ran away
Kaoru can you
tell me again?
Erina
Little Erina!
You give us so much worry
what a bad kid
You hate our home
that much?
Such a bad kid doesn't
belong to this family
Enough now
she is scared
Please Erina
Please, don't run
again, please
Etsuko, let's go home
Please don't go anywhere
Let's go home
Erina let's go back
Sorry for the trouble
OK, let's go home
"Write the truth
in your diary"
"No need to feel ashamed"
"I'm embarrassed
when people see me"
"The end"
You want me to
sing your song
Erina do you like songs?
Sing the song
of the Star
OK
Twinkle, twinkle
little star
No not this one
Not this one
It 's not this one
Well
The stars twinkle
in the sky
Not that one
You know
Ah right
So, what could I sing
Why do you do
that to me!?
Why is that?
Why? Why?
Why?
I'm sorry Mom
I'm sorry ...
Etsuko!
I'm sorry Mom
You're hurting me!
Stop
I'm sorry Mom ...
Stay calm!
I'm sorry
I'm sorry Mom
A Souvenir
What are you doing
at this hour?
I was an examiner in today's
Exam but they canceled
I came running
how stupid of me
Sorry it's not a good time
I missed you so much
How about you? Did you miss me?
The cake is wasted
You dropped it
Makes no difference
once it's swallowed
Tastes just the same
When you quit my classes
I thought you'd met someone
it's not that
I was trying to forget you
But I can't forget
I thought if I could
stay away for a month?
I'd forget you
Why do you say that?
I don't know, anymore
How does love feel?
How can we stop loving
someone we loved?
You don't need to stop
You and me
we are solid
Are you working
all summer vacation?
Yeah
Such a job
you have there
Living on my own I have
to see for everything
I would be a terrible mother
I thought you'd come
back as soon as I call
I was wrong
You are tough
you live your life
Flatter me
You're doing fine
Enough
Struggle on your own
You finally appreciate
your parents
Ah, I don't want
to return work
What if you
didn't return?
Don't say that
Really I don't
want to go back
I love you
What do love in me?
The smiles you
give only to me
and when we part
the rear side of you
How about you?
What do you love in me?
the lies you make
when you're exposed
Can't you find
something better
Thanks for your kindness
Her husband
threw her out
she has nowhere to go
She's asleep
a girl, right?
Let's do the
formalities tomorrow
Just the paperwork tonight
then you can rest
The application
Mrs. Bani
Yes
If you please
Good morning
Oh! It's shorter
A prospective
member has come
You are welcome
Make yourself
at home
This is the
"House of Angel"
When Humans do stupid things
Angel Always come to the rescue
as long as you are here
Angel will thoroughly
fulfill her mission
when a human does
a stupid thing
I have to come and help
Your child's so cute
And Who are you?
You do everything
that you're told, right?
You're a woman?
Yes
Why Do you think so?
Because I am not a man
What do you mean by that?
And what do you think
about yourself?
I'm nothing
How that?
Then, how do you consider
yourself a woman?
You had an abortion
I'm talking to
you from my soul
So please talk
from your soul too
You don't talk of worldly
things through your soul
If one is old or young
man or woman
If she has money or not
Isn't it futile chatter?
It's good to drop
one's obsessions
About being a
man or a woman
If you can let go
of it, you're happy
This is what it means
to live from the soul
You don't mean anything
Really?
Simply
I want to go live
with this child
To me
This child means
everything
Somehow
Please help me
I got it
Please help me!
In this place
people are reborn as
angels in this world
There are several rules
Sarai and the others
will tell you
Listen carefully
Yes
This way, please
In charge of farm work
Ms. Abel
Ms. Esther
Ms. Tobit
Ms. Bani
Ms. Ezekiel
That’s it
Why is that?
I thought I heard Kaoru cry
She’s fine, she’s looked after
The baby is the treasure
of House of Angel
She’s not here
There is so much
to do now:
Crawl, touch, walk
Soon you can
speak with Mom
I wish I gave
birth to a girl
Then he would have
left her when he went
You know
my boy was taken away
by my husband
Or rather by my
husband’s mother
I lost him in court
Without money I couldn’t
get parental authority
They wouldn't let
you meet him?
hmm
Angel takes away
the sadness
but I can’t
I just can’t
His name’s Hikaru
Although he's a boy
his name's Hikaru
It's a good name
That’s right
I gave it to him
This kid is Rebecca
And you're Ruth
Angel gave you a name
Ruth and Rebecca
As you received it
today from Angel
It’s become your birthday
From today you’re
official members
of House of Angel
your old birthday
and your old name
have both become
useless luggage
You can leave behind
you the pain
Let's help each
other live
Happy Birthday
doh-bee-dah
was-was-waaaa
Happy birthday to you
I'm sorry to bother you
Alright, alright
You called me because
you remembered something
Here
Ah thanks
You read it thoroughly
Yes
You always eat
on your own?
Why on your own?
It’s stress-free
Really
So maybe you have
things to say?
What do you remember?
What?
Shall we go?
uh?
Aah summer’s over
I didn’t go anywhere
again this year
Did you go somewhere?
I had to work
Sure
A person has to work
Excuse me
How do you eat?
Uh?
How do you organize
your life?
I live an easy life
my mother has
an apartment
she doesn’t say anything
even when I don't work
This is no thing
to be proud of
Well
I think I have
a child on the way
With whom could I discuss it?
Other than my parent
To your friends?
I don’t have anyone
Are you saying
you're pregnant?
I don't know yet ...
Your boyfriend is
that kind of stalker?
Mr. Kishida is
not a stalker
Oh ...
Did you tell him?
Not yet
Why?
Kishida has a wife
and a kid on his own
So you like him
I don't know whether
I like him or not
Are the cicadas gone?
When I told you Cicadas die
soon after coming out
You were not surprised
They live 7 days
it’s quite alright…
…if they all die
together the 7th day
it's not particularly sad
It's the same
for all of them
But suppose one
survived the 8th day
All her friends
have died
It is a sad situation
What?
Toilet
I just bought it
I'm checking it
What here? Now?
Now I'm drunk
Whatever the result
I won't be scared
You have to pee on this
If it doesn’t reach the
blue line, your fine
We'll think about it
Sure, take your time
Thanks
We haven't had lunch
in a long time
We need to talk
Before that, cheers!
Cheers
What would you do
if I was pregnant?
I’m saying "if"
But you're still
a student
It means we keep it?
or do I have
an abortion?
Of course I'd
like to keep it
But right in
this juncture
Practically
it's difficult
At some point
it will be OK?
Of course it will
I would like
to live with you
Once you graduate
Once my little one doesn't
need my help anymore
In the meantime
we'll be very prudent
I told you many times
Why are you laughing?
You look like my father
when you talk like that
Your Father?
What about him?
Nothing
Are you pregnant?
I told you
I said "if"
You're shocked?
Of course I am
Don't stress me
Alright let's eat
OK
How is it?
Yeah
Umm ... Mr. Kishida
What I couldn't
say until now
What now?
I wasn't raised
in a normal family
You celebrated birthdays
You would go to fireworks
Or to see blossoming sakura
you also had Christmas Parties
But I had none of
this in my family
All this is I did for
the first time with you
You taught me many things
There are so many
fun things you said
You taught me that
So where do you want
to go next time
We won't meet anymore
I really thought
I couldn't end it
But we won't
meet anymore
Thank you for everything
You said you loved
everything about me
Thank you
[WOMEN'S CLINIC]
Now it is
exactly this big
she said
What do you
mean by that?
They gave it to me
at the clinic
it's cute
Isn't it
Do you keep
the baby?
I keep it
Is that right
How do you plan
to raise it?
Did you tell
Mr. Kishida?
You didn't
You're an adult, you should
find the strength to tell him
It won't happen
He runs away
from the hassle
You fell in love
with a mean guy
You told me so
"It's not your fault"
you said
Did I say that?
You were one
of the few
to talk to me
like that
Only you and Kishida
I hated it
My mother was
yelling and crying
I thought everything
was my fault
I finally understood
I was not alone
not alone?
It's because my family
had been broken
My Father's mistress
was an abductor
She was wanted nationwide
He was working irregularly
drinking too much
My mother had enough of him
She was always out
not much at home
The meals were always side dishes
from the supermarket
I hated it
I got used to it
But when I was in
elementary school
There was a birthday
party for a kid
He showed family videos
when he was a baby
It's no big deal
I'll show you mine
There it was on this video
All the love and care
I hadn't received
What my parents said
was right
It's all Kiwako
Nonomiya's fault
If it wasn't for
Kiwako Nonomiya
Our home would
have been normal
Mom was kind
dad used to laugh
A usual home
as any other
That woman is
public enemy #1
She messed up
our family
I felt so bad I vomited
when I came back
OK, let's eat
OK
Thank you
Good appetite
Why are you
so kind to me?
You need material
for your article
I want to go some place
I need you to go there
What do you mean?
I have to go there
I can't do it on my own
With you I could make it
Isn't it what you think?
If I was that girl
I would just go
When things get better let's
make a trip to gather data
Gather data?
The place where you
lived with Kiwako, and all
Why?
There's no need to go
There's nothing
I want to see
The House of Angel
for example
You were called Rika
You were Rebecca
but they called you Rika
And Kiwako was
called Ruth
All characters
of the Bible
You were there
with Kiwako
We grew up
as sisters
You don't
remember me
"Maggie opened an
umbrella immediately"
"Ha, you won't
get wet like this"
"And you won't
get cold"
"Ahaha, funny, funny!"
"But as Maggie
drinks tea"
"It's raining heavily"
"Keeps falling heavily"
"Suddenly the whole
place became a sea"
What is a sea?
Rika, you've never
been to the sea
Have you ever been
there, Maron?
I have
"The waves are
rolling and rolling"
"...rolling and rolling"
"The water runs all over"
It's so big.
These guys are
brainwashed
They rip you off your
money, a scary gang
They're gonna fool you
House of Angel please
give me my family back
Give it back
I want to hear the
voice of my mother
They came again
They're coming in
Nobue
Come back!
Mommy! Mommy!
Maron!
Maron! Quick!
Kaoru! Kaoru! Kaoru!
All right, all right
Don't cry Kaoru
Hold me tight
When you come
visit please call
You surprised me
Yeah I'm sorry
Are you going to eat?
I don't need to
How about School?
You go regularly?
Yeah ...
I'd like to quit
I'm pregnant
Into the 4th
months now
So I came to
borrow money
I swear I'll pay
you back when I work
The father
He looks like dad
There is a family but
he won't be a father
Please have an abortion
I'll pay for it
Please have an abortion!
I'll take you
now to a clinic
Please terminate
such kid's pregnancy
No way!
Calm down
listen to her
You're not going to raise it
there's not even a father
That much I know
So
Mom
What did you say
to that woman?
"I can't believe she's
having an abortion"
"You're bare as
a tree in winter"
You told her, right?
It's a lie
It's all because
that woman is paranoid
Me
I'll keep it
So I won't have
abduct someone's kid
I'll raise her alone
Why is it you
can't forget?
It's been 20 years now
Just forget
You know how important
you are to me
How can I express
how much you mean?
Why would you believe
what she said?
You don't listen to a word
I say, but you trust her
Mom
You don't even consider
me as your mother
You want to hurt me, right?
Not at all
You think, if I
hadn't been there
it would all have
been much simpler
The person who took you
away from your life
You believe it's me
right?
You're wrong
What am I wrong about?
You always saw
me like that
Etsuko!
I wanted to be a
perfectly normal mother!
To offer you a
normal childhood
When I see a girl
Smile to her mother
I'm so envious
I could scream
Mom
I'm sorry
But you know
I don't want to
"become bare like
a tree in winter"
Why didn't I take you
in the car that day
Why did I leave you
back home that day
What should I do?
I want you to love me?
Mom
I often played house
with you here
I Don't remember
sure
You we're only three
Tell me
What was it
here exactly?
Well, a kind of
women's shelter
The staff at House of Angel
knew Kiwako was the abductor
and they hid her
Ah really?
The person Angel wanted
was not Kiwako
but you I think
Me?
Why?
They wanted a
purely bred angel
An angel untouched by the world
untouched by men
When the Asahara cult gassed
Tokyo subway in 1995
The press decided we were
a cult too and attacked us
10 years ago Mother Angel
died, it all petered out
Finally an executive
took the money and fled
So it was over
Looking at this wall
even today I'm stressed
and nauseous
In this place
They wanted to
lead an inquiry
Who wanted that?
The press?
The police?
Let them investigate
what they wish
We didn't do
anything wrong
It's not like we're
kidnapping people
Not to worry
There they speak the
language of the world
They are not speaking
with their soul
Whatever they ask you
never answer them
Al-right?
Yes
As usual today
Each one to her chore
Please start
your own meeting
Mother Angel! Please ...
when the families
came to protest
Why didn't you
deliver the person
That
Those who came here seeking
refuge can't be expelled
People come to live here
away from their circumstances
Do you understand? Ruth
For Ruth and Rebecca
I pray for angels to visit us
Mama, mama,
where are you going?
Mama, where
are you going?
Mama, mama!
Kaoru please
keep silent
I want to play
with Maron
I know, I know
I want to play
with Maron
Kaoru it's OK?
I want to play
with Maron
Go down to there ...
There
Mom, I want to
play with Maron
Enough now!
It's OK Kaoru
We're not coming
back here
Ruth!
Take this
Rika, I ...
Do not let
go of Kaoru
Stay with her
until she is big
From now on
forever
Go
Kaoru
Come on ...
Here, let's go
It's so tight
Kaoru
Mom it's dark
Look Kaoru
The starry sky
Stars?
Those twinkling
dots are stars
You saw them in
a picture book
Hey Mom
It's Scary
There's nothing
to be afraid of
With me you're safe
Come
Mom
What sweetie?
Sing your song
... for me
Which song?
Alright
Then
I sing the song
of the Star
"Look up at the sky"
"The stars at night"
"There's a small star"
"A small light"
"A modest happiness"
"singing"
"Look up at the sky"
"The stars at night"
"just like us"
"A Star with no name"
It's so high above?
Stars are so beautiful
It's the first time
I stop in such hotel
Really?
I used love hotels but
They are different
A love Hotel is
more cozy
Usually it's the contrary
Say
Has Kiwako Nonomiya
finished her jailtime yet?
Yeah
The lawyer received
a postcard from her
Posted from Tokyo
But she's probably
not living there
She doesn't have much
good memories in Tokyo
So where then?
You know where
she lives?!
You want me to
meet that woman
It's not my intention
I don't know her
whereabouts or anything
Why?
You're really
Going back?!
I really don't know
Stop, there are
no more trains
You find all
this entertaining
You'll write it all
An abducted child, commits
adultery, makes a child
She's doing the same
as the criminal
I don't find it
entertaining
It's not because
I am pregnant
that I'm the
same as her
You just think
I'm stubborn
I don't think so
I talked about
it with you
I really needed to hear
someone's opinion
about it all
I told you everything
Why do you think
I want to become a mother?
I can't figure
myself as a mother
I can't even
raise a child
I have no idea
How to cherish
her or scold her
How to get close
to her, to know her
I won't become a mother
I won't write
if you like
anything
If you're worried
let's raise her together
As for me
I'm afraid of men
Their thick shoulders and arms
their Adam's apple
even now they
frighten me
I've never dated a man
I have no experience
with a man
I can't understand
your feeling
I can't become
someone's wife
I think I'll
always be alone
sometimes my mind
withdraws far away
What I always wonder is
Why wasn't I raised
in a normal world?
But you know
Maybe I could be
a good mother
together with you
You and me together
can make a good mother
You think it
wouldn't work
May I touch
your belly?
I hear something
Its heart beating
I can't say if it's
Yours or the babies
You girls came
from Tokyo?
You mean Shodoshima
in Okayama?
Yeah, I went
sightseeing
Did you visit
the Okayama area?
You have to
visit that park
Walk in Kurashiki
look at Korakuen
eat Rose sushi
Tokyo people should know
what rose sushi is
I don't know what
rose sushi is
What? You don't?
Well rose sushi is
... rose sushi
Welcome
Please, thank you
very much
We take it?
Wait for the next?
Kagawa Prefecture
Shouzugun Fukuda 4028
If you visit there
tell them I'm fine
Kumi Sawada
What's going on?
So much water it's scary
No need to fear
Kaoru
Look
Look how beautiful
the sparkling
Seto Sea is so calm
Sparkling and beautiful
Excuse me
Is this Kumi
Sawada's family?
Who are you?
I'm sorry to come
unexpectedly
It's Kumi she asked me...
to tell you she's fine
Kumi did?
Where does she live?
Her company has
gone bankrupt...
We lived in the
same dormitory
Everyone is gone
I see
So you came here
to deliver the message?
I wanted to come
and see once
Kumi was often talking
about the island
She was talking
about our place?
If you don't mind
could I work here?
What?
The company just
went bankrupt
we don't know
what to do next
and I saw the poster
over there
This has been
there for 2 years
Now I can't hire
any staff
Is that so?
If I could help
it's OK
I'm sorry
Let's go
Just a minute
You …
You have nowhere to go
How long are you staying
on this island?
Two, three days ...
Alright, today
father's not here
Before you go back
You can stay one
night at our place
Oh
Dad is worried
about Kumi
Because of her divorce
the quarrelling at her home
That's what we know
Would you tell us about it?
You are so cute
what's your name?
Kaoru
And how old are you?
Oh!
The same as
Kumi's daughter
We are there
So beautiful
Come Kaoru
This is the Sea too?
There are many here
This is a town
All kinds of people
live there
It's immense
Yeah
It's big
Kaoru
Let's go sightseeing
We haven't yet
discovered anything
Let's go see places
You're going to see
many things with Mom
All the beautiful things
The sea?
Yeah, sea, sky, stars, flowers
Let's see spring and
autumn and winter
Mom's gonna work
to earn money
and buy things
a beautiful book
let's buy chocolate
Chocolate!
I'll buy you anything
I'll show you
anything you want
I introduce to you
our new worker
Kyoko Miyata
She's far away
from home
She's a distant
relative
I'm Kyoko Miyata
Pleased to meet you
OK, let's start
Have a nice work
Aaaaah!
Let's play
Come here
Where are you from?
"Where are you from?"
She said
Come over here
Let's play together
Come on
Let's play
Let's swing
together
Little Kyoko
Come here
How was work?
I'm doing my best
Quick to the park
let's play
What is your name?
Shin Noriyuki
Yuri
Sakura
Let's swing
together
Kyoko look
It's men's things but
you can wear them
In fact it was for Kumi
I wanted you
to wear it
I'll give it
to Kaoru
It's too much
It's alright
I'm happy to
offer it to her
Grandpa bought
it for her
Kaoru you can
wear it
It's as if my granddaughter
was back, I'm so happy
Look
Thank you
OK, let's get on
There you are
There
Here we go
All aboard!
Hi there
Hello
Kaoru, I feel good
It feels good, Mom
What did you
pray for, Mom?
To stay together
with you
Tomorrow and the day
after and the day after
Let us be always together
To be with you always
On this island, there
are so many gods
Let's visit them all
and pray to each one
Yeah
One, two
Three, four, five
Everyone makes
mistakes at first
I'm sorry!
It takes time
to learn
Let's do this
without rush
Yes
Thanks for the
good meal
Mommy?
Mr. Sawada
is a girl?
A "Mr." is a
man of course
but Kaoru is a boy?
Kaoru is a girl
She's a Cute girl
But ...
Really
You saw men only
in picture books
Yeah
Where we lived
there was only women
The fact is, man is one half
and woman the other half
Isn't it right?
When you grow
up a little
You'll want to
marry a person
He will be a man
Mom, you're a man?
I'm a woman
But I want
to marry you
so you won't have to
work so hard anymore
Is that what
Mr. Sawada said?
You hurt me
Kaoru
One day you'll fall in
love with a gentle boy
You'll follow him
to his home
I'm not going
anywhere
I'll stay with
you always
In fact
I thought of getting
an abortion
I went to the clinic
to get an appointment
Then I saw her figure
on the scan
I was suddenly
hit by the light
I saw the whole
landscape
The landscape?
Flowers, trees,
sky, sea and light
I saw all these
beautiful things
So I thought
I had a duty to show them
to that baby in me
all these beautiful things
things I saw and
others I will see
All the beautiful things
You know
Yeah?
We spoke about
the cicadas
They die after 7 days
That cicada surviving
the 8th day is sad
hmm
I thought so too but
maybe it's not so
the 8th day cicada
saw something
that no other
cicada saw
It could be
something
very beautiful
Yeah
Maybe so
Mama, on top
of that shrine
There is a ghost
Uh, what ghost?
A princess wearing
a beautiful kimono
But she's smaller
than me
She hasn't seen
anyone for years
she finally
disappeared
Why?
Last year she fell in love
with a handsome student
visiting the shrine
she didn't go
with him?
Oh, it started
Yes, cheese
Alright
Hold your bag's straps
Turn your back
Yes, look this way
Give me a smile
cheeeese
Alright
This time, everyone
side by side
Leave it here
Kyoko too, come
into the photo
Me? It's OK?
Of course, no
need to be shy
No, no, Really
If you're sure
This is for memories
We'll have one
in a photo studio
We'll take one
in studio too?
Kaoru not yet
Go to school, you'll
get a school bag
Let's go to
the photo studio
Hey, gimme a
smile everyone
Kaoru what's going on?
Smile, smile
Yes cheese
Mr. can we
play now?
Alright
Let's go
play soccer
You want to
come along?
Al-right
Kaoru come
play soccer
Oh?
She's a typical child
of the Island
Yes
Kumi just called
I told her about you
and Kaoru she was happy
She said she comes
back to the island
Kumi said that?
Yeah
If Kumi is back
I owe it to you
I didn't do anything
What do you say?
I didn't think
I'd meet her again
Instead of my granddaughter
Kaoru visits me
Thank you
It's nothing
I owe it to you
and Kaoru
A lot happened to you too
that you don't talk about
No I …
I just enjoy being
with Kaoru
You know Kyoko
Let me buy Kaoru's
school bag
Thank you
hmm
Someone knows
what this is?
OK, What is it?
Yes, teacher!
Yes, Kaoru Miyata
first year
An elephant!
It's correct!
Look, Mom
Little Shin
Kaoru come
Hello
"Body is nothing
more than emptiness"
[Heart Sutra]
OK, you lit it
I'm scared
You're not scared
To keep the bugs
away from the rice
we pray
Let's do it
You're with Mommy
nothing to fear
Lit it
Lit it on, lit it on!
Hold it tight
Look Mom
It's so beautiful
So beautiful
What's going on?
I have been here ...
Excuse me
Kaoru, come eat
Kaoru let's swing!
Shin, the cicadas
Kaoru be careful
when you play
Kaoru come
Kaoru
Mom
Uh?
You're tickling
You tickle me too
Kaoru!
Look at the sky
Kaoru
It's so good
Kaoru ...
Ah Kyoko!
Come here
a minute
a while
Check this
it's incredible
Such a beautiful
work
It's really
a prize
It's the national
contest
This is incredible
It's so beautiful
The faces are
beautiful
Yeah
We should pin it
where everyone can see
We need to show
it to everyone
Please stop this
Kaoru
Let's move home?
Where to? Near
Sakura's place?
Let's get out
of the Island
No way, I
like it here
You'll be with me
you'll be fine
No way, I am
not going anywhere
Kaoru ...
No way, I am
not going anywhere
Excuse me
I'd like to have
our picture taken
A family photo
Come inside
Now we're ready
Chin up
Kaoru
Come
Where are
you going?
You take a
boat with Mommy
We take a boat and then
... we go to the zoo
Do they have
giraffes?
They do
And also hippopotamuses
and elephants?
Hippopotamuses and
elephants, all there
We are moving
home now?
Yeah
Once we're back
from the zoo?
Can I play again
with Shin and Sakura?
Let's play a lot
Come
Kaoru ...
I can't keep
up anymore
Are you Okay?
Alright
Let's buy something
to drink
I'm sorry ...
Why? It's OK
Please
Here too
Mom ...
It's 630 yen
Here
perfect
Thank you
for coming
Let's go
Kaoru
We must get on
the boat in turn
Why?
Mom will follow
you later
Please
Let's go
together.
Yes
Come
Go
You're Erina
Akiyama
I'll take you
back home
Infant protection here
to protect little Erina
Mommy! Mom!
You're Kiwako
Nonomiya, right?
Suspected for the abduction
of Erina Akiyama
arrested at 19:10
Let's go
Mommy!
I'm taking you back
to Mom's place
All right, all right
Please wait!
This child!
Hasn't eaten yet
Thank you
Shall we go?
Mommy! Mommy! Mommy!
where are you going?
It's OK
Mommy! Mommy!
Wait, what happened?
Wait
Excuse me
Here, a long time ago
You took a picture
Show me your face?
Kyoko Miyata & Kaoru
As for the photo
Kiwako Nonomiya
took it
She came here?
About 5 years ago
SHe asked if I had
pictures of that time?
That person ...
Kiwako Nonomiya
told you something?
No, Nothing
She didn't say anything
She just took the photo
Come
Kaoru
Thank you
Mommy was happy with you
Yes, raise your hands
Yes
What sweetie?
I don't need anything else
With you by my side
I have everything I need
I love you
Kaoru
Chin up!
Erina
Erina!
You're ok?
I had no grudge
I didn't have any grudge
For mommy also
For daddy also
For you also
I wanted to return
to this island
The truth is
I wanted to return
I though it
was forbidden
It's fine
When this child is
born we'll come here
I ...
I will work
Yeah
If I work I can afford to
show her many things
Yeah
buy her beautiful clothes
and delicious foods
I'll take away
all her worries
Yeah
I'll tell her
it's all fine
That she's my
favorite in the world
I'll tell her often
Every problem
can be solved
When she's born
We'll show her to
your Mom and dad
We'll let
them hug her
Will they love her?
She'll be so cute
they'll love her
I don't know why...
I already love
this child
I haven't seen
her face yet
Why is that?
song by Mika Nakajima: "Dear"