This way!
- There!
- Where?
Next to the further beech tree!
Get Down.
THE RED BARON
Are you out of your bloody mind?
Yes, sir.
You risk the squadron planes to
attend an enemy funeral?
Yes, sir!
Lehmann and Sternberg knew him, sir,
Captain Winston Clyde Walker.
The chap in the coffin I meant, sir.
Yes! I mean, sir...
My uncle, the Duke of Westchester
is his mother's brother-in-law.
Lehmann and I, we went to school
with him. Eton, sir.
You're talking about a British pilot,
for heaven sake.
One of the best in the
Royal Flying Corp.
It's a pity that he's not with
us anymore, sir.
Oh, what the hell!
Dismissed!
I've heard you got yourself
some holes,
while paying your condolences,
Richthofen.
Ah, I love these small gossipy
airfields, Kielmeyer.
- Anyone wants a cigarette?
- French?
- De rien.
- Merci.
Richthofen brought down a two-seater.
I supposed that's to make up for
ignoring my orders.
No...
Just adding to my score.
I have just got a report,
a British RE8
crashed 12 km from here.
My utmost respect, Baron.
Let's go find your plane, let's get
your kill confirm, you bastards.
Help me, come on... Help me!
Careful... Alright.
One,
two, three...
I said careful...
Hurry up... He's bloody heavy.
He's losing a lot of blood.
Take these off.
You'll be alright, you'll be alright!
You can take him.
Pick him up!
Thank you!
You saved this man life.
No.
I shot him down.
You're down, Sternberg.
Oh no. You attacked single seater
DH2 from above towards the...
Listen Sterni, if the attacker
has a rotary engine then....
What is a rotary engine?
Oh Lieutenant Sternberg...
Oh... Hello!
Hey...
Well obviously she prefers
men like me, Voss!
Men like who?
- Moses, Freud...
- Better get
ourselves circumcised, Voss.
Good evening!
- Bonjour lieutenant.
- Hello, Monique.
Hey, not so fast.
Hey Manfred... Look,
she looks like your little nurse...
...at least from behind.
My little... Voss.
Oh la la!
I'm sorry, sir.
What are you doing here?
Have a seat, have a drink on us.
I thought you chaps just
wanted to have some cocktails.
Sit down and have a drink with us.
Here!
I'm married you know...
So am I!
I mean, almost... at least.
...We need a bucket of water.
The driver says the engine
is overheated.
- Lieutenant.
- The name is von Richthofen.
Pleased to meet you again,
Mademoiselle.
- I know your name.
- Well?
The pilot you shot down told
me who you were.
Did he survived?
Do you really care or are
you just curious?
The latter.
At least you are honest.
It's a start, isn't it?
Can you be caring without
being curious in the first place?
So... What's your name?
His name is Captain Roy Brown.
And he's alive, no thanks to you.
He told me you're
a supreme professional
Well done!
and a tricky rascal.
Well...
Look...
Tell him that I'm honor
by his compliments
and hope I never have to meet
him in the skies again.
He might get the better of me.
And I might not be lucky
enough to have
such a gorgeous attendant.
Unbelievable. Enjoy your evening.
Do you happen to know what
became of my scarf?
I'll have it send to you.
No... Keep it.
It will bring you luck!
The French have sent
their condolences
and claimed the kill.
The service for Kielmeyer will be
held at 1600 hours.
The pilot who lead the attack
against us 4 days ago,
it was Hawker.
What?
Major Lanoe Hawker?
The very man.
I saw his face... Full beard.
And the Grim Reaper painted
on his fuselage.
It's their top man.
Oh shut up... Scary fellow.
He downs 9 of us.
When they used to fly the
unarmed reconnaissance, he latched
a one shot hunting rifle
to his fuselage.
We almost touched wings.
Had a hard times to stay
out of his ways.
When you got that close,
why didn't you attack?
I only attack if I can win.
How badly do you want the
Pour le Merite?
I would kill for it.
I just received a cable from
Supreme headquarters,
...and guess what?
They badly wants to give it to you.
Why don't they then?
You know the rules.
And not even Imperial command
would bend them for you,
so hurry up and shoot down
a captured balloon.
I hunt aeroplanes, sir!
Not objects that cannot move.
You are not a hunter lieutenant,
you are a soldier
and you will follow orders
especially when it comes straight
from General von Hoeppler.
What if I shoot down Hawker?
Stay away from Hawker.
You are no match for him.
Let me through.
Has anybody got a spanner?
I don't believe it.
So you finally did it!
You bagged yourself a legend.
That made you a legend too!
Have one, my mother made them.
Oswald Boelcke... First of the Aces.
They are desperate to find someone
to fill the gap he left.
You know what he once said
to me when I asked
how he managed his business.
"Well, it's quite simple...
...I fly close to my man...
...aim well...
...and then of course he falls down."
Sterni and I are off to Arras,
why don't you join us for a drink?
Not tonight!
You could look for the little nurse.
I mean the sooner you have her,
the sooner you get her out
of your system.
Can't have ties that involved,
can we?
Werner?
Hmm?
I will filled the gap!
I will be the first of the Aces.
Stop!
There you go.
I'm starving.
Yeah, me too.
Prussians don't whine, gentlemen.
Let's go.
Go and find us some breakfast.
At ease, gentlemen.
L'ordre Pour Le Merite...
Where is it...
Prussia's highest bravery award.
A year ago Boelcke was the first
pilot to ever received it.
A lot has changed since...
...right, Baron?
Indeed... sir!
He only had to down 8 to get it.
I shot down twice as many.
An exception for you has
already been made, Richthofen.
You... Still owe us that balloon,
don't you?
However having shot down
the enemy's best
"the notorious Captain Hawker"
you are now Germany's premier
air ace.
You'll take over command of
11th Fighter wing.
- Come!
- Excellent, sir.
Have a look at this.
Here in the east,
the Tsar's armies are the least of
our problems, gentlemen.
He'll soon have a revolution
on his hands.
Amusing, isn't it?
Lenin and his communists helping
the German emperor...
The Western front is where
the danger lies.
The British 1st and 3rd armies
are probing our lines
with everything they've got.
And they have got plenty.
I must drive them back,
inch by inch and day by day,
without Lenin's help.
Richthofen, you'll be station
at LaBrayelles,
Northwest of Douai... Here!
Right in the middle.
Sir?
Yes?
Isn't the middle supposed to be
closer to Paris by now, general?
I mean, didn't you said that
we'll be there in 10 days...
...2 months ago?
Manfred!
High command has given you a
tremendous responsibility,
young man...
going far beyond this medal.
You're promoted to lead not
only the men
of our futures placed under
your command,
you've been chosen as a leader
of all fighting men.
Symbol of courage, bravery
and overtness, determination.
A symbol of Germany's superiority.
Pilots are like Gods, Richthofen.
When we lost Boelcke,
our troops lost a hero.
And if our enemy can killed God,
what chance...
Does the poor farmers dug deep
into the trenches thinks he has, hmm?
Gods don't die.
Do you understand it?
Yes, sir.
Fine!
You're dismissed, gentlemen.
Sir!
Yes?
Asked!
Any chance of some croissants
and coffee?
Here you are!
Good morning mother.
I take it you've a comfortable trip.
When you're finally rid yourself
of this worn out jacket, Manfred?
- Where is it?
- Cousin... Brother!
You bastard!
May I see it?
It's in there!
Here he is, my famous brother.
And he is still wearing
this old jacket of his.
I've already told him...
Stop making a fuss about my jacket!
Give me a hug.
- I still think that the jacket...
- Mom!
Good to have you home, son.
- Slow down... Low torque.
- I know!
Keep your rudder straight.
- Stop now. Let me...
- Close up...
I said straight... I said straight!
- You're not going straight.
- I can't concentrate.
Everybody comes to honor our son,
and all they do is played
with that plane.
...like little boys.
As if my brothers would ever grow up.
- Handsome little boys.
- Watch out!
I'm taking a left now.
Slow down!
Let them enjoy their youth,
whilst they can.
Watch out!
Watch the hay stack!
You said you could fly a plane.
I can't!
Wait till I'm sitting in
a real plane.
I'll beat your score.
Hey!
Let go of me!
Keep the sun on your back.
Don't fire too soon.
It just warn your opponents,
it has no other effects.
The best range for shooting
is 50 meters, not more.
But remember,
our tasks is to bring
down aeroplanes, not men.
So stop firing when your
opponent's falling.
Gentlemen, we are sportsmen...
not butchers.
- Merci.
- De rien.
Gentlemen!
I'd like you to meet my
chief mechanic...
Sergeant Reuber.
Dismissed!
Sir!
Stop clicking your heels, Wentzke.
Yes, sir!
- Hello!
- Oh, I almost forgot...
if each of you hasn't shot down
at least one in the next 4 weeks,
you're fired.
Lieutenant!
This is a hospital,
who do you think you are?
I'm sorry.
You knew him well?
I still don't know your name...
Kate Otersdorf.
Un nom allemand, a german name?
My father was German,
my mother is Belgian.
I see.
I love these french cigarettes.
You are...
...a very beautiful woman.
I was hoping to see you again.
And I thought maybe wearing my scarf.
I will get it for you.
I couldn't get all the stains out.
Mademoiselle!
Have I done something wrong?
Am I not worth an answer
or is it just you hate all men?
Hate?
I don't hate you.
Hate is men's domain.
But you are angry, aren't you?
There is another man's blood on it.
And you do not seems to care.
Men like you scared me because
I do not understand why
you do what you do.
And being scared makes me angry.
And now please, leave me alone.
Wait, Wait!
Imagined you were out there...
Like a hawk.
Looking down...
The wind blows around you.
The smell of the engine,
draft from the propeller.
Out there you can just not fall,
you can climb, turn, spin...
Freedom!
That's what men always dreamt of.
I've dreamt of it since
I was a little boy.
But the best part,
is the chase!
The fights...
The hunt!
It's like a match.
A joust, just like sports.
Tennis does not kill you.
It's childish dreams that
got your friends killed.
No, I don't hate you, Baron.
I pity you.
Gentlemen, please!
It shouldn't be that hard...
to paint a plane, should it?
Just do it!
Reuber!
Manfred...
What's wrong with you?
What is this crazy paint
job all about?
Honestly, you know damn well OCA
will crucify you for this!
I don't care about what the 'Officers
in Charge of Aviation' think of this
and you better not question
my orders.
I just think you're making a mistake.
They will spot you from
a long way off.
We completely lose the
advantage of surprise.
I don't want them to be surprise.
I want them to be scared.
Lieutenant Kurt Wolff reporting
for duty, sir.
Planning to take a nap up
there, lieutenant?
Never fly without it, sir!
You know, for luck!
Superstitious huh!
Like me...
My mother keeps ordering new coats
from our tailor,
I've never pick them up.
See you around.
Sir!
The general!
General von Hoeppner!
Over here, sir!
You've become quite
a celebrity, Baron.
You are making headlines.
The emperor himself mentioned
your name
after hearing about your
29th victory.
So...
I brought a little surprise
for you...
Didn't they runs out of medals
to give me?
Well, it isn't exactly a medal.
Sir...
It wasn't my idea.
We just thought it would
be good propaganda.
"The Richthofen Brothers
flying together."
Welcome.
Your brother is a nice chap.
He really has the spirit our
Fatherland needs right now.
So tell me...
They comes out with this
strange names for you...
"Le Diable Rouge"
or "The Red Baron"
Why is that?
I see.
So much about army rules
and regulations.
Interesting!
Very interesting!
Tried to keep the sun on your back...
Watch out for the winds.
And never forget,
a pilot greatest virtue is to know
when to run.
What... What this a joke?
Just do what he tells you
to do, Lothar.
Run away from a fight?
Yes!
- If you cannot win, you fly away!
- Fast!
It's a thin line between cowardice
and cleverness.
It's true.
Alright!
Morning, gentlemen.
That's a great idea.
I already heard rumours that
the French thinks
this paint is bulletproof.
I wouldn't take this with me.
It could get on the way up there.
This looks much better.
The crop stays here.
- Scattered them up, didn't we?
- Yeah, it was getting busy up there.
Damn French knows how to
protect their observation balloons.
I'm alright.
It was fun, wasn't it?
Can I stay at your cottage tonight?
- Already feeling lonely?
- Yeah.
Did you have him transfer?
Who?
Your brother, Lothar.
Where is he? Did you see him?
He was right behind me.
You better keep an eye on
your little brother.
He has a hell of
a dangerous attitude.
Oh for God sake.
Let the poor fellow land.
What is he doing?
God... for Christ sake, Lothar!
You shot this poor bastard to pieces.
You think this makes our
father proud?
He lost his hearing saving
a wounded enemy.
So now you want to win a war
without killing anyone, huh?
I've watched you and Voss, and
I don't like what I see.
You are all...
you are all brilliant pilots,
but you've got the wrong attitude.
This business of painting
a war plane red...
Stop dreaming!
This is just not a polo game.
We are not boys anymore,
we're grown men
fighting a bloody war.
I'm quite aware of that.
I'm quite aware of that!
But still,
we can fight it with grace.
What?
You were listening?
The Marseilles heard you in Paris.
- ...and Berlin.
- Come on, he is just ambitious.
Well, have him contained then.
I for one, I don't want to get kill
because of his ambitions.
And I hate to see you
get kill either.
Morning my dear Hindenburg,
and my dear friend von Hoeppner.
Welcome to Berlin, gentlemen.
The young man already seems to be
more famous than...
...What was his name?
- Oswald Boelcke, your Majesty.
- Yes... Yes!
We need men like him.
I supposed...
We'll have to give you
another promotion, Richthofen.
You are a real hero.
I take it the ladies're all over you.
There aren't many ladies
at 10,000 feet, your Majesty.
Corp, attention!
Well, are you ready, gentlemen?
Move on!
Don't fall asleep.
Move on.
Captain!
What shall we do, sir?
I could run them over.
Put the pistol away.
What did he say?
He wants my Captain's autograph.
Merci!
Ready!
Go!
- Ready!
- Go!
How did you know?
I saw you lose it.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Bodenschatz! Welcome!
My new adjutant.
Kurt Wolff!
- Welcome!
- I've heard a lot about you.
Thanks.
Orders, Sternberg, orders.
My new commanding officer is the man
I commanded not so long ago.
So...
I've heard you chaps ran into some
massive Allied aerial activities?
More than massive.
Germany produces 10 planes,
they've got hunderds unloaded
in the French coast.
Let them come.
We'll shoot them out of the
skies by the hundreds.
Meet brother Lothar...
No! Damn!
You bastards! You fucking bastard!
Damn gophers!
You know it's pure luck I didn't ran
into one of those damn holes myself.
Thank you for being so tactful.
After embarrassing me by landing
safely with shredded fins.
I've come to have a look.
Sopwith, right? New, isn't it?
It was...
Captain Brown,
Royal Academy Flying Corp.
Notorious Red Baron, I presume?
Didn't I shoot you down a year ago?
Indeed you did.
Why're you still flying around then?
Well, your prison camps
are quite fancy,
however they don't have airfields.
Thanks for pulling me out
of that wreck,
for saving my life.
Pulling you from that wreck
didn't save your live.
True.
Without her help I probably wouldn't
have make it back into a plane.
She's sure is a great girl.
She nursed me for weeks.
Did you ever get back your scarf?
What now?
I guess we could try killing each
other with our pistols.
Killing you would make me famous too.
Sorry, I didn't bring mine
but you might want to button up
your holster before you lose yours.
How long have you been
station in Europe?
Ever since Mother England called
the kids for help.
Meaning us,
the Commonwealth colonies.
You're right. The entire war seems
to be a family affair.
Family ties is what you aristocrats
are all about.
Russian Tsar, the Royal familes
in Britain,
France, Austria, Germany...
Everyone is someone's nephew,
uncle, brother.
Man, your love life sure knows
them all borders.
But to protect those borders,
we killed each other off anyway.
And we always managed to find good
enough reasons, don't we?
You didn't unsnapped that holster's
guard because you were
afraid of me, did you?
You have damn good eyes.
You thought about killing me?
Isn't killing each other the reason
why we are here?
Yes!
Be seeing you.
Don't get me wrong but I hope not.
Yes!
So long then.
Good luck.
Fucking family...
Sooner or later this war
will be over.
You should hook up with that nurse.
I think she's got the hot for you.
What makes you say that?
She kept bitching about
you for weeks.
Stop the truck!
There you are, we just found him.
Sterni!
Get a doctor here.
He doesn't need a doctor,
he needs a priest.
A rabbi.
Oh really?
He's dead, Manfred.
I'm catching up, brother.
It's days now since we buried him.
Why is it you can't enjoy
the fact that
I've been promoted. I'm your brother.
He was a friend of yours, I know.
But he was a fighter pilot too.
He knew the risks he took.
Every oath soldiers proudly take,
but you are more than a soldier,
you are a superior officer!
You have a responsibility
towards the men out there!
Towards your country and your people.
You know what our father
always said...
"A leader cannot afford to mourn."
You smell nice.
Much better than all the flowers.
You're still a little boy playing
silly games.
You haven't changed.
I'm not so sure about that.
A while ago, I wouldn't have let
myself got shot down.
Turn over.
So much for "Germany's bravest."
I'm sick of men keeps bringing
this report of
our lack of success every damn day.
I'm just trying to fill
your seat, sir.
You send out single squadron,
Doering.
They're in no position to
battle successfully
against enemy formations.
Captain Doering has his orders.
The 'Officer in Charge of Avaition'
arranges us on a time table, sir.
They are a bunch of idiots.
Condemning us to routine
burial flights.
We needs to be flexible.
Loose!
Hit the enemy where he actually is.
The British and French moved
their airbase
wherever and whenever they like.
Yes!
We hardly ever down their
damn planes.
I order you, to ignore OCA orders.
Mademoiselle Otersdorf,
what are you doing?
Just following orders, Baron.
You were ordered to come with us?
Yes.
Richthofen, nice to have you
back, sir!
Welcome back.
The red ones are the 11th wing.
The yellow 10th.
The Zebras... No: 6.
And the black ones No: 4.
You're looking at the most successful
fighter squadron of the war.
And these men are the best pilots
in the skies.
I thought it would never happen.
What?
See you smile.
I thought you're not supposed to fly.
Your nurse is a very good
looking girl.
I've got a hole in my head
but I'm not blind.
I am already fit enough to
punch you in the face.
What are you writing?
A book.
About flying.
What are you reading?
I never see you without a book.
No?
Oscar Wilde!
You ever read one?
No...
I cannot see any
British literature in here.
Hmm!
Try this!
There must be
Shakespeare in there somewhere...
My father read his play's once.
'Lear...'
'Comedy of Errors.'
You might find a couple
of songs too...
and a lot of playing billards,
hunting, flying, riding...
ahem... How to flirt.
A hole in the head makes reading
someone mind
pretty easy, Baron.
So...
Just ask.
Would you...
Would you join me for dinner?
Yes.
So?
Difference...
from what I thought you would be.
Different?
Your write,
it's entertaining.
You thought it would be blunt,
boring...
and deadly serious.
No!
But you write about war.
I thought there would fanaticism...
Patriotism.
Patriotism... hmm.
"...the virtue of the vicious."
You did read Wilde.
Even a little Dante.
It's helpful right now.
To knows a little about infernos,
isn't it?
Dance with me.
No.
Better not... no.
I am an infernally miserable dancer.
Imagined you're flying...
Great!
To have a hole in my head.
Without it I wouldn't be sitting
here next to you, would I?
Mentzke...
Can you turn the car around?
There are so many hospitals
now they have
to give them numbers.
This is No: 76.
There's 500 patients.
Most of these men will die.
Those that don't,
will never walk again,
see again,
taste again...
love again!
No, it's not great to have
a hole your head.
You're lucky to be still alive.
Being born of nobility, you've
advantages these men here do not.
They don't have choices.
It's not a game.
This is the lowest we'll ever get.
It never gets darker.
Come in.
Can you give me something
for my head?
Go to the cellar.
Now!
They fly at night?
Get yourself a gas mask.
Do you fly at night?
No, we don't!
Here.
Find a save place.
Lights out!
Everybody turns off the lights.
Give it to me.
It's OCA, sir.
This is Bodenschatz.
Turn off all the lights!
Night bombers!
Good morning captain!
Four already passed
and four more coming.
Just take it all,
it could be worse, sir.
It's not as if they just happened
to fly past, Doering.
They know about this field and
there will be more than eight.
Lots more!
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Morning, sir!
Wolff, you alright?
I can't find my cap!
All machine-gun posts are
being manned.
There's nothing more we can do
to protect the planes on the ground.
Mentzke, get my gear!
Ready my plane.
You are injured,
you cannot fly, Manfred.
I'm not going to be a sitting duck.
I've got wings.
You flew right in between them,
are you out of your mind?
Take me to her...
You've to lay still.
Go and find her.
I just need to know if
she's not hurt.
It looks plainer.
Fokker built this great new plane,
as maneuverable as the devil.
They climb like monkeys.
I know you are angry with me.
I've been ordered back
to the hospital.
I know.
I'm sorry about Kurt Wolff.
He was a charming young man.
He forgot his night cap, you know.
His lucky night cap.
Baron...
Yes?
Take me to dinner again
with you sometime.
And promise to always
wear this lucky jacket of yours.
We are not late, are we?
No, we aren't.
Lavatory?
Down the stairs to the right, sir.
Back in a minute.
Attention!
Everything goes according to plan.
- Yes!
- Very satisfactory, yes.
Oh.
Our famous flying ace
visiting our frontlines!
Thank you for answering
my invitation.
Quite a dornier sight from
down here, isn't it...
...Richthofen.
Your Majesty...
Your Majesty!
Aha... The little brother.
You're looking desposed,
my dear Baron.
Yes, your Majesty.
I'm fine.
I always am.
Sometimes even irritated, sir.
How can you be "irritably fine"?!
It happens out here.
We kill a couple of men.
And while they fall down in flames,
we feel just fine.
I find this irritating.
My soldiers, do not...
kill people.
They simply destroyed the enemy.
Well,
the effects seems to be the same.
Yes, Mentzke?
You have a visitor, sir.
I thought you might want
to celebrate.
They published your book!
The whole of Europe is reading it.
So...
How about dinner
and then a dance?
They shut down the "Metropole."
Yes, I know.
A British bomb hit the kitchen.
Damn those English!
They won't be happy till
all of Europe foods
is as horrible as theirs.
They don't want me to fly anymore.
They're doing everything they can to
make me stay back on the ground.
Really?
They want me to command the
entire airforce,
the emperor himself.
That's so wonderful!
So many times I woke up in
the middle of the night,
and read...
the lists of missing pilots.
It is so good to have you down here.
Safe!
Good!
Your dancing has improved.
I have a lot of times to
do this anyway.
- Good evening, men.
- Good evening, sir.
- Bloody freezing, huh?
- So true, sir.
A brand new Bentley.
Where did you get it?
Bentleys don't fall out of the sky.
Trust me, I've to argue a little
with the chap.
You always wanted to be first
of the Aces.
Now they offer it to you
and you hesistate.
Yes...
I always wanted to be like him.
Werner...
Could you ever give up flying?
I don't think so.
But if you ask my advice...
You should grabbed your chance.
You only want me to stop,
so you can be first.
I'll let you find out.
Alright... Alright.
- I'll stopped...
- Good.
If you stop first.
I don't think so.
I am married to my plane.
This is how I spend my spare time.
These are fine planes you're
building us, Fokker.
- The best.
- Yes, thank you.
And yet somehow our own pilots seem
to think they can do better.
Oh well...
We sometimes modified
the plane a little.
- Here and there.
- Modifications is one thing,
...but replacing our engines with
those from enemy planes...
- How did you hear of this?
- Early this morning
we received a report of the recovery
of a new triplane.
Well...
The Brits were less than
amused to find
one of their own Bentley engine's in
a Fokker, they shot down.
- I need to see it.
- Of course.
I need to see it at once.
Get me the damn report, now!
Just three more weeks, Manfred.
I already had my marching orders.
I'm going to join your combat wing.
What's become of him?
Fallen in combat.
And him,
his name is Voss, right?
They are all dead.
I will fight with you and Lothar!
Our big offensive is in
full preparation.
They called it "Operation Michael."
We will win this war, won't we?
Wolfram, please...
It's alright, father.
Of course we'll win.
The Allies don't have a clue about
what's coming at them.
For weeks we've been flying out,
and decepting their reconnaissances.
Keeping them from finding out
where we'll breakthrough.
And we did a bloody good job.
This offensive is going to push them
back into the channel.
Sir!
Morning, sir!
Please...
Follow us, sir.
Take cover!
What an unexpected surprise!
You came to visit another
British defeat, captain.
Lieutenant,
go and see if you could find
somebody with a camera.
It's excellent propaganda and
makes a very good picture.
We have our flying ace down
here with us,
on this victorious day.
Your excellency,
we need to talk.
You don't want me down here.
If you give me the power to make
strategic decisions,
you won't have like them.
Why wouldn't we?
We very much trust your
abilities, Baron.
I suggest we surrender!
Huh... What arrogances...
What a pompous child you are!
I was victor...
in 63 aerial battles.
You know how I did it?
When I faced a battle I couldn't win,
I flew away.
What makes you think we cannot
win this war?
What about our boys?
Our holy cause...
Our soldiers out in the field...
You want to give all our efforts
to the enemy...
...von Richthofen!
French...
Great cigarettes.
What makes us think
our causes is better than the French,
or the British and the Americans?
It isn't!
It's not even difference from theirs.
We just need an excuse for
what we do because
without it
we would see who we really are.
Put this fool back into
his aeroplane,
and give him a parachute.
I can't afford to lose another
idealistic hero.
Operation Michael...
Our ground forces attack on
both side of
Socome town from here and from here.
That's a 70 kilometers battleline.
Right!
Three armies...
The 2nd army and 17th army
are launching the offensive
from here.
The 18th army will attack from here.
Our task is to gain control of
the entire
airspace and keeps it, my friends.
Shouldn't be a problem should it,
Bodenschatz?
Our planes are outnumber
4 to 1, Udet.
We've lived with that for months
and weeks.
It will be worse than ever.
They'll send everything they've
got against us.
Fucking cold.
What the hell are you doing?
Sorry if I have bother you, sir.
What're you doing with my
brother's picture?
He ordered me to take them down.
All of them.
Sir!
Move out!
May God be with us.
Gentlemen...
Let's go!
Contact!
He's really back, isn't he?
His 'Flying Circus' swept the
British from the skies!
I saw him fly past,
waving at us.
Sir!
Gentlemen!
High Command of the Northern sector
thanks us for our accomplishments.
I want to add my thanks.
You've show me some splendid flying.
Thank you.
Bravo! Hear! Hear!
Thank you captain!
This isn't how you imagine your
famous cousin to be, is it?
The glorious captain that you
often saw photograph.
Fatherland greatest hero.
The first of all the aces who
shot down 80.
Nobody ever down that many.
I am really proud to be his brother.
You can't beat family, Udet.
Peace? Peace!
Is that one of yours?
I can't tell anymore.
You're flying again, ain't you?
Why didn't you tell me?
Why did you lie to me again?
I didn't want to scare you.
I wanted you to be happy.
Kate, I just cannot do what
they asked me.
They offered you safety,
your life.
When I was a little boy...
I could hit all the targets
with my father's rifle.
Targets so faraway the others
couldn't even see them.
I dreamed of seeing everything.
Trying to think like a bird.
Hawk eyes!
"Eagle eyes" I was called.
When I became a pilot,
I truly thought I had see everything
from up there.
I saw nothing.
I was blind before I met you.
You opened my eyes.
You thought me to see what
I didn't want to see.
We all choose to fly.
Voss, Sternberg...
Lehmann, Wolff...
Hawker.
On whatever side we fought,
we all knew the risks we took.
I wanted to be the best,
I wanted to win and I thought I won.
But I can see now, Kate...
I have seen.
That we have turn the world into
a damn slaughter house.
And I'm already too big a part of it.
They're using my photograph,
to give hope
where there is none.
They used my name to
feign immortality,
where else in reality,
there is annihilation.
You said it yourself,
"The men dying out there,
they have no choice."
I have!
I cannot order them into battle.
I can perhaps leads them.
Help them!
Die with them,
but I will not betrayed them nor
keep the truth from them
by remaining the immortal
God's Berlin wants me to be.
You...
...are my greatest victory.
Sir?
Excuse me, sir.
Sir...
Sir... British aeroplanes are
approaching the front, sir.
Thank you.
Sir.
Yes, thank you!
They were last reported
at Lagnycourt.
So...
They are coming in from
the Northwest.
Thank you.
Brother.
You don't mind if I lead No:11 and
you fly on my right?
Be my guest.
Wolfram...
Stayed clear of any involvement.
Keep close to Lothar.
If you are attacked,
break off and fly home!
Fast!
It's a thin line between cowardice
and cleverness.
A great day to fly.
You are a brave man, Baron.
A very brave man...
Thank you!
Contact!
Thank you.
You are welcome.
Miss...
I could not come sooner.
It's not so easy to cross the line
into British territory.
Finally a friend of ours help me.
He asked me why it was important
for me to come here?
I told him I love you.
Did I ever tell you?