When your city is no longeryour city
History can turn the right
man into the wrong choice
Who's that in the set?
Lili
Get out Lili
Qiyao
Lili, l've something to do
Let's try it again
Miss, don't run
lsn't your cousin very fond of you?
That's not true
l want dreamy looking eyes
As if...
they've no focus
Lili, why did you come in here?
Cheng, my cousin Lili
Nice to meet you
She's my schoolmate, Wang Qiyao
l'm a photographer
Who cares if you take photos
Lili, he takes photos for actresses
ls that true?
Then, who...
do you think is the prettiest?
Time to leave
You promised
l could look anywhere l like
Miss Wang
Wheneveryou have time
l'd like to take yourphoto
l'm still going to school
l knew a few ladies named Qiyao
But l was most interested
in taking photos of this Qiyao
Tea, Miss Lili Thank you
l waited fortwo weeks
and she didn't appear
l guessed she wouldn't be coming
Lili
Come, let us talk in my room
Sit down
Return the hairpin you borrowed from me
You said you were giving it to me
But it's fine
lf you want it back
lt's fine with me
You're second to me in everything
So you're trying to get back at me
Lili
What gives you the right to accuse me?
Because l'm so good to you
And you betrayed me
l didn't
You're still saying you didn't
You went to Cheng's studio to
have yourphotos taken
He blew them up and hung
them outside the studio
And you say you didn't betray me
Mother said she wanted to
have herphotos taken
l was accompanying her
Then where are herphotos?
She didn't take any
Why?
l didn't ask, l didn't dare to ask
You should have told me
l knew
you would be mad
Miss, how many please?
l'm looking for someone
Have a seat
Miss Wang, what would you like?
Coffee
And a piece of cream cake
Sorry that l'm late
We went to see my grandma
Motherbrought the photos along
Grandma
didn't like the way l look in them
She said my eyes and
eyebrows don't look right
lt's my fault
My grandma is more beautiful than l am
Old folks may find it
hard to accept new things
l heard my photos
are hanging outside the studio
They look great
People say they're great
l'm concerned with
what my relatives will say
MrCheng, can you take them down?
Yourphotos...
Yes, yourphotos
People at the magazine
said you look elegant
My friends who saw yourphotos
agreed with me
We should let you enterthe
Miss Shanghai pageant
They're willing to help
Lili won't support me on this
Thin eyebrows are no longerin fashion
Thick eyebrows look healthier
ls this a bit too thick?
Once is enough forthis kind of event
Or else ourrelatives will laugh at us
Mrs Wang, you're too modest
Yourfamily is full of beautiful maidens
all worth adoring
Who would dare to laugh?
Awedding dress?
She is just a child
Mrs Wang, that's normal
They change dresses several
times in beauty pageants
They wearwedding dresses as well?
The reason is,
l know how beauty pageants work
Everyone wants to wearred or green
to stand out...so
l want Qiyao to wearwhite
to impress the judges
Lili, how do l look?
Beautiful
Would you be happy
Qiyao won?
Would you?
l'm asking you
The reporter of Sung, this time can be
good friends with to like to thank you.
Why aren't the reporters
taking photos of Qiyao?
Those people
Talk to them
lt's no use
Welcome, Officer Li
Officer Li Hello
May l introduce
my wife and daughter
Hello Welcome, Officer Li
This way please
Sorry
Qiyao Lili, where did you go?
l found out one contestant got roses
lt just means she has her supporters
l heard it costs a bar of gold
for each rose tonight
How much is that?
My father said...
many of the contestants
have found wealthy supporters
As l said before,
don't take this so seriously
Officer Li
Which girl are you supporting tonight?
Too many VlPs here,
l won't stand a chance
But you're the most important one
Qiyao, we're your supporters
My parents will be here
to support you too
Relax
Quick, it's yourturn
l lost my earring
lsn't your dress a bit too plain?
Officer Li, your seat is ready
Let's go then
Only those who throw
roses onto the stage
can tell me how l look tonight
ls this decided?
That's what Officer Li said
Thank you
Have you started working yet?
No
They're showing a Gregory Peck film
l know, The Yearling
Want to see it?
Well
My son and Qiyao grew up together
What happened?
They get along well as cousins, but...
He's too young
ls this what Qiyao wants?
How would l know?
She's my only child
You think it doesn't break my heart?
What do you think l should do?
l'll go and have a look
Can you say something?
Son
Let's go
Say goodbye to yourAunt
Come visit us when you've time
Goodbye, Aunt
Goodbye, Qiyao
Goodbye
Goodbye, Aunt
Are you alright?
l don't know
Don't worry
You'll be fine
l'll go bring a towel
Officer Li, Miss Shanghai
Welcome, Officer Li...
Welcome,Miss Shanghai
Ms Mu, you're a starin my eyes
l'm honored
Officer Li, it's been a long time
What brought you to Shanghai?
Let me hearyou sing, Ms Mu
My horse is in a race this weekend
They're going to let herwin
Come and share my joy
Of course
l'll reserve a private box foryou
Miss Shanghai, please come as well
Let me have the honor
to take a photo with you
l'm overwhelmed
Mr Wei
This can wait till later
You were like a kitten
on the stage that night
Qiyao
Do you know how to dance?
They taught us at school
Ourmasterwants a dance
with Miss Shanghai
Tell yourmaster, the answeris No
Ms Mu
May l have this dance?
Awoman is a woman...
Go over and ask yourself
Herbeauty is so pure
No wonderyou're obsessed
So you saw through me
lt's not like we just met
Qiyao
Shall we dance?
l just told them
l don't know how to dance
The world is bleak
And life is no better
l can't cope with this solitude
Wandering the world
Suffering the hardship
To find you as my companion
Go to sleep first
Where are you going this late?
Some things can't be
discussed during the day
l'll be right back
Promise me you won't stay up
Then l won't know when you come back
l'll wake you, is that fine?
You're lying to me
Stay quiet, they're all sleeping
Qiyao, your apartment is very pretty
What good does that do
when l'm always alone here
Then...
we'll come visit you more often
And you'll find us a nuisance
How can that be?
l'll be more than happy
Qiyao, look at me
Do l look like one of those girls
on the calendars?
How about me?
Enjoy the taste of Beauty Cigarettes
Enjoy the clean of Beauty Soap
Cheng, if you'd brought your camera
Then it'd be perfect
Lili, it's a long time since
we had western style dinner
Wait till you're not busy
The two of us go all the time
That makes me hungry...
l'll go tell them to get some cakes
Qiyao
We're just here to see you
Just sit down and talk with us
Lili, when does yourfather
plan to leave Shanghai?
lt could be just a thought
Very hard to read his mind
How about you?
Leaving with yourfather?.
Ask him
Let's wait and see
Shanghai is a good place afterall
You've friends here?
Yes, Lili... you met herbefore
They're here often?
No, we've not met for a long time
Lili is my best friend from school,
remember?.
MrCheng is Lili's friend
Nice to meet you both, l'm Li
l'm Cheng
l nominated Qiyao to the beauty pageant
Really?
Then l must thank you wholeheartedly
Did you prepare anything to eat?
They said they're not hungry
How impolite
lt's not easy to have old friends here
Go ask them to prepare something
Seeing Qiyao's smile
l knew l was no longerneeded here
Please, come inside
That night, l agreed to
leave Shanghai with Lili
How come your eyebrows are like that?
Look good?
They're not the type l like
What do eyebrows have to do
with liking someone?
Look...
Yourhair
is darkerthan mine
We Chinese referto marriage as
tying knots of hairtogether
lf you tie these together
Then aren't we husband and wife?
You're the one who said that
These businessmen in Shanghai
are going to be quite upset
When they know you came from
Chongqing to investigate them
That goes without saying
l bet they killed Hu's son to show
you what they're made of
They've gone totally insane
Have everything ready
Yes Sir
They're looking for death
Hello
Miss Wang, yourmotheris not back yet
Thank you Not at all
You're quite late
The food is getting cold
Take a rest, no need to be so busy
Although l seldom socialize with
the neighbors
l neverknow how to answer
when they ask about you
They just enjoy prying
so don't worry about them
Need to do it up to your elbow...
Can't be lazy about it
Hands... they can really betray your age
lt's the anniversary of
father's death next month
Let's hold a prayerritual for
him at the temple
They say it's good forboth the
dead and the living
Who are we doing it for after
all these years?
People say
the dead still care
how theirfamilies treat them
Chambers of Commerce ask people to
join the rally
Qiyao, switch it off
To oppose investigations of corruption
Such investigations are damaging
the prosperity of the city
And creating conflict within
the nationalist party
Beautiful and elegant
Du Shiniang
Sorry to have landed in a pleasure house
Officer Li here?
He's inside
Officer Li...
Like a masterless flower dancing
in the wind
Like willow cotton drifting away in tears
To be...
Have a cigarette
Surrenderyourweapon
Your superiors have gone home
But l still have a few Shanghai
big shots behind me
So yourlife
is not something l can easily spare
ls it worth it? Doing this for Li?
Search the place Yes Sir
Go ahead and pull the trigger
You'll hearfrom my father's army
l'm the one who is shot in yourhouse
Yourfatherwill hearfrom me
Start the car
You contacted the right person
Are you hurt?
He said you helped him before
l've helped a lot of people
l've arranged a place foryou
Thank you
Do remember
l'm not one of those you've helped
Of all the people l've met
you're one of the toughest
ls Miss Wang here?
When was the last time Li was here?
More than two months ago
How many days is that?
Sixty eight days ago in the evening
That was the last time l saw him
That was exact
You really don't know where he is?
You really think he'll tell
a woman who lives off him?
Sir, we haven't found much
That's it?
We looked through every
drawer and this is it
Rest is clothing
How can that be?
What else do you think there'll be?
Don't think you've won
Believe me
We'll find him
l've been with Li a long time
This woman is the one
he's been with the longest
Disrespect me now
and l can finish you off
with one word when he returns
Took us two days to line up for
the boat tickets
Can't imagine how many people
are trying to leave Shanghai
l thought we were going to
Japan orAmerica
Neverthought...
fatherwould finally decide on Hong Kong
Where is Hong Kong?
ln the south
l heard it's a dirty and messy slum
Yourfatheris a big businessman
He should know best
You talk just like my very own Cheng
Still joking at a time like this?
Miss
More tea?
Yes
Qiyao
How's life?
Everything is fine
People say...
Shanghai is too unstable
lt's best to go some place
for a few years
Ride it out and come back
when things settle down
Perhaps...
You should think about it too
Leaving just like that?
lt's easier said than done
Qiyao
lt's yourhousehold
l know l shouldn't interfere
lt's none of my business
But...
That Officer Li can't even
take care of himself now
There's an old saying...
Couples are birds in the same wood
that fly off when there's trouble
This crisis won't end in a month ortwo
Women
should think forthemselves first
You're leaving now?
Yes Miss
Please take good care of yourself
We no longerhave the honorto serve you
Don't say that
lt's going to be lonely here by myself
lt won't be
You take care
l will and thank you
You're MrCheng?
Sir, your guest is here
Come in
Haven't seen you in a long time
l was busy
Nice to see you again
Must be cold outside
lt's not
How are you?
Fine
Did Qiyao...
say anything?
No
She's still living there?
We haven't seen each otherrecently
Could l trouble you
to make a trip to the apartment?
lf she's still there
please deliver a message forme
You haven't seen herin a while
Your situation can't be that bad
Why don't you tell heryourself
Tell herl'm dead and don't wait forme
How dare you lie to her
You can run away
But what is she supposed to do?
lf l see a way out
Do you think l'll be asking you?
Aren't you having some?
l'm not thirsty
Lili left yesterday?
l should've gone to see her off
You shouldn't be worrying about this now
l'm fine
l'll stay here for a few more days
Get changed and l'll take you home
We're good friends
He was gone just like that...
How can you be heartbroken?
He's dead! He's dead!
He was thinking of me when he died
Forhim...l can give up my life
And you all think l don't care
He made me lie to you
He'll come back
Qiyao believed loving someone was more
important than anything in life
Yet my wife believed
we should love everyone
That was what l heard
from the radio everyday
And l was beginning to
believe what my wife said
Do it tomorrow
Aren't you tired working
so late every night?
l can't sleep well
if l left any work unfinished
Hasn't snowed for a few years
Don't just stare at the snow
Do you have enough clothes on?
Yes
That's good
Let's go out and eat
Thank you
The songs of a New China
Gave people the courage to
make brave new decisions
Miss Wang
Please come overhere
Thank you foryourhonorable donation
of this apartment to the country
Please, have a seat
Please sign here
lf it's our country that needs it,
l've nothing against it
Donate your stock holdings now
to benefit the proletariat
When our country is stronger...
What's that?
Documents foryourfather
MasterMing
You're packing up already?
You haven't had yourinjection yet?
MasterMing
Sorry
You're packing already
Don't bother
MasterMing, you go first
l'm not busy, you go first
What will people think of us?
l won't ask for anything
l will
Say it
Think of me
when you feel sad, will you?
Ask me again
during the day
l won't say it again
What is said during the night
doesn't count
What will become of me
if l can't make you stay?
l'm trying to work it out
l...
have nothing now
We finally went too far
Why?
You irresponsible man
The father of my child
Do you want to leave Shanghai?
With you... l can go anywhere
Qiyao
My love foryou is true
Ming
Say it again
Then perhaps l may believe you
What can l promise you?
Ming
l'm now more desperate
than you are
Foryou...
l can give up everything
Everything?
What is everything to you?
Lili, stay a few more days
since you rarely come back
lt's not too convenient because
l'm living with my relatives
Miss Lili, what is Hong Kong like?
They all say they want to
flee to Hong Kong
ls it really a good place?
Does it really matter?.
We're only there forthe stability
How can that place
compare to Shanghai
TRUE
Can't even find a place to
buy good western desserts
lt's better at home
Thankfully motherinsisted on bringing
our cook when we left
Or else l don't know
how we would live through it
l'll go
Qiyao, you brought a cake
Has Lili arrived?
They're here
Qiyao
l miss you so much
You alright?
Ming
This is Ming
My old schoolmate, Lili
Nice to meet you
Come take a seat
Ming
Hong Kong's a betterplace
forbusiness than Shanghai now
l know
Qiyao
l'll join you
Seeing old friends together again
makes me happy
Cheers
Lili, l made some suits foryour son
l don't want him to grow up
and say this Auntie
never cared forhim
As soon as he can walk,
l'll bring him back
to meet his uncles and aunties
Lili, you're Qiyao's best friend
You've got to come back forherwedding
l'll drink to herthen
and l'll drink to hernow
Qiyao
You should thank me
Thank you
Ming
Do you know who Wang Qiyao is?
lt took a lot foryou to be together
Treat herwell
Thank you
This beautiful Shangri-La
This adorable Shangri-La
l'm deeply in love with the place
l'm in love with the place
This beautiful Shangri-La
This adorable Shangri-La
l'm deeply in love with the place
l'm in love with the place
This beautiful Shangri-La
This adorable Shangri-La
l'm deeply in love with the place
l'm in love with the place
This beautiful Shangri-La
This adorable Shangri-La
l'm deeply in love with the place
l'm in love with the place
Lili, l'm so happy
lt's a way out afterall
l've a small investment
in Song's wheat factory
His letters say
lt's doing good business in Hong Kong
lf we go there, we can
live off the interest and bonus
Getting by shouldn't be a problem
But we'll be alone in a strange land
You'll betterbe prepared
Life won't be easy foryou anymore
All these years of blood and sweat
l'm sure l can have a new
start overthere
All l ask
is foryou
to come with me
lt's our child
You're still thinking about it?
Are you sure about this?
lt's still a long way to the hospital
We'll be right there
All they need is your signature
Afterthe operation,
no one will be held responsible
Why don't we put our signatures
on a marriage certificate?
Then we can bring our
child to this world
Can't wait anymore
Give me some more time
l can find someone to
abort the child secretly
And then what?
Stop
Ming
You're crying?!
Miss Wang
We won't be here if we're not facing
difficulties of our own
Let's do it neatly and beautifully
lf you know what l mean
What do you mean by that?
Stop this ambiguous talk
We agreed on a price
l brought you here so that
you'll know who she is
And she'll know who you are
How can you talk like that?
Who's asking who forhelp?
My elderbrotheris highly eligible
if it isn't forhis terminal illness
Awoman with such a shadowy past
won't stand a chance of sharing
his name in marriage
We're a family of good reputation
There's a middleman in this deal
Miss Wang has no opinion on this
When the child is born
with a father's name
on the birth certificate
Then the deal is done
No surprises please
lf worse comes to worse
Be aware that...
l've passed the point of no return
Qiyao, l'm leaving
Aunt, goodbye
Goodbye
Aunt
Thank you
Have some tea
Are you using the good tea leaves?
Thank you
No problem
Want some tea?
l didn't bring anything
fancy except for some candy
Qiyao, l want candy
You all have some
Come
No, l shouldn't Come on
No, please Mrs Cheng
Don't be so courteous
We're not encouraged to have
wedding banquets nowadays
At least have some candy
as a gesture of luck forme
Then...
l'll have some
You have some too
Qiyao
Let's do it
When MrGuo is healthier
we'll take more photos at the park
Pull the backdrop forme
Here we go
Not a single soul in days
The toilet is still leaking,
don't know what to do about it
Can't even wash my face
Did you notice that in the morning?
No you won't because
l always get up earlier
The wateris always yellow
Don't know what to do about it
Don't worry
lt'll get better
l need to go and see my father
The trip will take two weeks...
He's always sick
l'll give him some money to buy medicine
He's my father
and l must take care of him
Little Weiwei, look at Papa
Dinneris ready
Chicken soup is good foryourhealth
l'll take care of myself
Does she drink hermilk?
She's a good child
Drinks hermilk with all her strength
And then go right to sleep
How sweet
Yes
l neverhave to worry about her
That's good
Every man wants a family
he can call his own
With a wife and children
Living a steady and peaceful life
l grew up watching
my uncles' families and l envy them
in my heart
lt makes me want to grow up fast
So that l can be like them
And introduce to everyone...
My wife
My son
And my daughter
l thought...
So what if we don't go to Hong Kong?
We can stay in Shanghai
But that doesn't solve anything
No use thinking about it anymore...
lf my motherwere still here
She could at least get a golden
bracelet from her grandma
Such a sweet little child
Born into this cold loneliness
Don't worry about yourliving expenses
Even when l'm in Hong Kong
and not by your side
l'll still send you money
l'm counting on you forthat
l know
Come on, eat
The food is getting cold
Ming died in San Francisco at age 59
My wife kept asking me
why Qiyao didn't come for dinner
l guess she felt sorry forQiyao
But l understood Qiyao all too well
When she was sad she did not
want to be disturbed
l don't want to pretend anymore
lf you can't forget her
l'll make room forher
l'm someone who can find a way out
How was school today?
Good
Want egg fried rice for dinner?.
Yes
Tell Mama
How much are the eggs in the black market?
Does it matter?.
l'll get them if you need them
Ma, wheneverUncle Cheng comes,
we have egg fried rice
Let Uncle Cheng kiss you
Run along now
Qiyao, the egg shells
l'll dispose them outside later
Can't be careless with the small details
That family out
front is always turning people in
With so many enemies
One of these days,
someone will return the favor
Don't mind otherpeople's business
and just take care of yourself
Going to rural areas
to help those in need
l believe in that
When l said goodbye to Qiyao
She asked me to take care of myself
And l told herto
take care of herself as well
Great as are heaven and earth,
what we owe the Party is greater
Dear as are father and mother
Chairman Mao is dearer
Ma, l'll teach you how to sing
Okay
Chairman Mao taught us...
The world is yours
As well as ours
But ultimately it is yours
lt works now
Kela, where did you find this?
Don't let anyone find out
Of course not...lt's very safe
Working yet?
How come there's no sound?
No needle
Cousin, see if you can find a needle
What needle?
How can we find record
playing needles here?
l've been ripped off
l gave him a watch forit
What did he tell you?
He guaranteed it would turn
No sound
Forget it
Cheng, take a rest
Cheng
Stop working like this
Look at you, doing nothing all day
Cousin
Don't disturb ourmodel worker
Kela, why are you always
protecting him?
Don't run
Cheng, help me
l'll write to Aunt and tell on you
Go ahead, see if l'm worried
Let go of me
Cheng
Watch what you say
Don't worry about her
And you too
Cheng, do you think about home?
l do
l wish l could go back
to Shanghai tomorrow
Must be nice having a wife
lt depends
Not if she's not around
lt's the same for everyone
My husband is in Tibet
Cheng, is yourwife beautiful?
Very beautiful
Everyday in the countryside,
l wanted to write a letter
To know what my friend's life
was like in Shanghai
l had to think about every word l wrote
For one wrong word could bring trouble
l ended up only sending one letter
On it, l drew a picture
of a young Qiyao
She should know l was asking...
How are you?
Are you happy?
Ayearpassed... and then another
people gradually returned to
their own cities
Comrade, how many?
l'm looking for someone
l burnt the letters from you and
Ming afterreading them
l didn't dare to keep them
The few times you sent me rice
lt tasted so good
And smelled so nice
Ming didn't send money twice
Turned out he was sick
Amazing how a strong man like him
can fall ill so easily
Weiwei tries hard to improve herself
She asks me to teach herEnglish at home
But pretends not to know it in school
Need help to clean up yourplace?
l'll come by tomorrow
l cleaned it already
lt's been a few years
You look older
lt's good
To be older
Neverthought it'd be like this
Yonghong, have some coffee
Thank you, Auntie Wang
Ma, the coffee is bitter...
lt needs more milk and sugar
lt's not coffee when it's too sweet
Was it hard to get the
telephone installed?
Had to go through several departments
How much did you spend?
Can we use yourphone for
organizing parties from now on?
Most people share one phone
among several buildings and they get by
Weiwei, you got married too early
House parties are a lot of fun
l need to cook when l get off work and
my husband is busy learning English
l've to do all the housework
How can l find time forparties?
Why do you have to stay at
that tiny place
and do everything yourself?
l have room here
l've said it before and
l won't say it again
Auntie, may l use yourphone?
How is yourlife?
Same old, same old
Living in Shanghai is meaningless anyway
Do something with yourhair
when you have time
l think this looks fine
Ma, it's not like l didn't try to
talk him out of it
We don't have any relatives in America
lt'll be very tough
l heard...
A loaf of bread there is more
expensive than a chicken here
Since it's decided,
why worry about the details?
l've been packing the last few days
Didn't even dare to
leave our slippers behind
ln case...
they're expensive overthere
Yourhusband is right
Go early when you can still take it
Accomplish everything
before it's too late
Let's be frank
Go ahead
They say...
You used to be
the mistress of an officer
Do you see l'm dyeing my hair?.
Hiding all that money is
useless so can we discuss about it
Then let me ask you,
if l give you the money
How am l supposed to
live when you're gone?
l'll be paying you back
Did you ask me when you decide to leave?
Why should l ask you?
l should be asking my father
You tell me where my fatheris
You're asking me after all these years?
Did you feel cheated by
the way l raised you?
l don't care how it happened
You may have suffered
but you had yourfun
l was innocent and
l had to listen to all the gossip
l suffered, l had always suffered
Americans are tallerthan we are
Put a stack of cash underneath your shoes
Then you can talk to them
with more dignity
l'll definitely pay you back
You have a good husband
That makes you strongerthan yourMa
Ma, he is not good to me
Life is hard forme
The doorto China was opened
They all came back to visit the home
they'd missed forthirty years
According to the information on you
Between Sept 1948
And Jan 1949
You were living
with a high ranking nationalist
official named Li
Yes
Li never contacted you?
Never
Li went to Holland
and then Brazil, did you know that?
No
Why?
He never contacted me again
You want some tea?
Thank you
This is the key to your old apartment
Go claim back
the things that were confiscated
Sign here
This is his address
He's still in Brazil?
Yes, with a huge ranch
The photo you took of my parents
was ruined
when rain waterflooded ourhouse
Cheng, when you have time
can you develop another one forthem?
l need to find the negative, Kela
Cheng
When are you taking me out?
Shanghai looks so colorful
l want to revisit the place where
l lived when l was small
You've just been here a few days
What's the hurry?
Cheng
Thanks forputting me up
Both of us have no relatives here
You can't lift that curtain
Don't worry, l won't go inside
Have you written to yourparents yet?
Not yet
Let them know you're safe
Something wrong?
They wouldn't let me come
Why?
No reason
Any clothes you need to wash?
You left without telling them?
No point explaining to them
Just don't regret it later
One should expand one's horizon
Don't you agree? Cheng?
Why are you so late?
Auntie Wang, this is Kela
Auntie Wang... Cheng, you know her?.
We all call him Old Color
How can l be an Old Color
Shanghai people call
the classy ones Old Color
Cheng is the real Old Color
l prepared a few dishes
Don't go out to eat tonight
Put them in the kitchen first
l'll put them in the refrigerator
And make you some coffee
Thanks
lt's too hot
Smells good
Have a glass Thanks
Cheng, coffee tastes awful when cold
ln a second
You drink first
You've been waiting long?
Let's go shopping
There's a shortage of refrigerators
but the prices are good
Don't be impatient...ls this
black market business safe?
Cheng
l'm going to the Overseas Chinese Store
You're so busy lately
Business must be good
Can't live on my salary alone
l'll do some shopping too
Leaving together?.
He's taking me to the bus stop
Good
Auntie Wang, this is too difficult...
l can't learn it
Yes you can
Keep Cheng company
Want a drink?
Later
You came late
lt's too hard forme to learn
You're here
Dance with me
l need a rest
Simon, come take a rest
Okay
Auntie Wang
My daughter's schoolmate, Yonghong
Simon is from Hong Kong
How are you? How are you?
Are there parties like this in Hong Kong?
No
We go to discos and
we don't dance to this kind of music
What's it like?
The music is fast and the beat is strong
We dance till we're sweating
Come to Hong Kong and l'll show you
l'll come find you in Hong Kong
You know that boy from Hong Kong?
No
Why force me to rememberyou
l'll take a look
The tape is damaged
Change it
l want to dance with you
What music do you want?
You came so late
You still don't trust me
For some unknown reason
l'm surrounded by melancholy
Dinneris ready
Okay
Have a seat
Simon, did yourMom learn to cook?
She cooks once a year on Dad's birthday
What kind of dishes?
Western style
My Dad
doesn't like Shanghai food
That's perfect, Lili likes Western
style since she was young
l've applied for a long distance line
so that l can call Lili
Cheng, what do you think?
Does Lili go to work?
She never did
Dad says she's still like a little girl
She neverinterfered with my life either
lsn't that good?
Mom asked when you'd go to Hong Kong
Among everything in Shanghai
She said she missed you the most
l definitely will
l wrote her a letter
Can you bring it to her?.
Sure
ls everything alright?
He's fine
Don't behave
like that in front of children
Let's go to Hong Kong to see Lili
Eat
Let's eat
Lili died in Taipei at age 61
Any news, Yonghong?
They said they could get the money
back in a couple of days
There are always risks involved
in black market dealings
First time l took on such a big deal
When the money arrives
the passports can be easily arranged
The furtherwe go the better
Talk about that later
Afterthe money arrives
What?
There's something you can't leave behind?
You're leaving?
No
l'm taking a shower
ln a few years
You'll be able to leave wheneveryou want
lt's not something
that has to be decided in a few days
Why mention it?
What do you want?
Whateveryou want you can tell me
l just want to take a look at the world
And then l'll come back
Can't you wait a few years?
What's the difference?
Nevermind
Go shower
What are you doing here?
Hungry?
l'll go buy something to eat
lt's okay
l'm not hungry
Stay for a while
He moved out suddenly?
Sit for a while
l'll go check the photos
Did he leave anything?
Abuse yourself all you want
Don't abuse my photos
You've neveryelled at me
You're yelling at me now?
These are my photos...
How dare you say l abuse them
He has all the time in the world
Do you have
the same luxury to forget him?
Afriend took me to a grand hotel
Even the doormen wear suits
So what?
You know a lot of foreigners?
They brought you there?
Yonghong introduced me to them
But l couldn't speak to them in English
Qiyao and l both know English
What good does that do?
You took great care of me
l left my parents
when l was in my twenties as well
Back then
l thought l'd return to them very soon
What were you thinking at the time?
l was tired of them
Why?
Qiyao was asking about you recently
Cheng
l know she's a close friend of yours
Not close
But long
l like her
One day l'll return
Wang Qiyao here?
Yes
Telegraph from Brazil
Sign here
Let me get my name chop
Thank you
Officer Li died in Brazil 1981
lt's inevitable
at this age
Don't feel sad about it
Qiyao
lt's good enough that you
can come to keep me company
l've something l want to say
But that can wait a few days
May l come in?
lt's very late
Qiyao, l got into trouble
l'll stay here a few days
Qiyao, the police are afterme
l have some family problems
l want to be alone
Qiyao, just a few days
Sorry, just a few days
l've nowhere else to go
l won't be here if there's anotherway
Please don't botherme
What are you doing? Listen to me
l'll be fine in a few days...
Friends will get me overthis
Yonghong double-crossed me...
She's yourfriend too
That's yourbusiness
l don't care
l'll call the police
Yonghong deceived me
My passport is ready
l can go abroad next month
Kela was sentenced to life
imprisonment in 1983
l had walked from my house
to Qiyao's house
so many times
Neverthought there would be a last
Qiyao
You must have known
that with this young man
There could be no happy ending
Yet l could not interfere
Qiyao
l would miss you
MrCheng died in Hong Kong 2001
Lili, among all our schoolmates
who do you think about the most?
Definitely not you
Then who?
Originally it was you
But time and time
again you've been insincere
There's a darkness in yourheart
as if there's a hole in there
Lili
lf that's what you think of me
When you're old and think of me again
You'll regret it
l don't want to be old
A city never grows old
Because everyday someone
is embracing his youth