Open the door, you stupid motherfucker!
Open the fuckin' door!
I had the fuckin' keys, Stan!
This is faster.
I need it.
Relax, you'll get it.
I need it so bad.
Get the fuckin' door, Johnny!
Come on!
No! Honey, don't you
dare go down there!
Yes, it's Osman's Drug
at 7th and Burdoch.
What the fuck! I thought you
knew where the good stuff was!
He always keeps
it right in here!
Shit!
I'm gonna count to three.
Or?
Or my wife will be mopping up
your blood tomorrow morning.
Yeah, Pops?
You'd shoot your little boy?
With that big gun..
you'd shoot and kill
little Johnny D.?
You ain't gonna shoot
your little boy!
- Shut up!
- You shut the fuck up!
And help Johnny D.
Find the good shit!
Cops!
No, don't!
I live here!
Do you want to fuck around?
Come on, you motherfucker!
You want to play with me?
Let's do it!
Did you find any?
What?
Let's go.
Come on!
Sit down!
Sit down, you ugly bitch!
Put her in the chair.
You're not only ugly,
you're stupid, too.
Get smart with me and
I'll rip your face off!
Now then..
what's your name?
- Maggie.
- Full name.
Blowjob.
Maggie Blowjob.
Go ahead. Grin away.
We'll put you on Death Row,
you'll lose that grin real quick.
Here.
Sign that. I don't have any
more time for your bullshit.
Can I have a pencil?
Having been found guilty
of the crime of murder..
it is the judgment of this court that you
be sentenced to die by lethal injection.
You are hereby remanded to the
federal prison in Pleasanton..
where you shall remain until
your sentence is carried out.
And may God have
mercy on your soul.
Motherfuckers!
No.. no!
Please wait for my mom!
Wait, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Wait till my mommy comes!
Wait for her!
You've got to tell my mom!
My mom will come and get me!
Mommy!
Hi.
I'm Bob.
Is that "Maggie" short
for "Margaret"?
Mister, what is this place?
Where am I?
You're dead. At least, that's
what everybody thinks.
Your funeral.
We staged it Saturday afternoon.
You're buried here.
Oakmont Cemetery.
Plot 48, row 12.
- There's your father.
- Didn't my mother come?
No, your mother, she..
You know you can't get out.
I work for some people.
"The government,"
let's call them.
We've decided to give
you another chance.
Is that about me?
Yes, it is.
You know a lot about me.
We do.
So..
you're gonna give
me this chance?
What do I gotta do?
Learn, Maggie.
Learn to speak properly, learn to
stand up straight, for a start.
Learn languages,
computers, and so on.
Do something to help your
country, for a change.
What if I'm not interested?
Row 48..
plot 12.
Can I think about it?
Yeah, why don't you
think about it?
You've got one hour.
Stupid fucking asshole!
Come on, up! Up!
Which way is out?
This way.
- Who are these assholes?
- Just people who work here. It's okay.
Put it down. There's no problem.
Just go back to your desks.
Bullshit! Everything's fucked!
Come on. You know you
can't get away with this.
Put it away!
Get back to the wall.
Everything's under control.
- Open it!
- I can't!
- Open the fucking door!
- I can't.
- Tell them to do it!
- They won't.
I'll blow his
fucking brains out!
They still won't do it.
Just give me the gun.
Good girl.
Just put it down.
Come on, Maggie.
You're too smart to
fight these odds.
It's okay.
It's okay. Put it down.
Rule number one:
Never chamber the first round.
That'll slow you
down for a while..
"Maggie for Margaret."
So?
What's it to be, yes or no?
What if I said I have a couple of
questions & that I need some more time?
What if I said there
is no more time?
What if I said you can kiss
my ass right in the crack?
What's it gonna be, yes or no?
I'm gonna have a few
things that I'll need.
I'm gonna need some stuff.
I need some music.
Some good music.
I'm gonna want some Nina Simone.
Nina Simone.
Yeah, and..
I want some more pain killers.
My leg is fuckin' killing me.
Is that it?
I'll make a list.
You do that, Maggie.
Bet your fuckin' ass.
We're gonna start with a
simple program first.
This is just like a typewriter keyboard.
You got letters here..
numbers here. Return, okay?
Tab.. Wait, wait, wait.
This is a mouse.
You use this to write with, draw, save..
Things like that.
See the roller? Roll that
around and watch the screen.
Good, good.
Wait!
Wait, wait. Real easy, okay?
Real easy. Like that. Now move the
arrow down to where it says, "Play."
Right here, click once.
Pay attention, Maggie.
- Can we make the dinosaur eat him?
- You want to make the dinosaur eat him?
Very good, very good.
Feel a little bit more relaxed.
You.
I can't. My leg hurts.
That's okay. We're just working on reflexes.
It'll be easy. Come on.
I've taken my guard. See
if you can hit my face.
Hit me. Come on, hit me.
Hit me. Hit me. Come on.
Always smile when you
enter a room, dear.
It relaxes others, and it lifts
the features of the face.
You know what "Nature's
first green is gold" means?
"Nature's first green is gold."
It means that the
first is best..
that youth is better
than old age.
You have the gift of youth.
That is what we'll build on.
It's charming, my dear, but
it doesn't address my point.
Put the gum here.
That's better.
Sit down.
Are you an ugly duckling..
or a swan?
Because the choice
is yours, you know.
Belief is half of being.
It's a fancy way of saying, if
you believe you're pretty..
then you will be pretty.
You'll see.
What do you do when you're
most uncomfortable?
When you're angry or scared?
I hit.
You might want to try smiling.
Just smile a little smile and..
say something offhand. It doesn't
have to fit the situation, really.
Say..
Say, "I never did mind
about the little things."
Say it!
Please, dear.
A smile, and the sentence.
"I never did mind.."
"..about the little things."
Chin up. Shoulders back.
Have some pride in yourself.
Show me.
Yes, Maggie.
Better. Good.
"I lie down for a nap today.
"Yesterday I lay
down for a nap."
"If something unfortunate
happens, I feel bad.."
Louder, please.
"I feel 'bad' about it, not
'badly.' 'Bad' is an adjective.
"Remember to say, 'It is a secret
between her and me.' Not, 'she and I."'
Turn it down, will you?
Please, turn it down.
People are beginning to complain. Why
don't you use the headset I got you?
'Cause they're crappy.
You know, you..
This is Nina Simone.
You got it for me, remember?
She wants sugar in her bowl?
No, she's saying:
"Baby, just stick it in me twice a
day, and I'll do anything for you."
"I'll lick the
ground you walk on."
Why do you talk so dirty?
Why do you talk so faggy?
So, how is it going?
Man, I'm so majorly bored.
Think I'm going crazy. Started talking
to myself and all kinds of stuff.
Your reports are excellent.
All right!
So, do I get a reward or something?
It's my birthday next week.
Why don't you let me go outside?
Just for one night?
You can have me followed.
Please!
I can't. Okay?
Look, Maggie..
I know how you feel.
- Bullshit!
- Yes, I do.
I used to be a recruit myself.
I used to be where you are now.
And, just like you, I
hated every moment of it.
So you understand.
I'm going stir-crazy. Please!
Just let me go out for a walk.
I said I can't.
That's it. Okay?
I want to go for a walk!
Girl number five?
Take out the bad guys. Do
not shoot the good guys.
You got two seconds
for each target.
Understand?
Ready, set..
and go.
What was that?
- Fun.
- Yeah, right.
What is it with you?
Eating should be
graceful, yet natural.
If you get a bone in your mouth,
take it out with your fingers..
and put it on the
edge of your plate.
No fake middle-class delicacy.
No hiding the bone
behind a napkin.
Today we'll start
with the entrée.
Let's begin.
Bone!
May I be excused?
You've done better.
She's a pain, but I can bring her around.
She's got great potential.
I like her potential, too. She
has some mighty nice potential.
So, bottom-line me
about this girl.
We need a young female operative.
I think she's the one.
Usually, it takes two years.
In this case..
Six months.
That's right. I don't want to
see any more attitude from her.
Enough with this crap. She bites, she
kicks, she throws food.. what is that?
So, you got it?
Six months. I want immediate results
or she gets a bullet in the brain.
Turn it off.
Ask me why I'm so serious.
Why are you so serious?
Because I've got serious stuff to
tell you, "Maggie for Margaret."
First, the good stuff.
Happy birthday.
Okay, now the bad stuff.
Kaufman has drawn a
line in the sand.
He says he's not gonna take
any more crap from you.
He mentioned the word "bullet"
and the word "brain."
You hearing me? Is
this going in, Maggie?
Because I want you to know,
it's now out of my hands.
Happy birthday.
Will you help me?
Of course. Come upstairs.
All you need is balance. We have
to find your feminine strength.
Some moon to go with your sun.
A bit of the poet to
balance the warrior.
Don't you want to
carry your jacket?
Surely not just for
a dinner lesson.
What's worth doing..
is worth doing well.
- You've mentioned that before.
Et tu as pris longtemps
pour I'apprendre, ma chère.
J'ai pensé me le faire
tatouer sur le bras.
Very good!
You look..
beautiful.
You've really outdone
yourself this time.
Yes, about this
one, I am pleased.
Then why do I have to have another
dinner lesson after six months?
Or are you afraid I'll revert and
put my feet back up on the table?
I think that..
tonight we should
have dinner out.
Really?
Thank you!
Shall we go?
Good evening. Would you
like to see the wine list?
No, thanks. Just a bottle
of Dom Perignon, please.
Very good, sir.
Thank you.
Don't open it yet.
That's fine.
More than you can
possibly imagine..
I wish you every good thing.
It's loaded.
I don't understand.
A lady and two men are sitting
behind you on the balcony.
The man on the right is a VIP.
The other one's his bodyguard.
I want you to put two bullets in
the VIP.. two bullets minimum.
Then go to the men's room.
In the last stall there's a small
window that leads to a courtyard.
There will be a car
waiting for you.
Don't do anything till I leave.
You've got three minutes, okay?
It was bricked in.
The window was all bricked in.
Yes, of course it was.
That was your final test.
Motherfucker!
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Son of a bitch!
You get out tomorrow!
You get out tomorrow.
That was your last test.
I'm really gonna miss you.
You know that.
I'll never kiss you again.
What level of operation
is she ready for?
S-1.
Ambitious as ever.
Don't sit down.
I need her ready by March.
You're gonna love this.
A woman goes into a bar
with a duck under her arm.
She orders a few beers. Bartender says,
"What're you doing with that pig?"
She says, "This is a duck." He
says, "I was talking to the duck."
I was talking to the duck!
I think you're dangerous.
A real loose cannon. If it was up to me
we'd put you down, so make no mistakes.
I'm telling you, if you cross on
a red light, you are worm bait.
Entiende?
'Bye.
I was talking to the duck.
Your name's Claudia Doran. You're from
Chicago. You live in Venice, California.
You're a computer expert for Super Mac.
You travel a lot.
Here's your passport, driver's
license, birth certificate.
There's cash in here to
buy yourself a new car.
Your code name is Nina.
As in Nina Simone?
Yeah.
I'm scared.
You?
That'll be the day.
Go on.
I warned you.
It needs a lot of work!
That's not a urine stain.
It's fully..
Actually, there's another one
that's closer to being done.
I'll take it.
All right.
Here's your..
ravioli.
And your ravioli.
And your..
oh, my goodness, it's ravioli.
Thanks.
Cammie Swiss Cake Rolls. Now
that sounds nutritious.
Sorry. I suppose it's embarrassing to have
some fool pawing through your food.
Don't worry about it. I
don't get embarrassed.
What do you mean?
Just, nothing embarrasses me.
You mean, ever?
That's great! You'll have
to teach me that trick.
Where're you from?
- It's not a trick question.
- Chicago.
I'm from Denver.
So I know you're from Chicago,
and you love ravioli.
That's a start.
So how does someone get
to know you better?
For you, it'd be easy.
Then have dinner
with me tonight.
Okay.
Let me guess..
Ravioli?
It's a deal.
All I have to do is show any
apartment that's vacant..
change some light bulbs, sweep
the stairs once a week..
pick up rent checks. For that..
half off my own rent.
Mostly what I do, though,
is work on my portfolio.
I'm a photographer.
I take some good
stuff sometimes.
I've sold to some galleries.
Weston and Levinson's, you know?
All day, though, all
I do is run around..
and just take care of stuff.
You really like ravioli, huh?
I usually make the first move.
This is fine, too.
This is hard.
Shut up and finish it.
- It's hard as hell.
- Shut up and finish it.
Let's go out, get a hamburger..
Shut up and finish it.
I'll call Ned and Karen and
see if they want to come.
Sure.
You don't really like
them much, do you?
They're okay.
Why don't you ask
somebody sometime?
Like who?
I don't know.
A friend. One of your buddies.
Somebody you like to hang around with.
You haven't had one person in
this place in four months.
I know.
Not one.
'Cause I want only you.
You're so guarded.
I'm not guarded.
- Yes, you are.
- No, I'm not.
You're like living with a ghost.
You never tell me anything.
All right. So, then..
what do you want to know?
I don't know. I want to know what
your fifth-grade teacher was like.
I want to know if this pretty face
had pimples on it in high school.
I want to meet your
friends from work.
I want to know why you listen to Nina
Simone when you're in a bad mood.
Forget it.
My mother loved Nina Simone.
She used to play her
records all the time.
I grew up listening
to this music.
It..
sounded so..
passionate..
so savage.
All about love and loss.
I play Nina Simone when I
think about my mother.
- Hello?
- Nina?
J.W. Marriott in Century City.
Personnel entrance. One hour.
All right.
'Bye.
Who's that?
I'm about to lose a sale
on 500 video cards.
I gotta go all the
way to El Segundo.
Hurry back.
I will.
Excuse me.
What do I do?
Change.
Now what?
Now we wait.
Testing, one.. two.. three.
Good morning. Room service.
Certainly. About 15 minutes. Yes, sir.
Thank you for calling.
- What do I do?
- Take this tray where I tell you.
- Then?
- Nothing.
You take the tray up, give him the
tray and you come back down here.
That too much for you?
Thanks.
Now what do I do?
Go home.
That's it?
So?
How are you?
I just blew up a hotel. How
the hell do you think I am?
Everybody at headquarters,
especially Kaufman, is very happy.
I just thought you'd
like to know that.
Fabulous.
So, I hear you've met somebody.
What's he like?
He's really great.
I never would've met him
if it hadn't been for you.
I have to meet him.
What?
Yeah. It's just a
routine checkup.
- I can't.
- Just invite me to dinner, okay?
No.
Just invite me to dinner.
Uncle Bob!
You must be J.P.
You shouldn't.
You should've.
Come on.
It's such a pleasure to meet you.
I haven't met any of her family.
Claudia.
Long time no see.
Uncle Bob.
You look..
great! Really great!
Thanks.
- Can we get you..
- Something to drink?
Scotch. Scotch would be nice.
Here. These are from Uncle Bob.
Great!
She looks really beautiful.
Must be something
to do with you.
It is.
You know, you're older
than I thought.
I bet you're not the youngest
photographer in town.
That's true.
But the other guys are just out of
high school.They have no experience.
He may not be the youngest, but
he's certainly the cutest.
So..
How old are you, Uncle Bob?
I'm..
37.
So that makes you..
Thirteen years older.
It's funny. The other day I was
reading something, it was really..
It's actually closer to 14. Her
birthday's in three months.
What exactly is
your point, P.J.?
J.P.
You guys!
Wait a minute.
Easy. Why don't you just arm-wrestle
right now and get it over with?
What was she like as a child?
I ask her all the time. She never talks
about herself. No details, nothing.
- Let me see.
- What?
He just wanted to know what you
were like when you were a little girl.
You promised.
- She hates questions.
- Do I ask you questions?
No, I wish you would, though.
- Can't we just drop it?
- Not this time.
Don't you fucking get it? I
don't want to talk about it!
I didn't drag my ass from the gutter
in Kansas City to take shit from you!
I thought you were from Chicago.
Kansas City.
She was born in Kansas City
but raised in Chicago.
I used to see her during the
summers on my uncle's farm.
You didn't know she spent
summers on a farm, did you?
Well, she did.
I remember one summer..
the local kids..
the kids' family
owned this mare.
She was..
black as a raven's wing, completely wild.
Remember? They called her Beauty.
She was trained as a trotter, but
she'd never really been ridden.
Anyway..
The kids told Claudia that
she had to ride Beauty..
that it was like an initiation, a
kind of thing they all had to do.
Anyway, one day, I remember..
about noon..
it was really, really hot.
We heard this scream.
We ran outside.
There was Claudia.
Claudia..
bareback on this wild horse.
The horse went completely crazy.
Bucked, reared.
She hung on.
She just gritted her
teeth, dug her heels in..
and she hung on.
By God, she rode that horse.
I guess that's how I
remember her really.
This slip of a girl on
a wild black horse.
She was so beautiful.
She was so beautiful
that she gleamed.
Do you know what I mean?
That's really you.
That's what I'd have
thought you'd be like.
By the way..
did Claudia tell you what I do?
No.
I'm in the travel business.
I'm a partner in a
travel agency and..
I've got these two tickets here,
if you'd like to take them.
They're for New Orleans
for the Mardi Gras.
Thought you might like to go.
You're so sweet.
I'll enjoy thinking
of both of you there.
I will.
- I'm hungry!
- We gotta get out of here!
We gotta go!
Let's go to the hotel!
Wait! Let's try here!
Down here!
Can't we just eat here?
Food's crappy. I know that
place is just down here.
You better be right.
It's right over here.
What do you want?
We want your money.
Maybe you could help us out
with something to eat.
Me and my friend,
we real hungry now.
That's real good but we
want all your money.
Go to hell.
Come on!
- What the hell was that?
- I don't know.
You beat the hell out of them.
You didn't even give me a chance.
It was just a reflex.
You've got some reflexes!
Where'd you learn how to do that?
I don't know.
I took a self-defense class
once when I was just a girl.
I'm so hungry!
I gotta have food.
What is it? It's five, right?
- Room service. May I help you?
- Hello?
This is Room 30.
I'd like to order
some food, please.
Could I have a couple
of chicken salads..
and a couple of
pieces of pecan pie..
and what kind of
soda do you have?
All right, then. I
guess I'll have..
I'll take Pepsi.
Can I have four cans of that,
because we get thirsty after sex?
Kiss my neck.
Okay.
Kiss it harder.
Yes?
Nina?
The bathroom cabinet has
a hidden compartment.
All right.
Then make it two pieces
of chocolate-rum cake.
They're all out of pecan pie.
Okay, we're out of this joint.
I gotta take a bath.
I feel really dirty.
If you could just wait for
room service, please.
Nina in position.
First item's under the sink.
- Assembly completed.
- Open the window.
- There's no handle.
- Claudia?
- Yeah?
You know what I've
been thinking?
What?
I've got a really good idea.
Just thinking we could make Bob's
present an engagement present.
Save the poor slob some money.
Okay.
What do you say, you want to do it?
Make it formal?
Honey?
The limousine.
Take aim on the limousine.
We're waiting for
further instructions.
I asked you a question.
Don't I deserve an answer?
In a minute.
It's how I always imagined it.
Proposing through a door.
Christ! What is it with you?
Say something.
Say, "Go to hell, J.P."
Tell me you love me..
or "Get lost" or whatever.
Just answer me, okay?
Room service.
- How many targets?
- One.
- What's he look like?
- I haven't been informed yet.
How're you enjoying our
beautiful Mardi Gras?
Real well.
Target visible in five seconds.
- Thanks.
- Y'all come back and see us, you hear?
Which one is it?
I don't have that data yet.
You've got nothing to say to me?
Which target, dammit?
The woman.
The woman in white.
The woman in white, I said.
The fucking woman!
What is with you?
What the hell's going on?
What's this?
You've got nothing to say to me?
A while ago, I did
something really bad.
I came through it, but I'm
always gonna be paying for it.
It's okay.
It's in the past.
You can just let it go.
I can't.
But you've got to believe me.
If I'm secretive..
I've got my reasons.
For now, I'll take that.
For now.
Students, this is a defensive tactic.
Watch me.
So how was New Orleans?
Everything you touch
turns to shit.
Why'd you send me on a job with J.P.?
What happens to him if he finds out?
I know it wasn't an easy job.
You're so pathetic.
Listen to you.
You stand there with that little smile.
Drop the fucking mask, for once.
Fuck you! That was my last job.
You stupid, ignorant
little girl.
You think you can decide you
don't want to play anymore?
Where the fuck do
you think you are?
Haven't you heard
anything that I've said?
- I mean it!
- You don't know what you're saying.
- I'm through! I'm out!
- Which word do you not understand?
There is no "out." There is no
"through." There is no out!
You've gotta help me.
I can't do this. I can't
live like this anymore.
Don't you like me well
enough to help me?
Like you?
I know..
you like that you made me
into something different.
But you're not looking
close enough.
I am different.
Help me be better.
Please, Bob, let me go.
You know who Fahd Bahktiar is?
He's one of the
world's richest men.
He's peddling nuclear
information to the Middle East.
I need a woman for this one. It's the
kind of job you were trained for.
I want you to do three things.
Number One:
Impersonate his girlfriend
so you can get into his house.
Number Two:
Take the disk that he's been sending
the data on, then destroy his computer.
And number three:
I want you to take him out.
If I do this job, if
I bring this off..
will you do what you can
to help me get out?
No.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Would you take these, John?
Thanks.
Maggie! What a pleasure!
How are you?
Does anybody ever get out?
Thank you, John.
I'll do the rest.
Were you like me once? Would they
let you leave if you wanted to?
Happiness in life comes from braiding
together what one would like to have..
with what is inevitable.
Stop that shit! Stop talking
like that and answer me!
I'm sorry.
I don't want to be rude to you. You were
the only one who was nice to me here.
Please, could you tell me?
Could you just leave
if you wanted to?
Just get on a plane
and disappear?
To tell the truth, dear..
I don't know. It's a possibility
that never entered my mind.
You won't tell Bob I came?
Thank you.
- You look tired.
- I am.
- Want a back rub?
- Yeah.
- With the hypnotic fantasy oil?
All right.
On the bed.
I'll be right back.
Hello, Maggie.
These are copies of the
photos I gave you.
Amanda says that you..
dropped them.
I don't think I can do it.
If you pull this
job off for me..
I'll see what I can
do to help you.
See the upstairs corner?
That's his bedroom. Right here.
You arrive early. You do it here.
With the right wig, clothes,
attitude, you can..
look sufficiently like the
girlfriend to get into his house.
What happens to her?
Does she die, too?
Absolutely not. No
unnecessary wetworks.
Good.
Look at those earrings.
Got the buck in the walk.
I have those glasses.
- Yeah? Great.
- I'll get that brand of cigarettes.
- She's right-handed.
- Me, too.
Long cigarettes.
Is that mole real?
Not on me, it won't be.
Here we go again.
"Happy birthday to you"
They don't go out!
It won't go out.
It's heavy.
"It's heavy."
Get out of the way now.
"Get out of the way now."
There he is.
Frank, for Christ's sake, do us a
favor and put the camera away.
All right.
Let's go over it again.
We've only done it 20 times.
Look, it's tomorrow night.
This is our last chance.
Okay. We meet at 4:00
to go to Angela's.
Let's make it a quarter to.
That'll give us more time.
Hey, honey!
Uncle Bob, is it really you?
How nice to see you.
No, it can't be Uncle Bob.
It's got to be..
Aunt Pauline or Cousin Molly..
or something, right?
Wait a minute! I got it!
This must be Cindy D'Amato. Used to
work for Super Mac. Quit to get married.
Hi. How the hell are you?
What in heaven's name
have you got there?
You bought it for me, remember?
When I moved into the studio.
- Give me that nonsensical object. Give it..
- You keep away from me.
Don't you try to intimidate me.
You are not going to tell Carol.
Swear you won't!
I'll swear nothing!
- Hi.
We're from Sherry's.
Where's Francine?
Francine's sick today,
so Sherry sent us.
They said Francine was coming.
I guess they got it wrong 'cause
Francine's sick. I don't know.
Sherry sent us 'cause
Francine ate something bad.
She got sick.
I could really care less if I
did another head of hair today.
So make up your mind.
All right. Come on.
Who are these people?
Where's Francine?
Francine's sick, so we're here.
Great. Some new fucking blood.
Can you do me out here?
Sure. I can burn hair anywhere.
Is this outfit all right?
- Is the stain gone?
- Yes.
Fine. Put it in my room
with the red boots.
I want some fucking
softness around my face.
Last time Francine did me, she
slicked all my hair back..
and made me look like some
kind of fucking dyke.
Did you guys meet my friends?
This is "Stupid" and the
other one is "Stupider."
- Would you like some ginseng tea?
- No, I don't drink tea.
Francine says you love her ginseng tea.
It's great for the sex drive.
I've got no trouble
in that department.
It's really very good.
Enough with the fucking
tea, for Christ's sake.
Suit yourself.
- Do you have silk, please, for my fingers?
- Sure.
Oh, God! I'm dead!
- Let me see.
- Damn it, I'm hit!
It's okay.
Hold still. Just push it hard.
I'm calling Kaufman.
- I'm calling Kaufman.
- I can finish it. I have to!
He said if anything goes wrong,
we're supposed to call him.
It's screwed up. There are
two down and I'm hit.
How?
Okay, okay. Yes, okay.
They're calling in a cleaner.
Jesus!
We've heard reports of shots.
Did you hear anything?
I'm Victor. I'm the cleaner.
The job's gone bad, but I
think I can finish it.
This part of the job's over.
I'm the cleaner.
Where's the material?
Outside.
What's that for?
Cleaning up your shit.
Christ! What're you doing?
She's not dead.
Oh, God! Kaufman said no wetworks.
He said no wetworks. I'll call him now.
"I never did mind about the
little things."
I'll go get ready
for the next step.
- You look nice.
- Thank you.
All right, have a nice evening.
Hi, Angela.
- New driver?
- For Christ's sake, open the stupid gate!
It went off the tracks and
I called in a cleaner.
What happened?
Two down. I was afraid we'd get splashed
with shit. I told him to get it cleaned up.
- How clean?
- Down to the nap.
The cleaner's going with
your girl to Bahktiar's.
After she finishes..
he'll clean her, too.
Of course, it was me. I
heard the bloody thing.
He's upstairs. You're early.
- So sue me, stupid.
- Want a drink?
Salty Dog. Leave it down here.
I must piss.
Go to your computer, bring
up your nuclear program.
What are you going to
accomplish by this?
Do it!
Suck my dick.
Go to your computer.
Should the Arabs be the only people
not to have this technology?
Is that what you think?
Hurry up.
I cannot access the data.
Yeah, right.
The system is down.
Get around to the other
side of the desk.
I can make you very rich, beyond
anything you can imagine.
And if I say I will, I will.
I'll do it, I promise.
What's the password?
Try to imagine what a bullet
in the stomach feels like.
Peddler.
You can't park there. Move it around
to the back with the other cars.
Are you deaf? Move the car!
On the ground.
Don't be a stupid bitch. I'm
offering you anything you want.
Get on your knees, forehead to the
ground, hands behind your back.
You think killing me
will solve anything?
You think you can keep 800 million
people in the 14th century forever?
That's it. I've had it.
Be sure it's hooked up.
Wait till he gets down there.
Is there a woman down there?
There could be 20 women down there,
for all I know. The car's in a bad spot.
That's it.
You awake?
I know you are. I can tell
by the way you're breathing.
I'm so tired.
My God!
What happened to your face?
She's gone.
Where?
I don't know.
She took off empty-handed.
She didn't take any of her
clothes or even her purse.
So whoever it is you are..
just leave her alone.
Let her go.
- I can't. She's got information.
- Yeah.
Why don't you get out?
She left you a note.
Yeah?
I tore it up.
What did it say?
Can I take this?
Yeah, sure.
You like Nina?
Yeah.
I love her.
We'll miss her.
We had a bad car
wreck last night.
No, no.. no.
I have all the
information we need.
The cleaner's dead..
and the girl is..
the girl is..
the girl's dead, too.
Yeah.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326