♪ A rumor is a forest fire ♪
♪ So kill it dead ♪
♪ Or run it wild ♪
♪ We could blow this out ♪
♪ Or let it burn us up alive ♪
♪ Cannot stop
what's in my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause now I want
your body on mine ♪
♪ 'Cause when the
world's so cold ♪
♪ Somebody gotta
hold you tight ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Come run inside,
run inside my love ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Come run inside my love ♪
♪ Everyone needs
a little place to hide ♪
♪ When you're about
to blow it open wide ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Come run inside,
run inside my love ♪
♪ Run inside my love ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Come run inside,
run inside my love ♪
♪ Run inside my love ♪
♪♪
♪ Come run inside,
run inside my love ♪
Mom, I want to talk
to you about something.
Mom.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
me, too, honey.
I don't want to
make you nervous,
but Morgana Ferzari is here.
She wants to see how
you do in the shoot.
Now, don't worry.
Just be professional, okay?
I was talking about college.
- Honey, we've been through this.
- Sofia.
Yeah, Madeline, wait over there
until Farriet is ready.
Right now we have exciting
things on the table...
A modeling contract most
girls can only dream of.
All our hard work
is gonna pay off.
Yeah, but I would still love to
apply, you know, have options.
Uh, lift it up.
Okay, turn to your right.
Stop. Okay.
This... will give you options.
- The latest proofs.
- Oh, excuse me.
Um, hey, you are
coming tomorrow, right?
Darling, we can't do everything.
Graduation's important.
I know, and so is a meeting
about your contract.
Yeah, she's ready.
I'm ready.
Let's go. I'm waiting.
Oh, this is futile!
None of this is gonna work.
Fashion Week is two weeks away.
Where are my others assistants?
Huh.
If you remove the wings,
you can let the simplicity of
the dress speak for itself.
And with this burnt rouge...
bring the eye from the hemline
through the bodice,
highlighting the neckline.
What a remarkable idea.
- No, I just...
- No, no, no, no.
Why stop at one outfit?
If I knew we had
an expert in our midst,
I would have relied
on you earlier.
Morgana?
Cora Hamilton,
perhaps you should
just, uh, curate
the entire shoot.
Now, while I don't mind
letting Sofia's daughter
play dress-up,
it might be stretching
the friendship
just a tad to give her my job.
Don't you think?
Cora?
Where are you going?
The dress.
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Come run inside,
run inside my love ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Come run inside my love ♪
Stop!
Get away from me!
♪ Come run inside,
run inside my love ♪
Mom?
Um, Sofia wants to know
if you're all right.
Why can't she ask me herself?
She's on a call at the moment.
She's doing damage control.
Okay.
Happy 18th, Cora!
Sending you good vibes
from sunny Tea Tree.
Hope to see you soon.
All my love, Aunt Margot.
Did you see his shoes?
This is a general announcement.
Flight 1138 bound
for Sydney, Australia,
your departure gate
is now changed to gate 26.
What on Earth do you
think you're doing?
Do you think I wouldn't
notice a $7,000 charge
for plane tickets to Australia?
I have got a catastrophe
on my hands
that affects both
of our reputations,
and you're running away.
Was this her idea?
- Aunt Margot's?
Yeah, of course.
I'm horrible.
She's the fun surfer aunt.
You know, I've barely heard
from her since Caleb died.
No, it wasn't her idea.
It was mine.
She's always written and said
that I'm welcome
to come stay whenever,
so I took her up on the offer.
She said she'd love to see me.
What? Is that
so surprising...
Someone actually
wanting to see me?
You know, taking a genuine
interest, asking them things,
wondering what they think,
maybe listening to them?
I'm running New York's
top model agency,
one that will launch
you into a career
that will take care
of you your entire life.
Darling, I cannot give you
my attention all the time.
I don't want your attention
all of the time.
But maybe once, you could
have made an exception,
done something I wanted to do
that was important to me.
I missed most of my childhood,
missed my graduation
so I could be
where you wanted me,
when you wanted me there.
I've fit into your life,
and now I'm doing something
on my own terms.
Sweetie, I know
that you're upset,
but people like us
can't afford accidents.
This was your chance
to show Morgana
and the industry
the polished young woman
you've become,
not some melodramatic teen.
Why won't you listen to me?
Even when your daughter
is plastered on
every magazine in New York,
it's like you
still can't see me.
Cora, you can't just
always run away.
I am not running away.
I am running towards
something else, anything,
as long as it's not your idea.
Now, why don't you just go back
and do what you usually do...
Get on with your busy life
and forget about me?
♪ I got a little
secret in my heart ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your
first officer speaking.
In a few minutes,
we will be commencing
our descent into Sydney.
Cabin crew, prepare
the cabin for landing.
♪♪
♪ Outside is black and white ♪
♪ We laying color on the floor ♪
- That's her.
- No way.
Good morning, miss.
We'll be landing soon,
so here's your next
boarding pass.
It's gate 4.
Uh, I booked first class.
There's no first class
on a prop plane,
but I'm sure you'll have fun.
♪♪
We'd better get out there.
It'll be smooth as glass.
♪♪
You know, tai chi
is only beneficial
when you don't actively
work against it.
I'm not working against it.
It's working against me.
It calms the mind.
Imagine how much calmer you'd be
if you did it really quickly,
finished, and could
do something else.
You seem to be
missing the point.
You used to hate all this stuff.
The need for stillness
outweighed my ego.
Luckily, I don't have
that problem.
My life is a well-oiled machine.
All set to pick your
niece up this morning?
She doesn't get
in until tomorrow.
You said that yesterday,
and as its habit,
tomorrow is now today.
You've waited for 10 years
for her to come back,
and now you're gonna be late.
Breathe.
Cora?
Oh, my gosh! Look at you!
You're all grown up!
Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
Oh, you're moving in, huh?
Uh, got to be prepared
for anything.
All you'll need is
your bathing suit.
Jump in.
You want to drive?
Oh.
- Thanks for having me.
- Of course.
It was a wonderful surprise.
Last-minute trip, huh?
Yeah. You know, things
are so busy right now.
If you get a chance for a
holiday, you got to take it.
Well, I'm glad you did.
So, what's the plan?
Oh, uh, no plan, really.
Just kind of gonna
see what happens.
What does your mom think
about you coming to stay?
Hey, you know, she thinks
it's a great idea.
Okay. Good.
How is your mom?
She's good.
She's fine.
Just always working.
It's a shame she couldn't
come out last year.
I'm so sorry about Caleb.
Well, that's life.
I should call Sof anyway.
It's been too long.
Sof.
That's really nice, actually.
Nobody back home calls her that.
Old habits die hard.
You remember when you were
here last with your mom?
Yeah.
Mom and I made a pact
we'd come and visit
every year after that trip,
but I guess life happened.
Well, you're here now.
♪ I had my cake
and you had your doubt ♪
♪ Long gone ♪
♪ My baby's gonna carry on ♪
♪♪
Ohh.
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
You better be
the new paper boy, Owen.
Margs, I just need
you to hear me out, okay?
I want to help you.
- Oh, do you hear that, Bee?
Owen wants to help out.
You can start with the bags,
and then, you know,
the lawn needs a mow.
Sell me the surf school,
and I'll do you a good deal.
You've only got
one instructor left.
The thing is just sitting there.
We had plenty of instructors
before you started
stealing them.
And don't call me Margs.
You know how much I hate it.
Hello, little fish.
Cora, you remember
my mother-in-law, Bee?
Yes, of course.
It's very nice to see you.
You're all grown up.
Listen, they
needed the work, okay?
Things have been
drying up here for months,
and Tom's a good kid,
but you're wasting his talent
on a handful of tourists.
- How many times
do we have to have
this conversation?
- Let's get your luggage.
- Margs.
Margot.
I'm just trying to help you.
Really?
Yeah. Really.
Because I do need help.
I'm overwhelmed.
I got all these surfboards,
and some of them
have a leg rope.
And I know it's called
a leg rope,
but do I put it on my leg
or my ankle?
And wet suits...
I know they get wet,
but sometimes they're dry.
What does it all mean, Owen?
Right.
Okay. I'm done.
Everyone, I tried.
I'm done.
You have a nice visit, Cora.
- Hi.
- You're taller.
See you later, Bee.
I'm sorry, hon.
Just ignore him.
Ignore them both.
A heads up would have been nice.
You don't have a mobile phone.
What was I supposed to do?
Send a pigeon?
I was gonna clean up today.
Oh.
Your place is very Boho-Chic.
It's not bad for
a couple of surfers, I guess.
Your aunt took out
the world championship
the year you were born.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And twice after that.
Margot is a world record holder.
I'm sure her mom has
bored her with that already.
Um, no, actually.
She has not.
I better get going.
This surf festival
is doing my nut.
All those geriatrics
organizing events.
Someone is gonna
pop their clogs.
I'll leave you to it.
Have fun.
- Okay.
Bye.
Uh, what's the festival?
Oh, well, surfing is
a way of life around here,
and this year is 100 years
since Bee's grandmother
paddled out
and surfed with the boys.
Violet was a bit
of a trailblazer.
So they're throwing her a party.
That's pretty cool.
Yeah. It is.
Now, come on.
Let's get you to your room.
Uh, okay.
Nothing much has changed.
Your drawings are
still on the wall.
And I found some of
your kids' books.
I better get that.
Uh, the bathroom
is down the hall.
The blue towels are yours.
Make yourself at home.
Hello?
How are you?
Why are you knocking?
You usually just walk in.
You have a guest.
Well, should I ask what that is?
It's a welcome gift.
You know, the ocean, sunshine,
"Welcome to Australia."
You're gonna give a girl
from New York a dead fish?
Well, now it seems weird.
Oh! You're purdy.
Owen dropped by
this morning.
- Again?
- Uh-huh.
Margot, you have a girl creeping
outside of your bathroom.
Oh, that's Chicka. She popped
in for lunch post-surf.
- 'Sup?
- Cora, this is Chicka,
who thinks my house is a hotel.
I ate your sandwich.
Sorry.
- And this is Tom...
Blue Soul's surf instructor.
- How you going?
- H-How am I going where?
Did you want a coffee?
Yes, please.
Oh. Okay.
Belinda, no, no, no, no, no.
No chickens in the kitchen.
Oh!
Honey, honey.
- Can you...? Thank you.
- N... uh.
- Yeah.
- Okay, it's...
- So, what did Owen want?
- Oh, the usual.
He wants to buy Blue Soul Surf,
the kit, you, our contracts.
- And what did you say?
- She said yes.
Owen's your father now.
I said no.
Cora, did you want to, you know,
check out the rock pools?
You used to love them
when you were a kid.
Oh, uh, thank you,
but I should actually
really check in back home.
Um, what's your Wi-Fi?
What?
Margot doesn't
have the Internet.
Doesn't have the Internet?
Like, i-is that 'cause you
call it something else...
Kangaroo line or something?
No, I'm just not great
with things like that.
Things like the 21st century?
It's nice not having
to be connected
to the rest of the world
when I'm at home.
It helps my Zen.
Zen?
But Tom set up Wi-Fi
at Blue Soul,
so you can, you know, pop down
there whenever you like.
Great. Yeah.
Uh, I'll just... I'll go change.
Are you gonna get changed, too?
'Cause I'm just gonna wear this.
Popping candy?
Every time I eat them, I just...
I imagine a bunch of guys
in suits in a boardroom
surrounded by takeaway boxes.
They're tired,
but then this one guy
slams his hand on the desk,
and he says, "I got it!
A candy that when you eat it
makes the sound
of frying onions!"
Then the other guys
are like, "Wow!
Yes! Good idea, Steve!"
Oh, I just... just
love popping candy.
So, who are you talking to?
I'm not talking to anyone.
Margot says you're
a bit of a fashionista.
Yeah, yeah,
I'm a model, actually.
Sweet.
I know a guy in New York.
His name's Patrick.
You know him?
There are over 8 million
people in New York.
Mm-hmm.
He always wears a hat.
No.
I'll let you get back
to your mates.
Hey, Mom.
I think I really focused up
on the plane here.
So, um...
I've just been...
I've been feeling...
I just...
Why don't you give me
a call when you get this?
You've reached
the office of Sofia Hamilton,
New York's premiere
modeling agent.
Please leave a message.
Everything all right?
Yeah. Fine. Just tired.
Max... e-mail...
Is okay with your short list
for Wednesday's job.
- No response.
- Jennifer...
Cellphone voicemail... wants...
- Anything from Cora?
No. Nothing from Cora.
What else?
Dobrovski...
Cellphone text...
"Moved meeting
to Tuesday morning."
You're free.
- Book it in.
What's wrong?
Something's bothering Cora.
I think a code coconut
is in order.
Well...
We'll need helmets.
Chicka was definitely
concussed last time.
Batter up!
- They can't be serious.
- Come on!
- Whoo!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah!
You can't be serious!
Whoa!
What am I supposed to do?
You've got a bat, woman.
Hit it.
You could have killed me.
It's all right.
We've got helmets on.
Eye on the coconut.
It'll make you feel better.
I promise.
Aim to hit it from underneath.
- Better about what?
Better about whatever you need
to feel better about.
Now, go low!
She's gonna lollipop it!
- Go!
- Whoo!
Come on!
♪ You run ♪
♪ You run from me ♪
Whoo-hoo!
♪♪
♪ You run from me ♪
♪ You run ♪
♪♪
♪ 'Cause I ♪
♪ 'Cause I know ♪
♪ You run, you run,
you run from me ♪
Come on.
It's time for the best part!
- Whoo!
- Catch you later!
Uh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Come on!
What about sharks or jellyfish?
When's the last time
you went swimming?
In the ocean?
As a kid.
The last time
I was here, probably.
Well, then, it's about time.
It's nice as!
The air's different here.
I mean, it's, like, perfume.
It's a bit different
from New York, huh?
Margot said you model.
Yeah, yeah.
Teen fashion, mostly,
but Mom's been
training me for editorial.
Training? How hard can it be?
- Chicka.
- What?
You just lie around in clothes.
I do that all the time.
I'm doing it right now.
Yeah, it's... it's okay.
A lot of people think it's easy.
It actually requires
a surprising amount of work.
Sof must be very proud of you.
Yeah, well...
I might take a break from...
modeling soon, anyway.
Yeah, I don't blame you.
That video was pretty mean.
I mean...
It wasn't that bad.
Yeah, look, there are
a lot of people
who work really hard
to get the cover shoot.
If you make one mistake,
even if it's a little one,
it's the end of the world.
You know, it seems like you're
the most important person
in the room.
In actuality, you're nobody.
You can't be perfect
all the time.
I know a thing or two
about making mistakes
in front of a critical audience.
Oh, yeah.
Like that time you wiped out
in the Wahine's Women's Open.
- Chicka.
What? It was in the heats,
not even the final,
and she just, like,
completely ate it.
Thank you.
I forgot about that.
I did wipe out more than once.
Mm-hmm.
But every time I made a mistake,
I learned something...
Something about my technique
or my attitude,
who to trust.
Exactly.
And who cares what
those fancy pantses
in New York think, anyway?
I know it sounds silly,
but where I come from,
the fashion that we wear,
it's... it's just art.
It's pure art.
You should see what
these designers do.
They don't just buy fabrics
and follow a pattern.
I mean, they're architects.
They... They research,
and they're always
hunting down new materials
and seeking out ways to make it
all come together, you know?
You sound very passionate.
Yeah, I mean, it's
just my observations.
Here's an idea... Why don't you
two go for a surf tomorrow?
It's gonna be a beautiful day.
Sweet.
Yeah, let's do it.
I can't surf.
Oh, well, that's all right.
Neither could I before
I went out the first time.
Up.
Upright. Okay.
Move this back foot.
Breathe in.
Feel the movement of the water.
You are a part of the sea.
You are the current.
You are a jellyfish.
You are at one with the ocean.
You're a dolphin.
I don't think this is working.
Oh, well, this is
how Margot taught me.
Yeah, speaking of Margot,
maybe she can come out
with us next time.
Open your eyes!
And go, Cora! Go!
Paddle! Paddle!
Yeah, girl!
Whoo! Go, Cora!
- Hello?
- Margot.
Sof.
Hey, uh, how are you?
Fine.
Well, as fine as you can be
when your daughter skips town.
Oh, I thought as much.
Didn't seem like you to push
for a last-minute holiday.
I haven't heard
from you in a while.
I have tried to call.
Did you get the flowers
I sent for...
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
Thanks.
I meant to call back,
but, well, you know...
So, Cora grew up.
She's great, Sof.
She's... She's gorgeous.
Yeah, she is.
Is she all right?
Not getting in your way?
No, no, no, no. Not at all.
I mean, she was...
She was a bit out of sorts
when she arrived,
but actually,
she's out surfing right now.
- Wow. That sounds dangerous.
- It's strange.
It's kind of like having
my teen sister back again.
How's your, uh...
How's your work?
Uh, busy. How about you?
Yeah, yeah, tied up
with things here.
So, have you sold Blue Soul?
Why would I do that?
I thought
it wasn't going so well.
You don't know how
it's going, actually.
It's just basic
business principle.
It doesn't have to be personal.
Of course it's personal.
Isn't that why you deigned
to visit us last time?
Because you were
struggling with work,
and you needed a break?
Because sometimes it's personal.
I'm sorry to cut this short,
but I'm being hassled
by my next appointment.
I just wanted to see
if Cora was all right.
I'm glad she's okay and that
you're both having fun together.
I'll talk to you later.
Okay. Sof, I...
Sof?
Cora. You're doing well.
I think Chicka's
trying to kill me
and make it look
like an accident.
I've seen worse first attempts.
Well, thanks.
Who are they?
- Wave Masters.
Only other surf school
in Tea Tree.
Come on, guys. Let's go.
Come on.
All right, grab it now.
Now, let's move it, move it.
Come on, guys. Follow me.
We're heading down to the beach.
Let's go, go, go.
Hey, that guy was
at Margot's the other day.
Yeah, Owen.
He's been trying to get Margot
to sell for a while.
She's having none of it.
You want to boost my numbers?
Join my lesson tomorrow?
Tell you what, if Chicka
gets taken by a shark,
you will be my first call.
Before you say anything,
this wasn't my idea.
I didn't want to be the head
of the festival committee.
No, Frank, we are not having
a Guess Your Weight stand.
Why not?
Beryl, how much do you weigh?
- Excuse me.
- That's why.
I thought Dolores was
head of the committee.
Well, she was until she had
the nerve to jump ship.
- Dolores has moved?
- She's on holiday.
She's in Cairns.
The details are not important.
We just have to band together,
and if I'm stuck with them,
you're stuck with them.
What's wrong with your house?
Darling!
Wonderful!
We need your fashion eye.
This is the one
I was talking about.
She works in fashion
in New York.
We are putting together
a vintage swimsuit display
that spans 100 years.
What do you think?
We can't get it to work.
It's not supposed
to hang like a sack.
Yeah, uh, I don't
really do this, so...
I'll... I'll let you guys to it.
- No, no, no, no.
Don't you worry about
hurting our feelings.
What do you think?
I mean, honestly?
Yes, yes, darling.
Hmm.
Ready, Mommy?
To begin, I'm gonna need
a sewing machine.
Now, the idea is to show
different eras
of swim wear fashion,
but all ideas are welcome.
Aha! Here we go.
Ohh! Now...
this was Grandma Violet's,
given to me by my mother,
and now I'm giving it to you.
- Ohh! Ohh!
- Careful.
Have fun with it.
Go wild.
- Yeah.
No one's ever really asked
for my opinion before.
More fool them.
Do you got it?
- Yeah.
- Shall I help?
- No. Arm day.
All right, I'll stand behind
you in case you drop it.
Ah, she's flying.
It's beautiful.
It's like a dance.
It's 'cause
they're working together...
Surfer and the sea.
Can't tell with the wave ends
and she begins.
♪♪
First thing... We're gonna need
some awesome surfer girls.
Can you help me with that?
Yeah. You're looking
at one, sister.
Second...
Can you keep a secret?
Sealed.
♪ Yes, I'll come back to you ♪
♪ No, I won't ask
where you run ♪
♪ Under the sun ♪
♪ Yes, I'll come back to you ♪
♪ Then I'll ask,
"What have we done?" ♪
♪ Under the sun ♪
♪♪
♪ To be free, be awake ♪
♪ Big breath
that you can't fake ♪
♪ Once you've begun ♪
♪ On the right side,
coming on the right time ♪
♪ On the right time,
coming on the right side ♪
♪ On the right side,
coming on the right time ♪
♪ On the right time,
coming on the right side ♪
♪♪
Thought this might get
the creative juices flowing.
These are really good.
Thank you.
Do you see them
in your head first
and then draw it,
or does it just happen?
Yeah, yeah,
I see them in my head.
Well... Or I feel it, actually.
- Feel it?
- Yeah.
I imagine what it would feel
like if I was wearing it.
Hello?
Whoa! And goodbye.
Chicka, wait.
Come here.
I need you to be my model.
What?
Little, old me?
I thought you'd never ask.
It's, uh, nice.
It's not exactly
what I was going for.
Hmm...
Maybe if I strike a pose.
Ohh! Sorry!
We need functionality,
not just aesthetics.
I could skate down the runway.
Whoo!
- No!
- Aah!
♪♪
Need a hand?
No.
Thank you.
We have a, uh...
A certain percentage of...
Of customers that will
only seem to book once.
Is that a statement,
or do you want my opinion?
Well, you've never been one
to keep your opinion
to yourself.
Well, in that case,
maybe you should stop
running your lessons
like a military exercise
and let people have some fun.
That's all fun and games until
someone runs out of business.
What is this?
What is it?
This music...
I'm nearly falling asleep here.
It's the blues.
Yeah, I'll say. Shocking.
Oh, here we go.
You're gonna like this.
That's better.
We never have,
and we never will
agree on music.
Mm-hmm.
Come on.
No. The '90s are over.
You need to let them go, Owen.
Come on.
♪♪
We had some good times...
You, me, and Caleb.
Yeah.
We were pretty blessed.
Sometimes I feel like he's...
I feel like he's slipping away.
He's still out there, Margs.
I feel him every time
I paddle out.
♪♪
Hold your horses, kiddo.
Oh, hey. Just gonna
go catch up to Margot.
Why don't you put
these on instead?
We... I would, but she's...
Margot isn't gonna
go for a surf.
Uh, she just walked down.
I just saw her.
Well, that's true,
but she won't go out.
What's she doing, then?
The same thing she's done
every day for the last year.
She doesn't go
in the water anymore.
Wait, she... she hasn't
surfed in a year?
I thought she was
a pro surfer... the trophies.
Well, she is, darling.
That... That doesn't make sense.
Sometimes
when we're hurting,
the last thing we want to do
is what will make us
feel better.
Is she scared because of
what happened to Caleb?
When I was a kid,
we had this big,
old eucalyptus tree
in the garden.
It was beautiful.
It had a little magpie in it,
and every morning,
it would warble away.
For five years,
I was sent to school
to the sound of that
happy, little fellow.
One day, my father got an ax,
and he chopped the tree down.
I was devastated.
No more branches to cast
shadows on the wall.
No more Mr. Magpie.
We got a pool...
An above-ground monstrosity.
Well, it was so hot
the pavements were melting,
and I still refused
to get in it.
Why did you hate the pool?
Because if I'd got in the pool,
it would be like I was okay
with the tree being gone,
and I wasn't.
I was still angry.
But I realized there were
things to be happy about,
and that put the sad
things into perspective.
Things happen and they change us
and we can't control that.
What you can control
is how they change you.
I'm sorry about Caleb.
And about your tree.
Oh, don't be.
Now, 4:00 p.m. tomorrow,
Chicka says
she's lined up some girls
for the fitting.
Oh, yeah. Uh...
You'll be fine.
Walk this way.
Now... Now, come over
here to me,
and you see up here?
That's what I'm doing.
You just nip those off.
Cora! Whoo!
- Hey.
- Hey!
Yeah!
- Okay.
Ooh, check it out, girls.
I thought we were
getting bikinis.
No, uh, bikinis weren't
invented until the '40s.
Your outfit is inspired
by the Edwardian Era.
Ta-da!
What are you doing?
It's heaps better.
Now you can see my legs.
Oh, is it? Is it heaps better?
Well, is there anything else
you'd like to make heaps better?
No. What? No.
I didn't realize
Tea Tree Beach was home
to such a fashion expert.
Uh, I just thought that...
Why don't you take over
and design the whole thing?
Come on, Cora.
She didn't mean to upset you.
Dressing up is
supposed to be fun.
You think this is
just dress-up?
What's her problem?
Ah!
What's going on in there?
She ruined my design.
And talking to her like
that's gonna fix it?
She hacked it to pieces.
Well, I don't know.
Does she have a point?
A point?
It's like you people
don't know anything
about beauty or design.
"You people."
It's these people
that have embraced you
and asked you to help out
with their festival.
What have your people
done for you, Cora?
Pushed you around,
spread rumors about you?
You're right. My people
are nothing like your people.
And I'm fine with that.
Thanks,
but I'm not hungry.
Well, I'll just leave
it here, then.
Aunt Margot, did you
and Caleb ever fight?
Never.
Yes.
Oh, all the time.
Blue Soul nearly killed us
more than once.
Why do you keep
running it, then?
It's all I have left of him.
Is that why you hate Owen?
I don't hate Owen.
The three of us
were great friends.
Owen was there surfing
with Caleb the day that he died.
I heard the fitting
didn't go so well.
Ugh! Yeah.
I kind of lost it.
- You're passionate.
Don't apologize for that.
You just need a bit of patience.
I don't know.
I-I constantly just feel like
I'm saying the wrong thing.
It takes courage
to speak your mind.
Our family makes strong women,
and you're one of them.
Be proud of that.
That chicken.
Belinda! No!
Out, out, out,
or I will cook you!
♪♪
Chicka. Hey.
I owe you an apology.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
You were real mad.
I thought you might explode
into a thousand pieces.
I know.
Do you think the others
might forgive me?
We're going out to surf soon
if you want to join.
Yeah, I'd love to.
You looking for Tom?
He's on the beach.
And don't worry.
He's not one to
bear grudges, either.
Here.
Thank you.
Hey.
They won't hurt you.
Whoo.
They're beautiful.
Whose are they?
Don't know.
Hey, listen, I was thinking,
and I might bring out
a line of bikinis, after all.
That's a shame.
Kind of liked
the knee-length look.
♪♪
Hello?
Hey.
This place is incredible.
These boards are amazing.
Margot really wouldn't
like you being in here.
This is so beautiful.
I almost thought
it would have a heartbeat.
It's not finished.
I need to, um...
It needs to be finished.
Wait, is this place yours?
This was Caleb's workshop.
Those are his boards.
This one is mine.
Wait, you design boards?
You never asked.
So, how come you haven't
finished it, then?
Can we come out of here?
Yeah.
Nice to have you home.
Mm-hmm.
It's good to be back.
Are you sure?
Sometimes I think
you prefer touring.
Are you fishing for something?
I'm proud of you.
Those waves in Indo...
They were big.
Mm.
And to be honest...
I was really worried about you.
You know if it's up to me,
I will always come home.
My wife,
out taming monster waves.
I love you.
♪♪
Ow! Belinda!
No, no, no.
Oh, no,
you're not doing that today.
Chicka, I really want to.
Oh, but the surf's too good!
And everyone's out.
Even some by the name of Thomas.
Hmm...
Well, we better get going, then.
Let's go.
♪♪
Um, this is very isolated.
Should I be worried?
No. It is a bit weird
around here, though.
When I was a kid, I thought
a witch lived in these rocks.
My brothers told me
stories about her...
How she drowned sailors
and rode whales
to the bottom of the sea.
Have you told me that before?
Don't think so.
It's cool, huh?
Cora Hamilton!
So, you still want
to make boards?
Sort of forgotten
about them, to be honest.
I haven't been in the workshop
for about a year.
Do you miss it?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
I love starting with nothing
and seeing it sort of reveal...
Reveal itself to you.
Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
I don't know.
It kind of seemed
like he was in there
waiting to be finished.
- Who?
- Your unfinished board.
It's like he was just in there,
waiting for you to come back
in and finish him up.
It's a "he," is he?
Well, yeah.
Well, a woman wouldn't
wait around like that.
You did that.
What?
You don't remember, do you?
Wait, that was you?
You were that annoying boy
that I used to chase around?
Yes!
- So I have been here before.
- Mm-hmm.
And you've told me
that story before.
You tried to scare me
with the witch.
Bet you can't catch me anymore.
Okay.
Huh.
So a guy can wait around, then.
I wasn't waiting for
you to come back,
but I'm glad you did.
Hello, you've reached 1955.
There's no Internet
but great gas prices.
Darling, it's me.
- Mom?
- How are you?
- Good. Great.
- That's good.
It's lovely to hear your voice.
Yeah. Yours, too.
I have to
say the apartment
is very quiet without you.
But I have some
very exciting news.
What's up?
Well, I've been
working like a dog
to get you that contract,
and guess what.
Morgana wants you to launch her
upcoming New York campaign.
So, uh, wait,
what does this mean?
This means
you have a new chance,
and I think your trip
to Australia has
actually been a good thing
for both of us...
A new perspective, some time
away to work things out.
But you'll need to come home
as soon as possible.
Lily is booking flights
as we speak.
We can get you
on a plane tonight.
Wh... Tonight?
Th... That's so soon. I-I can't.
Morgana wants
to see you on Tuesday.
Look, I'm sure
the schedule is tight,
but there's this festival...
This is a chance for you
to wipe your slate clean,
and I want to help you do that.
Lily will send through
the flight details.
Oh, my appointment's here.
I got to run.
Call me on your way
to the airport.
Bye, darling.
I can't believe this.
What?
That I actually thought that
I could stay here, have this.
Have what?
That was my mom.
My modeling contract's back on,
so I have to go
back to New York.
You're leaving?
I was always gonna have
to leave eventually.
You... You get some
modeling thing and you...
You go?
It's not just
some modeling thing.
I mean, it's...
It's a really big contract.
You know...
If that's what you want.
I've worked years for this.
I thought modeling
made you unhappy.
It does. Sometimes. But...
- But what?
- I'm not like you.
I can't just give up
a good opportunity
because it got too hard.
What does that mean?
It means the keys
aren't locked up, Tom.
Okay, nothing is stopping you
from going in there
and finishing that board.
Tom.
Hey. What's wrong?
I got the contract
with Morgana Ferzari.
Well, congratulations.
But what about design?
I'm really sick of people
telling me what is
and is not my dream,
especially when no one here
has the courage to actually
do what they love.
I'm just saying don't be afraid
to do the thing
that's gonna make you happy.
Yeah, says the pro surfer
who doesn't even surf.
Look, I walk around
this place and Blue Soul,
and it's like I can
almost still feel Caleb.
But it's this dark
and sad version of him.
It's so heavy. No wonder you're
afraid to get in the water.
You'll probably sink.
I lost my husband.
Yeah, you don't want
to sell the school,
but you don't want to run it.
You don't want Tom
to work with Owen,
but you don't want him
to work for you.
It's like you're stuck.
Why don't you look around
and see all of the people
who are willing to be
stuck with you?
Whoa. Sorry, miss.
This is way too heavy.
You can't take this.
We got to go.
Miss, we've a storm
front coming in.
Are you on or off?
What do you want?
Margot!
Margot?
Wait, Tom.
I couldn't do it.
I couldn't go.
I'm so scared
because I feel like
I may have just ruined
the best things I've ever had.
You haven't ruined it.
I've got to go check the boats.
There's a storm coming.
Can you find Margot, tell her
I'll meet her at Blue Soul?
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm?
Margot.
Her board.
I love you.
♪♪
Caleb.
Margot!
♪♪
Are you sure?
So she didn't even
board the plane?
Yeah, I see.
Yes, I will notify Morgana.
Yeah, good night.
- Ready, mommy?
- We're ready.
It's going to be
my new party dress.
Wow, darling,
it's certainly unique.
It's wonderful.
You're so creative, Cora.
Is that sticky tape?
Yep, and I used staples, too.
It's perfect.
Can you make me one?
- But you're a giant.
Now, come on, model it
for us. Come on, darling.
Keep your shoulders
back and chin up.
Chin up.
Look like you're having fun.
Smile, Cora. Smile.
You beam when you smile.
I just wanted to show
you what I made.
And it's fabulous.
Sof, I don't think she wants to.
Do it properly.
Cora, do it like we practiced.
Walk like this.
Here. Copy me.
Good girl.
Oh, you pretty girl.
I don't want to do it anymore.
I didn't think I would ever
be ready to say goodbye.
I'm surrounded by
people who love me
and this life that
we built together.
And I'm gonna be okay.
So I'm letting you go, honey.
♪♪
Okay, girls,
time to get dressed up.
Chicka, boards sorted?
- Yes.
- And no one saw you?
- None.
Ooh, except for Belinda,
but we have an understanding.
Ladies and gentlemen,
girls and boys,
welcome to the main event...
The vintage fashion show
designed by Cora Hamilton.
Take it away!
Okay. Just have fun.
♪ And if I close my eyes ♪
♪ I can taste it,
can't erase it ♪
♪ Some things are
meant to last forever ♪
♪ Some hearts, they burn
like a wildfire, wildfire ♪
♪ Keep wishing
I could set it free ♪
♪ Some things you
can't release ♪
♪ Burning, burning like
a wildfire, wildfire ♪
♪♪
♪ Keep wishing
I could set it free ♪
♪♪
♪ Keep wishing
I could set it free ♪
♪ We live forever
in my fantasy ♪
♪ Boys like you,
and girls like me ♪
♪ Can't find the words and ♪
♪ I can't escape it ♪
♪ Boys like you ♪
♪ And girls like me ♪
♪ And when you held my hand ♪
♪ Electricity was raining down ♪
♪ Can you hear that sound ♪
♪ Light a match,
we're burning up this town ♪
♪ And if I close my eyes ♪
♪ I can taste it,
can't erase it ♪
♪♪
♪ Some things are meant
to last forever ♪
♪ Some hearts, they burn
like a wildfire, wildfire ♪
♪ Keep wishing
I could set it free ♪
♪ Some things you
can't release ♪
♪ Burning, burning like
a wildfire, wildfire ♪
♪♪
All right, girls, are you ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
♪ Keep wishing
I could set it free ♪
♪ Another time, another place ♪
♪ I see your eyes
in a stranger's face ♪
♪ And I'm frozen ♪
♪ Frozen, frozen ♪
♪ How could we know? ♪
♪ How could we see? ♪
♪ How beautiful
that this could be ♪
♪ I'm frozen, frozen,
frozen, frozen ♪
♪♪
♪ Some things are meant
to last forever ♪
♪ Some hearts, they burn
like a wildfire, wildfire ♪
♪ Some hearts are meant
to last together ♪
♪ Some hearts, they burn
like a wildfire, wildfire ♪
What are you doing here?
I came to apologize.
For not listening to you
when you needed to be heard.
Mom, my heart isn't
in modeling anymore.
But that doesn't mean
that I don't love you
and appreciate everything
you've done for me.
When someone runs headlong
into the ocean during a storm,
rather than getting on a plane
to fame and fortune,
I guess they're trying
to tell you something.
I'm so proud of you.
Deep down, I think I knew
modeling wasn't your first love.
But you're my first love.
And I wanted you to be
as close to me as possible
for as long as possible.
You know, designing's
no walk in the park.
You've just jumped from
the frying pan into the fire.
I know.
And I can't wait.
Cora!
My friend Patrick liked
your designs on Instagram!
Wait, Patrick Delamore?!
Yeah! Yeah, I told you.
He's one of the most iconic
fashion photographers
of our time.
Oh, so you do know Patty Cakes?
Hey, I'll give you his number.
Maybe he'll post
some of your clothes.
Let's go!
Sof.
What are they doing?
Something they should
have done ages ago.
Margot's selling Blue Soul?
No. They're gonna join forces.
Margot's starting a pro
surf school for women,
like she always wanted,
and Owen is taking over
the day-to-day students.
Now, close your eyes.
♪ Still I ran in the opposite ♪
It's for you.
Tom, it's beautiful.
Thank you.
- ♪ Until I realized ♪
Welcome to my workshop!
♪ Doesn't matter
where you're going ♪
♪ Baby, I'm just
making my way back to ♪
♪ Making my way back ♪
♪ Life is always ♪
♪ Just to realize ♪
So, I've been speaking
to some colleagues
about design school.
There are some great ones here.
I'm right ahead of you both.
I've already been accepted
into college.
- Congratulations!
- That's fantastic!
Yeah, I got into one
in New York and one here.
And...?
What did you choose?
Let's get out there!
Cora!
♪ Rewind ♪
♪ Then I can see your face ♪
♪♪
♪ We all want to change
this feeling ♪
♪ We're all gonna waste
♪ We all want to change
this feeling ♪
♪♪
♪ We won't ever change
this feeling ♪
♪♪
♪ Leave this feeling tonight ♪
♪ We all want to change
this feeling ♪
♪♪
♪ We won't ever change
this feeling ♪
♪♪