(haunting piano music)
(slow resonant music)
(bus engine)
(voices arguing)
(muffled arguing)
(piano music)
- [Voiceover] I read a sign
once above the rear view
mirror of my old school bus.
It said: Be kind to
everyone because everyone
is fighting some sort of battle.
- [Boy] When I grow up,
I want to help people.
(frantic medical orders)
- Will, put it at
360 and go again.
- CPR
("The Sun II" by Snakadaktal)
* Touch my mouth
* Help me sleep
* Embrace my lungs
* Your breath I keep
* Share your warmth
* Knock our teeth
* My shoulder blade
* You lay your cheek
* Scratch my arm
* Kiss your crown and hold
* Your head to mine
* And feel you breathe
* Bastille
* I could have been
* I could have been you
* Bastille
* You couldn't control
* You couldn't
control the blue *
(multiple conversations)
- See you Harry, see you at
work next week, all right?
- Who's driving?
- [Everyone] He is!
- Will? Straight home, okay?
- Thank you so much,
I've had a great time.
(rock music)
(techno dance music)
- Where's your girlfriend?
- Single. What about you?
- Just broke up.
- All right, we're out
of here, have a good one.
(haunting vocals)
* Should I do this, it was bliss
* My heart singing it was his
* Cause you changed everything
(doors closing)
(knocking on door)
- William!
William McIntyre,
it's the police.
(knocking on screen)
William McIntyre?
Constable Rossi, this is
Senior Detective Bridges.
- Do you have any
problems with us
searching your premises?
- What for?
- [Rossi] I'll
check the bedroom.
These aren't yours are they?
- They're just from work,
I ran out of my script.
- Whatever you say
may be taken down
and used in evidence,
do you understand?
- You're kidding me.
- Come on, let's go.
- Josh!
- Do you know this girl?
- Yeah. Just the other night.
- Your career is over.
- I don't know what
you're suggesting.
- [Detective] William, we're
not suggesting anything,
because we know you did it.
- Mr. Palmer.
- Jane, please tell the
court what happened next.
- And then, he had
my arms pressed down
- Your honor!
This is all hearsay evidence!
- [Judge] Mr. Peters
please sit down.
(multiple voices)
Order!
This court will
adjourn till 10:30.
- She drank with me
for ten hours, Francis.
Of course she's going to
feel weird and out of it.
- Then how do you
explain the morphine?
- I don't know.
Maybe she took
some pain killers.
Maybe we scored some
drugs when we were out.
- Maybe's not good
enough, William, okay?
Maybe's not good enough.
(door slamming)
- [Judge] Jury foreperson,
how do you find the defendant?
- Guilty, Your Honor.
- What?
No!
William!
(sad music)
- Will.
We'll lodge an
appeal immediately.
- You said 80/20 our way.
- Yeah, I know, but
I'll have it sorted
in a couple of weeks, okay?
- I didn't do it.
- Okay, come on, let's go.
- Hold your head up, William.
- McIntyre?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Get your clothes off.
- What? Now?
- Hurry up.
- Raise your arms.
Lift your nuts.
Turn around.
Bend over.
Now cough.
(coughing)
- There you go.
- Have a good one.
- See ya, Patsy.
- Hey, bro
- I'm Benjy, the subway bandit.
You know I was on four
TV stations last night?
First store, I was
in an Elvis suit
and then I dressed
up as Spiderman.
(laughing)
You should have seen
me on the cameras.
You know they got
cameras in stores now?
Are you listening
to me straighty?
- [Will] Yeah.
Yeah, well just as well, mate.
Because no fag boy
brushes me off,
you know what I mean?
No one.
What are you looking at bushy?
- A dead man.
- What he'd just say?
- [Will] I didn't quite,
I didn't quite catch it.
- Oh mate, you are
so full of sh...
(thudding)
(dramatic music)
(cat calls and yelling)
(yelling and jeering)
- Morning muster is at six.
There are seven
further musters a day.
Any questions?
- Yeah, I need a see a nurse.
- McIntyre, Reed, Taylor.
B-Yard.
- Hey, Benjy!
Asked to be put in with me.
- Up yours, princess,
you can't afford this!
- And my prison will not
tolerate this kind of talk!
(yelling and jeering)
- Welcome home, Jimmy.
- Don't you tell 'em.
- Tell 'em what?
- What you're in for.
- I like those.
Boo!
(low sustained noise)
(multiple conversations)
- Hey, pretty boy.
- Bruno, move it.
- Hello pretty boy! Ha!
- Cal's still going to
get that big fellow, mate.
- Boo!
- Don't talk too
much to this one,
and for God's sake don't
tell him what you're in for.
Butch.
You got ten days before
parole review, right?
- Now why would I do
anything to stuff that up?
- So we have an
understanding then?
- What are you in for?
- Uh, robbed a servo.
- A servo?
- Yeah, yeah.
A petrol station.
- I know what a
fucking servo is.
- Can you get me smack in?
- No.
- Vs? Wizz? Juice?
- Uh, no.
- I shit, shower and shave first
and every night I get
your dessert, got it?
- Yeah.
I'm Will.
- Tuck your shit up there.
- Here.
(crickets)
(jeering and yelling)
- [Butch] You awake?
- Yeah.
- Ta for the smokes.
Butch.
- Pardon?
- Me name's Butch.
- Oh.
Oh.
Right.
(loud alarm)
- McIntyre.
Hurley.
Where's Hurley?
- I'm taking a shit.
(laughter)
- Wrong answer, get out here.
You think that's funny, boy?
See me after muster.
Reed.
Benard.
- [Warden] Count is correct,
all prisoners break off.
(alarm ringing)
- Hey, I'm George.
How long ya?
- Six years.
But I'm appealing.
- That'll take a few
months to come through...
- A few months?
- At best, copper.
The system is jammed
up with appeal.
We're all innocent.
Look pal, the best
way out of here,
and the earlier for you,
is to stay out of trouble.
And read this.
If you want a new
cell mate I'm in a two
all by myself, just ask Graham.
- Says here you were a nurse.
- Yeah. I'm a nurse.
- Were.
A nurse.
Seeing you're such
a caring person,
we need someone to
look after Fung.
- Sorry?
- Fung Poi, over there.
Now don't get too close to him.
He killed his mother.
Now he will need
assistance, with everything.
- You'll get five
dollars 20 each day.
- When do I start?
- By the look of things, he
needs to excrete right now.
Enjoy, McIntyre.
- Which one's your cell?
Come on, Fung.
Hi.
- You might want to keep
books like these on the low.
- Yeah.
- Heard you came in on
the bus with Jimmy Cove.
- Yeah, he took my shoes.
- Listen kid, that
boobhead's done time in every
state in Australia.
Story goes he ate a
bloke's ear for breakfast.
- [Announcement]
Attention prisoners,
the church service will
be held in the prison
chaplain's room in five minutes.
Any prisoners wishing to
attend the church service
please come to the guard's desk
and collect your ID card.
(yelling and cheering)
- Oy!
- Hey.
- Come here.
(groaning)
Did you see my boys
in the library?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Did they say anything to ya?
- No, mate not a thing.
- I'm not your mate.
- I'm Will.
- I know.
- Okay then.
It's okay, Fung.
Thanks for the ciggies.
(groaning)
- That Walsh prick
put you in with Butch?
So he had a good
job in the outer
and now he's got you
looking after Jackie Chan.
(laughing) Piss off.
These walls have ears, pal.
Don't trust no one.
- Sorry there, Fung.
Almost, yep.
- You're needed at
the front house.
You've got a visitor.
- Who?
Can I just finish here?
- Yeah, you can finish there.
But, I wouldn't miss this one.
- [Radio] Front gate clear.
- William McIntyre?
- You know who I am.
- Well if I go by what
someone shouted at you
from the gallery at your trial,
yeah, a sick maggot.
- You drove an hour and
a half to call me that?
- No. To deliver these.
We're appealing your sentence.
Only six years.
What kind of crack was
your judge smoking?
Appeal shouldn't be too long.
Enjoy your new home.
("Bad Luck" featuring Ke M)
* Always be labeled guilty
until proven innocent
* Mind of a convict a
veteran of vigilance
* A hero to some
but a legend to many
* In useless
correctional centers
* all over the world listening
* Never been patched up
but always been affiliated
* Never been cashed up
but always money motivated
* Never been stressed
out about a total loss
* Born to struggle
but also for the cause
* Accused of misdemeanors
and serious offenses
* Abused deck the halls it's
the person with the platinums
* All the ghosts is supposed
to be the most rebellious
* Comatose they're getting
toasted with the devilish
* Doing time behind
these concrete walls
* Just a fucked up
judgement of my flaws
* So you run around plead
guilty for the fact that
* The lawful lead always
has you backtracked
* I'm not a bad man just
a man with some bad luck
* Corruption in the system
got everyone handcuffed
* Best with the curse
reverse the boon hills but
* Dress will traverse
to burst open the cut
* I'm not a bad man just
a man with some bad luck
* Corruption in the system
got everyone handcuffed
* Best with the curse
reverse the boon hills but
* Dress will traverse
to burst open the cut
* I've always been a man to
push through my limitations
* Never been short to abort
my heart's visitations
* Stuck in the mainstream
gray beams won't let me down
* But with a little luck
man I could turn it around
* Full responsibility
accepting imprisonment
* Look there's no humility
accept for futility
* Brainwashed condition
no signs of innocence
* Like you move away from
every chance at deliverance
* Caught out of a pro with
not suspended sentence
* No matter, you're still
behind electrified fences
* Closed off from the world
labeled as an outcast *
- I'm not coping too
well here, Francis.
- [Francis] William, things
are moving along we just have
find a Queen's Counsel.
- Why can't you do it?
- Me? This matter
is way beyond me.
Look, your matter
is going before the
Supreme Court of Appeal.
- I know, and it's not
about my innocence.
- Don't worry
about their appeal,
the court has to hear
about ours first.
Look, I'm going to find
someone experienced
who can fight the appeal against
your conviction technically.
- I need someone who
can fight the charges
based on the truth,
Francis, not a technicality.
- We're going to get the
right person for the job.
- Bah!
- McIntyre. You're up, let's go.
- Get your clothes on.
- Will, William McIntyre.
William.
This was your father's,
before he passed away.
How are they treating you?
- I'm okay, Mum.
- How can you say that?
- Mum, I'm okay.
- You're in a maximum
security prison for
something you didn't do.
You've got years to serve.
It is not okay!
- Ma'am, I'm going to have
to ask you to keep it down.
- I knew this would happen.
- This is not right!
- Mum!
Mum.
- Ma'am you're going
to have to leave.
- Don't you touch me!
- She's going to be okay.
- You don't touch me!
William!
They can't do this to you!
(crying) I love you!
- I love you too.
- Was that your mum?
- Yeah.
- How was it?
- Shit.
- At least you got
someone to visit ya.
- I reckon it makes
your time harder.
- Ah, turn it up.
- Baxter.
Sanders.
- Anything beats the
same old same old.
- What did you do?
- I burned a bridge.
- What'd you do?
- I had a one night stand.
- Then why aren't you in there.
- I didn't rape her.
We were drunk.
We had sex. I left.
- Then why would she cry rape?
- Turned out she wanted
her boyfriend back.
His best mate saw us getting on.
- Didn't your mother
ever tell you not to have
sex before you were married?
Sanders? That's from Cove.
- What the hell are
those guys doing?
- They fatten em up
and bang 'em in the pot
Baxter.
- Will.
- Jimmy Cove has
taken a liking to ya.
- How do you know him?
- Me five-eight crossed
him on another tour.
- And?
- Now that was a bridge
Andy shouldn't have burned.
Jimmy whacked him on the spot.
- He doesn't seem like...
- They never do,
kid, they never do.
(hip-hop music)
- Hey Will!
How you doing, buddy?
I heard some copper
came and saw you today.
- Yeah, mate they want
me to do more time.
I'm fighting these
bastards George,
I'll be out of here
before Christmas.
- Christmas, eh?
Sounds like that
little book I gave you
is starting to make sense, mate.
(punching)
- What are you appealing?
- The whole thing.
I found that every
successful conviction
gets the DPP.
- DP what?
- Public prosecutions.
They allocate credit
points for funding.
Rape is such an easy
charge to go down for.
- Does that really effect
the jury's verdict though?
- Yeah, does that really?
- We lost all the intelligent
jurors through selection,
we're left with the ones
with nothing better to do
than watch Judge Judy live.
- Maybe they're worried
they all get ahead of you?
- Come over to their house.
- Shut up Benjy!
- We'll win the
appeal, I'm sure of it.
She won't know what's hit her
with a defamation lawsuit.
(cheering)
- Hey, Macker.
Story says your friends
with Jimmy the big
whacker from A-yard.
- We've had words.
- Can you tell him
Taz needs a suit?
- Yeah, sure.
- Careful.
- Yeah, careful Will.
- It's all good.
(rap music)
- You've been in
a bit I take it?
(laughing)
- First time.
- Jimmy?
- It's not enough.
Come here, I won't hit ya.
(groaning)
I told ya I wouldn't hit ya.
You tell that ration
it's this next time.
- Okay, Jimmy.
- What are you in for?
- Parking fines.
(laughing)
- Fucking parking
fines (laughing)
(crickets)
(dogs barking)
(alarm ringing)
- Out of bed! Get up!
Right lads, out of bed!
- What do we have here then?
- What?
(knocking on door)
- McIntyre.
Do you know that if we
were to inform the police
about what we found
in your possession,
you'd be looking at
another four to five years?
We'll be investigating
every visitor on your list.
- Yes, ma'am but
I'm telling you...
- And know this.
Your every move will be
under closest scrutiny.
- McIntyre.
- Ralph if they want to settle
two million out of court
then surely you've got
to accept that offer.
Look Ralph, I've got an
old friend at the door
can I give you a call back?
Okay, bye.
Francis.
How are you?
- Yeah, I'm good.
I wanted to have a quick
chat to you about something..
- Francis! You've never
been a very good liar,
I told you you should
never become a lawyer.
What's going on?
- I went down on a case
I did for Legal Aid.
- Legal Aid?
- Yeah. I took it as
part of my percentage
for community placements.
- Nothing wrong with
a Legal Aid case.
I'm intrigued as to why
you've brought it to me.
Julie, he didn't do it.
- You haven't forgotten
our first year subject
on professional
boundaries have you?
Who sentenced him?
- Hoggins.
- Hoggins hasn't had an
appeal against conviction
in 20 years.
- And that's why
we need you, Julie.
- We?
- Well I need you,
okay, I need you.
This case, it's
different, it's not right.
- Yeah, and I'd need 40
thousand dollars up front.
- He's only go two.
- Then I'll see you at
the Christmas party.
- How's Liz?
- She's taken it a little hard.
How are you going?
- What do you mean?
What has she said?
- You know her, she's a
sensitive little thing.
Look, how are you really going?
- Hanging in there.
That bitch is still
sticking to her story, John.
This is bullshit.
- William, you have
to forgive her.
- My life has been ruined.
I've lost my career, my freedom.
The newspapers have
smashed any reputation
I have left, and even
some of my good friends
have snubbed me.
And you expect me
to forgive her?
- Then you'll be free.
- Time's up, come on.
- You're crazy, you know that.
- The hard part
will be you'll have
to keep forgiving her.
Will?
Liz believes you.
- Come on!
Let's go Will!
- You can join us.
- Sure Benjy.
- You just need to
wear this outfit.
- Mcintyre!
- You're girlfriend's
here, mate.
- This is for you.
Smells nice.
- [Benjy] Razz, what if they
offer you to play inside?
Razz? Razz!
- [Voiceover] Dear Will.
I really don't
know what to write.
I cry nearly every
night thinking of what
has happened to you.
I'm sorry that I have
not come in to see you.
I'm glad Dad has been
able to visit though.
He says I should
just keep praying for
a positive outcome.
His faith in God
drives me crazy.
I would love to come
and see you but don't
know whether I'll be
able to keep it together.
I'm thinking of you.
Your special friend, Liz.
- Watch it, pal.
- Will!
Razz? Razz?
I knew you'd come around.
You just gotta drive
the getaway car.
- Benjy, shut up. Not now.
Look, I think Fung wants to
help you when you get out too.
- So, can you drive?
- What's up?
- Got a letter.
- You blokes are all the same.
Want everything to be perfect
and then you'll be happy.
- I know what you're in for.
How many armed
robs have you done?
- Enough.
You gotta take risks, cupcake.
- Can you not call me cupcake?
- Risks.
Without them you'll never know.
- My friend John
calls that faith.
- Faith? Fuck faith.
(laughing)
- Something you
hope for and certain
of what you can't see.
- Yeah, well my rewards
are certain, pal.
- Oh, they don't really
pay off though do they?
- What's her name?
- Liz.
- Liz. Lizzie.
Well I'll tell
you this for free.
Everyone you thought
would be in your business
apart while your here won't
be seen for 500 mile and
others you never
expected just rock up.
- I had some really good mates.
- Bullshit. Bullshit!
Really good mates, eh?
So where are they now?
You see 'em?
They watch ya?
They would take a bullet for ya?
- Rode the wave, eh?
- The what?
- The wave.
- You guess.
- You are so missing out.
You don't know what I'm
talking about do ya?
The ocean waves.
It's like, it's like
you're completely alone.
You're surrounded by
this massive thing.
The swell comes up behind ya.
You snap up onto
your board, and boom!
You're away.
It's gotcha.
You're hurtling
along this barrel
and you can hear your heart.
Boom. Ba-boom. Ba-boom.
- Then what?
- Then bang!
You lose your balance, it
knocks you upside down.
Madness.
You're smashed up in its
grip like a rag doll in
a washing machine.
That's worth the risk.
(yelling and screaming)
(heavy breathing)
(piano music)
- Excuse me.
Wouldn't it be good to
break Hoggin's track record
of not having one conviction
overturned in 20 years?
- I'm sorry.
Now what were we saying?
- That's it!
That's it, Fung!
Hi mate, just a can of Sustagen,
a can of coke
and some of those noodles.
Awesome.
Can I grab a
plastic bag as well?
(moaning)
Come on, mate.
- Oy! Macker!
Give us your tin of powder.
- Butch.
I worked for this.
If you want some powder,
don't put me on the show.
Come to me in private
and ask for it.
- Come on, move along.
- What?
(laughter)
- You know the drill.
- Got delectable
beans today, boys.
- Rubbish again as usual.
- Can I have some Sustagen?
- Sure.
I'll get some for you
when I finish my meal.
- I'm getting a
little impatient.
- Fuck off.
- You look like crap.
- Great to see you too.
- You look like you're
handling yourself all right.
- I was actually
scared shitless.
(laughing)
- Okay
- You been in the slot?
- Oh yeah. Three weeks, mate.
- What's it like?
- Fish and chips.
- What brings you to B-yard?
- Politics. How's
your appeal going?
- It's going.
One minute they're saying
it shouldn't be too
far away, the next...
- I've been thinking
about this tart.
- What tart?
- The one that got
you into this mess.
You need to get hold of ten G.
- Ten G? What for?
- Yeah, you get ten G to
me and I'll sort it out.
- Sort what?
- Sort her out, idiot.
You shouldn't be locked
up in this shithole.
- Jimmy, are you saying that
for ten thousand dollars
you could have this girl
murdered, that's what you meant.
- I didn't say that.
For ten thousand dollars
exactly what your said
- Don't bring your Bible
bullshit here, son!
I've heard you're shacking
up with Georgie boy.
Don't you get caught
up with all of his...
- Caught up?
Caught up.
The only person caught
up here Jimmy, is you.
When are you just
going to be yourself?
- What was your first job, Will?
- Mowing lawns.
- Mowing lawns?
You remember your first day?
- Yeah, yeah I do.
- Well I was eight me first day.
I used to ride my
little yellow scooter
through the streets
of the cross.
My mother's friends
would give me a couple
coins, you know give me a cuppa.
Couple a coffees.
Five cents for
every cup delivered.
That was me pocket
money, next couple years.
Coffee run for hookers.
One day, I couldn't find mum.
It was a Friday
when I went looking.
I found her up this
alleyway and just
getting the crap
beat out of her.
So I stabbed the prick.
And he never did get up.
So I am who I am, boy.
And I don't need no life lesson
from some pimply ass kid
who knows shit.
Ten K.
And she's gone.
(grunting)
(crashing)
- [Will] Dear Jane.
(crying)
Don't know why you said
what you said against me.
One thing I do know
that happened that night
is that we slept together.
I forgive you.
(crying)
Apples are up.
- Playing in
Friday's forty game?
- Now that you're in
B-yard, I think I will.
- Attention prisoners,
the church service will
be held in the prison
hamplain's room in five minutes.
Any prisoners wishing to attend
the church service
- (jeering and yelling)
please come to the
guard's desk...
- Thank you.
- You got a buddy today George.
(laughing)
- Don't worry about the boys.
- Oy, Macker.
You better watch your back.
- Why is that Butch?
- Cause you're not always
going to have your bodyguards.
- George says, I've got
angels all around me.
And if anything were
to happen to me,
I'd hate to imagine what
would happen to them.
- You're filling this kid's
head with shit, George.
- It's only shit
if it stinks, mate.
And frankly, right
now, all I can smell
is the stench of
your rotting soul.
- Are you crazy George?
- Butch it's time
you found the truth.
Look.
Whoever believes and is baptized
shall be saved.
But whoever doesn't
believe shall be condemned.
- So what?
- So we gotta do this for you.
- Do what George?
- Will get the door.
- Have faith, Butch.
- Look out, Fung.
- Rip your top off.
Come on.
We claim this soul in
the name of the father,
the son and the
holy ghost, amen.
- Welcome to the kingdom.
(door slamming)
(alarm ringing)
- [Warden] All prisoners
return to your cells.
Night lockdown in two minutes.
All prisoners
return to your cells
Night lockdown in two minutes.
(thunder claps)
- McIntyre.
- Sorry, sir.
What's up?
- You're up.
You've got a visitor.
- William.
Hi, Julie Nile.
- Hi, Will.
- Francis told me you've
been studying the law
closely in regards
to your matter.
- I have.
It seems a pretty
clear cut case.
- Your trial judge has
died and the police have
lost important video
footage, and the complainant
still isn't backing
down from her story.
And I'll be taking your case.
- I have no idea who
you are, but thank you!
- First things first.
No guarantees.
- I'm praying
we're going to win.
- William please know
the prosecution counsel
is not going to
back down that easy.
- But I didn't do it.
- I know what your stand is.
- Mrs. Nile it's not my stand.
- Okay we better get
this ball rolling.
How are you doing in here?
- You know what?
- What's that?
- I actually like some
of the guys in here.
- You don't belong in here.
- So you know I'm innocent.
- I didn't say that.
- But it's the truth.
- Truth?
- It's the law that
sets us free, William,
not the truth.
- This is the best day I've had.
- Lizzie seen ya.
- Naw, it's my new mouthpiece.
Francis was my old mouthpiece.
He's not old but he was the
one who represented me...
- Slow down, pal,
slow down you're
giving me an ear ache.
- Sorry, man I'm
just pretty stoked.
- Good for you.
You know that suit
you were in court,
Des is still looking for one.
- I really need it
for my appeal though.
- Of course, mate, of course
I'll get it back to 'ya.
- Hey Jimmy, hey Will.
- Hi Will!
- Hey, I overheard the
boys are going to get
you back for breaking
our Randy's jaw.
- Ow! Well I'll break it
again if he comes near me.
And yours too if you
talk to me again.
- Just sayin'
- He's just trying to help.
- I think Brooks is right.
(laughing)
- He's far from right, Macker.
Far from right.
- No, I mean I haven't
heard Benjy talk like that.
- Heard it all before,
pal, all before.
- [Warden] Count is correct.
All prisoners break off.
(alarm ringing)
- I've gotta make a call, mate.
- I gotta talk, Braz.
Braz!
- Hello?
- Francis, hi it's Will.
- Oh, hey Will, how are things?
- Yeah, hanging in there.
Listen, thanks so
much for sending Julie
to come and see me.
I tell you what, she
sounds pretty serious.
Francis?
You there?
- Weil I told you
I'd do my best.
- Nearly a year and
a half, Francis,
I guess that's not too
far off a couple of weeks.
- These things take time.
- Do we have an appeal date yet?
- Yeah, about that,
I wanted to say that
(alarm ringing)
hello?
Will, you there?
- [Warden] Attention
staff, code blue,
all prisoners return to
your cells immediately
I repeat, all prisoners return
to your cells immediately.
(alarm ringing)
(dramatic music)
(door slamming)
- It's Benjy.
- In here, even the
small things can
make people crack.
- I hate this place.
- If it wasn't today it would
have been tomorrow, mate.
A walking time bomb.
Those who hope in the Lord
will renew their strength.
They will sore on
wings like eagles.
They will run, and
not grow weary.
They will walk,
and not be faint.
Welcome to the
jungle, my friend.
(hard rock music)
(yelling and jeering)
* The underdog I won't
break and won't bend
* Don't need no rules
* We rise
* Rise
* The battle lines
have been drawn
* Why's the man a
prisoner of a man
* A heavy hand a broken back
* The dogs of war
are ready for attack
* We rise
* A prisoner of man
* Ready for attack
* Rise
- Touchdown!
- [Jimmy] For the first time
in all me 26 years behind bars
I felt like a free man.
* We rise
* Rise
(groaning)
- You got bugalugs?
- Stop it, stop it.
You all right?
- I'm okay, Mum.
- Oh good. It's just
that, I shouldn't
listen to that stupid
woman next door
- Mum, what is it?
- You must be Mrs.
Cove. I'm Will.
- You better take a seat, bloke.
- About your plea, what
are you going to do?
- I'm not sure, Mum.
I'm still on the fence.
- Well I think you should
tell them the truth son,
plead guilty.
That'll set you free.
I didn't mean to upset you.
Look, I've been in prison too.
Here.
I just want you to be free.
(piano music)
(laughter)
- Julie, what a surprise!
- Good morning, Francis.
- There's just one more thing.
- There always is.
- Appeal date.
- The ninth of May.
- That's just weeks away
- I need you to keep
the dates quiet until
we gather the
necessary paperwork.
We need to get access to
the witnesses who weren't
brought forward in
the first trial.
- Yeah.
Do you think we'll win.
- Well we have to.
He's innocent.
(hip hop music)
- You know William McIntyre?
If things get too tough
- How many times
you want Brooksy?
- An many as it takes.
Jimmy hasn't been
telling you to keep
away from me, has he Will?
- I tell him to keep away
from the game, not the player.
(laughter)
- Oh, Jimmy that is so sweet.
(upbeat music)
- Watch it Brooksy.
- Or what?
- Boo!
(laughter)
- Cut this off.
(cheering)
* You'll be the
life of the party
life of the party *
(alarm ringing)
- Get out of bed!
Come on!
- Get a move on
- You must have really
pissed the chief off.
- It's not like you to
keep bad company, George.
- Yeah, it's all that
home brew under my bed.
- Sorry for the early
wake up call, boys.
- It's not your fault.
- Actually it is.
- What do you mean?
- I've got something
important I need
to ask Will.
- Ah shit.
You ratted on us so you
could have a tea chat...
- Yeah, yeah,
righto, St. Georgie.
(dog panting)
- It's pretty cold, mate.
- It's pretty important, mate.
- Come on boys, up.
Let's go, Jimmy.
- Will, ya there?
- Yeah.
- The other day you were
telling me about surfing.
- Yeah.
- Where do you go?
- Anywhere.
- But where do you go?
- Rainbow Bay.
- Sounds nice.
- Yeah, yeah it is.
- You know the last job
I was telling you about.
- Yeah the...
- Well I gotta go to court
today and enter a plea.
- Oh yeah?
- What should I do?
If I plead guilty
they'll shoot me off to
Risdon for another ten years,
if I plead not I have a
trial or two and they'll
move me anyway.
Either way I'm screwed.
Still there, Will?
- Yeah, yep.
I'm thinking.
- What would you do?
- I'd...
I'd plead guilty.
Then face the music.
- Sounds good, Will.
- I'll say a prayer for you.
- Love you, ya bugger.
- I love you too, mate.
- What's wrong McIntye?
Lost your bum chum?
- [Fung] (moaning)
- Everybody knows why
you were his friend.
With a charge like yours,
you'd be dead in here.
(laughing) Why'd you
give him a return, eh?
Now look who's got your back.
A useless invalid.
- [Fung] (moaning)
- Leave him Walsh,
you bloody coward.
- What's the matter McIntyle?
Did you think you were
going to get your suit back?
There was no poor
prick going to court.
Jimmy sold it for
a pouch of tobacco.
I can see right
through you, McIntyre.
- I said leave him!
- Leave him boy!
- George!
- George, it's not worth it.
(alarm ringing)
- [George] Leave me, Butch.
He was beating up Fung!
- Fung, breathe
Fung, breathe, mate.
Come on, mate.
(alarm ringing)
- Right, we ready?
- Yep. Here are the affidavits,
the precedent cases,
and the last trial
transcript queries here.
And uh,
Will gave me this to give
you just in case needed
some help.
- Okay.
- McIntyre?
- Yes, sir.
(dramatic music)
You happy, sir?
- It's a job.
- Not with your job.
In here.
- I haven't been since
I was a kid, sir.
- Nice of you to
join us Ms. Nile.
I didn't think the tall
poppies came down here.
- It's Mrs. Nile, Barry.
- All stand.
This court is now in session.
- Bring the prisoner in.
- All people to do with
McIntyre vs. the Crown are
under oath by order of
her Majesty the Queen.
- Yes, Mrs. Nile.
- Your Honors, I'm here today
representing Mr. Mcintyre.
Our case is succinct.
We have three pertinent
precedents which prove
Mr. McIntyre's first trial
was a miscarriage of justice.
- A miscarriage of justice
is certainly going for the
jugular, Mrs. Nile.
- Yes, Your Honors.
I wish to waste no one's
time on this matter.
And by doing so we
can hopefully achieve
a decision forthwith.
- In reply to the defensive
submission, Mr. Darnbury.
Will you be seeking adjournment?
- Yes, of course, Your Honor,
that will be necessary.
- These shifty fucks.
- Yes, William,
welcome of the world of
getting your stripes.
Now stick with me here,
we're almost there.
Okay, they're going
to take you back
to the prison tonight, and bring
you back early in the morning.
Then we're going to
hear the prosecution's
argument against our submission.
Then the judges are going
to go away and decide.
This may take a few days.
- I'm burning up, Julie.
- This is the last leg
of the marathon, yeah?
- Okay.
- See you tomorrow.
- Julie?
Thank you.
(crickets)
(television news)
- Doubtful.
Almost.
Will?
- Hey.
You know how it is.
Hey, Fung.
- How was your mouthpiece?
- Yeah, she's good.
- McIntyre.
- Yes, ma'am.
- You have been
cleared of any further
inquiry into the contraband
found in your cell.
Keep out of trouble.
That's all.
- Here's to staying
out of trouble.
Here, Fung.
- Here's to a four percent
of prison sentences being
directly alcohol related.
- If there was no alcohol
there'd be no prisoners.
Cheers!
- Still would have been
easier to have pleaded
guilty than go through all this.
- [Television] An armed bandit
today has pleaded guilty
to his latest
- Turn it up!
- [Television] armed
robbery in Hamilton and has
walked free from court.
After presiding Judge
Hanlin took into account
his remorse and time
already spent in prison,
James Francis Cove,
51, now wants to walk
from his life of crime.
He has revisited the staff
he terrorized at the bank,
asking for their forgiveness.
Cove, who has served
jail time in every state
in Australia culminating
26 years, is confident
he can turn his life around
with the help of his mother.
- I haven't earned an honest
days living in all me life.
That's not cricket.
it shouldn't be that way.
- Aw, it's real good
to have him home.
He'll be fine.
- Can you believe it George?
- [Reporter] Has he been
- [Reporter] welcomed
back into the house with
open arms?
- Yes I can, mate.
- [Mum] Oh, yeah,
yeah, definitely.
(alarm ringing)
- [Warden] All prisoners
return to your cells
Night lockdown two minutes.
All prisoners
return to your cells
Night lockdown two minutes.
- [Julie] Scientific
evidence led by Dr. Ulas
and Dr. Flogan during the
first trial which formed
an important part
of the Crown case,
now turns out to be invalid.
Effectively as a result of
the concessions made under
oath by both witnesses
the scientific support for
the complainant's
allegations of drink spiking
offered in the first
trial, have now evaporated.
- None of this takes away
from the fact that traces
of morphine were
found in her urine.
- Mr. Darnbury brings
new light to an important
fact, Mrs. Nile.
- Yes, I'm well aware of
this only fact the Crown's
entire case rests upon,
but as we've been told
by experts during the
first trial, that any
codeine pill purchased off
the supermarket shelf,
for let's say a hangover,
when broken down to its
base form is morphine.
I'm sorry Your Honor, I
think I need to take a
bathroom break.
- (laughing) So
what is your point.
- All stand.
This court is now
adjourned till, 4:44 pm.
- William, it's not
looking too good.
- You're doing great, Julie.
We're nearly there, I
can see the finish line.
- Topper's giving me grief.
I'll show him tall poppy.
- Stuff Darnbury,
you're not a tall poppy.
- What did you just say?
- I was just using
the marathon analogy
- No, no you said
something, Darnbury...
- You said a tall poppy.
- Francis, wait right
here, if I'm not back
in five minutes tell
him I'm the lavatory.
Come on!
(phone ringing)
Shit!
- Bugger, forgot
to feed Mr. Chips.
(phone ringing)
- You guys go on,
I'll see you in a bit.
(phone ringing)
Hey, Mr. Chips.
- Come on, Stevie,
my battery's dying!
(phone ringing)
Oh, Dad, what have I
gotten myself into?
Come on, come on, come on.
(phone ringing)
Come on, come on, come on,
- Department, Stevie Best.
- Stevie, you're alive!
- Jules.
- Stevie I need you to
do me a favor, right now.
- Sure, sure, what is it?
- Okay, I have a morphine trace
level I need you to check.
- Okay, just let me
get in the system.
- Stevie, we only
have two minutes.
- Okay, fire away.
- Okay, the reading is
500 micro milligrams.
- It's coming up pretty low.
- I need you to fax
that to me right away.
(clock ticking)
See anything come through
the fax yet, Donna?
- Must be the water
us commoners drink.
- Indeed, I'll be taking
a filter next time.
- No, not yet.
- All stand.
- Mrs. Nile, you were about
to respond to Mr. Darnbury's
point regarding the morphine
in Ms. Tier's urine.
- Yes, Your Honor, I was.
Furthermore, to the
concessions made earlier,
I believe significantly
damaged the Crown case during
the first trial
for many reasons.
The jury was simply left
with the evidence of
Ms. Tier's symptoms.
- What is your point Mrs. Nile?
(fax machine)
- The truth, Your Honors,
and anybody else
who cares to listen,
is this.
The reliability of the
account Ms. Tier gave during
the first trial is not only
weakened by this report
from Dr. Grieven, showing
sedative or stimulant drugs
are found in less than five
percent of reported cases
for drink spiking.
But if you care to take
a look at this drug level
analysis report, just
sent over by our state's
leading toxicology
laboratory, you will see that
the levels of morphine
found in Ms. Tier's urine,
are equivalent to that of
someone having ingested
poppy seeds on a bagel.
(laughter)
- This can not be
entered as evidence now!
- Sit down Mr. Darnbury.
It's a fact of
pre-existing evidence.
We are going to need
time to make a decision.
- All stand.
- McIntyre.
Come with me.
They overturned your
conviction, son.
(piano music)
- We won.
- Yep. You're free to go!
- Yay! (laughing)
Sorry, sir.
- Never mind. Now, listen,
you can't tell anyone,
not even George.
We want to get you
out of here alive.
We'll call by before
tomorrow morning's let out.
- I'm sorry.
(piano music)
- [Will] Jimmy Cove.
- [Jimmy] Love you, ya bugger.
* Somewhere there's forgiving
* It's what I'm stronger for
* The world had
turned against me
* Left me standing tall
* There's hope in these walls
(hawk call)
* The first time I cried
* My feelings can't hide
* On the other side
* The hands that I hold
* My stories now told
* On the other side
* I loved lost and found
* It breaks down these walls
* I begin to rise
* Somewhere our horizons
* Or what we're searching for
* Falling in together
* Living day to day
* To feel any more
* I first heard this sound
- [Will] I read a sign
once above the rear vew
mirror of my old school bus.
It said: Be kind to every
one because every one
is fighting some sort of battle.
* My stories untold
* On the other side
* And after the fall
* The darkness will call
* Til it's time to rise
(waves crashing)
(piano music)
* Final journey now begins
* Let your soul unfold its wings
* Step into the light of love
* Reach for blue
and tranquil skies
* Soar into a paradise
* And touch the
face, the face of God
* The bonds of mother earth
* Are clearly left behind
* Upwards keep ascending
* Beyond the hands of time
* Over sunset hills that rise
* Where the golden eagle flies
* We will walk and meet again
* We know this is not the end
* Love like ours will never end
* It shall never end
* Behold a beauty so pristine
* Moral hearts can only dream
* You are now where we will be
* And until then we'll reminisce
* A trail of memories we'll kiss
* And those you love
you must set free
* The bonds of mother earth
* Are clearly left behind
* Upwards keep ascending
* Beyond the hands of time
* Over sunset hills that rise
* Where the golden eagle flies
* We will walk and meet again
* We know this is not the end
* Love like ours will never end
* It shall never end
* Over sunset hills
* Sunset hills
(piano music)
(heavy metal music)
* We gotta walk this battlefield
* The underdog he won't
break he won't bend
* Don't need no rules
* No referee
* There's no surrender
and no territory
* We rise
* No referee
* Rise
* The battle lines
have been drawn
* Why's the man the
prisoner of the man
* A heavy hand a broken back
* The dogs of war
are ready for attack
* We rise
* A prisoner of man
* Ready for attack
* Rise
* We rise