Creating Destiny
Enjoy:)
Episode 10
Do you know?
My father didn't mention marriage.
My grandmother didn't talk
about a marriage date either!
So this can be taken as a success then.
I think so.
At least we don't have to worry
about getting married right away.
We just have to work on
the engagement first.
This is enough already.
As time drags on, it will all end, right?
I'm hoping for that too.
At least for today, we settled the matter.
Let's get back.
Wait.
This is not over yet.
Let's make a contract.
What? Make a what?
Contract.
Whether it's real or fake,
it's best to have a contract written out.
As if we don't know you're a lawyer.
Fine, we'll do it.
Make things clear.
No matter what happens,
don't be angry with me.
That's not me, you know.
Let's get to it now.
Mutual non-interference.
That's a good one.
Second thing, time period.
For how long do we have to meet up?
Until the elders believe us.
So how long does that take?
I'm sorry but the contract must
state a specific period, you know.
Mmm... How about once a week?
That often?
If we want to keep the elders in the dark,
that frequency might not even be enough.
Then we can't do without that.
When we meet up,
what do we do?
I'm not sure what we will do,
but let's first cancel
shopping from our dates.
How can you do that?
Didn't we agree to do
something we're both happy with?
But it has to be at least reasonable.
If I bring you to a
soccer match every day,
would you be happy?
I like soccer so that's fine with me.
Ah! And...
definitely no skin ship*.
(*touching)
Do you have any common sense?
If we're dating but we're
not even holding hands,
you think Grandmother will believe us?
So how far are you going to go?
It depends on the circumstances.
ah... I told you the contract
has to cover details.
So you mean when grandfather's around,
we hold hands,
when Grandmother's around, we kiss?
Is that how we put it?
Let's do it that way then.
Who says to write it like that?
Well..
Just say we allow some proper skin ship*.
(*touching)
See if you dare violate that.
That's my line.
I dare you to try me.
No matter what,
we try our best to avoid behavior
which create suspicion in the elders,
We date according to this contract.
All right.
And both parties must keep
this contract a secret.
Absolute secret.
Call, absolute secret.
So that's about it.
If the contract is violated,
how do we handle the penalty fee?
- Penalty fee?
- Yes.
Otherwise, there won't be a
need to write this contract,
if there's no loss when
the contract is violated.
So hand in one piece (of cheque)
each time a mistake is made.
One piece?
How much is that?
100,000 won.
So that we won't want to make a mistake.
Fine, since I've started
to earn a living now.
The last thing is,
if one of us make a mistake
and is found out by the elders,
that person has to be fully responsible.
For that, the price has
to be higher, correct?
Then we won't use money as penalty,
use something else.
What?
Whoever it is,
that person must
get married first no matter how.
Fine.
That way the other person
will get to live freely.
Our contract is made then.
Taek Soo, where are we going?
You'll find out when we get there.
Let's go, Father.
Yes, I want to have a look where we go.
You guys have been going
everywhere together, haven't you?
This way.
Kyung Tae
Have a look.
- Wow, so spacious.
- You like it?
Father's room...
How is it, Father?
You like it?
Of course I like it.
So long as you like it.
It has been some other
people helping to do this up,
so some things may
not be to your liking.
But if there's enough time,
I'll make sure every spot is perfect.
Then you can work on any
leftover spots on your own.
Ah friends...
No need for all the trouble.
We'll just live in a normal house.
So why did you leave your house,
and live in some other house then?
But I still can't trouble you.
How is that trouble to me?
Or shall I return the bakery to you?
That was yours originally.
No, no, don't say that.
Forget it, don't quarrel anymore.
Since we're not leaving,
it works out just nice.
Comparing the price of
the bakery and this house,
we'll call it even.
- Yes, yes, Father, you're right.
- I know.
Kyung Tae, you!
Wow, this place is so clean.
Everything's good.
The furniture's coming in today.
Wait, is there anything else you need?
But I said you don't have to do so much.
Aish... This is all out of my own will.
Back then when you went to Australia alone,
there was nothing I could help you with.
But here now, what is
it I can't help you with?
Am I right?
Thank you.
What is it?
How could you do that?
Didn't we say we're keeping
that house for Yeo Jun?
Who said it was for Yeo Jun?
He should settle it for himself.
When he gets married,
we should at least prepare a house for him.
How can he get married without a house?
Easier said than done,
it's enough that we fed
him and housed him so far.
Parents are not slaves who have to get
a house ready for him to get married.
- Honey!
- What a shock!
Why must you always shout so loud?
Back then when they gave us the
bakery for free, you said nothing.
Now we have to give him something
of ours and your heart's aching?
Even if your heart's not aching,
mine is aching, aching to death.
So was I having fun all this time?
Why didn't you think about me
suffering and doing all this work?
How can you make all the decisions
as you like it by yourself?
If you're thinking of doing this,
at least discuss it with me.
Discuss? What do you mean 'discuss'?
I'm just returning the object to its owner.
Man must have conscience!
Really.
Where are you going?
We're not done yet.
Aigoo,
now everything's solved
and settled nicely.
And with Taek Soo's help,
our housing problem's solved too.
I thought it would take us a
few months and I was worried.
That's true.
How is it?
With sufficient sunlight,
this environment is not bad, right?
Yes, I'm so happy with this.
I'd wanted to live in an
apartment, this is great.
We had so much space in Australia,
I never thought about living
in an apartment or something.
- Sang Eun
- What?
Have you brought your luggage back?
Yes, you can't keep living
there by yourself,
your family's all here,
why must you owe them a favor?
No, you must thank them profusely.
No, I have to be there with you.
For this house too,
I have yet to say proper thanks to
Grandmother and sister-in-law too.
That's true.
According to etiquette,
we can't let Sang Eun go by herself.
Sure.
But Father, aren't you coming along?
Oh well, I think I won't go along.
I don't want to get into any
quarrel with that old woman.
Brother-in-law's really too much.
The apartment is not just any object,
an outsider is still an outsider,
he didn't give it to me
when I'm the one living here,
yet he gave it to Kyung Tae.
Every day he calls him his real brother.
Hey, how does this involve you?
Noona, you mustn't
treat me like this too.
It's because you treat me so casually
that's why hyung-nim ignores me too.
I'm so upset, Hyung-nim.
- Why is he acting up too?
- Ah?
Hey... This is all your fault.
Why must you blow up the matter?
Who says the matter is blown up?
You're the one who started it,
I definitely won't let
go of the apartment.
- I spent so much effort on it.
- You're really.
We're here.
- Oh, you're here.
- Yes, we've come.
Is something wrong?
No, nothing's wrong.
- Sit down.
- All right, sit down.
How is it going? Have you
finished cleaning up the house?
- Are settled in already?
- It will take some time.
Some of our stuff's being
shipped here still.
All thanks to you.
The apartment is really clean and
the environment's very good too.
Of course.
I spent so much time before I found it.
As long as you're happy with it.
Sister-in-law,
I'm not sure if it's all right for
us to just move out like this?
That's why, Kyung Tae,
that apartment...
Hey, that apartment,
it was my wife's idea to put you up there.
Since the last time you came,
she said she wanted you
to live at that apartment.
When did I...?
I see.
Sister-in-law, we are so grateful to you.
All this while, you've had to take care
of Sang Eun, we're already so thankful,
now the whole family owes you a favor.
I will never forget your favor.
We will surely repay you in future.
Well, let it be then.
What favor, you fella?
If what you say goes,
if I had to repay the favor I owe you,
I'll have to piggyback you every day.
Don't say that.
Mother,
Sang Eun's leaving now.
Grandmother, I'm leaving.
Let me bow to you.
Aigoo, Sang Eun, Sang Eun!
Bowing twice means...
When I came, I bowed once,
I'm leaving now, I have to
bow at least twice, right?
Really.
Grandmother, thank you for everything.
Don't be sick anymore.
Like what Yeo Jun said,
you mustn't get angry again.
You girl, when did I ever get angry?
Grandmother,
thank you.
- Aigoo
- Aigoo!
Aigoo... Hey!
I'll be back to see you.
You girl, you're always hugging.
And what do you think you're doing?
Don't you like everything your way?
So you lay your own bed out,
the way you like it.
Hah! Hah!
You think I'm scared of you?
Really.
Wife, water.
Water.
This woman is so stubborn.
You don't need to get
for Sang Eun now, right?
It's not easy to forget about her.
She's the only one missing,
but why is there so much rice left?
The house feels so empty,
like something's missing.
Don't you know how important a person is?
How can it be so easy to forget as you like?
That's right.
The house is very quiet.
Kyung Tae must have
been so lonely out there.
He has no wife,
and Sang Eun's overseas too.
He only has his friend, right?
The more you think about Kyung Tae,
it makes up for what you owe him, right?
Not completely.
If the children get married,
that will be better.
Mother, eat more.
Yeo Jun,
I hear you two are dating,
but why haven't I seen you two together?
Ah... Well...
Well, that's because the
children are very busy.
What else can they be busy with?
Yeo Jun,
are you two really dating?
Why is it so quiet?
We said we'll meet tomorrow.
For our first date,
let's negotiate it together.
Negotiate?
Fine with me.
So have you thought of a place to go?
I don't know.
I haven't been to many places in Korea.
Don't you have any suggestions?
I don't know.
Just spend the day together causally.
Casually?
Yeo Jun,
you've never dated before, have you?
And you have lots of experience?
At least more than you.
Having lots of experience
is such an honorable thing.
So what do you want to do?
I don't know what
there's to do in Korea.
If this was Australia,
I'll know where to go.
Date?
With a girl?
Yes.
With a girl.
What do you suggest we do?
Sleep together.
What?
I said to sleep together.
To get to know each other really well,
that's the best way.
Just sleep together.
Hang up.
You jerk.
Why do you hang up like that?
Is he your friend?
I have my reason for doing so.
What did he say?
Nothing.
You don't have to know.
Sleep with him.
What?
You guys are dating with
marriage in view, right?
Then that's the most direct way.
Hey, Han Hyo Eun,
all this while, have you been
meeting your friends like this?
Of course not.
It's not like I'm getting married.
Looks like around me,
no one can help at all.
Around me too, no one can help.
What shall we do?
You finally chose this.
But I have absolutely no
interest in this at all.
This has to do with brain surgery,
I have to attend this.
Even so, what is this?
We're on a date, right?
I told you to just
listen for a bit, right?
Ah! Pretend like you don't know me.
If folks from the hospital sees us,
it won't be good for me.
If that's the case then you
shouldn't have brought me here.
You and I don't have a common time slot.
At least we're together.
Otherwise, how are we going to
answer to grandfather and grandmother?
I can't understand a single thing here.
Shh...
Who is that woman?
How am I supposed to know?
He's two-timing, I'm sure he is.
I can't stand this woman.
Hello.
What do you want?
Isn't it enough you look for me every day?
Now, you want me to come to you?
Let's eat.
You like it here, don't you?
Forget it.
I'm not in the mood to eat with you.
Your father came to see me.
What?
You... don't tell me...
It wasn't me,
he came to me himself.
I heard you almost died.
It has nothing to do with you.
Everything about you, has to do with me.
You decide.
What?
You want your father
to kneel to me again?
What?
You...
Jerk.
You threatened my father again?
You threw money at him again?
Money?
What are you saying?
What kind of a man do you take me for?
And you said 'again',
what do you mean by that?
If you didn't, forget it.
Postpone this meal some other time.
I'm not done talking yet.
I can make you shop close down tomorrow,
and I can put a stop to your
brother's job at the hospital too.
In order to get my daughter back,
I'll do anything.
There's so much I want
to do for my daughter.
You decide.
Oh, what has this kid
been eating every day?
The fridge's all empty, really.
What's up? Something happened?
You're here. You want a drink?
Did that man come again?
No.
Then tell me what happened.
You can't solve it by thinking all alone.
Tell me so I will know.
How can I help you, Noona?
How can you help?
Even I don't know what to do.
No matter what I hear, it's all right.
But I don't want my father, mother
and Jin Ju to hear others say awful things.
He keeps pushing me to the edge.
Ah... I don't know what is to do anymore.
It's all right,
don't worry, it will all work out.
What are you doing?
What are you doing here at this hour?
- Madam Shim, what's wrong with you?
- Who is Madam Shim?
Yun Hee, you might not like what you hear,
Kyu Han may be Yeo Jun's
friend but he's still a man.
It's terrible that a man
frequents your shop every day.
People will think badly of you,
it's bad for Jin Ju too.
I hear Jin Ju's dad comes here often, right?
Mom!
I know what you're worried about,
it's nothing like that.
Is it? That's good.
I don't want to hear unnecessary rumors,
destroying my son's reputation.
It's enough for people
to talk behind my back.
Yun Hee, you know very well,
how scary other people's mouths can be.
Yes.
Mom, what's wrong with you?
Let's talk outside.
- I'm sorry, Noona.
- You go out,
I want to talk to Yun Hee some more.
You know, you have Jin Ju
so you should work harder.
Ridiculous!
What did you say?
What's wrong with my daughter's behavior?
Mind your own business.
You have your own children too, is this
the way to talk to other people's children?
You scratch their wounds and
then you even scatter salt on it?
Why do you think only about your daughter?
What about my son?
If we switch places, a single mom
loiters around your son Yeo Jun,
would you be happy?
What? What did you say?
Mom.
- Mom, let's go out. We'll talk outside.
- Let me go.
- This is ridiculous.
- Really sorry.
Oh, this woman is really...
How could I have taken this
kind of person as my friend?
And you, why aren't you arguing back?
Have you done any wrong?
What can others say about you?
Why did you have to fall
in love with that fella?
Why must it be him?
Mom, I'm sorry, I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry
Why did you do that?
That's what I wanted to say to you.
If you keep hanging around here,
I'll get really angry.
You want some cakes,
go get it elsewhere,
this is not the only shop around.
Why must it be Yun Hee's shop?
- Mom!
- Don't call me.
Promise me you'll never come here again.
I can't promise you that.
Why not?
Have you really fallen for her?
Why did you do that?
Even if you didn't do that,
she's already having such a hard time.
Why must you add to her pain?
You are siding with Yun Hee now, are you?
I'm not siding her, it's a fact.
Someone who runs around
trying to hang onto her child.
You remarried 3 times because of me too.
Why can't you empathize with her?
I can empathize but not my son.
Why?
What?
What do you mean by that?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Are you... and Yun Hee...
Mom, your son isn't such a great man.
And Yun Hee noona has
no such feelings for me.
So stop getting ahead of yourself.
I have to go, I have a photo shoot.
Honey, he couldn't have
fallen for Yun Hee, can he?
He didn't say he's marrying Yun Hee,
why get worried so soon?
I'm afraid if this goes on,
they have feelings.
Worse than a life or death love,
having feelings is even scarier.
That's true,
but Kyu Han is not
one to marry someone with a child.
Your son hates that, doesn't he?
Is that right?
That should be the case, right?
Also, you said the kid's
father is back, right?
So of course she will
marry the kid's father,
why would she marry Kyu Han?
Isn't it?
Of course if she marries, she will marry
the kid's father since they have Jin Ju.
And he's not just anyone, he's from a
chaebol* family. (*conglomerate)
For the sake of the kid,
of course she should marry that man.
A chaebol family? Then there's
nothing to worry about
Would such a man allow
his kid to be taken away?
Who? Who is from a chaebol?
Oh well, nothing.
You might not have understood it,
but you could even
sleep at such a place.
You try listening to that for 2 hours,
see if you will fall asleep.
Ah, That's...
but I won't drool.
Who drooled?
Shall we do a DNA test?
You wait here. I'll say hello
to the professor then come back.
No need for me to go?
You want rumors? Then come with me.
Se Won!
No, Manager Kang.
Just call me Se Won, why be a stranger?
What are you doing here?
That's what I want to ask.
I had a meeting.
It's not easy to meet up like this.
Ever since the airport,
we're fated to be together.
If you're done,
how about dinner with me?
Oh! Well...
Shall I?
Sorry, we have an appointment.
Why didn't you tell him about me?
Tell about what?
We have a deal between us.
By a deal, do you mean an engagement?
It's the first time I'm
hearing that Sang Eun's engaged.
It was since long ago,
we can't go through all the details.
We almost forgot about it too.
Yeo Jun!
I'm just stating the facts, am I not?
Not engagement!
Yes, then we're betrothed.
But there's no difference
between the two.
No matter what,
you're not married, right?
Of course.
That's fine then.
Ah! Sang Eun,
do you still remember
that Shakespeare dialogue?
Oh! A person who knows true love, falls in
love with someone in one sight. That?
You still remember.
When I was 11 years old,
I fell in love with you.
You're putting me in a spot now,
but we were betrothed when we were born.
Let's go.
Se Won, see you back at the school.
You made a violation.
Why?
Contract Term no. 4.
We won't behave in a manner that
elders will be suspicious of.
What has that got to do with my job?
Your first love is so proactive,
how will the elders not be suspicious?
There's nothing between us.
It's best there's nothing.
I don't care how much you like that man,
for the sake of our future,
you just have to put up with it.
Otherwise you can marry
him straight off too.
Forget it.
How about dinner?
Our relationship is not good enough
for us to want to eat together.
I'm so thankful for that.
Yes, this is Kim Yeo Jun.
Yes, attorney.
Yes, I understand.
Thank you.
Frustrating.
Is this about Yun Hee unni?
Is it a tough fight?
The other party is far too strong.
As her brother,
there's nothing I can help her with.
If I knew this would happen,
I wouldn't have studied medicine,
I should have studied law.
Sang Eun!
Oh! Dad.
- The two of them look nice together.
- Yes
- Dad.
- Have you eaten?
Not yet.
You still haven't eaten at this hour?
Hello.
Hey, are you penniless
or was it intentional?
We ate a late lunch, Grandfather.
What?
You didn't eat on time for lunch too?
Treating my granddaughter
like this is too much.
You really.
You must eat your meals on time.
You should have asked me for money.
No, I was afraid she'll be too late
getting home and the family would worry.
Don't worry.
What's wrong with eating a little later?
Yeo Jun, come on in.
Let's eat.
We'll go in too.
Really, he should take
good care of Sang Eun.
Yeo Jun,
I'm not happy with you.
Oh hello, brother-in-law.
Brother-in-law?
She still hasn't sorted out her Korean yet.
Hey, how can you call
him brother-in-law?
Why not?
Why can't she call him that?
You're dating, right?
You may not yet be now,
but very soon,
you'll be brother-in-law.
Here, here, here.
Sit down. Wait a bit for the rice
First, have some tea.
How did it go today?
Did you have fun?
Just normal stuff.
Your answer is rather stifled.
Ah! Brother-in-law,
what are you doing this weekend?
Nothing special.
Then let's do a Seoul tour.
Bring me along on your date, all right?
Han Hyo Eun!
Yes. Yes, Yeo Jun!
Hey, keep yourself free.
Show Sang Eun and
Hyo Eun around in Seoul.
What?
Ah! Okay.
No,
Hyo Eun can just go with me.
That way, Hyo Eun will
be more comfortable.
No,
I think I'd be more comfortable
if I go with brother-in-law.
Unni, you have no car.
Why are you so thick-skinned?
I'm not thick-skinned, I'm just honest.
of course it's more
convenient to go by car.
Unni, what did you do today?
- I did what you said.
- What I said?
What did I say?
Ah! So you two really slept together?
Hey!
What?
I almost took that for real.
But Unni, are you two really dating?
Certainly.
Then why aren't you calling him?
Call whom?
Yeo Jun oppa.
To ask if he got home safely.
From our place to his is not that far,
it's too troublesome to call.
Of course he'll be home safely.
You sure you're dating?
Yes, Se Won.
Tomorrow?
I'm not free tomorrow morning,
I have something on.
Sorry.
Unni,
let me give you an advice.
If you really want to
hide it from everyone,
you need a cellphone.
You can't even call each other,
how can that be dating?
I got mine already.
The newest model.
Your brain sure works fast
for such stuff, Hyo Eun.
Yeo Jun,
Yes?
You must be treat your noona well.
Not because you're the eldest son,
but because we're family.
I know.
I just met with father,
what exactly are your plans?
Hyung, I really can't accept
you behaving like this.
Collaborating with Seoul Electronics...
The walls have ears, watch what you say.
Who is that man?
What is it you want?
I have no way out.
You won.
Other than Jin Ju,
you can have whatever you want.
So stop bothering my
family members from now on.
That grandfather is
part of your family too?
Sang Eun's grandfather?
Whoever he is.
Of course he's family.
I'm not family,
yet that grandfather who's not even
blood-related,
he's family to you?
He's different from you.
Just tell me, what is it you want?
I told you the other time,
I want you to tell Jin
Ju about my existence.
Fine.
That is all.
You have no demands to make of me?
Of course I do.
Stop coming to bother me and Jin Ju,
but you just wouldn't agree to it.
Let's start over again, Yun Hee.
I'm sorry but I cannot accept that item.
Ah! If you can give up everything
including your family and come back to me,
I will give it some thought,
but I don't think you
will agree to that, right?
After Jin Ju is done with her ballet class,
come to the shop.
You should know very well
what time that is, right?
Thank you but I have to reject it.
My blablah is never going
to withstand this thing.
Blablah?
Jin Ju's favorite teddy bear.
Jin Ju,
I told you before,
where is Jin Ju's dad now?
America.
I thought you told her I was dead.
I told you,
I never lie to a kid.
What did you tell her
I went to America for?
Why? You're worried now?
Then you ask her yourself.
Jin Ju,
why did your dad go to America?
Mom and I are not his family,
he has another family there.
He's living with that family there.
That's right,
but your dad's here to see you now.
This ahjussi is my father?
Yes.
I see.
Hello.
Yes, hello.
So from now on, we will live together?
- Well...
- That will not happen.
I told you,
Jin Ju, you will live with me,
your dad will live with his family.
Then Mom, can I go over
to Kyu Han ahjussi now?
Yes, go ahead.
Dad, goodbye.
Are you happy now?
This is all you can do
for your duty as a father.
Ah! Jin Ju is a girl,
she doesn't quite like
blue, nor huge dolls.
Grandma, I saw my dad today,
he came back from America.
Jin Ju, go get grandpa
some juice, all right?
Grandpa!
What does she mean by 'dad'?
Today, I arranged for
the two of them to meet.
Why did you go to that fella?
What are you planning to do?
No matter how, he's Jin Ju's dad.
Yeo Jun found out from the lawyer,
no matter how unwilling we are,
we can't take away his right to see Jin Ju.
How is Jin Jun? Is she shocked?
Better than I expected, I guess.
Maybe she's used to not living with her dad.
Aigoo! Who knows how she thinks?
Father,
stop lowering
yourself in front of that man.
For the sake of my own child,
can't I do that?
Even so, I don't like you doing that.
Whether it's for me or for Jin Ju,
don't do that again.
It's nothing big,
as long as you can be happy,
what is it I won't do?
I'm sure I saw that man before,
where was it?
And he's not just anyone,
he's from a chaebol family.
That's right.
The number you dialed is engaged,
please call again later.
Got it, I think it'll take 20 minutes.
Remember to call Doctor Lee.
Sorry for doing that to you.
Why be sorry for an
emergency situation like this?
Yes but luckily you didn't
have any other appointment.
Ah! Lend me your cell phone.
Noona, help me get in
touch with Sang Eun.
Ask her to call me.
I arranged to meet her this afternoon
but I think I'm going to be late.
Hyo Eun has a cell phone?
That's better than someone else we know.
We'll talk later.
Sang Eun?
That was Sang Eun the other time, right?
Something's fishy.
Oh, Hye Rim!
You said Yeo Jun oppa
came to work, where is he?
I have something important to tell him.
He'll be right out,
do you want to wait at the lounge?
Lounge?
Can I get you something?
Hye Rim, if you're interested
in Dr. Kim Yeo Jun,
I'd advise you to drop the idea.
He's dating his betrothed now,
they have a date today too.
Date?
That's right.
Why would he push aside Hye Rim
and go for the overseas-returnee?
That's not the right thing to do!
Have you always liked to talk
about others behind their backs?
What?
Yeo Jun oppa takes you as his
junior so he looks after you,
you shouldn't be doing this.
Ah... Well...
Anyhow, I'm disappointed in you.
But...
I'm not...
Where are you?
You're looking for Yeo Jun oppa?
Oh dear, oppa's busy at the moment.
I already told you the other time,
you're not supposed to pester oppa.
What?
When he comes back,
I'll let him know you called.
But I'm not sure
if we'll have the time for that.
Oppa.
What? He's so busy at the hospital,
yet he has time to be with a girl.
Who is that girl?
There's a girl who is rather nasty.
Is she prettier than you, Unni?
So, brother-on-law's not coming?
He's not coming.
Oh yes, stop calling him brother-in-law,
puts me in a bad mood.
Hello?
That man with Yun Hee unni is
from Sung Hyun Group, correct?
How did you know that?
I'm a model for that department store,
so I recognize most
people from that company.
I've been pondering
whether to tell you or not,
I still think you
have the right to know.
What is it?
It's about Sang Eun.
I think Sang Eun made a blunder.
maybe it wasn't intentional.
What?
Jin Ju...
How did they find out about her?
Oppa, you know Sang Eun is
seeing other men too, right?
Sang Eun.
Oh! You're here.
She's your younger sister?
I'm Kang Se Won.
Ah... Yes,
Hello.
But how did you know Hyo Eun's number?
I haven't memorized it yet myself.
I called back and someone
gave me her number.
It was written on your memo notebook.
Ah!
Unni, we did the right
thing coming to Seoul.
Why?
If we were in Australia,
how could you have so many men?
Se Won...
Se Won is only my boss, that's all.
Ah... You're the same whether
you're there or here.
Who is it?
Who else will call you
now except Yeo Jun oppa?
Forget it, the bus has
left the stop already.
This has no syrup.
- Thanks.
- Cappuccino for Hyo Eun.
How did you know my unni likes it black?
That's right, how did I know that?
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Se Won oppa, thanks for today.
Why say that? Remember to
call me any time you need me.
Really?
I'll take your word for it, bye!
A tiring day, right?
It was nothing.
Whenever you need me,
just call me any time.
What are you doing to this woman here?
Let go of Han Sang Eun!
Are you still pestering her?
Were you really going to sell my
noona in order to teach at that school?
Can't Jeong Kyu Han like Kim Yun Hee?
Why are you doing this?
You don't know who is her betrothed?
What do you mean by
'Jin Ju has disappeared'?
Hey, Kang Hae Seong, where are you?
Tell me now, where are you?
Oh dear, we have a date today.
Are you dating only because you're
betrothed or are you sincere about it?
Don't tell me I'm
really jealous about him?
I don't like it,
I'm not comfortable with it.