And another quick
knock out for Mason Dixon,
although de facto, the fans let
him know how they feel about it.
Hide the women and
children, this could get ugly.
This crowd does
nothing to hide its anger,
over this latest debacle.
Fans are mad as hell, they
don't want to take it anymore.
They seem to be blaming
Dixon, a good fighter,
for decline of not only the
heavy-weight division guys,
but of the entire sport.
They're actually pelting the undefeated
heavy-weight champion
of the world with ice!
Maybe this angry visceral reaction
will pressure Dixon to fight someone
who could fight back for a change.
If there's somebody out there.
World of the boxing is hoping for a
warrior who threw us with his passion.
Andrian Balboa
Time goes by too fast.
Yeah, not fast enough.
Your kid should've been there.
Nah, it's alright, Paulie.
No, it ain't alright!
Oh you know, the kid gets
a little busy sometimes.
He don't get that busy.
Well, let's not talk
about it here, okay?
You're coming tonight, right?
I'm working!
I took the tour the last three years!
I know, but it's the anniversary.
Fine, you got my word.
I appreciate it, thank you.
I owe you, Paulie.
Yo, Robert. What's going on?
Where have you been? You're late!
No, I don't want to hear any excuse!
Look, your job perfomarnce is no
way near good enough. It's pointless!
I don't give a damn who your
father is, you understand me?
- Yeah.
- Alright.
Alright. Now get outta here.
Thank you, Sir.
Yo, Robert!
- Yo!
- Hey, Rocky.
Hey, how're you doin'?
- Hey!
- What's up, champ'?
You caught me off guard!
I know I caught you off guard.
I wanted to catch you
before you got to busy!
Yeah, it gets busy up there.
- So how ya doin'?
- Real good.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yo, Rock!
Yeah, how're you doing?
Yeah, real good.
Hey listen, you want to go
out and get some coffee?
I'm kinda behind...maybe later?
Yeah...that'd be great!
You know, you ought to come
by to the restaurant tonight,
I can have something
made special for you.
Tonight I can't...I've got plans.
Few other guys, stick
together, you know...
Did I say something wrong?
What...what do you mean?
Well...
I don't know exactly what I mean,
but I just think like when I come
here you don't feel so comfortable,
and I certainly don't want to do that.
You throw a big shadow.
A big shadow?
You're not getting anything
done down here, Robert.
You're not gonna
introduce me, then I will.
- Hi, I am William Tomisson.
- How ya doin'?
Your son has the
misfortune of working for me!
It's a good job.
You know, I gotta tell ya,
I told Robert about twenty
times that I wanted to meet you!
But I guess you're pretty busy!
- Which is a bad thing, isn't it?
- Well, I get a little tired...
Hey look, grab a shot, will you, please?
I may not get this chance again,
us old war horses gotta
stick together, don't we?
- The old horses, yeah.
- I tell you!
It's not your left.
This makes very popular with people.
- One, two, three.
- Finally, we get to meet!
Oh look, I kind of get going, it
was nice to meet you face to face.
- How ya doin'?
- Alright, you take care of yourself.
Robert, I'll see ya later.
I've got to get going.
I'll change my plans for tonight.
Oh, that'd be great.
- I'm looking forward to!
- Okay.
- How ya doin'?
- Okay!
- Alright.
And do not let those
numbers drive you crazy.
Too late!
Use an eraser, and
get rid of all of them!
- Hey Rock'.
- Hey guys.
- Hey Rock'!
- Hey, how you doin'?
Here you go.
You know, I'll buy 10 of them, OK?
You guys take care, OK?
You got it.
Tell you what, I'll try
a few of these later on.
This good for making.
How much?
Yo, Paul, what's the cost?
$58.40, Sir.
Alright, take out of that. I trust you.
Yeah.
- Here you go, Rock'.
- You're generous.
No problem!
Hi, you guys!
How are you doing, Isabel?
Okay, except for the freebee
reading the Bible over there.
Nah, he's ok.
You know, just because
you've fought him,
but you don't got to feed him forever.
He doesn't even look like a fighter!
Spider Rico can hit!
Listen, how's your stomach?
You know, if you keeping rubbing
that oliver oil on your stomach,
and your kid's gonna
be born very strong!
- OK, I don't know what to say.
- No, really.
- Yo, how're you doin', Spider?
- God bless you, Rocky.
Thanks.
- How you guys doing?
- Alright.
Jose, can you make
something special for my kid,
he's coming tonight.
- No problemo.
- Good, I appreciate it.
Back and forth. Give and take. And then,
I went down there like an animal,
and I threw him into the corner.
And I unloaded everything I had!
Hook, hook, hook. Left, left, left.
But Creed, he kept
busting me back pretty good.
In the end, it did begin to pile up.
Then I heard the best sound
I've ever heard in my life...
- The bell!
- That's right, the bell.
And I ain't never been so tired
and I'm sitting in my corner,
and I'm trying to figure out
how to survive the last round
when Mickey leans near my ear and says:
"C'mon, get out there and
fight this guy hard, you bum!"
"You gotta be first,
you gotta be first!"
I said: "Yo Mick', if I could...
- I would!
- I would.
- The end.
- Salute.
Salute.
And another quick knock out for
Mason Dixon, although de facto
the fans let him know
how they feel about it.
They are actually pelting the undefeated
heavy-weight champion
of the world with ice!
Hello, Adrian's.
Yeah.
Tell him you can't make it?
Yeah, I'll leave the message.
I just kept hear it,
Voice in my head all over again,
I just dug down before I knew all
of this. Just try toe to toe, he was...
Excuse me.
Your son said he can't make it,
he said he'll take a rain check, ok?
These birds...
Don't these birds look like candy?
Flying candy! Hey bird,
you want to fly me home?
You need somebody to walk you home?
It's a cold night.
We need a few laughs around
like, what do you think? Maybe?
Maybe?
Maybe? Okay, let's get outta here!
That place didn't change
much from last year.
We're done?
Hey, how you doin', Mick?
The sign's falling apart, Paulie.
The whole world is falling apart.
- Look at us!
- You talk crazy, Paulie.
You know, I think if you live
in some place long enough...
...you are that place.
I ain't no talking building.
Go on, it's getting late, Rocko.
I get a headache from this train.
I remember when she
was standing there...
All nervous and shy
with that little smile.
And all I wanted her
to do was to trust me.
She did.
You're done?
- How long we stay at it?
- Not long.
Well, I'm glad they
tore this ice rink down!
- Come on!
- You heard me?
I'm happy they tore it apart.
First time I walked your sister
across this ice, we was over there.
She was nervous, but I
wasn't so great at blades either.
Ice is stupid, people
standing on ice are more stupid!
And over there...
...where she was fallen,
and my hand grabbed her...
And I got her arm through
that coat I could feel...
...electric.
You said the same
thing last year, Rock'...
Did I?
You weren't born much of the body,
you'd better develop your brain.
You never got a chance
because you're left handed, huh?
Absolutely, but...
Come on, Rock! Let's go.
We're done.
There's no place to
sit down around here.
Oh, it's alright!
It ain't alright, it's
depressing and freakin' cold!
What's the matter with you, Paulie?
You're livin' backwards, Rocko!
Jesus, change the
channel from yesterday!
- Yesterday wasn't so great.
- It was to me.
Not to me!
You treated her good!
You had your good times.
I treated her bad, I don't
have to think about this.
She always loved you, Paulie.
Sorry, Rocko. I can't do this no more.
Can I help you?
Nah, I used to come down this place
a long time ago, I just look around.
No big deal.
Can I get you a drink?
Alright, maybe just a short beer.
Okay.
Listen...
I don't mean to cross
the line or anything, but...
...I read about your wife's
passing a few years back.
Yeah, it was a women cancer.
Yeah.
I always heard she was a nice person.
Yeah, the best.
- Do I know you?
- We met a long time ago.
We did?
When I was a kid, you walked me home.
I did?
Told me to stop smoking and things...
Stop smoking...
Are you the lil Marie that used to
hang around that atomic hoagie shop?
Yeah, that's right.
Now I remember...I walked you home,
and when you got there,
you turned around and said:
"Screw you, creepo!"
- I didn't say that.
- Yeah, you did.
You sure?
Great insults last a long time!
Yo!
Yo, was that you, is that really you?
- How're you doing?
- I think he wants to drink alone.
Well then give him his drink
then. I ain't stopping you.
What's that your man or
something? No, I don't think so!
Anyway...
...me and my friends,
we are right down there.
You think, you think
you can buy us a round?
Come on, you've got the
money, just one round!
Hey, hey...
- Take care.
- What are you...?
What're you doing,
pushing my hand away like that?
What's your name?
Angie, what do you wanna know for?
Angie, don't be playing the
fool for that guy, alright?
- A fool?
- Yeah.
A fool? I'm the fool?
You're the fool, not me!
You've got it twisted. You're the fool.
I'm a person just like you.
You ain't no better than me. You think
you're a big shot there? You ain't!
You ain't no better than me!
No better!
Wow...
Glad you dropped in?
Think the neighborhood's
changed a little.
- What was that all about?
- I don't know, forget about it, it's ok.
Well, I'm gonna lock off,
so if you want to take off,
I'll tally everything up.
Yeah, thanks.
- How're you doing, Rock?
- I'm good, thanks.
- You live around here?
- About eight blocks from here.
Eight blocks...
Would you need a lift?
Alright.
- You ever get married?
- Yeah, sort of.
- Sort of?
- Yeah, he took off.
- Pouf, just like that.
- Yeah, just like that.
- Are you sort of have any kids?
- Yeah, yeah I've got one kid.
Yeah, me too...me too.
- A wonderful boy.
- Hey...tough guy!
What's the matter,
you can't buy a round?
Huh? Girl has been nice, you dumb ass!
Yeah, what're you doing with that pig?
...go around here, and disrespect us?
Come on back, come on back!
Hey, don't listen to 'em.
You ain't no better than me.
Come over here.
Everybody ain't perfect.
You punch-drunk!
- Goofy bastard.
- You ain't no big shot. Look at you!
You haven't even got a
car to take that pig home!
You alright?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Don't get out, it's alright!
No, little Marie...it ain't alright!
Yo!
What? I'll tell you
what! You get inside.
You get inside.
Hey, leave him alone!
- Alright.
- You see that?
- Yeah, yeah.
- What do you say?
- I'm sorry.
- C'mon, I'm sorry!
- Get a job!
That guy sends his apologies.
Okay.
Martin?
Yo, Mart'!
I see you still got your key...
Yeah, I've got a key.
You've got time to talk?
I've got a lot of time
since you people let me go.
You know I had nothing to do with that.
Yeah.
Yeah, we moved in about a year ago.
Yeah?
- Yeah, but it's only temporary.
- Yeah, I can see that.
- I'm gonna look for an apartment.
- Your apartment is nice.
- Yeah, it is what it is, you know.
- Yeah, it is what it is.
But you know, this place
used to be pretty nice.
You know, there's a lot
of history around here.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, like...
...down the street
there there's a fight club.
They used to call that place
like the bucket of blood,
I took some massive beating down there!
But it was nice, good memories.
And I've heard these buildings
are like, I don't know...like
...150 years old.
So, I mean if I was 150 years
old, I'd be falling apart too, so...
...it's okay, building!
Does that light work?
- Nah, it's burnout or something.
- Oh yeah?
Yeah.
Hey listen, thanks for the ride and...
...I'm sorry about those
guys and everything.
Oh, it's ok. Y'know some of those
guys just let the brains on them,
backwoods or stuff.
What's he doing out so late?
- Is it your kid?
- Yeah.
Wish he wouldn't stay out so late.
Amazing!
- Yeah? What's that?
- Oh...
Last time I've seen
you, you was the kid...
And now you officially
got one on your own.
It's amazing.
You know, he sorta resembles
you, he got that...y'know...
...big Irish hair!
Yeah, it's the other one.
Yeah?
- His father was from Jamaica.
- Jamaica, European...
Was you on a cruise ship or somethin'?
- No, not really.
- What's his name?
Steps.
- Short for Stevenson.
- Makes sense.
Is he look on like he's mad at me,
or is it maybe the
angle I'm standing at?
No, no. He's a good kid.
You wanna meet him?
No...It's getting kinda late,
I've got so much things to do.
Yeah, I understand.
Thanks again for the
ride and everything else.
See you.
You too.
Hey Steps, come on, let's go!
Say good night to your friend.
What are you doing in the
cold with no hat on? You cold?
- You get something to eat?
- Yeah. I already ate.
- Yeah? Alright.
- Yeah.
- You're late, you know?
- That's not a problem.
Yo, little Marie!
Ain't you gonna
introduce me to your kid?
- How're you doing, Steps?
- What's up?
Listen, I've got this place.
restaurant, nice little eatery.
Not too far from here.
So much junk tissue!
Sometimes, I feel like a kangaroo with
all that stuff in my pocket, you know?
Here you go. I've got
a card, there it is.
And if you ever get a chance, it'll
be great both of you come down there,
to eat everything with great free!
I'll leave it over there...
Here.
Leave it on the steps...
...Steps!
See ya later.
Come on, let's go.
You know what's best
for you since you were ten,
since you walked in here alone.
You got everything money can buy...
except what it can't.
It's pride.
Pride is what got your ass outta here.
And losing is what brought you back.
The people like you...
...they need to be tested!
They need a challenge!
But you know that ain't never
gonna happen, it'll not Mart!
There's always somebody out there.
Always.
And when that time comes, and you
find something standing in front of you,
something that ain't running, and that
ain't backing up, it's hitting on you,
and you're too damn tired to breathe...
You find a situation on you that's good.
Cuz that's baptism under fire!
When you get through that,
you find the only kinda respect
that matters in this damn world.
Self-respect.
Thanks, Mart. I appreciate it.
What can a champ do for you?
You can give me some
of the money you got.
- You know I like you, Mart!
- But not that much!
How about a picture with
the kid, Rock? Is that alright?
Sure.
Hey son, hold up your fist, make
sure it looks more hazardous.
- There you go.
- Nice ones.
Enjoy your meal.
- He's a nice guy, isn't he?
- Rocky?
- Yeah?
- Listen up...
Spider's went downstairs, I don't
know if that's alright or not, so...
- What's he doing down there?
- I don't know, it's your friend!
Yo, Spider!
Let me do some dishes. I'll feel better.
- Oh, come on! You're my guest.
- Let me do something.
Well, keep the Indians do that.
Don't make me fight again!
Last time, you got lucky!
Lucky? Okay.
Jesus wants me to work.
Yo, Rocky!
Yeah?
You've got guests.
Don't get too wet, okay?
Glad Jesus didn't ask him to cook...
- You kept the card.
- Yeah, I kept the card.
Yeah, why don't you sit down?
Yeah, sure.
Excuse me.
Because you know what? I walk
in there, I say good morning...
...I do this, I do this.
Tonight, boxing once again!
Two contrasting styles
in almost every way.
- Hi, everybody welcome to ESPN.
- Hey, can you turn this up?
Turn this up, please!
Who was the best of all time?
If two athletes from different eras could
actually compete against one another,
who would come out on top?
Giving the same rules,
using the same equipment,
who was the greatest?
This week, we feed our
facts into computer.
They will weigh up who
they think will win supreme.
While fill the good comments of
our lustrous panel of sportswriters.
Champ!
- Yo, champ.
- Yo!
Man come check out this trash,
they're talkin' about you, man!
What are you talkin' about?
Come on man, come
check this out, hurry up!
Tonight, the former two-time
heavyweight champion from Philadelphia,
Rocky Balboa.
All right, Chuck Johnson, USA Today.
There's no question
that Rocky Balboa fought
the much tougher fights during
the much tougher era of boxing.
We look in Mason Dixon and his career,
he's basically been
spoon-fed to his opponents.
No question in my mind, no
matter what he does Rocky win,
but he wins knock-out!
Offspring!
Juan Fernandez, what do you think?
Dixon is a victim of his own dominance.
He's never been in real
knocked on drag on brows.
He's never had to
dig down to rally back.
What if he tries to dig
down against Balboa,
he's gonna find that he does
not have a big enough travel.
What happened to you?
Come on, take it back!
Let's take it to Bert "rand up" Sugar.
Dixon has fought cream pot.
So we really don't know what he's
made of, but both in their primes,
you got a factor in here.
Dixon's unbelievable
speed and slashing offence,
he cuts Balboa, no doubt!
Dixon wins all the way.
Alright, here's where
our subjectivity ends.
Let's see what the computer
has to say. What's happening?
Dixon unloads on Balboa!
Rocky has no answer.
What time is it? Mason time!
Now Dixon is standing...
He's almost out on his feet!
Balboa turning up the heat!
He's been on corner
this time. Believe it!
Oh, a murderous raider!
And Dixon is out on his feet...
...as he crumbles to the cannon.
And it's Balboa who...
Ladies and gentlemen:
"Baby Rocky, Baby Rocky"!
Yo, I'm glad you liked
the food, but heat that up
it's pretty good in the morning.
Yeah, thanks man.
Nice kid. I hope this music
ain't giving you a headache,
but I like this whole stuff.
No, I like it...it's nice.
Good.
Yo. You think...
...Steps wants a job, y'know
to make a few bucks on weekends.
It's good makin' your own jean.
I keep stash a few bucks during nine.
Why are you being so nice?
You know, I don't want you to
think nothing's off, you know.
My wife, she's gone...
...but she ain't, you know what I mean?
Yeah, I was't thinking that, believe me.
- No?
- No.
What were you thinking?
I think about you
don't know us nothing...
- What are you doing?
- Oh, be patient!
Now.
I don't know you nothing.
But why you gotta owe something...
...to get...
Bingo!
But why you gotta owe something
to get something. You know?
Really.
You know...I think hanging
out with your kid would be nice.
- What do you think?
- I think that'd be nice.
Good.
That's very nice.
I'm glad you come by.
Nice...
Nice watch you eat.
Good company.
Yo, lil Marie!
Let there be light!
- You like dogs?
- Dogs?
Dogs. This is like a dog pawn,
so they keep...
...a large rally of dogs.
I used to come here all the
time for sight seeing, but...
You know, you learn
a lot talkin' to dogs.
- Really, you do.
- Yeah?
Hey, man. How about this one?
Hey, he don't look
too friendly, my friend.
Oh, man this is the one.
Hey, how're you doing?
Hey, hey what about this one here?
- Come here, boy.
- Oh, him?
- Yeah, why not?
- Oh, hell no!
That's one ugly dog, man!
I know, but it's kind
of a cute dog, you know?
If you look at him closely,
the color, a kind of looks like
old furnish, like some kinda...
...pirate chest thing, goin' on here.
Yeah, sure man.
Hey, so how about the young one?
Yo, Steps. Get him.
Come over here. I want
you to see something.
Now you know what
this animal is doing here?
Lying in that position?
He ain't doing nothing.
No, he's doing lie, he
ain't wasting no energy.
Cause he's dead!
No, no he ain't dead!
There's a lot of good mileage
who was left into that animal.
You know, some good food, a
dish and a couple of new friends...
Bingo, he's back!
But what do you think
is like a good name?
I mean, it's your dog...you name it!
Hey, no, it's like a
cumulated animal, 50-50.
Look, I don't know much about no dogs.
Oh, you know Steps, it
ain't that complicated!
Y'know, you pet'em, you feed'em...
The nature takes its
course. You know so, but...
Don't you want to name an animal?
I think every guy
should one time try to...
...name an animal or something.
I don't know...Fleabag!
It's catchy, I don't know...
It ain't original, but
it's pretty good, and...
I think though you can come
up with your young brain,
something better to throw out...
...than like fleabag.
Punchy! How's that?
- Punchy?
- Yeah, Punchy!
- I like it. You know?
- For real?
Yeah, for real! Y'know punchy it is.
I think Punchy is easy to remember,
it's not that hard to spell...
Once it's in your brain,
you'll never forget it.
- Punchy, very good!
- Alright, man!
Good call.
Alright, Punchy!
You ready to be belled up, my friend?
Okay!
Hey, you know it was a joke, right?
Yeah, I know. You're a very funny guy!
Uh, Rocky?
- Excuse me.
- No problem.
- Rock...
- Yo, Paulie...
Hey, they're gonna be talkin'
about that fake Looney Tunes fight!
Hey, come on! We're about
to serve today's special.
Italian food cooked up by a bunch
of Mexican ain't so special, Rocko!
Hey, yo.
Hey, I skipped work for this!
What an ugly dog!
It's a cute dog.
- Hey, Rock.
- Yep.
I'm gonna take off, alright?
Hey, that stuff back
there is pretty cool!
- Oh, you liked that?
- Yeah, man!
Thanks, I appreciate it.
- I'll catch you later.
- Good night.
- Who's the criminal?
- He's a nice kid.
He dresses like a bum!
Coming from a human hamper,
that's quite a compliment!
- Hide the silverware!
- It's nice.
Hey, Spider.
Haven't you knocked up that bum once?
Will you give a rest?
I'm gonna be late for work
for this, gimme a break, huh?
Alright, just for a few seconds.
In the late 60's, a simulated fight
took place between two legends.
Muhammad Ali and Rocky Marciano.
Marciano, long retired,
and Ali, unable to fight
legitimately for 3 years
for having refused induction
into the Armed Forces,
was in need of money and agreed
to the so-called dream match,
whose outcome would
be decided by a computer.
It's almost 35 years
since Rocky Marciano
won the much disputed computer decision.
And guess what? Not much has changed!
Last week, Rocky Balboa...
See? That's the cartoon
fight I told you about!
Yeah.
A stunning knock-out,
and keep in mind this has
taken the human factor out of it.
- Wow, that was beautiful.
- It says Rocky Balboa...
- ...would be triumphant.
- K.O. thirteen.
And here's some of the fallout.
You know, what has started as
a simple form of entertainment,
has now become this
rallying cry for people
who think an old-school
athlete like Balboa
could actually be better.
So the computer technology
has to create what is it.
That's just not responsible.
Get up, will you?
How do you think Balboa
would have done against Dixon?
Badly! Personally, I think
Balboa was completely overrated!
You know he owns a little
restaurant, in south Phila.
What's his specialty, pounded chicken?
Anyway, I would have
paid to see the fight!
Next topic, NASCAR and the
controversy that won't go away.
Let's go back to sunday's race...
Hey, hey, hey! Cheer up.
Free advertisement.
Come on, meat house's closed.
Yo, Robert.
What is this? What are
you doing out so late?
Uh, you know, I tried calling
but no one was picking up.
- Something wrong?
- No,no.
I just wanted to come by
and see you personnaly.
You wanna come inside?
No, uh you know, I just want to
get your opinion on something.
Sure. Opinion on what?
Well, y'know what they say,
you only go around once, right?
- Yeah, I've heard that.
- Well...
I think I wanna like...do something.
Like what?
Fight!
Y'know, nothing big!
Small stuffs like locally.
Don't you think you're too...
...y'know, old?
Yeah, but you think I
ought to stop trying things
cause you've had a
few too many birthdays.
I do not.
People gonna think you're goin' crazy!
What's crazy about standing
toe to toe, sayin': "I am"?
It's just the ego you talking.
What are you trying to
prove to other people, pop?
Prove? Listen, I...
I stopped thinking the way the
other people think a long time ago!
Ya know, you gotta think like you think.
- I do.
- Do you? Good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Face reality!
Okay? It's a different world now.
Only the clothes is different.
I really don't know
what you want from me.
I just want us to get
involved you know, like...
...home team.
Whatever it is...
whatever you're going through...
It'll pass.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Time's gonna catch up for all of us.
Especially for standing still, you know?
Hey, come on.
C'mon, I'll call you in the morning.
Did you tell this to
your kid by the way?
Yeah, I did.
What did he think, you're nuts, right?
Yeah.
Well, you don't believe in you?
Welcome to my world, buddy!
Rocko, nobody's
giving you no title shot.
I know that, I don't want one.
So this isn't a mental disturbance?
No.
You're mad maybe because
they took down your statue?
No.
- No, really no.
- If it's about money...
...just hang a sign around your
neck, saying: "Punch Me!".
Five dollars. You'll make big money!
What? You haven't peaked yet?
- Peaked?
- Yeah, peaked!
I don't know, there's still
some stuff in the basement.
- What basement?
- In here.
Tell me about the stuff.
- What about it?
- Tell me about the stuff inside.
- Is it angry?
- Angry?
Are you mad because Adrian left you?
She didn't leave, Paulie. She died.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
You know...sometimes
it's hard to breathe.
Y'know I fell this...
...beast inside me.
It's ok, Rocko. Please, it's ok.
Is it...
...ok.
I didn't know...I just never knew
it was supposed to be that hard.
It wasn't supposed to be
like this, Paulie. You know it.
I say, you wanna come
by and help me train?
- I've got a job here.
- I understand.
Remember you said if you
stay in one place long enough...
...you become that place?
Rocko, this is all like that.
I understand, Paulie. I do.
Well, if you get time, you may
come down and see me train.
I'd appreciate it.
Of course, Rocko.
Bye, Paulie.
Goodbye, Rocko.
Take care, Rocko.
This plenary session of the
Pennsylvania Athletic Commission
is convened in order to consider
the application of Rocky Balboa
for the issuance of the discretionary
professional boxing license.
Due to his ineligibility
to be licensed as a matter of right.
Mister Balboa, you're welcome here.
Since you're representing yourself,
we invite you to make an
opening statement if you'd like to.
No, I'm just curious
how I did, that's all.
Alright, well.
The medical advisory
report has informed us
that the battery of tests to
which you've been subjected,
you've passed these
tests with flying colors.
And we congratulate you for that.
- Thanks.
- However, this commission
in good conscious,
cannot recommend you for a license.
And we therefore deny your application.
- Didn't I do what you asked?
- Yes, you did.
So I should get license, right?
Not exactly.
So, why did you give me all them
tests if you was never gonna passing me.
We've got to stand by our decision here.
And we have to deny your
request for a license at this time.
Yo, don't I got some rights?
What rights do you
think you're referring to?
Rights, like in that
official piece of paper
that they wrote down
on the streets there.
- That's the Bill of Rights.
- Yeah, yeah, the Bill of Rights.
Don't it say something about
going after what makes you happy?
No, that's the pursuit of
happiness. But, what's your point?
My point is I'm pursuing something
and nobody looks too happy about it.
But we're just looking
out for your interest.
I appreciate that, but
maybe you're looking out
for your interests
just a little bit more.
I mean, you shouldn't been
asking people to come down here
and pay the freight
on something they paid,
it still ain't good enough,
I mean, you think that's right?
I mean, maybe you're doing your job,
but why you gotta
stop me from doing mine?
Cause if you're willing to
go through all the battling
you got to go through to
get where you want to get,
who's got the right to stop you?
I mean, maybe some of you guys
got something you never fill in,
something you really wanna do,
something you never said
to somebody, something!
And you're told "No", even
after you have paid your dues.
Who's got the right to
tell you that? Who? Nobody!
It's your right to listen to your
gut, it ain't nobody's right to say no
after you earn the right to be what you
wanna be, and do what you wanna do!
You know, the older I get,
the more things I gotta
leave behind, that's life.
The only thing I'm asking you
guys is to leave on the table...
...is what's right.
Yo! Have you seen the paper today?
One row, one row.
That is so great!
Alright. You know what? Let's
go get some food. Food food!
Come on, come on!
Come on! Hey!
The last two papers went in the toilet!
Nobody cares, you're not making
heavy-weight championship money.
There's a bunch of nobody out
there Mason, this is the bottom line
but I want to talk to you
about something I think
is an interesting opportunity.
We should run with it.
Alright? Look at me.
You heard Rocky Balboa applied
for a license and got one, yeah?
Yeah, I heard he got a
licence, forget about it!
- Hear me out, hear me out!
- Hear what out?
You want me to fight a guy
that I can beat with both
hands tied behind my back?
Everybody knows you
can beat the guy sit down.
But that's not what it's
about, it's about making money!
We gotta capitalize
on that computer fight.
This thing could do a million buck,
that's 15.20 million to you, Mas'!
- Forget about it!
- Then what you wanna do?
Cause no one's beaten the door
down to watch you fight anymore.
Look man, we've got guarantee fight.
We don't have guarantee fight!
You wanna do this now? In front
of all your friends, well do it now.
- Whatever.
- We've got nothing, Mas'.
All the fights you command
with the pay-per-view fights,
all are rejected, you
know why? Am I rude?
There're all bummers out
there. Nobody's care about that.
There's no market value.
But, this Balboa thing is interesting.
- I won't do it.
- Because...listen to me!
It's a has-been name
remembered by the world.
And you wanna call this nostalgia
or whatever the hell you want,
but people can relate to that stuff.
This is a no-lose for
everybody, it's all good.
- Good for who?
- For you, not for me, for you!
Excuse me, maybe you don't understand.
People don't like you no more.
They don't follow you or they
don't support you anymore.
Don't you understand that?
And don't look at me like I'm
messing with your legacy.
Every jerk now thinks they got a legacy.
A legacy is what you get instead
of getting paid. That's a legacy.
Hey, man! Don't talk to
me like I'm stupid, alright?
I'm not, I'm not no more.
Mas', Mas'! Everybody knows
you can kick this old man's ass.
But you don't. You leave him
with a little bit of dignity.
So they say: "Mason
Dixon's got compassion."
"He's a decent guy, he's a nice guy."
You'll get a whole new audience,
with double of your
money on the next fight.
You wanna a new image
Mas'? That's how you get it!
What you mean, to replace the one at...?
Whoa, whoa wait, we made your
world green, you made the rest.
All this is you. You made
all this junk happened!
I've had enough to
you with this mess, man!
It's time for me to make some
changes, I'm goin' back to Mart's gym.
Alright, we'll talk about that.
I want Martin back,
there's nothing to talk about.
- Hey, how're you doing?
- Hey, what a surprise!
I was just driving around
the neighborhood, I thought:
"Well, why not drive
by, and say hello?".
Do you want to come inside?
No, I gotta let the
dog do some exercise.
- Do you want to take a little walk?
- Uh, yeah, yeah, alright.
It's nice outside.
Alright.
Nice and brisk.
When did you get a dog?
Uh, we picked up Punchy
a couple of days back.
- Punchy?
- Yeah.
You named a dog "Punchy"?
Well, actually, your
kid come up with the name!
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I think that's disrespectful.
Oh, no no, it's fine really, no.
It's easy to remember,
you told that, you know.
Listen, what do you think about
coming over to the restaurant?
- What for?
- Well, you know, for like...
...for work! The hostess
is gonna be having a kid.
- You'll do good!
- Uh, I don't know.
I tell you you'll do
good, you'll do so good.
I appreciate what you're
doing for my kid. But I can't.
But you know...Hey listen,
I think you'll like it a lot.
It's a nice environment,
it's very pleasant.
Can we drop it?
What's bothering you?
Nothing, it's alright.
Listen, I got to get back.
- No, it ain't alright.
- Oh, come on.
Why?
Well, am I supposed to be the first
person people see when they walk in?
Yeah, you just give them menus,
you say "Hello how are
you?", you sit people down...
But look little Marie! If I
can do it, anybody can do it.
But you can find ten byte of people,
a hundred byte of people for this job.
Give it a trial, like two weeks.
I don't wanna try.
Yo, who put that stuff in your head?
Nobody.
Well, it just don't
get in there by itself.
Thanks for coming by.
Yo!
When was the last time you
went dancing? Has it been a while?
Why are you asking me that?
Well, I'm askin' cuz you dance
around all these promises,
you might want to
come and dance with me.
I ain't that good, but you know,
I'm probably better
than the average bear!
Where that came from, I don't know!
Crazy!
Yeah, a little bit. But the way you're
thinking, the way you're talking...
...that's a little crazy, too!
Come on, you deserve better, really.
Come on...
I need you to class my place up.
Feel I need ya!
And if you say:
"Screw you, creepo"
again, I totally understand.
But I warn you right now.
I'm gonna put myself like
geographically in the
middle of the street here,
and staying here, me and Punchy
and wave to the first bus:
"Come on over here, mash me!"
Cause little Marie turned
down the job at the restaurant!
She thinks she's better than us.
Oh, yeah?
Well, there hasn't been a bus
down here in twenty years.
- Yeah?
- No.
That was a close call!
Listen, seriously.
Come on, be nice.
Alright.
Paulie.
Sorry, Paulie.
Sorry, came from upstairs.
How are you, get my unusual over there.
Excuse me...
Deliveries here are in the back.
I'm not a delivery guy.
Well, do you have a reservation?
Do I look like a freakin' Indian?
Hey, Rock. Rocky!
I think we got a little bit
of a problem with this guy.
A problem? No, no, he's just a relative.
Oh...
Oh, okay.
Yo, Paulie.
- What happened to your eye?
- I hit it.
- Why?
- Needed to.
- What happened?
- I'm celebrating, Rock.
- Why?
- I'm retired.
Retired?
So when they start giving retired
people meat instead of watches, Paulie?
I don't need a watch.
I've got a watch.
You gave me a watch.
Paulie...
I don't need a goddamn watch!
- Yo, Paulie.
- I've got a watch!
I've got two watches.
Yo, Paulie!
Yo, Paulie.
Rock.
It takes guts climbing
back in that ring,
knowing you're gonna take a beating!
- You're gonna do alright, Rocko.
- How do you know that?
The stuff in the basement.
Thanks, Paulie.
- Hey.
- Hey, Rocky.
You're OK?
Yeah, yeah, good, good. How're you?
- Oh, yeah, fine.
- Good.
Listen, there's some guys
who'd want to talk to you.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Yeah.
Thanks for coming by, I appreciate it.
No problem, our pleasure.
So, you wanna hear some stories?
What kind of stories?
Well, a lot of people like to hear
these old fight stories, you know?
- Maybe later.
- Okay.
I'm Lou DiBella.
This is Elso Luca. He's
Mason Dixon's manager.
Would you sit down with us?
Sure.
Please.
You know, we have
the commercial contract
for Mason Dixon, who's
a big fan by the way.
Really?
And when he heard you're
interested in fight again,
he thought: "Why not to
try to work something out?".
Like a special event.
Like a first class exhibition fight.
- Why me?
- He respects the helluva you.
Alright, and let's be honest, that
computer fight got people curious.
This could be very interesting.
Yeah, but I ain't interested in
getting like mangled and embarrassed.
No, that's not gonna
happen, never happen.
Truthfully, I was thinking
more, you know like
minuscule, small level.
You know, small fights.
Not big fights, small fights...
Things that local...you
know what I mean?
Not a bad idea, but
don't think of this as big.
Think of it like a
set, like a exhibition.
Think of this like a
glorified sparring session.
And here's something
I think you'll like.
We're gonna donate a
portion of the gain to charity.
- That's always nice.
- Well, it's good to give.
Yeah.
- Where is it taking place?
- Las Vegas.
Nice and warm. This
cold's gonna be killing you.
It's stiff.
You'll do better when you're
warmer, you know that.
- Yeah...
- And not nothing else...
...you'll have new stories to tell.
I really got to think about this.
Absolutely.
- Is that okay?
- Understand. No problem.
I'm gonna go over there,
you guys can order something.
- What do you recommend?
- It's all eatable.
OK...thanks.
We got him.
Imagine Dixon met this
bastard in his prime...
- He'll kill him!
- No kidding.
Man, I'm confused...
I didn't think this
is gonna come along...
But this is what you wanted, right?
I don't know...
You know, I talk and I talk,
and sometimes I think what
I'm saying is true, and then...
You know, I look at myself, I'm not
even sure what is true anymore.
Cuz it's like I pushed this
crazy idea about fighting.
I mean, what's it all about?
Do I really care about standing
toe to toe, and all that stuff?
Or like my kid says, it's just like...
...ego?
What am I like, this old pub?
Who's just trying to replace
old paint with new paint?
I don't know...I don't know.
Look, I know I usually don't say a lot.
Almost...
...listening and looking.
But you know who you are,
you know the part of
you that's so full of life.
I mean...we all have
that feeling, that fire,
but we usually never
get a chance to use it.
And then it just goes away.
But you can, you've got this
opportunity. So you do it. Why not?
I mean this is who you are. You
know, this is who you'll always be.
And you don't move the side for
nobody until you're ready to move.
And it doesn't matter how
this looks to other people.
All that matters is how it looks to you.
Rocky...
Rocky, look at me.
How it looks to you.
And if this is something
that you wanna do,
and if this is something that
you gotta do, then you do it.
Fighters fight!
You're not gonna punch me, right?
Alright, listen. I gotta go
before I wear up my welcome.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Thanks.
Fighters fight, right.
It's rare when you got to promote
an event that's bigger than boxing.
This is skill versus will.
With part of the
proceeds going to charity.
The brave child of Mason Dixon...
...to honor passed
heavy-weight champions.
Warriors like Rocky Balboa.
Let's open up for questions.
Hey, champ!
Rocky, a few great fighters
have fought in their fifties,
often with disastrous results.
Why risk the danger of embarrassment?
The smart money says you
have virtually no chance.
Puncher always has a chance.
This fight will be competitive.
Why are you doing this, Rocky?
I'd rather do something...
...I love badly, but...
Rocky, the press has
labeled you "Balboasourus"!
How do you feel about that?
Mason, let's say before it happens.
You win, we'll say
you've beaten an old guy.
You lose, say a thumb in the eye,
you'll be the joke of the decade!
Y'all know that will never happen.
This is only exhibition!
Don't go try to make more out
of this than that computer tried.
Is this sport had enough trouble
without these circus events?
Next question.
This looks like a cheap bit of ring
theater between, no offense,
a has-been and a man whose own
credible legacy and popularity is in doubt.
- What's the up-side?
- Doubt?
Up-side? I mean...
What do you mean upside?
I mean what do I have to do?
You know, I'm 33 over 30 knock-outs.
I'm doing you people a favor, I'm
gonna do this exhibition for you all!
And you got to get up here
to make a mockery outta me?
I'm the champ!
I mean, I get pissed this guy get hurt!
See you at the fight!
This guy's a joke,
he's gonna get crushed!
Hello, look who's here!
Hi, uncle Paulie.
- Have you seen my father?
- He's in the back.
Thanks.
You're doing good.
Go eat something, alright?
Excuse me.
How ya doin'?
Glad you'd come by!
- Can I talk with you?
- Sure.
Can we do it outside?
So, you're going through with this?
Yeah, I start training tomorrow.
Hey, Rock!
I've made some connections.
I can make some money
on these endorsements.
Absolutely, do that.
- Thank you, Rock.
- Sure.
So, you're nervous about the fight?
I'm scared to death!
- You don't look scared.
- Well, I ain't supposed to.
Then you don't have to do it.
Yeah, well, I think I do.
You know, living with
you, it hasn't been easy.
People see me, but they think of you!
Now with all this going on,
it's gonna be worse than ever!
- It don't have to be.
- No, sure it does!
Why, you've got a lot going on, kid.
About my last name?
That's the reason I got a decent job.
That's the reason why people
deal with me in the first place.
Now I start to get a little ahead.
I start to get a little
something for myself.
And this happens!
Now I'm asking you as a favor
not to go through this, OK?
This is only gonna end up bad for
you, and it's gonna end up bad for me.
- You think I'm hurting you?
- Yeah, in the way you are.
It's the last thing
I ever wanted to do...
I know that's not what you wanna do.
But that's just the way that it is!
Don't you care what people think?
Doesn't it bother you that
people making you out to be a joke,
and I'm gonna be included in now?
Do you think that's right?
Do you?
You ain't gonna believe this.
But you used to fit right here.
I hold you up and said to your mother:
"This kid's gonna be the
best kid in the world."
"This kid's gonna be somebody
better than anybody ever knew."
And you grew up good and wonderful.
It was great just watching,
every day was like a privilege.
Then the time come for
you to be your own man,
and take on the world. And you did.
But somewhere along the line,
you changed.
You stopped being you.
You let people stick
a finger in your face,
and tell you you're no good.
And when things got hard, you
started to look for something to blame.
Like a big shadow...
Let me tell you
something you already know.
The world ain't all
sunshines and rainbows.
It's a very mean and nasty place,
and I don't care how tough you
are, it'll beat you to your knees
and keep it there
permanently if you let it.
You, me or nobody...
...is gonna hit as hard as life.
But it ain't about how hard you hit.
It's about how hard you can get hit,
and keep moving forward.
How much you can take,
That's how winning is done!
Now, if you know what you're worth,
then go out and get what you're worth.
But you gotta be
willing to take the hits.
And not pointing fingers saying
you ain't what you wanna be
because of him, or her, or anybody.
Cowards do that, and that ain't you!
You're better than that!
I'm always gonna love
you, no matter what.
No matter what happens.
You're my son, you're my blood.
You're the best thing in my life.
But until you start
believing in yourself...
You ain't gonna have a life.
Don't forget to visit your mother.
- Yeah, that is beautiful.
- Yeah.
- You got off early from work?
- No...I left.
I quit.
Quit, why?
I wasn't very...
I don't know, I just...
...I didn't fit in there.
I understand.
- So, what are you gonna do?
- Right now?
Right now, I'd rather be with you.
You're not alright?
Yeah.
It's been a long time
since I've seen a fight.
You know all there is
to know about fighting.
So there's no senses of going
down that same old road again.
To beat this guy,
you need speed.
You don't have it.
And your knees can't take the pound.
So hard running is out.
And you got arthritis in your neck.
And you've got calcium
deposits on most of your joints.
So sparring is out.
I had that problem!
So what we'll be calling on,
is good old-fashioned
blunt force trauma.
Horsepower.
Heavy duty, cast iron,
pile driving punches,
that will have to hurt so
much that'll rattle his ancestors.
Every time you hit him with a shot,
it's got to feel like he tried
kissing the express train!
Yeah!
Let's start building some hurtin' bombs!
Come on, you can do it.
You'll get it, you'll get it.
You can do it, Rocko.
Getting stronger.
Up, up, up!
Come on!
Rocko.
You can do this.
Yeah!
Come on, Rocko.
Come on, come on.
Take him, take him.
You can do it, Rocko.
Getting stronger!
Up, up, up!
Push!
- Oh, yes!
- Yeah!
Rocky Balboa...
...217!
The undisputed heavy-weight
champion Mason Dixon...
...221!
Thank you very much, I
appreciate it, champ! Thanks a lot.
- How much money is in this?
- A lot of it!
Imagine trying to clean this place!
- Seriously...
- Balboa!
Alright you guys, I'll catch
up with y'all later, okay?
Robert, I want you to hang with me.
- How ya doin', champ?
- I'm good.
Yo man, there's no reason for
neither one of us get hurt in this fight.
I'll do my best to care you.
Make sure you save face.
There'll be no embarrassment.
But I promise you...
...you try to press me, you hit
me, you hurt me, you hit me low,
cheap shot me, I'll get you outta there!
You know...a lotta people
come to Vegas to lose, I didn't.
- It's already over.
- It ain't over till it's over!
- Where's that from, the 80's?
- That's probably the 70's.
Just remember what I said.
Hey, yo champ!
Yo, aren't you a little scared?
I don't get scared.
You know, I think you try a
little harder when you're scared...
This is...
...what has worked for me.
- You scared, aren't you?
- Oh, yeah, you're even scarier than me!
Come on, let's see what you've got.
Come on...
Hey, don't hurt me, I'm brittle!
- Hey.
- Hi.
How're you doing?
No, I was just thinking to
tomorrow. Do you want to come in?
No, no, no, no, it's okay.
Uh, I just wanted to...
...I don't know, come by and
wish you good luck for tomorrow.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
I've brought you something.
I hope you don't mind I
took it from the restaurant.
Adrian...
Yeah...thought you keep it safe here.
Yeah, she's always brought me luck!
Yeah!
Yeah...listen, I wanted
to say thanks for everything
you've done for me and my kid, you know.
You've been great and...
It's, you know, tomorrow...
You're gonna prove that the last thing
to age on somebody is their heart.
- I'll try.
- You go showing.
Thank you.
The heavy-weight championship has
been one of sports most coveted titles,
for a hundred and twenty years.
Two-time heavy-weight
champion Rocky Balboa,
the Philadelphia slugger,
renowned for his cast iron jaw,
coriaceous body
attack and will of steel.
All of it to carry the
much smaller fighter
to numerous victories over the years,
against physically superior opponents.
And Mason Dixon, the current
heavy-weight title holder,
with all the speed, determination
and confidence any fighter could want.
But many still question,
whether he has the
heart of a true champion.
Never having been
pushed to go the distance.
Tonight, we find out.
We're at the Mandalay Bay
Events Center in Las Vegas, Nevada,
for the much anticipated showdown,
between Mason "The Line" Dixon,
and Rocky "The Italian Stallion"Balboa.
Hello again! I'm Jim Lampley with
Larry Merchant and Max Kellerman,
live from the Mandelay
Bay Hotel in Las Vegas,
where we anticipate one of the most
outrageous and compelling events,
in boxing history!
The current, unappreciated heavy-weight
champion Mason "The Line" Dixon,
putting his reputation on the line,
against legendary
ex-ex-ex-champion Rocky Balboa.
Even though most see this as
more of a glorified sparring session,
the energy in the room is electric!
Larry, why is this
built as an exhibition?
Well, I guess, so they wouldn't
have to call it an execution!
Zechariah 4.6 says:
It is not by strength...
...not by might...
...but by his spirit...
...we have already claimed the
victory in our Lord Jesus Christ.
- Good luck, Rocky.
- Thanks, Spider.
I appreciate it.
Nobody's expecting much I think,
from the way past his prime
former champion, Rocky Balboa.
Rock...
I gotta talk to ya.
Look...
Look, I know you got a lot of stuff
you want to get outta your system.
Tonight, you do it!
Right?
Get rid of the damn beast.
Let it be done once and for all!
Please, I love you.
Here go the lights! The applause is
bulding toward the glory present off.
Where that come from?
I chose it...
...I love Sinatra!
He's very good, Sinatra.
Let's go!
Very good.
Here comes Rocky Balboa.
A fairy of the warriors,
here for one more last round.
Or the last supper, perhaps
with him as the main course!
What's that music, you can't be serious!
High hopes. Talk about wishful thinking.
Well, maybe no hopes
is more realistic, anyway
the crowd likes it!
Look at the Italian
Stallion, cool and relaxed.
Rocky's off the board
underdog, and they don't care at all.
This is about his pride and dignity,
and this punch guy's
the last thing to go,
is the guy's punch. Rocky
always has that puncher's chance.
Rocky Balboa is still, as you can
hear, the people's champion!
Prediction guys, for
at least two rounds,
Dixon's gonna have his head fold.
Two whole rounds? We have a
cockeyed optimist in the house!
How ya doin'?
Crowd wants to see something,
real or at least.
Rocky Balboa just asked
me how I'm doing now,
I grew up watching this guy!
I never thought I'll be
covering one of his fights!
This is unbelievable,
I'm a fan, I can't help it!
Now here comes Mason Dixon.
Mason Dixon is establishing
his presence on the ring, and...
...somewhere near, a conversation
breaking out at the ring side.
Mike Tyson, calling out
Mason "The Line" Dixon.
You can't win...
I'm the champ!
You should've fought against me!
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
to the Mandalay Bay resort,
and casino in Las Vegas.
And a special main event of the evening,
ten rounds of heavy-weight excitement!
Session by the Nevada
State Athletic Comission.
And when the bell rings, the
referee in charge of the action,
Joe Cortez.
And now, for the
thousands in attendance,
and the millions
watching around the world.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...let's get ready to rrruuuummmmble!
Into the scene first,
fighting over the blue
corner, wearing black with gold,
official weight 217 pounds.
His professional record, 57
victories including 54 knock-outs,
with 23 defeats and 1 draw.
He's the fighting pride of Philadelphia,
the two-time heavy-weight
champion of the world...
..."The Italian Stallion", Rocky Balboa!
I'll beat him till his head busts.
Shut up!
Across the ring, fighting
up at the red corner,
wearing white with blue.
Official weight 221 pounds.
He has a perfect professional record.
Consisting of 33 bouts,
33 victories, including 30 knock-outs.
Originally from Tampa, Florida, but
now fighting at Las Vegas, Nevada,
The reigning, undisputed, undefeated
heavy-weight champion of
the world, Mason "The Line" Dixon.
Alright, gentlemen.
Alright, Mason.
Rocky, we went the
rules at the dresser room.
I expect a good clean fight,
watch for kidney punches,
rabbit punches, those low blows,
be careful with those, alright?
Gimme good sportsmen-like combat.
Remember, gentlemen a fair, but a firm!
Touch your gloves.
Enjoy the ride.
Champion's not in the best
shape we've seen him in.
Maybe just plans to pound this winning,
and go home early.
That wouldn't be a surprise.
Love you, kid. Glad you could make it.
One thing about Rocky we know for sure:
this guy's showing up in shape!
The old man's crazy!
You know what, he's
gotta be crazy, he's in here.
Okay.
You just take it easy,
this is an exhibition, alright?
- Alright, alright.
- You'll tune it.
You got three rounds to set a pace now,
every time you hit him,
you gonna make a damp.
Got it.
The moments before Rocky Balboa
fight. I can't believe it's here!
Round one begins. If old George Foreman,
shocked the world with one
punch, why can't be Rocky Balboa?
And as much the excitement
as the race in the arena,
there's a sense of foreboding as well.
And now, Mason "The Line"
Dixon goes to work with his jab,
as though he's fighting against
the number one challenger,
in the heavy-weight division.
See, this is to be expected early on.
You knew the champ is
gonna control the distance
with his jab, his height, his range.
Balboa, looking to get
a shot, misses wildly!
You like that?
It looks like a speed bag
against a punching bag.
Now Rocky is understandably frustrated,
he came out of retirement
to get into a fight.
The guy's named Rocky,
don't like to be toyed with.
One punch can still turn it around.
Apparently, he forgot his
arthritis meds this morning!
Rocky misses.
There's a meat-seeking missile
from the jab by the champ.
Pour pinpoint dance by Dixon.
There's a hard right hand
and a left and a right by Balboa!
He prised Dixon into the
rope with a series of shots.
And the crowd goes insane!
C'mon!
Dixon punishing Balboa
for the temerity of landing those shots.
It's toe to toe in the corner,
Balboa and Dixon letting it all go.
Balboa landing hook combination
to the head of the champion.
A wake-up call for Dixon.
- Are you alright?
- I'm alright, yeah!
Sit down.
Man's got bricks in his gloves!
What happened to your
angry stuff in the basement?
It's still there, it's still there!
Well, he came to battle you, okay?
Listen to me!
Things that he bomb in your body
he can break, he's gonna do it!
His bomb breaks too.
- Alright? Give the man a little respect!
- What about my respect?
Rocky box numbers
tell a ghostly story here.
Balboa landed 9 to 13
punches in that round.
Dixon landed an incredible...
...59 out of 69!
Are you listening to me?
Rocky's been here a
million times before.
Coming out to start another round,
after he took a beating.
- Remember what I said, okay?
- I won't...I won't.
Rocky's tired. His legs are
going fast or already gone.
And what's truly extraordinary,
is that Rocky can still take it!
The Boxing Comission, which remember
was criticized for licensing again,
will be massacred if
something happen to Rocky.
And a monstrous straight left hand!
Down goes Rocky, and that could
conceivably be the end of the fight.
That could be the
exhibition right there, but no.
Balboa up.
As referee Joe Cortez asks if he
wants to continue, and Rocky says yes!
Even Rocky Balboa could be
too brave for his own good.
Dixon comes right
back to try to finish it!
Balboa almost went down.
Rocky actually shuts Dixon back.
As Dixon lands these brutal shots.
Cover up! Cover up!
Open shots at close
range right and left hands,
and down goes Balboa,
perhaps for the last time,
in his fighting career.
That should do it.
4, 5, 6, 7...
- Get up, get up!
- Eight.
Nine.
- How do you feel, man? You OK?
- Alright, alright.
Rocko! C'mon!
He convinces Cortez he
wants to keep fighting.
Dixon's pointing the ref to end it.
Rocky waving his arm to say he's fine!
Let it go, let it go!
And Balboa comes back
with a left and a right,
and bows Dixon into the ropes,
for the second round in a row!
And back comes Dixon
with brutal left hand shot.
Dixon hurt his hand there!
Go after him!
This is Rocky's best chance
right here, the champ
obviously just turning
his hand on Rocky's rib.
And Balboa immediately
going to work to the body!
Huge right hook.
Balboa ripping the way Dixon's body.
These are big punches.
Yes!
Rocky Balboa has knocked the
reigning heavy-weight champion down!
- Two, three...
- You hurt him, Rocky!
Mason the Line Dixon
has never taken this kind
of punishment in his
entire professional career!
Maybe he's fearing that guy, but the
body shots nearly caved in his ribs.
Balboa is thinking knock-out himself!
Another counter hook by
Balboa followed by two more!
Dixon fires back his own hooks.
- Now Rocky's stunned.
- All along the ropes...
...as round two comes to a close.
I mean a giant turmoil into the ring!
Incredible!
You're alright!
Welcome to Rockyland!
- How's the hand?
- My hand's broken.
We lose, it's your ass. Your ass!
It will numb up on you, alright?
It will numb up in a few rounds.
Once the hand numbs up,
Dixon's gonna be able to throw it hard.
Until then, here's Rocky's chance.
You can do it!
Take the pain, champ.
Hey, stay on! Everybody thought
this was a joke, including me!
Now nobody's laughing!
Stay on, you go get him!
Go out strong!
Keep him up there.
That's it, that's it!
You won that round, break him down!
Bomb him, bomb him!
Yeah!
Just keep throwing the bomb!
Come on!
You can do it!
Yeah, go on.
Go to him, run over him.
Unload on him.
Dig down, Mason!
There's nearly nothing
left on the table, guys.
The fans are still standing.
They'll not be able to
sit down for a week.
You're doing great.
I can do better. I feel good.
He's okay?
I've gotten worse.
Toe to toe, one round to go.
Who would have
believed this was possible?
Can you see out of your eye?
Wait, let me talk, let me
talk! Look at me, look at me!
Don't take any more chances
out there than you have to.
There's nothing more to prove, pop.
There's nothing more to prove!
I gotta go out, the way I gotta go out.
You can do it, Rocko!
- You can do it, Rocko!
- One more round, we go home.
Okay, then do it.
There's an old saying
that every great champion
has one great fight left in their own.
And Rocky is proving it, so far.
Come on, let's go
guys. Touch your gloves.
Rocko! The last round of your life!
- Come on, guys.
- The last round!
Come on, touch your gloves. Let's go.
- You're one crazy old man!
- You'll get there.
Let's go.
Tenth round of a scheduled ten.
Who would ever have
dreamed that Rocky Balboa
would still be in this quoit
exhibition against the
heavy-weight champion of the world?
You can do it, come on!
This fight is what goes Dixon got
on the job training and courage.
Cover up, cover up.
They're both in a pain freeze-up,
these guys to fight in
another dimension by that.
Unbelief, Balboa's just walking
straight into the Dixon's punches!
Target practice for Dixon.
They're exchanging right hooks.
Balboa's thrilled, here comes Dixon.
He's exhausted punching the man.
Rocky's sprawling out, Mas'!
What is it you said to the kid?
It ain't about how hard you hit.
It's about how hard you can get hit,
and keep movin' forward.
How much you can take,
Get up.
Let's go, get up!
Another monster body shot.
Come on, Rocky! Shovel with his head.
Just two minutes to go!
The crowd is astonished
that Balboa got up!
- Come on, Come on!
- Kill him, all the way through.
...and retaliate with fury!
Chop him down!
Come on, Rocky, come on!
Take him out now.
They're trading shots again!
Balboa's trying anything, in anywhere!
Win it, win it!
Yes!
You're a great champion, you got heart!
Thanks, man.
Thanks for the opportunity, good man.
That's unbelievable. That's the
greatest thing I've ever seen!
You did it, baby. That's the
kind of pride I told you about.
Hey, Paulie...
The beast has gone now.
The beast is out.
One of the most overused words
in sports guys, is "incredible".
I hate to say it.
This is incredible!
Let's go!
Ladies and gentlemen,
before we go to the score cards,
a round of applause for these
two heavy-weight warrior!
We have a split decision.
Dominique Bird scores it, 95-94...
...Dixon.
Tom Chuck has it: 95-94...
...Balboa.
And Bill Grant, scores it 95-94...
to the winner by split decision...
and still undefeated, the
heavy-weight champion of the world...
Mason "The Line" Dixon!
You know I couldn't have
done nothing without you.
Yo, Adrian we did it.
We did it!