[Man #1 Over Radio]
We can't hold out much longer, sir
General Hummel, you've got
to get us out of here now!
[Hummel]
I won't let you down
I won't let you down, son
Goddamn it, sir!
How long do we have to wait?
I've lost 15 men already!
[Man #2]
Sir, they're lighting us up
like a firestorm!
This is Gen Hummel
You gotta get my men outta there!
[Man #3]
We don't have clearance
to go behind enemy lines, sir
[Man #1] They're not comin'
for us, are they, sir?
[Hummel]
Congressman Weaver and esteemed members
of the Special Armed Services Committee,
I come before you
to protest a grave injustice
[Marine]
Aim!
[Hummel]
It has to stop
I miss you so much
There's somethin'
I've gotta do, Barb
Somethin' I couldn't do
while you were here
I tried
You know I tried everything,
and I still don't have their attention
Let's hope this elevates
their thinking
But whatever happens
please don't think less of me
Marine! Inform the garrison CO
that Gen Hummel's coming on board
- with a security inspection team
- Yes, sir
Sir, it's an honor having you, sir
Aah!
- Uuh!
- Oof!
Ya know, at least we can get some...
[Continues, Indistinct]
- Yeah, I'll tell ya... Uuh!
- Ooh!
- [Bone Crunching]
- Aah! Aah!
Uuh!
I got the access card We got
30 minutes 'til those darts wear off
Move it!
The access card, sir
Let's do it
[Beeping]
Twenty-four hundred
magazine check
- Man, it's wet out there
- Check me through, will ya?
[Men Grunting, Groaning]
[Assailant]
Clear!
- I want 16, Major
- [Major] Move it!
[Grunts]
- EVAC! Seal the door!
- No! No!
[EVAC Commander]
Come on, man, seal it! Seal it!
No-o-o!
Lemme outta here! Oh, God!
[Muted]
Lemme outta here! God!
Clear out
Get outta here!
[Pained Gasping]
- [Gasping] Please!
- Sorry
[Gurgling]
Let's move out
[Technician]
Two more CCs of acetylene chloride
That'll be five dollars,
Isherwood
You suck
[Phone Ringing]
You guys have too much time
on your hands
Yes! She's here
Bring it to me now Thank you, Phil
What's that?
Why'd you get it sent here?
Carla wouldn't approve She thinks
it's dumb to spend $600 on an LP
Carla's right Why don't you just
spend $ 1300 on a CD, man?
First of all,
it's because I'm a Beatle maniac
And second, these sound better
- [Alarm Blaring]
- Could be serious
Could be sarin gas
Dog out at JFK caught a whiff
of something in this package
postmarked
to a Bosnian refugee camp
It could be detergent,
it could be sarin gas
Bosnian refugee camp?
Half a million Serbians reside in
the US Serbians don't like Bosnians
You guys wanna get suited up?
- Bring the cockroaches?
- Got 'em
We have air lock, Stanley
You're all set to go
October 1, 0900 hours
Agent Stanley Goodspeed,
Agent Trainee Marvin Isherwood
initiating exam of wooden crate
Suspicion of sarin gas inside
- Marvin, sarin is a...
- GB aerosol
That is correct
I see we have some dirty magazines
Stone Age Cave girls In the Raw
Kinky
And, uh... Not a good sign
Helloo-oo-oo, little baby doll
Lookit, Stan
- Hi, there, Stanley!
- Marvin, don't!
- Hiya, Stan!
- [Hissing]
Shit! Move back!
Move back!
- Power landings offed
- [Technician] Hang on, guys
We'll have that room cleared
in 50 seconds You're going to be okay
Jesus Christ!
Okay, I've got some bad news
and some really bad news
The bad news is that the gas is
corrosive and it's eating our suits
- It's all over my hand, man
- The really bad news
is there's enough C-4 explosive and
poison gas to blow the whole chamber
- and kill everybody in the building
- Detonation too heavy
- Everybody, out of the room, now!
- Seal us inside
Where are the sprinklers,
Lonner?
The acid's eating my su... It's eating
my fucking suit, all right? Shit
just wash us off
Where are my sprinklers?
We're working on it
It's just a flow problem
Well, it's a pretty big friggin'
problem, Lonner Fix it now!
We're working on it! How much time
do you have on that detonator?
- A minute, ten
- Hey, look at this!
[Technician]
We're gonna have the room clear
- Tell 'em to take the atropine, now
- The atropine, Isherwood
- What?
- Where's my water? One minute!
Marvin, the atropine! Inject it
in your heart before your suit melts
Shh-it!
- Make him take his dose!
- Where's that water?
- Get that away from me!
- Come on, Phil, fix it,
for Christ's sake!
- Take the atropine now,
Stan, for Christ's sake!
- We're fucked
- [Stanley] Poison's mixing
- What the fuck are you waiting for?
- You take the fucking needle now!
- Fucking shit, oh fucking shit...
- Forty seconds!
- If that suit melts...
If you die, we all die!
Inject your heart
- and then diffuse the bomb!
- Come on, just do it, Stan!
Shit, what if I miss my heart?
I can't see shit!
- [Technician] Do it now!
- Look how big this is
You want me to stick this into
my heart? Are you fucking nuts?
The sprinkler's coming
It's coming
Okay, here we go, man!
[Technician]
Sprinkler activated!
How much time left?
Twenty seconds
We're not gonna make it
- [Beeping]
- Fifteen
[Whispering]
Oh, come on!
Clear!
[Panting]
Get me the fuck out
of this gas chamber
I almost stabbed myself
in the heart with this thing!
- # Please lock me away#
- (music)(music) [Plucking Discordant Notes]
- Stan?
- Hey, darlin'
- # And don't allow the day here inside#
- Hi, baby
(music)# Where I hide with my loneliness#
I had such
an interesting day today
- # I don't care what they say#
- Yeah, I had kind of
an interesting day myself
- # [Continues]
- Okay, you go first
Oh, just some terrorists decide to send
a little care package... box o' goodies...
- which had to be neutralized
before blowing up the office
- (music)(music) [Plucks Discordant Note]
So, I took the rest of the day off
Glass of wine, a little guitar...
- just relaxing
- Wow
The world is being
Fed-Ex'd to hell on a handcart
I believe that anyone who's thinking
about having a child in this world
is coldly considering
an act of cruelty
I know, I'm rambling, I'm complaining,
I'm sorry What's your news, baby?
- I'm pregnant
- I'm sorry?
I'm pregnant
- [Chuckling]
- [Laughs]
- Really?
- Yeah
- Wow
- Is that all you're gonna say, "wow"?
- You're pregnant?
- Three weeks
How do you know?
I mean, h-how do you know?
[Sighs]
Blue
Just turned blue,
so I went to the doctor
- Well, you didn't mean
what you just said, did you?
- When?
Just right now, when you were talking
about bringing a child into the world
- and having it be an act of cruelty
- I meant it at the time
Stanley, at the time? You said
it seven and a half seconds ago
Well gosh, kind of a lot's happened
since then We're not even married
I know It's funny
you should mention that
- It's funny?
- Do you love me?
- Of course I love you
- Good
- Will you marry me?
- Whoa, whoa, hey...
Marriage Police, pull over
Come on, Stanley
I'm proposing to you right now
[Man]
The Rock is the most famous and
was the most feared prison ever built
Is it really true that there's
never been an escape?
Ah, that's true From 1936
until '63 when the prison closed,
there were 14 attempts
No one is believed to have made it
to shore... alive, at least
[Conversation, Indistinct]
Uh, hey, hey, fellas I'm sorry,
but tourists are not allowed back here
I don't really give a shit
You give a shit?
- No Come here, fruity
- Move!
- Hey, girls? Hi
You all havin' a good time?
- [Girls Together] Yeah
Will you do something for me?
It's really... It's really important
I need you to tell your teacher
that you need to get back on the boat
and go home right now
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Broadway!
This cell block housed
the most awesome scum
in America
Ladies and gentlemen, I, Ranger Bob,
cordially invite you
to become inmates of Alcatraz...
temporarily, of course, heh!
On line!
Pretty tight quarters,
aren't they, huh?
Like being a caged animal
Spend a couple of years in there...
What's the matter, fellas?
- Something wrong with the tour?
- Tour's over, Bob
What kind of
fucked-up tour is this?
Gen Hummel, Captains Frye
and Darrow reporting, sir
Welcome to the Rock, gentlemen
Land the choppers on the back side
and deploy as planned
- Aye, aye, sir
- Aye, aye, sir Move out!
I'm not allowed
to carry a gun!
Oh, you're not allowed to carry a gun?
I got a goddamned gun!
If I'd had known this was gonna happen,
I'd have brought my motherfuckin' gun!
Help!
All right, this'll be our new home
Tom, I want a command center right here
- I want coms up
- Roger that, sir
Put the satellite over there
I want to be up at 1600
Let's move it
- [Electronic Beeping]
- Systems up
Possible penetration point in shower
room We're setting anti-intrusion
I brought a personal touch, sir
It's an antimotion trembler device
It's custom-made Nobody knows
about it, and nobody expects it
- What's it do?
- We head-fake 'em with the laser beam,
and then if they disturb Mr. Backup
here [Chuckles] we own 'em
- [Gunshot]
- [Tourists Screaming]
Ladies and gentlemen, you're
being detained against your will
For that I apologize It is not
our intention in any way to harm you
You will not be detained
one minute longer than is necessary
for us to complete our mission
[EVAC Commander]
Attention on deck!
[Sighs]
Stand easy, men
Make no mistake about it, gentlemen
We are now in harm's way
For Major Baxter and I, this is the last
campaign in a career dating back
to Tet '68
Likewise for Captain Hendrix
and Gunnery Sergeant Crisp,
who cut their teeth
under my command in Desert Storm
Capt Frye, Capt Darrow, this is
my first operational situation with you,
and I have to say thus far your conduct
reflects your reputations
- Thank you, General
- Thank you, sir
We have achieved our position
through poise, precision and audacity
To this we must now add resolve
We'll be branded as traitors;
the gravest capitol crime
Punishable by death
Couple hundred years ago, a few guys
named Washington, Jefferson and Adams
were branded as traitors
by the British
And now they're called patriots
In time, so shall we
God willing, in less than 48 hours, we
will Evacuate this island in gunships
under cover of hostages
and VX gas warheads
Your destination:
A non-extradition-treaty country
You will each be paid a fee
of $ 1 million for services rendered
But you can never again
set foot on your native soil
- Can you live with that?
- [All] Yes, sir!
The men of Marine Force Recon
are selected
to carry out illegal operations
throughout the world
When they don't come home
their families are told fairy tales
about what happened to them
and denied compensation
Well, I have choked
on these lies my entire career
Well, here and now
the lies stop!
God be with all of you
Man your positions, men
[Phone Ringing, Receiver Clanking]
This is FBI Director Womack
Director be advised,
81 I say again,
81 civilians are under my control
as of this moment
You are to take measures to assure this
remains a need-to-know classified fact
- Who is this?
- Mr. Director, you have
a very serious problem
A battery of VX gas rockets
is presently deployed to deliver
a highly-lethal strike on the population
of the San Francisco Bay area
I will call again at 0100 hours
to state my demands
- I wanna know who I'm talking to
- This is Brigadier General
Francis X Hummel, United States
Marine Corps from Alcatraz out
I'll cancel your reservations
Get the Pentagon
and call the San Francisco office
It seems Alcatraz
was just reopened
[Man]
Last night, Gen Hummel using
brutal but nonlethal force
under the guise of
a security exercise,
walked off with 15
VX poison-gas rockets
He lost one of his own men
in the process
That's Gen Hummel in Vietnam
I think he was a major at the time
Three tours in Vietnam,
Panama, Grenada, Desert Storm,
Three Purple Hearts, two Silver Stars
and the Congressional Medal of...
Jesus This man is a hero
Well, I think "legend" might be
a better description, Mr. Sinclair
Well, now we can add kidnapping
and extortion to his list of accolades
Mr. Sinclair,
Gen Hummel is a man of honor
General, it's him
- Frank, it's Al Kramer
- Hi, Al How ya doin'?
I don't know, Frank
Why don't you tell me?
There are a lot of very,
very worried people here, Frank
I'll come straight to the point
83 Force Reconnaissance Marines
have died under my various commands
47 in Northern Laos
and Southern China
Southern China? We never admitted
we sent troops into China
Who is this?
Identify yourself
White House Chief of Staff
Hayden Sinclair, General
How old are you,
Chief of Staff Sinclair?
- I'm 33
- Well, Mr. Sinclair,
you've probably got no fucking idea
what I'm talking about
By your ninth birthday,
I was runnin' black ops into China,
and my men were responsible
for over 200 enemy kills
Now put some rigging tape
over Mr. Sinclair's mouth
- He's wasting my time
- Ah, you want to continue, Frank?
Remember Operation Desert Storm?
Those surgical hits made by our
smart bombs covered so well on CNN?
It was my men on the ground that made those hits
possible by lasing the targets
Twenty of them were left to rot outside
Baghdad after the conflict ended
No benefits were paid to their families
No medals conferred
These men died for their country, and they weren't
even given a goddamn military burial
The situation is unacceptable
You will transfer $ 100 million
from the Grand Cayman
Red Sea Trading Company account
to an account I designate
From these funds, reparations
of $1 million will be paid
to each of
the 83 marines' families
The rest of the funds
I will disperse at my discretion
Do I make myself clear?
Except for the Red Sea Trading Company
What is that?
- Identify yourself
- This is FBI Director Womack, General
It's a slush fund where the Pentagon
keeps proceeds from illegal arms sales
Jesus, Frank!
This is classified information
You alert the media,
I launch the gas
You refuse payment,
You've got 40 hours...
'til noon, day after tomorrow...
to arrange transfer of the money
I am aware of your counter measure
You know and I know it doesn't stand a chance
- Hummel from Alcatraz, out
- [Receiver Slams]
[Womack]
All right
We have to identify the hostages
and contact each of their families
Tell 'em somethin' Make up a story,
and we've got to keep this undercover
If this comes out, the city of
San Francisco will be in chaos, anarchy
Wait a minute, wait a minute
What is the potential casualty rate
for a single rocket armed
with VX poison gas, Gen Peterson?
- Sixty or seventy
- Well, that's not so bad
Thousand
Seventy thousand dead
- Oh
- One teaspoon of this hits the floor,
it's lethal up to 100 feet
One teaspoon of this shit
detonated in the atmosphere
will kill every living organism
in an eight-block radius
Get the point?
What did Hummel mean by
your "counter measure," General?
Standard poison is countered by napalm
It consumes it upon detonation
Now, the problem with VX poison gas
is that it's designed specifically
to withstand napalm; that's
where thermite plasma comes in
- Gen Peterson?
- Thermite plasma incendiary systems
can burn hot enough to consume VX,
but they're still in the test phase
It's not operational
Hummel knows this
We are dealing with
one smart son of a bitch
What's it gonna take
to equip a flight of F-18s
with thermite plasma
within the next 36 hours?
- An act of God
- Excuse me?
All right We can try
But I strongly urge you to consider the
use of this as a secondary initiative
Then we have to go to our
primary initiative Uh, Admiral?
Sir, I'd like to bring in our SEAL
ground commander, Cmdr Anderson
Mr. Womack, who is your best
chemical/biological man?
[Stanley, Grunting]
That's interesting
- Oh, yeah
- That's very compelling
[Both Moaning]
Ahh, you like my pigtails?
Oh, yeah
Pigtails are naughty
- Naughty, naughty...
- [Moans]
You're just an amaretto cream
with peach sorbet persuasion
- [Phone Rings]
- This isn't happening
- No, Stan Don't answer it
- This isn't happening!
- No, just don't answer it It's okay
- I have to
- It's the office, baby
They know I'm home
- Oh-h-h-h!
- How could they possibly know
that you're home?
- It's the FBI
[Ringing Stops, Receiver Clicks]
- Stanley! Tsk!
- Goodspeed
Yeah Okay Yeah, I'll be...
I'll be down...
- Yeah, downstairs in ten minutes
- No, you won't
[Phone Beeps Off]
- I have to go to San Francisco
- No, you don't
Stanley No, you do not have
to go to San Francisco
Right now, you need to stay here
and talk to me about things
- I've got to go, baby
- I am a Catholic
Do you realize that?
I am pregnant, and I am unmarried
and this causes
a serious problem for me
I cannot believe you
N-N-No
- [Kissing Sounds]
- I love you
I will marry you
I just didn't plan on this, that's all
- [Relieved Laugh]
- Come to San Francisco
- Really?
- Yeah I'm sure it's just
a training exercise
Check into the hotel,
order up some champagne...
- And we'll finish what we started?
- Exactly
- Baby, you gonna marry me?
- You know it
[Laughing]
You're gonna marry me!
Oh, honey, come on
- just a really quick one
- Oh! Oh! I gotta go!
A nighttime airdrop incursion
is out, due to the full moon
Likewise,
a frontal seaside attack
If we're compromised and shots
are fired, Hummel might launch
Our only alternative is an attack
from within the prison
We penetrate the island through tunnels
under the prison buildings undetected
and emerge in its center, that way,
we can jump the marines from behind
And if we're lucky, take their rocket
positions without a shot fired
I don't understand You-You've
studied the architectural plans?
They're useless Alcatraz has been
ripped up and rebuilt for years
- Under there is a maze of shit
- There's no question, gentlemen
We need firsthand intelligence
of the tunnel systems
- So what about the former warden?
- Died in 1979
All the guards
we contacted were useless
Umm there is someone who,
I think, can help us
This is for the sake
of national security
No, it's the sake of national security
that got us here in the first place
33 years ago
I knew someday this would come back
to bite us Forget it
- He does not exist
- He does exist!
We chose to forget him for 30 years
We locked him up and threw away the key
Oh, and a lot of
goddamn good it did us
He broke out of two maximum security
prisons, and if he hits the streets...
He's not gonna "hit the streets," Jim!
[Chuckles]
Thirty years ago, he was
a highly-trained SAS operative
He is my age now, for Christ's sake
I have to get up three times a night
to take a piss
[Quietly]
We can't risk letting him out
He's a professional
escape artist
[Womack]
Oh, here he is now
- Ah Neat, uh...
- Yeah
- Neat, neat plane
- Dr Goodspeed James Womack
- Pleasure meeting you, sir Thank you
- Welcome
You come very highly recommended
BA, Columbia;
MA, PhD, johns Hopkins
Biochemistry/toxicology?
Well, I'm one of those fortunate people
who like my job, sir
Got my first chemistry set when
I was seven Blew my eyebrows off
We never saw the cat again
Been into it ever since
[Chuckles]
- What do you know about VX gas?
- Liquid
Failed pesticide discovered
by mistake in 1952
Actually, it's like champagne that way
The Franciscan monks thought
they were making white wine, somehow the
bottle carbonated, voila, champagne...
- The gas, Dr Goodspeed
- It's very, very horrible, sir
It's one of those things
we wish we could disinvent
This isn't
a training exercise, is it?
No, Dr Goodspeed,
it's not a training exercise
[Siren Blurting]
- Ernest
- Good morning, Director
This is Ernest Paxton, agent in charge
of the West Coast operation
- Dr Goodspeed
- Pleasure to meet you
- How do you do, sir?
- It's been a fairly
interesting day so far
The prison's here Shall we?
Now, my boys, they haven't been
able to find a file on this guy
- Who is he, anyway, sir?
- His name is john Mason,
a British national
incarcerated on Alcatraz in 1962;
escaped in '63
- I was under the impression that
no one escaped Alcatraz, sir
- Paxton, don't argue!
[Womack]
This man has no identity, not in
the United States or Great Britain
He does not exist Understand?
I want one thing;
how he escaped the rock... specifically,
how he took through the island's bowels
[Man]
Papers are in order, sir
[Womack]
We're prepared to offer him
a full pardon
And Paxton, no strong-arming Mason
I know him too well
Well, if you know him,
why don't you question him?
No He'll remember me I don't want
his anger clouding the issue
All right,
I'll take care of him
[Latch Clinking]
Mr. Mason, I'm special agent
in charge Ernest Baxter
In charge of what? Fucking me over
for another three decades?
I don't know anything about your
previous matters I'm here because
a special situation exists that we feel
you might be able to help us with
Now, what might that be? I've been
in jail longer than Nelson Mandela,
so maybe you want me
to run for president
- Not exactly
- Ah, pity
- I feel rather like Alcamenes
- Who?
Alcamenes He was imprisoned
by his king in ancient Greece
Like Sir Walter Raleigh
Same fate
- James the First
- Even someone as bright as you
must be aware that, uh, there's
a certain pattern emerging here
- Alexander Solzhenitsyn?
- Yeah, I heard of him
Didn't he play hockey
for the fuckin' Redwings?
- That's the chap
- Get this straight, Pops
I don't like you any more
than you like me
But I'm here to make you
a legitimate offer
You wanna hear
what I have to say or not?
By all means,
dear Paxton, by all means
[Paxton]
We got a problem in a place
that I think you know
There's a hostage situation
on Alcatraz
- Hostage?
- Eighty-one tourists
The Rock has become
a tourist attraction?
Why don't we cut the shit, huh?
You know the Rock You broke out
- Yes, successfully
- Yeah
So why don't you do yourself a favor
while you're helpin' us
I mean, it'd be nice to get out of jail
while you're still vertical
Hmm? While you got a little lead
left in your pencil?
While I'm considering
your offer,
I want a suite
at the Fairmont Hotel
You know, I'm here
to cut you a deal
I am not here to bend over
and take it up the ass from you
Here Here's a quarter
Do yourself a favor
Call your lawyer
You're goin' back to jail
- You're sending him back to jail?
- I'm not sending him anywhere
I'm just givin' him
somethin' to think about
I don't think we have time for him
to just sit around and think about it
- Oh, really?
- No, Goodspeed's right
You, go talk to him
- Me? Sir, I'm not qualified for that
- Yes
- You're an FBI agent
- What is your specialty again?
- Chemical weapons
- Don't mention that!
- You want me to lie?
- Yeah, lie
We got less than 24 hours
Give it a shot
Okay
Hiya!
I'm an agent with the, uh,
eh, Federal... FBI
Uh... Eh, well, my...
I'm Stanley Goodspeed
- But of course you are
- At least he got his name right
- Of course I am
- And you have an emergency
- That's right
- [Chair Thumps]
- And you need my help
- Exactly right
- [Sighs]
- Coffee
No, no, I'm fine,
thank you
Offer me coffee
Oh, yes Well, that was, in fact,
going to be my next...
Could we get a cup of coffee
in here, please?
And offer
to take these off
Mr. Mason, really
- All kidding aside...
- As a gesture of your good faith
- Prisoner requests
to have his handcuffs taken off
- [Whispering] No, no, no!
Look, why don't you go ahead and have
his handcuffs taken off, please?
Well, I guess that's
one way to go
This is a pardon and release contract
from the Attorney General's office
Now, it makes you a free man
provided you cooperate
So, if you'll just, ah, sign,
uh, eh, where it says...
- "Signature"?
- That's... Yes "Signature"
Well timeo Danaos
et dona ferentis
"I fear the Greeks
even when they bring gifts"
Oh, an educated man
That rules out the possibility
of you being a field agent
In point of fact,
I am a field agent, Mr. Mason
- Really
- Yes
- In which field?
- Antiterrorism
Then you're trained in weaponry,
explosives and mortal combat
Well-trained
- [Slaps Table]
- Then it's the Fairmont Hotel
Okay
I want a suite
a shower, a shave
and the feel of a suit
May I also suggest a
a haircut
- Am I out of style?
- Unless you're a 20-year-old
guitarist from Seattle
- It's a grunge thing
- Grunge?
Yeah Well, uh, uh...
Okay Thank you very much
All right Call the Fairmont
Close the floor if necessary,
but I want him sealed off
and he gets two hours max
[Coin Clinking]
- Great job, Goodspeed
- Why don't you throw in a trip
to Tahiti while you're at it?
I'll deliver this
to the Attorney General
Ah, no, you'll give it to me, Reynolds
And take Attorney Reynolds outside
There's a car waiting for you
Thank you
That's a signed Federal document, sir
Isn't that illegal?
You're not acquainted
with the full facts, Goodspeed
With all due respect, sir, I'd like
clarification I gave that man my word
Damn it! You're on a need-to-know
basis, and you don't need to know!
It's uh, eh, kind of curious,
but, uh...
Sir Walter Raleigh, Alcamenes,
Solzhenitsyn, they, uh...
Well, they were all
wrongfully imprisoned
[Screeching]
[Alarm Sounding]
Womack!
Now, why am I not surprised?
You piece of shit!
- Hey, peace! Peace!
- [Guard Shouting, Indistinct]
[Sirens Wailing]
[Punching Keypad]
[Ringing, Carla's Voice]
Hey, we're not home Leave a message
- [Answering Machine Beeps]
- Hi, darling, it's, uh, it's me
Uh, listen, don't come to San Francisco
I repeat, do not come to San Francisco
- Stanley, like hell I'm not comin'!
- Carla! Carla!
- Wait! Carla...
- [Punches Keypad, Ringing]
Who's Carla? And why don't you
want her to come to San Francisco?
[Ringing Continues]
You're on a need-to-know basis,
and you don't need to know
- [Barks]
- Watch it, he'll bite you!
[Agents Laughing]
Good Mobile command
is fully operational
We'll be there
in approximately two hours
- I'm not armed, sir
- Right
- I am unarmed, sir
- Well, where's your issue?
I left it in my...
uh, my sock drawer
[Scoffs]
A gun?
For what?
You're a chemical freak
No, I'm a chemical super-freak,
actually, but I still need a gun
Give 'im a goddamn gun
Have you fired one of those things
since the academy?
- # [Recording, Indistinct]
- (music) If you're going to San Francisco (music)
(music) Don't forget to wear flowers
in your hair (music)
(music) If you're going to San Francisco (music)
(music) You're sure to meet
some gentle people there (music)
- # Gentle people there#
- (music) And you come for... (music)
- (music) If you're going to San Francisco (music)
- # [Recording Continues]
- [Woman] Fairmont Hotel
- Heh, uh, room service?
Uh, this...
this is the penthouse
Do you have any snacks
and drinks, huh?
[Man]
Hello-o-o
- You the barber?
- No Stylist
- Barber
- just clippers, no scissors
No scissors? You've got to be
kidding me, no scissors
I mean, did they tell Picasso
"no brush"?
With scissors,
this man could kill you
I can't cut anyone's balls off
with a trimmer, now can I?
Why don't we do this outside?
Get some sun
Oh! Who did this to you? This is
just not right In fact, it's nasty
- Well, it's a grunge thing
- Well, it's some kind of thing
Do you think we have time for a sea kelp
protein pack and maybe some color?
- No
- Okay [Disgusted Sigh]
- Not very nice, is he?
- [Clippers Buzzing]
- No, he's not
- # [Stylist Humming]
[Frank Sinatra]
(music)# 'Cause I'm leavin'#
- # On a jet plane#
- Hey, can't let it go to waste
- # Don't know when I'll be back again#
- Don't you ever stop eatin'?
- Not when it's free
- # [Continues]
- We're supposed to be on duty
- Hey, don't worry He's an old man
The boss is watchin' 'im
Come on, Try some of this lobster
- Mm-hmm
- My secretary here will settle the bill
So, what do you have in store for me,
Womack, when this is over?
You'll get your life back, Mason
But you could've given me
my life back years ago
Why should I trust you now?
You've got my word
Will you shake on it?
- [Mason Grunts]
- [Womack Screaming]
- [Gasps]
- Freeze, mister!
[Womack]
Oh, man!
Help!
Drop the gun
or I drop your boss
- You will not!
- Aaah! Get!
- He's gettin' very heavy
- Then pull him up!
Aah! Uuh!
- [Cocking]
- Please don't
- [Womack] Ohh!
- [Whimpering]
Help! Shit!
- # Hold me like you'll never... #
- Come on, have a scallop Catch
[Womack]
Ohh!
[Whimpering]
Ooh-ooh!
- You hoist him in!
- Yaah! Oh!
Help! Help! Help!
- Where's Mason?
- Hang on!
- Mason's gone!
- Gone?
- [Agent] Clear!
- [Stylist Gasps]
Living room's clear!
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- [Elevator Bell Dings]
All units, this is Caretender We have
a signal six He's in the hotel!
Okay, I don't wanna know nothin'
I never saw you throw that gentleman
off the balcony
All I care about is,
are you happy with your haircut?
- Aah! Easy! Aah!
- [Grunting]
Watch it, you fuckhead!
You're gonna pull my arm out!
[Waiter]
Watch out! Aah!
[Shouting In Japanese]
- Uuh!
- Watch it!
- [Man] Hey, watch it!
- He's right over there!
Uuh! Ah!
Uuh!
Hey! Uuh! Ooh!
This is my Humvee I don't want
any dings, dents or scratches
Or I'll have your ass Hey!
Hey! Stop! Hey!
[Tires Squealing, Sirens Wailing]
- [Pedestrians Screaming]
- I was inside with Jack Powell!
- Hey, call the guard!
- Go!
FBI
[Engine Revving, Tires Pealing]
Whoo!
- [Sirens Continue]
- Whoa! Whoa!
Suspect is in a black Humvee
heading west on California
Speed approximately
70 miles per hour
Get out of the way!
I want a net put on this
son of a bitch, you hear me?
This guy's hittin' every fuckin' thing
in sight tryin' to block us!
Aah!
I hope you're insured!
- Oh, well, why not?
- [Engine Revving Higher]
You're goin' down!
[Phone Ringing]
- [Receiver Clicks, Phone Beeps]
- Hello?
[Humvee Owner]
Sie haben meine Hummer gestolen!
I'm only borrowing your Humvee!
[Mason]
Information?
San Francisco
Uh, jade Angelou
That's A-N-G...
[Bell Ringing]
Welcome aboard, y'all
How y'all doin' today?
Hang on!
- [Riders Screaming]
- Holy shit!
[Horn Honking]
Whoa-oa!
- Oh, no!
- [People Screaming]
We're gonna crash!
Save yourselves!
Oh, my baby!
Oh, no!
Oh, no
Oh! Oh, God
Oh, God!
Hey, man
You just fucked up your Ferrari
- [Conductor] Oh, no!
Baby's goin'down in flames!
- It's not mine
- [Chuckles, Grunts]
- Neither is this
[Engine Revving, Tires Pealing]
Damn! This sucks!
Where's that son of a bitch at?
I'm gonna hunt him down!
That motherfucker ain't safe nowhere!
- [Ringing]
- Chem Weapons, Isherwood
Marvin, look up
Wolfburg Federal Penitentiary
The inmate is Mason, john
Hey, Stan, listen I'm gettin'
out of this government shithole
I'm goin' over to Orkin
to design Roach Motels Cool, huh?
Look, I just stole
a kid's motorcycle
I'm not really feeling too good
Wolfburg, got it?
Yeah, I got it All right,
Magrane, Masconi, Masters No Mason
Go to February '76 Who was transferred
to Wolfburg from San Quentin?
- [Beeping]
- [Marvin] This is weird
They got medical records,
they got place of birth... Glasgow...
Uh, but they don't have a name
Uh, wait a minute, wait a minute!
They have next of kin, a Jade Angelou
of 32 Stenson Drive, San Francisco
[Motorcycle Approaching]
Jade?
No, I'm Stacy, jade's Friend
Were you afraid to come alone?
Yeah
[Whispers]
It's okay
I'll be over here
if you need me
- Last photograph I had of you
you were about ten
- Yeah?
Well, I found a picture of you
among my mom's things when she died
Oh, yeah? Well, uh...
- Why don't we take a walk?
- I got him Palace of Fine Arts
Your mother, uh... [Sighs]
Ya know, well, sh-she was very special
Yeah, she was
But I don't think we should romanticize
what happened between you and her
Meeting in a bar
after a Led Zeppelin concert
Head out,
and I was the result
Well, I'd like to think
it would've led somewhere, if only...
If only what?
Six federal marshals
hadn't kicked down our door
and dragged you back to prison?
I'm sorry
[Mason]
It's all right
- So they let you out?
- Yeah
That's good
[Sighs]
What did you do?
Jade, I don't have
a great deal of time here
But I'll be coming back,
and, uh, maybe we can...
What? We can what?
You know you're almost
the only evidence that I exist
But I don't know you
That's what I want to change, eh?
I've rehearsed this speech a thousand
times on the chance that we would meet
Here we are and I'm lost
Well, I don't know how I'm
supposed to be feeling either
Jade, I'm not an evil man
If you can believe that,
then it's a start
Okay
[Sirens Wailing In Distance]
Is this about you?
You broke out of prison again,
didn't you?
- Why did you come to me?
- FBI, ma'am
Your father's working with us
He's helping us resolve
a dangerous situation
- He is?
- Yes, ma'am
Well, gee whiz, john,
I guess we oughta get goin', huh?
Whatever you say, Stanley
Thank you for that
You could've handled it differently
What do you say we cut
the chitchat, a-hole?
You almost got me killed twice,
and my jaw hurts like hell
- Good
- Cocksucker!
If I had my way, you would be shipped
back to Wolfburg in leg irons
and caged like an animal for the rest
of your natural fuckin'life!
You wrecked half the city!
[Electronic Beepings,
Phones Ringing, Low Voices Chattering]
- Give me a hand with the system
- Now, tell me about the tunnels
If you know the system, it will take you
wherever you need to go
There's an intake pipe here, below
low tide Is that our best access?
- Yes, that's exactly where I came out
- Then beneath the cistern
there's a connection
to the abandoned septic system
- How many feet is that?
- Ehh 57 paces
Where do we go from there?
[Muttering]
Where do you go from there?
That's a good question
- I have no idea
- What?
I mean I'll know
when we're all inside
No You're not goddamn goin'
Show us on the blueprints
I can't!
My blueprint was in my head
I was underground
for three days in the dark,
just waiting
for the tides to be right
But don't worry
It'll all come back to me
You're not going anywhere, Mason
Wait a second
This piece of work might be the only
chance those people over there have
If he's not going, then why the hell
did we get him out of jail?
- He's smart
- I got him out to get you
people in, not go with you
If it's the only way of getting
the intelligence I need, then he goes
He'll fuck with you
You compromise my men's lives,
and I'll bury you out there
Now, Womack you're between
the Rock and a hard case
Hmm
How's your bowling arm?
Dr Goodspeed, the goal
is to take out the launchers
then neutralize
the VX chemical rounds
Well, we know the poison's
being kept in the prison morgue
from the satellite thermal imagining,
which is right here... these dots
Have you ever actually seen
one of these devices?
No, sir,
but I've studied them
I should really begin briefing your guys
on defusing and detoxification
Got a really neat layout here
of the chem round as well as the rocket
- So let's get rolling
- That won't be necessary
Oh, it's very necessary, sir
The power of this chemical
is way beyond anything you can imagine
An ecological disaster, sir
Plus, the devices themselves
are complicated
That's why you're coming with us
I am?
You're the expert
What's your problem?
You mean I'm going...
going out there under the water?
Well, earlier today you wanted a gun
Now you're getting a gun and a wet suit
Have you ever been
in a combat situation?
- Define "combat," sir
- Shep?
An incursion underwater
to retake an impregnable fortress
held by an elite team of US Marines
in possession of 81 hostages
and 15 guided rockets
armed with VX poison gas
Oh In that case, no, sir
Excuse me
[Retching]
[Gagging, Coughing]
- Here
- Ah, thank you
[Gasping]
You don't look too good
In fact, you look like shit
My stomach's doing hula hoops
around my ass
You all right? I mean,
you gonna make it through this thing?
I don't know
I always expected something
like this was going to happen,
but nothing prepares you for it
Now I'm...
I'm responsible
for a whole city
- [Faucet Creaks, Water Splashing]
- Look, I know this isn't easy for you
Remember, you were trained
for this kind of situation
and believe me,
it'll come back to you
Besides, you got the best SEAL team
in the country backin' you up
Okay
You're right
I'll be on the wire
I'll help talk you through it
There's something else
It's terrible
N-No, it's wonderful
except it isn't
My girlfriend's pregnant
and she's
just flown in to see me
You keep your mind on what you're
going to be doing out there tonight,
and I'll send someone to pick up
your girlfriend and bring her
here to the command center
- Hummel!
- Hello, Frank Lou Linstrom
I'm at the White House
with General Kramer
Uh, Frank, uh, we're havin' a few
problems with the account transfer
Don't tell me problems,
tell me solutions
We've spoken to the President,
and I know that you're aware
of his stance on terrorism
- So what we'd like to do...
- This isn't about terrorism
This is about justice
It's about reminding people who found it
politically convenient to forget
- This is goin' nowhere, Frank
- Well, let me tell you what is:
15 VX gas rockets into
the heart of San Francisco
You've got 17 hours
to deliver the money
Or be prepared to reap
the whirlwind, gentlemen
What's the word from Mojave?
General Peterson can give us no definite
assurance on the thermite plasma
That is the word
Green light to SEAL incursion
Fall in!
All right Listen up
Mr. Mason will run point for us
Lieutenant Shepard will be
attached to his hip
You breathe, he breathes with you
You piss, he helps Understood?
Dr Goodspeed is our specialist
When he neutralizes the threat,
we launch green flares
and we wait for the cavalry
Make no mistake, gentlemen,
we're in the fight of our lives,
against maybe the greatest
battalion commander
in the Vietnam War,
I shit you not
Any questions?
Let's load up!
After you, ace
Pass out and activate
the Minicams
Everything set here?
Minicams operational?
Roger that, sir
We are on line
Shep, what's the status on the special
operational gear for Mr. Mason?
Let's see, we have, uh,
one quart of kerosene
and a squeeze bottle,
three washers
and waterproof matches
Use the green flares to signal
when the threat has been neutralized
Now, this is atropine
If you come in contact with the gas,
you have 20 seconds
to inject it into your heart
Don't fuck with me on this
It may save your life
I have three incoming bogeys
bearing 2-7-5 Range; 6,000 meters
FBI Command Center?
Oh, I would just love for you
to tell me what is goin' on
- Nope
- Stanley Goodspeed is my boyfriend
- Actually, he's my fianc
Where is he?
- Classified, lady
Okay, well you just sit here
and act like a Bureau bonehead, then
Hey, where are you...
Goddamn it
Decoy choppers commencing
run to Alcatraz
I just lost one, sir
I just lost one
We only got two flying in
Shit
In my day, we did it all
with a snorkel and a pair of flippers
- Your day?
- Yes, didn't you read my resume?
I don't... I don't know
anything about you
- I know something about you, Godspell
- Goodspeed
Goodspeed,
Godspeed, Godspell,
you never went
to any anti-terrorist school
So just make sure you don't
get us all fucking killed
- We're going dark
- Night vision!
Raider One has dropped
below radar coverage,
heading around Treasure Island
Sir, we've got two bogeys
bearing due east and closing
Decoys?
- Prepare to deploy!
- Good luck, Commander
Sir, Raider One
is at the drop zone
Stanley's not a very good swimmer
I mean, he can't even snorkel
- Everyone, good to go?
- Good to go!
- [Muffled Words] Good to go!
So the SDUs have been deployed,
and the Eagles are in the water
Major, I want the perimeter
patrolled to the west end of the island
Yes, sir
Hendrix, you lead the patrol
- Aye, sir
- Let's move! Move out, move out!
The Eagles are on the Rock
They've entered the cistern room
Thank you very fucking much, Mr. Mason
You sent us into a room with no exit
Any ideas, Dillinger?
Figure it out soon
We're sitting ducks
- Real tight on time
- You stand by the door
Until I open it
I'd like to know how you plan
on accomplishing that
Through here
You're shitting me
I memorized the timing
I just hope it hasn't been changed
You catch one of those
flame bursts, you're a corpse
- Thank you
- Commander, you said never
leave his side, but, uh...
- Stand fast, Lieutenant
- Have a nice day
- Where'd you dig up this guy?
- That's classified
Clear here, sir
No motion sensors tripped
- Nothing
- Well, tell them to stay out there
Sweep forward!
Looks like he fucked us,
Commander
I knew it
That son of a bitch jumped ship
Welcome to the Rock
- Mason
- That's a no-no That's the subway
- That'll drop you into the tunnels
- Do it!
Sir, the Eagles
have breached the tunnel system
You enjoying this?
Well, it's certainly
more enjoyable than my average day:
Reading philosophy,
avoiding gang rape in the washroom
Though it's less of a problem these
days Maybe I'm losing my sex appeal
We've got seismic activity
in one of the storm grates North side
Continue patrolling the area
Sweep forward
Commander, halt
We've got movement
They're hearing sounds above, sir
Stand fast
Down, down, down
West storm drain's clear
Ninety-seven paces
to the shower room
The Eagles are now at the access tunnel
They're right under the shower room
Fiber optics
- Something's not right
- I've got a bad feeling about this
Quiet
Motion sensors
- Beams cutting across manhole covers
- Deal with it
Commander, the beam is hitting
some sort of reflective device
Possibly a prism
I want to use a mirror
to cut the beam,
send the beam
back to its source
and then I'm
going to move the prism
[Electronic Beeping]
We've got motion on a trembler
in the shower room, sir
We've got visitors
Let's move
Got it Good to go
[Indistinct Shouting]
Stand fast
We'll secure the area
They're entering
to the shower room, sir
They're securing the area
Just sit tight
Drop your weapons!
Drop 'em!
- Get back!
- Hold your fire
Drop your weapons
Hold your fire!
It's a fucking trap
This is Gen Hummel
Drop your weapons
Drop 'em!
Anderson here, Gen Hummel
Commander Team leader
Cmdr Anderson, if you have any concern
for the lives of your men
you will order them to safety their
weapons and place them on the deck
This is not happening
Sir, we know why you're out here
God knows I agree with you
But like you, I swore to defend
this country against all enemies
foreign, sir, and domestic
General, we've spilled
the same blood in the same mud
You know goddamn well
I can't give that order
We're dead
Your unit is covered from
an elevated position, Commander
I'm not gonna ask again
Don't do anything stupid
No one has to die here
Men following the general, you're
under oath as United States Marines!
Have you forgotten that?
We all have shipmates
we remember
Some of them were shit on
and pissed on by the Pentagon
But that doesn't give you
the right to mutiny!
You call it what you want!
You're down there; we're up here
You walked into the wrong
goddamn room!
- Stand fast!
- Commander, one last time
You tell your men
to safety their weapons
- I cannot give that order!
- I am not gonna repeat that order!
- I will not give that order!
- What the hell is wrong with you, man?
- Stand fast!
- Oh, my God!
- Let's waste these fuckers
- One last time
- Order your men to safety their weapons
- [Screaming]
Cease fire!
Don't go
[Screaming]
Cease fire!
Shit Goddamn it
Let go of me Let go of me!
Don't, don't go
[Yelling]
Fuck
It's over
[Gasping]
Oh, God!
- [Beeping]
- We got some movement
- Who? Who is it?
- Two of'em Eagles 11 and 12
- It's Goodspeed and Mason
- I knew it
I've gotta get a team together
We've gotta move with the second option
What, and invite another
massacre? No way
We've got a 60-year-old convict and
a lab rat I'm telling you, it's over
Not for Mason, it isn't
Goodspeed,
I'm not gonna kill you
- Where are you going?
- Off this bloody island
What? Wh... What for?
[Man On Radio]
Goodspeed, do you read me?
It's for you
- Sir?
- What's the status?
The status is, they're dead
They're dead!
It's just me and Mason
Now he says he's leaving
That is unacceptable,
do you hear me? Unacceptable!
Well, there's a problem, sir
He's got a gun
What do you have,
a fuckin' water pistol?
- No, sir
- Go after him and stop him
I didn't want this
- Jesus, I didn't want this
- We knew this might happen
- Well, maybe now they'll pay up
- Maybe now they won't, Captain
Then maybe we need to execute
a few hostages
- Got a live one!
- Put a bullet in him
You heard him, end it
Holster that sidearm, Captain!
Sir?
You made a terrible mistake And more
of our brothers have died in vain
Damn you for forcing me
into this position
I need to talk to you
Right now, alone
Now, you told me
I'm on a need-to-know basis,
and I'm tellin' you right now
I need to know
who the fuck John Mason is right now
All right, you wanna know?
1962,j Edgar Hoover
is head of the FBI,
some say the country
It's no secret he kept microfilm files
on prominent Americans and Europeans:
De Gaulle, British members
of Parliament, even the Prime Minister
I mean, this guy had dirt
on everybody in the world
Yeah, I know all the cloak-and-dagger
stories Where does Mason fit in?
Mason was the British operative
who stole the files
But our Bureau agents caught him
at the Canadian border
Of course, the British claimed
they'd never heard of him
And we held him without trial
until he gave up the microfilm
But he never did
I'm surprised Hoover didn't
use his daughter as leverage
Hoover was dead in '72
She wasn't born yet
Today, well,
it's a different bureau
So you held this guy without trial
his whole life No wonder he's pissed
This man knows our most intimate secrets
from the last half-century:
The alien landing at Roswell, the truth
about the JFK assassination
And Mason's angry, he's lethal
He's a trained killer
And he is the only hope
that we have got
Mason! Mason!
There are 81 hostages
still up there
Yeah Like me
You wanna play tough?
You wanna play tough with me?
Okay, FBI!
Freeze, sucker!
- I'll fire
- No, you won't
- Throw down
- You're not the sort
Let's find out
I could; you, no
Besides, your safety's on
Goodspeed, have you
resolved the situation?
[Gasps]
Not yet
- He's got all the guns now, sir
- Shit!
You're right, I don't use guns,
and I don't kick down doors
- This is what I do
- I haven't got my glasses
What it says is,
"Chemical Weapons Specialist"
That's right
I got a lunatic up there,
man, with 15 missiles
armed with some
really funky stuff
That lying Womack
You could've told my daughter
It was classified
Look, I'm in the same situation
They've got my girlfriend
in the city with a baby on the way
Look, I can defuse the rockets
I really can
But I'm gonna need your help,
and I'm gonna need it right now
Sir, this man's weapons
and tack radio are missing!
Shit, we got a rodent problem
Flush the pipes
There's probably a maze of
tunnels on this goddamn island
- Check every access you can find
- Sir!
Even if you escape
from the island
you can't escape the rockets
So, where are you gonna go?
Go where?
What're you gonna do?
[Stanley]
Show me where
the morgue is, Mason
[Mason]
I'm out of here
[Stanley]
What about your daughter? Mason?
Rodents located
The way I see it, you don't
really have any choice, do you?
I don't think you do
Move!
Ooooh!
- They're on to us
- Burn 'em out
This mother's gonna blow big
I don't understand How could we lose
radio contact all of a sudden?
We've lost coms
Still got 'em on locaters
- So what's it gonna be?
- What?
- How do you like your choices?
- I don't
That's what I thought
Come on
This is the oldest part of Alcatraz
Did you know it was originally
a Civil War fort?
Oh, really? Yeah, wow
You know, I like history, too,
and maybe when this is over, you and I
can stop by the souvenir shop together,
but right now, I just... I just...
I wanna find some rockets
Don't tempt me
We are going to the morgue
- You sure you're ready for this?
- I'll do my best
Your best?
Losers always whine about their best
Winners go home
and fuck the prom queen
Carla was the prom queen
- Really?
- Yeah
Locaters have them
approaching the morgue, sir
Come on, come on,
you can do it, Doc
Shit! Aaaaaah!
You must never hesitate
I think you're shooting
too close to the rocket
Him, but not the rocket
Any other news, professor?
The rocket!
Not the rocket!
Aaah! Uhhh!
I got a little something for ya
Yaaaah!
Uh, yeah, okay, that's just about
the most awful thing I've ever seen
Mason the second you don't
respect this, it kills you
Put it over there
You've been around a lot of corpses
Is that normal?
- What, the feet thing?
- Yeah, the feet thing
- Yeah, that happens
- Can you do something about it?
Like what?
Kill him again?
Listen, I'm just a biochemist
Most of the time, I work in a glass jar
and lead a very uneventful life
I drive a Volvo, a beige one
But what I'm dealing with here
is one of the most deadly substances
the earth has ever known
So what do you say
you cut me some friggin' slack?
[Hissing]
A really elegant
string-of-pearls configuration
Unfortunately,
incredibly unstable
What exactly
does this stuff do?
If the rocket renders it aerosol, it can
take out the entire city of people
Really? What happens
if you drop one?
Happily, it'll just
wipe out you and me
- How?
- It's a cholinesterase inhibitor
It stops the brain from sending messages
down the spinal cord within 30 seconds
Any epidermal exposure
or inhalation, and you'll know
A twinge at the small of your back as
the poison seizes your nervous system
Do not move that!
Your muscles freeze,
you can't breathe
you spasm so hard you break
your own back, spit your guts out
- But that's after your skin melts off
- My God
Well, I think we'd like God
on our side at the moment, don't you?
So what I'm doing now is removing
the guidance system chips
so the rocket'll splash
down after 500 feet
All right, let me have that
You can let go of it
All right, just back away
Just back away!
Sir, morgue team
has not checked in
Blackbird One,
it's Blackbird, over
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird
Come in, goddamn it!
Somebody's still there
Let's move!
Rats alive! Close on the morgue!
Close on the morgue!
Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go!
Frye, Darrow, hustle up
We got more company!
[Hummel]
Hold it! Converge
on the morgue! Move out!
Goodspeed, come on
Come over here
Yeah, I love pressure,
I eat it for breakfast
Come on Time's up
There's three rockets somewhere else
We have to find them!
Come on!
Clear!
- I'm too old for this!
- Where's it go?
I've no idea
Sir, all the guidance
chips are gone
Captain, I guess you didn't quite
take care of the rat problem
No, sir
Well, there are two dead men who
strongly suggest you go finish the job
Yes, sir Yes, sir!
[Indistinct Shouting]
- You really don't know where this goes?
- No, I don't know where it goes
Well, we're picking up speed
Do you know how to slow it down?
No, I don't
Aaaaaaah!
Uhhh!
[Grunting]
God!
[Groaning]
Mason! You all right?
Yes, perfectly okay,
you fucking idiot
They're coming
- Who?
- The marines!
Where?
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
- What the fuck's goin' on?
- Let's cut him off
[Screams]
[Screaming Continues]
[Screaming]
Mason!
[Grunting]
You motherfucker, die, die, die!
I'm rather glad
you didn't hesitate too long
How do you do it?
Oh, I was trained by the best
British Intelligence
Come on
But in retrospect, I'd rather
have been a poet or a farmer
Okay
Okay, the president
arrives in three hours
His directive is to string Hummel along
until the air strike is operational
What's the word
from Mojave, General?
Same as last time, Lou
They're going as fast as they can
Do it over here
On your knees
[Hummel]
Navy SEALS, listen up
You've got something that belongs to me
Twelve guidance chips,
to be precise
Let me remind you that there are lives
at stake, civilian lives
Speak up
- Speak up!
- Oh! I, uh...
- Uh...
- Tell them your name
My name is Larry Henderson
Oh, man
And I'm a father
of three, and, uh,
they've got a gun to my head
You've got exactly three minutes
to return the guidance chips,
or Mr. Henderson
won't have a head
Oh, no Hey, what...?
Now, three to go
You find them and defuse them
- Okay? All right
- All right
I'll try and delay Hummel
and give you more time
Hey, what about
Mr. Henderson's head?
Okay What do you mean?
Okay
[Hostages Chattering]
- General
- Who the hell are you?
I'm all that's left
of the enemy
Bingo
Stand easy
Thought I'd been
in the service a long time
- Name and rank, sailor
- It's army, actually
Answer the question
And address him as "General, sir"
Captain john Patrick Mason,
General, sir
of Her Majesty's SAS
Retired, of course
You're a long way
from home, Captain
How the hell are you
involved in this?
I have a unique knowledge
of this prison facility
I was, uh
formerly a guest here
Hi, sweetie
[Screaming]
Hey, come back here,
little boy
Did they bother to tell you
who I am, why I'm doing this,
or are they just using you
like they do everybody else?
All I know is you were big in Vietnam
I saw the highlights on television
You wouldn't have any idea
what it means to lead the finest
men on God's earth into battle,
and then see their memory betrayed
by their own fuckin' government!
I don't quite see how you
cherish the memory of the dead
by killing another million
And, uh
this is not combat
It's an act of lunacy,
General, sir
Personally, I think
you're a fuckin' idiot
"The tree of liberty must be refreshed
from time to time
"with the blood of patriots
and tyrants" Thomas Jefferson
"Patriotism is the virtue of
the vicious," according to Oscar Wilde
[Grunts, Groaning]
Thank you for making my point
Where are the guidance chips?
Where are the guidance chips!
I destroyed them
That was a bad move, soldier
Does that mean
you'll execute us both?
[Rapid Gunfire]
[Choking, Yelling]
[Screams, Grunts]
You're lucky that old man
Hummel wants you alive
'Cause I'd take pleasure
in guttin' you, boy
[Stanley]
I'd take pleasure
in guttin' you boy
I'll take pleasure
What is wrong with these
people, huh, Mason?
Don't you think there's a lot of, uh,
anger floatin' around this island?
Kind of a pubescent volatility?
Don't you think?
A lot of angst, lot of "I'm 16;
I'm angry at my father" syndrome?
I mean, grow up!
We're stuck on an island
with a bunch of violence-for-pleasure
seeking psychopathic marines
Shame on them!
[Clears Throat]
Anyway, I only got one chem rod,
and there's two left
Mason?
Yes, I'm here
I was just thinking
how wonderful it was
when the inmates weren't
allowed to talk in here
Not allowed to talk
How did you do it?
[Sighs]
Nurtured the hope that there was hope
that one day I'd breathe free air
Perhaps meet my daughter
Modest hopes,
but they kept a man alive
What did they put you away for, John?
Oh, that's a long story
Well, I'm not going anywhere
When was the last communication
from our men on Alcatraz?
Seven hours
[Phone Rings]
- Thermite plasma is operational
- Get me the president
Be seated Gentlemen,
consider yourselves on ground alert
If we receive launch authority,
your mission is
the complete thermal destruction
of Alcatraz Island
The entire island is to be blanketed,
not one square inch missed
81 American civilians and a number
of US Marines will lose their lives
Why didn't you just tell them where the
microfilm was and create a solution?
[Chuckles]
The moment they had the
microfilm, they'd suicide me
- Some solution
- You ended up here
Which brings me
to another question
You broke out... let me see
if I can get this straight...
you went down the incinerator
chute, on the mine car,
through the tunnels
to the power plant,
under the steam engine...
that was really cool, by the way...
and into the cistern
through the intake pipe,
[Clears Throat]
But how, in the name of Zeus's butthole,
did you get out of your cell?
I only ask because
in our current situation,
well, it could prove to be
useful information, maybe!
Trade secrets, my son
Wow
General, two operational
rockets left
One at the lower lighthouse
and one at the roof
Both of the birds are ready to fly, sir
General, can you hear me?
- I heard you, Captain
- just makin' sure
Should we prepare
for launch, General?
- I'll handle the strategy, Captain
- Yes, sir
The hour is approaching, sir Just
letting the General know of the time
I'm very aware
of the time, Captain
Aye, aye, sir
Lettin' you know
Me and my boys are cocked,
locked and ready to rock
Mason, where are you going?
Thirty years ago I vowed
I wouldn't die in this toilet
You're not leaving! There's a madman
in there with his hand on a button!
Shhh Some sniper's
gonna get his ass
Stop moving, Mason
Mason, stop moving
Hummel won't do it
He's a soldier, not a murderer
I read it in his eyes
Read his eyes? Oh, well,
then everything's just fine!
- I can't afford to take that chance
- Why don't you talk louder?
Three minutes to go, sir
- They're not gonna call for it
- Oh, they'll call
They'll call if we fire
one of our rockets up their ass
Sir
[Phone Ringing]
- Hummel
- Hi, Frank, it's Al Kramer here
- How's it going out there?
- How do you think it's going?
- We're gonna need another hour, Frank
- You've got three minutes
- We have to get authorization
from the president
- You've got three minutes
Frank, please
don't do anything stupid
They want another hour
That's bullshit That's bullshit,
General They're lying
They're calling our bluff, sir
They're playing you for a fool
Sir, order the launch, General
Come on, General,
let's be all we can be
The mission's not complete!
Well, mine is
When this is over,
you'll go back home,
driving Carla and your baby
insane in your beige Volvo
And I'll be dead, or back in prison
which is the same thing
You're not leaving
[Grunts, Groaning]
All right
I'll do it myself
I got three weeks'
weapons training
I'll kick the...
And a platoon full of marines
No problem
- Major, patch me into roof battery
- Aye, sir
Fire open control circuit
coordinates to the roof, sir
Let's go!
- Laser powered up
- Oh, no
I said, on your knees!
My name's Stanley Goodspeed
I'm a chemical weapons
specialist for the FBI
- Uh, glass or plastic?
- What?
- Glass or plastic!
- Shut the fuck up!
Because if the winds change and if you
launch those rockets, we're gonna die
Shut up!
And you're gonna end up
in a glass jar or a plastic bag
So do the math, hand over the gun
and let's go find some rockets!
I said shut the fuck...
[Neck Snaps]
[Panting]
You made the right choice
I decided I didn't want your child
growing up without a father
Hey, the last time I swam
this channel, I was your age
So I'm fucked either way
So come on
The weapon is hot
I am standing by for the launch command
Man, killing Navy SEALs is one thing...
Is this for real?
Hey, it's business
Access code entered
Weapon available for release
Launch coordinates;
six, seven, five, four, five, niner
The weapon is hot
I'm standing by
for launch command
It's affirmative
[Bell Chiming]
Standing by for command
I'm waiting for
a launch command, General
- Fire
- Fire!
Missile loose!
Origin; Alcatraz, 67253725
- What's the heading?
- Heading 185 degrees south southeast
- Speed?
- 300 knots Headed right at Oakland
The football game
Oh, my God
Missile radically
changing direction
New direction; 275 degrees west
It's headed out to sea, sir
Oh, Christ!
Missile losing altitude
Falling
Falling, 300 feet, 200, 100
Bogey detonated underwater
What the fuck?
- It missed
- Well, that's great
Extremely great,
but there's still one left
What happened to the rocket?
What the fuck happened?
What the fuck is going on
to the coordinates? Sir! Major!
Captain, step outside
- Talk to me, sir
- Captain, step outside!
Get me the Pentagon
What the hell was that, Frank?
- I said, what the hell...
- I heard what you said!
- I'd appreciate a little more respect
- Cut the crap, General
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm not ready to kill these people
- Call the Pentagon Ask for more time
- No
Do it, Frank!
We're coming loose
You're coming loose
The rest of us are in complete control
- We're gonna ask for a new deadline
- Put the phone down
- The men are falling apart!
- The men are marines!
Are they?
I wanna talk to Gen Kramer
- You've been asked by an old friend
- Put him on the phone right now
- You've been ordered
- This is Major Baxter!
Now you're being given your last chance
by a man with a gun
Put the phone down
- I thought you weren't ready to kill
- I'm warming up
At ease
They need a decision,
Mr. President
[Sighs]
These past few hours
have been the longest,
darkest of my life
How does one weigh human life?
One million civilians
against 81 hostages
And in the middle, Frank Hummel
[Sighs]
That we have ignored, abandoned
or marginalized a great
soldier like Frank Hummel,
and American boys have paid
for that neglect
with blood is equally real
and equally tragic
We are at war with terror,
and fighting war means casualties
This is the worst call
I've ever had to make
Air strike approved
Red Thunder to Tower
Request clearance
The amount of firepower
they're gonna drop in there...
- This is strike leader Prepared to go
- It'll be over in a few seconds
[Pilot]
Flight time to drop point; 17 minutes
Excuse me, General, sir,
with all due respect to you
- What the fuck is going on?
- You changed the coordinates,
didn't you, General?
- That's affirmative, Captain
- So now they think we're gutless?
The Feds?
They think we won't actually do it
They're gonna come at us with
everything they got Air and sea
They're gonna bomb our ass
back to the Stone Age
They don't know
we missed on purpose
Great We're not gutless
We're incompetent That right?
I don't think I like your tone, Captain
We planned for this contingency
Load the VX into the choppers,
take four hostages and Evacuate
The consequences of our actions
I'll face alone
Excuse me, General, but
what about the fucking money?
There is no fucking money
Mission's over
Bullshit it's over
You're talking to a General, soldier!
Maintain discipline!
I'm not a soldier, Major The day
we took hostages, we became mercenaries
And mercenaries get paid
I want my fucking money!
This mission was based
on the threat of force
I'm not about to kill
80,000 innocent people
Do you think I'm
out of my fucking mind?
We bluffed They called it
The mission's over
Who ever said anything
about bluffing, General?
Stand down, Captain
Stand down, Captain!
Major, I'm ordering you to take
these men to the choppers and Evacuate
That's a simple order, Major!
It's not so simple, Frank
Sgt Crisp, secure the general
I'm relieving you
of your command, sir
Sergeant!
- I'll have that sidearm, sir
- You mean this sidearm?
Maj Baxter, you're either with us
or against us
It has been the greatest honor
of my life to serve with you, General
But like he said it's over
[Grunts]
Let's get him
Mason!
[Groaning]
My God, what have I done?
Where's the last rocket?
Where's the last rocket!
- Where's the last rocket?
- Lower lighthouse
- Lower lighthouse!
- Go
[Shouting]
Darrow, go to the lighthouse!
I'll take care of this fucker!
One, two, three!
Eat that!
[Groaning]
Did it
[Grunts]
Come here Come here,
you little chickensh...
You shoot me, I drop this
We're both dead
Come on Come on
Don't be scared I won't hurt you
- Come on
- You know how this shit works?
You know how this shit works?
Come on
I don't need a gun
I'll put it down
Come on Let's play
Come on Come on
Listen, I think we got started off
on the wrong foot Stan Goodspeed, FBI
Uh, let's talk music Do you like
the Elton John song, "Rocket Man"?
- I don't like soft-ass shit
- Oh, you... Oh, oh
Well, I only bring it up because,
uh, it's you You're the Rocket Man
[Screaming]
How do you like
how that shit works?
Second rocket's away!
[Screaming Continues]
- [Squelching Noise]
- [Groaning]
It splashed into the bay, sir
No detonation
Shit
Darrow!
Open up!
Come on
[Grunts]
Hey, you mothe-e-e-er!
[Groaning]
[Grunting]
Oh, I'm gonna
get you now, baby
Okay
Got ya I got you, baby
Come on
[Groaning, Screaming]
Fucker!
[Grunting]
[Groans]
Red Thunder strike leader
Time on target: Seven minutes
[Grunting]
English prick [Grunts]
I tell you my old man was Irish?
Maintain air speed
4-5-0 knots
[Grunting]
- [Thud]
- Aw, fuck!
[Gasping]
It's me and you, pal!
I want that fucking chip!
I love pressure
I know you're in here,
and I know you can hear me
Now pay the piper
and come out like a man
[Yells, Grunts]
[Groaning]
[Grunting Continues]
Increase speed to 5-0-0 knots
You motherfucker!
[Yelling]
[Gasping, Groaning]
I'm gonna choke my million bucks
out of you! You're gonna die!
- Eat that, you fucker!
- [Grunts]
[Choking, Gasping]
[Grunts]
All right, team inbound
Time on target: 60 seconds
On course heading 1-4-2 degrees
[Anderson's Voice]
When he neutralizes the threat,
we launch green flares
and we wait for the cavalry
- Let's tighten up that formation
- May God have mercy on your souls
Please don't let this happen
There has to be something you can do
[Grunting, Groaning]
Let's drop to the deck,
100 feet below radar
Target acquired
Rolling in
[Groans]
This is Red Thunder
Master arm
Master armed
Time on target: 12 seconds
- TO T; ten seconds
- Please
Stay tight, gentlemen
I got green smoke
I got green smoke!
This is CQ1, CQ1 Green smoke!
We have green smoke, over!
- Gimme that, gimme that Abort
- Abort!
- Flight leader, abort, abort!
- Jesus Christ!
- I already dropped 'em
- [Screaming]
Oh, goddamn it!
Oh, my God
Get out of my way
Let me through, please Let me through
The cells did not get hit
The bombs hit on the back of the island
- [Grunting, Gasping]
- I'm fed up saving your ass
I'm amazed you ever
got past puberty
I suppose all this will make
a great bedtime story to tell your kid
You're insane, Mason
The kid'll have nightmares
I'll spend all my money
on shrinks
Goodspeed, come in Goodspeed,
Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in
Scanning all radio frequencies
Goodspeed, do you read me?
Come in
[Walkie-Talkie Clicks]
Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in
Goodspeed?
Do you read me? Come in
This is Goodspeed
Are the hostages alive?
Every one of'em
[Cheering]
Goodspeed, it's Womack
What about Mason?
He's dead, sir
- How? When?
- Just come and get me
Womack tore up your pardon, john
[Chuckles]
But of course I knew he would
The SDUs and the scuba gear
should still be where we came ashore
If you can get
to the Pan Pacific Hotel,
there's clothes in my closet
and $200 in the bible
Room 26
Well, it's been a long time
since I've said thank you to anybody
But thank you
Well, Stanley, uh, this is when we go
our separate ways, huh?
Uh... I'm sure you know the etymology
of your name, "Goodspeed"
Yeah, "Godspeed" To wish someone
a prosperous journey Why?
Well, if you fancy a journey,
I recommend Fort Walton, Kansas
I was thinking of Maui
No
Forget Maui
"St Michael's Church,
Fort Walton, Kansas
"Front pew, right leg
Hollow"
Is this what I think it is?
Mason?
- Congratulations,
Dr Goodspeed You did it
- Thank you, sir
You know, for a while there,
I didn't think you were gonna make it
Well done, son
So, where's Mason?
Vaporized
Blown out to sea
Blown out to sea, huh?
Yeah
Poor bastard
Goodspeed, where's Mason?
Where's his body?
I wanna see
that son of a bitch
Vaporized, sir
Excuse me, gentlemen
What? Vaporized?
A body can vaporize?
Oh, yeah
Absolutely, sir
[Stanley]
St Michael's Church
Front pew, right leg
[Man Shouting]
Vandals! Vandals!
Oh, yes, baby, come on!
- Stop! Vandals! Stop!
- I'm sorry
- Come on, baby!
- I've got it Okay, let's go!
- Stop! Stop!
- Sorry!
Stop! Hey, hey, you!
- Vandals! Vandals!
- [Panting]
Honey, uh, do you wanna know
who really killed JFK?
Subtitles by ARAVIND B
[by_agentsmith@yahoo.com]