There are would-be murderers all round the world
who want to kill you and me and themselves,
because they are motivated by what
they think is the highest ideal.
Of course politics are important,
lraq, Palestine, even social
deprivation in Bradford,
but as we wake up to this huge challenge
to our civilised values
don't lets forget the elephant in the room,
an elephant called religion.
The suicide bomber is convinced
that in killing for his God,
he will be fast-tracked to
a special martyrs' heaven.
This isn't just a problem of lslam.
In this program I want
to examine that dangerous thing
that is common to Judaism
and Christianity as well
the process of nonthinking called faith.
I am a scientist, and I believe there is a profound
contradiction between science and religious belief.
There is no well-demonstrated reason
to believe in god
and I think that the idea of a divine creator
belittles the elegant reality of the universe.
The 21st century should be an age of reason, yet
irrational, militant faith is back on the march.
Religious extremism is implicated in the world's
most bitter and unending conflicts.
"We want the non-Muslims off the lands of
Mohammad. We want the kafir out of it."
America, too, has its own fundamentalists.
"The Issue for the next generation is
going to be the islamification of Europe."
And in Britain, even as we live
in the shadow of holy terror,
our government wants to restrict
our freedom to criticise religion.
Science, we are told, should not tread
on the toes of theology.
But why should scientists
tiptoe respectfully away?
The time has come for the people of reason
to say enough is enough.
Religious faith discourages independent thought,
it's divisive and it's dangerous.
Root of All Evil?
The God Delusion
lt looks lovely doesn't it?
Inoffensive and gentle.
But isn't this the beginning
of that slippery slope
that leads to young men with
rucksack bombs on the Tube?
If you want to experience
the mediaeval rituals of faith,
the candle light, incense, music,
important-sounding dead languages,
nobody does it better than the Catholics.
At Lourdes in southern France, the assault
on the senses appeals to us not to think,
not to doubt, not to probe.
And if we can retain our faith against the evidence,
in the teeth of reality, the more virtuous we are.
Pretty impressive sight isn't it? I could imagine
finding it very seductive,
partly because of the tremendous feeling of group
solidarity that there must be.
If you have the delusion
that you're Napoleon,
it must be fairly a lonely feeling
because nobody else agrees with you.
Your faith that you are Napoleon
needs a lot of shoring up.
But these people here, thousands of people all
have exactly the same delusion,
and that must give wonderful
reinforcement to their faith.
I used to think reason had
won the war against superstition
but it's quite shaking to witness the faithful
droves trooping through Lourdes.
This is a benign herd but it supports
a backward belief system
that I believe reason must challenge.
Daylight reveals more of this shrine,
where a myth is perpetuated that a virgin
who gave birth, Christ's mother Mary,
appeared here once to an impressionable,
and I do mean impressionable, young girl.
The faithful make the pilgrimage
here because they believe
that terrible afflictions can be cured by dragging
their poor bodies up to a pool of water
where the Virgin Mary made
her miraculous appearance.
In reality, they're probably more likely to catch
something from thousands of other pilgrims
who've wallowed in the same water.
Is it something that Catholics feel
they ought to do in their life,
rather like Muslims
going on the Hajj to Mecca?
Well no, but you don't have
to be a Catholic to do it you see,
I know a lot of people that are not
Catholics at all and they've been here.
And what are you hoping to get out of it?
Well I've got a lot out of it: I've got faith,
I've got trust and a belief that
there is a person out there who is
stronger than any medical person.
Right. What about a cure though?
It may seem tough to question these poor
desperate peoples' faith,
but isn't bracing truth better than false hope?
What is the evidence for any miracles?
There are actually 66 declared miracles, there
are about 2000 unexplained cures here,
but then we would say there are millions of people
who have been healed in different ways.
healed in some sort of mental way?
Healed in spiritual ways where people who have
come to terms with their own particular situation,
people who have rediscovered
God in their lives again,
people who have received
a new grace here in Lourdes.
So you tend to get
about 80,000 people per year?
About 80,000 sick pilgrims
who come here every year.
That's been going for more than a century now?
About a century and half? - Yes.
So, 80,000 per year, and of those 66
have been cured. I just want to ...
...you see the way I'm thinking.
- Yep.
So the hard fact is that over the years,
with their millions of pilgrims,
there have been 66 supposed miracles.
I cant help remarking that nobody has ever had
a miraculous re-growing of a severed leg.
The cures are always things that might
have got better anyway.
People lean on their faith as a crutch,
but I fear that the comfort it
provides is a shallow pretence,
and I want to look at how the suspension
of disbelief inherent in faith
can lead to far more
dangerous ideas beyond.
People like to say that faith and science can live
together side by side, but I don't think they can.
They're deeply opposed.
Science is a discipline of investigation
and constructive doubt,
questing with logic, evidence
and reason to draw conclusions.
Faith, by stark contrast, demands a positive
suspension of critical faculties.
Science proceeds by setting up hypotheses, ideas
or models, and then attempts to disprove them.
So a scientist is constantly asking questions,
being sceptical.
Religion is about turning untested
belief into unshakable truth,
through the power of institutions
and the passage of time.
Let me give you an example of this with
a story of the assumption of Mary.
Catholics believe that Jesus' mother Mary was so
important she didn't physically die.
lnstead, her body shot off into heaven when her life
came to a natural end.
Of course there is no evidence for this, even the
Bible says nothing about how Mary died.
The belief that her body was lifted into heaven
emerged about six centuries after Jesus' time.
Made up, like any tale,
and spread by word of mouth.
But it became established tradition.
lt was handed down over centuries.
And the odd thing about tradition
is that the longer it's been going,
the more people seem to take it seriously.
lt's as though sheer passage of time makes
something that was to begin with just made up,
turns it into what people believe as a fact.
By 1950, the tradition was so strongly
established that it became official truth.
It became authority.
The Vatican decreed
that Roman Catholics must now believe
in the doctrine of the Assumption of the Virgin.
Now if you had asked Pope Pious XII
how he knew it was the truth,
he would have said you had
to take his word for it
because it had been
''revealed to him'' by God.
He shut himself away and thought about it.
He just thought, private thoughts
inside his own head,
and convinced himself that,
no doubt on tortuous theological
grounds, that it just had to be so.
None of this is particularly harmful
when it is limited to the
Virgin Mary going to heaven.
But what about the Pope's personal
convictions when it comes to,
say, discouraging the use of
condoms in AIDS-ridden Africa?
Then, the power of the church
through tradition, authority
and revelation comes with
an appalling human cost.
It would be unfair to pick on the Catholics.
All religions are up to the same tricks.
It could be Muslim Imams issuing fatwahs,
it's the same principle.
It's issued by the authority, it then passes
down through the ranks to parents,
to children, and all
without a shred of evidence.
Unlike science, which sees it as a challenge,
religion thrives on unsolved mystery.
For early humanity, what was mysterious and
unexplained was so vast
that only an equally vast higher being,
an Alpha male in the sky,
could fill that gap.
How would our ancestors have
responded to the sunrise?
There must be a fiery charioteer, a Sun God, to
accept our sacrifices.
A supreme being who, on the first day
of creation, announced ''let there be light''.
But scientific investigation
has rolled back that mystery.
Today we know the sun
is a giant nuclear reactor.
One of billions of stars pumping out
electromagnetic radiation, heat and light.
How do scientists know
the things that they know
about the world and the universe?
How do we know, for instance,
that the Earth is 4.5 billion years old
and that it orbits the sun that nourishes it?
How do we know that these dinosaurs
are hundreds of millions of years old?
The answer is evidence.
Tons and tons
of mutually supporting evidence.
Science is about testing, comparing and
corroborating this mass of evidence,
and using it to update old theories
of how things work.
I do remember one formative influence
in my undergraduate life.
There was an elderly professor
in my department
who had been passionately keen on a particular
theory for a number of years.
And one day an American
visiting researcher came,
and he completely and utterly disproved
our old man's hypothesis.
The old man strode to the front,
shook his hand and said, ''My dear fellow,
I wish to thank you. I have
been wrong these 15 years.''
And we all clapped our hands raw.
That was the scientific ideal
of somebody who had a lot invested,
a lifetime almost invested in a theory,
and he was rejoicing that
he had been shown wrong,
and scientific truth had been advanced.
So what does the overwhelming evidence of
all these fossils tell sceptical science?
How did we and every creature get here,
in all our improbable diversity?
In past centuries, humanity had no choice
but to resort to a supernatural hypothesis.
Among the many creation
myths around the world,
the Book of Genesis imagined a designer God
who fashioned the world
and life in just six days.
Finally, in the 19th century, science pieced
together what had really happened.
Charles Darwin hit upon a truly brilliant idea
that elegantly explains all of life on earth,
without any need to invoke
the supernatural or the divine.
Here's a helpful way to look
at the problem Darwin faced.
Climbing a mountain.
Let's call it Mount Improbable.
Let's say at the bottom we have the simple
bacterial beginnings of lifeon earth.
At the top, man today,
or any complicated piece of biology.
So how did we get to the top?
If it had happened by blind
chance or by design,
lt would be equivalent to leaping up
a sheer cliff in a single bound.
Utterly out of the question.
If we come round the other
side of Mount Improbable,
we find something very different.
Here, there is no sudden precipitous cliff,
here there's a gentle slope,
a gradient of evolution.
All we have to do is put one foot in front
of the other and we'll get to the top.
Darwin's great insight was that
life evolved steadily and slowly,
inching its way gradually
over four billion years.
Natural selection, not a divine designer,
was the sculptor of life.
So evolution, driven by Darwin's
motor of natural selection,
gets us to the top of Mount Improbable.
From primeval simplicity
to ultimate complexity.
The design hypothesis couldn't
even begin to do that,
because it raises an even
bigger problem than it solves:
who made the designer?
The abundance and variety of life
on earth may seem improbable
but it's self-evidently futile
to invent an improbable god
to explain that very improbability.
l thought that in my lifetime
evolution would be accepted
and taught around the world
as a scientific fact,
supported by overwhelming evidence.
But unfortunately, the whole point about faith
is that even massive and constantly
accumulating physical evidence cuts no ice.
Evolution today is under threat.
ln the Bible Belt of middle America,
evangelical Christians are
fighting back against science.
In the new world, religion is free enterprise.
Rival groups set up shop
on every street corner,
competing to save people's
souls and collect their money.
Fundamentalist Christianity is
on the rise among the electorate
of the world's only super power.
Right up to and including the President (Bush).
If you believe the surveys,
45% of Americans,
that's about 135 million people,
believe the universe is less
than 10,000 years old.
This is the New Life Church
in Colorado Springs.
Where conservative Christians have built
an 18 million dollar worship center
as their new Jerusalem, in the
foothills of the Rocky Mountains.
Evangelical churches like this
have become a powerful lobby,
exerting enormous influence
on everything in America
from the teaching of science
in schools, to foreign policy.
This place strains belief.
It isn't just a church but
a ready-made social network.
The 12,000 strong congregation can
also attend 1,300 organized programs
where they can meet
to exchange Christian tips
on everything from marriage
to dog walking.
It's all terribly exuberant and intense.
Much less tradition here than in Lourdes,
but plenty of swaggering authority.
The pastor is Ted Haggard.
A powerful man.
Chairman of the
National Association of Evangelicals
and the New Life is Ted's evangelical Vatican.
''Welcome to all of our friends!
Take a moment and say hello
to the people behind you,
in front of you, to your right,
to your left.''
''Hey we wanna welcome all of you
that are visiting here with us today,
if you are here for the very first time,''
''we have a packet of information
that we wanna give to you ...''
Sadly, the warmth of the
welcome would prove short-lived
when I started talking to Pastor Haggard
about the Bible and scientific fact.
You will find yourself wrong on some things,
right on some other things.
But please, in the process of it.
Don´t be arogant.
We exalt
you here this morning, Lord God.
Everything that's within us wants
to give you praise and glory and honor,
'cos we are so grateful for ...
The New Life Church in Colorado Springs
is a bastion of American
religious conservatism.
''Thank you for transforming our lives.
Thank you, Lord God, for ...''
I've come to try to understand why
what I see as irrational faith is thriving.
And why it's attacking science.
'' ... and in Jesus' name we pray.
And everybody says Amen!''
''Amen!''
''Welcome to the United States!''
- Thank you very much.
Pastor Ted Haggard has a hotline
to God and to George Bush.
A staunch Republican, he claims he has
a weekly conference call with the President,
and has also rubbed shoulders
with Tony Blair and Ariel Sharon.
Well that was really quite
a show you gave us today.
A fair bit of money seems
to have been spent here.
Yes. I wanted people to be
able to worship and enjoy it,
and be in a setting where
the speaker is close to them,
that's why it's in the round,
and so they can be up close to me
and so l can look at them.
Well it's certainly very effective,
what you do,
I mean, it seemed to me
you have all the arts of ..
I mean, I was almost reminded me,
if you'll forgive me,
of a sort of Nuremberg rally. I mean ...
such incredibly ...
Doctor Goebbels would have
been proud.
Well I don't know anything
about the Nuremberg rallies,
but I know lots of Americans
think of it as a rock concert.
When I prepare a presentation,
I don't prepare  it to get
a group of lunatics to come in
and just say ''oh yes Pastor Ted,
you're just so wonderful,
I believe everything you say''.
I would be opposed to that.
Here the Bible says '...
who have been chosen according
to the foreknowledge of God, the Father,
this is talking about us,
we've been chosen for ...
what's that word there Betty?
''Obedience.''
- ''Say it out loud.''
''Obedience!''
- ''Okay, so we have been chosen ...''
Every person needs, at the center,
some sense of meaning about existence.
It is life and death to us.
It makes us who we are.
Yet most of us, as we grow up and become
responsible adults,
accept that life is complex, that we live
in a world of subtle shades,
not sharp black and white.
I worry that these born-agains
are being persuaded
to return to childish certainties.
The only truth they need is God,
God as interpreted
for them by their pastor.
You've been set free from sin!
Think about that!
Everybody knows that we believe the
Bible's the word of God.
And today I talked about love
your neighbor as yourself.
Now, I didn't have to produce evidence,
sociological evidence or
psychological evidence ...
But you have a book,
How can you say
they're asked to think for themselves...
...and they're told everything in this book is true?
Because they don't have to believe that.
The evidence that I presented
you can go and read.
This book, it says one thing,
that book says another,
that book contradicts the others ...
Well the evidence I can present
is we've got a book,
written over 1500 years
by 40 different authors,
on one subject,
and it doesn't contradict itself.
It doesn't?
Where you cant give me two,
two experts in certain areas
that are in the same generation,
in the same area of study,
that don't contradict themselves.
That's the beauty of science.
We have lots of evidence,
and the evidence is all the time coming in,
constantly changing our minds.
Whereas you have one book which you say it
doesn't change ...
Exactly.
That's not getting them
to think for themselves!
... and we've all decided as a group, to go to the
holy place. True or false?
(Congregatlon) True!
True! Everybody say TRUE!
''TRUE!''
Alright then. That's the vote ...
But my biggest concern
is that evangelicals like Haggard
are foisting evident falsehoods on their flock.
... are so wonderful, and so necessary,
that I wanna ...
The evangelicals
are denying scientific evidence
just to support Bronze Age myths.
... alive in our lives. And then of course,
we need the power of the Holy Spirit.
We fully embrace the scientific method, as
American evangelicals.
And we think, as time goes along,
as we discover more and more facts
that we'll learn more and more about
how God created the heavens and the Earth.
The scientific method clearly demonstrates
that the world is 4.5 billion years old.
I mean, do you accept that?
Yeah, you know what you're doing is you are
accepting some of the views
that are accepted in some portions
of the scientific community, as fact.
Where in fact, your grandchildren might listen
to the tape of you saying
that and laugh at you.
You want a bet?
Sometimes it's hard for human being to
study the ear or study the eye,
and think that
happened by accident.
I beg you pardon? Did you say by accident?
- Yeah.
What do you mean, by accident?
That the eye just formed itself somehow.
- And who says it did?
Well, some evolutionists say it did.
Not a single one that l've ever met.
Really?
- Really.
You obviously know nothing
about the subject of evolution.
Or maybe you haven't met the people I have.
But you see, you do understand,
you do understand that this issue right here
of intellectual arrogance is the reason
why people like you have a difficult
problem with people of faith.
I don't communicate an air
of superiority over the people
because I know so much more,
and if you only read the books I know,
and if you only knew the scientists I knew,
then you would be great like me.
Well, sir, there could be many
things that you know well.
There are other things
that you don't know well.
As you age, you'll find yourself
wrong on some things,
right on some other things.
But please, in the process,
of it don't be arrogant.
We just had a rather disconcerting experience.
We were just packing up
our stuff ready to go,
when he suddenly drove up in
his pick up truck and said,
"Get of my land immediatelly", "I´ll have you
thrown in jail" and "I´ll have seize your film".
And he then says a very curious thing,
he said,
"You called my children animals."
Afterwards we worked out,
that what he must have meant,
was that I talked about evolution.
He thought that I was saying,
that his flock were animals.
Which of course in some sense I was,
because all humans are all animals.
Haggard's approach is to say
let's teach evolution
as just another theory
alongside the Bible's creation story.
Or so-called Intelligent Design, which claims
God helped evolution along.
It sounds so reasonable, doesn't it?
But of course it's nothing of the sort.
These are not equal theories.
Evolution by natural selection is supported
by mountains of evidence.
and is only backed by
some ancient scribblings.
With Haggard and his followers
on their doorstep,
the rational atheist minority
here feel so browbeaten,
that they've organized themselves into
what they call ''a freethinkers group'',
which meets furtively, perhaps
to fantasise about moving to Canada!
How nice to meet you!
Hey Richard! lt's wonderful! Welcome,
welcome, it's so good ...
Do freethinkers in America feel pretty
beleaguered at the moment?
I've had my fair share of vitriolic letters and
messages from parents
saying that I'm Satan's incarnate
for teaching evolution,
and there are ministries here
in Colorado Springs that indoctrinate
students in summer programs
to challenge biologists,
biology teachers, in the classroom. And I've ...
So it's an organised campaign to
challenge biology teachers?
Oh they're organised campaigns, absolutely.
I do not tolerate it, because I ...
But they have this mindset that they are right.
If a person comes out
in this country as an atheist,
they're likely to suffer career damage,
they might lose a job,
they might not get a job,
they might lose an opportunity
for an apartment.
Waking up, as most Americans do,
very late on this,
coming to a realisation,
as we did during the McCarthy era,
and even during ...
It's very similar to the McCarthy era ...
Yes, it is. We do begin now to see the
dangers of this extremism.
Christian fascism isn't it?
Yeah. And whatever mantle you want to give
it, which I've heard lately
is ''domination theology'',
''dominion Christianity'' ...
(Christian radio advertisements)
Fundamentalist American
Christianity is attacking science.
But what is it offering instead?
A mirror-image of islamic extremism,
an American Taliban.
We live in a time of lethal polarisation.
When the great religions are pushing
their conflict to a point where
it is difficult to see how they
can ever been reconciled.
In New York, Madrid and London
we've witnessed the religious insanities
of the Middle East penetrate
the heart of the secular west.
(George W Bush voiceover)
To understand the likes of Osama Bin Laden,
you have to realise
that the religious terrorism they inspire
is the logical
outcome of deeply-held faith.
Even so-called moderate believers
are part of the
same religious fabric.
They encourage unreason as a positive virtue.
What's really scary is that
religious warriors think
of what they are doing as the ultimate good.
Those of us brought up in Christianity
can soon get the message:
'Onward Christian soldiers',
'fight the good fight',
'stand up! stand up for Jesus,
ye soldiers of the cross!'
But as far as I'm concerned,
the war between good and evil,
is really just the war between two evils.
This is the holy land,
where the terrible certainties
of faith began and still rage.
I've come here because it's a microcosm
of the religious conflicts
which threaten rational values
and civilisation.
The dreadful combination of politics
and extreme faith has caused the
death of almost 4000 people here,
in shootings,
suicide bombings and reprisals
in the last five years.
Despite the troubles,
tourists still flock to Jerusalem,
to places that their particular brand of religion
taught them to revere as a child.
The Via Dolorosa, where Jesus
was allegedly whipped
and beaten during the last hours of his life.
Or the Muslim Dome of the Rock.
Or the Western Wall, Judaism's,
and the world's, most holy ruin.
On the surface, it looks like
a place of harmless myth.
Because here is the hill of Calvary,
where Jesus was crucified,
and the tomb of Jesus.
And here, what we are facing,
to the stone of anointment,
where the body of
Jesus was taken down from the cross,
so this is the slab where Christ's
body was anointed with oil.
How do we know that?
Is there any evidence that it was here?
You see, this is by telling
from person to person.
It's tradition.
Traditional, from generation to the next.
We can see the hole where
the cross was stood,
Where they put(ing)
the cross inside the hole,
and this is the place where,
the place of the crucifixion,
where Jesus died on the cross.
You don't really believe that, do you?
Ah, this is the Christians, as I explained to
you that they believe,
this is the place where the
crucifixion took place.
lf we come in closer
to my side please, thank you.
[The] guard of the tomb is a Greek priest.
Guarding of tomb of Jesus.
This is left from big part of the
stone which closed the tomb,
What we call the rolling of angels.
Watch your head please,
thank you very much.
This is where he stayed,
and rose from death,
we call it Sepulchre, is empty tomb.
God bless you, you can touch[ing] the tomb,
you can make your prayer.
I get four days off! You come here tomorrow...
This holy city has to be one of the least
enlightened places in the world.
And it is also a place of barely
suppressed religious hatreds.
There will come the day and that day is now.
When you are on our lands,
spreading these ideas,
that the soldiers of Allah
will not put up with this.
We live at a time
when religious belief is fighting back
against reason and scientific truth.
This is a problem for all of us,
because religion's irrational
roots nourish intolerance
to the point of murder.
I'm in Jerusalem's old city,
trying to understand the role deeply-held
faith plays in the bitter conflict here.
One of the first things you notice
is the edgy watchfulness,
the different ethnic and religious
communities live cheek-by-jowl,
but there are security checkpoints
throughout the old city,
and one section above all
is under heavy guard.
For the Muslims, the compound enclosing
the Dome of the Rock and
Al-Aqsa mosque is, after Mecca and Medina,
the third holiest site in lslam.
It was from here, they believe,
that the prophet
Mohammad flew up to heaven.
As bad luck would have it,
the Jews believe the same place
is the site of the long-destroyed first
and second temples,
the holiest shrine in Judaism.
Jews are not allowed to
worship inside the compound,
their prayers are restricted
to the ruined western, or wailing, wall.
''When Jesus came here
to overturn the tables,
there was no mosque in view.''
''When the Arabs conquered
this part of the world,
they established the Al-Aqsa mosque.''
And then they put over where
we think is the main temple compound,
where the altar was, where the
holy of holy was,
they put another building
called the Dome of the Rock,
it was not properly a mosque,
and we at the present moment are
simply not allowed in there, inside the compound,
identifiably as Jews.
The Muslims reject these Jewish claims.
And when Ariel Sharon entered the Temple Mount
area in the Year 2000:
''I came here with a message of peace.''
His visit sparked the second,
or Al-Aqsa Intifada,
a Palestinian uprising that
has cost 4000 lives so far.
And if the Jews sincerely want
peace with the Arabs and Muslims,
then they should stand away,
keep away from the Al-Aqsa mosque.
''In the Muslim religion, there is no possibility
anyway of sharing the territory.''
If l come in there, in some far corner,
far away from a mosque,
in an open area, under a tree
somewhere, if a Muslim will catch me
murmuring psalms or some other prayer,
he will call the police
to have me 'egressed', shall I say.
As far as  the Al-Aqsa mosque is considered,
there are no negotiations,
absolutely no negotiations about it.
Because no Muslim has the right, worldwide,
to negotiate over the Al-Aqsa mosque.
Again and again my conversations come
back to the solid walls
that religion puts up. Back to
implacable faiths.
''My holy book is true" ,
" I am right" ," He is wrong''.
So I went to meet someone
who, in my naivete,
I thought might be able to see
both sides of the story.
Yusuf Al-Khattab used
to be called Joseph Coen,
born and brought up as
a secular Jew in New York.
In 1998 he moved to Gaza as a Jewish settler,
but there he discovered a different God, Allah.
What I notice coming to this
centre of world religions,
is what a lot hatred religion fosters.
I mean, I'm an atheist, and I am rather gentle,
I don't hate people.
But it seems to me that I'm
hearing hate on all sides,
and it seems to me is all to do with religion.
I hate atheists because atheists don't care
if somebody fornicates
in the middle of the street,
they don't care if their women
go bouncing around on TV topless,
it makes no difference, they don't
believe in anything.
If you don't believe in a set rule,
and you believe
that a constitution can change,
and you can amend
the rules as they go along,
and if you don't believe in God's rule,
then what law do you have?
You just have man-made laws.
I realized I was in the company of someone
who has willingly bought into
fundamentalist dogma.
What do you think about the
September 11 attacks on New York,
and the July 7 attacks in London?
Okay, since you like to speak about evolution,
I'd like to start before
- what do you think about
the Jews that have
destroyed over 417 Arab villages,
including all mosques and majids,
which wouldn't affect you,
'cause you're an atheist.
So what are are you saying?
That we should sit back...
Not at all.
...and say 'oh, you know what?
Let us progress and
let us sit down and drink tea,
and talk about what to do.
I think that's the most ridiculous thing.
All I could say is if there was
noquote-unquote "state of Israel",
there would have been no September 11 .
But if we've all got to live together,
it's not going to be helped if there
are people of very, very strong faith
who simply ''know'' they're right,
and are not amenable to
argument because ...
There's somebody out there
who's just as faithful as you,
and has his faith just as strong as yours,
which is opposite to yours.
You see the problem is, Richard,
I think that you have fear.
You know that this party
of occupying Muslim lands,
and polluting society with these
evil ideas that are around,
it's not gonna last forever. There
will always be the soldiers of Allah
there to give the response to this.
So we also want the same thing.
All we want is ...
we want the non-Muslims at this point
off the lands of Mohammad,
sal-allahu-alleihi-wasallam.
All the lands of Mohammad,
We want the kaffir out of it.
Dawkins: Do you want Islam to
take over rest of the world?
- Of course I want it to, and it will.
So my advice is
to clean up your show at home,
take your forces off our lands,
correct yourselves,
fix your society, alright?
Fix your women ...
Fix your women?
That's not my business,
that my women's business.
They're not my women...
No, it is your business.
It is your business.
When you take the women and
dress them like whores on the street ...
I don't dress women,
they dress themselves!
But you allow it as a norm, to let the women
go on the street dressed like this.
What's goin' on with
your society?
But I'm interested in religion and the effect
that it has on peoples' minds,
and I'm worried about it.
And we're very worried about you.
I mean, what's goin' on with the stealing?
With the theft? It's out of control...
Clearly, historic injustice
towards the Palestinians
breeds hatred and anger.
But we must face up to the fact
that in creating the death cults of
suicide bombers, it's unshakable,
unreasonable conviction in your
own righteous faith that is the key.
If preachers then tell the faithful
that Paradise after
martyrdom is better
than existence here in the real world,
it's hardly surprising that some
crazed followers will actually swallow it,
leading to a terrible cycle of vendetta,
war and suffering.
I'm here on the Mount of Olives,
looking out over
this beautiful old city.
We've heard some pretty
extreme statements,
some hatred, some bigotry,
such as I haven't really heard before.
I don't see what future the world has,
as long as
people think like that,
and people are going to go on thinking
like that, as long as they're
brought up from childhood,
from the cradle,
to think that there's
something good about faith.
To think that there's something good
about believing
because you've been told to believe,
rather than believing because you've
looked at the evidence.
I want to say that killing for God
is not only hideous murder,
it is also utterly ridiculous.
Unlike religion, science doesn't
pretend to know everything.
There are still deep questions about
the origins of the universe
that have yet to be explained.
But just because science can't
answer them right now,
doesn't mean faith, tradition, revelation
or an ancient holy text, can.
Science can't disprove the existence of God,
but that does not mean that God exists.
There are a million things we can't disprove!
The philosopher Bertrand Russell had an analogy:
Imagine there's a china tea pot,
in orbit around the Sun.
You cannot disprove the existence
of the tea pot, because it's too small
to be spotted by our telescopes.
Nobody but a lunatic would say 'well,
I'm prepared to believe in the tea pot
because I can't disprove it'.
Maybe we have to be technically
and strictly agnostic,
but in practice we are all tea pot atheists.
But now, suppose that everybody
in the society, the teachers,
the tribal elders, all had faith in the tea pot.
Stories of the tea pot had been
handed down for generations,
it's part of the tradition of the society,
there are holy
books about the tea pot.
Then, somebody who said they did
not believe in the tea pot, might be
regarded as eccentric or even mad.
There's an infinite number of things like celestial
tea pots that we can't disprove.
There are fairies, there
are unicorns, hobgoblins.
We can't disprove any of those.
But we don't believe in them anymore than
nowadays we believe
in Thor, Amen-Rah, or
Aphrodite.
We are all atheists about most of the gods that
societies have ever believed in.
Some of us just go one god further.
In the next program, how faith acts like
a virus that strikes the young,
and how the good book, which people
follow for moral instruction,
actually reveals a god
who is surely  the most vindictive
character in all fiction.
How do we explain the mysteries of life?
Science has steadily overturned
old religious myths about
how all this came to be.
Yet those who adhere to
Judaism, Christianity or islam
still prefer to ignore reason,
and have faith in their forever
unprovable, omniscient creator.
I had thought science was
rolling back religious belief,
but I was wrong.
Far from being beaten,
militant faith is on the march
all across the world,
with terrifying consequences.
As a scientist, I am increasingly worried
about how faith is undermining science.
It's something we must resist,
because irrational faith is feeding
murderous intolerance
throughout the world.
In this programme, I want to examine
two further problems with religion.
I believe it can lead to a
warped and inflexible morality
and I'm very concerned about the
religious indoctrination of children.
I want to show how Faith acts like a
virus that attacks the young
and infects generation after generation.
I believe in a law-giver;
a god right there
actually not behind it, right
imminent here; right now.
I want to ask whether ancient mythology
should be taught as truth in schools.
Professor Dawkins, I'm very impressed
that you're the new messiah, and I
appreciate your desire to
redeem the world, but-
It's time to question the
abuse of childhood innocence
with superstitious ideas
of hellfire and damnation.
I would rather for them to understand
that hell is a place that they
absolutely do not wanna go.
And I want to show how
the scriptural roots
of the Judeo-Christian moral edifice
are cruel and brutish.
"...thou shalt save alive
nothing that breatheth:
But thou shalt utterly destroy them..."
"DESTROY"
What in the 21st century are we doing
venerating a book that
contains such stuff?
Science weighs up evidence and advances.
Religion is high-bound belief for belief's sake.
It's bad for our children,
and it's bad for you.
"Root of All Evil?"
There is something exceedingly odd
about the idea of sectarian religious schools.
If we hadn't got used to it over the centuries,
we'd find it downright bizarre.
"The Virus of Faith"
Sectarian education has proved
to be deeply damaging.
It has left a terrible legacy.
When you think about it, isn't it weird
the way we automatically
label a tiny child with its parents' religion?
These are Jewish children.
In another part of Jerusalem,
we've seen Moslem children.
In Northern Ireland we have Catholic children
and Protestant children
all going to separate schools.
But what's so special about religion
that it is allowed
to label small children 'Catholic' or
'Protestant'; 'Jewish' or 'Moslem'?
Nobody would categorise children
by the political party their
parents support; call them 'Tory'
or 'Labour' children.
We agree they're too young
to know where they stand
on questions of politics.
So why is not the same for where
they stand on the cosmos,
and humanity's place in it?
In genetic evolution,
a species divides into two,
initially geographically. There's
some initial separation
between the two sub-species,
and they divide away from
each other genetically.
There's no longer gene
flow between them,
and so they can become separate species.
It's a divisive force.
Sectarian education acts in a similar way.
Children are initially isolated from each other
because of their parents' Faith.
Then their differences are
constantly drilled into them
and they embark on opposing life trajectories.
Such divisions are encouraged,
not just in faraway Israel
but right on our doorstep, in
Northern Ireland for instance
or in London.
In north London, the
Hasidic Jewish community
is the largest after
Israel and New York.
Here, religious division is taken to its extreme.
These ultra-orthodox Jews
only marry within their sect.
Television is frowned upon,
and of course
children attend exclusive
religious schools,
cloistered away from external influences
which just might persuade them
to look outside their community.
I want to find out why these children
are being segregated,
and whether their culture allows them
to open their minds to reality.
Hello?
- Hello.
- Rabbi Gluck. Nice to meet you.
- Richard Dawkins.
- I'm Richard Dawkins. How do you do?
Thanks for coming, nice to meet you.
Please come in.
Thank you very much.
Rabbi Gluck is London born and bred,
but you wouldn't
necessarily know it.
His accent is a testament to the
isolation of this religious sect.
Why should children be victims of the
particular tradition in which they
happen to have been born,
rather than choosing for themselves
by being shown all the
evidence that's available?
We are all to a certain extent
affected by our surroundings.
There's no such thing as a
person living in a vacuum.
No, indeed.
We're all affected by our parents, by our families
but at the same time we have a choice
to stay or otherwise.
I think it's important for
a minority to be able to have a space
where it can express itself; where it can
learn about itself.
Well couldn't you preserve the customs,
the traditions, the history
without somehow imposing upon the children
views about the universe which modern
science would say are simply false?
I would say impose upon a Jew anything,
I would say that's something
which is impossible,
I think it's scientifically impossible.
We believe that God created
the world in six days,
we know about evolution - every single
Jewish kid knows about evolution
and has thought about it and has studied it,
and has looked at it, and has
thought, "What's going on here?"
How many of the children who come up
through your system, your school system
end up believing in evolution?
I'd- I think that- that- that the- the majority
don't believe in evolution, they...
but at the same time it isn't they don't
believe because they don't know about it.
You realise they're being taught
that the entire world
began after what archaeologists would
recognise as the agricultural revolution?
I mean, these children are being brought up
in a very distorted world indeed,
and I worry about children being victims
of this kind of what I can only
describe as mis-education.
I find the terms 'distorted' and
'mis-education' rather disturbing.
Judaism has its tradition.
I think there are various er, scientists
who have their tradition.
This so-called 'the theory of evolution'-
Well it's called that, but that's
in a very technical sense.
But still, but still it's called that,
and it's not called the 'law' of evolution.
Well I will call it the 'fact' of evolution, and-
Then you're- you're a
fundamentalist believer in it.
No, no, I'm not a
fundamentalist believer.
The age of the earth: 5,000 years?
I mean that is-
I'm sorry, Rabbi, that is ridiculous!
Of course, Rabbi Gluck is
right that it's important
for us to learn about
our own background,
but what upsets me is
that in pursuit of that,
these innocent children are being
saddled with demonstrable falsehoods.
And this is not just a
problem of the Jewish minority.
There's pressure from
an increasing number
of Faith schools of other religions
to put scientific fact on a par
with primitive creation myths.
In science classes, why can't they
simply teach science?
- You said this is truth 'cos it's based on evidence.
- Well no, you don't exactly say that,
you say, "We're struggling
towards the truth," and
as new evidence comes in,
we refine it.
And in the middle of that, Jesus
says, "I am truth."
We live in the shadow of
a religiously inspired terror
in an era when science
has plainly shown
religious supersitions to be false.
And yet it's a strange anomaly that
Faith schools are increasing
in number and influence in
our education system,
with active encouragement from
Tony Blair's government.
There are already 7,000 Faith
schools in Britain,
but the government's Trust Reforms
are encouraging many more.
Over half the new City Academies
are expected to be sponsored
by religious organisations.
The most worrying development is
a new wave of private evangelical schools
that have adopted the American
Baptist A.C.E. curriculum:
'Accelerated Christian Education'.
Have you been to one of
these schools before?
- No, I never have.
- No. Okay.
Accelerated Christian Education slips
religious superstitions back into science.
If you want to be rude, you'd say
it's "programmed learning",
If you want to be polite,
it's "individualised instruction".
- Okay.
- So really, each one is teaching themselves.
To a certain extent, of course. That
has to be modified
with adult supervision and so on.
I had a look at the curriculum
booklet that you use for science,
and it was very noticeable that God or
Jesus did come on just about every page.
Yes, yes. We don't have anything like
religious instruction in the school
- because it is part of the-
- I can see you wouldn't need it.
No, of course not. Absolutely.
In one section of this thing, I
suddenly - I was sort of taken aback,
because I suddenly started reading
about Noah's Ark.
I mean, what's that got to do
with a science lesson?
Well I suppose that depends on your
opinion. It could have a lot.
If you believe in the story, it could
have a lot to do with science.
But I mean the stuff that I was taught
when I was a kid at school in science
now you would laught at
and say it was a myth,
- But that's what I was taught-
- But what were you taught?
When I was taught at- one of the
things that they told me at school
that I've always remembered was that the
moon came from the ocean here on earth.
and was flung into space, and
that's where it came from.
Well what you should have been taught,
I suppose, is that there is
a strong current theory that
that's what happened.
So what you're really
trying to ask me is,
"Do you think the Genesis story
was true, and that
God created the world in seven days?"
That's what you'd really like to ask me, right?
My answer to that is, "I don't know."
Having said that, do I think that if God
wanted to do it in seven days he could?
- Yeah, I think he could.
- He can do anything.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
So it's sort of an academic question,
which actually I don't care about
the answer very much really.
Does that make sense?
Kind of, yes. It does make sense.
It doesn't make sense to me
because I do care about the answer.
Why?
Because I care about what's true, and I-
- I care about what's true.
- Yes.
Well I find Christianity encompasses
everything about life.
Christianity is life, so it's about
everything. It touches
education, politics, care, social
services, everything.
Let me ask about another thing
in the booklet, which was
about AIDS and HIV. I think
somewhere it talks about
AIDS being the wages of sin.
Is that mixing health education
with moralistic preaching?
I suppose the flip side of that is that if
there is no God and there is no law-giver,
why does it matter what I do? Why is
rape wrong? Why is paedophilia wrong?
Why are any of these things wrong
if there is no law-giver?
You've just said a very revealing thing. Are
you telling me that the only reason
why you don't steal and rape and murder is
that you're frightened of God?
I think that all people, if they think they can
get away with something,
and it is- there is no consequences, we
actually tend to do that.
I think that is the reality. Look at the
world in which we live.
That is the reality.
- Okay, well I think better leave it at that.
- Okay.
Adrian Hawkes, I'm sure, is
a well-meaning man.
But why should he impose his personal
version of reality on children?
Not only are they encouraged to
consider  the weird claims of
the bible alongside scientific fact,
they are also being indoctrinated
into what an objective observer
might see as a warped morality.
Let me explain why, when it comes to children,
I think of religion as a dangerous virus.
It is a virus which is transmitted
partly through teachers and clergy
but also down the generations,
from parent to child to grandchild.
Children are especially vulnerable to
infection by the virus of religion.
A child is genetically pre-programmed
to accumulate knowledge
from figures of authority.
The child brain, for very good Darwinian
reasons, has to be set up
in such a way that it believes
what it's told by its elders,
because there just isn't time for
the child to experiment with warnings
like: "Don't go too near the cliff edge," or
"Don't swim in the river; there are crocodiles."
Any child who applied a scientific, sceptical,
questioning attitude to that would be dead.
No wonder the Jesuit said, "Give me the child for
his first seven years and I'll give you the man."
The child brain will automatically
believe what it's told, even if
what it's told is nonsense.
And then, when the child grows up,
it will tend to pass on
that same nonsense to its children.
And so religion goes on, from
generation to generation.
For many people, part of growing up
is killing off the virus of Faith
with a good strong dose
of rational thinking.
But if an individual doesn't
succeed in shaking it off,
his mind is stuck in a
permanent state of infancy,
and there is a real danger that he
will infect the next generation.
I'm going to meet someone who has
experienced religion as child abuse first-hand.
- Jill Mytton.
- Oh, hello.
- I'm Richard Dawkins, how do you do?
- Hello, Richard.
Jill Mytton was brought up in a
strict Christian sect.
Today she's a psychologist who
rehabilitates young adults
similarly scarred by their
narrow religious upbringing.
They need to be allowed to hear
different perspectives on things.
They need to be allowed to investigate.
They need to be allowed to
develop their critical faculties, so that they
can take a number of different viewpoints.
and weigh them up, and decide
which one is for them.
They need to find their own pathways; not to
be forced into a particular mould as a child.
If I think back to my childhood, it's one
that's kind of dominated by fear.
And it was a fear of disapproval while in the
present, but also of eternal damnation.
Do they get taught about hell
fire and things like that?
Absolutely. And to a child, images of hell
fire and gnashing of teeth
are actually very real; they're not
metaphorical at all.
- Of course not.
- No.
If you bring a child up and discourage
it from thinking freely and making
choices freely, then that's still- to me that is a
form of mental abuse or psychological abuse.
Or if you tell a child that when it dies
it's going to roast forever in hell.
In hell. That is abusive, yes.
What did they tell you about it?
I mean, what happens in hell?
It's strange, isn't it. After all this
time, it still has the power to
affect me when you asked me that question.
Hell is a fearful place. It's
complete rejection by God.
It's complete judgement.
There is real fire.
There is real torment; real torture,
and it goes on forever, so there
is no respite from it.
It's deeply disturbing to think that
there are believers out there
who actively use the idea of hell
for moral policing.
In the United States, Christian obsession
with sin has spawned a national craze
for 'hell houses' - morality
plays-cum-Halloween freak-shows,
in which the evangelical hobby-horses of
abortion and homosexuality
are literally demonised.
Pastor Keenan Roberts is rehearsing a new
production of his Colorado-based hell-house,
which he's written and staged for
almost fifteen years.
He fervently believes that you have
to scare people into being good.
The call upon my life as a pastor, as a
minister, is to tell people what the book says,
and what I, and we in our church,
and hundreds of churches
across this country and around the world
are doing is, we have found
a very creative, effective tool that is
getting people's attention
- to consider the message.
- I believe it. I believe it.
We want to leave an indelible impression
upon their life that sin destroys.
Every scene preaches the truth that
either sin destroys or Jesus saves.
If this is a rehearsal, think how
horrific the full production must be.
I presume you have a cut-off age for the tour,
I mean no children below an age of-
What is your cut-off age?
Well over the years of having
audiences and people go through this,
we have come to the decision that the best
age for young people is really at twelve.
Would it worry you if a child of twelve
coming to see your performance
had nightmares afterwards?
Or would you like that?
I would like them... I would like
for their life to be changed.
No matter what.
I would rather for them to understand
that hell is a place that they
absolutely do not wanna go. I would rather
reach them with that message at twelve,
than to not reach them with that
message, and have them live a life
of sin and to never find the lord Jesus Christ.
In the case of homosexual marriage,
what harm does that do?
Why would you be so
passionately against that?
They're living in sin.
That's your opinion. But it's nothing to
do with you, is it. It's their decision.
It's not my opinion. I'm
telling you what the bible says.
It's the bible's opinion. But these are two
people who want to live together.
Isn't it their own business? What
right have you to interfere?
I want them to know
homosexuality is sin.
But you believe it presumably on the
basis of scriptural authority.
- Absolutely.
- Yeah. Um...
- Unapologetically.
- Yes, unapologetically. But why are you
so sure that's right? I mean if you think
about where the scriptures come from,
I mean, who wrote them, and when?
What makes you so confident
they're right?
- It's what I believe.
- I know you believe it, but why?
It is a Faith issue with me.
Why do you not believe it?
Uh... because of evidence.
Hell House is the brash end of a much bigger
problem with the way religious belief works.
Taken to its extremes, as by
American evangelists, the bible
is scanned for passages to justify right-
wing views on abortion and 'family values'.
I'm about to meet a believer
who uses the word of God
to fight against centuries of human progress.
I think execution for adultery is not rejected.
Not rejected by who? By you?
- No. By the New Testament.
- What about you? Do you
favour execution in adultery?
I think that's fair to say; that that's
still a proper punishment that
the State ought to prosecute.
It's not so bad, surely,
to believe in moral codes
handed down to us from the good book.
Doesn't the bible give us a
moral framework in which to live?
Well no. The holy texts are of
dubious origin and veracity,
and they're internally contradictory.
And when we look closely,
we find a system of morals
which any civilised person today
should surely find poisonous.
The Old Testament is in every church and
synagogue throughout the world,
and is the root of Judaism,
Christianity and Islam.
If your brother, the son of your father
or of your mother, or your son or daughter,
or the spouse whom you embrace
tries to secretly seduce you,
saying, "Let us go and serve other gods"...
This is God's advice on what to do
to a friend or family member
who suggests you believe in another deity:
...you must kill him, your hand must strike
the first blow in putting him to death...
...and the hands of the rest of the people following.
You must stone him to death, since he
has tried to divert you from Yahweh your God...
The god of the Old Testament has got to be
the most unpleasant character in all fiction.
Jealous and proud of it. Petty. Vindictive.
Unjust. Unforgiving. Racist.
An ethnic cleanser, urging his
people on to acts of genocide.
If God doesn't set a good
moral example, who does?
Abraham, the founding father of
all three great monotheistic religions?
The man who would willingly make a
burnt offering of his son Isaac?
Maybe not.
How about Moses, he of the tablets
which said, "Thou shalt not kill"?
Well the same man, it says in the book of
Numbers, was incensed by the Israelites'
merciful retraint towards the
conquered Midianite people.
He gave orders to kill all male
prisoners and older women.
But all the women children, that have
not known a man by lying with him,
keep alive for yourselves.
How is this story of Moses
morally distinguishable
from Hitler's rape of Poland,
or Saddam Hussein's massacre
of the Kurds and the Marsh Arabs?
So let's leave Moses out of it.
But there are lesser characters facing
somewhat more everyday moral dilemmas.
Maybe they provide a better role model.
In the book of Judges, a priest was
traveling with his wife in Gibiah.
They spent the night in
the house of an old man.
But during supper,
a mob came to demand
that the host hand over his male guest.
"so that we may know him..."
Yes, in the biblical sense.
Well, the old man replied:
Nay, my brethren. Nay, I pray you.
Do not so wickedly.
Behold, here is my daughter a maiden,
and his concubine;
them I will bring out now, and humble ye them,
and do with them what seemeth good unto you;
but unto this man do not so vile a thing.
So enjoy yourselves by raping
and humiliating my daughter,
but show a proper respect for my
guest who is, after all, male.
Whatever else this
strange story might mean,
it surely tells us something
about the status of women
in this religious society.
Now of course, nice Christians will
be protesting, "Everyone knows the
the Old Testament is
deeply unpleasant."
The New Testament of Jesus, they claim,
undoes the damage and makes it alright.
Yes, there's no doubt that,
from a moral point of view,
Jesus is a huge improvement, because Jesus
- or whoever wrote his lines - was not content
to derive his ethics from the scriptures
with which he'd been brought up.
But then it all goes wrong.
The heart of New Testament theology
- invented after Jesus's death - is
St Paul's nasty sadomasochistic
doctrine of atonement for original sin.
The idea is that God had himself
incarnated as a man - Jesus -
in order that he should
be hideously tortured
and executed to redeem all our sins.
Not just the original sin of Adam
and Eve; future sins as well,
whether we decide to
commit them or not.
If God wanted to forgive our sins,
why not just forgive them?
Who's God trying to impress?
Presumably himself, since he's judge and
jury - as well as execution victim.
To cap it all, according to scientific
views of prehistory,
Adam - the supposed perpetrator of
the original sin -
never existed in the first place; an
awkward fact which undermines
the premise of Paul's whole
tortuously nasty theory.
Oh but of course the story of Adam and
Eve was only ever symbolic, wasn't it.
Symbolic?!
So Jesus had himself tortured
and executed for a symbolic sin
by a non-existent individual?
Nobody not brought up in the Faith
could reach any verdict
other than 'barking mad'.
The strange theology and questionable
texts wouldn't matter,
but for the unfortunate fact
that there are people out there
who really believe this stuff is
the word of God, and act on it;
challenging progressive values
- and the rule of law.
If you take the 'good book' to its
literal extreme - and some people do -
you can justify murder.
In 1994, the reverend Paul Hill
shot and killed Dr John Britton
outside his abortion clinic in Florida.
In 2003, Hill was executed for murder.
But he went to his death claiming his
actions were backed by holy scripture.
I'm going to meet the Paul Hill's friend
and defender, the reverend Michael Bray.
- Mr Bray?
- Yes, sir.
- Hello.
- I'm Richard Dawkins.
- It's good to meet you, sir. Michael Bray.
On what moral basis can he, as a Christian,
defend a self-professed, cold-blooded killer?
Your friend Paul Hill, who was convicted
of murdering a doctor,
he took the law into his
own hands, didn't he.
No.
Paul Hill, by his own testimony,
acted defensively,
not in retribution.
That's the job of the law.
- The job of the law is to punish.
- No.
The job of citizens is to - is indeed, out
of love - to protect one another.
Does it ever occur to you that that
doctor had a wife to grieve for him?
Paul Hill killed him!
Now the embryos that Paul
Hill was 'defending',
they were tiny little things without any
knowledge, without any memory,
without any fears, without all the things
that a full-grown adult doctor had.
Doesn't that give your conscience
a little bit of a twinge?
Well I don't think we measure the value
of someone by their cognizance of their
surroundings or their- or even of
their relationships.
The value that we give human beings
historically - and thankfully
from the scriptures - is that they are created
in God's image, and they are-
they have a certain sanctity
because of that.
So whether they be imbeciles or...
To most sensible people, Bray's
fellow clergyman Paul Hill
looks like a dangerous psychopath,
righting what he perceived as wrong
by committing another,
more terrible wrong.
Yet people like Hill and Bray
don't see the world that way.
They declare that their justification
is in the bible,
and by re-declaring the bible
as the absolute word of God
they give their actions validity.
Many of us who don't subscribe
to any particular holy book
worry about suffering. We actually
worry about whether the victim
of a murder, whether it's the murder
of a - in your terms - of
an embryo, or of an adult doctor.
I mean, can you not see
that there's a big imbalance there
between those two deaths.
Well I couldn't take into account
- because I'm not omniscient -
to know all the sufferings that
various people suffer.
Where do you think he is? Paul Hill.
Oh, I have high hopes that he's doing well.
-You think he's in heaven.
-Yes.
You think Jesus approves of
murdering doctors.
I think that, uh... he said that, uh...
he said that we're to love the children
just as we love others.
Suffer the little children
to come to me.
I reckon I have a fairly strong moral
conviction as well, but I'm not that confident.
I wouldn't like to
go and kill somebody
for the sake of my morality.
How can you be that confident?
I think, uh... my own confidence,
I guess, has come with time.
The more I- I think the scriptures- the more
I live, the more satisfied I am intellectually
that they interpret reality for me.
It was curious. I quite liked him.
I thought he was sincere.
I thought he wasn't
really an evil person.
And I was reminded of a quotation
by the famous American physicist
Stephen Weinberg - the Nobel prize-
winning theoretical physicist -
Weinberg said, "Religion is
an insult to human dignity.
Without it, you'd have good people
doing good things
and evil people doing evil things,
but for good people to do evil things,
it takes religion."
People like Michael Bray are a
big problem for Christian morality.
Not all Christians are as rooted
in the spoil of scripture,
but they do all take inspiration
from the same holy text.
But who is right?
The established Church of England
is being painfully torn apart
by these differences of
opinion over the scriptures.
The battleground is not so much abortion,
but homosexuality and gay clergy.
On one side are vociferous
scriptural purists;
on the other: more moderate believers
who interpret the bible selectively.
You're on the liberal wing
of the Anglican church.
Maybe the other side are the ones who
are being true to their scriptures
in a way that you're not. I mean you, who
are liberal and much closer to what
I would think, are the one who's departing
from the- certainly from the scriptural,
and perhaps from the fundamentals.
Um, well if you take the issue of
homosexuality there's no doubt about it,
there are a number of texts - not as many as
people think, but a few texts - which
clearly regard homosexuality as wrong, both
in the Old Testament very strongly,
but they're also there
in the New Testament. But of course it's
a question of how you interpret the bible;
whether it's really right to just
simply extract a few isolated texts
rather than seeing the whole message of
the bible; the whole message of Jesus.
But I think there's another, perhaps even
more fundamental one which links in
to your fundamental interest in evolution. Our
understanding of what it is to be a gay or
lesbian now is very very different from what
it was, let us say in the Roman world,
when the New Testament was written.
Therefore it's purely
a matter of choice.
We now actually know that a significant
percentage of people
are predominantly attracted
to members of their own sex.
So it's a question of the changing facts, as
well as a changing understanding of how
the bible should be interpreted.
This of course is all music to my ears,
but I'm kind of left wondering
why you stick with Christianity
at all therefore.
And maybe some of the fundamentalists
might say just that to you.
I think that moderates need to be passionate,
both about their religious beliefs, and
about rationality, and it's possible to be a
passionate moderate. It's much more difficult...
Some say that while religious fundamentalists
betray reason, moderate believers
betray reason and Faith equally.
The moderates' position seems
to me to be fence-sitting.
They half-believe in the bible. But how do
they decide which parts to believe literally
and which parts are just allegorical?
I take it that as an Anglican
bishop you wouldn't deny miracles,
and I think you ought to, to be consistent
with what you've just been saying.
I think if God was doing miracles the
whole time, then we would live in
an Alice in Wonderland-type world.
- Yeah.
- It would be unpredictable.
And you and I wouldn't be able
to have a rational conversation.
It's almost as though you think there's
a kind of 'ration' of miracles,
which mustn't be exceeded, or we
get into 'Looking Glass' territory.
We can't say what that 'ration' is. If
miracles were happening all the time,
whenever we wanted them to happen, then
human life as we know it couldn't exist.
And what about the sort of really
big miracles, like the virgin birth?
What do you think about that?
I don't think that it's on a par
with the resurrection, for example.
I mean, I actually do believe that the
resurrection of Jesus from the dead
is absolutely fundamental to Christianity,
in a way that I don't
believe the virgin birth is.
It seems to me an odd proposition
that we should adhere to some parts
of the bible story but not to others.
After all, when it comes to
important moral questions, by what
standards do we cherry-pick the bible?
Why bother with the bible at all, if we have
the ability to pick and choose from it
what is right and what is
wrong for today's society?
I suspect that religion is simply a parasite
on a much older moral sense.
I want to examine how science reveals
the true roots of human morality.
Morality stems not from some fictional
deity and his texts,
but from altruistic genes that have been
naturally selected in our evolutionary past.
Humans have much more sophisticated
versions of the kinds of social
instincts you see in chimps
and other creatures.
But really there's no great leap. It's just...
If you can think of chimps as MS-DOS,
and humans as Windows 2000.
Religious believers like to claim that
their god and ancient texts
provide them with an inside track to
defining what is good and what is bad.
But it is surely far more moral to do
good things for their own sake,
rather than as a way of sucking up to God.
Our true sense of right and wrong
has nothing to do with religion.
I believe there is kindness, charity and
generosity in human nature.
And I think there is a Darwinian
explanation for this.
Through much of our prehistory, humans lived
under conditions that favoured altruistic genes.
Gene survival depended on
nurturing our family
and on doing deals with our peers.
The 'I'll scratch your back if
you scratch mine' principle.
I don't think we need
religion to explain morality.
And if anything, it just gets in the way.
Morality is a lot older than religion.
Humans have an innate moral sense,
or a range of moral senses that
you could think of as
sophisticated versions of the
kind of social instincts you see
in chimps and other social species.
What sort of morality or proto-
morality would you expect
to find in a chimpanzee troupe?
We find that they live in family groups,
the mothers look after their kids,
they work in teams, and also
chimps are particularly good at
competing for status through
what's been called public service.
So they compete for status not
just through brute force, but
by being good leaders, by
intervening to settle disputes...
What are the main evolutionary reasons
for cooperating and being altruistic?
Working together often produces mutual
benefits for those that are involved, so
you can often just do better by working in a
team than you can by working by yourself.
Perhaps it is our genetic inheritance
that explains why those of us with
no allegiance to a holy book or a pope or
an ayatollah to tell us what is good
still manage to ground ourselves in a moral
consensus which is surprisingly widely agreed.
As social animals, we've worked out
that we wouldn't want to live in a society
where it was acceptable to rape,
murder or steal.
We have a moral conscience
and a mutual empathy,
and it is constantly evolving.
Religious or not, we have changed in unison,
and continue to change in our attitude
to what is right and what is wrong.
Fifty years ago, just about everybody
in Britain was somewhat racist.
Now only a few people are.
Fifty years ago, it was impossible for
gay people to walk along the street
hand in hand. Now it's easy.
Some of us lag behind the
advancing wave of moral standards,
and some of us are ahead.
But all of us in the 21st century are ahead
of our counterparts from the time of
Abraham, Mohammed or St Paul.
But progressive shift often emerges
in opposition to religion.
It's driven by improved education, and then
expressed by newspaper editorials,
television soap operas,
parliamentary speeches,
judicial rulings
and novels.
I guess my starting point would be: The
brain is responsible for consciousness,
and we could be reasonably sure that
when that brain ceases to be,
when it falls apart and decomposes,
that'll be the end of us.
From that, quite a lot of things
follow, I think especially morally.
We are the very priveleged owners of
a brief spark of consciousness,
and we therefore have to
take responsibility for it.
You cannot rely - as Christians or
Moslems do - on a world elsewhere;
a paradise to which one can work towards and
maybe make sacrifices - and crucially,
make sacrifices of other people.
We have a marvellous gift - and you see it
develop in children - this ability to
become aware that other people
have minds just like your own.
and feelings that are just as
important as your own.
And this gift of empathy seems to me to be
the building block of our moral system.
I profoundly agree with you, and I've
always felt that one of the things
that's wrong with religion is
that it teaches us to be satisfied
with answers which are
not really answers at all.
And if you have a sacred text that
tells you how the world began,
or what the relationship is
between this sky-god and you,
it does curtail your curiosity.
It cuts off a source of wonder.
The loveliness of the world
in its wondrousness is not apparent
to me in Islam or Christianity and
all the other major religions.
To an atheist like Ian McEwan,
there is no all-seeing, all-loving God
who keeps us free from harm.
But atheism is not a recipe for despair.
I think the opposite.
By disclaiming the idea of a next life, we
can take more excitement in this one.
The here and now is not
something to be endured
before eternal bliss or damnation.
The here and now is all we have; an
inspiration to make the most of it.
So atheism is life-affirming, in a
way religion can never be.
Look around you. Nature demands our
attention; begs us to explore; to question.
Religion can provide only facile,
ultimately unsatisfying answers.
Science, in constantly
seeking real explanations,
reveals the true majesty of our
world in all its complexity.
People sometimes say, "There must be more
than just this world; than just this life."
But how much more do you want?
We are going to die, and
that makes us the lucky ones.
Most people are never going to die
because they're never going to be born.
The number of people who
could be here in my place
outnumber the sand grains of Sahara.
If you think about all the different ways
in which our genes could be permuted,
you and I are quite grotesquely
lucky to be here.
The number of events that had to
happen in order for you to exist;
in order for me to exist.
We are priveleged to be alive,
and we should make the most
of our time on this world.