Russia, isolated from the world for years.
Now a free pass reveals secret places.
In southwestern Caucasus lies removed.
A compact region filled with a rich fauna.
Here live animals of all colors, shapes and sizes.
Snowy hills and dry deserts stand together,
each with their own vieþuitoare.
Sea border between Europe and Asia, Caucasus.
Russia spans 11 time zones and two continents
is a bridge between East and West.
With 140 million inhabitants,
Much of its territory is inhospitable or inaccessible.
Placed between the Black Sea and the Caspian is the Caucasus.
The size of California, has lots of climates and vieþuitoare.
Green hills and alpine meadows,
ºesuri small sand dune arid and make room for feral mountains.
The landscapes here rival those of any region on Earth.
In northern hills heights lives a species found only here.
Caucasian chamois.
A subspecies of those in Europe can run on terrain 50 km / h
And can jump two meters.
Supradimensionaþi lungs compensate for the thin air,
and their blood is adapted to high altitudes and cold.
But deforestation, poaching and fires threaten their existence.
The remaining copies can retire inaccessible regions,
at the height of 2,500 m, where few dare to venture.
They are not the only ones who face these mountains abrupþi.
Chamois share capped with ture.
On the slopes, Warm males during the mating season.
Turi males away from females living on cliffs and steep slopes.
The females live somewhat downhill.
Before the reunion, tighten measured forces to establish hierarchy.
The horns grow two or three rings per year and can reach 90 cm.
From their vegetarian food lacks essential minerals,
So that eating ground in places where the soil gives them what they need.
Soon they will descend in search of females.
Discovered coasts will have to roam the hills.
Females and kids prefer the lower slopes, wooded valleys next.
The danger spotted mountainside rout them.
It's a pair of brown Syrian Bears in search of food.
They coat the open and are most easily Bears that roam the Caucasus.
Hunting has decimated the population.
Even at high altitudes, they are threatened by poachers.
Caucasus Mountains belºug provides all of grassland and wood
plus the spectacular natural wonders.
Over 2,000 gheþari ºlefuiesc high valleys.
Mountains massive span 1500 kilometers, from northwest to southeast.
The highest peaks are 5,000 m, the mass of their time controlling the region.
Clouds dial in the west, above the Black Sea, are împinºi up.
These barrier issue over 4.5 m annual precipitation,
seven times more than in London.
A coast is dry and without vegetation, the other is wet and green.
Here grow more than 6,500 species of plants.
A quarter of them can not be found elsewhere in the world.
Bears do not miss any.
They spend more time in wooded areas and meadows coming out for food.
Their food is made up more of vegetation.
As you descend, the landscape becomes more forested.
When preparing for hibernation, bears may eat 40 kg per day.
The vast territory is divided for different types of Brown Bears.
But populations are threatened.
Hunting and cherestegii and they come here.
Currently, the region live less than 3000 Bears.
Humid forests of the northwest, which housed Bears and attract cherestegii,
They are full of pine, chestnut, oak and beech trees.
Under the canopy of greatness, in the sun, it's a battlefield.
Mistreþii, often hanging out, tighten settle disputes by fighting.
This time it comes to access to females.
Build and tanks, mistreþii can reach 350 kg.
The two pairs of corner ascuþiþi are some effective weapons.
Battles can keep tough 20 minutes but in the end there is a winner.
Elsewhere, a male enjoying the company of females.
And he already earned the right to mating.
Flocks can have over 30 boar,
one led by the matriarch, with piglets of different ages.
The strongest boar can pair with up to eight sows.
In trees, a green woodpecker chicks, asking for food.
Parents share the load tighten.
Carefully regurgitates food.
After being fed, the baby wants more.
Everywhere forests and wet meadows bloom,
Some plant species can be spotted and in the gardens of Europe.
But these are not Maral garden ornaments. They came to graze.
And they are in danger.
In the Georgian mountains are protect.
Russian across the border are easy prey for hunters.
But not all hunters carry firearms.
Eurasian lynx is the largest of lincºi.
30,000 copies caroling Russia, several than anywhere else.
It's one thing not to Maralal liniºtitor.
But now this young mother is not in the hunt.
Tighten lead pups six weeks in a first trip,
Whether you like it or not.
They have not left the den where they were born and are eager to explore.
It's normal calving two young mother and being able to grow without problems.
Now harm, but more than one year will be hunted desãvârºiþi.
Their table will be the image.
So far received only milk.
The mother will breastfeed three to four months and will gradually receive meat and hunting.
It grows alone, until they leave at the age of one year.
Râºii males play no role in raising chickens.
Tufts of fur captures any sound to their ears fine.
Le smeared camouflage
and 11 weeks, the cats will be difficult to detect.
Puppies play, and the mother's careful hazards or table at the break.
Râºii hunt at dawn and sunset,
but the need for milk makes hunting day to eat more.
Râºilor hearing is phenomenal. Can detect the movements of 65 m,
their vision sharp and can spot a mouse, 75 m.
They can easily bring down big deer, but prefer smaller prey.
With so many eyes and ears atâþia waking attack is difficult.
Puppies and deer are targets better if you can get close enough.
But not today.
No matter, the place offers enough opportunities for it and chicken
Even though the area is gradually transforming from deforestation and agriculture.
Caucasus has only 440,000 square kilometers, but is full of contrasts.
Just 400 km north-east, the landscape becomes smooth.
This is the Caspian Depression.
Russia's minimum height is 30 m below sea level.
In these vast meadows where only 30 cm of precipitation falls annually,
pools of water are vital.
In nesfârºita high grass, lives an animal puppet with a face.
Saiga antelope.
Oversized nose filters dust dry plains
And heats the cold air when the temperature drops.
Once counting million, now there are only 18,000.
The collapse of the USSR left them unprotected in the face of poachers.
Chinese medicine uses them today and horns to treat fever.
Studies have shown that, if protected,
antelope population may increase by 60% in one year.
Aºadar, someday, huge flocks could reoccur.
While cleans after antelope dung beetles,
Spring steppe turns into a sea of ​​pink flowers.
A nuns moving to a new place of hunting.
Perfect camouflage, waiting for insects attracted to the flowers.
Grass rãtãceºte another inhabitant of the Caucasus.
Long-eared hedgehog the size of a hamster higher.
He watched carefully by a ºopârlã agama.
This piece of land is the background of the life and death struggle.
A grasshopper gives everything he can, but does not have any chance.
Finally, just will stay on his feet.
His remaining leg is amputated, becoming an easy prey for someone else.
Chitin beetle wrapper saves him,
while ºopârla collect debris.
Another Hedgehog pursues prey, guided by his ears fine.
A Centipede, armed with two veninoºi corner, care must be attacked.
Despite the onslaught of the insect, the little warrior retains lunch.
Turning our south, land is barren and dry and more.
There are lakes with salt, not snow
And tall grasses that hide you.
With only 90 cm height and weighing just 2 kg
Crane has the lowest small size of the family.
They mate for life and chicken to be fast to keep up.
Meanwhile, the father înhaþã a delicious snack.
Headed for the water source, represented by a salt lake.
No chance for a cool dip.
With temperatures above 40 ° C, the water evaporates, leaving behind salt.
It's a dry, hot and inhospitable.
Under a harsh sun, salt parents looking crustaceans.
Let tighten hot chicks on shore, enduring heat înãbuºitoare.
In this compact region, the landscape can change suddenly.
Just 50 km south,
Caspian Depression disappears and is replaced by a new landscape.
North-Caucasian steppes.
On the green hills, sheep and goats bring shepherds to graze.
The strong sun plants grow even in this dry area.
Here broaºtele þestoase out and enjoy the warmth and flowers.
And after winter hibernation, and must regain his strength.
In April and May males tighten resistance increase, for the mating season.
Courtship happens in stages.
First tracking.
Then blow convincing.
Usually followed by a surprisingly fast tracking.
And some blows stronger.
Eventually, the male courtship ends and earn their right.
A mating can fertilize more eggs,
which will be submitted at a time, three to fourth.
But female seems to be impressive offering.
La o aruncãturã de bãþ,
e o priveliºte superbã.
A miniature desert, an oasis.
Near mountains înzãpeziþi area of ​​30 square kilometers of dunes
It has its own climate and desert fauna.
Sarykum called "golden sands"
Desert was formed by centuries of erosion neighboring mountains.
A pair of ºopârle agama face off.
These energetic reptiles are not afraid of fighting,
even against ºerpilor.
But today taken a different tack.
Habitat strange old adãposteºte knowledge,
As long eared hedgehog's.
HUNT night and day in the cool hours.
Their long ears helps to thermoregulation.
They are more and more iuþi ºireþi than those in Europe
And can travel up to 9 km in the road for food.
The best defense is to stay under the ground or have a hard shell.
Prevesteºte grass struggles danger.
It is time for birds to keep it as best I can.
And for those who have the opportunity to hide.
In summer, sandstorms blowing with winds over 100 km / h.
The flocks caught at the open do not have shelters.
Other animals put them underground.
The storm's arrival as suddenly as they end.
Life resumes.
But it's a wind that some harms.
Together, the rocks, eagles build nests pleºuvi tighten measures.
They can live 40 years and often mate for life.
Females rarely leave their chicks, so that males should be without corpses.
Adult eagles can soar seven hours. And hunt using sight, smell.
I can eat 5 kilograms of meat at one meal.
On the edge of the dune, a steppe eagle found a dead goat in the storm.
Eagle is strong, but opening carcass may last.
Starve will arrive a few days whether it will keep to herself.
Already arriving coþofene that put patience to the test.
But there are so courageous. Eagles gathered chase them.
Whether he likes it or not, the first eagle feast will not single.
Eagles glimpse shake,
but with weak beaks, you have to wait opening carcass.
If too much flies, eagles shall eat it all.
With an empty stomach, male eagle glides towards his family.
The puppy, eager for food, will stay hungry today.
The female can not give food, but at least they can provide shade.
If you survive, barely four months will fly like his parents.
For thousands of years, shepherds have crossed this region, called Dagestan.
Not only that pass by.
A community-installed colorful and reside summer.
Bee eaters, birds þipãtoare African
And dug holes 1.5m nests in sandy slopes.
They came looking pair and thickets roar of chirps.
Social birds, make their large colonies, but males do not tolerate competition.
I can eat more than 200 bee or wasp day.
The first time hit to kill,
then shake to get rid of the poison.
Well crushing an insect's a nice gift for female.
When they reached the gifts will lean, signaling he's ready.
After mating can result ten eggs, submitted at the end of the nest.
The whole community increases young, very unusual.
The distant hills are furiºeazã a strange animal.
ªopârla without feet long by one meter, not a snake.
This may break tighten the tail when it is threatened.
It makes bucãþele as glass, bedazzle enemies.
Eyelids and ears ºopârlã reveal his identity.
ªerpii not have. It has the features of a ºopârle, except degenerate feet.
Another ciudãþenie is that some lay eggs, others give birth to live young.
To the east of this varied landscape is home to the largest inland sea in the world.
Caspian Sea.
With an area of ​​422,000 square kilometers, it is larger than Germany.
Along its western banks is found another surprise.
Here, Earth clocoteºte and boil.
Over 400 Bãlþi muddy beats on methane.
Occur along a tectonic plate where the heat comes out of the Earth's crust.
Mind volcanoes forms noroioºi let sunshine strengthened.
In other parts, stufãriºul discreet hide jungle cats.
Despite the name, jungle cats prefer wet areas.
In Russia, it is believed that only 500 still alive.
This caught the eye of quail.
But one fly, and the other into the water,
cats must seek another specialty dining.
There are many other options.
Millions of birds pass through the Caucasus pausing migrations.
800 km away in the mountains of western împãduriþi,
animals are preparing for the fall.
Mistreþii s-au îngrãºat.
Herd multiplied by a new generation.
With only a few weeks already piglets energy
that will turn into some aggressive adult boar.
Each sow gave birth to 12 piglets dungaþi,
but many will not catch maturity becoming prey animal feed.
The piglets will be breast-feeding up to four months
but will not leave until the next mating.
Sows tighten recognize piglets after guiþ,
But if a mother pig and finds not, it will suck from other sows.
When piglets resting, sitting next to each other to keep warm.
There were still quite thick fur.
Elsewhere in the mountains, another family has different activities.
Two days ago, my mother laughed killed a deer and fed to chickens.
Holt has already provided some meals
and now it is again brought out of hiding for another lunch.
There will be complaints from starving chickens.
In five months of age, apprentice hunters rarely receive milk.
For several months, tighten mother watching in action,
studying them fast attack tactics and feeding on prey.
A mature laughter gobble 2.5kg of meat at a meal,
So this chamois will reach a time.
The chicks will stay with the mother until spring,
Then, one year, will go in search of their own territories.
When you are tired, mother covering the carcass until the next meal.
Cover leftovers with great attention,
Althea to prevent inhabitants of the forest to steal his book.
At the foot of the Caucasus mountains of natural rezervaþia,
slowly traverses a huge green slopes.
A male bison.
The old man weighs nearly a tonne solitary animal.
In the past, there were many bison Caucasus Mountains Caucasian
o subspecie a zimbrului european.
The last wild specimen was killed in 1927.
Zimbrii zoo were multiply and release in nature.
This small population represents some of their descendants.
Few have the chance to see these shy and rare animals.
Their finding may take days to follow.
Today, about 500 roam these hills.
Family threatened by multiplying the population is unstable
And despite protection, attracts poachers.
Fortunately, some instinct of reproduction.
Rolling in urine, tighten applying perfume.
Once he entered the fur should be irresistible.
Maybe I should be hung from a replica.
But not all the Caucasus mountains are inviting places to live.
Zimþate peaks of mountains are as hostile as the moon.
Even plants can barely survive,
So it's hard to believe that an animal lives here.
And yet I do.
With singuranþã that defies gravity
ibex mountain goats are masters of these rocks.
Nu has to cãzãturi.
It's mating season.
Males live in groups of four or five
but now everyone is on their own.
When induce, use their long horns in heavy fighting.
Find herds of up to 50 females.
If you find any, try to isolate it with extravagant movements.
Try Hail, rub heads and feet, and raises.
But if does not move quickly, competitors take advantage of opportunities.
Suddenly, the race is open to all.
Finally, a lucky male obtains its right.
Multiplying is the only time when males and females meet.
Silverback will mate with several females.
This game with high stakes keep more than one month
over some mountains with altitudes of 4,200 m.
Five months later, the next generation will be born goats
Cath cliffs capable from day one.
On the highest peaks, there are no signs of life.
Snows stretch as far as the eye can see and often have 7 m thick.
Quiet is broken only by the sound of the wind and avalanºelor.
In the Caucasus mountains abrupþii most avalanches occur in Russia.
LOWER speeds of up to 250 km / h.
It represents a major threat to all vietãþile mountains.
Summary Russia's Caucasus region,
stretched, unknown, wild.
And mysterious.
Secrets and surprises are piled in a limited space.
Sea border between Europe and Asia,
this is Caucasus.