Get up
Let's go.
Who's that?
Don't you ever come out again...
Fighting with your wife again?
I didn't come home last night
You're out of line
I know
But my girlfriend threatened to kill herself
Unless I stayed with her
You shouldn't be having a girlfriend because you're married!
Italians can't live without love
All you Chinese know is work
We're very selective about love
We've got to go to work
I can't go out. She'd kill me
Move over and let us out
She'd kill you too
We'll go down from the balcony
Aren't you afraid of the Spaniard below?
No. I'll go first
I'm going down
What's going on with you?
Don't you Chinese use the stairs?
The Italians are fighting in the stairway
Come on
You signaled me to jump
I signaled you not to
You should have shouted
I was going to...
What?
But you jumped before I could yell
Which is the way to Via Layetana?
Via Layetana?
Where's Via Layetana?
Why do you ask?
Straight on from here and first on your left
When you get to C. Mallorca then...
Then what?
You're lost
You've just missed C. Bilbao
What should I do then?
Turn left at C. Bilbao where you'll see a fountain
Make sure you know whether it works or not
If it works?
Then Via Layetana is right ahead of you
What if it doesn't?
That means the City Council has closed the street for repairs
Then you'll have to find another way through
I now understand. Thank you
Hi...
I'm terribly sorry
I really didn't mean it, officer
Let me help you, officer
I'm sorry.
We apologize, officer
Don't let me catch you washing your car here again
Move on. Do you here me?
We won't do it again
Good morning, sir
Have you been chimney sweeping?
No
Then why the blacken face?
Damn Chinese!
Private detective Matt
Hold it!
Boss?
What are you doing?
Just exercising
Why didn't you have the light fixed?
Power's been cut off
My account's only 3 days overdue
And they cut the supply off
You haven't paid me for 3 months
I've kept you employed though
If I had let you go
You couldn't have found another job
Without a job, bye bye to Spain
But I could have paid the electricity bill for you
Now you're talking like a good employee
Anybody looking for me?
The phone company sent 2 guys here
They couldn't have come to hire me
They came to take the phone away
No wonder it's so quiet here
Alfonso also came here to see you
Alone?
No, with two muscle types
What did he want?
He said you owed him 10,000 Pesetas
That's a coded message
It means he's got a new lead
He also asked when you’d be back
Next time he comes, tell him I'm out of town
That's another coded message
You can tell him yourself
Why?
He said he'd back at noon.
Which is about now
What? Why didn't you tell me sooner?
What's the big deal? Another coded message?
It means my life's in danger
I have to find a place to hide
You're now the acting chairman of this agency
You're in charge
That means a promotion.
And a raise?
Don't kid yourself
Acting chairman's still a chairman
I'd better put a tie on
Please have a seat...
Before you tell me why you're here
Let me tell you my principle
I don't kill, I don't lie, I don't cheat
because I have no guts
Now, you can tell me how can I help you
How about find a person for me
Find a person? I won't...
What? You won't find person?
I won't disappoint you.
You are...
Chinese, a real Chinese
Then I don't want to waste time
I'm now appoint you
to find a woman Gloria and her kid
A boy, a girl?
No, only one
Boy or girl then?
You have to find it out
This is Gloria's information
and a picture
but it was 22 years ago
It's really not that easy
I won't pay you if it's a easy job
If you take this case
I still have 2 conditions you've to follow
I got a condition, too. You tell me first
Firstly, you must be low profile
Secondly, you must finish the job
in 14 days
This is the deposit
After the job's done
You'll be entitled with 20,000 US dollars
Now, tell me what's your condition
Mine one is I accept all your conditions
Great! Whenever you got any news
call me on this number
Want to test me?
What are you doing?
My antiseptic is better than yours
I'm awaiting your good news
Let's got started
Go take orders
A coke please
What would you like?
Coffee, with milk.
Coming right away
Anything to eat?
No
What would you like?
One 22, and one 16.
Coming right away
You want something to drink?
A coke.
A coke
These are the orders.
Okay
A salad, 2 hot dogs
Fried rice
A double, that's fit
Here
There you go.
Thank you
What's going on?
How dull!
Let's go
You're ruining my business
Can you go somewhere else?
What's your problem?
You're ruining my business
Do your business elsewhere
Well?
Let's race one round this square
The loser picks up the tab for today
Sure
I'll be the referee
Ready, go!
Faster
Get away
Faster, we're counting on you
Where are the customers?
Scared away by the Hell's Angels
I'll take to them
I've done that already, no use
Pack up and drive off
Why?
We'll play Robin Hood
Faster
My mother told me I shouldn't fight
Did she tell you not to come here?
Yes, but I forgot all about it
I won't fight you. I'm leaving
Get back to work
Good morning.
Show me your pass
Thank you
Bye
When will your father out?
Mental illness is tough to handle
God knows when he's be out
Damn, a flat tire
That's no big deal
What said it's a big deal?
You sure sounded like it's one
How should I have reacted then?
"Ha! Ha! A flat tire!"
No normal person would have reacted that way
Ha! Ha! A flat tire!
You're right. Only nuts would say that
Change the tires
Have you got a magnet?
No, but what for?
I can tie a string around it
What the hell are you talking about?
I can then lower it into the gutter
Are you sober?
Yes
Why would you lower a magnet into the gutter?
I have to salvage the nuts
What nuts?
Those nuts?
You're quite smart
We really need a magnet
I told you
We're stuck
I've seldom seen people so dumb
And you're not?
At least I know how to solve the problem
Enlighten us
Take one nut off each of the other tires
Then you got three
That'd hold the tire temporarily
I agree
You're a smart guy. Why are you here?
I'm here because I'm psychologically unbalanced
Not because I'm dumb
Those are 2 different issues
You're really dumb
I'd better not waste my time with you guys
I'll find another beach
Let's change tires
What does he doing?
How do I know?
Let's go and ask
No...
Come on
Hey pal, what're you doing?
I'm a clock. I'm counting time.
So what's the time?
Two-thirty
Wait a minute. It's two forty-five
Oops...
What's your Dad doing?
Fishing
Dad, we've come to see you
Speak softer. You scared my fish
Are you bored, uncle?
The whole world's boring
Found a girlfriend for David yet?
There aren't that many Chinese girls in Spain
Who said it had to be a Chinese?
Love transcends nationality
He's changed
I'm really worried
What's that guy doing?
Telling himself a joke
Isn't that funny?
What's wrong this time?
He's heard that joke before
Fishing?
Catch one for me
I didn't know you're a nut too
How can one fishing from a bucket?
Your father seems getting better now
It rings
It's time for the date.
I don't mind if you come with me
I wonder who his date is
Beats me
That's why "love transcends nationality"
No wonder he's getting better
Where's your Mum?
She's making herself up.
She sent me here so you won't be impatient
Tell her to take her time
I'll wait here very patiently
I know what you're thinking
I know what you're guessing
But I'm not thinking about that
I'm not guessing
I know, because I'm think about that myself
We're on the same wavelength then
Which means we should both forget about it
So pretty
She belongs to my Dad
Okay...
We'll be on our way
See you next week
Don't go. You have to meet my date
Some other time
There
Gloria Darling
You look terrific
I miss you so
I know what you're thinking
Likewise here
We're thinking about the same thing
Make a move then
I've got to run.
Goodbye
Tell your Dad we're leaving
Dad, we've got to go.
That's right
Wait, I want you to meet Gloria
That's my son David
and his friend Thomas
How do you do?
Go and leave us alone
Come on
She's waiting for a cab
What an opportunity!
Tell her we'll give her a ride
Cabs are too expensive
What if she likes taking cabs?
Don't be silly
You go talk to her
I'll drive the van here
I'm giving you a break
You go talk to her
Hello
Your cab
Bye
She turned you down?
I didn't offer anything
You're so useless
The result would have been the same
Of course not
You had zero chance because you didn't ask
You had a 50% chance if you did though
Elegant, nice
She may be a princess
A princess with a crazy mother?
Why not?
Maybe. Get in
2,000 Pesetas? Not enough!
Don't be nasty. Let's make a deal
How about 4,000?
Okay
Thomas, 2 coffees please
Order afterwards
You won't take that long
Get them to settle their accounts tonight
How much do I owe you?
1,250 Pesetas
Here's 1,300.
Keep the change.
Thanks you
Can I have a free spring roll?
That spring roll cost 70 Pesetas
Are you new here?
What's your price?
How about 3,000?
Save that for pension
Get away
Hello
Princess wouldn't come to a place like this
You can go and take a look yourself
15,000 Pesetas
That's US$100, very reasonable.
Let's go
She went with him
So? She's not your girlfriend
What's your problem?
You've treated me too many free spring rolls
Let me give you a good time tonight
Thank you, but we can't
I didn't know she'd be a hooker
At least she's an expensive one
She may need money
How much cash do you have?
Why?
Come on
20,000 and change
Too much for a good time
What?
I'm giving it to her
So she's got a night off. What about tomorrow?
There are so many hookers here
Everyone has her own problem
Can we help them all?
We can't even afford one free spring roll each
Let's work
You stole my wallet
Don't you dare running away
Did you see a girl running through?
What does she look like?
Dressed in red. Tall and with long hair
One should be careful with one's wallet
What's wrong?
I think I've got a fever
What do you want to do?
I want to go home
Take this last order then
Thomas, did you see a tall and skinny girl?
Like this?
Yes
There are many over there
Be serious.
No
Let's search
So Princess is a hooker
and a pickpocket
Maybe that guy lost his wallet elsewhere
One shouldn't condemn people on rumors
We've arrived home
You think I don't know?
I wasn't talking to you
No wonder you said you're not feeling well
Calm down, don't be mad at me
Let's all get off first
This is the end of your ride
I want to be with you
Come visit our apartment
You want me to tell her she's not welcome?
No, I grabbed the wrong hand
Our home is over there
It'll be our pleasure
Thanks
Mr. Lover's home tonight
Have you seen fatso around?
Not for a while
Someone close and dear just passed away?
No, why?
You look as if you’re dressed for a funeral
Hey, long time no see
It's you! Come and have a drink with us
Come... I can't get drunk today
Have you see fatso around?
Just got here myself. What's the big deal?
How do you know about our "big deal"?
I'm now the deputy chief of Matt's agency
But don't tell anybody about this
What sort of person do you think I am?
Drink this or else
I can't get drunk today.
I really can't
Moby, it's been a long time. Have a drink
Only a drink.
Fine, just one drink
Come, sit I'll have another as well
Have you seen fatso?
No, what do you want him for?
Can I trust you guys?
But we've known each other for years
Keep your secrets to yourself
I don't care much to keep your secrets for you
Okay, listen good
Swear you won't tell anybody about this
I'm now...
the deputy chief of Matt's agency
I want to talk to fatso about something important
That calls for a celebration drink
Thanks...
Cheers...
Moby's been promoted!
I really can't get drunk today
I'll have to find fatso
Many congratulations, Moby
Cheers...
Keep my little secret to yourselves
Goodbye
See you
Darling, this is Moby
Can I have a little kiss?
How can I ever forget you?
I've been very busy
I swear to God that was the truth
Okay, that's alright
Just look at her friend! What a pig!
I really can't do it tonight
Alright, can I have another kiss?
Am I speaking loud enough
Just a minute.
It's your wife!
I'll kill you for fooling around
Come out. Let me shoot you
Susanna, calm down
Dino's got lipstick on his underpants
I'm innocent
Those are lady's panties
Not mine
Why are you wearing them?
I was in a hurry
I'll kill him
Susanna, this is our door
Let me go in
Don't point your rifle at our door
Let go
Let go of me
You're mad because you don't want to lose him
So you don't really want him dead
That might have been a one night affair
But you're his wife. He loves you
Though he's no good
it doesn't mean you can have another one better than him
In fact, I love him too
Do you remember the first time we meet?
Love at first sight.
Really?
You're my whole life
I can't live without you Dino
You bastard
I got to kill you. Don't run away!
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have barged in
Don't stay too long though
I'm not leaving tonight
What?
You've any objections?
No, as long as she's not afraid
Afraid of you guys?
What would we do?
Sleepwalking
Fatso?
Fatso. What happened?
Were you robbed?
You're too heavy
What happened?
It's none of my business anyway
I need some information from you
You've to be honest to me
You were Mr. Pimp on Hookers Street 18 years ago
Did you know any Gloria then?
She might had been pregnant
or just got a baby then
What?
They were asking for Gloria just now?
Did you tell them?
Didn't...
That's better
If I didn't tell... I'd have been killed
It means you know where Gloria is
No... yes...
Buddy
Could you try not to be stammered
Where did Gloria use to live?
62 Thanksgiving Street
Aren't you mind she might...
We can hide our money
If she really try to do that
and can't find the money anywhere
Then she'll know we've taken precautions
And her pride will be hurt
Let's just leave little money in our wallets
Even if she did steal it The price we pay for
to know a person won't be too high
and it worthwhile
I didn't know you could be that smart
You gave her the shirt?
Yes
It looks better on her
What are you talking about me?
Beauty
I heard you said more than one word
You're gorgeous
Where am I going to sleep? Have you decided yet?
In... Living room
Thanks. My name's Sylvia
I'm David.
I'm Thomas
Good night
I don't want to sleep yet. You go to bed if you feel sleepy
I want to watch TV
Let me turn the set on for you.
Thank you
Good night
You'll sleep much better with this pillow
Thank you
Can I get you a glass of water?
Please
It's cold in the night
I'll get you a blanket
Thank you
My pleasure
Water has no taste. I'll get you a cup of milk
It's true
Here you are. Thank you
Let's not wasting time
Who wants to sleep with me first?
Makes no difference to me
Forget it
Good morning
Did you calm Susanna down?
Of course. She loves me.
That's good
Have you seen my car?
No
Susanna, my car was stolen
I'm going to report it to the cops
Princess left so early
Don’t be biased against people
I'm just being prudent
Have some faith in mankind
My money's gone
See, I told you
I knew she's steal our money
Hiding your money in the drawer was dumb
I put mine in one of my shoes
Damn, she stole my money too
That's only fair
You shouldn't have let her stay over night
Did you try to stop me?
She's quite good at stealing
She left us some money though
I sure hope I run into her
Likewise here
What would you do?
See if she needs more
Do you know how to drive?
Do you have a license?
I'm terribly sorry.
I'll pay for the damages
That goes without saying
You've ruined my beautiful car
Please forgive me
Fortunately I'm a super-nice guy
It's dangerous to drive like that
My brother says I'm a reckless driver
I think he's quite right
This Dino Martini is my brother's car
You call him up.
He'll get your car fixed
But...
I've got to go to work
Call me. Let's have lunch
Sure
Thanks
Back up
Bye. Take care
Bye
Who's that?
What do you want?
To take you to a place
The police station?
You're not cops
And I don't know you
Where're you taking me to?
A place of wealth and comfort
What if I won't come along?
We'll be very rude then
Let me go. Help...
Help
Come on, get the broad
Let's split up
That's them
You are not bad
When will you be able to deliver
Wait, I got to ask you
You don't trust me or something?
You hire me
and you hire another gang to find the girl
What gang?
I should have asked that question
They were quite nasty too
I didn't hire another gang
Then why...
Stay out of that issue
Just don't let them capture Sylvia
Either you tell me who they are
So that I know what I'm up against
Or I quit
Stay there
I'm sorry for all your sufferings
But I can't be of help
I can only increase your expense money
You need time to think it over?
Three seconds
1, 2, 3. I'll carry on
Good. May God bless you
Thanks
Why would Moby want to meet us here?
He must be up to something again
We'd better say no to whatever he asks
Sit
Can't say no to that.
True
Something to drink?
3 beers, one bottle of brandy
How's business lately?
Worse than before
Did my friend do a good job on your van?
No, it's worse than before
How's David's father?
Worse than before
He can't get any worse
No
He's much better now
That's terrific. Here's the beers
To David's father
No
You can't say no to that. Cheers...
Our trick's not working
Let's play "mismatched answers"
I need a favor from you guys
I bumped into a girl's car this morning
No wonder Susanna's dog gave birth to 4 puppies
What does that have to do with my accident?
Why should we know about your accident?
Just let me finish it
After I had bumped into the girl's car
She gave me a card
Said that's her brother's car
Still nothing to do with us
When I contacted the guy
he said he had no sister
And claimed his car was stolen
When I described the girl to him
He said she might have been your girlfriend
Still none of our concern
True
But she gave me some money
and asked me to give to you
She's returning the money to us
Not returning, just giving
Giving? She stole that money from us
So you were her victims too
Still none of our concern?
Just give us our money
She hasn't given it to me yet
I'm going to dance a little
So am I
Tell me where does she hang around?
Her home
What place does she go everyday?
The lady's room
Come on, tell me the truth
The truth's I don't know
Be that way
Come on, tell me
You were quite rude just now
Forgive me then. Tell me please
We really don't know
Be that way
I thought you're friends
Fellow Chinese
All I'm asking is a small favor
And you don't even want to know
Of course you can hear me
What?
Spaniards are bad, but they are better than you
I can't hear you
Speak louder
Spaniards are bad...
Sorry, I'm way out of line
Is that what you want?
I wonder who Sylvia is?
A Spaniard
Bullshit
I mean why is she wanted
Because she's gorgeous
Stupid
She's not stupid. She's bright
You are though
Sylvia
David
Long time no see
Not really
They're forcing me against my will
Be nice to the lady
You kicked me?
What's up?
Ask them
A girl picked my wallet
These two are her accomplices
Don't run
She fooled us again
We can't trust her
You'd better remember that
I've never trusted her anyway
She got us into such complications
No need to over-react.
It's you!
Why are you here?
I came to thank you
for saving me from ending up in jail
If we knew why they were after you
We wouldn't have helped you
Tell her to stay
Weren't you saying...
Don't let her go
Don't go away
We want to ask you something
Come up and sit for a while
I'd like that very much
You want to ask her something
I think you should ask her
Me?
Go
What... would you like to drink?
Wine
I'll get that
Do it
You slept here last night
This morning we found that...
Everything was tidied up
But our money's gone
And so were you
Take a break. I'll ask her
David would really want to know
Did you steal our money?
Yes
And those men's too
Don't be so rude
You do the asking
You're so pretty, you can...
What he mean is
You can do well just being a hooker
I hate being called a hooker
I don't sell my body
I don't sleep with anyone for money
I'm just his interpreter
You should have slapped him
Stealing's still a vice
My mother's been put away since I was 14
I've been supporting myself since then
Nobody would give me any opportunity
All the men I met
No matter how good they treated me
They just wanted my body
That's what he wanted too
I stole their money
I see nothing wrong in that
Beware of pretty girls from now on
I warned you not to get involved
You two are different
I know you're real nice to me
I'll pay you back as soon as I can
No real hurry. I just want to now the truth
Pay him first when you've got the money
He needs that for his wedding
Nonsense. I was only saving for emergencies
You'd better pay me then
Let's don't argue about this
Just make sure the money's legal
Thomas mentioned to me
You mum and my Dad are very close
We can’t just let you carry on stealing
Right
He's afraid of you might like stealing though
Nobody'd like to be a criminal
Unless he had no other choices
And if you did have other choices?
I'd start all over again
It's great
David, didn't you say we're understaffed?
No, I didn't
Oh, yes, but...
You may not last
I'd like to have a shot at it
You're on probation for 3 month, a raise is given
Pedestrians pacing
Yet I'm rushing
Passion is filling my heart
Whenever I'm depressed
I fall
I believe I could stand up again
Although It's painstaking
I'll still be smiling
All because of faith
I try my best and
I'm getting closer to my dream
With faith. I'm free to pursue my dream
With you be with me, I'll be even stronger
I'm here to find myself
Happiness, I'm coming for you
How are you...
I need to talk to you
Come with me
What do you want?
Listen to me first
I'm not after my wallet
I want you to meet someone
You'll benefit tremendously from the meeting
Would you come?
Help!
Don't yell
I mean no harm
I'm a private detective
Just come with me to see this man
And I'll owe you one, okay?
Trust me
Don't get rough
And I'll let go, okay?
I grew up on the streets
You can’t just con me like that
Don't waste your time
Where's he?
Over there
Miss
Don't come over. I'll throw it to you
Thank you
Let me tip you off
Sylvia's in great danger
Trust me or you'll regret it
I'm borrowing your stool
Over there. There
What should we do now?
Pack up for the day
Stay there
Let me go
Set me free
Let her go.
Don't come near
Come on
Get in
After them
That's my car. Stop...
Floor it. They're closing in
I can't stand this.
Come and sit here
Like hell I will.
Go sit in the back seat
Back off... hurry
You must be out of your mind
Luckily I've got a great car
Otherwise I'd have been dead
Slow down. Be careful next time
It's a dead end
Up the ramp
Hang on
You're great
They aren't behind us anymore
I know. But they're in front of us
Let's see who has more guts
Excuse me
Time to use my weapons
Ready, aim, fire
I'll have some fun too
Some oil for you
This will enhance your ride
How about a ramp
How are we doing?
The enemies are all wiped out
You guys can't even grab a girl
There can only be one explanation
You guys are useless
You've wasted 6 out of my 14 days
God created the world in 6 days
8 days should be more than enough to grab a girl
I am whether able to inherit the Count's legacy
It's all counting on you two
Who do you...
You first
Who are those people?
Your turn
You told my mind
They tried to grab me before.
True
Moby?
You'd have been dead if I had a gun
Couldn't I have ducked?
They'll keep coming after Sylvia
Until they've got her
Who are they?
Bad guys
How do you know?
Because I'm the good guy
Tell me the whole story
It's a simple story that turned complicated
There are 2 parties
Those guys, and me
I'm officially looking for Sylvia
Those guys want to kidnap her
I want to deliver Sylvia to my client
I don't know why they want to kidnap her
I'm getting very confused
I wish you hadn't explained it
You should know why your client wants me
Yes, I should
But since my client didn't tell me
I really don't know
Detective Moby
Can you tell me something you do know?
I can tell you two
Firstly, this place's dangerous
Do you smell gas?
No, but you’d better trust me
Secondly, if Sylvia wants to know
why I come for her
It's better for her to come with me to meet my client
I know one thing too.
What?
We've got the dumbest private detective
in our home
Don't you dare insulting me
We don't want you insulted
But how long have you been a private detective?
6 days
That's not even one full week
We'd be stupid if we trusted you
Okay, please stop
You've both insulted me and broke my heart
Moby, don't let them in
We'll leave from the balcony
Moby, we're leaving
Come on, hurry. Okay
Come on
Moby, run
Hurry
Go...
Why are we running?
They're trying to grab Sylvia
And there's nothing we can do?
Can't we stop them?
They've got 6 guys
We're used to deal with numbers
This is no time for bragging
Let me and David prove ourselves
Stay with Sylvia
They're tough. They're super-tough
We'd better run
Come on...
What place is this?
Headquarters of filth
That's a dead end
What should we do now?
Find a place to hide
Who got a torch?
I've got one
Kid's stuff
Eyeball them carefully
It stinks here
Just be patient
We couldn't find them
But I saw they coming in here
Much better now
I can't stand this any more
Be patient, or we'll be dead
I can't stand the stink
That Fatso
You've reined everything
Run
Money for everyone
Move over
They can't be too far away
What do you want? I'm an easy guy
I'm glad to hear that
How can I help you?
Someone hired us to push you down
You can do it yourself
You've got the wrong man.
No
Who hired you?
I did
Sylvia?
You want me kidnapped
I want you dead. Push him down
Please don't...
Help...
Please don't... Help...
I'm your father...
He's your father?
You're my father?
No... I'm not your father
I'm your father's butler
You'd better tell me the whole story
Your father's Count Lobas
Gloria is your mother
She used to work in his castle
One night, while the Countess was out
The Count raped Gloria
After Gloria pregnant
He sent her away
Son of a bitch
But he's your father
I hate him. I don't want to see him
He's dead
Before he die
He wanted you and your mother to be found
So that his brother Mondale wouldn't inherit the legacy
I didn't tell this story earlier
For fear of endangering you
That's why I hired an unknown private detective
I'm glad Moby's not here
Of course I am
I sure am lucky
I always barge in at the wrong time
And hear things I don't want to hear
I sure hired the right guy
According to the family's tradition
Gloria and Sylvia have to appear within 14 days
Or else Mondale will inherit the legacy
Those must be Mondale's men
Only 3 days left
Where are you going?
We've been helping Sylvia because she's been helpless
But now she's the daughter of a count
You mean...
If Sylvia's an orphan
You can be friends
But not if she's a count's daughter
We really wanted to help her
Then don't you know
Now's the time she needs most help
Don't you want her to lead a better life?
We do, but you can help her
I'm just one man
You've seen Mondale's men
They wouldn't quit now
If you're real friends of Sylvia
You wouldn't leave her now
Okay, Okay...
You don't have to rub it in
Let's plan to get Gloria out
What're you staring at? I'll kill you
What're you staring at
I'll kill you
Don't come over
I'll kill...
I'll kill you...
Let me go! Get in
Let me go! What do you want?
Done
Let me go
That's too risky. People may find out
Siren off
Mum and David's Dad are dancing over there
What's up?
Your Dad's dancing over there
We've got a nut here
Is he eating or speaking?
I hate guessing games
I'm not a nut. I'm normal
Please unite me
Are you really as normal as we are?
Yes
Ask her a question to see if she's normal
Right. Listen well
There's 3 bugs lining up and crawling towards
The first bug says, "I have two bugs after me."
The last bug says, "There're two bugs before me."
But the one in the middle says,
"There's no bugs before me."
"None after me."
Do you know why?
It's blind
No
Then I got no clue
Why do you give him such a difficult question?
Is it really difficult?
Yes
Why the bug said that?
"No bugs before me and none after me"
Because he's lying!
How would a bug ever lie?
Who tied you up?
That's a secret
Come near me and I'll tell you
Don't tell me anybody else
That's why I had to play crazy
What did he tell you?
Not to tell anybody else
I'm your buddy, tell me
I told you already
Speak up
You hit me all the time. Don't you bully me
Don't go away
Now I'm really stuck
What did you tell him?
Why should I tell you?
Tell me and I'll unite you
I don't trust you
You promised to tell me
I told him not to tell anybody else
What's there to tell though?
We like it here. We don't want to go out
What are you waiting for? Let's go
Not yet
They don't want to leave this place
Tell your Dad you want to marry Sylvia
He has to go our for the ceremony
One shouldn't lie to one's father
One has to be flexible
Go tell him
I'll tell him
Why don't you two leave here and get married?
Why haven't I thought of that?
Are you crazy?
Are you object?
No
Nobody objects
Gloria, will you marry me?
What took you so long?
Congratulations
Sylvia will be your sister soon
You're not pleased about that?
Call him brother
Brother
There's a solution to every problem
Just deny that he's your father
Good idea
Finally
What's this monster doing here?
I don't know
I guess we'll have to find out
Should I go?
Or maybe you should go
All you should say is please
What?
You sure aren't that bright
Moby...
Are you okay?
Not really
Why do you hit my son?
Let go...
Quite!
Get it out of the way
Back it up.
I don't have the keys
Push it away
You do that
He's right
To get into the castle isn't difficult
To do it unnoticed is hard
Come on
If you want to get in
I've at least 7 ways to do so
Why 7 and not 6 or 8?
7 is my lucky number
We only need one that works
Unfortunately that's not among my 7
I'll go in from the rear
Guards are usually quite careless
I'll go in from the front
That's dangerous
What about you?
I don't like either of your plans
We sure are an unorganized bunch
No, just an unorganized three
You're really terrible
Go down now if you have guts
I don't have any
How will you get in?
Through the door
It's guarded.
I'll wait
Till dawn?
Let's climb trees
Elephants can't climb trees
Go ahead and wait
Stop playing, meal time
Don't argue
That would have been a home run
Hide them up
I've got some good news
Someone's here to save you
But the bad news is he's caught
How are you
Don't be rude to my guest
Give him the seat
Thank you. Cheers
Cheers...
What now?
Let's hit the sack
Are you crazy?
Let's find a way to save her!
Why do you have to ask?
Come up here
Like hell I will.
But I weren't you
Think of a way yourself
It's me.
I know
But you kicked me
I kicked you but you dared not scream
That's how I knew it's you
We'd better split up
What are you doing up there?
Are you guests for the party?
Yes
I told you don't come
You almost screwed everything up
We're guests for the party
What a match between the movements
Does that mean I look very classical?
Sit down, Mum
I'm quite hungry
We've got one more dinner guest
Why don't you present yourself properly?
I'm sorry I'm late
What's the main course for tonight?
Roast lamb
I was born in the year of the lamb
May be that's a good omen
I'm really honored tonight
To have so many guests
This is an important night for me
To the Lobas family
Tonight's a disgraceful night
To have you two in the family
That's disgraceful
Don't upset yourself
Mr. Mondale
If people found out you kidnapped Sylvia
Your reputation'd be jeopardized
Thanks for reminding me
I don't see it as a problem
Cardi, entertain them.
Yes
Put the girls in the dungeon.
I haven't finished my soup yet
Reinforcement
Hang in there. He's not that tough
You take care of him
Come on...
I'll tackle him, get the girls
Can you handle him?
No, but you can.
Come on
Dirty tricks
This one's tough
Don't panic, relax
Take it as a training session
Another round
Wait
1,2,3,42,2,3,4
You're good
Got you
I should have trained more
What a hit!
Pull me up for another round
Don't let go. Pull me up please
You're still fighting
I'm waiting for you
3 musketeers
Do the impossible
Upper half
Lower half
Chinese firedrill
Invincible
How are you?
What would you like?
One burger and a coke
Have a seat over there
David, thinking of Sylvia again?
David, come here
What's up?
Look
Dropping in on us?
Would you hire me for the summer?
Of course
Make a wish that summer never ends
Hi there
Moby the private eye
I've got my private detective license
I'm now legitimate
Congratulations
Do you want to make some money?
I've got another assignment for you
You'll be rich
Another castle?
No, a hut this time
Who are we saving?
A black president
He's been kidnapped by some African cannibals
Cannibals...
Someone's looking for you