Starling!
Crawford wants to see you
in his office.
Thank you, sir.
- Clarice.
- Hey.
Looking for Crawford?
He should be back soon.
Why don't you wait in his office?
Starling.
- Clarice M. Good morning.
- Morning, Mr. Crawford.
Sorry to pull you off the course
at such short notice.
Your instructors say you're
in the top quarter of your class.
I hope so. They haven't posted
any grades yet.
A job's come up,
and I thought about you.
Not a job, really,
more of an interesting errand.
Sit down.
Yes, sir.
I remember you from my seminar at UVA.
You grilled me on the bureau's civil
rights record in the Hoover years.
I gave you an A.
A minus, sir.
Double major, psych and criminology,
graduated magna.
Summer internships
at the Reitzinger Clinic.
It says when you graduate you want
to work for me in Behavioral Science.
Yes, very much, sir. Very much.
We're interviewing
all serial killers in custody...
...for a psycho-behavioral profile.
It could be a real help
in unsolved cases.
Most of them have been happy
to talk to us.
Do you spook easily, Starling?
Not yet, sir.
The one we want most refuses to help.
I want you to go after him
in the asylum.
Who's the subject?
- The psychiatrist, Hannibal Lecter.
- "Hannibal the Cannibal."
I don't expect him to talk to you...
...but I have to be able
to say we tried.
If he won't cooperate,
I want straight reporting.
How's he look? How's his cell?
Is he sketching, drawing?
If he is, what's he sketching?
Here's a dossier on Lecter...
...copy of our questionnaire
and an I.D. for you.
Have your memo on my desk
by 0800, Wednesday.
Okay.
Excuse me, sir, but why the urgency?
Lecter's been in prison for years.
Is there some connection
between him and Buffalo Bill?
I wish there were. Now, I want
your full attention, Starling.
- Yes, sir.
- Be very careful with Hannibal Lecter.
Dr. Chilton at the asylum will go over
all the physical procedures used.
Do not deviate from them
for any reason whatsoever.
You're to tell him nothing personal.
You don't want Hannibal Lecter
inside your head.
Just do your job
but never forget what he is.
And what is that?
Oh, he's a monster, a pure psychopath.
It's so rare to capture one alive.
From a research point of view,
Lecter is our most prized asset.
We get a lot of detectives here...
...but I must say I can't remember
one as attractive.
Will you be in Baltimore overnight?
Because this can be quite a fun town
if you have the right guide.
I'm sure this is a great town,
Dr. Chilton...
...but I must talk to Dr. Lecter
and report back this afternoon.
I see. Well, let's make
this quick, then.
We've tried to study him, but he's too
sophisticated for the standard tests.
Oh, my, does he hate us.
He thinks I'm his nemesis.
Crawford's very clever,
isn't he, using you?
- What do you mean, sir?
- Pretty young woman to turn him on.
I don't believe Lecter's seen a woman
in eight years, and you are his taste.
So to speak.
I graduated from UVA.
It's not a charm school.
Good. Then you should be able
to remember the rules.
Do not touch or approach the glass.
Pass him nothing but soft paper.
No pencils or pens, no staples
or paper clips in his paper.
Use the sliding food carrier,
no exceptions.
If he passes you anything,
do not accept.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, I understand, sir.
I'm going to show you why we insist
on such precautions.
On the afternoon of July 8, 1981...
...he complained of chest pains
and was taken to the dispensary.
His mouthpiece was removed for an EKG.
When the nurse leaned over him,
he did this to her.
The doctors managed to reset her jaw,
more or less. Save one of her eyes.
His pulse never got above 85,
even when he ate her tongue.
- I keep him in here.
- Dr. Chilton.
If Lecter feels
that you're his enemy, then...
Maybe we'll have more luck
if I go by myself.
What do you think?
You might have suggested this
in my office and saved me the time.
Yes, sir, but then I would have missed
the pleasure of your company, sir.
When she's finished, bring her out.
Hi, I'm Barney. He told you,
don't get near the glass?
Yes, he did. Clarice Starling.
Nice to meet you. You can hang
your coat there if you like.
Okay. Thank you, I will.
He's past the others.
The last cell.
You keep to the right.
- I put out a chair for you.
- Yes, that's very good, thank you.
I'll be watching. You'll do fine.
I can smell your cunt.
Good morning.
Dr. Lecter, my name is Clarice
Starling. May I speak with you?
You're one of Jack Crawford's,
aren't you?
I am, yes.
May I see your credentials?
Certainly.
Closer, please.
Closer.
That expires in one week.
You're not real FBI, are you?
I'm still in training at the academy.
- Jack Crawford sent a trainee to me?
- Yes, I'm a student.
I'm here to learn from you.
Maybe you can decide
if I'm qualified enough to do that.
That is rather slippery of you,
Agent Starling.
Sit. Please.
Now then, tell me.
What did Miggs say to you?
"Multiple Miggs" in the next cell.
He hissed at you. What did he say?
He said, "I can smell your cunt."
I see.
I myself cannot.
You use Evyan skin cream.
And sometimes you wear L'Air du Temps.
But not today.
Did you do all these drawings?
That is the Duomo, seen
from the Belvedere.
Do you know Florence?
All that detail just from memory, sir?
Memory, Agent Starling, is what
I have instead of a view.
Perhaps you'd care to lend us
your view on this questionnaire, sir.
No, no, no. You were doing fine.
You had been courteous
and receptive to courtesy.
You had established trust with
the embarrassing truth about Miggs.
And now this ham-handed segue
into your questionnaire.
It won't do.
I'm only asking you to look at this.
Either you will or you won't.
Yeah. Jack Crawford must be
very busy indeed...
...if he's recruiting help
from the student body.
Busy hunting that new one,
Buffalo Bill.
What a naughty boy he is.
Do you know why he's called
"Buffalo Bill"?
Please tell me.
The newspapers won't say.
It started as a joke
in Kansas City Homicide.
They said, "This one likes
to skin his humps."
Why do you think...
...he removes their skins,
Agent Starling?
Thrill me with your acumen.
It excites him.
Most serial killers keep
trophies from their victims.
- I didn't.
- No.
No, you ate yours.
You send that through now.
You think you can dissect
me with this blunt little tool?
No! I thought
that your knowledge...
You're so ambitious, aren't you?
You know what you look like, with
your good bag and your cheap shoes?
You look like a rube.
A well-scrubbed, hustling rube
with a little taste.
Nutrition has given you
some length of bone...
...but you're not more than one
generation from white trash...
...are you, Agent Starling?
The accent you've tried
so desperately to shed...
...pure West Virginia.
Is your father a coal miner?
Does he stink of the lamp?
I know how quickly the boys found you,
all those tedious, sticky fumblings...
...in the back seats of cars,
while you dreamed of getting out.
Getting anywhere.
Getting all the way to the FBI.
You see a lot, doctor.
But are you strong enough
to point that...
...high-powered
perception at yourself?
What about it?
Why don't you look at yourself
and write down what you see?
Or maybe you're afraid to.
A census taker once tried to test me.
I ate his liver
with some fava beans...
...and a nice Chianti.
You fly back to school now,
little Starling.
Fly, fly, fly.
I bit my wrist...
...so I could die.
Look at the blood!
Gotcha.
Miggs! You stupid fuck!
Agent Starling! Come back!
Agent Starling! Agent Starling!
I would not have had that happen.
Discourtesy is ugly to me.
- Then do this test!
- No, but I will make you happy.
- I'll give you a chance at your love.
- What?
Advancement. Listen. Look deep
within yourself, Clarice Starling.
Go seek out Miss Mofet,
an old patient of mine. M-O-F-E-T.
I don't think Miggs could
manage again so soon...
...even though he is crazy.
Go now!
Hi, Bill.
- Daddy!
- Hey, Clarice.
- Did you get any bad guys, Daddy?
- No, angel. They all got away.
Ah, shoot.
FBI! Hands up! Don't move!
Turn around. Hands behind your back.
Thumbs up.
You're dead, Starling.
Johnson, good entry, good command.
Starling, where's your danger area?
- In the corner.
- Did you check it?
- No, sir.
- That's why you're dead.
3-1-0-9?
Breaking doors or windows
to enter or exit.
Rule 404?
Clarice, phone. It's the guru.
Crawford? Thanks, Ardelia.
- Starling?
- Sir.
Miggs is dead.
Dead?
How?
The orderly heard Lecter whispering
to him all afternoon.
They found him at bed check.
He'd swallowed his tongue.
Starling?
Yeah. I'm still here, sir. I just...
I don't know how to feel about this.
You don't have to feel any way.
Lecter did it to amuse himself.
Look, I know it got ugly today...
...but you mentioned a name,
"Mofet." Any follow-up on her?
He destroyed most of his patients'
histories prior to capture...
...so there's no record
of anyone named Mofet.
But I thought the "yourself" reference
was too hokey for Lecter...
...so I figured he's from Baltimore,
and I looked in the phone book.
And there's a
"Your Self" storage facility...
... right outside
of downtown Baltimore, sir.
Unit 31 was leased...
...for 10 years, prepaid in full.
The contract was in the name...
...of a Miss Hester Mofet.
So nobody's been
in here since 1980?
Not to my knowledge.
Privacy is a great concern
to my customers.
Yes, I won't disturb anything,
I promise.
I'll be out of here
before you know it.
- May I help you?
- Yes, actually.
Here.
- It's stuck.
- We could return tomorrow with my son.
What about him?
I would ask my driver to help you,
but he detests physical labor.
Right.
You stay here.
I'll be back in one minute.
It's stuck. Will you hand me
that flashlight?
If this door should fall down...
...or anything else...
...this is the number
for our Baltimore office.
They know that you're with me.
- Call them if anything should happen.
- Yes, Miss Starling.
Clarice. Here, they're waiting
for you.
Watch your step.
Hester Mofet. It's an anagram,
isn't it, doctor?
Hester Mofet: "The rest of me"?
"Miss The Rest Of Me," meaning
that you rented that garage?
Thank you.
Your bleeding has stopped.
How did?
It's nothing.
It's just a scratch.
Dr. Lecter, whose head
is in that bottle?
Why don't you ask me
about Buffalo Bill?
Do you know something about him?
I might if I saw the case file.
You could get that for me.
Let's talk about Miss Mofet.
You wanted me to find him.
His real name is Benjamin Raspail.
A former patient of mine...
...whose romantic attachments
ran to, shall we say, the exotic.
I did not kill him, merely tucked
him away, very much as I found him...
...after he'd missed
three appointments.
If you didn't kill him, who did?
Who can say?
Best thing for him, really.
His therapy was going nowhere.
His dress, makeup...
Raspail was a transvestite?
In life? Oh, no.
Garden variety manic-depressive.
Tedious, very tedious.
I now think of him as an experiment.
A fledgling killer's first effort
at transformation.
How did you feel when you saw him,
Clarice?
Scared at first, then...
...exhilarated.
Jack Crawford is helping your career,
isn't he?
Apparently, he likes you
and you like him too.
I never thought about it.
Do you think Jack Crawford
wants you, sexually?
He is much older, but do you think
he visualizes scenarios, exchanges?
Fucking you?
That doesn't interest me. It's the
sort of thing that Miggs would say.
Not anymore.
Thank you, Barney.
What happened to your drawings?
Punishment, you see, for Miggs.
Just like that gospel program.
When you leave, they'll turn
the volume way up.
Dr. Chilton does enjoy
his petty torments.
What did you mean
by "transformation," doctor?
I've been in this room
for eight years now, Clarice.
I know they will never
ever let me out while I'm alive.
What I want is a view.
I want a window where I can see a tree
or even water.
I want to be in a federal institution
far away from Dr. Chilton.
What did you mean
by "fledgling killer"?
Are you saying he's killed again?
I'm offering you a psychological
profile on Buffalo Bill...
...based on the case evidence.
I'll help you catch him, Clarice.
You know who he is, don't you?
Tell me who decapitated
your patient, doctor.
All good things to those who wait.
I've waited, Clarice. But how long
can you and old Jackie-boy wait?
Our little Billy must already be
searching for that next special lady.
Hey, little cheeper.
I'll be right there.
Jeez!
Can I help you with that?
Would you?
Sure.
Thank you.
That's all right. You look
kind of handicapped.
Yeah. I got it this far, I just can't
get it up in the truck by myself.
Here, grab this. Up!
Okay.
Just set it down. That's good.
Get in the truck. I want to
push it all the way up.
I really appreciate this.
Thank you.
Just go all the way back.
Okay. Is this good?
Yeah, that's good.
- That's great.
- Okay.
Say, are you
about a size 14?
Sorry?
Good.
Oh, good. Good.
Holds!
Ones!
Starling!
Outside. Let's go.
Cindy, in the ring for Starling.
Let's go!
Pack your field gear.
- You're going with Crawford.
- Where?
Found a girl's body
in West Virginia.
Been in the water a week.
Looks like Buffalo Bill.
Keeps them alive for three days.
We don't know why.
No evidence of rape or
physical abuse prior to death.
All the mutilation you see
there is postmortem.
Okay, three days...
...then he shoots them, skins them
and dumps them.
Each body in a different river.
The water leaves us no trace
evidence of any kind.
That's Fredrica Bimmel, the first one.
Her body was the only one he
weighted down.
So actually, she was
the third girl found.
After her, he got lazy.
Okay, let's see.
Circles where the girls were abducted.
Arrows where their bodies were found.
This new one today washed up here.
Elk River, West Virginia.
Look at him, Starling.
Tell me what you see.
Well, he's a white male.
Serial killers tend to hunt
within their own ethnic groups.
He's not a drifter. He's got his
own house, not an apartment.
- Why?
- What he does with them takes privacy.
He's in his 30s or 40s.
He's got real physical strength.
Combined with an older man's
self-control. He's cautious, precise.
And he's never impulsive.
He'll never stop.
Why not?
He's got a real taste for it now,
and he's getting better at his work.
Not bad, Starling. Questions?
Yes, sir.
You haven't mentioned anything about
the information in my report...
...or Dr. Lecter's offer, sir.
I'm considering it.
That's why you sent me
in there, isn't it?
To get his help on Buffalo Bill, sir?
Well, if that was the case, then...
...I just wish I was in on it,
that's all.
If I'd sent you in there with a real
agenda, Lecter would have known it.
He would have toyed with you,
then turned to stone.
Excuse me, Sheriff Perkins?
These are the FBI people.
Sheriff Perkins, Jack Crawford, FBI.
Special Agent Terry, Agent Starling.
We appreciate being invited
to your jurisdiction.
Somebody from the state attorney's
office called you.
We'll extend you every courtesy,
but right now...
Sheriff...
...this type of sex crime has aspects
I'd just as soon discuss in private.
Know what I mean?
Oscar, fetch Dr. Akin
from the chapel.
We're back here.
Tell Lamar to come on when
he's finished playing his music.
Yeah, we'll be sending in a minute.
It's working.
I need a six-way link up.
Chicago, Detroit...
What? What?
Excuse me.
Excuse me, officers and gentlemen.
Listen here, now.
There's things we need to do
for her.
Y'all brought her this far, and her
folks would thank you if they could...
...for your kindness
and your sensitivity.
Please, go on now,
and let us take care of her.
Go on, now.
Thank you.
Okay, good.
Yeah, that's right. Elk River.
Stand by for transmission.
Ray.
Doctor, Lamar.
Let's take a look at her.
Jesus...
Okay, Starling.
Star-shaped contact entrance
wound over the sternum.
A muzzle stamp at the top.
- Wrongful death.
She'll have to go to the state
pathologist's at Claxton.
Well, I better get back
to that service.
Lamar will help you.
Lord Almighty.
What else do you see, Starling?
Well, she's not local.
Her ears are pierced three times
and there's...
...glitter nail polish.
It looks like town to me.
Two of her fingernails
are broken off...
...and there's dirt or grit
under them.
It looks like she's tried to claw her
way through something.
Ray, get pictures of her teeth.
We'll fax them to Missing Persons.
Right.
Let's do another.
She's got something in her throat.
When a body comes out
of the water...
...lots of times there's
leaves and things in the mouth.
What is that?
Some kind of seedpod?
No, sir. That's a bug cocoon.
There's no way that could get
way down in there.
Not unless somebody
shoved it in there.
She'll be easier to print
when we turn her.
Lamar, give me a hand?
Yes, sir, I will.
Oh, Jack.
What do you make of these?
Different configuration than
the other victims. Get close-ups.
Victim's skin removed...
...in two diamond-shaped sections
above the buttocks.
Exit wound level with the second
or third thoracic vertebrae...
... approximately six inches from
the right shoulder blade.
Starling...
...when I told that sheriff we
shouldn't talk in front of a woman...
...that burned you, didn't it?
It was just smoke, Starling.
I had to get rid of him.
It matters, Mr. Crawford.
Cops look at you to see how to act.
It matters.
Point taken.
Ligature marks found around wrists...
... not around the ankles.
This would indicate that
the skinning was postmortem.
Time, Pilch. My move.
- No fair! You lured him with produce.
- Tough noogies. It's still my turn.
Nice and slow, baby.
If the beetle moves one of your men,
does that still count?
Of course it counts. How do you play?
Agent Starling?
Where the heck did this come from?
It's practically mush.
It was found in a murder victim.
The body was in the Elk River.
It's Buffalo Bill, isn't it?
I can't tell you any more.
We heard it on the radio.
You mean this is a clue
from a real murder case? Cool!
Just ignore him. He's not a Ph.D.
Sphingid Ceratomia, maybe...
Boy, he's a big sucker.
Okay...
...let's check morphology.
What do you do when you're not
detecting, Agent Starling?
Try to be a student, Dr. Pilcher.
You ever go out for
cheeseburgers and beer?
The amusing house wine?
Are you hitting on me, doctor?
- Yes.
- Gotcha!
What do you got?
Agent Starling,
meet Mr. Acherontia Styx.
Weird.
Better known to his friends
as the Death's-head moth.
Where does it come from?
That's what's strange.
They only live in Asia.
They're specially raised from
imported eggs.
Somebody grew this guy.
Fed him honey and nightshade.
Kept him warm.
Somebody loved him.
Where are you?!
Let me out of here!
Hey!
Please help me!
Help me, please!
Why won't you answer me?! Please!
- Good morning. I'm Donna Ferucchi.
- I'm Gene Cassel with sports.
And I'm Tim Langhorn.
Our top story this morning:
Catherine Martin, the 25-year-old
daughter of Senator Ruth Martin...
... listed as a missing person...
... is believed to have been kidnapped
by the killer known as "Buffalo Bill."
Memphis police say the missing girl's
blouse has been identified...
... sliced up the back, in what has
become a kind of grim calling card.
Young Catherine is the only daughter
of U.S. Senator Ruth Martin...
... the Republican senator
from Tennessee.
And while her kidnapping is not
considered politically motivated...
... it has stirred the government
to its highest levels.
Reached for comment on the ski
slopes of Vermont...
... the president himself said to be,
and I quote, "intensely concerned."
Just moments ago, Senator Martin
taped this dramatic personal plea:
I'm speaking, now, to the person
holding my daughter.
Catherine is very gentle and kind.
Talk to her and you'll see.
You have the power.
You are in charge.
I know you can feel love
and compassion.
You have a wonderful chance
to show the whole world...
... that you can be merciful,
as well as strong.
That you're big enough
to treat Catherine better...
... than the world has treated you.
You have that power.
Please. My daughter is Catherine.
Boy, that's smart.
Jesus, that's really smart.
She keeps repeating the name.
If he sees Catherine as a person, not
an object, it's harder to tear her up.
Please, release my little girl.
What you're doing, Ms. Starling,
is coming into my hospital...
...and refusing to share information
with me for the third time.
Sir, I told you this is just
a routine follow-up on the Raspail...
He is my patient. I have rights.
I understand that.
Look, I am not just some turnkey,
Miss Starling.
This is the number for
the U.S. Attorney.
Please, either discuss it with him
or let me do my job, you understand?
If your profile helps us catch
Buffalo Bill...
...in time to save Catherine Martin...
...the senator promises you
a transfer to the VA Hospital...
...at Oneida Park, New York,
with a view of the woods nearby.
Maximum security still applies,
of course.
You'd have reasonable access to books.
Best of all, though...
...one week of the year, you get
to leave the hospital...
...and go here:
Plum Island.
Every day of that week,
you may walk on the beach.
You may swim in the ocean
for up to one hour...
...under SWAT team surveillance,
of course.
And there you have it.
A copy of the Buffalo Bill case file.
A copy of the senator's offer.
This offer is non-negotiable
and final.
Catherine Martin dies,
you get nothing.
Plum Island Animal Disease
Research Center.
Sounds charming.
That's only part of the island.
There's a very nice beach.
Terns nest there.
There's beautiful...
Terns?
If I help you, Clarice, it will be
"turns" with us too.
Quid pro quo. I tell you things,
you tell me things.
Not about this case, though.
About yourself.
Quid pro quo. Yes or no?
Yes or no, Clarice? Poor little
Catherine is waiting.
Go, doctor.
What is your worst memory
of childhood?
The death of my father.
Tell me about it.
And don't lie, or I'll know.
He was a town marshal...
...and one night he surprised two
burglars coming out of a drugstore.
They shot him.
Was he killed outright?
No, he was very strong.
He lasted more than a month.
My mother died when I was
very young, so...
...my father had become
the whole world to me...
...and when he left me, I had
nothing. I was 10 years old.
You're very frank, Clarice.
I think it would be quite something
to know you in private life.
Quid pro quo, doctor.
So tell me about Miss West Virginia.
Was she a large girl?
Yes.
Big through the hips, roomy?
They all were.
What else?
She had an object deliberately
inserted into her throat.
Now, that hasn't been made public yet.
We don't know what it means.
Was it a butterfly?
Yes. A moth.
Just like the one we found in
Benjamin Raspail's head an hour ago.
Why does he place them there,
doctor?
The significance of the moth
is change.
Caterpillar into chrysalis, or pupa...
...and from thence into beauty.
Our Billy wants to change too.
There's no correlation between
transsexualism and violence.
- Transsexuals are very passive.
- Clever girl.
You're so close to the way you're
gonna catch him. Do you realize that?
No. Tell me why.
After your father's murder you were
orphaned. What happened next?
I don't imagine the answer is on
those second-rate shoes, Clarice.
I went to live with my mother's cousin
and her husband in Montana.
They had a ranch.
Was it a cattle ranch?
Sheep and horses.
How long did you live there?
Two months.
Why so briefly?
I ran away.
Why, Clarice? Did the rancher
make you perform fellatio?
Did he sodomize you?
No. He was a very decent man.
Quid pro quo, doctor.
Billy is not a real transsexual.
But he thinks he is.
He tries to be.
He's tried to be a lot of
things, I expect.
You said I was very close to the way
we'd catch him. What did you mean?
There are three major centers for
transsexual surgery:
Johns Hopkins, the University of
Minnesota, and Columbus Medical Center.
I wouldn't be surprised if Billy
applied for sex reassignment...
...at one or all of them,
and been rejected.
On what basis would they reject him?
Look for severe childhood
disturbances associated with violence.
Our Billy wasn't born
a criminal, Clarice...
... he was made one through
years of systematic abuse.
Billy hates his own identity,
you see...
... and he thinks that makes him
a transsexual...
... but his pathology is
a thousand times more savage...
... and more terrifying.
It rubs the lotion on its skin.
It does this whenever it's told.
Mister, my family will pay cash.
Whatever ransom you're asking for,
they'll pay it.
It rubs the lotion on its skin
or else it gets the hose again.
Yes, she will, Precious.
She'll get the hose.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, I'll do it.
Okay.
Mister, if you let me go,
I won't press charges. I promise.
See, my mom is a real important woman.
I guess you already know that.
Now it places the lotion
in the basket.
Please!
Please, I want to go home.
I want to go home!
Please! Please let me.
It places the lotion in the basket.
I want to see my mommy.
Please let me.
I want to see my mom again.
I want...
I want to see my mom.
Put the fucking lotion in the basket!
You still think you're gonna walk
on some beach and see the birdies?
I don't think so.
I called Senator Ruth Martin.
She never heard of any deal with you.
They scammed you, Hannibal.
Stand outside.
And shut the door.
Barney.
There never was a deal with
Senator Martin, but there is now.
I designed it.
Of course, I worked in a few
conditions for my own benefit as well.
Identify Buffalo Bill by name...
...and if the girl is found in time...
...you'll be transferred to Brushy
Mountain State Prison in Tennessee.
Answer me, Hannibal.
You answer me now...
...or, by God,
you'll never leave this cell.
Who is Buffalo Bill?
His first name is Louis.
I'll tell the rest to the Senator
herself, but only in Tennessee.
And I have a few conditions of my own.
Clean him up and get him ready to go.
Jack, Hannibal Lecter
is being transferred to Memphis.
Transferred?
Did you have a trainee make a phony
offer to Lecter in the senator's name?
I rolled the dice. I had to.
Well, she's mad as hell, Jack.
Paul Krendler's here from Justice.
She's asking him
to take over in Memphis.
Welcome to Memphis, Dr. Lecter.
I'm Lieutenant Boyle.
This is Sergeant Patrick.
We'll treat you as good
as you treat us.
You be a gentleman,
you'll get three hots and a cot.
Sir, if you sign right here,
we'll have us a legal transfer.
Here, sir, use mine.
Senator Martin...
...Dr. Hannibal Lecter.
Dr. Lecter...
...I've brought an affidavit
guaranteeing your new rights.
You'll want to read it before I sign.
I won't waste your time or Catherine's
time bargaining for petty privileges.
Clarice Starling and Jack Crawford
have wasted too much time already.
I only pray they haven't doomed
the poor girl.
Let me help you now.
I will trust you when it is all over.
You have my word. Paul.
Buffalo Bill's real name
is Louis Friend.
I met him just once. He was referred
to me in April or May, 1980...
...by my patient Benjamin Raspail.
They were lovers, you see.
But Raspail had become
very frightened.
Apparently, Louis had
murdered a transient...
...and done things with the skin.
We need his address
and a physical description.
Tell me, senator.
Did you nurse Catherine yourself?
- What?
- Did you breast-feed her?
- Now, wait a minute!
- Yes. I did.
Toughened your nipples, didn't it?
You son of a bitch!
Amputate a man's leg,
and he can still feel it tickling.
Tell me, Mom, when your
little girl is on the slab...
...where will it tickle you?
Take this thing back to Baltimore.
Five-foot-ten, strongly built,
about 180 pounds.
Hair, blond. Eyes, pale blue.
He'd be about 35 now.
He said he lived in Philadelphia
but may have lied.
That's all I can remember, Mom.
But if I think of any more,
I will let you know.
Oh, and senator, just one more thing:
Love your suit.
In a meeting earlier today
with Senator Ruth Martin...
...Dr. Lecter agreed to help in the
investigation to find Buffalo Bill.
- How do you fit in?
- My unique insight...
...into Lecter made the breakthrough.
Buffalo Bill's name?
His name is now a matter of record
with the proper authorities.
- Can you give us..?
- I'm Dr. Frederick Chilton.
- Spell it?
- That's C-H...
Are you with Dr. Chilton's group?
Well, I just saw him outside, sir.
Access to Lecter is limited.
We've received death threats.
I understand, sir.
Log in and check your weapon.
I can't take all the credit myself.
Senator Martin,
Justice Department, FBI...
...folks at the Baltimore State
Hospital. Now for the hard part:
Apprehending the suspect.
Excuse me, I have to catch a flight.
Command desk, Officer Jacobs.
- Is it true what they're saying?
- Huh?
He's some kind of vampire?
They don't have a name for what he is.
You do know the rules, ma'am?
Yes, I've questioned him before.
Go ahead.
Good evening, Clarice.
I thought you might like
your drawings back.
Just until you get your view.
How very thoughtful.
Or did Jack Crawford
send you for one last wheedle...
...before you're both
booted off the case?
No. I came because I wanted to.
People will say we're in love.
Anthrax Island.
That was an especially
nice touch, Clarice.
Yours?
Yes.
Yeah.
That was good.
Pity about poor Catherine, though.
Ticktock, ticktock, ticktock.
Your anagrams are showing, doctor.
Louis Friend?
Iron sulfide,
also known as fool's gold.
Oh, Clarice, your problem is, you
need to get more fun out of life.
You were telling me the truth
back in Baltimore, sir.
Please continue now.
Well, I've read the case files.
Have you?
Everything you need to find him
is there in those pages.
- Then tell me how.
- First principles, Clarice.
Simplicity. Read Marcus Aurelius.
Of each particular thing, ask:
What is it in itself?
What is its nature?
What does he do, this man you seek?
He kills women.
No. That is incidental.
What is the principle thing he does?
What needs does he serve by killing?
Anger...
...social acceptance
and sexual frustration...
No!
He covets.
That is his nature.
And how do we begin to covet, Clarice?
Do we seek out things to covet?
Make an effort to answer now.
No, we just...
No, we begin by coveting
what we see every day.
Don't you feel eyes moving
over your body, Clarice?
And don't your eyes seek out
the things you want?
All right, yes.
Now, please tell me how.
No.
It is your turn to tell me, Clarice.
You don't have any more
vacations to sell.
Why did you leave that ranch?
Doctor, we don't have any more time
for any of this now.
But we don't reckon time
the same way, do we?
This is all the time you'll have.
Later. Please listen.
We've only got five...
No! I will listen now.
Your father's murder orphaned you
when you were 10.
You went to live with cousins on a
sheep and horse ranch in Montana. And?
And one morning I just ran away.
Not "just," Clarice.
What set you off?
You started at what time?
Early, still dark.
Then something woke you.
Was it a dream?
What was it?
I heard a strange noise.
It was...
...screaming.
Some kind of screaming,
like a child's voice.
What did you do?
I went...
...downstairs. Outside.
I crept up into the barn.
I was so scared to look inside,
but I had to.
And what did you see, Clarice?
What did you see?
Lambs.
They were screaming.
They were slaughtering
the spring lambs?
And they were screaming.
And you ran away?
No. First I tried to free them.
I opened the gate to their pen.
They just stood there, confused.
They wouldn't run.
But you could and you did, didn't you?
Yes. I took one lamb
and I ran away as fast as I could.
Where were you going, Clarice?
I don't know. I didn't have
any food, any water...
...and it was very cold.
It was very cold.
I thought...
I thought if I could save just one...
...but he was so heavy.
He was so heavy.
I didn't get more than a few miles
when the sheriff's car picked me up.
The rancher was so angry he sent me
to a Lutheran orphanage in Bozeman.
I never saw the ranch again.
What became of your lamb, Clarice?
They killed him.
You still wake up sometimes,
don't you?
Wake up in the dark...
...and hear the screaming
of the lambs?
Yes.
And you think if you save
poor Catherine...
...you can make them stop, don't you?
You think if Catherine lives...
...you won't wake up
in the dark ever again...
...to that awful screaming
of the lambs.
I don't know.
Thank you, Clarice.
Thank you.
Tell me his name, doctor.
Dr. Chilton, I presume.
I think you know each other.
Okay.
- We found her.
- Let's go.
It's your turn, doctor.
- Out!
- Tell me his name.
Sorry, ma'am, I've got orders
to put you on a plane.
Come on, now.
Brave Clarice.
You will let me know when those lambs
stop screaming, won't you?
Tell me his name, doctor!
Clarice!
Your case file.
Hey!
Goodbye, Clarice.
Ready when you are, doc.
Just another minute, please.
Son of a bitch demanded
a second dinner.
Lamb chops, extra rare.
Wonder what he wants for breakfast?
Some damn thing from the zoo?
Good evening, gentlemen.
Okay, doc. Grab some floor.
Same drill as before, please.
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
Okay.
Hand me that, would you?
Thanks.
Mind the drawings, please.
Thank you.
Pembry, watch it, he's cuffed me!
Jesus Christ!
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
What is this shit?
Did somebody go up on five?
- No, nobody went up.
- Call Pembry. Ask him to tell...
CP, shots fired on five.
Repeat, shots fired on five.
Sergeant Tate!
Proceed. Shots fired on five.
Holy shit!
- What the hell?
- Bitch!
Shut up!
Bobby, get the vest.
Right, sarge.
- Brady, Howard, cover...
- Look!
It stopped.
Seal off a 10-block radius.
Get me the SWAT team
and an ambulance, double quick.
We're going up.
Pembry?!
Boyle?!
Oh, God!
Go.
- Clear.
Command post.
Two officers down.
- Clear!
Lecter's gone, sarge.
Prisoner is missing.
Boyle's gun is gone.
Repeat. Lecter is missing and armed.
He stripped the bed.
Might be making a rope.
Check all the windows.
Where the fuck is my ambulance?
He's alive.
Sergeant Tate! He's alive!
Get ahold of him and feel his hands.
Talk to him!
What do I say?
It's Jim Pembry.
Now talk to him, damn it!
Lecter is missing and armed.
- Pembry. Pembry, can you hear me?
- He took Boyle's gun.
Pembry got off one round.
There's a chance Lecter's hit.
Keep breathing in and out.
You're doing a good job.
You look real good there.
Yeah, you look... Look real good.
- You ready?
- Let's go!
- Let's do it.
- Okay, let's go!
Looking good. You're gonna make it.
Everything's just fine.
- I need that IV now!
- Lactated Ringer's.
Can we get the strap?
Where's the oxygen?
Doing good, buddy. That's right.
Stay with me here.
We're losing him!
Downstairs, quickly!
And up!
- Elevator!
- This way!
- Out of the way!
- Get out of the way!
CP to Tate.
Roger, lieutenant. Tate here.
I'm on the elevator
bringing Pembry down.
He seems to be hanging on.
Top three floors secured.
Main stairwell secured.
We think he's on two.
Tate, you still with me?
We're pretty sure
he's somewhere on two, sir.
That's all for now. Over.
He's on the roof of the elevator.
Okay, guys.
I see him.
There's a gun by his hand.
He's not moving.
- One warning. We need him alive.
- Got it.
Lecter?
Put your hands on your head.
One in the leg.
No movement.
Johnny, hold your fire.
We're coming into the car.
We're opening the hatch.
Watch his hands.
If there's any fire,
it'll come from us. Affirm.
Got it.
Memphis General, this is Unit 26.
We're inbound with
a 50-year-old male officer...
...with severe facial lacerations.
He had grand mal seizure activity.
He's postdictal now.
- I copy.
- Vital signs are good.
- Pressure is 130/90.
- Ninety?
Yeah, that's right, 90. Pulse, 84.
We got him
on lactated Ringer's running...
...and the patient
is on 10 liters of oxygen.
Watch it!
The ambulance was found in
a parking garage at Memphis Airport.
The crew was dead.
He killed a tourist too.
Got his clothes, cash.
By now he could be anywhere.
- He won't come after me.
- Oh, really?
He won't.
I can't explain it.
He would consider that rude.
It's over. She's dead.
It's not your fault.
Lecter said everything we need to
catch him with is here, only I can't...
Dr. Lecter said a lot of things.
He's here, Ardelia.
Is this Lecter's handwriting?
"Doesn't this random scattering
of sites seem desperately random?
Like the elaboration of a bad liar?
Ta. Hannibal Lecter."
"Desperately random."
What does he mean?
Not random at all, maybe.
Like there's a pattern here.
But there's no pattern
or the computers would've nailed it.
They're even found in random order.
Random because of the one girl.
The one he weighted down.
- Fredrica Bimmel.
- Right.
From Belvedere, Ohio.
The first girl taken,
third body found. Why?
She didn't drift.
He weighted her down.
What did Lecter say
about the "first principles"?
Simplicity.
What does this guy do? He covets.
How do we first start to covet?
We covet what we see.
Every day.
Hot damn, Clarice.
He knew her.
Mr. Bimmel?
That's me.
Hello, I'm Clarice Starling.
I'm with the FBI.
I appreciate you letting me
take a look around, Mr. Bimmel.
I don't know nothing new to tell you.
Police been back here
so many times already.
Fredrica went into Chicago
on the bus to see about a job.
She left the interview okay.
She never come home.
Her bedroom's how she left it.
Upstairs.
Door to the left.
He's making himself a woman suit.
Out of real women!
And he can sew!
He's very skilled.
He's a tailor or a dressmaker or...
- Starling!
- That's why they're big.
He keeps them alive
so he can starve them...
...loosen their skin and...
Starling!
We know who and where he is!
We're on our way right now.
- Where?
- Calumet City, edge of Chicago.
Be on the ground
in 45 minutes with HRT.
That's great news, sir. But how..?
We fed the names Johns Hopkins
came up with into Known Offenders.
Subject's name is Jamie Gumb,
a.k.a. John Grant.
Lecter's description was accurate.
He just lied about the name.
Customs had some paper on him.
They stopped a carton
two years ago at LAX.
Live caterpillars from Suriname.
The addressee was a Jame Gumb.
Chicago is only 400 miles from here.
I'll be there in...
No, there's not enough time.
We want him for murder,
not kidnapping.
Link him to Bimmel
before he's indicted.
- See what you can find in Belvedere.
- Yes, sir. You bet. I'll do my best.
Starling.
We wouldn't have found him
without you. Nobody will forget that.
Least of all me.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you very much, Mr. Crawford.
Mr. Crawford?
Thanks for the scraps, asshole.
I got a better idea.
Okay, Precious.
Time for a little treat.
Precious!
Come on, girl!
Come on, Precious. Come on, Precious.
Come on, Precious.
I got a yummy, yummy snack for you.
Come and get it!
Precious!
Are you up there, you little shit?
Come and get it, pretty girl.
Precious!
Please come. Come on.
Come on, Precious.
Would you fuck me?
Come on. Take that bone. Come on.
Come on. Come on! Come on!
I'd fuck me.
Come on.
I'd fuck me hard.
I'd fuck me so hard.
No!
Is that a good job, FBI agent?
You get to travel around and stuff?
I mean, better places than this?
Sometimes you do.
Freddie was so happy for me
when I got this job at the bank.
Toaster giveaways and Barry Manilow
on the speakers all day.
She thought it was such hot shit.
What did she know? Big dummy.
Stacy, did Fredrica ever mention
a man named Jamie Gumb?
Or a Jame Gumb?
- How about John Grant?
- No.
Would she have had a friend
you didn't know?
No way. If she had a guy,
I'd have known.
Sewing was her life.
Did you ever work together?
Me and Pam Malavesi used to help her
do alterations for old Mrs. Lippman.
Can I get Mrs. Lippman's address?
I need to talk to her.
So powerful.
So beautiful.
Precious?
Down here, you sack of shit!
- Put her in that bucket.
- No!
You get me a telephone
and lower it down here, now!
Oh, poodlie-poo. Precious?
Darling, are you all right?
She's in a lot of pain, mister.
She needs a vet.
She broke her leg on the way down.
She's licking...
Hey! Don't you hurt my dog!
Don't you make me hurt your dog!
You don't know what pain is!
Get me that telephone
or I'll kill him!
- Oh, fuck!
- You better get me that telephone!
I'm gonna do it, mister!!
I'm gonna snap her neck off,
I swear to God!
All right, mister. I'm doing it!
Okay, I'm coming.
We're going in.
Good afternoon. Sorry to bother you.
I'm looking for Mrs. Lippman's family.
FBI! Everybody down!
Lippmans don't live here anymore.
Excuse me, sir.
I need to speak with you.
- Clear!
What's the problem, officer?
I'm investigating the death
of Fredrica Bimmel.
There's no one here, Jack.
Clarice.
Your name is?
Oh, Jack Gordon.
Mr. Gordon. Good.
Fredrica worked for Mrs. Lippman.
Did you know her?
No, uh-uh.
Oh, wait.
Was she a great big fat person?
Yes, she was a big girl, sir.
Yeah, I may have...
No, I read about her in the newspaper.
Mrs. Lippman had a son.
Maybe he could help.
I got his card in here.
You want to come in?
- May I?
- Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Are you close to catching somebody?
Yes.
We may be.
Did you...
...take over this place after
Mrs. Lippman died, is that right?
Yeah, I bought this house
two years ago.
Did she leave any records,
any business records...
...tax forms, lists of employees?
No, nothing like that at all.
Say, has the FBI learned something?
The police around here don't seem
to have the first clue.
Have you got, like, a description,
fingerprints, anything like that?
No.
No, we don't.
Here's that number.
Very good, Mr. Gordon.
May I use your phone, please?
Sure you can use my phone.
Freeze!
Put your hands over your head
and turn around. Spread your legs.
Spread your legs!
Put your hands in the back...
Freeze!
Hey!
Are you there?
I'm down here! I'm down here!
Catherine Martin?
Yes!
FBI.
You're safe.
Safe, shit! Get me out of here!
You're all right. Where is he?
How the fuck should I know?
Just get me out of here!
Catherine, you've gotta be quiet!
Now, shut that dog up!
Just get me out of here!
Oh, my God.
Catherine, I'm gonna get you out.
But right now, you listen to me.
I've gotta leave. I'll be right back.
No! Don't you leave me here,
you fucking bitch! No!
Don't you leave me here!
This guy is fucking crazy!
Wait! I gotta get out of here!
Please!
Catherine! The other officers
will be here any minute now.
Wait! Don't go! Please!
Quiet!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- You okay?
- Gunpowder. It's nothing, I'm okay.
Agent Starling, how did you
track Buffalo Bill here?
Clarice M. Starling.
Congratulations.
Ernest W. Stevens.
Special Agent Starling!
- Special Agent Mapp.
- Phone call.
Thank you. Excuse me.
Starling.
Pilch, could you take our picture?
Sure.
I just wanted to say congratulations.
I'm no good at this kind of thing,
so I'm gonna duck out of here.
Okay. Sure.
Thank you, Mr. Crawford.
Your father would've been proud today.
Don't forget your phone call.
Starling.
Well, Clarice...
...have the lambs stopped screaming?
Dr. Lecter?
Don't bother with a trace.
I won't be on long enough.
Where are you, Dr. Lecter?
I have no plans to call on you.
The world's more interesting
with you in it.
So you take care now
to extend me the same courtesy.
You know I can't make that promise.
I do wish we could chat longer...
...but I'm having
an old friend for dinner.
Bye.
Dr. Lecter!
Dr. Lecter.
Dr. Lecter?
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
The security system's set up?
- We have the big shot security.
- I appreciate it.
Thank you for using the subs
regards, shock...