Watch full movies online for free at www.awooh.com
I feel like you're driving me
to a court-martial.
This is crazy. What did I do?
I feel like you're
going to pull over...
and snuff me.
What, you're not
allowed to talk?
Hey, Forrest.
We can talk, sir.
- Oh, I see. So it's personal?
- No, you intimidate them.
Good God, you're a woman.
I honestly... I couldn't
have called that.
I mean, I'd apologize,
but isn't that what
we're going for here?
- I thought of you
as a soldier first.
I'm an airman.
You have, actually,
excellent bone
structure, there.
I'm kind of having a hard time
not looking at you now.
Is that weird?
Come on, it's okay, laugh.
- Sir, I have a
question to ask.
Yes, please.
Is it true you went 12 for 12...
with last year's
Maxim cover models?
That is an excellent question.
Yes and no.
March and I had a
scheduling conflict,
but fortunately,
the Christmas cover was twins.
Anything else?
You're kidding me...
with the hand up, right?
- Is it cool if I take
a picture with you?
Yes. It's very cool.
All right.
I don't want to see this
on your MySpace page.
Please, no gang signs.
No, throw it up. I'm kidding.
Yeah, peace. I love peace.
I'd be out of a
job with peace.
Come on. Hurry up.
Just click it. Don't
change any settings.
- What's going on?
- Contact left.
What have we got?
Jimmy, stay with Stark.
- Stay down.
- Yeah.
Son of a bitch.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Give me a gun.
Stay here.
Whoa.
Tony Stark.
Visionary. Genius.
American patriot.
Even from an early age,
the son of legendary...
weapons developer
Howard Stark...
quickly stole the spotlight...
with his brilliant
and unique mind.
At age four,
he built his first
circuit board.
At age six, his first engine.
And at 17, he graduated
summa cum laude from MIT.
Then, the passing of a titan.
Howard Stark's lifelong friend
and ally, Obadiah Stane,
steps in to help fill the gap
left by the legendary founder,
until, at age 21, the
prodigal son returns...
and is anointed the new CEO
of Stark Industries.
With the keys to the kingdom.
Tony ushers in a new era
for his father's legacy,
creating smarter weapons,
advanced robotics,
satellite targeting.
Today, Tony Stark has changed...
the face of the
weapons industry...
by ensuring freedom
and protecting America...
and her interests
around the globe.
As liaison to
Stark Industries.
I've had the unique privilege...
of serving with
a real patriot.
He is my friend
and he is my great mentor.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is my honor...
to present this year's
Apogee Award...
to Mr. Tony Stark.
Tony?
- Thank you, Colonel.
- Thanks for the save.
This is beautiful. Thank you.
Thank you all very much.
This is wonderful.
Well, I'm not Tony Stark.
But if I were Tony,
I would tell you how
honored I feel...
and what a joy it is...
to receive this very
prestigious award.
Tony, you know...
The best thing about Tony
is also the worst thing.
He's always working.
Work it. Come on.
- We should just stay
till the morning.
You are unbelievable.
- Oh, no. Did they
rope you into this?
Nobody roped me into anything.
- I'm so sorry.
- But they told me that...
if I presented
you with an award,
you'd be deeply honored.
Of course I'd be
deeply honored.
And it's you, that's great.
- So when do we do it?
- It's right here.
- Here you go.
- There it is. That was easy.
- I'm so sorry.
- Yeah, it's okay.
Wow. Would you look at that?
That's something else.
I don't have any of those
floating around.
We're gonna let it ride.
Give me a hand, will you?
Give me a little s
omething-something.
Okay, you, too.
- I don't blow
on a man's dice.
Come on, honey bear.
There it is.
Lieutenant Colonel
Rhodes rolls. And...
Two craps. Line away.
- That's what happens.
- Worse things have happened.
I think we're gonna be fine.
Color me up, William.
- This is where I exit.
- All right.
Tomorrow, don't be late.
- Yeah, you can count on it.
- I'm serious.
I know, I know.
Render unto Caesar...
that which is
Caesar's. There you go.
Mr. Stark. Excuse
me, Mr. Stark.
Christine Everhart,
Vanity Fair magazine.
Can I ask you a
couple of questions?
- She's cute.
- She's all right?
- Hi.
- Yeah. Okay, go.
- It's okay?
You've been called
the da Vinci of our time.
- What do you say to that?
Absolutely ridiculous.
I don't paint.
And what do you say
to your other nickname?
'The Merchant of Death'?
That's not bad.
- Let me guess. Berkeley?
- Brown, actually.
Well, Ms. Brown,
it's an imperfect world,
but it's the only
one we've got.
I guarantee you, the
day weapons are...
no longer needed
to keep the peace.
I'll start making
bricks and beams...
for baby hospitals.
Rehearse that much?
Every night in front
of the mirror...
before bedtime.
- I can see that.
I'd like to show
you first-hand.
All I want is a
serious answer.
Okay, here's serious.
My old man had a philosophy,
'Peace means having
a bigger stick...
than the other guy.'
That's a great line...
coming from the guy
selling the sticks.
My father helped
defeat the Nazis.
He worked on the
Manhattan Project.
A lot of people,
including your
professors at Brown,
would call that being a hero.
And a lot of people...
would also call that
war profiteering.
Tell me, do you plan to report
on the millions we've saved...
by advancing medical
technology...
or kept from starvation
with our intelli-crops?
All those breakthroughs,
military funding, honey.
You ever lose an hour of sleep
your whole life?
I'd be prepared to
lose a few with you.
Good morning. It's 7:00 a.m.
The weather in Malibu...
is 72 degrees with
scattered clouds.
The surf conditions are fair...
with waist-to-shoulder
high lines.
High tide will
be at 10:52 a.m.
Tony?
Hey, Tony?
You are not authorized
to access this area.
- Jesus.
That's Jarvis. He
runs the house.
I've got your clothes here.
They've been
dry-cleaned and pressed,
and there's a car waiting
for you outside...
that will take you anywhere
you'd like to go.
- You must be the
famous Pepper Potts.
Indeed I am.
After all these years,
Tony still has you...
picking up the dry-cleaning.
I do anything and everything
that Mr. Stark requires,
including, occasionally,
taking out the trash.
Will that be all?
Give me an exploded view.
The compression in
cylinder three...
appears to be low.
Log that.
- I'm gonna try
again, right now.
Please don't turn
down my music.
I'll keep you posted.
You are supposed to be...
halfway around the
world right now.
- How'd she take it?
- Like a champ.
Why are you trying
to hustle me...
out of here?
Your flight was
scheduled to leave...
an hour and a half ago.
That's funny, I thought
with it being...
my plane and all,
that it would just wait for me
to get there.
Tony, I need to speak to you
about a couple things...
before I get you
out of the door.
Doesn't it kind of
defeat the whole...
purpose of having
your own plane...
if it departs
before you arrive?
Larry called. He's
got another buyer...
for the Jackson
Pollock in the wings.
Do you want it? Yes or no.
Is it a good representation
of his spring period?
No. The Springs was actually...
the neighborhood
in East Hampton...
where he lived and worked,
- not 'spring'
like the season.
So?
I think it's a fair example.
I think it's
incredibly overpriced.
I need it. Buy it. Store it.
Okay.
The MIT commencement speech...
Is in June. Please,
don't harangue me...
about stuff that's
way, way, down...
They're haranguing me,
so I'm gonna say yes.
Deflect it and absorb it.
Don't transmit it back to me.
I need you to sign this
before you get on the plane.
What are you trying
to get rid of me for?
What, you got plans?
- As a matter of fact, I do.
I don't like it when
you have plans.
I'm allowed to have plans
on my birthday.
- It's your birthday?
- Yes.
I knew that. Already?
Yeah. Isn't that strange?
It's the same
day as last year.
- Get yourself
something nice from me.
I already did.
- And?
- It was very nice.
- Yeah.
Very tasteful. Thank
you, Mr. Stark.
You're welcome, Miss Potts.
Okay.
You're good.
I thought I lost
you back there.
You did, sir.
I had to cut
across Mulholland.
I got you. I got you.
What's wrong with you?
- What?
- Three hours.
I got caught doing a piece
for Vanity Fair.
For three hours.
For three hours...
you got me standing here.
Waiting on you now.
Let's go. Come on.
Wheels up. Rock and roll.
- What you reading, platypus?
- Nothing.
Come on, sour patch.
Don't be mad.
I told you, I'm not mad.
I'm indifferent, okay?
- I said I was sorry.
- Good morning, Mr. Stark.
You don't need to
apologize to me.
I'm your man.
Hi. I told him I
was sorry, but he...
- I'm just
indifferent right now.
Hot towel?
You don't respect yourself,
- so I know you
don't respect me.
I respect you.
I'm just your babysitter.
So, when you need...
your diaper
changed... Thank you.
Let me know...
and I'll get you
a bottle, okay?
Hey. Heat up the
sake, will you?
- Thanks for reminding me.
- No, I'm not talking...
We're not drinking.
We're working right now.
- You can't have
sashimi without sake.
You are constitutionally...
incapable of
being responsible.
It would be irresponsible
not to drink.
I'm just talking
about a nightcap.
Hot sake?
- Yes, two, please.
No. I'm not drinking.
I don't want any.
That's what I'm talking about.
When I get up in the morning
and I'm putting on my uniform,
you know what I recognize?
I see in that mirror
that every person...
that's got this
uniform on got my back.
Hey, you know what?
I'm not like you.
I'm not cut out...
No, no. You don't
have to be like me.
But you're more
than what you are.
Can you excuse me if
I'm a bit distracted here?
No. You can't be
distracted right now.
Listen to me.
General.
Welcome, Mr. Stark.
We look forward...
to your weapons presentation.
Thanks.
Is it better to be
feared or respected?
I say, is it too much
to ask for both?
With that in mind,
I humbly present
the crown jewel...
of Stark Industries'
Freedom Line.
It's the first
missile system...
to incorporate our proprietary
repulsor technology.
They say the best weapon
is one you never have to fire.
I respectfully disagree.
I prefer the weapon
you only have to fire once.
That's how Dad did it.
That's how America does it.
And it's worked out
pretty well so far.
Find an excuse...
to let one of these
off the chain,
and I personally
guarantee you...
the bad guys won't even want
to come out of their caves.
For your consideration,
the Jericho.
I'll be throwing
one of these in...
with every purchase
of 500 million or more.
To peace.
- Tony.
- Obie, what are you doing up?
I couldn't sleep
till I found out...
how it went. How'd it go?
It went great. Looks
like it's gonna be...
an early Christmas.
Hey. Way to go, my boy.
I'll see you tomorrow, yeah?
Why aren't you
wearing those pajamas
I got you?
Good night, Tony.
- Hey, Tony.
I'm sorry, this
is the 'fun-vee.'
The 'hum-drum-vee'
is back there.
- Nice job.
- See you back at base.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
What the hell
did you do to me?
What I did?
What I did is to
save your life.
I removed all the
shrapnel I could,
but there's a lot left,
and it's headed into
your atrial septum.
Here, want to see?
I have a souvenir.
Take a look.
I've seen many
wounds like that...
in my village.
We call them the
walking dead...
because it takes about a week...
for the barbs to reach
the vital organs.
- What is this?
- That is an electromagnet,
hooked up to a car battery,
and it's keeping the shrapnel
from entering your heart.
That's right. Smile.
We met once, you know,
at a technical
conference in Bern.
- I don't remember.
- No, you wouldn't.
If I had been that drunk,
I wouldn't have
been able to stand,
much less give a lecture
on integrated circuits.
Where are we?
Come on, stand up. Stand up.
Just do as I do.
Come on, put your hands up.
Those are my guns.
How did they get my guns?
Do you understand
me? Do as I do.
He says, 'Welcome, Tony Stark,
the most famous
mass murderer...
'in the history of America.'
He is honored.
He wants you to
build the missile.
The Jericho missile
that you demonstrated.
This one.
I refuse.
Tony.
He wants to know
what you think.
I think you got a
lot of my weapons.
He says they have
everything you need...
to build the Jericho missile.
He wants you to make
the list of materials.
He says for you
to start working immediately,
and when you're done,
he will set you free.
- No, he won't.
I'm sure they're
looking for you, Stark.
But they will never find you
in these mountains.
Look, what you just saw,
that is your legacy, Stark.
Your life's work,
in the hands of
those murderers.
Is that how you
want to go out?
Is this the last
act of defiance...
of the great Tony Stark?
Or are you going to
do something about it?
Why should I do anything?
They're going to kill
me, you, either way.
And if they don't,
I'll probably be
dead in a week.
Well, then,
this is a very
important week for you,
isn't it?
If this is going to
be my work station.
I want it well-lit.
I want these up.
I need welding gear.
I don't care if it's
acetylene or propane.
I need a soldering
station. I need...
helmets. I'm gonna
need goggles.
I would like a smelting cup.
I need two sets of
precision tools.
- How many languages
do you speak?
A lot.
But apparently,
not enough for this place.
They speak Arabic, Urdu.
Dari, Pashto, Mongolian,
Farsi, Russian.
- Who are these people?
They are your loyal
customers, sir.
They call themselves
the Ten Rings.
You know, we might be
more productive...
if you include me
in the planning process.
Okay, we don't need this.
What is that?
That's palladium, 0.15 grams.
We need at least
1.6, so why don't...
you go break down
the other 11?
Careful.
Careful, we only get
one shot at this.
Relax. I have steady hands.
Why do you think
you're still alive?
- What do I call you?
- My name is Yinsen.
Yinsen. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
That doesn't look like
a Jericho missile.
That's because...
it's a miniaturized
arc reactor.
I got a big one
powering my factory at home.
It should keep the shrapnel
out of my heart.
But what could it generate?
If my math is right,
and it always is,
three gigajoules per second.
That could run your heart
for 50 lifetimes.
Yeah. Or something
big for 15 minutes.
- This is our
ticket out of here.
What is it?
Flatten them out and look.
Oh, wow.
Impressive.
Good.
Good roll. Good roll.
You still haven't told me
where you're from.
I'm from a small
town called Gulmira.
- It's actually a nice place.
- Got a family?
Yes, and I will see them
when I leave here.
And you, Stark?
- No.
- No?
So you're a man who
has everything...
and nothing.
Relax.
The bow and arrow...
once was the pinnacle
of weapons technology.
It allowed the great
Genghis Khan...
to rule from the
Pacific to the Ukraine.
An empire twice the size
of Alexander the Great...
and four times
the size of the Roman Empire.
But today,
whoever holds the
latest Stark weapons...
rules these lands.
And soon,
it will be my turn.
What does he want?
What do you want?
A delivery date?
I need him.
Good assistant.
You have till tomorrow
to assemble my missile.
Okay? Can you move?
Okay, say it again.
41 steps straight
ahead. Then 16 steps,
that's from the door,
fork right, 33
steps, turn right.
Yinsen. Yinsen. Stark.
Say something.
Say something back to him.
- He's speaking
Hungarian. I don't...
Then speak Hungarian.
- Okay. I know.
- What do you know?
- How'd that work?
- Oh, my goodness.
- It worked all right.
- That's what I do.
- Let me finish this.
Initialize the power sequence.
Okay.
- Now.
- Tell me. Tell me.
Function 11.
Tell me when you
see a progress bar.
- It should be up right now.
- Yes.
Talk to me. Tell me
when you see it.
- I have it.
- Press Control 'l'.
- 'I.' Got it.
'I.' 'Enter.' 'l' and 'Enter.'
Come over here
and button me up.
Okay. All right.
Every other hex bolt.
- They're coming.
Nothing pretty,
just get it done.
- Just get it done.
- They're coming.
Make sure the
checkpoints are clear...
before you follow
me out, okay?
We need more time.
Hey,
- I'm gonna go
buy you some time.
Stick to the plan.
Yinsen.
- Yinsen.
- Watch out.
Stark.
Come on. We got to go.
Move for me, come
on. We got a plan.
We're gonna stick to it.
This was always
the plan, Stark.
Come on, you're gonna go
see your family. Get up.
My family is dead.
I'm going to see
them now, Stark.
It's okay.
I want this. I want this.
Thank you for saving me.
Don't waste it. Don't
waste your life.
My turn.
Not bad.
Hey.
How was the 'fun-vee'?
Next time, you ride
with me, okay?
Watch it, coming up here.
Are you kidding me with this?
Get rid of them.
Your eyes are red.
A few tears for your
long-lost boss?
- Tears of joy. I
hate job hunting.
Yeah, vacation's over.
Where to, sir?
- Take us to the
hospital, please, Happy.
No.
No? Tony, you have to...
- go to the hospital.
- No is a complete answer.
- The doctor has
to look at you.
I don't have to do anything.
I've been in captivity
for three months.
There are two things
I want to do.
I want an American
cheeseburger,
- and the other...
- That's enough of that.
...is not what you
think. I want you...
to call for a press
conference now.
- Call for a press conference?
- Yeah.
- What on earth for?
Hogan, drive.
Cheeseburger first.
Look at this.
Tony.
- We were going to
meet at the hospital.
No, I'm fine.
Look at you.
- You had to have
a burger, yeah?
Well, come on.
- You get me one of those?
There's only one
left. I need it.
Hey, look who's here. Yeah.
- Miss Potts?
- Yes.
Can I speak to
you for a moment?
I'm not part of the
press conference,
but it's about to
begin right now.
I'm not a reporter.
I'm agent Phil Coulson,
with the Strategic Homeland
Intervention, Enforcement...
and Logistics Division.
- That's quite a mouthful.
- I know. We're working on it.
You know, we've
been approached...
already by the DOD,
the FBI, the CIA...
We're a separate division
with a more specific focus.
We need to debrief Mr. Stark...
about the circumstances
of his escape.
- I'll put something
in the book, shall I?
Thank you.
Hey, would it be all right
if everyone sat down?
Why don't you just sit down?
That way you can
see me, and I can...
A little less formal and...
- What's up with the love-in?
- Don't look at me.
I don't know what he's up to.
- Good to see you.
I never got to say
goodbye to Dad.
goodbye to my father.
There's questions
that I would have asked him.
I would have asked
him how he felt...
about what this company did.
If he was conflicted,
if he ever had doubts.
Or maybe he was
every inch the man...
we all remember
from the newsreels.
I saw young
Americans killed...
by the very weapons I created...
to defend them
and protect them.
And I saw...
that I had become part
of a system that...
is comfortable with
zero accountability.
- Mr. Stark.
- Hey, Ben.
What happened over there?
I had my eyes opened.
I came to realize
that I have more...
to offer this world...
than just making
things that blow up.
And that is why,
effective immediately.
I am shutting down...
the weapons
manufacturing division...
of Stark International...
until such a time
as I can decide...
what the future of
the company will be.
I think we're gonna be selling
a lot of newspapers.
What direction it should take,
one that I'm
comfortable with...
and is consistent with
the highest good...
for this country, as well.
What we should take
away from this...
is that Tony's back.
And he's healthier than ever.
We're going to have...
a little internal
discussion...
and we'll get back to you
with the follow-up.
- Where is he?
- He's inside.
Well, that... That went well.
Did I just paint a target
on the back of my head?
Your head? What about my head?
What do you think
the over-under on...
the stock drop is
gonna be tomorrow?
- Optimistically, 40 points.
- At minimum.
Yep.
Tony, we're a
weapons manufacturer.
Obie, I just don't
want a body count...
to be our only legacy.
That's what we do.
We're iron mongers.
We make weapons.
It's my name on the
side of the building.
And what we do...
keeps the world from
falling into chaos.
Not based on what I saw.
We're not doing a
good enough job.
We can do better.
We're gonna do something else.
Like what?
You want us to
make baby bottles?
I think we should
take another look...
into arc reactor technology.
Come on.
The arc reactor, that's
a publicity stunt.
Tony, come on. We
built that thing...
to shut the hippies up.
- It works.
- Yeah, as a science project.
The arc was never
cost effective.
We knew that before
we built it.
Arc reactor technology,
that's a dead end, right?
Maybe.
Am I right? We haven't had...
a breakthrough
in that in what?
- Thirty years.
- That's what they say.
Could you have a
lousier poker face?
Just tell me, who told you?
- Never mind who
told me. Show me.
It's Rhodey or Pepper.
- I want to see it.
- Okay, Rhodey.
- Okay.
- Okay?
It works.
Listen to me,
Tony. We're a team.
Do you understand?
There's nothing we can't do
if we stick together,
like your father and I.
I'm sorry I didn't give you
a heads-up, okay?
- But if I had...
- Tony.
Tony, no more of this
'ready, fire, aim' business.
- You understand me?
- That was Dad's line.
You gotta let me handle this.
We're gonna have to play...
a whole different
kind of ball now.
We're going to have
to take a lot of heat.
I want you to promise me
that you're gonna lay low.
Stark Industries.
I've got one recommendation.
Ready? Ready?
Sell, sell, sell.
Abandon ship.
Does the Hindenburg
ring any bells?
Let me show you the new
Stark Industries
business plan.
Look, that's a weapons company
that doesn't make weapons.
Pepper. How big
are your hands?
- What?
- How big are your hands?
- I don't understand why...
- Get down here. I need you.
Hey.
Let's see them.
Show me your hands.
Oh, wow. They are small.
Very petite, indeed.
I just need your
help for a sec.
Oh, my God, is that the thing
that's keeping you alive?
It was. It is now an antique.
This is what will be
keeping me alive...
for the foreseeable future.
I'm swapping it up
for an upgraded unit,
and I just ran into
a little speed bump.
- Speed bump, what
does that mean?
It's nothing. It's
just a little snag.
There's an exposed wire
under this device.
And it's contacting
the socket wall...
and causing a little
bit of a short.
It's fine.
- What do you want me to do?
Put that on the
table over there.
- That is irrelevant.
- Oh, my God.
I want you to reach
in, and you're just...
gonna gently lift
the wire out.
- Is it safe?
- Yeah, it should be fine.
It's like Operation.
You just don't let it touch...
the socket wall or
it goes 'beep.'
- What do you
mean, 'Operation'?
It's just a game, never mind.
- Just gently lift
the wire. Okay? Great.
Okay.
You know, I don't think
that I'm qualified to do this.
No, you're fine.
You're the most
capable, qualified,
trustworthy person
I've ever met.
You're gonna do great.
Is it too much of
a problem to ask?
'Cause I'm...
- Okay, okay.
I really need your help here.
Okay.
Oh, there's pus.
It's not pus. It's
an inorganic...
plasmic discharge
from the device,
- not from my body.
- It smells.
Yeah, it does.
The copper wire.
The copper wire, you got it?
- Okay, I got it. I got it.
- Okay, you got it?
Now, don't let it
touch the sides...
when you're coming out.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
That's what
I was trying to
tell you before.
Okay, now make sure...
that when you pull
it out, you don't...
There's a magnet
at the end of it.
That was it. You
just pulled it out.
- Oh, God.
- Okay, I was not expecting...
- Don't put it back in.
Don't put it back in.
Okay, what do I do?
What's wrong?
Nothing,
I'm just going into
cardiac arrest...
'cause you yanked it
out like a trout...
- What? You said it was safe.
We gotta hurry. Take
this. Take this.
- You gotta switch
it out really quick.
Okay. Okay.
- Tony? It's going to be okay.
- What?
- Is it?
- It's gonna be okay.
- I'm gonna make this okay.
- Let's hope.
Okay, you're gonna attach that...
to the base plate.
Make sure you...
Was that so hard?
That was fun, right?
Here, I got it.
I got it. Here.
Nice.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I feel great.
You okay?
Don't ever, ever, ever,
ever ask me to do
anything like that ever again.
I don't have anyone but you.
Anyway...
- What do you want
me to do with this?
That?
Destroy it.
Incinerate it.
You don't want to keep it?
Pepper, I've been
called many things.
'Nostalgic' is
not one of them.
- Will that be all, Mr. Stark?
That will be all, Miss Potts.
Hey, Butterfingers, come here.
What's all this stuff
doing on top of my desk?
That's my phone,
that's a picture
of me and my dad.
Right there. In the garbage.
All that stuff.
The future of air combat.
Is it manned or unmanned?
I'll tell you, in
my experience,
no unmanned aerial vehicle...
will ever trump a
pilot's instinct,
his insight,
that ability to look...
into a situation
beyond the obvious...
and discern its outcome,
or a pilot's judgment.
Colonel?
Why not a pilot
without the plane?
Look who fell out of the sky.
Mr. Tony Stark.
- Hello, sir.
Speaking of manned
or unmanned,
you gotta get him to tell you...
about the time he
guessed wrong...
at spring break.
Just remember that,
spring break, 1987.
- That lovely lady
you woke up with.
Don't do that.
- What was his name?
- Don't do that.
- Was it lvan?
They'll believe
it. Don't do that.
- Okay.
- Don't do that.
- Pleasure meeting you.
Give us a couple
minutes, you guys.
- I'm surprised.
- Why?
I swear, I didn't
expect to see you...
walking around so soon.
I'm doing a little
better than walking.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Rhodey, I'm working
on something big.
I came to talk to you.
I want you to be a part of it.
You're about to make a whole...
lot of people around
here real happy,
'cause that little stunt
at the press conference,
that was a doozy.
This is not for the
military. I'm not...
It's different.
What? You're a
humanitarian now...
or something?
- I need you to listen to me.
- No.
What you need is time
to get your mind right.
- I'm serious.
- Okay.
It's nice seeing you, Tony.
Thanks.
- Jarvis, you up?
- For you, sir, always.
I'd like to open a
new project file,
index as Mark Two.
Shall I store this on...
the Stark Industries
Central Database?
Actually, I don't know
who to trust right now.
Till further notice,
why don't we just...
keep everything on
my private server?
Working on a secret project,
are we, sir?
I don't want this winding up
in the wrong hands.
Maybe in mine,
it can actually do some good.
Next. Up.
Not in the boot,
Dummy. Right here.
You got me?
Stay put. Nice.
You're of no benefit at all.
Move down to the
toe. I got this.
Okay, I'm sorry,
am I in your way?
Up.
Screw it. Don't even move.
You are a tragedy.
Okay, let's do this right.
Start mark, half a meter,
and back and center.
Dummy, look alive.
You're on standby
for fire safety.
You, roll it.
Okay. Activate hand controls.
We're gonna start
off nice and easy.
We're gonna see if...
10% thrust capacity
achieves lift.
And three,
two,
one.
Up two. All right, set that.
I've been buzzing you.
Did you hear the intercom?
Yeah, everything's... What?
- Obadiah's upstairs.
- Great.
- What would you
like me to tell him?
Great. I'll be right up.
Okay.
I thought you said
you were done making weapons.
It is.
This is a flight stabilizer.
It's completely harmless.
I didn't expect that.
How'd it go?
It went that bad, huh?
Just because I brought pizza
back from New York...
- doesn't mean it went bad.
- Sure doesn't. Oh, boy.
It would have gone better
if you were there.
You told me to lay low.
That's what I've been doing.
- I lay low, and you
take care of all...
Hey, come on. In
public. The press.
- This was a board of
directors meeting.
This was a board of
directors meeting?
The board is claiming
you have posttraumatic stress.
They're filing an injunction.
- A what?
- They want to lock you out.
Why, 'cause the stocks
dipped 40 points?
We knew that was gonna happen.
- Fifty-six and a half.
- It doesn't matter.
We own the controlling
interest...
in the company.
Tony, the board
has rights, too.
They're making the case...
that you and your
new direction...
- isn't in the
company's best interest.
I'm being responsible.
That's a new direction for me,
for the company.
I mean, me on the
company's behalf...
being responsible
for the way that...
This is great.
- Oh, come on. Tony. Tony.
- I'll be in the shop.
Hey, hey. Hey, Tony. Listen.
I'm trying to turn
this thing around,
but you gotta give
me something.
Something to pitch them.
Let me have the
engineers analyze that.
You know, draw up some specs.
- No. No, absolutely not.
It'll give me a bone
to throw the boys...
- in New York.
- This one stays with me.
- That's it, Obie. Forget it.
All right, well, this
stays with me, then.
Go on, here, you
can have a piece.
- Take two.
- Thank you.
You mind if I come down there
and see what you're doing?
Good night, Obie.
Day 11, test 37,
configuration 2.0.
For lack of a better option.
Dummy is still on fire safety.
If you douse me again,
and I'm not on fire,
I'm donating you
to a city college.
All right, nice and easy.
Seriously, just
gonna start off...
with 1% thrust capacity.
And three, two, one.
Okay.
Please don't follow me around
with it, either,
'cause I feel like I'm gonna
catch on fire spontaneously.
Just stand down.
If something happens,
then come in.
And again, let's
bring it up to 2.5.
Three, two, one.
Okay, this is where
I don't want to be.
Not the car, not the car.
Table.
Could be worse.
We're fine. Okay.
No.
Yeah, I can fly.
- Jarvis, are you there?
- At your service, sir.
- Engage Heads Up Display.
- Check.
Import all preferences
from home interface.
Will do, sir.
All right, what do you say?
I have indeed been
uploaded, sir.
We're online and ready.
Can we start the
virtual walk-around?
Importing preferences...
and calibrating
virtual environment.
Do a check on
control surfaces.
As you wish.
Test complete. Preparing to...
power down and
begin diagnostics.
Yeah. Tell you what.
Do a weather and ATC check.
Start listening in
on ground control.
Sir, there are
still terabytes...
of calculations needed
before an actual flight is...
Jarvis. Sometimes
you got to run...
before you can walk.
Ready? In three, two, one.
Handles like a dream.
All right, let's see what
this thing can do.
What's SR-71's record?
The altitude record for
fixed wing flight...
is 85,000 feet, sir.
Records are made to be broken.
Come on.
Sir, there is a
potentially fatal...
buildup of ice occurring.
Keep going.
Higher.
We iced up, Jarvis.
Deploy flaps. Jarvis.
Come on, we got
to break the ice.
Kill power.
Notes. Main transducer
feels sluggish...
at plus 40 altitude.
Hull pressurization
is problematic.
I'm thinking icing is
the probable factor.
A very astute
observation, sir.
Perhaps, if you intend
to visit other planets,
we should improve
the exosystems.
Connect to the sys. co.
Have it reconfigure
the shell metals.
Use the gold titanium
alloy from...
the seraphim
tactical satellite.
That should ensure a
fuselage integrity...
while maintaining
power-to-weight ratio.
- Got it?
- Yes.
Shall I render
using proposed specifications?
Thrill me.
Tonight's red-hot red
carpet is right...
here at the Disney
Concert Hall,
where Tony Stark's
third annual benefit...
for the Firefighter's
Family Fund...
has become the place to be
for L.A.'s high society.
Jarvis, we get an
invite for that?
I have no record of
an invitation, sir.
...hasn't been
seen in public...
since his bizarre and highly...
controversial
press conference.
Some claim he's suffering
from posttraumatic stress...
and has been
bedridden for weeks.
Whatever the case may be,
no one expects an appearance
from him tonight.
The render is complete.
A little ostentatious,
don't you think?
What was I thinking?
You're usually so discreet.
Tell you what.
Throw a little
hot-rod red in there.
Yes, that should help you
keep a low profile.
The render is complete.
Hey, I like it.
Fabricate it. Paint it.
Commencing automated assembly.
Estimated completion
time is five hours.
Don't wait up for me, honey.
Weapons manufacturing is only...
one small part of what
Stark Industries...
is all about, and
our partnership...
with the fire and
rescue community...
- Hey, Tony, remember me?
- Sure don't.
You look great, Hef.
We're going to have
a great quarter.
What's the world
coming to when...
a guy's got to
crash his own party?
Look at you. Hey,
what a surprise.
I'll see you inside.
Hey. Listen, take
it slow, all right?
I think I got the board
right where we want them.
You got it. Just cabin fever.
I'll just be a minute.
- Give me a Scotch.
I'm starving.
Mr. Stark?
- Yeah?
- Agent Coulson.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
The guy from the...
Strategic Homeland
Intervention.
Enforcement and
Logistics Division.
God, you need a
new name for that.
Yeah, I hear that a lot.
Listen, I know this must
be a trying time...
for you, but we need
to debrief you.
There's still
a lot of unanswered questions,
and time can be a factor
with these things.
Let's just put
something on the books.
How about the
24th at 7:00 p.m.
at Stark Industries?
Tell you what.
You got it. You're
absolutely right.
Well, I'm going to
go to my assistant,
and we'll make a date.
You look fantastic.
I didn't recognize you.
- What are you doing here?
Just avoiding
government agents.
- Are you by yourself?
Yes. Where'd you
get that dress?
- Oh, it was a
birthday present.
That's great.
- From you, actually.
- Well, I got great taste.
Yes.
- You want to dance?
- Oh, no.
- All right, come on.
- Thank you. No.
Am I making you uncomfortable?
No. No. I always
forget to wear...
deodorant and dance
with my boss...
in front of everyone
that I work with...
in a dress with no back.
- You look great
and you smell great.
Oh, God.
But I could fire
you if that would...
take the edge off.
I actually don't think that...
you could tie your
shoes without me.
- I'd make it a week. Sure.
- Really?
What's your Social
Security number?
- Five.
- Five?
- Right.
You're missing just
a couple of digits there.
The other eight?
So I got you for
the other eight.
- How about a little air?
- Yes, I need some air.
- That was totally weird.
- Totally harmless.
It was totally not
harmless, by the way.
We're dancing. No
one's even watching.
Everybody who I work with...
No, you know why?
I think you lost
objectivity. I think...
they just... People...
We just danced.
No, it was not just
a dance. You don't...
understand because you're you.
And everybody knows
exactly who you are...
and how you are with girls...
and all of that, which
is completely fine.
But, you know, then
me, you're my boss,
- and I'm dancing with you.
I don't think it
was taken that way.
Because it makes me look like
the one who's trying to...
- I just think you're
overstating it.
You know, and we're here,
and then I'm wearing
this ridiculous...
dress, and then we
were dancing...
like that and...
- I would like
a drink, please.
Got it, okay.
- I would like a
vodka martini, please.
Okay.
Very dry with olives,
a lot of olives.
Like, at least three olives.
Two vodka martinis, extra dry,
extra olives, extra fast.
Make one of them
dirty, will you?
Wow. Tony Stark.
- Oh, hey.
- Fancy seeing you here.
- Carrie.
- Christine.
That's right.
You have a lot of nerve
showing up here tonight.
Can I at least get
a reaction from you?
Panic. I would say
panic is my reaction.
'Cause I was referring
to your company's...
involvement in this
latest atrocity.
Yeah. They just put
my name on the...
invitation. I don't
know what to tell you.
I actually almost bought it,
hook, line and sinker.
I was out of town
for a couple months,
in case you didn't hear.
Is this what you
call accountability?
It's a town called
Gulmira. Heard of it?
- When were these taken?
- Yesterday.
- I didn't approve
any shipment.
Well, your company did.
Well, I'm not my company.
- Please, do you mind?
Have you seen these pictures?
- What's going on in Gulmira?
- Tony, Tony.
- You can't afford
to be this naive.
You know what? I
was naive before,
when they said,
'Here's the line.
We don't cross it.
'This is how we do business.'
If we're double-dealing
under the table...
Are we?
Tony, your picture, please.
Let's take a picture. Come on.
Picture time.
Tony. Who do you
think locked you out?
I was the one who filed
the injunction against you.
It was the only way
I could protect you.
No. No.
The 15-mile hike to
the outskirts...
of Gulmira can only
be described...
as a descent into hell,
into a modern day
Heart of Darkness.
Simple farmers and herders
from peaceful villages...
have been driven
from their homes,
displaced from their
lands by warlords...
emboldened by a
new-found power.
Villagers have been
forced to take...
shelter in whatever
crude dwellings...
they can find in the ruins
of other villages,
or here in the remnants...
of an old Soviet
smelting plant.
Recent violence has
been attributed...
to a group of
foreign fighters...
referred to by locals
as the Ten Rings.
As you can see, these men are...
heavily armed
and on a mission.
A mission that
could prove fatal...
to anyone who stands
in their way.
With no political will
or international pressure,
there's very little hope
for these refugees.
Around me, a woman
begging for news...
on her husband,
who was kidnapped
by insurgents,
either forced to join
their militia...
Desperate refugees clutch
yellowed photographs,
holding them up to anyone
who will stop.
A child's simple question,
'Where are my
mother and father?'
There's very little hope
for these refugees,
refugees who can
only wonder who,
if anyone, will help.
He's all yours.
What the hell was that?
Were we cleared
to go in there?
No, they were using
human shields.
We never got the green light.
Put me through to State.
They're going to
be all over this.
Get those monitors up.
We got a bogey.
- Wasn't Air Force.
- We got the CIA on the line?
I've got Langley on the line.
They want to know if it's us.
No, it definitely
is not us, sir.
- It wasn't Navy.
- Wasn't Marines.
I need answers.
Can I please get
eyes on target?
- Negative, negative.
- Cannot identify.
Get me Colonel Rhodes from
Weapons Development
down here now.
We ran an ID check
and cross-referenced...
with all known databases.
We have nothing.
Any high altitude surveillance
in the region?
We got an AWAC
and a Global Hawk in the area.
So this thing just appeared
out of nowhere?
How come it didn't show up
on the radar?
Got a minimal radar
cross-section, sir.
- Is it stealth?
- No, sir, it's tiny.
We think it's an unmanned
aerial vehicle.
Colonel, what are we
dealing with here?
- Let me make a call.
- Sergeant, clear a hole.
- Hello?
- Tony?
- Who's this?
- It's Rhodes.
- Sorry, hello?
- I said it's Rhodes.
- Speak up, please.
What in the hell
is that noise?
- Oh, yeah, I'm driving
with the top down.
Yeah, well, I need
your help right now.
It's funny how
that works, huh?
Yeah. Speaking of
funny, we've got a...
weapons depot that
was just blown up...
a few clicks from where
you were being held captive.
Well, that's a hot spot.
Sounds like someone stepped in
and did your job for you, huh?
Why do you sound
out of breath, Tony?
I'm not, I was just
jogging in the canyon.
- I thought you were driving.
- Right, I was driving...
to the canyon, where
I'm going to jog.
You sure you don't
have any tech...
in that area I
should know about?
- Nope.
- Bogey spotted.
- Whiplash, come in hot.
Okay, good, 'cause
I'm staring at one...
right now, and it's
about to be blown...
to kingdom come.
That's my exit.
Ballroom, this
is Whiplash One.
I've got the bogey
in my sights.
Whiplash One, what is it?
I've got no idea.
- You have radio contact?
- Non responsive, sir.
Then you are clear to engage.
Hit it.
That bogey just
went supersonic.
I got a lock.
- Inbound missile.
- Flares.
Wait a second. Bogey
deployed flares.
Deploy flaps.
Holy.
That thing just jumped
off the radar, sir.
The sat visual has been lost.
No way that's a UAV.
What is it?
I can't see anything.
Whatever it was, it
just bought the farm.
I think bogey's
been handled, sir.
- Hello?
- Hi, Rhodey, it's me.
- It's who?
- I'm sorry, it is me.
You asked.
What you were
asking about is me.
No, see, this isn't a game.
You do not send
civilian equipment...
into my active war zone.
- You understand that?
This is not a
piece of equipment.
I'm in it. It's
a suit. It's me.
Rhodey, you got
anything for me?
- Mark your position
and return to base.
Roger that, Ballroom.
On your belly.
It looks like a man.
Shake him off. Roll. Roll.
I'm hit. I'm hit.
It's confirmed.
He has been hit.
Punch out. Punch out.
Whiplash One down.
Whiplash Two, do
you see a chute?
Negative. No chute, no chute.
My chute's jammed.
Sir, I've got a
visual on the bogey.
Whiplash Two, reengage.
If you get a clear
shot, you take it.
Major, we don't even know
what we're shooting at.
- Call off the Raptors.
That thing just
took out an F-22...
inside a legal no fly zone.
Whiplash Two,
if you have a clear
shot, take it.
You've been reengaged.
Execute evasive maneuver.
Keep going.
Good chute. Good chute.
- Tony, you still there?
- Hey, thanks.
Oh, my God, you
crazy son of a bitch.
You owe me a plane.
You know that, right?
Yeah, well,
technically, he hit me.
Now are you going to come by
and see what I'm working on?
No, no, no, no, no, no,
the less I know, the better.
Now, what am I supposed
to tell the press?
Training exercise.
Isn't that the usual BS?
It's not that simple.
An unfortunate
training exercise...
involving an F-22 Raptor
occurred yesterday.
I am pleased to report...
that the pilot
was not injured.
As for the unexpected
turn of events...
on the ground in Gulmira,
it is still unclear
who or what intervened,
but I can assure
you that the United
States government
was not involved.
Hey.
It is a tight fit, sir.
Sir, the more you struggle,
the more this is
going to hurt.
Be gentle. This
is my first time.
I designed this to
come off, so... Hey.
- I really should
be able to...
Please, try not to move, sir.
What's going on here?
Let's face it. This
is not the worst...
thing you've caught me doing.
Are those bullet holes?
Welcome.
Compliments of Tony Stark.
If you'd killed him
when you were...
supposed to, you'd
still have a face.
You paid us trinkets
to kill a prince.
Show me the weapon.
Come. Leave your
guards outside.
His escape bore
unexpected fruit.
So this is how he did it.
This is only a
first, crude effort.
Stark has perfected
his design.
He has made a
masterpiece of death.
A man with a dozen of these
can rule all of Asia.
And you dream of
Stark's throne.
We have a common enemy.
If we are still in business.
I will give you
these designs...
as a gift.
And in turn.
I hope you'll repay me with
a gift of iron soldiers.
Technology.
It's always been your
Achilles' heel...
in this part of the world.
Don't worry. It'll only
last for 15 minutes.
That's the least
of your problems.
Crate up the armor
and the rest of it.
All right, let's
finish up here.
Set up Sector 16
underneath the arc reactor,
and I'm going to want
this data masked.
Recruit our top engineers.
I want a prototype right away.
Hey. You busy?
You mind if I send
you on an errand?
I need you to go to my office.
You're going to hack
into the mainframe...
and you're going
to retrieve all...
the recent shipping manifests.
This is a lock chip.
This'll get you in.
It's probably under
Executive Files.
If not, they put it
on a ghost drive,
in which case you need...
to look for the lowest
numeric heading.
And what do you
plan to do with...
this information if
I bring it back here?
Same drill.
They've been dealing
under the table,
and I'm going to stop them.
I'm going to find my weapons
and destroy them.
Tony,
you know that
I would help you
with anything,
but I cannot help you if...
you're going to start
all of this again.
There is nothing except this.
There's no art opening.
There is no benefit.
There is nothing to sign.
There is the next mission
and nothing else.
Is that so?
Well, then, I quit.
You stood by my side
all these years...
while I reaped
the benefits of destruction.
And now that I'm trying
to protect the people...
that I put in harm's way,
you're going to walk out?
You're going to kill
yourself, Tony.
I'm not going to
be a part of it.
I shouldn't be alive,
unless it was for a reason.
I'm not crazy, Pepper.
I just finally know
what I have to do.
And I know in my
heart that it's right.
You're all I have,
too, you know.
Sector 16?
What are you up to, Obadiah?
You did not tell us
that the target you...
paid us to kill was
the great Tony Stark.
- As you can see,
Obadiah Stane...
Oh, my God.
...your deception and lies
will cost you dearly.
The price to kill Tony Stark
has just gone up.
So, what are we going
to do about this?
I know what you're
going through.
Pepper.
Tony. He always gets
the good stuff,
doesn't he?
I was so happy
when he came home.
It was like we got him back
from the dead.
Now I realize,
well, Tony never really did
come home, did he?
He left a part of
himself in that cave.
Breaks my heart.
Well, he's a
complicated person.
He's been through a lot.
I think he'll be all right.
You are a very rare woman.
Tony doesn't know
how lucky he is.
Thank you. Thanks.
I'd better get back there.
Is that today's paper?
Yes.
Do you mind?
- Not at all.
- Puzzle.
Of course.
Take care.
Ms. Potts? We had
an appointment.
Did you forget about
our appointment?
Nope, right now. Come with me.
- Right now?
We're going to
have it right now.
- Yeah, walk with me.
- Okay.
I'm going to give
you the meeting...
of your life. Your office.
Yeah, we've been working
our best to do it.
Absolutely, we're...
I'm going to have
to call you back.
Mr. Stane? Sir,
we've explored...
what you've asked
us, and it seems...
as though there's
a little hiccup.
- Actually...
- A hiccup?
Yes, to power the suit, sir,
the technology actually
doesn't exist.
- So it's...
Wait, wait, wait.
The technology?
William, here is
the technology.
I've asked you to
simply make it smaller.
Okay, sir, and that's
what we're trying...
to do, but honestly,
it's impossible.
Tony Stark was able
to build this...
in a cave. With
a box of scraps.
Well, I'm sorry.
I'm not Tony Stark.
Tony?
Tony, are you there? Hello?
Breathe.
Easy, easy.
You remember this one, right?
It's a shame the government
didn't approve it.
There's so many applications...
for causing
short-term paralysis.
Tony.
When I ordered the hit on you.
I worried that I was...
killing the golden goose.
But, you see, it was just...
fate that you survived that.
You had one last
golden egg to give.
Do you really think
that just because...
you have an idea,
it belongs to you?
Your father, he helped give us
the atomic bomb.
Now, what kind of
world would it be...
today if he was as
selfish as you?
Oh, it's beautiful.
Tony, this is your
Ninth Symphony.
What a masterpiece.
Look at that.
This is your legacy.
A new generation of weapons
with this at its heart.
Weapons that will help
steer the world...
back on course,
put the balance of
power in our hands.
The right hands.
I wish you could've
seen my prototype.
It's not as...
Well, not as
conservative as yours.
Too bad you had to
involve Pepper...
in this.
I would have preferred
that she lived.
What do you mean,
he paid to have Tony killed?
Pepper, slow down.
Why would Obadiah...
Okay, where's Tony now?
I don't know.
He's not answering his phone.
Please go over there...
and make sure
everything's okay.
Thank you, Rhodey.
I know a shortcut.
Good boy.
Tony?
Tony.
Tony. You okay?
- Where's Pepper?
She's fine. She's
with five agents.
They're about to
arrest Obadiah.
That's not going to be enough.
Section 16. Section
16. There it is.
My key's not working.
It's not opening the door.
Oh, wow. What's that?
It's, like, a little device?
It's, like, a thing
that's going...
to pick the lock?
You might want to take
a few steps back.
That's the coolest
thing I've ever seen.
Not bad, huh? Let's do it.
You need me to do
anything else?
Keep the skies clear.
Damn.
Next time, baby.
Looks like you were right.
He was building a suit.
I thought it'd be bigger.
How do you think the Mark One...
chest piece is
going to hold up?
The suit's at 48%
power and falling, sir.
That chest piece...
was never designed
for sustained flight.
Keep me posted.
Pepper.
- Tony. Tony, are you okay?
- I'm fine. How are...
- Obadiah, he's gone insane.
- I know.
- Listen, you'd better
get out of there.
He built a suit.
Get out of there right now.
Where do you think
you're going?
Your services are
no longer required.
Stane.
I love this suit.
- Put them down.
- Collateral damage, Tony.
Divert power to chest RT.
Power reduced to 19%.
Lady.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
For 30 years, I've
been holding you up.
I built this company
from nothing.
Nothing is going to
stand in my way.
Least of all you.
Impressive.
You've upgraded your armor.
I've made some
upgrades of my own.
Sir, it appears that
his suit can fly.
Duly noted.
Take me to maximum altitude.
With only 15% power,
the odds of reaching that...
I know the math. Do it.
Sir, you're not going
to believe this.
That thing is back.
Get me Major Allen.
Scramble the jets.
Not necessary, people.
Just a training exercise.
Yes, sir.
- Thirteen percent power, sir.
- Climb.
- Eleven percent.
- Keep going.
- Seven percent power.
- Just leave it on the screen.
Stop telling me.
You had a great
idea, Tony, but my...
suit is more advanced
in every way.
How'd you solve
the icing problem?
Icing problem?
Might want to look into it.
Two percent.
We are now running
on emergency backup power.
- Potts.
Tony. Oh, my God,
are you okay?
I'm almost out of power.
I've got to get...
out of this thing.
I'll be right there.
Nice try.
- Weapons status?
Repulsors offline.
Missiles offline.
Flares.
Very clever, Tony.
- Potts?
- Tony.
This isn't working.
We're going to have
to overload...
the reactor and
blast the roof.
- Well, how are you
going to do that?
You're going to do it.
Go to the central console,
open up all the circuits.
When I get clear of the roof,
I'll let you know.
You're going to hit
the master bypass button.
It's going to fry
everything up here.
Okay. I'm going in now.
Make sure you wait
till I clear the roof.
I'll buy you some time.
This looks important.
I never had a taste
for this sort of thing,
but I must admit,
I'm deeply enjoying the suit.
You finally outdid
yourself, Tony.
You'd have made
your father proud.
It's ready, Tony.
Get off the roof.
Tony.
How ironic, Tony.
Trying to rid the
world of weapons,
you gave it its best one ever.
- Pepper.
And now I'm going to
kill you with it.
- You ripped out my
targeting system.
Time to hit the button.
- You told me not to.
Hold still, you little prick.
- Just do it.
- You'll die.
Push it.
Tony.
You've all received
the official...
statement of what occurred...
at Stark Industries
last night.
There have been
unconfirmed reports...
that a robotic prototype
malfunctioned...
and caused damage
to the arc reactor.
Fortunately, a member...
of Tony Stark's personal
security staff...
'Iron Man.' That's
kind of catchy.
It's got a nice ring to it.
I mean, it's not
technically accurate.
The suit's a
gold-titanium alloy,
but it's kind of evocative,
the imagery, anyway.
Here's your alibi.
Okay.
- You were on your yacht.
- Yeah.
We have port papers
that put you...
in Avalon all night,
and sworn statements
from 50 of your guests.
See, I was thinking
maybe we should...
say it was just
Pepper and me...
alone on the island.
- That's what happened.
- All right.
Just read it, word for word.
There's nothing
about Stane here.
That's being handled.
He's on vacation.
Small aircraft have
such a poor safety record.
But what about the
whole cover story...
that it's a bodyguard?
He's my... I mean, is that...
That's kind of flimsy,
don't you think?
This isn't my first
rodeo, Mr. Stark.
Just stick to the
official statement,
and soon, this will
all be behind you.
You've got 90 seconds.
Agent Coulson?
I just wanted to say
thank you very much...
for all of your help.
That's what we do.
You'll be hearing from us.
- From the Strategic
Homeland...
Just call us S.H.I.E.L.D.
Right.
- Let's get this
show on the road.
You know, it's
actually not that bad.
Even I don't think
I'm Iron Man.
- You're not Iron Man.
- Am so.
- You're not.
- All right, suit yourself.
You know, if I were
Iron Man, I'd have...
this girlfriend who
knew my true identity.
She'd be a wreck,
'cause she'd always...
be worrying that I
was going to die,
yet so proud of
the man I'd become.
She'd be wildly conflicted,
which would only
make her more...
crazy about me.
Tell me you never
think about that night.
- What night?
- You know.
Are you talking about
the night that...
we danced and went
up on the roof,
and then you went downstairs
to get me a drink,
and you left me
there, by myself?
Is that the night
you're talking about?
Thought so.
- Will that be all, Mr. Stark?
Yes, that will be
all, Miss Potts.
And now, Mr. Stark has
prepared a statement.
He will not be taking
any questions.
Thank you.
Been a while since I
was in front of you.
I figure I'll stick to
the cards this time.
There's been speculation
that I was...
involved in the events
that occurred...
on the freeway
and the rooftop...
I'm sorry, Mr.
Stark, but do you...
honestly expect us
to believe that...
that was a bodyguard...
in a suit that
conveniently appeared,
- despite the fact that you...
- I know that it's confusing.
It is one thing to
question the official...
story, and another
thing entirely...
to make wild accusations,
or insinuate that
I'm a superhero.
I never said you
were a superhero.
Didn't? Well, good,
because that would...
be outlandish and fantastic.
I'm just not the
hero type. Clearly.
With this laundry list
of character defects,
all the mistakes I've made,
- largely public.
Just stick to the cards, man.
Yeah, okay. Yeah.
The truth is
I am Iron Man.
Jarvis.
Welcome home, sir.
'I am Iron Man.'
You think you're...
the only superhero
in the world?
Mr. Stark, you've become part
of a bigger universe.
You just don't know it yet.
Who the hell are you?
Nick Fury, Director
of S.H.I.E.L.D.
I'm here to talk to you
about the Avenger Initiative.
Watch full movies online for free at www.awooh.com