In the days before the event,
he had the whole world
wondering if he would show up.
While he napped
or took walks
and ate sandwiches.
Henry Kissinger called
and asked him to go
for his country's honor.
Soon after arriving,
he offended the Icelanders
by calling their country
inadequate
because they had
no bowling alleys.
He complained
about the TV cameras,
about the lighting,
about the table and chairs,
and the contrast of
the squares on the board.
His hotel room, he said,
Had too nice a view.
None of this had anything
to do with chess, of course...
or maybe it did.
If he won,
he'd be the first
American world champion in history.
If he lost,
he'd just be another
patzer from Brooklyn.
On the 40th move
Of the 21st game,
he countered
Spassky's bishop to king-6
with a pawn to rook-4.
And it was all over.
He came home An American hero.
He bragged to the world
he'd beat the Russians.
He delivered.
He can now command
The same money
as heavy weight prize fighters.
He was invited to dinner
By statesmen and kings.
Then Bobby Fischer made the most
original, unexpected move of all.
He disappeared.
Where is he?
Maybe he gave up.
Shh.
Do you see anything?
I think we lost him.
It's cold. Let's go home.
If he doesn't find us
in two hours,
I say we go.
Hello, boys.
Aah!
Theo, what are you doing here?
I thought you wanted to go home.
I have to buckle
my own shoes, right?
You said something
about rolling on your own side
of the board, right?
This is my side.
Remember that?
Roll it on your own side.
You talk too much.
Josh?
Your move.
Josh!
That's good.
Well, there you go.
Not too much, but that's good.
A little more.
Yeah. That's good.
You got to be careful
not to use it too much,
but you want just enough.
A little more.
That's great.
O.K.
That looks pretty good.
How's that look to you?
Pretty good.
Good.
Now rub that in there.
See how the leather
drinks that up?
That's got a great smell, huh?
Smell that.
Yeah. Great. O.K.
Now...
Ohh.
What's wrong?
I forgot to buy a ball.
Do you believe it?
You got to put a ball
in the pocket.
A hard ball...
to get the shape right.
Yeah.
That'll work.
O.K.
Put that in like that...
bend that over.
All right.
Get in bed.
Tomorrow I buy a real baseball.
You know what?
I don't believe this.
I can't believe it.
What?
You're 7.
Happy birthday.
Good night, Josh.
Good night.
Josh!
Bye.
How was school?
Good.
O.K. Bye.
Bye. See ya.
How you doing?
Fine. Bye.
Bye-bye. See ya.
Are you in the mood
for some pizza?
I don't know.
Are you?
Are you feeling all right?
Yeah. Why?
Where we going to get pizza?
You want to go watch the men
in the park?
What men in the park?
I'm going to smack
this guy's ass, man.
There's fire in the bush.
It ain't over.
We still got a minute.
When it slaps 12:00,
then it's over.
Then it's over.
We playing chess.
What we playing here?
Now we playing chess.
Come on, Josh, let's go.
Is that the best you got?
That's the best you got?
You ain't got nothing.
You sure
you've played this game?
You want to go to Chinatown
and play Chinese checkers?
No, that ain't it.
You want that? O.K.
You can have that.
But you can't have that.
That's my baby.
You got to leave with that.
You can't trade queens with me.
I ain't in the trading business.
What you trying to do?
You're going to have
to do better than that.
That's Kamran Shirazi.
That's Kamran Shirazi, man.
Shirazi!
The Grandmaster's here.
You come to hustle the hustler.
Don't look at my clock.
My time is fine.
I want to go home.
Come and take my money.
Let's go, Josh.
Come on, Grandmaster.
Show me something.
All right.
Check to his majesty.
No, no. Back up.
Check yourself
before you wreck yourself.
You can't have it.
Mmm. Hello?
That's right. Run.
Run.
Somebody call the police.
The man is loitering.
Excuse me, sir.
I noticed your sign.
Where is your camera?
No. My son would like to play
a game of chess with you.
Check.
Nyet. Nyet.
It's over.
You lose.
Thanks.
What's his name?
Josh.
Josh what?
Don't tell him...
Waitzkin.
Josh Waitzkin.
I'm going to watch out
for you, Josh Waitzkin.
Tell these patzers
I watched you play
like Bobby Fischer.
Show them this.
Your boy used pieces in
combination to attack, lady.
Shut up, man.
Look what you did.
And here's the pitch.
A short grounder to second base.
Here's the throw.
And he got it.
Hey, babe.
Hi.
Where's Josh?
He's over there.
Hey, Josh.
How's it going?
Eddie.
Come here.
Give me a hand.
What did I miss?
No score.
I took Josh to the park today.
He played chess.
Um...
Josh doesn't know
how to play chess.
Don't ask me how, but he does.
You going to write about sports
like your dad,
or you going to play?
I'll play second base
for the Yanks.
Make that
a four-game streak!
They could use a second baseman.
Careful.
Careful, careful.
Oh, here.
Hey...
Look what I found.
Want to play a game?
Why?
For fun.
Let's go to a dealership instead
and get some brochures.
Well, show him.
Your dad wants to see you play,
Like with the men in the park.
Hey, it'll be fun.
Then we'll go to a dealership.
Now go easy on me.
It's been a while
since I've played.
Check.
Oh, uh...
checkmate.
You see,
I've got you here and here.
See?
Can we go to the dealership now?
Sure.
Pee and get your coat.
Yeah, I know.
I should've let him win one.
I gave him every opportunity.
He wasn't trying to win.
Oh, no?
Come on, Bonnie.
It doesn't matter.
No. Say what you mean.
You don't get it?
He doesn't want
to beat his daddy.
Dad.
She thinks you're
throwing the game.
You know what that means,
throwing the game?
No.
Well, this time, really try.
I was trying.
Well, I know you were,
but we're going to play one more
just for fun, O.K.?
Josh...
it's O.K. to beat him.
You won't hurt his feelings.
It's your move.
Your move, Josh!
I can't.
I'm playing chess with my dad.
Chess. It's a game,
like Monopoly.
Josh!
Don't hang up.
Hi.
Your move, Josh!
Did you move that pawn?
I moved a pawn, yeah.
Yeah, that one.
Move my horse
in front of my king.
You mean your knight.
Yeah.
O.K.
He's going to lose his queen.
Oh, really?
Did you do it?
Yeah.
Can we go out now?
Well, the game's
not over yet, Josh.
Yes, it is.
Bobby Fischer was 6
when his mother moved the family
to a small apartment
near Ebbets Field.
At night,
when the traffic noise
died down,
you could hear the roar of the crowd
from the stadium.
His sister brought home
games to amuse him
while their mother was at work.
Monopoly...
Parcheesi...
chess.
Even though
she was five years older,
she was soon no match for him.
It became more interesting
for him to play against himself.
He'd play both sides
of the board equally hard,
careful to be fair...
and he always won.
And up...
3...
4.
Now over.
Arms long, girls,
and down.
Let's go to the other side.
Long neck.
And plié.
And down.
3...
4. Very nice.
J'adoube.
What are you doing?
J'adoube?
You moved the piece.
No, I adjusted the piece.
J'adoube.
No, you moved it,
then took it back.
No, I adjusted...
Who are you with again?
No, you picked up the piece...
The Hadassah chapter
on Staten Island.
I'll take it back.
What did you have in mind?
Lecture? Exhibition?
I'm looking for
Bruce Pandolfini.
What are you prepared to pay?
$30.
Do you know how much I'm accustomed
to getting for a lecture?
Want to play?
Can I have one of those?
Yes, I'll be there.
Yes, l... I'm agreeing to the $30.
Yes, I have it.
Ahem.
Bye.
I work for a newspaper.
I wanted...
I don't know
where Bobby Fischer is.
I was talking to the guy
who writes the chess column.
He told me I could find
Bruce Pandolfini here.
I'm looking for
a teacher for my son.
I don't teach anymore.
He was sure that you did.
I don't.
Come on, Josh.
Just a second.
Thanks.
What was the score?
33 to 8.
33 to 8?
What did you do?
3 home runs, 3 triples,
and 2 singles.
I almost had 4 home runs,
but I slipped coming home
from third.
I ain't playing this game.
Oh, caught you looking.
You want some smoke?
Never play defensive.
Always attack.
Even when you retreat,
you attack.
You understand?
Yeah.
There you go.
Now you're playing chess.
That's right.
Make him run.
Got me in trouble.
I'm on the run.
What can I do?
Where can I go?
Young Fischer.
Come after me.
There you go.
Outstanding.
Nothing I can do.
I'm in major trouble,
major trouble.
I got big problems now.
What's this?
This goes like this.
And this goes like this.
And this can go over pieces.
That piece should go over here.
And the pawn go...
And the pawns...
The pawns can take like this.
This is a pawn...
You sneak in here again, Katya?
Yeah.
It's way past your bedtime.
Say good night to your brother.
Good night.
There.
Mom?
Yeah?
Does Vinnie sleep in the park?
I have no idea where he lives.
Well, I was thinking...
maybe he could sleep
in my top bunk instead.
Then when I get old enough
to sleep in it,
he could sleep down here.
You have a good heart.
And that's the most important thing
in the world.
Good night.
Good night, Mom.
Glad you could make it.
So how's it going?
All right.
Great.
That's great.
So what do you think?
Have you ever been
to a tournament before?
No.
Ah. You're in luck then.
This is one
of the most prestigious.
The talent gathered here's
the strongest in the country.
Everybody's here.
Joel Benjamin...
Former U.S. Champion,
among the six highest-rated players
in the country.
The man in the corner's
Roman Dzindzichashvili...
Two-time U.S. Champion.
A few years ago, he was ranked
among the top 10 players
of the world.
Asa Hoffman.
He's the son of two lawyers.
He grew up on Park Avenue,
went to Columbia and Horace Mann
before dropping out
to play chess full-time.
He plays about 200 chess tournaments
a year.
Asa.
How much do you make
at the tournaments altogether...
about $2,000 a year?
Look at that. I got him thinking.
I got him thinking.
Maybe I can win a pawn.
Clearly, you had me come here
so I could see all this.
But if you really
wanted me to say no
to letting my son play,
you wouldn't have bothered.
You want me to think
you want me to say no,
but you actually...
want me to say yes.
You have no idea what I want.
What is chess, do you think?
Those who play for fun,
or not at all,
dismiss it as a game.
The ones who devote their lives to it,
for the most part,
insist it is a science.
It's neither.
Bobby Fischer got underneath it
Like no one before him
and found at its center...
art.
I've spent my life
trying to play like him.
Most of these guys have.
But we're like forgers.
We're competent fakes.
His successor
wasn't here tonight.
He wasn't here.
He's asleep in his room
in your house.
Your son creates like Fischer.
He sees like him...
inside.
You can tell that
by watching him
play some drunks in the park?
Yes!
You want to know what I want?
I'll tell you what I want.
I want back
what Bobby Fischer took with him
when he disappeared.
Yeah, look at that.
Oh!
You're his father.
It's your decision.
Josh.
I... I'd like you to meet
a friend of mine.
Hi, Josh.
This is Bruce.
Hi.
Well, I'll let you two, um...
I'll be downstairs.
I love water basketball.
Well, supposedly, he used to, uh,
really be someone.
Some sort of, uh...
master level...
something or other.
Used to.
Well, yeah. Well,
he doesn't play anymore...
on the circuit...
or... or whatever, um...
they call it.
Well, he's interesting.
All right, this is it.
Mr. Green
in the conservatory
with the candlestick.
Wrench.
Frère Jacques
Dormez-vous?
I need to talk
to your dad a minute.
I'll see you
next week, O.K.?
I really had a great time, Josh.
Me, too.
Bye.
The first lesson went
very well, I think.
Oh, good.
So, uh...
uh, were you guys...
talking about...
chess up there?
No, it didn't come up.
So I'll see you
next Saturday then?
Uh, right.
That's great.
So long.
How about some Pac-Man
next week, Josh?
Pac-Man and pizza.
Great.
O.K.
I'll see myself out.
It was very nice meeting you.
Mate is four moves
from the position
in front of you.
Don't move until you figure it out
in your head.
Don't look to me for a hint.
I can't do it without
moving the pieces.
Yes, you can.
Clear the lines of men
in your head,
one at a time,
and the king will
be left standing alone,
Like a guy on a street corner.
Here, I'll make it
easier for you.
Knight to c8.
Yes.
I want to show you
something else.
This is very rare.
It says, "Master
Chess Certificate..."
awarded to..."
and there's a blank here
for a name...
"for highest achievement
on this day of blank,
nineteen hundred and blank."
Careful with it.
It's a mysterious
and powerful thing.
It's only been given out...
I don't know...
a few times in history.
And then only
to those who achieve
a lot of master-class
points.
Then there's a big ceremony
and so on.
How do you get
master-class points?
You earn them.
You just earned 10...
for that knight to c8.
10.
10...
master...
class...
points.
O.K., Josh, let's go!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Take two!
Hi.
You're overdressed, Bruce.
Two, four, six, eight,
who do we appreciate?
Eagles!
Yay, Eagles!
O.K., yeah!
Nice game, guys.
Let's get that equipment in
and head on out!
Good game, fellas.
Come on, Josh.
His chess ideas are like
pieces of his body
he's reluctant to give up.
For instance, he simply can't cope
with being told
not to bring his queen out
too early in the game.
Why shouldn't he?
He's won many a game
in Washington Square doing exactly that.
Why is this suddenly wrong?
Try getting him to brush his teeth
sometime.
What I'm trying to teach him
and what he's learning there
are two very different things.
Park hustlers play
tactics, not position.
They rely on wild,
unpredictable moves
meant to intimidate
their opponents.
Great in a two-minute
speed game for drug money,
but it'll cost Josh
dearly in real games.
Well, he's learning
some new words.
Could you keep him from playing there
so much?
Sure.
No.
Not playing in the park
would kill him. He loves it.
Just makes my job harder.
Then your job's harder.
What are you talking about?
We're already packed.
We're, like, out the door.
Make sure his laces are tied
if there's escalators.
I don't know why
I O.K.'d this anyway.
Well, you didn't.
He wants to do this.
I should've dissuaded him.
I grew up playing
in tournaments.
They have nothing to do
with what's important.
They're about all
winning and losing. So?
It's not chess.
Ah. Chess is art.
That's right.
No. Chess is you appreciating
the beauty of Josh's play
at 60 bucks an hour.
Will you be ready to go
in 30 minutes or not?
He's not coming.
May I talk to him?
Hold on.
Josh!
I don't...
Telephone.
Hi.
Josh, how are you doing?
You excited?
Yeah.
Listen, I can't make it.
I've got some things
I have to take care of.
Hmm.
That's O.K.
I'll be thinking of you.
You'll do great, I know it.
And I'll see you
when you get back.
O.K.
Bye.
O.K. bye. Don't bring
your queen out too soon...
This is great.
Which one's yours?
Over there by the steps.
Oh. That...
That one's mine.
All right, yeah.
What?
Looks like they're friends
already.
Uh, what's his rating?
15.
15 hundred?
Yeah.
How old is he?
7.
Well, I doubt that they'll be playing
each other then.
Morgan's not rated 1,000 yet.
Oh.
15 hundred?
Questions during
the course of the game,
raise your hand.
He was cheating. He tried to castle
when I had him checked.
O.K., I want to remind you
to conduct yourselves
Like adults.
I don't want any trouble.
And you know exactly
what I'm talking about.
If you're going
to watch the game,
do so from behind the player.
No throat noises.
No comments.
No eye contact.
Nobody cares if you're
guilty or not.
If you all behave yourselves,
I think we'll all have
a very good time.
I'm not kidding.
Listen, my son can't play
with these pieces.
My daughter needs her own clock.
Oh, this is unfair.
Start...
your clocks.
I did not pull on my ear!
You pulled on your ear!
I did not!
I scratched my ear!
- You're a liar!
- Break it up!
He's out of his mind!
Break it up!
I don't care!
Take your hands off me!
You're the one
who's trying to...
We just came to have fun.
I don't understand this.
Hey!
Hey, what... Hey!
See, you can call me
the man of many signals.
Many signals.
Knock it off, for Christ's sake.
I don't want to "knock it off,
for Christ's sake."
I'm a man of many signals.
Yeah, I pull
my nose, my elbow...
and whatever else
I want to pull.
You play the game fair.
That's the way it's played.
So... you see me
pulling my ear,
it's not an itch.
You might think it's an itch,
but it's not an itch.
So watch for the subtleness.
You're lucky you don't get nervous
at these things.
Hi.
If your son wins his game
and my son wins his,
they'll be playing each other
in the final round.
I can hardly wait.
Hey! It's only a game.
I'm going to get myself
a tuna fish sandwich.
- Can I get you a sandwich?
- No, that's...
I'm going to get you
a tuna fish sandwich.
Queen takes pawn.
Josh is in trouble.
He's down another pawn.
Don't you believe it.
Your boy'll pull it out.
No, he's down too much material.
He's going to lose.
Knight takes rook.
Petey just hung his rook!
He probably sacrificed it
for position.
He's probably still got
the advantage.
It's over.
Wha... d...
Who won?
In school,
before he dropped out,
Bobby studied chess books
while his teachers
taught other things.
When they told him
to put his books away,
or took them away,
he studied in his head.
When a science report
came back to him once
with the words
"not satisfactory"
written across the top,
he wrote under it
just as big,
"Tough."
He was 14
and had already beaten
the strongest adult players
in the country
to become the youngest
U.S. champion ever.
Welch is on the mound.
Now Casey signals.
He winds up...
the pitch!
Bye, mom.
Have fun.
We'll call you
when we get there.
Bye!
There's your dad.
Yes!
Look at this.
Look at this. See this?
None of you patzers
ever won anything like this.
Shut up.
We're trying to play a game.
He gets it,
throws to first...
Gets him!
And one out.
Thanks.
That's a high-15
instead of a high-5.
I think we got it
in the bag now.
Come on, Bruce!
All right.
The windup and...
the pitch!
Great.
He's out.
Oop!
And in first place...
Josh Waitzkin.
Mr. Waitzkin?
Oh, Hi.
How you doing?
Hi. I'm so glad
you could make it.
Me, too.
This is really great.
Isn't it? The children worked
very hard on it.
I understand from Josh
you just got back from Washington.
I think that's super.
Yeah, it was great.
He told us all about the hotel.
He was impressed with that.
You've been taking him
a lot of places lately.
I think it's good.
It's important
for kids to travel.
It's a great education.
They start to realize
there's more to the world
than Washington Square.
Yes. He's been talking a lot about
Washington Square, too.
Uh...
uh, let's see...
we've heard about hotels
in, uh, Syracuse, Philadelphia,
Boston...
Washington now.
That seems to be
all he can remember.
Not the White House
or the capitol building
or the Lincoln Memorial.
And you're wondering
why that is.
It's because I'm a rotten father.
You're right.
I drag him all over the country
for my own selfish reasons.
Fred! Is Josh falling behind
in his schoolwork?
He is,
but I'm more concerned about
other things...
Like his friendships.
- There's a problem there?
- Possibly.
Well, is there or isn't there?
Mr. Waitzkin...
I'm sure he's very good
at this chess thing,
but that isn't
really the issue...
Chess thing.
I'm sorry?
I'm sure he's good at it,
but I'm worried.
To make an analogy...
If it was like, say...
oh, I don't know...
um, cards,
pinochle.
Pinochle.
For instance.
Fred...
Bonnie...
She's comparing chess
to pinochle.
What am I supposed
to say to that?
She's trying to make a point.
Maybe we should listen.
Vinnie thinks he's spending
too much time at it, too.
Vinnie? Vinnie's a drug addict.
I'm supposed to listen to his
opinion, too?
I'm sorry, but your analogy
is a very bad one.
If you want to make
a comparison to something,
have it make sense.
Compare it to math
or music or art,
because otherwise it belittles him
and it and me.
I don't mean to belittle you...
Oh, but you are,
even the way you're looking at me.
Mr. Waitzkin,
I think perhaps...
I'll tell you how good he is.
He's better at this
than I've ever been
at anything in my life.
He's better at this
than you'll ever be at anything.
My son has a gift.
He has a gift,
and once you acknowledge that,
then maybe
we'll have something
to talk about.
Josh.
Chess is what it's called.
Not the "chess thing."
Chess.
What's its number?
It doesn't have a number.
It's a private school.
Only the public schools
have numbers.
It's called Dalton.
You can still see your friends
whenever you want...
After school or on weekends,
when there's not a tournament.
Your friend Morgan goes there.
Morgan goes there?
Oh, yeah.
He wouldn't go there
unless it was great, right?
Ah, it's the best.
They, um,
even have a chess class.
What's the yard like?
The yard?
Do they have good stuff
to climb on?
I'm sure it does.
Um, I haven't seen it,
but I'm sure it's great.
So, um...
what do you think?
If you say it's great,
then it has to be.
It's a mistake.
What was wrong
with the old school?
I don't know.
I guess it was no good.
And the new one's better?
They have a chess class.
Are you O.K.?
What the hell's
going on over there?
Bobby Fischer.
Young Fischer.
Check.
Trick or treat.
Why is black better?
Take your time.
White has more pawn islands.
Which is white's weakest island?
The isolated pawn.
Only the king can save it.
That's right.
That's very good.
You just earned
20 master-class points.
You studying up
on your end game, Bruce?
Josh, go get yourself a Coke.
We're through here.
Get yourself a Coke.
What do you want?
Hello. How are you?
How have you been?
How's your health?
Any one of these
would be appropriate.
I want to join the club.
Well, actually, not me,
my young friend Jonathan here.
I suggest you bring him back
in a couple of years.
We'd like an application,
if it's not too much trouble.
He's been my student
since he was 4 years old.
His parents
have given him to me.
Does nothing but play chess.
No other interests.
He goes to school?
Oh, no.
Well, that's great.
You should be proud of yourself.
I am.
You should watch him play.
He reminds me of you,
only he never gives up.
Josh.
It's not a part
of his character.
He's not going to disappoint
his teacher.
"And when he knew that the cottage
was entirely destroyed,"
the monster screamed once more
in agony and hatred
"and retreated backward
to seek refuge in the woods."
Wow! Then it gets really scary
because they chase him
and light torches and stuff.
So we'll get to that tomorrow.
Good night, tiger.
Good night.
Dad...
Maybe we shouldn't go
to the state finals.
What are you talking about?
Of course we're going.
That's what we've worked
so hard for.
If I win...
Everybody will say,
"Well, of course he won.
He's a top-ranked player."
But if I lose...
You won't lose, Josh.
What if I do?
You won't.
I'm afraid I might.
Josh... they're afraid.
They're terrified of you.
Now you get some sleep.
Maybe it's better
not to be the best.
Then you can lose,
and it's O.K.
It took people a while
to realize he was really gone.
He disappeared before...
Once for 18months
before the crushing defeat
of Petrosian in Belgrade.
But when he didn't show up
in Manila in '75
to defend his title,
they took it away from him
and gave it back
to the Russians.
O.K., let's go.
I'm standing here
with Fred Waitzkin.
I hope I pronounced that right.
Fred, what's it like
being a chess parent?
In my case, the hardest part
is keeping track
of my son's toy cars,
making sure he eats something
other than French fries...
Hi.
Your son's the odds-on favorite,
I understand.
He's rated number one
in his division, yes.
So every other parent
in this room hates you.
I'm just kidding, Fred.
Thank you, sir.
He can go to his table now.
Next, please.
Oh, my God.
That was quick.
I hate this part.
What?
No.
Seven moves.
Seven.
How is it possible
to lose in seven moves?
Maybe I don't really have it.
Well, you know that's not true.
That's not why this happened.
I don't understand
why this happened.
Why did this happen?
Well, think.
Take your time.
Take more time than you took
losing to that patzer
and figure it out.
Did you fall for a trap?
Did you bring your queen out early
even though Bruce warned you
time and again about that?
Maybe he's just better than me.
No, don't tell me
that kid's better than you
because he isn't.
Why are you standing
so far away from me?
Come here.
It's O.K.
I'm sorry.
For all his natural ability,
Bobby Fischer studied harder
than any player who ever lived.
He woke up thinking about chess.
He went to bed thinking about it.
He dreamt about it.
Why? Isn't it enough
to be a natural?
If you don't care about winning,
it's enough,
but he wanted to win.
He had to be champion,
and in order to do that,
he had to work,
which is what we're going to do.
O.K.
Promise you won't
argue moves with me,
no matter how much
you think you're right.
I promise.
Everything I tell you
imagine is coming from him
because I know
every game he ever played,
so, in effect, he's going to be
teaching you,
and you'll become him.
Promise.
All right.
Some new rules...
No more speed chess.
I know you like it,
I know it's fun,
but it's no good.
It ruined Arbakov,
and it'll ruin you.
And no more games
in Washington Square.
They're patzers, and they're teaching
you all the wrong things.
They're not patzers.
They're losers,
and unless you want to end up
just like them,
you'll stay away.
They're not patzers.
I mean it.
Now...
which one is you?
What do you mean?
I mean, which one is you?
None of them.
They're just pieces.
This is you.
So what's your best move?
Rook to d 1.
What about taking on e5?
What about it?
You didn't consider it.
You're still not considering it.
Sit up.
I'm right.
Rook to d 1 is the best move.
You didn't study the board.
You're moving
before I know the answers.
Give me your book.
Why?
You just lost
some master-class points, tiger.
I can't lose points.
No? You just lost some more
for arguing with me.
Fine, Tim, it's not enough.
What's happening?
I hear a whole lot of talk
and don't get much for it.
Ooh, it hurts!
Damn!
Do you know what the word
contempt means?
It's to think of others
as being beneath you,
to be unworthy of being
in the same room with you.
I don't feel that.
Well, you better start.
Because if you don't think
it's a part of winning,
you're wrong.
You have to have contempt
for your opponents.
You have to hate them.
But I don't.
They hate you.
They hate you, Josh.
I don't hate them.
Bobby Fischer held the world
in contempt.
I'm not him.
You're telling me.
In the primary division,
In first place with a perfect
six out of six...
Jonathan Poe.
Let's give a round of applause
for all the winners.
It's white's move.
Can we expect it any time soon?
How many points is it worth?
To make the opening move?
Yes.
Forget the points.
How much is it worth if I do it?
Do it for its own sake.
I want to know how close I am
to getting the certificate.
Forget that.
I want to know.
- I don't know.
- What do you mean?
I don't care.
I don't understand.
It's white's move.
I want the certificate.
You want the certificate?
You have to have
the certificate?
You won't move until you get
You win.
Here's your certificate.
Fill it out.
Doesn't mean anything.
It's a piece of paper.
It's a Xerox
of a piece of paper.
Do you want another one?
Do you want 10?
You want 20?
30?
I've got a briefcase full of them.
They mean nothing.
Get out of my house.
To put a child in a position
to care about winning
and not to prepare him is wrong.
Get out of my house.
Look, I know you don't want to admit it,
but he's right.
I mean, you wouldn't sign your kid up
for little league
and then not get him a glove.
You equip him.
It's over.
Bonnie, he's in a slump.
This is a slump.
It happens.
When you get into a slump,
you get out of it eventually.
You don't give up.
This is like baseball to you.
If you're afraid to lose,
you lose.
He's afraid.
He's not afraid of losing.
He's afraid of losing your love.
How many ballplayers grow up
afraid of losing
their father's love
every time they come up
to the plate?
All of them!
He knows you disapprove of him.
He knows you think he's weak,
but he's not weak.
He's decent.
And if you or Bruce
or anyone else
tries to beat that out of him,
I swear to God
I'll take him away.
When did you start to get serious
about chess?
Uh, I got serious, oh...
hmm, oh, well, I was always
pretty serious about it.
You know, when I was maybe 7.
People say they've received letters
from him over the years,
but never show them.
They say he lost his nerve,
and he'll never play again.
They say he lost his mind
and roams the streets
of Los Angeles hiding out
under assumed names.
Check.
Some people say...
he's dead.
I think he's lying low
and getting stronger,
waiting for just the right
moment to come back
and reclaim his crown.
Hey, Josh.
Shh.
What happened to your room?
I cleaned it.
Hey, you know,
you don't have to
do this anymore.
You could give it up,
and that's all right with me.
In fact...
I want you to.
How can I do that?
What do you mean?
You just do it.
But I have to win.
No, that's what I'm saying...
You don't.
But you told me I did.
Well, I'm telling you now
that you don't.
But I do.
I do.
Why?
Because I have to.
It doesn't mean anything.
It's just a game.
No, it isn't.
Good morning.
These belong to you.
Want to play?
Two minutes.
What's that?
Schleimann attack.
Where'd you learn that from,
a book?
My teacher taught me.
Forget it. Play like you used to...
From the gut.
Get your pawns rolling
on the queen's side.
Put it out.
Josh is playing.
He taught you how not to lose,
not how to win.
You got to risk losing.
You got to risk everything.
You got to go
to the edge of defeat.
But...
But what? Play.
Never play the board,
always the man.
You got to play the man
playing the board. Play me.
You have to beat me,
not the board.
You're not who I have to play.
You're playing me now.
Better.
All right.
Better! Yes!
Come on, move.
Good!
Yeah!
All right!
Better!
Yeah!
Good move!
Yeah! Uh-huh!
Yes!
Move!
Ooh, yeah!
Good, good, good! Move!
Yeah, that's it!
Ooh, good! Yeah!
What's that?
Mate.
Yeah.
How's it going?
All right.
How's Josh?
Well, he's good.
Sit down.
Still planning on going to Chicago
for the nationals?
Yeah.
I've seen you both at the park.
Yeah. We've been
hanging out there a lot.
Think that's a good idea?
Yes, I do.
He's playing better than ever.
How would you know that?
You're right.
I... I don't know.
But what I do know
is that he likes playing again
for the first time
in a long time.
I know you think
you're doing what's best,
but you're setting him up for
the biggest disappointment of his life.
That other kid isn't
spending his afternoons riding bikes
and playing Pac-Man,
I can guarantee you that.
I'm doing the only thing
I know how to do for Josh.
I don't know what else to do.
Don't let him
go down there to lose.
That's what you can do for him.
You're his father.
Forbid it.
I can't do that.
Fred...
he's going to get killed.
There's not going to be
much left of him.
You have no idea what a fall like this
can do to you.
I think I do.
You know what?
You should come down with us.
It would mean a lot to him to have
you there.
That I can't do.
There you go.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Come on, Katya.
O.K. That's not bad,
but that's not right, O.K.?
That's not what Casablanca did.
See?
You want to be patient.
Fools rush in.
You want to go
to the 7th rank...
Hi, Morgan.
Josh, where you been?
Fishing.
Whoa. Look at this.
No chess boards, no chess books.
I wasn't allowed to talk about chess
for two whole weeks.
Just fish.
Whoa.
It was my dad's idea.
Hey, Kalev.
How's it going?
Fishing?
Sure.
The 200 young players
finding their seats behind me
represent some
of the strongest chess minds
of any age in the country.
Traveling from as far away
as Alaska and Hawaii,
they've come here to compete
against each other
over the course of the next two long,
grueling days.
To become champion,
one must win all seven games.
That's right.
This is Donovan Clennan,
Director of the National
Scholastic Championship.
Tell me,
is the next Bobby Fischer
somewhere in this room?
Hi, Mom.
This girl you're playing
is ranked 82nd.
All right.
Get through it quick,
and you can rest
before the next round, O.K.?
O.K.
I'll see you in a little while.
Bye.
Josh...
good luck.
Some of you maybe unfamiliar
with sudden death rules.
If you're writing moves down
while a player gets down
to where there's less
than five minutes left,
it's no longer
your responsibility to...
Hi.
Is that clear?
Good luck.
One more thing...
If you have a problem...
Morgan.
If you have a problem,
you don't have to discuss it
with your opponent.
All these people
with purple hats around here,
they'll be wandering around.
Just put your hand up,
and they'll straighten it up.
O.K. Just hold up your hand,
and they'll see it.
Don't argue with your opponent.
That's ridiculous.
O.K. good luck.
Start your clocks.
Can I come in?
How are you feeling?
Scared?
I can't beat him.
You might be right.
I'm not supposed to say that,
but you'd know I was lying if I said
anything else.
I have something for you.
It says,
"This is to certify that Josh Waitzkin,
on this day,"
has in the eyes
of his teacher...
"attained the rank
of Grandmaster."
I have never been so proud
of anyone in my life.
I'm honored to call myself
your teacher.
I'm so scared.
I know.
Will you stay until it's over?
Will I stay?
I wouldn't miss it
for the world.
It's unsettling, isn't it?
When you realize there are only
so many things
you can teach a child.
And finally...
they are who they are.
Good luck.
Start your clocks.
What's happening?
Why isn't he moving?
Letting his time run.
Trying to psych Josh out.
Don't do it, Josh.
Don't even think about it.
Bring her out.
Keep her back.
Bring her out, Josh.
Oh, Jesus!
What?
Is it over?
Over? He's setting him up.
Josh is setting him up now.
I taught him that.
Check.
There it is!
Trick or treat.
That was a mistake.
What was a mistake?
Who made a mistake?
Look deep, Josh. It's there.
It's 12 moves away,
but it's there.
You've got him.
Take his pawn with your pawn.
G takes F6 forking
his bishop and rook.
Don't take back
with your bishop.
You'll need that to guard e7.
He'll take back,
either with his bishop
or his knight.
When he does,
this is the hard part,
sacrifice your rook.
Capture him on f6
and get him to check.
King has to take your rook.
He takes f6.
Give him the knight to check e7,
forking his king and his rook.
He'll move to safety.
King f5.
Take his rook with your knight.
He'll take back with his king,
and you've got him.
Don't move until you see it.
I can't see it.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Here, I'll make it
easier for you.
He's got it.
He's got it?
How do you know he's got it?
He's got it.
What?
Come on, move.
What's that supposed to mean?
He's offering him a draw.
I'm offering you a draw.
Draw? You've got
to be kidding.
You've lost.
You just don't know it.
I've lost?
Look at the board.
I have.
Take the draw,
and we'll share the championship.
Take the draw.
Move.
Check.
Good game.
Yay!
Hey, you did good.
All right!
Yes!
Josh, my man.
All right! All right!
My man!
I'm so proud of you.
I knew you could do it.
I told you. I told you.
Bobby Fischer played
in Washington Square Park, too.
See this? Look. Josh Waitzkin.
Morgan, what...
Morgan...
will you come here?
I tried to give him a way out.
I know you did.
Why did you bring
the queen out so early?
You know what I'm saying?
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Are you listening to me?
What happened?
I lost.
That's all.
What did your dad say?
"You should have
taken out your knight"
instead of your queen.
"You took out your queen
too early."
I do that, too.
That's all he said?
Pretty much.
Morgan...
you want to know a secret?
I'm going to tell you a secret.
You're a much stronger player
than I was at your age.
Thanks.