I can't let you out, Hedwig.
I'm not allowed to use
magic outside of school.
Besides, if Uncle Vernon Harry Potter!
Now you've done it.
He's in there. Vernon?
I'm warning you, if you can't control
that bloody bird, it'll have to go.
But she's bored.
If I could only let her
out for an hour or two.
So you can send secret messages to
your freaky little friends? No, sir.
But I haven't had any messages
from any of my friends.
Not one
All summer.
Who would want to be friends with you?
I should think you'd be
a little more grateful.
We've raised you since you were a
baby, given you the food off our table
Even let you have
Dudley's second bedroom
Purely out of the
goodness of our hearts.
Not now. It's for
when the Masons arrive.
Which should be any minute.
Now, let's go over our
schedule once again, shall we?
Petunia, when the Masons
arrive, you will be...?
In the lounge, waiting to welcome
them graciously to our home.
Good. And, Dudley, you will be...?
I'll be waiting to open the door.
Excellent.
And you?
I'll be in my bedroom, making no noise
and pretending that I don't exist.
Too right, you will.
With any luck, this could be the day
I make the biggest deal of my career
And you will not mess it up.
Harry Potter, such an honor it is.
Who are you? Dobby,
sir. Dobby the houseelf.
Not to be rude or anything
But this isn't a great time for me
to have a house elf in my bedroom.
Yes, sir. Dobby understands.
It's just that Dobby
has come to tell you....
It is difficult, sir. Dobby
wonders where to begin.
Why don't you sit down?
Sit down? Sit down?
Dobby, I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to offend you or anything.
Offend Dobby?
Dobby has heard of your greatness, sir
But never has he been asked to sit
down by a wizard, like an equal.
You can't have met many
decent wizards then.
No, I haven't.
That was an awful thing to say.
Bad Dobby! Bad Dobby!
Stop, Dobby. Dobby, shush.
Dobby, please, stop.
Don't mind that. It's just the cat.
Bad Dobby. Stop! Stop,
Dobby. Please, be quiet.
Are you all right?
Dobby had to punish himself, sir.
Dobby almost spoke
ill of his family, sir.
Your family? The wizard
family Dobby serves, sir.
Dobby is bound to serve
one family forever.
If they ever knew Dobby was here....
But Dobby had to come. Dobby has to
protect Harry Potter. To warn him.
Harry Potter must not go back
To Hogwarts School of Witchcraft
and Wizardry this year.
There is a plot, a plot to make
most terrible things happen.
What terrible things?
Who's plotting them?
Can't say.
Okay, I understand. You
can't say. Don't make me talk.
Dobby. Dobby, put the
lamp down. Bad Dobby.
So when they arrive
at the ninth hole....
Give me the lamp.
Dobby, stop!
Let me go. Get in there and keep quiet.
What the devil are you
doing up here? I was just
You just ruined the punch line
of my Japanese golfer joke.
Sorry.
One more sound and you'll wish
you'd never been born, boy.
And fix that door. Yes, sir.
See why I've got to go back?
I don't belong here. I belong
in your world, at Hogwarts.
It's the only place I've got friends.
Friends who don't write to Harry Potter?
Well, I expect they've been....
Hang on. How do you know my
friends haven't been writing to me?
Harry Potter mustn't
be angry with Dobby.
Dobby hoped if Harry Potter thought
his friends had forgotten him
Harry Potter might not want
to go back to school, sir.
Give me those. Now. No!
Dobby, get back here.
Dobby, please, no.
Harry Potter must say he's
not going back to school.
I can't. Hogwarts is my home.
Then Dobby must do it, sir,
for Harry Potter's own good.
It spread as far as the eye could see,
all over the floor of this building.
One plumber said,
Look at all that water.
The second plumber said, "Yes,
and that's just the top of it."
I'm so sorry. It's my
nephew. He's very disturbed.
Meeting strangers upsets him.
That's why I kept him upstairs.
You're never going back to that school.
You're never going to see those
freaky friends of yours again. Never!
Hiya, Harry.
Ron. Fred. George. What
are you all doing here?
Rescuing you, of course.
Now, come on, get your trunk.
You better stand back.
Let's go.
What was that? What was it?
Potter!
Dad, what's going on?
Go. Go. Go.
Dad, hurry up.
Come on. Come on, Harry, hurry up.
Petunia, he's escaping!
I've got you, Harry. Come here!
Let go of me! No, boy!
You and that bloody pigeon
aren't going anywhere.
Get off! Drive!
Right. Right!
No! No! No! No!
Dad!
Damn.
By the way, Harry, happy birthday.
Come on.
Okay, come on.
Think it'd be all right if we had
some? Yeah, Mum will never know.
It's not much, but it's home.
I think it's brilliant.
Where have you been?
Harry, how wonderful to see you, dear.
Beds empty. No note. Car gone.
You could have died.
You could have been seen.
Of course, I don't
blame you, Harry, dear.
They were starving him, Mum.
There were bars on his window.
Well, you best hope I don't put
bars on your window, Ronald Weasley.
Come on, Harry, time
for a spot of breakfast.
Here we are, Harry. Now, tuck in.
That's it. There we go.
Mummy, have you seen my jumper?
Yes, dear, it was on the cat.
Hello.
What did I do?
Ginny. She's been talking about you
all summer. A bit annoying, really.
Morning, Weasleys. Morning, Dad.
What a night. Nine raids. Nine! Raids?
Dad works in the Ministry of Magic, in
the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts Office.
Dad loves Muggles, thinks
they're fascinating.
Well, now.
And who are you?
Sorry, sir. I'm Harry,
sir. Harry Potter.
Good Lord. Are you really?
Well, Ron has told us all about
you, of course. When did he get here?
This morning.
Your sons flew that enchanted car of
yours to Surrey and back last night.
Did you really? How did it go?
I mean That was very wrong
indeed, boys. Very wrong of you.
Now, Harry, you must
know all about Muggles.
Tell me, what exactly is the
function of a rubber duck?
Well, that'll be Errol with the post.
Fetch it, will you, Percy, please?
Errol. He's always doing that.
Look, it's our Hogwarts letters.
They've sent us Harry's as well.
Dumbledore must know you' re here.
Doesn't miss a trick, that man.
No. This lot won't come cheap.
The spell books alone are
expensive. We'll manage.
There's only one place we're going
to get all of this. Diagon Alley.
Right.
Here we are, Harry. You go first, dear.
But Harry's never traveled
by Floo powder before, Mum.
Floo powder?
You go first, Ron, so that
Harry can see how it's done. Yes.
In you go.
That's it.
Diagon Alley.
You see? It's quite easy,
dear. Don't be afraid. Come on.
Come on.
In you go. That's it. Mind your head.
That's right. Now,
take your Floo powder.
That's it, very good.
Now, don't forget to
speak very, very clearly.
Diagonally.
What did he say, dear? Diagonally.
I thought he did.
Not lost, are you, my dear? I'm
fine, thank you. I was just going....
Come with us. We'll help
you find your way back.
No. Please Harry?
Hagrid!
What do you think you're
doing down here? Come on.
You're a mess, Harry. Skulking
around Knockturn Alley? Dodgy place.
Don't want no one to see you there.
People will think you' re up to no good.
I was lost, l
Hang on. What were you
doing down there then?
Me? I was.... I was looking
for FleshEating Slug Repellent.
They're ruining all the school cabbages.
Harry. Hagrid.
Hello, Hermione.
It's so good to see you.
It's great to see you too.
What did you do to your glasses?
Oculus Reparo.
I definitely need to remember that one.
You'll be all right now then,
Harry? Right. I'll leave you to it.
Okay, bye. Thank you. Bye.
Come on, everyone's been so worried.
Harry.
Thank goodness. We'd hoped you'd
only gone one grate too far.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Gilderoy Lockhart.
Here he is.
Mum fancies him.
Make way there, please.
Let me by, madam. Thank you.
Excuse me, little girl. This
is for the Daily Prophet.
It can't be. Harry Potter?
Harry Potter!
Excuse me, madam.
Nice big smile, Harry. T ogether,
you and I rate the front page.
Ladies and gentlemen, what an
extraordinary moment this is.
When young Harry stepped into
Flourish and Blotts this morning
To purchase my autobiography, Magical Me
Which, incidentally,
is currently celebrating
Its 27th week atop the
Daily Prophet bestseller list
He had no idea that he
would, in fact, be leaving
With my entire collected works
Free of charge.
Now, ladies?
Harry, now you give me those,
and I'll get them signed.
All of you wait outside. That's it.
I'll bet you loved
that, didn't you, Potter?
Famous Harry Potter. Can't go into a
bookshop without making the front page.
Leave him alone.
Look, Potter. You've got
yourself a girlfriend.
Now, now, Draco, play nicely.
Mr. Potter.
Lucius Malfoy. We meet at last.
Forgive me.
Your scar is legend.
As, of course, is the
wizard who gave it to you.
Voldemort killed my parents.
He was nothing more than a murderer.
You must be very brave
to mention his name.
Or very foolish.
Fear of a name only increases
fear of the thing itself.
And you must be Miss Granger.
Yes, Draco has told me all
about you. And your parents.
Muggles, aren't they?
Let me see. Red hair, vacant expressions
Tatty, secondhand book.
You must be the Weasleys.
It's mad in here. Let's go outside.
Well, well, well.
Weasley senior. Lucius.
Busy time at the Ministry,
Arthur, all those extra raids?
I do hope they' re paying you overtime
But judging by the state
of this, I'd say not.
What's the use in being a
disgrace to the name of wizard
If they don't even pay you well for it?
We have a very different idea about what
disgraces the name of wizard, Malfoy.
Clearly.
Associating with Muggles.
And I thought your family
could sink no lower.
I'll see you at work.
See you at school.
10:58, come on. The train
will be leaving any moment.
Fred, George, Percy, you first.
Okay.
After you, dear.
Come on, Ginny, we'll
get you a seat. Hurry.
Let's go.
What do you two think
you're doing? Sorry.
Lost control of the trolley.
Why can't we get through? I don't know.
The gateway has sealed
itself for some reason.
The train leaves at exactly
11:00. We've missed it.
Harry, if we can't get through
Maybe Mum and Dad can't get back.
Maybe we should just
go and wait by the car.
The car.
Ron, I should tell you
Most Muggles aren't accustomed
to seeing a flying car.
Right.
Okay.
Oh, no! The lnvisibility
Booster must be faulty.
Come on, then. Let's go lower.
We need to find the train.
Okay.
All we need to do is
catch up with the train.
We can't be far behind.
Do you hear that? We
must be getting close.
Hold on.
Harry!
Hold on!
Take my hand!
I'm trying. Your hand's all sweaty.
I think we found the train. Yeah.
Welcome home.
Up! Up!
It's not working!
Up! Ron, mind that tree!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
My wand. Look at my wand. Be
thankful it's not your neck.
What's happening? I don't know.
Come on, go! Fast!
Scabbers, you're okay.
The car!
Dad's gonna kill me.
See you, Hedwig.
So a houseelf shows up in my bedroom
We can't get through the
barrier to platform 9 3/4
We almost get killed by a tree....
Clearly someone doesn't
want me here this year.
Well, take a good look, lads.
This night might well be the
last you spend in this castle.
Oh, dear, we are in trouble.
You were seen by no
less than seven Muggles.
Do you have any idea
how serious this is?
You have risked the
exposure of our world.
Not to mention the damage you
inflicted on a Whomping Willow
That's been on these grounds
since before you were born.
Honestly, Professor Snape, I
think it did more damage to us.
Silence.
I assure you that were you in
Slytherin, and your fate rested with me
The both of you would be
on the train home tonight.
As it is They are not.
Professor Dumbledore.
Professor McGonagall.
Headmaster
These boys have flouted the Decree for
the Restriction of Underage Wizardry.
As such I am well aware of our bylaws
Having written quite
a few of them myself.
However, as head of Gryffindor house
It is for Professor McGonagall to
determine the appropriate action.
We'll go and get our stuff, then.
What are you talking about, Mr. Weasley?
You' re going to expel us, aren't you?
Not today, Mr. Weasley
But I must impress on both of you
the seriousness of what you have done.
I will be writing to your families tonight,
and you will both receive detention.
Morning, everyone.
Good morning, everyone. Good
morning, Professor Sprout.
Welcome to Greenhouse Three, second
years. Gather around, everyone.
T oday we' re going to repot Mandrakes.
Who here can tell me the
properties of the Mandrake root?
Yes, Miss Granger?
Mandrake, or Mandragora
Is used to return those who have been
Petrified to their original state.
It's also dangerous. The Mandrake's
cry is fatal to anyone who hears it.
Excellent. Ten points to Gryffindor.
As our Mandrakes are
still only seedlings
Their cries won't kill you yet.
But they could knock you out for hours,
which is why I have given you earmuffs
For auditory protection.
So could you please put
them on, right away? Quickly.
Flaps tight down, and watch me closely.
You grasp your Mandrake firmly.
You pull it sharply up out of the pot.
Got it? And
Now you dunk it down into the other pot
And pour a little sprinkling
of soil to keep him warm.
Longbottom's been
neglecting his earmuffs.
No, ma'am, he's just fainted.
Yes, well, just leave him there.
Right, on we go. Plenty
of pots to go around.
Grasp your Mandrake and pull it up.
There's Nearly Headless Nick.
Hello, Percy, Miss Clearwater.
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
Say it. I'm doomed.
You're doomed. Hi, Harry.
I'm Colin Creevey.
I'm in Gryffindor too.
Hi, Colin. Nice to meet you.
Ron, is that your owl?
Bloody bird's a menace.
Oh, no.
Look, everyone. Weasley's
got himself a Howler.
Go on, Ron. I ignored one from
my gran once. It was horrible.
Ronald Weasley!
How dare you steal that car!
I am absolutely disgusted!
Your father's now
facing an inquiry at work
And it's entirely your fault!
If you put another toe out of line
We 'll bring you straight home!
And, Ginny, dear, congratulations
on making Gryffindor.
Your father and I are so proud.
Let me introduce you to your new
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
Me.
Gilderoy Lockhart
Order of Merlin, Third Class
Honorary member of the
Dark Force Defense League
And five times winner
Of Witch Weekly's
MostCharmingSmile Award.
But I don't talk about that.
I didn't get rid of the Bandon
Banshee by smiling at him.
Now, be warned.
It is my job to arm you
Against the foulest
creatures known to wizardkind.
You may find yourselves facing
your worst fears in this room.
Know only that no harm can
befall you whilst I am here.
I must ask you not to scream.
It might provoke them.
Cornish pixies?
Freshly caught Cornish pixies.
Laugh if you will, Mr. Finnegan
But pixies can be devilishly
tricky little blighters.
Let's see what you make of them.
Come on now, round them
up. They're only pixies.
You just stay there!
Please, get me down!
Get off me! Stop. Hold still!
Peskipiksi Pesternomi!
I'll ask you three to just nip the
rest of them back into their cage.
What do we do now?
Immobulus!
Why is it always me?
I spent the summer devising
a whole new Quidditch program.
We' re gonna train
earlier, harder and longer.
What? I don't believe it.
Where you think you're going,
Flint? Quidditch practice.
I booked the pitch for Gryffindor
today. Easy, Wood. I've got a note.
I smell trouble.
I, Professor Severus Snape, do
hereby give the Slytherin team
Permission to practice today, owing
to the need to train their new Seeker.
You've got a new Seeker. Who?
Malfoy? That's right.
And that's not all that's new this year.
Those are Nimbus 2001
s. How did you get those?
A gift from Draco's father.
You see, Weasley, unlike some,
my father can afford the best.
At least no one on the Gryffindor
team had to buy their way in.
They got in on pure talent.
No one asked your opinion,
you filthy little Mudblood.
You'll pay for that
one, Malfoy. Eat slugs!
You okay, Ron?
Say something.
Wow! Can you turn him around,
Harry? No, Colin, get out of the way.
Let's take him to Hagrid's.
He'll know what to do.
This calls for a specialist's equipment.
Nothing to do but wait
till it stops, I'm afraid.
Okay. Better out than in.
Who was Ron trying to curse, anyway?
Malfoy. He called Hermione....
Well, I don't know
exactly what it means.
He called me a Mudblood.
He did not. What's a Mudblood?
It means ""dirty blood. "" Mudblood's a
foul name for someone who's Muggleborn.
Someone with nonmagic
parents. Someone like me.
It's not a term one usually
hears in civilized conversation.
See, the thing is, Harry, there are
some wizards, like the Malfoy family
Who think they' re better than everyone
else because they' re pureblood.
That's horrible.
It's disgusting.
And it's codswallop
to boot. Dirty blood.
Why, there isn't a wizard alive
today that's not halfblood or less.
More to the point, they've yet to think
of a spell that our Hermione can't do.
Come here.
Don't you think on it, Hermione.
Don't you think on it for one minute.
Harry, Harry, Harry.
Can you possibly imagine
A better way to serve detention
Than by helping me
to answer my fan mail?
Not really.
Fame is a fickle friend, Harry.
Celebrity is as celebrity does.
Remember that.
Come.
Come
To me.
What? Sorry?
That voice.
Voice?
Didn't you hear it? What
are you talking about, Harry?
I think you' re getting a bit drowsy.
And great Scott, no wonder. Look at the
time. We've been here nearly four hours.
Spooky how the time flies
when one is having fun.
Spooky.
Blood.
I smell blood.
Let me rip you.
Let me kill you.
Kill!
Kill! Harry!
Did you hear it? Hear what?
That voice. Voice? What voice?
I heard it first in Lockhart's
office. And then again just
It's time.
It's moving. I think it's going to kill.
Kill? Harry, wait! Not so fast!
Strange.
I've never seen spiders act
like that. I don't like spiders.
What's that?
The Chamber of Secrets has been
opened. Enemies of the Heir, beware.
It's written in blood.
Oh, no.
It's Filch's cat.
It's Mrs. Norris.
Enemies of the Heir, beware.
You'll be next, Mudbloods.
What's going on here? Go
on. Make way, make way.
Potter?
What are you...?
Mrs. Norris?
You've murdered my cat. No. No.
I'll kill you.
I'll kill you! Argus!
Argus, l....
Everyone will proceed to
their dormitories immediately.
Everyone except
You three.
Ravenclaws, follow me.
She's not dead, Argus.
She has been Petrified.
Thought so. So unlucky I wasn't there.
I know exactly the countercurse
that could've spared her.
But how she has been
Petrified, I cannot say.
Ask him. It's him that's done it.
You saw what he wrote on the wall.
It's not true, sir. I swear.
I never touched Mrs. Norris.
Rubbish. If I might, headmaster?
Perhaps Potter and his friends were just
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
However
The circumstances are suspicious.
I, for one, don't recall
seeing Potter at dinner.
I'm afraid that's my doing, Severus.
You see, Harry was helping
me answer my fan mail.
That's why Ron and l went
looking for him, professor.
We'd just found him when he said....
Yes, Miss Granger? When
I said I wasn't hungry.
We were heading back to the common
room when we found Mrs. Norris.
Innocent until proven guilty,
Severus. My cat has been Petrified.
I want to see some punishment! We
will be able to cure her, Argus.
As I understand it, Madam Sprout has
a very healthy growth of Mandrake.
When matured, a potion will be
made which will revive Mrs. Norris.
And in the meantime
I strongly recommend caution
To all.
It's a bit strange, isn't it? Strange?
You hear this voice, a
voice only you can hear
And then Mrs. Norris turns up
Petrified. It's just strange.
Do you think I should have told them?
Dumbledore and the others, I mean?
Are you mad?
No, Harry. Even in the wizarding
world, hearing voices isn't a good sign.
She's right, you know.
Could I have your attention, please?
Right. Now, today, we will
be transforming animals
Into water goblets.
Like so.
One, two, three. Vera Verto.
Now it's your turn. Who
would like to go first?
Mr. Weasley. "One,
two, three. Vera Verto."
Vera Verto!
That wand needs replacing, Mr. Weasley.
Yes, Miss Granger? Professor
I was wondering if you could tell
us about the Chamber of Secrets.
Very well.
You all know, of course
That Hogwarts was founded
over a thousand years ago
By the four greatest witches
and wizards of the age:
Godric Gryffindor, Helga Hufflepuff
Rowena Ravenclaw and Salazar Slytherin.
Now, three of the founders
coexisted quite harmoniously.
One did not. Three guesses who.
Salazar Slytherin wished
to be more selective
About the students admitted to Hogwarts.
He believed magical learning should
be kept within allmagic families.
In other words, purebloods.
Unable to sway the others, he
decided to leave the school.
Now, according to legend
Slytherin had built a
hidden chamber in this castle
Known as the Chamber of Secrets.
Though, shortly before
departing, he sealed it
Until that time when his own
true Heir returned to the school.
The Heir alone
Would be able to open the Chamber
And unleash the horror
within, and by so doing
Purge the school of all those who
In Slytherin's view, were
unworthy to study magic.
Muggleborns.
Naturally, the school has
been searched many times.
No such chamber has been found.
Professor? What exactly does legend
tell us lies within the Chamber?
The Chamber is said
to be home to something
That only the Heir of
Slytherin can control.
It is said to be the home
Of a monster.
Do you think it's true? Do you think
there really is a Chamber of Secrets?
Yes. Couldn't you tell? McGonagall's
worried. All the teachers are.
If there really is a Chamber of Secrets,
and it has been opened, that means
The Heir of Slytherin has returned to
Hogwarts. The question is, who is it?
Let's think. Who do we know who
thinks all Muggleborns are scum?
If you' re talking about
Malfoy Of course. You heard him.
You'll be next, Mudbloods.
I heard him. But Malfoy,
the Heir of Slytherin?
Maybe Ron's right, Hermione.
I mean, look at his family.
The whole lot of them have
been in Slytherin for centuries.
Crabbe and Goyle must know. Maybe
we could trick them into telling.
Even they aren't that thick.
But there might be another way.
Mind you, it would be difficult.
Not to mention we'd be
breaking about 50 school rules
And it'll be dangerous. Very dangerous.
Here it is. The Polyjuice Potion.
Properly brewed, the Polyjuice
Potion allows the drinker
To transform himself temporarily
into the physical form of another.
You mean if Harry and I drink that
stuff, we'll turn into Crabbe and Goyle?
Wicked! Malfoy will tell
us anything. Exactly.
But it's tricky. I've never
seen a more complicated potion.
How long will it take to make? A month.
A month?
But, Hermione, if Malfoy
is the Heir of Slytherin
He could attack half the
Muggleborns in the school by then.
I know.
But it's the only plan we've got.
Another goal for Slytherin!
They lead Gryffindor 90 to 30.
Yeah!
All right there, Scarhead?
Watch yourself, Harry!
Wood, look out!
Blimey! Harry's got
himself a rogue Bludger.
That's been tampered with, that has.
I'll stop it.
No! Even with a proper wand, it's
too risky. You could hit Harry.
Training for the ballet, Potter?
You'll never catch me, Potter.
Let's go.
Harry Potter has caught
the Snitch. Gryffindor wins!
Finite Incantatem!
Thank you. Are you okay?
No. I think my arm is broken.
Not to worry, Harry. I will fix
that arm of yours straightaway.
Not you. Boy doesn't
know what he's saying.
This won't hurt a bit.
Brackium Emendo!
Yes, well, that can sometimes happen
But the point is
You can no longer feel any pain, and,
very clearly, the bones are not broken.
Broken? There's no bones left.
Much more flexible, though.
Mr. Malfoy, stop making such a
fuss. You can go. Out of my way.
Should have been brought straight to me.
I can mend bones in a heartbeat,
but growing them back....
You will be able to, won't you?
I'll be able to, certainly.
But it'll be painful.
You're in for a rough night, Potter.
Regrowing bones is a nasty business.
What do you expect? Pumpkin juice?
Kill.
Time to kill.
Hello.
Dobby?
Harry Potter should
have listened to Dobby.
Harry Potter should have gone
back home when he missed the train.
It was you. You stopped the barrier
from letting Ron and me through.
Indeed. Yes, sir.
You nearly got Ron and me expelled.
At least you would be away from here.
Harry Potter must go home.
Dobby thought his Bludger would
be enough to make Harry Potter see
Your Bludger? You made
that Bludger chase after me?
Dobby feels most aggrieved, sir.
Dobby had to iron his hands.
You better clear off before my bones
come back, or I might strangle you.
Dobby is used to death threats, sir.
Dobby gets them five
times a day at home.
I don't suppose you could tell
me why you' re trying to kill me?
Not kill you, sir. Never kill you.
Dobby remembers how it was
before Harry Potter triumphed
Over HeWhoMustNotBeNamed.
We houseelves were
treated like vermin, sir.
Of course, Dobby is
still treated like vermin.
Why do you wear that thing, Dobby?
This, sir? It is a mark of
the houseelf's enslavement.
Dobby can only be freed if his
master presents him with clothes.
Listen.
Listen!
Terrible things are about
to happen at Hogwarts.
Harry Potter must not stay here
Now that history is to repeat itself.
Repeat itself? You mean
this has happened before?
I shouldn't have said that.
Bad Dobby! Bad! Stop it!
Stop it, Dobby!
Tell me. When did this happen
before? Who's doing it now?
Dobby cannot say, sir. Dobby only
wants Harry Potter to be safe.
No, Dobby. Tell me. Who is it?
Put him here.
What happened? There's
been another attack.
I think he's been
Petrified, Madam Pomfrey.
Look. Perhaps he managed to
take a picture of his attacker.
What can this mean, Albus?
It means
That our students are in great danger.
What should I tell the staff? The truth.
Tell them Hogwarts is no longer safe.
It is as we feared, Minerva.
The Chamber of Secrets has
indeed been opened again.
Again? You mean the Chamber of
Secrets has been opened before?
Of course. Don't you see?
Lucius Malfoy must have opened
it when he was at school here.
Now he's taught Draco
how to do it. Maybe.
We'll have to wait for the
Polyjuice Potion to know for sure.
Enlighten me. Why are we brewing
this potion in broad daylight
In the middle of the girls' lavatory?
Don't you think we'll get caught?
No. No one ever comes in here.
Why? Moaning Myrtle.
Who?
Moaning Myrtle.
Who's Moaning Myrtle?
I'm Moaning Myrtle.
I wouldn't expect you to know me.
Who would ever talk
about ugly, miserable
Moping Moaning Myrtle?
She's a little sensitive.
Gather round!
Gather round. Can everybody see me?
Can you all hear me?
Excellent.
In light of the dark
events of recent weeks
Professor Dumbledore has granted me
permission to start this Dueling Club
To train you all up in case you
ever need to defend yourselves
As I myself have done
on countless occasions.
For full details, see
my published works.
Let me introduce my assistant
Professor Snape.
He has sportingly agreed to
help with a short demonstration.
I don't want any of
you youngsters to worry.
You'll still have your Potions master
when I'm through with him. Never fear.
One.
Two.
Three! Expelliarmus!
Do you think he's all right? Who cares?
An excellent idea to show
them that, Professor Snape
But if you don't mind me saying, it
was obvious what you were about to do.
If I had wanted to stop you, it
would have been only too easy.
Perhaps it would be prudent
to first teach the students
To block unfriendly spells, professor.
An excellent suggestion,
Professor Snape.
Let's have a volunteer pair.
Potter, Weasley, how about you?
Weasley's wand causes devastation
with the simplest spells.
We'll be sending Potter to the
hospital wing in a matchbox.
Might I suggest someone
from my own house?
Malfoy, perhaps?
Good luck, Potter. Thank you, sir.
Wands at the ready.
Scared, Potter? You wish.
On the count of three
Cast your charms to disarm
your opponent. Only to disarm.
We don't want any accidents here. One.
Two. Everte Statum!
Rictusempra!
I said disarm only.
Serpensortia!
Don't move, Potter. I'll
get rid of it for you.
Allow me, Professor
Snape. Alarte Ascendare!
Vipera Evanesca.
What are you playing at?
You' re a Parselmouth?
Why didn't you tell us?
I'm a what? You can talk to snakes.
I know. I accidentally set a python
on my cousin Dudley at the zoo once.
Once. But so what? I bet
loads of people here can do it.
No, they can't. It's not
a very common gift, Harry.
This is bad.
What's bad? If I hadn't told
that snake not to attack Justin
That's what you said to it.
You were there. You heard me.
I heard you speaking
Parseltongue. Snake language.
I spoke a different language?
But I didn't realize
How can I speak a language
without knowing I can?
I don't know, but it sounded like you
were egging the snake on or something.
Harry, listen to me.
There's a reason the symbol of
Slytherin house is a serpent.
Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth.
He could talk to snakes too.
Exactly.
Now the whole school's gonna think
you're his greatgreatgreat grandson.
But I'm not.
I can't be.
He lived a thousand years ago.
For all we know, you could be.
I'll see you back in the common room.
I want blood.
They all must die.
Kill.
Time to kill.
Caught in the act.
I'll have you out this time, Potter.
Mark my words.
No. Mr. Filch! You don't understand
Professor
I swear I didn't.
This is out of my hands, Potter.
Professor Dumbledore
will be waiting for you.
Sherbet Lemon.
Professor Dumbledore?
Bee in your bonnet, Potter?
I was just wondering if you
put me in the right house.
Yes. You were particularly
difficult to place.
But I stand by what I said last year.
You would have done well in Slytherin.
You're wrong.
Harry?
Professor.
Your bird.... There
was nothing I could do.
He just caught fire. And about time too.
He's been looking dreadful for days.
Pity you had to see
him on a burning day.
Fawkes is a phoenix, Harry.
They burst into flame when
it is time for them to die
And then they are
Reborn from the ashes.
Fascinating creatures, phoenixes.
They can carry immensely heavy loads.
Their tears have healing powers.
Professor Dumbledore, sir! Wait! Listen!
Professor Dumbledore,
sir, it wasn't Harry.
I'd be prepared to swear it in
front of the Ministry of Magic.
Relax.
I do not believe
That Harry attacked
anyone. Of course you don't.
Right. Well, I'll....
I'll just wait outside, then. Yes.
You don't think it was
me, professor? No, Harry.
I do not think it was you.
But I must ask you
Is there something you wish to tell me?
No, sir.
Nothing.
Very well, then.
Off you go.
Everything's set. We just need a
bit of who you're changing into.
Crabbe and Goyle.
We also need to make sure
that the real Crabbe and Goyle
Can't burst in on us while
we're interrogating Malfoy.
How? I've got it all worked out.
I filled these with a
simple Sleeping Draught.
Simple, but powerful.
Now, once they' re asleep
Hide them in the broomstick cupboard
and pull out a few of their hairs
And put on their uniforms.
Whose hair are you ripping out,
then? I've already got mine.
Millicent Bulstrode. Slytherin.
I got this off her robes.
I'm going to go check
on the Polyjuice Potion.
Make sure that Crabbe
and Goyle find these.
Ron, maybe I should do it.
Yeah. Right.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
How thick could you get?
Come on, let's get them.
We'll have exactly one hour before
we change back into ourselves.
Add the hairs.
Essence of Crabbe.
Cheers.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Me too.
Harry?
Ron.
Bloody hell!
We still sound like ourselves.
You need to sound more like Crabbe.
Bloody hell. Excellent.
But where's Hermione? L....
I don't think I'm going.
You go on without me.
Hermione, are you okay?
Just go. You're wasting time.
Come on.
I think the Slytherin
common room's this way.
Excuse me.
What are you doing d?
I mean, what are you doing down here?
I happen to be a school prefect.
You, on the other hand, have no business
wandering the corridors at night.
What are your names again?
I'm.... Crabbe, Goyle,
where have you been?
Pigging out in the
Great Hall all this time?
Why are you wearing glasses?
Reading. Reading?
I didn't know you could read.
And what are you doing
down here, Weasley?
Mind your attitude, Malfoy.
Well, sit down.
You'd never know the Weasleys were
purebloods, the way they behave.
They' re an embarrassment to
the wizarding world. All of them.
What's wrong with you, Crabbe?
Stomachache.
I'm surprised the Daily Prophet hasn't
done a report on all these attacks.
I suppose Dumbledore is
trying to hush it all up.
Father always said
Dumbledore was the worst thing
That ever happened to
this place. You' re wrong!
What?
You think there's someone here
who's worse than Dumbledore?
Well? Do you?
Harry Potter?
Good one, Goyle.
You' re absolutely right.
Saint Potter.
And people actually think that
he's the Heir of Slytherin?
But then you must have some
idea who's behind it all.
You know I don't, Goyle.
I told you yesterday.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Is this yours?
But my father did say this:
It's been 50 years since
the Chamber was opened.
He wouldn't tell me who opened
it. Only that they were expelled.
The last time the Chamber of
Secrets was opened, a Mudblood died.
So it's only a matter of time before
one of them is killed this time.
As for me
I hope it's Granger.
What's the matter with you two?
You' re acting very odd.
It's his stomachache.
Calm down.
Scar.
Hair.
Hey! Where are you going?
That was close.
Hermione, come out. We've
got loads to tell you.
Go away.
Wait till you see. It's awful.
Hermione?
Are you okay?
Do you remember me telling you
That the Polyjuice Potion was
only for human transformations?
It was cat hair I plucked off
Millicent Bulstrode's robes.
Look at my face.
Look at your tail.
Have you spoken to Hermione?
She should be out of
hospital in a few days
When she stops coughing up fur balls.
What's this?
Yuck!
Looks like Moaning Myrtle's
flooded the bathroom.
Come to throw something else at me?
Why would I throw something at you?
Don't ask me. Here I am,
minding my own business
And someone thinks it's
funny to throw a book at me.
But it can't hurt if someone
throws something at you.
I mean, it'll just go right through you.
Sure! Let's all throw books at
Myrtle because she can't feel it.
Ten points if you get
it through her stomach!
Fifty points if it
goes through her head!
But who threw it at you, anyway?
I don't know. I didn't see them.
I was just sitting in the
Ubend, thinking about death
And it fell through the top of my head.
Tom Marvolo Riddle.
My name
Is Harry
Potter.
Do you know anything
About the Chamber of Secrets?
Can you
Tell me?
Excuse me. Could you tell
me what's going on here?
Are you T om Riddle?
Hello, can you hear me?
Riddle!
Come.
Professor Dumbledore.
Dumbledore?
It is not wise to be wandering
around this late hour, T om.
Yes, professor. I suppose l....
I had to see for myself
if the rumors were true.
I'm afraid they are,
T om. They are true.
About the school as well? I
don't have a home to go to.
They wouldn't really close
Hogwarts, would they, professor?
I understand, T om, but I'm afraid
Headmaster Dippet may have no choice.
Sir, if it all stopped, if the
person responsible was caught....
Is there something
You wish to tell me?
No, sir. Nothing.
Very well, then. Off you go.
Good night, sir.
Let's get you out of
there. Evening, Hagrid.
I'm going to have to turn you in. I don't
think you meant it to kill anyone....
You can't. You don't understand.
The dead girl's parents will be here
tomorrow. The least Hogwarts can do
Is make sure the thing that killed
their daughter is slaughtered.
It wasn't him. Aragog
never killed no one. Never.
Monsters don't make good pets, Hagrid.
Now, stand aside. No!
Stand aside, Hagrid. No!
Cistem Aperio!
Arania Exumai!
Aragog!
I can't let you go.
They'll have your wand for
this, Hagrid. You'll be expelled.
Hagrid!
It was Hagrid. Hagrid opened the
Chamber of Secrets 50 years ago.
It can't be Hagrid. It just can't be.
We don't even know this T om Riddle.
He sounds like a dirty, rotten snitch.
The monster had killed somebody,
Ron. What would any of us have done?
Look, Hagrid's our friend. Why don't
we just go and ask him about it?
That would be a cheerful
visit. Hello, Hagrid.
Tell us, have you been setting anything
mad and hairy loose in the castle lately?
Mad and hairy? You wouldn't be
talking about me, now, would you?
No.
What's that you've got, Hagrid?
It's FleshEating Slug Repellent.
For the Mandrakes, you know.
Now, according to Professor Sprout,
they've still got a bit of growing to do.
But once their acne's cleared up,
we'll chop them up and stew them
And then we'll get those people
down at the hospital unPetrified.
In the meantime, though, you three
Had best be looking after
yourselves. All right?
Hello, Neville.
Harry, I don't know who did
it, but you'd better come.
Come on!
It had to be a Gryffindor.
Nobody else knows our password.
Unless it wasn't a student.
Whoever it was, they must have
been looking for something.
And they found it.
T om Riddle's diary is gone.
All right, listen up.
We play our game, Hufflepuff
doesn't stand a chance.
We're stronger, quicker and smarter.
Not to mention they're dead
scared that Harry will Petrify them
If they fly anywhere
near him. Well, that too.
Professor McGonagall.
This match has been canceled.
We can't cancel Quidditch.
Silence, Wood. You and your teammates
will go to Gryffindor T ower. Now.
Potter, you and I will find Mr. Weasley.
There's something the
both of you have to see.
I warn you. This could
be a wee bit of a shock.
Hermione!
She was found near the library
Along with this.
Does it mean anything to either of you?
No.
Could I have your attention, please?
Because of recent events, these new
rules will be put into effect immediately:
All students will return to their house
common rooms by 6:00 every evening.
All students will be escorted
to each lesson by a teacher.
No exceptions.
I should tell you this:
Unless the culprit behind
these attacks is caught
It is likely the school will be closed.
We've got to talk to Hagrid,
Ron. I can't believe it's him
But if he did set the
monster loose last time
He'll know how to get inside the
Chamber of Secrets. That's a start.
But you heard McGonagall.
We're not allowed to leave
the tower except for class.
I think it's time to get my
dad's old cloak out again.
Who's there?
Hello?
What's that for? Nothing.
I was expecting....
It doesn't matter. Come on
in. I just made a pot of tea.
Hagrid, are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm all right.
Did you hear about Hermione?
Yeah. I heard about that, all right.
Look, we have to ask you something.
Do you know who's opened
the Chamber of Secrets?
What you had to understand about that is
Quick, under the cloak.
Don't say a word. Be quiet, both of you.
Professor Dumbledore,
sir. Good evening, Hagrid.
I wonder, could we...?
Of course. Come in. Come in.
That's Dad's boss.
Cornelius Fudge, Minister of Magic.
Bad business, Hagrid, very
bad business. Had to come.
Three attacks on Muggleborns.
Things have gone far enough.
The Ministry's got to act. But I never
You know I never, professor.
I want it understood, Cornelius
That Hagrid
Has my full confidence.
Albus, look, Hagrid's
record is against him.
I've got to take him. Take me?
Take me where? Not Azkaban prison.
I'm afraid we have no choice, Hagrid.
Already here, Fudge?
Good.
What are you doing here?
Get out of my house!
Believe me
I take absolutely no
pleasure being inside your....
You call this a house?
No.
I simply called up the school and
was told the headmaster was here.
Well, what exactly is
it that you want with me?
The other governors and I have decided
it's time for you to step aside.
This is an order of suspension.
You'll find all 1 2 signatures on it.
I'm afraid we feel you've
rather lost your touch.
Well, what, with all these attacks
There'll be no Muggleborns
left at Hogwarts.
I can only imagine what an awful
loss that would be to the school.
You can't take Professor
Dumbledore away.
T ake him away and the
Muggleborns won't stand a chance.
You mark my words,
there'll be killings next!
You think so?
Calm yourself, Hagrid.
If the governors desire my removal
I will, of course, step aside.
However
You will find that help will
always be given at Hogwarts
To those who
Ask for it.
Admirable sentiments.
Shall we?
Fudge.
Come, Hagrid.
Well?
If....
If anybody was looking for some stuff
Then all they'd have to do
would be to follow the spiders.
Yep. That would lead them right.
That's all I have to say.
And someone will need to
feed Fang while I'm away.
Good boy.
Hagrid's right.
With Dumbledore gone,
there'll be an attack a day.
Look.
Come on.
Come on, Fang.
What?
You heard what Hagrid
said. "Follow the spiders."
They're heading to the Dark Forest.
Why spiders? Why couldn't it
be "follow the butterflies"?
Harry, I don't like this.
Harry, I don't like this at all. Shush!
Can we go back now?
Come on.
Who is it?
Don't panic.
Hagrid?
Is that you?
We' re friends of Hagrid's.
And you? You're Aragog, aren't you?
Yes.
Hagrid has never sent men
into our hollow before.
He's in trouble. Up at the
school, there have been attacks.
They think it's Hagrid.
They think he opened the
Chamber of Secrets. Like before.
That's a lie.
Hagrid never opened
the Chamber of Secrets.
Then you're not the monster? No.
The monster was born in the castle.
I came to Hagrid from a distant
land in the pocket of a traveler.
Harry.
But if you' re not the monster, then
what did kill that girl 50 years ago?
We do not speak of it.
It is an ancient creature we
spiders fear above all others.
But have you seen it?
I never saw any part of the castle
but the box in which Hagrid kept me.
The girl was discovered in a bathroom.
When I was accused,
Hagrid brought me here.
Harry! What?
Well, thank you.
We'll just go.
Go?
I think not.
My sons and daughters do not
harm Hagrid on my command.
But I cannot deny them fresh meat
When it wanders so
willingly into our midst.
Goodbye, friend of Hagrid.
Can we panic now?
Know any spells?
One, but it's not powerful
enough for all of them.
Where's Hermione when you need her?
Let's go!
Arania Exumai!
Go!
Glad we' re out of there.
Arania Exumai!
Thanks for that. Don't mention it.
Get us out of here.
Now!
Come on! Come on, move faster!
Come on! Go!
Get us in the air.
The flying gear's jammed!
Come on! Pull! I'm trying!
Follow the spiders. Follow the spiders.
If Hagrid ever gets out
of Azkaban, I'll kill him.
I mean, what was the point
of sending us in there?
What have we found
out? We know one thing.
Hagrid never opened
the Chamber of Secrets.
He was innocent.
Wish you were here, Hermione.
We need you.
Now more than ever.
What's that? Ron....
This is why Hermione was in the
library the day she was attacked.
Come on.
Of the many fearsome
beasts that roam our land
None is more deadly than the basilisk.
Capable of living for hundreds of years
Instant death awaits any who
meet this giant serpent's eye.
Spiders flee before it. Ron, this is it.
The monster in the Chamber
of Secrets is a basilisk.
That's why I can hear
it speak. It's a snake.
But if it kills by looking people
in the eye, why is it no one's dead?
Because no one did look it in the eye.
Not directly, at least.
Colin saw it through his camera.
Justin Justin must have seen the
basilisk through Nearly Headless Nick.
Nick got the full blast of it. But
he's a ghost, he couldn't die again.
And Hermione had the mirror.
I bet you she was using it to look
around corners in case it came along.
And Mrs. Norris?
I'm pretty sure she didn't have
a camera or a mirror, Harry.
The water.
There was water on the floor that night.
She only saw the basilisk's reflection.
Spiders flee before it.
Lt all fits. How's a
basilisk been getting around?
A dirty, great snake.
Someone would have seen it.
Hermione's answered that too.
Pipes? It's using the plumbing.
Remember what Aragog said
about that girl 50 years ago?
She died in a bathroom?
What if she never left?
Moaning Myrtle.
All students are to return to
their house dormitories at once.
All teachers to the secondfloor
corridor immediately.
As you can see, the Heir of
Slytherin has left another message.
Our worst fear has been realized.
A student has been taken by the
monster into the Chamber itself.
The students must be sent home. I'
m afraid this is the end of Hogwarts.
So sorry. Dozed off. What have I missed?
A girl has been snatched by the monster,
Lockhart. Your moment has come at last.
My moment? Weren't you
saying just last night
That you've known all along where the
entrance to the Chamber of Secrets is?
That's settled. We'll leave you
to deal with the monster, Gilderoy.
Your skills, after all,
are legend. Very well.
I'll just be in my office getting....
Getting ready.
Who is it that the
monster's taken, Minerva?
Ginny Weasley.
Her skeleton will lie
in the Chamber forever
Ginny.
Lockhart may be useless, but he's
going to try and get into the Chamber.
At least we can tell him what we know.
Professor, we have some
information for you.
Are you going somewhere?
Well, yes. Urgent call.
Unavoidable. Got to go.
What about my sister? Well....
As to that, most unfortunate.
No one regrets more than l.
You' re the Defense Against the
Dark Arts teacher. You can't go now.
I must say, when I took the job,
there was nothing in the description
You' re running away?
After all you did in your
books? Books can be misleading.
You wrote them. My dear
boy, use your common sense.
My books wouldn't have sold as well if
people didn't think I'd done those things.
You're a fraud.
You've been taking credit for
what other wizards have done.
Is there anything you can do?
Yes, now you mention it. I'm
rather gifted with Memory Charms.
Otherwise, all those wizards
would have gone blabbing.
I'd never have sold another book.
In fact, I'm going to
have to do the same to you.
Don't even think about it.
Who's there?
Hello, Harry.
What do you want? T o
ask you how you died.
It was dreadful.
It happened right here
in this very cubicle.
I'd hidden because Olive Hornby
was teasing me about my glasses.
I was crying, and then
I heard somebody come in.
Who was it, Myrtle? I don't
know. I was distraught!
But they said something funny,
a kind of madeup language.
And I realized it was a boy, so I unlocked
the door to tell him to go away and
I died. Just like that? How?
I just remember seeing a pair
of great, big, yellow eyes
Over there by that sink.
This is it.
This is it, Ron. I think this is the
entrance to the Chamber of Secrets.
Say something. Harry, say
something in Parseltongue.
Excellent, Harry. Good work.
Well, then, I'll just be....
There's no need for me to stay.
Yes, there is.
You first. Now, boys,
what good will it do?
Better you than us.
But Obviously, yes.
Sure you don't want to test it first?
It's really quite filthy down here.
All right. Let's go. Oh, Harry?
If you die down there, you'
re welcome to share my toilet.
Thanks, Myrtle.
Now, remember: Any sign of movement,
close your eyes straightaway.
Go on.
This way.
What's this? Lt looks like a snake.
It's a snakeskin. Bloody hell.
Whatever shed this must
be 60 feet long. Or more.
Heart of a lion, this one.
The adventure ends here,
boys. But don't fret.
The world will know our story. How
I was too late to save the girl.
How you two tragically lost your minds
At the sight of her mangled body.
So....
You first, Mr. Potter.
Say goodbye to your memories.
Obliviate!
Ron! Ron, are you okay? I'm fine.
Hello.
Who are you?
Ron Weasley. Really?
And who am l?
Lockhart's Memory Charm backfired.
He hasn't got a clue who he is.
It's an odd sort of place, isn't it?
Do you live here?
No. Really?
What do I do now? You wait here
And try and shift some of this
rock so we can get back through.
I'll go on and find Ginny. Okay.
Ginny! Ginny, please don't
be dead. Wake up, wake up.
Please wake up.
She won't wake.
Tom. Tom Riddle. What do
you mean, she won't wake?
She's not...? She's still
alive, but only just.
Are you a ghost? A memory
Preserved in a diary for 50 years.
She's cold as ice. Ginny,
please don't be dead. Wake up.
You've got to help me,
T om. There's a basilisk.
It won't come until it's called.
Give me my wand, Tom.
You won't be needing it.
We've got to go. We've got to save
her. I'm afraid I can't do that.
You see, as poor Ginny grows
weaker, I grow stronger.
Yes, Harry, it was Ginny Weasley
who opened the Chamber of Secrets.
No. She couldn't. She wouldn't.
It was Ginny who set the basilisk
on the Mudbloods and Filch's cat
Ginny who wrote the threatening
messages on the walls.
But why? Because I told her to.
You'll find I can be very persuasive.
Not that she knew what she was doing.
She was, shall we say,
in a kind of trance.
Still, the power of the
diary began to scare her.
She tried to dispose of
it in the girls' bathroom.
And then who should find it but you?
The very person I was
most anxious to meet.
And why did you want to meet me?
I knew I had to talk to
you, meet you if I could.
So I decided to show you my
capture of that brainless oaf Hagrid
To gain your trust. Hagrid's my friend.
And you framed him, didn't you?
Lt was my word against Hagrid's.
Only Dumbledore seemed
to think he was innocent.
I'll bet Dumbledore
saw right through you.
He certainly kept an annoyingly
close watch on me after that.
I knew it wouldn't be safe to open
the Chamber again while I was at school
So I decided to leave behind a diary
Preserving my 1 6yearold
self in its pages
So that one day I would
be able to lead another
To finish Salazar
Slytherin's noble work.
Well, you haven't finished it this time.
In a few hours, the Mandrake
Draught will be ready.
And everyone who was Petrified
will be all right again.
Haven't I told you? Killing Mudbloods
doesn't matter to me anymore.
For many months now, my
new target has been you.
How is it that a baby with no
extraordinary magical talent
Was able to defeat the
greatest wizard of all time?
How did you escape
with nothing but a scar
While Lord Voldemort's
powers were destroyed?
Why do you care how I escaped?
Voldemort was after your time.
Voldemort is my past,
present and future.
You. You' re the Heir of Slytherin.
You' re Voldemort.
Surely you didn't think
I was going to keep my
filthy Muggle father's name?
No. I fashioned myself a new name,
a name I knew wizards everywhere
Would fear to speak when I became
the greatest sorcerer in the world.
Albus Dumbledore is the
greatest sorcerer in the world.
Dumbledore's been driven out of
this castle by the mere memory of me.
He'll never be gone. Not as long as
those who remain are loyal to him.
Fawkes?
So this is what Dumbledore
sends his great defender.
A songbird and an old hat.
Let's match the power of Lord
Voldemort, Heir of Salazar Slytherin
Against the famous Harry Potter.
Parseltongue won't save you
now, Potter. It only obeys me.
No!
Your bird may have blinded the
basilisk, but it can still hear you.
Yes, Potter. The process
is nearly complete.
In a few minutes, Ginny Weasley will be
dead, and I will cease to be a memory.
Lord Voldemort will return
Very much alive.
Ginny?
Remarkable, isn't it
How quickly the venom of the
basilisk penetrates the body?
I'd guess you have little
more than a minute to live.
You'll be with your dear
Mudblood mother soon, Harry.
Funny, the damage a
silly little book can do
Especially in the hands
of a silly little girl.
What are you doing?
Stop. No!
It was me. But I
swear, I didn't mean to.
Riddle made me, and....
Harry, you're hurt.
Don't worry.
Ginny, you need to get yourself out.
Follow the Chamber and you'll find Ron.
You were brilliant, Fawkes.
I just wasn't quick enough.
Of course.
Phoenix tears have healing powers.
Thanks.
It's all right, Ginny.
It's over.
It's just a memory.
Amazing! This is just like magic!
You both realize, of course
That in the past few hours, you have
broken perhaps a dozen school rules.
Yes, sir.
There is sufficient evidence
to have you both expelled.
Yes, sir.
Therefore, it is only fitting
That you both receive
Special Awards for
Services to the School.
Thanks, sir.
Now, Mr. Weasley, if you would
Have an owl deliver these
release papers to Azkaban.
I believe we want our gamekeeper back.
First, I want to thank you, Harry.
You must have shown me real
loyalty down in the Chamber.
Nothing but that could
have called Fawkes to you.
And
Second
I sense that something is troubling you.
Am I right, Harry?
It's just....
You see, sir, I couldn't help but
notice certain things, certain....
Certain similarities
between T om Riddle and me.
I see.
Well, you can speak
Parseltongue, Harry. Why?
Because Lord Voldemort
can speak Parseltongue.
If I'm not mistaken, Harry
He transferred some of his powers to you
The night he gave you that scar.
Voldemort transferred
some of his powers to me?
Not intentionally
But yes.
So the Sorting Hat was right.
I should be in Slytherin.
It's true. You possess many of the
qualities that Voldemort himself prizes.
Determination, resourcefulness
And if I may say so, a certain
disregard for the rules.
Why, then, did the Sorting
Hat place you in Gryffindor?
Because I asked it to.
Exactly, Harry. Exactly.
Which makes you
different from Voldemort.
It is not our abilities
that show what we truly are.
It is our choices.
If you want proof why
you belong in Gryffindor
Then I suggest you look
more closely at this.
Be careful.
Godric Gryffindor.
It would take a true Gryffindor
to pull that out of the hat.
Dobby.
So this is your master. The
family you serve is the Malfoys.
I'll deal with you later.
Out of my way, Potter.
So it's true. You have returned.
When the governors learned
that Arthur Weasley's daughter
Was taken into the Chamber,
they saw fit to summon me back.
Ridiculous. Curiously,
Lucius, several of them
Were under the impression that
you would curse their family
If they did not agree to
suspend me in the first place.
How dare you! Beg your pardon?
My sole concern has always
been and will always be
The welfare of this school
And, of course, its students.
The culprit has been
identified, I presume?
Yes.
And?
Who was it?
Voldemort.
Only this time he chose to
act through somebody else
By means of this.
I see.
Fortunately, our young
Mr. Potter discovered it.
One hopes that no more of Lord
Voldemort's old schoolthings
Should find their way
into innocent hands.
The consequences for the
one responsible would be
Severe.
Well, let us hope
That Mr. Potter will always
be around to save the day.
Don't worry. I will be.
Dumbledore.
Come, Dobby. We're leaving.
Sir? I wonder if I could have that?
Mr. Malfoy.
Mr. Malfoy!
I have something of yours.
Mine? I don't know what
you' re talking about.
I think you do, sir.
I think you slipped the diary
into Ginny Weasley's cauldron
That day at Diagon Alley.
You do, do you?
Why don't you prove it?
Come, Dobby.
Open it.
Dobby.
Master has given Dobby a sock.
What? I didn't give
Master has presented Dobby with clothes.
Dobby is free.
You lost me my servant!
You shall not harm Harry Potter.
Your parents were meddlesome fools too.
Mark my words, Potter. One day soon
You are going to meet
the same sticky end.
Harry Potter freed Dobby.
How can Dobby ever repay him?
Just promise me
something. Anything, sir.
Never try to save my life again.
Welcome back, Sir Nicholas. Thank you.
Good evening, Sir
Nicholas. Good evening.
Good to see you, Sir
Nicholas. Thank you.
Hello.
Hermione! Welcome back.
Thanks, Sir Nicholas.
Harry. It's Hermione.
Welcome back, Hermione.
It's good to be back.
Congratulations. I can't
believe you solved it.
We had loads of help from you.
We couldn't have done
it without you. Thanks.
Could I have your attention, please?
Before we begin the feast
Let us have a round of applause
for Professor Sprout, Madam Pomfrey
Whose Mandrake juice has been
so successfully administered
To all who had been Petrified.
Also, in light of the recent events
As a school treat
All exams have been canceled.
Oh, no.
Sorry I'm late.
The owl that delivered my release
papers got all lost and confused.
Some ruddy bird called Errol.
And I'd just like to say that if it
hadn't been for you, Harry and Ron
And Hermione, of course
I would still be youknowwhere
So I'd just like to say thanks.
There's no Hogwarts without you, Hagrid.