Hey, I'm Josh. And this is, uh... Carla?
- Kayla.
- Right.
- This is Kayla.
- Hi.
Hey, man, this is, uh, my friend Kayla.
- Hey.
And this is my plus one, Kayla.
Hey.
- This is my date, Kayla.
- Hi.
This is Kayla.
Oh. Hi. Uh, Mom,
this is the woman I came with, um, Kayla.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
Uh, this is my girlfriend Kayla.
So, "girlfriend," huh?
Well, uh, sorry?
Well, I just, I noticed back there
you introduced me as your girlfriend.
Oh.
Yeah, so I did.
Uh... is that okay?
- Yeah. I like it.
- Really?
I like it, too.
I-I just, I...
I don't know, I feel like...
there's kind of something here, and...
maybe we should, like,
- go for it.
- Well, are you sure
you're not gonna miss...
No. No, no. No, not at all. No.
Um...
so I don't know, I guess we're, like,
official now, huh?
Yeah, yeah. From-from this day forward,
we are officially, uh,
boyfriend and girlfriend.
- Yeah.
- Yeah! Yeah.
Okay, coming in, coming in hot.
Mmm...
Yeah. That's, uh...
What...
Uh, Kayla?
Kayla?
Uh... oh, my God,
she's having a stroke. Hey, Kayla?
Ew.
Oh, man. Oh, man. Kayla?
Kayla! Kayla...!
Who are you guys?
We are sex aliens from the planet Sex.
We have come to have sex with you.
Prepare yourself for sex.
Man Seeking Woman - 01x06
Gavel
sync and correction by solfieri
www.addic7ed.com
Hey, whoa, whoa. Stop, stop, stop.
Just-just stop.
- What's wrong?
Well, I kind of just
started seeing someone.
Who? Her?
Y-Yes, her.
Listen, if you guys
had shown up literally...
yesterday...
okay, yesterday...
I'd be all over this.
But I-I am... I am...
Whoa, mama...
I am not the kind
- of guy that cheats.
- Please,
- come have sex with us.
- No. No.
Condom-less sex.
- Oh, my God. No...
- Please?
No, I can't. Girls, I can't. Back off.
Yeah, yeah. Okay.
I'm sorry, okay?
I care... I care about this.
Okay? We can't help it.
We find you irresistible.
You... I can't believe you guys
think I'm handsome.
We don't. We are blind.
Ah. Our noses, though,
are extremely well developed.
We've evolved to smell confidence.
And there's no one more confident
than a man in a committed relationship.
He gives off a powerful musk.
Oh...
Please have sex with us.
Please. It can be quick.
Quick is actually what we prefer.
- Really?
- On our planet,
premature ejaculation is the sexual ideal.
Holy...
Okay, ah, buh-buh-buh!
Back off! Back!
Okay, we respect your decision
not to cheat on Kayla.
So how about this?
Let's smoke this space joint.
Watch a movie. And just kind of hang out.
Wait, uh...
which movie?
Showgirls.
Unrated version.
Aha...! Okay,
okay, I see what you're do... yeah, listen,
I'm not a piece of meat.
I'm a man... with feelings and...
and a girlfriend, so, tell you
what, I think you should all
- just take your, uh...
-  oh, that's amazing...
You guys need to take your-your space bras
and get back up to space.
Okay? Okay, fine,
we'll leave.
But we'll rub one out to you later.
Holy shit.
Oh, God.
Mmm.
- I'm so happy.
- Yes.
Me, too.
- Mmm...
- Me, too.
Mmm...
So, okay, these girls are all up
in your nuts... and then what?
Well, then I look them
in the eyes and I said...
thank you very much... I said, "Listen,
"I appreciate it,
it's very, very flattering,
but I-I-I-I-I... I can't
cheat on my girlfriend."
- Oh, you're being serious.
- Yes.
Wh-Wh-What has happened to you?
What is happening is that
for the first time since Maggie,
I found a girl that I actually
like hanging out with.
Oh.
- Oh, I-I got to go.
- What? I thought
we were gonna get high and look at bugs.
No, I kind of have a bit of a
plan to surprise Kayla at work.
You bought her chocolates.
- Salt-encrusted.
- Josh, if you're not careful,
you're gonna end up married to this girl.
- We-we just started going out.
- Does she keep
any stuff at your apartment?
Uh, no. Uh... Don't you lie to me.
- Don't lie to me!
- Okay, work-work clothes
and... almond milk.
Oh. Oh, my God.
Listen, everything's golden.
Okay?
I know what I'm doing.
- My plant's broke.
- Aw, he'll be okay.
He just needs a little more
water and some sunshine.
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
- ♪ Are you ready for some chocolate? ♪
- (laughs)
- How's it going?
- Josh! What are you doing here?
Oh, you know, I just thought,
uh, you could maybe use a, uh,
a little mid-afternoon pick-me-up.
Oh, my God, you are so sweet.
Oh, I do what I can. Also, would you like
to have dinner with me tonight?
- I'd love that.
- I was thinking
we could do quinoa and maybe whatever else
Mm-hmm. goes with quinoa and...
mm-hmm... mm!
Uh...
Where-where-where are they taking us?
Hell if I know.
Listen up, punks!
You're all here for the same reason!
You're not married! Yet!
But if you continue
down the road that you're on,
you continue to make the kinds
of choices you've been making,
you're gonna end up...
in the suburbs.
Take a good look, ladies.
This is where you're headed!
See any sports bars or clubs
or sexy single ladies?
Ew...
Hey, Mike?
I-I don't have time for this.
I got to go home
and cook dinner for Kayla, so...
Don't you get it? I'm doing this for you.
Ooh! What the hell
is that guy carrying?
It's a Diaper Genie.
It's full of human shit.
Oh, God!
Oh, my... oh...
Welcome to hell, boys!
Let's go. Now. Out.
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
This looks like a nice street.
Got three-car garages and speed bumps...
Oh, hey, look at that guy
grilling hamburgers!
Do those look like burgers to you?
What the hell is on that grill?
Portobello mushrooms.
Yeah, Portobello mushrooms
would be pretty good with quinoa.
Okay!
It's time to introduce you
to a special speaker.
His name is Daniel Schultz
and he's been married for 11 years.
I suggest you listen carefully
to what he has to say.
I brought you some fresh meat.
Hi, guys. My name is Daniel.
I'm 39 years old,
and I'm serving a life sentence
to my wife, without
the possibility of parole.
You know, when I met Amy, she was fun!
She... chugged beer faster than me.
She loved cocaine.
Do it whenever it was around.
A month ago,
she caught me smoking
a cigarette right there
on the porch, and she started to cry.
She made me promise
to start taking my health more seriously.
Yeah. So I started doing Pilates.
I do this thing, and then I do this thing!
I got my Lululemons pulled up to here!
With my useless penis
sittin' in the middle,
looking like a little b...
How are you?
How's it going?
Did you call Deb about that thing?
Next on my list.
Next thing on my list.
'Kay.
Yeah.
What the hell is that?
- Sounded like a text.
- Oh, yeah,
- you got a text?
- Yeah.
Let's see what it says.
"Five...
"five little kisses
- for your cute little baby face."
- Five kisses?
Oh, 'cause we got eight...
eight guys here. I don't know
if that's enough kisses for everyone.
Who's gonna suck my dick?
- U-Understood.
- He's the one I was telling you about.
He's only 27, and already
in a serious relationship.
No, we just kind of
started seeing each other, so...
Oh, first you're just going out,
then all of a sudden she's got almond milk
and work clothes at your place.
ding-dong,
ding-dong, you're married, you're pregnant,
gravestone.
Listen, I mean, you're a great girl.
I just, I don't think it's working out.
It's not you... I mean,
everything's so crazy
- with my band right now...
- Uh-huh. Yeah.
I-I mean, maybe we can try,
like, an open relationship.
Uh... Becca?
You there?
Uh, hi, Kayla. So, I've been doing
a lot of thinking about, uh, us,
and I just needed to say that...
I like you a lot...
and also, what do you think
about Portobello mushrooms
for dinner? They do go with quinoa!
Exactly what I was thinking. So eight-ish?
We lost him.
Quinoa.
M... M-Maggie.
Hey.
I'm sorry for barging in like this.
I just, um...
I really need a friend right now.
- Can I come in?
- Well, yeah. Of course. Yeah. C-Come on in.
- Thanks.
- Whoa. Whoa.
Hi. Hi, uh, Kayla. I think... I think...
I think I need to postpone.
Um, I'm feeling kind of tired,
all of a sudden, like I...
like I might be coming down with something.
You don't have to cook, if it's a hassle.
We could just do takeout. Y...
W-Would it be okay if we just try tomorrow?
Yeah. Get some rest,
and I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay. Thank you so much.
That's-that's lovely.
I'll see you... I'll see you then.
and I told him,
"If you don't appreciate me,
I don't think I can do this anymore."
Wh-Which... I mean, I think you
did the right thing. Yeah.
- Yeah?
- It's none of my business,
but you don't deserve to
be treated like that.
I don't.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
for unloading on you like this. I just...
You know, nobody knows me
like you do, so...
Are you cooking something?
- Oh, crap. Yes, I am, too.
- Really?
That would be... You're
smelling portobello mushrooms,
uh, and quinoa.
Really! Well, I'm full of surprises.
Would you...
would you like some?
Um... can I?
- Yeah. Yeah. Is...
- Yeah?
No, there's enough, uh...
there's enough for two people.
Yes.
Okay, just...
- uh, will you just give me a few moments?
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
I need to...
They're ready for you inside,
Mr. Greenberg.
Okay.
Mr. Greenberg, you stand accused
of boyfriend misconduct.
- How do you plead?
- Not-not guilty,
Your Honor.
The fact is, all right,
I postponed dinner with Kayla.
But, uh, where's the crime in that?
Does a boyfriend not have the right to...
- rearrange a date?
- Son, that's not
what's at issue here. You are here today
because you lied to her.
Up, bup, bup, bup, bup, bup, bup!
Webster's Dictionary,
which I'm sure you're familiar with...
I'm sure all these good
people, familiar with it...
defines a lie thusly,
as a falsehood, an untruth.
All I did was kind of alter plans.
- No lies were uttered.
- Thank you for the vocabulary lesson, Mr. Greenberg.
What about when you said... and I quote...
"I am feeling kind of tired."
- I was feeling kind of tired.
- Maybe.
But that's not why you canceled dinner.
You canceled because
your ex-girlfriend showed up...
Well, now, listen, Your Honor,
we-we can split hairs all day,
jibber-jabber back and forth
until we're as mixed up as a...
as a one-legged man at a hoedown!
- Why is that funny?
- But the fact is
I have committed no offense,
and I defy this court to prove otherwise.
Aw, screw it. All right,
the court finds in Josh's favor.
I knew it! Thank you...
Do not give him high fives. Do not!
Indicate high fives. Multiple.
And then that guy was all like, Mm-hmm.
"Uh, reservation? What reservation?"
So creepy. Yeah... yeah. So scary.
- Remember how gross that pool was?
- Oh, my God.
Somehow didn't dissuade
the-the two of us dumb-asses
from swimming in it.
Not just swimming in it.
I'll... be right back.
I mean, how many times are we
gonna do this? Your Honor...
- I am completely innocent.
- Oh, please. She referenced sex
- and then she touched you on the hand.
- Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't...
Are friends not allowed
to touch each other's hands?
I didn't realize that.
Of course they are. Wh-What's next?
No more high fives? A ban on
fist bumps, perhaps, eh?
All right. What about the wine?
- Explain that.
- Aha!
Webster's Dictionary
defines wine as "the fermented
juice of grapes used especially
- as a bev..." I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean explain wine.
We know what wine is.
There's a precedent
for grown-ups sharing a bottle
- of wine at dinner.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hmm.
- But when's the last time
that you and Mike shared a bottle of wine?
Shared a bottle of wine
and touched each other's hands?
Listen, we-we can... we
can jibber-jabber all day,
back and forth Jibber-jabber a second time.
Until we're as... mixed up as a-a...
three-legged horse at a rodeo.
One lady.
Thank you, ma'am.
Uh, but the-the fact remains,
I have done nothing wrong.
Goddamn it.
All right, my hands are tied.
Due to a lack of hard evidence,
this court is forced to rule
in Josh's favor.
No one high-five him.
- Thank you. She did.
- Oh...
Susan...
- Hey.
- Oh.
I am so tired.
Yeah.
Oh. Yeah, I guess... I guess it's late.
It is late.
I should probably go.
Or-or-or...
or... we-we, uh...
could watch something.
Like what?
We never finished Carnivàle.
I know, I know.
People watch shows together
all the time, man.
But come on, man... I mean,
she was about to leave.
She was out the door, and you suggested
something that would keep her there.
That's, for me, when it became a date.
A-a date? Specifically a date?
- Yes.
- Because...
the dictionary might disagree.
Oh, God, the dictionary...!
Oh, fuck you off.
Webster's defines a date
as a romantic outing, okay?
- So did we go... did we go out?
- No. No. No.
Did we kiss? Maybe not. But,
come on, you're on the couch,
- you're watching Carnivàle.
- Listen,
- I am not the kind of guy who cheats.
- Well...
The point is we can
jibber-jabber back and forth...
Okay? Until we're
Jibber-jabber a third time.
As mixed up as a-a...
Here it comes... two-horned!
- As a two-horned, uh...
- Asian.
- Asian, um...
- Careful.
- You son of a bitch. Okay.
- Trapped.
All right. I used to be a prosecutor.
The point is what I'm trying to say is
technically...
I haven't done anything wrong.
- Well, technically, no, you haven't.
- Aha!
Technically, no, I haven't.
You said technically I
haven't done anything wrong.
That means... that means I win.
Remember this day.
The day that blind Lady Justice
took her own life.
It is with great shame
and utter disgust...
that this court is forced
to rule in Josh's favor.
Thanks, man.
"Thanks, man"?
Don't type that. What are...
Goddamn it.
The moment you put on that
red nose and threw in your lot
with the strongman and the dog boy...
Yeah. It's a pretty good...
pretty good episode
of Carnivàle.
You cannot stop the cyclone's swirl
or the dog boy's dog boy dance.
- The great orb spins despite.
- Um...
the will of man, and now the
dust has settled on the choices
thou hath wrought.
For this is no carnival, my friend.
This is Carnivàle!
We're ready.
Josh?
Think he went to the bedroom with her?
Oh... Told you!
Hi. Hi.
- Hi. How are you feeling?
- Uh, uh, uh, better.
Good. Good. And so do you want
to do dinner tonight?
Uh... Listen, you're a terrific girl
and I really, uh, enjoy your
company and I'm really sorry
about this, but I don't think
we can keep hanging out.
So we should probably not have dinner.
- This is abrupt.
- Yeah. Yep.
I know. I'm sorry.
- Okay, bye.
- Okay, bye-bye.
Frittatas.
Hey...
Hey.
- I'm so hungover.
- Oh, okay.
Well, tell you what, your best, uh, remedy
- is my delicious frittatas.
- Mm-mm. Josh...
last night was a mistake.
Um...
- Okay.
- Let's just pretend
- like it never happened, okay?
- Okay, so...
Um, yeah.
We-we finished Carnivàle last night.
Hmm?
We finally finished the last two
episodes of Carnivàle.
I don't remember.
Oh. What...
what are you... What is that?
Uh, no, I was trying to shake your hand.
Okay.
- Bye.
- Okay.
Uh, wuh, uh...
I just came to get my things.
- I saw Maggie on the stairs.
- Uh...
I-I'm so sorry. I...
It was an accident. I was drunk. She-she...
she-she took advan... look, I'm-I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You suck.
I-I know.