We did not think that karting
could become a career.
AYRTON'S FATHER
MILTON DA SILVA
But it has become a
big part of our lives
and we are a bit worried because
then along came Formula One.
May God protect him forever.
AYRTON'S MOTHER
NEYDE SENNA
All the dangers are my biggest fear.
I would like to thank him
because he is a good son
and this year he has worked
very hard and honestly.
For me, it is more important than any title.
The time has come.
Ayrton is ready to ride in a Formula
One car for the first time.
I believe it was God
who gave me this opportunity,
I've been waiting for a long time.
And now it is helpful
to remain calm, tranquil, relaxed.
Ayrton, this is a beautiful city,
with wonderful streets to walk,
but unsuitable to host a race, no?
REGINALDO LEME
Indeed. I arrived at the last minute
and I was surprised.
I've never been to Monaco.
I did some testing
And fortunately, I managed
to adapt to the track.
There is no margin for error:
any error would result in an accident.
But for now, I'm satisfied.
I was travelling a lot, as a
Formula One journalist
when Ayrton began to be noticed
driving a Toleman.
VOICE OF REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
Toleman was not a winning team.
The car was bad and never won a race.
That's why what Ayrton did in Monaco
was true genius.
Ayrton Senna overtakes Keke Rosberg
gaining third position.
VOICE OF GALVÃO BUENO
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
And overtakes Niki Lauda!
Ayrton Senna
takes second place!
At the most dangerous part of the track!
VOICE OF JAMES HUNT
1976 FORMULA ONE WORLD CHAMPION
Incredible!
Ayrton raises his arms
and gestures with enthusiasm!
Celebrating as if he won the race!
If we had continued for a few more laps,
I am sure Ayrton would have passed him.
I had a serious chance of winning.
But until you cross the finishing line
in first position,
it is impossible to make a prediction.
Formula One is politics, money
and while you are making your way through it,
you must deal with such things.
Ayrton Senna
the new star of Formula One!
Appearing for the first time
on the Formula One podium
after a fantastic performance.
JOHN BISIGNANO
LOTUS
VOICE OF JOHN BISIGNAGNO
ESPN COMMENTATOR
Even as a child, he
always knew what he wanted
and he always got it.
AYRTON'S MOTHER
NEYDA SENNA
For example, he always paid attention
in the classroom at school,
so he didn't have to study at home
and so he had more time
to play on his go-kart.
VOICE OF RICHARD WILLIAMS
SPORTS JOURNALIST, THE GUARDIAN
PORTUGUESE GRAND PRIX - APRIL 21st 1985
AYRTON'S SECOND RACE WITH LOTUS
Ayrton was exceptional when it rained.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
When the conditions were bad
and the track became slippery
he had a higher gear.
The Estoril race was incredible.
He lapped all his opponents except one.
It is wonderful!
An extraordinary feeling.
I am very happy because,
in my second year in Formula One,
I managed to fulfill my first dream,
which was to win my first Grand Prix.
It is something unique.
MILI OKADA
FUJI TV
I think many Japanese girls are fans of Mr. Senna.
Now I am close to him
and I'm so nervous...
ALAIN PROST
WORLD CHAMPION 1985, 1986
SELINA SCOTT
WOGAN TALK SHOW, BBC
The first year at McLaren
was decisive in the life of Ayrton.
VIVIANE SENNA
AYRTON'S SISTER
He was very nervous.
It was as if he bore the weight
of the world on his shoulders
because he now had the responsibility
to demonstrate he was a
first rate driver.
MONACO GRAND PRIX
14 May 1988
JAPANESE GRAND PRIX
30th OCTOBER 1988
It is the fifteenth Grand Prix of the season.
As the sun rises, Brazil will await the chequered flag
and for Ayrton Senna to win
his first world title in Formula One,
realising a dream he had
since he was a child.
VOICE OF PIERRE VAN VILET
TF1 COMMENTATOR
We are about to start.
Green light.
Senna does not start!
Prost came out ahead
while Ayrton Senna was left behind.
Ayrton Senna is in 14th place.
I thought, "So long title. It's over".
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
He takes eighth place.
An amazing comeback from Senna.
Then his favourite thing happened,
it began to rain.
Senna is now in fourth position.
Senna runs, runs, runs!
Ayrton Senna overtakes Prost and onwards!
I started giving thanks
during the last lap.
I thanked God.
It was incredible. I could not believe
I was going to win the championship,
Despite all the anxiety and tension.
I felt God's presence.
I have seen God
It was a very special moment for me.
An indescribable feeling.
It remains engraved in my
memory and as a part of me.
Ayrton Senna of Brazil!
World Champion 1988!
SAO PAULO
What an incredible race!
A great victory.
He had to come from 16th place.
AYRTON SENNA
WORLD CHAMPION 1988
Ayrton, how do you feel
as World Champion?
I feel so much peace.
It is as if someone had removed
a huge weight
from my shoulders and head.
It is difficult to understand what it means
to be a World Champion.
SAO PAULO
15th NOVEMBER 1988
He is an amazing person, wonderful.
He is very humble and imporoves the
image of Brazil abroad.
He shares his victory with us.
I admire him very much.
He is a very brave man.
I just know this.
We are proud of him.
It is one of the few things
that we can still be proud of.
Once, I asked Ayrton
"When will you think about quitting?"
He said, "Mum, the day I am
the champion I will stop."
In my heart,
I knew that was not true.
We all know that.
SENNA FAMILY HOME VIDEO
SENNA'S FAMILY AND THE
FAMILY OF TAMIN ANGRA
VIVIANE SENNA
AYRTON'S SISTER
After the 1988 Championship,
after he won the title,
We noticed that he had changed between
the beginning and the end of the year.
Because he had found himself.
He had discovered who he was.
It was a process that reached
its conclusion after his championship victory.
At Christmas, many things happen.
New friends are made,
like the person I'm about to introduce.
XUXA MENEGHEL
BRAZILIAN TV STAR
He was part of my 1988.
Ayrton Senna.
Isn't he cute?
I have a few questions for you.
I think everybody is excited,
but none more than me,
It is not easy to talk.
Ayrton is now my friend.
Ayrton, what do you want for Christmas?
As a Christmas present?
What I really want, I cannot say here!
Why not?
It would be censored.
Let's say I just want to be happy.
Whisper it to me.
Happy New Year.
Happy 1990.
Happy '91.
Happy '92.
Happy '93.
VOICE OF RON DENNIS
MCLAREN TEAM MANAGER
Senna and Prost. Prost and Senna.
The order of the grid is always one or the other.
It is a war between them.
For the French driver Alain Prost,
he believes his teammate is unfair to him.
and these disagreements could
affect the rest of the season.
Grand Prix after Grand Prix they were
more and more distant from each other.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
Ayrton said:
"This Frenchman is tough.
"He wants war."
After a little more time,
they became completely isolated
and they didn't speak anymore.
JEAN-MARIE BALESTRE
FIA PRESIDENT
I would like to give a warm welcome to
the President of FISA, Mr. Balestre.
JAPANESE GRAND PRIX
PRE-RACE DRIVERS MEETING
VOICE OF JOHN BISIGNANO
ESPN COMMENTATOR
JAPANESE GRAND PRIX
22nd OCTOBER 1989
Prost is first. Senna, second.
Prost jumped into the lead.
His start was better.
LAP 45 OF 53, CASIO CHICANE
LAP 46 OF 53, CASIO CHICANE
Finally they clash! It goes in the favour of Prost.
If the race ends like this,
Prost wins the title.
But, for Ayrton Senna it is a no win situation.
Nannini passes.
Nannini is now in the lead.
Senna is still in the pits.
Senna is back on track,
but he is far behind Nannini.
Catching up is almost impossible.
It's all or nothing,
five laps to go.
It will be a suicidal race for Senna,
if he decides to try anything.
Then Prost saw Ayrton return to the race
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
and immediately went to the stewards' office.
Nannini, first. Senna, second.
Senna tries to pass Nannini!
Senna is in the lead!
LAP 51 OF 53, CASIO CHICANE.
Waving Brazilian flags!
All stand up!
Ayrton Senna.
The checkered flag!
Senna celebrates in the cockpit.
AYRTON SENNA WINNER - JAPANESE GRAND PRIX
He hits his helmet.
The Brazilian Ayrton Senna.
Visibly moved,
He raises his visor
and wipes away a tear.
It is a fantastic victory.
I have never seen anything like it.
There was no podium celebration
immediately after the race.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
STEWARDS OFFICE
As the wait was prolonged, the more people feared
that the decision was becoming political.
The decision taken by the
team of FIA Commissioners
at the Grand Prix of Japan
is to exclude the number one car
and its driver, Ayrton Senna,
from the final outcome of the race.
After the race, a giant screen has
repeatedly shown the incident
and everything that happened to
enable Senna's return to the track.
After reviewing these images,
race officials have concluded
that Senna failed to use the
chicane to resume racing
Senna has infringed Article 56
of the FIA regulations.
REPLAY AUSTRIAN GRAND PRIX 1981
FIA HEADQUARTERS - PARIS
The Court of Appeals declares
a six-month license suspension for Senna.
A warning not only to Ayrton
Senna but for all the drivers,
And a fine of $100,000.
While he is one of the best drivers in the world,
you have no right to
cause stupid accidents.
That was quite a profound moment for Ayrton
VIVIANE SENNA
because Balestre had behaved
even worse than Prost.
He even thought about giving
up Formula One racing.
VOICE OF RON DENNIS
MCLAREN TEAM MANAGER
All drivers aspire towards their limits.
My limit is different from that of Prost.
This is the reality.
Instead of trying
to improve his own capacity,
he found it easier to attack me.
The fact that I believe in God,
the fact that I have faith in God,
is not to say that I am immortal,
It does not mean that I am immune from
danger, as has been said.
I'm afraid of hurting myself
just like everyone else,
especially driving in Formula One,
where the threat is constant.
SPANISH GRAND PRIX
30th SEPTEMBER 1990
MARTIN DONNELLY
LOTUS
AYRTON SENNA 1:19.844
POLE POSITION
JAPANESE GRAND PRIX
21st OCTOBER 1990
VOICE OF JOHN BISIGNANO
ESPN COMMENTATOR
VOICE OF RON DENNIS
MCLAREN TEAM MANAGER
VOICE OF AYRTON SENNA
If the race continues,
the title will have been decided.
The Championship is over.
Ayrton Senna
is the World Champion of 1990.
VOICE OF RON DENNIS
MCLAREN TEAM MANAGER
FIA AWARDS
PARIS 1990
JACKIE STEWART
FORMULA ONE WORLD CHAMPION 1969, 1971, 1973
Two of the greatest champions
in the history of Formula One
ended up in the sand.
Championship ruined.
They accuse each other,
but Prost was the hardest.
His reaction was violent.
I wanted to punch him in the
face, but I was so disgusted
that I did not succeed.
It makes me feel sick.
The situation in Brazil
was very negative and depressing.
VIVIANE SENNA
AYRTON'S SISTER
But many times,
when Ayrton won,
instead of trying to hide
his Brazilian origins, as others did,
he did the opposite,
waving the flag of his country.
He took it inside the car every Sunday.
He was an inspiration to people.
That's why they loved him so much.
Ayrton had never won the
Grand Prix of Brazil.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
Since he entered Formula One he always
dreamed of winning in his home country.
BRAZILIAN GRAND PRIX
21st MARCH 1991
The Brazilian Grand Prix has begun.
Red light. Green light.
A good start.
Come on, Senna!
Senna is in command.
LAP 54/67
VOICE OF RON DENNIS
MCLAREN TEAM MANAGER
Here's Senna. It's starting to rain.
It's raining. It must stop.
7 LAPS REMAINING
It seems impossible to drive a
Formula One car stuck in sixth gear.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
Ayrton wanted to stop.
He could no longer drive it.
But he had already tried many times
to win the Brazilian Grand Prix
and found a special force within himself.
The last corner.
And Senna crosses the line.
Go for the win!
Ayrton, Ayrton ...
The Brazilian Ayrton Senna!
In the lead from start to
finish, he wins at lnterlagos!
A wonderful victory for Senna!
No way!
God damn it, I won!
( Prost ) "son of a bitch"
He won and then fainted.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
It was his most heroic moment.
Because of the tremendous physical effort,
I had muscle spasms of my
shoulder and neck.
The pain was tremendous.
The physical and mental stress
this weekend was unheard of.
But there could be only one result.
I finished the race with no more energy.
Come here, Dad. Come on.
Come here.
Quiet, Ayrton.
Today, I fought hard.
I wanted to finish the race
and finish in first position,
because He is the greatest
and He will give me this
race after all.
That's what happened.
It is God who gave me this race
and I'm happy.
It was thrilling.
All hail the Brazilian Senna
for his victory. Congratulations.
I thank all of Brazil.
I thank all the fans.
This weekend I felt so
much warmth around me
that we could not do anything but win.
It could not have been any other way.
And we did.
SENNA FAMILY HOUSE, SAO PAULO
Ayrton was so well known in Brazil
VIVIANE SENNA
AYRTON'S SISTER
there were a lot of people asking for help
for personal problems. Sometimes hospitals
and charities sought his
support and donations.
Ayrton gave donations and tried to work things out.
But did not want to make random donations.
He wanted to develop a whole thing,
something organized and structured
to help Brazil, especially the children.
VOICE OF JOHN BISIGNANO
ESPN COMMENTATOR
MEXICAN GRAND PRIX
14th JUNE 1991
VOICE OF PROFESSOR SID WATKINS
F1 DOCTOR
GERMAN GRAND PRIX
28th JULY 1991
ROLAND BRUYNSERAEDE
RACE DIRECTOR
3 HOURS LATER
VOICE OF RICHARD WILLIAMS
SPORTS JOURNALIST, THE GUARDIAN
JAPANESE GRAND PRIX
19th OCTOBER 1991
LAP 9 OF 53
Mansell tries to overtake, but he goes straight on.
Mansell goes straight on!
The Championship is over.
Mansell cannot get out of the gravel trap.
AYRTON SENNA
three-time WORLD CHAMPION
Ayrton Senna of Brazil,
three-time Formula One World Champion!
A lifetime dedicated to this moment
by a genius of international sport.
Three-time world champion
and many other titles ahead of him.
And only 31 years of age.
Thirty three wins, three world titles.
Breaking record after record.
He celebrates as only Senna can do.
The third world title puts Senna
amongst the greatest of all time.
It is very special for me.
Thank you so much.
SAO PAULO
5th NOVEMBER 1991
I kissed the hands of Senna, the left hand
of Senna, three-times world champion.
I want to see Senna.
I want to hug him and kiss him.
I have got a box with
photos and newspaper articles.
Everything you can imagine.
He is the only good thing in Brazil, right?
It is a wonderful party.
Anything goes. What matters is happiness.
Have you spoken about Formula One today?
Formula One is too rigid.
Today is Carnival.
Have any of your girls
ever told you: "Faster, Ayrton?"
Yes.
Ayrton acheiving the third world title
was the culmination of a script
he had written for himself
well before entering Formula One,
because he knew he could do it
and could do even more.
The great idol of sport in Brazil.
With the third title, he became
the world's great sporting idol.
NIGEL MANSELL WORLD CHAMPION 1992
The negotiations were lengthy
and we still do not know who will be
Prost's teammate.
The three-time world champion has signed
a two-year contract with Williams
and during the week
will begin testing the car.
VOICE OF ALAIN PROST
I'm pretty sure of one thing:
I'm the one that has more to lose.
if I had to stop for a year or more,
Because I'm at an age near the peak of my career
and the number of years in the career
of a Formula One driver is limited.
So if I stop, I'd lose out
more than anyone else,
both professionally and personally.
ADRIANE GALISTEU
In 1993, Ayrton drove
his car so brilliantly.
For me, it was his best season.
BRAZILIAN GRAND PRIX
EUROPEAN GRAND PRIX
MONACO GRAND PRIX
AUSTRALIAN GRAND PRIX
FINAL RACE OF 1993
VOICE OF MARK FOGARTY
F1 JOURNALIST
AYRTON SENNA
WINNER AUSTRALIAN GRAND PRIX
ANNOUNCEMENT OF WILLIAMS DRIVERS
For Ayrton Senna, it is
a race against time.
He has to attune himself to be an integral
part of the team and adapt to the new car.
He says he is not yet comfortable.
The car no longer has the electronic
components used last year.
He is without traction control, special
brakes and active suspension.
The cars are much less stable
without the electronically controlled suspension.
As a result, they are more difficult to drive
and it is very likely that more cars will leave the track.
So we might see more cars crashing,
giving more excitement to the audience.
Also for us, as long as nothing happens to the drivers.
Otherwise, it is not a good situation.
BRAZILIAN GRAND PRIX
27th MARCH 1994
LAP 56 OF 71
PATRICK HEAD
CHIEF ENGINEER WILLIAMS
PACIFIC GRAND PRIX
17th APRIL 1994
FLAVIO BRIATORE
BENETTON TEAM MANAGER
VOICE OF FRANK WILLIAMS
TEAM MANAGER WILLIAMS
SAN MARINO GRAND PRIX, IMOLA
APRIL 1994
FRIDAY
29th APRIL 1994
Senna was so nervous that weekend.
I had never seen him so tense.
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBO TV COMMENTATOR
I never saw him smile,
even for a moment.
He maintained a bemused, bored, even a sad demeanour.
RUBENS BARRICHELLO
JORDAN
Do you know Ayrton
or should I introduce you?
We met four years earlier. I already met him.
Knew him by name, or in person?
I know him because I follow
Formula One and then we met in person.
Why are you so nervous, then?
When we stand next to a person like
him we always become emotional.
Good luck to the champion
and the future champion.
RUBENS BARRICHELLO
QUALIFYING
REPLAY
SATURDAY
30th APRIL 1994
VOICE OF JOHN BISIGNANO
ESPN COMMENTATOR
ROLAND RATZENBERGER
SIMTEK DRIVER
SIMTEK
VOICE OF PIERRE VAN VILET
TF1 COMMENTATOR
VOICE OF PROFESSOR SID WATKINS
F1 DOCTOR
REGINALDO LEME
GLOBE F1 COMMENTATOR
That Saturday, at dinner,
Frank Williams was not at all sure
that Senna would be present on the grid.
I was sure that he did not want to compete.
SUNDAY
1st MAY 1994
That morning when I awoke,
VIVIANE SENNA
AYRTON'S SISTER
God asked me to speak to him.
He opened the Bible and
read a passage that said
God would give him
the greatest gift of all,
that of God himself.
A collision.
Everyone swerves around. Look.
Lamy arrives at full speed.
Lehto is stopped.
JJ LEHTO
BENETTON
A nasty collision.
Lamy and Lehto have had no luck.
PEDRO LAMY
LOTUS
The safety car goes on track.
SAFETY CAR
Lights out on the safety car.
It means that the safety car
is about to come into the pits.
Starting again. Senna is in the lead.
Schumacher is second.
On the sixth lap, Michael Schumacher is
trying to put pressure on Senna.
IN CAR CAMERA
AYRTON SENNA LAP 6 OF 58
Bad impact for Senna.
At the Tamburello curve.
A very serious accident.
VOICE OF PROFESSOR SID WATKINS
F1 DOCTOR
There was a lawsuit?
In my opinion,
the steering column broke
and the car became uncontrollable.
But above all, it was inevitable
because the car crashed
at such an angle. The suspension arm
went into his helmet.
BOLOGNA, ITALY
SAO PAULO
4th MAY 1994
He was my idol.
He represented the best of Brazil.
I miss you, Senna.
I will never forget you.
Brazilians need food,
education, health
and a little joy.
The joy has been removed.
AYRTON SENNA DA SILVA
21/03/1960 - 01/05/1994
Nothing can separate me from the love of God.
Ayrton Senna died at the age of 34.
As a result of his death,
the FIA appointed
Professor Sid Watkins
to improve safety in Formula One.
No fatalities have occurred in
Formula One since.
The Ayrton Senna Foundation,
founded in 1995 by his sister Viviane,
has helped to educate more than 1.2
million needy children in Brazil.
Alain Prost is a member of the
advisory board of the foundation.
Perfect English Subtitles By DaveWeed :-)