World in
Action...
enters the
struggling,
changing
world...
of the
seven year old.
They're teddy bears,
they're not real.
A Polar, look
at those claws.
This is no ordinary
outing to the zoo.
It's a very
special ocassion.
We brought these twenty children
together for the very first time.
They are like any
other children...
except that they come from
startlingly different backgrounds.
No!
No feeding, it says.
Stop it
at once
I know there's no feeding but it
doesn't really matter.
We brought these
children together...
because we
wanted a glimpse of...
England in
the year 2000.
The shop stewards and the executives of
the year 2000 are now seven years old.
Give me a child
until he is seven...
and I will give
you the man.
Let's get to know
these children.
Taking her little sister to school on
the London Council Estate,
Jackie.
From the
Yorkshire Dales,
Nicholas.
He goes to a one
room village school...
four miles away
from his home.
From this
Liverpool suburb...
We chose...
Neil.
And this
is Tony.
His girl friend
calls him a monkey.
He goes to one of
the oldest schools...
in the East End
of London.
Would everybody,
please sit round now?
Get on with their work, I don't want
to see any backs to me.
Shouldn't be anybody
turning around...
Tony, do you
hear as well?
Next to Tony there
is his girl friend,
Michelle.
Tony!
Don't turn
around again!
In this class room,
Waltzing Matilda...
is being
rendered in Latin.
This is an exclusive
pre-prep school...
in Kensington.
I think the
Beatles are mad...
because they make
too much noise...
and their
hair-style's so bad.
If they
composed
softer music...
I wouldn't
mind so much.
I just loathe
their hair-cuts
That was John.
If you loathe their hair-cut...
you wouldn't have liked
Henry the Fifths hair-cut.
This is Charles.
And that is Andrew.
This dormetary is in
a children's home...
supported by charity.
This is Paul...
and Simon.
I had a dream when all the
world was on top of me...
and everything was on me,
and I just about got out
and everything flew up in the air...
and that all landed on my head.
Go on Potter.
If you don't now, don't go.
Now shoot!
- We're going to!
My heart's desire is to see my daddy
who is six thousand miles away.
Bruce doesn't live with
his parents either...
but for a different reason.
He goes to a private
boarding school in Surrey.
Bruce wants to
be a missionary.
I think the most important thing in the
world is everyone should know about god.
I think we should give all... some...
most of our money to the poor people.
In the head mistress' study...
of a fashionable school for girls...
we met Suzie.
We spoke to her "deep in the
chintz" of the staff room.
Tell us, do you have
any boyfriend Suzie?
Ummm...
yes!
-Tell me about him.
He's up in Scotland
and I think he's thirteen.
and I'm rather lonely up there
because he usually goes to school.
but we usually play till about...
half past six when he
comes home from school.
Then we go in and then...
he goes home to do his homework.
The world of the seven year old...
can be primitive... even violent.
What do the children themselves
think about fighting?
Is it important to fight? Yes!
Well I feel like joining in
when there's already a fight.
I always feel like that.
I always feel like joining in
when there's already one.
Neil from the Liverpool suburb.
We don't do much fighting in school
because we think it's horrible and
It hurts.
Sometimes we play nice with the boys
and sometimes we argue with the boys.
- Susan, Jackie's friend.
- Do you ever fight with them?
- No, just argue
Most of the time we are all right.
But. one day when
I remember we were
all coming to school and
at break time they started hitting us
and so we started to fight!
so we said we're never gonna
play with you again.
But we always do.
If they fight me I think someone if
someone comes up and starts fighting...
then I think it serves them right
We play with Richard the
Lion Heart and William Tell.
Well... we pretend we got swords...
and then we make the
noises of the sword-fighting...
and when somebody stabs us we'll go
....'aaaaaahh'!
Nicholas from Yorkshire...
seven this year.
I have quite a lot of
fun when I fight...
I always like to wait till someone...
you better watch out for me...
because as soon
as you're not looking...
I like to dash up and put my hands
in front and hit them against your back.
And on the grass...
we... we play international wrestling.
Yeah that's only in the
summer time though.
yes summer we
can go on the grass.
I just like fighting somehow.
- Yes, tell me about it.
I just want to. He was in the
washroom and threw soap at me
I chased him in the
class and I hit him
When I was down in
the place at Kent...
there was this little boy who I think
was younger than me... and...
my Nanny was having
a game with him...
and he was a naughty boy because
he slapped me in the tummy.
Some boys can be nice and
others can be horrible.
And then he slapped Nanny...
and I didn't like
that kind of boys.
Jacqueline, what do you think
about boys fighting?
Well... its really silly
to fight because...
if you fight and Miss comes in the
class-room then you only get told off
I think discipline is fair enough.
Farmer is the sergeant and he is quite
a good one, last term he wasn't...
He had a cold
and he didn't want to wear his
voice out from shouting.
And that's Farmer.
He gives me nightmares.
The vast majority of the seven years
olds know little of discipline.
But a few, from the
moment they are born...
are trained to accept it.
squad steady
squad left foot
in one place
squad breathe in
Well I don't like
the big boys
hitting us
The prefects sending us
out for nothing. And they
the staff in washroom
sends the nurse out
where there is no talking, no
I wasn't talking today...
and Brown set me up for nothing.
I think the system
of having House Captains...
is rather good because when
somebody's naughty
the House Captain asks him and...
and... and has a talk to him.
Once I had a talk to Gravel
he was in my house...
and...and I asked Sir he could put him
out of my house because...
he was always getting minuses.
What did the sir say?
-Yes.
The sir said that he was...
he... we would see
about it this term.
Well... I think
it's a very good system.
And you had to
speak to anyone?
Just because you
are one, I suppose.
No, no,
I haven't.
You're not
are you?
But I am. Straull Meckanace.
got three minuses in a day.
He is
a pest.
You think, House Captain should be
elected or appointed by sir?
Appointed.
Appointed
I think its more
fair to have elected.
Yes. So do I but I think it is best
to be appointed. -Because you didn't...
It saves lot of time.
-It doesn't!
Appointed!
It is much easier because all
that you have to do is...
count up the pluses and here
you are.  -Yes!
At Suzie's
school...
the exercise
is classical ballet.
For Neil and
his classmates...
its free
movement to music.
Michelle and her friends are
left to amuse themselves.
This distinction between freedom and
discipline is the key to their whole future.
What about
after school?
What do they do
in their spare time?
When I've gone
home, I have tea.
Then I practice
my piano.
And then I
practice my recorder.
Then I start
watching television.
What time do
you go to bed?
When I have my
bath at six o'clock...
and then go to bed at seven and
read till half past seven.
I usually go to bed at ten o'clock
or eleven o'clock.
When I
go home...
I go and
see my mother...
and I have tea
and watch t.v....
and then I... I do my homework and
then I go and see my father.
And then what
time do you go to bed?
last night I didn't go
to bed until seven.
When I go
home, I come...
I come in and mummy
gives me a cup of tea...
and then I go
out and play.
And when it
starts to get dark...
I come in again
and put on t.v.
I am the only child in the village
except for my baby brother.
he was one
last Friday...
I mean the friday
before last Friday...
Neil from
Liverpool,
said he prefered
living in town.
Because in the winter, if
you lived in the country...
it would be just all be wet and there
wouldn't be anything for miles around
And you get soaked if you try to go out
and there's no shelter anywhere...
except in your own house.
But in the town
you can go out on...
wet, wintery days because you
can always find somewhere to shelter...
because there
are lots of places.
They'd like to come out for a holiday
in the country when we like...
when I like the
holiday in the town.
In Tony and
Michelle's school...
unlike
others...
boys and girls are brought
together in the class room.
And they meet quite naturally in the
cinema queue on Saturday morning.
Sometime on Saturday
mornings I go to the cinema
Sometime with my friends
and sometimes with him.
You don't!
- I do!
she doesn't
I don't always
see you
you go to a
different cinema
last week i went to
the.....where you go
yeah but i
didn't go
How much does mixing or
segregating the sexes matter?
What effect does it have on what
boys and girls think about each other?
will it influence their chances
of love and marriage?
We asked the children what they
thought about the opposite sex.
Tell me do you
have any girlfriends?
Well...
not many.
What do you think
about girls?
well not much.
I don't think
much of girls.
Touch a boy,
kiss a boy.
Sometimes we get
our own back and say...
catch a girl
and kiss a girl.
Yeah
And what
was that?
The girls are always screaming.
-Yeah
When we
catch them,
we kiss them,
-Yes.
And when its catch a boy, kiss a boy
when the girls catch us, they kiss us..
they say 'aaaaah'...
-Yeah.
but much
louder though.
If we did...
all love Jeffrey
we all want to marry.
- Yeah.
I think I know the one that
he likes best and that's her.
Susan most of
all likes Lesley
She told me before.
-Do I?
You said, she keeps
changing her mind though
Yeah! I don't know
which one really
Well, my girlfriend
is in Africa...
and  I don't think I have another
chance of seeing her again...
and there were two in Switzerland which
I liked too in a hotel, Park Hotel.
Well, I know
he is hers...
He loves her.
I don't,
I love him.
And these two...
I love you, I
love Christopher
See, he loves Suzan
because Suzan loves him.
He loves Lindsay and Lindsay loves him.
-I don't love him
once Caroline
Tetford said
She loved me.
-And what happened after that?
And I am going to marry...
I marry her when I grow up.
I hate her. She's always getting
bad tempered and cross with me.
Is she?
Yes! Neil Hughes! Move your desk forward
and sometimes... and sometimes...
when...when she is supposed to have
the chair on the back of the desk...
and when I take it...
when I put it back...
she says, 'Neil Hughes!' take
your chair forward.
And she just gets into a girly
cross with me like that.
I'd like to get
married when I grow up.
But I don't know what sort of
boy but I think one...
thats not got
lot of money but is...
has got some money.
Not a lot though!
Would you like
to get married Paul?
Tell me
why not!
I don't like it. Say... say
you had a wife...
Say... say you have to eat
what they cooked you
And say I don't
like greens well I don't...
And say... she says you have to eat
what you're given... so...
I don't like greens so if she gives
me greens then... then that's it
When I get married I don't
want to have any children...
Because they are always
doing naughty things and...
making the
whole house untidy.
When I get married I will
like to have two children.
You'll have Nanny to look after
but you won't look after them?
No I want a
Nanny to look after them.
If I could I would have two girls
and two boys.  -Yes so would I
And what about
you Jackie?
My Mom because she got five
girls she had seven years bad luck
and seven years is a bad luck
thats why she has got five girls.
And so... when my baby was
supposed to be born...
and we all wished
it was a boy but...
But we were all waiting in my nans
for my dad 'cause he visited her
he came home and said
"it's another girl kids"
we all said "awwwww!"
What do you think about
girl friends at your age?
I've got one but I
don't think much of her.
No but I said that when
boys go around with girls...
they don't pay attention
to what they're doing.
My Grand mother had
an accident because...
a boy friend was kissing... his
girl friend in the street.
The girls never... never... never
do what the boys want them.
They always start
playing with dolls...
when boys want to play rough and tumble.
-It's not true!
They're rather boring you never get a
chance to play with them and things like
rough and tumble...
And they always start
playing with their dolls.
Yes... as soon as you start...
-and silly things like that...
Only intelligent girls start playing with
you -and they always take you away...
from whatever game
you are playing yourself.
Yes! They say `I don't want to
play that game with you...'
and they don't stop crying.
- Yes!
Do you have a girl friend?
I don't want to answer that.
I don't want to answer
those kinds of questions.
They Love.
-That's right!
Back to love, 'amo'.
Now let's have the
present tense of 'amo'.
Amos, amas, amant...
anamus, amatis, amant.
Yes, What's the last one?
Amant!
-Amant.
Fill up the gaps on
the board there
Have a little chalk?
-Yeah
In your best writing please. All right!
What's Major... what's
'amatis' mean?
We love.
No, Holden. Amatis?
You love.
-You love! Second person, isn't it?
Yes sir.
That was silly wasn't it
Now then Russell, let's hear
the present tense of 'porto'.
Porto, portas, portat,
portamus, portatis, portant.
-That's right!
Holden, let's hear the
present tense of 'evasto'.
Evasto, evastas... evastat,
evastamus, evastatis. evastant.
Yes, speak up.
Now let's... what does `evasto' mean?
I...
All right, let's...
Well, got it?
- Lay waste.
`Evasto'- to lay waste!
All right.
All right you can talk again.
Are the children themselves aware of
differences between rich and poor?
have they learned prejudice.
What do they think about money?
I think it's not a bad idea
to pay for schools...
becasue if we didn't...
schools would be so
nasty and crowded.
Yes.
-So do I think so.
Yes!
And... people in the schools wouldn't
-And poor people would come rushing in
The man, in charge of the school...
would get very angry
because he would...
And he would get bankrupt.
-because he wouldn't...
He wouldn't be able to pay all the
masters if he didn't get any money.
Yes. I think he would get
bankrupt because paying all the...
What does bankrupt mean?
Having no more money
and go to prison
Why do you have to go
to prison? That's strong!
Becasue that obviously means
you've been spending it too much.
I've got twenty three three penny pieces...
and I don't know how many
half penny pieces I've got now
I read The Financial Times.
I read Observer and The Times.
What do you like about it?
Well, I like...
I usually look at the
headlines then read...
about them... about it.
I like my newspaper because I
got shares in it
and I know everyday what shares are
-The stuff misers like you like
No. But...
on Mondays they don't
move up so I don't look at it.
What would you do if you have lots
of money, about say... two pounds?
Me?
I would help the poor.
Yeah because the poor if you
don't help them they would die
Wouldn't they?
And everytime we've a harvest
festival, we send them food.
Once these two, no Susan and Janet
went round giving food out
What do you think about rich people?
Well... not much.
Tell me about them
Well, they think they
can do everything...
without you doing it as well and
they think just because they're rich...
and they have to have people
like they have to do
all their work and stuff.
I don't think much of the accents.
Neither do I.
-Neither do I.
That doesn't prevent me liking them.
Poor children, they boast
about themselves. - No they don't.
Rich children boast about themselves and
say how clever I am and things like that
Yes, and rich children always
make fun of poor children, I hate.
Yes. -Yes they say, look at that lovely
little sissy and they laugh at them.
Yes, and they throw things at them.
Yes.
And poor child gets scared to death.
The posh ones
Oh Yes. Oh yes. Oh Yes.
They're nuts!
you just have to touch them
Jacqueline, what do you
think about coloured people?
You said to me once that you like them
but what do you really think about them?
Well, they're nice and its
as same as us really...
but one thing...
it's only because their skin is
brown and we're white...
sort of pinkish we're.
Some people from Africa come here...
but when they go, they
put their clothes on
I've only seen them on
television and places like that.
I don't... I don't know
anybody who is coloured.
I don't want to know anybody who is
coloured. Thank you very much!
Coloured people. I don't
like them very much.
No... it sounds like
ghostly coloured people.
Do you think of a purple person...
with red eyes,
yellow feet and...
I can't really think of
what they really look like.
They are just same as me, aren't they?
What do they think
about each other?
And how'll they act together?
To find out, we invited
them all to one big party...
and joined in
Tell me what did you
three think about...
the other children
that you met today...
and all that, there were
quite varieties?
Yes but they were bit
too tough for my liking.
Some hit me right in the back and
I 've still got some pain there.
And well, some of them
were rather dirty.
what did you think about them?
-I played with them quiet naturally.
I think they were rather nice, really.
I don't like the boys.
Those three,  I don't like all of them. None of them.
What about the girls?
Yeah, I liked that girl...
but not the boys.
Why?
Because once I pulled his scarf he said,
'Don't you pull my scarf' and I hate him
And when we were at that park...
he went round punching everybody.
If some of our children didn't
get on with each other...
does it really matter?
After all...
they're not likely to meet
in the same class room.
At the Kensington school...
all the boys are being prepared for
public school places and universities...
whereas of these thirty children
getting their milk from Tony.
Only, three are likely to win a
place at a grammer school.
Indeed, the vast
majority will leave school...
and start work at fifteen.
What plans do the
children themselves have?
When I leave the school, I'm
going to College Court...
and then I would be going to Westminster
Boarding School if I pass the exam.
Then we think, I am going
to Cambridge and Trinity Hall.
What does university mean?
Well...
before I'm old enough to get a job
I'll just walk around
and see what I can find.
When I leave the school, I go
to Broadstairs, St. Peter's Court.
And after that I'm
going to Charter House.
And after that Trinity Hall, Cambridge.
I like to be like Kathy Kirby
I want to be a jockey when I grow up. Ya
I want to be a jockey when I grow up.
When I leave school...
I'm going to the Dragon School...
I might.
I might go to Charles
House, Marlborough
And...
I can't.... remember
all other places...
because mummy has got so many
places... and those're some of them.
What about university Charles?
I might go to Oxford.
Well...
I don't think I need to go to university
'cause  I'm not gonna be a teacher.
I don't think you want to go to
university if you want to be an astronaut
When I grow up, I want
to be an astronaut but...
if I can't be an astonaut
I think I'll be a coach driver.
Tell me about the coach driver.
Well, I'm going to take
people to the country...
and sometimes take them
to the sea-side and...
And I'll have a big loud speaker on the
coach and tell them where about we're...
and what we're going to do.
And what's the name of the road is.
All about that.
When... if I can't be an astonaut
I would like to be a...
a bridal sergeant
in the police force...
like my dad is.
I was gonna be a policeman but...
how thought how hard
it would be to join in.
When I leave the school,
I'm down for Heathfield and
Southfield Manor and then maybe,
I may want to go to a university...
but I don't know which one yet.
I'll buy myself a nice new
made house you know.
one that's all
nice and comfy.
I am going to work in Woolworths
When I grow up I like to find out
all about the moon and all that.
Well, going to Africa...
and try and teach people...
who are not civilized...
to be more or less good.
At the end of their very
special day in London...
after their trip to the
zoo and the party...
we took our children to
an adventure play ground...
where they could do
just what they like.
There's from a children's home
set about building a house.
That's Nicholas.
And Tony.
Andrew.
And Bruce.
John.
Suzie.
Jackie and her friends.
Give me a child until he is seven...
and I will give you the man.
This has been a glimpse
of Britain's future.