I was born in Berlin, Germany.
My father and mother had
a fur business in Germany.
And I have a brother
who was a year younger.
We lived very comfortable,
had a nice life in Germany.
I remembered that huge,
beautiful building...
with gardens all around
and a stream going through it.
I lived there with my grandmother.
I went to a Jewish school-
a private school.
Had a nice girlfriend there,
Anna-Marie...
whom I was very friendly with,
and we spent a lot of time together.
My sister went to another school.
She was older.
I had my dolls.
My mother made clothes for my dolls.
My father was a peddler in Germany
which meant basically...
he would go to a place
and buy textiles...
cut in three-yard length.
Then he’d go into villages
and sell them door-to-door.
Usually when my father would return,
if it was a successful trip...
he brought back toys from the various
villages, and that was exciting.
We used to go to the suburbs
of Breslau on picnics.
In the winter
we went to Czechoslovakia...
to a place called Spindleruv Mlyn...
where my parents went skiing
and I went sleigh riding.
Jews in Germany felt at home
and felt it was their vaterland...
where they could live forever, and
they felt at home with German culture.
They felt proud of
Germany's achievement...
and of Jewish contributions to Germany.
While on the one hand German Jews-
especially when Hitler rose-
started writing a spate of books
called Jewish Contributions to Germany...
Jewish Contributions to Civilizations-
were not aware of the fact that the
Germans looked at it quite differently.
Instead of saying,
look how much we contributed to law...
to journalism-
created a whole new genre-
to medicine and science...
the Germans said,
"You took over our science.
You took over our law.
You took over the newspapers. "
In 1933, Adolf Hitler and
the Nazi party rose to power in Germany.
They immediately acted on their ideology
of racial discrimination and violence.
I came home from school...
and the Nazi party
was marching on the street...
and everybody's standing
on the side and saluting.
Suddenly they said-
That means "Hit the Jews. " They grabbed
a few people and started beating them.
They were yelling,
"We are no Jews. We are no Jews. "
They kept on beating them
for the cameras that were set up.
Till one day,
in the usual ice cream parlor...
we couldn't go in anymore...
and we were just beginning
to learn how to read.
That's when
the signs came up all over.
"No Jews, no dogs" in the stores.
"No Jews, no dogs" on the benches.
Couldn't quite understand
what this was all about...
but I remember my grandmother taking
us by the hand and says, "Haroldchen. "
That's how she used to call me.
"We can't go in here anymore.
We'll get ice cream some other place. "
Yeah, this "Jews and dogs forbidden"
was all over.
I had non-Jewish boys to play with...
and then sometime-
I don't remember what year it was-
none of my non-Jewish friends...
would play with me, talk to me-
just disregard me.
My next memory actually was of
our doorbell ringing at midnight.
I imagine it was shortly thereafter.
My parents wondering who's ringing
the doorbell at midnight.
It was my uncle,
my mother's brother.
He says, "I've got my chauffeur
waiting downstairs.
I'm on my way to France
via Switzerland...
because it's the end
for the Jews in Germany.
I think you should come with us. "
He had always been a bit of
an eccentric, this particular brother...
so, when my father heard it, he says,
"The meshuggener Leo.
What a crazy idea he has.
This madman's not gonna last. Things like
that have happened before to the Jews.
Impossible. Besides,
I fought in the First World War...
and we've been German for generations.
We've lived here.
Let's wait and see. "
In July, 1938...
President Roosevelt
convened the Évian Conference...
to try and solve
the refugee problem in Germany.
But the conference ended
with no solutions.
The refugees had nowhere to go.
Every country was told
at the Évian Conference...
that they do not have to take
more than their usual quota.
Britain won out in that Palestine
was not mentioned as a haven.
Goebbels writes in his diary...
"They are shedding crocodile tears.
They want us to do
their job for them...
and they really don't want the Jews
as much as we don't. "
So the Évian Conference
showed Hitler...
that the world didn't give a damn.
In 1938, a young Jewish man...
enraged at the treatment
of his parents by the Nazis...
shot and killed
a German diplomat in Paris.
The Nazis used the incident as a pretext
to orchestrate violent riots against Jews.
Thousands of shops were looted
and destroyed...
and virtually all synagogues
in Germany were burned.
Ninety-one Jews died,
hundreds wounded.
The police were told
not to interfere.
This night was called Kristallnacht.
"The Night of the Shattered Glass. "
When the ninth
of November came along...
and the Nazis wanted to
get into our house...
the Hausmeister, who was
a big Communist before 1933-
After 1933, of course,
he became a big Nazi.
He was standing in front of
the building in his uniform...
and saying, "There are no Jews
in this building. Keep on going. "
That saved us at that time.
My father put on the radio,
and all he heard was martial music.
He went out.
He wasn’t sure.
He didn't like to see
what was happening.
He decided to go into hiding.
When we got out the next few days...
I saw the glass...
and the burning synagogues
and all that.
We walked over to my grandmother's
house to see if they were all right.
I remember the crunching glass
under my feet.
Even now, more than 60 years later,
I can still remember it.
The day after Kristallnacht, my parents
and I walked out of our house...
and the grocery store near us,
which was owned by a Jewish family-
The windows were shattered
and had "Dirty Jew" on it.
Then we walked to the synagogue
which we attended...
and as we walked by we saw
in the courtyard of the synagogue...
there was a mound of ashes.
It was clear
that these were prayer books.
Sticking out of the center of the mound
were the scrolls of the Torah.
I remember being terrified by that...
because I had just learned...
that if the Torah was dropped
in the synagogue, even by accident...
the whole congregation
would have to fast for 40 days.
And here I saw the Torah
is being burned.
Internally I said to myself...
"There's no safety for us anywhere. "
All of a sudden...
almost all Germans sought a way out.
"Where can we go?
Where can we find a haven?
Where can we get out?"
Of course, the lines on
all the embassies and consulates...
were blocks long
with the attempts to find a haven.
The American consulate
closed their doors...
and no visas were ever
given out again.
You couldn't get into America.
You couldn't get to England.
You couldn't get to any of these places
because we had no passports, no visas.
The quota numbers were very small.
Among non-Jewish people
that lived in our house...
one of the men was a very high officer
in the German air force...
who warned my father
not to stay in Europe.
He says, "We are going to
conquer all of Europe. "
My father fortunately felt the same way.
He was a peddler...
and arranged with 11 other people...
to pay someone to get him across
the border to Belgium.
They did make it across the border...
and they were picked up
by the Belgian authorities...
who turned them back to the Gestapo
who turned them over to Dachau.
One of the ways in which the Austrian Jews
were encouraged to leave...
was to arrest the men...
and incarcerate them...
in concentration camps...
and then saying, "The only way
you're going to get your men back-"
To these women who were left behind,
the families that were left behind.
"The only way you can get them
is if you leave within a month...
24 hours, two weeks, two months,"
or whatever they decided.
My father decided
to come out of hiding.
It seems the Christian landlord
told him, "Don't. "
He went to the friend's house
to pick me up.
It so happened
the Gestapo was in the same house.
He got picked up, and he was sent
to the Buchenwald concentration camp.
I was picked up on the street...
taken with all other Jews
to Sachsenhausen.
We were standing there,
and the command came out...
"Anybody below 14 and over 80,
step forward. "
So, I was 13.
I stepped forward.
They put us on a truck,
and they sent us back home.
I spent one day.
So, all of a sudden,
there developed-
first in Vienna-
a haven that nobody
dreamed of before.
There's a place you can go to
without a visa, without papers.
It was extraordinary.
How could there be such a thing?
It was hard to imagine.
Where are you going?
8,000 miles away.
Shanghai...
a sprawling port city
on the east coast of China...
was forced by the British
to trade with the West...
after the Opium Wars
of the 1840s.
Powerful and decadent...
tremendously wealthy
and miserably squalid...
voracious and corrupt...
it became
the commercial center of China.
To sustain their booming trade...
the West created a section
of the city where Western law ruled.
It was called
the International Settlement.
Later on, the French created their own
settlement called the French Concession.
The International Settlement...
had grown up,
since mid-19th century...
outside of the walled town
of Shanghai.
Shanghai was a town
with walls around it...
and the International Settlement
grew up outside of it.
They built up those ports.
They built up all of them-
not only Shanghai,
but that was the biggest one-
into a major world harbor...
where the settlement created
a tremendous boom.
There were two Jewish communities
in Shanghai.
The first group came following
the British during the late 19th century.
They were Baghdadi businessmen
and their families.
As British subjects, they were able to
take part in the booming Shanghai trade.
They were English-speaking.
They did business with the British.
They did very well
by doing business with the British.
Some of them
were enormously wealthy...
like the Kadoorie...
the Sassoon...
and the Hardoon families.
The second community
consisted of Russian Jews...
who immigrated to China mostly to escape
the Communist revolution in 1917.
Although not as affluent
as the Baghdadi Jews...
they also had a rich community life.
The Russian Jewish community
which existed- the second one-
grew up parallel
but not identical...
or mixed with the Sephardim.
They were separate and unequal.
In 1937..
began the war to attack
the Chinese garrisons...
in the outskirts of China.
From that time began
the Sino-Japanese War.
In the Sino-Japanese War of 1937..
the Japanese conquered
large parts of China...
including Shanghai.
As it turned out,
that was the only avenue of escape-
Shanghai- without papers.
All you needed really
was passage on a ship.
What is not widely known, in '38,
before the beginning of the war...
you could get out of Dachau
if you could leave the country.
If he could have left the country...
he wouldn't have gotten
smuggled into Belgium.
So, he was in Dachau for about 20 days.
During that time
my mother found out...
that you could go to the Japanese-occupied
portion of Shanghai without a visa.
One did not need a visa
to come to Shanghai.
But that is wrong.
Because visas were indeed required...
in order to purchase a ship ticket.
Passport control, however...
after July, 1937...
was no longer in Chinese hands.
As a matter of fact,
nobody controlled passports...
because the foreign powers
did not want to control passports...
because then the Japanese would have
said, "We want to control passports"...
and the foreign powers...
did not want the Japanese
to control passports of foreigners...
and therefore
nobody controlled passports.
She decided to buy
steamship tickets for Shanghai.
How did she have the money?
It wasn't that easy either.
We had money,
but the bank accounts were frozen.
However, we were allowed to draw
household expenses from our own moneys.
So my mother inflated, as much as
she was able to, what she needed...
and was very frugal on spending it.
But she did go
and get the steamship tickets...
for leaving on the Hakozaki Maru...
a Japanese steamer...
the following February
from Naples, Italy.
My father was always
very careful with money.
He had money put aside.
Most of that went for...
bribing the NYK Line people
to give us tickets...
because if we hadn't
gotten out by the middle of May...
I wouldn't be sitting here today.
I remember my grandfather- It's one
of those things that sits in your ear-
You hear it.
He used to say to her, "Fuffchen. "
He called her Fuffchen.
"Where you taking the kid to?"
"To the Chinesin. "
"No, no. Forget it. "
He said, "Yeah.
I'm taking my boy. I'm getting out. "
On my mother's birthday, which was
December 5, 6:00 in the morning...
the bell rang...
and at that time
if you heard a bell ring at any hour...
but particularly at an ungodly hour,
you might say...
it did not sound too good.
I remember all of us huddling
in the little hallway...
as my mother opened the door,
and there was my father.
He had come home from Buchenwald.
With much trepidation,
she told my father...
"We're not waiting for
a United States visa.
I got tickets to go to Shanghai. "
She expected him
to make a big fuss...
and all he said was...
in today's vernacular...
"If we had left yesterday,
it wouldn't be soon enough. "
We left Germany in...
1939 in May.
We said good-bye to my grandparents.
It was chaos.
My mother was screaming.
My aunt was screaming.
They were very volatile.
It was terrible. Awful.
And, you know, the Germans
never came out to say good-bye.
They watched from
behind the curtains.
We could see them,
and they didn't come out.
They knew my mother
since she was a little girl.
They didn't come out. They didn't say
anything. They were really terrified...
and also probably glad
to see us leave.
At the train station
there was the whole family there.
I see it like you’re sitting
in front of me.
I see it like
you're sitting in front of me.
Under Anhalter Bahnhofin Berlin.
Everybody.
Everybody. Bruno.
Omi-Sozia, Ada, Mietek.
The cousins-Judith, Margot.
All names today are-
It's a long time ago.
But a lot of people.
A lot of people.
And they're all gone.
I had to say good-bye to Anna-Marie,
my girlfriend...
and all of that.
I give talks in schools...
and I talk about Anna-Marie,
especially to the age group that-
the nine-year-olds,
the 10-year-olds.
I always talk about
Anna-Marie and say...
"If you ever hear about anyone
called Anna-Marie Wallenberg...
let me know. "
I get letters from them.
One little girl wrote
a letter back, and she said...
"Don't worry
if you don't find Anna-Marie.
When you go to heaven,
you'll find her there. "
When the train reached
the Italian border...
and the Gestapo came
on board the train...
and my mother telling me...
"I want you to be very quiet.
Don't say a word.
Don't look up. Don't move.
Don't ask for anything.
Just sit. "
Funny how kids sometimes know
that it's really serious business.
I was eight years old,
and I did just that.
So I remember the Gestapo coming
aboard the train to check papers...
but I didn't see faces
'cause I was looking down.
My mother told me
not to look up.
All I saw was black boots
marching back and forth...
and them saying "Papiere, "
you know, "papers. "
The passports and whatever else
was needed- the permission.
They went through the whole train...
and after they got it from everybody,
they left the train...
and the train started again
and crossed the border into Italy.
Everybody cheering and clapping.
They had champagne corks popping.
We were out of Germany.
Shanghai became a real option...
for those Jews who had no place to go.
They scrambled to buy
all the luxury ship tickets...
to go to Shanghai...
because that was the only way
you can go at that point.
Got on the ship.
That was the Kashima Maru.
It was weird because
it looked like a pleasure cruise...
with the streamers
and the music-
the orchestra-
a Japanese real snappy orchestra.
We thought we were on holiday,
my sister and me.
I was nine, and she was 11.
So we had fun. We had a stewardess
who was assigned to take care of us...
and they gave us little cakes
and little dolls.
We had tea parties.
We took a ship in Naples- a Japanese
ship by the name of Hakusan Maru.
It was a beautiful four-week trip.
Long, beautiful trip.
I enjoyed every moment of it.
I didn't realize really what was going on
in the world. We were too young for that.
My mother bought first-class passage.
So we had a relatively luxurious cabin...
and there was more food
than anyone could ever eat.
I remember vividly
throughout the trip...
my mother kept saying
I should eat everything in sight.
At that time we were kosher.
We basically ate the fruits...
and the vegetables
and much of the pastry.
In Port Said,
the ship actually anchored...
and I remember
those sand dunes on both sides.
They later told us
that a few young Jews-
German Jews, Polish Jews-
jumped the ship...
and actually tried
to make their way to Palestine.
What's Israel today.
I don't know.
There was a recurrent theme.
She was saying, "Eat, eat, eat"...
because who knows what will happen
when we get to Shanghai.
Got off the ship in Shanghai...
if I remember correctly...
that was the shock of a lifetime.
It was completely different
from anything you could imagine.
Absolutely different.
Nothing could prepare you
for what we saw there.
I actually remember feeling
very, very afraid.
I didn't know where I was.
I t was a whole different world...
in overnight from white to black
or from black to white.
In 1937, what was conquered
was not the International Settlement...
not the French Concession...
but the Chinese portion of the town.
The Japanese did not want to establish
a concession of their own...
but they took a piece
of the International Settlement...
and that they said is under
our military control.
And that is Hongko.
Hongko- or Hongke was some called it-
was one of the poorest sections
of Shanghai.
Badly battered in the war
with the Japanese...
it was home to poor Chinese...
occupying Japanese
and many Jewish refugees...
who had little means
to support themselves.
We landed in Hongkew, which is
the place where all the ships landed-
particularly the refugee ships.
It was very dirty.
It was terribly hot
and very humid.
The heat is terrible there.
And crowded and smelly.
Thousands of people running around.
Chinese beggars with open sores.
It was just awful.
Shanghai was not prepared
for this kind of an influx-
for these waves and waves...
shiploads-
shipload after shipload.
One of my father's friends
who had gone there before us...
had rented us a room...
in one of the little lanes
that they have in Hongkew.
The room was fairly clean...
but it was just
one small room for our family...
another small one
for my uncle and my aunt.
No kitchen facilities.
very poor bathroom situation.
No what they called WC's
over there- water closet.
No flush toilets.
Buckets.
The first home
was also on Wayside Road.
Further down on Wayside Road
in a lane in an alley.
All of Shanghai was alleys and lanes.
Cars don't go through there. Bicycles.
With a wagon
you can pull through there.
Very narrow,
very crowded, very tight.
Not too much air.
Not too much light.
That's how people lived in those days.
So, a major problem arose already
in December at the very beginning:
How to support these people,
how to house these people...
how to feed these people
of already hundreds upon hundreds.
The Jewish Baghdadi families
stepped in to help.
They established soup kitchens
and temporary shelters called homes...
or Hei me in German.
We were picked up by
the Jewish Committee on trucks...
and they took us to a camp...
which was a converted school
and a Kinchow camp.
The camp was normal. We had a little
breakfast, a little lunch and no dinner.
We had to fend for ourselves.
We had a little money.
The first one to create what you call
the international committee-
or I CU-
was the COMA Committee...
which was subsidized by Sassoon.
victor Sassoon said...
that it was the cheapest place
in the world to support a refugee.
For five American cents
you could support a refugee.
But as more refugees were arriving
daily, more help was needed.
The JDC- the Joint Distribution
Committee- took action.
It was an overseeing organization
of Jewish-American communities...
uniting their philanthropic efforts.
The JDC was the main source
of hope and help for the refugees.
It financed the temporary shelters...
the soup kitchens
and the makeshift hospital.
Later, Laura Margolis,
an American professional social worker...
became the JDC's
head official in Shanghai.
Under her effective management...
the JDC was able to sustain
close to 10,000 refugees...
who had no means
to support themselves.
One morning...
the phone rang.
The boss at that time was Mo Levitt.
Moses Levitt.
He said, "Laura, how you doin'?"
Although "How you doin'?"
was not an expression in those years.
But he said, "How are you?"
I said, "Fine. "
"Busy?"
"Yeah, we’re very busy here. "
He said,
"How would you like to go to China?"
I have to laugh
when I think of it.
I said, "Where in China?"
"Shanghai. "
I said, "Sure. I'd like to go. "
I had no idea
what he was talking about.
She came in May, 1941.
She was a professional social worker...
who had worked in Cuba before that.
I found a news clipping
in the Joint archives...
describing "Laura Margolis from Cuba...
is coming to straighten out
the mess in Shanghai. "
Because you had
the local relief organizations...
by volunteers.
Laura Margolis,
a highly intelligent woman...
sent back weekly-
sometimes even daily reports...
describing precisely
the situation as she saw it.
The relief organizations
and how poorly they're managing...
and the refugee problem
and so on and so forth.
Now came the Polish Jews...
and the Lithuanian Jews
and the religious Jews and the yeshivot.
They wanted to be
taken care of separately...
because they were intellectuals...
and they had to have
their prayer books...
kosher food...
and chicken on Friday.
It was very, very difficult.
Very difficult.
Yet again, the Jewish communities
did try to accommodate them...
did respond.
"These are religious people.
They need to be treated differently. "
So we went to the camp kitchens...
for our first meals
like everybody else did.
They had set up
these homes- Heime-
which didn't look
much like Heim- or a home-
for people who had no place to go.
They had kitchens,
and they had a hospital.
Fortunately,
we didn't have to live there.
That was even worse
than living in the room- much worse.
It was kind of odd to see people there.
They all had these new German clothes
they had bought before they left...
if they had enough money left.
They were all decked out.
The men usually with hats and suits.
In that heat.
The women with nice suits
and heels and all that...
with a tin plate in their hand, waiting
for food from the communal kitchen.
The summers would get so hot...
that today you use a heat index
or humidity index.
Under those conditions,
the temperature could go up as much-
measured that way-
140 in the shade.
The sanitary conditions were about the
worst in the world that you can think of.
Every disease-
known or unknown to man-
was rampant in epidemic proportions.
Non-flushable toilet.
A Chinese woman would come
every morning...
pick that huge pot up...
take it down the stairs
and dump it into a wagon in the street.
So the street usually smelled
not like Chanel Number 5.
You could not drink the water.
In Shanghai, at the time,
you could not drink.
You drank water, guaranteed to get sick.
The older generation.
But when you were young,
you do things.
I remember distinctly the first time
I drank the water from the tap.
You had to boil the water.
Eventually we were able-
most of the younger people-
to drink the water from the tap.
There was a way to do the rice
that I remembered...
and I usually tell that to people-
how my mother used to
put it out on the windowsill.
We had these wide windowsills.
If you left it sitting there
for four or five minutes...
the bugs would come crawling out.
My sister and I would count
who had the most.
In summertime...
the river would overflow
on a regular basis.
Everyday, at certain hours,
the streets were flooded.
You'd have swimming in there.
You name it,
and it was swimming in there.
Most of the refugees
came almost penniless to Shanghai.
The German government had confiscated
most of their assets.
Many sold whatever
salable items they had-
clothes and furniture...
which they brought from Europe
in large crates called "lifts. "
The refugees now scrambled to find jobs
in Shanghai to sustain themselves...
although they did not know
for how long.
My father had studied to be a typewriter
mechanic before leaving Germany.
Also with the proceeds
of what my mother sold...
we established a typewriter business
in the British foreign settlement...
hiring a Chinese mechanic.
My mother stayed home.
She and my aunt knitted.
They opened up the old sweaters
and the old shawls...
and knitted for sale
to make a little money.
My father and my uncle went to
look for jobs in the city of Shanghai...
with Chinese companies.
My father got a job
with a chemical company...
knowing absolutely nothing- not a shred
of knowledge about chemicals.
But he learned.
He used to study every night.
She supported
her husband and myself...
with making hats.
She was an excellent hat maker.
Since the climate was cold,
people wore hats.
The hope was always...
create a temporary refuge
so they can get to America...
or elsewhere
in the western hemisphere-
Canada, South America.
Nobody expected Shanghai
to be a refuge for 10 years.
It was unintended to be
more than anything temporary.
As bad as were offin Shanghai...
we were still better off
than most of the Chinese around us.
The Chinese were very poor,
very hardworking...
and were under direct oppression
of the Japanese.
The poorer Chinese people...
lived even...
a poorer life
than the Jewish refugees, it seemed.
The relief organization
helped the refugees-
the Jewish refugees-
according to their standard.
The Chinese had this coexistence
with the refugees-
a sort of benign tolerance.
They had their own problems.
They kind of accepted us
in their midst there.
I never once
saw a sign of anti-Semitism...
or disgust or criticism.
I never saw it at all.
The lot of the Chinese people
was a very hard one to watch...
beginning with the coolies-
these poor guys
who were carrying all daylong...
and then the rickshaws.
A human being lugging
a little wagon with two wheels...
and rich people and running with them
through the streets for hours and days...
with the veins
popping out of their legs.
It's inhuman.
The wintertime,
there was no heating...
and some just froze to death.
Then you'd see
in the streets in the morning...
little packages wrapped up
where the children passed away...
and they wrapped them up
in a little straw mattress...
and when the garbage truck came,
they just picked them up.
Children play with other children.
It doesn't matter whether-
My sister writes in her diary...
"I gave the little Chinese girl next door
a piece of white bread. "
Big deal, you know.
That's the way this worked.
Her father gave me a pencil.
That's how these things evolved.
They didn't make
lifelong friendships out of this...
but they coexisted quite well.
So there was never-
We were lucky with that. After all,
we were sitting on their territory...
20,000 of us
Pushing 20,000 of them out...
because they were already there...
and overflowing,
living really in poverty, many of them.
Because that was
the poor section of town.
On the one hand, the white and the Chinese
were simply two different worlds.
very few understood Chinese
or spoke Chinese.
What refugees had a lot to do
with Chinese was in pidgin English.
They bought from them.
They bought the cheapest-
the last bit of vegetables...
and what was left in the stands
when nobody else would buy...
when they couldn't afford
anything else.
Sometimes the Chinese
were very good to the refugees.
They gave them credit,
or they let them buy on credit.
There was this
very sweet Chinese man...
who came with his bamboo stick with two
little baskets hanging on each side...
and became a real friendship
with my mother.
Used to come by-
I don't know about everyday-
but very often-
a good few times a week.
Then he'd be downstairs-
We lived on the second floor-
and he used to call, "Ufi. Ufi, "
and then my mother went down.
He had some vegetables...
or fish and some chicken.
He always had something
that she bought from him.
"Ufi. " She was his best customer.
In Shanghai...
there was a Russian newspaper...
for the Russian community.
And in this paper
there was a Yiddish page.
In that Yiddish page...
they recorded
their reaction to Shanghai.
It is the most beautiful,
heartwarming poetry that I've read.
I mean, it is just-
It's not self-pitying.
Some of the poems are sort of
reaching out to the Chinese population.
Like, "Oh, my God.
This is terrible
what is happening to you. "
This kind of sympathetic response.
So it comes straight from the heart.
Instead of saying, "Oy, poor me. "
You know,
" Gevalt! Who did this to me?"
They're saying,
"Oh, no. You poor Chinese. "
The utmost influence...
the Jews asserted...
on the Shanghai Chinese society...
was on music and on medicine.
The Chinese themselves, many of them
felt also sympathy for the Jews.
They're both being
oppressed by the Japanese.
The Chinese worse. When the Chinese
crossed a bridge they had to bow down...
and Japanese sometimes
stick 'em with a burning cigarette...
or jab them.
But the Chinese got
the better part of it.
They turned around and smiled.
And that killed the Japanese.
In other words, their smile-
In other words, they withstood
the torture and the embarrassment...
and said you-know-what to them
in that language.
That hurt the Japanese
more than anything else.
Every Chinese hated
the Japanese very much.
They killed 300,000 people...
when they occupied Nanjing.
I saw once...
a Chinese stealing
a canister of kerosene...
and he was caught.
Right on the spot
the Japanese tied up his hands...
and chopped them off.
And that's it.
I couldn’t watch.
I ran away.
But in my opinion,
man could never survive.
Although passport control was not
in anyone's hands after 1937...
the Japanese controlled
the Shanghai harbor.
In spite of their alliance
with Germany...
they let the Jewish refugees
into Shanghai.
I t is quite clear that they do not
wish to antagonize American Jews.
They do not wish
to antagonize world Jewry...
because this stereotype of the Jew,
which is still alive today in Japan...
was very much alive then.
Jews are rich,
Jews have power...
Jews control governments.
Jews are compared
to a blowfish or fugu.
If the skilled chef...
can know how to cut the little poisonous
sac out of the fish, it's a delicacy.
If not, it's a poisonous thing.
If we have such a great power
like the Jews...
we have to know how to
utilize them on behalf of Japan.
Japanese had to be very careful...
about being prejudiced against Jews...
because they had complained...
about German prejudice against Asians.
So, it was the Japanese,
Hitler's Axis partner...
that determined, based on their concept
of what the Jew was in the world-
on their control of the West...
and Western Jews
being synonymous in their ideas-
they thought, "If we are good to the Jews
in East Asia, they will be good to us. "
Meanwhile, war was raging in Europe.
In September, 1939,
Germany invaded Poland.
In 1940, Denmark.
Then the Netherlands, Belgium...
then France.
It seemed like
Hitler was unstoppable.
The beginning looked like total
devastation- we don't have a chance.
The Germans were
running across Europe...
and the Japanese were
storming all across Asia.
Till things started turning around, we
didn't really know. It looked hopeless.
We got once a postcard
from my grandfather.
We tried in Shanghai...
to get some of
my mother's family out...
or my father's,
but it was too late.
You had to go via Siberia,
and as I said to you...
the war was on already,
and you could not come anymore.
My other uncle, though-
Leo who had gone to Paris-
when he saw that it wasn't
that great in France...
he wrote my mother
he’d like to come to Shanghai.
My mother immediately got things moving.
The European part of HIAS
was called HICEM. H-I-C-E-M.
She went to the HICEM...
in Shanghai...
and sent papers.
At that particular time...
you needed-
it wasn't really sponsors...
but you needed somebody to write a letter
to say you wanted somebody to come.
It was very easy.
It was a semiofficial kind of thing.
There was no problem.
We did the same thing.
The HICEM took care of it.
And we got another letter
from my uncle...
that he was now interned
at Septfonds.
"Please get me out
as quickly as you can. "
My mother couldn't understand.
Why didn't he get the papers?
She went to the HICEM,
and he assured her the papers were sent.
Well, nothing happened,
and finally my mother got very upset...
and she went back
to the HICEM, and she says...
"You know, it doesn't take that long
for papers to get to Europe.
Something must have happened. "
The man said, "No. We sent them. "
"I want the receipt...
because you said you sent them
registered mail.
I want the receipt that you sent them. "
They weren’t very nice to her,
but she wouldn’t leave the office.
Finally he took out his file...
and the way she said,
his face blanched.
She said, "What's the matter?"
He said, "The papers were never sent.
They're in this file. "
So, my mother says...
"I'm gonna take the papers,
and I will send them. "
She took the papers, 'cause they had to
go to the HICEM in Marseille...
and they he could have
gotten on a ship.
She took the papers...
and she immediately sent them out,
registered mail.
They got to the HICEM in Marseille
the day France fell.
They never reached my uncle.
To the day she died...
my mother said, "Leo's gonna think
his sister deserted him...
that his sister
didn't want him to come. "
She always spoke about that-
how she sent him these papers.
They were overworked,
I guess- the HICEM.
She always says, "Why didn't I ask
to see the file earlier? Why, why?"
Because he could have come.
There were various schools
available in Shanghai...
including French and British schools.
There was also
the Kadoorie school in Hongkew.
It was built and financed by the Kadoorie
and Sassoon families for the refugees...
and was staffed by refugee teachers.
There was also an existing school:
the Shanghai Jewish School...
which was administered
by these two families...
the Sassoon and Kadoories.
It was a private school.
You had to pay tuition
If you could not pay tuition,
you went for free.
It was a school run
under the British school system.
The curriculum was
made up in Cambridge, England...
was sent to Shanghai,
meticulously followed.
Examination papers were sent back
to Cambridge for marking...
and then returned to Shanghai.
There were kosher lunches...
and there was a big, beautiful Sephardic
synagogue, still in existence today...
on the grounds of
the Shanghai Jewish School.
Had a very, very lovely
English lady...
in our Shanghai Jewish School-
Mrs. Beresford-
who every weekend...
would take from her class...
one kid to her house.
I remember I was there twice.
Her son was a boy
named Maxwell Beresford.
That was in downtown Shanghai.
They were beautiful-
beautiful woman, beautiful people-
and for two days
you lived again in a different world.
When we kids had nothing to do...
in the afternoon, after school...
we got active
and we had athletic competitions.
We had a soccer league,
where we played soccer every weekend.
There also was
a small boxing club...
because there were
some Jews from Germany-
Some of them were champion of Germany.
They had a little time
on their hands...
and they started to teach us
to be boxers.
We had a very good boxing league.
I was pretty good.
I was very good at boxing.
I had a very strong right.
I won most of my fights by knockout.
Now as a man of72 years old...
it doesn't look the same
and it doesn't feel the same...
but I was very strong
and I was very good.
So were others in our group.
They were really good.
We had good trainers
and we trained very hard.
We took enormous pride to win.
All of us wore the Magen David,
which was important.
When you're always on the bottom,
and everybody spits and laughs at you...
you are finally on even keel-
It was important.
Here you have a community...
that despite these disadvantages
that I mentioned to you...
created a viable cultural life...
that would have done justice
to a city of 100,000.
Newspapers,
dailies, weeklies, monthlies-
An incredible array of newspapers.
Of course one person bought it...
then gave it out
to 10 other people to read.
These were read and read
and reread until they were torn.
From Vienna, the sausages and bakery
and other things-
The café house, which was a standard
in Vienna and Germany...
they brought to Shanghai.
Architects created
a whole new area...
where the bombed-out part of Hongkew
had been rebuilt...
to create apartments,
rooms for refugees.
They created a theater, and this included
a German theater and a Yiddish theater.
They had cabaret evenings
in these little restaurants...
that were fabulous.
We would go there-
Once in a great while
my father would come out...
with enough money
for us to go to one of these places.
We would go there, and we'd listen
to them sing and make jokes.
People like Herbert Zernik
and Raya Zomina- she sang in Yiddish.
These two were so funny,
and they were so good.
There was a lot of that going on.
You have this attempt...
to bring some kind of cultural life.
It's not only the café houses.
It's not only recreating Little Vienna
or Little Berlin...
as some people have written.
It is much more.
Several newspapers-
The Gelb Reports, Shanghai Chronicle-
Many more that stopped and started.
Even books.
Poetry. People were writing
wonderful poetry in German...
not only in Yiddish.
It is that kind of thing
which I think is moving.
Among the squalor,
the poverty, the hunger...
and this feeling of,
"What's going to be with us?
Where will all this end?
Will it ever end?"...
there still is the human spirit
reasserting itself.
The Jewish refugees built...
an almost self-sufficient,
beautiful society.
There's sports clubs,
there's soccer clubs...
there are recreation clubs,
there are boxers.
It's an amazing story.
My father had
come out of Buchenwald...
where his war wound had acted up
and had not been treated.
He got sick,
then he got well, then he got sick.
He got checkups.
They didn't know what it was.
They pulled his teeth,
they thought it was that.
He kept getting fevers,
and it was called "Shanghai Fever. "
But he functioned and ran the business
with a Chinese mechanic.
My mother went knocking on doors
getting customers.
She did the bookkeeping, she did
the correspondence and appointments.
My father did the repairs
together with a Chinese mechanic.
Then he got sick again...
and he died, just like that.
He was 43years old.
They were never sure what it was...
but they presume it was
some kind of a parasite...
that he harbored from Buchenwald.
When he fought
in the First World War...
he was at the Battle of Verdun
in France...
which was a very big,
important battle.
I think it was in 1916.
He was born in 1897...
so he was about 19 years old.
He was a kid, really.
As he was standing with his gun...
he sees a young French soldier...
on the other side of him,
opposite him.
That's the enemy...
so naturally you shoot your enemy
or he's gonna shoot you.
My father tells the story.
He sees this French soldier...
and he raises his gun to shoot him.
At the same moment
that he's shooting the soldier...
the soldier shoots him.
And as my father fell-
He had a stomach wound, lying there-
he heard the young French soldier
say, "Shema Israel. "
That always affected him.
He killed a Jew.
All of a sudden, he wasn’t a German
soldier killing a French soldier...
it was a Jew killing a Jew.
It affected him all his life.
It must have,
because he always told that story...
and then my mother repeated it.
Although the situation
in Shanghai was bad...
it was far better than Europe,
where war was still raging.
The refugees felt relatively safe
in Shanghai under Japanese occupation.
That was about to change.
In December, 1941...
Japan attacked
the American naval base at Pearl Harbor.
The United States entered the war.
Pearl Harbor
was not only a major shock...
which verified to some that the Gestapo
had a long arm...
and it reached out to the Far East.
It was a double shock.
Here they thought, "We have difficulties,
but we're out of danger from Germany. "
All of a sudden, with Pearl Harbor
they find Germany and Japan are allies...
and Germans again
are involved in their affairs.
We got very frightened.
With America at war,
we're not going to get out of Shanghai.
Looked out the window...
and all the ships in the harbor
were burning.
Japanese had come
across the bridge...
marched into our hotel,
occupied the hotel.
We were at war.
The Japanese quickly took over
the International Settlement.
The British and the Americans
were now enemies of Japan...
and were regarded as
prisoners of war.
The Japanese imprisoned them...
in internment camps
at the outskirts of Shanghai.
That group included the Baghdadi Jews
who were also British subjects.
The Sephardic community,
which had been helping the refugees...
was no longer in the elite position
that they were before.
They themselves were reduced...
as to how much money
they could take out of the bank.
Most of their money was confiscated.
Within three quarters of a year or so-
certainly by the end of the year-
all the enemy aliens-
meaning American, British and Dutch
nationals- were interned.
I remember when they locked
all the British up.
A few of our guys- I was with them-
knew where the camp was.
Long way to walk,
the way I remember it today.
We gathered whatever we could steal-
some cans, some this, some that.
We walked for kilometers,
the way I remember it.
We brought them some. They were
all locked up in the British camp.
We paid back.
With America at war with Japan...
all lines of communication between
Shanghai and the US were suddenly cut.
Laura Margolis was cut off...
without money coming from America
to support the soup kitchens...
the local shelters
and the makeshift hospital.
Foreseeing such a problem, she had already
obtained permission from the JDC...
to borrow money
from local businessmen...
who were confident that they would be
repaid by the JDC...
at the end of the war,
as indeed they were.
But without the Japanese
approving the operation...
everything could fall apart...
leaving thousands of refugees with
no means to support themselves.
So I phoned up Captain Inuzuka.
He remembered me...
because we had
been to social affairs together...
and received me very nicely.
Made the tea ceremony, very nice,
very cordial.
Then we got to
the nitty-gritty of what I came for.
It's true that I'm an enemy alien.
I don't know what’s going to
happen with me next.
But for the foreseeable future,
apparently I'm free.
I would be able to take over
the whole operation in Shanghai...
and keep feeding the people...
if he would give me permission
to raise the money.
I said...
"You, as an occupying power...
can not afford
to have hungry people riot.
You're responsible for them.
On the other hand...
I can help you so they won't riot...
if you’ll give me an okay...
to raise the money. "
And he did.
The war years
were very difficult years...
in the sense that
there wasn't enough food...
and everybody had dysentery.
Having diarrhea was just usual.
Food got to be very difficult
in '43, '44, '45.
There wasn't a lot of food.
Lot of people were clearly
suffering from malnutrition.
You had a sense-
As a young kid, I remember...
the people were shrinking
into their clothes.
They looked gaunt and shabby.
Little Chinese boys
would be chasing grocery trucks.
They'd have a knife.
They'd cut a hole in the sack.
The noodles would fall
into the gutter.
They'd sweep them up,
and they would be sold very cheaply.
Then my mother and I
would sit around the kerosene lamp...
or whatever was available
in the way of light...
and we’d separate
the noodles from the debris.
Debris being
broken glass, rusty nails, stones-
whatever is swept up from a gutter.
I remember we were sitting
on the balcony once-
Werner, my second father, and I-
Tiny little balcony.
My mother was in the streets.
She had just bought bread.
And we saw
some young kid came up...
grabbed the bread from her arm
and started running.
When she came up, she said, "He must have
been even hungrier than we are. "
Those were-
There wasn't much of anything.
Since the Baghdadi Jews were imprisoned
in internment camps with the British...
Laura Margolis called upon
the Russian Jews to help the refugees.
The responsibility
for the refugees...
fell now on the Russian Jews.
And I would say-
They had no choice,
but we accept the responsibility.
But also they did their best.
They cannot be faulted.
After that, they simply had to do
whatever was possible.
My parents
and quite a few other people...
had their kids go
to a Catholic school.
Saint Francis Xavier's College-
SFX- which was an all-boys school.
Discipline extremely strict.
If I learned anything at all,
that's where I learned it.
It was a Catholic school. All brothers,
with the long black gowns.
Religious Catholics
from all over the world-
Brother Leo,
Brother Ladislaus from Hungary.
There was one big redhead,
Brother John.
I'll never forget...
every morning
when we walked into school...
Brother John would give us...
a little insight
into what the political situation was.
He was very, very anti-Allies.
He was very much pro-German
and pro-Japanese.
He was a real nice guy. He was very nice,
especially to us Jewish kids...
and yet...
his actions showed different and the words
that came out of his mouth were different.
After the war was over...
it came out that Brother John was actually
a very high officer in the British army.
He was no brother.
Not a religious man,
but set up in there.
Apparently he was one of those...
that gave a lot of information
of what was going on in Shanghai...
as far as the Japanese army
was concerned, to the Allied forces.
The refugee community was very worried
what was happening...
because after all the enemy aliens
of Japan and Germany were interned...
what was gonna happen to us?
Knowing that Jews
were always first in line...
when it came to bad things
happening to good people, so to speak...
what did they have in store for us?
On February 18, 1943...
the Japanese issued a proclamation...
ordering all stateless refugees
who came to Shanghai after 1937..
to move to a segregated area
in Hongkew.
That's when the German influence
became much more crucial.
German influence pressured
the Japanese into creating a ghetto.
This was the tendency of
the Japanese in ruling.
Here this whole puppet-state concept
comes into play.
If you have them nice and compact
all together...
you can watch them
and you know what they're doing.
Then what you do
is you give them...
someone to watch over them.
No direct rule.
That's the puppet government
that watches over them.
It's exactly what they did
in Shanghai.
It wasn't a real ghetto.
It wasn't a ghetto that we know
from Europe. It wasn't that.
It was a different concept.
It was a very Japanese concept.
And yes, all foreigners
need to be watched.
The ghetto didn't have
any walls around.
It didn't have to...
because if you saw a European face
in downtown Shanghai...
and they were not German or Russian,
they had to be one of us...
because all the Americans and all the
British were put into internment camps.
So we moved into that ghetto area.
My mother sold a bunch of the possessions
we had just to make room.
We had a very tiny room.
There were at the end-
three, four, six-
ten people in this house.
We lived in a Chinese house
owned by a Jew...
but there were five families
in a ghetto...
and we had the attic
which was like this.
We were not able to stand straight,
only in the middle of the attic.
On the side it went all the way down.
The major problem we had was
my brother contracted polio in China...
which was a disaster.
Food was scarce.
Eventually we couldn't get out
from the ghetto anymore...
so I started a job.
I worked in the kitchen.
The school had a kitchen.
We all had to move into one room
to 51 Chusan Road...
which was right smack
in the middle of the ghetto.
They never called it a ghetto.
They called it a segregated area...
but it was a ghetto.
I went back there too...
and took a look.
Yes.
- We lived upstairs, you know?
- There you go.
Take care.
- Be careful on the steps.
- Take care.
Yes, on the steps.
It all comes back.
The roof looks the same.
It's amazing how it didn't change.
I can't believe it.
We used to have the rice
on this windowsill...
and take the bugs out of the rice-
my sister and me.
There was another window
and we had a little kitchen...
where there's now a wall here...
with one little stove,
two rings of gas.
We never used it
because we didn't have enough gas.
And a little sink
with cold water running.
We put a curtain across it...
so that nobody
would come in when we washed ourselves.
Never took a bath during the war,
just sponge bath...
'cause the bathroom down the hall
was so dirty.
Everything comes back.
We did everything in this room.
We lived here...
we slept here, we argued here.
I learned to dance in this room
with my father...
to the radio.
Voice of America. We tried to get it,
but it was forbidden...
so we had to be very careful.
My mother always had flowers on the table.
You could buy flowers.
All the time we were wondering
what happened in Germany.
We didn't know
what was going on...
all during the war.
It's just amazing
how it all comes back.
To exit the ghetto
for jobs or school...
the refugees
had to get special passes.
The Japanese authorities
were represented by two officials;
Akura and Goya.
Goya- They called him "Meshuggener Goya"
or "Paranoid Goya"-
who had a-
He was really schizophrenic
in many ways.
I'm giving you
not a professional evaluation.
He could be very good to the children.
He'd give out candies to children.
He loved to play music,
even though he was a lousy musician.
He always forced the refugees
to play with him.
He liked to be called "King of the Jews. "
He was a short, ugly fellow.
He would stand on the desk
and yell at some Jews.
There was one Jew
who really caught his psychology.
A brilliant idea.
He saw the kind of person he was.
He had a silk top hat he'd put on.
He gambled.
He'd say, "You're making fun of me?"
He wore a silk hat when
he went down the line to get a pass.
He said, "No, I only wear it...
when I meet royalty
and important people. "
He caught onto
the psychology of that person...
and he was always put
in front of the line.
Anytime he came,
he got his pass immediately.
Mr. Goya was a very short,
little man...
and my stepfather Werner
was a very tall man.
He was about 6 foot 2, 6 foot 3.
The little Japanese man
didn't like that.
So he pulled out his gloves...
and he slapped my father
across the face.
He jumped on the table
and slapped him across the face...
and yelled at him to get out
and "no pass. "
I remember
Werner coming home that day...
and he was a shattered, broken man.
So now
my mother's typewriter business...
definitely was
down the drain altogether...
because many refugees now
were not just dying of disease...
they were dying of starvation, because
there was so little food around.
And what she decided was a ruse.
She wrote to one of her customers in
the French Concession, a French lady...
and asked her to send a letter...
saying that she was still
servicing her typewriter.
The lady wrote that letter.
Armed with that letter...
she made an application
for a special pass with Mr. Goya.
She stood in front of Goya,
and Goya said, "You repair typewriters?"
She says, "Yes, I was in business.
My husband died here,
but it was his business originally.
I still know how to repair them. "
She got a pass,
and armed with that pass...
she decided what she was gonna do.
She had no intention of
servicing typewriters.
She got a pass
to go to the French Concession.
What she did that was not legal...
she got off the tram
before she got to the French Concession.
She went to the parts of the city...
where Westerners did not go,
the Chinese parts.
She bought up sundries
like sunglasses...
nylon stockings, belts, scarves,
stuff like that.
She would put them under the toolbox
that she carried with her...
and bring them
back to the ghetto area...
and then give them to the peddlers
on consignment in the ghetto.
Even though it didn't
bring in much money...
it brought in just enough...
to keep us slightly above
the starvation level.
One night when my parents
thought I was asleep...
they were talking to one another...
and my mother said that
there were only $17 left.
I had no idea what 17-
It was a fair amount of money...
but it was clear that
when that was gone...
we would be in terrible shape.
We had what they called
a "paocha"...
so the Japanese
didn't have to do it...
and we were happy
they didn't have to do it.
Everybody was assigned
a couple of hours a week...
where you got an official armband
and a stick...
and you were standing
and controlling...
that the people
don't go out without a pass-
out of the ghetto without a pass-
and that they came in on time.
But as I said to you,
I worked for Russians...
and there was a Russian club.
The Jews that had Soviet passports
could live outside the ghetto.
They had the radio and everything...
and they got movies of the war
going on with Germany.
The way to get back into the ghetto
after the hour-
What I did is-
The ghetto
did not have a wall around it.
This side of the street was the ghetto,
the other side was not the ghetto.
So I walked on the other side
of the street which was not the ghetto.
There was one street
where the police station was.
Just as I came
to the police station...
I walked across the street
and into the police station.
If anybody would ask,
I'm going in to the police...
but then I looked around,
said, "I think I'm in the wrong place"...
and I walked out again.
This was maybe 10:00 at night.
Anywhere else I walked...
they would have caught me going into
the ghetto at 10:00.
I was supposed to be home by 6:00.
There was this White Russian boy.
He was good friends
with the Japanese kids there.
Whenever he got a hold of me,
I got my daily-
If I couldn't run fast enough,
I got my daily beating.
I remember one time I came home,
my mother almost fainted.
A black eye and bleeding,
no shirt, one shoe missing-
I took a bad beating.
George was his name.
Family name's not important.
George and his gang, always two
or three guys. They get you.
I used to go to bed at night,
I remember that vividly...
and I’d say, "Someday, I don't know,
I will get even.
I have to get even.
This can't go on. "
I took a beating
maybe three or four times a week.
They'd catch you, you'd get it.
Butter was very valuable,
very expensive.
I recall that my parents-
Later on there wasn't any butter,
but my parents in '43, '44...
would buy half a quarter of butter,
two ounces...
and they would watch
and make sure that I ate it.
I remember once, vividly...
walking out where my mother
was washing the dishes.
I noticed that she licked
the last bit of butter off the plate.
Till we moved into our-
Can't say a flat-
Till we moved into a room
of a larger flat...
which was shared...
by probably four or five families-
11, 12 people all in all.
We had one room in there.
Bathroom facilities,
if you can call it that...
shared by about 11, 12 people,
if I remember correctly.
In that one room,
my mother made hats...
and that's where we lived
and slept and worked.
I can't explain.
I don't think people today...
will understand what this is all about
unless you see it.
Here we had
our windows painted black...
and if a little light
would shine out...
the Japanese
would be cursing from the streets.
I don’t want to tell you what they cursed.
I could repeat it if I wanted to.
They used to yell from down there,
Bagero!
If a little light shone out,
they'd come smashing the doors in.
So we made sure
the windows were all blacked...
with shmattes covering
so nothing would shine out.
Werner and Fufi would lie
under the blanket at night.
They had a tiny little radio- I don't
know where they got that one from-
and all covered up,
they'd listen to the news.
Fufi understood a little Russian...
so they used to listen to the news in
Russian- what happened in World War II.
We'd hear from the Soviet Union...
that the Russian armies had started
turning things around...
and pushing the Germans back.
That gave us a little bit of hope-
gave us a little bit of hope
for the future.
It didn't all seem that bleak
in those days.
Otherwise, that's about it.
From here we went to school,
here we came home after we got beat up.
This room has a lot of history.
My mother was a very fine lady.
She made big pots of soup
with all sorts of things inside...
and then she fed
another three or four people...
who came for lunch
on a steady basis.
There was a painter,
Kurt Frankenstein.
There was a Mr. Rouget who in turn
taught me Russian for the food he ate.
There was another gentleman
whose name I forget right now.
We always had three people...
eating the same soup every day
for lunch. I remember them.
Yeah, my mom was a nice lady.
She was a good gal.
In the place where we worked,
we had a map...
and every day...
we put pins in for
the advances of the Russian army...
or the German-
We had the news
through the Russian club.
We had the newspaper in the ghetto,
in German.
And the official news came through.
The victorious German army
withdrew from Harkoff.
We knew they got
kicked out of Harkoff.
Shanghai,
apart of the Japanese empire...
was under attack by American forces,
mostly by air.
So far up to this point...
Shanghai itself had not been bombed.
There were strafings.
We'd see Japanese and American
fighter planes up in the sky.
Kids have no fear.
We’d be up on the roof.
We'd bet with marbles
who would shoot down whom...
as shrapnel was
falling all around us.
When I think of it now, how foolish.
We could have gotten killed.
But nobody ever got hurt by that.
I don't know.
We must have been immune.
They would push
the dining room tables together...
and put mattresses on top
and we would crawl underneath...
and that was
supposed to be a shelter.
It was July 17, 1945.
My mother was on one of
her illegal forays in the city.
I was on my way to see Sue and Chaya,
who were living together.
They lived on the exact opposite
end of the ghetto from where I lived.
It was a very, very hot summer day...
and in Shanghai
the clouds used to hang...
just a couple hundred meters
above your head. You would choke.
There was an air raid alarm
in the morning...
and then it was called off.
I think two or three times
and called off.
I remember I went to a haircut.
I'm walking down the road...
and I stopped-
Next to the prison was a hospital.
And that hospital
had become a prison hospital...
for American and British POWs.
They always had them out on a balcony
on a top floor...
which was maybe the fifth
or sixth floor.
We used to stop there
and wave to them.
Sure they must have been wondering
who we were.
They used to wave back
and we'd wave to them.
Suddenly you thought
the world was coming to an end.
Absolutely the world- Afterwards
they said it was about a hundred B-29s...
over Shanghai,
just over the clouds.
That's a-
That's a ear-cracking noise.
It is unbearable.
Just as I'm starting to continue
to walk over there...
the dreaded siren went off
that the city was under attack.
No bomb shelter, but a trench.
Jumped into a trench
with some other people...
and within a split second
the bombs were flying.
And then the bombs started flying.
The bombs,
when they go down, they go-
You hear that whistle.
I'll never forget that whistle...
right before the thud.
We were always taught
when the bombs start falling...
you take an inside post
of the building.
Never stand in the middle.
So everybody ran, grabbed some
inside post of a building.
People screaming, and then you heard
the sirens of the ambulances.
It was over very, very quickly.
Then we started running home.
Thirty-one refugees died,
as well as hundreds of Chinese...
in an attack by American forces...
trying to hit
a Japanese radio station in Hongkew.
The Japanese were terrific.
They had supplied
the ghetto hospital...
with medications
and emergency equipment...
in the event
there would be a disaster.
They had the ambulances.
They came and they
took care of everything immediately.
Didn't matter whether you were Chinese
or white or green or yellow.
We had shrapnel coming into
the window of the room where we lived...
on my sister's bed, actually.
On her pillow.
And I kept that piece
for many, many years.
You could see the evidence
of the destruction all over the place.
There were shells of houses...
and you could see that only walls
had remained where houses had been.
and there was rubble
strewn everywhere.
I n the afternoon
we went for a walk around the district...
and that was devastating.
Dead bodies, blood, this, that-
I remember I couldn't fall asleep
for a whole month.
I used to sit in bed
all night long with nightmares...
and I couldn't fall asleep.
I couldn't do my schoolwork.
My head was just not there anymore.
Then we heard about
the first atomic bomb...
on Hiroshima, then on Nagasaki.
We said, "Oh, my God. They're now
going to drop it on Shanghai. "
It was a terrible fear for us...
because we knew Shanghai
was a military target.
Otherwise, why would there be
strafings on the outskirts?
After the war was over,
it suddenly got very quiet on the streets.
That was in August
when that part of the war was over.
It got very quiet out there
and the Japanese soldiers were gone.
We looked out
through the blackout curtains...
and there was nobody out there.
We waited a while
to see if it was safe...
and then we went out
and there was nothing.
They were gone from the check posts
around the ghetto.
They were out of there.
That's when we found out
that it was over.
And when the war was over...
we were in good shape.
We're strong kids, played a lot of soccer.
I went out to the streets.
Everybody was running wild. The Jews-
Suddenly, everything opened up.
I went out
and two buddies came with me.
I went to look
for George Bremen.
George Bremen
saw me from a block away...
and he knew this was the end,
and he started running.
But I ran like a wild animal...
so he couldn't have gotten away
from me, no way.
I got a hold of George Bremen,
and I was never a violent kid.
If those two guys
would not have been with me-
I probably lost my mind.
I probably would have killed him.
I let out
three, four years of anger...
lots of pain.
I hit him with everything I could...
and if those two boys weren't there,
I probably would have killed him...
because I lost all humanity
at that time too.
After the war was over...
the Red Cross released lists of
surviving family members in Europe.
The refugees rushed to see
who survived.
Few did.
Soon after, news of what happened
in Europe reached the refugees.
I remember we got a few letters...
from the Warsaw ghetto,
which I have...
where my Uncle Mietek...
wrote to his sister, my mother...
if there’s anything she can do
to help us get out of the Warsaw ghetto...
and of course there was nothing to do.
There was nothing to do.
I have some of the letters
in Polish, in German.
They're very sad letters...
of „Help us get out of here,"
but there was nothing my mother could do.
A completely lost situation.
And those were the last letters.
I always admired
the people that resisted.
I've taught my children that.
I thought by being an athlete,
showing a different way of a Jew...
that I contributed something...
that we Jews are different
and it can never happen again.
It won’t happen again.
I will have nothing to do
with Germany.
Germany decimated my whole family.
Germany changed my whole life.
My father
who fought for the country-
In my mind, they murdered him.
I have no aunts and uncles
that I know of.
I grew up without cousins.
My mother had a very difficult life.
Everything was taken away from her.
I can't forget that.
Jewish life continues...
which is not guaranteed,
unfortunately.
I always say that if my grandchildren
don't grow up Jewish...
Hitler won the war.
And it's a problem.
Anti-Semitism never bothered me
as much as assimilation.
Most of the rest of the family...
that I'd gotten to know
from our yearly visits-
I spent a month or two in Poland
every summer- did not survive.
When we heard about
the concentration camps...
I remember vividly...
that my only recollection of some of
the people that did not survive...
were things that I was
very unhappy about.
That was long before
I learned about survivor guilt...
because there was the feeling
of we had survived and they had not.
I remember the last time I saw-
One of my cousins
who lived in Dembitz...
and his mother and I understand
his father survived-
I was always very jealous of him.
He was clearly the brightest
of all the cousins.
We must have had eight, nine cousins.
When we get together, he could
solve any puzzle and stump the rest of us.
But he was physically
somewhat more awkward than I...
and I remember vividly
that the last time we got together...
I had a big fight with him...
and his eyeglasses were broken.
I remember when I heard after the war
that he had not survived...
that was the only memory
that kept coming back to me.
How could I possibly have fought with him
the last time I saw him?
But on the whole they didn't know
what was happening...
so they focused on their own life
and on the misery of life in Shanghai.
Lo and behold, after the war they
found out they're living in paradise...
compared to what happened
to their brethren in Europe.
That's what it was.
It's all a relative thing.
You don't know you’re living in paradise
until you're kicked out.
After American liberation...
the living conditions in Shanghai
improved greatly.
In the following years...
all the refugees
left Shanghai and China...
and spread around the world.
The Israeli government had chartered
three small Greek ships.
These three ships sailed
up the Yangtze River, the Whangpoo...
with Israeli flags...
which is still a very moving
moment to me...
because obviously
if there were an Israel...
there wouldn't have been
a Holocaust.
It's as simple as that.
Of course, anybody who wanted to
was welcome to go aboard the ship.
And no one-
These are still moving moments for me.
No one was ever asked for a visa
or for a ship's passage...
and if that had been true
we wouldn't have been in Shanghai...
and there wouldn’t have been six million
Jews killed during the Second World War.
Many of the Jews in Shanghai
did go to Israel...
and others- most came
to the United States, some to Australia.
We came to the United States
on a US troop transport-
the SS Marine Lynx...
which was a beautiful ship
for transporting the US Army.
Beautiful ship that took us
from Shanghai...
through Yokohama and Hawaii
to San Francisco.
Couple thousand Jewish refugees
on the ship.
Ship got into San Francisco
3:00 in the morning.
I thought the ocean would overflow
with all the tears of the refugees...
when they see San Francisco
at 3:00 in the morning.
But on the transcontinental train
from San Francisco to New York...
I happened to be on the train
with two black soldiers.
And usually
as soon as the train would stop...
we'd get off just to stretch our legs,
get a different environment.
We got off at Albuquerque,
the black soldiers didn't get off.
I didn't understand why.
Then I walked into the station...
and there's a sign,
"White Men" and "Colored Men. "
I remember vividly
I felt as if I had been slapped.
I also felt that I couldn't face
the black soldiers.
It's not that I was that
racially conscious at the time.
Of course I knew about discrimination.
It wasn’t anything new to me.
But I'd never encountered it firsthand
since we left Germany.
And the one thing I learned...
having lived among
Japanese and Chinese people...
is that I can't find it in myself
to hate a nation...
or a people.