Other wars
have been photographed.
World War II was covered
from start to finish,
in every service,
in every theater.
For the first time in history,
civilians knew something
of how their sons,
husbands and brothers
lived and died
in this vast crucible.
The images of this war
burned our eyes and spirits
and welded us together.
I loved it because
it was dangerous.
I'm a fraidy-cat,
but if there was
a job to do, I did it.
No matter how horrible
the action was
that you were covering,
when you looked
through that glass,
that glass was your filter.
I got carried away one time
and got out in front of the gun,
shooting the gun firing,
and that was a big mistake,
because the muzzle blast got me
and knocked me about 40 feet,
ass over tea kettle.
We hit an intersection
where we were shot at.
The bullets just whizzed by us
into the cab of the truck.
When you're bailing
out of that airplane,
and you're on the way down,
you say, "Oh, no. Oh, no."
But shells...
You can't see anything.
You want to yell, "Stop.
This is... I'm here."
Those are some of the men
who took the pictures
by which
we remember World War II.
Some of their images
are immortal.
Many have been hidden
in the archives for decades.
But whether their pictures
are famous or not,
what you are about to see
is unique.
War stories backed
by the irrefutable evidence
of the films they made.
In their hands,
the camera became a weapon
more potent than the rifle,
a weapon whose impact resonates
even more powerfully now
as memory
is transformed into history.
[Tom Hanks] In 1941, we were
as unprepared to photograph war
as we were to wage it.
When John Ford made his film
on Pearl Harbor,
the Japanese attack
was recreated out of special effects,
intercut with old
newsreel footage...
and a few feet
of the real thing.
Men, man your battle stations.
God bless you.
[Bugle blowing]
[Hanks] The great Hollywood
cameraman Gregg Toland
restaged these scenes
months after Pearl Harbor.
The actors
are obviously amateurs,
but they are real sailors.
The attacking planes
were the contribution
of the 20th Century-Fox
special effects department.
In this outtake,
you can see the wires
supporting the model Zero.
Ford organized
his field photographic branch
before the war,
as part of the O.S.S.
Toland's crew set fire
to crashed planes,
adding drama to his footage.
But his first cut,
a feature-length fictional parable
about American unpreparedness
was judged unreleasable.
Ford now took
a more active hand,
cutting December 7th
to 34 minutes.
He retained much of the miniature
footage, also made at Fox.
This material,
never before seen,
was shot in color,
though the film was released
in black and white.
This is Hollywood's version
of Pearl Harbor's
battleship row,
and the Ford-Toland version
of the attack on it.
There was authentic footage
of the battleship Nevada trying to escape,
but Ford preferred this reconstruction.
It matched the rest
of his fake footage better.
Besides, his goal
was not strict authenticity.
He was out to stir the nation.
There was enough reality
in his film
to win an Academy Award
for Best Short Subject.
As Toland and Ford worked on
their film in spring 1942,
America mounted its first
aggressive response to Pearl Harbor,
a navy task force
under Admiral Bull Halsey.
It carried
James Doolittle's fliers
and 16 B-25s aboard the Hornet.
Hal Kempe was a photographer's mate
on the newly commissioned ship.
[Kempe]
I've heard many stories.
Some of them say that we slipped out
under the cover of darkness.
We went under
the Golden Gate Bridge at noon,
and we had the planes lined up
from one end of the flight deck
to the other,
and it looked like
a ferry trip.
After we were at sea
for about two or three days,
they re-spotted the flight deck.
They took each B-25...
they are tricycle landing gear...
and placed them
with their tails
extending out over
the flight deck at the edge.
They put one on each
port and starboard side
until the lead plane had
sufficient run for his takeoff.
[Hanks] That was one-third
the normal takeoff distance.
The raiders were spotted
by Japanese picketboats.
They were sunk, but might
have radioed a warning.
There was no choice but to launch
the attack prematurely.
[Kempe] They said, "Army pilots,
man your planes. We're going to launch. "
So we were launching
eight hours too soon.
Doolittle was first.
Boom, he went, and the rest
of the crews are wondering,
"Can it be done?"
[Hanks] The raiders,
all volunteers,
had practiced
short-run takeoffs on land.
A few had practiced from a carrier deck,
but never in bad weather.
Yet all were safely launched
for their 30 seconds
over Tokyo.
Halsey's concern?
The early launch made it
impossible for the planes
to make safe landings in China,
yet all but three fliers
survived the raid.
It did little damage,
except to enemy morale.
[Kempe] They carried
four 500-pound bombs each,
and that's not very much
when you really look at it,
but it was enough
to put the fear of God
into them for a while.
[Hanks] The Doolittle raid
provoked a huge Japanese counterattack
aimed at destroying the U.S. Pacific fleet,
but we had broken their code
and knew they would be
attacking Midway Island.
This evened the odds
for the Hornet
and two other carriers
as they approached the war's
first great naval battle.
Midway was a pair
of tiny coral atolls
vital to the defense of Hawaii.
This time, John Ford
was present with a film crew.
Ford himself
operated one of the cameras
and was wounded
getting these pictures.
He would win another Oscar
for the film
he fashioned from them.
The crucial part of the battle
was at sea,
between ships
that never saw one another.
[Kempe] They didn't know exactly
where the Japanese fleet was,
but our torpedo squadron
skipper had an idea
that it was off
in a certain direction,
and he went off there.
He ran into
the whole bunch of them.
And they lost...
Fifteen or sixteen
torpedo planes went down.
[Hanks] These are the men
of Torpedo Squadron 8,
who found
the Japanese carriers.
They scored no hits, but along
with other torpedo planes,
they distracted enemy gunners,
allowing our dive-bombers
to sink four carriers.
Only one man, George Gay,
on the right, survived.
One of Ford's crew
shot these pictures.
The director made them
into a short memorial film,
which he sent
to the squadron's next of kin.
Midway shifted the balance
of naval power in the Pacific.
It cost the Japanese
almost half their carriers.
Still, their wounded navy
continued to pose
a deadly threat.
October 1942.
The Hornet steams toward
the Battle of Santa Cruz
near Guadalcanal.
With her sister ship,
the Enterprise,
she was soon fighting off
massive assaults from the air.
Just how close
the combat often was
is demonstrated
by this sequence,
shot from the Enterprise.
A near miss
shakes the Enterprise.
An enemy shadow
is cast on the flight deck
as the ship fights on.
The camera catches
the wild swing of the huge ship
as it takes evasive action.
But still the bombs rain down.
The camera survived this hit,
but not the cameraman.
The Hornet
did not survive either.
[Kempe] We were listing
to the starboard.
Real heavy list.
I went to the fantail
to help with the wounded,
where I stayed the rest of the
day until we abandoned ship.
And I swam out on the quarter,
about 45 degrees out this way,
and got out so far,
and here come the destroyers.
I figured, "This is going
to be a piece of cake.
Pick us up quick. "
Then they backed down
and took off.
The destroyers start circling
way out around the ship
and start firing, and I figured,
"What are they firing at?"
We started looking in the sky,
and coming in on this line...
we had gone out
on the fantail...
was a "V" formation of
twin-engine bombers coming in,
and you could see the five-inch
antiaircraft bursts up there by it.
And they came and... shoop!
Went right over the head, and
one hit the fantail back here,
and the rest was in a pattern
around the stern of the ship.
And they continued on
and never came back.
I got picked up
right after that
by the 411 Anderson.
[Hanks] That final bombing run
was the coup de grâce.
The next day, the Hornet's
short, brave life was ended
when American destroyers
sank her.
Our ship had been in commission
for one year and six days.
[Hanks] But the carrier war
in the Pacific never ceased.
[Kempe] We didn't have
motors on the Mitchells,
but you had to hand-crank.
So when we did
flight deck operations,
we did not hand-crank
at three turns per second
on the small crank.
We used the big crank,
and we would start
going up to high speed,
because we'd want
slow motion of the crash.
The pilot coming in
for landing...
If you see the photographer
on the flight deck
start with that big crank,
look out, you bought the farm.
[Hanks] The footage Kempe and his
colleagues took on the flight decks
forms an eerie ballet
of destruction
and of unlikely survival.
By late 1942,
we were officially
training combat cameramen.
Standard army issue was the
35-millimeter Eyemo for movies
and the 4x5 Speed Graphic
for stills.
Many of the cameramen had been
photographers in civilian life.
Hal Roach's Culver City studio
was a major production
and training center.
Naturally, the students
took pictures of themselves
taking pictures.
Eventually about 1,500 men,
not a lot for a war this huge,
would become motion-picture
combat cameramen.
Many served in the air force.
On the endless strategic
bombing raids over Europe,
they worked as bomb spotters,
recording damage
for intelligence analysts.
The oil fields
at Ploesti in Rumania
were vital
to the German war effort
and among the most
bombed targets of the war.
On August 1, 1943,
these B-24s based in Libya
mounted the first
major attack on them
at a daring 500 feet.
Then, as later,
results were poor.
Ploesti was never knocked out.
Doug Morrell flew later
higher-altitude missions over Ploesti.
[Morrell] This mission
could be 10 hours long,
but the combat part
is only about 10 minutes.
Ten minutes is a long time.
Try holding your breath.
The Eyemo had
a hand-crank wind on it,
and it seemed like always when the most
important thing happened,
you're winding that thing,
trying to get it going.
I hated to reload
up at 20,000 feet.
Reloading up there,
your fingers get a little cold.
When you come into the target,
they put up so much flak
that the enemy fighters
won't come in there.
They'll get hit.
Bomb spotting
is when the bombs release.
Then you follow them
and pick up their hits.
When you get those hits down there,
the intelligence can use those.
We were bombing Ploesti,
and flak hit us.
We had to drop
out of formation.
And then six ME-109s jumped us
when we got out of formation.
We were quite a ways away,
all by ourselves.
They raked us back and forth
and set us on fire.
I opened the bomb bay door.
I was going to jump out there
instead of out the back end.
Here's this fire coming.
I says, "Oh."
I grabbed a little
fire extinguisher, about that long.
I'm starting to pump that.
I says, "I better leave."
I went out the back end.
Just as I left
out of there, it blew.
We averaged about five
out of an airplane.
When I bailed out,
I was the last one out,
and then the other five
got killed in there.
[Hanks] Another cameraman
who survived the often catastrophic
air war was Dan McGovern.
You were so busy,
you weren't thinking
about a battle.
You were thinking about
helping others and shooting.
In the meantime,
you couldn't
become a spectator.
You had to shoot.
If you're flying in a bomber,
there's 10 crew members
in a bomber.
You're the 11th man.
So then we had to
prove ourselves.
As a matter of fact...
This is a true story,
so help me God.
I photographed
my own crash landing.
The two engines
on the right side, out.
The third engine on the
left side, out. One engine.
So I cut to the right,
cut to the left,
look over the top,
and the airplane's coming in
for a crash landing.
You don't think about it.
You're so excited,
you're not scared,
but you're scared
after when you come back.
- You're just shaking.
- [Hanks] We dropped
over two million tons
of bombs on Europe,
but never matched the results
promised by air power advocates.
This war, like all wars,
would be won on the ground,
as Norman Hatch learned
when he made
the Tarawa landing in 1943.
[Hatch] I was with Jim Crow,
who was a battalion commander.
He wasn't happy with having me there
because, as he had told me earlier,
he didn't want
any Hollywood marines with him.
I testified to him that I was
a regular marine, I shot expert.
If I needed a rifle,
I could do something with it.
He said, "Come with me,
but don't get in my way. "
I was sitting alongside of him,
shooting what was going on,
and he observed
that his amtracs,
which were
the first three waves,
were not maintaining
their course.
And because
there was a.50-caliber
buried in the sand
that was shooting at them,
they kept edging
over to the right,
and Crow could see
his front disappearing
because of this maneuver.
So he told the coxswain
to put the boat in now.
We ran up on the reef.
The ramp wouldn't go down.
All of us had to go
over the side,
which is difficult to do
with 80 pounds of gear on your shoulder.
We got to the beach,
and we were exhausted
because you can't walk
through water
without having
a lot of resistance,
and loaded down with gear
and everything else,
it drained you completely.
It took us a couple of minutes
on the beach to get oriented.
[Hanks] Hatch was pinned down
with the rest of the invaders.
There was nothing
to do but shoot.
Combat footage with
a previously unknown ferocity.
[Hatch] The emplacements that were
there by the Japanese were fantastic.
They built a concrete bunker
and covered it with sand.
Then they covered it with logs.
Then they covered that
with sand.
They were pretty impregnable.
[Hanks] The Pacific war
favored the cameramen.
Spaces were confined,
the action within them
tightly focused.
The brutal reality of war
revealed itself here
as it rarely did elsewhere.
Hatch caught the marines
and their enemy in combat
in the same shot.
[Hatch] That was luck.
I was on top of this enclosure,
and somebody said, "Here they come."
I turned, and there it was,
and I just kept on shooting.
[Hanks] Had the Japanese mounted a
coordinated counterattack on that first day,
they might have driven
the marines back into the sea.
But the fighting remained
as Hatch's film showed it:
Ferocious yet disorganized.
Most of the Japanese
fought to the death.
The marines
took only 17 prisoners.
The seas continued
to run against reinforcements.
Among them was
another cameraman, John Ercole.
[Ercole] We didn't even
know what was going on.
We were going nowhere.
The propeller and the tide
didn't come together.
I was shooting
whatever I could at the time,
faces of people in my own boat
and things like that.
Nineteen hours later,
we finally made a landing.
[Hanks]
What Ercole found to shoot
was mostly the dead
and wounded.
At first their evacuation
was poorly handled.
Hatch credits a movie actor
with getting things organized.
[Hatch]
Eddie Albert was there.
He was a navy JG
at the time,
and he was a boat director.
And he discovered
early on in the game
that there wasn't too much coordination
on getting wounded out,
so he got on the beach himself,
and he stayed there during
the worst part of the fighting
and directed the navy boats
bringing supplies in
to carry wounded
back out to the ships.
[Hanks]
As the battle moved inland,
the futility of the preinvasion
naval bombardment was obvious.
[Hatch] Their pounding
didn't do too much good.
They were using
armor-piercing shells,
and there wasn't
any armor to pierce.
They were hitting sand
and bouncing off
and skittering
all over the island.
You'd see 16-inch shells
laying all over the place.
Nothing had ever happened
with them.
[Ercole] What grabbed me
and took hold of me
was the bodies,
the dead bodies,
God knows how many marines,
face down,
floating in shallow water.
That was the first time that I
had really seen dead bodies.
When you see bodies
floating in the water,
it really grabs you.
And they all seemed to look
like a buddy of mine,
Norman Hatch.
[Hatch] This was
a piece of ground
that wasn't as big
as Central Park in New York,
and in the course
of that 72 hours,
six thousand people died.
Five thousand
of those were Japanese.
One thousand were marines.
Then there were
another 2,000 wounded.
[Hanks] Passing a disabled tank,
Hatch heard this kitten's cry.
At first he thought
it might be a wounded enemy,
but it was just
another war victim.
He thought he might
make a pet of it,
but after getting his drink,
the kitten scampered away,
never to be seen again.
The quality of his Tarawa film
earned Hatch a trip home,
where this footage of him
was made for
an Army-Navy short subject.
[Hatch] We drove
down Market Street,
and every major theater
had my name on the marquee
as taking the Tarawa film,
and they were running it.
That's the best frame
of combat film I've ever seen.
That's okay.
When an army man says that
to a marine, he means it.
It was just luck.
[Hanks]
A movie cameraman,
a stills man,
and a driver.
That's how the Signal Corps
organized its combat
photographers in Europe.
[Doug Wood]
The cameras we were using
were Eyemo,
called a "bomb spotter" camera.
It had a big crank on the side.
You wound it up, and they
only had one 2-inch lens.
And if you can believe
the running you have to do
to get your long shot,
medium shot and close-up
with a two-inch lens,
it was really criminal that they sent us
with that kind of stuff.
[Hanks] Yet remarkable things
could be done with that equipment.
John Huston, one of several
Hollywood directors
who followed John Ford to war,
used it to make
what critic James Agee thought
the best of all
war documentaries.
Huston would write and speak
the strikingly
ironic narration.
[Huston Narrating]
Patron saint: Peter.
Point of interest:
Saint Peter's, 1438.
Note interesting treatment
of chancel.
[Hanks] Huston, however,
would find real war
more difficult to direct
than the Hollywood kind.
[Huston Narrating]
From the end of October 1943
until the middle of December,
San Pietro was the scene of
some of the bitterest fighting
on our 5th Army front.
The Italian campaign
had entered its second phase:
To push forward again
after a static period
brought on
by heavy seasonal rain.
[Man] Huston came over,
and he had a mission.
[Hanks] That was to make
a coherent narrative
of one small battle that would
represent the entire war.
[Man] He realized
that you have no control.
You shoot what you can get.
You come up, you can fire
three rounds and drop.
But you can't get 10 feet
of film in the same way.
But if you had control,
you can do a lot with an Eyemo.
So he came back.
They gave him two battalions
out of the 36th Division who were on
rest and said, "Here it is,"
and he went ahead
and staged that whole thing.
He used film that we had shot.
Actual battle film. And he
intercut it with what he had.
His stuff was much better than ours.
[Hanks] Ed Montagne has
a veteran's genial tolerance
of Huston's tricks.
He used the most
picturesque munitions.
He slammed the camera with his
hand to simulate explosions.
He even posed American Gls
as dead Germans.
[Montagne] But he scared the poor 36th.
That was a nervous outfit.
He'd have them going up a hill,
and he'd throw
a grenade down the hill
and yell, "Grenade!"
And, Christ, they'd dive.
Some of the stuff
he got was great.
I admire him for what he did,
but I resented the fact
that I would get critiques
from New York,
"Huston's men are able to
do this. Why can't yours?"
I had the same people.
Didn't speak well of me,
did it?
[Hanks] Some of Huston's
most moving footage
was of people
picking up the pieces,
of life reasserting itself
in the little town
of San Pietro.
[Huston Narrating] And the people pray
to their patron saint to intercede with God
on behalf of those
who came deliberately
and passed on to the north
with the passing battle.
[Choir vocalizing]
[Hanks] By 1944, the combat
photographers were everywhere,
even the China-Burma-India
theater.
To most Americans, that was
the war's most obscure corner.
Hidden behind high mountains
and deep jungles,
it was both a political
and logistical nightmare.
One air supply route was
called "The Aluminum Trail,"
after all the planes
downed flying it.
When Generals Joseph Stilwell
and Frank Merrill
met to plan a mission against
the key Japanese airfield at Myitkyina,
photographer Dave Quaid
was there.
[Quaid] When General Stilwell
flew off in his little plane,
I went up to Merrill
and I said, "Hey, General,
you mind if I join you guys?"
He said, "Come on along."
[Hanks] Technically,
Quaid was AWOL
when he joined
Operation Galahad.
He had no idea
what he was getting into.
[Quaid] Now we're on this trail
that is basically impassable,
and we had to cut steps
so even the mules...
The mules that can do anything,
handle any terrain,
could not handle this trail.
We ourselves
carried so much equipment...
five days' K ration
and ammunition
and rifles and, ah...
And I carried a 13-pound camera
and 2,400 foot of film.
It got so rugged
that the mules
could not make it,
and finally what they had to do
was take the loads
and the saddles off the mules.
They would get a GI,
and a bunch of guys would lift
this 96-pound saddle
and put it on his back,
and then he would
have to climb the steps.
And then when we got
to a more level area,
we would load up
the mules again.
[Hanks]
Quaid tired of repeating
the same front and back angles.
He found a precarious perch in
a tree to get this side shot.
[Quaid]
The drop is 300 feet.
So I was young then,
and I jumped down
and I made the shot.
[Hanks] On the way to Myitkyina,
Merrill's Marauders
twice encountered Japanese patrols.
Here you can see an enemy bullet
cutting through the brush.
During the skirmish,
Quaid stepped into the open
to get this shot
of a fallen foe
and the American
who killed him.
Probably the dumbest shot
I've ever made in my life,
because the Japanese
were so stunned,
they didn't fire.
They didn't believe their eyes.
[Hanks] This wilderness trek
took six days.
[Quaid] The method of handling
malaria was very simple.
Simplest thing in the world.
It's called
"walking it out of you."
All our walking wounded from
the two battles we had fought
while coming over the mountains
were still with us.
[Hanks] The weary Marauders
still took the airfield by surprise,
but the Japanese continued
to hold the nearby town.
[Quaid] I became fascinated
with the 88th Fighter Squadron.
They had death's-heads
on their P-40F airplanes.
They were only about
a mile and a half
from the Japanese bunkers.
So they could make
one climbing turn
and come down
right on a bunker.
They were great for support
for the American and Chinese
surrounding Myitkyina.
I was always interested
in unique ways
of looking at things.
I thought it would be great
if I could put my movie camera
into the P-40
on a dive-bombing run.
I see them up there,
and I see them make their turn,
and down they go,
and I see him right on the back
of the captain going down.
And the captain pulls out
after he releases his bomb,
and this guy is still
following the bomb down.
And there's this
terrific blast,
and I see him trying
to fly through the blast.
He can't get any altitude,
but he comes in
and crash-lands
at the end of the strip.
[Hanks]
When the flight leader landed,
Quaid thought a strategic
retreat was in order.
He was, after all, responsible
for wrecking the plane.
And he says to me,
"Quaid, get out of here!"
He said, "Four more,
and you're a Japanese ace!"
[Laughing]
I think it's one of the
funniest lines in World War II.
He said, "Aw, Dave, don't
take it too much to heart.
We really want to get P-51s. "
[Hanks] June 1944.
The marines land
in the Marianas
within bomber range
of the Japanese home islands.
The late Richard Brooks
was in charge of collecting
the exposed footage.
[Brooks] When the landing boats
came in for a landing at the beach,
the cameramen came in first.
They came in first so they
could photograph the marines
coming in to make the invasion.
[Hanks]
Like John Huston,
Brooks would edit, write and narrate this
footage into a great war documentary.
Also, like Huston, he would become an
Oscar-winning Hollywood writer-director
after the war.
[Brooks Narrating] The Japs bring down
another one of our planes.
A sniper is burned out.
[Gunshot]
A Jap makes a run for it.
Lieutenant General Holland
Smith, U.S. Marine Corps,
commanding the assault forces.
[Hanks] He was known to his men
as "Howlin' Mad" Smith.
Brooks was working up the nerve
to ask him a question.
[Brooks] I made sure to get
some shots of General Smith
up against the skyline
and against the sea.
Walking back to his jeep,
I said, "May I ask you
a question, sir?"
He said, "Go ahead.
I was a corporal. "
And I said,
"Is there any way, General,
that our combat cameramen
can carry side arms?"
He said, "What do you mean?"
I said, "We don't have arms.
We just got the camera.
"And if somebody's
shooting at you,
it's easier if you can shoot back,
even if you don't hit them."
He said, "I don't care
if you got film in the camera.
"I want those cameras there, and
I want them there all the time.
"Because in front
of those cameras,
"whether they got film
in them or not,
"those are
the eyes of the world,
and there are no cowards
in front of a camera. "
[Hanks] John Ercole was again
one of the photographers.
[Ercole] The sniper,
wherever he was,
I'm in his sights.
And I got to move
back and forth in order...
He's trying
to hit me in the foot
and keeps hitting the ground.
I'm photographing this tank
where our marines are carrying
some badly wounded marines
on their shoulders and using
the tank as protection.
[Hanks] The tanks were
a key element in the victory.
This footage was shot in color.
But like these pictures
from inside a tank,
it was released
in black and white.
The last Japanese strongholds
were the hills,
honeycombed with caves
from which they had to be
painfully rooted out.
[Ercole]
The big thing on Saipan
was knocking these guys out
up on the rocks.
We had people speaking Japanese
trying to get them to give up,
and they were
just shooting back.
In the Marine Corps,
we took an oath
that you were willing to die
to save your buddy
and you're willing to get
shot up to save your buddies.
And the Japanese
took it a little further.
Their oath was to die
rather than give up.
They were told we had
to kill our own children
to get in the Marine Corps,
or consume our parents as food
and all kinds of stories that
these people had been told.
[Hanks] As always, only a handful
of Japanese soldiers surrendered.
Mostly it was civilians
who gave up.
But even some of them
were too terrified to do so.
[Ercole] There's a shot on Saipan
where I come across a woman.
There's a cut in the cliff,
and she's maybe
60 yards away from me.
She's got a child
standing here,
baby in her hand,
and she spots me.
She sees the camera,
which is on a gun stock.
She doesn't know it's a camera,
so as I raise it up,
she kicks this kid
off the cliff,
throws the baby off the cliff,
and she takes a dive.
Now, that's all on film.
It only may be... four seconds?
That's the fear that these
people were embedded with.
[Hanks] This shot
of the dead child,
one of the most pathetic images
of the war,
was not released at the time.
These paratroopers
would be the first
to breach Hitler's
Atlantic wall.
They would land in Normandy
in the predawn darkness
of June 6, 1944,
forerunners of history's
greatest amphibious landing.
The bombers were next.
Every D day plane carried
broad identifying stripes.
This defense
against friendly fire
used up all
the white paint in England.
Carl Voelker
remembers that morning.
[Voelker]
On D day, we flew twice.
We went out early in the morning.
It was too dark to do much.
I was photographing the bombs
going down on the beach.
They brought sandwiches
and coffee out to the runway.
We stayed with the plane.
It was rebombed, refueled,
and we went back out.
We went across the channel
and we saw the boats and ships
from Tortie,
which was southern England,
all the way across,
and it was quite a sight
to see so much equipment
being moved across the channel.
They were bumper-to-bumper.
[Hanks] The troops
passed the hours
in the usual pastimes
of anxious waiting.
But inescapably, they were
alone with their thoughts.
And with the equipment
on which,
luck aside, and who
dared think about that,
their lives would depend.
In that whole vast armada,
only one creature
didn't know what awaited him.
But even he was prepared
for the worst.
Still, the choppy channel
and the fear took their toll.
As the day brightened,
the gliders appeared,
carrying more troops
to assault the Germans
from behind their lines.
Then the bombers,
flying low, returned.
[Voelker] But the second time,
we went over low.
Maybe 5,000 feet.
It was exceptional for us.
We never bombed down that low.
[Hanks] Voelker's bomb spotting
was also exceptional,
steady and unerring.
[Voelker] In most of the
documentaries of World War II,
you'll see a chicken foot
impression on the screen.
That day I got static
electricity in the camera.
The sparks appear in the gate,
and it's on every foot of film
goes through the camera.
That was my D day.
[Hanks] "It was like a thousand
4th of Julys rolled into one, "
an eyewitness said.
But the naval bombardment
came too soon.
It was too dark for accuracy,
or for Walter Rosenblum's camera.
[Rosenblum] I couldn't go in
on the first wave 'cause it was dark.
There was no way
I could photograph.
Boats going in, and then
the landing craft came back
and loaded up another crew,
and I went into that crew.
It's like you see
in the movies.
You climb down a rope ladder,
and I went in on one
of these landing craft.
[Hanks] The men
in these later waves
would confront
D day's grimmest reality:
The sight
of their fallen comrades.
[Rosenblum]
And we landed on the beach,
and the thing
that struck me first is
I'd never seen
a dead person in my life.
I was surrounded by death.
There was Gls in the water,
rolling up and back in the water.
Blood all in the water, and it
was a very frightening sight.
[Hanks] The Signal Corps cameramen
lived with a bitter irony.
Almost the entire surviving photographic
record of D day on the American beaches
was shot
by coast guard cameramen.
The film exposed by Rosenblum
and the other men of the 165th
Photo Company on the beaches
would be lost.
By late morning, the beachhead
was established. By the end of the day,
the cameramen were ready to surrender
their hard-won footage.
[Wood] We turned our footage
in to the beachmasters,
and they sent a colonel over
who went to each beachmaster
and picked up the film,
put it all in a duffel bag,
put it on his shoulder
and went out to a ship.
Going up the side
of the ship, he dropped it,
and all the film was lost.
[Hanks] There was
just one exception.
A cameraman named Dick Taylor.
He made this great shot.
By default, these few seconds
constitute D day's
most famous footage.
[Wood] The only film you see,
American film from D day,
was our motion-picture guy that
was with 1st Infantry Division.
He got wounded, and he carried
his film back with him,
and he got about three or four
scenes before he got hit.
Much of Taylor's footage
is of combat's aftermath.
It is of men who have
spent themselves in war,
trying to regather
their strength.
They dig in.
They tend to their wounded.
Mostly they register
the shock of survival.
Their history
has shrunk for the moment
to this one terrible day.
They can see nothing
but the awful shore
they so recently crossed.
They are forced to contemplate
the deaths they
by some miracle avoided.
On D plus 1,
the supplies rolled in.
So did the foul weather.
Everywhere you looked
off Omaha Beach,
boats and their crews
were in peril on the seas.
Walter Rosenblum
was there shooting stills.
So was his motion-picture
partner, Val Pope.
[Rosenblum] There was
a couple of sinking boats
that I presumed
had been shelled,
and a young army lieutenant
swam out with a life raft
in order to bring back
the people off the boat.
When I started,
I said to myself,
"Walter, you're a good swimmer.
You have two alternatives.
"You can go out with him
and help him bring them back,
or you could photograph."
And at that moment
I realized that my job
was to take pictures,
and that's what I had to do.
[Hanks] These stills and the
perfectly matched movie footage
helped fill some of the gaps left by
the lost D day pictures.
Tragically, Val Pope
would be killed in action
a few days later.
[Rosenblum] The well-known
picture of that sequence
was this young lieutenant
who was bending over a GI,
giving him first aid.
He looked like
the most heroic fellow
I'd ever seen in my life.
I was happy to be able
to make that photograph,
because to me it epitomized
what the war was about.
People who came to fight
for what they believed in.
Three weeks after D day,
there were almost half a million
well-supplied American soldiers
in France.
Stephen Ambrose calls
this logistical miracle
the great achievement of
the American people and system
in the 20th century.
Who would dispute it?
Only, perhaps, the Gls
still struggling to break out
of their beachhead
against unforgiving terrain
and a stubborn enemy.
[Hanks] On the ghostly beaches,
the barrage balloons arose,
protecting the masses
of incoming supplies
against the almost
entirely absent Luftwaffe.
Everywhere,
casualties were counted.
They were heavy
among the airborne troops,
but the planners
were ready for death, too.
It was neatly registered.
The high command
and their tankers
were less well-prepared for
a unique and hazardous feature
of Normandy's topography.
[Wood]
All through Normandy there,
it was all through
hedgerow country.
They were about six foot high
and six foot thick
and got trees growing out of the tops,
and they're real fortresses.
We could be digging in
on one side of a hedgerow
and the Germans would be digging in
on the other side of it.
[Wood] There would be
little openings
with gates and stuff
through them,
and guys would have to attack through
those damn things or over the top of one.
[Hanks] The hedgerows,
first planted in the Middle Ages,
frustrated the war of movement,
but not for long.
[Wood]
An ordnance sergeant
figured out that he could weld
two big prongs
on the front of a tank,
and they'd dig
into the hedgerow,
and the tank would shove
its way through a hedgerow.
After we got that,
it made it a lot simpler.
Some 60 years ago,
an anonymous German bureaucrat
poked his finger on a map
and decreed that here,
in this French farmer's fields,
would be the site
of these big coastal batteries.
They're still there today,
silent yet ominous reminders
of the way in which war
intrudes itself
on ordinary human life.
And yet that life
has an amazing stubbornness.
The guns may thunder,
but the fields
must still be harvested.
The geese
have to cross the road,
even if it's choked
with military traffic.
The ordinary skein
of human life goes on,
and our cameramen
recorded that, too.
[Hanks] The young liberators
were bored, restless, coltish
when they were off duty.
These American airmen discovered
these horses in a Norman pasture.
One of them
was an Oklahoma cowboy,
who for a moment
gracefully recaptured
one of civilian life's
lost pleasures.
[Rosenblum]
It was not commonly known
that our preinvasion
bombardment
killed a lot of French people
who were living behind the line.
I was always amazed at the fact
that the French people I photographed
didn't blame the Americans
for what was taking place.
They regarded us as liberators,
even though our bombs
killed some of the people
who lived there.
[Hanks] There was a sweetness
in these welcomes, and a certain haste.
After the Normandy breakout,
if finally became
a war of movement.
And for this Free French
tank battalion,
it was a very personal war,
as Russ Meyer learned
when he joined them.
Right off the bat,
took our jeep with the tank.
The French tank.
We'd go right between them.
[Hanks] His best
wartime buddy, Bill Teas,
was already
with the French unit.
He would lend his name
to the title
of Meyer's first
postwar erotic hit,
The lmmoral Mr. Teas.
Needless to say, the French tankers
were welcomed with special warmth
as they rolled through
their native land.
The Americans
were included in that welcome.
[Meyer] They would all say,
"Oh, Américain. Très bien."
[Hanks] There was danger
on these roads, too.
[Meyer] You go down the street,
and the guy says, "Stop now!
"Don't go. There's a bunch
of Germans down that road.
Now get the hell out of there."
[Hanks] Forewarned, they engaged
in a brief, violent firefight.
This time, they took prisoners.
I'd love to know the guy today.
If we hadn't been warned,
we would have had our...
They would have gotten
our tonsils.
[Hanks] But they
weren't always so lucky.
In a later engagement,
they took heavy losses.
As was so often the case
in tank battles,
the wounds were ghastly.
And hard to accept.
As some of the tankers
struggled to free
a trapped comrade,
others rethought the battle
and refought it.
There was a desire
to protect the home front
from war's harshest realities.
If these had been Americans,
these pictures
might not have been taken.
[Meyer]
You didn't want to get Gls.
You didn't want a GI dying.
If it was, I'd get something
where at least the American
wouldn't be readily recognized.
I was concerned
about their family
that would see somebody
in the newsreels.
[Hanks]
But Paris was nearly at hand,
less than three months
after D day.
As the liberators approached,
the Communist-led underground
rose against the Germans.
In the streets,
the German tanks were opposed
by members of the resistance
carrying only small arms.
Amazingly, they forced
an uneasy truce.
It is possible they prevented
the destruction of the city
that Hitler had ordered.
[Hanks] The honor
of entering Paris first
was given
to Free French forces.
But as their leaders
boldly showed themselves,
gunfire erupted.
There was de Gaulle
and I forget which
other officers were there.
LeClerc had to be there.
[Hanks] The city had not been
cleared of German troops
and their French sympathizers.
[Weiner] They all came marching
down the Champs Elysées
as part of this parade,
and there were snipers,
and there were shots fired.
And, of course,
everybody ducked.
[Hanks] The street fighting was
actually intense and deadly.
In many places, people
were pinned to the ground,
unable to move.
The terror was palpable.
Reprisals against
French collaborators
were swift and harsh.
That was not the end
of French vengeance.
[Weiner] We were advised of activity
regarding collaborationists,
and what they were doing
is taking,
in this case,
women collaborationists
and shaving their heads.
These are, I guess, women
who had socially gone out
or played around with some
of the German soldiers.
The idea, as I understood it,
was that for weeks
and months afterwards,
everybody would know
who the collaborationists were.
[Weiner] For the most part,
they said nothing.
Some smiled and some
just stared straight ahead...
and I guess tried
to make the best
of what they were faced with.
[Hanks] The Allies had
first intended to bypass Paris,
but it was unavoidably
in their path.
Most of these soldiers
did not stop.
For them, Paris was just
a quickly glimpsed place
on the road to victory.
In a smaller French city,
Fred Bornet
found the joy of liberation
more freely expressed
and more directable.
[Bornet] The people
were out in the street,
and they were
just absolutely ecstatic.
Hysterical with delight.
And they hung bunting,
and they'd lift
glasses of wine.
And what is so great is that
you don't have a script.
You seize
those wonderful moments.
And there were lots of girls,
flowers in their hair.
They were sort of
waving and greeting.
But they were not doing it...
with enough enthusiasm.
I thought this is
such a great moment.
It should be like
the big parade.
So I said to the girl, "Look.
"When that stream of soldiers
is walking by,
run against that stream
and kiss them!"
And I cried.
There was a release.
And then they offered me soup
and fried eggs,
and they were waving flags.
You have a feeling that
you're doing something
that is worthwhile.
In the fall of 1944,
American eyes
were fixed on Europe,
where headquarters spoke,
overconfidently,
as it turned out,
of the war's end
being in sight, almost within reach.
No such claims were made
for the war in the Pacific.
Combat there was as brutal
and furious as ever.
But many of its fighting men
felt isolated and ignored.
Navy cameraman Sam Sorenson.
[Sorenson] The marines
that I worked with
were happy to have
some pictures taken of them.
In the Pacific,
they were so lonely.
They never saw a woman.
One of the reasons
that I was happy
to work with the marines
was because we got better
pictures of combat action.
[Hanks]
Peleliu, September 1944.
The fury of the naval and air
bombardment was unprecedented.
[Sorenson] For three days
we shelled that thing.
When we approached
those islands,
it looked like little, nice,
green rolling hills.
When we got through,
it looked like little, rugged,
jagged mountains.
There were little
coral mountains
sticking up all over.
I couldn't believe
anything could live on there.
[Hanks] But the bombing
was ineffective.
The enemy remained safe
in their bunkers.
[Sorenson]
So when the marines started in,
there was an outer reef.
And they got hung up
on that reef.
They were caught
in Japanese crossfire.
So a lot of them
had to unload there
and go on in
with amphibious tractors.
Then when they hit the beach,
they got raked from
this "point," they call it.
[Hanks] The irony of Peleliu
is that it was unnecessary.
General MacArthur
thought he needed it
to shield his invasion
of the Philippines.
Military historians
now agree that he did not.
The marines
took almost 50% casualties.
[Sorenson]
They holed up in caves.
They never made banzai charges.
And they had
what they call "spider holes,"
where one sniper would stand.
They finally
would close them up.
They'd blow them up
and close the entrance.
Then the Japanese would
come out of another hole.
[Gunshot]
It took two months
to get them out.
They took maybe a hundred prisoners
out of this whole thing.
In the end, we had lost
something like 1,900 marines,
and we had to kill
nearly 13,000 Japanese.
[Hanks] Meantime, the war in
the China-Burma-India theater continued,
and Dave Quaid soldiered on.
It was a Thanksgiving air drop,
and President Roosevelt said,
"No matter where
your son or daughter is,
"on land or sea or in the air,
he's going to get
a turkey dinner. "
And I said, "That's hogwash!"
I said, "I'm going
to photograph this drop
and prove that it
never happened. "
[Hanks] Aerial resupply
had been taken over
by a new unit
fresh from Europe.
Their adjustment
to the C.B.I. Was poor.
Coming in too fast and low,
their drops
were often inaccurate
and often destroyed
their cargo.
[Quaid] The plane was directly
over the trail we were on.
So I yelled to these guys
to get off the trail.
In fact, the skinny, emaciated guy there
with the camera is me.
[Hanks] They scored a direct,
if accidental hit, on Quaid.
[Quaid] The medics immediately assisted
me, as did my buddy Bill.
[Hanks]
His ordeal wasn't over.
He is still moved
by Bill Brown's willingness
to risk his life for him.
[Quaid] Here was this chute
coming down right on my face,
and I said, "Bill! Bill!
Look at that!"
And Bill got up,
stepped across me,
said, "I'll get it."
So, there was a puff of wind,
and it blew just past my head,
and Bill didn't have to
sacrifice himself.
[Hanks]
Dave Quaid's war was finished.
He would spend the rest of it
in hospitals
having multiple operations
on his shattered leg.
[Quaid]
Here I am, leaving the war,
taken out
by a bag of mule feed.
[Hanks]
In northern France,
the fighting slowed
as the snows came.
The bad weather helped mask
a huge German buildup,
twenty-four divisions
near the Ardennes Forest.
[Meyer] The Ardennes
were cruel in the sense
that it was critically cold
and it was very difficult
to find somewhere
that you could hide from.
The Ardennes
did not have big trees.
You had to be very careful
and get down
at the base of a tree trunk...
and dig as deeply as you could
to protect yourself
from the standpoint of getting injured.
Or... finished.
[Hanks] In December,
the Americans manning this line
were often isolated
in small units.
Communications between them
were poor.
[Explosion]
They were not expecting the battle that
began on December 16th.
Many of the Gls
fought tenaciously,
though they were often completely
surrounded by the enemy.
The "Bulge," Hitler's last
great gamble of the war,
eventually extended
50 miles eastward,
but it did not burst.
It's hard to see from these pictures,
but this engagement eventually
involved more soldiers...
600,000 of them...
than any battle
in U.S. History.
20,000 Americans
died in the Ardennes.
Another 20,000 were wounded.
Among them was a cameraman
named Jim Bates,
who had been in the war
since D day.
At the Bulge, he did
what a lot of Gls did.
He hitched a ride on a tank.
Their motors provided warmth.
[Bates] I rattled this tank and asked
if I could ride on the back.
A lid flew open, and he says,
"Can you fire a machine gun?"
I said I had my basics
with the 11th Armored Division.
They picked me up
bodily practically
and put me
in the bow gunner's position.
[Hanks]
Bates didn't know it,
but he was heading into battle
with German Tiger tanks.
He grabbed these unique shots
of a German ambulance
aiding one of
their wounded tank crews.
[Bates] I could see
that the number one tank
had passed an open area
and was firing uphill.
About that time,
I could hear this "kah-thunk,"
and the commander says,
"Get out. They're shooting at us."
About that time,
that second "whoom" came along,
and it felt like a train
hit me in the back.
I didn't know
whether I was dead or alive.
I could hear him screaming,
"If you're not hit, get up.
If he starts that tank again,
he's going to run over you. "
I looked back, and my camera was
laying under the tank treads.
That's what made me move,
and on the radio they said,
"You get up here quick
with the medic's jeep.
"A photographer's been hit,
and there's not enough of them left
to photograph
the rest of the war. "
"I'll ride on the hood," I said.
"I could lay down. It'll be
a warm place to be for a bit. "
[Hanks] Ignoring his wounds,
Bates kept on shooting
as the tank rumbled
toward the rear.
[Bates] Arosi saw me,
the fellow I'd normally work with.
He was my buddy and
shooting partner, and he said,
"The hospital's next door.
I'll take you. "
I said, "Not yet.
Get on your typewriter.
I'm going to dictate to you
what, where, why and when."
He says, "You won't quit, will
you?" and I said, "No way."
[Hanks] The situation
remained fluid for days,
especially for Doug Wood.
Ailing with flu,
he took refuge in the basement
of a command post.
He sent his driver
and stills man for more film,
then fell asleep.
He did not hear the order to evacuate
the C.P. When it came under fire.
[Wood] My still guy at that time
was a new guy, a replacement.
And he told the driver,
whose name was Ivan Babcock,
"Babcock, there's some guys
over there in funny hats,
and I think
they're shooting at us. "
And the driver told me,
"I could see their tracers
going past my nose."
But he wouldn't stop.
Like the other guys
had stopped there,
and they'd captured them.
He just drove on through and
let them keep shooting at him.
[Hanks]
What Babcock drove through
was the Malmedy massacre.
It was the war's worst atrocity
visited on American soldiers.
Somewhere between
71 and 129 Gls...
the number remains in dispute...
were rounded up
and shot by S.S. Troops.
They had infiltrated our lines,
some of them wearing
American uniforms.
In this last-gasp
German effort,
many of their troops
were teenagers.
The Germans all escaped
serious punishment for Malmedy
at the war crimes trials.
The weather lifted
in late December,
and air operations resumed.
[Man] I was fortunate enough,
or unfortunate,
whichever way you want to look at it,
to lead the greatest air
combat battle of World War II.
There was eight of us.
We had climbed up
over the field,
and we were what
they called "joining up"
when 900 German fighters
made an attack
on the front
on January 1, 1945.
The squadron leader...
a squadron would normally
be 12 airplanes,
but we had eight...
he couldn't see them.
He said,
"You take over the flight."
And I dropped five of them
right on the field.
[Hanks] The pilots,
armed with their gun cameras,
were also combat cameramen.
[Paisley]
Hitler had decided
that he would deploy
all of the fighters he had
to knock out the fighter fields
to support
the Battle of the Bulge,
and they were going to do it
in early December,
which would have been
very effective.
Weather wasn't good.
They put it off
and put it off and said,
"January 1st, these guys
will all be in bed. "
It was all over the front.
It wasn't just at our field.
It was at the British field.
It was at all
the northern airfields.
I later got a hold of
Hermann Goering's interviews.
In those interviews,
Goering said
the largest loss that
the German Luftwaffe ever had
was the loss on January 1st.
[Hanks] Mel Paisley, who was also
this film's chief researcher,
was decorated with the
Distinguished Service Cross.
Over the course of the war,
he shot down nine planes.
The Battle of the Bulge
ended January 7, 1945.
Germany was now largely open
to the Allies.
Italy 1945.
Dictator Benito Mussolini
was deposed and exiled.
The government surrendered,
and the populace turned viciously
on their former allies.
[Montagne] I went to the C.P.
To find out what was happening
and was told
they had captured Mussolini
and General Crittenberger
was to take his surrender.
I went down to the C.P. About
5:00 the following morning,
and here's a limousine with
three German officers in it.
They'd been picked up
by the 1st Armored Division.
They'd run into a roadblock
and captured.
I went to Crit and said,
"What are you going to do?"
He said, "I'm going to get
this bird's surrender."
I said, "What about Mussolini?"
He said, "Mussolini will have to wait."
I'll never forget that line.
He said to him, "General,
we're both professionals.
"You can't get out.
The passes are all closed.
"The smart thing to do
is surrender the Ligurian Army,
which is the last
intact enemy army. "
Went back to see Crit,
and he was sitting on a rail
and sort of dreaming,
and he said,
"Montagne, do you know
that every cadet at West Point
"dreams of the day when an enemy army
surrenders to him?
Today it happened to me."
[Hanks] Crittenberger's
decision doomed Mussolini,
his mistress, Clara Petacci,
and other fascists
to death at the hands
of partisan guerillas.
Their bodies
were displayed in Milan.
[Montagne] It had been going on for
quite some time when we got there.
And we photographed what
we could. We got the crowds.
We got Mussolini
hanging upside down,
Petacci alongside him.
I remember her skirt
had fallen over her face,
and a woman came
and pinned her skirt
between her legs
so she wasn't exposed.
They cut him down...
I remember he got his head hit...
and picked him up.
The partisans were running it.
We had nothing to do with it.
They took them over
to the morgue.
There were bodies
all over the place.
You had to walk on two or three bodies
to get to where Mussolini was.
And I asked
the morgue attendant,
"Can you get him in the light?"
He said, "Lieutenant, if I move him,
his head will fall apart. "
So he got Petacci,
pulled her over
and put her head
on his shoulder.
Became quite a famous shot.
[Hanks] Meantime, Nazi Germany
was in its death throes,
but it desperately fought on.
Everything that could happen to me,
photographically speaking,
did happen that day.
[Hanks] The place was Cologne.
The date was March 6, 1945.
The street fighting
was intense.
It was often impossible to tell
soldiers from civilians.
Sometimes the victims
caught in the crossfire
were entirely innocent.
[Bates] By this time
we had a new T-26.
The T-26 was so far ahead
of the old Shermans,
it was unbelievable.
This German tank was sitting in front
of the Cologne Cathedral.
It had knocked out a number
of our tanks and causing havoc.
They had control
over that whole area.
[Hanks] Bates followed the tank into battle,
and, scrambling for position,
got this great footage
of armored combat.
[Bates] I heard
our T-26 coming up.
The first shot went in
and cut the legs off of the
tank commander in the Tiger.
In the film you can see
the armor-piercing shell
going through
the bottom of the picture.
Immediately, the driver and
bow gunner, they climbed out,
but the second shot shrapnel
had gotten them, too.
The concussion
from that 90-millimeter gun
is so tremendous that it would
just blow me off my picture,
and I'd have to
get back on it again.
I couldn't use a tripod.
I had to hand hold it.
The tank commander
that had his legs cut off
just laid on top of his tank and
burned up in front of the camera.
That thing was burning
even the next morning.
After it was all over,
there was still smoke coming out of it
because it had so much
ammunition and whatnot in it.
[Hanks] Two months and one day later,
the war in Europe was over.
Its dead, its "crusaders,"
as General Eisenhower
called them,
rest in cemeteries
all over Europe.
If anything, their deeds
are more revered now
than they were at the time.
Some of their immortality
derives from
the photographic record.
The combat cameramen
recorded the last days,
hours, moments,
even the last breath
of many of those who lie here.
It isn't something
that they talk about very much.
It was, as they say,
just a part of their job.
[Ambrose] But it was a more
important job than they knew.
For the film they made is now
beginning to outlive memory.
Eventually it will be the only
recollection made on the spot
of how our citizen soldiers
lived, fought and died.
[Hanks] The cameramen in Europe
had one more duty to history.
It was unquestionably
their most important one.
That was recording
the horrors of the death camps.
At Dachau, Walter Rosenblum
was too shocked to shoot.
These pictures
were made by others.
[Rosenblum]
There was a group of boxcars.
I climbed up the boxcar
to see what was inside.
And the boxcar
was full of dead people,
and there were about
30, 40 boxcars along that road.
When I looked in,
I was so shocked.
Could you imagine, not having
seen anything like that before,
to see a boxcar
full of dead, emaciated people?
At that particular moment,
I forgot I was a photographer.
I was just overcome by it all.
[Man] I was on assignment
with Ellis Carter,
and we went into Germany
to cover bomb damage
that was done
by the Allied air power.
On April 11th, the 3rd
U.S. Army liberated Buchenwald,
and when we heard of this, we
immediately drove over there.
[Hanks] What the cameramen
found behind these gates
was beyond their imagining,
but the inhumanity
they recorded
is literally undeniable.
As a soldier in the American Army,
I had no knowledge of these camps
and had not heard anything about it.
[Mainzer]
It was horrible.
There was bodies
stacked up like cordwood.
We judged them to be about
60 to 80 pounds in weight,
and people were actually dying,
day by day,
even after the camp
was liberated.
Many of the prisoners could not
speak English, of course,
but they raised
their hands to us
and showed their gratitude
for us freeing them.
This camp had about
20,000 survivors
at the time of liberation,
and about 8,000 of them
were children.
There was a section where
they displayed tattooed skins
which were made into lampshades
and book covers.
The German commandant's wife
would select tattooed men
to be doomed to die
and then use their skin.
After a few days, the German
civilians of the town
right next to Buchenwald
called Weimar
were paraded through
on a tour of the camp
to show the atrocities
and to show them
what the Germans had done.
Many of them wouldn't even look
at the torture or the bodies.
Some of them were crying.
Some of them had their mouth
and nose covered
with their handkerchiefs,
especially women.
So, in the filming that we did,
you could see this evident, uh,
where they just
kept going through
because they had to.
They weren't too interested
in looking at the...
at the atrocities.
There was a lot of people
that didn't believe in this.
They didn't believe
that it happened.
But here we had it on film.
I think in all the time
that I was over there,
this experience stood out
pretty much in my mind.
It took a while to get over it.
It was something
that you wouldn't want to see,
you wouldn't want
to go through again.
[Hanks] The horrors
of the concentration camp
had a more immediate effect
on Art Mainzer.
After what he had seen,
he yearned for normalcy.
[Mainzer]
I met her in Paris
the day before the
Battle of the Bulge started.
Believe it or not, we were
walking down the boulevard
and it started snowing,
and my buddy and I
saw these two lovely looking
ladies under an umbrella.
So we sneaked in
under the umbrella with them
and introduced ourselves.
I made the decision
after I covered
the Buchenwald assignment.
I said, "If I ever
get back to France alive,
I'm going to ask Germaine
to marry me. "
Being a camera unit, we had
three 16-millimeter cameras
and a couple of Speed Graphics
for the still photos.
We had gotten
some cases of champagne
that the Germans
had looted from the French.
So we got it back to France.
And a lot
of French people showed up
because in this suburb of Paris
they had not had a formal wedding
like this during the occupation.
It was quite an event for them.
[Hanks] It was a June wedding,
the month after V.E. Day.
These pictures were his unit's
gift to the bride and groom.
The Mainzers would live their lives
together in the United States
until Germaine
passed away in 1998
after almost
53 years of marriage.
Iwo Jima, February 1945.
As the Americans came closer
to the Japanese mainland,
fighting in the Pacific
grew still more bitter.
The bombardment crumbled
one side of Iwo's key bastion,
Mount Suribachi.
But it took five bloody days
for the marines
to fight their way
to its summit.
When the marines set out
to place a conqueror's flag
on Suribachi,
they still encountered
resistance.
But they persevered,
and the flag was raised.
Unfortunately, it lacked
properly heroic proportions.
Something would
have to be done.
[Hatch] It was too small
to be seen by anybody.
So the commanding general down there
figured we better get a bigger flag.
So they got some of the LSTs
that were there,
and one of the LST commanders said,
"When we stopped at Pearl,
we got a big flag,
but we've never flown it. "
My boss came to me and said,
"Make sure we send photographers up.
This is going to be considered
the official flag raising. "
I said sure and got in touch
with Genaust and Bob Campbell.
Bill Genaust was the movie man,
Bob Campbell the still.
They hooked up with Rosenthal
going up the hill.
[Hanks] That was Joe Rosenthal
of the Associated Press,
a civilian photographer who had taken
these pictures of the landing.
These are the shots Genaust
took on that second climb.
A few days later,
he would be killed in action.
He would not live to see
the images he made.
[Hatch]
People would always contest
whether or not
this was the first
or whether the other one
was the first,
but Bob Campbell
didn't like the position
that the other
two cameramen were in,
so he got over to the side, and
he's got a beautiful picture
of the first flag coming down and
the second going up at the same time.
[Hanks]
It was Rosenthal, however,
who got the immortal shot
and a lifetime's controversy,
for he shipped
all his pictures back
unseen and undeveloped.
[Hatch] Joe gets on a boat about
four days later and goes to Guam,
and he's bombarded
by press guys there saying,
"What was this picture?"
They had seen it, but they wanted
to know what he thought about it.
He says, "I don't know.
Maybe it's that picture I posed
with the men under the flagpole
in the typical 'banzai, '
raising their rifles. "
And that word "posed" got into
the lexicon of the problem.
It's hung in there for years
and years and years.
That thing we have fought
for 50 years
to try to straighten out.
I thought at the end of the 50th
anniversary we had it resolved,
but I think it'll probably
go on for another 50.
[Hanks] The comparison
between the movie footage
and Rosenthal's image is definitive.
He took exactly
the same shot Genaust did
from virtually
the same position.
This controversy,
to some degree,
masks the real story
of Iwo Jima: Its cost.
Almost 7,000 marines died here,
along with 21,000 Japanese.
The marines were awarded
27 Medals of Honor,
more than in
any other engagement.
Manila, spring of 1945.
It was now, unquestionably,
"war without mercy,"
as one historian called it.
The fires the Japanese set
destroyed 70% of the city.
They killed 100,000 civilians
in an orgy of destruction.
This act of vengeance
on an innocent population
was recorded by Don Honeyman.
[Honeyman] The next day,
the infantry was moving into the city,
and we got some
very good street fighting.
[Gunfire]
[Hanks]
Honeyman then joined forces
surrounding the presidential
palace outside the city.
[Honeyman] We were leaving the palace
aside and going to the gardens,
which included
the other side of the river.
We had the north bank of the river,
and they had the south bank.
So we made a crossing
of the river in assault boats.
I watched one wave
of boats go over,
and they didn't seem
to have trouble.
So I figured it was safe
to go on the second one.
We got out in the middle,
and the Japanese
began to shoot at us
from the side of the river
which we thought was ours,
which we thought was hardly fair.
[Hanks] The Americans brought up
armored amphibious vehicles
to bring their troops safely to shore.
[Honeyman]
We came across a BAR man
who happened to be
down on his elbows
next to a sign saying,
"Please do not pick the flowers."
[Hanks] In the city,
fighting remained intense.
A Japanese strongpoint
was the legislative palace.
[Honeyman] Eight-inch howitzers
lined up side by side,
practically firing point-blank.
Simply taking down the building
stone by stone, practically.
[Hanks] Despite the incredible
firepower leveled at them,
the Japanese hung on
in the ruined palace.
Infantry would have
to root them out.
[Honeyman]
Next day I went to cover
the transfer
of civil government
from MacArthur
to the Filipinos.
And he said very proudly
how Manila was now secure.
And I said, "All except
the legislative building."
[Hanks]
Okinawa, Easter Sunday.
The idea was to stage
the invasion of Japan
from this large island.
Rather innocently, Lloyd Durant
decided to shoot a film
on combat cameramen here.
What better subject to put on film
than the story
of the combat cameraman,
who was practically unknown
at the time.
We knew that our next operation
was coming off in the Pacific.
So I said,
"Let me go out there,
"let me find the cameramen
we have out there,
"and presumably they will be in on
the action, whatever it may be,
"and I want to be there
photographing them
photographing the action. "
So we hit the beach at Okinawa.
There I was,
working with these guys,
creeping in foxholes,
squirming along the beach
and trying to keep the sand
out of the camera
and out of my mouth,
and they're trying
to do the same thing.
Also, there were
a few bullets flying around.
[Hanks] The battle would
continue for three months.
Among the casualties,
the worst of the war,
was a cameraman.
[Honeyman]
He was a navy cameraman.
Somehow or another,
he was hit and blinded.
They had bandaged, in the field,
his eyes, and some of it
was still hanging down.
He, of course, could not see.
They brought him up on the side of
the ship, and he got to the top,
and he's reaching for help.
He can't see a thing.
And his buddies reached up
and took him down.
And our commentary is,
"For this cameraman,
the picture was over. "
And that's exactly what it was.
He never saw again.
Later that day,
the kamikazes came in.
These were guys
who were dedicated to giving
their lives for their country.
And they crashed into us.
Our antiaircraft guns
were working at them full-time.
And our other problem was
our own flak coming down
did as much damage
to many of us
as did the kamikazes,
because it'd go
right through your helmet,
of course, if it
hit you directly.
[Hanks]
Bull Halsey said,
"The kamikazes were the only
weapon I feared in the war. "
There were over 1,300
of these suicide attacks.
They sank 26 ships
and damaged 300.
The photographic record
of these attacks
includes some of the most
astonishing footage of the war.
There were many near misses,
as this one turned out to be,
but most of the navy casualties
at Okinawa
are attributed to kamikazes.
They damaged some carriers
but sunk none.
Yet they persisted.
The last kamikaze attack
was mounted
after the surrender.
These B-24s are over
Balikpapan in Borneo.
Known as
the Ploesti of the Pacific,
the huge oil refinery was
bombed for 30 consecutive days
in the summer of 1945.
They were softening it up
for what would be
the last amphibious landing
of World War II.
The American Coast Guard
took Australian troops ashore.
Jerry Anker was there
with his buddy Jim Lonergan,
also a cameraman.
He wanted a picture
of himself in action.
Anker obliged with a snap
that became famous
in the photo histories.
When the landing craft
hit the beach
at Balikpapan, I said,
"Oh, my God, that idiot!"
And pulled up my four-by-five
and shot the picture of him,
and I only took
one picture of it,
and it turned out
to be a prizewinner.
Here, in the war's waning days,
Anker was presented
with another more terrible
photo opportunity.
[Anker]
I had been following
this Australian infantryman
with a flamethrower
around, I guess,
for probably a half hour,
and it just so happened
that when he shot
this flamethrower
into this cave,
this Japanese soldier
came running out in flames,
and I was able to photograph
the entire sequence.
To this day,
I can still smell the stench
of that burning body.
That one anonymous soldier,
dying in agony,
vividly symbolizes
the waste of war.
Multiply his fate 100,000 times
and you begin to comprehend
Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
But not entirely,
for as many people died later
of radiation poisoning
as died in the initial blasts.
We are told these lives
were traded for the many more
that would have been lost
on both sides
in an invasion of Japan.
But all we know for sure is
that the atomic bombs brought
the war to an abrupt end
and finally stopped
all the killing
at over 40 million.
[Hanks] At Nagasaki,
as at the concentration camps,
the combat photographers
had one last service to render.
Dan McGovern
speaks for all those
who entered this charnel house.
My effort was...
to show the world
what the atomic bomb
had done to a nation.
What it had done
to human beings.
The Sorayama School
in Nagasaki...
Sucked out hundreds of kids
through the windows.
I remember one particular scene
that I shot,
and I couldn't figure out
what was wrong
with this particular person.
He reminded me of a monk,
orjust a priest
with his staff,
and he was standing
up on a rise
looking over the hill of Nagasaki
from the Urakami Valley.
He was a radiologist from
the Nagasaki teaching hospital,
which was just
down below the hill.
He told me then
that he had lost his wife,
that he was suffering
from radiation sickness.
Two days later, he was gone.
[Hanks] Where people were sitting
when the bomb exploded,
permanent shadows were burned.
It was the same way
with things.
You can paint over the shadows,
but you cannot erase them.
[McGovern]
That was my effort.
Thought because
we showed the...
burned bodies of children,
people would cry out,
"Let's not do this again."
[Hanks]
Yet we do.
These pictures have been
duplicated in every war
for over a half century.
The children reach out to us
in their abandonment,
their incomprehensible
loneliness.
The soldiers
offer what comfort they can.
These men and these children
share the terrible bond of war.
But the soldiers
will soon move on.
They will not know the fates
of these orphans
with whom they shared
their humanity for a moment.
These picture ought to assure
centuries of peace.
They do not.
But it may be that
after the shooting stops,
the combat cameramen
achieve their finest hour.