Subtitles brought to you by The GoF Team @ Viki
This program was funded by the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism and the Korea Creative Contents Agency
Episode 22
I will forfeit this competition.
But in return, release Gae Dong.
Are you bring serious?
Because of Gae Dong, you're going to give up the chance to become a ceramist?
He is a friend who helped me in troubled times.
I can't just ignore it.
Didn't you say you wanted to become a ceramist?
So why do you give up so easily?
I will if I can save Gae Dong.
Your will was only this much?
I'm disappointed in you.
Take it.
Excuse me?
Do you think it was easy for me to rise
to the seat of Royal Ceramist?
I also went through a hard situation.
I will prove that all my efforts during all
this time wasn't for nothing.
Hurry, take it and go.
I'll release Gae Dong, but
you will be punished for taking the porcelains lightly.
Thank you.
Leave.
It's the same. It's exactly like the one that broke.
It's just the right size, too.
You said it would be difficult,
but I guess you were just being fussy.
I'm honored, Your Majesty.
Why is this on the lid?
Because of this extra piece,
it doesn't go in well.
Please put in the protruding area first.
It's there to prevent the lid from
falling off and breaking.
It's amazing.
How did you think of this?
You also thought of a unique idea
for In Bin's flower vase.
You don't disappoint me.
Isn't it so, In Bin?
Yes, Your Majesty.
However,
I open and close this jar very frequently.
I can't help but liking the one I'm used to.
The details and the drawings are also
better with Royal Ceramist Lee's.
Thank you, Royal Ceramist.
What do you mean?
Thanks to you, I learned something.
What did you learn?
I saw with my own eyes that
royal porcelains must have dignity and
elegance that befit the royal porcelains.
From what I saw, too,
your lid suited the jar better than my lid.
Your royal face looks bright,
which I haven't seen in a while.
The writings, drawings and porcelains are
what soothe my troubles, aren't they?
Your Highness's happy face,
I wish the ministers could see it.
That's what I'm saying.
They always tell me, "No, you can't!",
"Keep your dignity!"
But what's such a big deal about me
meeting a ceramist personally?
Can I, who's also buried in work,
not enjoy even this much?
You're so right, Your Majesty.
So,
did I tell you to focus on basics or not?
You were being so greedy.
I'm saying I would've lost even if I did.
I also acknowledge the Royal Ceramist's skill.
I thought you would shrink up and starve yourself for
at least three days, but why are you so alright?
There's no time for that.
I have to practice the wheel spinning,
and work on drawings.
I'm already busy with those thoughts.
Alright, let's do it. Sit down.
OK.
Relax.
Imagine you don't have these.
Just those...
While I was in 3 year mourning for my mother's death,
Prince Gwang Hae sent those letters to me.
Wow...
You are very close to him.
All those writings worry about the nation,
coming from the loyal heart.
You all know Prince Gwang Hae's character.
I, too, don't disagree with the fact that
Prince Gwang Hae is the one fit for the crown prince,
but I believe the timing is what matters.
We must step up so that His Majesty
can decide His Royal heart.
I believe that's our duty as his subjects.
However, His Majesty's anger hasn't subsided yet...
Let's push for it once more.
I will speak up this time.
No.
This time, I will do it.
How tired are you with all the work?
This is my treat for all of you,
so please enjoy yourselves.
Thank you, Your Highness.
We only have one goal.
To do our best serving His Majesty.
So that they won't mention the crown prince
anymore while His Majesty's still well and healthy,
let's do our best to lead our government.
Yes, you're so right.
We get drunk when we drink,
and the water flows from top to bottom.
And His Majesty's throne is succeeded by the eldest son.
That is the natural order of things, right?
Pushing forward the discussion of installing
the crown prince even though His Majesty hates it,
is treason. Treason.
Great Scholar and his followers' moves are suspicious,
so you must stay alert.
The communication envoys have returned, Your Majesty.
According to Official Kim Seong Il,
there's no danger of them attacking us.
They wrote that
Toyotomi Hideyoshi is not one to be afraid of.
Official Hwang Yoon Gil thinks differently.
He recommended that, since a
Japanese attack is imminent, be ready for it.
Hideyoshi is known to be clever and bold.
Hwang Yoon Gil is a timid person.
When he went to Japan this time, too,
he was scared and subservient,
which undermined Joseon's dignity.
That's why we sent Kim Seong Il along with him.
It's hard to find a scholar who's
as upright and high-spirited as Kim Seong Il.
Hwang Yoon Gil saw it right this time.
Japan will invade us!
Hwang Yeong Gil's claim doesn't even make sense!
How can those who were living stuck on an island
attack a big country across the sea?
Hideyoshi's response clearly states that
he would conquest Ming through Joseon.
This means he clearly stated he will attack Joseon,
proclaiming a war against us.
Why do you mention the danger of war
whenever you open your mouth?
At a time when we need to soothe
the people's hearts,
get ready for war?
It's something that shouldn't happen!
You are blindly insisting Kim Seong Il is right
only because he's a part of your faction.
If the war breaks and this country is in chaos,
are the East People going to take responsibility?
How could you say such ridiculous
things in front of His Majesty!
Rather, you're trying to defend Hwang Yeong Gil
because he's in your faction.
Enough, enough!
The war doesn't happen so easily.
Our Joseon, since its foundation,
has been doing well without a war.
I will ask this to Great Scholar.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I heard the Confusion classics that were managed
by your office were damaged. Is that true?
I'm deeply sorry, Your Majesty.
Before worrying about a war,
you should've done your job first!
To punish you for neglecting the management
of the Confusion classics,
I will dismiss you from the position of
Great Scholar of your office!
Your Majesty!
The books getting damaged has always
happened over the long hot and humid weather.
What do you mean, to dismiss him over this?
No.
Dismissal is not enough.
I will exile him to Gyeong Heung!
Drag him out immediately!
Your Majesty!
His Majesty said
this is no use and to leave now, Your Highness.
He exiled Great Scholar to Gyeong Heung?
His Majesty must have been decisive.
Not only him,
but his supporters are to be
exiled as well, I heard.
You have to whip the horse when it's running.
This is only the beginning.
All of this is happening according to your plan.
Do you think my target was him?
My target has been Gwang Hae.
I made my decision you already.
Why do you still want to see me?
Your Majesty, cancel the exile, please.
He's a loyal subjects who only
serves Your Majesty, sir.
Withdraw the order of exile? Then, I'll have
to order him to die by poison.
Once they're dead, then you
won't bother me anymore.
Honored Father.
You still don't understand what I'm saying?
What should I do to make you no longer angry?
Angry?
You think I'm a clumsy king ruling this
country, based on my emotions?
I gave my trust to Great Scholar
as he's deeply academic,
but even threatened my sovereignty,
not knowing his place.
Threatened? That's absurd!
Did you goad him?
No!
What did you promise him?
It's all because of you.
Because of you, I lost my respected teacher.
Because of you, he's being exiled.
Didn't I tell you not to do anything?
Look at me.
Whether Honored Father is
picking on you or advising you,
he's doing nothing, isn't he?
When it's raining hard,
the best way is to avoid it.
Hyungnim.
For today, just leave me alone, please.
Don't even do that.
If you keep brandishing your sword like that here,
you may be charged with plotting treason.
Why are you looking for the letter
Gwang Hae gave me?
His Majesty is misunderstanding that the
relationship between you and him is bad.
Bad relationship?
I'm encouraged from reading his letter.
Yes, I know.
That's why I'm trying to tell him (the King) the truth.
His Majesty would be happy reading this.
Then, I will take my leave.
I heard you have someone
extremely good at forging handwriting.
Find him.
Are you trying to forge his letter sent to Great Scholar?
Just one clause - 'Help me with your authority'.
It'll be enough to charge him with treason.
I heard you can forge anyone's handwriting.
You must take this to your grave.
From Bunwon, an order was issued not to
bring any white clay of Bangsan for while.
Did you hear anything?
No, ma'am.
Should I go there to find out?
No.
Why ?
You think I would be seeing Bunwon Chief?
If you really want, you'd be seeing him anyway.
I don't know what you might think, so...
I find difficulty on knowing what to do.
If you're not hiding anything,
you shouldn't have any difficulty.
Anyway, things are strange.
Even until 2 days ago, they've been
clamoring for the white soil.
Their terrain is tough, they've always relied on us.
Did you call me, sir?
Yes.
Since we have a problem with getting in the Bangsan white clay, I need you to go dig it up and bring it here.
Can you do it?
Pardon?
I thought you had good knowledge
about soil and clay.
I've done it before, but...
Then, that's great.
They're your helpers.
Your help will be appreciated.
Be careful on your long journey.
Your job is just finding the white soil.
Manual labor will be their job.
Yes, sir.
Oh dear.
What has happened to me.
Master, I'll get some medicine for you.
Well, never mind.
Why should you be doing it?
Let Tae Do do it.
For you, you should be on my side, always.
I haven't been troubling you and
that's why you're not getting better.
You didn't do anything bad.
When you came to me, after your dad died,
I was very glad.
It was as if I came to have child of my own.
It was a revitalizing moment.
Since you've been here with me,
it was as if I've been living a really good life.
I'll go to tell him to get some medicine for you.
Why don't you rest and relax, Master.
Ok, ok.
Okay, my dear.
Where are you going?
Chief told me to get some white soil from Bangsan.
For you? Even to Bangsan, that far?
I'm leaving with them.
Even so. You're woman...
I don't mind on that, but...
My master is sick.
Ok. I'll provide breakfast and dinner for him.
Please take good care of him.
Then, I'll be going.
Hey!
Going somewhere?
Errand for Chief. Getting white soil from Bangsan.
No, the swordman Hyung-nim told us
not to get our eyes off of you.
Do you really have to go?
If I don't go, then, what?
Since my master may worry, don't tell him.
But, do tell Tae Do, my brother, please.
Hey, I'll accompany you.
You don't even have permission to do so.
You've even saved my life.
Permission? Well...
If they want to fire me, then, let it be!
Let's go.
Is it all right?
Prince Gwang Hae.
Your face is full of worry.
What's happened to your personal guard?
Why are you always alone?
Being alone is more comfortable here.
Guard Kim Tae Do . . .
Isn't he busy protecting the Bunwon errand worker?
Was that Yoo Jung?
Your first love, sir.
On a day like today, why don't you go see her?
Who would be better consolation than
the object of your first love?
Where the hell have you been?
I've been waiting for you to tell you something.
Gae Ddong, who does he think he is
to say he would help Jung?
- Hey, hey, guys!
- Hey!
Where is Jung?
Why are you coming back alone?
I... I lost the track.
What should I do now?
How come?!!
Well, I went to the toilet just for a moment.
What should I do now?
BECAUSE OF YOU,
WE'RE ALL DEAD NOW (by Tae Do)!
Hey, guys!
Your Highness!
We have something to tell you.
Tell me, then.
Tae Pyeong... no,
Jung went somewhere.
What does that mean?
Chief Lee sent Jung away
to get some white clay.
Chief Lee did?
Did she go by herself?
She went with two other senior menial workers
who are not even friendly to her.
We couldn't get in touch with that warrior bro either,
so we are very worried.
I was trying to follow her,
but lost the track.
Where did you send Jung to?
What's the matter, Your Highness?
To where did you send her away
to get white clay?
It's time to use that girl.
Who are you talking about?
I mean that girl named Yoo Jung.
No matter what excuses you make,
send her somewhere far from Bunwon.
Why do you want that?
Prince Gwang Hae and Jung...
I just want to follow my intuition, that's all.
That girl, Yoo Jung, said she's confident
at getting good white clay,
so I had no other choice but to send her there.
So, where is it exactly?
She went to get Bangsan's white clay,
so I only know
that it would be around there.
She went there again?
Huh? Where is Jung?
She said she would go get white clay
as per Chief Lee's order.
What? Chief Lee sent her?!
Darn it... Darn it...
Oh, Elder, where are you going this late at night?
My Jung... where did Jung go?
I'm asking where she was sent to get white clay?
I heard she was sent to somewhere far from here!
By Lee Kang Cheon!
What? Why would he send Jung?
There is... something going on.
This bastard... This bastard!
Gae Ddong!
Yes, Elder.
You guys, have you seen my Jung?
We are also worrying about her now.
Then... her brother...
Did she go with her brother?
Aigo... What's wrong with all these guys
who said they would protect Jung...?
Hwa Ryeong.
Have you heard anything from Kenzo?
No, I haven't heard any.
Really?
That's strange, then.
He was satisfied with the deal for sure.
Why hasn't there been any news afterward?
There would be soon, I suppose.
Recently, there haven't been many ceramics
coming from Bunwon either...
I'm not sure about Kenzo, but for Bunwon,
maybe it's because of Elder Moon Sa Seung.
Since Elder Moon Sa Seung is in Bunwon,
I guess it's difficult for Chief Lee to make a move.
This is quite strange.
What is?
In this kind of situation,
you used to be more anxious than I was,
but now you're very relaxed.
Your answer also has no hesitation,
as if it's already prepared in advance.
All those points are what I've learned
from you, Madam.
I have been working in this company
for many years, you know.
Now I can see the flow of process quite well.
I also started to be able to see
when it's good to buy and to sell.
After hearing your words,
I feel even more uneasy.
So far, my company has been increased
by our loyalty and trust.
I could achieve this much with a good reputation
despite being a woman,
because of my good products
and loyalty (to my customers/suppliers).
However, frankly speaking,
I can't figure out what's in your mind.
I'm just trying to do my work well
without any mistake
so that I can be recognized by you, Madam.
You'd better not include any lie in that, then.
I have favored especially you
among all other workers in this company,
because you're a woman
just like me.
Yes, I know that well.
As well as that you wouldn't let me
set even a foot in this industry
if I fall out of your favor, Madam.
That wouldn't be enough (if that happens).
If anyone back-stabs me,
and if that's you of all,
I might even get rid of you without a trace.
Such a thing won't be necessary.
If one has big trust in another, its sense of betrayal
(from the broken trust) is as big as the trust.
You always said so.
If you keep following me with your trust,
you will become my successor.
But if you betray me,
then there is nothing but death to you.
Keep that in your mind again.
Yes, Madam.
Finally, this is the first deal
between you and me.
Are all ceramic pieces from Bunwon
flashy like this one?
In three days, I will siphon off ceramic pieces
from Bunwon's storage room.
By then, we will have other kinds of ceramics.
I will look forward to those pieces.
I'm curious about one thing.
How did you leave Madam Sohn
out of this deal?
Leave out?
I wouldn't dare to do that to Madam Sohn.
I just want to make the company grow bigger.
So that you can swallow it whole
once you've made it big?
You're too funny, Chief Lee.
How can I swallow up the company as a weak woman?
I'm just learning the trade and building the experience.
As the Bunwon Chief, I need a
reliable place to do business with.
Even after I resign from the Chief position,
it will be the same since Royal Ceramist Lee
would have become the Chief.
But you're as good as Sohn Haengsoo.
Was my Yook Do a bait?
Sir Chief. That's too much.
I sincerely respect Royal Ceramist Lee.
I don't know what you're trying to do,
but Sohn Haengsoo is not someone to take lightly.
It's not too late to tell her the truth,
and give her the whole remaining profit, or...
Or...?
Or have Sohn Haengsoo
definitely subdued.
If I happen to want to do that in the future,
how I'll be able to definitely subdue her,
please just tell me the method.
Your Majesty.
I met with some ministers,
and became sure that Prince Gwang Hae
goaded the Chief Scholar.
What do you mean, goaded him?
In the house of Great Scholar,
there was a gathering among ministers.
At that time, they say the Chief Scholar showed
them a letter which Prince Gwang Hae wrote.
However, the content is...
What was the content?
I'm deeply sorry to say this,
but it was all about discussing the national matters.
I would... this Gwang Hae...
Is there anybody outside!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Go to the Chief Scholar's house immediately
and find Gwang Hae's letter!
Search!
Yes!
Teacher.
I saw a poor person who said
tributes are scarier than drought or the rainy season.
Teacher... I caught a Japanese spy, and that man
had a Joseon's military map.
In the three southern provinces,
there's severe famine, so...
How dare he!
Teacher,
please be my strength.
Gwang Hae.. this scoundrel!
Your Majesty. Prince Im Hae is here.
Honored Father! Gwang Hae has disappeared!
Where in the world did he disappear to?
Your Majesty. This is a lady's instinct,
but I heard that a female errand worker
whom Gwang Hae treasured
has also disappeared from Bunwon.
What?
Disappeared with a woman?
How pathetic is he!
Is the head guard outside?!!
What a relief that I hated language study?
If I liked reading and writing like
Gwang Haeand wrote a letter...
What a relief that every conversation I had
with the Chief Scholar was verbal.
What are you doing not going out there catching him?
Pardon?
I should boast my achievement by catching him
faster than Honored Father's guards.
Gather some fast men and depart soon.
Your Highness!
Are you the assistants that came with Jung Yi?
Yes!
How come only you guys are here?
How about Jung Yi? Where is she?
She heard there's a very capable doctor in this village,
so she said she's going to get her teacher's medicine.
Hya!
Was there a lady who came to get
a medicine effective for cough?
Yes, she said it's for her teacher,
so be especially careful.
Yes, I'm talking about that lady. Did she leave?
She said she needed to dig up the white clay quickly,
so she would return to get the medicine later.
Alright.
Jung!
Jung! Where are you?
Jung! Jung! Jung!
Jung!
Your Highness. It's after the rain,
so the ground's slippery
and due to the mud slide,
night search would be dangerous.
It will get dark soon, so as soon as the day breaks,
how about we search then?
In such a dangerous place, the lady is all by herself.
Then, I will send out the office guards,
so please wait here, Your Highness.
I will search the woods until I find her!
Your Highness!
Hold on.
Do you think I wouldn't be able to
find you if you're disguised?
There's an answer I need to hear from you.
Orabeoni!
Orabeoni. This trade is important to me.
I'm doing this trade with my life on the line.
Please, just one, ignore this.
I don't care about such a thing, so just leave.
All I need is this man.
Depart please.
Who ordered it?
On whose order did you kill Eul Dam ahjussi!
Orabeoni!
Stop it!
Step aside.
I have something to take care of with this man.
Didn't he tell you to follow my order
until the delivery ends?
If you're not going to kill me,
withdraw your sword immediately!
Sir Ghenjo is waiting,
so transport the items to the harbor now!
Let's go!
Orabeoni! Orabeoni!
Orabeoni!
Hwa Ryeong, I must catch that guy.
Orabeoni! Orabeoni!
Orabeoni!
Jung! Where are you?
Jung!
Where are you?!
Here!
It's here!
Jung!
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Your Highness!
- Jung!
Jung!
Jung! Are you alright?
Your Highness.
Can you move?
Wait there.
Please be careful. It's slippery.
Your Highness! Are you alright?
Are you okay?
How stupid are you? Only for mere white clay!
I'm sorry.
Your Highness!
Move aside!
Why is he not waking up?
He bled too much.
We'll watch the progress.
Please be careful on your way back.
Orabeoni.
Hwa Ryeong.
Yes, Orabeoni.
I have to find that man.
You can't get up. You have to stay down.
Your Highness. Thank you.
Thanks to Your Highness, I'm still alive.
There is someone I hold dear as my teacher forever.
The porcelain I made with you. I made it for him.
However, I couldn't save him.
I'm supposed to care for all people,
but I can't even save the one teacher.
That pathetic being, that's me.
However, you say that you survived thanks
to such me, so I'm the one who's grateful.
Your Majesty, Since things have
already gotten to this point,
why don't you install Prince Gwang Hae
as the crown prince?
What made you change your mind again?
Both Prince Shin Seong and I...
are spending each day in fear with a heavy heart.
What are you so scared of?
Think about Prince Gwang Hae.
He's been preparing himself to be the crown prince
by joining hands with Great Scholar.
And, as soon as you're looking for him,
he hides himself immediately.
When he targets us so persistently,
how can I not be scared?
I, too, was deceived.
I thought he had abandoned his desire
to become the crown prince.
That's right.
If you were to put Prince Shin Seong on the throne,
what if...
you pass away early, what will
happen to poor Prince Shin Seong?
He will become like Prince Woo San.
Don't worry about such things.
If I install Shin Seong as the crown prince,
wouldn't I also prepare plans for such possibility?
Wouldn't I order all ministers
and guards to safeguard him?
What good would that do?
Didn't King Sae Jong and Moon Jong also made such requests over and over again?
There were all those ministers and Kim Jong Seo
who guarded them as well.
Yet, what happened?
I...
see King Sae Jo in Prince Gwang Hae.
King Sae Jo?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Kneeling down in front of Prince Gwang Hae
for the rest of our lives,
would be our way of surviving...
This is what I'm thinking.
You see Prince Soo Yang
in Gwang Hae...
Did you sprain it?
It hurts less than earlier.
I think I will be able to walk by tomorrow.
Let me take a look at it.
No.
It doesn't hurt at all anymore.
I think it's completely healed.
You must be so tired. Try to sleep.
When you're sitting beside me,
how can I sleep?
You may go now.
How can I go while leaving you're alone
in a place like this?
Then...
Are you saying you'll stay in this room with me today?
I'm going to watch over you tonight,
so don't worry and rest.
I'm going outside after seeing you fall asleep.
Didn't I tell you I can't fall asleep
if you're sitting next to me?
Then,
until you fall asleep, let's talk through the night.
Sitting here like this, I feel so comfortable.
If I hadn't been born a prince,
if I had been born a common person like you,
then, like the simple father we saw at that time,
with the child on his knee,
I could've enjoyed living feeding
a spoonful of rice in a child's mouth.
Not being able to have such a dream is a
burden which I, who was born a prince, have.
If I, too,
hadn't promised my father that
I would become a ceramist.
As a simple woman, while baking small bowls,
I would've been living happily with kids.
Not being able to do that is a burden which I,
who wants to become a ceramist, have.
Did you recall what we did that time,
Sa Bang Chi Gi?
Yes, Your Highness.
The one where you fell that time?
Yes. That one.
After working hard at the farm and
being happy that my child is fed
and sleeping comfortably.
And, playing with my child
in that game of Sa Bang Chi Gi.
If I lived as such a ordinary man,
then my mind would be at ease.
You don't know what you're talking about.
Do you know how hard it is?
You work the whole day under the scorching sun. But during the day,your possessions are taken away by corrupt officials.
And at night, you're robbed by the thieves.
And you have to offer tributes to the country frequently.
It's not easy at all.
Why does a prince whom everyone envies
keep saying such things?
Do you envy me?
Do you know how tough it is being a prince?
You always compete and fight
even amongst the brothers,
and may even kill one another.
You may not know this.
But there are not that many princes
who died of natural causes.
Can you sleep yet?
No.
I can never fall asleep when you're next to me.
Why do I get to say these things
whenever I see you?
♫ I wonder how much time must pass until I forget? ♫
♫ How many tears must I shed until they stop? ♫
♫ When you call me indifferently, ♫
♫ My heart can't even say it's breaking. ♫
Your Highness, wait a minute!
♫ Even If I try to stop myself from always crying. ♫
What would you have done by yourself if I had ran way?
I'm your life savior, Sir.
♫ Even if I always try to forget those thoughts♫
♫ Those hidden words which I couldn't say, ♫
♫ Because I didn't have courage, because I didn't have the heart for it., ♫
♫ "I love you" still linger on my lips. ♫
♫ Because it hurts as if my breath were taken away, ♫
♫ Because the wounds remain, ♫
♫ I think that should be enough. ♫
♫ It must end here. ♫
♫ There will be no use to even try to shout. ♫
♫ I can't try the same thing twice. ♫
♫ I don't believe. I can't believe. ♫
♫ The hidden words I didn't have the heart to say, ♫
♫ "I love you", still linger on my lips. ♫
What happened to Gwang Hae
who I ordered the arrested?
They'll send in a letter soon, Your Majesty!
Are you saying they haven't found him yet?!
Tell them to catch and bring him in immediately! Quickly!
Are you awake?
How much time has passed?
It doesn't matter. You should rest more.
I need to go protect Jung Yi.
Don't worry about Jung Yi.
I went to Bunwon and saw her today, too.
She's well with Prince Gwang Hae.
Did you really see that with your own eyes?
I told you so.
That's a relief.
That she stays unharmed.
You're misunderstanding to think you're
the one to protect Jung Yi.
The one who protects Jung Yi would be Prince Gwang Hae.
Even now, and in the future as well.
Stay seated.
Why do you look so sad?
I have to return to Bunwon, but I'm afraid to do so.
Are you really?
But you went through all kinds of troubles
to become a Bunwon ceramist.
I guess the scenery here is too wonderful.
I, too, am like you.
I have to return to palace, but I'm afraid to do so.
Why are you like that?
It's the palace where everyone envies.
In palace, I always lived under a mask.
There's a mask I had to use in front of Honored Father,
and a mask I had to use in front of my brother.
A mask I had to use in front of the ministers.
I left the palace often because I hated that suffocation.
I think I know how that feels.
Because I was also wearing a mask to hide my feelings
when I was doubting and hating someone in the palace.
You did?
No.
Will you run away with me?
Pardon?
Don't you want to live, really caring for each other,
without the mask?
Why are you doing this all of a sudden?
It's not sudden.
You, Jung, were my first affection,
and until now, you were the only one
who made my heart beat.
I have to go dig up the white clay.
Did you really not know?
Your Highness.
Since sometime, it was only you.
In a tea cup when I was having tea,
in the book I was reading, in the dream I was having,
when my eyes were open and closed,
it was only you.
Even then, are you saying
you really did not know?
But you're Your Highness.
You're the Highness.
Will it work if I wasn't the Highness?
If I abandon my prince status,
will that do?
Jung.
Send the personal guard.
The prosecution guards whom His Majesty
sent have already departed.
We must find them first.
Pardon?
Find them, and tell them to hide to
avoid His Majesty's guards.
Your Highness...
As we do that, His Majesty's anger will only grow.
I have to make sure he loses His Majesty's favor this time.
So that he won't be able to return to palace forever.
Send them right away.
We must find Gwang Hae.
Did they arrest Gwang Hae?
They haven't found him yet.
I have to lessen His Majesty's worry
by finding him as soon as possible.
But why are you acting so slowly?
Prince Gwang Hae is your younger brother.
Uh Huh!
You really want to die, don't you?
I don't have a brother who schemes treason.
What are you doing, not going out to arrest Gwang Hae?
Are you saying you don't know where Hwa Ryeong is?
We haven't had a contact with her for the
last few days, so we were worried as well.
Shouldn't you search for her rather than just worry?
I'm about to send out someone to her house.
I will go there personally.
Since I've met you, I feel the happiest now.
Because you, whom I was only able to see
over Jung Yi's back and over the shade when I was young,
I could see you as much as I wanted, all by myself.
Orabeoni. Hold on.
Sir Royal Ceramist!
What brings you all the way here?
He's someone who's been like a brother
to me since I was young.
He had a big injury, so I cared for him.
Sir Royal Ceramist.
Please say something.
You said he's a patient. Go to him.
Orabeoni!
Hyung-nim! Are you injured?
It's nothing.
Where's Jung Yi?
- Don't even say!
We were looking all over for you because of her.
She went to get the white clay on Chief Lee's order,
but she hasn't been seen for the last several days.
Where did she go?
She said she's going to Bangsan,
but I don't know what happened.
Don't worry too much.
Prince Gwang Hae went to find her.
What are you doing?
Move aside!
Your Highness. We have a royal order to
bring you to the palace as soon as possible.