A CD compilation
Of every good '60s cut
And another...
a box set from the '70s
And I hear you're
buying a sequencer
And an arpeggiator
That's the best move
And throwing your computer
out the window
Why Because you'd like
to make something real
What would you like to make?
Like to make a Yaz record
I hear that you
and your friends
I hear that you and your friends
have sold your guitars
You bought turntables
I hear that you and your friends
have sold your turntables
and you bought guitars
I hear that
everyone that you know
Is more relevant
Than my favorite fuckers I know
Have you seen my records
This Heat, Pere Ubu, Outsiders
Section 25, Mars, The Black Dice
Did you ever hear
of these records I know
Sexual Harassment
Dorothy Ashby, PiL
Fania All Stars
The Human League
The Monks
Lou Reed, Scott Walker
Joy Division, 10cc
Eric B. and Rakim
Index, Basic Channel
Soul Sonic Force
Just hit me
Juan Atkins, David Axelrod
Electric Prunes
Gil Scott-Heron
You can't hide
Your love away from me
Hey?
But shame on you
Oh, I love the unity, man.
Unity!
The knuckle that Juan has.
Are we on?
Am I here?
Over here, spotlight.
Hi, everybody.
Well, well, well.
Madison Square Garden.
Guess who I'm here with.
This is James Murphy...
his older brother Tom.
Everybody say, "Hi, Tom."
Hi, Tom!
Tom, how do you think
your little brother is doing tonight?
I'm not gonna be critical.
I think he's doing pretty well.
How about you?
That was...
That's pretty good.
I think that was a pretty good response.
So you're enjoying the show
so far, everybody?
Good.
I think what we should do now
is thank LCD Soundsystem...
for making all this amazing music for us.
So, on the count of three, let's all say,
"Thank you, LCD Soundsystem."
One, two, three.
Thank you, LCD Soundsystem!
And now back to you, gentlemen.
It's all yours.
Thanks, guys.
Have a good night.
Something really quickly.
You might think this is a big show
and we're putting on a big show.
Um, there's a lot of people
who just volunteered to do this with us,
like, flew themselves here
and performed with us...
and who live here
and just put their time in.
And I want you to know
that there's a lot of people...
who just dedicated themselves
to doing this,
to put this weird thing on
in this totally...
in a boxing arena, basically.
We had a tour a couple years ago...
with our friends, with a band...
who is, I mean,
technically from Canada,
but there's two Americans.
North and south.
There's two Americans.
North... Southern...
Well, you guys are like...
You guys are like Bush.
You know, you've got the Maine... Texas...
There's Central America too, technically.
Yeah, you've got both.
So we did a...
We did a tour, and weirdly,
there was a song that thematically worked...
as well as musically worked
to have people play with us.
Shut up and play the hits!
Ladies and gentlemen,
for our live record called
Shut Up and Play the Hits...
Whoo!
Nah, I'm not going to...
Fuck you guys. Know what I mean?
And we have two...
Aw, man, this is like a history trip.
Two horny horns,
one kind of flatulent drummer...
and three troubled souls.
Three troubled...
Four troubled souls.
Huh, huh, huh
It's Australia, 2008!
Huh, huh, huh, huh
Huh, huh, huh
Oh, I don't know, I don't know
Oh, where to begin
We are North American
And for those, for those
who think that we're from England
We're not
We've been on planes and on trains
till we think we might die
Far from North America
Well, your buildings are old
and you might have lots of mimes
I hate the feeling
when you're lookin' at me this way?
'Cause we're North American
But if we act all shy
it'll make it go away?
Makes it okay?
Oh, I don't know, I don't know
oh, where to begin
'Cause we're North American
But in the end
make the same mistakes all over again
Come on, North Americans
Fuck, yeah, North American scum
Yeah
We are North American
Shout, shout, shout it
And all the kids, all the kids
they want to make the scene
Here in North America
And all your kids
get to read it in your magazines
We don't have those
So where's the love, where's the love
where's the love
Where's the love
Where's the love tonight
But there's no love, man
There's no love when the kids are uptight
Uh, uh, so
So throw a party till the cops come in
and bust it up
Check outta of?
North America
- Oh, you were planning it
I didn't mean to interrupt
- Sorry?
I did it once
and my parents got pretty upset
Freaked out in North America
And then I said the more I do it
the better it gets
Check out North America
We are North American scum
We're from North America
Check out
We are North American
New York's the greatest
if you've got someone to pay for it
North America
And it's the furthest you can live
from the government
Some proud American Christians
might disagree
- Hah!
- North America
New York's the only place
we're keepin' them off the street
Oh!
We can't have parties
where they go all night
Shut down in
North America
Or like Berlin
where they go another night
All right!
Uh, uh
You see, I love this place
that I have grown to know
- Come on
- North America
And, yeah, I know you wouldn't
touch it with a 10-foot pole
- Come on
- North America
We are North American scum
We're from North America
We are North American
Take me back to the States, man
North American scum
Where we can rock
To North America
Where the deejays are so much fun
Spinnin' North American scum
And don't blame the Canadians
Let's go, North America
So you strike me as somebody
who is acutely aware of your age,
that your age seems to play a role
in a lot of the things you think about.
Not just the years themselves,
but the amount of experience
and stuff like that.
And, you know, if you were a writer,
you would still be young.
That's why I've always wanted
to get into that.
And if you were an actor,
you'd be kind of right in the sweet spot.
Yeah.
But when you're a musician,
a rock musician...
or an athlete or, like, a mathematician...
the assumption seems to be
you have to succeed early.
So how much is your motive
for quitting the band...
solely a product of,
you feel too old to be doing it,
and it feels weird?
I was 38 years old and I said,
"I'm going to make a record."
Um, you know,
"Going to make another record."
And then I blinked and I was 41.
And I don't have any kids,
and I want to have kids
and I want to have a life.
And I feel like
that's, like, a genuine thing.
It's, like, I can't...
I blink twice more and I'm 50.
Every time I go on tour,
I get new gray.
When I don't go on tour...
I didn't go on tour for two years...
I got no extra gray.
I didn't age at all in two years.
I saw pictures.
When I got home
from Sound of Silver tour...
and when I got ready to go on tour,
and it's the same.
And then a month or two into tour,
you know, a big patch on my neck.
And I'm like,
"Well, that's the visible, funny sign."
Like, I'm getting gray hairs
on my face.
But what the fuck's
going on inside?
What's going on in my liver
or in my lower intestine, or...
You know, I don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
How you feelin'?
I'm fucked.
Fucking hell.
What...
I am absolutely fucked.
Smells a bit like gas.
It does. Actually, it's this...
It's this new addition and it's, like...
It's spewing gas,
but not enough to kill you.
Is that bad?
I feel like somebody
put my head on the desk...
and hit me with six bottles
of champagne.
That was me.
I think it was me, actually.
Good champagne though.
Yeah, I'm absolutely whacked.
I spent the whole morning
just staring at the wall.
Kind of like, "Am I here?
Am I there What the hell?"
You know,
27-hour day and all that.
But seriously,
how fucking amazing was that?
How fucking amazing
was that?
I feel great.
I feel super weird,
but I feel good.
It is super weird,
it's completely weird,
but it's, like, we fucking went out
on a total fucking high.
I didn't feel great this morning...
but I feel pretty good now.
There was backstage booze,
I think, that I want to make sure...
Believe me, you...
From what I saw,
you had your fair share, dear boy.
It's a long show.
Thank God you weren't drinking
Irish cunt, is all I can say.
Exactly.
Oh.
Uh, London.
Don't recognize it.
Uh, I think we'll say bye-bye.
Just wait till you see this.
You now have a weird one for me?
This is kinda like Monty Python
meets LCD Soundsystem...
at Madison Square Garden.
I'm going to leave this with you...
and go to the little boys' room
and have a pee-pee.
Dude, what is this thing?
It's your trophy, mate.
This is a sad object, dude.
There it is.
LCD Soundsystem sells out.
It literally says "sold out."
Sold out.
I've got a perfect solution
for your giant bottle of Scotch.
- What?
- Bring it to Marlow tonight for dinner.
Ahh.
Well, here's the thing.
I'm trying to keep
my marriage happy and intact.
Um, Laurie has to go away tomorrow.
Right.
And I need to be upstate
to look after the dogs,
take care of the farm.
Keep the serfs in line?
And to be fair, Marlow's
is kind of a young person's hangout.
You know...
You kind of...
You dress them up,
you put them on fucking
Madison Square Garden's stage,
you sort it all out,
and what do you get Abuse.
Yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah
Whoo!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
The red place used to be a...
It was something else,
wasn't it?
Yeah, it's a French restaurant,
and it's been, uh...
But all these places,
they've all changed.
It's New York.
Everything changes.
What?
"It's New York, darling.
Everything changes."
Well, it does.
Perpetual state of flux.
Including us.
Including you.
So this is weird,
but I've got to roll.
I've got to go.
Take care of yourself, huh?
Love you, dude.
Love you, James.
I'll give you a call tomorrow, all right?
Yes, boss.
Look after yourself.
Drive safe.
I'm retired.
Do you like talking about yourself?
Like, is it fun to have someone
ask you these questions...
and basically say,
"Consider your life
and put your life in a context...
"that other people will understand"?
I wish I could say, like,
"No, I find it so hard."
Why would you want to say that?
I would think you'd want to say,
"I love it."
No, because it just seems like,
again, you know...
I know you think that you
should say you don't like doing it...
I don't like...
but you seem
very comfortable with it.
I don't like boring interviews.
So when I have to do interviews
and it's just like,
"So did Daft Punk really play
in your house?"
Yeah.
And it's, like, you know what...
And we call that talk...
You gonna go talk about yourself?
That's what we always joke.
"I gotta go talk about myself
for a half an hour."
Um, that I find really boring.
But I think
that underlying loneliness,
or that underlying desire
to be understood,
like to clarify, you know,
this endless kind of like...
is pretty real.
And...
explaining...
I want to...
You know what I mean?
I want to explain sometimes.
Like, not everything.
I don't want to get into, like,
"What's that song mean?"
That stuff drives me a little bit crazy,
but explaining why,
explaining the position...
I'm obsessed with the position,
like where this stuff is coming from.
Like songs I like...
I like when songs are from a place.
Not about something,
but from a place, from a moment.
I wake up and the phone is ringing
Surprised, as it's early?
And that should be the perfect warning
That something's a problem
To tell the truth, I saw it coming
The way you were breathing
But nothing can prepare you for it
The voice on the other end
The worst is all the lovely weather
I'm stunned it's not raining
The coffee isn't even bitter
Because what's the difference
There's all the work that needs to be done
It's late for revision
There's all the time and all the planning
And songs to be finished
And it keeps coming
And it's keeps coming
till the day it stops
- And it keeps coming
And it keeps coming
till the day it stops
I wish that we could talk about it
But there, that's the problem
With someone new I could have started
Too late for beginnings
You're smaller than my wife imagined
Surprised you were human
There shouldn't be this ring of silence
But what are the options
When someone great is gone
We're safe
For the moment
Saved
I've always had this belief
that people or bands...
or whatever entities,
whatever you want to look at...
they're sort of remembered
for their collection of successes,
but they're sort of defined
by whatever is their singular failure.
This is kind of a sports example,
but Michael Jordan is remembered...
for all these great things he did
as a basketball player...
Right.
but I feel like
his singular failure was,
you know, his inability
to distance himself from competition.
That led to his gambling problem,
and it's led to his inability
to have a good life after basketball.
Right.
So I'm curious.
When you look at LCD Soundsystem,
or even just the trajectory of your life,
sort of, what were the successes,
and what do you feel might be
the defining thing you failed at?
You can climb a mountain
You can swim the sea
You can jump into the fire
But you'll never be free, no
You can shake me up
And I can tear you down?
You can jump into the fire
We can make each other happy?
You can climb a mountain
You can swim the sea
You can jump into the fire
But you'll never be free, no
You can shake me up
And I could tear you down
You can climb a mountain
You can swim the sea
You can jump into the fire
But you never will be free, no, no
You can shake me up
And I can tear you down
You can jump into the fire
You can jump
Into
The fire
You didn't answer the last part
of my question though,
which is, if you were...
I'll just ask the question.
What was the biggest failure...
What's the biggest failure?
of LCD Soundsystem?
Aside from like, you know,
when the volcano hit.
We didn't make it to Dublin
for the opening shows.
I felt really bad about that.
Yeah, that can't be
your biggest mistake.
You can't blame a volcano
for your biggest mistake.
I think the biggest failure...
I don't know if it's a failure.
I don't know yet.
Uh, stopping.
I've been a little obsessed
with, like...
Okay. You see these Kanye tweets.
People will be like, "You're"...
People call him ridiculous, or...
You know, make fun of him
for being egotistical
and all this other shit like that.
But I saw a quote
where he was just, like,
"Nobody's being a rock star.
None of you people are doing it.
Everybody is chicken.
Everyone is scared.
Like, scared to fail."
Scared... You know,
and it'd be, like, I'm doing it.
And I feel that if there is anything
that is going to be our great failure,
it's that...
even though I think I'm getting out
for what I think are not those reasons,
fear of failure or fear of
the responsibility of getting bigger,
it makes me suspicious,
because these other reasons
happen to also...
serve that potential fear.
Just the way it sounds to me
as you're talking, that actually,
if... if my theory is true...
that people are remembered
for their multiple successes,
but they are defined
by a singular failure...
it would seem your singular failure...
would be an inability
to stop being self... conscious.
The fact that you're saying that the problem
might be quitting the band,
but what it really is,
is you're already thinking
what quitting could mean...
or could be perceived to mean,
or what your real motive might be.
It's more inside.
I want to look back and be very,
very proud of everything that we did.
And I feel like right now I'm...
with a couple of snafus here and there...
I'm very, very like...
I like the way we've handled ourselves
and I'm proud of that.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
But this quitting stuff, even though
I'm, like, it's the right thing,
I wonder if me saying, like,
"I don't want to be a famous person
because I like riding the subway.
"I like eating food.
I like being a normal person.
"I like it. I'm 41.
"I don't think I could adjust
to the kind of weird dichotomy."
But is that a good enough reason?
If you believe in your band...
and you claim to like music
and you claim to like
making music for people,
is that a good enough reason to quit?
The lead-up to it
was so excruciating,
but I promised myself
that I was going to enjoy it...
Oh?
and I did.
Hello.
Very good. Williamsburg, please.
Second exit off the bridge.
Williamsburg,
second exit off the bridge, please.
Williamsburg.
Hey, hey!
Yeah, I guess we can...
This is our last song.
Okay, let me point this out,
that even now,
at the end of our band,
I fucking didn't say that
so you would say "Oh, no."
It wasn't the false...
It wasn't, like, "This is our last song."
"Oh."
- This is our last song!
- No!
And...
There's a lot of people here
that we don't know...
that came and put a lot of effort
into coming to see us,
and we want to thank you very much.
Everybody...
And the people who are sitting up there
who have a hard time seeing, I'm sorry.
Thank you so much for coming
and doing this with us on both sides.
And all of our friends,
a few that we know,
are in this little area here,
so give them a wave.
They're good people.
They're not shitty people
who wanted free tickets.
They're good people.
And my family, hi.
And my sister and brother are here,
and their kids.
And hi, you guys.
And...
Um, I hope it's okay.
I'm wearing my dad's watch, so...
Tonight.
New York, I love you?
But you're bringing me down?
New York, I love you
But you're bringing me down
I only get to pause
an interminable amount once more.
This is my last endless pause.
Like a rat in a cage
Pulling minimum wage
That's very... That's very dramatic, Nancy.
New York, I love you
But you're bringing me down
New York, you're safer
But you're wasting my time
Our records all show
You're filthy but fine
Oh
But they shuttered your stores
When you opened the doors
To those cops who were bored
When they ran out of crime
New York, you're perfect
Oh, please, don't change a thing
Your mild billionaire mayor's
Now convinced he's a king
Yeah
Oh, the boring collect
And I mean all disrespect
In the neighborhood bars
I once dreamt I would drink
New York, I love you
But you're freaking me out
Like a death in the hall
That you hear through your wall
New York, I love you
But you're freaking me out
But you're bringing me down
New York, I love you
Like a death of the heart
Oh, Jesus, where do I start
But you're still the one pool
Where I'd happily drown
And oh
Take me off your mailing list
For kids who think it still exists
Yeah, for those who think it still exists
Maybe you're right
and maybe I'm wrong
and maybe you're wrong
Maybe you're right
And just maybe you're wrong
And oh
Maybe Mother told you true
And there'll always
be somebody there for you
And you'll never be alone
But maybe she's wrong
Maybe I'm right
And maybe she's wrong
Maybe I'm wrong
Maybe I'm right
And if so
Is there
Standing in the door
of the Pink Flamingo?
Crying in the rain?
It was a kind of so-so love?
And I'm gonna make sure
it never happens again?
You and I
Had to be the standing joke
of the year?
You were a sleep-around,
a lost and found?
And not for me?
I fear?
I tried to make it work?
You in a cocktail skirt
and me in a suit?
Well, it just wasn't me?
You're used to wearing less
and now your life's a mess
So insecure, you see?
I put up with all the scenes
And this is one scene
that's going to be played my way?
Take your hands
Off me?
I don't belong?
To you?
You see?
Take a look?
At my face?
For the last time?
I never knew you
You never knew me?
Say hello, good-bye?
Say hello?
Wave good-bye?
Under the deep red light?
I can see the makeup sliding down?
Hey, little girl?
You will always make up?
So take off that unbecoming frown?
What about me??
Well, I'll find someone?
That's not going cheap in the sale?
A nice little housewife?
Who'll give me a steady life?
And won't keep going off the rails
Take your hands
Off me?
I don't belong?
To you?
You see?
Take a look?
At my face?
For the last time?
I never knew you
You never knew me?
Say hello, good-bye?
Say hello?
Wave good-bye?
We've been involved for?
Quite a while now?
And to keep you secret?
Has been hell?
We're strangers meeting?
For the first time, okay??
Just smile and say?
Hello?
Say hello?
Then wave good-bye?
Wave good-bye?
Say hello?
Then wave good-bye?
Say good-bye?
Good-bye?
Say good-bye, say good-bye?
Good-bye??