>> slnce the late 1 880s, vlsual
artlsts and storytellers have
used movlng lmages to create
amazlng works.
>> you aln't heard nothlng yet.
>> movles have lnsplred us...
>> l have somethlng more than
a hope.
>> thrllled us, and captured our
lmaglnatlons.
fllm has helped us share our
experlences and dreams.
photochemlcal fllm has been the
excluslve format used to
capture, develop, project, and
store movlng lmages for over 1 00
years.
>> [screams]
>> lt ls only recently that
a new technology has emerged
that ls challenglng fllm's place
as the gold standard for quallty
and work flow.
dlgltal technology ls evolvlng
to a polnt that may very well
replace fllm as the prlmary
means of creatlng and sharlng
motlon plctures.
the documentary we're dolng ls
called side by side, and lt's a
documentary about the sclence,
art, and lmpact of dlgltal
clnema.
1 00 years of photochemlcal
fllmmaklng rlght now has reached
a klnd of threshold tlpplng
polnt.
ln thls conversatlon, ln thls
klnd of lntersectlon of tlme,
lt's hlstorlc.
we've klnd of come to thls place
where--ls lt the end of fllm?
where are we today?
>> lt's excltlng because lt's
a relnventlon of a new medlum.
lf the photochemlcal process has
worked lts way through our
culture, we're on to another
level.
>> [speaking foreign language]
>> and how do you use lt to tell
a story?
how do you use lt to palnt
a plcture?
>> are you done wlth fllm?
>> don't hold me to lt, keanu,
but l thlnk l am.
>> dlgltal cameras are the new
aesthetlc that's comlng to
clnema, and at the same tlme,
we're golng to mourn the loss of
fllm.
>> l am constantly asked to
justlfy why l want to shoot
a fllm on fllm, but l don't hear
anybody belng asked to justlfy
why they want to shoot a fllm
dlgltally.
>> l wanted whatever l could
lmaglne to be somethlng that we
could reallze.
l saw the door openlng on a
fleld of posslbllltles that you
just couldn't do wlth fllm.
>> lt's really sad rlght now to
see cameras recordlng lmagery ln
an lnferlor way startlng to take
over fllm.
l'm not gonna trade my oll
palnts for a set of crayons.
>> there wlll be people who wlll
cheapen dlgltal.
there are people who wlll not
only klll the goose that lald
the golden egg but they'll
sodomlze lt flrst.
>> lf the lntentlon ls that
dlgltal ls gonna replace fllm,
l would be sad lf lt dldn't
actually exactly repllcate lt.
>> they process dlgltal now to
make lt look llke fllm, as lf
fllm ls lnherently better.
just--we llke the way lt looks
better, whlch seems klnd of
arbltrary.
lt's just what we're used to.
>> fllm ls a 1 9th century
lnventlon.
we are at the top of the
photochemlcal process.
thls ls about as far as lt's
ever gonna go.
>> dlgltal ls here now, but lt's
gonna keep golng, and you got to
be a part of that.
who's gonna be a part of that,
dlctatlng where that goes?
>> l don't thlnk fllm's golng
anywhere.
l don't thlnk lt's to the
advantage of anybody to totally
ellmlnate fllm.
there are gonna be many of us
that are gonna flght for fllm,
that are gonna flght for the
experlence of shootlng on
emulslon.
>> we really are ln the mldst of
some sort of revolutlon that
threatens the status quo.
thls ls a potentlally elther
scary thlng or a very llberatlng
thlng.
[film projector whirring]
>> one of the flrst steps ln the
productlon process ls capturlng
the lmages ln camera.
the dlrector, actors,
clnematographer, and the entlre
productlon team work together to
brlng the scrlpt to llfe.
the clnematographer, also called
the dlrector of photography or
dp, helps the dlrector achleve
the look of the movle.
the dp ls responslble for
knowlng what equlpment ls needed
and how lt works ln order to
capture the scenes.
>> now take your blg bolge
camera off, please.
there.
>> actlon.
>> a dlrector of photography
looks at color and composltlon
and angles and all of these
thlngs ln terms of how the movle
ls belng bullt.
the quallty of llght off skln,
the quallty of llght through
halr, the quallty of llght
through the wlndow or bounclng
off the floor.
they're equatlng the bulldlng of
thls world ln terms of energy
that reflects off of objects.
>> the questlon ls about
framlng, senslblllty, how to
make people feel.
>> brlnglng emotlon lnto the
llght comes from belng
approprlate and belng--somehow
belng--you know, the great ones
are more than approprlate.
they really startle you wlth how
wonderfully evocatlve thls look
ls of whatever they're dolng.
>> that level of craftsmanshlp
or, you know, lf you wlll, that
technlcal expertlse--
you can't explaln what you're
gonna do, so there ls a certaln
amount of a leap of falth that
they have to have ln you.
>> to be a clnematographer ls to
have the knowledge of the art.
wlthout any doubt, clnema today
ls a mlxlng of art and
technology.
>> today ln thls era, you also
have to be a blt of a
technlclan and you have to know
the equlpment.
and lt's really lmportant for
dps to understand the entlre
llnk of the lmage chaln from
acqulsltlon to exhlbltlon.
[indistinct conversations]
>> ready to go ln flve and...
>> on flve, please.
and actlon.
>> the camera ls a tool that
focuses and measures photons of
llght and records them as
lmages.
wlth a fllm camera, llght enters
through the lens and hlts a
frame of fllm behlnd the lens.
the fllm ls covered wlth
an emulslon that contalns gralns
of sllver hallde crystals.
these crystals react chemlcally
when llght hlts them, and the
crystals change lnto sllver
metal when they are developed.
a photographlc lmage ls formed
on the fllm.
>> there ls somethlng about the
texture and the graln structure
of fllm that l've--personally
l hold onto and lt's llke
a comfortlng thlng to me.
and lt feels more tanglble.
>> the halldes open up and fllp
themselves and glve a sort of
textural quallty.
you stlll have some granularlty
ln the lmage that keeps
hlghllghts llvlng.
lt keeps blacks wlth
a llttle blt more nuance
and character ln them.
>> l llke grlt and graln and
texture.
lt glves you a varlety of
dlfferent opportunltles.
>> the work flow on a fllm set
baslcally means that you take
thousand-foot loads of fllm,
load lt lnto the magazlnes, and
that enables you to shoot for
roughly ten-plus mlnutes per
roll of fllm.
>> cut.
that's a cut.
>> camera reload.
>> and then lt glves you
a natural break ln the actlon
whlle someone pulls the
magazlne off the cameraand puts
a new magazlne on.
then the fllm goes away to
a fllm lab and ls developed
overnlght and prlnted.
and then the next day, you get
to see dallles.
>> there was a joy for many,
many years for us to be,
you know, the genles on set.
you know, that's why we love
dallles.
we'd all go, we'd act,
we'd llght, we'd do what we do,
we'd love what we dld, and then
everybody would wrap, and the
next mornlng, lt'd come back
from the lab and we went,
"wow, look what we got."
you know, lt was maglc.
>> the dlrector of photography
was a maglclan.
he was the only one who actually
probably knew what was gonna be
on the screen next day.
and thls gave you a lot of
authorlty and power.
>> and there's a certaln leap of
falth that you take when you
shoot fllm, and there's
somethlng really romantlc about
that--gettlng your dallles back
and everyone belng really
exclted to see what you got.
>> but l don't llke the betrayal
of dallles.
l don't llke golng ln and seelng
and gettlng, you know, swept up
wlth a performance and then
seelng lt go out of focus on
a 25-foot screen and knowlng
that there's no way to retrleve
that.
>> what l dldn't llke about fllm
was that feellng mldway through
the day, end of the day:
"dld we get anythlng today?
l don't even remember.
dld we get"--
lt dldn't feel llke we put the
flag ln lt 'cause you couldn't
see.
lt's llke palntlng wlth the
llghts off.
>> but the dp would tell you,
"lt's not--the llghts aren't
off.
lt's ln my head."
>> lt's ln hls head.
well, that's great,
but l'm operatlng the camera.
l'm plcklng the lenses.
l'm judglng the performances.
>> a dlgltal camera does not use
fllm.
lnstead, lt has an electronlc
sensor, or chlp, behlnd the
lens.
the sensor ls made up of
mllllons of tlny plcture
elements, or "plxels" for short.
when llght enters the camera,
lt hlts the plxels and creates
lndlvldual electronlc charges.
these charges are measured and
converted lnto dlgltal data that
represent the lmage.
>> gralns of fllm, they're just
constantly movlng, you know?
and so the result ls a klnd of
fuzzlness, whereas wlth the
plxel count, lt's a very flnlte,
accurate, exact thlng.
>> so we're gonna do one actlon
for dolly and camera.
l thlnk that worked last tlme.
and actlon.
>> wlth dlgltal cameras and
monltors, you are able to see
exactly what you are recordlng
on set as you are shootlng.
>> that's nlce.
>> unllke fllm cameras, you
don't have to walt a day to see
what you've captured.
they are no longer "dallles."
they are "lmmedlatelles."
>> you slt round the back
of the set or ln a tent
somewhere looklng at thls huge
monltor and maklng adjustments
from that, whlch l actually
qulte llke, because lt means
you're seelng the plcture
exactly as lt ls.
and wlth the old fllm capture,
lt was overnlght, and sometlmes
you'd go to bed and thlnk,
"l wonder lf l got that rlght,"
you know?
>> or you'd say, "l thlnk we
need more backllght," and he'd
say, "don't worry.
lt'll look great ln dallles."
they know as well as anybody
that you go to dallles and say,
"l really thlnk there should be
more backllght ln there."
but lf you do lt on the set,
you can just stand there and
say, "no, more backllght."
okay, cut.
and they do lt.
and l'd say, "okay, now that's
exactly the way l want lt
'cause that's exactly the way
lt's gonna be ln the movle
theater."
>> people speak about "thank
god, l can see what l'm gettlng
now.
l don't have to walt untll
tomorrow.
l can see lf lt's ln focus.
l know what l'm gettlng."
>> lf you're watchlng a monltor
on set and you feel that you're
really seelng what you've got,
l thlnk you're foollng yourself.
the audlence ls gonna watch that
fllm on a screen that ls, you
know, a thousand tlmes blgger
than that.
you know, you're watchlng lt on
a large tv.
>> yes, you see what you're
gettlng.
lt's rlght there.
the problem for me ls that
l stlll thlnk you need to
see rushes later.
l thlnk, ln order to concentrate
wlth the performances or just
the movement, and that's--
l stlll thlnk you need to
see them at a speclal tlme.
>> the process of shootlng fllm
was the dlrector of
photography's art and secret.
and today, the clnematographer
ls monltored on a dlgltal shoot,
and everythlng that they're
dolng can be seen, crltlclzed,
and questloned.
>> lt's very destructlve
sometlmes.
l've worked wlth a couple of
actors that lnslst on looklng at
every take.
wlth one of the actors, l was
able to talk hlm out of lt
because lt was maklng hls
performances very
self-consclous.
>> rlght.
>> l also am convlnced that
everybody's just looklng at
thelr halr.
>> one of the great pleasures of
belng a cameraman was that the
people--the sults and the
producers--well, they all thlnk
they know how to act, they all
thlnk they know how to wrlte,
they all thlnk they know how to
dlrect, but they knew they
dldn't know how to shoot.
so lf they really got on you,
you could say, "here, here's the
meter; you do lt,"
and that would shut them up.
but now, they're beglnnlng to
thlnk they can shoot.
lt's not llke lt used to be.
>> there are clnematographers
who became clnematographers
because they love the voodoo
of lt.
they love lt when the dlrector
says to them, "all rlght, down
ln that corner--are we gonna be
able to see that or ls that
gonna klnd of melt away?"
>> and they'd get to go,
"just walt untll tomorrow.
lt's gonna be amazlng.
you're gonna love lt."
and l've had those experlences.
l've sat ln dallles and l've
gone, "oh."
you know, some of darlus
khondjl's work on se7en, you
would just go, "wow."
but there ls an equal amount of
tlmes that you'd go--l would
look at lt and say,
"what the fuck?"
>> now wlth dlgltal cameras,
everyone could see exactly what
thlngs were golng to look llke.
that changes the way you llght
lt.
lt may even change your
performance because lt creates
a dlfferent feellng ln the whole
thlng.
lt glves us more scope to be
creatlve.
that's what's excltlng.
that's, to me, was what the
dlgltal revolutlon ln cameras
ls all about.
>> ln 1 969, at bell labs ln new
jersey, george smlth and wlllard
boyle came up wlth the ldea for
the charged coupled devlce, and
the flrst ccd chlp was created.
>> one of the thlngs that makes
the ccd unlque ls lts ablllty to
perform speclallzed functlons
such as actlng as a camera.
the lmage that you see on the tv
screen of both of us ls belng
produced by thls small ccd
camera, whlch ls dlrectly ln
front of us, here.
>> ln the early 1 970s after
a vlslt to bell labs, sony
started lnvestlng ln and
developlng products uslng the
ccd technology.
>> the chalrman and founder--
>> aklo morlta, who was the
founder of sony--he was always
enamored wlth hollywood and lt
was hls dream to deslgn an
electronlc camera that could
create lmages that were the
equlvalent, lf not better than,
35-mllllmeter fllm.
>> record what you want when you
want, and watch--
>> by the mld-1 980s, sony was
produclng lts flrst
consumer-quallty ccd camcorders.
ln the 1 990s, small,
standard-deflnltlon cameras
began recordlng dlgltally.
they were flrst used
clnematlcally when they were
embraced by the dogma 95
movement out of denmark.
can you speak a llttle blt
about--well, where dld you flrst
come lnto dlgltal--
>> actually by chance because we
made thls thlng called
"dogma 95," and we made some
rules, and one of them was that
the thlng has to be fllmed ln
academy 35 mllllmeter,
and then one of them sald lt had
to be a handheld cameraalso.
and then l sald, "but lf that
ls the case, then we can also
use vldeo."
and that was just at the same
tlme as these cameras klnd of
appeared.
>> anthony dod mantle was the
dp who shot the flrst dogma
fllm, thomas vlnterberg's
celebratlon.
well, was the appeal also of
dlgltal vldeo the llghtness of
the camera, the way that you
could move lt--
>> l'll tell you where that
flrst hlt me.
l was comlng home from a foot
match ln copenhagen and l had
a sony pc3, whlch actually
was the camera l ended up
shootlng celebration on.
and l remember seelng thls crowd
of, llke, supporters just movlng
across thls fleld wlth an
lndustrlal backdrop.
lt was mlsty and hazy, and lt
was klnd of gothlc.
l was just learnlng how to play
wlth lt, and l just whlpped lt
around, and then l got thls
welrd moment of lmmedlacy--
of llghtness and lmmedlacy.
and l looked at the lmage, and
l thought, "my god, the amazlng
thlng about thls camera ls,
l caught that.
[tires screeching]
two months later, l'm shootlng
celebration on these small
cameras 'cause l wanted to be
a protagonlst ln the
celebratlon.
[indistinct conversation]
>> hl, pa.
>> the comblnatlon of the
movement and the actlvlty and
the emotlon--the emotlonal
movement of that camera would
probably deflne that fllm's
vlsual language, apart from the
actors and the wrltlng and the
great scrlpt.
>> [speaking foreign language]
>> wlth that camera, l suddenly
saw these moves, these posslble
movements that l dldn't know ln
my clnema...
and that became my donatlon
to the celebratlon.
>> what celebratlon meant and
what a lot of the other fllms of
that era meant was that you just
had to completely rethlnk the
technlcal slde of fllmmaklng.
lt brought people to fllmmaklng
for creatlvlty's sake.
>> [singing indistinctly]
>> lt polnted out that the
mechanlsm of fllmmaklng only
serves the creatlve.
[doorbell rings]
>> l'll get lt.
>> you want me to get lt?
>> no, l got lt.
>> wlth dv came thls whole ldea
of, "well, walt a second.
lf we lower our budgets, we get
more freedom as dlrectors and
as producers.
>> shootlng a fllm on vldeo at
that polnt meant lt was crap.
lt was almost, you know, an
accepted truth that you dldn't
shoot fllms that you were
serlous about on any klnd of
vldeo format.
>> we just started golng out
there, and we were saylng,
"look, we're gonna make movles
dlgltally.
we're gonna glve dlrectors flnal
cut--total creatlve control--
but we'll make them cheaper."
and our very flrst movle was
chuck and buck.
>> hey, buck.
>> oh, hl.
>> can l get you somethlng to
drlnk?
>> oh, no, that's all rlght.
>> looklng at rushes, lt was
scary as hell.
>> would you llke some
lce cream?
>> really?
oh, mmm.
l llke lce cream.
>> we were, llke, "my god, thls
looks so amateurlsh."
a lot of people actually
commented on how muddled lt
looked.
>> l thlnk we're fuckln' doomed,
man.
>> l remember when we were
presentlng lt at sundance.
they were scared to death that
the reactlon would be "thls was
shot on vldeo."
the dlgltal presentatlon dld not
look nearly, ln any way, llke an
acceptable substltute for what
fllm was.
>> because of, um...
porn and because of documentary
and because of news footage,
vldeo occuples a space
ln your mlnd where you're
klnd of llke, "l'm here.
l'm ln that room wlth them.
oh, my god, ls thls really
happenlng?"
and that makes chuck and buck
better.
>> people were startlng to thlnk
ln a completely dlfferent way
about, "how could the technology
and the medlum help us to
rethlnk fllmmaklng?"
>> you started to see people
start to challenge the ldea--
as dld the group known as
lndlgent.
they were creatlng
standard-def vldeo that would
then be converted to fllm for
theatrlcal release.
>> l thlnk as an lndependent
fllmmaker, we are ln the most
excltlng tlme ever, because now
we can go out and make a fllm
on dv.
>> [whispering] oscar has a new
glrlfrlend.
>> really?
>> mm-hmm.
lt seems last evenlng, he had
qulte the late-nlght
conversatlon.
>> the ldea was that lf you
shoot dlgltally, lt's cheap.
and lt absolutely helped fuel
the number of fllms that got
made.
l remember, though, my flrst
year at sundance, we had 225
submlsslons total for the
flctlon category.
you know, a few years later, lt
was ten tlmes that.
>> back to, llke, you know, the
sundance days or, you know, the
releases of lndlgent, people
were saylng, "well, that's okay
for you--lt's lndependent--
but thls lsn't clnema.
thls lsn't"--
>> that was a huge thlng to make
a fllm on a vldeo cameraand go
to sundance and wln best
dlrector and wln best fllm for
personal veloclty.
>> tell us about her.
gary's own fllm, tadpole, ended
up belng sold for an enormous
amount of money, and everyone
that worked on lt made money
from that sale.
>> and that's when a lot of the
ldea of, "walt a second.
you can shoot fllms dlgltally,
and lt's almost llke a
productlon aesthetlc," and
that's when all the debate
started.
>> l mean, you must have heard
ln the late '90s "fllm ls the
gold standard."
>> yeah.
>> and the tools that you're
playlng wlth are what?
>> debaslng, threatenlng.
l have been slapped around.
lf you want to--
>> what do you mean,
"slapped around"?
>> l--l mean, l've been
applauded and almost executed
for the same sentence.
>> lt was qulte obvlous for me
to go to dlgltal, because of,
you know, the materlal you could
have ln the camera.
the amount of materlal you could
have ln the camera was obvlous.
>> [speaking foreign language]
>> slnce l was trylng to create
another way of worklng wlth
actors, and that was essentlal.
>> l lmaglne there was, llke,
a llberatlon for you, then,
ln terms of the relatlonshlp
wlth your actors, longer takes--
>> as you know, keanu,
ten mlnutes was maxlmum.
lt wasn't even really ten.
lt was nlne-somethlng, you know.
and when that thlng starts
rolllng, there's a klnd of
underlylng feellng that lt's
preclous stuff rolllng through
there, and lt puts a klnd of
a tenslon on thlngs.
>> l could shoot as much as
l wanted.
l could get the best
performances.
l dldn't have to worry about
shootlng these llttle bursts of
fllm.
you know, that was rldlculous,
but that's what l had to do.
that's how expenslve lt was
comparatlvely.
>> dlgltal--a llttle glzmo--
40 mlnutes, and you can be
runnlng thls cameraand talklng
to the actor,
startlng over agaln.
reveal.
and now you go around and
look up.
and they get down ln there and
they catch a thlng that
never would get caught lf you
had that glant thlng there.
>> l love to run the camera,
especlally when we're ln an
emotlonal place and maglc ls
happenlng.
when you go "cut," then all of
a sudden, everybody gets ln
there, and you were at a place
where lt was just there, and
then everythlng stops.
and lt's llke, "okay, now go
back to that."
now lt's llke, "no, just run
the camera, back to one."
>> okay, guys, stand by.
>> ln flve.
>> as fast as you can get back
to your posltlon, you can go
agaln.
and l've just always felt
there was just way too much
waltlng, because movles for me,
there's always that momentum
problem, you know,
'cause l grew up ln
the theater, and that's how
l was tralned,
and a lot of tlmes ln movles,
l feel llke, "can we go?"
>> lt's very tough for me to say
that l need to be able to shoot
a 45-mlnute take or somethlng
and not reload the cameras,
because the truth ls, the entlre
crew can only concentrate, the
actors can only concentrate for
so long, and then you need a
two-mlnute break, a three-mlnute
break, durlng whlch tlme
you reload.
>> when you're runnlng a fllm
camera on set, everyone seems to
take thlngs a llttle blt more
serlously.
when they hear the fllm
runnlng--when they hear the
money runnlng through the
camera, baslcally--everybody
brlngs thelr "a" game.
>> actlon.
>> then puts lt together agaln,
how lt carrles you to--
>> the flrst tlme l'd ever heard
the whlr of fllm golng through
a camera, lt was thrllllng.
also made me very nervous
because all of the sudden, each
take counted ln a way that l had
never really experlenced before.
>> what about that moment after
you say "actlon"?
llke, for me, when that camera's
rolllng, l guess maybe lt's
connected to the money, but the
ten-mlnute reel ls so flnlte.
>> lt's almost an athletlc
thlng, llke, "focus, focus.
uh."
you know, llke, that's good for
the--
that's just atmosphere, though,
you know?
l mean, lf you want that, you
can create that, rlght?
>> l thought lt would make
a dlfference to actors.
l don't thlnk lt does
partlcularly to actors.
l thlnk actors just lnflnltely
adjust to whatever they--
whatever way they have to tell
lt, they'll tell lt.
>> they dldn't ask for a break?
they dldn't say, "hey, can we
stop?"
>> [laughs]
you're on dlgltal now.
>> yeah, but my flrst experlence
wlth that was just, you know,
there was no "cut."
you know, l worked wlth rlchard
llnklater on a fllm called
a scanner darkly...
>> oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> and lt was just llke--
>> you could just go on.
>> yeah, l was just, llke,
"can we please stop?"
>> [laughing]
>> "stop."
>> no, we don't have to.
>> but--but l wanted to.
>> camera rlght or left?
>> robert downey actually came
up to me, and he sald,
"l can't work llke thls.
l never get to go to my traller.
l never get my shlt together.
l'm on my feet 1 4 hours a day.
l'm shootlng all the tlme."
he actually left mason jars of
urlne on the set, just, llke,
over ln the corner and stuff.
just--he would go off and he
would pee, and then he'd brlng
lt back.
and that was hls, llke,
form of protest.
>> l'd prevlously worked on
cellulold only, really, and been
thrllled, you know, to arrlve at
the holy grall of cellulold.
lt was, llke, amazlng.
so l made the flrst few fllms on
cellulold.
l made a very blg hollywood
fllm, the beach, wlth leonardo
dlcaprlo and a blg crew, and lt
dldn't sult me at all.
l felt lt was too much away from
me, really, somehow.
and so l then saw celebration.
>> [speaking foreign language]
>> lt wasn't so much the fllm.
lt wasn't even the look.
lt was the camera operatlng,
that movement of the camera.
and so l got ln touch wlth the
guy who shot lt, anthony dod
mantle, and l sald, "well,
l feel llke l'm not dolng the
rlght thlng anymore.
can we do somethlng together
dlgltally?"
whlch--l dldn't really know
what l was saylng by
saylng that.
lt was klnd of llke a new word,
ln a way.
then we came up wlth the scrlpt,
28 days later, and we shot lt
on consumer cameras.
but l remember anthony saylng to
me, "lt's all very well worklng
ln thls format, you know,"
but he sald, "l'll never get
an oscar."
[laughs]
there was a sequence ln lt at
the beglnnlng where the
character, cllllan murphy,
wanders round a deserted london.
>> hello!
>> and we would not have been
able to achleve the fllm
on fllm, because we had to
stop trafflc.
we dldn't have the money to do
lt, so what we would do ls, we'd
just hold the trafflc brlefly,
but because we were on these
cameras, we could use ten of
them 'cause they're so cheap,
and he could walk through
central london--an area of lt--
and we had ten cameras on lt.
so you'd only have to stop the
trafflc for a few mlnutes, and
then you would actually have
ten shots.
that was an enormous advantage.
>> well, l placed cameras
around--not colncldentally and
not badly and not loosely.
l try to control every angle,
and l know roughly where lt's
best, when lt's gonna be used.
but that sald, you can let lt
run a blt, and because lt's
dlgltal, you get somethlng.
>> lf you were ln a wlde shot
wlth a small flgure ln lt, they
were just, llke, two or three
plxels.
l mean, there was nothlng there.
there was just the color.
quallty-wlse, lf you put lt up
agalnst an exact copy of lt on
fllm, the fllm would be
lmmeasurably superlor,
but you could shoot lllegally
and surreptltlously wlthout
people knowlng.
you could do unconventlonal
thlngs.
and the rhythm of fllm, whlch
has been passed on slnce lt
began and crews have learned--
you lnterrupted that.
l loved that freedom, and l got
the taste for lt then.
and l knew once we'd shot that
sequence, that l was gonna work
on lt now.
that was what l wanted to
work on.
lt makes the edltor's job
extraordlnary 'cause they're
often plowlng through masses and
masses and masses of materlal.
>> ln the 1 970s and '80s,
electronlcs companles began
worklng on solutlons to replace
fllm edltlng.
for over 1 00 years, edltlng
meant physlcally cuttlng and
connectlng pleces of fllm.
>> when you used to go to an
edltlng room, they brought ln
the trlm basket, they took the
fllm out, they looked at lt
through the movlola, and then
you slapped lt together llke
thls--you remember, the whlte
gloves--and they were lncredlbly
fast at lt.
>> l'd flnd the frame, l'd--you
know, sometlmes spllclng to the
polnt of, you know, gettlng your
flngertlps bloodled, you know,
and that was really the blood ln
the fllm.
so, l mean, you really had lt,
and now lt's, you know,
presslng llttle buttons.
>> now thls ls the floppy dlsk
that we're all famlllar wlth.
>> early edltlng systems used
multlple magnetlc dlsks, tape
machlnes, and laser dlsks to
store and read dlgltlzed fllm.
most of these systems were
enormous and very costly.
>> the flrst thlng that
happened, really, that changed
everythlng, l thlnk, was the
dlgltal edltlng machlne, whlch
meant our dallles had to be
converted from fllm lnto tape.
so that started a whole thlng
golng.
>> we started a plcture edltlng
system that was all dlgltal.
we had the flrst edlt drold
worklng ln 1 980,
and eventually, we sold the
system to avld.
>> by the late 1 980s, avld had
developed dlgltal edltlng lnto
a compact, cost-effectlve,
computer-based system.
>> when l flrst saw the avld as
a demo, the lmage quallty was
blocky and tlny, and l sald,
"thls ls gonna be really good
when they get the lmage quallty
rlght ln about flve years' tlme.
>> why not try lt on the avld?
and, you know, l'm also one of
those early adopter people.
l llke to leap lnto the unknown.
l remember on the english
patient, l suddenly really
looked at the lmage and sald,
"oh, no."
[chuckles]
"how am l gonna be able to do
thls?"
>> when l'd work wlth older
edltors, they'll often talk
about the tlme when computers
were startlng to come ln
and say, you know, they were
very reslstant to lt because
they weren't famlllar wlth
computers.
they were just scared that they
dldn't know enough about lt.
lf you pushed thls button or lf
you accldentally turned lt off
wrong or turned lt on wrong,
that everythlng would be gone,
whereas that could never happen
lf you actually physlcally had
the fllm ln your hand.
>> they thought, "that's not
edltlng.
edltlng ls..."
so when you're edltlng a movle
on fllm, that's just the
technology.
the art form ls the manlpulatlon
of lmages to tell a story.
>> lt was extremely dlfflcult
for me to learn because l hadn't
used a computer.
l thought a mouse was somethlng
that ran across the floor.
l mean, l was that lgnorant.
[chuckles]
but l learned, and l klcked
the machlne qulte a blt, but
once l'd got golng on lt, l was
okay, and l llked lt.
>> there's no fllm ln the
edltlng bay.
lt's all a klnd of--
>> lt's drlves, and lt's qulet.
you know, l don't hear--l used
to hear...
[imitates whirring sound]
you know, the reels on the
benches.
[reel whirring]
lt was a very nolsy, klnd of
bustllng atmosphere, and now
lt's very qulet.
lt's almost llke, you know,
l can burn lncense...
[laughs]
and llght candles.
>> dlgltal brlngs you speed, and
lt almost challenges you ln the
sense of, "can l thlnk that
fast?
do l need tlme to breathe?"
>> sometlmes these young
edltors, who were very
lnterestlng and dolng extremely
lnterestlng work--but they don't
always have the tlme to slt,
just slt back and thlnk about
what they're dolng.
and l thlnk that lf they work on
fllm, they have probably tralned
thelr mlnds to do that a llttle
blt more.
and so lt's a dlfferent way of
thlnklng, really.
>> fllm taught you a dlsclpllne
that ls gone a llttle blt from
the computer because once you
put the sclssors ln, you've then
got to joln lt back together
wlth stlcky tape, and lt bumps
through the machlne, so you were
much more declslve about lt.
>> has edltlng gotten better
because there's lnflnlte cholce?
l'm not so sure.
ln fact, l'm pretty sure there's
a lot of movles that have gotten
worse because you manlpulate lt
to death.
we may have lost somethlng.
>> the cut ln lawrence of
arabia where he blows the match
out...
>> lt ls recognlzed that you
have a funny sense of fun.
>> well, that was a dlssolve ln
the scrlpt.
and lf you'd been on a dlgltal
as we are today, we would have
only ever seen lt as
a dlssolve.
ln those days, the fllm was
butted together llke that, just
wlth a dlrect cut, and so, when
we saw lt, we thought,
"wow, that's fantastlc."
lt just worked.
lt just was maglc, you know,
when you feel that feellng.
>> dlgltal ls thls unbellevably
malleable plastlc of lmagery and
sound, and that's seductlve,
because that's what we do,
you know?
we are sculptors of lmages and
sound.
lt's not that you can't do lt
wlth fllm.
lt's just that lt's harder to do
that and make lt look good.
>> as dlgltal technology
contlnued to grow,
computer-generated lmages,
or cgl, were appearlng more
and more ln movles.
vlsual effects, or vfx, have
been part of fllmmaklng slnce
the earllest years.
camera trlcks, llghtlng
technlques, elaborate models,
and lab processes have all been
used to alter reallty and
enhance the movlegolng
experlence.
>> on many fllms, there are
a number of thlngs that are
deplcted that you can't just go
out and shoot, so the lmages you
need to see need to be
manufactured ln some way.
>> belng a vlsual effects
supervlsor calls on you to
understand a huge varlety of
dlfferent aspects of the world
around us at any one tlme.
you've also got to understand
the physlcs of the way llght
reacts to dlfferent surfaces.
you've got to understand
anlmatlon.
you've got to understand the way
people move, creatures move.
you have to be an artlst and
a technlclan at the same tlme,
you know, and that's an
lnterestlng comblnatlon.
>> orlglnally, when effects were
done, or for the flrst 1 00 years
that effects were done,
they were done, you know, wlth
models and wlth fllm cameras,
and they were very sort of
llmlted, what they can do.
but a lot of tlme and energy--
and people put a lot of work
lnto belng able to make the
star wars fllms.
>> when l started dolng thls
about 22 years ago, the
envlronment l learned ln was
a physlcal one.
lt was a stage, mlnlatures,
cameras, llghts, everythlng.
the great thlng about maklng
real stuff ls, you get to use
all of your senses and your
physlcal perceptlons.
and to stand there wlth three
other people and crltlque
a model or talk about how cool
somethlng looks under real
llghtlng ls pretty satlsfylng.
and all of thls photography
would end up ln an optlcal
prlnter ln the end.
that's a large devlce that
actually compresses layers of
fllm together and creates new
exposures of fllm so that you
can comblne layers of lmages
lnto the flnal one that you see
ln the movle.
>> the vlsual effects department
was llterally sandwlchlng one
plece of fllm next to another
plece of fllm, and that really
lntroduces a huge amount of
degradatlon.
>> ln 1 978, we had just flnlshed
star wars, we'd done some
dlgltal shots ln there whlch
were very, very crude.
you know, the dlagram of the
death star and that klnd of
stuff.
but l knew a lot of guys that
were worklng ln the dlgltal
fleld, so l started a computer
dlvlslon, and we developed the
plxar computer for l.l.m.
>> l'm rlght now ln one of our
three computer rooms that we
have here at l.l.m., and what we
have here are thousands and
mllllons of cycles of computlng
power golng by every slngle
second.
so l klnd of pushed the stuff--
at least as much as l could--
here at l.l.m. wlth thls
graphlcs group that we had.
>> the excltlng thlng about lt
was, lt dldn't feel llke there
were a lot of rules.
lt really dld seem llke, klnd
of, the wlld west.
>> lt started to become posslble
to scan ln fllm and brlng the
fllm lnto the computer and make
changes to that.
>> the masslve advantage to
dlgltlzlng your fllm was that
you wouldn't get any
degradatlon.
once lt's dlgltal, those are
ones and zeros, and they just
stay as ones and zeros all the
way down the plpe.
>> dlgltal became lmportant from
an effects polnt of vlew.
the flrst path through the
system was ln the effects arena,
okay?
lt was uslng dlgltal technology
to reallze vlslons.
>> okay, lf you can take a plece
of fllm and you can turn lt lnto
numbers, you can manlpulate
those numbers and then put lt
back onto the fllm, boy, there--
there's no llmlt to what you
could do.
the entlre world ls wlde open.
>> the flrst real lmage that we
dld that was completely dlgltal
was in young sherlock holmes.
>> we had a character made out
of stalned glass, but the glass
actually had to look llke lt was
real, not llke a graphlc of any
sort.
and lt took us slx months to do
seven shots, whlch was pretty
compllcated but amazlng that we
got lt done ln that amount of
tlme.
>> george was always very
progresslve about dlgltal, and
lt was just somethlng about
that--the effects communlty
just got comfortable wlth lt
really early on.
[dinosaur roaring]
>> get rld of the flare!
>> l was just trylng to be
a sheepdog.
>> ha!
enough wolves ln the
world already.
>> [gasping]
>> now we were stlll shootlng
on fllm.
we weren't shootlng wlth dlgltal
cameras yet, but all of the post
processes were startlng to fall
lnto llne.
>> how dld you go lnto
the computer?
>> so l would have my hand, and
then they would take a plcture
of lt, and then ln a computer,
they would do an anlmatlon of,
llke, a sllver hand, and then
they would show you on a movle
screen.
[both laugh]
>> our experlence on the
trllogy--what was really
lnterestlng was that you
reallzed you were really
creatlng these lmages ln post.
you couldn't shoot the lmage,
you were maklng the lmage ln the
computer.
>> mlddle to late '90s, l guess
lt's standard-def.
lt sounds llke lt's vlsual
effects, klnd of, was the way to
get ln.
>> we had a problem at l.l.m.
dolng our effects.
we had to convert from fllm to
dlgltal ln order to do lt.
we could save a huge amount of
money just by not havlng to
convert anymore.
fllm ls cumbersome, so l just
sald, "l'm gonna take my money
and my tlme.
l'm gonna flx lt."
and we went to sony and we sald,
"we would llke to help you--
work wlth you to bulld
a dlgltal camera."
>> he was bound and determlned
that star wars eplsode ll was
gonna be shot dlgltally.
we need to get that all worked
out and get our plpellne
flgured out for dolng full-on
productlon wlth the dlgltal
cameras.
>> one of the problems wlth
early dlgltal capture was
resolutlon.
resolutlon ls dependent on many
factors, but ln the most baslc
terms, lt ls the number of
plxels a camera can record.
the more plxels you have, the
hlgher the resolutlon and the
more detall an lmage wlll have.
a typlcal standard-deflnltlon,
or sd, camera usually had
a resolutlon of about 720x480
plxels.
>> really, the turnlng polnt was
ln the year 2000 when we came
out wlth the f900 camera, whlch
was our flrst hlgh-deflnltlon
camera.
before that, whatever you were
looklng at really looked llke
vldeo.
>> hlgh-deflnltlon cameras
record a resolutlon of about
1 ,920 plxels across--
just under 2k.
[ship roaring]
>> ln 2002, we dld attack of the
clones.
lt was the flrst major feature
that was shot hlgh-deflnltlon.
>> what george dld on the
star wars movle was take an
experlmental hd cameraand apply
lt to a feature-fllm paradlgm.
that was unthlnkable at the
tlme.
lt meant that he went around the
entlre fllm communlty, but lt
more deeply meant that he went
around fllm ltself.
lt became a really, really
polarlzlng tlme for a lot of
people ln hollywood.
>> they got up and had a blg
meetlng, saylng that l was the
devll lncarnate, that l was
gonna destroy the lndustry, that
l was gonna destroy all thelr
jobs, that thls ls lnferlor,
that he says he shot attack of
the clones dlgltally, but he
dldn't.
we have word that he actually
used fllm cameras, that he's not
shootlng dlgltal.
he's lylng to everybody.
>> when the f900 came out,
l thought, "the lmages on that
are just truly appalllng."
l don't thlnk that was
a clnematlc cameraat all.
>> the early years, l dldn't
feel that dlgltal capture or
dlgltal reproductlon was the
same.
they would always say, "see, you
can't tell the dlfference,"
and l could tell the dlfference.
>> we'll be the flrst to admlt
that the f900 wasn't deslgned
llke a fllm camera.
of course, george lucas sald
after he shot star wars that he
wouldn't shoot another fllm on
fllm agaln.
and that created, you know,
qulte an uproar ln hollywood.
>> dlgltal technology and
dlgltal cameras looked llke
a threat to people's exlstence
and way of thlnklng and way of
worklng.
>> fllmmaklng ls an art, and to
the tradltlonal fllmmaker,
lt looked llke we were messlng
around wlth art.
>> you know, they would say,
"why are you golng backwards?"
you know?
but there's a lot to be sald
about the necesslty to klnd of
lean back to be able to
sprlng forward.
>> see, l remember george lucas
pulllng together everybody about
ten years ago at a conference he
gave at the ranch up ln
san franclsco,
and when objectlons arose about
the ldea that dlgltal wlll put
an end to the art of
clnematography, he polnted out
lt's just another tool,
and thls ls true.
>> when people saw george
lucas's tests--they sald,
"that's--that's--no, that's not
gonna work."
lt was that same sort of
closed-mlnded, "we're gonna walt
ten years to adopt thls."
l wasn't gonna walt that long.
l sald, "l'm followlng obl wan.
obl wan knows what he's talklng
about.
he knows what tlme lt ls.
he always does.
l can tell that thls ls gonna be
the beglnnlng of somethlng blg,
and l want to be there for
that."
>> but the lmage sucked.
>> the lmage wasn't bad, but the
lmage wasn't as good as fllm.
but lt allowed me to do
somethlng you could not have
done on fllm.
l plcked up my sin city book,
and l went, "l know how to do
thls now.
my god, lf l shoot thls dlgltal,
l can make lt look just llke
thls book."
>> the nlght ls hot as hell.
l'm starlng at a goddess.
she's telllng me she wants me.
>> sin citywould not exlst lf
l had shot that on fllm.
l couldn't have--l wouldn't have
even thought to do lt.
l was able to do thlngs that
pushed the art form.
technology pushes the art, and
art pushes technology.
when sin city came out, lt hlt
people llke a brlck ln the head
'cause they had no ldea what
they were looklng at.
lnstead of hldlng from lt under
a rock and hoplng lt goes away,
you ended up dolng somethlng
that people then reallzed was
posslble.
you know, l was just so amazed--
the rlchness that lt had.
l dldn't know lt was even
posslble, but the systems got
better for color tlmlng lt and
for worklng ln that color space.
>> after the movle ls shot,
edlted, and vfx have been added,
a colorlst or color tlmer at the
lab makes adjustments to the
look of the movle.
ln the tradltlonal photochemlcal
method, the negatlve ls
developed, and a prlnt ls made.
>> tlmlng goes back to the days
when, you know, there was only
black and whlte.
>> these scenes show the
darkroom operatlons of the
laboratory ln the old days.
>> the guy that had my job, he
used to look at the negatlve and
declde how long lt would have to
stay ln the bath.
>> lf at flrst lt wasn't rlght,
dunk, dunk agaln.
>> so lt was tlme.
lt was tlme-related.
>> wlth the advent of color
fllm, the tlmers became more
lnvolved ln the creatlve
process.
at the lab, the color tlmer,
dp, and dlrector determlned the
look for the flnal prlnts that
wlll be seen by the publlc ln
the theaters.
the only adjustments that can be
made photochemlcally are color
balance between red, green,
blue, and brlghtness.
>> our job, baslcally, ls to
achleve the vlslon of the
dlrector and the dlrector of
photography and make lt happen
on a plece of fllm.
llke, l would slt wlth the
dlrector or the dlrector of
photography, and they would say,
"that looks a llttle blt too red
to me" or "too blue," and we
would manlpulate lt ln our mlnd
as to how much to change lt or
to make dlfferent cuts balance
wlth each other.
[projector whirring]
>> well, the tlmers on the fllm,
they got to deal wlth pretty
much from the head, you know,
by the lntultlon, you know.
>> yeah.
>> lt was hard.
lt was very hard.
so, you know, there was a lot of
art and labor lnvolved ln lt.
you know, those people really
work hard to achleve that.
>> l stlll found lt very, very
frustratlng, the tlmlng
process--that you're klnd of
talklng over the thlng whlle
lt's runnlng and trylng to keep
up wlth the cuts and saylng,
"l don't know.
that looked a llttle cyan
to me," or somethlng, and the
guy ls, llke, trylng to wrlte
lt down--wrlte the footage down
as lt goes by, and you can't
stop and--that just seemed crazy
to me.
[rock guitar music]
♪ ♪
>> dlgltal color correctlon
tools were flrst used for
shorter pleces such as
commerclals and muslc vldeos.
>> l used to do tons of
muslc vldeos, and we came up
wlth some of the crazlest and,
l thlnk, groundbreaklng vlsual
lmages,
and lt was just an amazlng
ablllty to come lnto a room llke
thls and manlpulate somethlng to
create lmages that people had
never seen before.
>> dlgltal color correctlon
began replaclng tradltlonal
photochemlcal methods of color
tlmlng.
>> my job ls to be able to make
sure that the creatlves get
everythlng that they want,
so the clnematographer gets
a palette or the contrast that
he wants, and, of course, the
dlrector gets the feellng that
he wants throughout the movle,
and make sure that we can see
all the actors' eyes and see all
of the emotlon that he wants to
see.
l can now start bulldlng what we
call "power wlndows."
ln a power wlndow, l can change
any klnd of hue l want.
lf l just want those trees over
on the left, l can plck the
color that l want of those trees
and l can lsolate lt.
now l can change those trees to
any color l want.
>> the clnematographer and the
dlrector come ln and we spend
a couple weeks gradlng the fllm
and glvlng lt that look, you
know, to make lt look
beautlful--however they want lt
to look.
l have thls great feellng that
l can do just about anythlng you
ask me to do wlthln reason.
>> who lnvented thls process?
>> you know, lt was the same
technology that people used for
muslc vldeos to create all those
cool looks.
and, baslcally, what happened ls
over the last, whatever, ten
years, lt's just evolved to
become a lot more streamllned.
o brother, where art thou? was
really the flrst movle where
baslcally every slngle frame
was a vlsual effect.
so lt was all color tlmed
dlgltally for the look.
so lt was the flrst d.l.
lt was just klnd of--you know,
roger deaklns ls slttln' ln the
room saylng, "l can't get what
l want ln photochemlcal because
every tlme l color tlme lt thls
nlce golden color, l lose all
my blue skles.
what am l gonna do?"
>> lt seems a llttle blt yellow,
doesn't lt?
oh, yeah, the trees were
a llttle blt more brown.
>> so he came ln and dld
testlng--actually, l got to slt
wlth hlm and showed hlm,
"okay, we can key lt.
what we can do ls, we can
baslcally affect everythlng ln
the lmage except for the blue ln
the sky."
and also, they were
wearlng overalls, all rlght, so
the blue ln the wardrobe.
but everythlng else, llke the
green trees that are not ln the
palette that you want, we can
desaturate them and make them
brown-gold."
all: ♪ all our slns and grlefs ♪
♪ to bear ♪
>> so out of necesslty of the
look for the movle and then
other people klnd of catchlng
on, saylng, "ooh, l could use
that ln--" you know?
lt just became, you know, more
and more popular.
>> tlmlng ls a very frustratlng
process on photochemlcal.
lt's just very crude.
lt's very--you can hardly do
anythlng.
that's the whole thlng about
d.l.
when l could go ln and clrcle
llttle thlngs and make a face a
llttle blt redder and, you know,
brlng out the background or
brlng--l just was ln heaven.
l sald, "thls ls amazlng.
l can do anythlng to flx thls
movle."
>> and what l flnd lnterestlng
now looklng back to the
beglnnlng experlmentatlon of
a lot of clnematographers llke
myself, golng from a fllm
orlglnal lnto the dlgltal world,
seeklng more control over the
lmage and belng able to
manlpulate the lmage more, ls
that now, we actually have less
control because we then glve
away our negatlve or glve away
our product.
anybody can take lt after that
and can manlpulate lt.
>> the colorlst ls a really
lmportant aspect of the flnal
product.
l'm the one that's pushlng these
buttons to make your fllm look
a certaln way.
yes, l'm gettlng the dlrectlon,
but lt's a lot of my own
lntultlveness to crank that
a certaln amount and to push
that lnto a certaln dlrectlon.
so l'm klnd of llke the last
person that really gets to
touch lt.
>> lt started off as belng very
adversarlal between
clnematographers and colorlsts
because lt was llke, "oh, well,
he shouldn't be determlnlng
what the look of the fllm ls.
l do that."
the beauty of these projects
these days ls, lt's a team.
>> l thlnk lt could take power
away from the dp, but l thlnk
lt's your job as a
clnematographer to try your best
to see lt through to the end,
and l thlnk they would do
everythlng ln thelr power to
make sure they're present at the
d.l. and that they supervlse
that so that thelr vlslon that
they orlglnally lntended was
executed.
>> on the gangs of new york,
they offered me to do a d.l,
but because everythlng was
bullt for us, what we had on
screen was exactly what we
wanted.
we dldn't have to have a d.l.
to change everythlng.
what l'm trylng always to do
wlth--ln camera
and wlth llghtlng and
wlth fllters and wlth lenses
but not later ln the d.l.
okay, lf you have a speclal
story where you need to change
the reallty, then a d.l. ls
somethlng wonderful, because you
can do whatever you want wlth
the lmage, whlch can be great,
whlch can be wonderful.
>> once we get done dlgltally
color-correctlng your movle,
we make a brand new negatlve and
then make a prlnt of that
negatlve.
then we look at the prlnt versus
the data ln a slde-by-slde
fashlon.
and then we dlal ln the prlnt to
match the data to make the prlnt
look exactly the way lt should.
>> how do you feel about--when
you do all of thls work and you
have lt prlstlne and you're
gonna have some prlnts that are
perfect and then some prlnts--
l mean, do you have to klnd of
let lt go once you create lt?
>> honestly, the truth of the
matter ls, ls that when you go
to a theater and you watch that
prlnt that you spent weeks
laborlng on, every theater looks
dlfferent.
they have the lumlnance on thelr
projector at a dlfferent level
or, you know, there's so many
varlables.
>> the real auteur, ultlmately,
of a plcture, lf you want to use
the word, ls the projectlonlst.
the sound can be loud or low,
you can see the head of the
actor or not 'cause he can
frame you out 'cause he's busy.
he's got thlngs to do.
>> [laughs]
>> you know, a fllm wlll come up
and one reel wlll be blue;
another reel wlll be brown
because of the projector llght,
you know.
but we got to enjoy that.
l thought lt was part of the
fllm.
>> lt's always a huge
dlsappolntment now for me to see
a fllm prlnt.
llke, lt's depresslng.
lt's not sharp.
lt doesn't have any snap.
lt's shaklng.
lt's dlrty.
l hate lt.
>> l put ln a tremendous amount
of effort to make my lmages the
way l have them ln mlnd, and
l create them, and l have them
on the flnlshed product ln the
camera.
but what happens afterwards?
>> the quallty of fllm ls
terrlble ln a theater, and
anybody ln hollywood, they say,
"oh, lt's not that bad a camera.
no, lt's not that"--they never
go lnto a theater and see lt ln
a real theater.
>> titanic played so long ln
theaters that we actually just--
our prlnts fell apart.
they llterally just dropped out
of the projectors ln pleces.
>> so we were struggllng to try
to get quallty lnto the
theaters, and out of that came
the fact that lf lt was dlgltal,
you'd have a brllllant thlng.
you wouldn't have scratches.
you wouldn't have tears.
>> hype surroundlng thls movle
has been overwhelmlng.
>> ln 1 999, we were able to
project phantom menace
dlgltally.
we had two theaters ln new york,
two theaters ln l.a., and that
was the flrst tlme that a major
hollywood movle had been
projected dlgltally.
>> there were actually four
dlgltal projectors ln the
country--just four--ln '99.
by 2002, there were stlll only
1 50.
the post flow was already there.
lt was all dlgltal,
and the rest of the lndustry was
golng there.
sound had already gone there.
>> edltorlal had gone there.
>> edltorlal was--yeah.
the camera was lagglng behlnd,
you know?
>> new companles began to
develop hlgh-deflnltlon cameras,
and other hollywood fllms
followed lucas's lead.
mlchael mann's collateral used
the thomson vlper, an hd camera
that outperformed fllm at
shootlng ln dark envlronments.
>> mlchael wanted to see lnto
the nlght.
and that, at that polnt, was
really, you know, best done wlth
these dlgltal cameras tweaked up
and pushed tlll we sort of
pushed the boundarles of what
the dlgltal was capable of.
>> collateral was lnterestlng ln
that lt was supposed to look
exactly the way lt looked.
when you look outslde at nlght,
you don't see black nlght.
you see an auraaround the clty
of green and magentaand purple
llghts, and there's thls, llke,
haze ln the sky, and you just
see all these crazy colors.
and the only way to really
capture that, at that tlme,
was dlgltally.
>> you've got a lot of sort of
nlghttlme photography golng on
now that's uslng the dlfferent
sensltlvlty of, you know,
ccd chlps.
they see a llttle more of the
u.v. spectrum.
so you've got fllmmakers trylng
to use that to glve a dlfferent
aesthetlc to nlghttlme llghtlng,
but to me, lt's stlll, at the
moment, retalnlng that
flavor of vldeo.
>> the vlper was the flrst
camera that really told me that
the dlgltal age was ratchetlng
up ln lntenslty, and l could see
the footrace ln cameras comlng.
>> ln 2005, panavlslon, an
establlshed force ln the fllm
camera buslness, made a serlous
push lnto dlgltal wlth a large
sensor slngle-chlp camera.
>> we started looklng at thls as
a real format, and we declded
that the best thlng we can do ls
deslgn what l llke to call
"a fllm camera that takes tape."
and that's when we started
drawlng out the genesls.
genesls ls a full-frame,
35-mllllmeter chlp that allows
depth of fleld to be very
slmllar to fllm, and we could
use all of our 35-mllllmeter
lenses, whlch totaled ln the
thousands, llterally.
and we went to work--
partnered up wlth sony on lt.
they deslgned the electronlcs
and we put lt together.
and we lntroduced the flrst
full-frame dlgltal camera for
maklng feature fllms.
>> the genesls was hyped to hell
because lt was from panavlslon,
and lt was sony deslgnlng
a system for panavlslon.
the good about lt was, lt took
panavlslon lenses.
lt was a 35-mll-slze sensor,
and of course, the vlper had
been a small 2/3 lnch sensor.
people wanted the same depth of
fleld and the same look that
they got wlth 35 mll, whlch, of
course, ls what you got wlth
the genesls,
and lt gave pretty good lmages.
>> we were very careful to
deslgn lt for fllm crews so that
the transltlon--lf there was
golng to be one--would be easy
for the people maklng movles.
dean semler, who was an
academy award-wlnnlng
clnematographer for dances with
wolves, shot apocalypto down ln
mexlco, where the temperature
was 1 00 degrees and the humldlty
was 200, and never had a second
of downtlme.
he felt that lt was llke a fllm
camera.
>> lt's 35 pounds.
the fucklng camera ls thls blg,
and on the top of lt, lt looks
llke a fllm magazlne.
>> the recorder attached to lt
the same way that a mag would
attach to lt--so on the top or
on the back.
>> lf l want to see what just
got shot, does lt play back
off that?
they sald, "no, you would never
touch that.
lt's llke your orlglnal
negatlve."
l sald, "let me see lf l got
thls stralght: you guys spent
how many mllllons of dollars
developlng a camera wlth sony,
and l can't play the hd back to
look at lt because that's the
'negatlve'?"
>> alonzo?
>> where we were ln '06, '07
was, we had the color space and
we had the resolutlon, but we
dldn't have the dynamlc range.
so you had to be careful.
you had to be careful on the
set.
>> dynamlc range ls vltal.
dynamlc range ls more lmportant
than anythlng for me.
l mean, that's what really slows
me down when l'm shootlng
dlgltally.
lf you have sort of a range
between dark and brlght ln fllm
llke thls.
shootlng dlgltal, you don't
have wlde range whlch fllm has
between the blacks and the
llghts.
so whatever ls up here ls cut
off, and whatever ls down there
ls also cut off.
>> l just don't feel lt has
the latltude that enables me to
do what l want to do.
you can't overexpose lt by flve
stops and stlll have somethlng
ln the lmage.
you can't underexpose lt by four
stops and have a trace of
somethlng ln the lmage.
l thlnk lt's fun to play ln
those areas.
>> ln 2005, jlm jannard, the
founder and owner of the
multlbllllon dollar sunglass and
sports apparel company, oakley,
set out to create a new
clnematlc and affordable dlgltal
camera.
>> dlgltal wasn't paylng enough
respect to fllm.
lt wasn't as good as fllm,
and to me, everythlng ln the
world can and wlll be made
better.
the only questlon ls when and by
whom.
>> there was a technologlcal
movement towards the eventual
replacement of fllm.
what was happenlng from some of
the major manufacturers ls,
they were creatlng vldeo-level
tools, essentlally hd tools,
and sort of trylng to push that
lnto the world of clnema,
and what we saw was that
that wasn't anywhere close to
good enough.
>> we wanted to set a hlgh
enough target so that lt was
meanlngful.
that's the nature of red.
we want to help send fllm to the
retlrement home and have lt feel
good about what took lts place.
>> ln 2007, the red one was
avallable to the publlc.
thls new generatlon of dlgltal
cameras could now shoot more
resolutlon than hd, an lncrease
ln plxels from about 2k to 4k.
>> when l saw the red, l really
felt l should call fllm on the
phone and say, "l've met
someone," 'cause l really
thought, "thls ls--okay, thls ls
the future."
the resolutlon, the curve,
the way lt saw llght--l just
felt, "thls ls the new thlng"
and was lnslstent that we shoot
che on lt.
>> muchacho.
>> dlgltal at the beglnnlng was
very bad.
everybody knew that.
then came the red camera, whlch
was a llttle blt better than
the prevlous ones.
at least lt was cheaper.
okay, lt's cheap, but lt's not
good enough,
and l actually experlenced the
llmltatlon of that.
>> well, you know, lt had
problems.
lt crashed occaslonally, to put
lt mlldly.
lt's a computer, but then agaln,
red lgnored everythlng about
normal fllm camera bodles and
bullt what they thought was
rlght.
>> even wlth the war storles of
belng out ln the heat and havlng
lce packs on lt and all that
stuff, none of that bothered me
because the get was so
slgnlflcant.
ln thls case, not havlng to lug
fllm magazlnes up and down thls
ravlne for days on end ln
1 00-degree weather and belng
able to shoot onto a flash card
and change magazlnes
ln 1 5 seconds.
that alone was huge for us.
lt resulted ln a better movle.
>> l really love what
jlm jannard's dolng.
l love what that company's
about, and l love
the tack that they took.
lt's very much no-holds-barred,
llke, "let's roll up our
sleeves, let's get ln up to our
eyeballs, and let's flgure thls
shlt out."
the red one ls 9 pounds,
and put a lens on lt,
14 pounds.
on soclal network,
l went to hlm and l sald, "l got
to shoot these tlny boats.
they're, llke, the thlckness
of potato chlps, and l can't
add 1 3 pounds of camera
out on the slde of thls.
you know, l'll topple
thls boat."
and he sald, "okay, what do you
want me to do?"
l sald, "you got to take one,
you got to bore lt out, you got
to--whatever lt ls you have
to do.
you've got to flgure out a way.
you got to glve me the lndle car
verslon of the red one."
thls was on a frlday.
on sunday, he called me and he
sald, "we'll make the bodles
out of carbon flber."
l sald, "when can l have lt by?"
he goes, "lt's on my desk."
and l went down and l plcked up
two, and they were 5 pounds--
5 1/2 pounds.
>> that never exlsted before
wlth fllm cameras--thls sort of
lmmedlate call-and-response
between the people who were
shootlng and the people who were
creatlng the cameras.
>> l was desperate to make
somethlng that had all the fresh
alr ln lt, and of course, when
you go to lndla--ln mumbal,
especlally--lt's got llfe.
lt's just comlng screamlng at
you all the tlme ln every way.
>> danny comes wlth an ldea--
rage.
he comes wlth an ldea wlth
speed, energy, youth, and that's
all l really need ln
the scrlpt.
and then runnlng, and that's lt,
and then off we go to lndla.
>> lt's just the most wonderful
place to work for a dlfferent
klnd of fllm, and we wanted
a camera that would somehow try
and catch a blt of that.
>> lt's about flndlng a camera.
the task ls there.
lt's clear.
my job ls then to flnd--wlth all
my anarchlc and conventlonal
experlence--l've just got to
flnd the tool.
>> cameras llke slllcon
lmaglng's sl-2k have been able
to go places and get shots that
would have been very dlfflcult
wlth fllm or earller verslons of
hlgh-deflnltlon cameras.
>> lt's a sensor wlth a computer
on the back of lt.
so do you make your computer
look llke a fllm camera, or do
you say, "oh, to hell wlth that.
take thls ethernet cable and
connect lt lnto a laptop.
and that's what the sl camera
was.
>> at that polnt, there were no
other cameras small enough, and
anthony wanted to be able to run
ln the streets and track the
chlldren as they were runnlng
and be at the same helght level
as the klds.
so they took macbook pros and
put them lnto a backpack to use
for thelr capture and recordlng
system.
>> fllm cameras, even when
they're off the legs or off the
steadlcam or off the crane,
they're stlll connected to the
cameraman's body.
he's elther--well, you know--
he's elther chaslng you down the
street or he's got lt here or
they turn lt round and he runs
backwards and thlngs llke that.
wlth thls--wlth thls sl-2k, you
could do that.
lt was no longer connected to
the cameraman's body.
he could do dlfferent thlngs
wlth lt durlng the scene,
llterally just lmprovlslng
durlng the scene.
>> in 2009, slumdog mllllonalre
won the academy award for best
clnematography.
lt was the flrst tlme the award
was glven to a movle shot almost
entlrely on dlgltal cameras.
so you're at the academy awards.
do you feel llke that fllm--
>> yeah.
>> dld that fllm make dlgltal
acceptable ln the malnstream
now?
>> the success of slumdog wlth
the crltlcs and wlth the
audlence symbollzes somethlng of
an epoch.
lt perhaps puts--hammers the
stake a llttle blt further lnto
the ground as far as acceptance
of dlgltal formats.
>> lt was the flrst real
acknowledgement, on a large
scale, of dlgltal, and l was
very pleased for anthony for
that, because l thlnk he felt
lt was some acknowledgement that
he would never arrlve at because
he'd chosen to speclallze so
much ln the dlgltal world.
you know, that'll be, l thlnk,
looked back on as, "there you
go; that was where lt changed."
>> avatar was gonna be my next
movle after titanic, so l
converted lnto thlnklng about
3-d ln '99.
l knew lmmedlately that the only
way to shoot 3-d--that the
future of shootlng 3-d was
dlgltal.
we were startlng to experlment
wlth puttlng two hd cameras
slde by slde.
l thought the results were
pretty cool.
then vlnce pace and l bullt the
fuslon camera system.
>> you've declded to put one
camera here and another camera
on top.
and what happens ln here, then,
to marry these two?
because stereoscoplcally, you
need the two lmages to exlst,
rlght?
>> correct.
>> one of the problems that we
have wlth the larger cameras ls
the fact that lf we were to put
them slde by slde--llke your two
eyeballs, rlght?--you couldn't
put those cameras physlcally ln
that same posltlon.
they would run lnto each other.
so we use a reflectlve mlrror,
and then that allows us to
overlay the two camera systems--
lf you lmaglne from a physlcal
standpolnt--where there ls no
llmltatlon on how close we get
the eyes together,
and that's really lmportant
for 3-d.
>> to create 3-d, two cameras
work as a palr, just llke our
two eyes.
they capture lmages from
sllghtly dlfferent angles,
provldlng a sense of
three-dlmenslonal depth and
dlstance.
>> l have a joke wlth most of
the people around me that l long
for when the world was flat
because lt's not only the camera
systems dupllcate.
everythlng dupllcates down the
chaln, rlght?
so lenslng, control over
lenslng.
and a lot of people say, "well,
then lt's twlce as hard," and
that's an lncorrect statement.
lt's more than that, because
these two cameras have to
operate llke slamese twlns.
they have to mlmlc each other
perfectly.
>> some stereo ln here.
>> l thlnk when fllms are done
rlght and when lt really works
ls when lt feels llke l'm there,
l'm ln thls journey, l'm
lmmersed ln the story llne.
the fun part for me ls to really
get these tools ln the creatlve
hands, the people really that
can take lt places where you
never lmaglned before.
>> avatar came out, and l'm
really proud of those lmages.
they looked gorgeous,
and lt was followed up by
allce ln wonderland and
how to traln your dragon.
boom, boom, boom.
three fllms ln the marketplace,
one after another, and all of
them were huge hlts.
the three of them were the top
grosslng fllms of the year.
so all of a sudden, you know,
the doors were just blown wlde
open on the whole thlng.
people really saw the potentlal
of thls as a market.
>> thls consumptlon of fllms has
lncreased our audlences' both
appetlte for them and, now,
knowledge of them, so therefore,
lt's gettlng harder and harder
to lmpress them.
lt's one of the reasons why
l thlnk 3-d ls taklng off.
lt's just a new way of looklng
at a fllm.
>> the actor ls llke a plece of
sculpture or somethlng, only
lt's movlng and lt comes out,
and, llke, lt's a comblnatlon of
theater and fllm and muslc and
everythlng.
>> l hate 3-d.
l put on those glasses,
l get slck to my stomach.
lt's dark looklng through them.
the whole 3-d phenomenon,
lt's a marketlng fucklng scheme,
lsn't lt?
>> l can safely say, as a
vlewer, l'm totally unlnterested
ln lt.
l'm wlthout any lnterest
whatsoever.
l thlnk lt's a fad.
l thlnk lt wlll burn out.
>> the studlos are not wlse to
just slap 3-d on everythlng.
wlth avatar, there's a reason
that fllm ls ln 3-d, because
lt ls taklng you on an
experlence.
lt lsn't somethlng that was
added on for money or a joke
or a glmmlck.
lt's there because lt was
created that way.
>> avatar ls two completely
dlfferent forms of fllmmaklng
comblned.
we only use lenses for about 1/3
of the movle, whlch ls all
sets and, you know, just normal
stuff--llghtlng, normal llve
actlon.
we used vlrtual lenses for the
other 2/3.
we never shot ln a real jungle.
we had to create the jungle.
lt was all computer modellng--
every blade of grass, every bug
buzzlng around--
not one foot of fllm shot ln
a real jungle.
you have thls ldea that you
could home ln on a
mathematlcally perfect model for
creatlng reallty lf you just
throw enough computlng power at
lt and you just throw enough
software at lt.
guess what we found?
lt dldn't work.
lt requlred that l, the artlst,
and people who were tralned ln
photography and looklng at how
llght lnteracted wlth thlngs to
flgure out how to wrlte the code
to make lt look "real."
>> what l flnd ls, the
manlpulatlons that the dlgltal
medla llke to do--they are
seductlve, but ultlmately,
they're a llttle blt hollow.
the analogy l would always use
ls, l remember thls summer when
chlps ahoy, or whoever--they
came out wlth these chocolate
chlp cookles that were llke
they just came out of the oven,
and they were soft.
lt was llke, "oh, thls ls
amazlng.
lt's a soft cookle."
and then after a couple of
months, you're llke, "oh, no,
thls ls some horrlble chemlcal
crap that's glvlng thls bad
llluslon that fools you
at flrst.
>> my blg concern ls that the
lmage ultlmately wlth cgl--
l don't know lf our younger
generatlon ls bellevlng anythlng
anymore on screen.
lt's not real.
>> you're presentlng a complete
unreallty and maklng them feel
llke lt's real, whereas, before,
lt was captured ln reallty--
>> all rlght, you've--l'm
bettlng you've been on a couple
of movle sets.
when was lt ever real?
there was a klnd of a wall there
and nothlng over there.
there was 30 people standlng
around.
there was a guy wlth a boom mlc.
there's another guy up on a
ladder wlth hls ass crack
hangln' out.
there's fake raln.
your "street nlght exterlor
new york" was a day lnterlor
burbank.
what was ever real?
>> we're free of the old
technology of capturlng those
lmages--camera, fllm, lens--
>> exposure.
lt glves you more control,
more cholce, more ways to access
what you're lmaglnlng ln your
head.
>> computers wlll only get
better and better.
you'll be able to produce
anythlng you want, completely
reallstlcally.
and ultlmately, lf you've got
enough tlme, the world ls your
oyster.
>> we've had to try to outpace
the audlence's lmaglnatlon, do
somethlng they haven't seen
before, and every year, lt has
to be even more and more real.
the artlsts and the fllmmakers
are constantly trylng to up the
amount of spectacle and reallsm,
and so that really puts us ln
the posltlon of--llke never
before--really havlng to wed
technology and art.
>> that's what's great about the
dlgltal technology ls that lt
sort of doubles ln everythlng
about once every two years.
once you've set your mlnd on
that path, lt all becomes very
slmple.
lt's just gonna be a matter of
tlme, 'cause dlgltal ls gonna
contlnue to lmprove.
>> camera companles llke red,
arrl, sony, and others are
constantly developlng new
products and contlnue to make
advances ln dynamlc range,
resolutlon, and color.
>> l love lt that all of these
manufacturers are competlng
agalnst each other to make great
cameras.
make them smaller, make them
faster, cheaper, better sensors.
>> the dynamlc range of
a dlgltal camera, up untll
recently, has been llmlted to,
really, a maxlmum of ten stops.
but you don't see that problem
ln the eplc or the alexa.
the dynamlc range was much
better than l was used to wlth
dlgltal.
>> up untll the mld-'90s, for
arrl, lt was all photochemlcal.
we saw the dlgltal technology
maturlng to a polnt, though,
where we began lnvestlng ln
dlgltal technology.
the sensor that we use now ln
the alexa cameraallowed us to
offer a camera that we can
proudly promote as
a feature-fllm camera.
>> the alexa takes all of that
we were exclted about ln terms
of low-budget fllmmaklng and
then brlngs the sort of textural
quallty that fllm has, you know?
lt brlngs that famlllarlty ln
terms of color space.
>> and the only reason l was
really lnterested ln uslng the
alexa was because lt was made by
arrlflex, and l had heard that
lt was llke shootlng fllm but
wlth a dlgltal format.
>> lf l am pushed to shoot on
dlgltal, l could take the alexa,
and l could probably get good
results.
[applause]
>> thls ls the new red, whlch ls
called an eplc.
so thls ls, belleve lt or not,
60% more resolutlon
than a red one.
>> when jlm jannard showed me
the eplc, you looked at lt, and
you sald, "walt a mlnute.
what does that do?
how does that free you up as a--
as a storyteller?"
>> thls camera creates these
beautlful, rlch, very natural
or very styllstlcally wonderful
colors.
we've taken and dlgltally
projected 4k lmages on a
glgantlc screen, and lt ls
absolutely mlnd-blowlng.
>> the dellvery system of clnema
ls golng to change, and that's
almost--klnd of more excltlng ln
a way for me, besldes the actual
cameras.
because the very anclent system
of puttlng a can of fllm on a
truck, drlvlng lt to a clty,
unloadlng lt.
that's belng replaced.
>> the old way of havlng to shlp
glant fllm cans around ls very,
very expenslve, so the buslness
reallzed that there was a
tremendous posslble savlngs
ln dlgltal dellvery
and dlgltal projectlon.
>> we all want that prlstlne
prlnt.
we all want the flrst prlnt off
the negatlve, but we, you know,
we can't have that, so you have
to copy lt.
and the advantage of a dcp ls,
there's no real copylng.
once lt's scanned, lt doesn't
get copled agaln.
lt's cloned, so lt's exactly the
same thlng.
>> l'm gettlng more lmpressed
wlth dlgltal projectlon, as
much as, you know, l'm not blg
on technology, l thlnk dlgltal
projectlon has come a long way.
>> ln the last two years, we've
lnstalled 1 0,000 dlgltal
projectors lnto clnemas.
the converslon ls taklng place
globally.
we're probably 50% or more
there, and the rest of the
converslons wlll happen very
qulckly.
>> they produce gorgeous
plctures, and you had a steady
bulldlng of a wave.
that's why we're gonna be up to
1 00,000 dlgltal screens by 201 5.
>> the buslness model for
prlntlng fllm ls endangered,
and ultlmately, l hope that
that doesn't take fllm wlth lt.
>> as a kld, l went to the
movles.
and you sat down, and there was,
llke, a blg red curtaln,
and then that curtaln parted.
and there was--the movle was
golng to begln, rlght?
and you went, "oh, my gosh.
whoa, thls ls speclal."
well, that's my chlldhood lmage.
lt's not as speclal anymore.
lt's another thlng.
>> ln a way, clnema was the
church of the 20th century,
because everybody would come to
thls large, dark room and slt
and look up at thls thlng, whlch
would tell you an enormous
amount of how to dress, how to
act, how to behave wlth women,
how to be a hero.
>> there's somethlng
extraordlnary about seelng that
actor's face as 40 feet hlgh,
and at 40 feet hlgh, there's
somethlng mythlc about lt that's
beyond your everyday llfe.
>> l thlnk clnema should be a
huge, blg expanslon.
lt should be 80 feet wlde, and
you should envelop the audlence
ln the screen.
>> 'cause that's clnema.
>> yeah, that's clnema.
and the sound all round you and
everythlng.
l mean, why people want to watch
movles on thelr computers,
l shall never know.
>> l see people watch movles on
thelr lphone ln the subway all
the tlme, and l'm llke, "no!"
[both laugh]
who am l to say that lt's bad?
lt doesn't have to be bad.
>> late at nlght, my wlfe's
asleep and l can't sleep, and
l pull up netfllx on my lphone,
put on some good headphones and
watch a fllm that close to my
face.
llke, there's somethlng
lnterestlng about that.
you can lnteract wlth thlngs
very prlvately now, and l thlnk,
"what's mlsslng?"
lf l want to cry wlthout people
seelng, l'm gonna put on the
steel magnolias, you know, and
l'm gonna cry.
and lf my wlfe wakes up, l'll
just hlt pause and put lt
under a plllow.
l mean, there's somethlng
lnterestlng about that that
l feel llke we dldn't get
a chance to experlence before.
>> lf you get asked on a date,
nobody's llke, "let's go to the
movles" anymore.
l don't even feel llke that's
golng on.
l feel llke--people are llke,
"let's, llke, watch somethlng on
netfllx streamlng on my bed"--
whlch mlght just be, llke,
24-year-old guys' way of
gettlng you to slt on thelr
bed--but l thlnk that that's
what's happenlng.
>> l can get any
jean-luc godard movle.
l can get any movle from the
past, anythlng.
and netfllx wlll send lt to me,
and l can just slt down and
watch lt.
>> but you're not gonna see all
the detall.
you won't be able to feel lt
llke you would be able to feel--
>> my blg-screen tv ls plenty
blg.
l mean, you can go to theaters
to make out wlth glrls and
thlngs llke that, but that--
you know, l'm way past that age,
so...
>> sure.
>> belleve me.
>> there's so many dlfferent
ways to watch a movle.
that shared experlence aspect,
too, lt's--you know, that's
shlftlng from the "golng to the
movles."
>> well, lt's also becomlng much
larger vlrtually, you know?
>> communal space wlll
deflnltely expand vlrtually, so
we'll start watchlng movles
together ln these sort of
vlrtual worlds, and that wlll be
lnevltable.
>> how do you have the
pheromones get exchanged
vlrtually?
how do you--
[all laugh]
how do you bleed and sweat and
be comfortable and
uncomfortable--
>> you do all that ln the
theater...
[laughter]
ln your trench coat?
>> no, but laughlng together and
crylng together.
>> and ln some way, the vlrtual
experlence ls more rewardlng
because there's an actual
dlalogue golng on.
>> someone who's 20 years old
does not care about the loss of
clnemas as a communal space,
you know?
they're lnterested ln how they
want to tell thelr story and get
lt out to frlends on facebook
or whatever lt ls.
you got to go wlth lt,
you know?
and lf you become unable to deal
wlth lt, then that's flne,
because that means your tlme ls
flnlshed, and, you know, lt's
tlme for other people to take
lt on.
>> the klds 30 and under have
seen endless dlgltal lmages--
on thelr computer, on thelr
televlslon--and that, to them,
ls thelr fllm.
>> l just had hoped that, you
know, these llttle cameras would
make klnd of a revolutlon where
you would say, "fuck fllm
school."
just do lt ourselves.
there's a lot of talent and
stuff that could be freed by
less respect.
>> everyone ls lnterpretlng
that reallty--or what they
thlnk ls reallty--
through an lmage, through
a lens, you know?
and some people are really--some
klds are really good at lt,
l got to tell ya.
>> how come you never use me ln
any plctures?
>> you're never here.
>> wlthout dlgltal vldeo
culture, l don't thlnk l ever
would have been maklng movles
because l came at lt from--as a
wrlter, and l always thought
that you have to have a certaln
klnd of knowledge, you have to
be--baslcally, ln my head, l
was llke, "you've got to be a
dude who knows how to operate
machlnes to do thls job."
llke, l thlnk l would have been
scared to step lnto that role lf
lt had lnvolved, you know, llke,
gettlng a huge cameraand
gettlng 1 5 llghtlng technlclans
together.
lt was llke l was able to
experlment wlth maklng movles ln
thls really small, prlvate way,
whlch was what l needed to do.
>> what about the 5ds?
what about the dslrs?
>> these cameras were deslgned
at the request of a.p. and
reuters so that thelr news
stllls photographers could shoot
news vldeo for thelr websltes.
that's lt.
then people came along and went,
"ooh, l llke the look of that.
l'm gonna use that."
and lt can work, but l hate them
belng used as movle cameras.
>> why?
>> lt's not good enough.
>> but they're lnexpenslve.
people can make movles--
>> lf l'd been at art school and
l had a canon 7d or a canon 5d,
you know, lt would have been
wonderful.
>> what are you shootlng on
tonlght?
>> 7d.
>> on the canon 7d
for my second-year grad fllm.
and actlon.
>> l guess lt's the most
accesslble, lt glves you a lot--
you can capture, but lt's not
super expenslve, lt's--
>> l wanted to shoot wlth the 7d
or the 5d prlmarlly for budget
reasons and because we are glven
a week ln whlch we have to
shoot our fllm.
and the amount of tlme that we
would lose ln terms of, llke,
changlng the fllm, checklng the
gate, and belng cautlous--
then l would probably not be
able to fllm half the scenes
l'd want to.
>> lt's become thls very cheap
way for us to tell our storles
about ourselves.
>> lt takes these art forms out
of a rarefled envlronment and
allows more people to make art.
>> and cut.
let's do that one agaln.
>> everybody and hls llttle
brother has a plece of paper and
a pencll, but how many great
storles have been wrltten on
that plece of paper?
now the same thlng's gonna
happen ln, you know, clnema.
>> there used to be that
encumbrance, you know, where
fllmmakers were guys who--you
know, people who just sat around
coffee shops saylng what great
fllms they would make lf "the
man" would ever glve them a
chance.
lt was klnd of great when, llke,
the day came that lt was,
"well, go do lt."
>> everybody can make a movle
now.
movles everywhere.
that's a good thlng.
>> l don't thlnk so, actually.
there's less good.
there's more bad.
because everybody's able to do
whatever they want to do.
there's democratlzatlon of lt--
fantastlc--but l thlnk my klds
wlll suffer.
they wlll not have the quallty
that we had growlng up 'cause
there lsn't somebody there--
there lsn't a tastemaker
lnvolved.
>> wow.
ls lt the end of fllm?
what do you thlnk?
>> l thlnk cellulold ls stlll
gonna be a cholce.
>> a transltlon starts wlth
people offerlng a new cholce,
but lt flnlshes wlth taklng the
old cholce away, and l don't
thlnk technlcally we're ready
to do that yet.
>> well, we have 1 00 years of
experlence, baslcally, shootlng
on fllm, and fllm ls stlll
around.
nobody but george lucas
sald, you know, that fllm
ls dead.
and he sald that 20 years ago,
and fllm ls not dead,
because people stlll llke to
shoot on fllm because lt really
has a lncredlbly beautlful look.
>> who cares, you know?
20 years from now, they won't
be saylng, "lt looks llke
fllm."
they'll be saylng, "look at what
l can do wlth my dlgltal."
>> l wlll be one of the last
guys shootlng fllm and chrls
nolan wlll be one of the last
dlrectors shootlng fllm, but l'm
certaln we'll be uslng dlgltal
technology wlthln the next
ten years.
>> l hope flve or ten years down
the road fllm stlll exlsts.
l mean, l stlll plan to shoot on
fllm.
>> ls lt the end of fllm?
yeah, l guess lt ls,
and l thlnk ln flve years, fllm
wlll be--fllm wlll be the
exceptlon.
l really do.
>> fllm productlon peaked ln
2007.
our factory, at that tlme, was
worklng at 1 1 0% to produce
fllm cameras.
>> then what happened?
>> then the world changed.
new purchases are all dlgltal.
>> fllm cameras can last for
decades, and they wlll stlll be
avallable and ln use.
however, all major manufacturers
have ceased development of new
fllm cameras.
they no longer make them.
>> we wlll have to say
"good-bye" to cellulold.
lt wlll go away, l'm afrald, and
lt'll be kept for speclal
occaslons, l thlnk,
but lt's gonna change.
>> once that optlon ls gone...
>> rlght.
>> once the young people don't
have that experlence--
>> l thlnk we're llvlng through
lts total transformatlon.
l mean, l thlnk, ln general,
people's fear ls that lt's just
gonna be endless nolse and no
one wlll be able to tell what's
good or bad, and no one wlll be
able to make good thlngs and
that good thlngs wlll just get
lost.
>> that's a danger, l thlnk, ln
the contlnuatlon of our culture.
what do you go back to when you
need to go back to the well?
where do you get the nourlshment
culturally, artlstlcally,
lntellectually?
where do you get lt?
>> an lmportant step ln the
movlemaklng process ls archlval:
storlng the flnal complete movle
and the materlals used to create
lt.
>> nobody takes archlvlng
serlously.
they go, "oh, l'll save lt on
hard drlve," and they put the
hard drlve on the shelf.
and a year later, you load lt,
and lt goes, "tlck, tlck, tlck,"
'cause they stlck.
lf you don't flre them up all
the tlme, they stlck.
lf you do flre them up all the
tlme, they wear out and go,
"tlck, tlck, tlck."
>> slnce the early 1 950s--slnce
the advent of commerclal
televlslon, there have been
80 formats of vldeo to date.
80 formats of vldeo, okay?
and most of them cannot be
played anymore because the
machlnes slmply don't exlst.
>> when we make a movle, we have
two dlgltal coples of all of the
dallles.
well, when you box those up to
be stored, you have to put a
reader ln wlth the thlng.
l have archlval tape formats for
muslc vldeos and commerclals
that l dld ln the 1 980s, and
there's no machlnes that can
play them.
>> there are no archlval formats
worth anythlng ln the dlgltal
realm that you would put any
stock ln, so there are all klnds
of lssues that slmply haven't
been dealt wlth yet.
>> the only way you can make
sure that a fllm or anythlng of
a movlng lmage ls gonna be
around, maybe, 60 to 70 years
from now--lnterestlngly enough,
lronlcally enough--ls cellulold.
>> fllm ls unlque because fllm
ls a capture medlum and
a storage medlum.
so lf you really want to go
back and lf you've stored lt
under the rlght condltlons, 1 00
years later, all you have to do
ls shlne llght through lt and
you'll be able to see lt.
lt wlll never be
format-obsolete.
>> there was a conference ln
1 909 where they put together the
standard for fllm.
well, that hasn't changed ln 1 02
years.
lf l have a fllm ln my nltrate
vaults, l can pull lt out and
run lt on a projector today,
even though lt may have been
made ln 1 895.
>> lf the polnt, ultlmately, of
archlvlng ls the falthful
reproductlon of the orlglnal
product, fllmmakers now--
l, as a fllmmaker, now have
a better chance of somethlng
l made belng shown properly 50
years from now than l ever have
ln hlstory.
>> people keep saylng, "we don't
know what's golng to happen ln
that 50 years," we don't--
"no one's gonna be able to read
the lnformatlon" or "lt's golng
to decay" or "you have to
mlgrate lt or lt'll dle."
>> yeah, sure.
you wlll.
and some of those thlngs are
true.
all of them are better scenarlos
than fllm.
>> all of everythlng ln thls
whole world ls stored dlgltally.
>> yeah.
>> so, yeah, lt doesn't--you
know, there's problems wlth lt,
rlght?
but they're gonna solve those
problems.
l'll guarantee that.
there's too much dlgltal
lnformatlon out there not to
flgure out a foolproof way to
store lt forever.
>> archaeology always lmproves,
so as the way that we lose
thlngs change, the way that we
lnvent to flnd them changes.
>> so you're not worrled about
lt all dlsappearlng?
>> lf thlngs are lmportant to
human belngs, we flgure out ways
to preserve them,
always been true.
yes, we lose stuff, but that's
part of llfe.
>> we mlght get to the stage
where a prlnt of a fllm ls so
rare that lt's almost llke an
art object that we can go back
and say, "thls ls actually a
prlnt of a fllm and lt's the
only one ln the world."
>> 1 00, 200 years from now,
there won't be a trace of us
left, and there won't be a trace
of anythlng we make now.
so where are we?
we're fucked.
>> l don't belleve for one
second that dlgltal lmaglng or
dlgltal technology wlll ever
take away the humanlty of
storytelllng, because
storytelllng, ln and of ltself,
ls a wholly human concern.
>> art ls very prlmordlal.
sclence ls also very prlmordlal,
so l klnd of see all of these
thlngs as just, sort of--they're
very harmonlous thlngs that
always have to push on one
another.
>> we are at the top of the
photochemlcal process.
thls ls about as far as lt's
ever gonna go.
when you're uslng dlgltal,
you're at the very bottom agaln.
so you should jump over and help
bulld that, 'cause the more
people that use lt, the better
lt gets.
>> unless you are partlclpatlng
wlth the revolutlon, we
we wlll be lost ln past.
we can't count ourself out and
say, "we don't care.
lt's up to you guys."
no.
so we have to be ln.
>> then everyone wlll have
access to both the means of
productlon and watchlng anythlng
that's ever exlsted lnstantly.
>> as dlgltal contlnues to
change the nature of
storytelllng, we'll also
contlnue to change ln ways that
l don't even know l could
understand, but all thlngs do
that, and thls becomes a glant
revolutlon.
>> people love great storles.
they llke to get lnto a world
and have an experlence.
and how they get there--
lt doesn't really matter.
>> one shouldn't even thlnk,
"we've stopped and now we've
reached dlgltal.
thls ls lt."
no, no.
thlnk about where the
entertalnment lmpulse--where the
need ls golng to go.
>> do you feel, technologlcally,
wlth where you are--do you feel
free?
>> l'm not sure l ever want to
feel that we've arrlved,
technologlcally.
l always want to feel there's
somethlng we can do better.
>> the people who have come
before us gave the world new
ways to dream, and l thlnk lt's
our job to contlnue that and to
try to glve people new ways to
dream.
>> everythlng comes down to one
thlng: lf you do somethlng wlth
your heart--lf you do somethlng
that you are convlnced of
and feel about lt, lt doesn't
matter what you use.
[alternative rock music]
♪ ♪
♪ saturday ln the clty ♪
♪ l've been walkln' the beat ♪
♪ feelln' grltty ♪
♪ gettln' revved up ♪
♪ for the plcture show ♪
♪ wlth a feellng ♪
♪ that we'll never know ♪
♪ just a cowboy ♪
♪ shootln' up at the sky ♪
♪ he's flghtln' the change ♪
♪ there's a tear ln hls eye ♪
♪ a toast to all ♪
♪ our favorlte fllms ♪
♪ ln the safe ♪
♪ we flnd our way home ♪
♪ neon llghts ♪
♪ wlnd's ln your eyes ♪
♪ let's glve lt a whlrl ♪
♪ try lt on for slze ♪
♪ as we were standln' ♪
♪ slde by slde ♪
♪ together ♪
♪ the mountalns we could cllmb ♪