Introduction
Who am I? City Hunter is my nickname
fighting crimes is the game.
I work alone I'm a private detective.
My sidekick comes along also
But, I'm better at kung fu and much cuter...
smarter too.
I'm taller as well.
He's too humble.
Oh! we're best friends. We have been through a lot.
Invincible!
One time when he was alone he did slip
up though...  big time. Huh?
You're shot!
Are you okay? How do you feel?
How would you feel if you're hit by 20 shots?
Hey, you have to try, promise you won't die.
Um... there is one thing...
Take care of my cousin Kaori, I'd appreciate it.
Ok, because you're a pal, I'll do it.
It can't be any worse of getting shot.
One more thing, never seduce her.
No! I swear on it, scouts honor.
Ok, I can die in peace.
So sad...
From that day forward, Kaori became my only family.
One thing I had overlooked however,
was how quickly little girls grow up.
One second they're cute innocent youngsters,
than you turn your back on them for a moment and...
Not fair.
Why did I ever swear that I wouldn't seduce Kaori?
I bet if he was still alive
my old friend would understand if I did?
Not.
Because of the promise I made,
Kaori has never been more than my assistant.
And I never suspected how she truly felt about me.
Until one day...
Why doesn't he answer?
Come on, wake up now.
Come on, you're too lazy, get up.
You won't do it, prefer to get a little wet...
no pool in here, so you're not drowning, are ya?
City Hunter tell me, won't your girlfriend get
jealous if you're here with us?
What, her? She's not a girlfriend at all...
Right now she's at home cleaning the toilet.
You mean me? I'm doing what?
Tell us about your job.
So fat I have to carry her on a wagon and...
Oh! she likes to eat.
She has seven meals daily.
And she misbehaves very bad.
Then, when she wakes up, she wants to go out.
Tongue out, paws up, back and forth.
She's useless, I'd give her away
but I feel too sorry for her.
Impossible!
Do it.
Wake up, will you? Come on,
I'm tired of holding your head up.
He's City Hunter, I'm his assistant Kaori.
Mr. Imamura set for us.
Wake up, you're in the middle of an office
and you haven't stirred yet, understand?
Wake up!
Will anything wake you?
That aroma, such perfect skin.
You're a model I'd guess? - Oh, no.
Then what?
A secretary.
Fascinating.
Somebody call my tailor.
Day dreaming?
What do you care?
As to why I brought you here,
I'm Mr. Imamura, owner of Imamura newspaper.
My daughter Kiyoko.
She lost her mother early, and I brought the girl up alone.
She's an only child and is a bit rebellious
I met a woman last year, we're in love with
each other and we intend to wed.
Kiyoko coudn't stand the idea and ran away.
After a very discreet probe,
we learned she was staying in Hong Kong.
I suppose you'll pay for her return.
You aren't to use any force, or to harm her.
He's extremely gentle with the pretty ones.
I know. But have you seen her anywhere?
Perhaps you'd like a shirt.
Where?
Or would you rather a surprise?
What skateboarding you say? What park? What gang is that?
Olsen Park?
Got it.
Ever been on the ocean?
Ok.
A voyage at sea and all around stars.
Yeah, you know it. Stay in touch now, will ya? Yeah OK.
Were you saying something?
You never hear a thing I say.
Ah!  how can you... Ahhh!
Have another pina colada.
I'll go to Olsen Park. You check all the
amusment galleries and beauty parlors.
Go ahead.
Oh, and don't slam the door.
If you see her, call.
You drive me nuts!
That's it. Great. Like your car?
Well, I don't like it.
Think you got the right to the whole road?
Yeah, that's right. Back off!
Who cares about your birthday?
So when are you and me going out?
We aren't going out. Just forget that.
Come on, we need to disco.
We'll go dancing another time.
Sorry.
Hey! a bit of good luck. I found you pretty fast.
What?
Come along, and just go quiet, ok?
My nose oow oow oow Huh?
Wait a minute!
What's the matter?
That man tryed to molest me, stop him. Huh?
That's far enough. Huh?
Bastard stole it.
Go on!
Oh! Beg your pardon.
Hi, there. Pretty.
Excuse me. Hey, there sexy. You got a minute?
You, Ah?
You, Ah? You bet, handsome.
Alright.
I'm starving.
I haven't eaten all day.
Are you here or not?
Gotta' chow down.
My poor stomach. Huh?
My birthday?
So sad... My birthday and nothing to eat.
A cracker.
Kaori, make me some lunch.
Surprise! It's your birthday!
Happy Birthday!
How fun.
You're all really here.
City Hunter!
Who are you?
Have we met?
It doesn't matter.
I want some cake.
No, once I've tied you up you can taste it.
Let's go for it, come on.
Whatever you girls want.
What? Try again. That was a little high.
You should try again. We've never met you before today.
Is that right? Well glad to know you all.
You put all of our men into jail.
Now you'll pay.
Go on.
Wait. Hold it.
We got him now. Grab him.
Hey!
Lay down your weapons. Don't move.
Surprise
Oh, good.
Who are those women?
Huh? Them?
They're a bunch of murderesses. That's who they are.
Yeah, and I guess you're scared to death. You got a gun.
Hmm? This?
Who is she? That girl.
Really?
Here catch, birthday boy.
You're despicable.
I'll sail away on a cruise. I won't be back.
Hey! wait Kaori.
Ugh! I'll give you what for.
A hero drop the gun.
Good.
You'll find out what I've got.
You were right... City Hunter is such a stupid fool.
Squinty eyed. Losing his hair. His ears are huge.
He's tiring.
Now I have great charm. he's clumsy.
A new fashion?
I'll take ya.. both on
I'm sorry.
Look who's taking a vacation
Now I'd guess that you guys are all sharing a state room.
You should really shine your head a little more often.
Where as You will always be ugly.
Are you familiar with all your pressure points
like the one in your back?
Ooh! Lost your pants.
Kaori.
Hey! wait for me.
I'll be right there.
Come on, foxy lady.
Hi, I was getting worried.
We don't wanna be late.
Sorry. Let's hurry.
Why is God so cruel?
He's cute. Who's the guy?
He's City Hunter. A big fool.
Ooh! a private eye?
He's a pain in the ass, really.
Kaori... Hey!
Go right on board.
You have something you'd like to show me?
There you go.
This is gum. I need to see your pass.
Right you are. Invitation, please.
A magician, that's great.
Wait. There's something odd.
Mah Jong club membership?
I really hate it when this happens.
Thanks.
Oh! I need to eat something.
I'm so clever.
Oh! I'm starving.
Ah, Beg your pardon. Where do I eat?
Ah, Yes, you...
I'll be going. Wait.
Don't panic the passengers, but get that stowaway
Hey, there. Drink?
Anyone? Care for a drink?
Thank you.
You looked upr her skirt
You're filthy.
No don't step on the bread.
Are you blind?
I demand you apologize. Go on.
There he is. Go that way.
Here.
You see him? - No.  Odd.
We can't give up.
Look everywhere. Right.
A ship! Blow the siren now!
Ay.
Wow.
Beautiful room.
Put away the luggage.
Gimme a hand.
You fall again?
I always lose my balance.
Yeah. Up you go.
You know what? I like living in style.
I heard this boat is filled with lots of single guys.
Yeah, what if one came along  who is rich and is just perfect?
Hey now, what is your mission?
I provide you with a cover.
I forgot. Is there a reward if you solve this case?
Sure there is.
If our information about a gang robbing
the boat is correct and we stop them.
We get our money once they're caught?
I was sent to investigate by my superiors.
To see if the information is right.
Did you bring me a gun?
Sure thing.
Watch it. Don't hit me.
You're late.
We got caught in traffic.
Hey, what a beautiful room.
This is gonna do perfectly.
You bastard. I'm gonna warn you once. Don't be late again.
Don't get uptight. Just relax.
And lets Try to enjoy ourselves.
Till midnight.
Always having your mouth full won't attract a lot of men.
I'm hungry. I coudn't wait.
Am I at a convention or mimes or is my hearing gone bad?
Must have been the fall I took Ahh! Food.
Hey, there's that cute guy.
He looks like he's lost, doesn't he?
He's barely human. In fact he's repulsive.
Hi!
Be more discreet!
Embarassed? Ha!
He is reputed to be an infamous sex feind.
I never met a man who wasn't.
He's always flirting.
He'll need some training.
No money at all.
Hamburger, come back. I want mine on a bun.
Nice, huh?
Yeah.
Just wait. They'll be ours.
That way. Hurry up... Come on.
Sorry.
But why? You know that we're supposed
to be lovers. It's written in the stars up above.
And will vow never to let the name
of City Hunter be spoken. Never again.
You know that he'll come to find me.
He can't. How could even get here?
He gonna fly? We're at sea!
Kaori.
Hurry, protect me.
Move and die.
Who is that?
Where are your six girlfriends?
Couldn't they come?
Are you talking? I can't hear one thing.
You know him. My cousin says go away.
Oh, it's scary. Not a single thing is getting in.
You're absolutely right. You refuse to hear.
Will I return?
You reform, no more flirting.
You can't sleep with other girls.
And you treat me like a queen.
I can't hear a single thing. Please repeat it.
Bastard. You're being so cruel.
Watch it, buddy.
If my cousin weren't here, I'd put you on the floor.
Cowards quake when they face the Dragon's Claw.
Huh! Yeah
Let's go.
Watch it.
- That's true.
- Honest?
- Yeah. I slept with them all.
- Everyone? The whole team?
Not with the coach.
I can hear everything now.
Mine's eight.
Banker has nine. Banker wins.
Alright!
Nine, won.
Didn't I tell you? He is a winner.
Yeah. Just you watch. You stay with the banker.
Welcome. Ah, wait, it doesn't make any sense at all.
Why stay in separate rooms?
You know that all great love affairs
must be given an opportunity.
And ours is no different.
My room, or better yours?
Alright, you sleep in my room.
Alright.
And I'll stay in yours.
Oh, she is gone.
But, no. I will still woo her for eternity.
It doesn't matter. A soul as pure as mine
will never feel despirited.
I'm gonna make love to you, baby. Cause I'm so potent.
Potent. I'm a potent hunk of man.
And I'm gonna show you all my charms.
You're Jane and I'm your Tarzan.
I'll possess her. On a chariot ride straight to heaven.
Go man, you'll get her someday.
Let's do a little gambling.
Don't forget, we're on a mission.
Oh, spoil sport. We can be looking for clues when we've won.
That man right there is cute. He could be wealthy.
Oh, he is. And I can tell you something else.
I know that he's dangerous.
But, gorgeous.
He means trouble.
In fact, murders another thing he plays.
It's a seven.
Huh? Yeah, yeah.
An eight, he wins.
You win again? I think you cheat.
I was polite. But losers are.
- Search him.
- Yes, sir.
Alright.
Stop! What's going on?
Self defense. Here, it's a tip.
Put this out, will ya?
And cash me out, please.
It's alright. Ok.
Thanks very much.
Your ace fell.
Yep, um, It's all yours. Bye.
Hey? Why did he have to give that card to you?
Good taste Dear.
Hm! Yeah right!
We must all pick the time.
Twenty nine minutes until midnight.
In twenty nine minutes we begin.
I want team A in place in 4 minutes Ted.
Got it, boss.
Mike, you and team B will start in 9 minutes.
Right.
While we watch some beautiful girls. Sounds good... Yeah!
Your balls are in a knot.
Come morning you're gonna be rich men so keep cool.
Beter listen up, he's got a full proof plan.
Ok.
I have sixty names written down on this page.
All of them are millionaires.
We grab them and their money as well.
What about the others?
Well, the sharks get hungry. So throw 'em some food.
Take a look over there.
Yes, boss.
Let's go.
Who's there?
Room service.
In a minute.
It's open.
What's the matter, miss? Is something wrong?
There is. In the next cabin.
I couldn't hear everything, but one came after me.
Now come down a minute.
I would be glad to help in any way miss.
You don't appreciate the danger we're in.
I'm sure I can help you. Are you a little bit sea sick?
There are armed dangerous terrorists on the boat.
May I ask you how you know this?
I could hear their voices.
They're getting ready to start right now.
I better get you to the Captain.
He'll wanna hear about this.
Watch your step.
I'm starving to death.
Huh... Huh?
D-Ahhh! It's a rat. Yaaaoo!
Wow, my prays were answer to snack at last.
Uh? Where's the Captain?
Up in the nightclub.
Why did you bring me here?
You mentioned that you thought
you overheard some terrorists.
Yes, sir.
I'm one of them.
You...
We'll take all the rich men on board to Thailand.
You... you scum.
Sorry, pretty girl.
Sorry.
What a blow. Who are ya?
I am City Hunter.
Gimme your hands. Hold this.
That was dinner.
Wait.
Halt.
Don't move. I'll shoot him, I swear.
Kiyoko, go away.
Good idea.
Shoot them.
NO!
Huh? Two bullets, cheap skates!
Attention! Intercept the couple. The're clothed in white.
Wait for me.
Hurry.
Spread out.
Quick, quick. Here.
Wait!
Drop it or I'll drop you.
Great.
Kiyoko, you ok?
Uh? yeah.
So princely.
Him I mean?
Yeah, I knew that.
The tall black man is really getting his clock cleaned.
Easy. I could fight a couple of those.
Hey, jump up quickly. What?
Listen. You need a worm if you're going fishing. I won't do it.
You wasted all the bullets you fool.
Ah! My fists are hammers.
You'd fight a couple, huh?
Get hold of them!
Run away!
Kiyoko, how can we escape?
Oh, you say that.
How can we escape?
I'm gonna take care of it. Watch this.
Are you alright?
He He! Hardly touch me. Don't worry.
Oo Oo! It hurts.
No fair at all. I'm just a little guy.
Your feet are like boats.
Hey, watch!
Help me!
Help me! Help me!
Put her down and fight.
Watch it!
Incredible, Hunter!
Were you hurt?
How many terrorists are there?
I don't know.
How many guns?
We need a hiding place.
Where?
Your room?
I just escaped from there.
Ah, they probably won't look for you there.
Hey, you're real good!
You too.
Hold it!
Don't move! Hands on your head!
We're taking over the boat.
Like hell.
Welcome, ladies and gentleman.
I'll now have Captain Williams un-cork
the cerimonial champaign,
and wish you all a happy voyage. Hi!
I wish City Hunter were around.
I want you girl.
My bow tie?
Looks fine.
The terrorists, they're really here.
Take it easy.
Hey, you dropped the gun.
Hey, gorgeous we meet again.
Oh, you finished off one.
What are you doing?
He may have some food.
Tobacco. He doesn't care about his health.
How about chocolate?
Why? Not one snack.
Want some gum?
I suppose so.
What's that?
A micro-computer.
And it knows the data on every terrorist using his prints.
It reads the fingerprints from
anything the man's touched.
Then a display appears on the screen. Huh, not bad.
Bend down.
Now let's just check you out.
Your bottoms has been touched at least once.
Known as City Hunter a private detective.
Distinguishing features: a handsome womanizer.
Undefeatable in battle, honest,
intelligent and good to his mother.
It's you?
Whoopsie!
They were right next door. There must be some fingerprints.
Chow, Kim. International gun for hire wanted for murder
An ex-member of at least two terrorist groups.
Huh, not bad. We'll see who else is around.
Hi, there.
Time to leave.
Ladies and gentleman, allow me to introduce myself.
I'm known as Mac. Or call me Mc Donald.
Now, my friends...
Now, we're only after your money.
If you cooperate, you won't force us to murder.
Now, if you don't... We'll kill you.
This is a list. When you hear your name,
please come forward.
I'll shoot and kill anyone who disobeys.
Ok. Here are the names.
First, Mr. Robinson.
- Don't.
- No.
I must or die.
Stay here.
Are you crazy? Get him.
Hey. What?
Want a turn?
We don't believe in violence.
What are you doing?
Playing videos together.
You know there's terrorists around?
You're terrifying us.
They'll kidnap or kill all of us.
What a bummer.
The best way to the casino?
Sure, the elevator.
How would I get there silently?
I know. In the elevator, don't whistle.
Ahh! That's all, I've had enough. I'm going.
Both you are better notify the police.
Oh right. Ba-bye.
Now what?
Here, this way.
This way?
Good. Excellent. Well, time for a little game now.
First, I'd like you to empty your pockets
quickly and open every purse.
I need cash, watches.
Give them all to the man in red as he goes past.
Quick, Hurry, Come on. Let's go. Everyone.
You. In the bag.
After that, line up one after another.
Since you like gambling
I'll be the banker I'll be happy to play with you.
Will you be a winner?
Let's go.
Someone's loose. I think City Hunter might be on board.
Take a man with you. I want him alive.
Right.
Oh! There you are.
Ooo! Hey, look at this? How do you like that?
A bomb?
Nah, a transmitter. It's the new 47-B.
A transmitter? Alright.
Yeah, you're probably wondering how I get the relay to go.
After we get rescued, you wanna play pinball?
- Hey, you're dialing 1234?
- Yeah.
- It's a cipher.
- What does it mean?
Look up. What's it say?
Help!
Stay in line.
You're first. Please, sit down.
You like baccarat?
Sure.
Good, alright, Let's play.
Ah Ha! Seven for me.
Oooo! Seven, nice.
Ahh! I have nine.
Goodbye.
Six.
It's a tie, then.
Sorry, all ties to the bank.
Next.
I won't, I won't. No one can win.
Be gentle. It'll be better in your room.
Let's go. No, stop it.
- No, wait.
- What's that?
No. Man, you wanna last all night,
You need this little vile it keeps...
I'll be next. Ok?
Seven.
Ok, deal us another one.
That way.
Excellent. You're very good. You've won 29 games.
Hello, there. I bet you'd like to find City Hunter.
I would, seen him?
Yes, sir.
Oh! tell me where he is and I'll spare you.
- Oh, forget it.
- Hmm?
Go with them over there. Ok?
Hey, that was your fault.
Hey, what about me?
I'll come back.
Glad you made it.
You do nice work.
That one man grab Kaori He took her.
Wow! I better rescue her.
Good idea.
Big muscle man, huh?
Why should we hurry? We're having a party.
You, you're so mighty. Fun, huh?
So you like to play games, huh?
It's my turn, ok?
Ok, come on.
Ah, not there.
Oh! Fantastic.
I want more.
Do you have a fall?
You animal.
I'm coming.
Stop!
What you want?
What's going on?
What do you think? Handsome and I are having a game.
Huh?
Who's that guy?
I am Hunter.
Oh! Wow!
I hear that you can fight.
Know what? He's also strong.
Hit him now. Huh?
How dare you, that's my girlfriend.
What was I hearing?
Girlfriend? Say that to me once.
What am I?
You moron.
Moron?
I hit hard.
Where as you hit like a girl.
Hold it.
Don't move.
Ok.
The gun.
-No! no firearms.
- What's that?
Are you afraid to use your fist chump?
Get a hold of her. Now. Quick.
So, nice to meet you. City Hunter.
Is it now.
Throw away the gun and we'll use our hands, Colonel.
You know who I am?
A Commando you used to work within the U.S. government.
Ah, but now a bandit. A big shot.
That's right.
And I sentence you to death.
Don't do it.
No mercy. I'll shoot you. And quite soon.
Why?
Where is Hunter?
Hm! Who's asking me?
Don't be like that. Have you any idea where?
He might be captured.
There isn't a choice. All of us must defeat them.
Hey, we don't have a single gun.
Are we to use our fingers...
I have a gun.
I don't think we can get by him. Should we surprise him?
Forget that. I need a gun.
I'll distract him.
Wow! Great idea. Good for you. Yeah!
You want a little practice before you go?
Cousin, go to the ladies aid right now.
You bet, darling.
Oh! I surrender, handsome. Be kind to me. Have mercy.
Now that I'm captured,
I have to be anything you like.
What's that? Yes, I'm on a cruise. Yes, that's right.
Yes.
No, wait. I'm willing to cooperate.
Keep me company tonight.
Pardon?
Hey, you break down the door and us two go in.
Is it hard to do?
Hey! Really simple. Go.
Go.
Duck!
Don't move.
Come on.
Get away.
White crane, crab, Dragon Claw.
Is this a private party?
Change and meet back here.
Alright.
This way. Yep!
You will need weapons.
Hey, girl. Want a weapon?
No, I don't think so.
Yes.
Oh, wait.
Go away.
There you go, teddy bear.
Are you both children?
You wanna put me over your knee?
Will you save the hostages or City Hunter?
Um? Hunter preferably. Hm-hm! Hmm!
We will save the hostages. Yeah!
I'll help you two. OK!
Well, my friend. Today's your last day to see the sun.
I'd like to get one last wish.
Yes?
Go pick me up a sandwich, I need to eat.
Fear has driven City Hunter completely insane.
Sorry, no way.
Fine for you. I'm starving to death.
Dogs, get ready.
Hold it.
Huhhh! Why did you do this?
Well, well, well, well, a princess. What do you want?
I beg you let him go.
I'm rich, I'll make you both wealthy.
My father is the owner of the japanese
newspaper and he's got plenty.
I'll have him give you a lot of cash.
Why should I believe you?
Listen, I can prove it.
Call 052789
Take it down. Check it out.
This man means that much to you?
He's the best man that I've ever met.
Good. I'll call your dad with the news,
after we shoot your City Hunter.
Oh! You scumbag.
- Nobody move.
- Drop your weapons.
- Hurry.
- Get them!
- Got it! Let's go.
- Grab it!
- No, my hands are tied.
- You're ok?
- Come on.
Where's the gun?
Take it.
Shoot the gun.
I'm heavy Huh?
I'm being crushed.
No.
Gimme that.
Go up and hide.
Where do I go?
Hurry.
- Where?
- Go on.
Jump.
Hey! You forgot about untieing me.
You really hit bottom.
- What the hell was that?
- Run!
Thunder Strikers.
Spread out in circle.
Two on the left of the rail, the rest follow me.
Anybody here?
Oh, that's great.
What are you two playing at?
Quickly, untie this.
Quickly, untie it.
You win.
Who's next?
You ok?
What exactly happened to me?
You had a fight.
Wow, you cleaned this clock.
He's still alive though.
Yeah, that's a pity.
Wait! Go back up on the deck.
The Thunder Strikers have gotten here.
- Ok.
- Alright.
- Wait.
- Where's Kaori?
Kaori? At the casino.
The casino? I'll head there.
Like he said. Well? alright.
- Hurry up!
- Quiet quiet.
Quick.
There's some over there. Hurry.
Run.
Get away. Run.
One left. I'll try my luck.
Lucks run out. No cards left to play.
Lo Che... Wait!
Hey!
- You ok?
- I'm ok.
Thanks to your ace of hearts.
You'd better go to the upper deck.
Reinforcements are aboard.
Coming?
No, to the casino to help them fight.
You'll be alright?
Oh, yeah. You and I should go out on a date someday.
Hmm! Yeah.
Move out. Right. Post guards everywhere.
Kaori...
Hey! Watch out!
Jump!
No bullets again?
I'm loaded.
Behind us!
How's that?
City Hunter.
You finally got here.
- Don't move.
- You halt!
Hey, put her down.
What? Oh! She's a weapon, really.
Oh! That's why you're carrying her? Huh?
MacDonald, there's no way that you can escape.
Soldiers are here.
With you as hostages I can go by lifeboat.
Let's make a deal.
You let me go and I will let her go.
Don't let him go.
He's beaten my cousin all to hell.
How bad?
Real bad. I feel awful.
Huh? It's pathetic.
Versal.
Thank you for being the fool.
You're very welcome.
Say goodnight, you moron.
The end, All done, No more, Finito, Phase complete.
Please don't kill me. I have seven children.
You've earn two centuries inside a jail.
I was wrong.
Yeah, that's true.
Your ears.
- I got them.
- And you swear you won't be back?
I will never do it again.
Can I go?
Say "May I?".
Hunter, grab this.
That hurt.
Weapon.
Here.
Up, middle, low, right.
You couldn't even hit the side of a barn.
Not even close.
You bastard.
I'm something, aren't I?
Yeah?
Goodbye...
Hunter.
Are you alright? Wounded?
I'm just bruised.
May I lift you?
I'm mad, Huh? Furious!
Huh? What?
- Were you hurt?
- Very badly.
- You seem ok.
- You were hold that coward.
Let me pick you up.
All better?
It's over now. Kaori, we're all set.
Oh. Where'd Kiyoko go, Hunter?
Where's she gone?
Be right back.
Why me?
Wait a sec'.
Remarkable.
Kiyoko, please don't go away.
No, I won't. I won't leave ever again.
And I'll do anything you like.
Anything?
I want a bowl of noodles.
City Hunter, are you ok?
Indeed. Again, you have our gratitude.
My pleasure.
Sit down.
City Hunter,
I would like to speak with no one else present.
Don't be long.
I guess I'll leave.
Thank you.
Let's wander out.
Hold my calls. I want no interruptions.
Sir, I'm impressed.
My daughter has returned to me.
And she is changed for the better, thanks to you.
Don't mention it.
You know you really should date her.
I think you'd make a very fine husband. You could tame her.
You'd make an excellent son in law,
and naturally when I retire my daughter
and her family will inherit everything.
If I am choosing who marries my daughter then
of course you'd be a wealthy man.
Well, can I assume you're in love?
No.
Why not?
Ah! Well, I can't do that.
I don't want one. I want'em all.
No, it would'nt work for me.
I figured you wanna know your friends going.
It's no big deal.
Thank you, sir. Thanks a lot.
Hey, watch out now. Think quickly. I charge interest.
Where'd that girl go?
- Outside.
- Outside?
Nice perfume.
How sweet.
Kaori, where are you going?
It's for you.
Kaori, what's wrong with you?
You rat.
Oh yeah! Kaori will be what? Your maid?
I don't think you understand.
You heard and you think I said yes. I didn't.
Alright? Of course not.
I'm through with other women.
City Hunter.
My, my, hello.
Hi.
You look bored.
You bet.
Hey! You want to go along for a ride?
Alright.
Wow. What is that?
You want it?
Thanks.
City Hunter.
I was born lucky.