Previously on Slasher.
Seven sins...six killings...
Only one victims remains...
Who is that unlucky soul?
Don't! No!
Please! No!
Help me!
Sarah.
Welcome home.
You glow.
He thinks this is over.
It's not even close to being over.
This town has been cleansed.
"And the Lord said in His heart,
'Never again will I curse
the ground for man's sake,
nor will I again destroy every
living thing as I have done'."
Please!
My God, Cam.
What is wrong with you?
Wake up, Cam.
Wake up!
- Suzy, would you...
- Shit, Alan!
Calm down.
Where am I?
- You're sleepwalking.
- And you wanna know why?
Because you were playing goddamn
videogames right before bed again.
And I told you not to.
If you would just frickin'
listen to me, we wouldn't
have to go through this
every frickin' night.
Oh, come on. You pissed yourself?
You are too old for this.
What is wrong with you?
I'm sorry, Mom. I didn't mean to.
Well, you did, Cam. You did.
And now I'm gonna have
to change all your sheets
and wash them, and your pj's, too.
And I'm gonna be lucky if I
get two hours of goddamn sleep
because you are such a little baby!
I oughta, uh, make you wear diapers.
Would you like that?
How would you like that?
Wearing diapers to bed.
That's what I oughta do.
I'm gonna make you wear diapers to bed.
And to school, in front
of all your friends.
To teach you a lesson
because you are such a little baby!
What the hell?
Cam?
Suzanne!
What happened?
Jesus, no.
Suzanne.
No! What have you done?
No!
Cameron!
Oh, come on. It's smiling.
It's wrong.
No, it's not.
- It...
- Look at it.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, it's a smile.
- Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
I bet you never thought
this was possible.
Havin' fun...
in Waterbury?
Yeah, I guess I didn't.
Sarah.
I know we both lost people we love,
this summer.
But...
Waterbury...
It had a problem.
Lots of problems,
lots of secrets...
There's a lot of darkness in this
town and it's not just The Executioner
Will you two be helping me hand
out candy tomorrow or...?
I don't know how many
trick or treaters we'll get.
It's, uh... it's Sarah's birthday,
tomorrow.
Oh, right. Right.
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
All right, so, you know,
I should... go back to work.
Remember, scary, okay?
Chase those demons away.
She seems in fine spirits.
Yeah.
She is.
We'll take anything you've painted
Money's no object.
Really? Since when?
Elise, I make six figures
drinking blood on the net.
Yeah, I know you do. I wish you didn't.
- Why? It's not cheating.
- Maybe not to you, it isn't.
You know what, I'm just
gonna leave you, um...
I haven't seen this
much black nail polish
since I worked the make
up count in the '90s.
I know. Can you believe this?
And what is this, exactly?
Happy Halloween?
Speaking of...
I wasn't gonna throw
one this year, but...
- You're doing it for Justin?
- Yeah.
It felt sort of wrong...
not celebrating it.
You know...
I... should make like Dracula and fly.
But I will see you at The
A-Frame tomorrow night.
- Hmm.
- Yes. Sarah?
No, you know, I just want to stay in bed
and eat my weight in candy.
I'm not giving up on you.
You will be doing the Monster
Ma with me tomorrow night.
Yeah, you know what? Just dream big.
Looking in fine form, son.
Whattaya want?
Talk for a minute?
I can't even imagine...
how upset you still must be.
About June?
That was three months ago, Dad.
It took me years to get over
the death of your mother, Cameron.
Mourning won't bring June back.
Didn't bring back Mom.
That's true.
But...
What?
You and Sarah...
I'm worried you might be
rushing into something...
unseemly.
Really?
Tell me, Daddy.
Are you this righteous when
you' down on your hands and knees
being whipped and
flogged with a dog collar
around that perverted little neck of yours?
...hm?
Hey...
You know, I'm...
I'm headed downtown. I could...
I could give you a ride
to the church, if you want.
No, I'm fine. You go.
All right.
Suit yourself.
I mean...I'm sorry, there's none
of my own work left.
Let me guess, the
"vamps" got here first.
Um, I do have a website,
then when more become available,
you can buy them online.
Could you... just
excuse me for a second?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
What am I...?
I've been calling for days.
You're not answering your phone.
Because I don't want to talk to you.
- It's your birthday, babe.
- Yeah.
Best present you can give
me is just to leave me alone.
Listen, babe.
You wanted me... to remove
myself from the story.
I did that.
You wanted me to cut
ties with Lisa-Ann?
I did that, too.
All I am now is the editor
of a simple small town paper,
and I'm fine with that.
Sarah, you are the single
most important thing to me
in the world.
And you only came to that conclusion
after everything had gone to hell?
Now, please. I'd like you to leave.
Sarah.
You know, some parents...
It takes time to love their children.
Your mother was like that.
But me...
The moment I saw you,
my whole life finally made sense.
Cam, was I a good father?
Yeah, of course.
Are you sure? 'Cause I worry.
I worry I didn't do everything
I needed to do for you.
Dad...
you're
- you're acting really strange.
I hoped you'd forget about that night.
I thought it better just...
just to move forward.
But now I don't think that
was the right thing to do.
I'm not angry at you, son.
I'm not.
I'm no angel.
Far from it.
And those people and their sins...
Who knows, a 100 years ago,
maybe the state would
have put 'em to death.
But you broke man's law, Cam.
More importantly, you broke God's law.
Hmm.
But I can help you with that.
We can ask God,
to forgive you, together.
And what happens after that?
I'm sorry.
"Lord of grace and truth,
we confess our unworthiness
to stand in Your
presence as Your children.
We have sinned.
Forgive... and heal us. "
Cam!
You know I'm terrible.
I am not!
Goddamnit.
Forgive me, God.
No one else needed to die.
Tennyson wrote, "'Tis
better to have loved and lost
than to never have loved at all.
Well, guess what?
Lord Tennyson had no idea
what he was talking about.
Waterbury has faced many
losses this year. But...
For me, my own personal
loss has been my wife.
I didn't lose her to
The Executioner, however.
I lost her to myself.
The greatest sin, the cardinal sin...
"... is pride.
It's been the downfall
of many a man and woman,
and now it's my own personal undoing. "
Wow.
God, if Sarah doesn't
take him back, I will.
Don't you have any actual work to do?
You know, it was
romantic, and it was brave.
I do appreciate the sentiment.
I didn't write that...
thinking you'd magically
change your mind, Sarah.
I wrote it so you'd hear me out.
You know, what, yeah,
and I want to believe you
in the spirit that it
was written in, but...
You know you lied to me.
For years.
Yeah.
I just... I just wish
we'd never come here.
You know what? I'd still
be a li even if we had.
I'm glad
- I'm glad we came here.
Because... you wanted the truth, Sarah.
And
- and you got it.
Maybe more truth than you bargained for.
Or we could do a piece on what to do
with all your Halloween
crap the day after.
Right? Like the
Jack-o'- lantern,
all the candy you don't
want your kids to scarf down.
Sound fun?
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Get down on the ground!
Nobody move!
Cam, what's...? What...?
Dylan Bennett, you are
under arrest for murder.
What are you talking
about? There's a mistake.
This is a mistake!
You have the right to remain silent...
You can refuse to anwer any questions...
Anything you say may be used against you in a court of law
Call Sarah. Tell her to meet me at the station.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
I don't understand.
Just take it easy. Okay?
Breathe.
You're gonna be okay.
It's like he wanted me to find them.
To punish me.
Or maybe he wanted to be caught.
I don't understand.
Sarah...
There's no telling what goes on
in the mind of a... a criminal.
We married the wrong people.
I should have waited for you.
And now...
I can never tell if...
you felt the way I did.
- I should have been more brave.
- No.
You are brave, Cam. You're the...
You're the bravest man I know.
Sarah, maybe
- maybe we should...
No.
I was thinkin'...
I'll go spend a few hours with Dylan.
See what
- see what I can find out.
And I thought, maybe afterwards...
we come back here, order some food?
I actually just need to be alone
Well...
It's been a long day.
Why don't you call me if
you change your mind, okay?
I need to talk to my lawyer.
No, you need to tell
me why we found
a box full of goddamn murder-scene souvenirs
in your house.
Brenda Merritt's fingernails.
Tell me, Dylan, did you
- you pull those out with pliers?
No! Cam, listen to me.
I didn't do anything to anybody,
Cam. You have the wrong guy.
- What about my wife's hair, huh?
What about your wife's hair?
How'd you come by that?
You sick son of a bitch!
Okay, I need to see my lawyer...now!
Yeah...maybe I'll do that...
tomorrow.
You better get used to that chair
because you're gonna be there all night.
Cam, listen to me.
Cam!
Please... Hear me out!
911. What is your emergency?
Hello? Are you there?
Hello?
Merlin! Merlin! Cut!
Uh, sorry, everyone.
Uh, I didn't mean to stop
the dancing. Just one second.
I just wanted to thank you all..
so, so much for coming.
- I really appreciate it.
- Whoo!
Yeah!
- Um...
You probably didn't know
this... I didn't, but...
Halloween, actually started
as a celebration of life.
We would, um, wear
costumes... to scare off death.
I, uh...
I lost the love of my life this year.
And I've...
I've felt very powerless, ever since.
But tonight...
Tonight I am giving...
a great big middle
finger to death because...
Because I'm still here.
That's right. You bet.
We are still here.
So, Justin...
Wherever you are, I really hope...
that you can see us celebrating
your favorite holiday.
As we raise our glass to you...
Justin.
Happy Halloween!
Let's party!
Merlin!
Robin?
- Honey, honey, honey.
I've got some very disturbing news.
- Listen, is Cam here?
- I... yeah.
Would you look at that?
Listen, I don't believe you.
Dylan can't be The Execu...
Yeah, he's not, okay?
But even if he is,
I want you to know
I'm here for you, okay?
- You're a victim, too.
- Okay.
Yeah, thanks.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
I thought you were
gonna lay low tonight?
Well, I thought you'd
be at the police station.
I decided to let Dylan stew for a bit.
He's
- he's lying through his teeth.
Denied everything.
But I'm gonna break him.
Do you wanna go outside?
The party's in here.
Exactly.
- Is everything okay, Sarah?
- Never better.
Come on.
Wait. Where are you taking me?
What's with all the questions, huh?
Aren't you supposed to
be interrogating, Dylan?
No, no, wait.
Are you sure, you're
okay with this, Sarah?
You mean, go back inside?
No.
Then, shut up.
What the hell's going on?
Robin? No, no, Robin.
Robin!
No!
Hey, what's going on down there?
Sharma!
Let me out of here!
Your wife called.
Pardon the outfit.
I assure you, I am a lawyer.
Can you tell him to let me out of here?
I'm sorry, I can't do anything
until I can reach Chief Henry.
I have brought with me
a writ of habeas corpus.
Do you have any idea what that means?
No.
It means...
either you charge my client with
an actual crime or you release him.
You can't just keep him here.
I don't have the
authority to do anything.
Fine.
I'll make a decision
for you. Mr. Bennett.
Wha...?
- Thank you.
- Wait, um...
Good evening.
Shit.
Help!
911. What's your emergency?
Please, you've got to help me.
The Executioner, he's here.
I'm sorry?
- Help!
- Are you there?
This is Sarah Bennett! He's
outside! He's trying to kill me!
Are you in danger?
Ma'am?
No!
Open the door, Sarah.
Open the goddamn door!
Get out!
Sarah!
Dylan?
Go! Get help now!
No!
No! Don't! Don't!
No! Don't!
No!
This isn't what I wanted.
This is the exact
opposite of what I wanted!
I
- I ruined this!
I ruin everything!
I'm gonna rest here, okay?
Hey.
Sarah.
Did I tell you about the
first t I saw you, Sarah?
Camp Motega.
Your first day there.
And you were sitting by the lake
running your fingers through the water.
In the air...
I don't know, I guess it was...
I guess it was dandelion
seeds or something, but...
Ah, just these...
white flecks...
flowing...
glowing in the sun.
You don't think...
I just...
You know, I stopped.
And I watched you.
You were just so perfect.
P...?
Perfect?
Yeah.
- No.
You're just so... pure.
And... innocent, you know?
Perfect.
Hmm.
Well...
I'm sorry.
Sarah!
What did you do?
Sarah, don't!
Don't, Sarah! Don't! Don't do it.
Why? Why?
Oh, why?
Don't.
Because you're not
a murderer. No, please.
No!
Please, Dylan.
Please, I need you to help me.
- No.
- Please... help.
Please, Dylan!
I need you, please.
Just... please!
No!
No! No!
I don't remember meeting you, Cam.
That's not true.
I remember camp.
I remember becoming friends, but...
I don't remember the
first time I saw you!
It was that day by the lake.
See, that's just...
It was just a Saturday.
I wasn't... I wasn't innocent.
I wasn't pure. I was 15!
I didn't know who I was. But I do now.
God!
I'll tell you what I'll never forget.
I'll never forget
seeing my grandmother...
drifting in the lake.
The life draining out of her.
I'll never forget Justin's last breath.
Cam, June worshipped
the ground you walked on.
How she trusted you...
The desecration of Verna McBride.
What you did to Robin.
Your father, Cam!
Your father!
Police! Open up!
No...
Never forget.
You'd never guess, just lookin' at it.
But you can feel it, right? There's...
just something wrong.
Three-story executive with bad juju.
How 'bout we leave that
part out of the listing?
How are you feeling?
I look like Frankenstein
with my shirt off, but...
I'll live.
Okay, no, you can't
look at me like that.
You're gonna make me
cry, and I hate crying.
- You're welcome.
- I'm very sorry.
Now, you stay out of trouble, okay?
Don't move into any cursed homes.
And don't... befriend
anyone with the last name
"Henry," "Dahmer," or "Bundy. "
Deal.
I'm gonna miss you, Robin.
- You take care of her!
- Don't worry about that.
Just worry about selling this house.
All right.
We're gonna be okay, right?
Better than okay.
The house has five bedrooms.
Which, I know, sounds
large for a family of three,
but think about it, you could
both have your own offices.
There's bedrooms for guests.
Plus, if you wanted to, you
could open up your own B&B.
People do it all the time.
After you.
The wood throughout is original,
as is all the stained glass.
Here, kitty, kitty.
You're such a pretty cat.
You've got all new appliances,
granite countertop, backsplash.
I love, love, love this little
breakfast nook over here.
What do you say, Scotia?
You like this house?
Yes, this house feels perfect.