♪ And I think
of all the good times ♪
♪ That I've wasted ♪
♪ Having good times ♪
♪ When I think
of all the good time ♪
♪ That's been wasted ♪
♪ Having good times ♪
♪ When I was drinking ♪
♪ I should've been thinking ♪
♪ When I was fighting ♪
♪ I could've done
the right thing ♪
♪ All of that boozing ♪
♪ I was really losing ♪
♪ Good times ♪
♪ When I think of all
the good time ♪
♪ That's been wasted ♪
♪ Having good times ♪
♪ When I think of all
the good time ♪
♪ That's been wasted ♪
♪ Having good times ♪
♪ All of my lying ♪
♪ I remember her crying ♪
♪ My useless talking ♪
♪ I could've been walking ♪
♪ Instead of complaining ♪
♪ I could've been gaining ♪
♪ Good times ♪
South Core Police Department.
Yes, is
Officer Spencer in?
Who's calling?
Mike Kendall.
Hey, Mike.
I'm checking to see
if he's received
my application.
It's a PIQ
for re-entry.
I know this isn't
what you want to hear,
but clearing
your background
is gonna be
a real challenge.
The department
does not let officers
walk right back in
after something
like this.
I see.
Would you be able
to give me any idea
how it looks?
The board makes
the final decision,
but it's not good.
Okay.
So they'll call me?
Yeah, Mike,
if they're interested.
Right,
Look, it'll take
a miracle to get you
back on here.
I just wanna be honest.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay.
Goodbye.
Shit.
- Fuck you, Kendall.
- Morning.
Tell me
about yourself.
Okay.
What would you like
to know?
You can start
with why you think
you're the best person
for the job.
Well...
I don't take any shit.
People
that work out here
usually have a way
with animals.
I can imagine.
Hey, buddy.
Ooh, whoa, whoa.
If you were to rate
your life success
on a scale
of one to ten,
what would it be?
Two.
Police officer, huh?
Yes, sir.
Is there a reason
you're still not
a cop?
Yeah.
I think I'd like
to hire you.
Really?
I can't say why,
but you struck me.
Let's get you
signed in.
You can start first thing
tomorrow morning.
There's, uh,
one other thing
I'd like to mention.
Sure, go ahead.
Well,
I have a problem
with alcohol.
I see.
Most mornings,
I'm about as worthless
as a park bench
in hell.
I usually don't start
thinking straight
until I get a couple
cold ones in me.
After that, I wouldn't
recommend me operating
any heavy machinery,
if you get where I'm going.
Yeah.
But other than that,
you know,
I'm ready to go.
Hey, Wendy.
Mister Kendall,
how'd the job hunt
go this month?
Pretty good.
I like my chances.
Get the fuck out of here.
That wasn't
my fault, man.
That asshole's wife
started the whole thing.
Come on.
Easy, boys.
Hey,
I just had this son
of a bitch dry cleaned.
All right, let me
have another beer
and I'll sober up
a little bit.
Yeah, try it, Mike.
I'll have you
hooked up to that
line pole
waiting for the cops.
You bastard.
I've been coming here
all my life.
Yeah, and you're
a nasty son of a bitch.
Nobody wants you around.
Teddy likes me.
Yeah, you're right
about that.
Hold on,
my dick is out,
my dick is out.
Just hold it.
Nothing wrong
with my prostate.
Hey.
That's a paying customer,
gentlemen.
Have a little respect.
Boys,
get the hell
out of here.
Bunch of pricks.
You okay?
I'm fine.
Let's go
to the Dead Dog.
We still got
another hour.
Uh-uh, mm-mm,
won't go back there.
Not since that pervert
attacked me in
the bathroom.
We ran that guy off.
I'm gonna tap out, buddy.
Told Kelly that I
would take it easy.
You serious?
Why don't you ride
with me, man?
Just take the couch.
Shit.
Gonna have to pass.
Last thing I want
is to wake up
at 6:00 AM
to watch SpongeBob
with your kids.
Okay.
Hey,
you wrap your car
around a tree,
I'm not gonna
feel guilty.
Neither am I.
♪ dollar signs ♪
♪ In their eyes ♪
♪ And I'll tell you what ♪
♪ I ain't got a dime ♪
♪ but I'm way ♪
♪ Past my prime ♪
Go get 'em, boys.
Come on, Mike.
I'm fine.
I just need
to get some coffee.
Like hell.
You smell like
a damned distillery.
The only asshole
drunker than you
might be this guy
right here.
I don't know what's
wrong with you, Mike,
but you could be
a good cop.
I am a good cop.
Turn off your engine.
Stay in the car.
I can do the job.
Hey.
You step one foot
outside this vehicle,
and I'm reporting
your ass.
Kendall,
I really like you,
but...
Jesus Christ.
Come on out, buddy.
Shit.
Officer down,
code three.
I repeat,
officer down,
code three.
Ooh, boy.
♪ She's ♪
Mike.
Scott.
Pete.
Mind if we do
this outside?
Appreciate you
hanging around.
I know the process.
Figured I'd save you
some time.
You look
like shit.
I missed my shower
this morning.
Hmm.
You've been drinking.
Do you even have
a license?
Work permit.
Got it on you?
Do I really have to deal
with this shit right now?
For all we know,
you hit that girl
with your car.
You wanna look
at my wheels, Pete?
They're right
over there.
Why don't you wait
it out in the car?
I'm all right.
I know.
Lot of the guys
are still pretty
ticked off
with how it went down
with Burke.
Think I'm happy
about it?
All right,
let's talk about
this girl you found.
I need you to start
from the beginning.
Don't leave one
damn thing out.
Think she'll make it?
I've seen them
come back from worse.
Is she local?
Could be.
How old is she?
Early 20s,
I guess.
Cops have any idea?
They were asking me.
Really?
You know,
this could end up
really nice for you.
You know,
damsel in distress
and here
comes her knight
in shining armor.
You don't get involved
with a victim, Teddy.
That's policy.
Stop.
It's policy.
Stop with
the cop talk.
You don't have to worry
about that anymore.
What is that,
blood in there?
Yeah.
That shit's gonna be extra.
Oh, man.
Good thing you don't
have any interior.
- I appreciate it.
- Thanks.
Found this,
underneath the seat.
Southside Medical.
Yeah, ICU, please.
Please hold.
ICU, this is Tammy.
Hello, this
is Mike Kendall.
I brought in a girl
yesterday morning.
Jane Doe, early 20s,
she was banged up
pretty good.
Oh, yeah.
Hi, Mr. Kendall.
I've got some
of her belongings
and I'd like
to drop them by,
personally,
to her.
Sorry, guess
no one told you.
She--last night
she passed away.
Mr. Kendall,
are you still there?
No, I'm still here.
Sorry to hear that.
Yeah.
Was her body identified?
I'm sorry,
I can't tell you that.
You'd have to contact
the police.
I understand.
All right.
All right,
well, you take care.
I will.
Thank you.
Pretty sure
that's gonna kill it.
Tina, why don't
you have a seat?
I'm working, Mike.
Come on, please?
It's been a shit day.
Fine.
Two minutes.
It's good
to see you.
Yeah.
Been a while.
You look great.
What are you
doing tonight?
You're looking at it.
You wanna stop by
after work?
Have a sleepover?
Guess it has been
a while.
Me and, uh,
Greg.
Greg?
Yeah.
Are you serious?
Since when?
About a month.
I thought we had
something going.
Mike, I haven't seen you
around in six months.
I've been real busy.
Yeah, well, I called,
left messages.
Don't try and tell me you
didn't get them either.
That's why I came by.
That's a bunch of crap.
I wanna make it
right.
Have Greg pour us
a couple drinks.
We can talk it over.
What?
Sometimes you're just
such a shit heel,
you know?
Want me to get you
the check?
Keep it open.
All right.
Girl,
where you at?
Kristy?
I'm not sure
of your relation,
but I wanna let
you know--
Who the fuck
is this?
Put Kristy
on the phone.
I don't think
you understand.
Put my bitch
on the phone.
You know something?
I don't like the shit
that's pouring
out of your mouth.
Do you know
who the fuck
you talking to?
I bet you think that
tired ass Motown
you're playing
makes you seem
old school.
I'm-a give you that,
funny man.
And I'm-a slash
your motherfucking throat.
How you like that?
Yeah, I doubt it.
Don't think
I can't reach out
and touch you,
motherfucker.
Try it.
I got to him,
rattled his cage.
He said
her name
was Kristy.
Mmm,
you got a name.
That's good.
So that's him?
The killer is
on that phone?
I don't think
he knows she's dead.
It's probably a pimp,
could be her boyfriend.
Depends on how
screwed up
this girl was.
Wait, you brought
a pimp into our house?
No, babe--
It's a phone, Kel.
With my babies
in the next room.
I didn't invite
the guy to dinner.
You shouldn't
be fiddling around
with some
dead girl's phone.
This guy is key
to the investigation.
He knows the girl.
He might even know
who she was
with that night.
You need to give it
to the cops.
Uh-hmm.
Of course
I'm gonna give it
to the police.
Okay, look, Mike.
I think what Kelly
is trying to say
is that you are
no longer a cop.
Don't tell me
what I'm trying
to say.
I know I'm not
a damn cop.
Thank you
very much, Ted.
Okay,
you know what?
I'm going to bed.
Listen.
I know you're going
through some shit
right now.
And I love you.
But it's been
17 months.
Here we go.
You're 45.
You don't have
a job.
This has nothing
to do with me
finding a job.
And no matter
what happens,
nobody's gonna hand you
another badge.
So you need to move on,
find something else.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
I know growing up
for you wasn't easy.
You didn't get
to be a kid.
And I sympathize.
Baby, I really do.
I'm not 12 years
old anymore.
I don't need people
to look after me.
Okay, where is
the endpoint
here, Mike?
When are you gonna start
taking responsibility
for what
you're doing?
Is it possible
for one supportive statement
to come out of your mouth?
Not when we've been
paying your mortgage
for the past
two months, no.
I'm out of here.
Oh,
but don't forget
your beer.
Yeah.
Oh, that's nice.
Nice.
Thanks for
the pep talk, sis.
Uh-huh.
- Teddy?
- Yeah?
I need the mop.
All over my damn
clean floor.
Why'd you answer it?
Thought it might
be a family member.
Come on, Mike,
you know better
than that.
I got
her first name.
That's great.
We already have that.
Family came
in yesterday.
IDed the body.
What's the family name?
Mike...
I wanna send flowers.
Nevil.
How'd it go
with the parents?
They're fine.
They seem upset?
Sure.
They have
any idea
who did it?
Thanks for the phone,
Mike.
I got
the coffee.
Oh,
there's still 15-20
numbers in there.
Plus the bar stamp
on the back of her hand.
You went
through the phone?
We start
with the most recent,
work our way back.
We can find this prick
who called
and twist his arm
up his ass.
Ten to one he knows
who she was
out with that night.
This is a police
investigation.
I doubt we really
have to get physical.
He's probably
all mouth anyhow.
There is no we.
You know that.
Yeah, sure.
Just got
the old juices flowing.
I know you found her.
I know
you feel responsible.
But you're not in this.
In any way.
Okay.
Got it?
Yeah.
Kristy Nevil
was a child of light,
a wonderful,
charming girl.
And although
we haven't had
the pleasure of Kristy
here during
the last few years,
I choose
to remember her
as the inquisitive,
God-fearing young lady
I received during
her first communion.
Departures are
always difficult.
How can I help you?
I need about 15--
you know what?
Let's make it
25 business cards.
Hi. Jack Winter.
I called earlier.
That thing leak oil?
I'm here because I knew
Kristy several years ago.
She and my younger
brother were friends.
They went
to Mt. Conyer
High together.
How old are you?
Winter...
I don't--
I don't remember
your brother.
He's a lot younger.
Their relationship
was brief.
She only came around
a few times
before they
grew apart,
but I was quite
fond of Kristy.
What was
his first name?
Kelly.
But everyone
called him Bill.
Billy.
Willy.
I think I remember
something about
a Will.
Exactly.
He could leave
an impression.
What can we do for you,
Mr. Winter?
I'd like to find out
who killed your daughter.
We've already talked
to the police.
I'm not police,
I'm a private investigator.
Police have a tendency
to miss certain details.
Important details.
And those are the types
of details
that I pick up.
We don't wanna hire
a private investigator.
Which is why I've decided
to take the case pro bono,
Kristy being
a friend and all.
The least I could do.
I have to be honest
with you, Mr. Winter,
Kristen was
a very--
she was a very
mixed-up girl.
She was
a free spirit, Deborah.
I'll give you that.
She took
this family to hell
more times
than I can count.
So maybe we would
just like for her
to find
some peace.
♪ Yeah, you saw me first ♪
♪ But you're not my baby ♪
Still here,
huh, Leslie?
Don't know
where else I'd be.
♪ oh ♪
Hey, Julian, get these
clowns out of here.
We got it.
Haven't seen you
in a while, Mike.
I haven't been in
since that pervert
attacked Teddy
in the bathroom.
We ran that guy off.
That's what I heard.
Place has
really picked up.
We're trying
something new.
How about a beer?
You talked me
into it.
♪ No more girls ♪
♪ No more ♪
♪ No more honeys banging
in my bed ♪
She's friendly.
Name's Heidi.
You should talk to her.
Maybe I will.
♪ Oh, baby,
do we fade ♪
♪ Oh, baby, do we fade ♪
Who's a tough guy now?
Shit.
Take a seat, Mike.
What are you
doing here?
Having a beer,
meeting a friend.
What are you boys
doing here?
None of your
Goddamned business.
Who are
you meeting?
What?
Who's your friend?
Ah, hot little blonde
over there.
You know her?
Heidi?
Yeah.
It's a new thing.
She seems like
a real catch.
She's a wizard
with a pool stick.
Uh, that guy gives her
lessons all the time.
He's great.
She's a hooker,
dipshit.
Why don't you
call it a night, Mike?
Yeah.
Before you get
someone else shot.
Hey, you wanna grab
something to eat?
I don't think so.
Can we do
this again?
Sure.
How about I call
you tomorrow?
Fine.
Who's that, your wife?
That's my sister.
Like a sister-sister
or that's your sister?
I was adopted.
How'd that work?
Compared to starving
and getting the shit
getting kicked out of me
by a couple of junkies,
I thought it
was pretty great.
Want a beer?
Yeah.
And in Whittier,
a man is dead
and police are searching
for two suspects
after a shooting
at their home
on Sherman
and US 31.
Twenty-four hour
news updates
with Marion Jones
who is on the scene.
Marion--
- Just till you hear the click.
- Can I get the keys
to the trunk
of his car?
We got
some identifiers
here, Jonathan.
Yeah,
those are Mike's shots.
All right,
let's get it open.
- Oh, shit.
- Jesus.
Mike shot her.
You know,
he's fucking drunk,
right?
Yeah.
Point-13.
Shit's not right,
I'm doing it again.
It's been calibrated--
I said
I'm doing it again.
Jack Winter.
Thank you,
Mr. Winter,
for being so...
expeditious.
Yeah. I had to shuffle
a few appointments,
but this
is important to me.
My granddaughter's
been dead a week.
Police are no longer
answering my phone calls.
And some son of a bitch
is getting away
with murder.
You know,
to them,
she is just
another toe tag.
I want this guy.
I wanna chain him
to the back of
my Bentley
and I wanna drag him
around a little.
I can understand that,
Mr. Yandell.
Can you do it, Jack?
Can you find
this guy for me?
I can.
My daughter
informs me
that you are willing
to take this case
for free.
That's correct.
Not a chance.
What's your rate?
You know,
it varies.
travel expenses,
food, you never
really know
with this kind of--
Twenty-five hundred
a week?
That'll work.
Oh, would you mind
making it out to cash?
Ex-wife's got me
by the balls.
How much do you
know about Kristy?
Well,
she was a handful.
Did you know
she was a drug addict
and a prostitute?
Something like that.
Everybody tried
to help her, of course.
But, uh,
she'd push
people away.
She was raised strict,
probably the reason
for her rebellion.
You ever meet
any of her friends?
She hung out
with some real
scumbags.
Anybody you could put
a name to?
If I could put a name
to someone, Jack,
I would be busting
down doors.
She, uh, come by
with a couple
of skank girlfriends
looking for
a little handout.
Guy who drove 'em,
wiry little shit,
Hispanic, I guess.
Uh, you think you
could pick him out?
No, I don't think so.
I won't forget
his car, though.
Impala.
New?
'60s, purple.
All right, racers,
are you ready?
Yeah.
On your mark,
get set, go.
Let's go.
Sir, is that
an open container?
Ha, ha.
It will be.
Hey, Mike,
where you been
hiding yourself, man?
Oh, I've been busy.
I got a job.
A job?
What kind of job?
Uh, sort of
an assistant type deal.
Uh, I run errands,
do fact checking.
Things like that.
Mike, that's great.
That's great, man.
Uh, it's
a temporary position.
You know what?
Let's get Kels up here.
Hmm. Well, I don't--
I don't wanna...
No, no.
Hey, babe,
come here.
Your brother's here.
Look, she looks busy
with the egg toss.
Don't...
Okay. Look,
look here, man.
She really wants
to talk to you.
She feels bad
about the other night.
All right?
Just hear her out.
What do you want,
Mike?
All right. Babe,
Mike got a job.
Nothing big.
Yeah.
He's some assistant
to some
big shot downtown.
Hmm, back to work.
That's, that's good, huh?
I wanted
to give you this.
Oh, yeah, he's
probably gonna have
his own desk by the end
of the week, huh, Mike?
Hm?
This is $500.
It's a start.
Wow.
Thank you, Mike.
You're welcome.
Well, I'm glad I got
to stop by.
I'll just add this
to the pile.
I have to hit
the road.
But wait,
wait, you,
you just got here, man.
At least stay
for the three-legged race.
Hey, you could buddy up
with JJ.
Uh, no, I can't.
Uh, I got--
I got a date.
A date?
That's incredible.
- Is it that incredible, really?
- Hmm,
I'm just saying, man.
I mean, this is like
a total windfall.
Hmm.
Anybody we know?
Hmm?
I don't think so.
I made you
some cereal.
Thanks.
What do you think?
It's good.
It's an off brand.
Yeah. There's a shit ton
of raisins.
That's what
I'm saying.
You know a lot
of the other girls?
I can, if that's
what you're into.
I picked up
a girl last week.
Kristy.
You know her?
Girls change their name,
like, every other week.
Short brunette,
real pretty?
Lot of girls fit
that description.
She hangs out
with a Hispanic guy,
drives an Impala.
Hmm, it's not
ringing a bell.
I mean,
girls come and go.
It's not something people
usually stick to.
Right.
But I can ask around.
That would be great.
Oh, shit.
I got a 10:30 across town.
Think you could drop me?
Oh.
Call me, baby.
Pull around the corner.
Do you have
brain damage?
Are you following me?
I'm following the girl.
But imagine my surprise
when a black Nova
picked her up
for the evening.
Not exactly
what you think.
Screwing a hooker.
I'm gaining
her trust.
You're compromising
my fucking investigation,
Mike.
I'm working
on a lead.
And I told you
to lay off.
She's gonna ask around.
She's not gonna ask shit.
Think she wants to get
in the middle of this?
They were
best friends.
She said that?
Hell, yes.
Then I'll bring her in.
You bring her in,
she's gonna clam up.
She's doesn't want
that kind of attention.
Why do you think
she's working with me?
Give her some room.
If she comes up
with something--
with something,
you bring it to me.
Of course.
I'm the first person
you call.
Right.
What did I say?
You're the first.
You don't check out the lead.
You don't get a bite to eat.
You don't wipe your ass.
You call me.
Is that clear?
Absolutely.
You get one shot
at this, Mike.
What?
Rose, you ain't got
a damn thing to eat
in here.
I just went shopping.
Yeah.
Well, that'd be great
if I was in the mood
for celery sticks
and a Fruitini.
- That's what I eat.
- Yeah.
We need to get
some protein up
in this bitch.
I'm about to pass out.
And how long I got to watch
all these desperate-ass
bitches
trying to get up
on this dude?
Sam never complains
when I watch my shows,
and he brings pizza.
Well, guess what?
Sweetie has
a night off.
So, do me a favor
and change this shit
to SportsCenter.
Hey, you got somebody
coming over?
Who is it?
You girls
were just too
fucking greedy.
Jack Winter here.
This young woman
was a friend of Kristy's.
Are you sure?
Positive.
She offered to blow me
on three separate
occasions.
For money,
of course.
This prick,
I don't know
who he is.
I do.
You all right?
Just waking up, Steve.
Mike?
Morning, Mike.
Beer?
You hear
the news, Randy?
What?
The news,
you know,
things that
are happening.
I don't recall.
Yeah.
Seems you ought
to remember
if you heard
something or not.
Didn't know.
An employee of yours
had a little accident
last night.
He worked the floor.
So what?
She was working
something else.
In the back.
All right.
You think
you know
something?
You got two patrons
and one employee
dead.
And Kristy Nevil
had your bar stamp
on the back
of her hand.
Have a drink, Mike.
How long
before the whole
damn police force
is breathing
down your neck?
You are the cop.
You tell me.
They already know
you're running a brothel.
It's a bar.
I can't do
a background check
on everybody that walks
through that door.
You solicited me,
Randy.
Which tells me
you're taking
a cut.
You can't prove that.
I don't have to.
Cops are gonna do
it for me.
They just want
a fall guy
and will take
the first one
that pops up.
All I have to do
is set it in motion.
What do you want?
The guy who
supplies the girls.
The one that drives
the Impala.
Can't help you.
How about
a number?
We didn't exchange
info.
The less we know
about each other,
the better.
If he wants
to say something,
he'll come by.
The guy's paranoid.
What if you have to get
a hold of him?
I use the girls.
Look...
All I have
is a name.
It's not something
you put on a driver's
license.
But it's what everyone
calls him.
It's what he
calls himself.
Mood.
Come on, man.
Hey.
Over here.
That's right.
Right over here.
Say Motown.
What?
Say tired ass Motown.
I ain't gonna ask you again.
I'm-a just pull the trigger.
Tired ass Motown.
I told you I was
gonna find your
ass, funny man.
I've been looking
for you.
Oh, yeah?
Funny.
A lot of fools'
been looking
for Mood these days.
Yeah, fuck him
up, Mood.
Baby, you take your ass
in that kitchen right now.
Can't you see
I'm conversating
with this motherfucker?
And what'd I tell you about
getting up in my grill, huh?
You messed up,
Mike Kendall.
Asking about Kristy
like you did.
We had
a good time once.
Nah, nah, nah,
stop it.
Kristy ain't gonna give
a John her real name.
That's rule number one.
So you can drop
all that bullshit.
I ain't trying to hear it.
Now, I'm down two bitches
and I'm in hot pursuit
for a third prostitute.
And Baby over there,
she seems to think
that you're the triggerman.
But I've been kicking it
with you for a minute.
I'm gonna say
that you ain't.
That's a cold-blooded
professional.
And you ain't nothing
but a...
a drunk
in a $50 suit.
I'm a private investigator.
I'm working
for the grandfather.
Now you starting
to make some sense.
So y'all figured
you'd come to me?
I'm the key
to some answers.
Well, I'm gonna tell you,
I ain't got shit.
You're missing
a third girl?
That ain't my girl.
But I'm looking for her.
That crazy ass bitch
got spooked,
climbed up a coon's ass,
pulled her tail all the way
in with her.
When?
Last night,
after Rose got smoked.
They knew each other.
She was friends
with my girls.
Braiding each other's hair
and whatnot.
There a place she'd go?
Oh, for sure.
You check it out?
We don't go
knocking on no doors
for no bitches.
As you can imagine,
most families...
ain't too enthusiastic
about seeing Mood
knocking on their door.
Feel me?
I feel you.
Hello.
I'm Jack Winter.
I'm a private investigator.
I'd like to speak
with Ms. Oarblocker.
Is this the Oarblocker
residence?
Can I see
some identification?
Oliver!
Let the man in,
for God's sakes.
Ms. Oarblocker,
I'm Jack Winter,
private investigator.
I'd like to talk with you
about your granddaughter.
Let me see this.
Oh.
Okay, come on in.
Don't mind him.
He's just overly
protective.
Come on in.
It's right down here
around the corner.
This is her room.
And she was living
here recently?
It's the only home
she has,
as far as I know.
I didn't realize someone
thought that she
was missing
until the officers
came by this
morning.
The police
were here?
Two of them.
And I told them
just give her
a couple of days,
you know,
she'll turn up.
She's always in
and out.
She's a very
independent girl.
Uh, if it's all right
with you, I'd, uh,
like to have
a look around.
Oh, fine.
Fine.
The officers wanted
to look around, too.
Can I offer you a drink,
Mr. Winter?
I got juice boxes.
No, thank you.
Ah. Milk or tea?
Or maybe the juice.
Okay. Perfect.
Perfect.
Thank you.
How'd you get
a hold of him?
Uh, he found me.
Yeah, I can see that.
You know,
there's easier ways
of getting yourself killed.
How'd you guys find out
about Ivy Oarblocker?
Who's Ivy Oarblocker?
The missing girl.
What missing girl?
The one
who was friends
with the dead hookers.
You didn't send
two officers
to her grandmother's house
this morning?
Nope, not us.
Are you sure?
Oarblocker.
Ivy Oarblocker.
If it got something to do
with the case,
then I'd know about it.
Give me
your notepad.
Why?
I'm giving you
the address.
Girl's been missing
a couple of days.
Grandma said
two officers stopped
by the house
this morning.
Could be
a different department.
Maybe.
You don't think so?
I don't know.
You think
these are our guys?
Possible.
Hey, where you going?
Was that
all I need to know?
For right now.
Hey, you get
something else--
You're the first
person I call.
Amateur hour.
Shit.
Who is it?
Sir, we're with the City
Planning Commission.
Okay.
We'd like
to talk to you
about a major
development coming
to your neighborhood.
Oh, that
sounds great,
but I'm not feeling
too hot right now.
Can we do this
another time?
It'd be best
if we talked now.
Don't know
when we'll be back, sir.
It will only take
a minute.
Sir? Sir?
Son of a bitch,
he's out the back.
We'll track him down.
Rode the bike.
Ah, Nova's
on the fritz.
Where's Kelly?
Oh, she took the kids
to a show.
Something with
some singing carrots.
Hell, I couldn't stomach it.
What's up
with your head?
At work,
low hanging shelf,
had a lot in my hands.
Look.
What's this?
I want the Glock.
What?
My gun.
The one I sold you.
I wanna buy it back.
That's the 250.
Yeah, you gave me
specific instructions
about the gun.
I was to hold on to it.
I was never to sell it
to you
or anybody else until you
were back on the force.
You made that very clear.
I know.
Are you back
on the force?
I got an interview.
Hot damn,
okay, come on.
Hello?
This thing
just went next level.
How would you like us
to proceed?
Okay,
we need you
to finish it.
We're not going to jail
for this shit.
I'm not losing my family.
Understand?
It's gonna cost you
double.
Just get it done.
We'll be in touch.
When the department sees
my targets, they're gonna shit.
Okay, look, you can't
let Kelly know, all right?
Interview or not,
she will not understand.
No way.
All right?
Where you headed?
Across town.
Hey, man,
I can drop you off.
Nope, I'm done
putting you out.
Be by tomorrow
to pick up my wheels.
Okay.
Oh, look who's back.
Deja vu.
You wanna piss me off?
Keep acting
like I'm one
of your drunks.
Not long ago
you were.
Got to say,
I liked you more then.
You had Julian
watching Rose.
Probably told him he could
make some easy cash
hanging out
with a beautiful girl.
Can't blame him.
Hell, I'd have taken
the gig myself.
Where's Ivy?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Sam, show Mike
to the door.
Sam, you touch me,
and I'm gonna rip
your fucking balls off.
I remember back
in high school,
I watched you
pitch a no-hitter
in the city championship.
Hell, you took us
all the way to state.
My dad said you
could have made pro
if you'd set
your mind to it.
You were
a real technician.
Not to mention a 90-mile
per hour fast ball
made you
one hell of a player.
A real bear,
they used to say.
Where is she?
I know
you think
she's safe,
but it won't last.
Not with these guys.
Just as sure as I did,
they'll track her down,
and they'll go through you
to do it.
Leslie.
You got the bar.
Okay.
- I got her at Fred's.
- Who's Fred?
One of my cooks.
Hey.
What can I help
you with?
Is Kelly Kendall in?
Banks,
Kelly Banks.
Yeah, she's been that
for eight years now.
Brother's Mike Kendall?
Yeah, yeah,
but she's not in
at the moment.
What--what's this about?
We're actually here
about her brother Mike.
She's listed
as a secondary
point of contact.
Oh, is that bad?
Well, not
for Mr. Kendall, no.
Uh, you see,
we'd like to lease
a nominal part
of his land
and he has
the opportunity
to make a significant amount
of money.
Okay.
So it's best
that we talk to him
as soon as possible.
Uh, yeah, well,
you just missed him.
He took off
in a cab.
He did?
Yeah.
Any idea where
he was headed?
No.
No, he didn't say.
But if you got
a business card,
I'll take it from you
and, uh, I'll pass it
along to him.
I got one of those.
Mr. Randy.
¿Y éste?
It's okay, Conchita.
Es mi amigo.
¿Dónde está Ivy?
Acá. Vamos.
Miss Ivy,
it's Mr. Randy.
Why don't you
hang back a bit.
Let me warm her up.
Hey.
- Hey, baby.
- I, uh,
I brought somebody.
His name is Mike.
I've known him
a good long time.
He used to be
a cop.
Just trying to help her out,
huh, Randy?
I thought you weren't
gonna tell nobody?
Yeah, I think I'm
starting to understand why.
Randy, this isn't
what we talked about.
You got a plan,
sweetie?
Something tells me
I'm looking at it.
Think you can
wait them out?
Maybe they'll get tired
of looking?
Let's say
they can't find you.
Doesn't mean it's over.
They'll grab somebody else,
someone close.
Let's say
your grandmother.
Well, it won't matter
if she doesn't know
the answers
to the questions
that they're asking.
They'll make
her suffer.
And when
her body is found,
beaten and mutilated,
and floating
in the St. John's River,
you'll wish
you'd come forward.
By then, they'll have
someone else.
Maybe another relative,
or a friend.
Maybe Randy.
That is if there's still
somebody you give
a shit
about besides yourself.
Let's cut the bullshit.
You tell me
what's going on.
What can I get you?
We're looking
for Mike Kendall.
No, he's not here.
But he was here.
I didn't say that.
So he wasn't here?
I haven't seen him.
Well, that's strange.
Because I just spoke
with a cab driver
who said no less
than a half hour ago,
he dropped Mike Kendall
off at this bar
and watched him
walk inside.
Huh.
That just kind of proves
to me that you're lying.
I could haul your ass
in right now, just
for that.
- What do you think?
- Cheese sticks?
End of the bar,
thanks, Fred.
Why don't you just
hold tight there,
Pablo?
Being a bartender,
you see a lot of shit.
You learn a lot of shit, too.
Useless knowledge
most of the time,
but once in a while,
you get a gem.
Let me give you
an example.
I bet you don't know
that our law
enforcement holds
a lot of pride
in the national bird.
Now that
makes sense,
if you consider
that the state's fowl
is the valley quail.
Let me tell you,
there's nothing
tough about a quail,
and you sure as hell
wouldn't want to put that
on your uniform.
Now, you see,
at the top
of your badge,
there's supposed
to be an eagle.
A bald eagle,
the national bird.
Now, what you
got there
looks more
like a hawk,
which is
a hell of a bird,
but it ain't
no bald eagle.
So, I'm guessing that
that badge was made
in, uh, Tijuana
by a counterfeiter
who didn't know
the difference
between a chicken
and chicken shit.
Is that right?
It could be.
Look, these guys are
a bunch of rich assholes.
They were in town
for some real estate thing
and they wanted
to get their dicks wet.
They wanted
some young pussy,
and they
were willing to pay
a lot of money for it.
So, you
blackmailed them
and now they paid
a couple of psychopaths
to knock off the girls.
Real smart.
I helped them
with the blackmail,
but the girls came to me
with the video.
They wanted to do it.
Maybe we hit them up
for more too many times
but who kills people
over a few hundred
thousand dollars?
How old are you?
How old do you
want me to be?
You teach her to say that?
God, no, he didn't
tell me shit.
But you saw
the opportunity,
didn't you, Randy?
Hey,
I've fucked guys
for money before.
Pack up your stuff,
we're going to the police.
Wait a minute, Mike.
We can't go
to no cops.
We can pay you.
We got money.
We already got
a hundred
and forty thousand
out of these guys,
and that was
just our cut.
I'm bringing
you both in.
I don't think
I can let you
do that.
I'm not asking.
What are you gonna do?
Shoot me?
Maybe.
That's for being
a scumbag.
Ivy, get your stuff.
- Come on.
- Jesus fucking Christ.
Abby, Abby, Abby,
get your backpack.
And JJ, close
the door after her.
Yes, ma'am.
Come on.
Okay.
Come on in.
Yeah, well--hey,
what do you want
for dinner?
Looks like poor Leslie
just got the one shot off.
Well, this guy
was a bouncer.
Looks like that poor lady
was just having a drink.
Sir?
I got
a witness.
Said there were
three of them.
They lit out of here
in a silver '90s
model sedan.
My nose is broken.
Be happy
you're still breathing.
What?
That car.
Yeah?
It's them.
Okay, get rid
of that Mexican.
Open the door.
Abre la puerta.
You open the door,
or I shoot you
in the fucking head.
He understood that one,
didn't he?
Holy shit.
Go, go.
Get down.
Damn.
Bitch! Hold tight.
Oh, shit.
You're bleeding, baby.
Fuck.
Hang on.
Fuck!
You can get out there.
You okay?
You see my leg
pissing blood?
No, I'm not okay.
Ease off.
We're clear.
Take your foot
off the gas.
There you go,
nice and easy.
Give it the brakes.
Ivy, look at me.
Look at me.
You're safe.
You did great.
We're safe.
Calling the cops.
It's over.
Teddy?
Not even close, Mike.
That was a pretty
good shot.
Where's Teddy?
Teddy?
I'm looking at him
right now.
Don't you touch him.
Gonna cut a deal
with you, Mike.
Don't you
fucking touch him.
You don't get to make
the demands here, Mike.
Now, whatever happens
or doesn't happen
to your friend here,
Teddy,
that's on you.
But I got to tell you,
he's not looking good.
But if I don't get
that girl,
I'm gonna kill him.
And then
I'm gonna kill
your sister, too.
And I don't care
if it takes a day
or a lifetime,
I'm gonna gut
those two fucking kids
of hers
from stem to stern.
I'm going to take
your silence
as a sign
of understanding.
I'm gonna call you
in a bit.
I'm gonna give you a time
and a place, huh?
But you fuck me,
you get cute,
you get stupid...
well, we both know
how that ends.
Change of plans.
What?
Hello?
Kelly,
I need you
to leave the house.
Why?
I don't have time
to explain right now.
Take the kids
and get out.
Meet me
at the Black Bear Diner.
You got a phone?
Uh-hmm.
Call us a cab.
Hey, guys,
I need to talk
to your mom
for a minute.
What's going on?
What did you do?
And who's that girl, Mike?
Listen, uh,
I messed up.
I got into some shit.
These are some really
bad guys and they're--
they got Teddy.
What?
They have him and, uh,
they're making threats.
No, Mike.
I'm gonna do
everything I can...
Mike...
You and the kids--
No...
I need--
I need you...
You stupid shit.
I can fix this.
You can't fix it, Mike.
You can't fix it.
You're the damn problem.
You need to call
the cops.
Tell them
you and the kids
need protection.
You stupid, stupid shit.
All we do is help you,
and all you do is
ruin people's lives.
That's what you do.
Your car's here.
I'm gonna get him back.
You better get him back.
You better bring him back.
Hey, you Ivy?
Uh, yeah.
Hop on in.
How's your day going?
Pretty good.
Good, where to?
Make a right.
Okay.
Men like this
don't forget.
They come back
and finish the job.
There you go,
sweetie.
I've dealt with people
like this before,
not in this exact way,
but in business.
These are sociopaths.
They don't give a shit
about anybody
but themselves.
We do this,
there's no halfway.
Are you sure
you're up for this?
Hello?
Yeah, I know the place.
Old train depot off 226.
Not a lot out there.
I'm counting on it.
Listen...
in three hours,
give this guy a call.
He's a good cop.
We could use
another man.
I might know someone.
Somebody you can trust?
I think so.
And he definitely
seems motivated.
You got to be kidding me.
Who the hell else
are we gonna get?
So, y'all got a plan
for this shit,
or we just gonna jump
into an old-fashioned
dog fight?
Both.
♪ I reach out
my hand to you ♪
♪ But the door is closed
to get you through ♪
♪ Just you and me,
together we would ♪
Do we have to listen
to this?
Hell, yeah.
This shit right here
gets my motherfucking
blood up.
Where you buy
a car like this?
You don't,
you got to build this.
Doesn't seem practical.
Because it ain't.
It's just
my weekend car.
Are you ready?
Is that all you bringing,
that musket?
It's a high-quality
musket, son.
It's your bed.
Frankly,
I'm surprised
you made it out.
These motherfuckers
murdered two of my girls.
You must've taken
quite a loss.
Oh, you think
this is business, huh?
I see what you did
to my granddaughter.
You know, I found her
living on the street,
rolling tricks
for dime bags.
I raised her rate,
gave her a roof.
You wanna get
all mystical
and start searching
for answers and shit,
maybe you ought to think
about what y'all did.
You sure
you can shoot
a fool from this far?
I can rip the heart
right out of his chest.
Just stay put.
You drunk?
I'm comfortable.
Looks like you caught
a stitch in your side.
Looks worse
than it is.
The girl?
Teddy first.
All right,
tough guy.
I'll show you
mine first.
Where's your partner?
Does it matter?
Oh, he got
the prick.
There's some shit
right here.
All right.
Just so we're all
on the same page,
Captain Shit Heels here
makes any sudden
moves,
trigger gets pulled
and off goes
his head.
The same
goes for me.
If I'm forced to make
any sudden moves...
trigger gets pulled
and off goes
his fucking head.
I'm sensing
a theme here.
Mike?
I'm here, buddy.
Oh, fuck.
Take the shot,
come on.
All right, Mike.
Time for you
to show me yours.
Sure.
Let's go, sweetheart.
Take the shot,
Steve, come on.
All right.
Here you go,
take her.
This all could
have been so simple.
Yeah, it didn't
work for me.
Yeah.
Mind if I finish
my beer?
Go right ahead.
Make the shot, old man,
come on, take the shot.
Stay down, Teddy.
Mike!
Aah!
Ah! Ah! Ah!
What the heck?
Mike!
Ah!
Stay put, Teddy,
stay down.
Shit.
Mike!
Fuck!
He wouldn't go down.
Motherfuckers had
vests on.
Steve.
I'm here.
I'm hit.
Son of a bitch.
Mike.
I got you, buddy.
Okay.
I got you.
Come on.
Somebody help these fools.
Mike.
We just spent our morning
in the judge's chambers.
It appears
the court is, uh,
inclined to rule
in self-defense.
Really?
You just lucked out.
What about the girl?
Agreed to testify.
She's in protective custody,
but she'll end
up in a home
after the trial.
We'll hope
for the best.
Right now we've got two
of the three pricks in custody.
They're partners,
all of them.
They run a high-end
real estate firm
in Orange County.
First one came pretty easy.
Number two gave us
a little chase.
He's running.
Freeze! Freeze!
On the ground.
Okay.
Get down
on the ground.
Those were
$200 wingtips, man.
Number three,
William Ritter,
owns a boat,
sailed himself
into Mexico.
So, it's
probably gonna take
a dump-truck-size shitload
of paperwork to get
his ass out of there.
At least six months
to extradite. And that's...
only if we can convince
the district attorney
this guy's even
worth the trouble.
Worst part is we know
exactly where he's at.
An old fishing village,
couple miles south
of Costa Maya.
We just
thought you might
wanna know that.
You have
two hours.
I repeat,
that is two hours
exactly to complete
this exam.
It is multiple choice.
You will begin... now.
Heard they ruled
that shooting...
self-defense.
They did.
That's good.
Took the private
investigator's exam
this morning.
Seemed like
I knew most of it.
I think this
is something
I could be good at.
Even if I am
a fuck-up.
Yeah.
Might be.
How's Kelly?
It's not gonna
happen right now, Mike.
Thought maybe
we could get a drink.
Maybe a coffee.
Uh, gonna need
some time.
♪ When I think
of all the good times ♪
♪ That I've wasted
having good times ♪
♪ When I think of all
the good time ♪
♪ That's been wasted
having good times ♪
Hey there, motherfucker.
Don't you
look comfy.
♪ When I was drinking ♪
♪ I should've been thinking ♪
♪ When I was fighting ♪
♪ I could've done
the right thing ♪
♪ All of that boozing ♪
♪ I was really losing ♪
♪ Good times ♪
♪ When I think
of all the good time ♪
♪ That's been wasted
having good times ♪
♪ When I think
of all the good time ♪
♪ That's been wasted
having good times ♪
♪ All of my lying ♪
♪ I remember her crying ♪
♪ My useless talking ♪
♪ I could've been walking ♪
♪ Instead of complaining ♪
♪ I could've been gaining ♪
♪ Good times ♪
Yes!
Yeah, we all are
having a jolly good time.
And everything
is working out fine.
Ha, ha, ha.
♪ Useless talking ♪
♪ All of that walking ♪
♪ All of my sinning ♪
♪ I could've been winning ♪
♪ I have it too easy ♪
♪ And it's a beginning ♪
♪ Of good times ♪
♪ Good times ♪
♪ I said good times ♪
♪ Talking about good times ♪
♪ Oh, good times ♪