Previously on
Sons of Anarchy...
Meet needs to
be on neutral ground.
There's an Indian
reservation ten minutes
from here.
Very private.
Juan Carlos just
locked down our Irish cartel
gun meet.
Where are the letters?
Tara's still got 'em?
Just leave her out of it, huh?
Too late.
We have an internal threat.
The doctor.
That's your VP's old lady.
We'll clean it up.
What?! Oh, my God!
What are you doing?!
Jax!
You'll be okay.
Oh, my God! Dad?!
Oh, my God! Shit!
What are you doing here?!
Clay killed your old man.
Clay's got to go, son.
Want to tell me
what happened to Piney?
You should know,
you're Clay's boy.
Clay killed my old man!
Did you know?!
No, Ope!
You're gonna die at the gavel.
Ope!
Put it down.
Please, Ope...
don't make me kill you.
Oh, shit.
I heard shots!
What happen?
Call an ambulance.
Oh, Christ!
Call an ambulance now!
Gunshots.
Sheriff's gonna be all over this!
Get me outside.
It happened in the garage.
Yeah. Come on. Come on!
On three. Two, three!
What do I tell Roosevelt, huh?
Mexicans?
No, say it was black.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, I'll take care of Opie!
Get rid of those guns and
clean up the blood!
I'm getting real good at that.
He was shot by
two black guys outside
the garage.
You ever want to make patch,
that's your story until
I tell you otherwise.
I get it.
Keep it wrapped.
Get out of here.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You think he's gonna make it?
I don't know.
Hey, you should get out
of here, too. Go.
Yeah.
I'm gonna kill him.
No, you're gonna let
me find out what the hell happened.
Talk to your mother.
Gemma and Unser found my
old man up at the cabin.
They knew Clay killed him.
Tried to pass it off
as a cartel hit.
How do you know all that?
Unser followed
me up there last night.
Jesus Christ.
I'm gonna drop you at the
emergency care off of Crane.
- Lyla'll pick you up?
- Yeah, man.
You've got to lay low, Ope.
I'll tell the guys
you're up at the cabin.
I will find the
truth, I promise.
Just what I need...
another promise.
- What's his blood pressure?
- Uh, 80/60.
- How much fluid has he had?
- Uh, two liters.
- Both lines in?
- Both lines in, Doctor.
- Okay. Call the O.R.?
- Right away, Doctor.
I was headed over to
get a new starter for my truck.
I roll up to the gate, see
a black SUV speeding out.
Mm-hmm.
A Yukon, I think.
Looked like two
African-American males.
Uh, tinted windows.
Didn't get a real good look.
Mm-hmm.
Uh... pulled in the
lot, find Clay laying there.
Did he say anything?
About the shooters.
No, he was...
barely conscious.
I called EMS.
And there was
no one else on the lot?
No.
We'd split an hour or so before.
So Clay was by himself?
Yeah.
He was keeping the
garage open late for me.
Yeah?
And what about security cameras?
They don't record.
Of course they don't.
All right, I want to speak to
Clay when he's conscious.
The rest of you, just...
stay available.
Hey.
So they were black Niners?
Had to be.
I'm not sure.
I didn't see colors.
Hey, Gemma.
This is on me.
Nah, nah, nah, Clay
wanted me to stay.
He had a feeling something
was going down.
We don't know
anything yet, Tiggy, okay?
I do, I do, I do.
A brother asked for help...
I turned my back.
Hey.
How bad is it?
Doc said he's critical.
One of the bullets hit a lung.
Where are you taking him?
I'm his wife.
We're prepping him for surgery.
Follow me and I can
bring you up to speed.
That's okay.
Just keep him alive.
♪ Riding through this world ♪
♪ all alone ♪
♪ God takes your soul ♪
♪ You're on your own ♪
♪ The crow flies straight ♪
♪ A perfect line ♪
♪ On the devil's bed ♪
♪ Until you die ♪
♪ Gotta look this life ♪
♪ In the eye ♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Lieutenant Roosevelt,
thank you for joining us.
The Wahewa land is proving to be
a bit of a logistical challenge.
You know Clay
Morrow was shot last night.
Yes, I know.
Black retaliation, yes?
He's in critical condition.
We got two other key
members in lockdown.
Do you really think this
meet is gonna happen?
The Irish are here.
The cartel.
They all have a lot to lose if
they let this opportunity pass.
My guess is...
Teller takes the reins.
Either way we
have to play this out.
That means you don't get Clay.
It appears someone else
is determined to right that wrong.
Rough night?
Clay got shot.
He's in critical condition at St. Thomas.
Hm. Who did it?
I'm not sure.
I'm still getting out, Tara.
Deal with the Irish
goes down today.
And then what?
Then I put my goddamn
family in a car and we drive the
hell out of Charming.
Just like that, Jax?
- Change your clothes, wash off the blood...
- Yeah, Tara,
just like that.
Look...
I know it's not gonna be an easy
shift-- I'm not delusional-- but
I also know you're not clear
right now.
I'd argue...
I'm the clearest I've ever been.
Trust me, babe...
rage feels that way.
Have Phil and Elyda
help you pack.
I'll be back tonight.
Yeah.
Okay.
Jax.
Tell me you love me.
I love you, Tara.
Do you love me?
If I could stop I would.
I love you, Jackson.
You need a bigger bowl?
I like cereal.
Stay close to Tara.
She's going to need
your help today.
Absolutely, man.
And if you see Gemma,
tell her I'm looking for her.
Okay.
Hey.
How's he doing?
They've gone back into surgery.
Having a problem with his lung.
Goddamn cigars.
Shit.
Any word from Bobby or Juice?
Nothing on Juice.
Hopefully he's off on
one of his joyrides.
We have bigger problems.
I talked to Lowen.
Bobby signed in at Stockton
and didn't sign out.
What the hell does that mean?
Maybe Lenny can tell us.
He wants a sit-down
with you today.
Lowen said he's pretty
jacked up about it.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
Ope and Tig are MIA, too.
Ope's at the cabin
checking on Piney.
Tig's so wound up about this
Clay thing he's probably neck
deep in cold pussy.
All right, I'm going
to go to Stockton.
Keep me in the loop.
Hey, you be careful, yeah?
Where is she?
Bedroom.
Jax is looking for you.
It sounded important.
Another vacation?
Yep. 'Cause the first
one went so well.
Clay was shot last night.
I know.
By Opie.
What?
Why would Opie do that?
Because Clay killed his father.
Piney's dead.
Clay put a shotgun to his chest.
Oh, my God.
He killed him because
he thinks he had the letters.
No.
Piney didn't...
he never even saw them.
I know.
But Clay will do anything to stop
that truth from leaking out.
He's the one that tried
to have you killed, Tara.
Clay hired those men
that came after you.
How do you know that?
He took money out
of our safe to pay 'em off.
I confronted him.
That's why he did this.
Clay... will keep on hurting
everything and everyone that
gets in his path...
until he gets those letters.
He threatened me yesterday.
Told me Jax and I would never
make it out of Charming unless I
gave them to him.
'Cause he's already read 'em.
The copies.
He knows how dangerous they are.
Where are the letters, Tara?
I'll give them to Clay;
we put this to bed.
I'm out of options.
This may be the only way
we get out of this alive.
And if we do
that-- get out of this alive--
then you know Jax
and I are leaving.
I know.
They're in the storage unit.
Towards the back, underneath
a stack of boxes.
Old TM receipts.
Okay.
Gemma.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
When did you get visitation?
That's what I
need to talk to you about.
Otto made some kind of deal.
What are you talking about?
I heard it from the guards.
He met with a Fed attorney, gave
up something, got me visitation
and yard time.
Shit.
Bobby visited Otto yesterday.
Never signed out.
Juice is MIA, too.
Why the hell would Otto flip?
Had to be something
to do with Luann.
Uh, talk to Clay,
let me know what I should do.
Yeah, all right.
Hey... thanks, Lenny.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
Oh, shit! Look out!
V!
Just be there,
just be there, all right?
I'm heading out of Oakland
on the 5-80, all right?
They got him at the
garage, hit him twice.
Do they know
who was responsible?
Not yet.
Could be all the shit we
stirred up in Oakland.
Well, we're sorry
about what happened to Clay.
But how do we handle today?
I can run the exchange
with the Kings, but we may have
a bigger problem.
I just heard from one
of my guys in Stockton.
We got a member inside
who may have flipped.
Otto Delaney.
He's been talking to the U.S. attorney.
Does Otto know about us?
No, but he might have
given up another member.
It means the Feds
could be circling us.
Too big of a risk for today.
We've got contacts
that can find out about Otto.
Don't do anything till
you hear from us.
Yeah, okay.
All right.
Call Medina.
Have him vet out every agency.
Find out what the
hell this is about.
Yeah.
Tig's in trouble, brother.
Needs an escort home.
Oaktown.
Shit!
♪ ♪
Drive, idiot.
Come on, boys.
Go.
Do not lose 'em!
Go!
Goddamn it!
What the hell's going on?
Go. Go ahead!
Chibs, stay with Tig,
we'll block him off!
Let's go, bro!
Damn it!
What happened?
I went after Laroy, man.
What tel hell
is the matter with you?
Hey, we don't even
know if it was the Niners.
Come on, man.
Come on.
The way we backed Alvarez in
Oakland, it had to be Laroy that
gunned down Clay.
It is a club call, not yours.
You're gonna start a
goddamn war, man.
I don't give a shit.
Yeah, obviously.
Hey, Jax.
Rat just called.
Clay's out of surgery.
I'm gonna go see him.
Hey.
No more rogue shit.
Do you hear me?
Yeah.
He's right.
Had to be Laroy.
He's got to die.
Like, a lot.
It's Romeo.
Yeah.
Had my contacts
look into Otto Delaney.
Not sure who he was talking to,
but he never sold out your club.
You sure?
My guy got it from inside.
I pay a lot of
money for information, Jax.
It's accurate.
Trust me, if I thought it was a risk,
I wouldn't be making this call.
I'll see you at 3:00.
Yeah.
Okay.
We're a go.
Head up to the
warehouse with Tacoma.
Pull one of each big gun.
We'll need 'em for the meet.
Thanks.
Track down Lowen.
Have her start making calls.
I'm starting to get really
worried about Juice and Bobby.
Aye.
Um, don't worry.
- We'll-We'll find them.
- All right.
I'm gonna dig into Clay's
scheduling info, get up to speed
for the Irish.
Sorry, brother.
I should have stayed.
Had your back.
I mean, just turning in this SA
tag-- I don't know, man--
was just kind of lost in
this cartel shit.
I love you, Clay.
I do.
I guess I'm having a hard time
wrapping my head around you
stepping down.
I don't know...
I don't know what I'm gonna look
like when that
happens, you know?
This is not your fault, baby.
Oh, honey.
It's okay, sweetheart.
It's okay.
Oh.
He knows you love him.
It's okay, really.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Ah, shit.
Shit. How are you?
I'm fine.
Where's Jax?
Oh, he's at the clubhouse.
Uh... give me a minute, yeah?
Okay.
Sorry.
I've been looking for you.
Shut the door.
What happened to Piney?
Clay killed him.
Look, I know Clay and
Piney were beefing over this
- cartel shit...
- It wasn't over the cartel.
It was over these.
Maureen Ashby put them in your
bag before you left Belfast.
They're letters
from your father.
Tara found them before you did.
Tara had these?
Why didn't she tell me?
She knew they
would break your heart.
Same way they did mine.
When Thomas got sick, your dad
stopped going to Belfast...
started writing to Maureen.
What does this
have to do with Clay?
JT and Kellan decided
to get the MC out of guns, away
from the IRA.
Clay thought it was a mistake.
He was afraid John would
destroy the club.
So he decided to kill him.
The first time... he sent John
into a Mayan ambush, unprotected.
Your dad made it out.
But he knew it was
Clay who'd set it up.
And he knew Clay
would try again.
He predicted it would
be mechanical.
He was right.
The accident.
The only person JT ever
let work on his bike was Lowell Sr.
Clay must have...
paid him off or threatened him.
He had to be the one who
sabotaged the Panhead.
Lowell Sr.
was killed by the Mayans a week later.
Yeah.
Clay buried the secret.
How do you know all this?
The letters.
The speculation.
The Mayan ambush.
John knew Clay would kill him.
And Clay knew those
letters would prove it.
Enough to get him voted out,
undo everything he'd worked for.
Piney got ahold of these.
He must have threatened Clay.
Oh, my God.
That's not all.
I found the cover letter Maureen
wrote telling you to read them.
It was in your house.
I knew Tara was the
one who'd found them.
I... I panicked.
I told Clay.
Clay knew...
that Tara had these?
He tried to kill Tara.
That thing that happened in the
park, that wasn't the cartel.
That was guys Clay hired
to kill your wife, Jax.
How did you get them?
Tara gave them to me.
Don't be upset with her.
She didn't want
you to read them.
She didn't know
what you might do.
Why are you
telling me this, Mom?
Why now?
Because I know how
dangerous secrets can be.
And it's time we all
knew the truth.
Clay Morrow killed your father.
Stole that seat away
from this family.
Gunned down your
father's best friend.
And he tried to kill your wife.
He's a murderous traitor.
And there's only one thing
to do now, Jackson.
For your father, your
family and your club.
It's in you.
It's who you are.
Clay has to die.
Read 'em.
See him in your
father's own hand.
And then you kill him, Jax.
You kill Clay before he's on
his feet and strikes first.
And when it's done...
you take your place at the head
of this table...
where a Teller belongs.
Where you belong.
Clay came through the surgery.
Lung's okay.
Should be out of intensive
care in a few days.
Good.
So...
what happens now?
Things are in motion.
Yeah.
I have no doubt.
But maybe you want to tell
me what the hell that means?
Tara gave me the letters.
Jax is reading them.
Oh, Christ!
Not all of them.
We're protected.
Clay... not so much.
Got a minute?
Uh, yeah, I'll...
go give Chucky a hand.
Doc.
I been waiting for you.
Yeah, I know.
Where are the letters?
Did you bring them to Clay?
No.
How many did you take
out before you gave them to Jax?
If you knew...
why'd you tell me where they were?
Because I'm smarter
than you are, Gemma...
and I know Jax
better than you do.
You should have told me.
I was going to.
When you got out, you were
so eager to leave, I just...
I was afraid it would push you back in.
I'm sorry.
I have to kill him, Tara.
I know.
And this is how you do it.
It's a blood thinner.
Inject it into his IV line and
pull the tube from his chest.
He'll bleed into his lungs and...
drown.
It'll happen quick.
You know, just...
look like he pulled it out in his sleep.
Jackie!
Time for the meet!
We got to go, brother.
You kill him...
and then you come and get me and
our boys and drive us out
of this poisonous town.
I will.
I promise.
What are you doing?
Everything you taught me.
He's mine.
♪ ♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com