In memory of Carl Th. Dreyer
A Film by João César Santos
on
SOPHIA DE MELLO BREYNER ANDRESEN
Assistant Camera Operator,
Emílio Pinto
Assistant Director,
Jorge Silva Melo
Sound Editor
Alexandre Gonçalves
Director of Photography,
Abel Escoto
A Production of
Ricardo Malheiro
Stanzas and children
as you bring to the world?
As on the beach
the shadows of corals converse you?
As of anguish the deep nightfall?
As one who splits
and scatters oneself?
As one who might kill you?
Or as one who shall never return to you.
JORGE DE SENA
"And so the Girl of the Sea
sat on the boy's shoulder and said:
"I'm so happy, so happy, so happy.
"l thought I'd never see you again.
"Without you the sea,
despite all its anemones,
"seemed sad and empty.
"And I spent my entire days sighing
and didn't know what to do.
"Until one day the King of the Sea
gave a big party.
"He invited many whales, many
sharks and many important fishes.
"And he told me to go to the palace
and dance at the party.
"At the end of the banquet
the time came for me to dance,
" I entered the cave where the
King of the Sea was with his guests,
"sitting on his nacre throne
surrounded by sea-horses.
"And then the dog-whelks started
singing a very ancient song
"that was invented
in the beginning of the World.
"But I was very sad and
so my dancing was very poor.
"Why is your dancing so terrible?,
asked the King of the Sea.
"Because I'm filled with longing,
I replied.
"Longing?, said the King of the Sea,
what's that all about?
"And he asked the octopus, the crab
and the fish what had happened.
"They told him everything.
"And so the King of the Sea
felt sorrow for my sadness
"and felt sorrow for a ballerina that
didn't know how to dance anymore
"and said: come to the palace
tomorrow morning.
"The morning of the next day,
I returned to the palace
"and the King of the Sea
sat me on his shoulder
"and took me up
to the surface of the waters.
"He called a seagull, gave it a bottle
with an anemone filter
"and sent it looking for you.
"And that's how I got you back.
"Now we'll never be apart again,
said the boy.
"Now you'll be strong as an octopus,
said the octopus.
"Now you'll be wise as a crab,
said the crab.
"Now you'll be happy as a fish,
said the fish.
"Now your land is the sea,
said the Girl of the Sea.
"And all five of them went through
forests, sands and caves.
"The following day,
"there was another party
at the palace of the King of the Sea.
"The Girl of the Sea
danced all night long.
"And the whales, the sharks,
the turtles and all the fishes
"were saying: we've never seen
such perfect dancing.
"And the King of the Sea
sat on his nacre throne,
"surrounded by sea-horses, and his
purple robe floated on the waters".
Did you like it, Xavier?
Yes, but you could have
used a more natural voice.
A more natural voice?
How would that be?
A natural tone.
- It's not yours!
- It's not mine?!
"The earliest thing I remember
is a bedroom facing the sea,
"inside of which, on top of a table,
there was an enormous red apple.
"From the shimmering of the sea
and from the redness of the apple
"there arose an irrefragable,
naked and unbroken bliss.
"lt was not at all fantastic,
it was not at all imaginary:
" it was the very presence
of the real I was discovering.
" Later the work of other artists
"would confirm the objectivity
of my own gaze.
" In Homer I recognised
the same naked and unbroken bliss,
"that splendour
of the presence of things.
"And I also recognised it, intense,
alert and ablaze
"in the painting
of Amadeu de Souza-Cardoso.
"To say that the work of art
is part of culture
"is rather scholarly and artificial.
"The work of art is part of the real
"and it is destiny, fulfilment,
salvation and life.
He Who seeks a just relation
With the stone, With the tree,
With the river,
is necessarily led
by the spirit of truth
that inspires him
to seek a just relation
With Man.
He Who seeks the amazing
splendour of the World is,
by force of logic, led to see
the amazing suffering of the World.
He Who sees a phenomenon Wishes
to see the Whole phenomenon.
It is simply a matter of attention,
sequence and rigour.
And that's Why
poetry is a moral act.
And that is Why the poet is driven
to search for justice
through the very nature
of his poetry.
Like Antigone,
the poet of our time says:
I'm the one Who did not learn
to yield to disasters.
Even While speaking merely
of stones and breezes,
the Work of the artist
Will alWays tell us this:
That We are not merely animals
sharpened by the struggle
for survival,
but that We are rather,
by natural right,
heirs to the freedom
and dignity of beeing.
Oh Sophia, if I were
to look back on my life,
in the end, the assessment I would
make is precisely the one
I have made many years ago when
I wrote The Coral, which is this:
I believe in the nudity of my life.
I don't believe in biography,
which is life told by others.
In the end, all there is,
the only biography I have
is the one in my poetry.
And, essentially, what I have sought
was that sense of nudity,
to put oneself
in the face of each thing,
as if it had never been seen
and start looking
from the first moment
as if it was the first day
of the world,
and, in essence, when I say
" I believe in the nudity of my life"
it's the same thing...
Oh I can't stand it, Xavier,
I can't, I can't, absolutely not!
Xavier, why all this?!
These people, Whose face is
at times luminous
and at times rough
here reminding me of slaves
there reminding me of kings,
rekindles my taste
for fighting and fraying
'gainst the vulture and the snake,
the pig and the fork-tailed kite
For the people Whose face is
chiselled by patience and hunger
are the very people on Whom
an occupied country
Writes its name
In the face of these people,
ever ignored and tramped on
Iike the stone on the ground
and, further than the stone,
humiliated and crumpled,
my chant reaWakens
and I resume the search
for a liberated country,
a pure life
and fair times
I'm not at all a nostalgic person.
For me, things,
the things I care about,
are those things that are still
actual, that are still alive,
that are still active.
If they ceased to be active it is
because they have ceased to exist,
it is because
they did not truly exist.
I deeply believe that we choose
eternity while in this world,
that is, it is here and now
that we build and create eternity.
And that which we will find later
is that which
we were capable
of finding here and now.
If we have not found it here, then
we will not be able to find it later.
It makes no sense to talk about
lsadora Duncan,
because nobody can understand
the kind of relationship that existed
betWeen her and my mother
from an early stage.
Even if they did,
it's not their business,
because the truth about a person
is not a spectacle
and the public is here
to be entertained.
Someone, do you recall
Who it Was that said
that first you have to decide
according to oWn mind
and your oWn taste
and afterwards have the time and the
courage to express all your thoughts
With regard to the chosen subject.
So, one must say everything
in simple Way,
setting as one's goal not seductions
but rather convictions.
All my life I recall seeing my mother
dancing when we were little.
All the time my mother would dance
and put flowers on her head
and do dance-steps,
while speaking to herself
as she walked down the corridors.
One of the funniest things
when we were kids
was that mother sometimes called us
and said she was going to make a film
and using the living-room
or bedroom lamp
she made animals appear
on the walls, huge shadows.
This is a rabbit, this is a wolf,
this is an animal,
and she would make up stories
in forests
through those animals that
she cast on the walls.
When I die I Will return to reclaim.