I took your advice. It was
good advice, thank you.
You're pale, everything ok?
Shawn. Shawn!
Hey!
Anyway listen I wanted to tell you, only
reason why I canceled..
Oh, he's calling me three times a day. I
hear more from him now, than I did when
we were together. What is it with guys?
I gave notice.
- Ticket. -Notice?-
May I see your ticket?
- I ehh...
Hey
You are acting a little strange this morning,
are you ok?
Are we gonna make up the 10 Minutes?
- We gonna try, Sir.-
Hey, grandpa,
what the heck was they delay back there?-
I just punch the tickets, Sir.
- You should punch your face...
Shawn, did I do something?
Look, I can see that you think you know
me but I don't know who you are
My name is Captain Colter Stevens.
I fly helicopters for the US Army in Afghanistan.
Shawn, that's .... -Shawn?-
I feel sick.
- Dammit!- Sorry! Let me help with that...
No, it's ok.
Hey Mister! Hey!
Hey, you dropped this!
- Thanks!-
What is that?
- Chicago.-
"All aboard, doors are closing"
"This is a Chicago-down train"
You ok there, Captain?
Did you see that?
You kinda freaking me out.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no....
Are you alright?
- I don't know, what's going on...-
Talk to me Shawn! -Look, I don't know who
Shawn is, and I don't know who you are!-
Ok, we get off at the next stop
and forget whatever is going on here, ok?
This doesn't belong to me.
Look at me,
everything is gonna be ok!
Captain Colter Stevens,
this is Beleaguered Castle.
Captain Colter Stevens, this is Beleaguered
Castle, acknowledge transmission.
Captain Stevens, do you copy?
Where am I?
You are with "Beleaguered Castle"
Are you functional?
I am dizzy. Did I ... Did I just a-lock?
Adjusting your rotation.
Can you report this time?
Fuck is this? What this is?
Wher.... who I am talking to?
Captain report what you saw.
What, I don't understand it - Where were
you before you were talking to me?-
There was an explosion.
- Coming from where?-
Some confusion is perfectly
normal at this stage, Captain.
Do you have a visual signal?
Who are you?
You already have that information, Captain.
- I do?
Recall my name.
We'll rebuild the pattern. Try to focus.
I... was on a mission
I was flying...
And then I woke up on a train.
Now I am here.
I need to be briefed.
Uhm, wha-what unit is this?
You're with Beleaguered Castle.
- Who?-
Stand by for thread 1 of alpha memory pattern.
- What is "beleaguered castle?"-
The exercises will assist you.
Memory thread 1. Listen to the Lilly awoke
in an evening dress and an opera cloak..
...in her hand were 5 play cards
- Is this a joke?-
The Queen of Spades, Four of Clubs...
..Nine of Clubs,
Three of hearts, Nine of Hearts
Is this a red flag exercise?
End of thread 1. Thread 2: The following
is a recording of a western screetch-owl
End of thread 2. End of pattern.
Acknowledge.
Acknowledge end of pattern.
Stand by to initiate pattern recall?
Go for pattern recall.
Arrange the 5 playing cards in order of
descending value irrespective of the suit.
Queen, two nines, four and a three
- That is correct-
The passage I read contained mention of
a woman's name. What was that name?
Her name is Lilly.
That's correct
Recall my name.
Goodwin, your name is Goodwin...
That is correct. Welcome back, Captain.
Ma'm, I need to talk to my father.
Has anybody been notified that I am stateside?
Who bombed the train, Captain?
What?
- Who bombed the train?-
A woman kept calling me "Shawn".
That is incidental.
Think Captain, remember back.
Who bombed the train?
I don't know who bombed the god damned train.
Then go back and try again.
- Back where?-
You will have 8 minutes, same as last time.
No, no, no, no, no. No more bullshit sim
tests, ok? I need to know, where I am, what
is the location and condition of my crew.
Does anybody know, that I am stateside?
You are obligated to give me this information!
- Start with the bomb!-
Where is it, what does it look like.
What kind of explosive, how is it detonated.
- Right, right...-
Find the bomb and you'll find the bomber.
- Find the bomb.... wait nooo!-
I took your advice.
It was good advice. Thank you.
Yeah, its good.
And I signed for a NALSAR course. Next thing
you know, I'll be moving to India to find myself.
Dont say....
- Know any good Gurus?-
Oh, she got your shoe...
So, what do you think? Am I on the right track?
It's the same train but it's different.
Deep. I hope it's different.
I feel the same way.
What?
- My hand... Brian... What is it with guys,
everything is more beautiful in retrospect.
This looks so real.
You know, I think it's gonna be really good for
me to get as far away from him as possible.
Unbelievable detail.
- Ticket.-
May I see your ticket?
Thanks.
They wouldn't put the doer in front of me.
The doer?
You are the pretty girl. The distraction.
"Distraction"?
- Every sim has one.-
Hey are we gonna make up the ten minute?
- We are gonna try.-
Are you talking about Brian?
- Hey Grandpa..-
What the hell was the delay back there?
What you late for? -What?-
You seem concerned about the time.
What are you late for?
I'm late to an asshole festival...
I hear you re headlining.
Oh thats funny. Who are you, a comedian?
Yeah, he is a... comedian.
Sit down, freak.
Fans...
Thats the guy. He came in 3rd on America's
Got Talent. Got sided twice for DUI.
We talked about him.
- Thank you, ma'm, thank you.-
You are welcome. - "Glenbrook station" - Yeah,
but at 1 o'clock the bridge is gonna be jammed.-
Damn it!
Ah, I am sorry.
Hey Mr., hey
You dropped this.
- Ah, thanks.-
"All aboard, doors are closing"
The explosion came from behind me.
What's with you?
- Out of time to talk to you right now.-
I got time for you.
Chicago, Union Station"
Oh, shit!
Goodwin, you gonna tell me how to disarm this?
Should I ..... unplug it?
Or do you want me to just leave it?
Ok, ehmm
I am just gonna leave it.
Ok?
Ladies and Gentleman, Transit Security.
You're not. - Due to a classified security-breach
I need all of you turn off your personal electronic
devices till we pull into the station, ok?
That means laptops, cellphones, Cellphone Sir.
Cellphone, Sir! Thank your very much.
Pagers, anything electronic. Thank you.
It's a precautionary measure,
it's nothing to worry about.
So which is it,
security breach or precautionary measure?
Sir!
Is there a problem here, Sir?
- I am in the middle of a very big deal...-
Shawn?
I need you to turn that off.
Why you don't show me that ID again?
Shawn!
Turn it off!
What's your problem, asshole?
Hey!
Shawn, what are you doing?
Hey, not a good idea m'am. Not a
good idea. Oh, that's not a good idea.
I think you broke his jaw.
It's ok, he is not any more real than you are.
I am not real?
How about next time you drive to work!
There's not gonna be a next time.
Stabilize.
Lower your pulse.
Did you find the bomb?
- Yes....-
There is hydraulic fluid all over the floor.
It's not a concern, Captain.
What is... -Tell me about the bomb.-
Where is that man?
I saw a guy with a crutch on the monitor.
He looks like he is in charge,
I wanna talk to him. - That's irrelevant, Captain-
I wanna talk to your commanding
officer! - You can talk to him upon
completion of your mission.-
My mission is in Afghanistan, where my unit is.
I flew two god damn sorties yesterday.
You've been with us for 2 months.
Did you id the bomber?
- No, where is my unit?-
And under who's jurisdiction is this simulation?
Captain, this is not a simulation.
Lives are depending on you.
What lives?
What do you remember about the bomb?
Tell me about the detonator.
No, no, no, what lives?
What you are talking about?
I need to be briefed!
Sir, I need to give him something.
- That's fine, go ahead.-
Get ready to send him back in.
At 7:48 this morning CST, a bomb
exploded on a commuter train outside
of Chicago, killing everyone on board.
and thats the train that you've been on.
No, no, no, I am right here,
you are talking to me right now!
A man named Shawn
Fentress was on that train.
He, for all intents and purposes, is now you.
Every second spent explaining things
puts more innocent civilians at risk.
This makes no sense.
The train explosion was the first attack
of a series. There are going to be more.
Now, did you find the bomb?
In the restroom, ventilation panel above the sink.
Cellphone detonator.
Are we done?
Eh, no no. But that's good,
that's very very good, Captain. Good.
Our record show that 1812 calls
ended at the moment of the explosion.
52 of those calls were tethered to the
cell tower nearest the train. So one of
those calls was made by our bomber.
Do you remember a freight train passing by
just before the explosion?
Yes.
The explosion was timed to engulf the passing
freight train which means, the bomber had to be
watching both trains when the call was made.
52 callers, one of those is our bomber.
I want you to concentrate on
the passengers in your car.
Get to know them, narrow the suspect
pool. Look for ones who seem quiet
or withdrawn, who seem nervous.
As always, you'll have 8 minutes.
8 minutes, and I blow up again?
Yes.
I need you to discipline yourself on this
next pass. Perform only the task that we
assign you. Everything else is irrelevant.
Charge the drivers.
Is my father even...
I took your advice...
It was very good advice.
You're kinda quiet today.
- Just got a lot on my mind. Careful.-
Yikes.
Oh, so sorry
- Don't worry about it.-
That's very kind of you.
You're very decent.
Thank you.
And real.
- Ticket.-
How's everything today?
- It's good.-
Anything out of the ordinary?
- Uhmm no.-
I mean behavior on the train.
Is anything... Anybody seems strange to you?
You look strange.
How about you,
does anybody looks suspicious?
Are you drunk or something?
- Come here. For a second.-
Come on.
Just think of it as a game.
- A game?-
They are all so utterly normal, Shawn.
That's what so terrifying about them.
Maybe there's a team network.
The sleeping giant coached with
the minister and them out there.
Don't forget the sullen college kid,
he is the expendable one.
I bet they are all controlled by the conductor.
Standing there dictatorial demanding tickets.
You are funny.
- Damn it.-
What about that guy?
- Deposition.-
About that woman sitting across from him?
Hair appointment, every Monday, you know this.
You talk to this people more than I do.
Right, right. And the guy behind her?
He's late for an audition, right?
To recorded offenses... That's the
guy that was sided to SUD. - A DUI, I
know. Hey, hows the signal in here?-
It's good.
Is teaching not stimulating enough
for you anymore, Sherlock?
Oh oh, now we slip to the racial
profiling, that is. - Did anyone else
come out of the bathroom over there?-
Well, I saw you coming out of there.
- Me?-
Yes.
- No-
Me?
- Hey Mr-.
Hold on, hold on a second.
Just hold on a second.
It's gotta be something near.
A broken phone.
Christina?
- Yeah?-
Excuse me.
Hey, hey come with me.
- This isn't our stop!-
Now come on, let's take a walk.
- We don't get off here.-
I don't know, just be spontaneous.
- You gonna freaking me up...-
I know this gonna sound really weird but
I have a really bad feeling about this train
and I think that we should get off, ok?
Just get your stuff.
"All aboard. Doors are closing."
Come on, come with me.
So what now?
- Wait, one ........, I'll be right back!-
Ready to get that coffee now?
Oh sorry, yeah, ah... Jus-,
just one more second, ok?
Oh for God's sake.
Feel sick?
It's motion sickness, I get it all the time.
Excuse me... Excuse me.
Are you following me?
- Can I borrow your phone?-
No, I don't have one.
Sure?
- Yeah, I am sure.-
Why you don't leave me alone please?
Or I call the police.
With what?
I thought you said you didn't have a phone.
You know, you have no right....
What are you doing? Gimme my bag back.
Are you crazy?
Shawn!
- Get back!-
Shawn, what's going on?
Shawn!
Stop, Shawn!
It wasn't you.
- What the hell is wrong with you?
Are you insane?
- No! -No, no!
Where is it? -Get away from me!-
Where is it? -Get away from me, please!-
Shawn, Shawn, get up! Shawn!
Shawn, listen to me, get up!
Shawn -Gimme your hand, get off the track......
Mr. C'mon- Shawn, Shawn, Shawn, get up....
Goodwin?
Come in, do you read me?
Captain Stevens, this is Beleaguered Castle,
do you copy? Please respond.
It's freezing here, whats going on.
What's that?
He is in trouble.
I think the oxygen just went out.
Goodwin?
Goodwin!
Find a way to get through to him.
What is it?
What's going on?
It's not the tertiary cooling ether.
Just keep sending strings out,
see if he hooks on to something.
It's hard to say exactly what he's going through.
Sir...
- Please-
It's not a whole lot we can do from here.
If nothing changes,
how much time does he have? - Some...-
....and not long.
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera
cloak, in her hand were 5 playing cards...
Goodwin, you out there?
Goodwin, who is Goodwin.
- This is Captain Stevens, do you copy?-
Captain Stevens?
The capsule lost power.
The capsule? Is that where you
are now, Captain, in a capsule?
You should know, who are you?
- Let me get Captain Goodwin, get to it!-
You invented this thing, right?
I did.
- Are you in command here?-
I am. Were you able to locate the
information we need, Captain?
That's a negative Sir. I was unable
to find the bomber, but I did save
her. A passenger on the train.
I got her off safely, a woman.
Captain, it's gonna be counterproductive
for you to try to save anyone on that
train. They're outside the mission.
Well, but she survived.
And maybe the rest could too.
She survived, but only inside the Source Code.
None of them will be safe.
What is this Source Code?
It's quantum mechanics parable calculus.
It's very complicated.
Try me!
Fine.
When a light bulb's turned off,
there is an afterglow,
a lingering halo-like effect. You seen it?
Yes
- Of course-
The brain is like that, its electromagnetic field
remains charged, just briefly even after death.
Circuits remain open.
Now there is another peculiarity about the
brain. It contains a short-term memory
track that's approximately 8 minutes long
like a convenience store's security
camera that only records the last portion
of the day's activity on its hard drive.
Now combining these two phenomena,
circuitry that remains viable postmortem and
a memory bank that goes back 8 Minutes
Source Code enables us to
capitalize on the overlap.
Shawn Fentress died on that train, of all the
passengers aboard he was your best link.
You two share the compatibility in terms of
gender, body size and your synaptic maps.
What happens after the 8 minutes?
- After? Nothing.-
You cease to exist on the train.
You cannot exist inside the Source Code,
beyond Fentress' 8 minutes.
Source Code is not time travel.
Rather, Source Code is time reassignment.
It gives us access to a parallel reality.
Now the deaths on the train were a tragedy
but Source Code empowers us...
- No, but I saved....-
one person, that girl, that's always sitting across
from me. I pulled her off the train.
Give me her name.
Christina, I don't remember her last name.
Her name was Christina Warren.
- Yes!-
She was 28
- That's her-
born in Moline, Illinois.
Died this morning on the train.
No, no, I pulled her off.
She's fine.
No, she isn't.
- Believe me, she is-
Believe me.
- She saw me get hit by the express train.-
This isn't us getting anywhere. -No, no, no, wait,
wait....- We have to send him in.
A second attack is imminent, Dr. Rutledge.
What second attack?
- The train was just the beginning-
A letter of intent.
- I am sorry, what are you telling me here?-
We have information that Downtown
Chicago is the next target. And they're
planning to detonate a dirty bomb.
You have any idea how many people
would die if an explosion of that
magnitude were to occur in the city?
We're evacuating as we speak. We've to
stop it before it happens, do you understand?
If you find the bomber, his second attack,
the real attack, we think, can be prevented.
We have very little time left.
Out here the clocks only move in one direction.
Charge the drivers.
On the upper deck of the next carriage
there is a conductor's compartment. It's
a small office containing a strongbox.
Inside is a loaded handgun.Get to it. You are
authorized to use whatever force necessary.
I took your advice.......
It was very good advice.......
You're still here.
- Of course I am-
Guess what?
You've quit your job and you enrolled in a
NALSAR course.
Good guess.
Soda can. Coffee spill.
Listen to me... Don't answer this.
You deserve better than that guy.
Everything looks more beautiful in retrospect,
doesn't it?
How did you know there was....
How well do you know me?
- Not that well apparently-
Do you know me well enough, that if I did
something that looked a little strange and
was maybe even a little bit dangerous
and told you to trust me anyway,
that you could do that?
No.
Wow, that was honest.
You are beautiful, you're kind,
and you are painfully honest.
Who are you and what did you do with
Shawn Fentress? - It's the new me-
I don't want to hurt you.
No I am not gonna sit in my seat, alright?
He is bleeding, he needs medical attention.
Is it true that you tried to steal a
gun out of the train security box?
Careful ma'm!
Dammit! -What were you thinking?-
Can I borrow your phone? -No!-
You need to go to the hospital, Shawn.
- Please, please- No, you need
help -Can I borrow your phone?- No!
Why do you want my phone?
What would you do if you only had
one minute left to live? - I don't know-
I would call my dad. I would hear his voice
and I'd tell him I am sorry.
Tell me everything is gonna be ok.
Everything is gonna be ok.
Oh yeah, the gun in the strongbox, that was a
really great idea. Thanks for that.
Did you make any progress?
- Can I get access to a phone?-
I need to talk to my father.
I will try to work on that soon.
Yes, I will try....
Goodwin, how I am doing? I am just
trying to measure my performance here.
Have you ever gotten back in?
Am I doing any better than you did?
No, we're wasting valuable time here.
No, no, I have never been on the
other side of a Source Code mission.
I wouldn't be a viable candidate.
Why not?
..CAOC-N, what is that?..
Because the specifications
are extremely narrow.
What are they?
Captain, you should have found the
suspect by now. This tactical advantage,
this tremendous tool that we've given
you. Don't squander it thinking.
Do.
Please contact my father for me.
This will stop at some point, Captain.
As soon as you finish the mission.
And you re doing really great. This will end.
Whoever planted the bomb had to
have equipment of some kind. Gloves,
a screwdriver to get into the over
the head vent, flashlight, something.
Check bags, backpacks, briefcases, anything.
So... I took your advice.
It was very good advice. -Hey Grandpa!-
What are you doing?
- I am just...-
trying to remember something.
What is that?
- It's a Military patch-
Were you in the Military?
A friend of mine was. He was in
Afghanistan and he disappeared and
no one has heard from him since.
Do you have the Internet on your phone?
No, it's just connected to the office
by a really long piece of string.
Do you think, you can see what you can find
on this guy? -Sure.-
He's been on my mind a lot lately,
his name is Captain Colter Stevens,
he is in the 17th Airborne.
Ok, you owe me.
I'll buy you a cup of coffee...
- Why don't I get one for you now-
Christina
Ehmm, I've been having these dreams lately...
Really vivid...
and you've been in them.
- Really?-
What... oh, no...
No that I wouldn't. I.. It's just...
Ehm, I'll call you back in a minute honey. Yeah.
Cramming?
- Uh, yeah-
For what?
Ehh, Psych.. And I got a big test this morning,
so I should get back to it.
Can I borrow a pen?
- Eh, yeah, sure-
Woooh! Hey, that's not cool man!
Man... Your is a mess.
- What you doing man?-
never find what I am looking for,
just like my bag. Just like my...
How about you let the guy have his bag back?
- Finish your deal!-
Stay out of this tough guy
or doesn't end well for you.
You can't do that.
What am I doing? What am I doing here?
Jesus. Dick.
C-O-C-N.
Excuse me, ma',m. Ehi, how you doing,
good morning. You work at Walter Reed?
Yeah, I used to.
Ehm, I am in the Military.
- You are in the Military?-
Yeah, yeah I am.
- What was going on down there?-
Oh you know, we were just having a little bit of
an argument actually about, about this patch.
Is that what they train you to do? Assault
civilians? - Ma'm please. Do any of
these letters, they look familiar to you?
Do you know what the "N" stands for?
- It's Air Force and the "N" stand for Nellis-
Can I borrow your phone? You know
what, actually I can pay for it. I don't
even have to borrow, I can pay you for it.
...have like 100 dollars...
- I don't want your money-
Just bring it back.
- All right, thank you so much-
Come on, come on, come on, come on....
Post operator.
Uhm, Rutledge please.
- Please hold-
Say, please? -You tell him Captain Colter
Stevens is calling- Hold the line.
All aboard. Doors are closing.
Dr Rutledge will be on in a moment.
I have to tell you something.
- I know, I found him-
Your friend...
- I got him.-
An Air Force Base. In Las Vegas.
- No, he's not-
He's dead, Shawn.
- What?-
I am sorry. Your friend
was killed in action two months ago.
No, you must have gotten
the name wrong.
Colter Stevens, 17th Airborne helicopter pilot,
was on the first site I tried.
His father's name is Donald, right?
"Donald Stevens will join host Eleonor
Gwah to discuss the death of his
son, Army Captain Colter Stevens
who died in Afghanistan in February and was
honored posthumously with the silver star.
Also on the broadcast will be Army
Sergent Rorbert Alvarez, whose life
was saved by Captain Stevens in
a firefight just outside of Kandahar.
I'm sorry.
Captain.
Shawn... talk to me. -Captain.-
Captain Stevens,
my name is Captain Colleen Goodwin.
You're with operation Beleaguered Castle.
You are safe.
Now, can you tell me what you see?
Just look and think. - I see a card- That's good.
Do you copy, we're taking a lot of RPG fire here.
Am I dead?
A radio listing is saying that I died in
a helicopter crash
in country, and my father received a medal
for me. - Your condition is not the issue here-
You need to focus on preventing
any subsequent attacks.
Everything else is irrelevant.
News report saying that I am dead is irrelevant?
Until the person or persons who blew up
that train are in custody... yes!
Goodwin.
One soldier to another.
Am I dead?
Part of your brain remains activated.
What about the rest of me? I can see my
hands and my feet. They still move.
They're a manifestation. They're just
your way of making sense of all this.
So..what are you saying? Are you saying
that I am imagining this? I'm imagining that
...I am still alive, that I am in this capsule?
We have fourth amp dropping.
Captain, what just happened?
Can I ask you a question?
The capsule is a manifestation as well.
Where am I?
- Thats classified-
Fuck you!
Captain, I can not imagine what you must be
feeling right now, but if are to prevent a second
attack, we need to send you back immediately.
And Captain, you cannot deviate from
the mission while inside the Source
Code. Even to investigate your, hmm...
Even to investigate what happened
to you. There is only one continuum
on this end and it can't be unsettled.
Well, you know, I did unsettle it.
I called you from the train.
Just before the explosion, so 7:46 this morning
they paged you with a call.....
You may have made that call from the train,
but I would never receive it here.
It's a different reality, Captain. If the
call even went through it would be
received by a different me entirely.
This may be difficult for you to hear,
but you are a hand on a clock, understand?
We set you, you move forward. We reset
you, you move again. And that represents
the entirety of your function here.
You know what, next time, I'll send you a pizza.
I see, if that makes an impression.
You cannot alter the continuum of this
reality from within the Source Code.
This can't be legal what you are doing.
In fact, your acquisition by this program
as well as the program itself, has been
reviewed and sanctioned by a military court.
You know, many soldiers would find
this preferable to death. The opportunity
to continue serving their country.
Have you....
Have you spent much time in battle, sir? Uh?
That's immaterial.
Any soldier I've ever served with could say
that one death is service enough.
Fine, you can have that in return
for completing this mission.
Wha... Have what?
- I'll give you what you want-
Terminate your service,
let you die.
This is taking too long, you've been to
easy on him. No more rest periods.
I am certain, we can find other service men
with wounds similar to yours who'll consider
being a part of this program an honor.
Uh? No, no, no, no, no. Wait, wait. What?
Send him back.
Charge the drivers.
And Captain Stevens, I'd like you to
remember that it's not only about you,
but it's also about 2 million
real world Americans. Now you
may not value your own life,
I do however ask
that you value theirs.
Advice....
Hey Grandpa.....
Calm yourself, you're back.
Did you find the bomber?
Uh..... There...
are hundreds of people on that train.
Well, then check them out one
by one. Doesn't matter what you
do to them, they're already dead.
Get to that gun and shoot them all if you
have to, but get us some usable intel.
No! No, wait!
We have to keep doing this, until you find the
bomber. - Please, I am trying, I am trying-
Who is the bomber?
I am trying.
I am sorry, Captain. I know you are
exhausted and we are all frustrated,
but we can not fail. You can do this.
I can't, I can't...
- Yes, you can-
You are a born hero, son.
Even your father thinks so.
Saving people is what you do best.
It was about a stir, too.
I didn't wanna regroup back
I just..... started feeling
like he didn't wanna come home anymore
- Dad?-
Somehow, he couldn't come home.
and he wouldn't talk to me.... wouldn't hear me.
Hardly said he just.... couldn't leave his unit
out there without him and that was that.
Those guys.... were his family.
I said two things I shouldn't have. I don't know.
I never fully understood him.
And I can't believe he is gone.
Send me back in.
Please don't
blow me up again.
Hello?
I know, its you.
I am gonna find you.
Turn around?
Hey there. -Me?-
Why you look so surprised?
Don't.
Move. Move. Move. The bag over there.
Move over, put the bag over there and move over.
Move over. Now hand me your phone.
You're done! You're done.
- What?-
You can't kill anybody anymore.
- What? I don't understand-
You gonna trigger the bomb with your phone.
- What?-
I swear I don't know
what you're talking about.
Listen, my name is George Troxel,
I am software engineer, ok?
I was talking to my wife.
Try it again.
Your call, dial it again.
Ok, I am gonna press redial. Your phone
is gonna ring and then I gonna shot you.
Shit, I am sorry. Sorry.
Hey! You dropped this.
Wow, thanks.
All aboard. Doors are closing.
Shit, no, no!
No!
Come on!
Stop the train!
Hey!
Derek Frost
- Yes?-
See this?
- Yes-
Recognize it?
- No-
Jesus.
- How about you give me your wallet?-
Ok
No, you left it on the train deliberately.
I... must dropped it.
No, you planted it there, so everybody
would think you were dead.
I know, it's you.
- How do you know so much?-
Hell is that thing?
Wow, wow, wow. wow, wow.
Slow down, slow down.
Do you wanna see it?
- Very patriotic-
Slowly, slowly!
All right, all right. Back up, back up! Back up!
Not many people could build that.
Alright, where is your next target?
Shawn?
Shawn Fentress.
Teacher. History.
I don't know you.
I think I killed your girlfriend.
Why?
Oh, you messed up my timing.
Why!?
Oh, you mean why this.
Because the world is hell.
But we have a chance to start over
in the rubble
but first there has to be rubble
You are teacher. You..... will understand.
Christina... Stay with me!
Stay with me!
Everything is gonna be ok.
This isn't the end.
Check through there
I'll go check this way.
This is Beleaguered Castle.
Captain, this is Beleaguered Castle.
Acknowledge transmission.
Captain Stevens, this is Beleaguered Castle,
acknowledge transmission.
I have your bomber,
I have his name.
You have the bomber's name?
Derek Frost.
He got into a rented white van in
the Glenbrook Station parking lot.
Illinois plate, 5CGY847
All right, let's move.
And Goodwin..... and Goodwin,
there is a radioactive device in the van
some kind of bomb.
Thank you, Captain.
- Yes, Ma'm-
You now off the clock. -About our deal?-
I had hoped that you might reconsider
that for the sake of the program.
I have,
I want something else now.
Good.
I.... I still wanna die, but I wanna go back in and
I wanna save all those people on that train first.
It doesn't work that way, it can't.
- No, I know, I know, I know....-
I am not really asking to believe
me, sir. I am just..I am asking to
have the decency to let me try.
CPD2 this is AS11
Van is approaching fens
cape to the quarry, over.
Roger that, AS11. We're on the vehicle,
that into the quarry road.
We'll stop him about half way down, over.
AU-SWAT2, this is CPD2, block
the east end of the road, over.
AU-Swat2, roger that.
We are going to switch now to a
live feed from our Chicago affiliate.
The swat team is approaching the white van.
An Illinois man has been
sorted through this morning...
The door is op... the door is open and the man
is on the ground. It appears he has surrendered.
Earlier today the police discovered
a..... -Congratulations, Captain.-
.....lab in the backyard shack..
In recent months Frost started posting
anti-government statements on his website.
Yes Sir, it's a real validation of the program
a clear window into just how
revolutionary Source Code can be.
We finally have a powerful
weapon now in the war on terror.
Congratulations Captain,
job well done.
He is not gonna send me back in,
is he, Goodwin?
I am still waiting an answer.
Are you married, Captain?
Jeff, why don't you go take a break?
You deserve to celebrate.
Sure.
Can I get you something?
- No, I am fine-
Why, you asking me on a date?
Sorry, poor taste.
Are you married?
No.
I am divorced.
You think there is
an alternate version of you?
A Goodwin who made different choices?
What do you mean?
like uh, you didn't get married or you didn't
get divorced, or just married someone else
a woman who has took a
different fork in the road?
No, I don't, Captain.
What you experienced was a shadow, it
was an afterimage of a victim on a train.
This is real life, here.
The one where you talking to
a dead helicopter pilot?
The program wasn't designed to alter
the past, it was designed to affect
the future. And you have done that.
I missed something, Captain.
That train shouldn't have blown up.
There must have been a second detonator.
Something I couldn't see. A fail-safe.
It's a computer program, Captain.
The girl on the train,
all the others, they're lost.
I am sorry about that.
I get it. I get it.
I know, quantum physics, parable calculus.
You're wrong, Goodwin.
You're just plain wrong.
Captain,
Christina is dead.
She doesn't have to be, Ma'm.
I'll ask Rutledge.
I'm asking you.
I'm asking you..... Just..... send me.....
Captain.
It's your choice.
At the end of this Source Code
I'll terminate your life support.
There willl be no
coming back.
I am gonna save her, Goodwin!
It was an honor, Captain.
And I thank you for your service.
Good luck.
I took your advice.
You're gonna move to
India and become a Guru.
Careful, ma'm.
Yeah, I am gonna go find
myself in the mountains.
Well maybe you have a cup of coffee with me
before you go.
Yeah, I like to do that pre-teen test.
Good.
Let's do it today.
Let's just skip work.
Bryan can find someone else to assist him.
You know what?
- What?-
I feel really good.
Why?
Cause I have been waiting for
weeks for you to ask me for a coffee.
Ticket.
Ok.
Just give me a couple of minutes ok?
And I'll be right back.
Gotta go...
save the world.
I knew he was a keeper.
Beautiful day.
Ticket. -Oh, I am sorry. Sorry.-
You trust the DOD?
They got the finances.
Yeah, well sure. Look, if we get the funding.
I guarantee you... we can have at least....
8 source code projects up and running
by the end of the year.
Really that many?
- Maybe more-
You're real hero, Dr. Rutledge.
- Oh, thank you-
We did save lives today.
- Yes, a true victory for the program-
A great victory for us all.
- We'll talk soon-
So...... exciting times.
Let's initialize the memory wipe on
SC-1 and start crunching the data.
...Sir...
We, we.... we told Captain Stevens,
that we were gonna let him die.
Let him die?
He just saved millions of lives today.
How many other disasters
might he avert down the line?
For all we know, he may be the only
candidate with which the system works.
So, let's clear his memory
and reinitialize Source Code.
Shall we?
Yes, sir.
Sorry, I just....
Hey Derek,
this isn't your stop.
Hey Mr. you dropped this.
Come on, back here.
Ops.
Derek.
It's over.
Do you understand?
Hey, my name is Derek Frost
I planted a nuclear device
in a white van,
parked in a Glenbrook Station CCR parking lot
right now I am handcuffed to a pole on the 944
CCR train, headed to Chicago Union Station.
I am a sick and pathetic human being.
And I need to be locked away
for a very long time.
Ok.
Derek, there's no more burying
the world in rubble today.
You mind if I borrow this?
Captain, some of the guys and I
are gonna go celebrate.
And.... they want me to initiate
the memory wipe, Captain.
Hello, Captain.
Hello?
- Donald Stevens?-
Yes.
My name is Shawn Fentress.
- Who?-
I served with your son, Colter.
Oh boy...
It's a..... I am sorry it has taken me so long
to.... call you. Sometimes it just takes a while
to figure out what you wanna say, you know.
Ah, don't be too hard on yourself...
It's not an easy call to make.
How are you doing, Sir?
Uh... Well ehm...
All that came back was some ash.
It's hard to believe that it was him.
How well did you know him?
I was there when he died, Sir.
He said...
that the last time that you guys talked, ehm...
was tough ....and
he wanted to say that he was sorry.
I just wanted him back.
I loved him so much.
I wish I could have told him that.
- He knows it-
Take care, Mr. Stevens.
You ok?
- Yeah-
Saved the world?
- Sorta-
So, where were we?
Getting some coffee.
Dr. Rutledge?
What?
Shit!
What is too hard about it? I run a business, ok?
Everything moves on time or people get fired.
That's how it works in the real world.
- 10 Minutes -
Hey buddy.
Don't sweat the small stuff, you'll drown.
Oh thank you for the moment of Zen,
but nobody was talking to you.
What do you sound, self help cds today?
Why don't you just mind your own business?
Security? Get me a detachment of MPs
here. This instant!
Why are you always so bitter, Max?
- It's a bitter world we living my friend.-
What you want from me?
It doesn't have to be.
I will bet you 100 dollars, that you can't
make all the people on this train laugh.
Oh right...
Actually, 126 bucks.
Is that your way of making fun of me?
- No, it is to have a better day...-
No, no. It's good. Easiest money ever.
Hey, I... excuse me, people.
One of our fellow passengers has
decided to offer me some money....
What has just gotten into you today?
You're like a different person.
It's the new me.
- I like it-
Women always mess up my last
name. I was with a girl the other night
and she kept calling me "Getoff".
She goes "get off, get off" "I am
"no, Denoff, Denoff", she: "No, you
are fat and you are heavy, get off!"
Good?
20 seconds.
Make it 10.
Goodwin.
Look at all this.
What?
All this life.
Goodwin,
open the SC door!
Why you keep looking
at your watch?
Christina, what would you do....
if you knew you had less than a minute to live?
I'd make those seconds count.
I'd kiss you again.
- Again?-
Goodwin, open this god damn door!
He has done enough, Dr.
Everything is gonna be ok.
It is a beautiful Monday in Chicago today.
Temperature is expected to reach the
lower 60. Right now 55 at the Lake....
What, he earned that money.
- Yea, he did- He is funny.
Speaking of which... I have no cash.
Come here, I wanna show you something.
It's such a beautiful day, isn't.
- Yeah, it is a really perfect day-
Do you believe in fate?
- Not really-
I'm more of a dumb luck kind of gal.
Come here.
So, what do you wanna do today?
- I think we should stay here for a while.-
This feels like exactly where
we're supposed to be, doesn't it?
Good Morning, Jeff.
- Good Morning, Captain-
"Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera
cloak. In her hand were 5 playing cards."
"At some point today, you re gonna
hear about a failed terrorist attack
on a commuter train near Chicago."
You and I kept that bomb from going off.
An attempted bombing on a
CCR train outside Chicago
but it was foiled. and the suspect was
found on board....
Named Derek Frost.
Goodwin, anything I can help you with?
No, that's fine,
I'll come back later.
Well, keep an eye out.
One of these days,
the right crisis is going to rear its head
and Source Code is going to have
its moment in the sun.
Yes, Sir.
If you re reading this email, then
Source Code works even better than
you and Dr. Rutledge imagined.
You thought you were creating 8
minutes of a past event, but you're not.
You've created a whole new world.
Goodwin, if I am right...
Somewhere at the Source Code facility,
you have a Captain Colter Stevens,
waiting to send on a mission.
Promise me you'll help him.
And when you do, do me a favor.
Tell him, everything is gonna be ok.
>> www.napisy.jcom.pl <<
>> Come to the dark side <<