Everybody out.
Get your ammunition
Hurry and you.
Casper ... Come with me.
They are looking for
rofessionals in Africa.
What, bitches?
No, mercenaries, Sgt.
Mexico, and LATIN
AMERICA as well.
$ 1300 per month,
plus transport.
They want real soldiers, Casper,
not typists.
I was told to come to the report, Sgt.
I'm Hardin.
Charles Hardin infantryman. Cpl.
You have o Charlie?
El Paso.
Really?
you have flat, the Louisiana
National Guard?
Not ...
But I liked not the Texas Guard.
Not like the Guard in Texas
was understandable.
But not like the Guard of Louisiana
can get you into trouble.
Pig?
Pig.
You'll be in the 2nd squad.
In recognition.
Casper, show him the path.
Presents it to others.
Cease fire!
We were still gts.
you will have the year, Simms.
A little muscle in the pants.
I really do not need a coach.
Unless a t'intresse.
Listen, Stuckey, I'll fold it in
half, you will make a same-you.
I like to laugh, but
it has not drle.
I'm with you, coach.
I like women.
We will not see the masses.
Life is full of surprises.
What do you mean?
I prvu fte a little, guys.
Six whores shock, borrowed
"for the assault.
They kiss us better than the
Louisiana National Guard.
DCON not you?
Not about women.
Women? Which women?
He has broads ahead, coach.
Prostitutes?
Exactly.
You've never fallen
so low, Spencer.
We have an appointment
just out of Catahoula.
They will be the merger of ...
when we
Great Swamp paramount.
You have one for me?
Me?
You mean we, my brother?
And then!
My guys
purpose of the Guard is prserver
ladies you, brothers of color.
Nevertheless have, in the
spirit of the New South
I have everything
Pipelines Limited.
And you, Hardin?
I am a husband.
Do not count on me.
The military must be
more srieux El Paso.
It's more organized.
We watch the baseball tl
ds we play, and sleep.
Guard in Louisiana is
quite Different.
We did things that really matter
beat up students, gassed nGRE.
If you flat, Mr.
Guard, more grenades!
Do not lchez your dogs on me!
You see?
We have a long and proud
military tradition.
Casper?
Stopped,
Behave like a soldier,
espce of bastard!
In life, you have a real job,
or you're just like them?
I work for Petramco, engineer
for a chemist.
You are all the Universe ...
Plutt is rare in Texas, right?
has come from time to time.
One might think that you do not like
chatting with your friends.
You want to know? You're right.
I can not say I bugging you.
Reece believes he lives
in a soap opera.
Stuckey, it is not even smart
enough to read one.
As for the coach ...
I think I know the type.
These are good guys.
They just want to laugh.
You are the new ...
These are not good guys.
It's the same version of Louisiana
pquenots I've always known.
When i was Fort Polk,
the coach was bitten
by a coral snake.
He put his hand on a tarpaulin,
and a section of a machete.
Cut net!
What bullshit!
You DCON, Stuckey!
I swear it's true!
I do not give fuck
Do you believe me or not.
For those that have INTERESTED,
we go on night patrol.
Shut up and open them well.
Our code-named Bravo.
The Bravo team.
Recognition and security.
Rendezvous Point Charlie.
Just out of Catahoula.
We will move forward in column
by noting the minimum.
And we must act quickly: no
tents, no sleeping bags.
Just the ponchos.
The MTO will be very variable.
Sun, rain, cold in the morning.
Get this idea. You go the fleet.
And it will be ice.
Cribbs!
You your with us?
Sr Sgt. I'm leaving.
has is great, you stay the rear.
Reece, you will head.
It is about 38 km,
fill your water bottles,
the tank.
Every man does his job.
I want no fights.
You all your friends.
You dpendez each other.
Everyone does his job.
For once in your life, have
the air of soldiers.
Civil peace. Soldier at war.
I am a Guard.
It's a. Tchez to remember it.
PROMOTION
- DISTRIBUTION A. M FILMS 1983
NO RETURN
They seem to have an ocean here.
There should be specific
on this point.
Or this map is wrong, or
I lost the compass.
Ad the river out of bed
with the winter rains.
The land is flooded.
Call the company?
No, useless. It's very simple.
Either can be crossed by l. ..
but presents itself evil,
or we will return zero
and start again.
Someone you Bambi.
Who are these boats?
To us.
They belong to the local population,
and not with DCON!
a fleet?
And how! It canoes.
Cajuns use it all the time.
For now, they use it.
If we took them down
to the bayou?
I'm for. I hurt the back.
It would Catahoula tonight.
And women, under martial law.
From what women tell you?
Spencer maze of good women.
He has girlfriends
that lie ahead.
Everything is ready.
"Noleen and queens
of the bayou."
Good for morale.
Really?
And I might add, Sergeant,
that these women rely on ...
pntration a member.
Do not take these canoes.
They are not us.
That's right, they
are not us ...
Jump in and barons us.
Minute, Mongolian!
Nobody has given the order.
But how are we going?
You may be right, Reece.
And how! Let's go.
One minute, Reece.
How will the owner rcuprer
their boats?
II do we need three.
They will use the others.
A shot, it's pleasant.
Catahoula, here we come!
What say you, Sergeant?
Bowden, leave them a word.
Take off your helmets.
Put the belt. Nerve!
In boats, and have the
air of soldiers!
Here they are.
Canoes must be them.
You the earth!
Read on!
You left a note.
Dirty gooks.
They understand it.
J'espre they find my word.
May be that they only
speak francs.
Does anyone speak French?
Reece, arrtez of a dick!
They Ramna!
No quarter!
Espce con!
Casper!
Bring your boat down the.
- Take shelter.
- They have you!
Hide yourself!
Spencer, over here!
Good God, what happens?
Are they still derive?
I know. I see them.
Stash now!
It should fetch Poole.
C'mon you. Me, I'll catch up.
No trace.
O is the dirt map?
He had hand
I remember.
The compass is gone.
How it happened?
In the fleet, what do you think?
And guess who put the?
True, Bowden.
Why hast thou renverss?
I have not spilled the canoes.
It was you who starts.
What are you talking about?
You panic, asshole.
I'll show you panic, jerk!
I did not panic, little shit!
What is mean!
We are all soldiers!
Both of you, shake your hand.
Good.
Simms, where is your radio?
In water, what do you think?
It is you who are responsible.
What are you doing!
It was dead here.
What we gonna do?
Let's get those who have
descended RP Poole.
It's me who is going
o DCID and when.
Magnon us.
And Sergeant Poole?
Allowed, unless you
want to wear it.
He's a soldier amricain!
He has a web of bronze, a Purple
Heart, a mdaille Vietnam.
We will not leave!
The sooner we shoot, the
faster they will get it.
We will complete this mission.
It is our responsibility.
Come, Casper. Here we go.
No, hell, we will not leave.
- Who told?
- Me.
It is I who command ...
And I want more discussion.
We leave.
Stuckey, you really made the
con, with your machine gun.
Nobody told you to shoot.
C'tait just for fun.
White balls.
Forget it.
Forget ... Damn!
This DBIL killed someone
and tell you to forget.
Remember one thing.
Stuckey is not that you Poole.
The thing is, when we
have ramen Poole
we will return to the Cajuns do.
You bet.
We did that swim 200 meters,
and end up in the box.
Then they catch it and shoot
them with our white balls.
So your opinion?
This bayou is going east.
The easiest way is to follow.
We want to go north.
The highway is to the north.
We're heading for the highway.
Not from the East.
The highway is to the north.
Will it bring you, Spencer.
What do you know?
There is a fireball in the sky that
rises up the East, and here we go.
We must go east to go north.
He's right.
Can rpter for me?
Need to go o go o?
Someone wants to see where
we go, and quickly!
Hardin, shut up!
It's my responsibility, we
will go east to the north.
Do what you want!
That's exactly what
I'd do, Spencer!
Turkey.
Turkey meat, turkey skin,
crackers, turkey fat,
salt!
The fags have good resists!
I saved a bundle.
Not bad, right?
Perhaps we should be
very rpart bullets.
What balls?
Reece ammunition.
It always brings on a case where
he would find the big game.
At camp, he showed us
a box of 556.
What is it,
a military secret or something?
No way.
I brought a box for
my personal use.
And I'm loaded, in cases where there
is manure that you Poole.
Give me your weapon, Reece.
O you remain who you are.
Give me ammunition.
We will be the rpart.
We'll share them.
Bugger!
They are me and that's it.
It is not normal, Reece.
Give him the ball.
It is the weapon here.
I give an order, Reece.
Give them to me.
Approach again and I'll give
you something else.
You are liable to the
Court Martial.
Give me the ammunition and
we do not talk anymore.
Otherwise,
I do not care it.
I do not give fuck.
Shall adopt the DCON and
give him your gun.
Immediately.
I'll give Hardin.
Your ammunition.
The knife to her throat, huh?
It's like we're doing
has El Paso?
It's like we had been the No.
I grew up.
I thought you engineer
for a chemist.
Yes.
And I'm used to trans with excitations
of the trigger.
In Louisiana, if not guns,
it's the strings.
It is not very smart ...
but we have fun.
What are you doing, Cribbs?
I'm on duty. You want a puff?
How can you smoke this crap?
I'm not in your team, coach.
You're right! You could not.
to kill the will.
How the guys market this year?
C'tait a transition year.
Top taient blesss.
What do you live?
I have two or three toeing,
but mostly I sell
the same grass.
You're lucky I do
not believe you.
It's true!
My best customers are the school,
and they have ten years.
I want to listen his bullshit.
When do we return the El
Paso kicked in the ass?
Ds that will be the
meeting point.
Then come back to look who
had the gooks Poole.
You think everything
is my fault?
Do not worry.
Done.
How you can play cards with
Sergeant Poole ct?
You have another idea?
I find it has not.
Poole does not care. He died.
I do not see what we
can do for him.
Why not play cards?
I find it has not.
It's here.
Spencer, and Command?
They think we should,
do not you think?
No, not yet.
We lost contact for
over 12 hours.
They should already
be our research.
Impossible.
That the National Guard!
We had to meet the truck
20 minutes ago.
In 1 hour 30, they will
point to good.
At 2 pm, they will
ask if you saw us.
At 3 pm, they will see in bars.
At 4 pm, they will butter.
At 5 pm, they will come to the
idea that might be lost.
At 6 pm, Captain DCID to
call the battalion.
At 7 h 30, it will.
The battalion will say it is too
late to wait until tomorrow.
That's their house!
It is he, this manure!
O are the others?
I think he is alone.
We will capture him.
Why? I can get it here.
It is the National Guard,
not a militia.
That's the program.
It was named one of the
Cajuns who you Poole.
We will capture him.
It is 250 meters.
Sr it is you're in the game?
Of course! What do you think?
If you talked to him before
him to blow his brains out?
Simms, Reece, Stuckey and
I are the vanguard.
The initial action
must be dcisive.
The surprise is the key.
Casper ...
You heard what I said?
I heard you.
He will speak when
we captured them.
The other, keep the rear.
You stay 100 meters away,
and you stash.
It will end when the objective will be curly.
Here we go!
Wait.
I volunteered to the forefront.
Forget a. Do what you're told.
Good God, what bullshit.
I was thinking the same thing.
You always come get you?
You n'tais not voluntary either.
Right.
I will not embark with
these crtins.
At four, with automatic
cons swamp rat.
The match may be zero.
What are you doing, Coach?
Shut up!
I t'arrte!
Bowden moves away
up the prisoner!
I told you to keep the rear!
Mission accomplished, sir!
Bullshit!
You gch your real bullets.
I did not panic.
Okay, now gently.
It must be questioned.
Give up.
Releases them the knife.
Manure, I told you lcher
this fucking knife!
Motherfucker!
You could have broken
his jawbone.
That's true.
He must speak.
Thou hast exploded
near his mouth.
Name of God, Simms!
How he will talk to him
if you qt jawbone?
It's his problem.
Why have you done?
This manure Poole you!
Fuck it!
Lonnie, will see the interior.
You can talk?
O are your friends?
How are they?
What is he talking about?
This has made some Cajun
aim this morning.
It's a poacher.
It turns the poachers.
He made his last stroke.
What happens, Casper?
It was a prisoner.
Congratulations.
You did a great job.
You needed to cut off an arm?
He uses dynamite to pcher.
A true off-the-law!
Casper! There is stuff here.
Simms,
I forbid you to hit it again.
It is you who have
broken her mouth?
A little, yes.
Why did you have?
I know.
I was bored.
This crap weapon you
mount the head.
Beans,
semolina
spinach.
It's better than our rations.
Guns, knives,
ammunition, food ...
Everything is there.
I'd say we made a
nice little raid.
We will pack everything later.
Will be interviewing
the prisoner.
Attach the prisoner.
How do we do when the
guy has one arm?
May be necessary to speak first.
You speak English?
Does anyone speak French?
What you got, coach?
Not look for me.
Not now, not ever.
I'll try.
I made two years the school.
I forgot how to say "shoot".
I think it says it did nothing.
Franais has not resemble
what I learned.
I've seen.
I was the too, but
I swear nothing.
I do not even know if the type
had only one arm.
It was more than 100 meters.
We will bring the prisoner
to be interrogated he,
then judged.
Everyone, and tank.
Fill your water bottles.
It should be distancing
us from here.
Bowden crtin, there's dynamite!
to teach them to play rec.
Indisputable.
What are you doing, Bowden?
You blew the whole mess.
I do what I do.
Why did you painted a cross?
was part of the joke.
What a joke?
It's a joke deuxime class.
Brothel, Bowden!
Asshole!
You blew all decision we made.
Weapons, ammunition and food.
Sometimes you have to abandon
the principles
to do what is right.
We better find the highway.
Come on, Casper.
Your little raid is finished.
This con Bowden
adtruit the cabin and we lost
everything we had before.
aa have alerted the cousins
​​of the bastard.
We will not yet for these
gooks IS CONCERNED!
Si But there's one that should IS
CONCERNED more than me and you.
Me about it.
They believe that you jinx.
They may be right.
I know that nGRE, and
I never had any luck.
Listen, fellas.
Dsol for the incident.
I just let go.
You can tell.
You can also say that you
Completely freaked out.
Sorry, but I admired
Sergeant Poole.
I loved him very much.
That was my excuse J'espre ...
excessive behavior.
Of course.
Say, coach, to take a
risk in the face ...
T'inquite has not, Hardin.
Why did you paint this cross?
You have heard of the
Exterminating Angel?
I thought you, you'd understand.
Dsol dcevoir thee.
If you allow, I would like
to apologize to the other.
I'll teach you a thing.
It's crazy.
Completely crazy.
You do not teach us much.
That's all you say?
APRS the numro he did?
What should I say?
He's an asshole.
There is a reason
and he cracked.
He cracked.
It is painted in red, he
laughs like a dment
and he thinks he is a volcano.
And then, if it is crazy?
What do you want me to do?
I put him in a cage?
As I descend?
I have no preferences.
We will make a successful
exit from?
A little one will escape!
We are two hours maximum of 10.
What is mean!
is meaningless.
A guy that makes dry
out her skin.
Drle of Manir to stretch
the skin.
You are not sr it for us?
There are eight.
And then?
It is eight.
And, what is it?
You know, you?
We must leave.
Why stay here?
We shall be no more.
Shit, Casper!
O is the highway?
has been hours.
Probably not far off.
She passed by here.
The ecologists have
of the displaces.
Shut up, Spencer!
It stops as five minutes.
I will do the calculations.
With what? We have no compass.
You know that is moving
with the sun?
Of course.
It rises east, it sets the West.
The highway is to the north.
We are not party to.
That's exactly what I'll do.
Thank you.
He knows what he's doing?
In your opinion?
So, why we follow?
It has stripes.
You have not forgotten we are
in the military maneuver.
Coming from you, Reece,
is already a classic.
C'tait what?
Dogs, what do you think?
Hunting dogs.
Then there are hunters.
They show us the path.
was getting closer.
Great.
We have hunting dogs
in the corner.
They will show us how we steer!
Good God, he had me.
Goddamned bastards!
Cribbs, all right?
Hardin, you are touch?
you doing?
I think. Damn!
Manure!
They have lch their dogs on us!
How they could make a?
Letting the dogs!
C'tait not the dogs!
And my ass!
Spencer, what you are ct?
Not yours, Reece, was sure.
Shit, Reece. Forget it!
All of you drop!
The enemy does not ask
us to fight better.
Damn, you arrtez five minutes,
and come home.
You, will you calm down.
I want to know what happens.
I do not follow you.
It's not complicated.
My company got transfr
Baton Rouge.
I've been here six months.
I really know nothing about
the Louisiana marshes.
It sends me exercises can,
and all of a sudden,
guys fall on us!
I'll ask again.
What's happening?
I'll tell you one thing.
Me, I'm from the city.
You ask me what happens?
I have not the faintest idea.
Except that we came across strange
people who want our skin.
Everything was shot because a
con white with a machine gun.
Because a fuckers
have stung boats.
Casper! It becomes heavy.
has will not be long.
If left here?
No. I've already told you.
PSE it a ton, the bastard.
Do not talk like a Poole.
He does not hear me.
But if!
Shit, Casper.
That motherfucker is dead.
I speak of that body.
I told you I do not want you
to speak of him as a!
Watch out!
You almost walk into it.
Look at these crap.
It looks like a pussy steel.
What kind of nnet you
frequent providers?
They are tense. All seven
Like rabbits.
There were eight rabbits.
And why there are only seven?
We lost someone?
They are for us?
For us, or
the last seven bears
in Louisiana.
What you asked him?
What did I.
My bastard, is that
there are others?
I'm talking to you!
Reece, drops! Shall adopt!
They have not had,
and we have not.
We lost enough time.
The motorway is not far.
Let's go.
Cribbs, you take the head.
Shit, Casper. I see why.
I do not know where is the highway.
You always say you know ...
Why do not you take the head?
No unnecessary noise, and
silence during the walk.
Our Father, that your
in heaven ...
I do not want to hear a.
We are at war, and that's it.
I want you to have the air
of soldiers, not factors.
Weapons must be kept properly.
We only have half an
hour of daylight.
We'll bivouac here.
The clairire is great.
These bastards will
not surprise us.
It's a. Casper, a second.
Talking about two
or three things.
Tomorrow morning, we
seek hlicoptres.
They will find us if
we stay discovery.
The only problem is
the Cajuns, eh?
We know neither the strength nor
the intentions of the enemy.
It has the advantage
of knowing The field
we have the advantage of
military entrainment.
The speech is gnial, Casper,
but I want to increase
our chances.
O you want to come, Spencer?
Maybe they want to be a trapper.
Can it be anything they want.
Take the risk to let him go.
He Poole you. He stays with us.
Sr is not thou he Poole.
It is the first Cajun
on which it fell.
They want to kill us all.
It's true!
I'm tired of hearing about a.
Reece and Stuckey,
ridging the prisoner,
and attach it.
Simms is on guard.
Casper, you're a real jerk!
Listen to me, Spencer,
and it costs me well.
Tomorrow morning we are heading
north with the prisoner.
The man who you Crawford Poole
one whose friends have
you Tyrone Cribbs.
In case you'd forgotten o Spencer
c'tait our friends.
Now we install.
No fire tonight.
you doing?
Yes, okay.
You might be due to the trapper.
So why have not said anything?
Because I can not believe
this crap.
Prviens me when you believe.
The problem is not what
I believe or not.
So what?
How long will we keep this
asshole from Casper?
I feel that makes us
turn in circles.
We need another leader.
You are a volunteer?
I'm the new, right?
You know these guys. Your turn.
And I'm not the kind
of volunteer.
You're unbelievable, Hardin.
You will not be voluntary
but you do not mind that I
am for the court martial.
Fuck you.
I must speak to you, Casper.
Fragmentation.
Remember the entrainment.
I produced a grenade.
Mrs.
White shot can save your
life if you improvise.
Good God, Casper, shall adopt the bullshit!
This is important.
This is Bowden.
It is reached. He can talk.
Spencer said he became
Completely crazy.
You better come.
I think he's right.
Listen, Bowden.
I know aa t hard for everyone.
I understand that you do
not feel very well.
Why not us?
Bowden is an order.
Name of God, respond to us!
I do not understand.
I do.
This motherfucker is crazy.
What are we going to do?
Let the l
Maybe it will be better
tomorrow morning.
No way.
This guy was a bomb, remember?
You will bind him.
We did not want him walking
around during sleep.
It is too big and dangerous.
Make use of your head, Casper.
He's right.
True, Casper.
will harm a person to tie.
It serves us nothing.
He has never served anything.
If we tied up, you lose
the power of fire.
Name of God, Casper, fetches
a rope and stops of DCON
with your firepower!
Do you remember the last time
you spoke to me in that tone?
DCON not Casper.
We're not having fun.
Well ...
there are 15 m of
rope in my bag.
Go get them, Simms.
What are you doing, Reece?
This guy will talk to me.
It releases them.
Te mle not a.
I told the lcher.
You're happy now?
made the time deuxime
that you look for me.
This time, you'll find me.
It is time, cowboy.
And if I did skip
the head, Reece?
You have not enough balls.
Kill him!
He is dead.
Reece died.
Your prisoner has
Chappe, Casper.
Lonnie!
I'll get you, you bastard!
You hear me? I'll get you!
How many graves we will still
leave it in the corner?
Most of ours, I say.
Yes, you can say ...
Shut up!
It's me you talking about?
I talk about everyone,
including you!
Shut up and dig!
Why not you?
It is you who you are!
I'll tell it twice.
Ferme ta gueule
and widening the fucking grave!
I want to hear any more crap
from you either!
Do what he says and dig.
We lost three men.
We did not lose more.
Survival is mental.
If you are not PRTS face
obstacles and evidence,
your chance to get out alive
Whereas Reduces are.
You start getting tired
of hearing you, Casper.
Name of God, Spencer!
I do my best.
I know, Casper.
But we do narratives manual
serves nothing.
You think you better?
I think so.
I am the team leader.
You're not even a corporal.
Just top class.
I'm starting to get
fed this crap.
I'm with you, Spencer.
Casper, you never find
the damn highway.
You promise me that this bastard
Texan goes to court martial?
He will have to.
It was you one of his
fellow soldiers.
So I'm with you.
What's that voted for the con?
Let's go!
Go Bowden. We go home.
Spencer, you can not
leave like a.
We are a squad, a unit.
The Bravo team.
Deserts you, guys.
And how we deserts!
You coming?
How's your arm?
was okay.
Let me tell you something ...
I know that Reece
silent a bastard.
I want to talk about it.
C'tait may be legitimized
by the defense.
Speak more of a.
Done.
What chance was to get away?
You who know everything.
Now you're the boss.
Sought not me.
Right now we have the troop,
helicopter, dogs,
all Louisiana's search for us.
You know, Spencer ...
For dogs, I have already given.
I'll tell you something else.
They are swarming intrt.
Simms, what happens?
I thought I saw something.
You're safe? I heard nothing.
Me either.
You have not heard?
You have d.
I heard nothing!
You gch your bullets as Bowden.
There is nothing yet.
Damn!
Motherfucker!
More than a!
They have dterrs.
They have all dterrs.
Bowden, Good God!
They have overflow solutions.
You're stuck.
You'll cover me, Simms.
With what?
I as white balls.
No radio, no ammunition,
no planes, no mortars!
How to fight with?
No wonder, Casper.
It is you who are
supposed to know!
White Tire!
Help yourself to
verything you have!
It has 4 cartridges.
I have mine.
Thou hast drawn, asshole.
Go ... replions us.
Pull up!
Listen.
I hear nothing.
I hear it.
If he saw us, he will return.
He could not land. Too trees.
O is Stuckey?
Damn!
Well, sparons us.
We must find him.
Me and Hardin.
I take Bowden.
Casper, you go with Simms.
Those who find, shoot a
ball every 5 minutes.
The other team will go by, OK?
And if you find it?
We wait an hour.
Shoot 5 shots, then a
ball every 5 minutes.
The two teams will join APRS.
Stuckey!
Stuckey, fucking pquenot,
where art thou?
Dirty son of a bitch!
Go Simms, join the others.
You're crazy.
You're crazy!
You hear? Go ahead, get lost!
I have done nothing wrong.
I did not ask to come.
I did not ask to come!
I think what we do is say
there is opposition o.
They had no trouble finding
us up presents.
Come on, do we draw.
It's every man for himself now.
If others get there, fine.
This state is really
gnial Spencer.
They sent a fucking hlicoptre.
What do you want them to send?
The National Guard?
Civil peace.
Soldier at war. I am a Guard.
H, Bowden ... Want to talk?
H, entraneur.
Entraneur what, anyway?
Football, what else?
I think he also teaches history.
It seems that for him, everything is more than history.
Asshole.
could become as a history for the
other two idiots, if continued.
This time tomorrow you will be
your office, a beer in hand,
watching your wife
and listen DCON.
I have no office.
I worry if we'll pay a lot of l.
Gnial.
You're husband how long?
Five years.
Happy?
As in "happy marriage" ...
I like it. It has humor.
What has you can fuck?
If I'm doing and you do
not, I'll go with it.
It has humor. I do not.
Mine is rather limited
at this time also.
They have their rcupr
trapper ...
They have to hunt just for fun.
You got an idea of
​​what can be done
or is it just to say something.
I'll tell you what I say:
I want to live.
I do not know how I'll do.
But I will fight to get out.
Remember to keep me a place.
T'inquite not, it
Pipelines Limited.
Asshole!
I'll kill you if you
force me not.
There is a down the bayou.
Take it.
Stay on the west bank.
You will find a road and
a half kilometer grids.
you would have nothing to
tell us what happens?
It's very simple.
We live here.
This is our territory and nobody
plays fuck with us.
And him?
Him?
He has done everything
yourself, your friends
aid have?
If I were you I would ask more
questions and I would draw.
My friends ...
they are not nice like me.
We must say thank you?
You have nothing to say ...
soldier!
A fucking truck.
You lost your?
Want to ride?
My God, yes!
The next town, yes?
Gnial.
can not be a Catahoula.
Is that corn.
And this city where we went?
has to be here.
O is the phone?
It was the reader,
but not on mobile.
We want to go in a city
where there on mobile.
Eat first. You go to town APRS.
No, we want to go now.
Have a drink. Have fun with us.
You will later on mobile.
Come with me.
I'll show you wash o.
What do you think?
I think I feel better.
Cleaner anyway.
Yes? And more security?
Not enough to go to sleep.
We should forget Mr.
and Mrs.
Cajun and find the city alone.
If they are still APRS us, they
will find in the swamp.
But we are shooting ourselves
ds we can.
It is safe here.
Quiet, Hardin.
These are good Cajuns.
The others are away.
You, you calm!
Look at these two guys.
Who?
They descend from the boat.
You think they are the ones?
I know. I've never really seen.
I think it's them.
I'm not the purview
of the paranoid.
I have enough to be paranoid,
and you too.
They must kill us.
It is the only tmoins.
T'angoisse not.
They can do anything in
front of everyone.
I tell you, Hardin, calm down.
Subtitle TITRA PARIS FILM