Right. Something I never knew it. . .
I know that there are dictators
around the world. . .
but you knew that some
dictators today. . .
apparently, it is assumed,
're addicted to drugs?
This explains many things. Hugo Chavez
admitted in a speech. . .
which, incidentally, was
largely unheralded ...
he chews every day''''cocoa,
morning.
He also eats something
he calls''cocoa paste.''
That's something addictive. And the dictator
Bolivia is your supplier.
- What did you say?
- It's "coca."
It's''coca''.
"Ah,''coca''
, Cocoa. . .
Cocoa-would not be problem.
SOUTH OF THE BORDER
I do not know very well
name drugs.
What a shame. For a moment
when he said cocoa. . .
I imagined people all over the country
Cocoa Puffs''spitting''.
They thought they would feel
it was great today.
I prefer Ovaltine''''
but now is not time for that.
What she is saying. . .
I also read it.
but the reporters wanted to know:
''What is he saying?''
He buys cocoa paste''.'' . .
-''Coca''!
-''Coca''. Confuse you.
Buy the folder. . .
Bolivia! The dictator.
He is also a dictator?
Millions of people watch
these programs regularly.
Day and night.
In the United States.
They believe what they see?
I hope not.
But broadcasters and press
more serious in the U.S. and Europe ...
follow the advice of Bush ...
and divided the world into friends:
That is, leaders who are
we want to do.
And enemies: Leaders who tend
to disagree with us.
Raul Castro
and the dictator Hugo Chavez ...
enemy
the Bush administration.
I think we should see. . .
Venezuela's government as
a negative force in this region.
This is the new Venezuela.
Being built with his own
money derived from petroleum.
Caracas is one of the places
most beautiful of the Americas ...
due to the wise use
of national income from oil.
Approximately half of the profits
derived from oil sales.
The domestic policy is to use
oil profits back Condo nation ...
buildings for physical,
new industries and public welfare.
After all, made a big mistake
Iraq recently.
And the bigger the lie,
more often it repeats.
We have concrete evidence. . .
the presence of members
Al Qaeda in Iraq.
With the help of the media to repeat
statements of the Bush administration ...
over 70% of Americans
're convinced ...
that Saddam Hussein
was involved ...
the massacre of September 11.
Is there any concrete evidence?
Concrete evidence
is an interesting statement.
The concrete evidence. . .
that may come in the form
of a mushroom cloud.
Why are we here?
This is the point.
Why are we here,
this war?
Where are the nukes?
Why it took so long for you,
Walt, questioning the vice pres. Dick Cheney?
We waited until 2007
for you piss him off!
It's a fair question e. . .
I saw Dr. Sanjay Gupta. . .
involved with the troops
early in the war.
He and the rest of you
traditional media. . .
refuse to ask questions
difficult for our leaders. . .
and demand honest answers.
So we're in this war.
Five years at war.
Because you, CNN ...
Dr. Gupta did not do his duty
and now we're in this mess.
The same strategy in Iraq was
Employed ...
revolts in South America
The electoral victory of Hugo Chavez ...
despite much opposition ...
was a triumph
for Venezuelan democracy.
But there is a problem
with democracy.
As it is practiced in the south ...
can topple politicians
who refuse ...
to accept the rules of Washington.
According to our leaders,
the elected president of Venezuela ...
Hugo Chavez, was
and continues to be a dictator.
The world's worst dictators:
Hugo Chavez. . .
The Venezuelan president has become
more dangerous than Fidel Castro ...
never been to the USA.
Exxon Mobil says it was stolen
President Hugo Chavez.
The Latin American strongman.
There is something called a clown
killer. Maybe he is one. . . .
Today, in Latin America.
Hugo Chavez is a dictator.
Dictators crooks,
like Hugo Chavez.
If he said he hates
Hugo Chavez or Fidel Castro. . .
I would say that I hate these guys.
On the cover of the book you cite
Otto Reich. . .
who was ambassador to Venezuela,
in 80 years. . .
who said:''He is more dangerous
than Bin Laden.
And the effects of war
between Chavez and the U.S.. . .
can be worse than September 11.''
Chavez supports terrorism
daily.
You're not doing anything
on drug trafficking.
Supports nuclear ambitions
Iran, North Korea.
Syria's nuclear ambitions.
He called on Al Qaeda and Hamas. . .
to settle in Caracas.
Who is Hugo Chavez?
Where did he come from?
The fall of the Berlin Wall ...
and the collapse of the Soviet Union
was seen by millions of people ...
as the end of every alternative
to Capitalism.
Washington seemed dominated
by an arrogance without triumphs ...
thinking,''Now
We can do whatever we want.''
Let's take a look. . .
in a mysterious presence
on the international scene today.
This is how the IMF
describes himself.
The IMF is an institution
powerful financial ...
which has members in 186 countries ...
but it is controlled almost entirely
by the Secretary of the Treasury.
Its support to governments of countries
low income and little ...
is often crucial
Condo political survival.
The IMF tries to keep
a stable global economy ...
with a steady stream of money
between countries with different currencies.
The biggest challenge for the newly
discovery domination of Washington ...
came from South America
A continent that the IMF
and the Treasury ...
often used
as a lab rat ...
your experiments in economics.
In 1988, the Venezuelan economy
was in chaos.
The minimum wage was downloading
and poverty, the rise for years.
The Venezuelan government was
on his knees asking for help from the IMF.
That attended, dictating
a structural adjustment program ...
guarantee that more money
especially for the poor.
When the bus fare
was increased. in 1989 ...
obeying the agreement with the IMF ...
Caracas exploded into a fiesta''''
of attacks and looting.
Police opened fire again
in Caracas, the Venezuelan capital. . .
against demonstrators
who were throwing stones.
Today is the fourth day of
violent protest. . .
against the government's decision
to increase the price. . .
some basic items
consumption.
The government called the army.
Hundreds, perhaps thousands
Venezuelans were killed.
''They killed my son!''Was the
the woman shouted at the morgue.
Relatives anxious look at the list
part with more than 200 names ...
people who were killed.
The morgue is literally ...
clogged with bodies
the dead.
That same month,
a group of young officers ...
met secretly
under the command of then ...
Lieutenant Hugo Chavez.
And they condemned the massacre, vowing ...
that would never happen again.
Chavez, say,
dropped with a parachute.
It was produced
within the army. . .
when the army killed
their own people.
Chavez and a group
of junior officers gathered. . .
and said:
No.''were created for this.
Our only purpose is to protect
the country from foreign invasion.''
Exactly three years later,
in February 1992 ...
Chavez launched a failed coup
to overthrow the government.
But the promised attack
never happened.
The Venezuelan government has avoided
Worse, when troops loyal ...
dominated a violent blow
midnight.
After killing 70 people ...
the rebel troops failed
to overthrow President Perez.
And the great news that I bring
to all Venezuelans. . .
is that all outbreaks
been mastered.
And they're all arrested,
have surrendered. . .
or because they were captured.
Chavez was caught
and was arrested two years.
He assumed full responsibility,
publicly.
Comrades, unfortunately. . .
for now, the goals
we plan. . .
were not met
in our capital.
Namely, we
here in Caracas. . . .
we can not control the power.
And I, in front of you and the country,
I assume all responsibility. . .
this movement
Bolivarian military.
Thank you.
No doubt, the coup was illegal.
And against the same defenders
democracy that Chávez ...
later, defend the coup
against their own government.
Moreover,
not gone unnoticed ...
that the majority of the population
saw Chavez as a hero.
And I guarantee
safely. . .
this will be the last time. . .
that Venezuela will
by a situation like this.
There was much celebration
in the Venezuelan capital, today ...
after the Supreme Court ordered
President Carlos Andres Perez ...
on trial for accusations
fraud.
He is accused of having
stolen $ 17 million from the government.
In 1997, Chavez decides
Condo presidential bid.
His greatest opponent is a blonde,
1.83 m, the former Miss Universe.
They begin to call the race
of the Beauty and the Beast.
The former Miss Universe employs
trembling platitudes ...
while Chavez is
preaching revolution.
And this is what the people want to hear.
In Venezuela, the election Sunday. . .
may end in an upset
leftist government.
His supporters called
voting for punishment.
And it took this man to power,
Venezuela.
The ex-army
they said go fight ...
against a tradition of corruption
and economic inequality.
In 1998, four years
after being released ...
the inflation rate in Venezuela
reach a record 78% ...
and the government have done more cuts
social spending ...
the body politic was
totally discredited.
Despite opposition from all media ...
Hugo Chavez
was elected president.
For someone who led
a coup just six years ago. . .
is so popular for the people?
We live 40 years seeing thieves
dresses politicians.
This power that you guys gave me. . .
not belong to me.
This power is of you.
You guys elected the government. . .
that will not be the Chavez government.
Because Chavez is the people.
It will be the people's government!
He has promised reforms to raise
living conditions of the poor.
Enhance democracy.
And share the profits
country's oil ...
with those who were never
benefited in the past.
In three years, Chavez
proclaimed Venezuela ...
a Bolivarian Republic.
And he began to fulfill his promise.
Statues of the beloved Simon Bolivar
The Liberator ...
watch his homeland,
Caracas.
He took six South American countries
Condo freedom.
Bolivar.
It's a photo of Bolivar. . .
in the fullness of his glory.
At its peak, Bolivar. . .
Peru, with all its glory.
Moreover, Bolivar thought
in terms of centuries. . .
and saw the world in terms
continents.
I'm with you, Chavez!
Hello, President!
For two consecutive days,
Bush administration officials. . .
declare your concern with
the political situation in Venezuela.
We are concerned
with some of the actions. . .
Venezuelan President
Chavez. . .
and their understanding of what is
indeed, the democratic system.
Of course, Venezuela is important. . .
it is the third largest producer
oil.
I would say that Chávez. . .
and the Department of State
might say that. . .
not have good intentions
Compared to the U.S..
Chávez's reforms have caused
Resistance of the oligarchy of the country.
We have a lying government.
They're a bunch of bastards.
Controlled the Venezuelan media
and used it to stir opposition.
Also mobilized officers
within the armed forces ...
and received U.S. aid
and Spain.
I think the most reasonable
for the president and his cabinet. . .
is to submit his resignation. . .
or disappear from the country.
A business man,
Pedro Carmona ...
was chosen to be
the new president.
He was taken to make Spain Condo
measures for the presidential sash.
The coup against Chavez had
only one reason: oil.
Bush's plan.
First, Chavez.
Oil.
Second, Saddam.
-Iraq.
-The cause of the coup in Venezuela. . .
and the invasion of Iraq
is the same: oil.
On April 11, 2002 ...
groups of Chavez supporters
and members of the opposition ...
in local marches were
different city.
Later, members
opposition decided ...
through the city toward
the Government Palace ...
where Chavez supporters
were assembled.
He wants us to be like Cuba.
There's no doubt.
Chavez, go fuck yourself, you dog!
As they approached the palace,
suddenly ...
shots were fired from buildings,
and members from both sides ...
were hit in the head.
On a bridge, supporters
hid ...
reciprocated shots of shooters
elite. And against the police ...
who shot them,
two blocks away.
The local press shows
Chavez's supporters ...
shooting the bridge, then showed
the street where the people were hit ...
by snipers.
Manipulating the video to think
that supporters of Chavez ...
had fired the lethal shots.
The press also said
that Chávez himself ...
ordered the massacre
and had used to justify ...
the coup that was already happening.
In the end, it was this that caused
the defeat of Chavez.
Armed gangs loyal
Venezuelan President ...
shots fired from thousands
of opposition members.
After 16 people killed
and hundreds injured ...
last night, soldiers surrounded
the presidential palace.
Mr. President,
I was loyal to you.
That is what the leader of the army
said on national television.
But the assassination of Venezuelan
today was unbearable.
I was under the bridge,
that day.
And I saw the street was empty,
when shots were fired.
When I got home and watched CNN
publicizing this and other stations ...
I was shocked.
There was a guy up there,
on the second floor of that building.
He started shooting, and many
we got hit in the head.
See you.
There was someone up there. . .
shooting people
the bridge on that side.
Shooting at people
who came up on the bridge.
It was a political coup. They're
saying that it was not a coup.
It was a political coup.
He was arrested by the army.
I saw the face of death.
They were about to kill me.
In front of me. Rifles.
Singled out for me.
In front of me.
Behind me.
And I discussed with them.
Thinking of Che Guevara. . .
who say they died standing.
And inside, I said:
''I'm not asking for forgiveness.
Nor mercy.
I'll die standing.''
Most of the American press
endorsed the coup.
The editorial board
The New York Times wrote ...
The Venezuelan democracy''
would not be threatened more ...
by a guy stuck a dictator.''
This reference to Chavez
unaware of the irony ...
what was happening at the hands
of a real dictator.
Shall be suspended for the positions of Members
and alternate members of the National Assembly.
Deprive themselves of their positions,
illegally occupied. . .
President and other judges
the Supreme Court. . .
District Attorney's Office. . .
and members
National Electoral Council.
Leaders of Democratic Action "
(Opposition party) had. . .
the Supreme Court
a certificate of insanity. . .
the president
Lieutenant Colonel Hugo Chavez.
The press in Venezuela
became part of the opposition. . .
in the months preceding the coup.
That is, were participating. . .
and supporting the opposition. Of course,
I'm talking about the private press. . .
that make up the bulk
Venezuelan press reports.
And basically, what they did ...
disclose any testimony that was
opposition that was done ...
Chavez is a coward! Coward!
He destroyed Venezuela!
Many analysts said that
was the first blow of the press.
And one of the participants
the coup said. . .
Thanks to the press''
by this blow.''
Thanks, Televen. Thanks, CNT.
Thanks, Globovision.
Thanks to the media.
The former presidential candidate,
Irene Saez ...
Condo urged the international community
who participated in this transition.
Today, I'm asking
the U.S. government. . .
and to all United Nations
and R OAS. . .
they see what happened
Venezuela is a crime!
They killed innocent people.
And everyone will support
the democratic process. . .
that exists today in our country.
FEW HOURS
AFTER THE COUP
The IMF, often slow
to respond to legitimate requests ...
made in Africa starving,
was quick to ...
show support for the coup.
I hope that this discussion
can continue. . .
with the new administration.
We are prepared
to help the new government. . .
in any matter
they find important.
The objective was clear.
The IMF was making it clear
that the overthrow of Chavez ...
was of great interest
for Global Capitalism.
And there's a reason Washington
is almost smiling.
We import more oil
Venezuela. . .
than any other country
OPEC.
The price of oil
lowered enough today ...
with the removal of Chavez.
The reason for the price
be dramatically lowered ...
probably is
because who replaced Chavez. . .
will be much more sympathetic
to U.S. interests. . .
what was this president.
Question why do not you kill me.
They sent to kill me.
But I am a soldier.
I spent half my life
in the military.
And the Venezuelan military,
especially the younger ...
see me as a leader.
The news spread.
What happened to the poor ...
who marched dramatically
to the palace, in large numbers?
I voted for Chavez! I
Chavez finish his term!
Because if it is a democracy,
must respect the laws.
The soldiers came to say
its official ...
would not support the coup.
The military is
with the people!
They surrounded me and protected.
Next, I rescued from the island.
Parachute with helicopters.
I am a paratrooper leader.
They were my men.
They brought me back to the palace,
surrounded by people.
CARMONA OUT
Carmon had to flee the palace.
A cardinal came Condo island
to where I was stuck. . .
to make me sign
a letter of resignation.
Because Washington was asking
signed a letter of resignation.
I told him:''Let us pray,
because they're coming to my rescue.''
He was afraid.
While he was there,
the paratroopers arrived.
Then they carried him back to the palace,
me in the helicopter.
The cardinal has changed sides. Said:
''Yes, we pray, Mr. President.''
Why something so sloppy?
It was a blow shoddy.
Why did not kill him
when caught?
He was not heavy weight.
Comparing R Guatemala
Argentina to Chile and R.
Venezuela 2000, 2002,
Guatemala is not the 54. . .
and is not the Chile 73.
This is a revolution,
I said, controversial. . .
but armed.
The Venezuelan army is
with his people!
Our president is still
Hugo Chavez.
We want Hugo Chavez!
Well, we came back.
Good morning everyone.
That we continue moving forward
with calm and prudence.
Continue.
The law regards the virtue and honor
The editorial committee of New York
Times seemed embarrassed ...
for giving support
the blow to his government.
The White House acknowledged today
that U.S. officials ...
several meetings with
Venezuelan opposition leaders ...
in recent months to discuss
the position of President Chavez.
But he insisted, every time,
signaled that even once ...
that a military option
would be acceptable.
It was expressly stated
the opposition leaders. . .
that the U.S. did not support a coup.
On Friday, it seems
they did just that ...
accepting the successor
Hugo Chávez ...
while simultaneously
U.S. allies in the region ...
condemned what they saw,
clearly, as the military coup.
When Chavez returned to power
the very next day ...
The White House seemed to have decided
argued that the blow to democracy.
Some Democrats have called
to it''deeply disturbing''.
It R greater democracy
the world. . .
governments to defend
democratically elected.
I think the U.S. had not
a very enlightened policy. . .
relation R in Venezuela
specifically. . .
to America or America, in general,
throughout the Bush administration.
But this incident
in particular ...
it was the worst possible decision
that the U.S. could have taken.
She not only caught a committee
Chavez's administration ...
but has become very difficult
for all Latin America. . .
like the U.S..
He says the coup in his country
was devised by the U.S..
And some in his administration
say, in fact. . .
you had something to do with it.
What he says, to hear this?
I have to laugh. Because
For starters, there was no coup.
Had there been a coup,
Mr. Chavez would have been eliminated.
There was a complete investigation
Department of State. . .
and there was absolutely
no U.S. involvement. . .
In this action Chavez
calls a coup.
Yes, the U.S. acted, had
people involved in the coup. . .
before it happened.
Involvement of NGOs
US-sponsored ...
some people who have trained
involved in the coup.
And in the immediate aftermath of the coup,
the U.S. government said ...
it was a resignation,
not a coup ...
recognizing, in effect,
the government had made. . .
briefly,
Return to President Chavez.
The coup failed.
But just eight months after ...
the company management
national oil started ...
a strike with its workers,
joined by dealers ...
who dismissed their employees.
Again, the strike
with support from the private media ...
ruined the economy,
causing serious recession ...
comparable to the worst years
the Great Depression in the U.S..
A general strike by opponents
the government of President Chavez ...
forced the Supreme Court
to stop work today.
The entire oil industry
Venezuela has been closed.
This attempt at opposition
Chavez also failed.
In support, the Cubans sent
ten thousand doctors and drug free ...
to open clinics
for the poor.
In an exchange made
between Chavez and Fidel Castro ...
he offered cheap oil
Cuba in exchange for physicians.
Some of these people,
says that medical ...
''I never saw a doctor.''
Chavez to stop talking
it did for reducing poverty. . .
which was much smaller
by leaders before him.
One of my colleagues
State Department says. . .
Chavez loves both the poor
that created millions of new poor.
After the government took
control of the oil industry ...
the economy doubled in size
within six years.
Poverty has decreased R half ...
and extreme poverty,
in more than 70%.
Here are grown all.
Sorghum, sunflower, corn, beans.
I want to test the model
community property here.
For example, a district like this
with a group of families.
"The owner" is perhaps 100 families,
500.
And this group of families owns
this whole area, 200 hectares.
This farm belongs
Condo community.
Chavez has a very poor record
in terms of human rights.
The Bush administration
compared him to Hitler.
Human rights have become
new expression of struggle ...
very similar to what was
freedom in the Soviet era.
But here too there
double political standards.
Comparatively, our neighbor
and closest ally in the region ...
Colombia has a record
worse human rights.
But, as President Uribe
is seen as Washington's friend ...
and its war against drug trafficking ...
gain a pass in the media
Chavez does not have that right.
Chavez has made a point
to appear in public ...
with tyrants
that Washington loves to hate.
We are able to eliminate it.
And I believe the time has come
to exercise that capacity.
We do not need another war
$ 200 billion. . .
to get rid
a strong dictator.
It seems to me that in the few days
I spent with you ...
you develop protection
it.
But, in principle, is
he was shocked.
It affected me personally, yes.
It was painful for me.
It pained me to see the lies
and disrespect to the people.
But then I realized
that is a game e. . .
no matter what I do. . .
I can dress as a priest,
with a fine hat on his head. . .
'll keep calling me
a tyrant. The people know the truth.
I understand the complicated approach
Chavez.
After the coup, began to seem
a little more like a war.
George W. Bush. . .
you are a donkey, Mr. Bush.
Yesterday the devil came here.
And this place still smells like sulfur.
This is your desk,
is where he works.
This is one of my posts
Preferred to work.
I've never seen so much energy. Never.
He said he intended to return here,
last night, for work.
Yes, I worked last night.
See.
What time was sleep yesterday?
Then, by three in the morning.
Three-thirty.
Worked-up the two?
-Worked, li.
I am obliged to study hard.
I know the team.
It's for fun or pleasure?
All this is a pleasure.
And went to bed reading this book?
That help you have
is boring.
Who does not walk with us
Do not walk with me
The first thing to know
Chavez is on ...
he was born in a shack
literally, and grew up in poverty.
And it affected
his vision of Venezuela. . .
and opened his ambition
of life to transform the country.
I was born a hundred yards
there ahead.
Welcome to our neighborhood.
Hello, my dear.
How are you, my life?
Look, that girl!
Venezuela has spent 50 years
without a project. . .
but now we have one.
Who is that?
-Ali? My grandmother.
This is the grandmother.
An old picture we recover
of an identity card.
At what age did she die?
She was born 70 years before.
Result, of course. . .
so much work.
That was where I was born. In a house
palm leaves.
And this is the house where I grew up.
As it was, at age 14?
He was thin. He was very fond
playing baseball.
-Baseball?
-Is.
What position?
He played as a pitcher.
And I was at first base.
It's always hard to win.
And he just likes to win.
Because he is trying very
to win.
We planted fruit trees
here. Tamarind, orange.
There was a coffee
and a hornet's nest here.
My grandmother told me to spoon
coffee. You see? I said!
Think back to Hugo.
His grandmother is there, behind you.
His grandmother comes to the door.
Can not do that.
I'll cry.
Action!
Oh, no! Broke!
I'll have to pay!
Who is this bike?
How's it going, girls?
What are you studying?
Engineering?
She is studying engineering.
Hello, Hugo!
"How many cows do you have?
Ten-giving milk.
Ten, giving milk.
As each cow produces per day?
Four liters each.
You must increase this production.
The property is yours
and his family.
-Studied until years?
Sixth-grade.
Sixth grade? You must go back to school.
You must seek Ribas mission.
When I came to power,
we had to import maize.
This is no longer necessary.
We broke records this year.
Now, we are building
processing plants.
It is here that we are building
Iranian atomic bomb.
The pump of corn.
We process our own corn
in our own plant.
We produce flour.
In this case, with the support of Iran.
And sell it very cheap
the poor, the people.
Two hundred years ago,
started a revolution.
Bolivar started ...
releasing all these people
the Spanish empire.
Thus began the dream
of a republic.
Free and sovereign.
But then came
the American empire. . .
Empire and English.
And split it into pieces.
Our history is terrible.
This continent want to be. . .
We want to be ourselves.
Oliver, I want to show you something.
See that building?
It is an old barracks.
I was there the day
the military rebellion.
On February 4, 1992.
Ali was the headquarters
the rebellion.
Our military rebels
Caracas took the palace.
I could have died there.
Some of my men died.
I am strongly connected
àqueles who died that day.
Those who died here.
In these windows, there is still
bullet holes that day.
The men who died,
I carry with me.
And this is part
my commitment.
As a former soldier,
I understand you.
The victories of Chavez in Venezuela
began to transform ...
their own country on offer
of hope to others.
Powerful social forces
gathered in the south ...
across national borders.
It seemed that the dream of Simon
Bolivar had begun to realize.
The old oligarchies,
privileged light-skinned ...
prepare to defend
his condition with his strength.
And the new social movements,
indigenous, darker-skinned ...
and, above all, poor.
Chavez advanced today
over a left ...
and proclaims that socialism
is the only way forward ...
attracting other states
South Americans to join ...
Condo Bolivarian revolution.
Gonna come?
Legalizing cocaine.
This is one of the main items
in the campaign of Evo Morales. . .
a pugnacious leftist
and consistent critic of the U.S. ...
Condo competing presidency
Bolivia.
He is a man who is not friend
the Bush administration.
Evo Morales, who presided
the union of coca growers ...
is the first Indian to be elected
president.
Morales, who called a month ago
President Bush a''terrorist''...
is part of a new wave
leftist leaders ...
South America
The stakes here are high.
Bolivia has the second largest
natural gas reserves in South America
The flight from Caracas to La Paz
is a straight line to the south ...
across the Andes.
It was Che Guevara in Bolivia
was captured and killed ...
by order of the CIA in 1967.
Forty years later, in 2005 ...
Bolivia, for the first time
elected a leader of the indigenous people ...
or 70% of the population,
Evo Morales as president.
As a leader of coca growers,
Morales was arrested by the oligarchs.
Huge social movements,
in defense of coca ...
order and against privatization
IMF aroused the country.
The government decided to sell. . .
the water supply of Cochabamba
Bechtel, an American company.
And this company, one of the things
she led the government to do. . .
was to pass a law saying that
from then, would be illegal. . .
Rs caves go to the poor
and collect rainwater. . .
because it challenged
its monopoly of water.
Anxiety increases in Bolivia.
The government declared
state of emergency ...
after days of protest,
among other things ...
rising water prices.
Five people, at least
were killed.
Movements like this
Morales drove ...
of such movements to power.
Some have called
Revenge of''Che''.
I'm not afraid to say.
I am a big fan of Fidel
and Hugo Chavez.
Others saw it as ...
the victory of truth
against corporate tyranny.
When we landed in La Paz,
we all struggle with the altitude.
It is the international airport
highest in the world.
For generations, the indigenous
chewed coca leaves ...
to relieve
The strain on the body.
It's not the same as cocaine,
as many in the U.S. believe.
Coca leaves have got to be
chemically processed ...
to produce cocaine.
But in its native form ...
has mild stimulant effects,
such as caffeine.
A day later, we still felt
nausea from altitude ...
and President Morales
helped us.
I'm curious if the president
show me. . .
or share with me
a little. . .
These sheets are bad.
These coca leaves
're not good.
Are not they?
Really?
They will not do you good.
Will not make you well.
You're the expert.
Must be greener,
not so dark.
So. . .
Washington brought the fight
on drugs for Bolivia. . .
and President Morales expelled
DEA few months ago.
The pretext of fighting
against drug trafficking. . .
that implemented
is a control policy. . .
not only against Bolivia. . .
but many others
Latin American countries.
The war on drugs
part. . .
geopolitical interests of
U.S..
The war on drugs
part. . .
geopolitical interests of
U.S..
Right.
This is better.
It's a control.
-A control.
It consumes so.
I invite you.
The two hands.
I invite you need. . .
Put on your hands.
Hold.
Take the talinho. . .
e. . .
What's with the stalks?
It is as safe.
It's not just political control.
Now we are told that
plan to commit murder. . .
political leaders.
Members of the Armed Forces
and National Police
we'll denouncing
as
during the past decade,
also in this decade. . .
were planning to end lives,
especially mine.
2 months ago, you put out
the American ambassador. . .
In October (2008)
there was the expulsion of the ambassador. . .
and in November (2008), the Embassy
and the DEA (Narcotics Agency) regulations.
How many times have you got arrested!
I was tortured.
Tortured.
E-trapped.
Tortured-by what?
I was accused of conspiracy
and revolt.
Tortured by Bolivian soldiers
DEA or the U.S.?
I was tortured
by Bolivian soldiers. . .
but were supervised
by the DEA.
When he was arrested last?
In 1997.
I was a member, but was
expelled from parliament in 2002.
The plan was to arrest me,
imprison me. . .
and disqualify me
Condo candidate as president.
But they failed.
For the first time. . .
not allowed here no
foreign military base.
-There is no now, no?
"If there is now? No.
Before there was now no.
Now he is joining. . .
Condo bad left wing,
to the U.S. media.
The media always
attempts to criminalize. . .
the struggle against neoliberalism,
colonialism and imperialism.
It's almost normal,
my worst enemy is the media.
We can say that the goal
the Presidency. . .
will have
their own natural resources?
Replenish natural resources. . .
is the base of the economy
worldwide.
As he describes himself?
I feel more like a leader
of a union president.
Because as a manager
There is a constant struggle.
It's a constant struggle.
Sometimes,
Ministers tell me. . .
''You're President,
not say that!''
Including this one deputy minister.
Now I wake up
with green leaves. . .
You can go outside
one instant?
Show whether he is awake,
I do not know if it is.
I always have energy.
I want to play football
with the president. . .
he show me some passes.
He likes of Maradona?
In football.
Sure. . .
President Morales of Bolivia,
VISIT TO VENEZUELA
The new anti-American triangle
Spanish-speaking ...
Evo Morales of Bolivia ...
Hugo Chávez of Venezuela,
and Fidel Castro of Cuba ...
says that the geopolitical map
Latin America ...
is changing
and he's right.
Buenos Aires
capital of Argentina.
A country that has done everything for 50 years
commissioned by the IMF ...
World Bank
and the U.S. Treasury.
In 2001, collapsed.
Banks closed.
Five presidents
fell in two weeks.
The president of Argentina
resigned today ...
because of violence sparked Condo
economic downturn.
At least 20 people died.
Now police fight ...
against hundreds
of antigovernment protesters.
Unions call for
a national strike ...
against the austerity measures
and unemployment of almost 20%.
People were Rs streets.
Factories were raided.
In a large park
Buenos Aires ...
union of all
localities, rich and poor ...
met
to discuss his fate.
Nestor Kirchner
was the president ...
and refused to agree
with the IMF conditions ...
forcing them to retreat.
When he finished his term,
his wife Cristina ...
with the same spirit Bolivarian
was elected.
It seems to me that
first in the region. . .
leaders look
the governed.
If Bolivia is r
and look at Evo's face. . .
her face is
the face of Bolivia.
It is the first time
it happens.
One of the last
presidents who had. . .
Sanchez de Lozada,
barely spoke Spanish. . .
lived in the U.S..
He had nothing in common
with Bolivians.
The other day I spoke
with a journalist, he said. . .
Hugo Chavez wants to export''
their revolution. . .
its changes, its socialism. . .
Condo Latin America
and this should not happen.''
I was told
some European journalists.
That way they think
those colonialists. . .
everything that could
in its "colonial lives"
and who always treated
installing your ideas
they had in other countries.
We who have no experience in the region
internal colonialism of one country over another.
Instead, we suffer
in the hands of colonialism.
I do not think anyone would want
to impose anything.
Instead,
believe in integration. . .
respecting differences,
the identity of each country. . .
culture and political processes,
ever are the same. . .
because we are different people. . .
with companies
and different histories.
What do you think the press
call Chavez a dictator?
I think I never experienced
in modern governments. . .
in Latin America or worldwide. . .
an election that many had
like those of Hugo Chavez
I think it's the 13s. election.
I have not seen many dictators
elected 13 consecutive times.
One can agree or not
with what he says. . .
but to say that there's freedom
Venezuela. . .
to say what one thinks,
do not believe it, otherwise.
How many pairs of shoes do you have?
I do not know, never told.
I do not understand, never ask
a man. . .
How many pairs of shoes
he has, or pants.
Always ask
women.
Okay, now established
your credit. . .
-Mrs. President.
Thank you.
It is much better indoors.
Bring a photo of May 25, 2003
my desk. . .
when Kirchner took over.
It's a great shot.
I'm with old friends.
I want to see,
is really great.
Let's see if the find.
How can men
be so slow, my God.
For how much longer
gonna be here?
This is May 25, 2003.
Kirchner was inaugurated.
Fidel laughing.
And I like the first lady.
Argentina had a recession
terrible between 1998 and 2002.
Can you describe
the role of the IMF. . .
and what Argentina did
out of recession?
Terrible was terrible.
The IMF recommended a wave
privatization. . .
non-intervention of the state,
that the market would solve everything.
and maintained the convertibility
(1 peso = 1 dollar)
to maintain this fiction. . .
in addition to the country into debt
financially brutally. . .
because the capital was (IMF). . .
and had an interest rate
impressive in Argentina
then they withdrew.
And caused the greatest debt
Argentina's history. . .
that reached up to 160%. . .
He left us 25% of
population without work,
56% poverty. . .
over 30%
misery. . .
Finally, everything that can be
considered as a social tragedy.
Then it all explodes
in 2001 and 2002. . .
with a huge
currency devaluation. . .
which meant a huge
transfer of wealth.
That's what Kirchner inherited
on May 25, 2003.
So we started a
policy substantially different. . .
with a big fight with the IMF.
There is a widespread notion ...
that the U.S. has ignored
Latin America ...
and their Chambers of Commerce
helped the rich ...
but wounded
the working poor.
Today, Argentine President ...
with worries about the policy
American Chamber of Commerce ...
seemed not to rush to embrace
his U.S. counterpart.
And oddly,
President Bush agreed.
It's not easy to receive
these people.
Maybe it's not easy
I receive.
Many say they played
an innovative role and heroic. . .
to challenge the IMF
the first time. . .
and successfully.
I would say that one of the highlights
his personal life. . .
would be the conference with Bush
Mar Del Plata?
I think so. That day,
Latin America defeated. . .
the intentions of the first
world power. . .
represented by the policy
President Bush with the FTAA.
And all we act collectively.
Never forget that day.
So much so that kept the chair
that meeting in my house.
That day we had the courage. . .
not to speak over the radio
when man is not. . .
or when the representative is
imperial policy is not. . .
but we act collectively
and coordinately.
It was one of the most important steps
we gave in the region.
How when he says''not''
to a banker?
You're subversive, leftist
a thief, scoundrel.
Was there a moment,
like a movie. . .
where one of the main
bankers bent. . .
in the eye of the President
and said. . .
Mr.'' Kirchner, realizes
the implications of what he says?''
Always.
When one sees political
very friendly. . .
very friendly
these sectors. . .
something's not right.
Because these sectors only think
in profitability. . .
and not on society as a whole.
Now, during this mandate
facing the current Chair
is a different time
and more difficult.
I had to pull the country out of hell.
The president must do
the economy grows. . .
ensure that the distribution
profit is fair.
The sectors that control
the economy. . .
they always want to profit
and never share. . .
they do not want to share,
are the sectors that react.
Corporately respond because
want a country for a few
concentrator, where much
just stayed with the Argentine people
President Bush
Condo meeting came ...
talk about your policy
Free Trade ...
that says it will help
alleviate poverty ...
and create jobs in the region.
There were some uncomfortable moment
with Pres. Bush that night?
I say there's not kneel
to power. . .
be rude not to say
you need to talk. . .
àqueles we explored
rs and who opposed our actions.
We had a fight
in Monterrey.
And I said that here the solution
to boost quickly. . .
What is the solution that will be
have to do now
would be a Marshall Plan
And so he stopped and got angry.
He said it was a crazy idea
the Democrats.
And what we have to do here
and the best way to boost it ...
"The U.S. had strengthened
the war, "she said.
So he said.
The war? He said that?
He said,
were his exact words.
He suggested that South America
go to war?
He spoke of the USA.
Never said South America
Democrats
were wrong.
Economic growth
U.S.. . .
rs due out several
wars they had.
He was very clear.
President Bush is. . .
Well, it only 6 days left, right?
-Yes.
Thank God.
Your work here is
hampered by Hugo Chavez ..
Socialist President
Venezuela ...
who now had the unusual gesture
to bring the meeting ...
the demonstrators in a stadium
Football next.
He said he wants to bury
the Free Trade Agreement (AFTA).
The FTAA be damned!
From Argentina to Paraguay ...
where the ex-bishop Fernando Lugo,
a liberal theologian ...
win the election and ended
decades of leadership ...
the pro-Washington, the Colorado Party.
.
This is the old palace
of General Stroessner.
The dictator's mansion.
My family was persecuted
by Stroessner.
My father was arrested 20 times.
It's a paradox I live now
where Stroessner lived.
Can you imagine?
These changes in Latin America
in the last 10 years. . .
were incredible, really.
Especially since 2003, 2004.
This resulted in some form
Liberation Theology?
Yes, certainly. . .
believe that the roots of change
in Latin America. . .
began with a
new way of thinking.
There are 15 or 20 years,
no one could imagine. . .
that an indigenous
become president. . .
that two women were presidents
of two important countries. . .
a metallurgical
would be president. . .
that a military
and even less that a bishop
would be president.
I believe that here there is a new
political actor, they're social movements.
The opposition has effectively
groups. . .
that historically
were privileged in Paraguay. . .
especially after after
61 years of hegemonic party. . .
not have been easy
make changes in the country.
Here is a group that
was privileged historically. . .
government
with the country's resources.
We want are consistent with
the option of Liberation Theology. . .
here if you happen to be privileged. . .
has to be the ones
historically overlooked:
The indigenous, the landless,
the illiterate, those without health
they're the ones who now must
be the first to be met.
The changes are having an
Fair administration,
transparency ...
institutions to recover
their dignity. . .
and economic growth,
but with plenty of social equality.
I can not get away from
30 years of pastoral care at church.
And we, as Saint Paul said. . .
''One sows, one fertilizes,
farms and other one will reap.''
Is there any phone calls from Paraguay to the IMF?
Yes, we have.
-What is the debt?
-US $ 2.3 billion.
Chavez lent R Argentina
$ 6 billion.
Do not do that.
Chavez would make the loan
if I talked to him.
How old is it?
-57 Years.
"He has time.
He is very good.
Well, Fernando Lugo,
is a very nice man. . .
and a very good man, I think.
I wish you good luck.
Thanks. This is something
that I will always remember.
In Brazil, the changes were
political rather than structural.
Lula da Silva was elected
President of Brazil ...
with the largest margin of victory
the country's history.
Mr. da Silva is the first
leftist President ...
working class
the country's history.
He was president of union
and political prisoner ...
when the right
ruled Brazil ...
which has 9 a. higher
economy in the world ...
and faces an economic crisis.
The Bush administration
supported his opponent.
President Lula was,
leader of the working class.
Lula may not have confronted
IMF directly ...
but refused any
Brazilian complicity ...
the destabilization plan
Venezuela or Bolivia.
Now at the end of his term
as president ...
I think so combative
as in the beginning.
Sees the possibility
of a bank. . .
a union of interests
South American Financial. . .
along the lines of the European Union?
Is it possible?
Thank you.
Want to talk to Hugo
the output?
My brother.
This is my brother.
The last two presidents
were on my list ...
Raul Castro, Cuba's ...
and Rafael Correa
Ecuador.
Correa shows his
dissatisfaction with Bush. . .
saying that the policy
U.S. in Latin America ...
is responsible for the appearance
of leftist movements ...
throughout the region.
When Washington rejected
Correa's requirement ...
removing the military base
of his country ...
the new president
required equity.
A military base
Ecuador in Miami.
Chavez began
a new era in Latin America.
For us, the moment is
very difficult to make changes. . .
we want to do
and that the country needs.
Now that many governments have
friends in the region. . .
just as President Chavez. .
President Morales. . .
the Kirchners in Argentina. . .
Lula in Brazil. . .
imagine what it must have been
difficult 10 years ago. . .
when he (Chavez) was
absolutely alone. . .
Latin America in a full
of neoliberal governments.
The main and perhaps only
Chavez's influence
is that it gave us an example
many things.
What is your position on
the United States?
We love the USA.
I lived there. I studied there.
We love the people too
the United States.
But obviously, the policy
outside the U.S. is questionable.
So when they wanted
push us to maintain. . .
the basis of their military
in our country. . .
a base for foreign
not pay a rent,
do not pay anything. . .
And they accused us of being extremists
not wanted by the base. . .
If there's no problem having
a base in a foreign country. . .
established
one condition very straightforward. . .
would maintain the base
U.S. at Manta. . .
since the Americans would allow us to
an Ecuadorian base in Miami.
If there's problems
with foreign bases. . .
then we can
have one there.
Do you accept the presence
AED in your country?
What they do is
a sort of consulting. . .
but we are limiting
the influence they had.
They financed large
part of our forces.
We are changing that.
Let's follow fighting drugs,
but independently.
Rafael Correa is now
considered. . .
a left
potentially bad. . .
with Chavez and Morales.
He sees this, or thinks it is
favored by the American media?
With all due respect, knowing
the American media. . .
I'd be more concerned
if they speak well of me.
Good night.
The bad news about plans
murder ...
was given today by the Committee
Intelligence of the Senate.
The Committee released a report
which states that ...
U.S. government agents ...
initiated plans to kill
Two foreign leaders ...
engaged in plans
to kill two others ...
're involved in one more ...
and that the CIA knew more
Two murder schemes.
Fidel Castro is alive and well ...
although 8 of the CIA planes
to kill him ...
and a plan to harm
your image ...
making his beard fall.
Some of the goals of the plans
murder ...
were very knowledgeable people.
Che Guevara, Raul Castro,
brother of Fidel Castro of Cuba.
In January, the Revolution,
50. . .
2003, more or less, with
the emergence of Chavez. .
and his victory after the coup.
You are the grandfather, godfather (godfather). . .
and what about this?
No. Perhaps the first,
but not a sponsor.
're All adults, go alone,
got their own ideas. . .
and bringing new ideas.
For example, socialism
21st century.
What do you think of these heirs?
There is optimism?
They're not heirs
our spare.
We are all definitely heirs
something, someone.
Cubans are heirs
the liberators of the Americas. . .
starting with Bolivar, Sucre. . .
Toussaint L'Ouverture,
The Haitian.
The first and only revolution
successful. . .
led by slaves
in world history.
We are the heirs of
most recent fights. . .
other fellow
which fell, like Che Guevara, etc. ..
Now some are young, as
Presidents Correa and Chavez
But each one is learning
their own knowledge. . .
and knowledge from the mainland,
of humanity. That's the reality.
We are not the sponsors,
and they're not the heirs.
And the Cuban Revolution came
the half-century as a whole.
And the Cuban people, despite
explosive personality. . .
learn to be patient.
And this is an incredible thing.
And this explosive combination,
As Fidel said of Europeans. . .
Spanish on our side. . .
and our African side.
We are ready to
more than 50 years.
6 years ago, in January 2003 ...
been here for
interviewing Fidel ...
and talked with him
for 3 days.
He was a lone wolf.
I was isolated ...
the island did not have advertising,
had not corporations. . .
was a return
the other was.
He was the mouse that roared,
who fought ...
80km U.S.
for 50 or 60 years.
As the old man and the sea.
As the old man and the sea, is a
sad story of Hemingway.
The old man leaves, fishing
this giant fish ...
What is the revolution in 1960.
And when the coast bring R,
he was eaten by sharks.
Still, the man
attempted, was noble.
And so it Hemingway
gave that strength of character. . .
beauty of this loss,
the tragedy of the effort.
What I like about Castro was
he told us ...
there is a pendulum in history
that these things change.
And he saw in a way
strange ...
this whole thing,
in 2000, would change.
And hopefully we can see the end
of predatory capitalism.
I think there
a benign capitalism. . .
but there is a predatory
that destroys people.
And we saw it all your life.
Chavez faces the same
Castro challenges.
I think it has more allies.
What struck me in him
was the force. It's a bull.
He has the same strength
Castro had in 2003.
This is reminiscent of how
Castro was strong.
He maintained the strength,
Chavez retains power.
Why do you think the U.S.
hate Chavez so much?
That is obvious. He is a
as big threat to the system. . .
when Castro was.
It is a great example, and
if it is successful ...
be the first time
in the history of Latin America ...
except for Castro ...
he took an entire region,
almost every continent. . .
away from the IMF and the control
U.S. economic.
Shortly after I returned
North to America ...
another president
entered the scene.
If there is someone. . .
who still wonders. . .
The dream of our founders
is alive in our time. . .
who still questions the power
of our democracy. . .
tonight is your answer.
I hope Obama is
a new Roosevelt. . .
Obama and implant
a''New Deal''. . .
not only to the U.S., but for
all continents of the world.
Since virtually all
international organizations ...
IMF to the Security Council
UN ...
are controlled in large
part by the U.S. ...
the new Bolivarian Society
strengthen regional links ...
to speak with the U.S.
with one voice.
This happened at a meeting
of hemisphere leaders ...
in Trinidad where most
South Americans ...
refused to sign any
document in the absence of Cuba.
That was not reported with
due respect in the U.S. media.
If this model is multiply
in other continents ...
American hegemony
will be seriously undermined.
A Conversation with Chavez
Good or bad decision
but certainly historic, right?
My president was
to Trinidad. . .
and all I got was a
lousy t-shirt of Che Guevara.
Barack Obama was Summit Condo
of the Americas in Trinidad ...
and saw the whole continent
supporting Colombia and Mexico ...
ready to face them.
Who is the man laughing
President Obama ...
and why everyone is talking about
about these images?
Embracing dictators,
the villains ...
Corrupt politicians, the gang
the Kirchners in Argentina. . .
Daniel Ortega, Nicaragua,
the biggest pedophile of the West. . .
what it does is give credibility
U.S. enemies.
Friends and enemies quickly
will take advantage of a situation. . .
if they think they're dealing
with a weak president.
But Obama
not behaved like Bush.
He met with Chavez
that made him an offer of peace.
Is unlikely. . .
as a consequence I have
handshake. . .
or had a conversation
educated with Mr.. Chavez. .
we are putting at risk
the U.S. strategic interests.
In particular,
from what I heard ...
The new president assured
Chávez that in his government ...
there will be no further attempts
destabilization ...
or otherwise interfering
in the internal affairs of Venezuela.
It is true that this is
a small step forward.
The 50 years were not in vain.
Because of this we Chavez. .
we Bolivia. . .
we Nicaragua
Ecuador, Paraguay.
Some are called
center-left, like Lula.
It is a great rebellion. . .
people against imperialism
in Latin America.
In a multilateral world, can not
have a potency to decide for everyone.
It's bad for one's potency.
Absolute power is
always bad.
It's what I always say to Chavez
I'm very close to Hugh,
he is a friend.
But I must tell you
collectively building.
It takes
10 candidates Condo presidency. . .
can not be just him.
Otherwise, when he is gone,
the whole process will end.
The belief that only a
one can guarantee. . .
is like believing that a single power can
solve all world problems.
The euphoria and triumphalism that existed
after the fall of the Soviet Union. . .
virtually disappeared.
Everybody knows it's a more
difficult to be confronted.
The size of the Hispanic population
United States. . .
is now greater than ever.
The new immigrants serve
Bridge to South America
The interesting question. . .
that in my moments
Utopian I do. . .
is whether the changes in America
South. .
can travel this bridge
Hispanic population in the U.S. ...
and produce something that no
of us can predict.
In Venezuela, Bolivia,
Ecuador and Paraguay ...
95% of the media were completely
hostile to the Bolivarian Circles.
Still, they won.
There is a lesson here
to be learned.
I hear he is a great
admirer ...
the year 1770, the revolution
Indians against the Spaniards. . .
Tupac Katari.
Tupac Katari was brutally killed,
quartered by the Spanish Empire.
And the moment that would be
dismembered, he said. . .
''I die, but one day
come back as millions.''
Now we are millions.
And perhaps this is one of
things that keeps us going.
The optimism, faith, hope. . .
and concrete evidence that, yes,
You can change the world,
change history.
It is possible, Oliver!