You want to break up with me?
Can't you not?
Please, can you break up with me tomorrow instead?
Vivian... Vivian!
You said Vivian broke up with you?
Hey, Mo Cheng Zhen, don't you know
that tomorrow is our birthday?
What?!
You broke up with your girlfriend on the day before our birthday?!
Happy birthday.
♫ What can I do if I lose you now? ♫
♫ I have to protect you every day now ♫
♫ If I lose you, I won't be able to breathe ♫
♫ So let me just gather up my courage for you ♫
♫ What can I do if I lose you now? ♫
♫ Even if the world ends, I have to protect you ♫
♫ There's only you and me left in this world ♫
♫ You and me ♫
♫ Looking at our childhood albums ♫
♫ The days pass by, one by one ♫
♫ I don't think there's any way I can let you go ♫
♫ Whoa... The time has already passed ♫
♫ Our story has become a timeless legend ♫
♫ You said you didn't want to leave me ♫
♫ Then I'll hold on tightly, and I won't let go ♫
♫ What can I do if I lose you now? ♫
♫ I have to protect you every day now ♫
♫ If I lose you, I won't be able to breathe ♫
♫ So let me just gather up my courage for you ♫
♫ What can I do if I lose you now? ♫
♫ Even if the world ends, I have to protect you ♫
♫ There's only you and me left in this world ♫
♫ You and me ♫
Happy birthday.
Love or Spend
Episode 01
Subtitles By The... Team @ Viki
Say that one more time.
I can say it as many times as you want, but that won't change it.
I broke up with Vivian.
What are you playing at?
Give me your phone! I'll plead with her!
Give me your phone!
Get up, where's your phone?
Mo Cheng Zhen, it's not possible.
There's no hope.
She already left with someone else.
Of the nine break-ups in my life, this was the most...
The most tragic.
She and I have always been inseparable friends.
Chen Zhen and I met when we were kids.
We ate together, slept together,
bathed together.
We even went to school together, hand in hand.
We were in the same kindergarten and elementary school classes.
We went to the same high school, and both got into the same college.
Just as everyone saw us, we were childhood friends.
So, we...
No way!
Of course I know we can't!
What I was going to say was...
What should we do right now?!
Who else knows about this?
While I was despairing, Cheng Han called me.
I told him a little bit about it.
You...
He's your brother, my good friend.
There's probably nothing to be worried about.
I'm worried about Cheng Han's mom, and his mom's best friend!
Your mom!
You can't go to my house!
- What are you doing?
Get up! Phone...!
It's not there.
Stop grabbing at random places!
Oppa, pick up the phone!
Oppa still wants to sleep.
Is it Zheng Xi again?
He's so annoying.
If you don't have a girlfriend, go find another one.
Are you saying that Zheng Xi and his girlfriend broke up?
Yeah, Zheng Xi and his...
Wait, why does this voice sound like...
Mom!
That's right, it's me, your mom, Ms. Huang Ji Xia.
No, Mom, listen to me.
I was just sleeping, and I had a dream.
So I was just talking in my sleep.
Got it?
Mom, it hurts.
This kid can tolerate quite a bit.
I already told you that I'm very tight-lipped.
I won't tell anyone that it was you who told me.
That's not it, Mrs. Pei.
I don't know, I really don't know anything.
Actually, there was a certain spot that was really effective with my husband.
Oh, really?
Then, Yong Jin...
He's fine. At first though, there was a little...
But everything was fine after a week.
What? Then...
Mom.
No! Mom!
I'm the only son in the Mo family.
Have you really thought this over clearly?
Mr. Pei Zheng Xi was the unfortunate witness to Vivian kissing someone else, and then he was dumped!
That's wonderful!
[Mo Cheng Han]
Give it to me!
Get away.
Cheng Han, what are you doing?
But you're just now calling back.
Are you awake?
Zheng Xi, listen to me.
While I was sleeping, I unintentionally–
Listen to me first.
You have to keep it a secret, don't–
Get to the point!
Mo Cheng Han, I'm warning you.
If you dare tell anyone about Pei Zheng Xi and Vivian breaking up,
I'll...!
I'll tell all the girls about the time you peed your pants in middle school.
Sis, can't you just let me off a bit? Just tell the story of the time I fell into a trench when I was in elementary school, okay?
Wait, Cheng Han.
By that, you can't mean...
Wait, did you hear that?
Yeah.
Cheers!
It's the Queen Mother and the Royal Consort Cai Ling.
Cheng Han oppa, hurry and come join us
as we open a bottle of champagne to celebrate!
Come and celebrate!
Let's drink!
Mo Cheng Han, I'm severing my ties with you!
So, what should we do?
What should we do?
This is all your fault!
If you hadn't promised our moms 5 years ago,
our brains wouldn't be hurting so much now!
Well, who was the one who gave the opportunity to suggest such an idea?
You could have not agreed to it.
Why did you agree?!
Sure, just blame me. It's not your fault at all.
Of course!
- Weird...
- Why did you agree to it?
You figure it out.
Daughter.
Cheng Zhen, whether you get promoted or not
depends a bit on luck sometimes.
But I was depending on luck.
I worked really, really hard at the office.
But every time someone gets promoted, it's a man.
How am I supposed to accept that?
Why don't you think of it in a different way?
A woman needs to get married and have kids.
You should put in all your effort to run the family.
That's more practical, right?
That's not what Chengzhen thinks.
She's always wanted to be recognized for her ability at work.
Here, drink some water.
After you drink, you should try to get in a good mood.
It's our birthday today, after all.
Eat some bread. It's your favorite - wheat bread.
You haven't eaten all day.
Add some butter.
Now, have a bit of soup.
Alright, I've decided.
You two, get married.
Where did that come from?
It was already decided when they were 5 years old.
Everyone knows about it.
Zheng Xi, you said you wanted to protect our Cheng Zhen.
And you said you'd definitely marry her.
Mom, when did that happen?
Don't make stuff up.
What do you mean, it didn't happen?
You were 5 years old.
Don't either of you have any recollection of it at all?
Auntie, wait a minute.
How can you hold us to the promises of a 5 year-old?
Plus, I don't remember it at all.
I knew you would say that!
That's why we recorded the evidence.
Really? Where is it?
Pei Yong Jin, where is it?
- Do we have that?
- Yes, you put it inside the drawer.
- No, I open that drawer every day.
- Yes, we do.
Alright, that's enough. Mom...
It sounds like you're pushing us to get married.
You want me to marry Cheng Zhen, but then what happens to my girlfriend?
Also, have you asked Cheng Zhen?
Isn't that being too disrespectful of her?
That's right, I'm not respecting you two.
And that's because you don't even respect yourselves.
You can't even keep your promises!
How can I respect a son like you?
Ji Xia, I'm so sorry.
How could I have raised such a son, who doesn't keep his promises?
I've really let you down.
Let me kneel down to you.
Mom!
Mom! Mrs. Pei!
Zheng Xi, look at this.
How did you let things turn into this?
Hurry and say something to make your mom happy.
Alright... Alright, Mom, just tell me exactly what it is you want me to do.
I'll do it.
No one forced to you say that.
No one forced me.
Okay, since you have a girlfriend right now...
Then, if you two are both single on your birthday,
you two will sincerely date,
and then get married.
What?
If we both just happen to be single on our birthday,
we will sincerely date,
and then get married.
Are you recording? Is it clear?
Good thing you came up with this strange idea.
Otherwise, who would know how long we'd have to wait.
Cheers.
But they really are made for each other.
One day, they will understand that.
There really isn't anyone else
who suits them better than each other.
That's right! Ji Xia,
we're going to really become
one family!
Cheers!
- That–
- Was–
It's 8 PM right now. There's 24 hours left until our birthday party tomorrow.
Let's face this together.
We'll each find someone.
Let's see if we can get through tomorrow.
Fine, let's find someone.
Who's afraid?
Pei Yongjin,
I told Jixia in high school that we'd become family.
I never thought it would really become a reality.
Hubby...
Hubby, do you remember
when Chengzhen was 11 years old,
her father left Chenghan in the park.
And Chenghan was scared, and cried loudly.
You were the one who carried him back, right?
Right?
Here. Endure it.
I know
that Jixia always tells me she's okay,
but then every time, she hides and cries.
How can I leave her to bear such a big burden by herself?
Right?
Cailing,
from your personality,
you wouldn't interfere with what kind of girl our son dates.
So why is it that this time you put in such effort to match the two of them up?
There was a bigger reason, right?
For Jixia?
You know, Jixia and I,
we're just like sisters, but when it comes down to it, we're just friends.
If something happened,
how much can friends do?
If we became family,
Zhengxi could take care of Chengzhen for us,
take care of Jixia, take care of all of them.
Am I right?
And haven't you always treated Chengzhen and Chenghan as your own kids?
That's because you care for them, and I care for you. Of course I should do that much.
Hubby, you're so wonderful.
I love you the most! Kiss!
- Alright...
- I'm so happy today!
- Okay, okay...
- I love you the most!
Be careful. Why did you drink so much wine?
Be careful!
Chengzhen, you're back?
Did you know that Zhengxi broke up with his girlfriend?
Okay.
Chengzhen, let me tell you.
I've always worried a lot about you.
Everyone says that a daughter's future is just like her mother's past.
Mom.
I was worried that you would follow in my footsteps.
Chengzhen,
anything can happen in this world.
I just hope
that, at least, there can be someone to walk this path with you.
To cry with you, to laugh with you.
Having you is enough.
Didn't we already agree?
I would stay with you until we're old.
No matter how you put it,
my farewell will come before yours.
I'll reach the end before you.
Mom, don't talk about that stuff.
Ms. Huang!
Hello, is this Assistant Manager Luo?
I'm Mo Chengzhen from King of Scissor.
Sorry to disturb you so suddenly.
It's very noisy here, I'll call you back in a moment.
How can my luck be so bad?
Well, so what if it doesn't start out great.
Hey.
You still have the yearbooks from elementary school to college?
Why?
I'm worried you won't have enough people from your business cards.
Thanks for your concern.
But please, before you worry about someone else, take care of yourself first.
Between the two of us, the one who doesn't need to keep worrying about this situation is me.
Pei Zhengxi, you've already taken care of it?
I just called Peipei, and she said she'd also really like to meet up.
Really?
I just called Assistant Manager Luo,
from 8mm Beauty Salon.
But he seemed to be busy, and said he'd call back.
Let's have a toast.
No matter what, I still have Peipei to help me out.
Wait, let me check my phone.
What?
He's decided to return tomorrow, and I have to pick him up at the airport?
I didn't realize Assistant Manager Luo was so considerate.
Good luck to you. Bye.
Youxin, what are you doing here?
I know you're the most considerate.
Every year, you play Happy Birthday for me.
But it's already late.
Why haven't you gone to sleep?
If you want to play the song, it's not too late to play it tomorrow.
But Mom said I have to play the Bridal Chorus tomorrow.
Brother, goodnight!
Okay!
Goodnight.
Happy birthday.
So? Where are you and Assistant Manager Luo going for your date?
What?
Didn't Assistant Manager Luo text you to pick him up at the airport?
You're not planning to grab some afternoon tea or something as well?
What?
- That text...?
- Yeah.
You... Are you set?
Peipei invited me out for lunch.
Is that so?
Then, good luck on your date.
What's that face supposed to mean?
Nothing. You also know that Peipei's laugh sounds just like a rooster.
Hey...
Hey, no one's perfect.
That's right, Peipei's laugh is indeed very unusual.
But she's very pretty.
If you can, why don't you find a man then?
That client was really crafty. He kept asking questions that I had no way to answer.
Really?
Maybe I haven't studied enough.
There's a very suitable candidate in front of my eyes. Do you want to think it over?
Who?
He Liyang?
You've got to be kidding.
- He's my–
- I know that he's your assistant.
Look at his deep eyes,
his wide shoulders, his sturdy chest.
And there's his bright and sunny smile.
Don't try to match up people so randomly.
Good morning, managers.
- Good morning.
Don't mess around.
Please, you first.
Thank you, Manager Pei.
Get in.
Be careful. Are you okay?
I'm fine, sorry.
What's the matter?
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Is there something bothering you?
There's nothing.
Yes.
I just called each of them, and they said they could come.
There's a very suitable candidate in front of my eyes. Do you want to think it over?
Who else is there?
Miss,
your shoes are very pretty.
Are they new? Size 25, right?
Excuse me, didn't you ask me the same thing two weeks ago?
And these are the same pair of shoes.
But they've already got wrinkles.
Really?
Just like you.
You were very pretty before, but now you're getting wrinkles.
What's on your mind?
Can I help you?
No...
You're still saying no?
You were just going through your phone, with your brows furrowed, saying you were looking for something.
I was looking for...
I need a man.
Tonight.
I already set up a date with Peipei.
Peipei?
Peipei's...
Oh!
You mean the one who's laugh sounds like this?
Her?
You two were almost together, right?
Hey, Zhengxi...
Hi, Zhengxi.
Zhengxi, it's been a long time.
How is it that you haven't changed at all?
Your smile...also hasn't changed at all.
Last night, when you said you wanted to meet up...
I was so happy!
Really?
I was thinking that we hadn't seen each other in a long time, so it wouldn't be bad to meet up.
But, what I wanted to say was
I don't want to be just friends.
Peipei, don't act like this.
We're in a public place.
Really, don't.
Oops, I'm sorry.
8mm's Assistant Manager Luo just got married yesterday?
I'm doomed...
Assistant Manager Luo? I remember I told you he wasn't bad, and that you should grab him.
But you kept saying you didn't need that.
I never thought that
there would be a day where Zhengxi and I were both single.
Since it's all fake anyway, and your search is so tough,
why not just pair up with Zhengxi?
Go home, and put on a nice show for your moms, and then it'll be done with.
Me and Pei Zhengxi? Impossible!
We're good friends.
Pairing us up together
makes me feel very uncomfortable.
It's not possible.
It matters how you feel?
Hey, are you seriously looking for a man this time?
Of course.
How seriously? This much, this much, this much?
Just as seriously as when I'm making a presentation to clients.
No, no, I didn't lie.
I really want to find someone to help me through tonight.
If it goes smoothly, I won't keep rejecting love.
So, this time,
you're looking for a man you can spend every day with, for the rest of your life?
And not just someone you play with and use, and then get rid of?
Of course I can't just play with someone.
- Hey, there's a decent candidate that might be able to help you.
- Really?!
His name is Victor.
He's flying into Taiwan from the US tonight.
I'll help you set something up.
You can meet at work.
Really?!
Really.
President, thank you!
You always treat me the best!
No need to act cute.
My pride is helping a beautiful girl in need.
I'll take care of it, don't worry.
I'll help you right away.
Thank you, President!
Ah Hao, send a car
to the airport to pick someone up.
It's all taken care of then, right?
I almost forgot about the airport!
Strange... Where's Chengzhen?
Why don't I see her?
Did I go the wrong way?
Hey! Mister, in the front!
Hey!
Mister, in the yellow sweater that looks like a banana!
May I help you?
Help me?
As if I would really say "help me."
Just now, your luggage just hit my foot.
Shouldn't you say somthing?
Oh, Miss, are you alright?
Your luggage is so big and heavy.
Do you think I'd be alright?
I'm sorry, I didn't notice.
Your cart hit my foot and you didn't notice?
I'm really very sorry.
If you'd like, I can compensate you for it.
Compensate?
Okay, ask my foot what kind of compensation it needs.
Hey! What are you doing?
You asked me to ask your foot. I should check to see the condition, let me see.
Hey! Are you trying to hit on me?
That's not it at all.
You're so annoying.
Pervert.
Youting, I've got an important meeting right now, so I could only send a car to pick you up.
When you leave, take note.
The license plate is 3883.
Called a car for me? I guess that's fine.
3-8-8... 3?
Wow, it's that one.
Chengzhen is being too kind.
She got such an expensive car to pick me up.
Hey, where's the driver?
Hey!
Hello, Stanley?
Something's come up over here.
Hey, Chenghan.
She just called and said she had to go to Nanbu.
She even took the day off from work tomorrow.
Come in.
President, where's Victor? Is he still not here?
Something's come up, so he can't make it.
Then...!
Then what am I supposed to do about tonight?
- You–
There's only an hour left.
Where am I supposed to find a boyfriend?
Manager, I wanted to go over the price for Yixuan Salon.
Take a look at this price.
There's a very suitable candidate in front of my eyes. Do you want to think it over?
Manager, you...
Look at his deep eyes,
his wide shoulders, his sturdy chest.
And there's his bright and sunny smile.
I'm sorry.
My mom went to work.
Chenghan said he'd leave before noon.
If you leave the room after noon, it should be safe.
Being close to your memories
is a kind of loneliness.
Don’t Say Goodbye - by Popu Lady
I don't want to be alone.
♫ Such a familiar laugh, and yet it feels so cold ♫
♫ Quietly watching you, when suddenly,
my heart starts to beat anxiously ♫
♫ I'd rather be worse off,
than have to guess at what you're hiding ♫
♫ Or maybe I just need to close my eyes,
and wait for your embrace ♫
♫ Once upon a time, your breathing ♫
♫ was beside my ear,
wrapped around the future that was set ♫
♫ But will your next words be 'I love you more'
or will you have no response at all? ♫
♫ I don't want to cry and have to guess ♫
♫ I don't want an answer based off a hunch ♫
♫ You borrowed all of my tomorrows ♫
♫ I don't want you to give them back ♫
♫ If this is a mistake, and I'm just scared of losing you ♫
♫ Please hold me tightly, kiss me, and tell me what to do ♫
♫ so that we won't have to say goodbye ♫
♫ I don't want to say goodbye ♫