(Previously on Prince William)The expropriation plan has been redrawn.Our house is included now!
How can this be?
Listen carefully, William Yi. I will not let you touch the land of Mei Village in my life!
- Go back!- You're not welcome here!
Stop throwing! Stop!
CEO has been very unstable these days.
As if he has schizophrenia.
Are you sick again, Stonehead?
Liu Wen Bin… Ahhh!
William Yi, you've gone too far!
I… I couldn't possibly have done it!
This is the CEO who leads Yi Shan Construction.
He actually has mental problem!
Protect Yi Shan… Protect Yi Shan!
Brother...
Protect Yi Shan.
What are you doing here?
"The Prince's DNA" by Antonio Huang
♫ I walk with my chin upto pursue my own kingdom. ♫
♫ Once I've made a resolution,there is no going back. ♫
♫ I don't need a royal mace or cape,or even a prestigious lineage, ♫
♫ to honor my dreams. Yeah~~~ ♫
♫ "Prince" is what they calla young man of my generation. ♫
♫ Love is my DNA. ♫
♫ As long as my heart is beating like a drum,I'll be able to fly high. ♫
♫ I want to go experience what the world has to offer.Say that's okay! ♫
♫ I want to builda whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
♫ As long as my heart is beating like a drum,I'll be able to fly high. ♫
♫ I want to go experience what the world has to offer.Say that's okay! ♫
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
♫ As long as our hearts are beating like a drum anyone can fly high. ♫
♫ I want to go experience what the world has to offer.Say that's okay! ♫
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ This will be yours and my fortress. ♫
Subtitles brought to you by The Royal Team @ Viki
~ Prince William ~EP #14 (Final Episode)
I know what I say may seem unreasonable to you.
I also shouldn't pressure you like this.
But… but he is my brother.
Just see it as my asking you to do me a favor.
Could you impersonate CEO one more time?
Are you kidding me? Impossible!
William Yi can live without me, but not without Yi Shan.
Even if he recovers, when he finds outthe CEO position has been replaced,
he won't be able to live with that.
Ah Bin, I beg you.
Please...
No.
Can you please stop pressuring me?
Look at the way he is now. He really is very sick.
I don't want to! Why should I?
Then do you want to take a look at my mom's blood stains?
What wrong has my mother done?
She is still in a coma. Don't you know?
She is not better off than your brother.
I'm very sorry.
I really can't help you.
CEO, this way please.
Not yet. Not quite yet.
The order for you to be the interim CEOwill be issued sooner or later.
It will surely happen soon.
By the way, CEO Zhao
how would you like your office decorated?
Just give me an order, I will hire a designerto take care of it right away.
Haste can make a person blind.
Once I get the last straw that'll break the camel's back,
my plan will not be like this anymore.
I've endured everything for so long.Do you think I can't wait another day or two?
Aren't we waiting for the board of directorsto have a vote in the board meeting?
All the directors are on your side, so the camel has already fallen. Why do we need the last straw?
Seriously, you...
With a brain like yours, how am I going to make youthe head of the secretarial department?
CEO, you mean...
I just took the medicine. Ask Maka Long to get the car ready.
I have to go to work.
- Brother..- Ok, ok.
I will call Maka Long right away for you.
Did he lose his temper again?
He yelled at all the doctors and the nurses just now.But at least he was willing to take the medicine.
Otherwise the doctor might suggest to tie him up again.
Are you ok? Your clothes are all wet.
I'm fine.Oh, don't be mad at him.
The doctor said, at first, because his mental state is still unstable, so the dosage is higher.
Very soon when the drug begins to take effect,
his mood will be more stable.
You've done a lot these days.
William is suffering more than me.
William, lie down for awhile.
I will let you know when Maka Long is here.
Be good and lie here.I need to go home now,
but I'll be back soon.
Don't worry.
You have to take good care of yourself.
You must be exhausted.
Take a rest after you get home.
No. I will be right back after I change my clothes.It won't take long.
Brother. Take a nap.
Don't think about the company, ok?
Have you told the board of directors
that I can go back to work now?
Brother, I'm sorry.
None of them wanted to see me.
There is nothing I can do to help.
I don't think I can protect your CEO position.
I'm sorry.
Mom, God did hear what we were asking him.
There is a chance Mei Village might not get torn down.
Dad's sea will still belong to all of us.
But… you need to get better soon.
Without you at home, no one nags me.
I am too lazy to clean up now.
Our house is almost like a pile of garbage!
Do you hear me?
Also, didn't you, Uncle and Aunt Ah-Zhu
plan to take a trip to Hokkaido during the New Year?
If you don't get better soon,
you'll miss the tour.
Don't complain to me when that happens,
or ask me to take you there instead.You hear me?
Mom!
Did your hand just move?
Move your fingers one more time.
I saw your hand moved. Do that again!
Ms. Lai Yu Xia, do you hear me?
Move your fingers again for me.
Mom!
Mom… I knew you could hear me.
Come out with me for a second.
Is it really a good idea to give him those booksabout bipolar disorder?
I think my brother needs to face his problem directly.
That's the only way to solve the current difficult situation.
Exactly what else can we do to help William?
Every time when I remember it was my dadwho made William the way he is now,
I feel everything is my fault.
- I have done wrong to William…- Katy Zhao.
Please don't look at it this way.
Your dad was only the last flash point.As the doctor has said,
the cause of bipolar can be very complicated.I think...
this is a test for my brother.
Perhaps if he can get through it this time,we'll all learn to understand ourselves better,
and to understand others better.
But I am very worried. I worry whether or not
William will dislike me because of my dad.
He won't. He is not that kind of person.
Besides, you've done so much for him.I'm sure he knows.
OK?
What the heck!
I don't believe any of these. Take them all away!
Where is Maka Long?
Why hasn't he come to tell me what's going on in the company?
Brother, could you let go of the company just for now?
You must face your illness first.Only then we can really solve the problem.
Besides, the doctor has said
bipolar is something that might stay with youfor the rest of your life.
Yi Xin!
Why should I let a incompetent doctor decide my future?
I am only here to rest. I am fine!
I must go back to the office. I am going to Yi Shan.
Ok. I understand.
Let's rest a few more days then we'll go home, ok?
The weather is nice today. Take me out to get some sunlight.
Have a walk with me, ok?
Come!
"A bigot in power will soon find his punishment."
“It's never too late for a gentleman to take his revenge!"
Secretary office. How may I help you?
Secretary Song? He is not here right now.
To confirm the meeting time with Interim CEO?
Hello, this is Secretary Song.
Yes. Wednesday afternoon at 3PM.
Ok. I got it. Thank you.
Maka Long. From this day on,
all the documents and phone calls in the secretary's office
are off-limits for you. Do you hear me?
It's your working hours. Why are you here?Go away now while William is still resting.
If he sees you, he'll definitely ask you what's happening in the company.
- There is one thing I must tell you.- What is it?- It's...
Is this something I shouldn't know?
I don't think this is a good idea.
That's ok. There is nothing we can't let Katy know.
Tell us!
I found out that General Manager Zhao and Shiji Bank's VIP service department
made an appointment to open CEO's safe.
Is this something strange? He is the Interim CEO.
He is given the power to do so.
But I don't know why, I just find it weird.
So I called and asked Secretary Wan.
He said, in the safe, there are all the operating-before-authorization agreements between Yi Shan and its collaborators.
In short, those are the original copies of the memosthat were given to you.
If General Manger Zhao gets hold of the information,I'm afraid he might use it against William.
I am going to scold him right now!
He has already made William this way,what else does he want?
Calm down first. Don't act so impulsively!
How can I calm down?
Yi Shan is William's life.
What does your dad want to achieveby getting these documents?
He is already the Interim CEO.
Even if he needs to call for a board meeting,all the board members are on very good terms with him.
If they are to elect a new CEO,
your dad is very likely to get elected.
So why does he want to get these documents?
There is more…Recently I found out that
they opened another company.
That company's capital flows look very strange.
Secretary Wan worries that, as the first step, Zhao wants tocompletely defeat William
and make him unable to return to Yi Shan forever.
Next, he will drain Yi Shan's bank accounts.
So we definitely can't let him get hold of these documents,otherwise we'll be doomed!
William?
I have to go to the office!
- Calm down!- I'll definitely find a way to stop Daddy.
Go away, all of you!
Maka Long, hold on to him.I'm going to call for help.
- Let me go!- CEO, please calm down!
Problem… can't be solved this way.
Maka Long, let's go get the documents from the safe.
- I don't believe I can't do anything. Let me go!- Brother!
Can't you focus on dealing with yourmental and physical health first?
I don't want to. I must protect Yi Shan.
I am nothing if I can't protect Yi Shan.Go away!
Don't be like this, please!
We'll definitely find a solution.
Scram! Go away!
You want to go, right? I'll come with you.
I will come with you. So please calm down.
Katy Zhao, don't do this.
Don't always yield to him, ok?
William Yi! We won't leave you.
Even if you don't have Yi Shan, or if you're not CEO,
I believe Dad would rather use Yi Shanin exchange for your health. Do you understand?
I don't understand! I don't.
- Go away!- Don't be like this.
Let me go! Let me…
Let me go!
What are you doing?
Let me go! Let me go...
Katy, Katy! Tell them to let me go.
Let me go...
All done! We can eat now.
Why are you standing there?
I forgot.
That's ok. Sit down first.
The doctor said
if there is a place to sit, don't stand.
He said we still need to watch out forthe increase of pressure in your brain.
But the doctor also said
after I'm home, I should also move around.
I was actually a "model patient" when I was in the hospital.
But after we came home, you won't let me do anything.
This feels harder than staying at the hospital.
Fine. Model patient.
Let me ask you. What exactly do you want to do?
Stop thinking if you can't figure out.
The doctor said this is the aftereffect of your head injury.We have to be careful in the next couple of years.
What exactly should we do now?
Are we going to keep sitting here withoutcoming up with an idea?
If you have nothing to say, I'll go and talk to Daddy directly.
There is one solution.
It won't be possible.
Even if it's not possible, we still need to give it a try.
Otherwise should we ask CEO to give up Yi Shan?
What solution?
I won't go!
Exactly what is it?
We'll go and talk to Ah Bin.
Buddy, we can only count on you now.
If you don't help, General Manager Zhao will take awaythe entire Yi Shan, you know?
Lower your voice. My mom is resting inside.
Ah Bin, we really don't have much time left.
William was going to rush out of the hospitalwhen he heard the news.
But he really is in terrible shape right now.
I beg you.
Frankly speaking, don't you think it might work betterif you go and beg your dad directly?
Do you think I don't want to?
I already threatened to cut the ties with him,
but he didn't cancel the appointment with the bank.
We must get to those documents before he does,so we can protect William,
and protect Yi Shan.
We are not begging you to go back to being the CEO.
We only hope you'll help us for just one day.
I beg you...
Alright. Please say no more.
Even if I want to help, I can't.
I really can't leave my mom home alone.
Besides, I really don't care what happens toYi Shan Construction.
You should go now.
Very well. Let's go.
William has to take care of his own future.
We shouldn't put all the responsibly on you.Let's go.
If Ah Bin doesn't go back to Taipei with us,I won't leave.
Miss Katy. Let's not make this difficult for Ah Bin anymore.
Let's go.
Subtitles brought to you by The Royal Team @ Viki
Mom, how come you didn't stay in your room and rest?
These days, in order to take care of me,
you have lost a lot of weight.
Not… not really.
When you eat, I eat too.Look at my tummy.
You're all skin and bones.
Madam Lai Yu Xia.
Couldn't you just simply enjoy the 6-star service that I offer you?
Be good. Go and rest.
I'm fine.
Sit down.
Son. Are you really not going to help Stonehead?
Very soon we'll get that last straw.
Yi Shan… Yi Shan.
I might feel reluctant to rename you "Zhao Hai" one day.
Congratulations, CEO!
Listen. Let's find a place tonight
and have a big celebration!This last blow
will definitely knock down William Yi so hardthat he can never get back up.
Only then will Katy give up on him.
Thank you.
Silly. Why did you say "thank you"?
Are you done being corny?
We're getting late.Let's go.
Let's go.
Hurry!
I thought my appointment was with General Manager Zhao.
Let me make a call and check.
I am the current CEO. Can't I open the safewithout an appointment?
Perhaps you prefer that I ask your General Managerto come and see me?
I'm been here so many times.What's the situation now? What's going on?
Sorry. My apology.This way, please.
Please key in the password.
Password?
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
I've signed the form.Can we go to the safe now?
Just a moment, please.
Please key in the password.
Password?
Sorry. It's not correct.
I haven't come here for a long time.Don't quite remember the password.
I thought everyone uses his own birthdate as the password.
Dad's birthdate is 0715
Try it.
Sorry. It's not correct either.You have one last chance.
Daddy… Daddy!
I've finally found you.
What are you doing here?
Daddy, didn't you tell me, because William's mind is unstable,that we'll have domestic violence?
I have thought it through. You should call President Guoand arrange a blind date for me and his son.
We'll talk about this later!
- Daddy!- What?
I want you to ask Secretary Song to make the call right now.
No… not now...
Come on, Daddy!See? I've waited so long that my hair has turned grey.
- General Manger Zhao, we're late.- Enough… stop...
- Daddy!- Hey! Stop this nonsense.
- Close the door.- Yes, Sir.
Oh, no!
Hello? My daddy just went up.
Yes. I understand.Very good.
Have you thought of anything?
We can try mom's birthdate, 1031.
CEO, this way, please.
How come no one is here?
Why haven't they come down yet?
♫ I walk with my chin up to pursue my own kingdom. ♫
Please help them get the documents, God.
♫ I don't need a royal mace or cape, or even a prestigious lineage, ♫
♫ to honor my dreams. Yeah~~~ ♫
So? Did you get it? Did you?
Yes!Hurry, let's go!
♫ As long as my heart is beating like a drum,I'll be able to fly high. ♫
♫ I want to go experience what the world has to offerSay that's okay! ♫
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
How did you guess that my brother would use the datemy mom passed away as the password?
Judging from your brother's eccentric personality,
I think the most conflicted and painful day in his life
is probably the most important day for him.
About your mother's passing away, I don't know if that brought him feelings of hate or sadness.
He probably couldn't tell himself.
I didn't expect that you would understand him so well.
I probably got too into it afterpretending to be William Yi for so long.
Right now I don't know if I feel happy or unhappy.
You two! Are you done yet?
If General Manager Zhao sees us, we won't see the end of it.Let's go now.
Okay!
Are you reading the books Yi Xin bought for you?
I'm going to tell you some good news.
About the documents in the safe, we've got them!
You don't need to worry anymore.
You? How did you do that?
Come. Come with me.
But you have to promise me thatyou definitely won't get mad.
Come on!
You guys are so strange.
You said you were taking me to the airport,but you brought me here instead.
Why do you want me here? You can simply hand him this stuff yourself.
He and I have nothing to say to each other.
Besides, I have to go back to Mei Village today.Uncle is helping me take care of my mom.
- I'm going.- Wait.
Ah Bin. I really think you two should have a talk.
Since you agreed to help him, why nothand him the documents yourself?
I don't want to.This really feels weird to me.
I've got to go.
Actually we've still got things to do.So you should have a chat with CEO.
Let's go! Go!
Subtitles brought to you by The Royal Team @ Viki
You…Are you alright?
You…Why did you help me?
Even my mom is not mad at you, why should I be?
Auntie doesn't blame me?
Son.
Are you sure you're not going to help Stonehead?
Secretary Wan said
for Stonehead, Yi Shan is as important as his own life.
If the company is lost,
I wonder if worse things will happen to Stonehead.
Look at the way you are now,
you should stop worrying about him, ok?
However, if not because of what happened to me,
maybe I would never have had a chance to know
how much my son treasures and cares about me.
Do you know?
I really don't blame Stonehead at all.
Have you ever thought about it?
It was because his heart was sick,
that's why he couldn't control himself.
If he knew he would make me go through an operationand stay in the hospital for so long,
I'm sure he would blame himself
and feel very bad.
I don't believe a bit of it.
He will feel bad? And blame himself?
That's because you don't know him.
When Stonehead was staying in our house,
when I was feeling unwell, he cooked for me.
He also helped me hang the laundry to dry.
He did take care of me.
There is more.
When I had a car accident,
he was more anxious and worried than anyone else.
You… should believe that your mom is right about him.
Stonehead is definitely not a cold-blooded person.
Mom. Hasn't Yi Shan given us enough troubles already?
Every time when I think of William Yi,I get incensed.
So… are you going to live your life in hatred?
Do you really think
you'll feel better this way?
You should put yourself in his shoesand think about how he feels.
He has to manage such a big company.Imagine how stressful that is.
Besides,
he only wanted to carry out his father's death wish.
So, I think he must be just like you.
He is definitely a very filial kid.
As you know,
he was kidnapped by his own mother when he was little.
What I got was a wound on my body.
But Stonehead? He had a wound in his heart.
Haven't you heard this before?"No medicine cures heartsickness."
The pain in the heart can't be helped by medicine.
What Stonehead needs the most now
is his family and friends
who will sympathize with his pain
and care about him with love.
♫ Is this me? I guess so. ♫
I'm really not used to this kind of situation.
This is the memo Secretary Wan gave me,
plus all the documents we took from your safe.
Now I'm giving them all back to you.
This is your reward for helping me. You should keep itas a way to protect your house. I don't want it.
To be honest, that idea did cross my mind.
However, when I was on my way to Taipei,I did a lot of thinking.
My dad used to tell me this.
Being a person, I should alway take the right path,
and do my best on everything.
Don't ever use dishonest methods to achieve my goals,let alone hurting others.
About protecting Mei Village, I'll never give it up.
But I will use my own methods.I don't need these documents.
Why?
How come I treated you this way
yet you chose to treat me like this?
I was once very mad at you.
I don't understand why you had to harass me like that.
But if I can't let this go, I can't move on with my life.
Aren't there a lot more beautiful things in the world?
My mom is right.
If I keep on hating someone. In the end,I'll be the one who suffers the most.
This time, it's not that I'm helping you.I'm helping myself.
So… we don't owe each other anything.
♫ I don't want to be a shadow-like manwho loses traction and loses his way, ♫
♫ getting lost in the coldest valley without sunshine. ♫
♫ The more I want to escape,the more winding roads I have to take. ♫
CEO, I've sent someone to check.
William Yi is still staying at the psychiatric center.
So the person who went to the safe that daywas definitely not him.
I knew it! It was Liu Wen Bin.
It looks like William Yi's illness is hopeless.
He couldn't even go to the safe himself.
But, CEO. Now we don't have the documents to prove thatWilliam Yi and his father worked in collusion with the government.
We can't defeat William Yi.What should we do next?
What are you afraid of?
Look at how sick William Yi is right now.
You don't believe I can handle a fishmonger?
Let me tell you.As long as I'm still in this CEO position,
whatever tricks they want to play...Bring it on!
I sincerely thank all the board members,despite your busy schedules,
for attending this emergency board meeting.
The purpose of this meeting
is to elect a new CEO.
Allow me to thank you again for coming today.Thank you.
I guess William Yi won't be able to attend this meeting.
Why don't we just count his vote as abstained?
- Secretary Song. Go and get the ballot box.- Yes, sir.
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
I guess William Yi won't be showing up today.
Why don't we just count his vote as abstained?
Secretary Song. Go and get the ballot box.
Yes, sir.
General Manager Zhao. Both William and I are board members.
The meeting shouldn't have started without us.
Excuse me. I'm the CEO of Yi Shan Construction now.
Please stop calling me General Manager Zhao.
It's "interim" CEO.
Are you… the real William Yi or the fake one?
Maybe you're actually the fishmongerfrom Mei Village, Liu Wen Bin!
What are you doing here? What are you trying to...
Everyone. You probably don't know about this.
William Yi, when he was sick,
got a stranger to impersonate him as CEO.
He treated Yi Shan Construction as a joke.
Do you think we should let this kind of personcontinue to lead Yi Shan?
That's right. I have been sick.
Therefore, I've decided to take a long vacation.
Now that's better.
Since you're sick, you should take a good rest.
Being able to understand yourself is a sign of growth.
Don't worry. You can leave the company with me.
All you need to do is to rest and get better.
Secretary Song.
Yes.
Wait.
Although currently I am not suitable,I would like to recommend someone for this position.
- How come they look so alike?- They look like twins.
Subtitles brought to you by The Royal Team @ Viki
Ladies and gentlemen. Allow me to formally introduce to you
Mr. Liu Wen Bin.
In these past few months,
he worked as CEO while I was sick.
That is the truth.In addition to myself,
Secretary Wan and Maka Long can also testify.
In order to avoid any chaos,we haven't been able to explain the situation to you all.
But please believe in us.
William never treats the management of Yi Shan lightly.
William Yi. What are you trying to do?
Do you think by finding someone who looks like you,you can fool the board members?
What exactly do you want?
Don't tell me you're going to say you two are actuallyblood-related brothers,
and use that as an excuse to keep your CEO position?
Of course there is a reasonwhy we made such a recommendation.
Director Zhang. Recently you just bought two houses.
I believe that was because Yi Shan's stock pricehas gone higher,
and brought you quite a lot of profit.
Director Wang. I believe you're in a very good mood too.
I heard that you bought anantique Qing Dynasty china piece at an auction,
and that you paid quite a lot of money for it.Jennifer from Ju Yi Gallery already told me.
In the past three months, everyone could seeMr. Liu Wen Bin's work as CEO was outstanding.
Yi Shan's stock price increased by 8%.
Because the negative news reportsabout our Gentle Village project
got turned around because of his Resettlement Plan.
In addition, he also obtained the land in Xi Chuan, which our Development Department spent two years still failed to get.
Everyone. Can you think of anyone more suitable for the job?
You…!
Everyone. You definitely should not believe him.
What kind of nonsense is this?
If you let me be the CEO,
I can also let you earn a lot of money,and enjoy a good, happy life.
You definitely shouldn't believe inthis pair of brother and sister.
Hey! Let's vote now. Hurry!
What are you doing?
Listen, don't do anything foolish.
If you insist on taking a vote,I'll have no choice but to show the board
where the company's capital wentsince you became interim CEO.
What do you think?
Everyone. If you would like to keep our company's stock priceat its current level,
and that the management of our companycan head to the right direction,
then please support Mr. Liu Wen Bin
and make him the new CEO of Yi Shan.
We've finally settled this.
I still don't think this is a good idea.
Can't you really come back to work?
Liu Wen Bin, if I could come back to work,
do you think I would've asked you to do me this favor?
You should know that I've never asked anyone for any favor.You are the first one.
But you still gave me quite a fright.
Seeing Prince William from Yi Shan Constructioncome to my house and refuse to leave,
my mom almost went nuts!
If I didn't agree to help you,I'm sure she would have kicked me out.
Why have you changed so much?
I realized, pride may blind a person
and cover his ears, or even his heart.
It made me hurt people around me continuously.
I thought I was invincible, and that I could do anything.
I thought no matter what difficulties I was facing,I would never get defeated.
But the truth is, I was only hiding my incapability.
Learning to understand myself
will be my life-long lesson.
Are you ok? Do you want me to pour you some water?
I'm fine.
This is only the side effect of the medication.
Oh. Let me get you some water then.
But seriously. Talking about your incapabilitywas really an overstatement.
You have such a fine educational background,and you are such a hard worker.
You are very impressive already.
You, Prince William, belong to the team of winners.
When I was lying on the sick bed,
what often came to my mind was the time
when I was with your mother at your house,
and how I helped her sun the laundry and the salted fish.
Helping my mom sun the laundry and the salted fish?
Only recently have I realized that my motherhas passed away for almost 20 years now.
While I was staying at your house, I felt the mostpeaceful and content, as I never experienced before.
It was fate that brought us together.
In this dog-eat-dog world,
all I think about everyday is how to be tougher than others.
I can never let anyone look down on me.
When you gave me those documents,I was in complete shock.
Why didn't you use those as a weapon to attack me?
That was too insulting, Liu Wen Bin!
What you did put me at a loss what to do.
Does this mean I should apologize to you?
There is more.
Maka Long, Secretary Wan, Yi Xin, and even Katy.
The way they look at you is so different fromthe way they look at me.
How come they love you more?
No doubt I'm more exceptional than you.How could I lose to you?
You people in the winning team really have a tough life.
Therefore, I decided to hand the company over to you.
What… what did you say?
♫ I've finally realized thatthe ability to be my true self ♫
♫ is the most precious gift of all. ♫
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
No doubt I'm more exceptional than you.How could I lose to you?
You people in the winning team really have a tough life.
Therefore, I decided to hand the company over to you,
and make you work like a dog.
What… what did you say?
To admit that I am weak, imperfect,
and that I lost to a fishmonger
is much more painful than managing a company, you know?
I haven't been talking this much for a long time.
It does make me feel tired,
so I'm going back to rest.
There are so many things going on in the company.If we don't have a discussion first, how am I to handle it?
Besides, my ideas are so different from yours.
Liu Wen Bin, Mr. CEO.Just do whatever you like.
- Bye.- Hey!
We agreed this is only temporary.You have to come back after you get better. Hey!
You can do it.
Good morning, everyone.
Before today's meeting starts, I havetwo announcements to make.
First. The development of Bella Villa Hotel Resortwill be halted immediately.
- No way!- How can this be?
But… CEO.
This is a BOT case with a signed contract.
If we halt the development, we might be suedby the county government for breach of contract.
About this case, I've already had a discussionwith the previous CEO.
We were going to begin the construction withoutdoing an environmental impact assessment first.
This would have brought us a lot ofpublic censure and social risk.
So if we insist on going ahead with the construction,we'll have more to lose.
There were flaws in this BOT case.
If the county government decides to sue us,
that's fine. I'll take the responsibility.
Any other questions?
The second announcement.Manager Wang.
I would like you to resume the Gentle Village Resettlement Plan.
Of course, the planning for Xi Chuan will have to beas how we initially agreed with the land owner, Mr. Ou.
You won't change it again, right?
This is the last time?
Yes, the last time.
You've been working very hard. Sorry.
General Manager Zhao. Do you have any important suggestion that you would like to share with us?
No.
Now let's begin our meeting today.
If you're not ready, we can go back.
I didn't expect it would be this hard.
Mom. Brother is here to see you.
Mom.
I really hate you.
When every Mother's Day comes,
my heart aches as if being cut by a knife.
How could you treat me like that?
How could you be so heartless?
Mom! Don't go! Don't leave me tied up here!
Why? Mom! Save me!
Be good, William. Don't cry.Someone will be here to save you soon.
- Don't cry. Be good.- Mom!
Don't leave me here. Mom!
I really, really wish I could forgive you.
But… but I can't.
I can't.
However...
I miss you so much.
Mom...
I miss you...
William. I'm sorry.
Mommy is sorry.
Brother...
Please don't cry.
The doctor said you've made a lot of improvement.What great news!
Even though the doctor has already reduced my dosage,
if I had to go back to work right now,
to be honest, I'm not sure I could do it.
But life is like that.
I think you used to push yourself too far.
Don't you think it's a good thing to relax a bitwhen you have this chance?
In fact, I'm quite happy,
because you have more time to be with me now.
I actually hope your vacation can go even longer.
Katy.
Thank you, for never giving up on me.
Without your being by my side andsupporting me unconditionally,
I don't know how I would have turned out.
This is just how love should be.
Besides… being able to stay next to you makes me feel... very happy.
Subtitles brought to you by The Royal Team @ Viki
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
Daddy.
Do you still see me as your dad?
I'm sorry, Daddy.
Would you please stop being mad?
General Manager Zhao.
What are you doing here?
This is my private place. Please get out.
Let me get straight to the point then.
I want to marry Katy.Please give us your blessing.
Where did you get your confidence from?
Wasn't it enough how you humiliated me in the board meeting?
You found a fishmonger to be my boss!Now? What are you trying to do?
You want me to let you marry my daughter?
Who do you think you are?
During the board meeting,
I was simply presenting my standpoint as a CEO.
I had no intention to show you disrespect.
Besides, when that fishmonger was the CEO,
everyone could see what a good job he did.
Liu Wen Bin also said,
about our company's affairs, big or small,
no one knows them better than you do.
Therefore, while he stands in as CEO,
he'll definitely consult your opinions.
As to Katy and I...
If you would let her marry me,will it still be necessary to say whom Yi Shan belongs to?
However, even if you oppose,
I will still marry her.
Is your face made of elephant skin?(meaning "very thick-skinned)
You really think you're a prince?
Can Katy only marry you?
Where did you get all that confidence from?
Daddy. William really loves me.
In my whole life, I'll only love him too.
Can't you just give us your blessing?
What are you talking about?
Daddy.
Dad.
Don't call me that!
You… watched me growing up since I was little.
As my father has passed away,
and Katy is your only child.
I really love her very much.
So… I will treat you as my own father.
You'll be the host of our wedding.
We will try to respect your
You're lucky that I haven't kicked you out of here.
What wedding?
I haven't agreed yet. What wedding?
Enough, Daddy.
You know William and I have been through a lot.
Now we're getting married.
Can't you just feel happy for me?
You silly girl. What's there to be happy about?
- Daddy…- Why are you talking about getting married?
Dad. I'd like to toast to you.
Don't call me that.
Daddy.
Are you going to let me walk into the wedding by myselfwithout anyone holding my hand?
If I have to walk down the aisle alone, I'll be so wretched.
My biggest dream is to have you,
the person who loves me the most,
hand me to the man I love.
Can't you grant me this wish?
Don't cry. You…I can't bear to see you cry.
Ok, ok...
Are you sure he is William Yi, not Liu Wen Bin?
Of course he is William.I won't make the same mistake again.
But you did make the mistake last time.
I know I did, but not anymore.
You'd better not mix it up again.
Auntie. How are you feeling? Are you tired?
Not at all. It has only been a short walk.
I am supposed to take walks often anyway.
Otherwise, being trapped in the house everyday
and not being allowed to do any work,
I'd feel like I'm going to get sick.
I understand. This is how a patient feels.
All day long you're being watched. You're not allowed to do this, and not allowed to do that.
Very annoying.
Actually, you really don't need to come and spend time with me.
I already told Ah Bin I can live alone. No problem.
If you have things to take care of, just go ahead.Don't worry about me.
Right now, I'm not busy at all.
The one who is busy working is Ah Bin.
I'm enjoying my life, and I feel very content.
Auntie, thank you.
Thank you for making Ah Bin agree to help me.
Stonehead. Ah Bin said
you were the one who told him to cancel the development plan.
Do you know? As soon as you halted the development,
the county government immediately stoppedthe expropriation plan.
I really want to thank you.
Thank you for letting the sea and the houses here
be preserved.
That project… shouldn't have been planned to begin with.
The coast of Mei Village really is very beautiful.
If a hotel resort is built, the coastwon't belong to everyone anymore.
Actually, we don't need to
keep things we like to ourselves.
Let things stay the way they are,don't spoil them,
and just simply admire them.That is the more correct attitude.
Stonehead, you really have changed.
That's all because of auntie.
That's strange. I didn't give you candies to eat.
How come you can say so many sweet words?
How about this? Tell me what you want for dinner.I'll cook for you.
No way. You can't get too tired.
I will cook for you instead.
Really. It's not that I like to praise you.
Your cooking skill is getting better and better.
Last time the stirred fried salted fish rice you made,
it tasted better than Ah Bin's.
Of course. My cooking skill was better thanAh Bin's from the start.
Ah Bin...What does he know?(In Taiwanese)
Showing off your Taiwanese now? Beautiful!
Stonehead, do you smell something?
I think I do smell something.
Help!
I burned my hair again!
What happened to you?
Sorry, Auntie. I burned another pot of yours again.
But that's ok. I have a lot of pots at my house.
I will definitely buy you a new one.
That's ok. Don't worry about the burned pot.
But did your hands get burned?
No. I'm ok.
Are you alright?
I'm alright, but the kitchen is not.
Didn't I tell you that you don't need to cook?
Luckily you only burned a pot.
If you burn down this old house, I can't afford to repay.
I just wanted to help.
Mom!
Mom.
How come you're home already?
We took an airplane.So we got here in no time.
How are you, Auntie?
Very good, very good.
Right now I feel very happy, with two sons here,
and two daughters-in-law!
- Katy, are you cooking?- Mhm.
But... I made a mess.
Let me help you.
Great!
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
Right now I feel very happy!
I have two sons here, and two daughters-in-law!
- Katy, are you cooking?- Mhm.
But... I made a mess.
Let me help you.
Great!
I'll take care of this.
Ok. You take care of it.
Auntie. Be careful.
Ok!
William Yi. My mom looks very well.
It looks like you do know how to take good care of her.
Of course. I use the discipline of managing a company totake care of your mom.
I carefully select every thing she eats.
I also cook the food attentively,making sure it's healthy and nutritious.
Really?
Bro. When are you going back to work?
You're having such a great time taking a vacation here,
but I have to read documents everyday,which almost drives me nuts.
Actually... I like staying at Mei Village very much.
What did you say?
Son! Go and bring me the biggest fish.
- I'll be right there!- Ok!
You've only stayed here a few days,
and you already think you are my mom's sonjust because you look like me?
Please remember who you are.
You haven't touched any fish for such a long time, how would you know what kind of fish your mom wants?
Give me a break.Who am I?
I am Liu Wen Bin.
I am the best fish expert in Mei Village. Ok?
That's hard to say.(in Taiwanese)
That's right. I know you don't know how to speak Taiwanese.
You can just speak Mandarin with me.
I don't want to.(in Taiwanese)
Whatever.
Where are you taking me exactly?
Your mom was going to teach me how to cook.
Isn't the sea at Mei Village very beautiful?
You can never get tired of looking at it.
I know.
Actually, this place has beautiful mountains, ocean, and fresh air.
Anyone who lives here probably can stay very healthy. Right?
By the way! Next month a new CEO will be elected.
I probably can come back here to sell fish then.
My life probably will be just like the way it used to be.
That's really great.
You... What exactly are you trying to say to me?
Can it be... you're going to break up with me,
and telling me "going back tothe way things were", that sort of things?
No... no... That's not it.
It's... Eh...
I... I want to know if what you saidin front of the office building was true.
What did I say?
You... you said you were ready to move to Mei Village.
That...?
But... am I not living here right now?
That's true.But...
Whenever I go back to Taipei, you also come with me.
When I come live at Mei Village, you do too.
This feel more like... traveling.
Therefore... you don't like it?
No... That's not what I mean.
Then what do you mean?You're making me very nervous.
I'm very nervous too.
What?
Take this.
What is this?
Hold it.
Where are you going? Hey!
Hold onto it!
Yi Xin. Will you marry me?
What did you say?
I'll speak louder!
Yi Xin. Will you marry me?
Speak louder! I can't hear you!
Yi Xin!
I love you! Let's get married!
♫ "Prince" is what they calla young man of my generation. ♫
♫ Love is my DNA. ♫
♫ As long as my heart is beating like a drum,I'll be able to fly high. ♫
♫ I want to go experience what the world has to offerSay that's okay! ♫
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ I welcome you, welcome you to experience it. ♫
♫ The earth is spinning, carrying hundreds of millions of dreams. ♫
♫ Inadvertently it might shake,and some people might trip and fall. ♫
♫ Use graceful and confident smilesto treat failures as a gift. ♫
♫ Then my heart will never be unhappy. Yeah~~~ ♫
♫ "Prince" is what they calla young man of my generation. ♫
♫ I won't pick up a glass sandal. ♫
♫ As long as my heart is beating like a drum,I'll be able to fly high. ♫
♫ I want to go experience what the world has to offerSay that's okay! ♫
♫ I want to build a whole new different world. ♫
♫ This will be yours and my fortress. ♫
Segment for Final Credits
"Shadow-like Man" by Antonio Huang
♫ At the intersection, there's someone who resembles me. ♫
♫ With a similar face and a fair outfit, ♫
♫ he lives an earnest life. ♫
♫ I emptied my soul and went into exile. ♫
♫ Who has confiscated my happiness? ♫
♫ I traded myself infor a moment of disguise. ♫
♫ Is this really what I wanted? ♫
♫ I'm afraid to become a shadow-like manwho chases aimlessly; ♫
♫ chasing after a counterfeit happinessthat doesn't belong to me. ♫
♫ The more committed I've been,the more indifferent I've become. ♫
♫ If flowers and grass could all grow into ♫
♫ towering trees that people look up to, ♫
♫ then who would see the butterflies dancing around? ♫
♫ I don't want to be a shadow-like manwho loses traction and loses his way, ♫
♫ getting lost in thecoldest valley without sunshine. ♫
♫ The more I want to escape,the more winding roads I have to take. ♫
♫ Layers and layers of foghave trapped my dreams thoroughly, ♫
♫ not giving me the road map home. ♫
♫ I've finally realized thatthe ability to be my true self ♫
♫ is the most precious gift of all. ♫