Welcome.
We, the sponsors, would like
to thank you, the audience,
for everything you've done for us so far.
Most of you have been
unwitting participants
in our greatest illusions.
So, at the end of our show,
we're going to reveal
how they have been orchestrated.
But first, it is necessary to learn
the methods we use every day
to captivate, misdirect,
distract and control.
All of our methods rely on you...
...and your natural attraction
to this one simple thing.
Who is this? I don't know.
Who are these people?
Who are these people, bro?
Who is this?
From now on we don't know each other.
I won't talk to you like I know you.
Mum's the word.
And I don't know any of you, OK?
This is Chris everyone and this is Felicity,
and these are our celebrities.
Give us a couple of minutes,
we'll go down to the street
and we'll ambush you there.
OK, you'll ambush us on the street?
Well, there's going to be a nice
staircase that you'll descend
and we'll get you at some point.
# THE SERENDIPITY SINGERS:
Everybody Loves Saturday Night.
You too can enjoy
the celeb-for-a-day experience
for only $300 per hour.
Now, you may be thinking
that you would not be bewitched
by the spell of celebrity,
but it is worth noting
that all of these people
would probably say the same thing.
Hey, paparazzi, ready to go!
So we're having a hard time. Can you
keep them out, get them arrested?
Have you guys got a back exit or something?
Thank you so much.
You saved our lives, thank you, thank you.
If you guys are here again,
call me in the office.
Everybody is naturally
and powerfully attracted to fame
even though most people will deny it.
This principle has allowed us access
into every part of your world
and is now the foundation
of our entire business.
These are the five lessons
that need to be learned
to be able to use fame
as a means of control.
In different ways,
they all take advantage of
your basic needs and desires.
It is only through
a combination of these lessons
that one can master
the greatest illusion of them all,
an illusion so great it has given us a seat
at the tables of power throughout the world
and unlimited influence
in raising the next generation.
Our first lesson is all about motivation,
as our business depends on everybody
believing that they can succeed.
We like this message
to be absorbed as young as possible,
because kids that follow the dream
will always be our best customers.
So, from the day they are born,
we convince kids that the key to happiness
lies in the entertainment industry.
(TV) 'It's all about the personality.
JT and Jessica
put the break-up rumours to rest.
This is E-News.
When Ri-Yan came up and said,
you know, "I want to model."
"Can you find me some place
where I can model?"
What, when he was three years old?
Hello, everybody, my name is Alex Simon.
I am the owner and founder of Kids Talent
Network, based in Las Vegas, Nevada.
We have - nationwide -
over 1,900 clients now.
People just contact us
and actually about 200 new faces
a day we see here.
Can you say hi, can you say hi?
How was it in there?
A lot of what we do
is we actually scout children
around the country for agencies.
I come looking for the kid
with the special "it"
that I can really work with
and get 'em to Hollywood.
So I've got to make it bigger
and better for my resume.
Why do you want it to be bigger and better?
Because... Oh, Jeez, that's a hard one.
To be a superstar?
Yeah, and a Grammy Award and...
I don't know.
An Oscar?
What the heck is that?
It's a big statue. (LAUGHS)
No matter where we go, it's just attention.
He causes a commotion.
Can he take some pictures
with you guys on the other side?
The other side of the street, yeah!
One, two, three... cheeseburgers.
They're doing a documentary on my son.
Do you want me to carry you?
No, you're good? OK.
Are you cold? OK, here you go. He's cold.
The next step in Ri-Yan's career
is breaking into
the Los Angeles and the Hollywood market.
Look at you! Superstar!
Oh, my God,
he comes with his own little crew!
This particular agent is, if not the best,
one of the top agents in Los Angeles.
Ri-Yan's just very advanced,
personally and professionally,
for his age, which makes him
very attractive for agents,
casting directors,
and for work on film and TV.
The kid barely reads at the age of five,
so it's more challenging.
So I overslept.
I just...
I just... No, no, no, no, no, no.
So I overslept, and what's the first
thing you want when you wake up?
I want my Kellogg's Corn Pops.
OK, let me start again.
OK, all right.
So I overslept,
I want my Kellogg's Corn Pops,
I just had to...
I just got to have my Corn Pops.
I just got to have my Pops. OK?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. OK, all right, again.
All right, you can do it.
So you overslept, you want your Corn Pops,
and you just got to have your Pops,
OK, all right.
So I overslept. I...
I want my Kellogg's Corn Pops.
I just nee... I just got...
We know smoking's bad for us, we know
fast food's bad for us, alcohol...
violence on television,
there's all this stuff about
how many killings kids will see on TV,
yet there's nothing about this.
I teamed up with Syracuse University
and we did a survey of about 750
American teenagers, and one of
the questions in the survey was.
If you could press a magic button
that would make you
either stronger, smarter,
more famous or beautiful,
which would you pick?
And we found that boys opted for fame
almost as often as intelligence,
and girls actually picked fame
more often than intelligence.
Children now spend twice as much
time in front of a screen
as they do in school,
and 1.5 times more time
in front of a screen
than with their parents,
which is quite phenomenal.
We found if you compared kids that watched
one hour of television a day
versus kids that watched
five hours of television a day,
they were twice as likely
to pick the fame button.
If you don't have anything
and you're constantly
being bombarded with images
of people who do have stuff,
that can make it quite tough.
In poverty, fame is just...
It's the cure-all.
It's the ultimate panacea.
Narcissism, what this means is,
people feeling they're
the centre of the universe.
But the characteristics of narcissism
seem to be rising within the population.
There was personality study
in the United States.
Well, back in the early '50s,
only 12% of teenagers said,
"Yes, I'm an important person."
By 1989, that number had risen to 80%.
I think there's no doubt that
the media are the main ways
that this is communicated to young people.
By turning our young audience into
narcissists, we encourage the belief
that they will one day get on television.
So we created reality television
to feed this aspiration.
Every day we go out into the public,
looking for new talent for these shows
and this is how it's done.
Set up a pitch in your local shopping mall
right next to the biggest candy stall.
So you wanted to have a go,
trying out for being on TV today?
Hire some attractive researchers
who are fluent
in impressive-sounding TV jargon.
Auditions for children's TV, yeah.
They're dealing a lot with social issues
that are affecting children at the moment.
Just enjoy it, relax.
It's just fun.
This is just about the release forms.
Get everybody to sign a consent form,
signing away the right to use
their child's image in any context
on all media, throughout the known
universe, until the end of time.
They say a couple of pieces to camera,
you sign a form to give consent
and if the producers like them,
they get to go on television.
Oh, wow!
We want to take young children
into abattoirs
and teach them what happens to meat
before it ends up on supermarket shelves.
Come into our studio!
Erect a sophisticated tent
with the latest technical wizardry
to shoot the screen tests.
There we go.
All right.
My name's Paris and I work
in the slaughterhouse.
There's going to be blood
at the slaughterhouse.
I feel like chicken tonight.
We're looking at the effects of
alcohol on younger children.
Do you want to go for the drinking one,
a bit of baby boozing? Brilliant.
Use charm and persuasion
to get the best performance
out of the young talent.
That's actually the name of the show.
And also, if you can just
act a little bit drunk,
just a bit kind of...
slurring, slurring your words,
that sort of thing.
That would be quite good.
My name is Jagon. I'm a baby boozer.
Don't worry, I'm not driving.
And no matter how far we go,
we can always blame the parents.
Amy, listen, all you've got to do
is look at the camera, say your name
and say, "The next round's on me."
That's it. OK? Go on then.
I want more!
You can have some sweets afterwards,
darling. Say, "Cheers."
Sweets are afterwards, darling.
Is she doing all right?
Well, we thought we'd just get her
to try and decapitate a chicken.
Cut the chicken's head off.
Like this...
...and go bang.
How would you feel
if your child was successful?
Er, pretty good actually cos
it means it'll give them a chance
to see something they don't normally see.
It's a parent's best dream, isn't it?
Like, having your kids sort of
being on TV. Yeah, it'd be good.
Take care, we'll be in touch. Thank you.
We can't help but be affected
by this kind of all-pervasive sense
of celebrity success.
It's absolutely... Not...
I was going to say surrounding us,
it actually invades us as well.
It becomes part of
the way we understand the world,
the lens through which
we look at the world.
The child could be in the jungle
and think that this is wonderful,
but the child won't know about
the dangers that are lurking.
And sooner or later that child,
just as surely as they would fall
foul of predators in the jungle,
will fall foul of predators
in the world of media.
We run a global business
but our British and American
affiliates have the best product,
as well as the most loyal customers.
Everybody has bought into
the dream we've created
and there is now an insatiable
demand for TV shows involving kids.
We are now making these shows
faster than anyone can watch them.
All in the name of factual entertainment.
I just feel really, really scared.
Please leave me alone! I hate you!
Fear no doubts.
I don't want to be here anymore.
They've stuck me in prison
because I fell in love with somebody.
I just love this girl so much, I really do.
My brother is, like,
doing a very big thing for Cyprus.
It made me cry.
Like any craving, the more we
supply, the greater the demand.
The key is making it seem
genuinely attainable.
Our second lesson is all about addiction,
which, fortunately for us,
is for life, not just for childhood.
This is how we can keep someone
trying to succeed,
even when they're likely to fail.
And, as failure is so abundant,
it's easy to find new ways
to make money out of it.
OK, welcome, everybody.
Give yourself a hand for being here today.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Good.
This is the New York Reality TV School.
You might be sitting next to,
you probably are, sitting next to
one of the next big stars.
I've been coaching actors,
directing theatre,
directing internet television
and live events for years.
Actors don't have money and need
training and there's this new genre,
called reality, where you don't
have to be an actor.
You have money, a job, cos you're
a real person. And you need training.
I'm going to introduce the wonderful
producer/casting director.
Risa Tanania.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
If I were to say, "Why should you be here?"
and you say you're interesting,
that is such a turn off.
If I were to say, "Why do you want
to be on reality TV?"
and your answer is, "Because
I want to piss my parents off."
That's fantastic.
Do practise your story. Do watch reality.
Watch reality TV.
How dare you not watch reality TV
and want to be a part of that culture?
It has changed the way we live, the way we look
at the world, the way we look at each other.
Huge amounts of children watch.
Yes.
And do you think that that's a good thing?
Do you think that 6, 7, 8 year-old
kids watching Celebrity Rehab
and 'I Want To Be A Pussy Cat Doll'
is good?
I'm not. I'm not, no.
That's a ridiculous question, I'm sorry.
Those children - 6, 7 and 8 -
they have parents.
Those parents need to be aware of what their
children are watching. That's not...
But they're not though,
I mean, everyone knows.
Did you ever sneak off
and watch television you weren't
supposed to watch as a child?
No, well, I actually was, like,
raised by a television.
I was raised by a television.
Here is the veteran.
Here he is - Robert Russell!
APPLAUSE
In here today, one in particular
that has actually auditioned for me
for Big Brother many, many times.
If you're not going to get on
once, you won't a second time.
People are obsessed.
Especially their specific show
that they want to be on.
When they want to be on it,
they will continually come
and continually try to make it happen.
And is that healthy?
No.
But who cares? We're making money.
Sign that.
No matter how often our customers
gamble with their future,
the house is always going to win.
Our profit depends on them constantly
returning to try their luck.
Even though the odds
are stacked against them.
So, I overslept.
I want my Kellogg's Corn Pops.
I just got to have my pops.
All right buddy, that was great.
All right, let's go do it.
10 minutes of practice that could mean the
beginning of a great career in acting
or it could be the end of it.
From what I heard, it went great.
The agent loved Ri-Yan,
has big plans for him.
It was, all in all, just tremendous.
So Ri-Yan, tell us how was the interview?
It was pretty good and...
I liked it and I'm going to sign
with it... sign with the agent.
They're ready to put him to work immediately
so we're really excited about that.
Instead of going "hmmm",
I want more "aarrgghhh".
Arrgh!
Good.
Arrrgh!
Arggh!
That was one of the best.
Usually, at this age...
I don't even shoot them.
Really?
Really.
Why, why? Do they just not
respond to you or...?
They're a pain in the ass!
I used to shoot a lot of kids
and I stopped doing it
because it was so much work, you know?
See, I like that attitude
more than I do that.
I think he's got great listening skills.
That's what makes him very unique.
That's the most important thing.
Most people don't.
I don't have great listening skills.
I have horrible listening skills. I don't
listen to anybody. Fuck them, listen to me!
Go back a little further and you
got to turn sideways even more.
Do you think that he's got what it
takes to make it to the big time?
Oh, without a doubt.
As long as he can take direction,
cos it's all illusion anyway.
Like you're looking down a gun.
Yo!
Yeah, I like that..
We don't have money, I work everyday.
My wife works here, you know.
We beg and borrow. We trade.
Like with Carlo, we trade.
With Carlo, he charges
$5000 for a photo shoot.
He gave us all the pictures, all the rights
and he said just pay
me whatever, whenever you can.
The little bit of struggle we have right now is
going to be a distant memory so we're really...
And Ri-Yan too, he talks
about it the same way.
On the way home the other day
and he said, "You know what, Mom?"
I'm going to buy you a really
big house when I make it big,
but I'm going to but it, not Dad.
I was like, "OK".
You know, of course they would
like him to be huge,
but I think they're realising now
that we've got signed in Los Angeles
and they started auditioning, it's a taller
task than they imagined it would be.
Now remember, they're driving
8-10 hours for a 30-second audition
and driving all the way back.
You know, the first time you do it,
it's OK, the second time...
but try 15, 20 times, 30 times.
And you're spending gas money,
taking a day off work.
A lot of people just say
"We can't afford it,"
or "We don't like it," or "We don't think
anything is ever going to happen."
So that's the stage
they're getting into now.
(RI-YAN'S MUM) So what did we do today?
I did a Coke audition in California.
So how you think you did?
Good.
You think so?
Yeah.
So, what are we going to do now?
Er... we're driving back.
You ready for school tomorrow?
Yeah, boring as all.
Did you do any homework?
No.
Whoopsee!
Yeah.
Got to do some homework, right?
Yeah, before anything.
OK, say bye.
Over-optimism is a great human trait.
In most areas in life, looking for
the positive side gets us through.
In very simple layman's terms,
I think the easiest way to say
what's the difference between
a healthy excess of enthusiasm
and an addiction is that
healthy enthusiasms add to life
and addictions take away from it.
I can see, theoretically, how people can be totally
hooked on the idea of wanting to be famous.
The younger you are, the more susceptible you
are to most types of addictive behaviour.
The earlier that you start smoking,
having sex, drinking, gambling,
you're more likely to have problems
with those behaviours later in life.
The fruit machine is ideally designed to give
lots of what we call near-win experiences,
so, psychologically, a gambler
does not constantly lose,
a gambler constantly nearly wins.
We aim to give you a near-win
experience as often as possible.
We carefully select stories
of ordinary people
who have hit the jackpot
and we give them blanket coverage,
reinforcing the belief
that it could happen to you.
Wesley Autrey.
A 50-year-old American construction
worker is being hailed a hero.
What's up?
What's happening?
I pretty much know everybody here.
How you doing?
Wesley Autrey saved a stranger
who'd fallen off a subway platform
by throwing himself on top,
pinning him down and protecting him
from a passing train.
So, they come in at about
50, 60 miles-an-hour.
So, when you were approached by the media,
did you say yes to every interview?
Well, I let my sister who was my
PR... More or less yes, yes, we did.
That's the day it happened, January 2nd.
And then you met the mayor.
The Mayor.
Donald Trump.
This is a brave man.
David Letterman.
That was a big day.
That was the night I was invited
to the State Of The Union.
There is something wonderful about
a country that produces a brave
and humble man, like Wesley Autrey.
This day was a very crazy day
because Deal Or No Deal
wanted me on that day
and Oprah wanted me on that day.
That applause is almost better than what I got
at the State Of The Union. Thank you, guys.
And then Time Magazine.
I was number 48 out of the most
influential people in the world.
In the world?
In '07.
Chrysler gave me that free jeep out there.
Chrysler gave you a jeep?
Chrysler gave me a jeep
behind me saving Cameron.
I would like to do a commercial for them
to let the world know that is a great jeep.
I mean, not only is it economising,
good on gas, it's an excellent jeep.
Und Heute Abend ist er bei uns zu Gast,
der U-bahn Engel von New York, Wesley Autrey.
Suddenly... You're on every TV channel.
I'm on every TV channel.
My name is like a household name
like Cornflakes.
So I'm telling him "don't move".
APPLAUSE
Is it true you've done
over 2,000 interviews?
Don't you ever get sick of it?
No.
So it's increasing your brand worldwide?
Exactly, exactly.
Thank you, baby.
If you stood for office in this ward,
in this council...
you would get a landslide, wouldn't you?
Yeah, that's what people tell me. They say,
Yo, you have so many people loving you
and you have some great qualities,
why don't you run for president,
for mayor, for governor?
Do you think you've changed by...
Has it changed you?
No, no, no.
Cos people said, "Don't let that change you,
don't let that money change you."
No, I don't think I've changed,
I think it's the people around me
that have changed
because I got friends
who think I should give them,
I've got friends, like I said,
who think I'm already a millionaire
and that I'm nowhere near yet.
The kind of work that I've been doing,
I would actually say that people
who have become famous,
that, in and of itself, can be
a potentially addictive activity.
When they do achieve something,
they get intense mood-modificating effects.
They really do feel buzzed up and high
when they've been on television, on radio
or they see their name in print.
They're living on this oxygen of publicity.
Who hasn't, among us,
had the sort of delicious experience
of being at a cocktail party,
telling a good story,
having everyone hanging on
our word and then laughing.
There's not a lot better in life than that.
If you could bottle that, you couldn't keep
it on the shelves. That's potent stuff.
Performing itself can produce a high
and it's doing that through all the
same chemistry that cocaine works.
Most addictions are about what we call the deficit
of a particular neurotransmitter called dopamine.
It's going to affect the catecholamines.
There's plasma changes that sort of
alters our chemistry a little bit
and that really sets us up
to need more of it, really.
The do-it-again part of our brain
is sort of activated.
There's more firing going off.
And of course those euphoric chemicals like
endorphins are firing off in other areas.
We create celebrities
by selecting the right candidates
and relentlessly boosting their profile.
This gets them hooked
on positive attention.
And to keep you hooked on them,
we sometimes need to change
the type of attention we give them.
When the terrorists tried to
attack Scotland's biggest airport,
they were answered by
the courage of the police
and of the fire fighters and a
baggage handler named John Smeaton.
Local hero - the airport baggage handler
who ignored the dangers
to tackle a suspected terrorist.
We're under attack here.
The British people have been under
a lot worse things than this,
and we always stand proud.
This is Glasgow, you know, so,
we'll set about you.
A year ago, an unknown baggage
handler at Glasgow Airport,
today, receiving a medal
from Her Majesty the Queen.
Fight on for freedom.
Fight on for Scotland!
What we didn't headline
when the story broke
was that there were three other
less photogenic citizens
who also bravely fought the terrorists.
Nearly a year later, having received
hardly any media attention,
they turned on Smeaton.
And this time, we were
only too happy to help.
And I'm like that.
Woah, stuck the heid back, foot oot.
It's almost instinctive...
Totally, you know, and it's like...
so you're saying I didnae do that, mate?
You know that, to me, is libel.
You know, to me that's libel but...
I'm a big man, I can take it,
I don't need to go and cry to newspapers
and take it to the courts and...
But when it's personal criticism,
something that's...
you know, it's overstepping the mark.
You know, that's when it hurts
and that's when you begin to say...
Bastards. Do you know what I mean?
But that's the nature of the beast.
That is the nature of the media.
There's no such thing as bad publicity.
Do you believe that?
Aye.
You do?
Oh, aye, you know?
So, you'd rather have it with
all the nastiness than not have it?
Aye.
Is it the case that we are
putting a unique kind of person
up in celebrity status,
and if that's true, why?
What is it about us that we care
about these people? Why do we care?
These are sick people.
Why are we focused on them?
Our entire global business is based on
understanding the answer to these questions.
In the previous lesson
you saw how a lucky few
can get trapped inside the spotlight.
Our third lesson is about your
irresistible attraction to them
and how we manipulate this for profit.
Evolution can sometimes produce
hard-wired behaviour
that generations later causes you problems,
like moths flying into a light.
Long ago, moths that instinctively
flew towards the moon
were better at navigating
and this urge got handed down.
Now, technology has changed
their surroundings
and this instinct is more of a hindrance.
Darwinists believe that humans
also developed powerful urges
that kept them alive in times gone by.
Our brains are hard-wired
to make us social.
Very few people
can really tolerate social isolation
for any length of time.
There is a theory that in the past,
there were two types of human.
Those who naturally wanted to form groups,
and those who wanted to be alone.
The team players were able to share tasks
and so were able to survive
when times got tough,
unlike the loners.
So the survivors passed on the urge
to be part of a group,
that modern man has inherited.
Some early humans
instinctively copied the successful,
while others tried to learn alone.
Well, it's not difficult to see
why those who copied the leader
would stay ahead of the competition.
TRUMPETING
This is your inheritance,
making you naturally copy
whoever appears to be
the leader of your gang.
What if there was also an urge
to get as close as possible
to whoever you're told
is the most successful?
This would have been good for women,
who would have got to mate with the top dog.
And those men closest to the alpha male
would have got to share his women,
as well as any leftover food.
Anyone who naturally
didn't want to join an entourage
wasn't going to much reproducing.
So it is possible that you have evolved
with an instinct to form groups,
copy whoever appears to be successful,
and to congregate around them.
But then technology advanced
so quickly that it became possible
to convince the mind
that a moving image is real.
As soon as the trick was used
to entertain an audience,
our industry was born.
By entertaining the world,
we were able to grow into powerful
and influential corporations.
Now our reach is unparalleled
and we deliver media to you
and your children,
in ways that you cannot control.
When we surround you with famous faces,
your survival instincts kick in
and you feel the urge
to get up close and copy them.
This has created a new social hierarchy,
based around your proximity
to anyone well-known.
No, this is... this is... Oh, right.
It feels miles away doesn't it?
Yeah. I know.
We like to keep our distance.
Yeah, absolutely.
We don't know too much about you!
It's a bespoke private celebrity PA agency.
What, attracted you to the advert?
Why did you look at the ad and think,
"That's something I want to do"?
Well, it's clearly simple,
it says "celebrity PA",
and they were looking for someone
in the industry
who already understands
what that word means.
Celebrity PA?
Flexibility and motivation.
They're buying an assistant,
in a way, like a pet.
And they can kick the pet?
Well, unfortunately...
They shouldn't do that, but...
Pets get kicked.
I'd been working as an actor
for about a year, since leaving uni.
I actually brought
a CV with me, just, uh...
just for general interest, really.
Yep, good.
Slide it across there.
I thought it would be far more
interesting to work in the industry.
Let's say you're working for a...
very high profile celebrity whose
wife is, you know, getting on a bit,
and he's having a series of affairs.
What if one of the girls was 16?
That's not really a problem...
15?
To be honest, if a 15-year-old girl wants
to do that, she's going to do it anyway.
Good on her if she gets to do it
with a celebrity.
You're quite young, got a social life.
Would you be happy to give all that up?
Yeah.
Not see your friends or family?
Yeah, that'd be fine.
They need five grams of coke.
That's fine.
If you drove,
would you break the speed limit?
No.
You wouldn't break the speed limit?
I'd try not to.
The rules are always to break them,
that's what the rule's for.
You always have to break them!
But I never drive, anyway, on the limit.
What if they wanted to pay for sex
and said, "Find me a prostitute"?
I would do that. I did that.
I did that. I had to do that as well...
Basically, this is your job, this is...
Even if things were illegal or...?
Even. You just have to do it.
You are the gatekeeper
to the celebrity's life.
They have crazy people after them.
Wow.
Like stalkers, psychos, nut nuts,
crack bags, the whole thing.
I mean, would you...?
Would that worry you?
No. I know it sounds
really weird, but, um...
Do you ever get this feeling where you
just want a bit of adventure in your life?
Yeah, yeah.
A bit like a movie.
This all sounds fantastic to me.
But you might end up taking a bullet for them.
Does that worry you?
Surprisingly, no.
Stupid thing to say,
I wouldn't mind taking a bullet
for someone I don't know, but...
That's the sort of adventure
and adrenaline I need in my life.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
Thank you, cheers.
Again there's some interesting research
on this, they call the phenomenon
"basking in reflected glory".
In this study, students,
several hundred of them,
read a short biography of Rasputin,
you know, the villain of Russian history.
For half of them, they customise the test
so Rasputin had the same birthday
as you did, without you knowing,
My birthday's July 28th,
so I'm reading it and Rasputin
was born July 28th whenever.
The people that had the same birthday
as Rasputin were, across the board,
more likely to say Rasputin
was a misunderstood man in history.
He was notorious but he was great
and he played an important role
and that shouldn't be forgotten.
And this is just because
they share a birthday.
The power of association with someone
who's famous, or even infamous,
is far more potent than we even realise.
Are you just taking one pair of shoes?
Just these, or you want to
take some other...?
Whatever's going to fit with that outfit.
See, I wash all his shoes, man.
Some of them are two years old,
they look brand new
because every night I clean them.
That's the military in me.
And sometimes we argue
about what we're wearing!
(MAN) But who's the commander
of the outfit?
He likes to say that it's him.
But it's always my wife.
I'll kind of draw from other celebrities.
I was trying to do something
LL Cool J-style,
like, with a tracksuit and track pants.
It's Chet Buchanan The Morning Zoo.
Give it to me.
On 98.5 KLUC.
Spence, while you're up,
would you please let in our guest?
Yes sir.
(MAN) So he's got his own
little slot on a radio show?
Yeah, he's doing the NFL season
and it's on the biggest
radio station in Vegas.
Where did the other mic go?
That's cos it's down near the floor,
where the little fella is!
No, it's not.
What's up, buddy?
Hey.
Ri-yan didn't have school today,
so he came in.
If you want to make money,
are you taking Cincinnati
or the Dallas Cowboys?
Dallas Cowboys!
Take it all to the bank and come back and
see us on Monday, that's what I'm saying.
I don't know as he gets older,
he'll say, this is a big deal,
I'm on the radio and I'm talking to
hundreds of thousands of people, you know.
They are listening to me.
What if he just doesn't understand
how important it is.
So far it hasn't fazed him.
You got slaughtered last weekend!
Yes, I did.
We keep throwing him in
more and more of these situations.
Right now, we try everything.
It was nice to see you, Ri-yan.
Nice meeting you, Ri-yan.
Great meeting you.
He'll be DJ-ing throughout the day.
APPLAUSE
I'm running the bookie.
The bookie!
(CROWD) Woah!
I don't want no problems!
Why do they call you the bookie?
Because I've been collecting money
and I've been breaking some heads.
Breaking some heads!
I'm going to buy a car here.
That's another show, it's an
info-commercial, but it's run, like,
ten times a weekend
on different channels in town,
so his exposure, people see him.
Let's make some noise for my boy, Ri-yan!
CHEERING
He also does like promos at different bars.
People have football parties,
he has his own booth
and he has his own fan base.
You've got your own fan base?
You've got your own fan base? Yeah.
Ye-e-ah!
(WOMAN) Ri-yan just made parole.
As his, you know, success progresses
we're going to have to be more
aware, more, way more aware
of who we speak to about him.
We still do what we got to do, you know.
They can't stop us.
Yeah.
We can't be, you know, afraid...
We'll be stuck in the house all the time.
We don't live our life that way.
No matter how many celebrities we create,
it's never going to be possible
for everybody to join an entourage.
But there are other ways
we can exploit your need
to be close to the famous,
all from the comfort
of your own living room.
Television probably played
the biggest part here,
because with television,
there's an illusion of intimacy
and that visual image, now quite realistic,
can be right in one's home,
giving us the illusion that
we actually know these people.
There is no way evolution could have
anticipated the internet!
And therefore, we are stuck
with a kind of brain machinery
which was designed to handle
face-to-face interactions.
It was not designed
to handle virtual interactions.
It is a brave new world
from that point of view
and that does mean
it's easily exploited by people
who can figure out how to use
that medium to their advantage.
A para-social relationship
is one of those awful technical terms
which sounds more fancy than it is.
It simply means that you have
a relationship with somebody
which is not based upon
a face-to-face relationship,
it's based upon what you know
about that person through the press,
what you know about that person
through watching him or her on TV
despite the fact that you
never actually meet the celebrity.
I say to my students that
the only example that I know of
where people have this
deep emotional attachment
to someone they've never met
is the attachment
that some people have to God.
But the para-social relationship
is created by the media,
fuelled by the media.
And we all do it?
We all do it, yes.
CROWD CHANTS
The more celebrities we create,
the more we can capitalise on these bonds.
And the younger
these relationships are formed,
the stronger they're going to be.
Her whole bedroom has posters of Zac Efron!
Zac Efron!
CROWD SCREAMS
I think there's some things
that celebrities do
that play right into this trick of the box.
Pretending it's a two-way relationship,
I think, enhances this.
Yeah, I feel like
there's a connection there.
Yeah. And he loves me!
There is this terrifying prospect I have
that it is actually replacing what
we used to call real life,
that people are developing stronger
imaginary relationships
with people who are themselves
imaginary constructions,
people who are not real.
And our purpose in encouraging you
to make one-way friendships?
It's simple - to make you buy stuff.
Your urge to copy the famous
influences your spending,
whether you like it or not.
See how easy it is to keep a man happy?
Why not give your husband
a carton of Philip Morris cigarettes.
Delivers flavour, 20 times a pack.
When it's tougher than ever
to be a tiger...
Success is down to finding
people like this...
Now for the good bit...
if you have a debt problem...
...and a prudent approach to banking...
...you could borrow anything...
...three and a half times your salary...
A million pounds...
...as long as you keep paying
the premium...
Is that too much to ask?
It's going to cost a pigging
fortune, this lot!
Don't treat me like an idiot...
Do you have advice for young people
who drive?
Take it easy driving. The life
you might save might be mine.
Celebrity endorsement works
on an emotional level.
We process emotions and we process rational
thought in different parts of the brain.
So the limbic system, which is the
very old part of the brain that says,
"Lion on the savannah, ..."
"Lion on the savannah, ..." LION ROARS
"..run away!"
That's where we process things on
an emotional, almost gut-feel level.
Imagine a horse and a rider.
That piece of the brain is like
the horse, just working away.
And that's where we make decisions
and do maths and use spreadsheets.
We try to control the more
instinctive parts of our brains,
that's like the rider. But sometimes
the rider loses control of the horse.
It's been shown in experiments.
If you ask people, "Would you like
fruit salad or chocolate cake?"
People will go, "I should take the fruit salad,
because that's the sensible thing to do."
So they'll take the fruit salad.
But if you give them a really difficult task to
do beforehand, so they're mentally exhausted,
they'll go for the chocolate cake,
because that's their instinct.
And that's how it seems to be with a lot of
emotional advertising that's not well-labelled.
We just process it instinctively.
These forms of advertising
are most effective
when you're not even aware
that you're being sold to.
This is Hannah Montana.
It's time to wake up!
Seriously, it is!
You know what else is serious?
Back to school shopping!
So gather your list of school supplies.
And don't forget Walmart has Hannah Montana
gear, the fashion and the music you love.
Be a superstar yourself and get
your things together. And have fun!
Good luck this year at school.
Children up to the age
of eight, nine and ten
don't really understand the persuasive
intent of advertisements.
There are people in there
trying to sell you something.
I've no doubt our society would be much better
if there was a total ban on advertising
for any child under 12, and really
limiting advertising towards teenagers.
It's possible that there is a link
between increasing materialism
and the mental health problems that an
increasing number of our children show.
In the last ten years,
something has shifted.
The number of young people
now that say a good life
is about money, fame, appearance,
has shot up dramatically.
That's what our young people
believe, and why wouldn't they?
Because that's the value system that
they're picking up from the media.
The media do not want to hear this message.
It is not in their interest
for people to be saying
that part of the problem with well-being, or
confidence or whatever, might be the media.
And that one of the best
and easiest ways for people
to actually look after their mental health
is to cut down on media consumption.
They don't like it.
As we set the public agenda,
we'll avoid giving exposure
to anything that will discourage
you wanting more of our product.
By attaching a product
to a familiar and likeable face,
we've developed an unstoppable means
of making you spend
what you don't have
on things you don't need.
Most people will say that
these tricks don't affect them,
but that makes the tricks even more potent.
How can you fight something
if you don't believe it exists?
So strong are these bonds
that every piece of information
about our celebrities is valuable to you.
When we insert famous faces
into your eyeline,
you're guaranteed to stop and look.
The need to gather social information
about the people we perceive
as influential and powerful
is something that is embedded
deep within us.
There are some studies that have been done
at Duke University on Rhesus monkeys.
They can do one of two things. They
have a device hooked up to the eyes,
so people can see which way
the monkey's looking at.
And if they look at one screen,
they get a squirt of juicy juice
which is, you know, payment, reward.
Or they can look at another screen
and see a series of pictures.