Accessing archive data...
The Renegade continues
to inspire the public...
Standing up to Tesler
showed those programs
that they don't have
to sit idly by.
They can choose to fight.
...while Beck meets someone else
who knows that Tron is alive.
You're not the first program
Tron trained to fight back.
I am.
Surprise.
I'm the first Renegade.
1x14 - Tagged
Halt, program!
Violation penal code 113.
- There he is!
- No, over here!
Split up.
You're fast, Renegade.
But not fast enough.
Wait, you're not...
[ groans ]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~
- My fan club strikes again.
- You mean my fan club.
Hey, you made a joke.
That's progress.
What did you find out?
Not much. The soldiers
still think it's me.
They haven't even figured out
that there's more than one.
So when do we bring them in?
We don't.
- Not yet.
- What do you mean?
This is what we've been
waiting for... recruits.
We have to build ranks eventually,
and they obviously
believe in the cause.
There's more to the uprising
than acts of vandalism.
You know that.
Well, you do now.
Yeah, because you gave me
the chance to do something,
make a difference.
I'm not sure if you noticed,
but I'm kinda on my own out there.
- I'm just asking you to wait.
- I'm done waiting.
As long as I'm wearing this suit,
you have to start
letting me make decisions.
These programs need to know
what they're fighting for.
They need to be willing to die for it.
You want to make a decision,
make one.
But be prepared to deal
with the consequences.
And you're walking away.
Big surprise.
Where is it?
- Identify.
- I told you, I didn't see anything.
I want every program
on this train detained.
No one leaves until
I've questioned them.
Yes, sir.
Well?
Open it!
I got it!
[ trilling ]
[ gasps ]
Get down!
[ grunts ]
[ screams ]
Triumph!
I wish I could've seen their
faces when the countdown hit zero.
I wish I could've seen
my masterpiece.
[ clears throat ]
Our masterpiece.
Next time let's hang
out at the scene longer.
It's more fun when they chase us.
That's how we get caught.
If we wanna
keep this operation running,
we stick to my plan.
[ gasps ]
- Now what?
- Run!
[ all groan ]
Huh?
Do you know how fast you could've
been derezzed for what you've done?
Vandalizing city property,
trespassing,
instigating disobedience
by spreading lies.
- They're not lies.
- Hey, be quiet.
And it's not vandalism, it's free code.
For the record, I have no idea
what you or these two
are talking about.
Hey, hey!
Whoa!
Oh, that.
Okay.
So you believe that Tron's alive?
- I do.
- And you?
- I let my work speak for itself.
- Then so be it.
[ screams ]
Wait!
No, no, no!
You can't!
- Tron?
- So you're not still gonna derez us?
Duh, he's here
to help us. Right?
[ all grunt ]
Actually, you're going to help me.
But first I have to trust you.
Name's Moog.
And this here's Rasket.
It's pronounced "Ras-kay."
And finally, the heart
and soul of the Jolly Tricksters.
Mara.
Nice to see you again, Tron.
Wait.
You two know each other?
- No.
- Yes.
He saved my life.
More than once.
Well, of course he did.
He's impersonating Tron.
[ groans ]
I mean, he is Tron.
We're both... all three of us...
huge fans of your work.
Uh, thanks.
I've brought all of
you here for a reason.
There's a revolution coming,
and I need recruits to fight by my side.
So...
so what do you say?
Are you up for the challenge?
- Absolutely!
- Of course!
That was easy.
But our task ahead won't be.
I just wanna say that I've been waiting
for an opportunity like
this for a while now,
a chance to show my commitment
to the revolution, to you.
That's very flattering, really.
Look, you've all been through a lot.
Let's call it for now,
then meet back here
at the start of next cycle
for further instructions.
Class dismissed.
Let's go, guys.
Let's bounce.
Whatever you want us to do, I want
you to know that I'm not afraid.
Remember when you first approached me?
I said I wasn't afraid.
But how did you really
know I was the right choice?
I didn't.
You kept coming back.
The more I pushed,
the harder you fought.
Was I your first choice?
Yes.
Really?
There was no one before me?
Why do you ask?
Is there something you'd
like to tell me, Beck?
No. I was just wondering if you were
afraid you made the wrong choice...
with me.
You're forgetting, when I found you,
you were already waging your
own war against the occupation.
I just steered you down the right path.
The right path...
what is it?
Defacing trains and billboards?
Or striking a significant blow
against the enemy's stronghold?
Whoa.
That's Tesler's ship.
And you three are going
to help me infiltrate it.
On that ship is a data key.
Tesler's ship is the
biggest canvas in Argon.
We hit that, we'll make history.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Nobody's
hitting Tesler's ship but me.
In fact, you won't be anywhere near it.
Every fifth cycle,
the ship docks with
the Argon refueling tower.
That's where you three come in.
While I circle by light jet,
you're going to do
what you're good at...
bombard the area with your free code.
In order to draw the guards away,
that way you can sneak
onto the ship undetected.
Do you like
how I put that together?
So we're just your distraction.
Where's the fun in that?
We want in on the thrills.
This isn't about thrills.
I'm trying to gather intel.
And if you can't understand that,
then maybe I've made a mistake.
Tron, wait.
I can't believe what I'm hearing.
Do you know who we're talking to?
This is the program who
inspired you to create,
and inspired you to help
Rasket realize his mission.
Uh, "Ras-kay."
[ sighs ]
Whatever.
He's risking his life out
there and he needs our help.
I don't know about you guys,
but I'm giving it to him.
Us, too.
When do we start?
Right on time.
Be careful.
Security zone compromised.
Alert commander Paige.
Stand clear of docking.
Prepare for refuel.
Perpetrators at large.
Report or be derezzed.
Hey, where are you two going?
The plan is to meet
Tron at the warehouse.
Change of plans, baby.
All personnel remain in docking area
until refueling is complete.
You're alone.
[ gasps ]
- Why?
- I tried to stop them.
Stop them?
Mara, where are they?
[ sighs ]
There.
What were they thinking?
They weren't.
I usually handle that part.
This is as far as you go.
I'll take care of the rest.
Uh, try again.
I'm the one who talked
them into joining you.
Besides, I know their plan.
Without me, you'll
never find them in time.
And I won't take no
for an answer.
[ sighs ]
I was afraid of that.
[ laughs ]
Zed is never going to believe this!
Hmm.
No sign of the Renegade.
Or whoever struck by
the refueling tower.
Unacceptable. Keep looking.
This "Tron lives" blasphemy must stop.
Then you definitely
shouldn't look outside, sir.
[ growls ]
Where is that coming from?
Far as I can tell, from us.
[ alarm sounds ]
Perhaps we better abscond.
Aw, I was just getting
in the zone.
Security alert.
[ grunts ]
[ laughs ]
What are you two grinning for?
[ both grunt ]
I'm disappointed that
you're not the Renegade,
but that doesn't mean we
still can't have fun together.
Moog, what are we walking on?
I think you mean...
"who" are we walking on.
- Did he scream?
- Yes, sir.
That's the problem with these
programs, they can't hold it together.
[ grunts ]
A little privacy, please.
[ alarm sounds ]
Security breach contained.
General Tesler, please report to
prison level for interrogation.
While you're able to
talk, why not tell me
the location of your
leader, the Renegade!
Look, we don't know!
You have to believe us, okay?!
Where's the fun in that?
[ screaming ]
Please! We're sorry!
We're just artists!
Oh, so you work with your hands.
[ screaming ]
[ grunting ]
[ screams ]
[ groans ]
Get him!
[ alarm sounds ]
They're sealing us in.
We'll be trapped.
[ gasps ]
I'll handle the Renegade.
You get the others.
You three get that gate open...
while I deal with them.
[ grunting ]
- You don't give up, do you?
- No, and I never will.
You're gonna wanna hurry, Mara.
I can't!
There's not enough time!
Then what are we waiting for?!
Catch!
No, wait!
What about Tron?
What about him?
He's fine. He's Tron.
[ grunting ]
We need to go now!
[ all gasp ]
I was wrong! It's not more
fun when they chase us!
I thought you were
all about the thrills.
Huh?
[ grunts ]
[ grunting ]
[ both scream ]
[ panting ]
[ cheering ]
Mara, go!
[ groans ]
[ grunts ]
Huh?
Oh.
- We messed up.
- Yeah, we messed up bad.
And thanks
for coming back for us.
- It's not just me you have to thank.
- You're welcome.
That right path you mentioned...
it's out there, isn't it?
It's Argon.
That's what you've been fighting for.
It's more than Argon.
You're taking the fight
all the way to Clu.
You're fighting so this stops.
Then join me. Let me put
your talents to good use.
The uprising needs you.
And so do I.
We're not good enough.
No way.
We barely survived up there.
I don't think we'll be
as lucky a second time.
Your cause is right,
but we're not your army.
Hey, it's a good thing Tron lives.
Argon needs you.
I'm still in. No matter the
risks, I'm ready for this.
[ sighs ]
I'm not.
What does that mean?
It means without your friends
you're of no help to me.
Go home.
It was the only way
to get her to leave.
She was the one true
believer in the cause.
But I wasn't prepared
for the consequences.
Then you made the right decision.
If she's really willing to
risk everything for the cause,
she'll still be there...
when you're ready.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~