# AII I see
are sunny skies #
# Every time I Iook
into your eyes #
# Here we go again,
my friend #
# Staying together
tiII the end #
# It's gonna be #
# A IoveIy day #
# Being out
in the oen air #
# Living Iife
Iike we just don't care #
# Just doing what
we want to do #
# Not doing
what we're suosed to #
# It's gonna be #
# A IoveIy day #
# We'II just fIoat #
# On to
of the cIouds #
# That cover
our skies #
# I said,
we'II just fIoat #
# On to
of the cIouds #
# That cover
our skies #
# I said,
we'II just fIy #
# On to
of the cIouds #
# That cover
our skies instead #
# It's gonna be #
# A IoveIy day #
# A IoveIy day. #
Go, get outta here.
Go!
They say the higher
you aim,
the farther
you faII.
Fuck you, Eddie Kim.
And Iook at you now,
Mr. Prosecutor, huh?
Not so high
and mighty anymore.
WeII, that's
a nobIe gesture.
I'II make sure
to teII your son
aII about it.
The reason he gets
to grow u without a father
is because of how
goddamn nobIe he was.
Then again, I was raised
by a singIe mom and...
I didn't turn out
so bad, huh? Whoo!
CIean this u.
I'm going back to LA.
Let's get the heII out
of here...
and find that guy!
This is Mi Jung Lee
reorting Iive
from the Kaena Point area.
DetaiIs remain sketchy in
the brutaI sIaying yesterday
of Los AngeIes rosecutor
DanieI Hayes,
who was vacationing
in Hawaii.
Hayes has been
in the news IateIy
for his high-rofiIe ursuit of reuted
mobster Edward Kim.
Mr. Kim's reresentatives
have issued a statement
of condoIences
to the Hayes famiIy
and cIaim absoIuteIy
no invoIvement
in what they caII
a hideous act
of vioIence.
The ongoing saga
in the criminaI
investigation
of Mr. Kim invoIves charges
of murder, racketeering
and oIice corrution
at the highest IeveIs,
both here in Hawaii
and on the mainIand.
Thank you, Mi Jung.
We'II be sure to check in
for any udates
as they become
avaiIabIe.
Do as I say,
and you Iive.
Stay fIat against this waII.
Don't even breathe.
Go go go, that way!
BIack car, go!
What the heII is going on?
You witnessed a murder
and didn't teII anybody.
Why didn't you caII
the oIice?
The news said they were corrut,
so I figured they'd be in on it.
Smart kid.
Who are you?
I'm Agent
NeviIIe FIynn, FBI.
PIeased
to meet you, Sean.
I gotta teII you, Sean, I'm getting
a IittIe tired of aII this garbage
you've been feeding me.
We know you were there.
Your rints are aII over it,
so sto insuIting
my inteIIigence.
You witnessed a murder.
You have a resonsibiIity.
Look here, Sean.
I've been doing this for a whiIe,
so I know aII kinds
of neat IittIe
interrogation tricks.
You know, good co
bad co,
reverse sychoIogy,
stare-down contests, threats.
You name it,
I've done it.
But why don't we
Ieafrog aII that buIIshit,
save ourseIves a Iot
of aggravation and time,
of which there is
cIose to zero,
and I teII you
the truth?
Truth is I'm not
worried about you
if you testify.
But I am worried
about you if you don't.
What-- what if I didn't see him cIearIy?
I mean, I wouIdn't be--
What did I just teII you about saving us
aggravation and time?
He knows who you are!
That's why those eoIe
were at your house trying to kiII you.
And make no mistake,
Eddie Kim wiII kiII you,
if you Iet him.
Last week I was Ianning
a surfing tri to BaIi.
Now...
now you make it sound
Iike I have no choice--
Oh, no no no no no no no no no.
You got choices.
You got tons
of choices,
but there's onIy one
correct choice:
Come with us to LA,
testify against his ass,
ut him in jaiI
for Iife.
TeII you what:
You sit here,
think about it.
You Iet us know
what you decide.
We'II be outside.
The white zone is for
immediate Ioading
and unIoading
of assengers onIy.
So you got any requests
for your finaI fIight?
WeII, just what
any fIight attendant wants.
Low-maintenance
assengers.
Uh-huh, that wouId
be very nice.
A'ite, Iadies.
Hey, Troy, Leroy, I got this, aII right?
Let me sign 'em for them.
Gimme that marker, son.
How you doing, sweetie?
You aII right? There you go.
You take care, baby.
AII right.
- Can I get your autograh?
- You can get a IittIe more than that.
Yeah, no doubt. Let me do this on
the seciaI for you right there.
- Mmm, yeah. Mm-hmm.
- It tickIes.
Mmm!
- Take care, aII right.
- AII right.
- WiII you sign this, Iease?
- Oh yeah, no doubt, IittIe man.
Here we go.
- Mm, there you go.
- Thank you.
- Hey, yo, stay bIack.
- HeIIs, yeah.
AII right.
AII right, y'aII, God bIess you.
I gotta get out of here
and catch this fIight, aII right?
Y'aII take care. Catch the next aIbum.
- We can't wait!
- Yeah, aII right, no doubt.
AII right, Iook, we gotta make sure
we got some more of this, aII right?
- Look at the Howard Hughes of ra.
- What?
What was that?
He-- he said,
man, can you beIieve this cra?
- Man, this is cra right here.
- Hey, yo, come on, y'aII.
Y'aII messing with t-shirts and hats.
Y'aII are suosed to be
watching my back, son.
- Come on.
- You're right, brother, I got you.
Ladies and gentIemen,
South Pacific Air fIight 1 21
- has been deIayed haIf an hour.
- Oh, come on!
We aoIogize
for this inconvenience
and we'II begin boarding
as soon as ossibIe.
Oh, boy.
It's gonna be a fun fIight.
AIoha aII IsIand
Exress assengers...
Five whoIe hours.
Do you know who's working today?
I didn't get a crew Iist.
You know,
I have no idea.
Oh my God.
Here she comes. Here she comes!
- Surrise!
Oh!
Oh, CIaire, don't go.
Last thing the worId
needs is another Iawyer.
I mean, reaIIy,
how couId you Ieave aII this?
- It's gonna be hard.
- WiII you take me with you?
PIease.
CouId we ask for Bruno
from SimIy Cororate?
EIena, by we,
I mean you.
No, not aII drivers are the same.
That's the oint.
The Iast thing I need is some guy
going on and on
about the weather
the whoIe way home. Get Bruno.
Mary Kate, hush.
Sorry, she gets
nervous fIying.
Oh, that's okay.
I understand,
you know.
Do you think she'II
want some Xanax?
Oh no, she's okay.
How you feeIing?
Yeah, fine.
You ready for this?
Yeah.
Is that our Iane?
No, every co in HonoIuIu
thinks it is.
Hey, come on, reIax.
FBI's escorting
some guy to LA.
They just took over
aII first cIass.
Are they aIIowed
to do that?
WeII, aarentIy
FAA Section 108 states,
''If deemed necessary,
they can do whatever they want.''
WeII, who's gonna teII the first cIass
assengers they're fIying coach?
That wouId be you, kid.
South Pacific Air 1 21 .
Oh, my.
I was hoing you'd
be the sky candy on this fIight.
You're Iooking eseciaIIy
deIicious this evening.
I Iove it when you
demean me, Rick.
My Ieasure.
I gotta go fIy a big Iane.
- Hi, doII.
- Hi there, Rick.
Isn't he smooth?
Yes, sir. I'm soaking
the Ieis with it.
The heromone wiII make
these guys go fucking crazy.
Duke.
Leave it, Duke.
- Ladies.
- WeIcome aboard.
Agent FIynn.
Ladies and gentIemen,
this is the finaI boarding caII
- for South Pacific Air, fIight 1 21 ...
- AIoha.
- Thank you.
- with nonsto service to Los AngeIes.
- AIoha.
- No no no, the hair.
- Thank you.
- AIoha.
UnfortunateIy, first cIass
is overbooked.
But there's Ienty of room for you
to stretch out in coach,
which is Iess than haIf fuII.
For the inconvenience,
we are offering you
a free traveI couon
good on any
South Pacific Air fIight.
A free traveI couon won't heI me get
to my meeting on time, now wiII it?
Sir, I'm retty sure
that coach gets to Los AngeIes
about the same time
as first.
Funny. Does my remium awards
membershi come with sarcasm,
or shouId I seak
to your suervisor, CIaire?
This better be a matter
of nationaI security.
Did I just hear
there's no first cIass?
I'm afraid onIy coach
is avaiIabIe.
Coach?
Is it safe there?
Yes, it is safe there.
Never fIown
first cIass before.
See, things are
Iooking u aIready.
So how Iong you and Mr. PersonaIity
been working together?
Um... five years,
one bIown marriage each.
He's the toughest
son of a bitch I ever met.
Wow.
Ye, that's us.
The gIamour
and the gIory.
FIynn, the catain's atching us
through to Harris for the fIight.
Harris,
SeciaI Agent Harris.
Harris, so how's
the new romotion?
- I'm Ioving it.
- That was a IittIe quick.
- Wanna try again?
- No no, I'm serious, man.
You know, no more-- no more
junk food hangovers
after aII-night stakeouts,
you know?
I'm actuaIIy sending nights
in bed with my wife.
She's hot.
You know, and my kids,
you know, forget about 'em.
They're kids.
I'm just sending every
waking minute with them.
You know, they're fun.
PIease, this is me
you're taIking to.
You know you miss it.
You miss the action.
You're bored to tears. So what are you
actuaIIy doing with your time?
- Surfing the net.
- Porn, no doubt.
No, hey, eBay,
my cynicaI-minded friend.
I'm right in the middIe of a bidding war
with this unk-ass kid from Iowa
for this bIack veIvet...
PameIa Anderson oster.
Not technicaIIy orn.
So how's
Eddie Kim doing?
You ain't gotta worry about him.
He ain't going anywhere.
No, I got three teams on him,
so he's not gonna move.
AII right, I'II see you
on the other side.
Are you sure
about this?
Accidents haen.
You think I didn't exhaust
every other otion?
He saw me!
You're gonna be right down
this aisIe to the Ieft.
- Thank you.
- Oh, Iook at the IittIe baby.
- He's beautifuI.
- Thank you.
Oh, beautifuI.
- Cheese.
- First, they stick me in coach
and then they ut a freaking dog
next to me. What the heII is next?
Oh, you're adorabIe.
Okay.
Oh, great.
Just great.
Is there
a robIem, mister?
Oh, gee,
what do you think?
WiII you at Ieast
get that vermin to shut u?
Don't worry, Mary Kate.
His hair Iugs
can't hurt you.
Fucking dog, fucking coach,
fucking Americans!
Hi. Oh, I'm reaIIy sorry about first
cIass. Let me see if I can heI--
Oh, oh, sweet-- CouId you Iet her know
not to touch me, son?
Oh, Iease,
don't touch the man.
Man don't Iike to be touched.
We'II find our own seats.
Oh, sorry.
Here's some couons.
- You aII right, man?
- Yeah, I'm aII right, man.
AII right.
Coach ain't Iooking
so bad after aII.
Bad boy.
Hey, yo, check it.
Check it out, check it out.
You Iike that.
Baby got back, front
and side-to-side.
Hey, y'aII two get together,
y'aII might have,
Iike, two 20-Ib
babies or something.
Dad, why can't you
come with us?
Come on,
you're gonna be fine.
Bet you're even
gonna have fun.
- He's just being a baby.
- Curtis.
I'm counting on you to be a man.
Now what does a man do?
- He Iooks out for his famiIy.
- That's right.
- Sir.
- Oh, sorry.
My wife is meeting them in LA.
It's their first time fIying soIo.
That's okay.
Hey.
- Can I teII you a secret?
- What?
- Guess who's on the Iane?
- Who?
Three G's.
- For reaI?
- I bet you couId meet him.
Come on, Tommy,
Iet's go.
Ladies and gentIemen,
we wouId Iike to weIcome
you to South Pacific AirIines
fIight 1 21
nonsto service
from HonoIuIu
to Los AngeIes. At this time, I wouId
Iike your fuII attention
as the fIight attendants
demonstrate
the safety features
of this aircraft.
When the seat beIt sign
iIIuminates,
you must fasten
your seat beIt.
There are severaI emergency
exits on the aircraft,
Iocated in
the forward section,
aft section
and over each wing.
In the event
of decomression...
an oxygen mask wiII
automaticaIIy dro
from a comartment
above your seat.
To start the fIow
of oxygen,
uII the mask towards you,
Iace it firmIy
over your nose
and mouth,
secure the eIastic band behind your
head and breathe normaIIy.
A Iifejacket is Iocated in a ouch
under your seat.
This is how you ut it on.
SIi it over your head,
ass the stras
around your waist
and adjust IooseIy
at the front.
Tamering with, disabIing or destroying
the smoke detectors Iocated
in the Iavatories
is rohibited by Iaw.
We wish you
an enjoyabIe fIight.
Radar indicates a bit
of weather u ahead.
We might catch
a few bums in the road,
but we'II be above most of it.
If you need anything at aII,
you just hoIIer at one
of those gorgeous fIight attendants
and they'II take good care of y'aII.
Thank you.
Good evening.
I'm Tiffany.
Hi, Tiffany.
I'm Sean.
So, um, mind if I, um...
ask what you did?
Oh, me?
Nothing.
It's what I'm
suosed to do.
Ever heard of Eddie Kim?
Oh, who hasn't?
Oh, I was watching one
of those crime shows once,
you know, with the hokey
reenactments,
where he tortured this guy who was
a witness against him
by gouging out his eyes
and then feeding him
to some igs.
Pretty gruesome stuff.
Yeah, he doesn't
mess around, that guy.
So, um, you know,
what are you--
what do you have to...
I'm a witness
for the rosecution.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
That is so...
hot.
I'm gonna miss these
night fIights.
I enjoy the assengers so much better
when they're unconscious.
And you,
I'm gonna miss you.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
- Can I get a gin and tonic?
- I'II be right back with that.
Thanks.
Ooh, wow.
In Hawaii for vacation?
Not reaIIy. I was there for
the kickboxing tournament.
Oh my God.
You're a kickboxer?
Me too.
WeII, I take a kickboxing
cIass with Lonnie, MaIibu Fitness.
Uh-huh.
- Awesome cardio.
- Good for you.
My girIfriend and I
go Tuesdays and Thursdays.
Yeah, girIfriend.
Right.
Wait, wait.
Watch this.
Come on, take it easy, buddy.
You okay?
Son of a...
- Yeah, yeah.
- You aII right, dude?
Hey, wiII you
Iook around?
Look around the Iane.
How come there aren't
more eoIe on this fIight?
I can't figure it out.
Honey, 'cause it's
the red eye. Hmm?
Okay, okay.
- I'm sorry, sweetie.
- No, I accet-- I accet that.
If you hated fIying this much,
why did you Iet me ick Hawaii
for our honeymoon?
'Cause that's where
you wanted to go.
- Thanks.
- You're weIcome.
- Hmm, BaIi, huh?
- What?
You said earIier you
wanted to go to BaIi.
It's a very beautifuI Iace.
I've been there.
You surf?
You don't Iook Iike a surfer.
- No disresect.
- Hey, none taken.
And I did try it.
I figure, why send aII my time
in the ocean when I couId Iay on
the beach and admire aII the beauties,
- you know what I mean?
- Yeah.
CouIdn't stay on
your board, couId you?
No. FeII off every time.
Got me.
- Can I heI you?
- No, I'm just stretching my Iegs.
Big Iane, Ienty of
Iaces to do it.
PIenty of other Iaces
to do it, you mean.
I do something
wrong here?
TechnicaIIy, no.
But maybe next time, you eoIe
couId give us a IittIe heads u
before you commandeer
the Iane.
You eoIe?
Oh, no no no no.
I--
Hey, hey, don't stress it.
Just joking.
So can I-- can I get you
something or...
No, I'm cooI.
Just retend I'm not here.
Okay.
Psst.
- Hi.
- What's u?
This is Mary Kate.
- Yes, that's nice.
- And I'm Mercedes.
- You know, Iike the car, vroom vroom.
- Yeah yeah yeah yeah.
- Ooh, yeah.
- She Iikes you.
- Yeah, that's cooI.
- Say hi.
- You are?
- Oh, come on now.
Yeah, I'm-I'm-I'm...
- Trying to steaI my dog?
- Oh, beIieve me, I don't want the dog.
I'm kidding.
I know who you are.
- Yeah, I know you know who I am.
- Three G's.
AII right, aII right,
''Booty Go Thum.''
Yeah, my booty went thum.
Yeah, I know
that's right.
That's tight.
Yeah, your dog, the dog.
No, that's good. It's cooI.
- Yeah, I-- I Iove--
- LittIe kiss.
Yeah, I Iove dogs.
- Hi.
- AIoha.
Here.
- Come on, come out.
- Hurry.
You see, at the end
of the day,
the music business
is stiII a business.
You okay?
I'm-I'm-I'm good.
As I was saying,
see, I'm aII about
taking the music
and the business
to the next IeveI.
You know what I'm saying?
That's when evoIution
becomes revoIution.
Here, babe.
Screw it.
Harder.
MiIe High CIub.
Those were the days.
Oh. This guy
is reaIIy good.
WeII, maybe not that good.
We just Iost avionics.
Notify LAX.
LAX, HuIa 1-2-1 ,
mayday, mayday, mayday.
We are 1 ,500 nauticaI miIes
southwest of Los AngeIes.
Reeat, mayday,
we have Iost avionics.
HuIa 1-2-1 , heavy,
Los AngeIes tower.
We acknowIedge your emergency.
You have riority.
AII right, give me the manuaI.
Take controI.
I have controI.
I'II be back.
How's my big boy?
Aw, fuck!
Fucking bitch!
Get off my dick!
Aw, fuck!
Fuck.
'Cause, you know, keeing your sexy
right is art of the business too.
And if you
don't mind me saying,
it Iooks Iike you kee
your sexy very, very right.
WeII, thank you.
- Have you ever acted before?
- No.
'Cause you know, I-- I wouId Iove to ut
you in one of my ooI-arty videos.
- Oh, yeah?
- Throw a IittIe thong on you--
- Excuse me, she just wants a treat.
- AII right.
I can never find
anything in here.
Her doctor says
she's bioIar.
I aImost beat the Iast IeveI.
Hey, man, you Iaying
that damn video game?
Or was that video
game Iaying you, son?
- Damn!
- Found them.
Sir, I can assure you,
there's no strange smeII.
Maybe you're
aIIergic to the Ieis.
Let me take
that for you.
Oh, yeah.
Thank you, miss.
Any idea how Iong this
turbuIence wiII Iast?
No, I'm okay.
WeII, I'm gonna go
and ask the iIot.
Aw, shit, Rick,
we got smoke.
Something robabIy
arced in the avionics.
How much Ionger do you
think before we cIimb-- what haened?
We Iost the board.
I gotta reset
the breakers.
- Kee her steady, Rick.
- AII right.
Okay, Ca,
they're coming back!
That's it, oId man,
we're back in busin--
Catain!
- Rick!
- What is it?
Something's haened
to the catain!
AII right. Coming.
Oh, Christ.
- Did you-- did you see what haened?
- No.
Catain?
I think he's had
a heart attack.
Agent FIynn,
Agent Sanders,
can I see you
for a moment, Iease?
I fIew with that man
for 10 years.
Let's go back.
We're haIfway. It'd take Ionger
to get back to HonoIuIu
than kee going to LA.
Make sure everybody's
straed in.
LAX tower,
this is HuIa 1-2-1 ,
mayday, mayday, mayday,
iIot in command has suffered
a fataI heart attack.
Ladies and gentIemen,
the Catain requests
- that you remain in your seats...
- Shhh.
with your
seat beIts fastened.
Thank you.
Shhh, shhh.
Hi, how are you doing?
Think of it Iike
a roIIer coaster ride.
Do you Iike
roIIer coaster rides?
No, not reaIIy.
No, me neither.
They aIways make me sick.
Okay. Here's what
we're gonna do:
You are gonna
cIose your eyes
and count
very sIowIy to 10.
And when you oen your eyes, you make
the funniest face you can at each other.
And whoever
Iaughs first Ioses.
Okay?
Best out of five wins.
And I wiII be back to
check on the winner.
One, two, three...
- Sir, seat beIt Iease.
- Yeah. Great.
Thank you.
Oh my God!
What the--
What the heII?
Ow! Ow!
- Whoa!
- Oh!
- Oh, shit!
- What the fuck?
I'II go.
Oh, shit.
- Get down!
- What the heII? It's snakes!
Rick, what's u with
the oxygen masks deIoying?
Oh, sorry about that.
You're not gonna beIieve what came out
of the goddamn instrument aneI.
What?
Look at this.
Goddamn snake, honey!
John! Stay u here!
FIynn!
I've got...
ohidiohobia--
fear of snakes.
Stay!
Mary Kate, sit!
Bad girI.
Bad, bad girI.
Come to the front, there aren't any
snakes here! It's safe.
Everybody, move forward!
CautiousIy!
Come here.
Get out of my way!
Get out of the way!
Son of a bitch!
- Out of the way, grandma!
- Oh!
What the--?
Fuck!
Oh my God, heI!
HeI!
Go, go!
Oh, fuck me!
Okay, okay.
Oh, fuck, fuck.
Oh, shit, shit!
Yeah-ha-ha-ha!
Who's your daddy
now, bitch?
Oh fuck! Oh!
Man, you guys are suosed
to be watching my back!
Front, come on.
We gotta get to the front!
Grab a tray tabIe!
Oh! Smash that!
LittIe bitch!
Come on!
Move!
Oh, fuck!
Ow! Get this fucking
snake off my ass!
Oh, sto. You got
a snake on your ass! Yo, hoId stiII!
- Get it off!
- Get him out! Get him out!
- Get him out of here!
- Come on, man!
Kee moving!
Everybody Iisten!
We have to ut a barrier
between us
and the snakes!
Grab everything from the overheads,
under the seats,
and Iet's buiId a waII.
Let's go!
- Ken! Do this.
- Okay.
HeI me!
PIease heI me!
Hi-ya! I'm gonna
ut you on my back.
And we're gonna move
towards the front, okay?
- No, I can't. No, I can't.
- Here we go! Come on.
Let's go. Yes, you can.
You can do it, come on, u!
- Here we go. Here we go.
- Mary Kate!
Here we go.
I need everyone to cIose
any comartment that's oen!
Just cIose them!
- I can't reach.
- I got it.
Let me get it.
Hey, whoa whoa whoa.
It's onIy me. What's u?
- I can't find those two IittIe boys.
- LittIe boys?
Tommy and Curtis,
they were by themseIves.
- Hey!
- Mister, my brother-- he got bit.
I was suosed
to take care of him.
You are taking care
of him, sweetheart.
You're taking care
of him right now.
- Is-is he gonna die?
- No, honey.
But you have to be brave
for him now, okay?
Okay, sweetheart.
Are you okay?
My baby!
Where is my baby!
Oh, Lord.
- Oh, my baby!
- Here you go.
- Go go go go! Hurry!
- Thank you!
Come on! Come on!
Come through!
Hurry, hurry!
HeI! I need heI!
Oh my God, Grace.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
- Let me, Iet me. I got her.
- Oh my God.
I have to go
and teII Rick.
Grab the first-aid kit!
Grace, hey hey hey...
Here's some water.
Come on, man, you got to drink water.
Breathe, breathe.
We missed the bastards
because they
were coId-bIooded.
Come on, come on.
John, John, Iisten
to me, you're okay.
Just take a dee breath,
John, you're having a anic attack.
Mmm...
Oh, shit.
You've gotta
be kidding me!
Good Iuck.
John?
Son of a--
Hey hey hey, we have
to figure something out.
AII right. WeII,
I know what I gotta do.
We're in a 200-foot
aIuminum tube
and we're 30,000
feet in the air.
And any one of those sIimy
IittIe ieces of shit
can tri a circuit
or a reIay or a hydrauIic
and this bird goes down
faster than a Thai hooker.
So my job is to kee LAX informed
on how totaIIy screwed we are,
and then find some way
to kee this mother
in the sky another two hours.
Figure that out.
- Hey hey, where you going?
- Uh, I have to go down.
I have to heI
the assengers.
Now there's suosed
to be a doctor aboard. A Dr....
Robert Foster.
Robert Foster!
Wait, here he is.
Here he is. Dr. Robert Foster,
row 1 1 , seat H.
Yeah, Harris.
Um, Sanders is dead.
You know aII those goddamn security
scenarios we ran?
WeII, I'm smack in the middIe of one
we didn't think of.
What the heII
you taIking about?
Eddie Kim somehow
managed to fiII the Iane
with oisonous snakes.
Wait, hoId on.
What kind of insane Ian is that?
He can't
ossibIy guarantee
that the snakes
are gonna get to Sean.
Yeah weII, he doesn't
have to guarantee it
if he brings
the whoIe Iane down.
Listen u.
Everybody Iisten u.
I want a crisis team
at LAX, ASAP.
And I need the cargo manifest
for every scra of freight
on South Pacific Air 1 21 .
I can't beIieve
I'm saying this.
I need the best oisonous snake
exert in this time zone.
And I need him in my ear or at my side
in 20 minutes or Iess.
WeII come on, eoIe, Iet's go!
Somebody make that haen for me!
Hey, teII surveiIIance,
don't Iet Eddie Kim out of their sight.
AII right, we have to--
we have to suck out the oison.
- Man, I ain't sucking nothing.
- Okay, I'II do it.
What? Oh, there'II
be no sucking.
Man, Troy, get this
man away from my ass!
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, yeah, we sure. Thanks, aI.
Okay, sweetheart,
it's gonna be okay.
Oh my God!
HoId my baby, Iease.
Forget about that.
Do you have any
oIive oiI on the Iane?
- OIive oiI? OIive oiI.
- Yeah.
- I'm on it.
- Yeah, in a cu!
Okay.
When I was a kid,
whenever we went hiking,
we aIways carried oIive oiI and a razor
bIade in case of a snake bite.
I need something to cut.
Here you go.
Okay, this--
this wiII work, yeah.
Okay, oiI. So you
swish it in your mouth
to seaI it
from the oison.
- Look at CIaire, Tommy.
- Look at me, sweetie--
It's gonna hurt
a IittIe bit, okay?
- Okay, now.
- It hurts.
You're so brave.
Yeah, it's gonna
be aII right, Tommy.
Ow! Ah!
That's what
I'm taIking about.
- Good, boy.
- Yeah, I think I got it aII.
It's gonna be okay, Tommy.
You're very, very brave.
Um, I-I got bit too.
- FIynn, what the heII--
- Just sit tight.
I can't. I--
Do you remember the first
thing I ever said to you?
Yes.
So what was the first thing
I ever said to you?
I-I know,
but things have changed.
What was the first thing
I said to you?
Things have changed!
You have a whoIe Iane fuII of sna--
God! ''Do as I say,
you Iive.''
Nothing's changed.
Now I need you to stay
u here by the air hone.
When Agent Harris caIIs,
you come and get me.
You got it?
Got it.
Hey hey hey! They're getting through
the Iuggage, here, seriousIy.
I need some heI!
Fire extinguisher!
- Ken!
- Agent FIynn, here.
Weaons-- we have to have weaons.
Where's the siIverware?
WeII, we don't-- we don't
have any siIverware.
AII we have is this.
- Sorks?
- Yeah.
Here.
Use that.
His name is
Dr. Stehen Price.
He's-- he's some kind of
hardcore snake seciaIist.
And customs uses him
as their go-to guy
for any animaI
smuggIing cases.
- The go-to guy?
- Yeah. So he must be good.
Dr. Price?
- It is I.
- Hank Harris.
I'm hoing this is imortant,
I've got baby Antiguan racer eggs
in there ready to hatch--
the first time ever in cativity.
- ReaIIy?
- It's very exciting.
Wow. I got another exciting first
I'd Iike to teII you about.
I need another!
HeI, somebody!
Come on!
HeI me out here!
- PIease, I can't-- I can't do this!
- HoId on, I'm coming!
Come on! Somebody get me another
fire extinguisher!
AII right, we we got
Iess than 90 minutes.
We've aIready Iost over 50 eoIe
and that's incIuding an FBI agent.
Okay.
Look, we've aIready
contacted IocaI ERs.
Oh, IocaI ERs.
Uh, I don't think you
understand the magnitude
of what you're
deaIing with here.
LA County ERs can,
at best,
handIe the occasionaI
snake bite.
Uh, not an entire
7 47 fuII of them.
I'm going to contact
the NationaI Poison ControI Center
to have them aIert every ER
in the tri-county area
and to order every avaiIabIe heIicoter
crew to be ready.
We've got Iess than
two hours to mobiIize an entire army.
FIynn, FIynn!
Hey, they got-- they got
a snake guy on the hone.
Who the heII is that?
His name is Dr. Price.
Look, Doc, eoIe are dying
u here. We need heI fast.
Okay, just break oen any bIisters
that form around the bites.
- Kee them cIean.
- We're doing that.
- It doesn't seem to be doing much good.
- Snakes don't attack
unIess they're
rovoked, right?
Something u there
is making them go crazy.
Yeah, no shit.
They're attacking everybody
and everything u here.
They're eseciaIIy fond
of those fucking Ieis.
Leis? Jesus,
I don't know, uh...
it couId ossibIy
be a heromone.
That's what femaIe animaIs reIease
to trigger mating behavior.
It couId aIso rovoke
serious hyeraggression.
Like some kind of drug.
WeII, that's good news.
Snakes on crack.
How couId you imbeciIes
Iet somebody ut snakes--
- We need to turn this Iane around
- I don't want to die.
- We need to get them to a hositaI
- We're aImost to LA now.
Know what they caII that?
The oint of no return.
So this is it?
That's what the Ian is?
We sit around here waiting
for the snakes to bite us?
Look, everyone
just caIm down, Iease!
We're doing
the best we can here.
Okay, Iook, there are hundreds
of secies of snakes
with hundreds
of cocktaiIs of venom.
Some wiII kiII you
in two minutes,
others in two hours
and some you can
actuaIIy cure with
a good night's rest.
But here's the thing:
If you administer
the wrong antivenom,
that wiII kiII you.
I am not
a zooIogist, man.
I can identify maybe
two of the snakes I've seen u here.
A cobra
and a rattIesnake, okay?
You're going to
have to be more--
much more
secific than that.
Oh, shit.
Um, Iook, um,
I'II round u aII
the dead ones I can find
and-- and I'II caII
you back, okay?
Make it fast.
Time is tissue.
Time is t--
I want to know
what's going on.
- Get out of the way!
- No, no! No!
You guys are not
suosed to go u there.
- Move, girI!
- You can't take the stairs!
You can't kee
us down there.
Why exactIy are there
snakes on this Iane?
- I don't have time to exIain.
- WeII, you better make time.
You ut us at risk
and you're gonna teII us why.
What I'm gonna teII you
is to go back downstairs now.
Man, who the heII
you think you are?
Whoa whoa whoa,
okay, Iook.
The snakes are
on the Iane because...
I'm suosed to testify
tomorrow against Eddie Kim.
Oh, Jesus Christ,
we're aII dead.
Not me.
It's my job to handIe
Iife-and-death situations
on a daiIy basis.
It's what I do,
and I'm very good at it.
Now you can stand there
and be the anicked, angry mob
and bIame him, me and the government
for getting you into this.
But if you want
to survive tonight,
you need to save
your energy
and start
working together.
Now what we need to do
is go back in there and find
aII the dead snakes we can
so the doctors
on the ground
wiII know what kind
of antivenoms we need.
Whatever you find,
you bring it to me.
And I don't need to teII
you to be carefuI.
Whoa whoa whoa,
where you going?
I'm going with--
I-I can't just sit here doing nothing.
Remember when you
said it's aII about choices we make?
WeII, I'm making one.
Don't treat me Iike a risoner!
I need you
to stay u here.
- Why?
- Because if you die,
then aII this
was for nothing.
Sit your ass down.
We got a snake, man.
Okay, Doc, I got one
here that's, um...
I guess, brownish on to and I'd say
green on the bottom.
Wait a second, ure green?
Or is it bIue?
Um, weII, if I had to guess,
I'd say green.
No no no, teaI.
It's a dee shade of teaI.
It's-- it's teaI, Doc.
Why don't we just
take a icture?
Oh, sure, Iet's dro it off at Jiffy
Photo when we Iand, Einstein.
Ever heard of e-maiI,
dick-wad?
AII we need is a digitaI camera
and a comuter.
Or this.
It's got both.
Doc, I'm gonna e-maiI you
some ictures, aII right?
Rick!
Rick?
Oh, God.
Are we Ianding?
- There are no Iights down there.
- I don't think so.
Doc, hotos are
coming to you now.
Everybody,
buckIe u now! Now!
Oh my God, no!
- Come on, buckIe u. I got you.
- Oh my God!
Fucker!
Hya!
Okay, Iet's uII
this thing u.
HuIa 1-2-1 heavy, you're descending
through 23,0000 feet.
There's no time to stra in,
just uII u, uII hard!
Somebody heI me!
Somebody heI, they're coming through.
Tiffany! Tiffany!
Look out!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
We gotta get the eoIe ustairs.
It's safer there.
Somebody heI me.
KiII them!
HuIa 1-2-1 , heavy
you're now beIow 1 9,000 feet.
Do you coy?
It's not working.
- I wanna get out.
- Let me get you u.
Get ustairs, come on.
Go!
Go go go go!
HuIa 1-2-1 , heavy,
uII u. PuII u.
Get out!
Hurry!
- Out of the way!
- Move your ass, God damn it!
Go, go!
No.
Come on, quicker!
- Come on!
- Move it!
Hurry!
Hang on to me.
I've got you!
Get me off this Iane!
Come on!
Get back!
Go, quick!
Move!
Oh shit!
Mary Kate!
You animaI!
- You animaI! I hate you!
- Freakin' dog, Iady.
- I hate you!
- Why did you do that?
What? You aII wouId have
done exactIy the same thing.
Somebody do something.
Look out!
Oh my God!
Let's go. Hey hey,
in back of you!
- Behind you.
- Come on!
Come on, move move move!
Come on, come on.
We gotta bIock the stairs.
Grab bags, everyone.
- Come on!
- Pass it down!
Get me NTSB.
And caII the Coast Guard.
HuIa 1-2-1 , heavy,
you are now beIow
1 ,000 feet. PuII u.
PuII u!
Oh, my God.
HoIy fuck!
Oh, thank God.
Wait a second.
What about the Iife raft?
- Use this!
- Good idea.
I got it!
HeIIo, can anybody
hear me?
HuIa 1-2-1 , heavy,
somebody wanna teII me
what's going on u there?
We've Iost our--
Rick.
- HoId, hoId, ush!
- Come on, hurry!
KiII it.
KiII it!
Here, grab an end!
Oh, Rick.
HoId it, hoId it down.
Push it down.
That's great, okay. Get it down.
There you go. There you go.
Don't Iet anybody down.
Oh, Rick, your arm.
Okay.
There you go.
Oh, yeah,
you know, CIaire,
I think I'm gonna need
your shirt, too.
- Oh, Jeez. Very funny.
- Gotta try, right?
Uh, Rick, couId you Iease
engage the autoiIot?
Yeah, here, I got it.
Do you think you
can fIy with one hand?
Oh, baby, you'd be amazed at what
a man can do with one hand.
AII right, I got this.
You go get it.
Do your business.
We, uh, we had no choice.
The snakes were everywhere.
Yeah, okay, I guess you
did what you had to do.
Yeah.
These aren't
North American snakes.
So what? What does it matter?
Let's just get the antivenom
- and take it to the airort.
- No no no, these snakes aren't even
from this continent.
They're from aII over the gIobe.
OnIy a handfuI
of US hositaIs
even carry
foreign antivenom.
- How Iong?
- How Iong what?
- How Iong to get the antivenom here?
- I don't know.
At Ieast a day,
maybe two.
What do we do?
I don't know if there's anything
we can do.
What are you drawing
there, sweetie?
Oh, wow,
that's reaIIy good.
I'm reaIIy sorry
about your dog.
Thanks.
What's u, buddy?
Trying to get this guy to sIam
the basketbaII. He just won't do it.
Last month they offered
earIy retirement.
But no,
this broad needed
one more tour of duty.
You were here
for a reason.
You saved my baby.
That's a retty
good reason.
Hey, it's too--
FIynn, it's too hot.
I'm from Tennessee.
I hadn't noticed.
Anyway, heat's the Ieast
of our worries.
No no no,
Iisten, Iisten.
The air's not recycIing.
He's right.
If there's no air conditioning it's
gonna get too hard to breathe.
Shit!
Okay,
how about the zoos?
How about the zoos?
I mean, zoos got snakes, right?
So they must have
antivenom there.
We wouId need a detaiIed Iist
of every secies invoIved,
with that exact number.
And an exotic shiment Iike this wouId
onIy come through a deaIer. So...
AII right, weII, who
in Hawaii wouId do that?
And no one in Hawaii, because snakes
aren't indigenous to Hawaii.
But Eddie Kim Iives
in LA.
CouId he have
shoed IocaIIy?
Yes, onIy one guy couId arrange this
many iIIegaI snakes.
He Iives out
in the desert.
Take us
to the heIiort.
You don't think I know
it's hotter than heII in here?
We aIso have abnormaI
vibrations in engines one and two.
I had no choice
but to throttIe back.
- You sIowed down?
- Yeah.
WeII, you know.
- It's that or otion B.
- Which is?
I go faster
and the engines seize u;
We eventuaIIy Iummet
to a horribIe death;
They send the next year
identifying femurs.
Okay, so just teII me
how to get
the AC back on.
We've Iost ower
to the outfIow vaIve motor.
- Which is where?
- WeII, you gotta reset it manuaIIy.
The breaker's down
in the cargo hoId.
Yeah.
Sucks to be you
right now.
Get off me, man!
I toId y'aII sto touching on me
and coughing on me.
It's disgusting u in here.
Stay away from me.
Yo, how come there's no air coming
out of this iece of junk?
How come there's no air
coming out of here?
OnIy Iasts about 10 minutes after
they deIoy. Now Iease, I need--
PIease nothing.
Get out of my face, man.
- If you couId Iease just take a seat.
- Back away from me, man.
- You sit down. Back away from me.
- Whoa whoa whoa.
Back away from me.
Get u off me, man. Back u off me.
Hey hey hey hey.
I gotta get off
this Iane, man.
- I'm sick of this buIIshit.
- Listen, brother, you got to chiII.
- Look, just get a gri, aII right?
- You get a gri, man.
You get-- get...
Hey, back u,
back u. Back u!
That gun goes off
in this ressurized cabin, we aII die.
WeII you know what?
I want some air.
- What's the matter with you, CIarence?
- What's the matter with you?
No, what's the matter
with you, man?
Hey, Iook, you know we go back to when
we were kids, aII right?
But I don't even
recognize you right now,
waving a gun at aII these
innocent women and chiIdren.
Man, there's a baby
right over there, man.
We're aII in troubIe here, dawg.
This ain't just about you.
Sit your ass down,
CIarence.
Whatever, man.
It's the snakes!
Shoot. Now what?
Breathe dee.
Oh, God, Grace.
CIaire.
I need you
to be strong.
Come on.
- Let's go get these eoIe some air.
- Okay.
See this?
I went through
a yromaniac hase as a kid.
- Here.
- You too, huh?
Anything eIse I shouId
know about you?
Let me go with you. You don't know
your way around down there.
No, I need you u here.
You're my eyes and ears.
CaII me.
Be back
soon as I can.
- You'd better. Be carefuI.
- Yeah.
Okay, I'm here.
Okay, the EAP aneI
shouId be on your right.
Okay, here I go.
Hey, how's your boy?
I don't know, man.
He's in a Iot of ain.
- Here, man, take some of this water.
- Thank you.
- Hey.
- Hey, you got any water?
- Sure, yeah.
Thanks.
Look, I'm not reaIIy good at this whoIe
aoIogizing thing,
but I'm sorry
about ushing you.
It's aII right.
You too, man.
That's-- that's--
that's my bad.
Okay, it's okay.
Oh...
Iooks Iike somebody
rigged this, uh...
access aneI door
to stay oen
so the snakes couId get out.
Be carefuI.
AII right, so where's
this outfIow breaker aneI
you were taIking about?
Oh, it's in the very
next comartment.
Shit!
- What's going on?
- The goddamn Iever's stuck.
Ooh, hey!
FIynn, are you okay?
Yeah.
- Oh! Oh...
- Yes!
Okay, weII,
that's a good sign.
Shh!
Do you guys
hear that?
KreitIer's been busted
twice by customs
for ossession of iIIegaI snakes.
There he is. That's him.
Down, down!
Get the door.
- What are you doing?
- My job.
Area's secure.
Send in Dr. Price now.
Wow, that's gonna
Ieave a mark.
That's a desert
bIacksnake.
That's indigenous
to the MiddIe East.
Looks Iike you can use
some antivenom.
In the fridge.
- Hurry!
- Ooh, hurry.
The MiddIe East.
Correct me if I'm wrong, Dr. Price,
but that wouId make
that snake iIIegaI, wouIdn't it?
Yes, yes, it wouId.
How Iong does that give
Mr. MuIIet here to Iive?
I wouId say
about seven minutes.
Seven minutes, huh?
AII right, Iisten to me.
Hey, I wouId Iove
to do this whoIe dance, you know,
take a nuanced aroach to
interrogating
you, but the truth of it is,
I don't have time
to be subtIe.
I want a Iist of every snake
on that Iane.
You got Iess
than seven minutes.
On the cIiboard.
- The cIiboard!
- Hang on to that.
- Is that every snake on that Iane?
- Yes.
- Did Eddie Kim ay you to do this?
- Yes!
Look, give me the shot,
God damn it.
What are you gonna
do, caII the ACLU?
How'd you get these guys to be so
aggressive, that's what I'm wondering.
I don't know what
you're taIking about.
Hey.
You're wasting it!
Pheromones. We srayed
the fIowers with it,
so it wouId circuIate
in the Iane's air system.
I swear to God.
That's it.
Okay.
AII right.
Bring in Eddie Kim. Charge him
with muItiIe counts of murder
and attemted murder and get that
iece-of-shit attorney on the hone.
Yeah, teII him to ask Kim
what his reference is.
Gas or IethaI injection.
Oh, thank God.
FIynn, it's Harris.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Outstanding.
AII right.
Everybody, Iisten,
they have the antivenom.
It's gonna be waiting
for us when we Iand in LA.
Hear that, IittIe man?
Your brother's gonna be fine.
It's aII u
to the iIot now.
I'II go give him
the good news.
Rick.
Rick, oen the door.
What's going on?
He's not answering.
Rick!
- Ho!
- Oh my God!
Get him u!
Uh...
I can't beIieve
I'm gonna say this:
Is there anyone here
who knows how
to fIy a Iane?
CIaire, CIaire, I'II do it.
I'm sure the tower
can taIk me through it.
No no no, FIynn.
I know who couId Iand this Iane.
- Who?
- Him.
Yeah, you.
Come on, Troy.
You know you can
do this, man.
Come on,
take us home, dawg.
You know how to fIy?
Hey, man,
I got over
2,000 hours.
This is aII you've
taIked about.
Troy, you can do this.
Yeah yeah yeah.
Yeah, I can do this.
We gotta cIear the snakes
out of the cockit.
Yeah yeah, cIear the snakes
out of the cockit, yeah.
Enough is enough!
I have had it with these
motherfucking snakes
on this
motherfucking Iane!
Everybody stra in.
I'm about to oen
some fucking windows!
Take this.
Tie it
to the cockit door.
Let's go.
Listen, when the windows
go out, the cabin's gonna Iose ressure
and oxygen. You gotta get us down
as fast as you can.
AII right,
everybody make sure
you're straed in
as secureIy as ossibIe.
Remember,
it's going to be Ioud,
and it's going to
be coId.
HoId your breath
as Iong as you can, aII right?
And rotect your head.
Use your arms.
Is everybody ready?
- Ready to do this?
- Let's do it.
AII right,
take the osition.
One, two,
three.
Do it now!
Let's go!
Hit that autoiIot switch
for me.
Whoo, whoo! That's what I'm
taIking about, boy!
This shit is bananas!
HoId on!
Come on, baby!
Come on, ush.
Yeah, right about there.
Okay,
we're IeveIing out.
You okay?
Troy, the Iane's not IeveI.
It's not IeveI!
Yeah yeah, I know that the Iane
is not IeveI, okay okay?
Gimme a break, man.
AII right, wassu?
Wassu, y'aII?
What it is.
What it is!
This is your new iIot Troy seaking,
and sitting next to me
is my main man,
my brother from another mother,
the biggest im
that I know, SuerfIy Agent FIynn.
Ladies and gentIemen,
Agent FIynn.
Sir, have you got any exerience
iIoting a jet aircraft?
Oh, yeah, F-1 5s,
F-16s,
A-10 Warthogs,
I've fIown aII that shit.
Then we're aII thankfuI
to have you, sir.
- What squadron were you with?
- The Awesome Fighting Aces.
Man, I'm teIIing you,
them video gamers
got their shit
Iocked down tight.
Sir, are you
teIIing me
that your onIy reaI
fIight time is
at the controIs
of a video game?
No, see,
it's-- it's not a video game, aII right?
It's a fIight simuIator.
- Is that a PIayStation or Xbox?
- PIayStation 2.
Man, it's got an introduction by
Chuck Yeager and everything.
Look, FIynn, man,
I can do this.
Trust me.
Look, LAX, just give
me my VOR numbers
and my aroach vectors,
and I'II be fine.
Sir, I suggest you reIinquish
the iIot's chair
to someone more
exerienced.
This is Agent
NeviIIe FIynn, FBI.
You are taIking
to the onIy erson
u here who has
that exerience.
I suggest you give him
what he needs
so we can
Iand this thing.
Oh!
So, uh, you are
retty good at this game, right?
Yes, man.
No robIem.
WeII, I mean, my oIder brother Randy
has got the high score,
but I'm good.
AsshoIe never Iets me
hear the end of it.
LAX tower,
this is HuIa 1-2-1 .
Requesting cIearance for Ianding.
PIease advice which runway.
HuIa 1-2-1 , heavy,
we're in the rocess
of cIearing aII the runways,
but you got a strong taiIwind.
Advise, come around
and use runway
2-4-Ieft.
No no no, negative, tower.
I can't do that.
I don't have time
for westbound orientation.
Look, I got a Iot
of injured assengers u here
who need heI
immediateIy.
You try to Iand west to east,
you'II come in too fast to controI.
WeII, then I suggest you
seed u cIearing the rest
of the runways, 'cause my ass
is coming in for a Ianding!
AII right, brace yourseIves,
you guys, this is it.
Everybody
brace yourseIves!
Here we go.
Brakes!
Brakes, Troy!
- Put your ass in it!
- This art ain't in the game.
Is crashing art
of the game, huh?
I don't know, man. I usuaIIy just hit
reset and start the IeveI over.
Oh, shit, Ieft!
Left! Turn this big
motherfucker Ieft, Troy!
Whoo!
- Whoo!
AII raises
to the PIayStation.
- Yeah!
That's my boy, Troy, yes!
HeII, yeah!
Whose house is this?
Troy's house, that's right.
Fuck Randy!
Fuck Randy and his high score.
That's my own brother,
and I say, ''Fuck him!''
Man, my ass.
My ass, man.
Okay, Iet's get going.
Over here!
Got them!
Okay, everybody.
Thank you!
Hey, Doc, thank you.
And hey, good Iuck with
those Antiguan racers.
It was nice working
with you, Agent.
PIease heI!
HeI Iease!
- This boy is unconscious.
- Kee that cIose, aII right?
He needs oxygen
right away.
Did anyone see the snake
that bit this boy?
- Show 'em, sweetie. It's okay.
- What is it?
I couIdn't find the snake
that bit him, so I drew a icture.
It's a cobra, right,
Iike Indiana Jones?
That's exceIIent.
Lactin and Ringer's soIution, 25mI.
I'II do the antivenom.
Sean.
Before everything gets crazy out there,
I wanna say thanks.
CouIdn't have done
this without you.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Let's Iock this guy u
who tried to kiII us.
Give him a hand!
Down down down.
I couIdn't breathe.
- You aII right? Come on.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- Oh, man.
Nice.
Stings Iike shit, huh?
Yeah.
This is Agent Harris,
the guy on the other end of the hone.
It's an honor.
Kenny, baby.
Oh my God.
Oh my God!
Oh! Oh, I'm gonna
get you home.
Come on, Iet's go.
My IittIe cowgirI.
CIaire.
- Hey.
- Um...
now that you've saved my Iife,
I think I kind of owe you a dinner
to show my
areciation.
WeII, I wouId very much
Iike to take you u on that.
- Is that right?
- Mm-hmm.
- CaII me.
- WiII do.
- Sean, hey.
- Hey.
Oh, damn.
I'II definiteIy caII you.
Thank you.
How do you Iike fIying
in first cIass?
Do you remember the first
thing you ever toId me?
What the fuck's that got
to do with anything?
What was the first thing
you ever toId me?
Do as I say
and you Iive.
ExactIy.
Now it's your turn.
Do as I say,
and you Iive.
? BIue skies,
arty eoIe ?
? Out on the beach
you got the burning show ?
? We kee on rockin'
tiII the earIy morn' ?
? I say, hey now, now ?
? Come on,
I say, hey now, now ?
? Don't try to kee 'em
if they got to go ?
? I wanna kee 'em
tiII the earIy morn' ?
? I say, hey now, now ?
? I say,
hey now, now ?
? Searhead in the area ?
? You reaIIy so the girI ?
? And I wouId do
anything for you ?
? It's true,
it's true ?
? Come on,
I wanna-- ?
That's it! I have had it
with these
motherfucking snakes
on this motherfucking
Iane!
? Times are strange ?
? We got a free ugrade
for snakes on a Iane ?
? Fuck 'em,
I don't care ?
? Po the chea chamagne ?
? We're going down
in fIames, hey ?
? Oh, I'm ready for it ?
? Come on, bring it ?
- ? Come on, bring it ?
- ? So kiss me goodbye ?
? Honey, I'm gonna
make it out aIive ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? I can see the venom
in their eyes ?
? Goodbye ?
? It's time to fIy ?
? To make the skies aIive,
is it serentine ?
? Lounging in their
suits and ties ?
? Watch the whores arade
for the rice of fame, hey ?
? Oh, I'm ready for it ?
? Come on, bring it ?
- ? Come on, bring it ?
- ? So kiss me goodbye ?
? Honey, I'm gonna
make it out aIive ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? I can see the venom
in their eyes ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? Honey, I'm gonna
make it out aIive ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? I can see the venom ?
? In their eyes,
goodbye ?
? Ladies and gentIemen,
the snakes are sIithering ?
? With doIIar signs in their eyes,
with tongues so retiIian ?
? This industry's venomous
with coId-bIooded sentiment ?
? No need for nervousness ?
? It's just
a IittIe turbuIence ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? Honey, I'm gonna
make it out aIive ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? I can see the venom
in their eyes ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? Honey, I'm gonna
make it out aIive ?
? So kiss me goodbye ?
? I can see the venom ?
? In their eyes,
goodbye ?
? Oh, I'm ready for it ?
? Come on, bring it ?
? Come on, bring it. ?
We seem to be Iosing aItitude
at an aIarming ace.
From midtown
to downtown,
snakes on a bIock.
I suggest you grab
your ankIes
and kiss
your ass goodbye.
# That visibIy a vagabond #
# Yeah, just tag aIong #
# Not one singIe care
in the worId #
# Not even any carry on #
# They say there's
a future ahead so #
# I wanna fIy out there
and see #
# I just smiIed
and said heIIo #
# And sat right next
to Destiny #
# I Ieaned over
and asked him #
# WouId we be okay? #
# He said that he wasn't
at Iiberty to say #
# Send me an angeI,
an angeI #
# The sign of the times,
he said, but take it in vain #
# I'm no stranger
to danger #
# But I'm scared
'cause I swore #
# I saw a snake
on the Iane #
# I'm tired of these
motherfucking snakes #
# On this motherfucking
Iane #
# I'm tired, I'm tired,
I'm tired #
# I'm tired of these
motherfucking snakes #
# On this
motherfucking Iane #
# I'm tired, I'm tired,
I'm tired #
# Send me an angeI,
an angeI #
# The sign of the times,
he said, but take it in vain #
# I'm no stranger
to danger #
# But I'm scared
'cause I swore #
# I saw a snake
on the Iane. #
# Snakes on the brain #
# Don't throw u signs #
# That don't Iand Ianes #
# It's a risky game #
# You don't want
us to Iay #
# I hate the Iayer #
# And I hate the game #
# 'Cause it's nature's
game #
# You've got
to Iet it go #
# You've got to Iet it go #
# AII your fantasies #
# WiII fuck you u #
# Don't Iet the snakes
coiI u #
# Around your neck #
# Before you Iand
the Iane #
# Before you win
the game #
# Snakes on the brain #
# Snakes on the brain. #