(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Parental guidance is advised.)
(This program includes virtual and indirect advertisements.)
Subtitles by OnDemandKorea
While top representatives from each country...
were convening at the UN to discuss global peace-keeping and security,
despite the lack of any official recognition,
the self-appointed G's from around the world...
are convening for the peace-keeping and security of global youths,
hence the Non-Summit Meeting.
We shall begin the session.
I'm the Chairman of Non Summit Meeting, Jun Hyun-moo.
I'm Secretary General Yoo Se-yoon.
- I'm Chairman Sung Si-kyung. We are Junyoosung! - We are Junyoosung!
(Welcome representatives.)
Now it's time for our Non Summit Meeting representatives...
to discuss global issues and share their diverse opinions.
It's time to discuss various issues. It's Global Side Dishes Time. What's important?
(Global Side Dishes Time, What is Important?)
- That was fresh. - Was it okay?
Let's go!
This is the issue brought up by the US representative.
From the Friday of the fourth week of November every year,
the massive sales event,
Black Friday begins.
On this day most items in the stores...
can be purchased 80 to 90 percent cheaper.
For people who love to shop, they wait every year for this day.
But from another angle, it has become controversial...
because it causes people to purchase unnecessary products.
I would like to ask all of you for your opinions on this matter.
So, I bring this issue to you.
The phrase "Black Friday" has become a word we use in Korea as well.
How did this shopping event first start?
In the US, when a company makes a profit,
it is represented with a black line on the sheet.
If however, it the company is making a loss, it is represented by a red line.
Let's say your company was making a loss,
but as soon as we enter the month of November, the holiday shopping season starts...
so the company starts to go from red to black.
- That's what it means. - Right, the company makes a profit.
From the consumer's perspective, since you are buying at a cheap price, it's good.
Also sellers can promote their sales.
- Because of this people purchase items they don't need. - Since it is cheap.
It is cheap. This is becoming a controversial topic.
We would like to ask you all for your thoughts on this.
Does Black Friday help stimulate the economy?
Or does it just promote excessive consumption?
Does it help the economy? Press the button in 1, 2, 3.
(Helps the economy 6, Excessive spending 5)
I don't know if it helps the economy but it does certainly help me.
- Of course. Everything is on sale. - It's because,
let's say I was in the desert,
if there was a sign that said there was water to the right 1km away,
And if there was a sign pointing the other way that said there was a sale 2km away.
I'd head towards the sale.
You'd rather head towards the sale than water in the desert?
- That's excessive. - Because I'm a shopaholic.
- I think you are too excessive. - But Indian people,
don't like buying expensive items, we like to buy things at a low price...
and brag about it.
This is just...
- an event to create excessive spending. - That is true.
Companies need to make sales, right?
There are so many ways that they could create sales.
They could have a great promotion.
They could promote values and promote their sale.
Or they could just promote it like, "It's a sale. It's cheap."
- But... - Hold on a moment.
Let's say this normally costs 200 dollars...
- but they sell it for 80 dollars and people buy it. - That's smart not stupid.
Hold on a second. Does that make sense?
When an item that normally costs 100 dollars and...
then they sell it for 20 dollars during the sale.
From the perspective of the consumer, don't you feel like you've been made a fool?
- How would the people who paid the full price feel? - Exactly.
I feel like this event has no value.
There are so many other ways to create more sales.
You could have a promotion.
I would like to say something. If you have a promotion,
then I can't buy that 1,000 dollar TV.
If that 1,000 dollar TV drops to 200 dollars, than I can buy it.
Would I buy it? Of course I would.
Because of that...
- That's a unique way of talking. - Normally,
- "Would I buy it? Of course I would." - "Of course I would."
- Normally people say they wouldn't buy it. - Right.
- I... - I'll try that way of talking some day.
(He tricked them with the way he spoke.)
What I would like to say is,
this is good for people who are not able to afford the items they wanted.
It's a chance for them to buy these products as well.
It's a good thing for a lot of people.
- Right. - Also, even if it is a product that they no longer make,
the sale of those products does help the economy.
This is a marketing technique, right?
- It's profitable for them, that's why they do it. - Right.
Spending does rise during this time.
But when the sale ends, people no longer purchase it, right?
If that happens, it will cause a big drop in sales afterward.
I don't know if this would be a big help for the economy.
People believe just saving money is not financially meaningful.
Like Black Friday,
you have Christmas and Valentine's Day,
you buy presents on that day, right?
The reason we do that is to help the circulation of money, right?
- Circulation? - Circulation of money.
- Circulation of money. - It's to help that, right?
I mean, well...
What was his name?
(Aurélien didn't know Christian's name.)
- He's boiling with rage. - He looks so angry.
- No, he did it on purpose. - No, I mean...
- Aurélien, how could you forget? - He did that on purpose.
- He did that on purpose. - Call him the representative for Mexico.
Just call him Mexico.
- No, don't do that. - Christian.
In our world, our natural resources...
are not infinite.
We'll run out. Therefore, if people...
keep consuming things,
we could go over that limit.
- Because it is cheap. - Swiss riches wouldn't mind sale events like this, right?
"I can just purchase it anytime."
- Well... - You can just purchase things at their original price.
What is there to worry about?
It feels like they are promoting consumerism.
If I want to buy something, I can just purchase it. That part is true.
I feel it is a bad habit to purchase something that you don't need.
That's why I would like events...
like Black Friday to disappear.
He doesn't need them.
Do we really need a day like this?
That is something that we agonize over a lot about.
Because, let's say it's Thanksgiving Day on Thursday,
and Black Friday is the next day.
Black Friday is sandwiched between the holiday and the weekend.
You should be spending that day with your family.
But instead of doing that, you go out to do shopping.
Because of this, the department stores can't close on that day.
The staff has to come out and work on that day.
- They can make money. - They're making money.
That depends on what you value more.
For Mark, he believes his family is more important.
But you just want to purchase items at a cheap price.
- Did you say you? - I mean...
That's what I think.
He's a good speaker.
- He is really good at offending people. - He makes people angry.
Since this causes people to act like this,
- it causes conflict. - You're right.
Or this TV has been discounted by 80 percent but there are only 2 of them.
So you fight with someone for the last one. Do we really need to do that?
(Go away! That one is mine!)
(In some cases, this leads to fights...)
(or they use weapons and cause a bigger fight.)
(Using an electric stun gun)
You've only seen this on TV, right? I've actually been in a fight like that.
I fought with someone and bought products.
- In China... - Wang Xinlin got into a fight?
I went shopping with my mom when they were having a big sale.
Before we went, my mom and I divided up what we needed to buy.
- You had a plan. - Yes. We'll go in like this and by getting into fights...
you create lovely family memories.
(This is like memories of a war.)
What is that?
(Isn't it true?)
- It's a beautiful memory. - So by fighting,
- you are making family bonds. - You fight together.
You're in like a war zone with your mom.
- Do you think it would have been fun? - Of course it was.
- Go to Jeju Island with your family. - That's awesome.
- You could make great family memories there. - No, was it good memories?
Yes, I was talking on the phone with my mom yesterday,
and I asked her what she would buy this year. She said it's no fun without me.
"We had fun having fights like that."
- This is how you make good memories. -Yes.
When did this happen? When did you make these memories with your mom?
In China, we have a big sale on November 11th,
This is Chinese Black Friday. There are four ones on that date.
So, we call it a day for single people.
"Single people, don't stay at home."
"Console yourself by shopping at stores or online."
- That's a weird event. - Console yourselves by shopping.
- That's strange. - It first formally began in 2009.
Normally products are discounted from 50 to 70 percent off.
On November 11th this year,
the amount of money that was spent was close to 18 billion dollars.
- The sales. - It was over 100 million dollars?
- Wow. - Wow.
If you are a second late online, then the product you want will disappear.
- You have to click very fast. - I was in Korea last year, right?
The internet in Korea is very fast.
- Did you purchase anything? - Yes. So, when I clicked on a product,
- I wouldn't miss it. - What did you buy?
I bought all the tools you need to make cookies.
They put everything on sale.
Do you have a special day for shopping in your country?
In France, we have a special period for sales...
but the country decides when the sale starts.
They decide when it ends as well.
So for six weeks starting from January,
and during July for six weeks, that when we have our sales.
Boxing Day is a bigger sales day than Black Friday.
It's something that country's in the Commonwealth celebrates.
During the Middle Ages, the servants received their presents...
in boxes from their masters.
That was the day after Christmas Day.
We call it Boxing Day because they received their gifts in boxes.
(I see.)
- That's why it's called Boxing Day. - Yes.
We have it in Canada.
All the Commonwealth Nations celebrate that day.
- Boxing Day. - That's why we prefer that day.
It's a better day to go shopping.
It has nothing to do with boxing. In India we have a celebration called Diwali.
If you purchase products made from gold or that are stainless steel...
they say you'll have good luck.
During this period, they give out discounts for gold and stainless steel products.
In the US we don't need Black Friday...
because we have a sale every day.
There is always a sale of some kind.
Online stores have a day called Cyber Monday.
There is an after Christmas sale.
We have Columbus Day sale, Martin Luther King Day Sale,
and Mother's Day and Father's Day sale.
We have a sale every month.
We don't need to have Black Friday.
In Japan we have a new event called Premium Friday.
It will start around the end of February next year.
- It hasn't started yet? - No. But it's going to start soon.
Usually we leave the office around 6pm.
But we'll be able to get off 3 hours earlier.
- So that we can start shopping earlier. - I see.
That's the intention, but it's facing strong public criticism.
Currently, people's wage and salary are not that high.
How can we spend money when we don't have enough money?
Also, the sales clerks would have to keep working.
So many people are against this idea, and we need to wait and see.
During the Ramadan period, Pakistanis...
- are on fast from morning to evening. - Right.
We can start eating after 8pm.
After that, food and ingredients are on massive sale.
During the period, we can eat luxurious dishes we couldn't afford throughout the year.
- Interesting. - Yes.
But there are certain accidents during Black Friday periods.
Are there issues that stirred controversies during such sale period?
There's "Buen fin" in Mexico.
It means "good weekend".
The sale is held on weekend, and it falls on the same day as Black Friday.
But it was found that before the Buen Fin period, some stores in Mexico...
intentionally raise the prices of their goods...
by 10 to 32 percent.
- They raise the price in advance. - Yes.
So that they can sell the products at their original prices even during the sale.
That's what happened. It was quite controversial.
- The biggest issue in China is delivery service. - Delivery.
It's expected that more than one billion parcels will be delivered this year.
- The number of parcels exceeds one billion? - Yes.
It's one billion.
The huge amount of parcels has been a big headache.
Last year, one of the delivery trucks had a traffic accident...
while it was delivering the parcels and 4,000 parcels were burnt.
One incident attracted people's attention last year in Italy.
One store put up a banner which says "Sale You've Never Seen"...
in front of the store. It was very big.
The problem was, they used the picture of Andrea Bocelli, who's visually impaired.
- Oh no. - It stirred a huge controversy.
Some said the banner depreciated people with visual impairment.
Moreover, they didn't pay Andrea Bocelli for using his picture.
They used his picture for free.
What strange people.
Arguments over sale are quite common and frequent in the US.
But last year's popular products were a bit controversial.
- They were guns. - Guns?
The daily gun sales...
hit a new record.
Some questioned "Do we really have to buy guns on Black Friday?"
That's absurd.
- It shouldn't be allowed. - I agree.
But we have nothing to do with Black Friday.
It takes place in the US.
So many non-Americans try to buy things through online cross-border shopping.
Despite the complex purchase process, many Koreans do this because of price advantage.
They're called cross-border shoppers.
Many celebrities love it, too.
- They can buy clothes and designer goods not available in Korea. - Right, we can't buy them here.
- Or things that are cheaper. - That's good.
Will you do cross-border shopping if it's cheaper though it's cumbersome?
Or do you want to buy things locally because you need to check it out yourself even though...
it's more expensive that way?
Who are cross-border shopper? In 1,2,3.
- Only four raised their hands. - It's no wonder.
We're living in the era of smartphones and world wide Internet.
It's ridiculous there are still people who don't try cross-border shopping.
But if you buy things based on their pictures only,
- you might be cheated. - Listen.
- True. - Hold on.
Why would I be cheated?
It could be because of my personality.
I feel it's safer only when I see and touch it myself.
It's a personality problem.
- No, it's not a problem. - No, it's not.
If you buy things online, there could be a size issue.
- Or you might not like it. - You can check them out in the stores first.
I tried that myself. I went to the store and checked the product.
And I ordered a pair of shoes and they were delivered.
They didn't fit my feet, and what's worse, even the size of right and left shoe was different.
- How's that possible? - One of them was 250mm but the other wasn't.
That can happen if you shopping at a strange online mall.
- Yes, Alberto's right. - No.
You can do cross-border shopping if you don't really have to check the product.
But you have to use reliable online stores.
- There are online shopping scams. - Can't you get a refund or return the product?
I can, but it will take so much time.
- It's annoying. - It's irritating to send it back.
I need to send it back to the seller if there's something wrong.
If I buy things at a store, I can just go back to them.
But if you go to the store in person,
sometimes you end up buying things you don't really need...
- because of persistent sales clerks. - Right.
- In case of online shopping... - True.
It's like "You look so great in this suit."
- I don't believe it. - It's the last piece we have.
I can read his face. He already decided to buy.
(You can't resist the last piece.)
We cannot resist the "last one".
It's not only about delivery. When I order something,
because I'm not good at English,
it's very stressful to do shopping at English websites.
- The stress is huge. - They offer Japanese language support, too.
Just one wrong click could cost you a lot of money.
As I'm not that fluent in English,
if I make an order mistake,
or click on something wrong, it may result in a loss of money.
Or buying a wrong product.
But you can take your time browsing the process.
No, online shopping in Korea is very complicated.
- ISP and everything. - Yes, online shopping is really difficult.
- True. - So hard.
I fill in all the blanks but sometimes it accidentally goes back to the previous page.
It's really annoying.
You need a certificate too.
Yes, authentication certificates.
Even if it's not cross-border shopping, you might be fooled if you buy things only based on their pictures.
I went to a burger place a few days ago.
There was a big signboard.
It has a picture of a gigantic and mouth-watering burger.
It looked so delicious and I ordered one. But the burger served was tiny, like this.
- Don't exaggerate. - You can't feed a fly with it.
I'm telling the truth.
Isn't it the size of a macaroon?
Or "I love you"?
(Satisfied)
- It was different from the picture. - I felt like cheated.
Let me take an example of my own experience.
I need a product that I used to use back in Germany...
but find it's too expensive in Korea.
I already know how much they actually are in my home country.
Products he has used before.
Even if you see a product with your own eyes in a store,
you could be cheated.
- The sales clerk will lure you to buy it. - Exactly.
If you really want to know about the products, you can go to a review website.
People who have used the product will recommend you the best one.
Review comments are important.
But I'd like to tell you...
reviews by purchasers are mostly fake in China.
- Really? - Yes. They just repeat the same words.
"I love it. I'll buy it again."
"I love it. I'll buy it again." These kinds of comments are repeatedly found.
Seasoned shoppers can tell the difference.
Then can you please talk about products you personally bought through cross-border shopping?
- What did you buy? - About 10 years ago,
when I was working hard on my diet,
I wanted to buy some good vitamin supplements but I was totally ignorant.
So I searched the Internet, and fount a research lab...
that buys vitamins themselves and studies the ingredients...
themselves.
I bought their products.
I lost seven kilograms in a month and my skin got a lot better.
Were you part of their clinical test?
No, it must've been a corporate event.
Hang on. I really mean it.
Why don't you try them with my body?
It's nothing like that.
Is your picture posted on their website?
No.
Like a model.
Look at how I've changed.
Do I sound like promoting the website?
- I'm talking from my personal experience. - All right.
- I'll check it out. - Good.
What I saw on the TV before I came to Korea was...
so many Korean people wearing stadium jackets.
I thought it must be a really cool and popular product there.
So I went to Alibaba in China,
and tried cross-border shopping.
The seller said he could send it to me...
via international mail. So I decided to buy it.
When when the parcel arrived, I found it was sent somewhere in China.
It wasn't international delivery.
I haven't tried it myself, but...
many Mexicans just go to the US for shopping.
Now you need to climb up a wall to go there.
You should learn wall-climbing for shopping.
Climbing.
Maybe it's not possible anymore.
Top three US products favored by Mexicans are...
clothes, latest models of mobile phones, and...
cosmetic products.
They are top three.
It's because they are way cheaper in the US than Mexico.
In case of clothes, there are a wide variety of brands in the US.
You can just enter the US on foot.
People living in northern Mexico,
which is very close to the Mexico-US border, can walk to the US for shopping.
Look at Mark. His expression says you can't go there on foot.
I'm not sure if you can do that in future as well.
We can build a tunnel then.
I'm worried that you'd make fun of me if you listen to my shopping story.
Does it look like this?
- Come on. - I bought it from the US.
No, it's not white porcelain this time.
It's a set of sumaksae made in the era of Three Kingdoms.
- What did you say? - Sumaksae.
- They are circular convex roof-end tiles with a flower or dragon design. - I see.
- But... - Where did you buy it?
An American had 23 of those tiles...
Did you buy them in the US?
Why did that person hold them in the States?
There are antique collectors.
They collect precious artifacts.
He's one of those collectors living in the US.
I feel sorry that such artifact of great historical value is held...
in the US, not Korea. I felt it isn't right.
- I wanted to buy and return it to Korea. - But it must've come with...
- a hefty price tag. - Yes.
He redeemed Korea's cultural asset.
I bought all 23 of them.
Did you buy them all?
He has to be realistic.
How much did you pay to him?
- I can't tell you. - You can't?
- He's not going to tell. - Why?
As I could buy them only in the States,
- I had to purchase them online. - All right.
I don't really need cross-border shopping.
Since my mother is a flight attendant,
- she travels all over the world. - Right.
Your mom is a cross-border shopper.
She can buy anything herself.
So you should treat me well from now on.
If you want to buy something, I'll ask my mother.
I see.
- I need to get along with him. - Do you have...
any shopping tips that you want to share with others?
Let's share shopping tips that only you know.
Let me share a shopping tip you can use in the States.
I had lived in New York before I came to Korea.
The biggest department store in New York is called Macy's.
It's in midtown, Manhattan.
There's an information desk you can't easily find on the second floor.
If you're foreigners or from other cities of America,
they'll give you 10 percent discount coupons after checking your passport.
- It's hidden on the second floor. Not many people know about this. - I see.
They'll give you coupons after checking your passport.
There's a shopping tip I know.
I live in Mok-dong. When I go to Omokgyo department store,
- on every Friday, Saturday and Sunday, - Omokgyo?
they offer huge discounts on designer brands.
They often offer discounts up to 70 or 80 percent.
So I bought a 200-dollar item for only 30 dollars.
When you go to department stores,
it's hard to receive discounts on your purchase.
Then you should go shopping at the end of the month.
Every company sets...
their sales target every month.
Every employee also has to achieve their sales target.
- At the end of the month... - They have to meet their sales target.
That's right.
- You'll find sales staff who are working really hard. - At the end of the month?
Hard-working staff at the end of the month?
It's a great tip.
In Pakistan, there's no fixed price.
So depending on how well you negotiate, the price varies.
There's no fixed price?
There are some shops that go by fixed prices.
But most of the stores don't sell things by fixed prices.
So if you look rich,
the seller will try to double the price.
So don't take a shower after you get up.
- To look poor? - That's right.
- Try to look poor. - You need to have a runny nose.
If they say the price is 100 dollars,
- Negotiate from 50 dollars? - You should negotiate from 50 dollars.
Then you'll be able to buy it at around 70 dollars.
It's a war of nerves. You have to negotiate really well.
- Right. - You can't just go there and buy things at half the price.
I once tried to purchase Jordan shoes in China.
They were promoting it as limited edition.
They said it's 300 dollars.
The person who was standing next to me said 300 dollars is way too expensive.
He said...
- Half the price. - I should knock the price down to half the price.
He said he'll sell it for 250 dollars, but I knocked the price down to 100 dollars.
(I won't sell it then.)
He looked really upset.
- Then the person next to me said, "Pretend you're leaving." - Right.
- So I left. - You have to pretend you're leaving.
I walked about 20m, then the seller said...
(All right. Come back.)
So I bought it for 100 dollars.
- If your looked back after walking 19m... - But the thing is...
the person next to me bought it for 20 dollars.
- Wow. - So we assign roles when I go shopping with my mom.
My mom would go, "This one looks nice."
then I'd say, "Mom, I don't like it. I'll never wear it."
My mom would say, "It looks good on you."
Is this the happy memory you had with your mother?
- You have many good memories. - Actually, we were able to knock the price down.
We bought it at a lower price.
There's a way you can get a discount in Korea.
If you tell old ladies...
how pretty they are,
- they'll really like it and... - Gosh.
You're too old-fashioned.
Goodness.
- That's such an old method. - Also,
if you sing a trot song...
for the old ladies,
they'll love it.
What kind of trot songs did you sing?
On that green meadow
- I sing this song. - I really want to give you a discount.
- I know. - Perhaps they just want you to leave.
When I was a student,
my friends and I used to get a discount after singing a song.
- What if you can't sing? - We sang this song.
All I can give you
- Is three dollars - Just take it.
- He only had three dollars. - It's...
I'm serious.
My foreign friends came with me and sang a song for them,
so they liked us a lot.
That's one way you can get a discount.
- All right. - People say merchants never sell things below cost.
But I have to say it's important...
to make a purchase wisely.
- Yes. - I wish the sellers and buyers will both continue...
to benefit from the purchases they make.
- Okay. Let's move on to "What Is So Important". - Yes.
Let's invite the Korean representative to the show.
(Siren sound)
- Are you sick? - He's from the emergency room.
Om Mani padme hum.
He is Goong In who diagnoses patients, not Gung Ye.
He's an emergency physician, Namgoong In.
Doctor Namgoong In.
(The 125th Korean representative is Namgoong In.)
Welcome.
Hello.
(A doctor who records the boundary between life and death)
(Emergency physician, Namgoong In)
For the first time in our show's history,
we have a guest whose profession is doctor.
Please introduce yourself.
I'm an emergency physician.
I published my essays a while ago.
I'm currently working as a medical essayist. I'm Namgoong In.
(Welcome)
- Good to see you. - When we think of emergency rooms,
we think about resident doctors or young doctors...
who work hard at night.
It's a major, right?
Yes, it's a major, and I'm an emergency physician.
- I see. - That's me.
It must be a difficult job. What's good about this major?
It's a profession which you have to take care of patients,
24 hours, 7 days a week at the emergency room.
As a doctor, it's really difficult.
But you get to help and treat the patients...
when they're in emergency situations,
so it's a rewarding job.
That's what's good about this major.
This is the 125th Non Summit Meeting. We will now begin our discussion.
Namgoong In, what's the topic you'd like to discuss today?
I'm an emergency physician with eight years of experience,
who has to make fast and wise decisions.
That's why I brought this topic today.
"Sometimes, emotional feelings come before rational decisions."
"Am I abnormal?"
It's a question that doctors will feel differently.
- For us, it's a different question. - Yes.
I wouldn't like doctors without emotions.
I wouldn't like emotional doctors...
who'd shake their hands out of frustration.
I don't want them to look after me.
You're going to get a shot.
It's going to hurt a lot.
(It will hurt a lot.)
Sometimes, emotional feelings come first, depending on the situation.
Do you tend to get emotional?
As for me, emotional feelings tend to come first.
There was this one particular patient who made me really emotional.
He was a man in his 50s.
He tried to kill himself by taking drugs.
Fortunately, he didn't take too much drugs.
He was willing to live after he woke up.
He was very cooperative and even received psychiatric treatments.
So I told him to live his life and encouraged him.
After two hours, a dead person had arrived at the emergency room.
I was told he fell from the seventh floor.
When I looked at his face, it was the patient who left two hours ago.
He really wanted to die.
So he was acting in front of me.
He was pretending he was okay.
That kind of incident is just...
Also, one of my jobs is...
to evaluate the recordings of 119 rescuers,
when they help out the callers and give medical advice.
To see if they gave the right advice?
Yes, people collapse, right?
If you think about it, it can be one of your family members.
They're near death. It's the worst moment.
You can hear people wailing from the recordings.
People scream, too.
I have to evaluate 100 recordings every month.
So I suffered from insomnia.
It's something you can't feel unemotional about.
Have you ever cried at the emergency room?
I get emotional but...
- You hold it back. - Yes.
Doctors who cry with the patients...
are not actually good doctors. You can't trust them.
You can't cry in front of the patients.
I go to the back of the emergency room and cry.
That's what I do.
- It's a difficult job. - Yes.
"Sometimes, emotional feelings come before rational decisions. Am I abnormal?"
That's today's topic. We will now begin the discussion.
If you think it's abnormal, please press the button.
One, two, three. Press the button.
It's about getting yourself together.
He's saying it's abnormal.
Alberto thinks it's okay.
Doctors and nurses are people, too.
Even the patients are people, right?
When people meet together, you're bound to feel emotions.
We, as patients,
I also prefer doctors who express their emotions...
- to doctors who are cold-hearted. - That's right.
From what I know, they receive a training before they become doctors.
They're taught they can't get emotional about patients.
- Right. - In my opinion, humans have evolved...
and became the wisest animal in the world.
- So I think we're able to control our emotions. - The wisest animal?
It's...
Are you saying Namgoong In isn't wise then?
That's is the reason why...
we can hide and not express our emotions.
When I go to the hospital, I don't expect the doctors to be considerate.
I just want them to treat me well.
I think emotions can make them treat you better.
- Yes. - That's right.
If they want to make you live...
- The doctors... - I mean...
- Oogi, - What?
you can also make mistakes when you get emotional.
Rational decisions and actions...
are more helpful when you try to save a patient's life.
- Is it more important? - That's right.
In emergency rooms,
- doctors have to save lives of the patients urgently. - Yes.
If your decision is delayed a little,
or if you make a wrong decision, you can kill a person.
Doctors will take the responsibility...
until the day they die. They're living with that sense of responsibility.
I agree with Xinlin.
I tend to sympathize with other people often.
So I knew that...
I could never be a doctor.
- Me, too. - You get emotional.
I think you can be a doctor, but you can't be an emergency physician.
People who tend to get emotional...
should avoid certain professions.
For example, the president of United States of America.
- Let's say the president of the US is annoyed, - All right.
and if he's willing to use the nuclear weapons...
You have to be able to control your emotions.
I don't know how the doctors really feel, but from a patient's perspective,
The warmth from a doctor...
can help a little to heal the patient.
The reason for this is, when we got sick as children,
and our mom just patted us on the head.
The fever dropped and we felt safe, right?
If you want to be loved,
you should go to your mom instead of going to see a doctor.
He's a very cold person.
Why would you go to a doctor?
That's true.
Let's say I received treatment and I died while I received it.
And let's say the doctor cried for me.
After that happened, let's say Oogi showed up.
Oogi sees the doctor crying.
Then how would Oogi feel?
Right?
You wouldn't be able to trust him.
I wouldn't mind.
(I'd be okay with that.)
He's in the emergency room, he wouldn't be in the right state of mind.
You just look sick.
I'm too emotional,
so I can't make an objective call on this.
I don't understand that.
When I watch a drama,
I cry like there is no tomorrow.
But I still can make objective decisions.
What kind of decisions do you make while you watch the drama?
I make all kinds of decisions.
Do you cry in another room away from the TV?
Do you cry in a room without a TV?
Now, first of all,
I would like to ask you about how professionals in medicine are perceived.
In China we have the saying, "To help the dying and heal the injured".
What that means is, they heal those who are about to die.
It's a good image.
That's why recently in China,
they showed us videos of doctors working.
It's truly a sad sight.
The doctor comes into the emergency room vomiting blood.
Yes, and the nurses are sick as well.
They also need to have an injection, but they don't have the time.
They get the injection while they eat.
- It's very serious. - It's because there isn't enough nurses.
We don't have enough doctors, either.
According to one survey, there are 2,3 doctors to every 1,000 patients.
It's apparently the worst among all the G7 countries.
- That's way too few. - Yes, so it is a problem.
Normally people think of doctors as...
a male occupation.
Doctors are also seen as rich. What shocked me about nurses in Korea was...
that nurses were perceived negatively in Korea.
In Korea?
- There are discriminated. - Yes, there is a little bit of that.
Nurses are a specialized profession.
Some people treat them badly.
Some people also still refer to them using the old colonial title.
And when female doctors, especially young female doctors,
go to a patient and explain their diagnosis.
The patient listens for a while and then asks when the male doctor arrives.
- Do you mean elderly people? - Yes, some elderly people still act like that.
The gender discrimination in the medical field...
- is a serious problem in our country. - It still is a problem.
We used to have that kind of discrimination in the US as well.
There was of course a little bit of discrimination...
against female nurses.
It is changing. We recently came up with a new title called nurse practitioners.
Nurse practitioner.
They are nurses who are qualified to treat certain medical...
problems without supervision from a doctor.
- They are creating this. - The status of nurses has gone up.
- Yes. - In the case of Mexico,
the cut-line for the university admission of doctors and nurses are the same.
They are the same but the medical techniques...
at Mexico aren't that advanced.
So when people are sick or are in need of surgery,
they go over to the US. They believe...
that their medical hospitals are safer.
- What about in Switzerland? - Switzerland has a very good healthcare system.
So, people have their own personal physician.
(Switzerland's standard is different.)
- It's different. - Switzerland's standard is different.
That's different.
- It's the same in France. - Is that so?
We have a family physician.
We have that as well.
We have that system as well.
- I see. - Do you?
Because...
Is that system only for rich people?
- No. - It's for everyone.
- We have that system as well. - That's the obligation...
of our healthcare system but it is expensive.
You have to about 350 dollars a month.
But the system is great so if you have any problems,
you can just call up your doctor.
That's great.
When you say family doctor, does that mean...
- the doctor only takes care of one family? - No.
This family just calls to the same doctor.
- Yes. - I mean, that doctor...
has his own life as well.
What does the doctor do if the family is healthy?
- That's good for the family. - In Europe,
Italy and Germany both have that system as well.
We don't go to see a doctor that often.
No, we are different.
You have your own personal doctor, and of course it's free.
The country pays for it.
- That's great. - When you're really sick, the doctor will tell you...
- to go to the hospital. - He'll tell you which hospital to go to.
- Right. - They connect you to the hospital.
In Germany, we don't have enough doctors.
Compared to the other countries,
doctors and nurses don't get paid a lot.
So when you are a doctor or a nurse in Germany,
you are seen as doing charity work.
(Doctors are seen as doing charity work.)
Are there any stereotypes then?
- Like... - Right.
I do have a personal prejudice.
I thought that I would never...
get ill. I didn't think I would.
Because you're a doctor.
I asked a doctor that I know about this.
We know people who get ill quite easily.
- Immune system. - Thanks to that our immune system has gotten stronger.
In truth the university hospitals are...
the first to experience the rising viruses in society.
So at first, the people who work there catch all the rising viruses.
Which one is the strongest?
It's like "Superstar Virus".
But as you work there, you get better.
- You don't get sick. - That could happen.
- You become immune. - You don't catch it easily.
They say people with tattoos recover faster.
Is that true?
- Is that true? - They've become immune.
That's what they said.
Because they've had so many wounds.
How often would you have to meet viruses for you to be like that.
In Japan, we have three stereotypes. The first is all doctors are rich.
The second is they are out of their minds.
Because they don't react to seeing blood.
They're out of their minds.
(Dizzy)
I mean, you have to bear those kinds of situations, right?
- Yes. - So, there is that.
The third stereotype is they are erotic.
- Erotic? - Why are doctors erotic?
It's because of adult videos.
- I see. - That's why.
- There are a lot of nurses. - That's right.
(Embarrassed)
Why do those Japanese videos...
- have doctors as the main characters. - Right.
The clothes in the videos are different to the ones in real life, right?
- No, they don't. - Who would wear that?
- Exactly. - It wouldn't be practical.
You seem to know a lot.
How do you know so well?
You must've watched a lot.
How do you know if they're practical or not?
I took a glimpse to see their image.
- As a doctor? - Yes, as a doctor.
- How we are perceived. - Was it for research, then?
- Nurses don't wear skirts. - Exactly.
I don't know how that image came about.
In Mexico, the nurses...
write the prescription down...
with a pen in their own handwriting.
Most of the time, the doctors write the prescriptions hastily,
that the patients worry that the nurses won't be able to read it.
They write it in like an Arabic script.
That's right.
In Mexico, the patients...
need to take it to a pharmacy and pick up the prescription.
- They have to order it themselves. - We don't do that anymore.
This happened to me. Once I couldn't read it...
so I just gave it to the pharmacist.
The pharmacist looked at it.
- "What did he write?" - He didn't know?
In the end, I had to go back to the hospital.
I asked the doctor to write it so it is readable.
This was such a serious problem,
that one person...
made a medical alphabet.
If you look at it, "A" is written like this.
That would be confusing.
(Medical alphabet)
The pharmacist might read it incorrectly and prescribe you the wrong one.
That would be dangerous.
That happened to us as well, but we now type everything out.
They use the mouse and type everything.
Exactly, the Korean system is so convenient.
In the emergency room, we still write everything out by hand.
- It's because you don't have time, right? - Yes.
A person actually took a picture of what the doctor had written down...
and uploaded it to his social media account.
No one could write what he had written.
- Is it the same in China? - Yes, no one could read it.
What is that scribbling?
That's harsh.
That's crossing the line.
- Did someone really do that? - Doctors got fined because of this.
I do have something to make public.
The words that doctors write down...
is not Latin or German,
it's all English. But it's not the handwriting...
they are just writing down the English letters like that.
- Is it because they are in a hurry? - Yes.
The doctors in the US do the same thing.
It's the same in Canada, too.
We can't read what the doctor wrote.
I think it's the same for everywhere around the world.
- It's the same in Italy. - Maybe all doctors have an agreement.
- I mean, it's my native tongue. - Are the doctors showing off?
- Or is it because they are busy? - They write it like that because they're busy.
- So, they're not showing off even a little? - They wrote it very slowly.
They might've been showing off.
(They might have been showing off.)
They wrote it down like that even when it wasn't an emergency.
If we write it in block form, it might be embarrassing for the patient.
In China, when you think of doctors,
the first word we come up with is a red envelope.
We have to pay the doctor first before we are treated.
You have to pay them if you want to be treated properly.
So...
The doctor isn't asking for the money, right?
- But we pay him first. - We hand it to him.
"Please take care of me."
How much do you have to pay him?
My cousin had surgery three years ago.
We paid him around 350 dollars.
Because at that time, I told my aunt not to pay him.
"It's not like he will kill her because we didn't pay him."
I was really angry.
My aunt just said, "You just don't understand yet."
We are asking him to take more care of her in the surgery.
It's to ask the doctor to take more care.
You do have to pay him for that.
Apparently in each country, you have branches of medicine...
that are more popular than others?
Right. It's different in each country.
- It'll be the same in our country as well. - Yes.
- Right. - In Japan,
Internal medicine is the most popular.
According to a survey it was number 1 with 33 percent of the votes.
- Because... - That is fascinating.
(Various medical comics has internal medicine as the theme.)
Internal medicine is the starting point of medicine.
It focuses on everything.
The salary is high so a lot of people are attracted to that.
The branch of medicine that pays the most is the department of ophthalmology.
We're an aging society, a lot of the population has cataract.
- It's an aging society. - A lot of people are affected by that.
They finish the surgery in one day.
The circulation is good like a ramen restaurant.
People come and leave.
Like a restaurant.
They make a lot of money.
You called it a ramen house.
"Like a ramen house."
It's the same with us.
Men select the surgery department while women select internal medicine.
The surgery department requires the doctors to have a lot of endurance.
Women tend to be more detail-orientated.
And you have to be able to a methodical check in internal medicine.
In Korea, surgeons look cool but they don't get paid a lot, right?
Right. So becoming a surgeon is less popular.
Yes, it's becoming less popular.
- What branch makes a lot? - Plastic surgeons.
It's plastic surgeons and dermatologists.
Plastic surgeons and dermatologists.
Internal medicine gets paid a lot as well, right?
- The pay had gone up... - Has it gone down?
but after it had been allowed to be covered by insurance, it dropped.
How much does a doctor in the emergency department make?
The emergency department wasn't popular.
But since we take care of people in pain who come to us,
this is to help improve the people's lives. We're directly...
- connected to that. - Right.
We do receive funding,
so we are just barely able to function.
Why does the popularity drop when it can get covered by insurance?
When that happens the price becomes set.
When it gets covered by insurance,
you can only charge the set price.
In the case of having no insurance liability, it doesn't follow the market.
I see that happening.
What branch is popular in France?
- Internal medicine? - I see.
That's number one.
Dermatology is number two.
Anesthesiology is having a hard time right now.
Because there is a chance that you might kill someone.
- You might kill a patient. - That is a huge risk.
You could kill someone.
- In Italy, anesthesiology is number one. - Why?
It's not that difficult to get into.
And it's easy to get a job after you graduate.
- That's anesthesiology. - You can get a job straight away, right?
Also diagnostic radiology is popular as well.
Surgeons and internal medicine is also popular as well.
- That's similar to Mexico. - Plastic surgeons...
are not even the top 30.
- It's 42nd. - Plastic surgeons.
- Is it because everyone is good-looking? - No, that's not it.
- He's annoying. - I know.
"I don't know why plastic surgery is so popular."
(I don't need it.)
Our hospitals are owned by the nation.
So there aren't many hospitals with a plastic surgery department.
- It's not easy to get a job. - You have to run your own hospital.
Then, you would need capital.
You'd have to pay a lot of taxes as well.
In Germany, we don't have a department for plastic surgery.
We don't even acknowledge it as an occupation.
- We... - You don't acknowledge it as an occupation.
Anyone who has learned how to do that kind of surgery can open a hospital.
In Mexico, the most popular branch of medicine is obstetrics,
pediatrics and anesthesiology.
These three are the most popular in Mexico because of the high birth rate.
- The birth rate is really high so... - because of the birth rate.
it's easy to get a job related to that.
In our country, obstetricians don't get paid that much.
- Right. It's not financially rewarding. - We have a low birth rate.
- What is the emergency room like in your respective countries? - I'm curious.
We have something called "Doctor Heli" in Japan.
- Doctor Heli? - Yes, they use a helicopter to pick up the patient.
This attracted the public's attention...
because of a 2008 TV drama called, "Code Blue".
It's drama set in an emergency room.
After that was aired, this caught the public's eye.
It was used a lot after the earthquake struck as well.
Because you can get there fast and it can get to those hard to reach places.
It's a well-run system and I hope it will continue to be like that in the future.
In Switzerland, a lot of people go climbing, right?
So like Japan, we also have a rescue helicopter as well.
- However... - This service is called Rega.
There are many cows up on high mountains as well, right?
These helicopters rescue these cows as well.
(It's a flying cow.)
(I always dreamed of flying. I always had that dream.)
If I was in a different country, and I needed to get to a hospital.
We have a service that allows me to be flown back to Switzerland.
There are no fees for that service as well.
I think most Swiss make use of this service.
However, we don't have a drama about that, unlike Japan.
There were many very popular drama set in an emergency room.
("ER", first aired in 1994)
("Grey's Anatomy", first aired in 2005)
("Code Black", first aired in 2015)
- I watched "Doctors" which stars Park Shin-hye three times. - Chicken fur.
It's "Doctors".
I'm watching it for the third time.
Did you start dreaming of becoming a doctor after watching a drama like that?
Doctors in Korea don't really have a lot of time to watch medical dramas.
They are really busy.
And the medical facts in the drama have been exaggerated.
Sometimes they are wrong as well. We can't empathize with it.
What was the most absurd scene that you saw?
The most representative one.
On the drama, "Descendants of the Sun",
(They did the impossible in that drama.)
- The one with Song Hye-kyo. - "Descendants of the Sun".
- In the scene where the patient had swallowed the diamonds. - Right.
Song Hye-kyo then shows him the X-ray with the diamonds on it.
However, X-rays can't penetrate through diamonds, so it wouldn't show on the scan.
But you can see it like a white substance.
Are you sure he didn't eat stones?
They are steel diamonds.
(Steel diamonds)
You're saying they're fake.
There was a mistake like that on an Indian movie.
There was a scene where a doctor throws a heart like this.
The heart flies in the air like this.
Does the person receiving transplant, receive it like this?
In Pakistan, we have an emergency room system that we are proud of.
There's a person nicknamed, "Father Teresa".
He gathered the money he got from begging on the street and bought an ambulance.
We use that ambulance as an emergency room.
A lot of people liked that idea and donated more money.
We now have over 1,500 vehicles being used in that system.
They also have a helicopter. They have started to operate internationally as well.
Is the emergency system responsive in Pakistan?
It's not well run, that's why people like him created a system like this.
- I think the emergency system in Pakistan is similar to Mexico. - Okay.
It's agonizingly slow. If you were to go to the emergency room in Mexico,
you have to be prepared to lose a day.
It's like that. They say emergency room, but it feels more like a waiting room.
People wait there for countless hours.
Some people go to the emergency room,
and then after a while their pain fades, so they leave.
- Time has healed them. - Yes, time has healed them.
- They go home. - If we're talking about slow, shouldn't we be talking about India?
The population of Delhi is 22 million.
But the number of emergency ambulances that the government has bought...
- is only 152. - Is that true?
So, each ambulance has to take care of 140,000 people.
When you order a pizza, at most it takes 40 minutes.
However the emergency cars run by the government...
takes longer than 2 to 3 hours to arrive.
So in India, private hospitals and private ambulances really well developed.
What I was most shocked about...
when I went overseas was how all the cars gave way to emergency vehicles.
I was so impressed.
When I asked about that,
- they said the fine for moving was huge in the US. - Yes, it is.
We move aside to the left and wait.
- After they pass we go back on the road. - It's really impressive.
In Pakistan, when an emergency car turns on the siren,
the other cars also start honking as well.
- Why? - "I'm late as well. Why are you being so loud?"
"I'm also busy, too."
- "I'm about to die as well." - "I have an emergency, too."
(The harmony of the siren and horns on the road)
Namgoong In, we heard that you brought us the top three things...
that the patients had said to you while you were working in the emergency room.
Yes. The most common thing that patients say is,
"Why are you late?" They say that a lot.
- "I'm in pain." - Yes.
The second most common thing is whether it's covered by insurance.
They ask that a lot.
When I'm about to do the check-up,
they ask, "Do you know who I am?"
What do they say afterward?
They say something like, "I live in a luxurious apartment."
- They say that. - You should have replied,
I live in a better area.
Whether you live in Tower Palace apartment,
- it's not that important to me. - Yes.
Do they really need to tell me that information?
They feel like you'll be more thorough if they tell that.
- They do think that way. - Yes, they do.
Next time, tell them where you live as well.
- Tell them where you live. - I live in Haebangchon District.
"I live in Haebangchon District."
We'll now turn our attention to medical techniques.
Tell us what your country is good at.
In Japan because of our aging society,
our care of the elderly is well developed.
That's why the nursing homes,
have bought lots of robotic nurses.
- They give the patients baths. - They give them baths,
and we also have a robot that cleans up as well.
We also have a robot suit.
- A robot suit? - Yes.
There are a lot of seniors that are lying down.
But you need a lot of strength to be able to do that.
- It's very hard. - This suit is designed to help you with that.
- Wow. - So it helps you to lift people up.
- You can lift up people easily. - It's like something from a movie.
- You can lift people up easily. - "Iron Man".
I think the US has the best surgical techniques in the world.
We are also a country that develops new drugs very fast.
We have a lot of drug companies. We also have a federal agency called the FDA.
The FDA meticulously looks at all the new drugs that are being produced.
It's an agency that checks all this.
Thanks to this, we are known as a country...
that develops new drugs and medicines very quickly.
We use a lot of drugs as well,
- so our dependency is a little bit higher. - It's higher, right?
That's a regrettable fact.
I think China has the best oriental medicine in the world.
We have this thought in China,
"Western medicine treats only what you can see from the patient."
"Chinese medicine treats what's inside him as well." We say that.
Also, these days...
the most popular form of treatment for sports athletes is cupping.
The US swimmer, Michael Phelps likes this as well.
- Can you see the cupping marks on his back? - Yes.
- Yes, when he swims, you could see the marks. - Right. I saw those.
If you're talking about traditional medicines,
Ayurvedic medicine from India is very famous, right?
- In India, we have our ways to heal asthma. - Asthma?
Yes, asthma.
We put the medicine into the mouth of a fish that looks like an anchovy.
We then tell the patient to swallow it.
You tell them to swallow the fish?
We put the medicine into the fish's mouth.
We put it into the mouth like this.
- "Eat it." - It's only for two days.
You can only get this medicine for two days in the middle of June.
- I don't know if it comes in capsule form, but... - The fish takes the medicine,
"Why are they looking at me?"
It's literally a doctor fish.
It's literally "Doctor Strange".
In Mexico, this was a long time ago,
I'm talking about during the Aztec civilization,
- they had folk remedies. - Aztec civilization.
- Folk remedies. - They had developed folk remedies back then.
We have a tree that represents this called the Eucalyptus globulus.
- Let's say you had a blocked nose. - Right.
You could boil the leaves from the tree in hot water,
and the smell from the boiling leaves is very effective.
There are people who can't sleep at night, right?
- Insomnia. - Insomnia.
You know banana leaves, right?
You can just cut them up and boil them in hot water.
If you drink the boiled soup, it'll help you to sleep.
- Really? - Yes, you just need to drink it.
- I tried it and I fell asleep instantly. - How was it?
Isn't it because of pesticides?
- No. - You might have fainted because of it.
That happens quite often.
It's also used by some Koreans, too.
Switzerland has a long history of watch and clock making.
That means it's highly capable of building other precision instruments as well.
A Swiss company which used to produce watch components...
happened to make bone implant materials.
They kept developing their technology,
and expanded to dental implants.
A number of other companies share similar histories.
Switzerland is well known for its advanced medical machinery industry.
There's a company called Olympus in Japan, famous for its digital cameras.
Actually 73 percent of their sales came from medical instruments.
There's no match to the company in the endoscope market.
- Endoscope. - Yes, endoscope.
Lenses are important.
Their products are widely used in Korea as well.
I was surprised that a camera company makes such precision instrument.
- Are they good? - Yes.
As I mentioned earlier, Pakistan...
- is known for scalpel production. - Scalpel.
- Knife, too. - You said we should buy a knife if we travel to Pakistan.
Scalpel and scissors.
Pins, too. We are so good at producing them.
Internationally, German-made products are more widely used.
But Pakistani products are also good...
and much cheaper. Hence it has strong price competitiveness.
Have you ever...
used Pakistani-made scalpel?
I use whatever nurses give me.
- Look at them closely. They could be made in Pakistan. - Okay.
- I'm sure they are. - I'll check it out.
- Why are you so sure? - Isn't it your first time to meet him?
(You'll see the difference.)
Countries of representatives here must have...
great doctors and nurses who touched people's heart with their wonderful sacrifice and service.
- We have Heo Jun in Korea. - Right.
Who else in your country?
We have Albert Schweitzer.
- Dr. Schweitzer. - Schweitzer.
He visited African so often throughout his life...
and built hospitals there. Also he built hospitals in France.
He's well known for his achievements.
(I see.)
He was born with a German nationality.
But he thought he was a French.
He wrote many books in French.
But Schweitzer is not that famous in France.
Isn't he famous across the world?
- I haven' heard of him. - You haven't?
Me, either.
We all read his story as a kid.
He's not famous in some countries?
- Not known in Mexico. - Same goes with the US.
- What about Japan? - Italians don't know him.
- Not in detail. - Haven't heard of him.
In Korea, he's a very well-known figure.
In Korea, he's as famous as Nightingale.
They are the two most prominent figures in the medical field.
- Can't believe it. - Goodness.
We have Nightingale.
- What? - It seems you lost your confidence all of a sudden, don't you?
Florence Nightingale is very famous, right?
She was a daughter of a noble English man,
but was born in Firenze, Italy.
- That's why... - Her birthplace is Italy.
- Only the birthplace. - No.
Her family lived in Italy.
- I see. - That's why her name is Florence, which means Firenze.
During the Crimean War, she volunteered as a nurse.
She introduced a totally new way of field hospital management.
She contributed to lowering the death rate of patients from 42 to 2 percent.
Thanks to her management.
Many people think she's the founder of modern nursing science.
Another famous figure in Italy is Maria Montessori.
- Montessori. - I know.
Maria Montessori was the first female student in the medical college in Italy.
At that time, mentally challenged children were...
treated like animals. Seeing that,
she started to study children.
She started the famous Montessori education.
There were many "Montessori" schools in Korea when I was young.
- Yes, like piano schools. - It still exists in the middle of Gangham area.
I thought it's related to sound, like sound of piano.
I had a similar question myself.
What does "ssori" mean?
I've never heard of it before.
But the private piano school was very popular.
I thought it's just the name of the school.
Montessori schools are all over the world.
Instead of teaching children,
they give children place and freedom to play around.
- I see. - It's a good way of education.
There's is a doctor whom all American would recognize.
- He's an Indian-American. He's name is Sanjay Gupta. - I know.
- Sanjay Gupta... - Is handsome, isn't he?
was named one of the sexiest men in the US.
His name is Gupta.
Most of shows related to medical science...
invite him as a guest and he was hugely popular.
(He became even more famous after turning down Obama's offer for a ministerial position.)
Isn't House M.D. the most famous doctor?
In the real world, Sanjay Gupta is the most famous doctor.
Maybe not if TV characters are counted.
Have you seen those dramas like "House M.D."?
I saw "House M.D."
What do you think of it?
Though it covers rare medical cases, its episodes are all based on...
cases that are likely to take place.
So I had much fun watching it.
- It's realistic. - Yes.
I have many friends who are doctors.
Many of them told me they watched the drama to study.
Who's the doctor that is locally respected among Korean doctors?
In Korea, there's a doctor called Lee Guk-jong.
He treated Captain Seok who participated in...
the Operation Dawn of Gulf of Aden.
That's how he was known to the public. He's a doctor of Trauma Surgery Department at Ajou University.
After he saved Captain Seok's life,
Dr. Lee emphasized the necessity to build trauma centers in Korea.
He's such a hard-working doctor.
Before he came into the spotlight, trauma treatment had relied on rule of thumb.
Since then, government subsidies were offered and trauma centers were built.
He raised public awareness on trauma treatment.
Everybody would want to see a famous doctor...
when he or she gets ill.
But in reality, you have to wait for long see those doctors.
You can see them only after waiting several months.
If you need a surgery, will you...
wait for six months to get a surgery from a famous doctor?
Or will you go to a doctor who can do the surgery right away?
Those who are willing to wait, please raise your hands in 1,2,3.
- Will you wait for six months? - If it's not that serious.
- If I'm not sick. - Right.
If I'm not going to die any time soon.
What if you're so sick?
But after six months...
All right. Let's hear out from the doctor first. What will you do in this case?
As I'm a doctor in Korea myself,
I trust my colleague doctors and the medical system here.
- I'll go with the latter. - It's because you're not sick.
No. I'll take my surgery in no time.
I'm so sure.
Even though the doctor...
who will operate is not famous, that doesn't mean he's a poor doctor.
While waiting for six months,
- my conditions will become worse. - It will get worse.
But it depends on what the disease is.
You might get better while waiting.
- No. - Ridiculous.
It's because...
there are some fraudulent doctors when it comes to surgery.
Personally, I think...
You talked about anchovy earlier.
Isn't it belated to talk about medical schemes?
- Wasn't the anchovy story a fraud? - No, it's a different story.
An anchovy fraud.
It's not always good to rush things for the patient.
That's what really happened in India.
One slightly sprained his ankle.
But just giving him a prescription doesn't make much money. So the doctor...
said that the patient needed a surgery.
Hasty surgery may lead to a medical accident.
Having a surgery requires a careful consideration.
You shouldn't hurry about it.
I'd be waiting only if my condition allows.
It's not pizza delivery. Rushing your decision will do no good.
There's a saying you'll get only worse if you wait.
- Right. - Yes.
That's what moms say.
- However... - Is that so?
it sounds reasonable to me.
In China, the level of doctors varies a lot.
Even if we have to wake up early...
and wait in lines, we should receive a surgery from a good doctor.
It's less risky.
- It's different in different countries. - Sure.
I underwent a surgery myself when I had appendicitis.
- Appendicitis. - Yes, when I had that operation,
there were two doctors in the hospital.
One said it's needed to cut out much of my appendix.
The other said small cutout would be enough.
I got a surgery from the first doctor.
There's been no problem yet.
- Wouldn't it be better to make a small cutout? - But I had to wait.
If it's a disease with which you can wait for six months,
it means your condition is really bad.
- Moreover, you need to undergo a surgery. - Right.
You might die if you wait for six months.
Becoming a doctor is not easy.
Every doctor is heavily educated for a long time.
- I believe all doctors are qualified enough to give us an operation. - We should believe them.
If it's needed to get a surgery,
I won't wait for six months. I'd get one right away.
But there must be a reason for his fame.
I learned a lesson. Going to a famous doctor...
wouldn't always guarantee 100 percent recovery.
But it is less likely to get worse.
Yes, we feel safer.
- What if I can't stand the pain for another six months? - Then you should get a surgery.
- As soon as possible. - Yes.
- Personally I believe... - It depends on.
It might be different depending on what your disease is.
Case by case.
Okay.
Don't be sick and let's move on to our next topic.
Tell us about disease which was found for the first time in your country.
We found Lou Gehric disease.
- Lou Gehric disease. - It's the name of a Yankees player.
He had the disease and it was named after him.
(Steven Hawking has the disease.)
Also, Noro virus...
was first found in the US.
It was named in the States...
but Japanese people complained about the name.
Because the word "Noro"...
is a very common family name in Japan.
- Yes. - They didn't like the name.
- We changed the name into "Norwalk" virus. - Changed the name?
But even after we changed its name,
it's still commonly called Noro virus.
It's officially changed but nothing really has changed.
- Right. - Just the official name.
This disease is also well-known in Korea.
- It's called Itai-itai disease. - It means "It hurts."
This disease was caused by...
chronic cadmium poisoning.
In Korean, "itai-itai" means...
"It hurts, it hurts."
Patients of the disease kept saying that when they passed away.
- Seeing that, people named the disease "itai-itai". - It's scary.
What's attracting people's attention again is Moyamoya disease.
What is Moyamoya disease?
It means "puff of smoke" in Japanese, right?
It is a disease in which certain arteries in the brain are constricted.
When you scan the brain after injecting contrast media,
the image will look like a puff of smoke.
It gives you a horrible headache. It's a painful disease.
There's a disease that was first discovered in Korea.
When you were young, people told you not to sit on the grass, right?
That's because of epidemic hemorrhagic fever.
It's a febrile virus that rodents carry.
The first person who discovered the virus was Korean.
It was discovered at Hantan River.
So the virus is called Hantan Virus.
- I see. - At first, it was called Korean hemorrhagic fever.
Now it's called epidemic hemorrhagic fever.
The disease still exists in Korea.
In 1907, a famous disease...
- called Alzheimer's disease was first discovered in Germany. - I see.
A German psychiatrist called...
Dr. Alois Alzheimer first discovered the disease.
He was the first one to discover the disease.
(President Ronald Reagan also died from Alzheimer's disease.)
In 2009, there was an outbreak of a new strain of influenza.
(Swine flu has got the whole world in a panic.)
- It was first spread from Mexico. - That's right.
In 2009, the virus was first found at a hog farm in Mexico.
Then an American was infected and went back to the States.
So the virus spread around the world.
The situation got really bad in Mexico.
Mexicans don't normally wear masks.
They only wear it when they're really sick.
- It's also very hot. - But everyone was wearing a mask back then.
People didn't leave their house, either.
A lot of people died from the virus.
To prevent swine flu from spreading,
a Swiss drug company called Roche...
- made Tamiflu. - I remember that.
- It was a Swiss medicine. - It was hard to get the drugs back then.
The demand of the drug had skyrocketed, so they increased the price.
However, many had said that...
the effect of Tamiflu was minimal.
Even a rumor was spread.
People said Roche made the swine flu virus...
- in order to sell their drugs. - To sell their drugs?
I took Tamiflu in 2009.
Did you recover after taking the drug?
- But I don't know... - Was it tasty?
whether I recovered after taking the pills or taking a rest.
- It makes you wonder. - Yes, that's what I thought.
In Korea, people say...
it takes 14 days to recover from a cold and 2 weeks if you go to a hospital.
- Right. - We're talking about Tamiflu.
Lets' talk about new drugs of each country.
In 1892, a German man called Felix Hoffmann...
- developed aspirin. - I see.
When he was 23,
- his father was suffering from rheumatoid arthritis. - Rheumatoid arthritis.
He wanted to treat his father's disease. That's how he developed the medicine.
When he first gave aspirin to his father,
his father told him he was able to sleep comfortably...
- without any pain. - I see.
It was developed, thanks to his dutifulness.
- You all know about Pasteur, right? - Yes.
- Their milk is delicious. - Yes.
He discovered microbial fermentation.
He also developed the vaccination for chicken cholera...
- and rabies as well. - I see.
He did his research in Lille.
He had worked with one of my ancestors.
- Who was it? - My grand father's grand father's brother.
- They worked together. - With Pasteur?
It could've become Aurélien's milk then.
You're right.
An important medicine was developed in America.
The story is quite fascinating.
It's fascinating. It's the story about Viagra.
Actually, Viagra was first developed...
- to treat heart disease. - It was developed to treat angina pectoris.
Yes. People started to take the pills...
and another effect of the medicine was later discovered.
- So they... - I'm sure they were really surprised.
They took the pills to treat heart disease, and...
How strong has my heart become?
It's...
The patient was lying on the bed,
and the doctor was curious what was going on.
- The doctor was surprised. - The doctor was surprised to see that.
That's right.
The principle is the same. The drug dilates blood vessels.
- When blood vessels are dilated, the flow of blood is increased. - Yes.
It's used to treat heart disease as well.
It's also used for mountain sickness.
- Mountain sickness? - The blood vessels get dilated, so is eases headaches.
When people find out that you have Viagra,
you can tell them you have mountain sickness.
People ask for a prescription, saying they're going to mountains.
Well... They get a prescription for Viagra.
- They get a prescription and use it for another purpose. - They say...
- they're going to climb a high mountain. - They say they're going to Nepal.
Don't they go to Nepal too often?
You know I'm going to Nepal.
I'm so jealous.
I'm going to Nepal.
Sometimes, a medical malpractice can lead to a medical dispute in Korea.
Is there a particular malpractice that you felt sad about?
Of course it's Shin Hae-chul's case.
(Shin Hae-chul's death shocked everyone. What happened for the past 10 days?)
Doctors tend to take side with other doctors when medical accidents happen.
But in Shin Hae-chul's case,
he was fine and was able to speak, then he died suddenly due to complications.
So doctors also think that he died from a medical malpractice.
- He was sentenced two years in prison. - It's not a final judgment,
- but he was sentenced two years in prison. - Right.
- There were similar incidents in the States. - In case of America,
Michael Jackson died in 2009.
The cause of his death was...
his family doctor. He was Michael Jackson's private doctor.
Michael Jackson had been suffering from a lot of stress and insomnia.
So he asked his doctor...
for more and more drugs.
After taking the prescribed drugs, he fell asleep...
and died. So the doctor was brought to court for trial,
and he was found guilty.
Propofol became famous in Korea because of this incident, right?
You could say that. It's also known as the "milk injection".
The color of the drug is white.
It's commonly used for endoscopy.
When it's injected, you lose consciousness...
and fall asleep.
It becomes a problem when it's overdosed.
Yes, this drug is used to make people fall asleep.
So if it's overdosed, the patient falls asleep...
and becomes short of breath.
It can lead to death.
You have to watch the patient's condition closely.
In Mexico, there were two sad cases of medical malpractice.
A baby boy was born...
and the doctor had to cut the umbilical cord,
but he cut the baby's penis instead.
- What? - How can he make a mistake like that?
This is insane.
Did he doze off?
- Even I wouldn't get confused. - It's insane.
So they secretively performed an operation for the baby for three hours.
In the court, they said...
they didn't make a mistake and were performing a circumcision.
- A circumcision? - That's what they said. They made a stupid excuse.
- That's one case of medical malpractice. - Gosh.
A baby had a tumor in his brain,
which affected the eyesight of his left eye. So he needed an operation.
But the doctor got confused and removed his right eye.
- What? - So the baby ended up losing both of his eyes.
Something similar happened in my country.
Actually, this medical accident happened in my hometown.
An 80-year-old patient...
- had a disease, so the doctor had to amputate his leg, - Oh no.
but the doctor amputated the other leg by mistake.
So this patient died from the malpractice.
- What? - It's something that shouldn't have happened.
For an important operation like this,
they should've checked at least 17 times.
- Yes. - They should've checked if his left leg was the problem.
His mindset is...
completely different from Namgoong In's.
It was work for him, so he just looked at the medical chart and amputated his leg.
Telling left from right is quite confusing.
(What?)
- I just got goosebumps. - Oh no.
What's wrong with you?
- I thought you were a nice person. - So...
(What's wrong with you?)
Of course I double check many times.
But if you do it every day,
- things like that happen. - It's an everyday job for doctors.
- Don't nurses mark it with a pen? - Don't they mark it?
They do mark it with a pen.
- The mark it with a huge X sign. - It's so dangerous.
The system requires you to double check many times.
- It's still confusing. - Like I said, you'd better wait to have an operation.
- Well... - I'll wait for six months and go to a nice hospital.
There's nothing good about rushing.
- France has some serious cases, too. - In France,
there was a blood scandal in 1980s.
Not many people were aware of AIDS back then.
HIV-contaminated blood was distributed, infecting many people with AIDS.
So 600 people died as a result.
The French Health Minister...
was sued, but he was found not guilty.
- Not guilty? - When French people...
see the former Health Minister,
they think of the blood scandal that had taken place.
- He's a bit... - So that happened in France.
Something similar had happened in Korea.
I don't know if they actually reused syringes at the clinic.
Hepatitis C was spread among the patients...
who got IV shots at the clinic.
So a few hundred people were infected with hepatitis C virus.
It's a serious virus.
- That happened in Korea. - I see.
Since we have a doctor as our guest today,
let's ask questions to Emergency Physician Dr. Namgoong In.
- Any questions from your everyday life? - What's your question?
In Korea, people say eating apple at night is bad for your health.
- Yes. - Actually, I argued about it with my friend.
Eating apple in the morning is good, and eating it at night is bad.
- What is the truth? - People only say it in Korea.
Since apple contains a lot of sugar content,
it's a little hard to digest if you eat apples at night.
Maybe that's why people say it's bad for you.
- All fruits are hard to digest at night. - You drink 20 or 30 glasses of bomb shot.
It's better to sleep after eating an apple.
- Right. - So I don't think...
- eating an apple at night will affect your health. - So the content is fine.
- Yes. - It's just a little hard to digest.
Your stomach might feel heavy. That's why people say that.
- It's completely fine. - I have a question, too.
People say you'll die if you sleep with a fan blowing on you. Is that true?
In India, we have fans on the ceiling.
We're fine, but Koreans keep saying that.
You won't die from it.
- Right? - That can never be the cause of death.
When electric fans were first introduced...
to Korea in 1920s, old people made jokes to save electricity.
People are still believing that?
- That myth has been going on for 100 years. - It's so sad.
- It's a myth. - People are still believing it.
People say...
- you lose your fortune if you shake your leg. - Yes.
- It's actually good for you. It prevents you from having varicose veins. - Really?
- They said it's good for you. It's good to move your legs. - Really?
I have a question.
When you get a medical checkup,
you get an endoscopy.
Is it better to have a sleep endoscopy?
Or should I just get a normal endoscopy?
Which one will you choose?
When you prepare for a sleep endoscopy, the drug content itself...
isn't really bad for your health.
The drug content doesn't make you fall asleep.
Patients can still move their body.
Sometimes they speak as well.
So watching them made me feel that I should get an awake endoscopy.
- It's the normal endoscopy. - People say you need to gather up your courage.
I was scared, so I've never tried it.
- You've never tried, have you? - No, it's scary.
If you haven't tried it, please don't say anything.
I got a normal endoscopy because I didn't have enough time.
- Getting a gastroscopy wasn't too bad. - Really?
It only took five minutes. I had a gag reflex, and that was it.
But getting a colonoscopy is no joke. It's so painful.
Air is injected into your colon.
It was just... I'm talking about colonoscopy.
- Oh! - Did you get a sleep endoscopy?
I got a normal colonoscopy.
At first, the nurses insert a tube. It's as big as this.
(My goodness!)
I'm serious. They insert a tube as big as this.
I'm not talking about my buttocks, and it didn't hurt.
- But I felt the pain in the abdominal area. - Of course.
They injected air into my colon, so my belly swelled up.
It was no joke. If you haven't tried it, don't even talk about it.
- Try the sleep endoscopy next time. - Sleep endoscopy is better.
It was Namgoong In's issue for the 125th Non Summit Meeting.
"Sometimes, emotional feelings come before rational decisions. Am I abnormal?"
That was today's topic.
Schweitzer, who had helped people with his medical knowledge based on humanity,
said this.
"Sometimes, emotional feelings come before rational decisions. Am I abnormal?"
That was today's topic.
Schweitzer, who had helped people with his medical knowledge based on humanity,
said this.
"The way you see the world decides your fate."
Let's hear it in German.
Schweitzer is known as a French-German doctor.
Let's hear it in French.
Did he say vitamins?
- Vitamins? - All right.
If the way you see the emergency patients decides your fate,
how will you look at them?
Seeing emergency patients is my job,
so it's my fate.
I think the fate of the emergency patients...
is my fate. With that thought in mind,
I will try to be humble and work hard.
How did you feel today?
As a Korean doctor,
it was interesting to hear what's happening in each country's medical field.
They all speak good Korean.
I had a lot of fun today. Thank you.
- Okay. - Thank you.
- It was good to have a doctor as our guest. - Yes.
We enjoyed having you here with us. Thank you.
I would now like to adjourn Non Summit Meeting.
Until the day we all become normal.
I wish people in this world would never have to feel any pain.
Let's live happily
Don't get sick
- Let's... - I'll adjourn Non Summit Meeting.
(Non Summit Meeting is adjourned.)
(A fictitious name called Gil Ra-im shook up the nation.)
(Donald Trump...)
(had used a fictitious name.)
(Former President Sarkozy...)
(used a mobile phone registered under a fake name.)
(Turkish president had established a foundation under a fake name.)
(Surprised)
(All these incidents from other countries...)
(aren't unfamiliar.)
(A global renaming variety show)
(Very very very)
(We missed them very much.)
(Zhou Jieqiong and Jeon So-mi of I.O.I)
(The 126th Non Summit Meeting, the Survival Stories of the World)
(A vivid behind story of survival)
(I don't want to participate.)
(Wasn't the prize money enough for you?)
(All the ladies from the country participated.)
(They eat gross things.)
(Each country's fascinating stories of survival)
(Growing with the auditionees)
(Is it an evil editing?)
(There are so many audition shows. What do they think about it?)
(I failed an audition.)
(What happened at the Christian's audition?)
(A global debate survival)
(Non Summit Meeting)
Subtitles by OnDemandKorea