Subtitles brought to you by the Sky Team @ Viki
I think they're the police. I'll leave.
CEO Han Young Won.
Yes.
We just came from Belle La Fair.
I'm detective Lee Cha Yun from the regional precinct.
If it's about Lee Eun Soo, let's talk later.
Yes, I understand.
Let's go.
Eun Soo.
They're here to take me.
Everything that has happened between you and me,
erase it all
and remember me as I am now.
Me, standing in front of you, running away.
How childish and cowardly I was.
Watch carefully, and remember that.
Even if it's for you.
Do you have a place to go?
Do you have to do this?
I'll leave everything and go empty-handed.
You're so great.
No matter how hard it may be to forgive, how can you say "My father is a swindler"
in front of the reporters?
In the least, I don't wish for any harm on anyone in this family.
Then to me,
why did you tell me the truth about Woo Jin?
So,
how far are you going?
The current problem with the slush funds existed since you were the CEO.
You think you won't be blamed?
Is that the only thing you have to say to me?
You were blinded by love, so in place of Jung Se Ro,
aren't you saying that you're going to get revenge?
Father made Woo Jin like that,
and buried Eun Soo socially.
How did you expect me to act after knowing all that?
Did you think I was going to suffer for a couple of days and get better?
Noona, even though I say I don't care about anything but myself,
I know this:
You can throw a man away.
You can abandon mom, and me too, but not dad!
Even if you take mom and me out, dad is your only family!
You'll only have a hard time if you fight against dad.
No.
For me, it's hard to abandon you and mother.
So abandon me, please.
Because of father, Lee Eun Soo was unjustly
framed as a murderer and spent five years in prison.
I would have nothing to say if he drowned me in the Han River.
That person was afraid that I'd find out what father did, so do you know what he said?
That he made Woo Jin like that.
It's not enough for that person to hate me,
I didn't know anything and called him a swindler,
but that person still
loved me.
"Do you know what your father did?"
He needed to say just that one thing.
Because he thought I would be hurting,
he couldn't say that til the end.
I knew everything,
so how can I act like I don't know him?
So? So are you going to hold hands with Jung Se Ro
and drive father to the edge of a cliff?
Yes.
That is all I can do.
I...am not your sister anymore.
I'm not father's daughter. I'm not a member of this family.
Even if you say I can't have it,
I have only that person now.
So please abandon me!
Think of it as the last thing you can do for me.
You didn't like me that much anyways.
I'm finally starting to like her, but I no longer have any excuse to hold on to her.
Am I right?
She's out!
Is it true?!
About your father, Han Tae Oh...
You're the one who exposed your father's deeds.
What I said...
everything is true.
Beyond the Clouds
Episode 15
Mirum Party's senator Jung Soon Young, in an emergency press conference,
exposed Chairman HanTae Oh's personal list of
10 people with whom illicit funds were discovered.
At 11:00 AM, Senator Jung at the press conference, in regards to an internet posting,
stated that the 10 names and the documents were
sent to him by the person who posted the news item.
These people used Belle La Fair, which was operated by Han Young Won,
and HK Distribution in Hong Kong.
It was discovered that they laundered their illicit funds.
Senator Jung strongly requested to the prosecutor, in order to expose the full truth,
the names of the people involved and the original transaction documents.
The people's identity...
Let's hand over the file to Senator Jung.
Yes.
Se Ro will give the original document to Senator Jung.
We need to block it before he does it.
If Han Tae Woo falls, we fall, too.
Hyung... Hyung.
Hyung!
What?
It's almost time to meet Senator Jung.
Oh! Really?
You don't look good.
Aren't you having after-effects after the car accident?
What after-effects?
I think you should go to the hospital.
Right now, I'm obvious, don't you know?
Who knows what will happen if I leave a trace behind.
Alright, are you following him well?
Yes.There's no problem as of now.
Don't let Senator Jung meet Se Ro.
If he meets Se Ro, catch him!
I understand.
Give it to me!
All the kids who followed Park Kang Jae around,
You've already learned disgusting things!
-Jung Se Ro betrayed us, first.
Then Kang Jae hyungim was supposed to look the other way with all those?
Is money your loyalty? Whether it's Hyungim or loyalty,
don't try acting like a gangster, you punk!
You can't even distinguish your tasks!
I found it.
You found it? Good job.
Verify the document right away,
to see if it's the original copy.
Oh, this bastard!
What's wrong?
I'm sorry, but it's not the original copy.
They threw us off on purpose,
because they thought we'd follow them.
What?
Then what about the original copy?
You were the one that called...
It's the original copy.
Thank you. We'll use it for a good cause.
Please take good care of it.
Your contact information?
Stop right there!
Cha Pyo caught on.
I'll lose him,
but you bolt from here, immediately!
Hello, Hong?
Hong?!
Jung Se Ro... where is he?
If you want to meet Hong,
come by Kang Jae Hyung's office.
-Don't come, Hyung!
It's bait... to catch you. So don't come!
I'm going now!
I have a bad feeling this time.
In whose hand will,
the original copy be passed on to?
I can't just wait for a prolonged time.
We need to clear out,
before the prosecutor barges in.
Incinerate all of secretary Kim's files, and wipe out all the computer hard drives.
So they can't even find a speck of dust.
But... what about the documents
that Assistant Ahn concealed...
If I can't intercept that...
Why do you want Se Ro Hyung here?
Do you honestly plan on sending him to prison again?
You're the one that 'honestly' needs to go to a prison!!
Wasn't it only an errand?
I'm sorry.
I didn't think the cop would
suspect a young child like you.
This world is not fair.
You brought it onto yourself,
yet you're blaming the world, like a loser!
Now,
I'm you?
Talking like that...
-Then should I call you 'Hyung', when you turn me into your bait?!
At the least, I..
didn't tell Se Ro Hyung your secret.
Because of you Se Ro Hyung's father was in an accident.
How you cunningly hid the truth,
and how you played on naïve Se Ro Hyung.
Then you joined forces with Han Tae Oh...
You also turned him into a thief.
Even though I wanted to tell him so many times in a given day,
it's so disgusting and complicated that I held it in.
Hyung...
It's all right for you to leave now.
Can you leave?
Hong... leave.
I'll be in front of the door.
Hyung.
The original copy?
- I didn't hear correctly, right?
Where is the original copy!?
I heard it incorrectly, right?
- Where is the original copy?
It's already been handed over. Tell me.
What did I exactly hear?
What about my dad?
While he was being chased by me,
he got into an accident.
Answer.
Answer! What about my dad?!
Gong Woo Jin's Gong Jin Diamond, we stole it.
We were supposed to divide it.
Your great dad took it and ran.
And I was chasing him.
We ran through Bangkok's dark streets,
like dogs.
Then...in front of my eyes~
Why didn't you say anything to me?
I'm the one who put Gong Woo Jin in ahjussi's storeroom,
and I'm the one who was chasing ahjussi.
Why didn't you say a word?
Every day, you looked upon my face,
pretending to be the best hyung in the world, but hiding all of that!
You want to kill me, right?
Shoot me.
Shoot! Shoot!
Shoot me!
You can't do it, right?
I'm telling you to do it, but you can't. Then, how about me
to Jung Do Joon.
No matter how crazy angry I might have been,
do you think I would want to kill him?
Well, that's just an excuse. Then how about this?
Because of Han Tae Oh,
similar to when you went to prison,
because of your father, I
went to prison.
I was only 15 years old.
What?
I went on an errand.
I should obey, so I did what I was told.
But it wasn't just an errand.
The police came.
I was caught! And at age 15,
I lived in there for a few months, with the sentiment of
"You did so well!"
After that, my life got twisted like this.
But, I thought Jung Do Joon would
compensate... at least to me...
until the day he closed his eyes.
Maybe I should have taken revenge... like you.
Stop there! Stop there!
Do you think I would believe you if you talk about nonsense?
Do I still look that innocent?
Come here!
It's not the truth. Don't lie, bastard.
Your father ultimately gave you the diamond
he took from my pocket.
After screwing other people,
putting it in their kid's mouth, is the same for your father or
Han Tae Oh.
You know?!
No. Don't say it like that.
There's something I realized.
Revenge, reconciliation, forgiveness, love...
those are all bull s**t...
Living well on my own...
is the easiest way to live in this damned world.
Interfere till the end.
I'm going to go to the end, too.
Why are you doing this to me, Hyung?
It's not true.
It's not true!
After being on the run his whole life...
why in front of my eyes,
why in front of me, because he couldn't avoid that one car!
Your father who screwed me over till the end, that great man... !
Your father was Han Tae Oh to me.
Let me make a request for the last time.
Please, get lost from me.
What are you doing here at this time?
You said you didn't want to see me anymore.
You said that you didn't need me anymore!
You said I was nothing to you!
I thought you might be lonely,
that you might be lonesome.
Perhaps... you might have been waiting for me.
I just need you.
Oppa, you changed too much.
You make me nervous. You scare me.
Yes.
It hurts.
Even if I love you,
I won't love you.
But... can't you trust me, just this one time?
I don't know... who Park Kang Jae is.
Just as you went to prison because of Han Tae Oh,
I was in prison, because of your father.
I was only 15.
Screwing other people,
and putting it in their kid's mouth, is the same for
your father and Han Tae Oh.
You know?!
I am... to Lee Eun Soo, I am...
the daughter of a conman.
Young Won, why are we so similar?
Maybe that's why I couldn't help but to love you.
This is Hangook Hospital's ER,
do you know Lee Eun Soo?
I'm calling you because your number was stored in #1 in his phone.
Have you regained your consciousness?
We checked the accident patient.
My belongings?
I called your guardian...
I don't have such thing as a guardian.
Patient? Patient?
I came after getting a call. Lee Eun Soo...
I got a call saying that he was carried in here a few hours ago.
Are you Lee Eun Soo's guardian?
-Yes-Please come this way.
What happened here?
Nurse Baek.
- Yes.
Where did patient Lee Eun Soo go?
He stubbornly left.
He left?
Yes.
How can you just let him go?
I'm his guardian. Is there something wrong with him?
Why was he here?
Ah. A few days ago, he was in a car accident.
At that time, he probably didn't get properly treated.
No wonder.
Why? What is wrong with him?
We would know the specifics once we do an MRI,
but the CT scan showed signs of hemorrhaging.
Do you mean in his brain?
- Yes.
If he is still hemorrhaging, then his condition is serious.
Every minute is urgent.
- Where is he now?
You should have looked after a patient. You just let someone who is sick leave?
Han Young Won
♫ I’m hurting more ♫
It's me. Where are you right now?
What is this, running away from the hospital?
I'm near the hospital. If you get this message...
Eun Soo,
they say you must
receive treatment.
Eun Soo, you have done nothing wrong.
Let's, you and I, meet the judge.
The video you took...
That... From my father's lips, if he were to say you have committed no crime,
you just need to hear that it's all his fault.
That's all you need to hear, right?
That kind of video... I can take hundreds of them.
So let's meet each other.
Call me. I'll be waiting.
♫ When I can get over you as meaningless memories ♫
♫ Then I can forget you even if I’m forced to remember you ♫
♫ That person, that one person... ♫
♫ That person I hate, the only person ♫
♫ The person deeply engraved in my heart, ♫
♫ painfully piercing me and my faded memories. ♫
♫ The person that is you ♫
Chairman Han Tae Oh,
this is a search and seizure warrant.
You've probably already cleaned up everything.
We expended some effort trying to get the warrant.
So, you skillfully got it.
Few hours ago, through Assemblyman Jung,
we got your original copies of the corruption incidents.
So he went over.
Don't expect a criminal investigation without detention.
As a formality, we'll start the investigation
by confiscating your things.
Let's start.
Yes!
Prosecution Services
There isn't a day that's calm.
It seems really serious this time.
I gave all the years of my youth to Belle La Fair.
I guess it's time for me to leave here.
It's nothing compared to CEO Han Young Won.
Then, what's going to happen to us now?
What do you mean "split up?"
What are you scared of when all that is left now is for Han Tae Oh to go to jail?
Shouldn't we be happily dancing right now?
Be it Han Tae Oh or Park Kang Jae, they won't just stand still?
Because of me, you two could be in danger.
Then, how about you? What are you being framed for?
I'll take care of it.
By yourself, how?
This isn't much, but it's what I have.
This is all I have to give.
Here.
You sure know how to stab a person in the back.
We've come all this way together,
what kind of nonsense is this?
Who said we want something like this?!
This is the first thing in my life that I did something,
without wanting something out of it.
I already know that.
Still, I'm giving you this because I want to.
Later, when you want to set up a store, it'll come in handy.
Where are you planning to go?
- Go? What do you mean go?
I'm thinking of going down to the country.
I want to take a rest, too.
I'm going.
Hyung!
What do you want?
I can't seem to contact Eun Soo,
so I thought you might be able to contact him.
Why should I tell you that?
He is not in good health because of the car accident.
They say that he needs to be examined immediately.
What do you mean...
That's why I'm asking if you can contact him.
I don't know either.
Hyung!
What did you talk about with Park Kang Jae yesterday?
You're like this because you're in shock from that, right?
Hong.
I don't have the right to say something like this, but
you being angry because your family was unfairly ruined and your parents passing away...
don't let that anger be your life.
No matter how much this world makes you angry, if it's damaging and ruining you, relieve your anger.
I think you're more valuable than wasting away like that.
How about you?
That's why. I'll be in touch.
Or why don't you take Han Young Won?
At least go and set up a house.
What is this? As if you're going to your death.
Let's see each other again.
I'm not joking. Take Han Young Won with you.
Should I tell her for you?
That hyung can live happily forever, if he has you.
That Jung Se Ro is way too kind and stupid.
Shall I tell her for you?
It's because of you.
If it weren't for you, do you think Se Ro would have turned out this way?
I didn't come here to be lectured by you.
All I need to know is where Lee Eun Soo is.
Why do you keep calling him Lee Eun Soo?
Because his real name pains my heart.
And I don't have the right to say it either.
Jung Se Ro,
under a 3rd rated conman as a father,
he passed the Higher Civil Service Examination of Foreign Affairs.
He went to meet his father in Thailand,
and was falsely accused of something absolutely unfathomable.
He was notified at the police station that he passed,
after his father passed away.
I wondered how much effort he put in to live that way.
But all he got was a prison life in a foreign country.
Do you think you can compensate him with your love?
If I was you,
I would be gone from Se Ro.
Don't you think your existence itself...
is too harsh for Se Ro?
We have to clean up the vegetables.
This... the one with 3... when are you going to eat it all?
It's okay. Give it to me.
♫ I can't believe it, they say it's love ♫
♫ What do I do? What do I do? What do I do? ♫
♫ I push it away, but it comes to me ♫
♫ What do I do with you? What do I do? ♫
♫ The more I hate you, the more you fill me up ♫
♫ I'm so afraid, I'm going crazy ♫
- Is there a law that says that a criminal's son has turn out like that?
♫ The sun fully shines all over ♫
- He could've been an ordinary kid who wanted to be a doctor or the President.
♫ my body. Because it's you, because it's you, because it's you ♫
Because of people who come to a conclusion like you,
♫ Words I'm saying with an aching heart and tears ♫
they might just be ending up like that.
♫ I love you, I love you, I love you ♫
You can go.
Chairman Han Tae Oh.
Did all the Korean police die?
I don't think it's time for you to be running around like this.
Please apologize.
With just one phrase, "I'm sorry,"
I'll forgive you.
Apologize.
Don't forgive me.
Did someone tell you that I need your forgiveness?
All the things you've done to me...
how dare you after making me like this.
Forgive?
Compare to what you did to me, I don't think it's nothing...
that's what I think.
Don't tell me your thoughts. It's really humorous.
Why do you find me humorous?
Why is a person... why is he humorous?
If your father wasn't a 3rd rated conman, you wouldn't have been involved with Gong Woo Jin.
If your father had as much power as me,
you wouldn't have been accused unjustly.
If you had a little bit of substance,
you'd have been able to get millions from me.
Then, now, you'd be living comfortably.
You foolish man.
You're getting beat up because you're allowing it.
Forgive?
Do you think you're in a position to forgive me?
The thoughts like that is repulsive.
Look at the reality. Who you are and who I am.
Jung Se Ro, making you like this... Yes, I regret it.
But... I can't apologize to you.
I should have killed you like Gong Woo Jin instead.
I could kill you, too.
You...
I want to kill you.
Put it down.
I could shoot you.
No. You can't shoot me.
Put the gun down.
Even though I said I'd forgive you, if you apologize,
yet, you still say you've done nothing wrong?
You still don't know?
You didn't just ruin my life.
You should know that you ruined your daughter's life, too.
Even then, you're right?
Say that you're sorry.
Say that you've done wrong.
At least, as a father.
What would change even if I do that?
To regret the path I walked on now,
I've lived for too long.
Instead of denying all that, I'd rather die.
Stop talking nonsense.
You are just a vicious and pitiful person,
who gave up living like a human being.
The reason why I want to get an apology from you,
is because your daughter, Han Young Won, could live while breathing a little easier.
Please,
don't make your daughter like me.
Speak.
Chairman, didn't anything happen?
What kind of anything?
Perhaps... did Jung Se Ro come to see you?
Why do you want to know that?
Don't meet him.
He...
has a gun.
So, even if you get a call, make sure you don't meet him.
He already came and left.
He didn't do anything.
You want to kill me, right?
It's me. Is Se Ro there?
Even if he's here, he's not, and if he's not, he's not, so hang up.
Find that punk.
Se Ro dropped everything and left as you wished
so stop looking for him.
Is that for real?
-Yes, it's for real.
Find him.
That guy has a gun.
What?
Dream
Yes?
It's me.
Hong?
Yes. Did you not get a call from Se Ro?
Yes.
I have a bad feeling.
Se Ro disappeared with a gun.
Disappeared with a gun?
What do you mean?
It's strange that he settled everything,
and left as if he's going to end it all...
It won't happen, but
I keep having ominous thoughts.
Can you perhaps think of a place that Se Ro might go to?
Why do you need the car suddenly?
What's going on?
Oh... thank you.
So why did you have to leave the car?
Making it troublesome for someone.
Get it! I'll take you there.
Where are you going?
I'll tell you later. It's urgent.
No, no Eun Soo.
If I could return,
to my younger days,
to my dad's wide back, who'd run with me on his back
when I blow the whistle.
Or when I first saw
your bright smile.
Or
if I could return to the day when
everything became a mess.
I don't know anything! I really don't know anything!
How could I kill someone!
Why would I kill a person! Why would I!
If I wiped your tears back then.
Should we run away?
Yes.
-Should we?
I'm Jung Se Ro.
And I killed Gong Woo Jin.
Could I have as myself ,
lived as Jung Se Ro?
Jung Se Ro!
Se Ro... Jung Se Ro.
Se Ro...
You... are Jung Se Ro.
Is that right?
You didn't hurt Woo Jin.
Answer me!
You didn't hurt... Woo Jin!
You were framed!
Is that right?
Yes.
You came to look for me because you were angry.
You wanted revenge.
Is that right?
Yes.
But then you,
you told me that you killed Woo Jin.
I was wrong.
Why did you deceive me?
Why did you lie to me?!
I'm sorry... I'm sorry... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I am sorry.
I am sorry.
I was wrong.
♫ What do I do? ♫
- You...
love me.
Is that right?
Yes, I was wrong!
♫ What do I do? What do I do? What do I do?♫
♫ I'm so afraid, I'm going crazy ♫
♫ The sun fully shines all over my body ♫
♫ Because it's you, because it's you, because it's you. ♫
♫ Words I'm saying with an aching heart and tears. ♫
♫ I love you, I love you, I love you. ♫
Beyond the Clouds
Preview
Although it's really late, thank you.
Later, even if we meet coincidentally,
it's the first thing I'm going to ask.
If you really remember.
Let's make up, Park Kang Jae.
I was confused about how far making up is.
I like it so much that I can be together with you like this.
Me, too.