It was the scoop of the century.
WikiLeaks lifts the curtain
on the secret communications
between Washington
and the diplomats we have stationed
all over the globe.
I'm not aware of any release
of information in human history
comparable to the amount
that was released via WikiLeaks.
These were cables that showed
a superpower's secret thoughts.
A quarter of a million
US diplomatic messages,
apparently stolen
by one of their own soldiers,
turned into a global sensation
by a whistle-blowing website
and its controversial founder
Julian Assange.
I like crushing bastards.
We've dug deep into the cables
to uncover stories
America did not want you to hear...
the difference between
what the US says in public
and what it says in private.
Last time,
we revealed from the cables
how America treats its allies.
Now, we investigate
how it confronts its nightmares.
Like how it struggles
with Russian aggression...
Russia was laying down a marker.
"We're still the big dog
in the neighbourhood
and you have to work with us."
China's rising economic power...
The level of the US debt to China
is a national security concern.
Its military might...
They have a targeted approach
to identify our vulnerabilities.
And the ultimate threat...
an Iranian bomb.
I've had three American presidents
saying Iran getting a weapon
is unacceptable.
From our detailed examination
of the secrets within the cables,
we ask if America,
in an increasingly defiant world,
faces losing its dominance.
It's not a superpower
that can click its fingers
and expect the rest of the world
to come to heel.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru
There has never been a country
as powerful as the United States.
Tens of thousands of diplomats
around the world
report to Washington
on the business of the empire.
They communicate through
secret cables
that were never meant to be seen
by the world.
Because of the WikiLeaks release, we
can all read their private thoughts.
Some of these cables
were light-hearted,
reporting on scandalous rumours
and the pursuit of America's ideals
in the world.
Others were darker.
There are secret reports
of old enemies
flexing their muscles.
And dire warnings of the dangers
of Iran with a nuclear weapon.
The publication of confidential
US diplomatic cables
by the website WikiLeaks...
The founder, Julian Assange, is now
on Interpol's Most Wanted list.
Russia has dismissed fresh WikiLeaks
disclosures.
Once again,
some of the leaks are embarrassing,
but some could be dangerous.
The revelation
of all of these documents
is extraordinarily embarrassing
for the US.
This disclosure
is not just an attack
of America's Foreign Policy
interests,
it is an attack
on the international community.
We've spent months analysing all
quarter of a million leaked cables.
Taken together,
they offer a striking new analysis
of the state of the superpower.
They show a nation
struggling to achieve its goals,
facing defiance around the world,
and locked into confrontation
with old enemies and with new ones.
Reading the cables, there is a fear
that has never really gone away...
Russia.
The secret documents showing
the rise to power of Vladimir Putin
in control of a more hostile Kremlin
gives America sleepless nights.
Russia's aggression is played out
in the former Soviet states
at its border.
Bizarrely, one of the people
recorded in the secret documents
pointing this out,
is Prince Andrew.
One cable describes a lunch
the Prince attended
in the tiny Central Asian state
of Kyrgyzstan.
But behind the bluster,
Andrew had a serious message.
He referred to a new Great Game,
a struggle with Russia
for control in the region.
One of Andrew's great concerns,
as reported in the secret cables,
was Russia's increasing efforts
to gain influence in Central Asia.
The Prince's warning
that Russia was a growing threat
is reflected in many cables.
This cable quotes
the Kazakh ambassador to Washington.
He says the Russians
want the Americans out.
We tracked the ambassador down.
I'm not saying this is you,
but this is what the Americans
were telling themselves you said,
"Russia is now playing a new
Great Game for all its worth
"and wants you totally out
of Central Asia."
Er.. I...
Of course, this is a quote of me
by someone else.
I do not take it as a truth.
He has interpreted maybe me...
It seems very clear, though.
No. What I was trying to say,
we have a very close and meaningful
relationship with Russia,
but I doubt that I said
that Russia wants to kick you out,
completely out of the region.
The cables reveal
how diplomats work,
the often large gap that exists
between public and private.
You will say, as part of your job,
one thing to me in an interview,
but behind closed doors,
you might say something different
to somebody from the US.
No, er... Well, er...
In normal life,
what you say at home, er,
sometimes is a bit different
from what you say outside the home,
right?
Finally, we can go beyond
the public statements
and official platitudes
and hear what diplomats really say
behind closed doors.
Particularly on the subject
of Russia.
This is one of the great stories
of the cables.
The Cold War may be over,
but America's confrontation
with Russia has never really ended.
"To transfer the S300 long-range
air-defence system to Iran."
First, I'd like to congratulate
President Putin
for being the only person
that caught a fish today.
We got one fish, but that was a...
A team effort!
The merit goes to the captain.
That's very thoughtful of you!
In 2007, publically,
the US was trying to show
how close the two countries were,
Bush and Putin
acting like the best of friends.
I've come to the conclusion
that when Russia and America speaks
along the same lines,
it tends to have an effect.
But as they were cosying up
for the cameras,
privately, US diplomats
were gathering worrying rumours
about the state of Russia.
"The elections
were not legitimate."
"The prosecutor considers Russia
to be a virtual 'Mafia state'."
And the cables show these views
were held at the highest levels.
Former Defence Secretary
Robert Gates
regularly met the most senior
Russian politicians and commanders.
We can now see his private thoughts.
"Gates observed that
Russian democracy has disappeared..."
Do you stand by that? I wouldn't say
that democracy has disappeared,
but I would say
it's under a real challenge.
Dissidents and spies,
politicians and journalists,
the Americans get their information
from anyone who's prepared to talk.
We've tracked one of the key
informants in Moscow.
Sergei Kanev
is an investigative reporter
for one of Russia's
independent newspapers.
Kanev helps us understand
how the cables are assembled.
American diplomats
pursue gossip and rumour,
gathered up by the armful.
He says he was called
by the US Embassy
and asked to meet an "official"
called Sonia.
She clearly took him seriously.
Kanev's views were wired back
to Washington.
But Kanev says this was
low-level intelligence gathering.
The woman he met
appeared almost naive
and seemed to know little
of Russian life.
"And he speculated that
the suitcases are full of money."
The cables show
increasing concerns
about Putin's attitude to the West.
And America's sources
don't hold back
in their descriptions of him.
The cables show the Americans
particularly worried
about Putin's attitude
to the countries around Russia.
Is there a sense that the Russians
are trying to exert more influence
in countries around their borders?
No question about it.
Should we be worried about that?
We are worried about it
and it's why we try to counter it.
One of the ways they did this
was to encourage
these border countries
to join the North Atlantic
Treaty Organisation, NATO,
the military alliance
of Western countries
formed to counterbalance Russia
during the Cold War.
The cables report Putin's attitude
to NATO.
For 50 years, NATO had been
America's first line of defence
against Russia.
But in recent years, it had expanded
and former Soviet countries
were now part of the alliance
and to Russia's fury,
NATO was now at its border.
Putin being himself,
you know, a very aggressive guy,
he viewed this
as a very aggressive act.
He felt he had to kind of break out
of this encirclement
that he saw NATO
as having planned for him.
The Russians started
to behave aggressively
to those wanting to join NATO,
like the small ex-Soviet state
of Georgia.
One cable reports Russia, in an
exchange about the supply of gas,
demonstrating its power.
By 2008, American advisers
were training Georgian troops,
and negotiations for their country
to join NATO
were at an advanced stage.
Hold the safety pin...
At that moment, Georgia's tensions
with Russia turned to violence.
The early cables
reflect America's horror.
"As continued Russian attacks are
inflicting terror on the population."
At the start of the crisis,
the US was careful to condemn
the violence on both sides.
The situation can be resolved
peacefully.
We've been in contact with leaders
in both Georgia and Russia,
at all levels of government.
We have urged an immediate halt
to the violence
and a stand-down by all troops.
But the secret cables show
that even though Georgia
made the first strike,
from the start, US diplomats
were seeing the confrontation
through Georgia's eyes.
Many felt the idea of Russian tanks
rolling into a neighbouring country
had been banished
with the end of the Cold War.
What were the US saying?
They were furious.
And they, er, believed
that this was a bad reversion
to Cold War-style politics.
Many Russians believed
there was more to this
than a mere border dispute.
Sergey Karagonov
was an adviser to the Kremlin.
In political terms,
we were stopping their,
er, the logic of, er,
indefinite NATO expansion.
It was a confrontation with NATO,
er, which we won. That's it.
Russia was laying down a marker
and saying,
"We're still the big dog
in the neighbourhood."
There were very, very high tensions.
Famously,
the Russian Foreign Minister
used some expletives to me
in a phone call
at the time of the crisis.
So it was a very charged
atmosphere.
And the spectre was of real...
conflict,
not of a military kind,
but of a diplomatic,
ongoing diplomatic conflict.
Those tensions between the West
and Russia were plain to see.
But the cables allow us
to go inside the room,
to see the extraordinary
personal nature
of the confrontation
between the West and Russia.
The Americans report that when the
French President Nicolas Sarkozy
meets the Russians to talk about
a peace plan for Georgia,
he ends up attacking
the Russian Foreign Minister.
"And at times
became openly hostile."
Russia routed Georgia's army, and
America was powerless to stop it.
The cables show how other countries
around Russia reacted to the war.
For the first time,
we can see the dramatic effect.
This cable reflects the fear
felt in the former Soviet state
of Estonia.
Any country that was formerly
part of the Soviet Union,
that was a former republic
of the Soviet Union,
would've looked what happened
to Georgia and thought
"This is a real worry."
They're small countries
next to a very big country,
and that always induces feelings
of fear.
I think there's no question that
the Georgia crisis exacerbated that.
Estonia was already a member
of the NATO alliance.
But in 2008,
after the war in Georgia,
that was no longer enough
to make it feel safe.
What the Baltic states wanted
was a plan.
They'd been in NATO for four years,
but, unbelievably,
there was no strategy in place
to protect Estonia from attack.
Kurt Volker was the US ambassador
to NATO.
I came at this from having worked
on NATO issues for 20 years
and my instinctive reaction was,
what they're asking for is normal.
It's a defensive alliance.
Our obligation, by treaty,
is to defend each other if attacked
and the prudent and responsible
thing to do is therefore make plans.
There was initially a murmur or wave
that said,
"Oh, no, that would be provocative!"
And for the first time,
the cables allow us
to see into this secret crisis
at the heart
of the Western Alliance.
Throughout 2009, attempts were made
to come up with a plan.
But it's clear from the cables
in private, America's allies
in Europe were nervous.
They didn't want to do
or say anything
that might suggest confrontation
with Russia.
"That the Alliance and Russia
are on course toward a new Cold War."
This is now a serious issue
for the West.
If NATO can't agree on a plan
to protect the nervous Baltic states
from Russia,
then NATO itself is threatened.
So this is a kind of
Cold War-style crisis
happening in the 21st century,
and happening in secret,
the issue being
how the West protects itself
from Russian aggression.
These were very sensitive times.
At the end of 2009, NATO made
a public approach to Russia
for help in Afghanistan.
In private, they were concluding
plans, known as Eagle Guardian,
to protect the Baltic states
from any Russian threat.
The plans made clear
where NATO units were to be deployed
in the event of an attack.
But it was decided
to keep the plan secret,
and not just from the Russians.
We've found a cable that suggests
the secrecy was essential
to the unity of NATO itself.
An American nightmare
was coming true.
Rumours of the Eagle Guardian plan
had already been around
before the cable release,
but through WikiLeaks, the Russians
could now see the detail.
And some in Russia believed
the deal, and the secrecy,
showed how weak NATO had become.
It showed us, er, simply that
the obvious fact that NATO
is not a very unified alliance.
Nobody in Europe wants the return
of the Cold War
like, er, some weird persons
in White House
or, er, in the state department.
I dare to say
to my military commanders
that if we wish, we could attack.
NATO would, er, collapse.
After the whole cable release,
there was fury
in the Russian Government
at the way their country
had been portrayed,
and with the people
who had helped the Americans.
The cable leak affected relations
at the highest levels.
What do you think it did
to the relationship between
the United States and Russia?
Without any question,
individual relationships are harmed
and many ambassadors will tell you
they were harmed,
that relationships
they had spent a long time building,
you know, there is a real chill.
America's alliances
weren't strong enough
to contain its old enemy, Russia.
But the cables show the US
also has a difficult relationship
with the world's rising power...
China.
The United States has to tread
carefully when it deals with China.
No other nation comes as near
to the United States economically
and China continues to develop
its military machine.
The cables reveal a major
military confrontation with China
that happened largely in secret.
It started in January 2007,
when, without warning,
the Chinese Army shot down
one of their own satellites.
They know how dependent we are
on satellites
for intelligence communications
and so on,
thus, their development
of an anti-satellite capability.
They have a sophisticated
and targeted approach
to identify our vulnerabilities.
Privately, the Americans registered
their anger at the Chinese move,
but they were determined
to keep public relations warm.
We don't want to see a situation
where there is any militarisation
of space.
I believe there is reason
to be optimistic
about the US-China relationship.
Behind the scenes,
things were very different.
The two powers were now locked
into a confrontation
about military power in space
and the tone of the cables
was direct and angry.
And what's interesting, in contrast
to the public pleasantries,
is the open aggression
in the cables sent to the Chinese.
In one cable, sent from the then-US
Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice,
the familiar, tactful language
has gone.
"With a wide range of options,
from diplomatic to military."
Assistant Secretary of State
Christopher Hill
was one of those taking the lead
in America's diplomacy
with the Chinese.
Condoleezza Rice,
she sends a very robust cable.
It even raises the prospect
of the use of force.
That's an amazing sense
of aggression and tension.
She was obviously, angry with
the Chinese, as we all were.
She really did let them have it
and I think they deserved it.
This is the cables
at their most revealing.
The language now being traded
between the US and China is fierce.
The Chinese response
to the American cables
is just as aggressive.
Certainly, we put down a marker
with the Chinese
and made it very clear
that we care about this.
The Chinese are not going to say,
"Goodness, we're sorry,
"we'll never do it again."
Instead they came back
with a very, uh,
you know, nasty statement
of their own.
The next message from America
was not diplomatic.
This is the USS Lake Erie,
operating in the Pacific
in the spring of 2008.
The Americans are about to shoot
down one of their own satellites.
In public, America said that
the satellite was out of control.
But from the cables,
we know the background
and the message to China
wasn't subtle.
You shot down one of your
satellites? That's right.
Was that to teach them a lesson? No.
It was to prevent the satellite
from falling to earth.
But it clearly had the, uh,
the ancillary benefit
of demonstrating
an important capability.
The more you dig into the cables,
the more the complexity of America's
relationship with China is revealed.
Despite China being
their closest rival,
the cables show the lengths
America will go to
to make the Chinese happy.
This became dramatically clear
in 2008,
when China hosted the Olympic Games.
REPORTER: Someone has tried to grab
the torch from Konnie Huq,
the Blue Peter presenter!
Someone, a man...
Protesters, angry at China's
human rights record,
tried to disrupt the journey of
the Olympic Torch around the globe.
This seemed to be the perfect moment
for America to take a stand.
We believe in human rights
and human dignity.
We believe in the human condition,
we believe in freedom
and we're willing to take the lead.
I remember when the Torch Runners
came to San Francisco,
we wanted to try and avoid
some of the same incidents
that, if I remember correctly,
occurred in Europe
where they had been prevented
from getting to their destination.
On the day the torch was to be
paraded through San Francisco,
the route was shortened
and changed at the last moment.
It was one of the few places
in the world
where the journey of the torch
was not interrupted by protesters.
America betrayed
one of its own ideals...
the right to protest...
to appease the Chinese.
And a cable
from the American Embassy in China
suggests the gamble paid off.
Some world leaders decided
not to attend the games themselves
because of China's
human rights record,
but America chose to go.
It was another US attempt
to show support for China.
I'm going to the Olympics.
I view it as a sporting event.
I'm not going to... use the Olympics
as an opportunity to express
my opinions to the Chinese people
in a public way,
because I do it all the time
with the president.
It was an important statement
by George W Bush...
"We value the relationship,
"we understand the importance
of this issue to you."
"And so, when we have issues
that we say are important to us,
"we hope you will also
pay attention." That's the message.
But did the strategy work?
One of the issues America
often raised
was the human rights
of Chinese citizens.
We raised specific cases,
uh, in particular,
an individual, noted individual
who's being detained,
who we would urge that they release.
We tried to do it more in private
than in public,
just in terms of, uh,
not antagonising, uh, the Chinese.
This is always
a very delicate balance.
Now, thanks to the cables,
we can see who America was trying
to help behind closed doors
and how they did it.
Individual cases were raised
at the highest level.
We've tracked this couple down.
Hu Jia and his wife Zeng Jinyan
are human rights campaigners
and have been in conflict
with the authorities for six years.
This video,
shot by the couple themselves,
shows the sort of intimidation
they have faced over those years.
Zeng confronts the secret police,
who follow her every move.
We could only reach her
by video phone.
In desperation, Zeng appealed
to the American Embassy for help.
What did you think
they would go and do?
What did they say to you?
What did they say they would do?
And now, thanks to the cables,
we can see the Americans
did raise the case.
But there are accusations
that this effort was half-hearted.
Sophie Richardson
is a human rights expert
who monitors China.
I think one of the things
that the cables reveal
is a gap between what people knew,
which was quite a bit,
and what they were doing about it,
which was not nearly enough.
We can see America
struggling to influence China
in the way it would like.
One of the reasons for this
is China's new economic strength,
a truth captured
in one revelatory cable.
Hillary Clinton
is talking about China
with her team
from the State Department.
After the financial crisis of 2008,
America went cap-in-hand to China.
By effectively lending the US
billions of dollars,
China saved the superpower's
finances.
The Chinese became the America's
largest foreign creditor.
It marked a seismic shift
in the balance of power
between the two nations.
The level of the US debt to China
is a national security concern.
It gives China leverage
that has significant
policy implications.
We are...
We understand that, intellectually,
we, as a government,
continue to wrestle with
"what do we do about that?"
In the months after
the financial crisis,
America bent over backwards
to emphasise the warmth
in its relationship with China.
I appreciate greatly the Chinese
Government's continuing confidence
in the United States treasuries.
But in private, American diplomats
were watching China change,
developing a new arrogance
in its diplomacy.
And in secret cables
they thought we would never read,
they make increasingly
undiplomatic comments.
And America realises its influence
over China is diminishing.
Diplomats secretly acknowledge
that China is no longer listening.
The cables report
that China is even turning
the arguments about human rights
against America.
The Chinese do not shy away from,
um, you know, using anger
and from speaking very, very plainly
on these things.
Not all diplomatic engagements
are decisive.
Sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose
and then sometimes it just,
it doesn't change.
In the end,
the cables track a failing strategy.
A strong China
chose to ignore a weakened America
and repression has worsened.
The reality is, that we are
eight or nine months into...
the worst crackdown we've seen
in China in about 15 years.
And though the US raised her case
at the highest levels,
little has changed for Zeng Jinyan.
So, what we see in that film,
is that still going on?
So, there are people
outside your house right now?
And, if anything,
the WikiLeaks cable release
has only served to harden
the conviction of some in China
that the Americans can't be trusted.
I think the cables, I think were...
became grist
for a very conservative
kind of hard-line element in China
whose entire modus operandi,
modus vivendi is,
"You must avoid
talking to foreigners.
"You must be very careful
dealing with foreigners."
The story of China,
told through the cables,
is a clear illustration
of America's declining power.
What we've found is
the United States struggling to deal
with its new rival.
But there are other nations
that America sees
as a far more direct threat.
And going through the cables,
we tracked one crisis
as it grew ever deeper.
America's ultimate nightmare is
Iran, armed with a nuclear weapon.
The start of 2012
has seen tensions rise
between Iran and the West.
The world's nuclear watchdog
says it thinks Iran could be moving
even closer to a nuclear weapon.
The cables show how America tries
and fails
to stop its worst fear.
"It may be well-suited, however,
for a military purpose."
It is possible that Iran
could have this capability
and we need to take it seriously.
Now.
But despite America's fears
and the President's strong words,
the US has a weakness
when it comes to Iran.
Since the siege of their embassy
in 1979,
the US has never re-established
diplomatic relations.
It's one of the few places
on the planet
where there are no Americans
sending cables.
The vital flow of gossip
was cut off.
From my view, we never know enough
about what's going on inside,
particularly inside
the circles of power in Iran.
But by 2006,
fresh Iranian nuclear plans
meant that had to change.
The US Government
created a web of informers,
called the Iran Watchers.
We tracked down
a state department official
who monitored their cables.
They started out in a handful
of countries and European capitals
in Istanbul and Dubai.
They would talk to
Iranian businessmen,
former Iranian diplomats,
former government officials,
academics, activists,
students, intellectuals.
They were what they call
Iran Watchers.
The Iran Watchers
are an extraordinary group.
Not quite spies, but crucial
in the gathering of intelligence.
CHANTING
The activities and identities
of the Iran Watchers
were supposed to be confidential.
Now, thanks to WikiLeaks,
those secrets are out.
"An Iranian law professor,
well known in Iran-Watcher circles,
"offered his views on his 'childhood
friend', President Ahmadinejad."
As ever with the cables,
it's the detail
that's extraordinary.
It's clear from the flow
of information
that one of Washington's
key sources was based in London.
He provided the Iran Watchers, based
in the UK, with crucial information.
We've tracked him down.
They contact me,
"Alireza, I am so and so,
"I'm an American diplomat
working for this office."
I don't like to go to embassies
or sit in a coffee shop outside,
then somebody say, "I saw Alireza
talking to this American spy."
So they come to my office.
We sit, we talk.
Now we can read
the secret intelligence
he was passing on in the cables.
I had a very reliable source
in Iraq.
He gave me a lot of information
about the Iranian agents in Iraq.
I met an American diplomat.
We talked about it.
That information was sent
to Washington in a cable.
They are very happy that
at least somebody else, beside them,
is confirming that.
The cables dealt with
a range of issues and, as ever,
any gossip or information
was coveted.
In mid-2009, accusations
of a rigged election in Iran
led to violent protests
on the streets.
The Iran Watchers picked up rumours
of what was going on
within the regime.
Amongst them,
reports of an astonishing account
of a confrontation between
Iranian President Ahmadinejad
and the head of Iran's
Revolutionary Guard.
It's one of the most shocking
revelations in the cables,
the sort of rumour
the Americans were desperate for.
That was absolutely true.
The knowledge about that event
was only between...
a bunch of people,
only about seven, eight people.
And when it came out
everybody was shocked.
When you get a cable like that,
that's a big deal.
If it ends up being true,
it demonstrates significant fissures
within the Iranian Government
that could potentially be irreparable
and the consequences
and the repercussions of that
potentially endless.
Whether the rumour is true or not
is impossible to test,
but it's clear the Iran Watchers
have plugged an intelligence hole
for the US.
Their significance is beyond doubt.
Since this process of the Iran
Watchers has been institutionalised,
it's improved the understanding
of Iran
within the US Government
exponentially.
Their importance was also not lost
on the regime in Tehran.
Worrying cables started to filter
back to Washington.
It seemed the watchers
and their sources were now targets.
"And friends in Iran suffer
harassment, intimidation,
"detention and worse."
And Ali Nourizadeh claims
he was one of the sources targeted.
They tried to kill me.
They sent, uh, the agent,
a young man, who came and showed
too much interest in me,
and he followed me for a while.
I went to United States
because he was an American citizen,
so he just came back from Iran
and met me in United States.
Nourizadeh's claim
is supported by a secret cable
which identifies the young man
as an Iranian named Sadeqinia.
The FBI was already
secretly tracking him.
When he was arrested,
he was trying to hire a killer
and the American arrested him
and he confessed.
So one day,
people from the authority here,
they came to my office,
they talked to me and they said,
"We are very concerned.
Once again, you were a target."
And this time, by this man.
He wanted to poison me.
I was shocked.
I had to be vigilant
and to be a bit more careful.
Sadeqinia confessed
to being an Iranian agent.
Iran denies all allegations of an
overseas assassination programme.
But such stories,
together with Iran's
continuing nuclear development,
revealed a new,
more aggressive Iran.
It's clear there was
a growing concern in the Middle East
at the prospect of Iran
with a nuclear bomb.
Some countries urged
the United States
to take military action.
How vociferously were you
being urged to attack Iran?
Um, people were pretty, um,
some people were pretty aggressive
in pushing it.
Who was it? What were they saying?
I'm not going to go there!
But now we know,
thanks to the cables.
Many of the calls,
perhaps not surprisingly,
came from Israeli politicians,
like cabinet minister
Yuval Steinitz.
What we did, and we are still doing,
is trying to encourage
the Western World
to handle this threat
and to prevent it,
because it's extremely
dangerous threat,
not just to Jews or to Israel
or to the Middle East,
but to the rest of
the Western democratic civilisation
all together.
But the cables also contained
a much bigger revelation...
It wasn't only Israel
that was calling for action.
It was Iran's Arab neighbours, too,
places like Saudi Arabia.
In public, Saudi diplomats acted
as though they wanted warm relations
with Iran.
Now, through the cables,
we can read what the Saudis
were saying in private,
including their ambassador
to the US, Adel al-Jubeir.
The difference is striking.
In public, the Americans
didn't distance themselves
from military action.
They made clear all options
against Iran were on the table.
Our message to the leaders of Iran
is also clear.
America will confront those
who threaten our troops,
we will stand by our allies
and we will defend our
vital interests in the Persian Gulf.
The enemy has made his
intentions clear.
The US strategy was to talk tough.
But the cables show
what they're were actually thinking.
For years,
the Americans were quite clear...
they didn't want another war.
"Wants to find an option...
other than military confrontation."
So, what could America do?
It didn't want a fight,
and Iran didn't seem keen to talk.
Faced with such limited options,
they chose a different path...
to try and strangle
the Iranian regime with sanctions.
But the cables show
this policy failed.
There wasn't enough
international support.
The documents show
that in America's opinion,
countries like Germany
said one thing in public,
but another in private.
In the end, only limited sanctions
were introduced
and these made little difference.
The US is still faced
with its worst nightmare.
Let me give you a very dark scenario
and I hope we never get there.
We're speeding along a highway, the
Iranian Nuclear Programme Highway,
and a lot of off-ramps are starting
to show up in our rear-view mirror,
you know,
the off-ramp about sanctioning,
and we're speeding towards...
And I can make out
there's a fork in the road
and I can even make out the signs,
and the fork in the road says
"Do something or do nothing."
That's a horrible place to be.
I've had three American presidents,
three successive presidents,
saying Iran getting a weapon
is unacceptable.
As a native speaker,
I think I know what that means.
The recent announcement
from the UN's nuclear watchdog
that Iran is enriching uranium
has moved the unacceptable
much nearer the reality.
Years of effort have failed to stop
Iran's desire to get a nuclear bomb,
an event the Americans believe
would have grave consequences.
Iran will use the possession
of nuclear weapons
to intimidate its neighbours.
I think it also is very likely
to spark a nuclear arms race
in the region.
At least one or two other countries
probably feeling compelled to have
nuclear weapons if Iran does...
I think it's incredibly
destabilising,
just as a war would be.
If we've learned anything
from Iraq and from Afghanistan,
it's how unpredictable war is
once it's started.
WikiLeaks exposed
the uncomfortable reality
of America's relations with Iran,
China and Russia.
But a year on, the impact
of the cables hasn't finished yet.
Bradley Manning, the man accused
of leaking the cables,
is still held
in US military custody.
He's due to go before
a court martial,
but no longer faces
the death penalty.
Julian Assange is appealing against
his extradition to Sweden
on sexual assault allegations.
He currently faces no charges
in the US,
though a grand jury
continues to consider his case.
And the website he founded
has been subject to an unprecedented
global financial blockade
by companies including MasterCard,
Visa and PayPal.
Assange recently announced
that the blockade
had cut off 95 percent
of WikiLeaks' revenues
and that it was suspending
publishing.
The website now carries
this message...
The WikiLeaks cables allowed us
a glimpse behind the door,
to see a superpower's secrets.
That door has now slammed shut.
Many Americans believe long-term,
the leaks will not cause
significant damage
and the US remains the world leader.
The US is still
the indispensible power.
Nothing in the
international environment gets done
in a constructive way
unless the United States
plays a central role.
And so what I saw
as Secretary of Defence is,
WikiLeaks not withstanding
and everything else,
the vast majority of countries
in the world
want a better, stronger relationship
with the United States,
and where there is still...
enormous respect
for all kinds of our power,
political, economic and military.
But others believe the cables
show America is a declining power.
People were a bit disturbed
how ineffective
the United States were,
that they allowed these leaks.
That came on the background
of other failures
of the US Government,
starting with Iraq,
through Afghanistan,
to their internal debt crisis.
So that diminished
the weight and the respect
towards the United States,
which is unfortunate.
I think the cables show the changing
shape of power in the world.
American remains
the one global superpower,
politically, economically,
militarily,
but it's not a superpower
that can click its fingers
and expect the rest of the world
to come to heel.
Hidden in these secret documents
are American dreams that died
and nightmares that came true.
They show the ambition, the scale
and, at times, the honesty
of a superpower's secret life.
And they also may reveal
the places and problems
that, in the end,
might weaken US power for good.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru