A Hiroto Yokoyama Production
HARUNA TAKASE
YOSHIO HARADA
Director
HIROTO YOKOYAMA
MAN“
(Swastika)
who're you?
Oh, you came to
give me hush money?
- I...
- Don't worry.
I'm not a busybody.
I won't tell the cops.
You can't tell anyone.
I won't.
Go away.
I have some money.
You're so uncool.
I'm really...
I didn't say
you could come in.
I...
My husband's a cop.
He's a detective in the
Ikejiri precinct.
So if this gets out...
I can get you some more.
Enough already.
Don't stare.
Tm son-y.
I won't tell anyone
you are a thief.
Will this do?
Thanks.
Leave.
I appreciate it.
May I clean your house
to thank you?
What should I do?
Wait.
I didn't say
you could come in.
Let me do something.
Hey, you.
Don't touch anything.
I said don't.
Hit me some more.
Are you satisfied?
You still want
to do something?
I'll do anything.
Then lick the milk
off the floor.
You said you'd do
anything.
You're a pig.
Since you're a cop's wife.
You cut my mouth.
Does it hurt?
There's dust in the milk.
You're very pretty-
You have cute breasts.
Do you want to suck them?
Damn you.
You forgot again.
Stop.
But... no.
Use protection.
Protection?
Okay.
Which one today?
The red one?
I can't get in the mood
just like that.
What about dinner?
What's this scratch?
Scratch?
This is no ordinary scratch.
I don't know
how it got there.
You must know.
Someone scratched you.
It's just an abrasion.
I must have...
That's a lie.
A lie.
What do you suspect me of?
Damn you.
Tell me.
- What did you do?
- I don't know.
You must know
You're lying.
I can't know everything
about myself.
Do you think
I'm having an affair?
Don't forget
the protection.
Welcome.
Sony to keep you waiting.
I thought I had
the wrong restaurant.
Tm son-y.
Forgive me.
This is my treat.
The paella here
is fabulous.
I love paella.
I thought so.
Two beers please.
Or do you prefer wine?
How long did you wait?
Three days.
But...
...here we are.
This is so extreme.
Yes. Like a horse.
An iron horse. This model
costs about 50,000 dollars.
Five? Mitsuko, you know
a lot about bikes?
I have an RZ.
Doesn't it have
a nice behind?
Yeah, how much?
I'll give it to you
for free.
Idiot.
Fool.
Oh.
I need to pee.
Hold it in.
I can't.
Hum!-
Sonoko?
Say' Pee...
Pee...
Pee?
Peeee...
I can't go.
Do it again.
Peee...
That's the third train.
Will you get on the next one?
I'll watch you go.
I don't like this.
Why won't you see me home?
It's already 11 p.m.
I'm not good at goodbyes.
Always.
I'm not a sprinter.
I want to be in
for the long run.
Along distance runner...
Someone I can run
with forever.
That's the kind of person
I like.
Then I'm not your type.
You can run.
Do you think
I can still run?
Not still.
I can run.
You should be positive.
Now.
Bye.
Mitsuko.
I'm home.
You're late again.
Tm son-y.
I hear the number of husbands
who don't want their wives
hanging around is increasing.
Do you have something
on your mind?
You can't do this
while you're pre-occupied.
You're not feeling well?
Yes?
Then let's not.
Did something happen?
Are you hiding
something from me?
No?
Is that the truth?
Okay then.
Go to sleep.
Wine and spare ribs.
Thanks for bringing them.
I've been hungry
since morning.
But I didn't feel like
doing anything.
My period started
this morning.
I have heavy periods,
I feel blue.
- Is that so?
- How about you?
Mine are light.
I envy you.
I'd rather do a lump-sum
payment. Don't you?
Lump-Sum payment?
Yeah, it's like paying
interest every month.
You think it's finished but
it keeps coming back...
Look, Sonoko.
Wouldn't it be great
if ours happened
at the same time?
If yours is heavy,
I wish mine could be too, so
I could feel blue.
Then I'll look forward
to my periods.
Well?
I couldn't tell what was
happening inside.
- Who is she?
- I asked the super.
She comes from Osaka,
2-18-3 Ashiya City.
Her name's Mitsuko,
an eldest daughter.
She works at Tokyo Research
in Jinnan, Shibuya.
It's a part-time job.
Did she have a man
in there?
I was outside the door.
But her hair seemed
a bit disheveled.
Disheveled?
Is that so?
Where are you going?
Please don't leave.
I won't.
You're lying.
You were looking
at your watch.
My husband comes home
at seven.
Oh?
I'm the type
who won't be lonely
even if I'm left alone.
Does he get mad when
you come home late?
Do you make up in bed, then?
You probably moan
while you're doing it.
Mitsuko.
Even so, I love you.
Your body,
your tender heart...
I can't leave.
When you say such things,
I don't care what happens
anymore.
Sonoko.
I had to hear your voice
before I went home.
I can't go home,
I won't sleep if I did.
Sonoko. Did you think
you could sleep tonight?
I've given up long ago.
No matter how many sheep
I count, I can't sleep.
I'm going to drink with
a friend till morning.
Friend?
I have friends from Osaka
and from work.
I have two friends
with me now.
I'm not lonely.
So don't worry
and go home.
Go home to your husband.
Mitsuko.
Come for just one hour.
Please?
I will.
Mitsuko.
Welcome home.
What are you doing?
You're a housewife.
I have obligations.
It can't be helped.
You have to be
more responsible.
Mitsuko Shido.
Who is she? The woman
in that apartment.
What do you do
in that room?
What apartment?
Don't act innocent.
But...
It's no use denying it.
Look.
You left home at 10 a.m.
and went to Hiroo in a taxi.
There you bought wine
and spare ribs.
Then you went to this
Shido woman's apartment.
Not me.
I didn't go to Hiroo today.
You...
That's a big lie.
Was it really me?
Can you say definitely
it was me?
Then why didn't you
call out to me?
You...
You followed
some other woman.
If you're following someone,
you don't announce yourself.
Who is it?
Yes?
Are you Miss Shido?
Yes...
What's your relationship
with my wife?
- Huh?
- Don't "huh" me.
How do you know my wife?
What do you mean?
You're brazen.
Lying like that.
I'm not really...
But who are you?
- I...
- You keep quiet.
You must be in the
wrong apartment.
You've got
the wrong person.
I don't. I saw.
What did you see?
I have something on the
stove. Please leave.
Tum it off.
I don't take orders
from you.
Who are you?
I have never set eyes
on this woman before.
That won't fly.
I'm a cop.
How long has it been
since I last saw you?
When I try to remember
your face at night,
the details escape me.
I hate myself for
not remembering.
I wrote letters to you...
many times.
Although I didn't send them.
Give them to me.
I tore them up.
Idiot.
We can't use my place
anymore.
Since the cop came,
my super warned me
in a roundabout way.
Let's meet somewhere else
from now on.
Where?
Let's see...
What was the grave
we just saw?
There were two names
on the same grave.
Two people who committed
double suicide
are buried together there.
Oh.
I'd like to be buried
with you, like that.
Let's buy a plot somewhere
for the two of us.
Then we can be buried
together.
We'll be together
forever.
You promise?
Look I'm going to hide
behind that grave.
Pretend I'm dead
and tell me everything
you're feeling.
I can't.
I want you to tell me honestly
how you really feel about me.
You can do it if you think
I'm really dead.
All right?
Tell me everything.
This is my grave.
Mitsuko.
Mitsuko...
You know...
When you were alive,
I always wanted you
so much it hurt.
That's right.
I loved everything about you.
Your breasts...
I wanted to rip them off
and make them my own
and always have them
with me.
When I kissed the eyes
I loved,
I wanted to suck them in
and swallow them.
Sometimes, I'd want to
tear you to pieces.
I was afraid of
my own feelings.
No...
I still am.
Mitsuko.
Say something.
Why did you die?
We should have died
together.
Exactly at the same second.
Mitsuko?
I can tell you this
because you're dead.
Laugh from beyond
the grave.
I wanted our bodies to be
connected deep inside
and do anything,
no matter how hard,
to create something
between the two of us.
You could have been
the one. Or I.
No, I wanted you
to have it.
Our baby.
If we had to die, I wanted
all three of us...
You and I alone, all three
of us to die together.
I'm freezing.
I wish the whole world
would just freeze over.
I wish everyone else would die,
leaving just the two of us.
I'm going to bury the sea.
It's so serene,
it's such a liar.
Idiot!
Pretending
everything': fine.
That's right.
Life's not like that.
She's right.
Say it will be.
Mitsuko. I got my period.
Now?
I'm hot.
I'm so hot.
Huh?
Me, too.
Mitsuko.
We're...
Sonoko,
we buried the sea.
Sea? We can do anything.
If you look serene
tomorrow
I won't forgive you.
Yes, this is Kakiuchi.
What?
Oh, you're staying over?
You're staying there?
You don't want
to come home?
Er, no. That's fine.
Yes go ahead.
Here you go.
You have to think about
the last train
when you're having an affair.
It's not like that.
You were always bad at
details, Sonoko.
Shoko, are you...?
Does it show?
How far along?
Twenty-four weeks,
so six months.
You're brave.
Single parents are in
these days.
Oh, you have a guest?
Here, Shoko.
Why did you come all
the way from Osaka...
You drank my liquor.
I thought you wouldn't mind.
Don't scold.
What about the
news dealership?
Who's going to manage it
if you're not there?
I hired a new guy.
He's really handsome.
A hard worker.
I left him in charge.
Oh, another man.
Forgive me. I really feel
guilty about you.
I was giving up men
and focusing on the business.
That was my intention, but
before I knew it,
I had a man. I don't know
how it happened.
How should I know?
I need to talk to you.
Have some.
Thanks.
Don't get mad.
I won't know until
you tell me.
You're so cold towards me.
It's hard on me.
I'm pregnant.
Again;
I didn't plan it.
It happened
all of a sudden.
At your age?
No? I guess I shouldn't.
I'm asking why
you weren't careful?
I was just drifting off.
I didn't want to refuse him.
So it just happened.
Tell me what to do.
What's there to do?
If you say get rid of it,
I was going to do it in
Tokyo secretly.
How shameful.
If I were you, I'd killed
myself long ago.
It's not like
I'm a nymphomaniac.
I'm just lonely.
Sometimes I'm so lonely
I can't stand it.
You'll understand when
you're my age.
As you get older,
you find a cold weight
settling on you.
A sorrow you can't
explain to anyone.
I bet Sonoko': awake.
She's all uptight.
Why don't you
help her relax?
Idiot.
No!
Stop.
Sonoko!
Mitsuko...
I'm home.
Hi.
We have a guest?
It's Ms. Shido.
- What?
- It's not like that.
I ran into her in Shibuya
after that.
We got friendly
over coffee.
You have lots of awards.
Any cop who's been working
for ten years has them.
You were so happy when you received
the Commissioner's Award.
He was like a kid. He did
a painting about it.
Commissioner's Award?
Does he do oil painting?
He's a weekend painter.
Rather, he paints
on his days off.
A cop Henri Rousseau?
- Is this his?
- Yes.
A clothes hanger?
What a strange painting.
This is a crime scene.
Crime scene?
The corpse was
under the hanger.
A Corpse?
“Di a girl.
I thought for a moment
the girl slipped off the
clothes hanger and died.
Scary.
I was a detective in
Fukagawa then.
The crime scene was
in Shimotakaido.
Shimotakaido?
When I moved to Tokyo,
my first apartment
was in Shimotakaido.
Oh yeah?
Then you must know
the theater near the station.
Of course.
It happened in
an old apartment behind it.
I see...
You're still up?
Why?
Does it bother you?
I thought you said you'd
see her to the station.
We got talking...
Come here.
I was hoping I was wrong...
What do you mean?
You must know what
I suspect.
Why don't you come out
and say it?
You two are...
you know...
les... lesbians.
You're so vulgar.
I'll try to forget everything
until now.
- So stop seeing her.
- No.
What if I refuse?
I'll kill.
Which one of us?
Me or Mitsuko?
I don't care which.
If one dies, the other won't
keep on living.
Don't you get it?
What you two are doing is...
unnatural.
It's abnormal.
I can't help being
in love with her.
I love Mitsuko so much...
It's not as though I'm
having an affair with a man.
What's it's to you if I have
a close woman friend?
Of course it matters.
Since we live together.
Are you out of your mind?
You're older so you'll be
held responsible.
I know that.
What about me, then?
Even if I look the other way,
even if I didn't know,
I'd be the one people
will blame.
I'll be mined.
You always think
of yourself.
You won't try to understand...
me GS a WONG“.
That's not true.
I've gone along with you
about not having a baby.
I've always worn protection
the past ten years.
I've tried to live
according to your wishes.
But I won't condone
lesbianism.
Then we'll have to split up.
Divorce me.
Let me go.
I have no reason to.
"Why did you get divorced?"
"My wife had an illicit lesbian
relationship."
How can I admit that in public?
Think about it.
What did our lives together
mean, then?
We can argue because
we have a ten-year history.
But you talk of divorce
so easily.
Let's try to work this out.
Right.
Then consent to my
seeing her.
I won't.
Are you kidding?
Think of your age!
It was a gift.
It's too much for me alone.
Dear? Can Mitsuko
stay over tonight?
Really? You sure?
Right?
I loved Kamakura.
Don't you want to go again?
Kamakura?
That cemetery, remember?
I wonder if the sea is flat
again tonight.
When did you go
to Kamakura?
When?
I forget.
I'm going to sleep.
But...
I'm not saying
you can't go.
I think your husband's cold.
Dear? Can you try
not to cough?
I can't sleep.
But I'm cold.
I have an idea.
It'll be warm if all three of
us slept close together.
Just like kids,
we'll squish together.
There's nothing dirty about it.
So let's.
Good night.
- Rice.
- Coming.
Aren't you eating?
I want to watch you eat.
I want to many you.
We're already a couple.
Why don't you move in?
I could... but I'm scared
of your husband.
I wasn't going to tell you...
but when I woke to go
to the bathroom,
your husband got up, too,
and when we passed,
he groped my ass.
I'm scared.
Is she still there?
What?
How brazen of her.
I... I hate that type
of women.
She's staying over again?
All right.
I'll come home early.
Dear which necktie?
What? The right.
Right? You mean this?
The other one.
Hey. Is that woman
still asleep?
She got up ages ago.-
Be careful. She's pushy.
There's no end to this.
'Morning.
Six.
He really is a cop.
He sneaked up on me
and whispered,
"We need to talk."
He's pretending he has
business with you and said,
- "Come to Ginza."
- "I'll buy you dinner."
"Meet me in front of Wako
at six p.m."
I wonder what he wants
to talk to me about.
I wonder if he's going
to seduce me.
Are you going?
Should I?
Go.
If you say so.
I'll go.
Let's go together.
What?
Sorry-
I love babies.
Go to your mama.
I have to go to work.
Oh, he's wet.
Excuse me.
Sonoko? Can you stop by
my apartment and get my boots?
Sure.
It's the slouchy one
near the door.
- All right.
- Thanks.
Mitsuko. Why don't you
just move in?
But, don't you like having
a second house?
And it's the place
where we first...
You'll be late.
Why don't you go?
I'm leaving.
- Come again.
- Thanks.
Sonoko?
Does your husband know
about you two?
Yes.
How long has she been
living with you?
Three months.
I think you're going to
lose control of her.
- It happened here?
- Oh, wait.
Now.
Wow.
It's that painting.
How old was she?
Sixteen.
Her grandpa killed her.
Her grandpa?
How old are you?
Sixteen.
Sixteen?
Should I strangle you?
You mustn't.
No.
I can't, where someone
was strangled.
You're a special guest
to my workplace today.
You mustn't object.
Not these.
I wanted the short one.
Oh. Tm son-y.
I'm home.
It's cold.
I asked her to fetch my
boots from my apartment.
She brought the wrong one.
I'll go exchange them
tomorrow.
No. I'll go.
I can fetch them
on my way home.
Really?
It's the grey one in the hack
of the shoe cabinet.
The grey one?
Okay,
If you need anything else,
write it down.
Is the bath ready?
Oh, my earrings...
I...
I'm thinking of going back
to my apartment.
I don't get
enough sleep here.
Why?
When you and your husband
are fast asleep,
I try not to disturb you
so I can't sleep.
All this time?
Yes.
Why didn't you tell me?
I can't be so selfish.
If you can't sleep,
I'll stay awake, too.
I will never sleep.
Can you sleep?
No.
I can't either.
Look, since we're all up,
why don't we play a game?
Whit game?
I'll be the wolf.
You two are travelers.
Us, travelers?
The travelers will be
mauled to death.
The travelers are camping
in a cold hut in the fields.
At midnight, the wolf starts
to howl outside the door.
You two. In here.
Sit and pretend
to be travelers.
Hum!-
Now. Make a campfire.
Hey, listen to the wolf.
Add wood into the fire.
What are you doing?
Slop!
Sonoko. I ate your leg.
You can't walk.
You win.
You're a corpse.
Don't get up.
Die.
When you killed me,
you did it so quickly.
Dear?
Bathroom.
Mitsuko?
What?
I want to be alone with you
like before.
Mitsuko?
When did you live here?
It was just when I moved
to Tokyo...
so three years ago?
Did you live here alone?
What are you asking?
You had sex with a man
here before haven't you?
I suppose.
How many?
One, two, three, four...
lots more.
I'm a savage, so I can't
count higher.
You're avoiding
my question.
Mitsuko?
How about women?
You fool.
I wanted to come here with you.
It's so quiet,
I love it here.
The hanger': strong.
It's a weird room.
You can see the firehouse
from the back window
and there's two firetrucks
in an otherwise empty garage,
crouched like beasts.
Mitsuko.
Let's play police
interrogation tonight.
Police interrogation?
- You're hurting me.
- Sit.
I am going to
start the interrogation.
We don't say that.
First...
I'll start the interrogation.
Tell us everything.
Takeshi Kakiuchi.
You know a woman
named Mitsuko Shido?
Yes, I do.
You do not have to make
incriminating statements,
but you must not lie.
When did you
and Mitsuko Shida
become intimate?
Answer me.
I did not have sex
with Mitsuko Shido.
How many times have you met her
in the room with the hanger?
I have proof.
I want dates and times of
the sexual encounters.
Sexual encounter?
I forget.
- Don't lie.
- Hey, don't do that.
Answer me.
Takeshi Kakiuchi affidavit.
About 6 p.m. on January 25th,
I met Mitsuko Shido at Sakamoto
restaurant in Dogenzaka Shibuya
and afterwards went to
Hotel Chateau nearby
and had sex with her
for the first time.
We were at the hotel
for three hours.
The hotel cost 62 dollars.
Since February 2nd
was a Saturday,
Hotel Chateau was full.
We went to Hotel Eden
next door.
After sexual intercourse,
Mitsuko asked my opinion
of the difference
between her body and
that of my wife Sonoko.
When I said Mitsuko's taut
stomach was more appealing
to my wife's sagging stomach,
Mitsuko was inordinately
happy-
Because of that, the
second sex act
seemed more pleasurable
than the first.
Stop, stop. I quit.
This isn't funny.
- I'm quitting.
- You can't.
- Don't run.
- This isn't play acting.
Sit.
- This isn't fun.
- Sit.
This is a real investigation.
You just listen and answer
the questions.
What is this?
Takeshi Kakiuchi.
First you were annoyed
when Mitsuko started
living in your house.
But in the end, you gave your
implicit consent
of a man and two women
living together.
Is that correct?
- Yes, that may be...
- It wasn't implicit.
He was very pleased.
Are you kidding?
I was just...
If you didn't want the
three of us to live together,
why didn't you
chase us out?
I thought many times
of leaving myself.
Then why didn't you?
You're really stupid.
If I left, how could you two
keep on living in police housing?
Have you lost your minds?
I was prepared to face
public opinion.
Who cares about
public opinion?
Don't underestimate it.
You're small-minded.
You had a lover then.
Tell me her name.
Sonoko Kakiuchi.
Yet, you had sex with
her husband.
Didn't you think
that was a betrayal?
I did.
But there isn't a law that
punishes a lover's betrayal.
But if you love someone
you want to be hers alone...
Even if you think so,
it's impossible to do.
In the first place,
why do you think I fell
in love with Kakiuchi?
Because he was
your husband.
That was huge.
If he wasn't your husband,
I wouldn't look twice
at this middle-aged man.
I bet it was the same
with him.
Because I was yours,
he was intrigued by me.
Isn't that right?
Then what am I?
Hey, Detective.
Shine the light on her.
You used the light on me.
Why don't you do the same
and make her talk?
Shut up!
Look...
I felt sexual pleasure
with him.
But what about him?
I wonder about that.
I wonder how
ejaculation feels.
- Do you want to know?
- I do.
But I'll never know.
A woman can't know
how intense it is.
Does a man really enjoy it?
When I think like that,
I find men unsatisfactory.
Do you mean you weren't
satisfied with my body?
That's not it.
I can't trust men.
Is it Takeshi Kaikuchi
you can't trust
or all men?
That's important, so
you must think carefully.
I will.
Who can't you trust?
Takeshi Kakiuchi.
But... I fell in love
with him
and I couldn't stop
myself even for you
because my body
responded.
- Mitsuko...
- It's true.
- When I...
- Stop.
You know,
sometimes it was
a burden...
You were so serious.
"I, Sonoko Kakiuchi
"begged Mitsuko to continue
the relationship
"in her apartment.
"I groveled for
three hours licking
“Mitsuko Shido's attractive
breasts, her underarm
"and lower abdomen...
every inch of her body.
"And was in ecstasy."
Did you really do that?
How did you do it?
Show me.
Were you always a lesbian?
Answer me.
I plead the fifth.
I inquire for background.
Are you glad you were
born a woman?
- Yes.
- Why?
Why is it better
than being a man?
Because women
have a uterus.
That doesn't mean anything.
Never mind that.
Talk about your relationship
with your husband.
No, don't.
Don't talk.
"What shocked me
"was being in bed with my
back to my husband
"and masturbating.
"I've done it several times
after my husband fell asleep.
"I loved the certainty of
masturbation.
"My husband confided that
he did it sometimes, too."
So what's wrong
with that?
How does that reflect
on our marriage?
Listen to me, Sonoko.
You must have enjoyed
doing it the last ten years?
Tell me the truth.
It just hurt.
Don't lie.
I remember, although
the times were few,
when you were convulsing
with pleasure.
There are those
infrequent moments.
More frequent than that.
So, Sonoko.
Tell me one thing.
That room with the hanger?
Why did you take
Sonoko Kakiuchi there?
When did you go?
Did you want to end all this?
Confess.
I said, confess.
What the...
No, not like that.
This is how it's done...
Ow...
Tell me.
Confess.
Answer me, Mitsuko.
Say something.
The telephone': ringing.
Aren't you going
to get it?
Hello?
Yeah?
What?
All right.
Who are you?
What?
He hung up.
A whistle blower.
Mitsuko Shido': hiding
that she's three months
pregnant.
That's ridiculous.
Who impregnated you?
He didn't say.
- Who is it?
- Stop this nonsense.
You have to tell the truth.
It's true.
I am pregnant.
Tell me the truth.
I'm pregnant with
your child, Sonoko.
Sonoko.
We've already paid
a heavy price.
Can we start over?
Live an uneventful life...
peaceful...
Then what was the ten years
you spent together?
It's no use trying to be
considerate of each other now.
Sonoko.
You have to leave him.
With me.
Why not?
You're pregnant,
Mitsuko.
Yes.
My period...
started this morning.
That interrogation?
That was Sonoko
holding her own wake.
Sonoko.
You mustn't say that.
Don't.
Sonoko.
Directed by
HIROTO YOKOYAMA
THE END