Edited at https://subtitletools.com
[Gildas] We have a spy
inside the Cantii citadel.
This spy tells me
Kerra came to see you.
What deal did you make with her?
[Divis]
Lokka himself is here.
[Cait] So why did
the Druids cast you out?
[Divis] Because
I was possessed by Pwykka.
He's one of the three
Demon Kings.
So he's still
inside you?
Pwykka's been asleep
for a year now,
but with all these rumblings,
| feel him.
[Quane] If Lokka is here,
Pwykka won't be far behind.
Veran took the Roman General
to the Underworld.
Follow his footsteps.
Only then will you know
what it is he seeks,
and what might save us.
It's you.
You will defeat them.
I must hurry.
Pwykka!
[gasping for breath]
[m]
J‘ Thrown like a star
in my vast sleep J‘
J‘ I opened my eyes
to take a peek J‘
J‘ To find
that l was by the sea J‘
J‘ Gazing with tranquillity J‘
J‘ 'Twas then
when the Hurdy Gurdy Man J‘
J‘ Came singing
songs of love J‘
J‘ Then when
the Hurdy Gurdy Man J‘
J‘ Came singing J‘
J‘ Songs of love J‘
J‘ Hurdy gurdy, hurdy gurdy J‘
J‘ Hurdy gurdy gurdy, he sang J‘
[m]
[crowd cheering in distance]
[crowd shouting and cheering]
Go on, see
what's happening.
[crowd cheering]
[m]
I pledge eternal loyalty,
my queen.
May the gods protect you.
Lindon of the Gaul,
come forward.
You have proved yourself
a noble warrior
in the service
of my father.
If you agree,
I would have you serve
as General of all our forces.
[quietly] Help me.
May the gods protect you.
My queen.
I pledge my undying loyalty.
May the gods protect you.
-Thank you.
-Next.
Two, please.
Two.
There you are.
Thank you.
There we go.
So..?
Come on,
paint me a picture.
Tall.
Pale skin.
Long hair...
like a proper queen.
Does she look wise?
Very.
She‘s going to need to be.
What colour hair?
Red, like fire.
I knew it.
Your mother
had red hair.
lslene had
a touch of it, too.
The gods only give their fire
to their favourites.
Only for
the special ones.
ltdoesnt
make sense.
What doesn't?
When I was out there
on the rocks,
day after day,
dragging wet salt
up that hill,
one thing kept me going,
that l was raising
someone special,
that the gods
gave me lslene
to raise for them
for a special purpose,
and I'd better not mess it up.
So why did
the gods punish me?
Your brother
spoke to the Roman,
then freed the girl
and they left together.
Whatever you're thinking
right now, it's wrong.
Your brother
is now your enemy.
There's is no love
left between you.
Phelan would never
betray his tribe.
Summon the Roman.
My brother
came to see you.
What did he say?
What did he want to know?
Your father
asked me questions, too.
Where did that get him?
Rome kept its word.
You're free to go.
But with this message.
Tell your General
that I will speak with him.
But he comes here,
to me.
I'll pass your message on.
[sighs with satisfaction]
I think he's going
to like it here.
After all,
it is a fine fortress.
[door creaks open]
What are you
doing in here?
The queen demands
that we remain together,
for the stability
of the tribe.
Then we must do
as the queen demands.
I'll find
somewhere else to stay.
If we're going to pretend,
we might as well
make it convincing,
for the good of the tribe,
and all.
[Lindon sighs sadly]
I don't hate you, Amena.
In fact,
I feel sorry for you.
Thank you, Lindon,
but there's really no need.
I've always been
very resourceful in adversity.
[door closes]
[m]
[Amena intoning]
Your hands protect me
from Dark Moon to Dark Moon...
[gasping]
Your sword covers me
from Dark Moon to Dark Moon.
Your care shelters me
[gasping]
All love and honour
to the Dark Mother Nehellania.
[gasping]
She shall be blinded
by the fear...
Blinded by the pain.
[words echo and repeat]
Bound by me, cursed by me...
Dark Mother, send me a demon
to do my will...
[gasping in effort and ecstasy]
[hissing and snarling]
Praefectus.
That night
the prisoner escaped,
you were in the sickbay,
had a clear view
of where he was tied up.
That's right, Praefectus.
Did you see
anything?
What like?
Like a blind man
freeing himself
and escaping from
a heavily-armed camp?
There was something...
What?
A small girl.
Pale.
Mousey hair.
She called him "father".
She freed him.
And you didn't think
to mention this before?
[soldiers shout in alarm]
[soldiers shout outside]
Shit, Shit, Shit!
Get up.
Get on your feet.
We're getting out of here.
Move.
She wants to talk.
Not in the field,
in her fortress.
[Aulus] Then talk we shall.
What, so we just
let this pass?
Roll over,
let her tickle your tummy.
We're dealing with
a new regime now.
What do you think, Vitus?
Do you think we can
persuade the new queen
of a golden future
inside the Empire?
She's not like her father,
is she?
I mean, why waste
Roman lives
on the battlefield
when common sense can win?
[sighs]
No skin off my nose.
Uaughs]
That's the spirit.
Vitus, the day of the ambush,
we've a legionary here
who was with you,
claims Vespasian
sent him back here.
Is that his story?
Oh, dear.
Assemble
an advance party.
We'll march
to Crugdunon
and parlay
with Queen Kerra.
Before I forget,
the blind prisoner.
Laughing Boy says
he knows how he escaped.
Oh? How?
A little girl.
His daughter.
She broke into camp
and freed him.
What?
A little girl?
He's a bullshitter.
I swear,
when | find him,
|wi|| fucking kill him!
Did he say
what she looked like?
Small, pale,
dark cloak,
mousey hair.
She called him "father."
Oh, he saw this happen?
I told you,
he's a bullshitter.
But I know this much,
someone freed that Cantii.
l fed his fucking eyeballs
to the crows.
A blind man...
A blind father.
Right...
Where are you?
Over here.
Whoever has the stick,
make a noise before I toss this.
What kind of noise?
Like a pig.
Squeal like a pig,
give me something to aim at.
[snorting]
Uaughs]
What happened?
[laughing] Too high, Dad!
Sounded like a very tall pig.
All right, let's try again.
-[snorting]
-Again?
[boy snorting]
Where'd it go?
[fabric tearing]
Ow!
Looking for this?
Your queen speaks to you.
What's your name?
I don't have a name.
Don't be scared.
I gave it away
at the Solstice.
The Romans attacked
before I had my new name.
Come with me.
Follow me.
[m]
Come.
My mother made this.
I wore it the day
after my solstice.
My first day as a woman.
It's beautiful.
Try it.
I can't take this.
It's yours.
It's for somebody important.
Well, soon be covered in mud,
if you're anything like me.
Do you have
family here?
Just me and Dad.
lslene was killed by a Roman.
lslene?
My big sister.
I'll see her again when I die.
Dad said there's a place
for the ones the gods love most.
It sounds like your father
misses her very much.
He does.
She was special.
Well, that can't be easy
for you.
How do you mean?
Well, sometimes,
fathers, they decide
who their children are,
for their own reasons.
It doesn't mean it's true.
lslene was special.
What do you think?
Is that me?
That's you.
[m]
I'm back!
Ah, we were worried.
Where are you?
[snorting enthusiastically]
[chuckling] That's my girl.
[all laughing playfully]
[m]
Afternoon.
Lovely day.
Aren't they all?
You look well.
Have you put on
a bit of weight?
I take it
they've met before?
Apparently, yes.
I thought so.
I need to thank you,
for sticking to your part
of the bargain.
Was there one?
Well, Pellenor's dead,
Kerra's queen.
And the sky is blue,
thank the gods.
Why don't you
thank them for me?
You were followed.
On your journey.
Or did you think you
were alone down there?
That it was
just for you?
And how do you know,
were you there, too?
You were careless, Rome.
Or perhaps too eager.
Either way,
someone else was there,
saw what you saw,
knows what you know.
Don't you want to know his name?
I know his fucking name.
Of course.
You've met before.
You've been most accommodating.
Very helpful.
But from now on, let's say
we strike another deal.
And what's that?
You keep away from me,
and I'll keep away from you.
You stay away
from the Citadel.
You have no power there.
Not anymore.
Are you threatening the Druids?
l'm warning you.
You remind me of someone,
someone I met a long time ago.
And who's that?
Julius Caesar.
What happened to him?
Do we have a deal?
The gods
don't deal, Rome.
The gods don't deal.
Is he ready?
Nearly.
Very nearly.
Who's your skinny friend?
He's no friend of mine.
Forward!
[legion marching rhythmically]
[Pwykka snarling and hissing]
[snarling]
[slathering]
Halt!
[gasping for breath]
Help me, please...
[dying man gasping and wheezing]
[whispers]
It's all right.
Who did this to you?
His name...
is...
Pwykka.
[gasping and choking]
[man sputtering and wheezing]
[bones crunching]
Forward!
You're late.
Yeah, sorry about that.
Where's my present?
Present?
The Druid's head--
[together] --On a stick.
Yes, I'm working on it.
How many?
5,000.
They're all standing by
across the river.
I can muster twice that
by the next moon.
My warriors are drawing lots
to cut the copperknob's throat.
They'll have to wait
in line behind me.
I'd like you
to stand your army down,
until I've spoken
to the new queen.
You'll all die in this field
before that happens.
It will take four days
to march three legions here.
Tell me,
how will your 5,000,
10,000 warriors fare
against 20,000 of us.
Like it red then, do you?
Do you want to bed her
before she dies?
Stand your army down
until I give the order
to attack.
You'll have to kiss
more than my foot
to sell that one to me.
Once the Citadel has fallen,
the emperor
will recognize you as queen
of all the Cantii lands.
Does that hit the spot?
One day,
and it will be sooner
than you wish,
you Romans will be no more than songs
and ruins in our land.
We don't want you.
We don't need you.
That is how the story ends.
But until then,
you will stand down your army?
Until dawn.
Then you can lick my crack.
Get in my way,
and we'll kill you all.
[crowd murmuring]
[gasping awake]
Is anybody there?
[m]
Amena...
Are you my demon?
I beg your pardon?
Amena...
Who is this?
Don't speak with her.
She's an imposter.
Amena, that's enough.
It's me you should speak to.
I'll do what you want--
-Guard.
-Anything you ask.
Anything.
This way.
Sorry for your loss.
We Romans have no truck
with sacrifice.
It's abhorrent to us.
Are the consequences
less abhorrent?
A new queen means new times.
A new way
of doing business.
A new future.
I presume that's why
you've asked me here,
to talk about the future.
[screaming in frustration]
[horse shrieks in fright]
Who's that?
Who are you?
Where are you going?
To the Citadel.
I've come to send her
to the underworld.
Then it's you.
Can you take me
to her?
Can you get me inside?
When we show up
with our ships,
and troops, and camps,
it can look, um--
Bad?
Misleading.
It's not
what the Empire's about.
Oh?
What is it about?
One thing.
Taxes.
Reasonably levied,
efficiently collected,
funneled back to Rome,
that's it.
That and a few million slaves.
War is the enemy
of the tax collector.
That's why we like to get
to the peace part
as quickly
as possible.
Which is where
your fortress comes in.
Roman soldiers
stationed here
with your permission
could keep the peace
for a hundred years.
Maybe even a thousand,
and that's a lot of...
peace.
And a lot of taxes.
You get the idea.
And the safety of my tribe
can be guaranteed?
That's the deal.
So you're here to help.
I think I've made that clear.
So, why are you lying to me?
I don't understand.
You made a deal
with the Druids,
and you made deal with my enemy.
Antedia's army is standing by
if this doesn't work out.
Do you deny any of that?
And you want me to trust you?
May I be frank?
I don't know my fucking Cantiis
from my Regnis,
and I genuinely don't care.
We both want
the same thing,
the safety and security
of these lands,
and these people.
Or do you trust
your Druids with that?
We're the future, you and I.
Chaos,
sacnﬁce”.
that's the past.
That's quite a trick
they have...
[m]
...to know your story
before you've lived it.
Do you believe it?
I will be my own queen.
So, we have a deal?
I will retain control
of my warriors.
Your soldiers will
protect my borders,
and no Cantii will ever
be a slave to a Roman.
If the agreement holds
in five years,
we can talk about taxes.
Ag reed.
What else?
I need to speak
with my elders.
You'll have your answer
by dawn.
The Empire is cemented
by many things,
not just war.
If things go
the right way,
I'd like us to become...
much closer.
I left my last suitor
scrabbling on the floor
for his balls.
Well, I've never shirked
a challenge,
but if it comes to that,
just give me a few yards
head start.
[chuckles]
I made you smile.
You should do that
more often.
What do the Druids
say about me?
That Rome is a demon.
What do you think?
I suppose I'll find out.
Oh, one last thing.
You've lots of people here
looking for safety.
lost their family,
lost their homes,
it's most unfortunate.
We came across a couple,
a young girl and a blind man.
We think it's his daughter.
Have you seen them?
What interest
do you have in them?
Are they here?
I'd like to meet them.
There is no one
of that description here, no.
Well, if you see them,
I'd very much like to know.
By dawn then.
It's been a pleasure.
[m]
[children's laughter echoes]
[crowd of children laughing]
[laughter echoing dreamily]
[crowd falls silent,
gasping in wonder]
Anyone
can make birds disappear.
Even your fat, old dad
can do that.
The trick is...
making them come back,
right...
[claps once]
on...
[claps twice]
...CU€.
[gasps of awe]
[Cait screams in terror]
Hey!
Get up now, wake up!
We have to go!
We have to go now! Move!
[Pwykka snarling]
[crowd shouting in panic]
[roaring]
This way.
[Pwykka snarls savagely]
Wait--
Please, he's going to kill us.
Is he your father?
Yes, and we have to
get out of here now!
-Come with me.
-Thank you.
Halt!
Seize them!
[swords ringing]
Stand aside!
Those prisoners belong to us.
You came here
to parlay.
Leave now!
Take them!
Guards!
[shouting]
Protect the Queen!
Come with me!
It's a trap!
Stand your ground!
Protect the General!
Stay close to me. Hurry.
Quick.
Keep left at every turn,
otherwise
you'll lose your way fast.
You'll come out
south of the castle.
Thank you.
Listen to me.
You are the one.
It's you.
Now go. Run.
-Thank you.
-Run!
[hissing and snarling]
Thank you.
[Pwykka snarling]
[snarling and hissing]
[seething with struggle]
[screams and shrieks]
[gasping in terror]
[groaning in pain and confusion]
[roaring]
Let them go.
You have made
a big mistake here today.
Are you all right?
Veran told me
what he put here,
the night
he took my mother away.
He said it means,
"Hope is the small daughter
of a blind father."
That's you.
I thought it was.
But not anymore.
[m]
They've sealed
the gates.
So that's
a big "fuck you"
from your new queen.
Things change.
Send word to the Regni.
They can start their siege.
J‘ Histories of ages past J‘
J‘ Unenlightened shadows cast J‘
J‘ Down through all eternity J‘
J‘ The crying of humanity J‘
J‘ 'Tis then
when the Hurdy Gurdy Man J‘
J‘ Comes singing
songs of love J‘
J‘ Then when
the Hurdy Gurdy Man J‘
J‘ Comes singing songs... J‘