To be able to lie down
together like this,
it's really great, right?
Yes, it's good.
Hyeong Seon, don't you feel
that this is going a bit too far?
You... what are you referring to?
Don't tell me that you're afraid
that I, before the marriage...
Could it be...
that you don't trust me?
I believe without a doubt that you'll hold
fast to your duties without wavering.
But I can't trust what is
within Your Highness
as the urges of a man have
been hidden away for so long.
But, how can I sleep under
these circumstances?
Then, can we come to
a simple agreement?
Agreement?
What agreement?
No matter what...
absolutely... definitely don't
give in to your instincts.
Don't touch a strand of agassi's hair.
(Agassi - young lady)
You're really becoming
more and more outrageous!
Hyeong Seon sir,
His Majesty and I have already
been separated for 8 years.
Think about all those days
we were apart.
Really wishing not to be apart and thinking
of him every second, every minute.
Please,
At the very least, here in the pitch
black night, let me see His Majesty.
I will cautiously advise you,
please look into each other's eyes as much
as you want, but keep to yourselves.
He has attended to me for
almost 20 years,
but instead he listened to you.
I will follow his damned instructions.
He can rest assured that I won't
touch a strand of your hair.
Are you serious?
Of course.
A real man will not go back
on his word. Absolutely.
For daring to touch your
hand without permission,
will you chase me out?
Impossible.
Will you punish me?
How can I?
Your Majesty, it was not you
who touched me.
The palace maid has disappeared.
I'm not sure if His Majesty
has become suspicious,
but it's said that she was
moved to another palace.
We couldn't find any trace of her.
Not only that.
Except for the few who have served
His Majesty since he was the Crown Prince,
His Majesty has replaced all his
palace maids in the past few days.
He replaced all his palace maids?
Yes, Your Majesty.
This is what I heard.
Something is definitely being
hidden in the King's Quarters.
What?
Just what is His Majesty hiding?
Your Excellency,
you shouldn't be running.
I'm sorry, Mother.
I just wanted to hurry and tell
the good news to mother.
I've felt your feelings of
happiness myself,
but you should be extra careful.
The physician has said so repeatedly.
Yes, Mother.
From this day on,
I will be more careful.
Have you been well these days,
Your Excellency?
Yes.
But, who are you?
I'm an official from the
Royal Investigation Bureau, Hong Gyu Tae.
Is that so?
You have the appearance of bravery
which is well suited to your position.
You must be loyal to His Majesty.
Yes, I will follow your command.
The matter I asked you to
inquire about, is there any news?
Yes, according to your command,
though rather difficult, I managed to
track down the former investigator.
However, there was nothing useful.
- Is that so?
- But...
What is it?
Before the former King issued an order to stop the
investigation into the death of the Crown Princess,
he frequently visited the Crystal Palace.
The Crystal Palace...
Wasn't the Crystal Palace the place
where Princess Min Hwa lived?
Yes.
The former King always showed
great favor towards the Princess.
This isn't surprising at all,
but I keep feeling
that it's a bit strange.
How? What is it?
The former King visited the
Crystal Palace many times,
and without another selection process, the current
queen was directly appointed as the Crown Princess.
This just feels a little...
So, I was anticipating what
you would ask next...
I discreetly found a palace maid who had been
working at the Crystal Palace at that time
to investigate further.
She said that the Great Queen Dowager was
also a frequent visitor at the Crystal Palace.
The Great Queen Dowager?
That's correct.
Ah, right. I've found out about the spell that
you previously asked me to investigate.
There's no need to report
on that any more,
I've already heard it from the
Celestial Hall's Head Shaman.
If it's like that
then I'll take my leave.
Wait. Since you have investigated it,
just tell me.
It's not much.
A normal spell will typically
use a straw doll,
but on occasions a human being can
replace the doll for the spell.
Replace a straw doll with a person?
Yes, Your Majesty.
If a person with a strong desire is
used in place of a straw doll,
then the effectiveness of
the spell is intensified.
Just what exactly are
you trying to hide?
I'm trying to hide
what you're looking for.
It's all for Your Majesty.
Let me say it more clearly.
It's to protect Your Majesty
and those people that you cherish.
The former king had a
reason to bury this matter.
You have that same reason.
Before the former King issued an order to stop the
investigation into the death of the Crown Princess,
he frequently visited the Crystal Palace.
If the former King wanted
to conceal the truth,
he must have had a good reason.
Your Majesty.
She said that the Great Queen Dowager was
also a frequent visitor at the Crystal Palace.
Your Majesty.
It's fine. You may leave now.
Yes.
Why...
Why would Princess Min Hwa...?
Did you say pregnant?
Yes, Your Majesty.
We've just been to the
Royal Physician
and confirmed that the
Princess is pregnant.
I couldn't be happier.
Recently the palace has been
filled with a gloomy atmosphere.
Now at long last I hear joyous news.
Recently the Princess hasn't
been feeling well.
She has been staying in bed,
so I was becoming very worried.
Now it seems like it was
due to morning sickness.
You did well, Princess.
You did really well.
But Mother,
may I please excuse myself
and return home first?
Why do you want to go now?
Are you feeling unwell?
No, that's not it.
It's just that I want to give the good
news to my husband as soon as possible.
The Queen Dowager will be disappointed.
You haven't been to the
palace in so long.
You should spend more
time with your mother.
It's not necessary.
It's said that a married daughter
belongs to her husband's family.
Just let the Princess leave first.
You can stay and chat with me
some more before you leave.
Let's do that, Mother.
Then, I'll be leaving now.
No matter how rushed you are,
don't forget to visit His Majesty first.
Yes,
I will.
Crown Prince,
I'm sorry.
Why do you say such a thing?
Your father is incompetent.
I was unable to help you
protect that child.
Crown Prince, you're clever
and quick-witted.
There'll come a day when you'll
understand the meaning of these words.
You must remember what
I'm going to tell you.
Please tell me.
Please, you must forgive all the
people I tried to protect.
Please protect them all.
What?
If you can't do it,
then the first person you
mustn't forgive is me.
Please forgive me for
being slow-witted,
but I don't understand
what you mean Father.
I am unable to understand.
Crown Prince,
the royal throne,
is a very lonely place.
There are people everywhere
who are your enemies.
It's possible for anyone to
become your enemy.
Sometimes you have no choice but to
make decisions contrary to your convictions.
Sometimes those enemies...
may be your close relatives.
My only hope is that you will
at least be able to forgive...
those relatives.
The people that I need
to forgive and protect,
who are they?
Min... Min Hwa, you...
Orabeoni, I hate you. I hate you!
Why are you like this?
You were saying bad things about me.
Furthermore, to say it in
front of him.
I hate you, hate you, hate you!
The Crown Prince's words
were all lies.
I'm not headstrong,
I'm a very dignified lady.
I've nearly finished memorizing the
Thousand Character Classic.
Your Majesty!
You've known... for a while.
So,
is that why you concealed from me that
you had recovered your memories?
You need to stop
this right now!
Your Majesty, please retract your
decree to make Heo Yeom the Uibin.
I order you to stand
up immediately!
If you stop someone as talented as
Heo Yeom from having any official post,
you might as well give the
order to execute him.
Is it not an honor to become a
member of the Royal Family?
How can you compare it to
a death sentence?
Is to lose a life the only thing that
can be considered a death?
What did you say?
I will comply with your
royal command.
As you have ordered, I will marry
the Minister's daughter.
But please, Your Majesty, retract your
decree to appoint Scholar Heo as the Uibin.
Leave immediately.
As long as Your Majesty refuses to
retract the order, I won't leave.
Must I have you dragged out in
disgrace by the guards
in order to obey an order?
Your Majesty!
Crown Prince, follow me!
You worthless brat.
Do you know what disaster
you're rushing into?
I...
only want to protect Scholar Heo.
Protect him?
Do you know how many
people you've hurt today?
Just by showing your true feelings
in front of all those people,
Heo Yeom and his father,
Heo Yeong Jae...
have both become political targets.
That's two people.
Furthermore, they'll start to question
your abilities as future King.
That makes three.
Because of you, all your attendants
will be held accountable,
and the common people of Joseon who will
someday have to suffer under your rule.
If you add all these together,
it's enough to topple the
whole of Joseon.
If you let your personal feelings
affect your decisions,
just who can you protect?
Then, do you simply want
me to be a bystander?
If I don't do anything,
don't change anything,
don't protect anything,
and simply follow the usual rituals,
being powerless and feeble,
is that how you want me to live?
The so-called King,
don't tell me that's
all there is to it.
The more you want to protect,
the more will be hurt.
The more you try to obtain
the thing you want,
the more you will lose.
This will someday,
be your fate when you
sit on the throne.
If you really want to protect,
you mustn't expose any weaknesses.
If you want to gain one thing,
you must give up the other.
Only then can you achieve
your goal.
You must lose one to gain one.
This is...
politics.
Then, Your Majesty,
what did you choose?
What did you gain,
and what did you lose?
I lost a loyal subject but
preserved his safety.
I lost Prince Yang Myeong
but was able to protect you.
I lost the Crown Princess,
but was able to protect
your sister, Min Hwa.
I...
won't do it the same way.
I only want to do it the right way.
Even if I had to put everything on the line,
I would still choose to protect it.
If it's something I feel is wrong,
I will give up any gain.
My Joseon,
will be like this.
Have you already forgotten
your resolution,
to change the way the nation's
affairs are managed?
Are these your so-called politics?
Don't tell me you've forgotten?
Let all things and all people
return to their rightful position.
Let those who aren't qualified
for their current position,
return it to those who are entitled.
This is the task of the future King.
This is the path you should follow.
Don't tell me you've already
forgotten it?
Didn't he say where he was going?
Your humble servant doesn't know.
Orabeoni.
I trust that you've been well
since we last met.
I heard from Mother that your
health had greatly improved.
But why does your face look so dark?
Min Hwa.
Yes, Orabeoni.
Teacher Heo,
did you really want him that much?
What?
Is that why,
you did such a cruel thing?
Cruel thing?
What are you... referring to?
Teacher Heo's sister.
What?
I don't know...
what you are talking about.
Why?
Why did you do it?
Why were you involved in the
curse on the Crown Princess?
Why?
For my husband and his family,
please help protect my secret.
For the sin that I've committed,
I'm very sorry.
But...
My husband and his family...
Please!
Lift up... your head.
I told you to lift up your head!
Do you... Do you know...
Do you know what kind of
disaster you have caused?
With those same eyes,
the same voice,
and also the same words,
Father once said that
to me too.
Please save me, Father.
Do you know what kind of
disaster you have caused?
I didn't know.
I really didn't know.
It was Grandmother who
told me to just sit there.
She said just by doing that
I could marry Teacher Heo.
I really didn't know
that it would kill Yeon U.
Listen carefully to what
I'm going to say now.
This matter,
must not be made
known to anyone.
Until you die,
you mustn't speak a word of it.
Do you understand?
At that time I only replied
I didn't know.
Because...
Because I really didn't know.
Afterwards,
seeing my husband sitting
in his sister's room so often,
crying tears of blood, I...
I...
realized the impact of what I had done.
You've committed an unpardonable
sin against our late father.
You've committed a mortal sin
against the late Chief Scholar,
and against myself and Yeon U.
All of these sins, exactly how
are you going to pay for them?
By what means will you be able
to redeem yourself?
Even if I go back to that time,
I...
I would still choose my husband.
Even if there's retribution
in the future,
even if I'm engulfed in the
fires of hell after death,
the choice I made then,
I will have no regret.
I will abandon you.
Only by abandoning you,
only in this way, can the others
that were involved be punished.
But you...
I will gladly accept my punishment.
But, my husband...
And within my womb...
is my husband's child.
Please don't abandon them.
Just now,
what did you say?
I should leave.
My husband is still waiting for me.
Princess.
Husband.
Why are you like this?
Could it be that at the physician,
you heard some bad news?
So, what was the result
of your examination?
I...
have your child,
within me.
What?
How terrible of me,
I should have known.
How could I be so oblivious?
It's nothing.
I didn't know either.
It's just that...
"It's just", what?
I have something,
to say to you.
Yes, please speak.
Actually...
Don't tell me
this isn't what you wanted?
No,
this is what I have always wanted.
Thank you.
No, just saying "thank you"
isn't enough to express my feelings.
Also,
I'm always receiving your kindness,
but I'm unable to repay you.
I'm really sorry.
From now on I'll return your kindness.
I'll be able to face my father proudly.
You are really wonderful.
In the future I'll work harder,
and return your kindness.
Don't be like this.
The child will be scared.
It's a son.
Like his father he'll be clever,
exceptionally wise, and noble with
unquestionable integrity.
He'll be a rare pillar for the nation.
Eonni, what is it?
Did I say something wrong again?
So, as I said...
That's why I told you not
to go there again.
Why did you not listen?
My young master is so pitiful,
what can be done?
The woman who killed his sister
is now bearing his child.
How can such a thing happen?
Be quiet!
You shouldn't have told me.
You were the one who threatened me
that if I didn't tell you the whole truth,
you would immediately run to the
palace and reveal everything.
That was why I told you.
But you still shouldn't have told me.
Our Agassi and Young Master
are just so pitiful.
What can be done?
Your Majesty.
May I enter?
No, you can't.
I...
can't face you.
I swore to find the people who had
done this to you, and then punish them.
But...
those responsible turned out to
be my own flesh and blood.
Those who placed the curse,
the people who killed you,
and those who covered up
the truth about your death,
are all my flesh and blood.
What right do I have to face you?
You once asked me why I didn't reveal
that I had regained my memories.
It was because I was afraid
it would turn out like this.
That you would be terribly hurt.
I was afraid you would never
want to see me again.
For you to have been
hurt this way...
it can be said it's actually
because of me.
If you say it like that,
I'll blame myself for still
being alive.
What should I do?
Please continue to conceal
the truth.
If Orabeoni discovers the truth,
it will be very hard on him.
Don't you feel wronged having
to hide all these years?
Don't you feel hurt having
to suffer all those years?
It's precisely that pain and anguish
I don't want to share with Orabeoni.
Do you only know how to feel
pity for your brother?
Don't you also feel pity for me?
If you're not the Queen,
I will have to embrace another woman.
Am I not pitiful to you?
How can you not feel pity for me?
Did you say Onyang Palace?
(Onyang Palace - royal vacation
residence with hot springs)
That's right.
Although Spring is approaching soon,
the mornings and evenings are
still very cool.
Compared to the palace, this will be
a more suitable place for your care.
Is it really for the sake of my health that
you want me to go to Onyang Palace
or--
It's time for you to let go
of your political power
and I advise you to now
rest in comfort.
This is definitely not possible,
Your Majesty.
There is no one who can
remove me from this position.
Then, please make your choice.
Either go to Onyang Palace
according to my advice,
or appear at the Interrogation Hall
and stand trial.
Interrogation Hall?
A trial?
Exactly what serious crime
have I committed
for you to actually say
such a thing?
Eight years ago...
the crime of killing the
innocent Crown Princess.
Please produce the evidence.
Also, the crime of using your granddaughter
in a spell as an accomplice in that act.
Please produce the evidence.
Please don't confuse me with my Father.
Your Majesty.
To determine the guilt in this matter,
I will not make any exceptions,
regardless of our family relationship.
So, I ask you to set aside everything
and go to the Onyang Palace.
This is... all the consideration
I can give you as your grandson.
Your Majesty, what do you think
you can achieve through this?
Justice. I only hope for this one word.
Your Majesty, there'll still be a time
where you'll need me. Don't you know that?
You said there'll be punishment for
those who go against the natural order.
So... we can only let nature
take its course.
Your natural course Grandmother
is to keep things as they are.
My path is to correct that
which is wrong.
So...
I will restore everything to
its rightful place.
Your Majesty, you can't treat me like this.
I won't be there to see you off tomorrow.
Please stay healthy.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, your position
on the throne...
Don't tell me you don't know
who made it possible?
That was me!
It was me, your Grandmother!
For the sake of Your Majesty...
I got blood on my hands in order
to secure your position!
Now you want me to go to Onyang Palace?
How can you ask me to give up my position?
This is impossible!
This cannot be! You can't...
Your Highness.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Your Highness!
Quickly summon the
Royal Physician! Quickly!
Your Highness!
Why the sudden departure
to Onyang Palace?
They said it's for a long vacation.
In truth, it's said that he asked his
own Grandmother to step down.
He is so disrespectful.
This is the same as declaring war
against us.
If His Majesty already knows
the whole truth,
and has decided to draw
his sword against us,
he will quickly eliminate us all.
Since His Majesty has drawn his sword,
none of us will be able to live.
What should we do about
this matter, Minister?
Then, our only option is to strike first.
You say we should strike first...
"If the temple is not to your liking,
then just get the monks to leave."
But,
with so many monks, is there really
a need to force them all to leave
when the problem can be solved
with just a change of abbot.
Isn't that right?
Are you leaving now?
The wound is almost healed.
I'm not a Buddhist, so there's no
reason for me to remain here.
Can you come with me for a walk?
Prince Yang Myeong.
Yes.
I won't waver.
I also won't break.
Live however you wish.
From now on,
you should follow your own heart
and mind Prince Yang Myeong,
and live your own life.
Are you being sincere?
Because I believe in you,
Prince Yang Myeong.
Because I believe you
will make the right decisions.
Believe. Do you know how
scary this word is?
Prince Yang Myeong,
everything shall pass.
Just like the passing of time,
the seasons also change accordingly.
One day, sadness will
also disappear.
Furthermore, an even better marriage,
predestined by fate, awaits you.
No matter what experiences you
may face in the future, Prince Yang Myeong,
no matter what choices
you make in life,
as your mother, I truly believe
in you Prince Yang Myeong.
Did you say no matter
what I choose?
Yes. No matter what you choose.
Lord Yang Myeong!
Why are you gathering here
in the cold weather?
Please don't be concerned.
Your servant is here to
pay his respects.
Paying respects at such a late hour,
let's go inside and speak.
Presently, our King is still
young and incompetent.
Inside and outside the Imperial Court
there has been restlessness.
Seeing that the country's future
will soon be in disorder,
your subjects are very concerned.
It is not simply the fact
that there is no heir,
up until now there has been
no consummation of marriage.
The people are beginning to worry.
The concern is groundless
as His Majesty is still young
and his royal body is healthy.
What is it that you're worrying about?
His Majesty should naturally be healthy,
but, there should be precautions
in case anything happens.
Be prepared?
That's not bad.
Don't you feel it is unfair
that you are passed over?
In truth, in terms of being able to rule
you are more than capable.
There's no one else but you.
The qualifications of a king.
What you are saying is not only
outrageous. It's also very dangerous.
So, what exactly are you saying?
If the king is unable to produce an heir,
there will be disorder in the selection
of the next successor.
Won't it be too late if we sit and
wait for something to happen?
So, what should I do?
His Majesty is still healthy and well,
yet you are already discussing
the next successor.
Look at the line of this sword.
Isn't it beautiful?
Y... Yes... it is.
It's a pity this precious sword will have
to be stained by the blood of pesky flies.
Whose head should it start with?
If I present your traitorous head to His Majesty,
I wonder how much the reward will be?
How can you say that we're traitors?
When did we...
You've misunderstood, Prince Yang Myeong.
Do you want me to cut out your long, treacherous
tongue first as an example to warn others?
Please don't misunderstand. We speak
only out of worry for this country.
Let's just go.
If you dare to speak such
nonsense again,
your head and body will part forever.
Seems like it's not possible.
When he unexpectedly invited us into his
house I thought he had changed his mind.
But, I almost lost my head.
Then again, it would have been
boring if he'd taken the bait so easily.
So, is this everything?
That...
Who is the main conspirator?
Go and tell him
not to use others to test me.
If he has something to say,
say it directly to me.
I understand. You can leave now.
However, why does it have
to be Prince Yang Myeong?
Prince Yang Myeong has always been
the most loyal person to His Majesty.
Minister of Defense, can't you see the
reason behind such an obvious matter?
Then, Minister of Finance,
do you know?
Since ancient times, a motive
is very important in everything.
He made such an effort to rescue
and escape with that girl,
but in the end, she was
taken by His Majesty.
Even if it's the King, he would like
to turn everything upside down.
Then, for a mere girl, would he
go against the King?
Won't it be dangerous? Even though
they have differences in opinion,
Prince Yang Myeong won't
betray His Majesty easily.
Betrayal usually comes from amongst
the most trusted allies.
A tiny crack can destroy a dam.
A small misunderstanding can lead
to tragedy.
If the King were to pass away,
the next in line to the throne
will be Prince Yang Myeong,
so he will naturally take
over the throne.
Moreover,
if you want to replace the
country's king,
if the quality of the candidate
doesn't measure up,
how could we complete the task
with an unknown?
But will Prince Yang Myeong
agree so easily?
We have to find a way to
make him agree.
Your Majesty.
Wouldn't you like to know what
your servant's last trump card is?
Mother.
Why are you visiting the
palace so frequently?
This child is our niece
who I told you about.
The Queen has been very depressed,
so I brought this child to keep
her company.
What is your name?
My name is Gim Su Yeong.
Is this the first time you've
entered the palace?
Yes.
What do you think of it?
The many layers of the
palace buildings
are like guardians of the
King and Queen.
I now realize it's true about the
nine layers of the palace.
If I could live in such
a beautiful palace,
it would be a wonderful thing.
That is what I think.
Do you want to live inside
the palace?
Yes.
Even though you are a girl,
you're quite outspoken.
Then, would you like to
look around this palace?
Do you want to see the
royal palace?
What?
If you want to,
I can let you live there.
Your Majesty.
Although she's young,
she's very sensible and clever.
She will give you great comfort,
so let her keep you company.
Mother.
Father is going to abandon me.
How can he abandon you,
Your Majesty?
Why would you say such a thing?
No...
With father's character,
he is able to do it.
If he feels I'm useless,
even if I'm his own daughter,
he'll abandon me without
the slightest hesitation.
But, who can replace you
in the position of Queen?
Court Lady Jo.
Please give your command, Madam.
Take this child out for some tea.
Even if it is as you say,
and this girl was brought into the
palace as an adopted daughter,
she could only be a concubine.
Moreover, His Majesty,
would not be interested
in such a young girl.
If the one who sits on the
throne is changed,
the situation will become different.
The one who sits on the Royal Throne,
how can it change?
If it's father,
anything is possible.
My Lord.
What is it?
Someone has come to see you.
Didn't I say I don't want
to see anyone?
Thi... This...
I, a lowly servant, don't dare
to offend this person.
I came here to ask you to have
a drink with me, Prince Yang Myeong.
Since the group of rats that came
earlier have prepared the way,
let's skip the small talk and
get to the main reason you're here.
Honestly, don't you want
to be the Sun?
The words that you've
just spoken, Prime Minister,
do you really not know
what they signify?
How would I not know?
Interesting.
Why me?
Why not go and find some
other royal gentleman?
Motivation and qualifications
are the most important.
The motivation to be the king,
and the qualifications to be king.
I'm just free-spirited.
What are my special qualifications?
In addition, I have a tendency
to be dissolute.
I'm afraid I would find that
being a king wouldn't suit me.
Neither do I have the motivation.
So you have no reason to
include me in your conspiracy.
All of this attitude is just to conceal
your ability to be king.
How would I not know?
Heavens! You already know?
Then it should be clear that
I have no wish to be pulled
against the wind.
If you leave now, I'll keep
this a secret from His Majesty.
Do you want to live your whole
life under his shadow?
Even if I have the motivation,
and the qualifications,
there must be justification for rebellion.
Justification can be easily produced.
Such as?
Avoiding the responsibility
of producing an heir.
He has made the nation waver,
making him an irresponsible King.
In a country based on Confucianism,
he lusted after a shaman and kept
her in his room.
An absurd King.
Not listening to his elders,
a useless King.
This should be sufficient.
That shaman is not an
ordinary shaman.
She's the Crown Princess who died
8 years ago and was reborn.
How dare you insult her in this way.
Personally, don't you find
this too shameful?
Seems like... you already knew this.
I knew about it
because my brain works pretty well.
So, you already knew,
but you still wanted to
possess the King's woman.
You must have known this
was too greedy of you.
You've worked hard.
Thanks to you, we were able
to unravel the mystery.
I was honored.
However, I'm afraid the details
of my investigation
will make Your Majesty
even more uneasy.
This was something I needed to
experience to understand the course of events.
Although I should reward you
for your efforts,
there's something that is
more pressing at this moment.
What is it that you need?
Written in this secret decree
are the things you need to do,
and the people you need to meet.
Once you have memorized it,
destroy it immediately.
I will obey your order.
Since I am ready to accuse them of
a crime, they will try to strike back.
Very soon they will begin to spread
rumors attempting to blacken my name.
I am afraid my presence has
become troublesome for Your Majesty.
Is it possible you thought I would
just allow them to attack me.
Just wait and see.
An interesting story will begin to spread
amongst the people very soon.
Do you want to take a walk?
Actually, I prepared a gift
and hid it for you here.
I already have everything.
How could I dare to want
anything else?
I've already prepared it.
Go and look for it.
Didn't you just say that
you didn't need other things?
For a person who just said that,
aren't you looking a bit too eagerly?
What is it exactly?
Could it be so small that it can't
be seen with the naked eye?
Small? It's not small!
Could it be...
you want to give me
the Secret Moon Pavilion?
You really do think big.
It's not.
Then what is it?
What I want to give you,
in this world there is nothing
that can be exchanged for it.
In the whole world there
is only one.
Every woman would want it.
The only one.
Is it possible...
Seems like you've guessed.
That's right, it's me.
What is the meaning of that laugh?
Don't tell me you think
that it's funny.
How can I dare be
disrespectful towards you?
It's because I'm happy.
I laughed because I'm
so very happy.
Haven't you already
given your heart to me?
Therefore, I will give my whole
self to you.
Your Majesty.
Could it be that you've
already given up?
His Majesty will take the shaman
as his concubine soon.
Besides, didn't the former king treat you
and the King very differently?
Didn't he mistreat you, Prince
Yang Myeong?
Could you possibly have forgotten?
Minister Yun.
You've completely miscalculated.
Did you think that I, Yang Myeong,
because of jealousy towards His Majesty,
would try to seize the throne?
I have no desire for the title of King.
I don't wish to conspire against the King...
for wealth, fame or power.
Things like power,
I don't need them.
With no ambition nor aspiration,
it's very disappointing.
It leaves me no choice.
A chess piece of no
use can only be given up.
What I want...
is my ancestral rites at
the Jongmyo Shrine...
(Jongmyo Shrine - Royal Ancestral Shrine)
and Heo Yeon U.
Only those two things.
~ I hope it isn't love. ~
~ I hope it isn't you. ~
~ I hope that not even an inch
of my heart will allow it. ~
~ My heart that is stained red ~
I...