Dilawar was a hard worker
and quiet.
A good man and honest.
From small ...
loved to drive tractors.
He brought stones from the mountain.
All stones of this wall.
Dilawar brought up here.
We are simple peasants,
but he said:
"Leave us to the field
and you see the taxi driver. "
The first of December
2002 ...
Dilawar, a young
Afghan taxi driver ...
up to three passengers
for a trip.
Never returned home.
.: WWw.Asia-Team.Tv:.
Presents:
TAXI TO THE DARK SIDE.
A translation of:
Ladybatissa and zatara04
Bagram AIR BASE,
AFGHANISTAN.
When the sun
begins to hide ...
the sand begins to blow,
as a large cloud of dust.
And I wonder
Is it well every night?
I recall that when
first, the smell ...
the smell is the first thing to note ...
and being in Washington,
if you've been at the zoo ...
when you enter
the cage of the elephant ...
this is the best
way to describe it.
A few lived in
prison and I was one of them.
Bagram Prison.
It is a huge site built
to instill fear in detainees.
After the invasion
to Afghanistan ...
U.S. forces
occupied Bagram ...
and an old air base
Soviet is the place ...
to collect and interrogate
Thousands of detainees ...
caught in
Afghanistan and Pakistan.
Were suspected Taliban ...
who had been trapped
by special forces ...
in the field,
and brought to Bagram for ...
questioning
and determine whether they were ...
high-value prisoners.
They were not good
people at all.
They were very bad ...
know, had
violent intentions.
On December 5, 2002 ...
Dilawar, a taxi driver,
was brought to Bagram.
Was designated as a PUC. "
Person under control,
number 421.
Was related to
the rocket attack.
That was all I knew.
Five days after
their arrival ...
was dead.
I would say it was
as at 5:00 am ...
and when passing
where Dilawar --
I think it was called.
When passing by his cell ...
he was there hanging
with his head down ...
but it was very quiet for
be hanging there sleeping.
Sergeant Curtis opened
the door and entered.
Did not react. So we started
CPR.
Was down
with other inmates ...
and I heard it called
Cammack to raise ...
was a nurse, and lower in
Cammack the stretcher and continued ...
top of it trying to
while bajábamos resuscitate.
He was taken to the main door
and continued to work with him.
To work until he reached the
physician and certified the death.
Perhaps his injuries
were compounded by something ...
or just got sick.
It was a very fragile person.
And I was surprised that
you take so long ...
die under
our custody.
There was concern
because it was the second.
Just a week before
Dilawar's death ...
another died
detained at Bagram.
Wondering if it will be
for something I did ...
or if someone killed him,
I do not know say so.
According to the coroner ...
the first prisoner died,
Habibullah ...
suffering from a disease
lung prior to his incarceration.
But it was the beatings
received in Bagram ...
what caused his death.
A clot that was
lodged in the lungs.
When he dies the second
a week later ...
when we were scared.
Something will happen now.
Two prisoners die
in a week, that's bad.
A preliminary investigation
Dilawar's death on ...
revealed severe bruising
throughout your body.
But not found that treatment
at Bagram has been the cause.
Next day
I was told that ...
how to draw remained
and when I was here ...
this simple picture.
The roofs of these
Isolation rooms ...
were simple metal railings ...
and were sufficiently hard to
wives put through it ...
to hang them so,
sideways.
Long compulsory
periods of standing ...
inflamed tissues injured
dents in Dilawar's legs.
But the press release
Initial no mention ...
wives or beating.
They said that both arrested
died of natural causes.
My opinion is ...
that the military wanted ...
Finally, finish
I quickly ...
before calling the attention.
Shortly after
Dilawar's death ...
the official responsible for
interrogation in Bagram ...
Captain Carolyn Wood
was awarded ...
the Bronze Star to the value.
After the invasion of Iraq ...
to Wood and his unit
Intelligence ...
were given a new mission ...
Abu Ghraib.
A few
Rotten apple.
My only memory
Abu Ghraib is the heat.
It felt like 58 ° C there
and it was all concrete.
Abu Ghraib was also
the infamous torture chambers ...
and things were
from the time of Saddam.
I remember having
visit and see ...
as marks of nails
the walls, blood stains ...
guillotines and the like.
An unreal feeling.
We arrived at Abu Ghraib,
in July or August of 2003 ...
to mount that prison.
If you put the people in a situation
insane, commit follies.
And Abu Ghraib received fire
mortars every night.
120mm projectiles
who killed the prisoners.
When it was first
should evacuate to another location ...
because they were not sure.
We were told that we were
violent with those who resist.
He also told us that
Those were the dogs.
So suddenly you see these people
as something less than human ...
and begin to make things
with which he never dreamed of.
When there was
became dark.
It was only the night shift.
There are always bad apples.
It is a great coup
for all of us.
It is clearly
an isolated incident.
The conduct of a
very small group ...
our officers and soldiers.
Due to media attention
about Abu Ghraib ...
the army began
A number of investigations.
The person conducting
abuses will be tried.
The world will see a
free and democratic system ...
works and operates
transparent ...
without cover.
The Secretary
and others will tell you ...
made
12 investigations.
But each of them ...
were made
to look down ...
Lynndie England to
Graner and ...
and not upward.
Soldiers of the photos,
PM or military police are ...
whose mission was to guard
and protect the prisoners.
In their statements, claimed
the Military Intelligence or MI ...
had ordered them to humiliate
and weaken the prisoners ...
as before
interrogation.
Clearly what
made in these photos ...
not endorsed by the rules
governing interrogations.
So yes, I think
were bad apples.
However, I also think
that still commands ...
Intelligence Service.
There were reports that
happening in Afghanistan ...
I speak of the humiliation,
to demoralize the prisoners ...
it all came from somewhere.
Not happened to the PMs.
The PMs are not even
trained to do these things.
Should have no
demoralized people.
We use them in Abu
techniques at Bagram.
Exactly the same rules.
It happened the same.
And they wonder why happened?
In his affidavit
on Abu Ghraib ...
Wood said that the captain felt
pressure for the information.
Thus techniques that led
Unauthorized:
dogs, nakedness, deprivation
sleep and stress positions ...
to Abu Ghraib
from Afghanistan.
Maintained that the model of Bagram
had higher approval of ...
but the U.S. Central Command
never replied ...
their applications.
So the mystery remains ...
Abu Ghraib Was the result
some bad apples?
Or evidence of a new
Global ...
detention and interrogation?
Sure that the interrogators
I said to the guards:
"Naked to this kind
espósenlo to bed ...
in an awkward position
and do what they want. "
And then decided
go a little further ...
and have fun with it,
take some photos.
You always have to
military people ...
are a step
the Marquis de Sade.
And one reason why
which should have rules ...
and this code of conduct
to help lead ...
a number of soldiers
and marines ...
is for you
use these tools ...
to limit this
trend in your soldiers.
When you have your friends
dying around you ...
sometimes you can
go a little further.
So a lieutenant, a captain
on the battlefield ...
need these tools,
and be able to punish a. ..
persons crossing the line.
Colonel Lawrence Wilkerson
CHIEF OF STAFF Colin Powell.
When the secretary
came to my office ...
at that time were
get out the photos from Abu Ghraib ...
and there were rumors
that would ...
I said: "I need to know
what happened and why. "
Then I began to collect
both documents freely accessible ...
and internal government,
classified or not.
And I began to see arguments
legal because the President ...
could do whatever he wanted
in the name of security.
Both the Secretary of Defense
their junior ...
were really looking for ...
the same pressure that they
exercised over the people.
The pressure to obtain
intelligence information ...
and that said
had already removed the gloves.
They created the environment
then we saw that reflected ...
in the photos of Abu Ghraib,
and for me much more seriously ...
these pictures that we saw,
are 98 deaths in custody ...
From this interview,
105 DEATHS AND SON.
and I learned by my colleagues
25 of them soldiers who ...
have been officially declared
as homicides by the military.
FROM THE INTERVIEW, 37 have been
SCHEDULED "homicide".
Some would say that these
Abu Ghraib photos do not show ...
real torture, I would
that murder is a torture.
Murder is
supreme torture.
In the case of Dilawar,
He was ...
brutal punishment
and unusual ...
and the final was
died because of torture.
GRAL. Dan McNeill:
Our intention is not to kill ...
especially if we
obtain information from them.
GRAL. Dan McNeill,
Cmdte. The coalition.
The treatment they received
in these cells ...
caused the deaths
these two men?
First, not chained to anyone
the roof, I had asked.
"First, not chained to anyone
the ceiling, "that's what it says.
Carlotta Gall, is a journalist
The New York Times in Kabul.
Dissatisfied with the
explanation of the military ...
the two deaths at Bagram,
undertook an investigation.
It took me a long time
families to find ...
because the military did not want
tell us where ...
and began to call
the governors.
They are a humble family
Farmers who do not speak English ...
but showed me a paper
he got along with the body.
There was when I read it,
in English ...
was a death certificate
the U.S. military.
And it was signed by ...
Enhanced U.S.
it was the pathologist.
Of the four cells that had,
It marked the murder.
MURDER.
I said:
"My God, they killed him."
Then we had to ask
the family if they knew ...
what was written here.
They told us:
"No, it is in English.
I do not understand. "
And I think that perhaps the Red Cross
helped restore the body ...
had been explained,
but I do not understand.
And then the pathologist said ...
who had injuries
contusions on his legs.
Did you suffer any trauma?
Any trauma by
contusion that is how his name?
At the moment I have no
evidence that ...
but we will review as
that the investigation continues.
"At the moment no
I have evidence of that. "
There is a signed certificate
for their people, and he says:
"At the moment I have no evidence
any injury by contusion.
And that is on the certificate
death, I saw him.
The story would have disappeared
if not for my fellow ...
Carlotta Gall. She found
Dilawar's family ...
and gave the track
showed that all ...
that this incident was
something completely different ...
what the army said.
Tim Golden continued
track of the story ...
and obtained a record
confidentiality of the investigation ...
army, including hundreds
pages of testimony ...
of the soldiers involved.
One of the things that
caught my attention ...
was that you were young
soldiers with very little ...
training and preparation,
mired in the middle of a hangover 11 / 9 ...
precisely when
the rules were changing ...
without having such
what they sought.
And you have this young Afghan
entered the system ...
at the wrong time
in all the wrong ...
and this was what happened.
I saw his picture in the New York Times.
Before you look at that picture
would not have acknowledged.
My memories of him are ...
chained with the hood
lay, sleepless.
After the questions
raised by the New York Times ...
and under the scrutiny of
Abu Ghraib scandal ...
the army finally accelerated
Dilawar investigation of the case ...
and began to accuse
soldiers abuse ...
mutilation and murder.
When you work with a
organization like the army ...
always blaming someone.
You can hide some things ...
but it was a death.
Were two deaths.
Well, it is logical
to accuse people.
It seemed that the army after
Abu Ghraib hit ...
wanted the opinion
public to see that ...
take action
regard to its soldiers.
So I said: "We have this
incident two years ago ...
yet we can process
some of them. "
Two years ago that I do not have
relationship with the army ...
and suddenly I hear
I will make a court martial.
That was a great
surprise to me.
From the standpoint of
defense immediately said ...
this was
a political spectacle.
Willie Brand is a good soldier ...
Good Soldiers
follow orders ...
are people who ...
what to do with
who were trained.
Interrogators
on the ground ...
almost all of them did not know
which were the rules.
They had never questioned before.
My training
question was ...
Basic Education
how to go ...
how to make
people to talk.
And then they took us to
see interrogations ...
of the types for which
We were going to replace ...
by about five or six hours ...
before making
my first interrogation.
Damien was chosen for this
work because it's big ...
speaks loud and scared.
That was his qualification.
"Soldiers are dying,
get information. "
It is the only thing you said:
"Get Info".
The soldiers say that when
prisoners arrived ...
as Dilawar at Bagram,
were attacked immediately.
Shock
Of the catch.
I put music
at full volume ...
often thrown
over barking dogs ...
and used some of
the most threatening ...
interrogators to
create a sense of danger.
One of them was Damien Corsetti.
With the hood trying to
giving what we call ...
"the shock of capture."
When the person comes ...
is the best time to
achieve information because ...
is frightened,
wondering what happens.
The procedure is not
limited to mislead ...
but also to terrorize.
It is designed to ...
cause terror and make
speak, so to speak.
I spit, insult,
barking dogs around you ...
you shoot flash
front of the face.
Please note that
the dog in their culture ...
is more afraid than in ours.
It's almost as if a woman
tell them what to do.
It is a cultural issue.
Using dogs is successful.
Then you immobilized
completely naked ...
to make what they call
Register corporal ...
registering cavities.
After you interrogate
naked titiritando.
After reading
rules and other ...
are brought to their cells,
and are prevented from sleeping for 24 hours.
That is all.
From there the
Military Intelligence says if ...
can go with the other defendants
or whether they were still in isolation.
And if still isolated
if you are able to sleep and when.
To weaken detainees ...
interrogators ordered
the military police to ...
find new ways to
sleep to prevent the prisoners.
You are in that room
without saying anything ...
good and think that maybe
knows anything more, we a. ..
know, to deprive
something more than dream.
That was the idea
keep them that way.
Why not sleep well,
're standing ...
as in
begin to fall asleep ...
feel the pressure
wrists and arms.
The only time the police
military help has reached us ...
was to keep
at the time of sleep.
Gave them some time to sleep.
Was that time continue?
With interruptions?
In periods of 15 minutes?
Who knows?
That was our goal.
Upon entering the room,
had a blackboard on the wall.
You could see an arrow pointing
upwards towards the ceiling y. ..
and perhaps one at his side a,
That meant an hour's walk.
Should be awake
for an hour.
Then one could see two
with an arrow.
That meant he could
spend two hours sitting.
The prisoners were kept
pens in these great ...
and had his number written in
the ventilation duct ...
it was a small opening
by which they got ...
to raise the
isolation cells.
The detainees were shackled
with your hands above your head ...
in these ducts, their number
I saw the 421 with frequency ...
because his head was just
in front of me in that line.
The numbers were written
on the back of the prisoners.
And we were all
front, too.
At Bagram
my number was 180 ...
but then I
changed by 558.
Thank you. It is a pleasure to be
with you here at Bagram.
GRAL. VISIT FRANKS Bagram.
I am sure that any
authority to visit us ...
saw the shackles ...
because you come visit to look ...
RUMSFELD VISITS Bagram.
are curious as
around the world.
Authorities must always
visited.
Bromeábamos saying that
was the largest show of the world.
Everybody wanted to come
to see the terrorists.
We are often called
the office of Mr. Rumsfeld.
GRAL. McNeill VISIT Bagram.
Senior commanders
wanted to learn every day ...
on certain prisoners.
They knew, saw
Shackled, hooded ...
told us: "Come
they do very well. "
When the Red Cross
visited Bagram ...
Slate on time
of sleep deprivation was erased ...
and the prisoners were
removing the shackles.
The military procedure
Traditional does not allow you to ...
shackling
people with fixed objects.
And certainly not with
arms over your head.
At first got a
handcuffed to the people ...
ventilation ducts
the cells to punish them.
And that was strictly
limited to 15 minutes ...
half hour
but soon escalated ...
When they entered, and there ...
had a pair
long wives ...
hanging from the wires
the mesh roof.
Ready for any
arrived.
The cause of death.
CAUSE OF DEATH: HOMICIDE.
The coroner's army
Dilawar who discussed ...
discovered tissue damage
mass in the legs.
Later testify that
his legs had been crushed.
What could cause
that kind of damage?
CORONEL HAYDEN:
This is not a hotel,
is not a place ...
to laze
fat and happy.
In a video that appeared in the
course of the investigation ...
Colonel David Hayden,
the most important lawyer ...
of U.S. forces
in Afghanistan ...
describes the policy of restraining
and beat the detainees.
Had approved a technical
for military police ...
hit in the legs
troublesome prisoners.
In theory considered
nonfatal strokes.
Never really heard
say no to top:
"Give them kicked in the legs
if they do this or that. "
What we said was
that this was an option ...
to which we could
use to control them.
It was just beaten
with the knee in the ...
upper thigh.
It was assumed that this ...
was a pressure point
to control them easily.
If you hit the legs
for more than two days ...
can cause
serious problems.
Throughout the investigation,
and even in trials ...
Several of the guards
and interrogators ...
described as Dilawar
a very combative prisoner ...
of strong character.
But that never
is compatible with ...
other evidence
that this man had.
He weighed 55 pounds when he died.
The passengers of the taxi
Dilawar told us to ...
he was absolutely
terrified at Bagram.
That through the walls
Isolation of the cell ...
they had heard yelling calling
his father and his mother.
I was in a position
very uncomfortable, sputter ...
sometimes praying,
others for help.
Or at least it seemed to me asking
help because they did not understand their language.
Several witnesses recall the night
Prior to the deaths of Dilawar.
Only that night gave
the best 10 in the kicking leg.
Some soldiers told
who gave knees ...
only silence,
because it did not stop shout.
The damage was done.
Their injuries were caused
multiple strokes, y. ..
many of them could have been
avoided having known ...
that the person who had gone before,
used the same technique with him.
When they finally reached
move to an isolation cell ...
I think it was
body devastated.
One reason for
why do we beat ...
it is believed that
was faking.
Was standing in the conduit
ventilation hooded.
His hands were above
of the head and complained.
Began to resist in
the duct.
The conduit has an entry
front and rear ...
but on both sides
There is barbed wire.
None of us wanted
get into the barbed wire ...
so I took the duct ...
it lying on the ground
and immobilized.
What kind of force had
be used for submission?
Physical strength, he was beaten.
There were four policemen
military with him.
And one of the PMs not stop
give blows to the kidneys.
The other two
threw it to the ground ...
and the fourth was
climbed into the back.
He had a huge cut on his nose.
There was no reason to beat him,
remember that he was handcuffed.
Even when controlling
was not a problem ...
eventually exceeded
to be enforced.
And possibly
it looked a mess.
Because the truth is
which could not be ...
kicking a man while
he was chained.
Dilawar was taken to
cell isolation ...
where they continued
giving knees.
In his appearance before the Tribunal,
The coroner said the army ...
it seemed as if a bus
had passed over his legs ...
and which have survived
would have required amputations.
Then came the question:
Is this what you did?
Not that I did or what made him
or what he did either ...
but what you have done.
Now it is almost incomprehensible.
There were soldiers like Willie Brand,
that seems kind of soft voice ...
but testified that struck many
times in the legs to Dilawar ...
being tired knee
and had to switch to the other.
Sometimes I think we should have ...
continued my
moral principles ...
instead of
practices.
A military policeman said that
acquired the habit of ...
entertain inflicting knees
Dilawar only to hear you scream.
Some would say, "Hey, you should
have stopped that ...
to see who was wounded,
you kicked.
Why not do something. "
Very good question.
My answer would be:
"We were against us there."
I was there and not
I wanted to look like that ...
I returned to my
fellow militia.
Is that wrong? Sit
here and say it's wrong ...
go there and say it.
No one inquired about who
established standards in Bagram.
The researchers will never
Wood asked the Captain ...
What high-ranking officers
had been authorized to use ...
techniques prohibited by
the rules of the army?
Captain Beiring
of the Military Police ...
was the only official
charged in the case.
Responsible for negligence
was dismissed ...
where the judge ruled
no one had ...
defined what the
Captain Beiring duties.
Despite repeated requests
an instruction ...
and standards of performance
for his soldiers ...
superiors
they are never hit.
We are all concerned about lack
guidelines written ...
but we are reassured
saying they were coming.
We knew perfectly well why
they gave no clear rules ...
if something happened.
If I had to do it again
certainly would say no.
That I will not do anything
to see something in writing.
And recalling, ¿cree
they were poorly informed?
I believe we all were.
CHANGING THE RULES.
A week after 9 / 11,
Vice President Dick Cheney ...
appeared in the program
"Meet the Press" ...
to ensure that practices
iban interrogation to change.
Revenge.
We must work
on the dark side ...
will be in the
shadow information.
Much of what needs to be done,
should be conducted in silence ...
without discussions,
using sources and methods ...
available for our
Intelligence Agencies ...
if we are to succeed.
So they operate.
And it will be vital for us to use
all means at our disposal ...
to achieve our goals.
It's been said that everything starts at
Vice President Cheney's office ...
fully convinced
that we were not so aggressive ...
in interrogations as
could or should.
SCOTT HORTON, EXPERT
IN INTERNATIONAL LAW.
Had to be tough
with detainees.
If Dick Cheney was the architect
first of a new policy ...
John Yoo was the
principal draftsman.
With a guiding purpose,
advocated a more flexible ...
to deal with
suspected terrorists.
Former United States considered
terrorism a criminal problem ...
the attacks of 9 / 11 showed
that the fight against Al Qaeda ...
had been transformed
in a war.
And I think that when an entity
foreign policy objectives ...
kills 3,000 Americans,
causing billions ...
dollars in damages and seeks to
eliminate the U.S. government ...
to most people because it
looks like a war, not a crime.
President Bush declared
the war on terror.
But that raised the question of whether
suspected terrorists should be ...
covered by the
laws of war ...
prepared by
Geneva Convention.
The atrocities of war
that shocked the world ...
led to the
Geneva Convention.
The purpose of the Treaty
International was to provide protection ...
basic to any human being
caught in a war.
Indeed, over 50 years,
Geneva Convention offered ...
under legal and prohibited the
Interrogators used torture ...
and even murder
humiliating and degrading treatment.
After 9 / 11, John Yoo worked
the office of Dick Cheney ...
and Alberto Gonzales,
Adviser to the President.
Together, they drafted a series of
reported that argued ...
that the Geneva Convention does not
protecting suspected terrorists.
And gave legal cover to
that the CIA and Special Forces ...
embarked on a
hidden agenda ...
using methods of interrogation
banned so far.
Have arrested more than 3000
suspected terrorists in many countries.
Many were
a different destination.
Pongámoslo well ...
are no longer a problem either for the
U.S. or our allies.
The problem of the president,
Gonzales said as ...
was that some of the new
interrogation techniques ...
were proscribed by the laws
U.S. and international.
Said one of its arguments:
"We do not want to apply
the Geneva Convention. "
"Because if it does, it can
constitute war crimes. "
Admiral (Ret.) JOHN HUDSON,
FORMER MILITARY JUDGE.
It is well known principle
of command responsibility.
It was established in the trials of
Nuremberg after World War II.
And instituted the principles of
international criminal law.
ALBERTO MORA, EX-PROSECUTOR
MILITARY LA MARINA.
Where to order
treatment illegal ...
be held responsible
of this treatment but no ...
they are violations
personally this abuse.
To avoid the
interrogation practices ...
U.S.
struck out with torture ...
John Yoo worked in the
drafting a memorandum of ...
devoted to clarifying the
meaning of the term.
Prohibits only extreme acts,
ie, serious physical injury ...
damage to organs or functions
body, or even death.
And that says a legal document,
the Memorandum of Torture. "
Was a
dubious law.
We discussed and finally
was accepted as representative --
It was the decision and final position
the Office of Legal Counsel.
The memo from the Office of Counsel
Imposed no legal restrictions.
That is, at any time
stated that the application ...
of inhuman treatment and
degrading prohibited.
And at one point,
I asked John Yoo ...
if the president could authorize
torture, and his answer was yes.
I think the lawyer should tell the
People come what laws and what not ...
to take
a political decision.
Prof. Doug Cassel: If the president
cree should torture someone ...
including crushing the testicles
child of that person ...
Is there no law to prevent it?
That is what I wrote
in their memorandum of 2002.
John Yoo: I think that depends on
why must I see the president.
The lawyer's
army were outraged by ...
the implications of
Memorandum from John Yoo.
I began to engage
on this issue when I ...
visited a group of lawyers
military top-class ...
more than a year after the
first news about Abu Ghraib.
Those who were concerned
much what happened.
And his main concern
was that the controls ...
military were responsible
for the acts of the soldiers ...
which were responsible for
offer clear guidelines ...
and straight on how to behave in
some very difficult circumstances.
And what we saw was
a decision ...
intentionally in the most
upper echelons of the Pentagon ...
to circumvent all these issues
with a haze of ambiguity ...
accompanied by a high pressure
for results.
To be willing to
violent prisoners.
But to use violence
the detainees is a crime.
Perhaps Al Qaeda or Taliban
or the worst people in the world ...
and it is certain that some are,
but there are certain rules ...
Basic and international agreements
signed by the U.S. ...
we must meet.
Forward, reply, please.
Allow me a quick clarification.
On the president's policy,
how to proceed ...
Armed Forces
the U.S. is trying to follow ...
the prisoners humanely,
adequately ...
and according to the
military needs ...
according to the principles of
Geneva Convention.
It is a legal affirmation
riddled with loopholes.
And it is clear that the interrogators
did not understand that the humane treatment ...
does not depend on color
the beholder.
On the ground in Afghanistan,
spread confusion ...
about what
exactly the rules.
We were told that the
Dealing with the "PUC" ...
ie person
custody of the U.S. ...
is not subject to the Convention
of Geneva, in a nutshell ...
the only thing we were not allowed
do was give them beatings.
Persons or persons in control
custody or something.
The call to dehumanize and
and not consider them persons.
I do not remember having heard anything
on the Geneva Convention.
Of course, I know, but not
told us about it.
Unaware of what the manual said
Army on interrogations ...
unaware of how they defined
the manual, I had seen ...
had a copy lying around,
I am sure that ...
and if he had wanted,
I would have taken to read it ...
but worked 16 hours a day.
Sit to read a regulation
was not my highest priority there.
It is a shameful situation,
vicious, dangerous and dirty.
And we operate
in that environment.
I am convinced that
we can achieve and successfully.
But we must take care not handcuff
our intelligence services ...
in carrying out its mission.
Play around with terrorists
completely different rules.
Will we be required,
using their own words ...
to be outrageous, atrocious and dirty
to deal with them?
Yeah.
LAB.
Guided by the advice
John Yoo's legal ...
the Bush administration sent
Prisoners considered important ...
the U.S. Naval Base
at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
At first I thought he
was a safe place.
You know, put them there,
surrounded by barbed wire.
But then it became clear
that the reason for doing so ...
was that we could argue
there were no laws.
Cuban laws and
Americans did not apply.
That was a great
false step.
I think that what people wanted
makers was to find ...
a place close to the U.S.
could be well protected ...
but at the same time
could benefit from ...
the rule that says the
U.S. Army ...
has the last word
with regard to ...
control of prisoners
kept outside the country.
One by one, the terrorists
are learning ...
what the
U.S. justice.
In December 2001, a man
named Mohammed al-Qahtani ...
was transferred from
Afghanistan to Guantanamo.
After eight months of captivity,
discovered that the army could ...
have been trained to be the
twentieth hijacker air 11 / 9.
Suddenly, al-Qahtani became
the most important prisoner in Guantanamo.
Here was a man
that I should have been ...
on the plane as far
outside Pennsylvania.
JAY HOOD, commander of the
FORCES IN GUANTANAMO 2004-2006.
So I think they felt
the urgency to find out ...
he knew what kind, so
prevent future attacks.
Resist interrogation techniques
usual at Guantanamo ...
for eight months and he
is the reason ...
LIEUTENANT GRAL. RANDALL SCHMIDT,
AUTHOR OF THE REPORT SCHMIDT.
the detachment of Guantanamo
requested the use of other techniques ...
able to overcome resistance
for which he had been trained.
In September 2002,
John Yoo and Alberto Gonzales ...
traveled to Guantanamo.
Shortly after his visit and
just before the arrival of ...
Dilawar at Bagram, Donald
Rumsfeld personally approved ...
a new set of
psychological techniques ...
interrogation, for use
with Mohammed al-Qahtani.
The exact
these methods ...
often entrusted to the imagination
of the interrogators.
"WAS THE STYLE AVOCADO Californians.
That is, totally free. "
LIEUTENANT GRAL. SCHMIDT.
(On the questioning
A al-Qahtani)
GITA GUTIERREZ.
ATTORNEY FOR AL-Qahtani.
Interrogation
are well documented ...
on a daily and from November
2002 to early 2003 ...
He was subjected to this regime.
Is tied to the ground.
Which included an intense
sleep deprivation.
PAGE 23: THE ARRESTED Had she
To stand with HIGH MUSIC ...
WITH THE OBJECTIVE OF
Stay awake.
He was only allowed to sleep four
hours per day from 7 a.m. to 11 a.m..
20 hours of interrogation.
And so for 50 days,
with one exception.
Placed in strict isolation
and private feelings.
DEPRIVATION OF STIMULI
Visual and auditory.
USING THE INDUCTION OF STRESS
FEAR OF ARRESTED (eg dogs)
According to the newspaper,
There were several occasions ...
which a woman
invaded your living space.
And it was a
interrogation tactics ...
intended to undermine their faith.
PAGE 56: A woman invaded
YOUR SPACE AND MOURN by Allah.
The interrogator was close to
stopped behind him rubbing ...
back, he whispered to
ear and stroked her hair.
It was a practice that allowed
called "the futility of technology."
Your mother is a whore.
The interrogators subjected to
I would call "sexual assault".
PAGE 51: WAS FOR Agache
Mounting like a horse.
He was forced to
women's lingerie.
It was called a homosexual
on many occasions.
And he said his
colleagues knew.
He was made to dance with
an interrogator.
He was forced to strip
register and thus to dominate it ...
and not for reasons
security.
And she was required to behave
like a dog.
PAGE 47: SE LE CONTINUE
TREATED AS A DOG.
And all this for
lower self-esteem.
PAGE 47: He was a dog
BELIEVES THAT IT IS BETTER.
They tried to be original, and
the interrogators themselves ...
began to innovate, to put
creative, in quotes.
PAGE 35: a glove was inflated and
YOU ARE SO played effeminate.
PAGE 17: A is placed
ENEMA stop.
PAGE 19: THERE WERE A PARTY AND YOU ARE
Put a cap CUMPLEAÑOS.
Interrogators and Guardian
Canto "God bless America."
Page 7: is placed THREE
BAGS SERA stop.
If you are willing
YOU CAN TALK TO PEEING.
He was told he was not
IBA A untied.
The detainee wet
IN THEIR PANTS.
PAGE 53: SE LE removed
COBIJA And it lit up the air.
The combination of lack of
food and dehydration ...
induced at reducing the rate
to 35 beats per minute.
And that was rushed
to the hospital to resuscitate.
PAGE 27: was taken to hospital
To make a scan.
Just questioning
Mohammed al-Qahtani ...
in many respects, contains all
evolution, the whole story ...
of torture by the CIA as
Over the past 50 years.
The CIA launched a
mental control project ...
an authentic Manhattan Project
mental domain in 1950.
The CIA investigated
exotic techniques such as ...
hypnosis and then
Sodium pentothal with ...
and later with
electric shock.
And in the end discovered LSD.
Anything ...
the drug had no consequences
except for the lawsuits.
But what if it works, was
that the CIA hired the service ...
most of the scholars preclaros
of behavioral science ...
of the best universities
U.S. and Canada.
Experiments
of the famous psychologist ...
Donald O. Hebb
from McGill University ...
attracted the
Researchers at the CIA.
Dr. Hebb found
which could induce a ...
state similar to
48 hours in acute hypnosis.
And all they did was sit
students to volunteer ...
comfortable in a cubicle
with air conditioning ...
with glasses,
some earmuffs and gloves.
Looked exactly the same
the prisoners in Guantanamo.
Those costumes that lead
Prisoners at Guantanamo ...
with gloves, goggles and earmuffs.
Everyone thinks it is for safety.
No, it is to isolate sensorially.
The first day you have hallucinations,
the two can no longer more.
When we were making
experiments, I started thinking ...
it was possible that something
involve physical ...
or even pain, could
be more tolerable than the ...
simple conditions
deprivation studied.
The CIA was fascinated, it was
rushed over immediately.
I had no idea that he could
become a weapon so cruel.
Identified two key techniques:
Identified
sensory disorientation.
And identify the pain
self when standing ...
for several days with liquid
accumulate in the legs.
And together in the ...
"Manual on Interrogation Kurbak
in Counter.
And the spread of
around the world and all ...
services
intelligence.
Think of the treatment
that al-Qahtani was subjected.
First there is darkness, then
Light passes cold, then heat.
They attack their receptors
perceived by the world.
And their upset
perception of time.
And this is the first phase.
In Guantanamo, under
General Miller's regime ...
he became a Guantanamo
veritable laboratory ...
of the behavioral sciences.
And Donald Rumsfeld, ordered to use
methods to overcome the manual.
And spread, spread
ambiguous in a way so ...
allowing people to make
as deemed necessary.
And explored the sensitivity
arabic men ...
before sex
and sexual identity.
And hence the charge
being gay ...
underwear on
head and all those things.
People said that the Arabs are
very sensitive to sexual humiliation.
Well, what the hell and who is not
sensitive to sexual humiliation?
Nobody wants you naked
and forced to masturbate ...
with a hood on his head.
It'sa ridiculous.
Then set up specialized teams
in the behavioral sciences.
And there was the army that psychologists
participating in interrogations ...
to discover the fears
and phobias of each prisoner.
And all this was done in
If al-Qahtani.
Did the communications
between General Miller ...
and Secretary Rumsfeld on
prisoner in this specific?
To our knowledge,
had a considerable amount ...
communications
entire chain of command.
As you know,
The report by Schmidt ...
it concluded that these
techniques alone ...
did not constitute torture, but said
than the sum of these techniques:
The cumulative effect
the application ...
many simultaneous
authorized methods ...
had an abusive
and demeaning to the person.
And recommended that the General
Miller was punished.
But she said
did not constitute torture.
We made a distinction
between torture ...
and inhumane treatment
according to the ...
General Guidelines
and then what could be abusive ...
and degrading.
Something can be degrading ...
but not necessarily torture.
Can not be inhumane ...
but humiliating
but not torture.
Or torture, or pain
physical, or injuries.
The environment was safe and devoid
risk at all times.
And of course, therein lies
the genius of the paradigm ...
psychological CIA.
Psychological torture is
a question of definitions.
And of course,
is very elusive.
That sounds remarkably similar
what happened at Abu Ghraib.
People with the collar
dogs, forced to put ...
lingerie. Perhaps a
coincidence, maybe not.
If you look at the
photographs from Abu Ghraib ...
that will always
the same techniques.
The first is the activity
sex with the woman's clothes.
Masturbation and the like.
This is exploited
sensitivity of their culture.
They were immobilized with
short chains and long ...
upside down, those are
stress positions.
The most infamous of all
the photos of Abu Ghraib ...
is that of the hooded Iraqi on
a box with arms outstretched.
He was told that if they fell
of the box, if you moved ...
is electrocutaría. So
counterfeit electrical cables.
Is the absolute immobility
for long periods of time.
And with
arms outstretched.
On television they say never
try to do this at home.
But try,
try spending 10 minutes ...
with arms outstretched
and unmoving.
Carolyn Wood was an example
how new techniques ...
spread
and as a mutated virus.
Before that Wood would
charge of interrogations ...
at Abu Ghraib,
his unit had practiced ...
brutal techniques at Bagram,
such as stress positions ...
required long periods of standing,
and sleep deprivation.
One of the memos, which shows
in early December 2002 ...
Bagram interrogators that
were in contact with the types of ...
Guantánamo via the Internet,
they learned that they had ...
received from the Secretary of State
new methods of instruction.
And began to use
although it clearly ...
had been approved for use
nothing else in Guantánamo.
When the Gral Miller
traveled from Guantanamo ...
to Iraq in August 2003
brought a CD and a manual ...
Advanced techniques
developed at Guantanamo ...
and gave the
Gen. Sanchez's command.
So there
these multiple paths ...
to track where
These interrogation techniques ...
performed this migration overall.
From Afghanistan to Iraq ...
and from Guantanamo
directly to Iraq.
And the final result,
is Abu Ghraib.
Long before knowing
abuses at Abu Ghraib ...
civil servants had
discretely alerting ...
techniques bestial
used at Guantanamo.
Had sent e-mails
the Department of Justice ...
FBI personnel
at Guantanamo, saying:
"Do not believe what
is happening here. "
"The FBI must dissociate
what is ...
going
at Guantanamo. "
The email reads:
"The Department of Defense ...
has orders
Secretary of Defense. "
Orders of the Secretary of
Defense tactics to use ...
that the FBI considered extremely
offensive and dangerous.
But the emails,
are, what we call ...
"Editing", which means
there are big gaps in them.
Now, some are completely
edited so that ...
ignore what they say.
This is an example ...
Many of the documents
we have here.
You can not see anything
in these documents.
One after another there is nothing.
THE INFORMANT.
In early December 2002,
continued to abuse detainees.
ALBERTO MORA, ATTORNEY GENERAL
ARMY OF 2001 to 2006.
I called the General Counsel
Army and asked ...
if he had any information,
I said: "I get some reports ...
Abuse of prisoners in
Guantanamo, you know something about it. "
And his answer was: "I know a lot
on the subject, come to my office. "
I spent a pile of
documents on the table ...
The first document was a
Memorandum of General Counsel ...
DoD
for Secretary Rumsfeld.
Memorandum was a covert
in asking ...
authorization to apply certain
methods of interrogation.
There was approval
Secretary Rumsfeld's ...
to implement
Some of these methods.
In this memorandum is a
Secretary Rumsfeld's note ...
that says if it passes
8 to 10 hours of walking ...
how was that these detainees
only spend 4 hours daily walk.
I was dumbfounded. My first
reaction was to believe that it was a mistake ...
someone who had not read the
document with precise care.
I think people's
Pentagon considered ...
Alberto Mora a loyal Republican,
in an important political post ...
never would have considered
a problem or a liberal.
He said he hoped
raise these issues.
And that people in authority read:
"Ah, thanks for telling us."
And that would be the
end of all this.
I wanted to ask about a
memorandum written by Alberto Mora.
Remember that this memorandum
wrote a note that they have ...
to spend more than 4 hours
stand because you do?
Yes, yes.
Counsel argues that this
could be interpreted as ...
seemed to go well beyond the
techniques prescribed in the memorandum.
No, no ... Not given
understand anything.
They said that they would have to
People stand for several hours.
And jokingly noted that a setentón
as I spent all day standing.
Although I should not do,
and it was well written.
- And life goes on.
- But he is concerned ...
should be advised to
best for their legal department.
And I heard your question the first time.
For me the most disturbing
was that the techniques themselves ...
alone or in combination could
reach the level of torture.
Well, allow certain
interrogation techniques ...
but since then has
to be some limit ...
it depends on the
harsh methods.
The deprivation of light could
mean having the prisoner ...
in a dark room
for 15 minutes.
Or it could be a month or two or three,
until you go blind.
Specific techniques
phobias of each detainee.
It refers to snakes,
the bats, the rats ...
to lock someone in a coffin,
the only limit is your imagination ...
any of these methods
alone could be seen ...
including torture and together could certainly
reach that level soon.
Dr. Donald Hebb: If subjected to
person during this process ...
more than six or eight days,
I think that is the maximum tolerable ...
- ... Then the price is very high.
- Is the price someone's life?
Presumably, it could be.
The medical literature describes
a phenomenon called ...
"Rising Force"
that was almost inevitable that ...
interrogators continue
increases in applied ...
force for increasing
obtain the desired results.
For example, in making the memorandum
Secretary Rumsfeld's ...
say, "Look, he says that
Dogs must wear a muzzle. "
Well this man does not understand
the behavior of ...
in a military zone
conflict, because as soon as the ...
soldier to see that the dog
because the muzzle not ...
impressed at all
interrogated, he was removed.
That is the reality,
it is human nature.
Alberto Mora threatened
to make public their ...
concerns unless
ended such practices.
If after all
there is concern ...
then I am also concerned,
so I'm ready ...
to cancel the orders, giving
A new approach to the case y. ..
talk to people all over this
to see what should be done.
, To his
Rumsfeld to abolish the ...
interrogation techniques and
for a year and a half later ...
not receive any
report that ...
was abusing the
detainees anywhere.
When it was discovered at Abu Ghraib,
the first thing I thought was ...
if I had been deceived.
If authorized the abuse of
prisoners without my knowledge.
You really had
withdrawn the orders?
According to the interrogators, the use
of shackles, dogs, posture ...
forced and sensory assault,
continued to spread.
Tony Lagouranis was an interrogator
who came to Iraq after ...
that the army knew
of abuse at Abu Ghraib.
Among the instructions for
interviews they gave us ...
stated that the authorizing
use of dogs to detainees ...
stress positions,
sleep deprivation.
All those things you did
and that it took ...
brutal or violating the Convention
Geneva told me to do that.
And were our superiors
we were told to do so.
The backbone
Armed Forces ...
Americans is
chain of command.
What begins in the
top of the chain of command ...
falls like a stone
the lower end of that chain.
And that's why Lynndie England
Donald knew what he believed ...
Rumsfeld even without
talking with Donald Rumsfeld.
In full Abu resaca
Ghraib, journalists ...
began to look harder
in previous cases of abuse ...
to try to understand what the
cause and who were responsible.
People like Tim Golden's
New York Times, addressed the topic ...
and began to examine the case of
Including Dilawar, the taxi driver.
I seemed at least plausible that
that man was not guilty ... more
that are at
the time of the raid.
And here is a man
killed while in custody.
THE WRONG MAN.
... pay tribute to those who
were killed ...
who are
selflessly every day.
Four years ago,
our nation was attacked.
9 / 11 in the floating
environment, and I think that ...
officials wanted to continue
floating in the atmosphere.
Try to remember these guys
that people are our enemy ...
but to understand how
iban these young soldiers ...
to discern who were the
real enemies ...
among a lot of
militia and peasants ...
in a society
completely alien to them.
If I remember correctly,
his case was about ...
with a missile attack
to a military base.
It was assumed that he was the driver
the order in which they fled.
Took his new car and
was obviously very happy.
That was until Khost
the provincial capital ...
where he began to seek
for taxi passengers.
In fact these three men found
in the market returning to Yakubi.
Imagine, again Dilawar
home from the capital ...
which was the Provincial
farther from their small world.
And on the basis of the artillery Salerno
stop a group of Afghan militia.
Apparently, men
found a stabilizer ...
electricity in the trunk of
car, or at least it said.
That same day the base Salerno had
been attacked with missiles from a distance.
And the Afghan militiamen arrested
immediately to the four ...
men who were suspected
be involved in that attack.
And then take him to
Bagram that is far away.
And you have a lot of types
in this detention center ...
and they say they have evidence
involved in an attack ...
with missiles
U.S. forces.
So I think
that whatever the change.
You are immersed in that
atmosphere in which only ...
you are in company
military, where you ...
feel isolated and morally
lose your moral ...
and are frustrated
because you do not get ...
information from a prisoner
feel guilty that ...
and that you feel may dártela,
then start sobrepasarte ...
want to see
where you can get.
Much of the pressure was due to
fact that we had a few ...
detainees who provided important
a lot of useful information.
And when they began to take
because the prisoners iban ...
Syria wanted to follow
getting the same around the world.
A few of those types
interrogábamos by the ...
mere questioning
and it was ridiculous, you did ...
with any of those types
and you say: "God ...
is not him who would
take prisoner. "
Especially if you watch,
at the precise moment when the ...
you enter, you realize
that should not be there.
We arrived a prisoner who was
diminished mental ...
and Sergeant Loring
argued that it was a theater ...
one that makes Al Qaeda,
and went and talked to him.
In short, he bore type
diapers and ate his own feces.
But still Loring
saying that pretended.
You said: "We want
going to shout that guy "...
so I took the box
I was having breakfast cereals ...
entered the room and said:
"Well, today I played gritarte" ...
and began: "dehydrated,
substitute for salt, "and me ...
he shouted,
I watched amazed ...
and I said "Yes, now you
have cast the blame for ...
this in my cereal, "or they
shouted that if Elvis was ...
truly the king of rock and
if still alive, things like that.
And that what I wrote in my reports,
and deliver them to my superiors ...
saying that everything we had
been doing for two hours.
You can not evaluate a person to
not talk to her a few times.
So the first three
Sometimes talking with someone ...
only verify the version,
looking for contradictions ...
looking for gaps, then
the third time, if your version ...
remained consistent, said
I felt that he was innocent.
They wanted that
people were guilty ...
because its unit
was well, and could ...
we say
60 people arrested ...
in a month and that all
they were terrorists.
"When was the last time you saw
Osama Bin Laden and Mullah Omar. "
These questions were routine
who were all detained.
It is very difficult to undertake
an interview with ...
very little evidence and almost never
we had against those guys ...
and yet they sacábamos
a confession ...
and you can get
information, but getting ...
criminalizing a type
himself totally ...
is very difficult, so you have
techniques that draw ...
increasingly outrageous to
make such a confession.
Sergeant Loring, I cried
for being very kind to him ...
told me that he had
that pressure.
As he liked to say, I had
that make you feel uncomfortable.
After a time,
particularly after the fourth ...
or fifth interview,
when the sleep deprivation ...
which is starting to subject them
effect of truth ...
interrogation
intensified.
The Sergeant Salcedo was a
inexperienced interrogator ...
but it was taking the initiative,
a prisoner who had not wanted ...
look for a woman who said that
the frustrated a lot, so I took ...
and the face turned towards her
look at that and take it seriously.
But of course, was an Afghan
belonging to a culture ...
not very conservative tribal
I watched women unknown.
The Sergeant was Salcedo
I felt a little aggrieved ...
so I
interposed between them.
And then when I got
by the shirt and throwing it to the wall.
They tried to stay standing together
to the wall, but slips ...
down,
it held against the wall.
Reasons not understood, no
was more than delusions.
The interpreter told me that ...
his wife came to
visit to the cell ...
which certainly
did not occur.
I do not know if you ever have seen
someone deprived of sleep ...
two days to begin
to be idiotizados.
For three days,
no longer worth anything.
I knew something was not right.
The next thing I knew
is that he died.
Not long after
murder of Dilawar ...
knew that the
commander of the guerrilla ...
Afghan arrested
Dilawar and to the other ...
was arrested for
them Americans.
And it turned out that he was the one who
rocket struck their base.
Then captured Afghans
innocent and delivered ...
the Americans
to ingratiate itself with them.
The three passengers were
Sent to Guantanamo ...
Passenger Dilawar.
and did not leave until
March 2004 ...
ie 15 months after
have been captured.
It is difficult to know
The reason that ...
Americans moved
Despite those men ...
that was completed
no doubt that ...
Dilawar was at least
innocent when he was murdered.
Of course, it makes you
if not send to ask ...
Hence, only those types
to cover their backs.
Worst of the worst.
Are not innocent
are the worst of the worst.
Are among the murderers
most dangerous ...
best trained and most cruel
that is on the face of the earth.
Are terrorists, manufacturers
pumps, working with terrorism ...
are members of Al Qaeda,
Taliban.
And if they are released,
continue killing.
All I know with certainty,
they are evil people.
Despite the fact that Rumsfeld, Cheney and
the Pdte. Bush say that these ...
types are the worst of the worst
captured on the battlefield ...
a recent study of
government documents ...
shows that only 5% of these
people were captured by U.S..
Only 8% are accused
of belonging to Al Qaeda.
More than 90% were delivered
by the Northern Alliance ...
or by Pakistani Forces
in return for rewards.
Offer substantial
rewards.
Newsletters that seem to throw
decembrinas snowfall in Chicago.
An analysis of documents
declassified government ...
revealed that only 7% of
Guantanamo detainees ...
were captured by U.S.
and Coalition Forces.
The remaining 93%,
as Dilawar and his passengers ...
were handed over by warlords
Afghan and Pakistani ...
sometimes in exchange for thousands
dollars in cash.
The army is not interested in spending
$ $ 40,000 a year ...
on Guantanamo detainee
people who are not Al Qaeda.
Make sure they are interested in more
that the detainees are actually ...
members of Al Qaeda
that wasting resources ...
and stopping time
innocent people.
It seems natural to stop
people in times of war.
Want to arrest any of the
suspect that it is dangerous.
The difference is that the
government first ...
U.S. history has not
met its own standards ...
requiring
a trial ...
immediately following
the capture in case of doubt.
During the war in Afghanistan, 2001
the U.S. military was ...
MAYOR DAN MORI. Lawyer
GUANTANAMO DETAINEES IN DAVID HICKS.
ready to comply with Convention
of Geneva and to hold such trials.
But the civil authorities of
Defense Department prevented.
When someone
Afghanistan said ...
certain person was
an important goal ...
for any reason
or based in ...
testimony of another Afghan
who hates that person ...
and I want to get rid of it
appropriate planting opium ...
was sent to Guantanamo
and that person no longer ...
took the form of a claim
nothing and still have it.
Moazzam Begg, citizen
British suspect ...
to be associated with commands
Al Qaeda was captured ...
some agents
Pakistani intelligence.
I was in my house
Islamabad when I was kidnapped.
I was a
hood on his head ...
wives in the hands and feet,
I boarded a car.
Since that time no
I went to see my family.
I was sent to Kandahar
and then to Bagram.
Y cuando me iban a
transfer to Guantanamo ...
I am covered from head to toe
with all sorts of things.
A mask, some earrings,
and black glasses just in case ...
still saw something, a hood
I covered my head.
Go sit in the plane
was a torment ...
I had
a third set of shackles that ...
carried around the waist
and chained to the back.
It was impossible to move,
impossible to breathe ...
was impossible to hear anything
so when I got to shout ...
I implore him one of the guards
I inject something ...
sleeping.
We strive for
two years and a half ...
just to see
prisoners and then ...
others strive months
for the military ...
give us the green light
good to go in there.
What a bizarre thing.
I never thought when ...
studied law in the U.S. ...
would have to talk to someone
to have access to my clients ...
or ask if
They had been tortured.
The "Habeas Corpus" is the essence
the rule of law.
Denying people a trial
basic to deprive him of his freedom ...
is one of the reasons
we made the revolution ...
so that the King could not deny
anyone of their liberty without trial.
In June 2004,
two years and a half later ...
that the first inmates
came to Guantanamo ...
the Supreme Court rejected
The claim of the administration ...
Bush to hold
prisoners indefinitely ...
allow them to challenge
their detention before a court.
After that decision
the army was ...
new courts
Special solved ...
prisoners had
remain in Guantanamo.
Courts Review
of the Combatant Status ...
rapidly
by the government nine days after ...
that to win
the Supreme Court, are a farce.
You have no rights,
not even a lawyer ...
not entitled
the testimony of witnesses ...
unknown
charges brought against you ...
and ignore what evidence
secret is against you.
You may never know.
That does not prevent ...
can
a case of why ...
if they are left free in the future,
why are no longer a threat.
My client could
found to be innocent ...
in those courts,
but then the army believed ...
it does not sound very good,
to be declared ...
that are not
enemy combatants (NEC) ...
should be declared
NLEC which means ...
that are no longer
enemy combatants ...
because before they were guilty,
but now that has changed ...
so we are not guilty,
but we were right at first.
These men are not
necessarily innocent ...
is not an accurate description.
The more specific designation
is that we ...
are no longer enemy combatants.
They were separated from the rest of the
arrested for the government ...
U.S. is a country
to be passed.
Some of these types are
withdrew from the battlefield ...
and if not here,
will be there ...
killing soldiers
Americans.
If you are here is something
our mission is ...
to ensure that
remain here until ...
conclusion that no longer
should continue here.
Guantanamo serves
to hide the fact ...
that the real bad
Mullah Omar and of course ...
Osama Bin Laden,
have not been captured.
Guantanamo along with their
"Malis" 750 types ...
are just a
Image to say:
"Look, we're accomplishing something
in the fight against terrorism. "
THE TOUR FOR THE PRESS
IN GUANTANAMO.
And that is the main entrance
Camp X-Ray
It would be very hard to escape here.
CAMP X-RAY WAS
Abandoned in April 2002.
The cells measured
2.5 x 2.5 x 2.5 meters.
By an individual cell.
Will be remembered for
individuals with orange clothes ...
were three or four knees
and looking over there ...
three or four knees
and looking into further.
If you take photos from here
obtain the same image.
No detainee has died at
Guantanamo for nothing.
MISCELLANEOUS FROM THIS INTERVIEW
Detainees have committed suicide.
Doctors will tell you that we have already
conducted over 100 operations ...
well, that's one advantage
to be here, to be healthy ...
and what they cure
to be curarles.
We have introduced new
sports here at Camp 4.
Recently assemble this
half basketball court.
And to the left of it
be a soccer field.
Living in Camp
4 is a privilege.
To live here have to abide
the rules of the camp.
And we've introduced things like
cake on Wednesday night ...
Pepsi on Monday night
ice cream on Sunday evening.
We will come to see the bed.
In bed with what they call
"comfort", which is ...
objects such as toothbrushes,
but also games of checkers.
And I asked: "And who is going
to play the ladies my client? "
It is only confined to
an isolation cell.
What problem is that
Press the pictures ...
talk to them, observe?
We do not want to give them a
means of expression.
We want to avoid that
detainees express their vile ...
Islamist arguments, its violent
and vile Islamic arguments.
Souvenir shop
OF GUANTANAMO.
It is a tactic of Al Qaeda.
Start hunger strikes to
attract media attention ...
81 detainees were strikers
HUNGER IN THIS JOURNEY.
and lobby the government
the USA.
When the number increased
significantly ...
You began to wonder
on the subject and they know it.
Camp 5 is a
isolation facilities ...
for maximum security
interviews with 100 beds.
If you are detained at Camp
5 days are always the same ...
and you spend 24 hours a
days alone in an isolation cell.
The two half-cell
and half by two meters.
I am unable to give three
steps in any direction.
I became convinced that would happen
Hence most of my life ...
and that perhaps I carried,
something told me often.
What especially pernicious
of Guantanamo Bay is ...
do not know when it will end,
not even know if it will.
The reason that the prisoners
on hunger strike ...
and die of starvation,
is that in the words of ...
Omar Deghayes: "Since I am
slowly dying in here ...
Guantánamo, at least they can
have my own life. "
INTERROGATION ROOM.
I have no intention whatsoever
to detain anyone here that ...
is no longer a threat
for our country ...
or unable to give information
useful in the war ...
against terrorism.
Collect data yet ...
of men
We locked.
One of the reasons that I
isolated were related ...
with the fact of having witnessed
of the deaths at Bagram.
I wonder what soldiers
had been involved ...
so I brought in pictures
of people in the unit ...
and indicated that they believed
who were involved.
I asked one of the things
more strange that I never ...
asked all the time
I was imprisoned.
And if he was willing to testify
in the trial of those soldiers.
And I thought:
"How ironic is this ...
That is the only court
get to see ...
after all these
years of captivity. "
THE RULE OF LAW.
The cruel ironies of
the story of Dilawar ...
echoed in a debate without end
the U.S. Congress ...
on abuses of detainees,
national security ...
and the rule of law.
To a senator, John McCain,
former prisoner of war ...
the abuse of prisoners
was both political and personal.
NORTH VIETNAM, 1968.
I want to say ...
my wife,
that I will be fine.
I love her and that
See you again soon.
I would like
being told.
That's it.
If this man, after
six or seven years of torture ...
said that it is not effective,
it is inhumane ...
and feeding
contempt towards the U.S..
He could stand up and be the voice
of morality in this matter.
Send to fight for
us to Afghanistan and Iraq.
The push to raise
information from detainees ...
pero luego obviamos las reglas con las
we train our soldiers ...
and replaced by a set
changing rules and confusing.
And when things were bad,
I miss the guilt and punishment.
I think we can
do better than that.
I strongly urge you to
do justice to your men ...
and women in uniform, to give rules
of conduct that reflect ...
the ideals for
who risk their lives.
On October 5, 2005
because every time ...
came more cases of abuse
detainees to the courts ...
Senator John McCain proposed the
"Detainee Treatment Act."
The Act sought to abolish a
of torture by the U.S..
As well as cruel,
inhuman and degrading.
And prompted a national debate,
plagued by a vicious details.
Is it still permissible
using a wet towel ...
and water to induce a
misperception of suffocation?
The use of wet towel
and water to induce ...
misperception
Choking was a ...
the methods applied
by the detachment ...
Guantanamo in its long
list. Never adopted.
It has never been a
technique adopted.
One technique that
made the transition ...
the scope
physical to psychological ...
in fact, the only
was "waterboarding."
Because in the Middle Ages,
times of the Inquisition ...
was used for its
terrible physics ...
was used to purge
and punish the heretic.
Water is introduced by the
throat to force ...
cree that the victim is
drowning, it's frightening.
You have the feeling that die.
Right after 9 / 11,
The CIA obtained the approval ...
the White House
use the "waterboarding".
One of the first
Where was tested ...
was in the interrogation
Ibn al-Shaykh al-Libi ...
alleged emir of a camp
Al Qaeda training.
Initially the FBI was responsible
his interrogation ...
but the administration is
impatient with the slow ...
that results obtained
techniques of the FBI.
So given
al-Libi to the CIA.
Was immobilized,
bound with a ribbon ...
hooded and iban
get a box ...
plywood box
for their own safety ...
during their transfer to the airport.
I boarded a plane and
sent to Egypt in an illegal flight.
Then during the two weeks
subjected to brutal torture ...
through all these techniques,
including the "waterboarding".
And what came from al-Libi was
that the regime of Saddam Hussein ...
had trained in Al Qaeda
methods of chemical and biological warfare.
One of the things we know about
torture is that torture ...
someone will say to his interrogator
cree what he wants to hear.
At the time when
he applied the "waterboarding" ...
al-Libi began
speak clearly.
But instead of questioning what
read and consider carefully ...
to see if what she said
could be substantiated ...
left immediately.
Rushed to inform you that al-Libi
had said and left the torture.
And "bang", what comes to the
highest ...
and suddenly it
Colin Powell says:
"Hey, no longer must worry
his doubts, because ...
just confirm that there was
contacts between Al Qaeda and Baghdad. "
In February 2003, the then
Secretary of State Colin Powell ...
appeared before the UN
advocating the invasion of Iraq.
I can recount the history of
as a major terrorist ...
that Iraq trained Al Qaeda
in the use of these weapons.
Fortunately, this is a terrorist
arrested and had their history.
A year later the CIA
accused al-Libi ...
distort information and invalidated
all reports ...
intelligence services
with that information.
That is, get information,
but false information.
I think Colin Powell said he had
been the most embarrassing days of his life.
According to all experts,
the torturing people ...
is not the best way
to obtain information.
Breaking down barriers
between you and them ...
earn your trust,
is the best way to achieve it.
Experience is needed,
true talent, a little patience ...
and maybe you say something
worthwhile.
And then, if they
should run ahead.
If you want to understand
well with someone ...
JACK CLOONAN.
FBI agents 1977-2002.
must be your salvation, because his life
as we know, is over.
Can I do something for your kids?
Are you concerned about them?
Want to education?
I will give you education.
What do you want?
Tell me what you want ...
Tell me how
think out of this.
How are you going to wage
of this so ...
terrible in which, for
Incidentally, you got yourself?
You can not go home, right?
Not so good ... llevémonos
let it help you to find a
strategy to get a life.
And this is how it works.
The amount of information
obtained before 9 / 11 ...
for me it was valuable.
Who else would tell us
how to come to Al Qaeda?
What it meant "Billah"?
How do they communicate?
What used satellite phones?
What Bin Laden had a double?
And get all this information,
were able to perform certain operations.
As boring as it may seem, for
me remains the best method.
And we do not have to ask
Apologies to anyone.
We do not know what revenge
us.
And if I wanted to encourage
the believers ...
would take a
those with photo of the necklace ...
dog, report,
and watch his brothers ...
children and say:
"They have a duty to take revenge."
LA BOMBA DE TIEMPO.
Advocates of torture
tend to focus on the hypothetical.
They talk about the impending explosion
a time bomb.
Imagine that there is a
bomb in Times Square ...
which is about to erupt, we
custody to a lawyer type and want to ...
Does it respect the right
A lawyer or to save ...
a million lives we will apply
electrodes to his testicles?
In the series "24", week after week
are scenes of horrific torture.
Tell me what you regard
with terrorists.
Its intention is to prevent any
a terrorist bomb ...
time kills hundreds of thousands
but millions of Americans.
Are we torturing
this man?
I say do what
necessary to avoid ...
that the nuclear warhead
used against us.
It is merely an absurd,
because you can tell them:
"Hey, cítame
one time ...
the last 500 years
we've had in ...
arrested someone
a time bomb. "
The probability that
happen, is remotísima.
And although the case, who you
ensures that knocking ...
you'll get the information?
If a guy is as committed ...
I think it will die before giving.
Just after the
appearance of the pictures ...
Abu Ghraib in mid
2004, 35% of ...
U.S. respondents,
believed that torture ...
was acceptable
certain circumstances.
Even after the photos of Abu
Ghraib, and I think this shows ...
that this kind of popular culture
causes an endorsement of torture ...
which allows the White House
Bush is getting his own way when ...
distorted the laws and treaties
without outraged public opinion.
In a radio trend
conservative, the vice president ...
Dick Cheney defended without any detour
the practice of "waterboarding."
Do not you think that "waterboarding" is not
must question whether lives are saved?
Well, I do not question it,
but during a time ...
criticized me for being the
"vice president for torture."
Do not forgive torture.
"We do not torture", footnote
page, according to our definition ...
means of torture which
appears to us and nothing else.
In the election campaign of 2006,
Bush defended the administration ...
the brutal methods that the rest
the world defined as "torture."
Bush and Cheney played the fear
of voters and politicians.
If Congress gave them no power
to do what was necessary ...
How to be iban
except the Americans?
In addition to the terrorists
Guantanamo ...
a small group
suspected leaders of ...
and terrorist activities
arrested in the war ...
have been captured and
questioned outside the USA.
In a separate program run by
Central Intelligence Agency.
The CIA program included:
Some people question, "Why recognizes
Now the program?
Waterboarding,
Forced nudity ...
Some believe that the military
and intelligence personnel ...
involved in capturing and
interrogation of terrorists ...
PLANTS BOUND
(MORE THAN 40 HOURS)
now could be at risk of
be accused of war crimes ...
simply for doing their jobs
conscious and professional manner.
This is unacceptable.
President Bush was
forced to reveal ...
the secret CIA program
when the Supreme Court ...
intervened to limit its
powers in wartime.
Hamdan's historic decision,
The Supreme Court concluded that ...
interviews and
processes of terrorists ...
be subject to
Geneva Convention.
This debate has
because the failure ...
Supreme Court
says that we must act ...
under Common Article 3
of the Geneva Convention.
And the Common Article 3 says that no
infringe upon human dignity.
That's ... is ... is, I do not know
very vague. What does it mean?
Do you think the use of
evidence obtained through ...
techniques such as waterboarding,
stress positions, jobs ...
intimidatory dogs
military, sleep deprivation ...
and sensory, forced nudity
no common Article 3 attacks?
Lord, I believe that the most
important is that I can not ...
imagine that such testimony
can be trusted.
Mr. Attorney General, cree
that data from ...
through an unlawful treatment
and inhuman treatment to be admitted?
Senator, I ...
Well, again ...
I will say this ...
I am concerned
of such a ban ...
is: what does that mean?
How do you define?
And who would define it?
The Bush administration
introduced a new law ...
to circumvent the restrictions
Supreme Court.
In a legal sense,
I think they wanted to eliminate ...
the Constitution
and rewritten.
But you can not do that,
so what do ...
is to provide a new
interpretation of the former.
The new interpretation
is that the Executive ...
in time of war and maybe
this war will last forever ...
is almighty.
Congress gave the president
more than they wanted.
Agree to abide by
the Geneva Convention ...
provided they could define
its meaning and application.
A few prisoners
Guantanamo would be tried ...
but the rest would never
access to habeas corpus.
The fundamental legal right
to challenge their detention.
Thinking submitted
the presidential election ...
to Senator McCain
voted for the law ...
shortly after the
Bush administration threatens ...
to discredit him with
Conservatives votes.
Very hidden within this law ...
There is a provision
forgive President Bush ...
and all members of
administration of all ...
possible crimes
torture-related ...
and abuse of prisoners
since September 11 2001.
At least Nixon had Gerald Ford
to do the dirty work.
President Bush tries
forgive himself.
Forgiveness is not extended
to soldiers in battle.
The trial was a time
very confusing to me ...
had never been in one,
I did not know what was going on.
All that is included
I faced a long ...
conviction, that is the only thing
I understood everything.
WILLIE SOLDIER BRAND
CONVICTED BY:
ASSAULT, mutilation
AND ABUSE.
They put me in jail ...
a corrective to the army.
SGT. Anthony Morden
GUILTY OF: ASSAULT AND NEGLECT.
I lost my job ...
I was low
for misconduct ...
I am prevented from getting
work in the same field.
I have been financially devastated.
Glad you have finished
and be able to continue with my life.
DAMIEN CORSETTI SOLDADO
ACQUITTED OF:
ASSAULT, ABUSE, USE
Of hashish and IMPROPER ACT.
GLENDALE WALLS SPECIALIST
I should plead guilty to:
assault and two counts of negligence.
I was told that a change does not happen
more than four months in jail.
Instead of spending money on a
view, would have invested ...
better training for soldiers
and ensure that other people ...
enters into battle well equipped,
directed and understanding ...
quite new
rules and responsibilities.
When a prisoner is abused,
or a detainee alleges abuse ...
want someone
pay for the damage.
And there are people who have
eagles or stars on the sleeves.
No official has been
If convicted of Dilawar.
Following his service at Abu Ghraib,
the Captain Carolyn Wood ...
was assigned to the School of
Interrogation of the Army ...
Fort Huachuca, Arizona.
And what it reflects on ...
the intentions
of senior executives?
Not eradicate abuse ...
but the perpetuation of abuse.
I think there is a possibility
other terrorist attacks ...
of dying
more Americans.
And the argument that we should
abuse of detainees ...
to protect lives
Americans ...
I believe violates
our values rooted ...
and against its own
security of our country.
Not only strive
to protect lives ...
fight to protect
our principles.
If I say that Afghanistan,
Guantanamo and Iraq ...
We have caught 50 thousand
people, I would say ...
less than 1% were terrorists.
FROM 11 SEPT 2006
ARE MORE THAN 83 THOUSAND PRISONERS.
None have been
Brought to trial.
Some were insurgents?
Possibly.
Will all of Iraq
to become insurgents ...
after the treatment?
Sure.
I was kidnapped, imprisoned me
unfairly, I was tortured ...
and threatened me with more
torture, without charge, without trial.
Released by Moazzam Begg
PRESSURE OF THE BRITISH GOVERNMENT.
Many soldiers
I said then:
"Hell, if you were not
terrorist when you came ...
when you leave you will be safe,
by how they treat you. "
I think there are
certain prejudices ...
that this religion and people
who hijacked the planes ...
just feels so
respect for life ...
that we look and say:
"if you have life
in such low esteem '...
is clear that the 11 / 9
is an example of this ...
"they are the devil
Here anything goes. "
Villagers come
the tomb of Dilawar ...
to pray for
his soul already departed.
I pray for him and for all
others are in the cemetery.
"Dilawar, the martyr"
VILLAGE OF YAKUBI.
BROTHER OF Dilawar.
What would you say to
Americans?
My brother was innocent.
It was almost a boy and killed him.
Since he died,
I can not taste the tea.
I can not taste food.
I can not prove anything.
Imagine coming out of here and
someone kills him on the road.
In what state would be
his children and his wife?
How would he feel his father?
Not surprisingly, the
end of all this ...
Dilawar, the victim,
been forgotten.
Dilawar was almost invisible
during trials.
Never saw pictures yours,
no one ever mentioned the ...
women and children who stayed
without husband and father.
You will not be took
account at all.
Dilawar was unable to work
in the field ...
so I said:
"Drive taxi ...
and bring meat and potatoes
the family at night. "
There are many people out there that ...
fall into the same system
if not resolved.
And you only need one case for
remind you of what is capable.
American values
are based on the concepts ...
of human dignity and
the sacredness of the individual.
Allowing the use of the
cruelty of an officially ...
tantamount to saying that
parents of our homeland ...
were wrong on
those inalienable rights.
Obviously Americans
we believe that ...
somehow it is our moral
higher than the rest of the world ...
and for whatever reason,
We have a strong desire to believe.
And the truth is I do not know
what the consequences will bring us ...
and I think that many people
decided that after ...
9 / 11 and everything is different
we can no longer be good ...
we have to be tough.
- And let's see what results from that.
- What do you think?
I think that is nonsense.
I think we should keep trying
be the best you can.
DEDICATED TO MY FATHER
FRANK B. Gibney. 1924 to 2005.
I find it totally inconceivable
that the highest authorities ...
Rumsfeld, Bush and Cheney,
not only tolerate torture ...
but also
advocate it.
The truth is that it destroyed my
faith in the U.S. government.
Because during the Second
World War and the Korean ...
in which I served well,
I had the feeling ...
be on the side
of the good guys.
That justice was always
in the United States of America.
That people receiving treatment
decent and law prevailed.
Never forget that behind the facade
hate the war ...
had a rule of law
that people follow.
It was something we thought.
It was what made the
United States differently.