The live broadcast starts now.
Come in everyone.
- It's the nation's favourite food. - Yes, it is.
(Yoon Min Soo is teaching people to sing better.)
That's it.
- We are working together today. - Let's draw each other's portrait.
- Do you mean a portrait? - Yes.
(Yu Bin is getting a makeover from Jung Saem Mool.)
(The show starts now!)
(My Little Television)
(The day of MLT-20 live broadcast)
- Oh, my. - Hello.
- Hello. - You know each other, right?
- Yes, we've met. - Yes, we have met.
Well, you are not the type of person to say hello first.
Last week, I came last.
Why? It was because of Jo Young Gu, right?
Was it because I was away? I was in the United States.
- Yes, I know. - You shouldn't have invited him on.
- Anyway, for today's show... - Where's Seo Yu Ri?
- Did she go Suyuri? - Suyuri? You're funny.
- Hello. - My goodness.
Why are you so late?
It looks like she just came back from Suyuri.
(She quickly conceals her emotions.)
- Why do you keep doing that? - You came early.
- Were you sleeping somewhere? - I'm sorry I'm late.
Enough about me, let's talk about you Kim Gu Ra,
last week you tried to show...
the viewer something a little more highbrow...
- and it backfired. - Yes, I did.
Well, it was a difficult topic and...
Young Gu made it worse.
It was a nightmare, but today I'm going to do something more...
mainstream and accessable.
Jung Saem Mool, this is your third appearance...
we are curious to know the identity of today's guest.
I do have a new guest coming on today.
Can't you tell us?
I can't tell you, I'm sorry.
It must be a very special guest.
Of course, it must be a very special person.
Does that mean Kim Hye Soo won't be coming on today?
She won't be coming on.
I really want to see Kim Hye Soo.
What do you want us to do about it?
Okay, I'm almost done.
- Do you know what it means? - We're ready.
Let's go in.
(Who is the woman coming in with him?)
- Welcome. - Hello, Lee Mal Nyeon.
- Hello. - It's Yura.
He's Lee Mal Nyeon.
(Webtoon artist Lee Mal Nyeon and Girl's Day, Yura)
I am a webtoon artist, Lee Mal Nyeon.
I am Girl's Day member, Yura.
(Girl's Day debut six years ago in 2010.)
(They are a group that are both cute and sexy.)
(Yura gives energy to the group.)
(They will work together today.)
I think we should be looking at each other as we talk.
This feels like a formal interview.
Should I turn my chair a bit like this?
No, this is perfect.
Oh, really? Okay.
I just feel a little awkward.
I think we will be closer near the end of the show...
and when we feel comfortable that's when the show will end.
No, it's not going to end like that.
I am a professional singer...
but I like to draw in my spare time.
I thought it would be nice to show the viewers my hobby,
and that's why, I decided to be on today's show.
Please stay tuned to our channel.
Let's go!
Let's go.
- Let's go. - Wow.
I've never done this gesture before.
(I've never done this gesture before.)
- Have you met her before? - Hello.
- Do you know who she is? - No, I don't.
I've seen you a few times before.
You told me last time you would take in me as your stepdaughter.
Did you really say that? Oh, goodness.
- I remember. - She is a member of Girl's Day.
That's right! She is a member of Girl's Day.
- Yes, she is. - My name is Yura.
- I know. - Welcome, Yura.
(A beautiful voice is coming from this waiting room.)
Hello.
It feels like I'm on my way to sing on "I Am a Singer".
(Yoon Min Soo, a singer with a soulful voice.)
Hello, I'm Yoon Min Soo from Vibe. Nice to meet you.
Most people still know me as Yoon Hu's father.
Older people still recognise me and greet me when they see me.
Yes, I'm mostly known as Yoon Hu's dad.
Many people believe singing in the original key means you sing well.
But everyone has their own unique voice.
So I thought if I explained more about this,
the viewers would appreciate it.
Please stay tuned to my channel.
- There he is. - Hello.
- Welcome, Yoon Hu's dad. - Hello.
- Whose dad? - Is there anything that you know?
He's a singer.
- Yes, I'm a singer. - Are you really?
I'm the president of the Singers Association.
Haven't you heard of Vibe?
Haven't you heard of the song, "Drinking"?
- That was him? - Yes.
Former members of "Dad! Where Are We Going?", Ahn Jung Hwan and...
Kim Seong Ju, did a great job on our show last week.
Do you feel more pressure because of them?
- I have my own area of expertise. - That's right.
You seem very calm, Yoon Min Soo.
I'm very nervous right now.
Drink some soy sauce. It will help.
Did you say soy sauce?
He's the president of the Singers Association.
- Just imagine you're performing. - Yes, just enjoy it.
- Do you have anything more to say? - Yes, I do.
Goodness me, this is hard.
(Goodness me.)
We make a great team.
(Someone's knocking on the door.)
(A new guest shyly enters the room.)
- Welcome. - Hello.
(A rising star of Chungmuro, Han Ye Ri)
Hello, my name is Han Ye Ri and I'm an actress.
I starred in the films, "As One" and "Haemoo".
My name is Hong Mae.
Hong Mae.
I also starred in the film "A Dramatic Night" last year.
Currently I'm acting in a popular drama, "Six Flying Dragons".
When I was a student of the Korea National University of Arts,
they were looking for dancers for a film.
So I volunteered for the part. That is how I first started acting.
Now, here I am.
I want to show people that Korean dance can be...
fun. I want to help people understand more about...
Korean traditional dance and become proud of our heritage.
I also want to show people...
how passionate I am about Korean traditional dance.
You seem very calm. What's your real personality like?
I think I'm a very calm person.
What should I do? People might leave because I'm boring.
Please keep watching.
You're all dressed up in hanbok.
Is this related to what you're going to do today?
Yes, I'm here to teach the viewers about Korean dance.
- Do you remember Oh Jung Hae? - Yes, I do.
She starred in "Seopyeonje".
She reminds me of Oh Jung Hae. They are both good actresses, too.
Thank you.
"Seopyeonje" is different.
Yes, that film was about Korean traditional singing, not dancing.
- Well, they both wear hanbok. - I see.
Thank you.
(Live broadcast starts in 25 minutes.)
(This is Han Ye Ri's room,)
(Han Ye Ri is warming up.)
(She can do Taekwondo too.)
(She leaves her room out of boredom and...)
(heads towards the Min Soo's room.)
This room feels like a recording studio.
(Next she visits Lee Mal Nyeon's room.)
(She visits their room.)
I wish I had a partner too!
Why don't you visit Kim Gu Ra's room?
(I don't want to!)
He might scold me if I do.
What kind of ramyun do you want?
(Kim Gu Ra is in charge of today's cooking channel.)
I'm very good at cooking ramyun.
Did you live in a boarding house?
If you want to enjoy the perfect ramyun,
you just need to follow the recipe.
The live broadcast hasn't even started. What's the rush?
By them time the live broadcast starts,
they can zoom in the ramyun while we're eating it.
Are you going to make a movie someday too?
Countdown for the beginning of live broadcast.
Take this.
In five,
- four, - Oh, goodness.
- three, - Hide your face.
and 2, 1.
MLT-20,
the live broadcast starts now.
(MLT-20, starting its transmission around the world)
(Yura and Lee Mal Nyeon's "Yoo and Nyeon")
Hello.
Hi, everyone.
We are working together today.
It's an interesting combination, right?
I did mention once that it would be better...
- if Duk Dak E was my assistant. - Okay.
I'm exhausted. I wish I had an assistant, so he can help me out.
- What I wanted was Duk Dak E. - Yes.
But they invited you instead.
- It feels like I'm your assistant. - Yes.
A viewer just wrote "Hello, Mal Dak E."
The name of our room, "You and Nyeon" is not a swear word.
- It's a combination of our names. - That's right.
- So in the Year of the Red Monkey, - Yes?
please watch "Yoo and Nyeon"!
"Yoo and Nyeon"!
(- Say something, Mal Nyeon. - Stay calm, Mal Nyeon.)
- Is that our catchphrase? - Yes, it is.
If you want to attract a large audience.
You need to do things like this. Let's do this together.
- Do you want me to say it? - Yes.
- Watch "Yoo and Nyeon". - "Yoo and Nyeon".
Every day is...
(Lee Mal Nyeon is now a member of an idol group now.)
Many people tell me that I have a strange laugh.
- Yes. - I think yours is strange too.
(They have something in common.)
Can I see one of your drawings before we start?
Of course, I brought my drawings with me today.
Someone said, "I think she can draw better than him.",
"Lee Mal Nyeon lost." and so on.
I'm a professional, everyone. Please, show me your drawing.
- Here it is! - Wow!
This is a pencil drawing.
Someone said, "Lee Mal Nyeon lost",
Another person wrote "Learn from her, Lee Mal Nyeon."
- This is an oil painting. - Wow.
Please don't write, "Yura is better than me."
We don't know yet. I can draw like this too. I could.
This is my latest painting.
Someone wrote, "She beats you for the third time."
I haven't shown my drawing to you yet. I can do this too.
- No one's on my side. - They're not on your side.
So for our first activity, I thought we could draw each other.
- We will draw our portraits? - Yes.
- I will draw you first. - Okay.
What is unique about Yura?
Yura the Explorer wrote, "Her nostrils". What about them?
- What about my nostrils? - For Yura says "Her cheekbones."
- What do you mean? - Her forehead?
Her cheekbones? Oh, I see.
I don't have a strange face, right?
Right, you don't.
(- Let's be honest. - Your nose will grow longer.)
Her face is fine.
Other than the cheekbones, what about her eyes?
I will start from drawing her eyes very big.
Don't mention my dark circles.
I do see something dark under your eyes.
It's true that my face gets chubbier when I smile.
It doesn't matter how much weight I lose.
Why are you adding dark circles?
- I see something under your eyes. - No, you don't.
- Okay, let's say it's your makeup. - Okay.
Someone said, "Let's write a petition."
Let's stop teasing her.
Are you saying that because he's drawing me terribly?
They are asking, "Who are you drawing?"
- Are they asking who I'm drawing? - Yes.
What are you doing to my lips?
My lips are not dry.
Why are you drawing my lips like that?
I put lip balm on too.
I will make it look moist later.
Hold on. Is that my cheekbone?
People say it looks like Park Na Rae.
That's not true.
This is Yura.
- Could you add my double eyelids? - Double eyelids? Okay.
Of course, I can do that.
(Here you go.)
You're really mean.
(- It's plastic surgery gone wrong. - It looks like Yura.)
That does not look like me.
It's not like a reflection. Do I really look like that?
(They look the same.)
I won't talk to you anymore.
I'm not that puffy today.
I will add eyelashes too.
(She's blushing.)
- My face feels hot. - It's almost done.
I lost my temper after I saw the drawing.
If you say something like that,
it will only inspire them to attack you more. Look at that.
Please don't say that you lost your temper.
What are you doing?
I'm done.
(Don't forget his signature mark.)
This means I didn't have enough time to draw.
He wrote my name in English.
Look at those emoticons.
They are just reacting to the drawing.
Can you give me a chance to fix this drawing?
- Okay. - Really?
Hold on, everyone.
- Where's the eraser? - Press "E" to erase.
- Is it this one? - Yes.
(She seems uncomfortable since it's her first time using a tablet.)
Is it working? Yes, press "E".
Press "B" is for the brush.
(I will make my face more oval.)
Is this what you wanted? It's worse!
It's funny though.
- That's really funny. - Please undo this for me.
No, that's it.
Now it's your turn to draw me.
(-Yura's face has been damaged. - It looks like a slice of pizza.)
You're really mean.
Why are you teasing me?
Hello, this is "Kim Gu Ra's True Story".
- Today, - Yes.
we're going to make ramyun. It's everyone's favourite.
We have invited a professional on our show today.
He's a ramyun mania.
- Please come in. - Welcome.
- Welcome, sir. - Hello.
Please welcome Cao Lu.
- Your ramyun delivery is here. - Wow!
Nice to meet you. Please introduce yourselves.
I'm Choi Yong Min a marketing manager at "P" Ramyun.
Oh, does the name of your company start with "P"?
- Yes. - I was right.
- How big is your market share? - Eight percent.
It's more than 10 percent.
- What's your rank? - There are four major companies.
- We are... - Fourth?
- I see. - Yes.
- Your company has caught up a lot. - Yes, they have.
- I like your Bibim noodles. - Right, it's delicious.
It's Cao Lu. You know Cao Lu, right?
I'm Cao Lu from a girl group that start with "P".
(Really?)
- Oh, I know that group. - What group?
- What's her team? - We're both from group P!
- That's right. - Yes. Group P.
Oh, his company and her group have the same sound. I get it.
Cao Lu has brought some ramyun from China.
- Look at the variety. - Yes.
China uses noodle a lot in their cuisine.
I assumed ramyun would not be popular in China.
Am I right?
No, China consumes the most noodles in the world.
- Really? - China has a big population.
- Yes, of course. - So there's a big market.
China alone accounts for half the world's ramyun sales.
- Really? - Yes.
Roughly that's about 44 billion.
- Annually? - Wow.
- Korea eats 3.5 billion each year. - That's right.
- 3.5 billion? - They consume 10 times more ramyun.
- I see. So Cao Lu, - Yes.
is there a ramyun, that you'd like to recommend?
- Kimchi ramyun. - This is Korean.
- I want to eat that one. - Yes, kimchi ramyun.
- Can I have that one? - Later.
- This is also good. - This one?
- Can you cook this for us? - Sure.
- What is it? - It's gopchang ramyun.
The noodles are made out of sweet potato, not flour.
- I want to eat this. - I'll cook them both.
No don't do that, we can eat kimchi ramyun anytime.
- Please don't be upset. - Please don't.
- I don't want to eat the other one. - What else is there?
There's also abalone flavoured ramyun.
He's the head of the Korean Singers Association.
- He is? - Is she a singer?
Yes, she is.
I pity you
Did you just say that to me?
(- She said she pities him. - He doesn't know what to say.)
Did you really just say that to me?
That's the lyrics to our song.
- Why don't you cook that for us? - Sure.
Some of you are asking about Jung Min.
- Take a look at these. - It says, "Cha Jang Geum".
(- She's super cute. - She came prepared.)
She came prepared today.
She's a deputy department head. I didn't know that.
(- That was funny. - Even his jokes are old.)
- Right. - So ramyun is a popular dish...
- all over the world. - That's right.
Which country consumes the most?
- That would be China. - I see.
- Whose in second place? - Indonesia.
- Indonesia. - It's because of their population.
- Of course. The population is... - 14 billion.
- It's a population of 100 million. - It's over a billion.
- No, they don't. - Are we talking about India?
- India has over a billion people. - Right.
- Aren't you the expert here? - You're the host. Help him out.
Indonesia has less than a billion people.
- Vietnam and the United States. - Help him out.
- The United States? - They eat a lot of ramyun as well.
So how many bowls of ramyun do we consume every year?
- About 72 per person each year. - We're the highest in the world.
That's right.
Why do Koreans like ramyun so much?
- Because of how it tastes. - The flavour?
- Because it's a dish. - Yes.
So we don't enjoy dishes that aren't tasty.
Also, it's cheap.
- I see. - It's affordable.
- I see. - That's why people love it.
Can't you sound more like an expert?
Everything you've been saying...
is something we could have also said.
- This is quite the collection. - It's from Southeast Asia.
This is a stir-fry ramyun from India.
Isn't this too small? Is this it?
- It's the highest selling ramyun. - What's it called?
- Mie goreng. - I've heard of it before.
(- Is Cao Lu doing another show? - Does she have anyone to talk to?)
Mi goreng ramyun.
(- Who are they talking to? - Cao Lu looks like a maid.)
- It's not bad. - I agree.
- Do kids like it? - They do.
I see.
- Is it popular in the States? - Yes, it is.
(- She's scared of fire! - Look how adorable she is.)
I've never done this at home before.
These noodles are made from sweet potatoes,
so you should turn down the heat once the water comes to a boil.
If you heat it for too long,
the noodles will melt and get mushy.
(The gopchang ramyun is ready.)
- Here it is. - Is it already done?
- Yes, doesn't it smell nice? - Yes.
- It's glass noodles. - This is gopchang ramyun.
- It's one of my favourites. - It is?
- Oh, my. - What's wrong?
- Don't you like it? - I don't like the smell.
Right. Aren't you acting like a baby though?
Well, I am a baby.
(He only likes what kids like.)
They're saying, "I'm a baby, so I should wail."
- The smell is unique, I like it. - In China...
Can you order me a bowl of jajangmyun?
(Chinese ramyun are more pungent than Korean ramyun.)
The viewers are saying...
that you're Heungseon Daewongun when it comes to ramyun.
(He's satisfied.)
We must keep the pride of our ramyun.
Of course.
- He has a closed-door policy. - That sounds perfect.
(Heung Kook only wants to eat Korean ramyun.)
This Thai ramyun only needs hot water to be poured over it.
- Heung Kook, you're up. - No, I'm okay.
- Try it. - No, you go ahead.
- Just try it. - I can't stand the smell.
But still, you should try.
What's this smell? Is it from coriander?
You're smelling lime which is what is the smell in tom yum soup.
- Lime? - That's right.
I like tom yum soup and I like the smell.
- What's wrong? - It's just weird.
I've never tasted anything like this before.
- Let me try some. - I like tom yum soup.
- It doesn't smell so bad. - It's very good.
If we were living in the late Joseon Dynasty,
Heung Kook would be Heungseon Daewongun...
and I would be a modernist.
I would be part of the revolution like Kim Ok Gyun.
In terms of ramyun...
How could you sneeze on my face?
- I mean... - What is this?
You're the same.
(- It's a ramyun revolution. - Look at his nose.)
I'm sorry but I can't help it because of the smell.
I thought you said that you didn't mind the smell.
(I can't take it anymore.)
(Can I get a tissue?)
Give me that. Come on.
- Isn't it good? - It's good.
(Gu Ra is sweating.)
(- He's vomiting through his nose. - He's cleaning his nose.)
- What's wrong with you? - Give me some tissue.
("Saem Mool's Colourful Life")
Hello.
Thank you for coming once again back to...
"Saem Mool's Colourful Life".
Thank you for saying that I'm pretty.
(- You're pretty. - You are really pretty.)
I've been getting a lot of questions...
and most of them are about how to deal with a darker complexion.
So we'll be tackling that today.
I can't talk about...
darker complexions without mentioning retro.
It's this year's trend so I thought it would be nice...
to show you how to achieve a retro look.
Do you want to know who our guest is?
When you think of darker complexions, who comes to mind?
I see. So let's see if you're right.
Shall we ask her to come in? You can come in now.
(It's a member of Wonder Girls.)
- Ta-da! - Hello.
(She has a healthy and tanned skin.)
(She's the sexy idol rapper, Yu Bin.)
- All right! - Hi, I'm Yu Bin.
- The viewers are happy. - This is so fascinating!
Look! They love you.
They're excited to see you.
- I normally don't get nervous, - Okay.
but I did when I heard that you were my model today.
- I'm very nervous as well. - Really?
(I'm nervous too. What should I do?)
Did you see Gimi Writer's transformation last week?
- I made her look like you. - I saw it!
- I was so surprised. - You were?
Strike a pose like Yu Bin.
(She borrowed Yu Bin's clothes.)
You look so pretty. Okay, let's move on.
- Retro is so hot right now. - That's right.
My group is known for always bringing back the retro look...
and we were lucky that retro sexy is the hot trend.
Okay, so let's go ahead and show the viewers...
the secret to doing the retro look.
They're saying that you should brighten up my skin tone.
You're wrong. I don't have a drab skin tone.
- How could you say that? - You don't look drab.
First, I'm going to clear her face of any excess oil.
Yu Bin needs to use shades darker than number 25.
She has a darker skin.
You can get tanned easily right?
Yes. I can even get tanned in the winter...
- or sometimes by the stage lights. - That's right.
- I get tanned easily. - I know.
In the past, I couldn't find the right tone for me.
So I had to buy my makeup products abroad.
She doesn't need to use number 30.
Some people are asking if you use shades over number 30.
- No, I don't. - That's absurd.
Number 301? Isn't that an apartment number?
(- Apartment 105 number 25. - Lee Dae Ho.)
Now it's time to apply the foundation.
But before I do that, I'm going to apply...
a thin layer of this gold shimmer.
We're going to apply it on her cheekbones.
The shimmer will act as a bonding agent...
when you're applying the foundation.
So now we move onto the foundation.
I'll show you the darker shades that I have.
Watch carefully. I'm going to take a small amount...
of this darker shade of concealer.
Mix it with...
the foundation like so.
You're worried that she'll look like a cave woman?
Then stay tuned and watch.
- My skin is naturally dark. - Right.
As you can see, she looks very natural.
I've levelled out her skin tone.
You think her skin looks yellow?
That's not it. This is just her original skin tone.
- This is normal. - My skin looks different...
- under different lighting. - She's right.
(- She's blaming it on the lights. - The producer is the real victim.)
So let's move on.
Those with lighter complexions...
look amazing when this pink shimmer is applied.
But people with yellow or darker complexion,
gold is the way to go.
This is a gold coloured loose powder.
And it'll make her look fabulous.
I've applied some today on my cheekbones.
- Even a thin layer of it... - Okay.
can make you look younger.
Your skin will also look really firm as well.
I'm going to apply some on her cheekbones.
- Remember what I said earlier? - Someone said "Gold poop".
I like poop. I'm also fond of Producer Dung.
My daughter is four years old and...
we sing "The Dung Song".
I sing it to her when she's on the potty.
Okay, we're done.
- I look better. - You look way better.
- But we're just getting started. - Great.
- What we're going to do next is... - "Dung makeup."
- Can't you say "Gold" instead? - I'd like that too.
It begins now.
("Han Ye Ri's Flying Ye Ri")
Wow! This is more than I expected.
You're all excited and so am I.
Before we talk, I'm going to...
first show you a short dance. After that let's talk.
(Happy New Year!)
(- I'm not giving you pocket money. - When are you getting married?)
Here I go.
(Elegant)
(She elegantly starts to dance.)
(- She's cleaning the floor. - That looks like toilet paper.)
(This the dance she performed on "Six Flying Dragons".)
(She choreographed it herself.)
(- She is so pretty. - It's strangely captivating.)
(Throws)
(- It's a carpet of toilet paper. - She is making a new road.)
(The song reaches climax.)
(Stepping lightly)
(- It's a toilet paper carpet ride. - Miss, walk on this line.)
(Ye Ri dances.)
My goodness.
Did I do well?
"It looks like an exorcism." What?
"Step lightly as you leave." What a poetic expression.
I showed you my dance as an opening of my programme.
Not many people know...
who I am.
So I will show you a popular movie I was in.
Ye Ri knows how to play table tennis.
Look at us in blue uniforms.
(She received a Newcomer Award at Paeksang Arts Awards.)
(Her role was a North Korean table tennis player, Yu Sun Bok.)
If you can't take us on,
how will you win a gold medal?
I miss Doo Na so much.
Ta-da. It's the next movie.
(It's a movie with a production cost of 10 billion dollars.)
I'm here to eat ramyun.
(She played a Korean Chinese woman, Hong Mae in "Sea Fog".)
Would you like some?
I ate a lot of cup ramyun during that time.
What are you trying to do to me?
What are you saying?
Don't go anywhere and stay here, okay?
I'm good with Korean Chinese accent, right?
"Han Ye Ri defects to North Korea."
My goodness, I can't believe it.
You don't know much about my life before the movies.
So I brought some pictures from the days...
I used to dance.
Ta-da. Can you see "1996" printed on the picture?
I took this picture in middle school to apply to high school.
I was such a baby then, right?
And this was taken during my dark days.
It's obvious, right? My cheeks are about to burst.
Ta-da. This was taken on the day of my presentation.
I look old, right?
"I'm the mother of Chosun."
I thought I would become an Intangible Cultural Property.
I once dreamed of taking my last breath on the stage,
but this is how I turned out.
My ideal type? Guess who my ideal type is.
There is an actor I like very much.
Tony Leung! Someone guessed it.
He is the actor I admire the most.
I would gladly marry him even if he turns 80 years old.
He is so cool. I love his movies.
I loved his acting in "In the Mood for Love".
I'm about to get a nosebleed.
I'm sure everyone has an actor they like very much.
I like him so much.
Someone asked what my preferred way of eating sweet and sour meat is.
I always dip the meat in the sauce.
I can't pour sauce over it. How can people prefer that?
Flying Chuk Sa Gwang asked,
"What would you do if Tony Leung prepares pouring sauce over meat?"
Then I will pour sauce over meat.
I'm very simple.
If that's what he likes, I will follow him.
"A traitor."
(- A traitor. - She changes her mind easily.)
I'm sorry.
I can't help it. Love is the best.
Mangtaegi wrote that "I look very young."
How do I maintain my looks? It's important to do what you like.
1907 asked me...
Mi Ju Love wrote...
Yoon Chul Won wrote...
Ayla Song wrote, "My ideal type is Tony Leung."
Byeolgyo Cockle likes "Dancing Princess".
"Billy Elliot"? Fish Seller, I like that movie, too.
It's nice to converse with you all.
Hello, hello.
I can't really eat spicy food. Singha. My goodness.
"What do you do when you have free time?" I really like to sleep.
I love conversing with people.
So it's great to chat...
and converse with you.
(- When will you dance again? - Ye Ri can do anything.)
The live broadcast has started.
Let's go.
- Let's give the viewers a heart. - Hello.
(Ben, Singer)
Hello.
(They start off with a performance.)
Let's go.
("Promise U" by Vibe)
Look at the camera.
(Every singer who comes to the show begins with a song.)
(Lilting)
(A girl who could be Min Soo's nephew in age sings a classic song.)
(Strange ad lib)
(Tough)
(He's getting ready for his part.)
(It's Min Soo's part.)
(Min Soo can rap well.)
(You are a good singer.)
(He debuted in 1998.)
(Yoon Min Soo is a musician everyone admires.)
- Hello. - Let's stop right here.
Hello.
I'm Yoon Hu's father.
Someone wrote that I'm a mix between Oh Se Deuk and The One.
People tell me that all the time.
I am here today...
because everyone has a different vocal range.
I will help you find what vocal range works for you...
and give you tips on how to sing...
your favourite songs at the karaoke better.
This is the title of my programme.
Shi... Gosh, that came out wrong.
(- Did he just swear? - He started off with a swear word.)
I get tongue-tied in front of the camera.
It is called "Yoon Min Soo's 25-hour Karaoke".
My mother used to own a karaoke called "25-hour Karaoke".
Thus the title.
"Shibasaki joins the game again."
(Laughing)
I wasn't swearing.
I invited some talented people to help me today.
- Hello. - Hello.
I'm a classical singer and a vocal trainer, Yoo Seul Ki.
It's nice to meet you.
(- I'll have the cutlet. - Waiter.)
People have different vocal ranges.
You can use a piano or a piano app...
to find your vocal range.
Do is the first note of the solfege scale.
Do. Start from there.
Do, ti, la, sol, fa. Let's say you can hit Fa...
with ease. Then you are a baritone.
- I'm a baritone. - Min Soo is a baritone.
(A baritone has a wide vocal range and is most common male voice.)
Do. Let's check if you are a bass.
Do, ti, la, sol.
If you can hit Do that is one octave lower, you are a bass.
(A bass has the lowest vocal range and sounds solemn and deep.)
Do. And if you can hit do two octaves higher,
then you are a tenor.
(A tenor has the highest vocal range of the male voice types.)
How about we invite the staff members...
- and help them... - That's a good idea.
find their vocal range?
- Hello. - Hello.
- They look familiar. - My goodness.
They have the body of a classical singer.
- It's nice to meet you. - They look like classical singers.
(Crowded)
All right. They look more like classical singers than me.
- To see if you are a tenor... - "It looks like a ssireum team."
Classical singers look like ssireum athletes.
Let's start. In 1, 2, 3, 4.
(They try each note to find their vocal range.)
(Singing)
Give up if you can't hit the note.
(Gloomy)
- In 1, 2, 3, 4. - Someone wrote, "This is hell."
We will lose viewers.
(Dark)
Someone wrote that it looks like a choir in jail.
(The criminals are being reformed.)
- We are testing the vocal range. - That's what we are doing.
- Let's have them take turns. - All right.
- Let's go. - In 1, 2, 3, 4.
(Singing)
All right.
- His voice got quieter. - That's right.
People who are short and stout...
tend to be a tenor.
All right. Okay.
Keep going.
Okay.
His voice became thicker towards the end.
- He is a low baritone. - That's right.
I'm sure you now have a sense of how to test your vocal range.
- Let's take a few staff members... - Okay.
- and teach them how to sing. - All right.
He will give them tips on singing.
All right.
("Like Salmons That Travel Upstream" He is a baritone.)
(He follows the beat.)
(He looks unusual.)
(Salmons...)
(that travel upstream)
(He is charismatic from the start.)
(He looks like he would eat the salmons.)
(His singing will invoke deep sorrow in salmons.)
(Among many paths)
(I'm sorry.)
He abruptly stopped the song.
- Yes! - He was good.
He sang well.
You felt it, right?
The song seemed stuffy...
- and was a bit hard to listen to. - Right.
The song was a bit out of his vocal range.
If you lower the key of the song...
by one key or half,
you will be able to sing more comfortably.
Someone wrote, "Men should sing in the original key."
"It's a matter of pride." I think he just began watching.
Every person has a specific vocal range.
Singing the song that suits your vocal range...
makes you a good singer.
That's right. If you sing a song of your vocal range,
your song will sound better. It's the right way.
Let me give you another tip.
People often change the keys at the karaoke,
but not many people change the tempo.
I will try changing the tempo.
(How will the song sound now?)
Wow.
There. I slowed the tempo...
by two measures.
(He slowed the tempo.)
(Salmons...)
(that travel upstream)
(Slow)
(- I'm getting sleepy. - Good night, my baby.)
People think it sounds too gloomy.
(Reasons)
Yes.
(If salmons travelled upstream this slowly,)
(they would get eaten.)
- You all felt it too, right? - There is a difference.
- You felt it, right? - Yes, it sounds smoother.
"Did he sing in slow motion?"
No, he wasn't singing in slow motion.
But, if you slow down the tempo a little,
it becomes a lot easier to express emotions with your voice.
Why would we need to express emotion during a company dinner?
Well, there might be a colleague you like.
"That would ruin the evening."
"I am craving salmon sashimi."
(This is not going to be an easy show.)
- Let me try drawing this time. - Okay.
I will get my revenge. This is my chance.
But I thought my drawing was really good though.
Is this the type of drawing you like?
Of course.
(She's my style.)
I had a quick look at your cartoons, I heard you are starting to go bald.
My hair? Yes, that's right.
So, I drew your hair very lightly.
Yes, it's okay. That's fine.
- I'm being generous with your hair. - Okay.
What's unusual about him?
My double eyelids look fake.
Fake double eyelids.
My nickname during high school was...
Yi Hwang.
Another one was Lee Bong Ju, the marathon runner.
Can you look at me, so that I can see your face clearly?
He has triangular-shaped eyebrows.
(- It looks like him. - He has the face of a traitor.)
Can you smile a little?
(Twitch)
(Look at that cunning smile.) (They both have a unique laugh.)
Why are you laughing?
Does he look like a eunuch?
One moment please.
(Your Majesty)
I look frivolous?
I think I captured you perfectly,
Focus on the chin line, the chin line.
I just drew the chin.
It looks like this. I have a double chin.
Let's add dark circles.
(He looks very tired.)
What do you think?
How does it look?
It looks exactly like me.
They say they may have a nightmare from looking at the drawing.
They say it looks very gloomy and scary.
Now that we are done drawing portraits...
Let's draw the image that pops up...
when you think of the other person's occupation.
- When I think of female idols, - Okay.
they look very fancy on the outside, but inside...
they are struggling. That's how I see idols.
When I think of idols, I think of swans.
(- It has sinister eyes. - Isn't that an ostrich?)
A swan. Here we go.
(Yura the Swan.)
Since this Is my first time on My Little Television,
everything is fascinating.
It really is.
Why are you only focusing on her?
That's unfair.
"Lee Mal Nyeon is a slave to his art."
(Is that the swan's leg?)
The legs are...
Hold on a minute!
What's the point in drawing.
All of you only care about Yura, so I don't know why...
- I am drawing. - Hold on.
Weren't you drawing me?
No, I'm drawing the image I have about girl groups.
- They look very fancy, but... - I understand now.
their legs are...
Is this the kind of artworks the viewers like?
The viewers of this programme aren't mainstream.
I should have drawn something else.
He looks a bit like a raccoon.
Me? I have never heard such thing in my life.
He looks like the Raccoon in the cartoon, "Bonobono".
- I know who you're talking about. - Right?
- Why do you think I look like him? - I'm a raccoon.
- You sound exactly like Bonobono. - Really?
Like this?
(- Mal Nyeon is having fun. - She makes my heart flutter.)
- You know what it is, right? - Yes.
- Do you have anything else? - Like this.
- Show us something else. - Show me something, first.
I don't have a special talent.
Can you imitate anyone?
Hello, I'm Gum Nan Se.
Don't you know what this is? He runs a radio programme.
No one seems impressed.
Someone wrote, "I thought you were imitating Yang Hyun Suk."
I did a great Gum Nan Se impersonation.
Yang Hyun Suk!
- So this is the image. - The legs are very muscular.
The drawing shows how hard female idol group members work.
This is the message I am trying to convey.
Girl group members look glamorous on the outside,
but their legs are continuously working underneath the surface.
(One day they will soar into the sky like a swan.)
They work very hard beneath the surface.
I feel like it would be a constant struggle.
That's how a swan swims.
Someone wrote, "Look at those muscular legs."
"What kind female idols have legs like that?"
"Whose legs are those?"
That's not the point.
They are saying that those legs are Kim Jong Kook's.
(They are Kim Jong Kook's legs.)
(- Jong Kook has impressive thighs. - It's Lake Turbo.)
I drew a picture that captures how hard girl group members work.
We have an expert with us...
who will tell us about the history of ramyun.
Let's start with the origin of ramyun.
Chinese people have a specific way of making noodles.
- Okay. - Like how we make jajangmyun,
- the noodles are stretched thin. - Okay.
It's one way of making noodle dishes.
I see.
In Chinese, cooking noodles in this particular style is "Ra mien".
- It's "Ra mien" in Chinese? - Ra mien.
These are the characters for Ra mien.
- Go on. - This became popular in Japan.
- How did that happen? - The First Sino-Japanese War.
The First Sino-Japanese War.
After the war, Chinese people lived in Japan...
and made noodles.
And the Japanese...
pronounced it as "Ramen".
It was a Japanese man who first invented...
instant noodles.
- Yes. His name is Momofuku Ando. - What was that?
- What was that? - A packet of ramyun fell down.
- Okay. - The ramyun is angry.
- Is it angry? - It's an ominous sign.
- My goodness. - It's an ominous sign.
The funny thing is, the one that dropped on the floor is...
a ramyun from your company.
- It's an ominous sign. - My goodness.
It was a ramyun from company P.
Someone wrote, "It's the curse of company P."
(- Are they doomed? - The curse of company P.)
Someone wrote, "It's time to sell your shares in P."
Someone wrote, "It's time to sell your shares of Paldo stock."
The company isn't listed on KOSDAQ.
Really?
(- He looks so happy. - He is happy it isn't listed.)
So Chinese noodles and the Japanese instant noodles...
use a different cooking method.
This is how the Japanese instant noodles came to be.
Momofuku Ando, the father of instant noodles got...
- Momofuku Ando. - his idea from fish being fried.
- When you fry something, - Okay.
the oil bubbles as the water evaporates.
- That's how frying works. - The hot oil cooks the ingredient.
So that's where he got the inspiration for the cooking process.
That's how he cooked ramyun noodles.
That's how...
the Japanese instant noodles came into existence.
- "This is boring." - People don't think it's fun.
They are saying that we will come last.
How do you say "No fun" in Chinese?
- Mei yo yi si. - Mei yo yi si.
- Dui bu qi. - What does that mean?
I'm sorry.
(I'm sorry.)
What can we do to make the programme fun?
How about, the expert will teach us how to cook ramyun...
- so they taste the best. - Shall I?
- Give us a few tips. - That's right.
You need to establish yourself as an expert.
It's very easy to cook tasty ramyun.
- The thing with ramyun is, - Okay.
it loses its original taste if you add too many ingredients.
You just need green onion, garlic, egg and chili pepper powder.
These four ingredients will make any ramyun taste good.
- Is that so? - Please cook it for us.
- Let's try it. - Try this on.
I heard that you need to follow the instruction to the letter.
This is...
You look fine. Don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it. It suits you nicely.
- You can do it. - I'm so glad Cao Lu is here.
Show us the skills of an expert.
I'll cook this for us.
When you cook ramyun,
is it better to break the noodles?
- There is a line in the middle. - Okay.
The noodles are about 60cm long.
- 60cm. - That's if you don't break it.
- It will be too long to eat easily. - That's right.
- So you should break it in half. - Do you break it down the middle?
- I see. - Wow.
- It will break cleanly. - We always break it like this.
I always broke the noodles horizontally.
- So that's the way you do it. - It's easier to eat that way.
- I have a question. - Okay.
Why are you making ramyun from your company?
We test our ramyun against other companies'.
And I can say with confidence that ours wins every time.
Is this so? Is this the star for your company?
- Is this your star product? - Yes, it is.
How well does it sell?
We sell about 1 million packets every month.
What about the always popular S ramyun?
They sell about 25 million packets a month.
You said that your ramyun wins every time. Why do they sell...
- more than your company? - This is...
- the rising star of the industry. - What?
- The rising star? - Yes, it is.
Scatter the egg into the soup.
- No, don't do that. - We can't do that.
Don't ruin his work.
- If we scatter the egg, - Okay.
the taste of the soup will change.
It'll just taste like ramyun with eggs.
You need to follow the instructions on the packet to the letter.
- To the letter. - Don't scatter the egg.
Heung Kook and I will taste the ramyun he has cooked.
(Heung Kook only eats Korean ramyun.)
(Does he like the taste?)
This is delicious.
It's perfect.
It tastes amazing.
- Is it good? - I'm so happy.
That's good.
When we run a blind test with our rival company's product,
we win 7 times out of 10.
Then why doesn't it sell better?
Our company isn't as popular.
But we'll slowly take over the market.
- It needs a better concept. - Really?
Change the model to a woman.
- A woman? - Do you want a ramyun commercial?
- A ramyun commercial. - Our current model is a man.
Replace him with a woman.
Replace him with a woman?
She came prepared.
- That's right. - Try some ramyun.
You need to give it a variety of sound effects.
(Blowing)
(Cry of surprise)
(Slurping)
(Sigh of content)
Cao Lu Ramyun is unrivalled in its taste! It's the best.
What did you think?
- Didn't you like it? - I like it.
(Heung Kook focuses on ramyun.)
Wipe your mouth.
Now, we will apply some colours.
Before you start applying makeup,
think about in what order you will apply the colours.
You'll come out looking so much better that way.
So...
- I will start with the lips. - The lips.
I will apply lipstick to her lips.
- Burgundy is a trendy colour. - That's right.
She knows what the latest trends are.
- Of course I do. - Celebrities know what's trending.
I mixed true red and burgundy for Yu Bin's lips.
I didn't know you could mix the lip colours.
Mixing the colours creates a more dramatic look.
(- Is there such thing as fake red? - It looks like she ate a lollipop.)
- I have applied the lipstick. - Wow.
"Is that makeup for a shaman?"
Don't be ridiculous.
You think it looks like a colour your mother would wear?
That is correct.
Retro look is the look that was popular in the 70s.
This colour is what the mothers of today would have worn.
Our viewers are very observant.
I will now apply eyeshadows.
What characterises the retro makeup...
is the lack of pearls.
Apply just a touch of natural eyeshadow.
Like this.
Apply shade to the sides of your nose.
Retro makeup is all about shading.
"The model looks like Yu Bin."
Thank you. I hear that all the time.
You are so witty.
- After that, - Yes?
apply eyeshadow starting from under your eyes...
and until you reach the edge.
By drawing it like this the line will look better.
- Now look at this. - Wow!
Look at me, everyone. This is amazing.
I've never seen the progress of wearing makeup on a screen before.
- That's why it's so interesting. - You're right.
"You're good." I've been doing this for 25 years.
- She is the famous Jung Saem Mool. - That's right.
Now, we will add gradation on the eyes.
Like this.
You will find that the gradation covers the eyeliner a little.
So draw the line again one more time.
Draw it like this. After this...
- Someone said, "That's too much." - Really?
It will look different once we work on her eyebrows.
- But we need to remember that... - That's right.
we want to make sure that make up stand out, that's how we create...
- the retro look. - That's right.
The eyebrows have to be shaped into a seagull shape...
- to complete the retro look. - That's right.
Follow the outline of your eyebrows.
This helps to give a more sophisticated look.
Retro makeup emphasises lines and textures.
So you have to go over the top...
with the mascara.
Just in case the mascara...
smudges under the eyes,
use a dry cotton swab and dab at the smudge.
Make sure the mascara is dry, otherwise it will be a disaster.
Wait until it's dry enough.
It's about time we need to finish the look.
- "Run away, Yu Bin." - Someone told me to run away.
- Why? Why would you say that? - They know what's coming.
I will work on it like this. That's right.
(She has claimed many victims.)
Wow, you look sexy.
- Please welcome our dark priests. - Really?
(The dark priests stride towards her.)
(We're three minutes away from seeing something shocking.)
(They're the dark priests.)
Someone wrote, "Good luck."
(- The drum sounds are ominous. - Rest in peace, Yu Bin.)
- We're done. - Ta-da.
- Ta-da. - Yes?
This is her hair and makeup style that she had in...
- the song "I Feel You". - Yes, it is.
Wasn't this a success? She looks pretty.
- I will dance to "I Feel You". - Yes, "I Feel You".
Actually, I am wearing...
my "I Feel You" costume, right now.
But I'm shy to take off my clothes here.
- You can change over there. - Please be patient.
Someone wrote, "Please show us". They like the idea.
Someone wrote, "Her pants are too short."
- I'm back! - She's back.
- She looks so pretty, right? - Yes.
- I wore this for my performance. - Yes.
It is actually a swimsuit.
(- It's okay, I'm an adult. - I'm okay with that.)
- Good. - I wore pants for your sake.
(The dance version for "I Feel You".)
Show us the dance moves.
Let's do it together. Type the song for me.
(- Okay! - I've never heard the song before.)
(- When I'm alone - I feel you)
(All I can do is clap along to the song.)
(She's sexy.)
(While she's performing passionately,)
(she only claps.)
(The dance performance must go on.)
(The room is starting to heat up.)
(- She moves like an old lady. - It this an exorcism?)
Look how I move.
(- You're so pretty. - I'm glad I'm watching this.)
Let's dance together.
(Jung Saem Mool is so cute.)
I'm about to... So we are going to now...
talk to each other.
I'm not taking off all my clothes.
Don't worry. I'm only taking off this one.
I wore another layer inside. "What are you doing?"
(She wore a white cotton t-shirt inside her hanbok.)
I thought long and hard about the best way to communicate with you.
So I thought we could communicate better if I wear...
my practice clothes.
That's why I wore...
the shirt I wear for practice underneath.
(Her microphone has come off.)
My microphone? Thank you.
I almost forgot to put my microphone back on.
"Are you wearing long johns?" No, It's a shirt.
(- That's her grandmother's. - What are you wearing?)
This is not heattech innerwear.
I knew this would happen. I knew I shouldn't have worn white.
I would never wear innerwear in public.
I'm here meeting you all for the first time.
Someone wrote, "Is that a sweat absorbing one?" No, it's a shirt.
(- You can buy 3 for 12 dollars. - What brand is it?)
To wish you all a happy New Year,
let me perform a traditional Korean dance.
Happy New Year, everyone.
Bring in the Buk!
Open the door, open the door.
I bring you luck for the new year.
(- Is that Kwon Do Woo? - It's the Chuk Sa Gwang Band!)
(The rhythm adds sophistication.)
(This is a traditional folk dance performed by female dancers.)
(The Chuk Sa Gwang Band leaves the stage.)
So, did you receive the luck we just sent to you?
Do you feel lucky?
Did you see me dancing with this?
I can use it like this,
I can just hit it on each side, from the front and the back.
"Was this the Joseon Dynasty's tambourine dance"?
Yes, I can use it like a tambourine.
She is my assistant for the day.
Yes, my assistant.
She is my teacher who leads the beat.
This might be surprising to you, but her name is Sol Ji.
(Surprisingly, her name is Sol Ji.)
Let me apologise for that. Her nickname is drinking Ji.
But she's also an amazing musician.
Now, I'm going to show you...
the Buddhist dance.
It has been designated an...
Important Intangible Cultural Property of Korea.
It is a Buddhist ceremonial dance.
I will put this red band around me.
"Miss Goryeo"? You're right.
Did you say, I look like a "Triangle kimbap"?
I'm ready. Let me show you the dance now.
(She is being reverent.)
(It is considered the most artistic dance among all folk dances.)
(- Can you play it faster? - Could we speed the beat up?)
(She's moving very slowly.)
(- It's healing me spiritually. - It's boring, but I love you.)
(It's too slow for young people to watch.)
(But she keeps dancing with the Buddhist monk's robe on.)
(Concentrating)
(The king of cameras appears out of nowhere.)
(She hasn't seen him yet.)
(She's startled.)
(What is that?)
(She fell down. She can't stop laughing.)
(The camera man approaches her like a hyena.)
(He gets as close to the dance as he can.)
Let's go!
(- Go away, ghost! - He looks like a satellite.)
Wake up, wake up!
You have lost your mind.
(She fights her laughter alone.)
Stay focused.
(- Sol Ji is part of the song. - She's lost control.)
(She tries to hold back the laughter.)
(I will finish strong!)
(And the master of dancing manages to finish her dance.)
(- This dance makes me feel drunk. - It's healing me spiritually.)
- What song do you want? - "MaMa".
"MaMa" by Bobby Kim.
You're very popular in this chat room.
It's true. Everyone's talking about you.
(He's maintaining his poker face.)
("MaMa" sung by Park Seung Chul, a lighting team staff member.)
Someone wrote, "The heart of perfection from Wisdom Sutra"
(Mum)
(I still remember)
Sounds great!
(It's a good song to sing at a dinner party.)
(He is about to cry.)
He's good.
(He's tapping his foot to the music.)
Someone wrote, "He sings like my boss."
(He sings like my boss.)
(He sounds like he's chanting Buddhist scriptures.)
(It's a statue of Buddha.)
(May you attain enlightenment.)
(Where am I going)
- I'll stop you there. - Okay.
Did you hear that, everyone? "I'd like to order two more beers."
(- Two more bottle of beer please! - He is too muscular to sing.)
Yes, I feel like having a bottle of beer too.
In the beginning, his voice wasn't singing to the melody,
that's why he sounded unstable.
(I still remember)
I think he can sing a little higher. And then...
you will sound more stable.
You'll sing better too.
By doing that you will be able to convey the emotions better.
Park Jin Young say this all the time, "Vocalize while breathing".
When you go to karaoke,
there's a locked part on the machine. But if you...
unlock and open it...
- Ta-da. - Look at that.
- They have something like this. - Okay.
There's a dial that says "HI".
Tweak the nob a little.
Microphone check.
It's not as clear, right?
But if you adjust it a little,
Microphone check.
(His microphone test is unique.)
Do you hear screeching sounds?
You can adjust the sound by...
controlling this dial as much as you want to.
It will add that extra something to your voice.
Let's try singing a song.
- Are you raising the key? - Yes, I am.
Because he's a tenor.
(He's preparing himself.)
Mama
Do you hear the wheezy sounds?
(His voice is conveying the emotions better.)
(His voice was unstable before...)
(as if he was chanting Buddhist scriptures.)
I will always
(He gives us a wink.)
(He is full of confidence as he...)
(finds the perfect key for his voice!)
(- Drinking while breathing. - I'm feeling sad now.)
(He makes eye contact with the camera.)
(He's become a man of sensitivity. His emotions are exploding.)
That was great.
(He missed a beat.)
(Although he missed the beat, he still sings with confidence.)
I'm impressed.
(He's getting emotional.)
(Embracing my shadows)
- That was awesome. - Bravo.
(His singing problem was solved and everyone's delighted.)
Did you hear how he finished that note?
That's not easy to do.
Did you hear how his tone changed?
Dream researcher says "Min Soo finally gets a win."
Thank you so much. I love you.
I really love you. Here, take my heart.
(- I enjoyed the song. - I cried listening to it.)
Thank you. So this is what it feels like.
It's time to learn about the history of ramyun.
- S Company sells the most, right? - Yes, S Company.
- Their ramyun came out in 1963. - In 1963.
It was influenced by the ramyun in japan...
- which were based on chicken stock. - I see.
- Look at this. - I ate this a lot.
- This is how we used to write Beef. - That's right.
- This is from S Company, right? - Right.
- S Company. - That's right.
- Beef ramyun. - This ramyun from S Company...
- will later on become this. - That's right.
This is the ramyun they made in the 70s.
- Do you have anything to add? - No.
(There's nothing more to explain.)
He didn't even hesitate.
He doesn't care about the rival company.
- Who remembers this? - Soybean paste ramyun!
- It was released in 1979. - This was really tasty.
- It was. - Why don't they make this anymore?
I loved the hearty flavours.
The majority of the public weren't too fond of...
- paste flavoured ramyun. - I have to say this though.
If this is how you're going to be,
you'll need to maintain this level of enthusiasm.
Don't get excited when we start talking about P Company.
- Okay. - Do you understand?
- I won't get excited. - I'm giving you a warning.
Cao Lu will be familiar with these ones.
- Okay. - Have you had this before?
- I have! - Do you know the name?
- It's frog ramyun. - No, it's Racoon ramyun.
You aren't allowed to say brand names on television.
- So let's just call it frog ramyun. - Is that so?
- Okay, frog ramyun. - Yes.
- But it's pretty obvious. - It's really delicious.
Anyway, this is N ramyun.
It's a steady seller.
It's the first ramyun to use thick noodles.
- Yes, thick noodles. - That's right.
This ramyun has quite the tragic story.
This is chlorella ramyun made by P Company.
At that time, chlorella was very popular.
- So we made ramyun with it. - It was quite expensive though.
- This... - It was expensive.
- Cuteness says, "It's green tea." - Green tea ramyun!
Hyo the massager says "The Four Rivers Ramyun Project".
(I have to laugh if I want to look cool.)
Because it's "Green Tea"?
Now this is the product that made the ramyun market...
- in Korea what it is today. - That's right!
- It's a masterpiece. - Yes, it is.
It's like a Samsung smartphone.
It's a masterpiece.
And this...
is the masterpiece that made P Company...
what it is today.
It's a steady seller.
"Mix with your right hand and with your left."
This is the first Korean ramyun...
- to use liquid flavour packets. - That's right.
We still have the most knowledge on...
- how to make liquid flavour packs. - Right.
We collaborated with...
a company in Japan and we came up with...
- what you're seeing right now. - I see.
The liquid sauces from other companies...
I think that's enough.
We don't want to promote...
- any specific product. - Right.
So let's leave it at that.
Really? What's that?
(The best ramyun from each ramyun company)
(We cooked all of these in secret.)
(They were all put into the same identical cups.)
Really? What's that?
- It's a blind taste test? - We're doing that now?
Wouldn't this blind taste test make him even less credible?
- They look identical. - I can't tell them apart.
This is insane.
- This will be difficult. - I know.
(The answers are written on the bottom of the cup.)
Can you guess which brand it is?
Can't you tell by just looking at the noodles?
Someone wrote, "Are you trying to get him fired?"
He can do this.
(- Nose, get to work. - What if he gets it wrong?)
"He should get ready to write an apology letter."
- What if he gets it wrong? - I'm doomed.
- I don't know what these two are. - He's an expert.
- He should know all these. - What's wrong?
(Cao Lu goes ahead and eats one.)
- This is the frog ramyun. - The frog ramyun?
Just say the real name!
- It's raccoon, not frog. - You can't say that on television.
He's been in the business for 30 years.
- Who are you trying to teach? - He still shouldn't say it.
Okay. So you think this is frog ramyun?
- Am I right? - You're right!
- Really? - Yes.
Yes! Should I become a ramyun fanatic?
All right. Here he goes.
(The expert gives it a go.)
- This is squid jjamppong. - Is it squid jjamppong?
That is correct.
What's next?
This is S ramyun from S company.
S ramyun from S company.
- Is he right? - No, that's incorrect
This is Namja ramyun from P Company.
That's where you work.
In a blind taste test, this ramyun always wins.
Really? This is your start product?
- It's the next rising star. - Is that so?
In a blind taste test 7 out of 10...
prefer this ramyun.
What's wrong with you? How could you not know?
You can't air this.
- This is a live show. - You can't air this.
Everyone's already seen it.
- This is a live show. - You cooked it for me...
- earlier. - No, it's not.
(There's no way I got this wrong.)
I'm doomed.
(I'm doomed.)
Is this one cooked?
(- He even cooked it earlier. - His desk will be gone tomorrow.)
Come on. You can redeem yourself.
He should at least know the ramyun his company makes.
He's doomed. Will he still have a job tomorrow?
This is S ramyun from N Company.
S ramyun from N Company?
S ramyun from N Company. That is correct.
Here we go.
- It's S ramyun. - S ramyun from S Company?
- That's right. - You are correct.
He seems to know the products from his rival companies well.
But he can't tell apart his company's product.
I received some urgent news.
"The HR Team is finalizing the paper work as we speak."
(You're lying!)
(He drinks it like it's soju.)
Hang on.
Didn't I guess this one correctly?
This? No, you didn't.
- I didn't? - No.
You're unbelievable.
He still got many of them right.
But he couldn't guess the ramyun...
that he called...
the star product of his company.
- That's because... - Okay, we'll hear you out.
That just shows how delicious it is.
We're fourth in the business...
but our products taste just as good.
I was told to inform you, you don't need to come into work tomorrow.
(He's sad.)
- Would you like to say a few words? - Yes, he should.
You might want to say something to your CEO.
I was confused because...
I've eaten this so many times.
No, to be honest, we eat products made by our rivals more.
So that is probably why I was so confused...
(He chokes.)
That's why I was confused.
I hope you understand.
You should drink some water.
(He sacrifices himself to bring people laughter.)
He choked on the noodles.
I'm going to draw something with a Lunar New Year theme.
We'll each draw the image that pops up when we think of theme.
I'll do my specialty which is oil painting.
We don't have a lot of time so we'll do this simultaneously.
Do you want me to put this up?
Why are you putting that up?
One of us could cheat.
Cheat? Why would I do that?
You never know.
- Really? Okay. - People change.
- If you say so. - You might take a glimpse.
It's like we're in separate rooms.
Okay, so let's get started.
Can you see what I'm doing?
Do we get separate chat rooms as well?
("Lee Mal Nyeon's Lonely Cartoon Life")
Is that so?
Let me show you this.
This is what I clean my brushes with.
I'm starting my drawing.
- Sure, go ahead. - Okay.
Oh, gosh. I spilt nearly all of it.
You're running out of time.
(- Yura hasn't started yet. - Mal Nyeon, be quiet!)
Do you think you'll have enough time?
Oh dear.
(Glance)
- Did you spill a lot? - It's none of your business.
I hear you loud and clear.
Now I'm ready.
- So... - I have a big heart.
I'm sure you do. Hang on, let me just...
(- Yura ran away. - It's only been five minutes.)
You need a lot of things when doing oil paintings.
Now it's time to paint.
- Let me guide you through it. - Are you sure you have time?
They're saying that I'm running out of time.
I'll leave it over here for now.
Have you still not started yet?
- Next I'll... - This isn't a joke.
Hang on. I'm missing my white paint.
This is not good. I'm in big trouble.
Where's the white paint?
Oh no. What now?
(She stops because there's no white paint.)
I'm doomed.
Is this going to be an easy win?
So it's Lunar New Year.
Families gather around to celebrate the day.
- Among them might be an aunt... - Right.
- who brags about her kids. - Yes, there always is.
So I'm going to draw some of the family members.
Here's a nephew that's trying to...
break something valuable in his uncle's collection.
This is how I always draw people so...
I'm sure that you'll be satisfied with my work.
- Wow! - But the grandfather...
This desk divider is useless.
She still hasn't started.
I can see what you've drawn on the screen.
- You're right. - I don't know what to do.
There's no white paint. What should I do?
I'll have to make do without.
So we start with the background.
When you wake up, you see that the sky is so pretty...
on the morning of Lunar New Year.
Once you've done that, take a towel and...
rub the oil paint to give it a smudged look.
(- My heart is pounding so hard. - How can you not love her?)
This is the sky.
Let me try that, too.
All right. So I've finished painting the sky.
(He's giving us a real heart attack!)
"You've already won."
They're saying that I've already won.
Why?
They're saying that my painting of the sky is that good.
That's absurd. I need you guys to be fair.
All right.
- What's wrong? - Got Yura wrote "Hurry up and..."
- "go buy her white paint." - That's a great idea.
That's it. I'm done!
- I'll get you your white paint. - I was only kidding.
- I'll be right back. - Where are you going?
- I'm alone. - Keep going.
They're asking you buy paint.
I'll be back with some white paint for you.
Now I'm going to draw roof tiles.
I feel so lonely right now...
- for some reason. - You should've been nice to me.
Were you still here?
You should've been nice when you had the chance.
Okay, so now I'll draw the roof tiles.
(Silent)
(- Say something! - This is why we need Mal Nyeon.)
I have stopped talking. This is bad.
How do I communicate with the viewers?
- Right now, I... - Have you finished drawing?
I didn't buy white paint.
Communicating with the viewers while drawing...
- is very hard. - It's hard.
- You need to concentrate. - It's very hard.
But some viewers can get so childish.
When I stop talking for even a second while I draw,
they write "This is no fun" in the chat room.
- Really? - It's hard to talk while you draw.
No, I will try my best to communicate with the viewers.
- Such is life. - You are making me look bad.
- You should have supported me. - I didn't mean it like that.
This is what I'm drawing.
On the day of Lunar New Year, a grandfather is happily...
watching ssireum.
Since other family members don't care for ssireum,
they are doing other things.
You are good at drawing a tree.
I only drew two branches so far.
- It's not ginseng, is it? - What?
It's not ginseng.
- I need to add a few more details. - Okay.
I have originally planned to draw...
a magpie and beautiful snow.
But I won't have enough time.
I think I was too ambitious.
- I glued my work on an envelope. - Stop boasting.
I wanted to add more branches, too.
I glued my work on an envelope.
- Come on. - Now,
I will put money in it.
I don't have any money. Does anyone have money?
Give me some money so I can put it in this envelope.
- I messed up. - I'll put this in the envelope.
- This is hard. - I told you so.
I messed up.
I will read the comments.
"It looks like Lee Mal Nyeon's hair in 10 years."
That will make a good title for the piece.
- Let's use that as the title. - I have realised once again...
how hard painting is.
What comes next is a special on lips.
About 70 to 80 percent of people don't know...
how to take care of their lips.
That's right. Dead skin cell are the biggest problem.
Discolouration is another problem.
So I will give you useful tips.
Who is ready?
My goodness.
Hello.
We have the Primary Schooler and the General.
I won't give you any restrictions.
Apply any lipsticks as you usually do.
Here are the lipsticks.
Some are moisturising and some are matte.
- Have you picked one? - Yes.
Apply the lipstick.
- I need a mirror. - Right.
All right.
(They have different ways of applying lipstick.)
The three women are applying lipstick.
I will give you various tips shortly afterwards.
- I'm done. - Okay.
This is what the General did wrong.
There are dead skin cells and scars on her lips.
When she has dead skin on her lips,
she rips it off unconsciously.
This is what you should do with such lips.
Take a wet tissue and lip balm in a pot.
Put a generous amount of lip balm to the wet tissue...
and remove the lipstick.
Like this.
This will really help your lips.
Put some concentrated face oil to the wet tissue.
And rub your lips.
If you apply oil to dead skin and discoloured area...
regularly,
your lips will become glossy and moist.
There is blood on her lips.
Apply lip balm over discoloured areas of the lips.
- My goodness. - What is it?
Someone wrote that I look like Douner.
Douner? Who is Douner?
He is Dooly's friend.
When you have pale skin and dyed hair,
orange and reddish orange...
make you pretty in a retro way.
Since the General has plump lips,
she shouldn't line her lips.
And since her lips are very dry,
it will help to apply lip balm over the lipstick.
Don't use lip gloss when your lips are dry.
It will only make your lips drier.
Someone wrote that this should be my signature lip colour.
Signature lip colour? That's right.
She looks very cute.
- It's The Primary Schooler's turn. - Okay.
The Primary Schooler...
Her lips are dry,
but she hasn't pulled the dead skin on her lips.
We will remove the lipstick.
(She roughly handles the Primary Schooler's lips.)
You do this.
I look like a mother wiping off a child's drool?
Goodness, my baby's lips are cracked.
This is how I applied lip balm to my child yesterday.
Now, get rid of excessive oil.
Use a tissue paper.
It's hard to apply lipstick along your cupid's bow.
I will share an easy way to do it.
Apply lipstick to about one tenth of a cotton bud.
Lightly apply lipstick to the tip.
Move the cotton bud back and forth along your cupid's bow.
- It shaped your cupid's bow easily. - It did.
Then take the cotton bud to your lower lip.
This is how you sharpen the edges of your lips.
Take a foundation...
and apply some to the tip of a cotton bud.
Sharpen the edges of your lips with a cotton bud.
This way, you can use a cotton bud...
to apply and erase the lipstick from your lips.
It's an easy way to easily apply a dark lipstick.
What do you think? Does she look pretty?
Cotton buds are the best.
Producer Dung, come over here.
There aren't a lot of dead skin on her lips.
Among the three of them, her lips are the best.
This is what you can use as a substitute for lip balm.
Eye cream is a good choice.
It's effective for wrinkles on your lips.
Rub eye cream on your lips.
Gosh, her lips became so kissable.
She has that innocent beauty.
Let's apply a pink lipstick.
Make the colour pop on the upper lip,
but don't apply as much product on the lower lip.
Women in their 20s like the look of a lip stain.
There you go.
She looks so innocent. The colour looks very pretty on her.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Red, pink and reddish orange...
are trendy colours of 2016.
Keep that in mind.
They go well with a retro outfit.
It's very trendy.
This time, I will show you a fan dance.
Isn't this fan beautiful?
(She begins the fan dance to the rhythm of janggu.)
(Peek-a-boo)
(Smiling)
(People often think fan dance is a traditional dance of Korea.)
(But the dance only emerged in 1954.)
(Blooming)
(Fans only serve as a decoration in fan dances of other countries.)
(But the movements of the fan are crucial to the Korean fan dance.)
(- Look at her triple axel. - I'm drunk on the Korean soul.)
(It's an extravagant beauty hidden inside the sublime elegance.)
(Flying Ye Ri)
(She continues on with salpuri dance.)
(It's a dance to ward off evil that utilises white outfit and shawl.)
(Creeping)
(Holding back laughter)
(I won't laugh this time.)
(Let's think of something sad.)
(Your professionalism is impressive.)
(The dance reaches its climax as the tempo quickens.)
(- Salpuri dance is glamorous. - It's a funeral for the laughter.)
(Salpuri dance transforms deep sorrow into beauty.)
That was salpuri dance.
I prepared salpuri dance with a wish to ward off evil...
and bring good luck to everyone in the new year.
If you would like to do something for your grandparents,
take a white shawl and dance like this.
You can even use a toilet paper to enjoy the salpuri dance...
during a company dinner.
I think it would be nice to have fun with the dance.
Utilise an exfoliating towel?
That's a good idea.
I prepared the Chunaeng dance.
During King Sunjo's reign, Crown Prince Hyomyeong...
made the dance for his mother.
Since this is a dance of the palace,
we will need a king and a queen.
Where did the king go?
Put on your outfit and join us. Where is he?
Your highness.
Please come this way.
Have you been drinking by any chance?
His cheeks are red.
- I swear I didn't drink alcohol. - Okay.
My face gets flushed easily.
All right.
We will now show you the Chunaeng dance.
Chunaeng dance...
was originally done...
on a small mat of about three square metres.
(Crown Prince Hyomyeong turned a nightingale's chirp into a dance.)
Showing a dancer's bare hands to the king was prohibited,
so dancers hid their hands in long sleeves.
(Movements of Chunaeng dance are perfectly controlled.)
Your Highness, do you like the dance?
- No. - You don't like it?
I only have eyes for my queen.
Your attention is focused on me.
No, I was talking about my wife.
(Embarrassed)
(Chunaeng dance is over.)
Let's give Ms Park a round of applause.
(She exits with a peculiar walk.)
Let's learn the basic dance moves.
We will first learn how to strengthen your lower abdomen.
Please let me touch you for a second.
All right. You need to tighten your lower abdomen.
Your belly is very soft.
Bring your feet together and push your knees forward.
Your hips stay in position.
Push your knees forward. That's right.
Push your knees forward.
This man...
This man has a defective body.
(- He is the king of defect. - He won't be a powerful king.)
"The king of defect"?
You need to work the muscles of your inner thighs.
Blushing won't help you.
Let's stretch out your arms first.
Lower your body from that position.
Stand on your toes and push your knees forward. Good.
- You're doing really well. - So, I'm allowed to raise my heels?
- Yes, of course. - Oh.
I thought I wasn't allowed to lift them.
(Why are you doing something that we never told you to do?)
He finally realised that he was allowed to lift his heels.
Now you know how to do it, right?
As you go bend down, use your heels.
Could you stop right there? Thank you.
Hold that pose. We are going to hold this pose for 10 seconds.
And 1, 2, 3, 4...
again 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 and 10.
That was fantastic.
(- Was he being tortured? - She is a strict instructor.)
I will now announce the...
half-time results for MLT-20.
- They are announcing the results? - It's too soon.
- They're out? - The half-time results?
- Currently coming in third place... - They're not the final results.
is "Jung Saem Mool's Colourful Life".
(Jung Same Mool is coming third with 14,906 viewers.)
- Currently coming in second... - Am I dead last?
is Kim Gu Ra.
- That's us. - Wow.
- That's us. - Thank you.
Currently coming in first place is...
(Currently in first place)
Currently in first place is "Yoo and Nyeon".
- I knew we could do it. - We're coming in first place.
- We're number one. - We're number one.
- This is a great feeling. - Thank you, we won't let you down.
- No, we won't. - Don't worry.
- We're in last place. - Yes.
(Crying)
It's okay. I don't mind if I come in last place.
- Half-time intermission... - I'm going to do my imitation.
- I'm so happy right now, thank you. - Yes.
"Lee Mal Nyeon, you should be grateful to Yura. You did nothing."
I'm going to start drawing now.
Here we go.
As we go, it turns into happiness
We're starting to develop chemistry and teamwork.
(We watch and listen.)
It tastes different now.
Round and round we go
- We're going to work together. - I never envisioned this.
We're going to try on bikinis now. Doesn't she look gorgeous?
What does your nickname mean?
I can overcome the rhythm but I can't overcome this cold
You're doing great.
I'm going to be teaching you a dance.
(You can have a sneak peek by going on the mobile app Kakaotalk.)
Help yourself to some ramyun.
Which one do you think will taste better?
- I still got it. - Yes, you do.