Are you really that surprised?
Well, yeah, I mean--
Yeah, I'm-I'm honestly--
I'm more than surprised.
I'm sort of shocked.
I mean-- Yeah.
Katie, when was the last time
you saw me really happy?
Well, I don't know. You know?
Nobody's happy all the time, right?
I mean, it sort of, you know,
comes and it goes and...
Rita, have you hormones checked?
Because I know that sounds crazy
but women have killed their own
children in hormonal rages.
- You know, maybe that's a part of this.
- Katie, listen.
There's nothing wrong with me.
Just like there is
nothing wrong with you.
You're in the same situation.
It may be your version of it, but--
No, I'm not.
No, I'm not. I would--
I would never leave Dave.
I've never wanted to leave Dave
and, you know, he doesn't
wanna leave me, so...
You haven't had sex in a year.
Well, so what?
So what?
I mean, we love each other.
You know?
If-if-if his legs fell off
I wouldn't leave him.
What does that mean?
It means,
sex isn't everything, you know?
No, it isn't.
It's only a part of it.
- I know that.
- So fix the other parts, Rita.
- I mean, come on.
- I can't.
I tried. And now I just
don't want to.
I'm just trying to get out
of what we have been
complaining about to each other
for the last 10 years.
Yeah, I, uh...
I just don't remember
complaining though, you know?
It was fun. I mean, I just, I th--
You know, we were complaining
so that this wouldn't happen.
Right? I mean...
Do you remember a couple years ago
when Dan and I were thinking
about having another kid?
Well, if we did, right now
that kid would be 3 years old.
I wouldn't be able to leave.
It would've been
the worst mistake ever.
Okay, Rita. You know what?
I'm not you. All right, Rita?
You don't need to warn me.
And you know what I think?
I think that you are making
a huge mistake right now.
I think you are about to
destroy your life,
and you're gonna come to me
in a year from now
and you're gonna ask me
why I let you do this.
Jesus Christ, Katie.
You'd think I'm leaving you.
No, come on. I understand
what you're talking about--
No, you don't.
I thought you would, but you don't.
There's the yolk sac,
and...
there's the heartbeat.
Oh, my God.
It has a long way to go.
It does.
But it happens fast.
Uh, how fast?
Well, by your next ultrasound
you'll see the beginnings
of arms, and legs,
and the heart,
and before you know it,
it will be keeping you up at night.
It's pretty incredible.
That's why they call it
the miracle of life.
Do you guys want a picture?
Start showing off?
No, that's all right.
Uh, yeah. Yeah, we do.
Yes. Definitely.
There you go.
I'll see you both in six weeks.
- Okay.
- Okay, thank you.
That's unbelievable,
that that, uh...
will be us one day.
It's okay.
It's okay. No one expects you to fall
in love with a grain of rice.
Hon, just
give it some time.
Oh, give it time.
- Oh, okay.
- Come on.
No, I know.
- I just-- I mean, you know.
- I know.
We'll get through this together.
I'll get us through it.
Hi.
- Hey, babe. How ya doin'?
- Good. How you doin'?
Good. Just tryin'
to figure out my night.
Did you get my text?
Yeah. I'm sorry, I got busy.
So we're still meeting up?
I already ate but I'll meet up
with you afterward.
All right. All right, well,
I'm gonna go out
so I'll just meet you
back at your place.
I love you.
Anyway...
- I'll see you later.
- Okay. Bye.
What?
I'm just not ready to tell her.
I don't think we should.
I-I think it's too early.
She's your mother, Palek.
Since when do you give a shit
about my mother?
Since she became
our baby's grandmother.
I just don't want her fuckin' drama.
I don't wanna deal with
her hugging, kissing bullshit.
We'll throw it in the middle
of one of her stories.
- She'll barely notice.
- Hon, she'll notice.
Look, if I had a mother, I'd want her
to know, even if I hated her.
Don't pull
the dead-mother card. It's not fair.
I-I'm just saying,
I would want to tell her.
Just like I wanna tell your mother.
I just wanna tell family.
All right, all right, all right.
Are you okay?
And I wanted to tell her
that she was out of line
but I didn't feel that I could.
We've known each other
for so many years
and it just seemed
inappropriate and rude,
to tell her what I really felt.
Th-there's rudeness
attached to this movement
that seems to be going around.
People tell each other,
you know, what they want
and feel and need.
Don't-don't you think?
We're pregnant.
So...
Oh, my God.
- What?
- Why say it like that?
- Why? Why not?
Oh, my God.
Oh, Carolyn,
I don't know what to say.
- I love you.
- Oh, well. I love you.
God, could the, um...?
Uh, I'll be right back.
What is it with you
and the heat in this place, Mom?
I'm cold.
Carolyn,
I can-- I can finally tell you.
Now, I did my very best
not to say anything. No to--
Palek's not happy.
And I don't know what to do.
Oh, he's...
- Well, he's-he's happy.
- No.
He isn't?
He doesn't want this baby.
He doesn't wanna be a dad.
Did-did he tell you this?
Well, he-he doesn't
have a choice, does he?
No.
He'll come around.
Oh, sweetheart, it's wonderful news.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Maybe Isabella can read to Josh.
We could pay her.
I wanna watch my show.
How was your day?
Oh, you know. Good.
Same as it was yesterday.
- How was your day?
- It was good.
And, um, I got a lot of stuff done.
Went over to Rita's
for a while, hung out.
Yeah? How's she doin'?
How's she doin'? She's, um...
She's good.
Have you talked to Dan lately?
Well, you guys don't really
talk very much, do you?
No. Only when you girls
are together.
Well, Rita was telling me how,
a few years ago,
Dan wanted to have another baby
but she didn't want to.
She's smart.
I think that your reasons
for not wanting to have a baby
and her reasons are probably
different though, you know?
I'm tryin' to watch this.
What are you reasons, Dave?
I don't know. I-- I mean, you--
Honey, you don't really
want a baby, do you?
That's not what I'm asking.
You know, I just--
I would like to know
what your reasons are.
It's-it's-it's not that
I don't want one,
I just, I just, you know--
We're gettin' old.
Not really. I mean, there was
that woman in the Philippines.
What was she? Like, she was 62
and she had a kid?
W-what am I supposed to say to that?
I mean--
Look, I-I-I don't know
what's goin' on here
but I feel like
there's this weird trap
and I'm afraid to take a step
'cause my foot's gonna get cut off.
You know what?
Maybe that's the problem.
You know that? Maybe we're just--
We're just afraid.
I don't know. I don't know.
We can't redo the patio every year.
Yeah, well,
I-I-I never wanted to redo it.
You're the one who wants to redo it.
I-I'm fine with the way it is.
I always have been.
Yeah, exactly.
So how have you been?
Good.
Have you talked to Hugo
since our session?
He'll never talk to me again.
How's it going with Nick?
Fine.
We had shitty sex,
and then we had good sex,
and then he told me he loved me.
And, um...
And, um, what?
Now, every time we leave each other,
he says, "I love you."
When Nick tells you
he loves you, what do you say?
I kiss him,
and then change the subject.
Well, that's a tried
and true method.
Yeah, but not for me.
I mean, usually when a guy
tells me he loves me--
Which happens a lot.
--I just say it right back
even if it's not true, you know?
Just seeing it in their face, and...
feeling all that stuff,
you just feel is worth it.
And then what happens?
I usually fuck around on them,
try to figure out
a way to leave them,
usually blame them for something,
and then get into another relationship.
But this time
you said was different.
This time you said
you weren't doing that.
Tell me why you think
you weren't doing it.
I don't know.
I mean, I can't tell him
I love him back.
I don't want to.
And I wish that I could
because it would just make it
a lot easier to lie about it.
You know, he's not upset,
I'm not upset.
There's not that, you know,
weird moment or that awkward space
that just kinda sits there
wherein I'm not saying
I don't love you.
I don't think that's a bad thing.
Yeah, well, it makes me feel shitty.
I mean, what if he's the guy,
you know?
What if I'm so fucked up
that the right guy is standing
right in front of me
and I can't say it?
And what if I can only say it
to the wrong people?
Well, I don't think that's the case.
I think you're examining
some very valid issues.
You know, I've spent so long
in relationships that I don't know...
It's like, I have no lines,
no boundaries.
And it never used to bother me before
and now it drives me crazy.
Now I wanna run.
But I'm afraid to run
because I'm afraid
to be alone, so I stay.
Only now, I'm like this
blob who can really fuck,
and there's no--
There's nothing.
Well, the obvious answer
is of course
to spend some time,
a decent amount of time, alone.
Changing who you're with
obviously doesn't work.
Unless you change,
the issues will remain the same.
You know, part of me just wants
to run off an marry him.
I mean, he's a great guy.
So what am I doing?
Jaime, if you really
find it difficult to be alone
it seems to me you have few choices.
One.
You can tell him you love him,
see what happens.
Or you can keep on kissing him
and changing the subject,
which doesn't come
without its own challenges
but you seem to be up to it.
Or you can tell him the truth.
You can tell him how you feel,
that you need some time.
- Hello?
- Yes.
I'm calling about the job
for the digital artist.
- Do you have experience?
- Yes I did. I mean, I do.
How much, about?
It was-- It was a few years go, but--
- Do you have a portfolio?
- Yeah, I have.
- References?
- Both.
Could you come in tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
- About 2:00?
- Sure, I can.
Great. E-mail your résumé
and I'll see you then.
- Okay.
- Okay, I'll see you then.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
- Bye
- Thank you.
The client is not happy,
and I can't say I blame them.
Hinton was a dropped ball,
and I would never say this to them,
but that was a fuckup.
And that was our fuckup
because due diligence wasn't.
Carolyn, I want you to go back
over all the documents.
All four contracts.
Go over it with a fine-toothed comb,
make sure we're protected.
And then, tomorrow
you'll review it with Philip.
What?
I need more time.
You don't have more time.
I need it tomorrow.
Then get somebody else.
I don't know what to tell you
about the cement.
We're gonna do what we need to do.
Okay?
Hey. I don't have
any more time, okay?
That's it. I--
Okay, I gotta call you back.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Where are you?
Uh, at work. W-what's up?
Well, I-- I think I just quit.
What?
I just walked out.
Well, are you gonna walk back in?
No.
No, I'm not.
We're doing fine.
And you know how I feel,
I don't wanna work
once the baby's born, so...
I think I'm done.
You're done?
Palek, you know, honestly,
I don't think I could go back in there.
I mean, I--
Shoulter has probably
cleaned out my office.
I mean, I just walked out on her.
You know, I gotta go, and, uh,
maybe we can talk about this later.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Bye.
- How are you today?
- I'm fine, thank you.
Could I get a room started for you?
No thanks. I think I'm
just gonna keep looking.
Thanks.
Hi, it's Katie Walker
and I'm sorry this is so last minute
but we're not gonna
make therapy today, it's just--
It's been a crazy day
and so I'll just, um--
I'll just-- I'll-I'll talk to you soon.
Okay.
I'm-I'm sorry about that.
Okay, bye-bye.
Dave?
Katie's not here yet.
No, I just got a message
from Katie, cancelling therapy.
Yeah, I--
I must've just missed her call.
Well, you're here.
We have the hour
and it's already paid for.
Why don't you come in?
Sally, you're doin' pickup, right?
Do you think you could
get Isabella and Josh?
Sure. Everything okay?
Yeah, I just got tied up.
I'll have Dave come and get him
before dinner, okay?
Rita called. She said you guys got
in a fight. She's really upset.
Well, so am I.
Why?
You know what? Let's just
talk about it later, okay Sally?
Thanks for gettin' the kids.
So...
I-I don't-- What am I doin' here?
Dave, a few minutes ago
you made choice.
I think it was a good one.
You chose to stay.
I imagine there's a reason why.
There are a number of ways
I can get you to talk.
- Are they all painful?
- Yes, most of them.
Katie wants another baby.
Do you?
No.
- Why not?
- Too old.
And to tell you the truth,
as-as much as I love my kids,
I wouldn't mind having my wife back.
So you miss her?
Every day.
Many couples come to me
because they think they've,
grown distant.
Yeah, we really have.
Well, I think
it's just the opposite.
Sometimes,
there's no passion left when,
when the space is so small
you can't reach across it.
But all there is, is space.
There-there is so much space,
I can't--
I-I don't even know
how to get to her.
I don't know how to get to her.
I don't even know where she is.
What about you?
Tell me where you've been.
I didn't go anywhere. I, I just--
I mean, life--
Things...
changed.
Some of these guys
I sell steel to, they--
They're builders.
They're young, no kids.
I always wanted to build things.
And I look at them and then I think,
"Why isn't that me?"
"Why am I who I am?"
And then I go home,
and then there's Katie.
I love her, I-I--
I never even knew what love was
until I met Katie,
but sometimes I hate her.
I know that's wrong.
I know I shouldn't blame her.
But I do.
And you still think we're too close?
I think all of your resentment,
your disappointment and your regret,
is all mixed up with Katie's.
That's a difficult knot to untangle.
It's more than that. It's...
like something came in one day,
and took it.
One night I looked over
and I didn't want her.
And I didn't know why.
And I didn't know what to do.
You know, that's something
you should share with Katie.
You can't tell your wife
you don't want her anymore,
and recover.
No, but you can tell her
that you're lost
and you don't know what to do.
Does it come back?
I mean, does it?
Once you've gotten to the point
where we are?
Can it come back?
Can we reverse time? No.
But sometimes
there can be something else.
And sometimes that something
else can be better.
What?
Something better.
- Love Crush.
* I'm sorry?
That's what it's called.
It's pretty silly, huh?
You know, it would look good
on you though. Would you like to see?
- No, that's okay.
- Sit.
Sit down.
This looks good. You know,
I'm gonna grab some shadow.
Sure, okay.
Close?
Other eye.
Well, so we had the, uh,
the first inspector out to the house,
the guy that you suggested.
- Kurt.
- Yeah, Kurt's a good guy.
Well, he was tryin' to put
a happy face on, but...
I could tell there was something
he wasn't saying.
So I had another inspector
come out to the house.
This guy Mike.
Former Marine.
Tells it like it is.
Mold.
Mold?
It's everywhere. It's, uh--
It's all over your house.
Wait. No it's not.
We never saw any mold.
No, of course you didn't see it.
That's the whole thing, it's mold.
It's the silent killer.
All right.
I'm still gonna buy it.
Clean up's gonna cost
at least 50,000.
- Sure, of course.
- Maybe more.
So...
It's your choice.
- You all right?
- Am I all right? What is that?
Some kind of trick question?
What is that?
You look pale.
I'm fine.
Jesus.
Fuck.
Oh, fuck.
So where is Mom anyway?
On her way, honey.
She-she called and she's on her way.
She gained like 400 pounds
and then blew up in the parking lot.
When's she gonna get here?
Soon.
See?
Hey, what happened?
Uh, I just, um--
I lost track of time.
- Hey, Mom.
- Hey, sweetie.
- Hey, you look pretty.
- Thank you.
And-and this morning,
I mean, what happened with therapy?
Well, I, uh-- I got busy, you know?
I thought--
I thought you would be relieved.
Uh, I-I would've been if I had
gotten a message sooner.
Oh, so you went?
- How was it?
- It was, uh--
It-it was irritating.
- You want some chicken?
- Sure, okay.
How was everybody's day?
- Fine.
- Good day.
Did you go to--? Thanks.
- Did you go to baseball today?
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hi.
You know what? What?
I think we're moving too fast.
Look, I wanna be with you. I just--
I mean, it's not us,
I just wanna slow down.
Right.
I went to the shrink and-and
I'm just trying
to deal with my shit and
I'm trying to do something
right for a change.
I'm tired of this shit.
Maybe we should just
talk about this later.
There's nothing to--
There's nothing to talk about.
I'm falling in love with you
and you're not
falling in love with me.
But I am in love with you.
No, you're not.
I want to be.
You're everything that I want.
Oh, fuck you.
I had a session with a patient.
A man, 40 years old.
He'd never been there alone.
He always comes with his wife.
And he's not comfortable in therapy.
And for the first time
in a long time,
I wasn't comfortable either.
He...
I was stumped
by something he asked me.
I can't imagine you stumped
about anything.
Unless it's about building a house.
It was about marriage
and I think I let him down.
Really?
How?
He and his wife
have been struggling.
And I told him to stick it out,
that there was something
at the other end of it.
And then when he asked me
what it was, I c--
I didn't know what to tell him.
Tell him it's the same thing
he has now, only he loves it.
He wouldn't change a thing about it.
How can I explain that to him?
You can't.
You didn't fail him.
He just can't grasp what we have
from his point of view.
Hey, Jaime, it's Nick.
I left some softball stuff over there,
and a pair of shoes, I think.
So if you could
leave 'em by your door
I'll grab 'em some time tomorrow.
I think you're right.
I think we need a break.
Well, I mean, I know I need to.
So take care.
So what did you do all day?
Can you just give me the run down?
- Just. You know, I was running errands.
- All day?
No, I was-- I went shopping.
You know, it's--
It's not like I disappeared,
like I hopped a plane to Vegas.
I just-- I, um...
I had an interview and I didn't have
anything to wear so I went to the mall.
What do you mean, you had an interview?
What-what kind?
For what?
For a job, Dave.
What?
Why are you laughing?
It's just-- This is a job job?
Full-time?
Yeah, full-time.
Why is this so funny?
No, it's funny because it's-it's--
It's not like, hah-hah funny.
It's more like, funny hah-hah.
I mean...
You know, first you want a baby
and now you want a job.
You want to go to therapy,
you don't want to go.
You don't answer your phone,
your eyelids are blue.
- You noticed.
- Well, of course.
Who wouldn't notice? I mean,
you wanted to get a pass for the day?
Fine. Who doesn't wanna
get a pass for the day?
I do, but I busted my butt
to get to that appointment.
I left work early
to pick up the kids,
I looked like an idiot because
I didn't know where you were.
You don't even tell me
about Rita and Dan,
I have to hear it from Sally.
I mean, come on.
I'm sorry, I should've told you.
- Why didn't you?
- Because, because--
Because it's Rita and Dan.
It's Rita and Dan, Dave. Okay?
She can do that, I mean, if-if--
If they can do that then, I don't know,
anyone can do it. And I just, I--
You know, it just threw me, okay?
I just-- I'm confused
right now, and I just--
- Well, me fucking too.
- Don't swear, okay?
Let's not do that.
Let's just...
Tell me what to do, Katie.
I've done everything
you asked me to do.
So tell me what to do now.
I don't know.
- We're fine, Dave.
- No.
- No, no, no.
- We'll be fine.
Stop doing that.
Just-just make it-- Just cm down.
You know what I was
gonna tell you tonight?
That I changed my mind.
What?
I think we should have a baby.
I'm just--
I'm saying you were right.
No, I wasn't.
Okay, I'm beat. I'm goin' to bed.
I had a panic attack?
You'll be fine, just take it easy.
I thought I was dying.
You know, I'm not
a hypochondriac or anything.
I've never even been
to an emergency room.
No, babe, they ran the tests.
I mean, you're fine.
It's a physical thing.
You know, it's just like a physical
thing in your head.
I guess.
I can't believe I quit my job.
What?
It is always about you,
isn't it, Carolyn?
Good job gettin' us through this.
You know what, Palek? Grow up. Okay?
You're gonna be a father,
'cause we're having a baby.
He said to reduce my stress level.
Do you think that
is reducing my stress level?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I got scared.
I never get scared--
This was really scary.
...just sitting there.
I mean, like, fuck.
What do you expect him to do?
I don't ca-- I don't--
You know, I don't care.
I don't care. Whatever.
- You so fuckin' care.
- I don't.
I mean, what kind
of a name is Anya, anyway?
I don't know. Who cares?
Sounds like a industrial cleaner.
Fuck, I don't know, man.
I don't know. He kinda
looks like a girl, anyway.
What?
- I don't know.
- What?
How do I make you
feel better about it?
We drink.
Right. That's what I do,
is I get you hammered.
- That's what you do.
- You know, I don't--
That's what I do,
I pay for the alcohol.
Have we not established this?
This is how I roll.
I roll big. I roll big.
We'll do this, okay?
Awesome.
You. You wanna
go out?
Yeah. Pick the place.
Do you have a, um, number?
- Got a pen?
- A pen?
How old are you, man?
I got this phone.
Hello.
Morning.
- What happened?
- What do you mean, what happened?
I took the kids to school.
Well, why didn't you wake me?
You were out.
I figured, let you sleep.
Well, what'd you tell the kids?
- You were tired.
- What'd they say?
They didn't say anything.
Good.
I'm sorry you had to
do the morning alone.
It's okay. It's fine.
Yeah, it sounds like it.
Katie, you oversleeping
is the least of our problems.
Bye.
A panic attack?
Yeah. It was scary.
Have you had one before?
No, why?
Am I gonna have another one?
Probably not, but
a panic attack is a warning sign.
It's the body's alarm system
going off.
That's a good description.
Anyway, it's over now, so...
Good.
I quit my job.
- Yeah, the day of his attack.
- That's not why I had it.
No, I'm not saying that's why
you had it. I'm just saying,
the day I quit my job,
when I needed you,
you had a panic attack.
Yeah, I did.
Well, that's fucking scary.
We're pregnant, I don't have a job,
and you're disappearing
in front of my eyes.
You quit your job
without even telling me.
It's the first time in my life I depend
on someone, and now I find I can't.
And that's, just hard.
I'm sorry, have I not been clear?
I mean, you know how I feel
about all this.
- Yeah, I do.
- Okay.
Carolyn, how does he feel?
Scared?
I wanna get us back
to where we were, you know?
I-I know that I may have been
too focused on getting pregnant,
and maybe I stopped listening
but I'm here now
and I want to now, so...
Good.
You lost faith that you were
gonna get pregnant.
I lost faith that we should.
Yeah, I want to be a good husband,
I can be a good husband, but...
I don't think I can
be a good husband and a father.
I don't have it in me.
What do you need me to do?
I've said I'll wait,
I've said I'll stay,
I've said--
What do you need from me?
What do you need me to do?
I think it might be too late f--
I think we should spit up.
Why?
I'm not happy.
I've been for a long time.
Transcript: testexam
Synchro: Hutch
Season 1 Episode 09
_/Yellow Sub Team\_
contact@yellowsubteam.com