Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Final Episode
This is supposed to be good for you.
No.
Broccoli is good for you,
so let's get some more broccoli, Seo Yeon.
Should we buy ice cream, too?
Seo Yeon.
Where did she go?
Seo Yeon!
Seo Yeon.
What do I do?
That'll be 1,600 won.
Yeah, Mom. What is it?
Where?
Mom, where was your head at?
- What is it, honey?
- She lost Seo Yeon.
- What?
- Alright. Alright, Mom.
I'll go that way. Mom, mom!
Call Father, alright?
I'm sorry, there's been an emergency.
- Ho Shik!
- Yes!
Honey, I can't. I'm in the middle of -
Alright, it's fine.
Seo Yeon!
Where were you going to go?
Where?
Home.
This isn't the bus home.
You came out to buy groceries with Mom.
You should've stuck to her side.
How can you wander off like this?
What would've happened if
you got on the bus?
You'll forever be a hindrance to my mom.
Come here.
I said come here!
I'm going to go crazy.
What is it?
Hey!
Hey, hey.
I know it's because you're sick,
but please don't give my mom
such a hard time.
I heard you were dragging around
my mom for three hours yesterday.
You think it's easy for an elderly to walk
around during winter for three hours?
I found Seo Yeon.
At the bus stop, near the dermatologist.
It's here, here.
Home is this way, here.
You can understand what I'm saying,
what were you thinking when
you disappeared like that?
Tell me. Why did you?
Were you going to go home on that bus?
But that bus takes you to a
completely different place.
Seo Yeon!
You can't do this when we're out!
It's bad.
It's really bad!
Tell your father we found her.
Let's go, Seo Yeon. Let's go.
I'll get you some tea, Seo Yeon.
Just wait a moment.
You're cold, right?
My goodness! In this cold weather,
just where were you trying
to go by yourself?
Where did you want to go?
You probably lost her while you're chatting
away with someone from the neighborhood.
I wasn't chatting!
I took my eyes off her
for just a moment,
it was only for a moment when I was
picking vegetables, just a short moment!
That doesn't mean the same thing
won't happen again.
Let's not lose her for real and
all fall into a state of panic.
Tell my husband to buy a handcuff,
or tie a string around her wrist
when you go out!
What is it?
It's for your benefit,
for the benefit of all of us.
I told you not to treat her
like a mindless child!
What do you mean handcuffs?
You want to wash your hands?
Aunt.
What is it?
Who is she?
Why is she over there, looking at me?
It's... it's you, Seo Yeon.
It's you, you.
Look carefully, it's you.
It looks exactly like you.
This is a mirror,
and you're being reflected off
by that mirror.
Right. When you stand in front
of the mirror,
there's another one of you.
You're right, you're right.
Yeah, you're right.
I want to take a bath.
He said you already took one.
Your husband said that before
I came this morning,
you already took a bath.
They want us to take care of both its
functionality and what it symbolizes.
The two contradict each other.
It's going to be difficult.
But why is it two?
I made two of them
with the location of the sun in mind.
This one has a staircase in the center, huh?
That might be more practical.
Seo Yeon is deteriorating quickly,
fast enough to shock even her doctor.
Seo Yeon.
You have to eat soup with a spoon.
Here.
Like this.
You spoon it...
How about putting the rice in the soup?
Wait, wait...
Seo Yeon often flies into fits of anger,
and when she gets angry,
she's unable to bring it to a halt.
Nuna, I'll do it.
Our Ye Eun has so much pretty clothes.
Oh my!
You put this on top.
Put your hand through here.
There.
She still has a grasp of who she is.
And every time she faces
that wall and despairs,
in a deep corner of her heart she rages.
Unable to hold back, she explodes.
At times she vacuums the floors,
and even rushes saying
she needs to make the rice,
but she spends much of her time
with an open book,
looking again and again
at the same page.
At times, she starts sobbing.
On some days
she sleeps for the entire day.
And on others, she watches the orchestra
playing for the whole day.
Her aunt says that there's a difference
when I'm there and when I'm not.
She says that when I'm not there,
my wife is even more confused.
At some point, I'll have to start
working from home.
You eat so well!
Ye Eun must like it. Is it good?
Is it good? You're so nice.
- Let's have another bite.
- Wait a bit.
She's having trouble eating it
every time you feed her.
Really?
Should we take a rest?
Should we take a rest before eating?
There's only one spoonful left.
Ahjumma, there's only a spoonful left.
If we take a rest,
she may lose her appetite.
Fine, then. Feed her the rest.
Alright.
Here.
That's right. It's good, right?
It's really good.
I'll come back after I put the bowl back.
You're already done?
I boiled and dried the bottle correctly.
Did you come here to watch me?
No, I didn't.
We may be able to use these until
the day after tomorrow.
I see.
If the wedding hadn't been called off,
you would've been a mom, too.
That's right, isn't it?
Dad's here.
Ye Eun's dad is here!
Dad, Dad!
Did you have fun?
Did you behave well?
What is it?
- She peed on grandpa's pants.
- What?
Your dad was going to change her diaper,
and in that short period she did it.
You should've held it in a little, lady.
What did Father say?
He said I didn't change the diaper
earlier and blamed me.
I was busy making preparations for dinner.
Your father was lecturing
Ye Eun for a long time.
He said she should let us know if
she needs her diaper changed.
That it's more hygienic and feels cleaner.
He told her she shouldn't kindly
wait for us to notice.
Give her over.
- Are you going to go now?
- Yes.
- Hey, Hee Soo!
- Yes!
- You're here?
- Yeah.
- I'll take Ye Eun out.
- No, she's heavier than you think.
I know. It's okay.
She's not heavy.
She's not heavy at all, right?
Right?
When did you get here?
About two hours ago?
There are two types of bottles in there.
She eats it well.
Just give her half of the milk and
half of the other.
Alright.
Your mother is going to be angry with you.
What do you mean?
I just wanted to see Ye Eun.
Don't worry yourself for no reason.
I've met a person I'm thinking of dating.
I should congratulate you.
He's a pianist.
Mom likes him, too.
He's nice.
Yeah, I hope it works out well.
You two...
What are you two doing?
What is this?
Mom!
Why did you lie?
If you said you were going to exercise,
then you should've gone and exercised.
I heard you cancelled
your session yesterday.
Mom, Mom!
I remembered that all of a sudden.
We threw away the menu while we were
ordering lunch, and ran over here.
Even if I grab my head in frustration
and try,
I truly cannot understand you.
How could you have no anger?
Is that kid yours?
What connection do you two have
that you follow her around?
Go, Mom. Go, go.
- Hey, Ji Hyung.
- Yes.
You know she's an idiot, right?
Alright, my kid's an idiot
and you're so great,
that you stomped on her and
didn't even look back.
If you have even a shred of conscience,
don't you need to help Hyang Gi
go on her own path?
- Mother -
- Why are you accepting her?
You, and your mom, as well!
I'm going to go my own way.
Don't let your imagination run wild!
Ahjumma doesn't like it when I'm here,
she's worried about you.
Oppa doesn't like it, either.
I'm the one who wanted to come.
I wanted to see Ye Eun.
Don't get any misconceptions!
Don't say anything more and get in the car.
Hurry and get in!
Sorry, Oppa.
Ji Hyung.
Yes.
You-
It really worries us that Hyang Gi
still hangs around you.
You need to help us.
You don't need to worry, Father.
Neither Hyang Gi nor I have any intention
of giving you cause to worry.
This is the first time
I've seen Hyang Gi here.
I... want Hyang Gi to meet
a nice man and be happy.
You're being honest, right?
I can trust you, right?
Yes.
Alright, I'll trust you.
Then, I'll be going now.
Kid...
If you had just shut your eyes
for a moment,
it would've saved a lot of people
a lot of stress.
Do you know just how undutiful of
a son you are to your parents?
Yes.
What is it?
I'll do it.
Aunt will do it, Seo Yeon.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. I make the same mistake, as well.
I told you it's okay.
Aunt.
What is it?
I think Park Ji Hyung ran away.
What are you talking about?
He didn't run away. He went to work.
He'll be here soon with Ye Eun.
It's almost time.
This morning, after giving you a bath,
he went out to work at eleven.
Think back.
I don't remember.
No...
Yeah... I remember.
No... I can't remember.
I'm a liar.
Our Seo Yeon isn't a liar.
Our Seo Yeon is very honest, smart,
talented, kind, determined.
You don't have any bad traits.
You're such a great catch!
Why doesn't Jae Min come?
He came yesterday.
Oh... yesterday. Yeah.
Aunt.
What?
I've become really dumb, haven't I?
No, not at all.
You haven't become dumb.
You're exactly the same.
You've stayed exactly the same.
Don't worry.
I think... there are times that I disappear,
when I feel like I'm not myself.
Ye Eun's here, Ye Eun!
Where did you go off to?
Honey, I'm home.
Yeah.
- Have you been well?
- Yeah.
And you took your medicine?
Milk, green tea, yogurt and rice.
I ate it all.
- I love you.
- Me, too.
Tomorrow, I'll love you 5,200 times more.
Me, too.
Seo Yeon! Ye Eun, Ye Eun!
Hi.
- Let's go in.
- Hi.
Yeah.
One moment, okay?
Alright.
- You're going to sleep?
- No.
What did you do?
Just... nothing much.
The weather's nice.
Let's go for a drive tomorrow.
No!
Let's put the food in first.
Ye Eun, I'm going to put the food
your grandma sent into the fridge.
Don't cry. Don't cry, don't cry.
What's in here that's so heavy?
No wonder! It's heavy because of this.
She tries to avoid eating this.
We still have leftovers from
the last one they sent.
I'll make dinner, so you should
go home and rest.
Yes?
- Ji Hyung.
- Yes?
I went to the market before
and nearly lost her.
Just for a short moment,
in the time I took to put vegetables
in the cart, she somehow disappeared -
Where did you find her?
Myung Hee found her
about to get on a bus.
I don't think I should take her out
with me now.
This town's so small, we'd probably
be able to find her.
But what if she gets hit by a car?
I was terrified.
Why is she doing things she's
never done before?
Did you ask where she was going to go?
Home.
That's what she said to Myung Hee,
though it's a bus going to Eui Jung Boo.
And before,
she looked at herself in the mirror
and asked who it was.
She asked why she was looking
at her from there.
I was so shocked I nearly collapsed.
What do we do about this?
Why is she like that?
Why is she deteriorating so quickly?
What is she thinking?
I can drink it later.
Really? Should I leave it?
Yeah.
Seo Yeon.
What is it?
You can't go out by yourself.
I can't go out alone anyway.
In order to prevent me from going out,
you put that on the inside, too.
I don't know the code. I can't go out.
Aunt hides it from me so I can't see.
When you go out with Aunt,
I told you to stick by Aunt's side,
didn't I?
I know.
It'll be difficult
if you lose your way home.
I said I know.
Seo Yeon. You love me, right?
Do you think I don't?
Do you think I've forgotten
that I love you?
No, I wanted to make sure.
Even if I forget everything else,
I won't forget that. Don't worry.
Park Ji Hyung. My husband.
Ye Eun's father.
The person who loves me to death.
The person who is going up the mountain
with a cross on his back.
You can't give up, Seo Yeon.
For me, who you love...
For our Ye Eun, you can never give up.
I won't give up.
When I look at you, it looks like
you've already given up.
I think you've started to let go and
accept whatever happens.
It looks like you've given up.
Yeah. You're right.
I don't like being tired.
It's so difficult trying to
hold on and be alert,
you have no idea.
And even if I do, it doesn't mean
the inevitable won't come.
It keeps slipping out.
When I look at aunt and you,
I think, "Oh, I've made another mistake. "
I don't realize it while I'm doing it.
I realize afterwards that I've
done something wrong.
And I feel like going crazy.
But you still can't give up.
You can't just let things be.
The answer is already written.
Just because I hold out doesn't
mean it's going to change.
Those thoughts... push those thoughts away.
That's despair.
We... for you and I, our child,
every day is special.
Even if it's for just one day more,
I want you to stay as yourself by our side.
I want to, honey.
But I can't.
I can't do it.
No matter how hard I clench my fists,
I keep slipping through my fingers.
When I wake up, some days I don't
even recognize my own room.
The bathroom, living room...
It's as if
I'm seeing them for the first time.
I try to not let it show
and even that's hard.
I'm sorry, Seo Yeon.
I can't hurt with you. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, really.
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm sorry.
My wife said the answer is already written.
I know the answer is already written,
as well.
Wanting her to be Lee Seo Yeon
for just a day longer...
was no more than a selfish wish,
justified by love.
Yeah, my husband has such a bad cold.
I can't just leave him alone.
I'm not showing off the fact
that I have a husband.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
My daughter will be there with the money.
Yeah.
Oh, right.
Aren't you going to get insurance?
You never know what'll happen.
If you each get one...
Really? Six of them?
Hang up! Hang up!
I'm going to call my son and tell him to
send someone with the contracts.
Hang up, hang up!
Alright, hang up.
Son, it's mom.
I sold six insurance policies.
Yeah, to the members of our gathering.
Yeah, call Myung Hee
and send someone with the contracts.
No, I'm busy right now.
Ye Eun!
Ye Eun is here, Aunt!
If you're going to take her,
you should've said so!
I thought someone stole her,
I was so shocked!
Aunt, how could someone steal a child?
It's because I couldn't see her.
Ji Hyung said he was going to wash up,
and your sister doesn't even touch the kid.
You looked busy doing the dishes.
- What do you think your mouth is for?
- I'm sorry. I was wrong.
- Check her diaper.
- I just changed it five minutes ago.
She had a big one.
Who would take your clothes?
No one here would do that.
They're disappearing one at a time.
I'm not lying.
I'm telling the truth!
I'm not going to move one step
from this spot.
If I'm not here,
all my clothes will be stolen.
Who?
Who would take them?
The ahjumma outside,
in order to give them to her daughter.
Snap out of it.
What ahjumma?
She's your aunt! Your aunt!
How can you say that about your aunt?
Why are you getting angry?
What did I do wrong?
You... you're Lee Seo Yeon.
You're a writer.
You're Team Manager Lee Seo Yeon,
who was known for her competence at work.
This isn't it, Seo Yeon.
This isn't it.
I was wrong.
You're Lee Seo Yeon.
I'm Lee Seo Yeon. Did I say otherwise?
This is our house.
Your aunt is in the living room.
She comes every day in order to help us.
Moon Kwon didn't go to work today.
He's in his room.
There's no one here who would
take your clothes.
Right... let's go for a drive.
I need to protect my clothes.
Seo Yeon.
Drive... let's go.
I need to wear my clothes.
Move so I can take out my clothes.
No.
It's winter.
Wear something else.
This is Jang Jae Min.
Oh, yes.
You didn't pick up
so I sent a message instead.
Yes.
My mother's at a gathering right now.
No. Of course, not.
My mother said it was six people.
There may be more, though.
Yes.
Yes, goodbye.
Oppa.
What are you doing here?
I was going to go for a drive with
you guys and get some fresh air.
- I suggested we go together.
- What should we do?
- Should I follow or should we take one car?
- I called you over so you could drive.
Alright. You guys get in the back.
Let's go, Seo Yeon.
I know.
You're my guard in case I make a mistake.
I've been caught, Ji Hyung.
That's not it. You were angry that
Jae Min turned his back on you.
That's why I told him to come.
Why is the weather so stifling?
It's like Gotham City.
I'll start going now.
The driving won't be smooth for about
five minutes, just endure it.
Alright, let's go.
Where are we going?
Don't you remember?
It's the road you liked.
Really?
Look at the lake over there,
you'll remember.
I'm looking.
Don't you remember?
It's okay.
I like it because it's new.
Kiss me.
The guard is up front.
It's okay.
As if you're kissing a baby, kiss me.
More.
Do it more.
It's quaint and nice, right?
Yeah.
Let's go in.
It's delicious. Right, Oppa?
Yeah, eat up.
How did you find out about this place?
I came here quite a few times, with you.
Oh... you did.
We did.
Before we left,
she mistook Aunt for an
ahjumma for a moment.
They say the first thing they forget are
the things most familiar to them,
but I guess that's not necessarily the case.
For how long?
Just a moment.
A very short moment.
Seeing as how that road and
the hotel has been erased,
it's probably not far before
I'm erased, as well.
There have been two cases
when I also wondered if she didn't know me.
Won't the people closest to her
be the last to be forgotten?
Seo Yeon, what is it?
What?
It suddenly came to me.
I want to die
when the cherry blossoms bloom.
When the petals fall like flakes of snow,
it's sad and beautiful.
It's cold. Let's get in the car.
I'm not cold.
It's not cold.
it's not cold.
You must be cold, right?
That's it, right?
Right, I'm cold. I'm freezing to death.
It's so cold!
- Nuna!
- Seo Yeon!
Why are you yelling?
I was so surprised!
I'm going to faint...
Hurry and take it from her. Take it!
Nuna...
Seo Yeon, what is it?
This...
It's dangerous.
I know.
What? What were you going to do?
I wanted to give her a haircut.
I see.
I don't like her hair.
It's not pretty.
It looks stupid.
Alright.
Let's have it trimmed prettily tomorrow
at the salon.
You're not a hair stylist.
We should put this in the hands
of a professional, right?
Don't yell!
I don't like it when you yell!
Alright, Nuna. Alright.
Take her home.
You should go, Aunt.
Alright.
No, no.
Later, later.
You, come here.
Let's do acupressure on your arm.
His aunt over here,
although she's never raised a child,
she knows a lot of things,
and will be of great help.
So rest at ease. Leave her to us,
and you can concentrate on your treatment.
Yes, Mother.
I'll leave her in your hands.
If you want to see her,
you can come and see her at any time.
And Ye Eun can come here
maybe once a week.
Of course, she can come at any time.
When you want to see her,
just give me a call.
Even if I'm sleeping, I'll get up and
come here right away, alright?
Yes.
Thank you for being so understanding.
I know you're doing it because
I may make a mistake.
We're not doing it because
you're a danger to the child,
that's not it.
Yes.
What about the crib?
She needs to take the crib, right?
No, Seo Yeon said that she may
come over and need the crib.
She told me to leave it.
At times like that she seems fine.
Bye, Ye Eun. Take care.
Later, I'll tell you about your mom.
I'll tell you everything.
I'll tell you everything there is
to know about her.
Yes?
Ye Eun...
Ye Eun's leaving.
Seo Yeon...
Bye.
Take... care.
Aunt...
Please, please take care of her.
Yes, of course. Don't worry. Don't worry.
Here.
Let's go.
Ye Eun...
Ji Hyung, Ye Eun's car seat.
Oh...
She already left.
I can bring it over later.
Seo Yeon had been so indifferent
to our child,
to the point of where I wondered
how she could be so cold.
But for the first time
she placed her hands on our child's face,
and spoke to her.
"Good bye. Take care. "
My wife did not watch our child leave.
My wife smiles.
I don't know why she smiles,
or the meaning behind it.
Is it going to get infected?
Why does it hurt so much?
I was cleaning fish
and I got pricked by a bone.
They sent it from Bang Bae Dong.
Ahjussi, who are you
that you're eating at our house?
It's your uncle.
I'm your aunt and he's my husband.
Myung Hee and Jae Min's father.
Oh...
I see.
Hey, come out.
Come here. Talk to me.
I don't have friends.
Come out, okay?
Come out.
Seo Yeon.
Ahjummoni, Ahjummoni.
What is it?
There's some ahjussi in my room.
Chase him out. He won't listen to me.
He's your husband, Seo Yeon.
Husband. He's your husband!
I... got married?
You did. You even had a child!
Oh...
Aren't you going to work?
Honey...
Yeah, what is it?
Why are there so many people in our house?
It's so disruptive. Chase them out.
Alright, let's chase them out.
Burn it! Burn them all!
I love you.
Tomorrow,
I'll love you a million times more.
Thanks.
Moon Kwon.
Moon Kwon, where are you?
Moon Kwon is at work.
Oh..
Oh.
He got a job.
It's time for him to be at work.
Yeah, I know.
For long periods, Seo Yeon is
no longer Seo Yeon anymore.
Now, she doesn't read books.
She no longer recites poems.
For short periods she's Seo Yeon,
but then
she disappears somewhere else again.
She slips into her own world,
into her own game.
- How did you take this all out?
- Seo Yeon, please.
- Oh my goodness.
Since last week,
I've started going to the office
only once a week on Monday,
and have left most of the work
up to Representative Song.
Tada!
Look!
Seo Yeon, pretty, right?
The color's awesome, right?
That's right, it suits her
pearl-like skin perfectly.
It's from the mall. It's not cheap.
You want to try it on?
I'll put it on you.
Seo Yeon!
You're a bad witch.
Seo Yeon.
You're bad. You're really, really bad.
I was wrong, Seo Yeon.
I know I was wrong.
You're mean.
I was wrong.
Forgive me, Seo Yeon.
Seo Yeon.
Ahjussi, who are you?
I'm Lee Seo Yeon's cousin, Jang Jae Min.
Oppa?
Dad.
Oppa...
I'm home.
You must've gotten off early
from your part-time job.
From the company.
I know, company.
Have dinner first.
Yes.
Now all men have become ahjussi,
and all women ahjummoni.
The only one she remembers is Moon Kwon.
I've become an ahjussi, as well.
And even though
she doesn't really know who I am,
she understands that I take care of her,
and it's a relief she doesn't reject me.
- One second.
- Alright.
- Yes, Aunt.
- Listen!
Seo Yeon has disappeared!
- Did you go to the market?
- No, at home.
- Was the door open?
- No, no!
She must've fooled us!
I think she knew what the code was!
I saw her sleeping and went to clean
but when I came out,
she had disappeared!
Alright, Aunt. I'm going now.
I'm going now.
What were you doing?
Seo Yeon!
Ahjumma! Ahjumma!
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Stay here! You'll die!
- Do you want to die?
- Let go, let go!
Come to your senses, Ahjumma!
Seo Yeon!
What is this?
Take this off, take this off
and give it to Ji Hyung.
Here, put this on. Here.
What is this?
Here, here. Put this on.
Seo Yeon! Seo Yeon!
- Seo Yeon!
- What's wrong with her?
Seo Yeon!
You never know when the economy
is going to get better.
You've left everything to Seok Ho.
How long are you going to keep this up?
I do the minimum of what I must do, Father.
The problem is that you only do a minimum.
It's not even enough if you say
you do everything you can.
In this tough economy,
you set up a company and
only do the minimum?
Think of how much you are
inconveniencing your partners.
It would be better if you removed
yourself completely.
I actually suggested that,
but Seok Ho wouldn't hear of it.
They'll take care of it themselves.
You should be working hard
at your age. It's a waste.
Drink your tea.
From what your mother has said,
it looks like her condition has nearly
reached the last stages.
It's been a while since going
to the bathroom has become a problem.
You should stop suffering now.
It would be better to put her
in the care of professionals.
You've done enough.
I can't do that.
Your mother agrees with me, as well.
I promised her that I'd protect
her until the end.
- Ji Hyung.
- I'll do it. I can't agree to that.
Stop being so stubborn.
Don't suffer with a girl who
doesn't know anything.
Leave her with professionals, and you can
go about doing your own job.
Even if she doesn't know anything,
she's still mine.
She's Ye Eun's mother.
I can't leave her in the hands of another.
Please don't bring it up again.
You don't need to think of it so negatively.
Professionals will use their knowledge-
Stop.
I told you it wasn't going to work.
Ye Eun's up.
Ye Eun came out to see her dad.
Dad's here. You have to go to dad.
Let's go down.
Were you well?
Are you happy?
Look at Dad.
Peek-a-boo.
You know, Ji Hyung...
Yes?
I think it's time... for a diaper...
It won't be long before she soils herself.
Before... it's a relief I realized
what she was doing.
She was crouched there with
her clothes still on,
and was going to take care
of her business there.
Alright.
I'll talk to her again.
When she's in a good mood.
Yes.
What are you doing?
Seo Yeon, look at me.
Let's go to the bathroom together,
and put this on.
It's time for you to use this.
Aunt will have less of a hard time that way.
Seo Yeon...
Why should I?
Am I a baby?
Who are you?
Who the hell do you think you are?
Who do you think you are?
I'm Lee Seo Yeon!
- Yeah, I know.
- I'm Lee Seo Yeon!
Yeah, you're Lee Seo Yeon.
Lee Seo Yeon doesn't need such things.
- Alright, alright.
- Don't look down on me.
Don't look down on me!
Seo Yeon.
Don't do it.
Don't do it, Seo Yeon.
It's okay. Don't do it.
You don't have to do it,
Seo Yeon. Don't.
Don't.
[Lee Seo Yeon]
[I love you. I'm sorry. Thank you. ]
Say hi to your mom.
Mom.
Ye Eun's here.
I...
I still...
I still haven't, Seo Yeon...
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Main Translator: csnrain
Spot Translators: nysophia_x_ii, fore
Timer: starstruck
Editor/QC: PTTaT
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com