Thirty seconds and counting.
Power transfer is complete.
We're on internal power with
the launch vehicle at this time.
T minus 20 seconds and counting. All
the second-stage tanks now pressurised.
T minus 15 seconds.
Guidance is internal.
Twelve, eleven,
ten, 9...
Ignition
sequence starts.
Six, five, four,
three, two, one, zero.
All engines
running.
Lift off! We
have a lift off.
And so in 1972,
the Atlas Centaur rocket
blasted off from our planet,
a 4-stage rocket that launched a probe
way out into the blackness of space.
The probe would use the
energy from the sun and the
gravitational pull of our neighbouring
planets to cross our solar system.
That momentum would then carry it on into
the farthest reaches of the universe.
The mission, to find
intelligent life similar to ours
out there in
deep space.
The probe carried a tablet
which had inscribed on it the
image of us humans, a man and a woman,
and a map to locate us in the universe.
Stage four disconnects and our
probe is fired on its long journey.
The world wished
it bon voyage
and may it find a friend
out there in deep space.
Thank you so much. Thank
you. Thank you. Thank you.
Hey! Thank you very much. Thank
you. Thank you, nice to see you.
Welcome, ladies
and gentlemen.
When I interviewed Neil
Clarke for The Book Programme,
I knew he was
extraordinary.
Now, with the publication
of his brilliant novel,
reviewers agree he's joined the
ranks of Britain's immortals.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Neil Clarke.
Um, so I suppose I wanted
to start off by asking you
how did you manage such amazing
insight into the soul of modern man
and how do you know what
men and women really want,
just really the whole relationship
between humanity and the cosmos?
Yeah, well, I think
I probably achieved
that by looking into
my own soul, Catherine.
Um, I studied its flaws, its
potential, its urgent needs.
I listened to its
cries for help...
...and its yelps of
anguish and, um, I...
I spent five long
years in a book
which I hoped would throw open
the doors of human perception
and allow us to be engulfed in
a sense of our own futility.
Sorry about
this, it's...
Go watch TV.
Your dog
is barking.
My dog was barking because
you rang the doorbell.
I rang the doorbell because
your dog was barking.
-Your lease says no pets.
-Well, he is a guide dog.
-You're not blind. -I prefer the
term "optically challenged".
You're not optically
challenged, either.
Fiona, you live, like, three
floors up. I mean, I don't...
If you don't control
your bloody dog,
I am going to get it sent
to Battersea Dogs Home.
-Right? Hmm?
-All right.
Come on, Dennis, let's go
and evacuate your bowels.
Come on, Dennis.
-Hi, Neil.
-Hi, Catherine.
Hey, it's funny, I was
just dreaming about you.
-Really? -Yeah, you were presenting
me with an award for my novel.
-Oh, did you deserve it?
-Well, I was proud but humble.
-Have you finished it, actually, in
real life? -Absolutely, almost, yeah.
Cos last spring you
were on chapter...
-Yeah, I've renumbered them. In
fact, I've removed them. -Oh. -Yeah.
I find the whole concept of
chapters just gets in the way so...
Yeah. Yeah, no,
I can see that.
I want reading it to be like being
sucked into a giant vortex, you know.
-Like going on Facebook. -Like
Facebook, yeah. That's a good one.
"Like being sucked
into a giant vortex."
Dennis, why do you let me
say things like this, hey?
Come on.
Come on, Ray.
It's only 20 quid.
-No, I can't, Neil. -Yeah,
but it can't lose. -No.
I guarantee you a 50% return on your
money before the end of classes today.
So when do you make your move on
Miss Booker Prize downstairs, then?
Oh, I don't. Turns out she's a
bit literal-minded, no foresight.
Whereas me, I can see for
miles into the future.
A man needs a
woman, Neil.
-I've got Dennis.
-Dennis is male.
And he's a dog, in case
you hadn't noticed.
Yeah, well, I don't want
to complicate my life.
This is a tenner!
Walk!
Earth!
Accessing representative
images of earthlings.
Communication will be carried on in the
language of the species to be judged.
-I'm sorry, I'm not understanding.
-[speaking in French]
-Is that better, Kylie?
-Understanding you now, Sharon.
By the power invested in me by the
Intergalactic Council of Superior Species,
I hereby pronounce a destruction
order on the planet Earth.
With great respect, Sharon, we should
not pronounce a destruction order
before we've given these earthlings
a chance to prove themselves.
-They've penetrated intergalactic
space. -Maureen is right.
They're clearly not
a superior species.
Look at the way
they copulate.
If these earthlings can convince
us that they are superior beings,
then they may join our society. If
they cannot, we must eliminate them,
for the moral well-being of the
entire Intergalactic Community.
-Thank you for explaining it to me,
Sharon. -Not at all, Miss Barker.
No, Grant, I don't want to talk to you.
No, I don't want to see you, either.
We had a great time
last summer but it's over.
What part of over
do you not understand?
Thank you for
calling. Goodbye.
These questions of yours make it sound
as if I thought this bloody author
-can string two words together.
-But he can. It's a wonderful book.
Darling, didn't you read the memo?
We're doing a demolition job.
But it's the best thing he's
ever written. Everyone says so.
That's why we have to pee
on it from a great height.
I want ten new questions,
please, before noon.
Don't you know? She never reads
the books. She hates books.
Why is she presenting
a book programme, then?
I spy trouble.
Just...
Look, Catherine,
you may despise her ego, but
that's what people tune in to see.
Not books, not
authors, God forbid,
but Fenella's rampant,
pulsating, sexually arousing ego.
No, I think people watch because it's
a book programme and they love books.
Books are
finished.
Our job is to provide scandal,
gossip and character assassination,
with a thin veneer of
literary respectability.
-Oh, so we're not just selling out,
then? We've sold out? -Exactly.
For God's
sake, smile.
It's enough to make
you weep, isn't it?
-What? -The price of pickles. Don't
even look at the marinated herring.
-Honestly, you'd be suicidal.
-I didn't want them, anyway.
Thanks.
I also offer support and counselling
on dips, dried fruit and pasta sauces.
She's gone.
-The usual test, Sharon?
-The usual test, Kylie.
One earthling will
be chosen randomly,
as defined by the Intergalactic
Manual of Good and Evil.
-Page 56, paragraph B.
-Uh, page 56, paragraph D.
Uh, right.
To prove that they understand the
difference between good and evil.
How will they
prove it?
They will be given the power
that all superior beings have.
The earthling will be capable
of doing absolutely anything.
What if he uses
his power for evil?
The Earth will
be eliminated.
But if he uses
it for good?
Then we welcome them to the
Intergalactic Community.
Are we ready,
gentlemen?
Commencing random
selection of earthlings.
Processing...
-Earthling.
-Jolly good!
-Wait!
-Selected.
The earthling has ten
days to prove he can use
absolute power for good
rather than for evil.
God.
Screw you!
All they want me to
do is help them sneer
at people who
write wonderful books.
Well, my producer just wants me
to dig up dirt on Amenhotep III.
I keep telling them
he had a kind nature
and lovely hands.
I would have loved to spend
an evening with Amenhotep III.
Yeah, except he's been
dead 4,000 years, Rosie,
and he'd spend all day long
talking about embalming.
-Well, find me a good one that's
still breathing. -Tell me about it.
-What about Grant? -Oh, well, Colonel
Grant turned out to have issues.
-Issues? -Yeah, like
being clinically insane.
-Shame. -Maybe that's
overstating it.
Uh, just obsessive, possessive
and pathologically jealous.
-What about him upstairs? -Oh, he tried
to cheer me up in the supermarket.
-Oh, so he's
gay? -What?
Well, he's sympathetic,
interested, available.
-That's the way life works. -No,
he's not gay. He's... very likeable.
-Mr Clarke.
-Hi.
This is the twelfth time you've
been late this month, Mr Clarke.
-Yeah, I got knocked off my bike.
-Yesterday you had food poisoning.
Friday you thought
it was Saturday.
-Monday you forgot to put your clock
forward. -Oh, everybody does that.
Week last Wednesday it seems you had
an appointment with the Dalai Lama.
-Yeah, I showed you the picture. -That
had Michael Jackson in it as well.
Well, he's
a great man.
Great enough to appear in
photographs when he's dead.
You, Mr Clarke, are
totally irresponsible,
you are idle and
you are feckless.
-Feckless? -Yes, you
are without feck.
If I could replace
you, I would.
Yeah, well, so would I. I just don't
have anybody to replace me with.
Hello, gorgeous.
How about cocktails for two
this evening? Go halves?
-Drop dead, Ray. -All right.
Think about it and get back to me.
-Knob.
-Neil? -Yeah.
If you could do anything,
what would you do?
Hello, Neil, love. Tinned mouse
or fricassee of war victim?
-I will have the roast headmaster,
please, Mrs B. -You are a one.
-There you go.
-Thank you.
Uh, I'll have the
casserole, please, Mrs B.
You'll enjoy that, Mr Ray.
As long as you don't eat it.
No, I mean, if you could make anything
you want happen, what would it be?
I would make Dennis regurgitate
my notes from chapter three.
-If you could make something
impossible happen. -Intact.
What if you could make someone
worship the ground you walked on?
What, even if she thought
you were a little shit?
Come on, Ray. That would be taking an
unfair advantage of an innocent girl.
But suppose there was one thing you
could do that would change your life
-for the better? -Oh, that's easy. I
would make alien spaceships destroy 10C.
That sounded like it
was in the school.
Out of the way! Out of the way!
Stand back. Stand back, stand back.
Now, just
stay calm.
Oh, my God!
Who was that?
It was the Salubrious
Gat of Galaxy G946 WOT.
-Gat, what do you think you're
doing? -Just practising, Sharon.
We haven't done the judicial review yet.
We may not want to destroy this species.
Who are you
kidding?
445,349,722 new alien
species encountered.
Number granted membership
of the Intergalactic
Community of
Superior Beings? Zero.
-We have high standards. -You know
you're going to wipe them out.
It all depends
on the earthling.
And signs of a recovery
seem as far away as ever.
Hey. Hello,
Dennis.
Oh, Dennis. Couldn't
you have waited?
We can now go live to
our reporter Brenda Emmanus
at the scene
of the incident.
It was here at Kinbrook
Comprehensive School
that an explosion
killed 38 pupils.
A police spokesman said they could
not rule out a terrorist attack
but say there were no connections with
reports of a UFO sighting in the area.
The head
teacher Mr. Ro...
Oh, sure, Dennis, it
was an alien spaceship.
What are you
talking about?
If I could make an alien
spaceship destroy 10C,
then I wouldn't be farting
around with this, would I?
I'd just say, "Dog mess,
clean yourself up."
See?
It's just shock.
It's just post-hallucination
shock. That's all it is.
I mean, it couldn't have been
an alien spaceship, Dennis, could it?
I mean, it just,
I mean, it couldn't have.
Oh, my God.
That's my notes.
Ah, damn it!
Whisky, go back
in the bottle.
See? You see? There's
nothing. It's nothing.
There was nothing. It's nothing.
Whisky, go back in the bottle.
Oh, my God.
I have to
wave my hand.
Whisky, exchange yourself for
another bottle, a single malt.
Hey, come back!
Door, open quick.
Not that quick.
I didn't mean go back to
the shop to get exchanged!
It's closed.
Oh, shit.
-Gotcha! -Help
me, Dennis! -Gotcha!
-Priority.
-Help me!
Shh, Dennis, be
quiet. Oh, shit.
All right, laddie.
You're nicked.
Me be at home having
dinner with Dennis.
Oh, yuck! Chumzy!
You say one word about this, Constable,
you'll be on community relations.
Oh, my God. 10C!
Uh, let everyone who
died be alive again.
Oh, God. Oh, no.
No, no, no, no.
No, I meant everybody
in 10C be alive again!
Obviously. Not everyone who's
died ever. Are you crazy?
Shit. Shit.
And everybody who
died in the bomb blast
that is alive again,
be completely uninjured.
Oh, shit,
shit, shit!
Uh, okay, me feel better.
Oh, that's better.
Me have a really good idea
about what to do next.
Oh, that's a good idea. Um, let
the explosion never have happened.
No, I mean, if you could make anything
you wanted happen, what would it be?
I'm sorry, what?
If you could do anything,
what would you do?
That's very weird. I think
I just dreamt that I could.
-What? -Do
anything.
I dreamt that I
could just wave my hand
and say such-and-such
and it would happen.
-So what did you do? -I made
alien spaceships destroy 10C.
Good thinking.
I would make Dorothy Pringle
worship the ground I walked on.
You wouldn't
be so cruel.
Hello and welcome
to Book News,
the show where you get to know
what books are coming to you
and authors get
what's coming to them.
What's the truth under
publishers' blurbs?
Why do writers' photographs always
show them looking ten years younger?
You've come to the
right place to find out.
Our first guest tonight
is Mortimer Stanley,
whose latest novel is entitled
"What You See With Your Eyes Open".
Mortimer, your last novel was
published nearly ten years ago.
It got what they call "mixed reviews"
and sold fewer than 3,000 copies.
-What possessed you to write another
one? -Well, my wife was dying.
You were estranged,
weren't you?
Well, yes, but on her deathbed,
she urged me to write another book.
-Knowing that she would
never have to read it? -Well...
Fenella's complaining
that you didn't
tell her about his
shoplifting conviction.
Well, he was 14, James. It's
got nothing to do with his book.
Well, neither has
the show, Cath.
Listen, what upsets Fenella
about you is your integrity.
But me, I
quite like it.
Play your cards right, you
could get your own office
with a bigger
desk and a view.
Sorry. Excuse
me one second.
Mind you, you've gotta
play your cards right.
What the hell are
you doing here?
-Don't I get a kiss?
-Please go away.
That wouldn't be
fair to you, Cath.
This is a wonderful opportunity
for you to get to know the real me.
Well... I'm
calling security.
-No, not just the charming, high-flying
military strategist. -Hello, security?
Not the inventor of
extreme rendition, either.
Yes, I've got an
intruder in room 405.
Or the mastermind behind
warrantless domestic surveillance.
Just a humble officer
who adores you.
-Okay, Grant, I appreciate that
you like me... -Like? Like?
What do you think,
I'm one of these
cardboard cut-outs?
Like? No. No, no, no.
Adulate. Worship.
Okay, well, I don't adulate or worship
you. I don't even really like you.
So that's why I'm asking you to
just go away and leave me alone.
-So there's some hope? -No,
no, no. There's no hope.
Cath, I came all the way
to England to see you.
Doesn't that show you how
much I care about you?
No, it shows me
that you're obsessed.
-Obsession's not a quality
that I admire. -Really?
I think the lady wants
you to go, Colonel.
-You work for the
BBC, don't you? -I do.
You know who ultimately controls the
British Broadcasting Corporation?
A little guy that used to
work down the hall from me
at Fort Bragg,
North Carolina.
And he did it in
his spare time.
I'll catch you
later, honey.
It was a party. I was doing
a documentary. I was drunk.
Judging me.
Let 10C become a model
class, kind and considerate.
Oh, and eager
to learn.
-Good afternoon, 10C.
-Good afternoon, Mr Clarke.
Um, could you all turn to page 73,
please, and read the entire chapter?
-What, the whole
chapter? -Yes.
-Oh, good.
-How exciting!
-He's letting us read the
whole chapter! -Great.
Well, you get on
with it, then.
Let the headmaster be
nice to me for a change.
And what you did
with the guitar quite
beggars belief.
That is not how Kumbaya goes.
Neil. So good
to see you!
I love what you're wearing. It really
does, it's just a great ensemble.
So similar to what you
were wearing before.
But your laissez-faire
attitude to work is a
great counterpoint to my
by-the-book approach.
-Great having you on the staff,
Neil. -Thank you. -Right.
He must love you an awful lot
to fly across the Atlantic.
No, he just can't
bear losing anything.
As far as Grant's concerned,
I'm just a piece of lost
property he wants to retrieve
and put back on his mantelpiece.
He was really
scary. Crazy.
I had a boyfriend
like that once.
-The sort who wouldn't take no for
an answer. -Did you? What happened?
I married him.
Mr Eriksson, you know the romance
languages, French, Italian...
Yes, Miss Pringle,
I teach them.
Well, I was wondering
how they got their name?
It's to do with Rome,
ancient Rome.
It's from
the Latin.
So it's just a coincidence
that they sound so romantic?
Actually, I'm thinking of
switching to economics.
Let Miss Pringle
worship Ray.
Ray.
I can do abso-fucking-lutely
anything.
Me be President of
the United States.
-Thank God we found you, sir. -Sorry?
-We've been looking for you everywhere.
-Help! Help! Guns! They're
shooting! -Move, move, move! Move!
I am sorry about
that, Mr President.
Now, here are the briefing papers
for Syria, the deficit, Israel and
the Middle East, China,
global warming, unemployment
-and the Arctic Wildlife
Reserve. -They're shooting!
Me be my old
self at home!
I can do anything.
Okay, but what
do I really want?
Give me a
really big dick.
Ouch, not that
big, obviously!
Just... Dick, return
to the old size.
Okay, um... Let me have a
penis that women find exciting.
Yeah, it's good, yeah.
Can I have it in white?
Right, okay, um...
Let me have a
really great body.
No. Um, no, look, no, look,
give me the body of a great man.
What the fuck? Not
Albert Einstein.
Let me have the
great body of a man.
Me be able to see Catherine
from downstairs, now.
Shit.
Let me not be
able to see her.
No, I don't mean
me go blind.
Let me be able to see
but floor be as it was.
Uh, Catherine from downstairs,
forget what just happened.
You know earlier on we were talking
about being able to do anything?
-Oh, yeah. -Yeah,
well, um...
This is going to sound kind
of stupid but suddenly I can.
-Can what?
-Do anything.
Just make things happen.
Things that shouldn't
happen, I just wave
my hand and they do.
You feeling okay?
Yeah, um,
just look.
You, tell us
who you were.
You'll never believe this
but I was a conjuror!
I went by the name
of The Great Alfredo.
Real name was
Reg Hoskins.
I did variety, clubs,
private parties, the lot.
What is this? 3D projection
or something, right?
-Course, it's all gone now.
I blame the wogs. -Hey!
All that black minstrel stuff.
Once they started allowing that...
That's not me, that's
what I'm saying. It's...
Jews took over the business.
It was never the same again.
-Just go and jump out the
window. -Right-o. Watch this.
-How did you do
that? -I don't know.
I could swear it was
the skeleton talking.
-Yeah, it
was. -Okay.
-Let me see you do another one. -Well,
what? I can't think of anything.
Oh, come on. You know,
how about some flowers?
Bunch of flowers in
my hand. It's pathetic.
How about room
be covered in flowers?
Come on, Ray. Ray. Think of
something more imaginative.
Bloody hell, Palmer. Did you
just throw this out the window?
Neil. Did you throw
this out the window?
That's very funny.
What are you doing here?
Go on, get on home.
I'll cover for you.
Oh, my God.
-This is the best sandwich
I've ever tasted. -Told you.
You know what? We
could own a racehorse.
Ray, we could own every
racehorse in the world.
No shit.
-We win every time?
-They're all ours.
Let's forget about the horses.
We could have anything, Neil.
Wealth,
fame. Women.
We could make any woman
fall in love with us.
Neil, any
woman we want.
Jump in, babe.
Kerb crawling is illegal
in this country, Grant.
That doesn't really apply to
people with my security clearance.
-Besides, how else are you going
to get home? -On the Tube. Go away.
The London Underground is worse than
anything we ever did in Guantanamo.
-You don't deserve that. -No,
I don't deserve this, either.
-Please, leave me alone.
-Okay, okay, I get it.
-But you gotta let me down
gently, huh? -What does that mean?
Well, there's somebody
else, right?
No, Grant, that's not
what this is about.
You and I are
not compatible.
So, we could grab some
coffee, sit and talk.
What would that even achieve?
There's nothing to talk about.
Except for the luxury
apartment I rented for us.
It's got a view of
St Paul's Cathedral.
Oh, my God. Go
home, Grant.
-Here's the key. -I don't want it.
-And when I get you up there,
you're going to think you
died and went to heaven.
Fuck all TV
producers.
Especially ones that say
you can sleep with them.
But if I play
my cards right.
Why do I always end up
with the control freaks?
-Or gays.
-Yeah.
-Who? -Him
upstairs.
Oh, honey,
he's not gay.
He's attractive.
He's kind.
Well, then,
fuck him.
-No, he's nice. -No,
I don't mean fuck him.
I mean fuck him.
-You mean fuck
him? -Yeah.
-What, right now?
-No, not now.
You've got to let me
do your make-up first.
Malfunction. Galactic
power failure.
Bother, we'll have
to suspend the test.
-What? -This is on
the blink, Sharon.
The earthling won't have galactic
power until I get it working again.
Botheration!
I thought our galactic powers
meant we could do anything?
Catherine from downstairs,
be madly in love with me.
That was quick.
-Hi.
-Um, you're not gay,
are you? -No, no.
-Let's go to
bed. -Okay.
Oh, shit!
Ow, my leg!
-Got it. -Galactic power now
returning to earthling.
"Gone to get
ready for work."
Weather, be like it
is in Los Angeles.
I didn't mean be like it is
in Los Angeles right this
moment. It's the middle of
the night, for crying out loud.
Weather, be like it usually is in Los
Angeles during the day. So pedantic.
All right.
Clothes, get
dressed on me.
And smarten
yourselves up. Better.
Miss Pringle, this
really... has to stop.
-Oh, Lord.
Could you just stop that,
please? You, stop tapping.
Let's just have a break, shall
we? Just... Right, what's next?
This one's in
German. Wow.
Let me be able to understand
German. [speaking in German]
What are you talking
about, Dennis?
Look, just shut up,
okay? I can handle this.
She's not going to
ask me to marry her.
Or have my
children, okay?
Dennis, what are you talking
about? That's a good idea, actually.
-What are you talking about?
Dennis, be able to talk. -Biscuits.
-What?
-Biscuits.
Maybe if I make her fall in love
with me like a little bit, you know, so
-she doesn't want to marry me, but she
would have sex on a reg... -Biscuits.
-For crying out loud, they're
in the cupboard. -What are?
Biscuits. Red biscuits,
black biscuits.
-Nothing else matters. -Is that all
you think about? -Yes, yes! Biscuits.
All right, Dennis, become a
rational, thinking creature.
I just can't concentrate on anything
until I've had one of those biscuits.
I know it's crazy but that's how it
is. I guess I'm kind of hooked on them.
So please give me
just one biscuit, then
I'll be able to think
about something else.
-That makes sense.
-Oh, oh, oh! He's getting
the biscuits!
He's getting them! This is it!
He's got them.
He's got them. He's going to throw one.
Get ready, get ready. Here it comes.
God, it must be
terrible being a dog.
I never realised you
had so many cravings.
It's no worse than
you and that bitch.
-What bitch? -The bitch you
were shagging last night.
Oh, my God. She's not a bitch,
okay? She's a lovely human female.
And we weren't
just shagging.
Right. Come to think of it,
I wouldn't mind shagging your
leg right now. A little leg dance,
huh? Just above the sock.
-Ah... -How about
it? Come on, Daddy.
I thought I turned you into a
rational, thinking creature.
Rational, thinking creatures
still have desires.
-Oh, well, we can soon
deal with that. -No!
-No, no, don't take my desires
away from me. -Why not?
They're what makes my life worth
living. Biscuits, shagging.
I don't think I like
your conversation.
But I worship you, master.
I love you so much.
-I can't bear displeasing
you. -I... I know.
-My whole world collapses when
you're cross with me. -I know.
Look, maybe it was better
when you didn't talk.
Oh, no, don't take away my power of
speech now that I can think rationally.
-That would be so cruel. I heard the
bell. Somebody at the door. -Okay, no...
-The bell! Hey! The bell! -No,
no. Dennis. Dennis, good dog.
-Hey, somebody. There it goes
again. -Dennis... Just quiet.
Somebody at the door. Oh, no, have
I done something wrong again?
No, just... Just be quiet.
Do you understand me?
Yes. Yes, anything to stop
you being angry with me.
The bell! There it goes
again! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Dennis, listen. Just listen,
listen, listen, listen.
-Be quiet. That is an
order. -Right. Quiet.
I like obeying orders,
especially your orders.
Good. Well, then,
shut the fuck up.
Right, right. Shut the
fuck up. Yeah, right.
Good boy.
Oh, God, I made her do it. I
made her do it... I... okay.
-Hi.
-Hey.
-Can I come in? -Yes,
yes, yes, yes, of course.
-So, look, um, about
last night... -Yes.
-Is this a bad time?
-No, no. No, no.
Okay. Um, I just... I don't
want you to think
that I, um, do that
sort of thing all the time
because...
Because I don't.
-Um... I was slightly drunk.
-Yeah, well, I mean, naturally.
Otherwise we probably wouldn't
have done the thing with
-the beard trimmer. -No, that's not
what I mean. I mean, I like you.
I've always really
enjoyed talking to you.
I just... I probably wouldn't have
jumped on you like that if I hadn't...
-Been pissed as a
newt? -Well, sort of.
Yeah, okay. Well, then, let's just
forget it. It never... happened.
No, no, no, that's not
what I'm saying, Neil.
-Oh, well, um, what did you
want, then? -Shag her, Neil!
-That's Dennis. -Dennis?
-Yeah. He is a plumber.
Um, I'm having a few problems with
my waterworks. My water pipes.
Shag her, Neil!
I'd better get him the shagger. It's
a special wrench that plumbers use.
-I thought I told you
to shut up. -I'm sorry.
-I'm really sorry. -You're supposed
to be a rational, thinking creature.
Sorry, sorry. Can't help myself.
Sorry. Oh, dear. I wanna shag your leg.
Shh. It's not a great time, to be
honest. Maybe later, if you behave.
Oh... Couldn't find the shagger,
so he just went with the old decoupler.
-I love you, Neil!
-Shut up, Dennis!
It's odd, isn't it, shouting
at the plumber like that?
But, uh, the fact is he's my
brother. The plumber is my brother.
Say you love
me, Neil.
-And we're very close.
-God, Rosie was right.
-Rosie? -Please can
I shag your leg?
-Jesus, Neil, how could you?
The next morning! -What? I...
Why do I always
end up with creeps?
-I'm not a creep! -There was a
cat, Neil! Neil! Hey, you, cat!
Stay out of my garden, go
on! Neil, it's a ginger tom!
Dennis, be a dumb animal
again for five minutes.
So she thinks I'm gay. I
mean, so what, you know?
I mean, it means that she won't
want to marry me or have my kids.
Bingo. Problem solved.
Thank you, Dennis.
Catherine!
Um, me be
on the bus.
Ah! I don't mean on the
bus. I mean in the bus.
Not in the engine. In the
passenger accommodation!
Catherine!
-Ray. -You've gotta
stop Miss Pringle.
She's... She's set up shrines all over
the school. There's even a website.
-Look, you wanted her to worship
you, okay? -Not like this.
-Ray, I don't have time for this.
-You haven't lost the powers, have you?
-No, I haven't lost the powers. Ray.
-You have. You've lost...
-I haven't lost the powers. -Do
the thing. -Ray, become a duck.
Ray. Ray, stop it. Ray, stop it.
Ray, stop it. Ray, become a sausage.
-I haven't lost the powers, Ray,
okay? This is... -Where is he, Neil?
Oh. That's his car.
-Oh. Behold the car
of Ray! -The car of Ray!
-Catherine, can we talk?
-No. -But I love you.
You also love
Dennis, apparently.
-Did you take that off there? -Uh,
no, this is mine. -Yours? -Yeah.
Look, you've got it
all wrong about Dennis.
I've nothing whatsoever
against Dennis.
You love him, he loves you.
I'm happy for both of you.
Just don't
bring me into it.
Yeah, no, but there's something
I need to tell you about Dennis.
You are going to have to pay for
that now that you've touched it.
-It's mine! -No, it isn't. -Look, I
heard what you said to each other, Neil.
Look. There's something crucial about
Dennis you don't know. He's not a man.
I don't want to
hear this, Neil.
I know, but I'm just
saying, he's not a man.
-Ow! Ah! Hell's tits!
-You pervert! -Ow!
-You come in here and steal our stuff?
-I told you, that's not your sausage.
-It is my sausage.
-Get off. -Give it back.
-Be careful, be careful.
-Just let go! -Oh, God!
-Give me
80p. -Fine.
-I'll just get your change.
-No, it's... Never mind. It's...
-Well, no, cos it's
4.20. -Keep it.
-It's too much for a tip.
-Have it your way.
-I should think so,
too. Jesus. -Feck.
Sausage,
become Ray.
Jesus, Neil. Have you any idea
how vulnerable a sausage feels?
-There he
is! -I'm off!
-Leave me alone, you nutters!
-Ray! Ray! -Here you go.
You must have
been hungry.
It's clear he has no idea of
doing any good whatsoever.
Why can't we just get
on with the destruction?
Because there are
rules, Maureen.
We must follow
galactic procedure.
Rules didn't stop you from eating
the inhabitants of G4378, Janet!
They were delicious. Very
crunchy, as I recall...
-Surprise, surprise! -Oh, my God!
No! -Wait. Wait, wait. Catherine!
You're crazy, do
you know that?
-Crazy in love, darlin'.
-Get out of my flat, Grant.
Well, I can't because
you've locked the door now, babe.
Well, then, get out
the way you got in.
Oh, honey, come on,
now. That ain't nice!
Just get out, Grant. I
never want to see you again!
Get out of my
life! Get out!
Come on, now,
open the door.
Sorry. Sorry
about the noise.
-At least it wasn't
barking. -Feck off. Not you.
-Walk out the front door, okay?
-Honey! -Then sneak in the back.
Then climb up to my place.
No moves, no funny business.
-You can just stay out of his way and
I will make you dinner. -Love me!
-I hate doors! -All right. But invite
Dennis. We'll behave like grown-ups. -OK.
-Catherine? Catherine,
come back. -I'm leaving!
Okay. I'm coming! Hold
on. Wait for me, now.
She's coming
to dinner!
-This episode looks at doggy fantasies.
-Whoa. Hey! It was just about to start.
-She's coming to dinner. -Who?
-Catherine. -Oh, the bitch.
Don't call her that, all right? I don't
want you chipping in, either, okay?
-Just pretend to be a dumb
animal again. -Me? A dumb animal?
Well, you know how to pretend, don't
you? It's just... It's called acting.
Oh, you mean like when I'm
having my tummy tickled?
-You love having your tummy
tickled. -No, I don't.
-What? -It's a sham,
Neil. All dogs do it.
-Why? -Why do humans like
tickling dogs' tummies?
Because they love having
their tummies tickled.
Uh-uh. Dogs pretend to like it because
they know human beings like doing it.
Well, just pretend to be a
perfectly ordinary dog, okay?
-Can't I join in the conversation
just a little bit? -No.
That is so cruel.
Somebody at the door! Hey!
It's the bell! It's the bell!
-I know it's the bell,
Dennis. -Right. No, no, sorry.
Just one more peep out of you, okay, and
the flea collar is going back on again.
Right, right, right.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
-Bark.
-Woof.
-Do it properly. -Woof! -Yeah,
good. Okay, thank you. -Got it.
-Hi. -Has he gone?
-No, I don't think so.
-Ooh!
-Dennis, down.
-You named him after the
plumber, then, did you? -Uh...
Ah. Do you want
your tummy tickled?
Why do dogs like
that so much?
I don't know.
So the producer promises to take
me out of the general office
and give me a big desk
with a view, but he won't.
He's just trying
to get me into bed.
What did you
want to tell me?
Uh, just try
this first.
Oh, that's
incredible.
That's the most wonderful thing
I've ever tasted in my life.
Mmm. I had no idea you
were such a fantastic cook.
I've... I've... It's unlike anything
I've ever tasted. What is it?
I just said, "Let the soup be
the most amazing thing Catherine
has ever tasted, unlike
anything she's tasted before."
-And it is.
-Really? -Really.
I can make things
happen. Anything.
That's what I was trying to
tell you this morning, you know?
I wasn't talking to a live-in homosexual
plumber. I was talking to Dennis.
-The dog?
-Dennis the dog.
-Who answered you back? -Yeah,
because I made him talk.
-Oh. -With
my powers.
Special powers?
I mean, what, you... You want
a bigger desk? You got it.
You want a great
view? You got it.
Um... Neil, how long have
you had these special powers?
-Well, they came upon me very
suddenly. -Very suddenly?
Yeah, I was knocked
off my bike.
Just ask me to do something,
anything. Just, you know...
-Listen, Neil, it... It's okay. You can
get help with this. -Son of a bitch!
-Shit, Grant! -I'm out of here!
-There's nobody else, huh?
-Who is this guy?
-She didn't tell you?
-I'm her fianc. -You're
not my fianc, Grant.
-Yeah? And you weren't just making out
with this apology of a man? -Stop this.
You know how long you'd last
on a battlefield, soldier?
-I'm sorry,
Neil. -That long.
-I'm warning you.
-You're warning me?
-Yeah, I'm warning
you. -Who is this guy?
-Why don't you suck on
this, asshole? -Grant!
All I have to do is go like
this and... And say what?
-Where did you find this
fruitcake? -Put that away, Grant.
Uh, what can I say?
Grant, become a fairy?
It's Grant,
not... Grant.
-Stop it. -And you're
the goddamn fairy.
How about Grant go back
to where you came from?
-It's Grant. -How about kiss my arse,
Grant? -Neil, don't. He's crazy.
How about you say, "Please, Grant,
don't put a bullet through my brain?"
-Grant, stop it! -I prefer,
"Let all bullets bounce off me."
-Go on, shoot me. -Oh, my
God. You're both crazy.
-He doesn't dare.
-Neil, please, please.
Go on, pull the trigger.
What's the matter, "Grant"?
-Shut up. -Go
on, shoot me.
-Neil, he will. -No, he won't.
-Yes, I will. -No, you won't.
-Grant, drop the gun.
-You little shit!
-You're idiots, both of you. -I
wouldn't do this if I were you.
"I wouldn't do this if I were
you." God, I hate the English.
Let Grant's arm break if
he tries to throttle me.
Shut up.
It's Grant!
-Help! Help! Help!
-Who the heck was that?
Uh, that's Dennis.
It's just a dog!
English dick.
-Shit! Shit! What happened? -Yeah,
yeah. Do you want me to make it better?
-It hurts. -Grant's
arm be better.
-Hey. Hey, hey, hey. Hey, what is
this? -Grant be stuck on the ceiling.
-Oh, shit! -Grant be
plastered to the wall.
Wait, wait, wait.
Let's talk about this.
Grant be buried head
first in the plant pot.
What do you mean,
potted plant?
Grant be standing
in front of me.
Yeah. You wanna be nice to me,
Grant, okay? Maybe I can help you.
-You? -I could make your
life absolutely hell
or I could say, "Grant be
holding a million dollars."
-Or I could say, "A million
dollars, disappear." -Fuck! Come on!
I can do anything. All I
have to do is wave my hand.
-You gotta wave your
hand? -That's right.
Isn't he great? I love
you. I love you so much.
-Dennis, keep out of this.
-But you are great, Neil.
-You can do anything. -Dennis,
shut up. I'm not... -Master! Neil!
Hi. Made your
mind up yet?
-How about tonight?
-Good girl.
-8:00, my place. -Yeah. I always
pick the wrong guy, anyway.
Oh, and, uh, I got
you a new desk.
Well, it's about
time. Now, listen up.
When I take that gag
out of your mouth,
you're going to say exactly what's on
that piece of paper, you understand?
The moment you say a word that is not
on that piece of paper, I kill the dog.
-Don't let him shoot
me, Neil. -Understand?
Nod if you
understand.
Okay. Okay. I'm going to take
the gag out now. Remember,
one wrong word and
the dog gets it.
Okay, read. Item number
one, let's go. Come on.
"Item number one.
All pasty white Englishmen..."
"Pasty white Englishmen to get
big ears and webbed feet?"
-Now wave your hand.
-What? -Wave your hand!
Yes! Yes! Oh,
it's beautiful.
Neil!
-You don't worship
me, do you? -What?
Ray. You're Ray.
-I can't find Neil. -Isn't he
here? -He wasn't at school, either.
Oh, I left him with my crazy,
gun-toting ex-boyfriend.
-Neil's got these powers.
-No, I know, I know.
He got Miss Pringle to... To worship me
and now she's turned me into a religion.
-They think I'm
immortal. -So what?
They want me to prove it
by rising from the dead.
-We've got to
find Neil. -Wait.
Hey! Hey!
What are
you doing?
Got it.
-Where's your car? -Why?
-I know where they are.
-It's just out here.
We can... Shit! -Lord.
Oh, no.
Run for it!
Get him! Lord!
This is working beautifully. Okay,
keep going. Number three. Let's go.
Okay. "Three. All British
police to have pink uniforms."
My personal
favourite.
What's this
all about?
There he is!
Oh, it's beautiful. I can't believe
it. All right, next one. Come on, read.
"Let all traffic lights be
permanently set on green."
-Come on. That's just...
-Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Huh? Do it, do it.
Wait. Now, listen.
Grant, are
you in there?
Skip to the end. Hurry
up. Just skip to the end!
Skip to the end. Just...
There. Come on, quick.
-Read it. -Uh, uh... okay, okay,
"Item 417, Catherine West..."
-Come on. -All right.
-Let them go, Grant.
Why should I? Go on,
Neil. Read the last item.
"Item 417, Catherine West be madly,
deeply in love with Col. Grant Kotchev"
"and leap on him like a
tigress begging for sex."
-You bastard. -Now, come on,
now. Wave your hand. Come on.
-Neil, don't! -Or
the dog gets it!
-Don't let him shoot me, Neil.
-Come on, wave your goddamn hand!
But I don't want to love him, Neil.
I don't want to go anywhere near him.
I don't wanna die.
-Grant, I love you. Please, please,
let's have sex now. -Oh, yeah.
-Dennis, be free.
-I'm free! I'm free!
Please.
Uh, uh,
-Grant become a corgi! -What? Oh, shit.
-Do it. Do it, Grant. Do it, do it.
-Me be free.
-Yes, yes!
Master. You chose to save
me rather than that bitch.
Yeah, don't
call her that.
Catherine be her normal self
and not in love with Grant.
And all Grant's
wishes be cancelled.
-Ray! -Oh, shit.
Oh, no. Get off me!
-Neil, stop them! -Lord,
show us how to conquer death!
Dorothy Pringle, think about
Ray the way that you used to.
-What the hell, Ray? -It
was nothing to do with me.
Get lost,
you creep!
-Thank you. -Everyone
else, forget about Ray.
Thanks, Neil. Thanks
a whole bunch.
-Ray, could you take
me home, please? -Sure.
I'm... I'm
sorry...
-Any thoughts?
-Pathetic!
He has no concept
of good or evil.
Well, the dogs
seem all right.
Yes, yes, the dogs are all right.
It's the people I can't stand.
Oh, hey.
Catherine, hi.
Hey, sorry about the
other night. It was...
-Can I cook you supper?
-Uh, no, thanks, Neil.
-I'm doing a whole
suckling pig. -No.
Hey, what's the matter? Is it because
I made you throw yourself at Grant?
No. Look, you did what you had
to do. It worked. Forgotten.
Well, what
is it, then?
Do you know what it feels like
to be in someone else's power?
To have no
will of your own?
Look, I thought that
I made you love me.
-What? -You know,
with my powers.
Oh, my God. Did I really
come home early
tonight because I wanted
to or did you make me?
Have I always lived opposite you or
have you somehow rearranged things?
-I'm never going to
know. -Look, I love you.
How could any woman love a man who
could make her do whatever he wants,
any second, every
day, forever?
Look, I'm sorry, Neil, I could never
love you, not in a million years.
Catherine!
Sharon, Sharon,
terrible news!
This is indeed
grave news.
It appears that the
Salubrious Gat has been
interfering with our
translation devices.
What's he
done, Sharon?
I'm afraid, Janet, that we
have been calling ourselves by
foolish-sounding earthling names.
Female ones, at that.
It seems that Sharon is particularly
favoured among female earthlings from
Australia.
-The shame of it. -Sharon... I mean,
what should we be calling you?
Call me the Death-Dealing
Darkness-Bringer.
Yes, oh,
Death-Dealer.
-Great waffles, master.
-Who cares about waffles?
Catherine hates me. Ray
hates me. Everybody hates me.
I don't hate you and
I care about waffles.
I think I like them even more
than biscuits, even red biscuits.
You know what the worse thing
is, Dennis? This is all my fault.
You know, I was just thinking
about myself, what I could get.
And yet with these powers,
you know, I could
have solved every
problem in the world.
-I could have made people happy.
-You couldn't make Catherine happy.
Yeah, because I wanted her to love
me. You know, I was being selfish.
I mean, take world
hunger, you know? Uh...
Let everybody in the world
have as much food as they want.
I mean, take homelessness. Let everybody
in the world have somewhere to live.
No, no, no, live in
their dream house.
And war, senseless
war, over forever.
-Let there be no reason for anyone
to make war on anyone any more. -Yeah!
Oh, and reverse
global warming.
Has it happened?
The latest nation to succumb
to the sudden mysterious
exponential growth in world
food supplies is China,
where the average weight is
now 300 pounds and rising.
Well, today a party of picnicking
schoolchildren brought down
a mile-long section of
the Great Wall of China.
As homelessness becomes
a thing of the past,
the last undeveloped
area of the Sahara Desert
has become a gated community
known as Beau Geste Towers.
Property developers are now
converging on Antarctica.
-At least I got rid of war. -That was a
good one. "Let there be no reason to
-...make war..." -"To make war on anyone
any more." How could that go wrong?
-For no reason at all, New Zealand has
declared war on Iceland. -Oh, dear.
Barbados has declared
war on Somalia.
And in a surprise move, the tiny
island of St Kitts and Nevis
has declared war on the
entire rest of the world.
Our war correspondent says
he is unavailable for comment
because he's too busy covering all the
other wars which have just broken out
for no reason
at all.
A short time ago,
scientists were afraid
of constantly rising
global temperatures.
-But none of them have any
explanation... -Oh, my God.
-...for this sudden
return... -Global warming.
...not only to the
last ice age but to a
snowball Earth of half
a billion years ago.
On the other hand, plans
to turn the Antarctic
into the Captain Scott gated community
have been put on hold... -Shit!
Shit, shit, shit!
Oh, it's not so easy
trying to do good, is it?
Yeah, but this
is just unfair.
Let everything go back to
how it was before I started
trying to make everything
better for everybody.
Beautiful though the
Earth looks from space,
we all know how fragile it is, how much
damage human beings have done to it
and will, it seems,
continue to do to it.
Absolute power doesn't corrupt.
It just drives you bloody mad.
Tell Catherine
I love her.
Don't do it,
master. I love you!
I've made arrangements
for your biscuits.
You'll never have to
worry about them again.
-You're the kindest master. -Just
shush, okay? I can't concentrate.
Master, don't
you love me?
I can't stand it, Dennis. I just...
I can't stand the responsibility.
-You need to get that into
your stupid dog brain. -Neil!
I'll save you,
master. Here I come!
Oh, wait a second.
I can't swim.
Master, help! Woof! Help!
Help! Oh, dear. Woof! Woof!
Bless you! Bless you,
master! Bless you!
-You do love me, master. -Of
course I love you, Dennis.
I just don't
love myself.
Time's up! Prime the
Destruction Generator.
-Hang on. -What? -We need to
check if he's passed the test.
Well, he did start
all those wars.
-That was good. -But then he
stopped them all. -But why?
He said he was trying to make
things better for people.
That's very
appalling.
The only good is to destroy.
The only evil is weakness.
Weakness must
be annihilated!
Agreed. Vaporise the earthling
and his wretched planet.
I told you so.
Reprime the
Destruction Generator.
Try her again,
Neil. Go on.
She... She
won't have me.
-Then, give up the
powers. -I can't.
Then, give
them to me.
You wouldn't have the powers
but you'd know where they were.
And being a dog, all I want
to do is follow orders.
I'll do what
you tell me to.
-Dennis, you're a
genius. -Not bad, huh?
Destruction Generator already charged,
Death-Dealing Darkness-Bringer.
Commencing
destruction.
It is a curse that our numerals
take so long to pronounce.
Uh, yeah, it's like, uh, you
just wave your hand, like that.
-I feel it. Wow!
-Yeah. There you go.
So what's it going
to be? Biscuits?
But the power made
you miserable.
Yeah, but I don't have
them any more, do I?
Look, tree become
Eiffel Tower.
See?
What are you
thinking, Dennis?
-Forgive me, master. -What? Wait,
wait. What are you going to do?
That's the
only short one.
If I have any power, let the source
of that power be destroyed, forever!
All this marking be suddenly
finished and neatly stacked up.
Fiona Blackwell,
go away.
Fiona! How lovely
to see you.
Hey, great news. I
got my sight back.
Hey, I think I
hear Catherine.
-Catherine.
-Hi. Hey. Um...
Look. Letters
become cucumbers.
Us be on the prow
of the Titanic.
I got rid of
the powers.
I'm impressed.
Yeah. So I thought maybe we
could have some dinner sometime?
-Yeah, maybe,
yeah. -Okay.
-How about tonight? -I'll
be down in half an hour.
We're going out to dinner. I'll
bring you both back a doggy bag.
I suppose I'd better
keep my mouth shut.
-Turn me back, Den. -I
can't. I like you as you are.
-Those stubby legs. Look at
you. -I'm not a dog, I'm a man.
Hey, nobody's
perfect.
This is chewing a
biscuit, boss. I'll try
and give you that right now,
hold one second.
Oh, red biscuit.
Great. No! No!
-Oh, got it. -Licking.
Licking somebody.
This is like porn.
Now a shagging noise.
Oh, look. There's
the red bit.
-Oh, there, oh, right, oh...
I'm done. -Okay, great.
That's enough chewing biscuits
for fucking half an hour.