The Ballad of the Salty Sea
The Map of the Pacific Ocean.
Once I didn't know how to read it.
My name is Pandora,
Pandora Groovesnore
I met Corto when I was a child.
It was November 1913,
precisely the first of November.
On that day I saw Corto
Maltese for the very first time.
Now I'm a good man's wife.
But when my cousin
Cain comes to visit me,
we always draw out this
map, ruined by the sprays
of salty water and by time.
We unfold it slowly,
almost ceremoniously.
We think back of that
adventure we like to call
our ballad.
We simply say "the ballad"
but it was the turning
point of our lives.
Nothing could tear us
apart, my cousin and I.
We were castaways, lost in
the middle of the Pacific,
surrounded by mysterious islands
and adults we couldn't understand.
The First World War
hadn't been declared yet,
and it seemed to me
as distant and unlikely
as the day when I would turn twenty.
Yet, on board of terrible
Captain Rasputin’s catamaran,
which had rescued us,
no one would have bet a bottle of rum
on the chances of the peace.
On the other hand, nobody wished for it.
Everyone wanted that war:
pirates, sailors, soldiers and spies.
Cain had succeeded to
determine with precision
the exact point where we
had crossed Rasputin’s route,
between the 155° meridian
and the 6° parallel,
and also the point where, after a while,
we were rescued by a Dutch boat.
He told me that during
the first months of the war
a part of the Pacific had
been under the Germans
but thanks to the Japanese, the Allies
succeeded in getting rid of the Prussians.
Cain gets excited when
he recalls Pitcairn.
That island is so small it
doesn't appear on the papers
and it's there that in January 1790
the mutineers of the Bounty, led
by Lord Chief Fletcher Christian,
chose to hide together
with some Tahitian women.
That story was told him by Corto.
It still makes him daydream.
We always think about the "Escondida",
the hidden island,
the Monk's island,
our mysterious island.
Our "ballad" lasted longer than a year,
the year 1914,
a year when everything changed:
the world, its frontiers
and two youths, Cain and me.
But no, nothing has changed.
The Pacific is always the biggest,
the most violent, the most indifferent.
As calm as a lake
or as violent as a volcano.
I'm the Pacific Ocean,
I'm the biggest of all.
But I'm not always Pacific.
I've just calmed down,
but yesterday I dusted away
three or four islands
and a bunch of nutshells.
I wonder how this one could make it.
Perhaps because captain
Rasputin knows his business,
perhaps because his
sailors come from the Fijis,
or maybe because today is "Tarowean",
"the day of the surprises".
Old pig!
Wild cat!
Don't you dare touch me!
And that's how you thank
the man who risked his life to save
the two of you?
Cain! Is he alive?
Captain Rasputin! Come, quick!
They're calling me,
but first I want you to understand this:
on this ship, the only one who can
lift his hands against others is me.
Captain Rasputin!
That's Corto Maltese.
Last time his boat was bigger.
Obviously this could be a good
occasion to get rid of him,
but the Monk would not agree.
One day or another one I'll make you
shut that big mouth of yours, Cranio.
Forever.
And so, Corto,
are you sun tanning?
Among all the sharks in the
Pacific I had to meet you...
Given your situation,
you should be more polite.
What happened to you?
Help me get on board.
We'll speak later.
You aren't being very nice, you know...
I could also leave you there.
Of course you could,
but then you'd never hear my story...
Come on, pick him up!
So?
How did you lose your ship?
Give me a drink.
It's me who gives the orders here.
Help yourself.
So, Corto, will you tell me or not?
It's a love story Rasputin,
a story of love and honour.
A long time ago I made
a promise to a girl.
The promise was sincere,
but crazy.
The girl was beautiful.
It looks like
my boatswain
was her brother.
He set my men against me.
They took up arms...
And they didn't kill you?
Damn savages! They always
leave things half-done.
Maybe they want to try
their luck as pirates.
We cannot blame them.
After all they've learned it from us.
At least I know how to restrain my men.
Now what? Why are you
looking at me that way?
You have a tired face, mate.
Try and sleep with both eyes shut.
Maybe you'll get sweeter.
And who are you?
Pandora Groovesnore, sir.
Groovesnore?
From the family of the
famous ship-owners from Sydney?
Thaddeus Groovesnore is my father.
Who did that to you?
Your friend the captain.
Friend is a big word.
Let's say we have
some business in common,
at the moment.
Is that what we were waiting for?
Yes.
Where are the youths?
Downstairs, in the cabin.
How strange,
it looks like a Fijian catamaran
but the Fijians never get
so far towards the west.
Maybe the hurricane forced
them to change their route.
Maybe they need help.
Look commander,
they're hoisting a flag.
That's most unusual.
There's a white officer
with some black sailors.
Pandora
Finally!
I thought you'd never wake up again.
My head hurts.
Where are we?
It's alright.
We're on a catamaran,
but the crew behaves strangely.
I believe they're pirates.
Don't worry, I'll take care of them.
I don't like that boat,
I don't like it at all.
Sometimes you remind me
of my sister, Van Herdern.
She no longer felt safe in Rotterdam,
so she moved to a small
village near the German border,
but she miscalculated
because now, with the
rumours about the war,
she feels even less safe.
Lately I've heard
she doesn't even go out anymore.
Poor Marike.
Hello captain.
Captain,
in the name of His Imperial Majesty
I take possession of
this ship and its load.
You're transporting coal, aren't you?
I don't understand...
We aren't at war...
Because everything is
delayed in the South Pacific.
How humiliating, isn't it?
So, this time we have decided
to take the initiative.
Then...
you're pirates!
Of course.
What was that?
I don't know.
I'll go and see.
What happened?
Go back inside.
Assassin!
He died immediately,
there's nothing we can do for him.
Put those idiots in a lifeboat.
with some luck they'll
be able to find an island.
We better do what he's saying.
Why have you killed that man?
To each their own methods, Corto.
Now I have two boats,
while yours was stolen,
therefore don't preach to me.
You were supposed to take the
coal, not to kill him for fun.
Who told you it was fun?
We'll see how the Monk will react.
Oh, the Monk... No one
can ever read his mind.
Come on, move away,
or I'll make you regret it.
Let down the lifeboat.
At least give us some water!
You don't need it.
Rasputin, no!
I can't see anything.
Listen,
the important thing
is for us to be alive.
They know our parents are rich,
I'm sure they won't do us harm.
Perhaps someone on the boat could...
...someone could help us.
I'm scared, Cain.
You're completely crazy.
Why?
In these times
we can't afford to leave any witnesses.
Rasputin, you're a filthy coward.
Just move a finger and you're dead.
But...
you saved my life.
Moor the catamaran.
Let's leave, quickly!
Lock up this idiot till he calms down.
Captain Rasputin wants to see you.
It's cool upstairs,
and the sea looks beautiful.
Let's go.
Looks like you need me.
Me? Need you?
I have never said such a thing.
Very well, end of discussion.
Soon we'll reach the island of Kaiserine
and if the Germans see
the two Groovesnores
they'll take them
under their protection,
and you can forget your ransom.
You can't bet on that.
I can instead,
and since you don't trust Cranio...
Not even you, I trust you no more!
Of course you don't,
but there's no one left
unfortunately.
You can't always solve
everything with a gun.
Listen,
once in Kaiserine I'll sell
the coal to the Germans,
while you stay with the youths
on the catamaran, agreed?
And then we'll share
the ransom, me and you,
leaving out the Monk.
I think you're crazy, Rasputin.
Sooner or later the
Monk will get to know.
Cranio is on his side.
Nobody trusts him anymore,
not even the Monk.
We'll make it, Pandora.
Kaiserine
is where we're headed to.
New Guinea? But it's German territory!
Exactly. As soon as
we have met the Germans
they'll put us under their protection.
I don't think they'll let us show up.
Our parents are rich
and they surely want to
ask them for a ransom.
I think your cousin
is right, young fellow.
You were lucky so far, and if
you want to keep being lucky
you'd better not have
your brain work too much.
Especially you, Cain.
Stop calling me by name.
We have nothing in common.
Alright,
but if you want me to be
polite, you have to be as well
otherwise go to hell.
Kaiserine!
Captain Corto!
Captain Rasputin wants to speak to you.
Too many captains, aren't there?
Take the youths inside. I'm going.
Hey, wait!
Damn it, that cannot be!
But what are they doing?
We won't be able to meet the Germans.
Release the moorings!
See you by the mouth
of the river, as agreed.
Do you think they will
offer you champagne?
I don't really hope so.
I'm going there for our business's sake,
so don't play tricks, understand?
Wow, you're scaring me!
So?
What are you going to do with us?
We'll go fishing.
Are you cold, Slütter?
Here comes our coal,
it should warm you up.
Captain Rasputin has
organized things well,
it's good to deal with professionals.
Professionals?
Yes, Slütter
you're about to meet
a real modern pirate.
You seem shocked.
"Surprised" is more correct.
I didn't know the Kaiser's Navy
had similar allies.
You're no longer at
the Academy, Slütter.
In a while, nothing
will shock you anymore.
Welcome to Kaiserine.
Admiral Von Stecke is very
sorry for not to being here,
You'll have to deal with me.
You aren't too disappointed, I hope...
On the contrary, Galland.
To our deal.
Aren't you going to drink, Slütter?
This champagne is tepid.
Don't be too demanding, please.
In this dirty country everything that
isn't boiling hot must be welcome.
Don't you agree, Rasputin?
I like this country,
and the champagne, yet Mr. Slütter
doesn't look happy.
Slütter never looks happy,
but I assure you he's full of joy,
he only needs a little
lesson in Realpolitik.
This champagne is undrinkable indeed.
Let's talk about something more serious.
It's a real pleasure to
deal with you, Galland.
Calm down, stop it!
Stop what, huh?
Rasputin is sipping champagne
while we're rotting in here!
The world is going to shit,
that beast can't even use a fork.
I can see you're accustomed
to shellfish, captain.
Not particularly, but I like crabs.
How about you, lieutenant?
He lost his appetite
when he lost the case
which contained his books.
It disappeared between
Lubec and Surabaya.
A tragedy.
What kinds of books? By Goethe?
By Goethe, Lenau,
and above all Rilke.
"Who, if I screamed, would hear me
among the ranks of angels?"
I feel like shouting too, sometimes.
It can't be farther
than sixty meters.
I could swim, speak to
a German soldier and...
They would shoot you.
If the Germans and these
pirates are partners,
I don't think they'll renounce
everything only to help us.
I don't recognize you, Pandora.
Maybe you're afraid?
Do as you wish.
I don't want to spend the
rest of my life in regret.
Cain!
When the war breaks out
all the German bases
will be neutralized.
We'll have to get by
with our two torpedo boats
and a submarine.
Obviously we can't make a legal war
therefore we'll lower the German flag.
We're talking piracy here!
Call it as you wish.
The Germans will show the British
that the sea doesn't
belong to them at all.
We need provisions for these boats,
and some fuel...
Captain Rasputin offered
us this Dutch collier.
When the war breaks out
he'll give us the fuel.
And what shall we give
back to captain Rasputin?
The best thing of all apart
from friendship, Slütter: gold.
Gold...
and your collaboration.
My collaboration?
Cain?
Good evening Pandora.
I thought you wouldn't
mind chatting a little.
Get out of here at once!
As you wish.
Corto Maltese?
Wait... You're right,
I feel like chatting.
I know you won't set us free,
but I also know I'll
never make it by myself.
Cain is too young. You instead...
you're a man, you aren't
afraid of Rasputin.
Me?
Of course I'm afraid of him,
I'm not that crazy after all...
What do you want?
I don't know, I thought
that maybe, you and I...
What are you saying?
- Enough! I'm going...
- No! I... Stay...
You know what, Pandora?
Let's go to Manila.
- We'll get married and forget the rest.
- No! What are you doing?
Let go of me! Let go of me!
You really thought you could
fool me with that farce?
Farce? I don't understand!
Don't worry, now you'll
understand. Bring him here!
Don't be afraid, he wasn't hurt.
Luckily I was on board
instead of Rasputin.
It takes some courage to do
what you did,
but I'm an old sea wolf,
and it takes more than
a spoilt brat to fool me.
One day I'll kill you, Corto Maltese!
What a night... Do you think
she'd really kill me, Cranio?
If we stayed by the mouth
of the river, she could.
If we stay here we'll get swept away!
Out! Come on!
Pandora!
Dam it!
I can't believe it! Pandora...
That cannot be...
Are you still there, Friday?
My name isn't Friday. And
you aren't Robinson Crusoe.
- You speak my language?
- Yes, and I also have a name.
My name is Tarao. I was
on the catamaran as well.
And you know the story
of Robinson Crusoe.
A teacher told me,
she gave some lessons in our village.
I had a look around while you
were sleeping. I saw nobody.
I'm not surprised. I also
believe that Pandora is dead,
- I'm quite sure that...
- ...Listen!
- Oh, No!
- Yes...
Don't do anything. Let me speak.
- Then?
- Everything's great.
The beach and the jungle
are full of cannibals.
If I could choose, I wouldn't
like to be anywhere else.
Why are you
looking at me like that?
I understand you, you know, but I hate
to be with someone who
said they want to kill me,
and if it weren't for the cannibals,
I'd leave you alone in your
boudoir, my little romantic bijou.
Stop it!
It's not fair for Cain
to die while you...
A group of Papuans.
Perhaps the same ones who caught Cain.
- Cain was caught? But then...
- Then what? Cain's alive,
but he's a prisoner of the Papuas'.
Damn liar, why did you lie to me?
Maybe not to cause
you a fit of hysteria!
Come on, give me the gun.
You're too young to play...
Cain!
I thought you had died in the shipwreck!
How did you make it?
Did you swim up to the shore?
No, Corto Maltese saved me,
otherwise I would have drowned.
And where is he now?
I think I've killed him.
Here they are. They must
have taken a decision.
The men of mysteries are
going out of the big house.
Wait a minute! But what...
Calm down Pandora.
Don't be afraid now.
You... you know my name?
I know many things.
Come and see.
I thought I'd killed him.
It would have been a big
loss. Why did you shoot him?
- But you are...
- Yes, that's me, Cranio.
- But then you're a cannibal too!
- No,
I have taken the place of one of
their wizards and healed Corto.
This situation can't last long.
I have set a pirogue,
and now I need your help.
You want us to help you? Cain and I?
Don't worry, Tarao will
take care of the pirogue.
I trust him more than you.
You're only two whites, after all.
It could be a trap.
Think about it, after
we've helped Cranio,
what can prevent him from
handing us over to the cannibals?
He counts on us, Cain, and on Tarao.
He trusts your skills as a sailor.
I hope he's right.
Fire! Fire!
It's time!
I can't believe it all went so well.
I have a bad sensation.
Shoot, come on! Shoot!
You too, Cain!
What are you waiting for?
Trigger happy Pandora!
What if I dug a nice
hole in your head now?
- Cain!
- Pandora has been very brave,
we're out of danger at
last. How do you feel Corto?
What are you singing, Tarao?
- The song of the sbimpe fish.
- Really?
And you think it'll show up all
of a sudden because you sing?
- I don't think anything.
- A submarine!
Corto! but where the hell
were you, you ugly bastard!
Why, maybe you know who you father is?
You wanted to see me, Mr. Slütter?
Yes, Mr. Maltese.
It's about some delicate matter.
It's about the girl,
I'd like you to tell Mr.
Rasputin to leave her alone.
Why don't you tell him yourself?
I'd rather avoid accidents,
but if you force me...
I won't force you to do anything.
You're doing everything yourself.
I'd like to have some
explanation, though.
How come those youths are on board?
Their ship wrecked
and we picked them up.
Simple as that.
It seems to me a bit too simple...
I like Slütter.
As long as we're with him, we're safe.
I doubt it, he's
always a soldier at war.
Only because his eyes are blue...
I apologize, I hope not
to disturb you, but...
I'd like to have something explained.
I was wondering how come you didn't
get off the boat in Kaiserine.
Perhaps you were kept prisoners?
Leave my cousin alone.
I'll tell you how come.
So when we reached Kaiserine
Corto Maltese took us away
not to let the Germans see us.
Rasputin and Maltese made an agreement.
They want to ask for a ransom.
- What do you want to do with that gun?
- Are you spying on me?
Who me? No... you know
I love you. Are you angry?
- Go away, Corto, otherwise...
- Otherwise what?
- I'll kill you!
- Will you?
Try to.
But, what the hell do you want?
Haven't you heard? The boy
said everything to Slütter!
And who cares? What
difference does it make?
Do you think that Prussian
will disobey the orders
to help two spoilt brats?
I cannot see what you
see, but you may be right.
You're so stupid that it's not
difficult for you to be right.
You find me stupid?
We'll discuss it later. Let's
go get us something to drink.
Honestly I don't understand you.
I got us out of trouble
and you're pulling a long face, cousin?
Do you really think that men like
Slütter and Rasputin and Corto Maltese
will let a 16 year-old
boy manipulate them?
Why not?
Now that they're
all against one another
there's no longer need for that.
And then you should
have taken care of it
- as you're 17 instead...
- Great! You're so cunning...
At least I did something.
Yes you have, but you don't
care for the consequences.
"Alone, alone, all, all alone...
"Alone, alone, alone,
on a wide wide sea!
"And never a saint took
pity on my soul in agony.
"The many men, so beautiful!
And they all dead did lie;
"And a thousand thousand slimy
things lived on; and so did I".
How come you're here, my romantic bijou?
- I was looking for you.
- Don't look for me,
I don't want to fight.
I'm sorry to have been so
impulsive the other time.
The other time? Why,
will there be others?
- No, I didn't mean that.
- Then what did you mean?
Nothing. You'll never
take me seriously anyways.
Take charge of the submarine
and take me to my father!
I thought millionaires were
crazy, but now I know for sure.
Maybe it's something
they put in your dollars.
Listen to me well.
The best thing that you
and your cousin can do
- is to stay close to me.
- Really? And why?
Because I bring luck.
I'm really curious to know
what the Monk will decide.
If you're referring to the youths,
the Monk won't decide anything at all.
I'm responsible for them, just me.
It doesn't have to be an
unpleasant responsibility...
Watch out, Rasputin. Don't
forget whom you're speaking to.
Don't make me laugh, lieutenant...
I know what you have in mind very well.
You won't forget her that way!
What's happening up there?
Nothing. Slütter is
fighting with Rasputin,
and I think I know why.
You'll pay for that, I swear! You better
never turn your back on me anymore!
Exactly, and in the
meantime you watch out, too
otherwise you'll get hurt.
You'll pay for that too, Corto!
All of you!
- Do you recognise that flag, Mr. Maltese?
- Of course.
It's flag of the Monk,
the king of the sea.
It may seem foolish,
but I like to give
a proper name to things.
What's the name of that island
which isn't reported by any map?
Escondida, the hidden island.
The fleets of three nations
looked for it for a long time
but they couldn't find it.
- I hope you appreciate your fortune.
- Look, lieutenant!
I suppose they're still
friends of yours...
Very dear friends.
They have just prevented us
from bumping against the reef.
Welcome to the Escondida,
guys. My name's Sbrindolin.
The Monk will be back soon.
In the meantime,
if you need anything
let me know.
Are you still angry?
No, I never got angry.
- That's good.
- It wasn't worth it.
Have you seen how
polite everyone is here?
I'd like to know what
the Monk looks like.
What should he look like?
He certainly is a
pirate like the others.
A pirate like the others?
You can't generalize...
Corto Maltese for example
has always helped us.
There has to be something good in him.
I think we could even make friends
with him. Don't you agree, Cain?
Cain?
Are you talking to yourself?
I have just met him in the
courtyard, he seemed furious.
I can drive you around
the island if you want,
so you'll pass the time
waiting for the Monk to be back.
Pretty girl...
Who's this Monk?
Cain says that according to
the native he's 200 years old.
Who knows... 200 years?
Sometimes I believe it too.
But it's not true. Perhaps
he'll tell you his story.
You're not as bad as you try to look.
Have you come to keep me company?
In any case, you haven't found anything!
Are you crazy? What's wrong with you?
Why have you destroyed my hut?
Don't pretend not to understand,
you perfectly know why.
I don't know what you're talking about!
Damn you! You thought you could kill
me, but sooner or later I'll kill you!
I still haven't killed anyone today.
But I could start from you.
You're such a liar!
When I got in you were
cleaning the rifle!
Whatever… The day I'll kill you
I won't need a rifle.
My hands will do!
Corto Maltese, but...
What's wrong? Maybe
you've you seen a ghost?
I don't know what you mean...
Sbrindolin!
- Why are you dressed like a nun?
- It's for Miss Pandora,
so she'll think this place is refined.
Get out of here, idiot.
I know you.
You're annoyed because
you didn't think of it yourself.
Is that you, Sbrindolin?
No, it's me. How are you,
romantic bijou?
Corto! I was told...
You saved my life.
Now I'd like...
I would like...
What?
Promise me
you'll never hurt Cain.
Promise me.
Good morning everyone.
I've got some interesting
news for you.
On 4th August 1914, England
has declared war to Germany
and therefore we're at war as well.
I have already set two
islands for the Germans to refuel.
Monk,
I've taken the coal to Kaiserine;
I've also picked up two youths
who are worth a fortune,
but Corto Maltese and lieutenant
Slütter interfere with my plans.
The youths
must not be involved.
I suggest that we take them
to some island of the Fijis'.
They mustn't be involved.
No one can tell me what to do.
No one.
I thought you were less
impulsive Mr. Slütter.
Your commander ordered you
to be at my disposal.
Never forget it!
And you Corto Maltese,
have lost a schooner
and the power on your men?
Because of a woman.
However, power
is something you've got,
till you have to use it.
Your answer is subtle.
Unfortunately it also shows
you're unable to command.
You're an individualist, Maltese.
You're a subversive.
That's not bad,
but isn't good either.
Corto, you'll stay
on the island with Cranio.
Slütter, get ready to set sail.
We'll leave in two days.
That's all.
The Monk said
nothing about the youths.
Don't be worried about them.
they're worth a lot of money,
they aren't at risk.
How about Rasputin?
Rasputin doesn't matter.
And then I'll stay there.
I wanted to tell you...
that despite what the Monk said,
I believe you're a good commander.
A good commander...
Who gives a damn...
Come out!
Oh, it's you. What do you want?
- You want to kill me as well?
- Can I have a drink?
Help yourself, as you're there.
Since you whites have been here,
everything has gone wrong.
Every people is specialized
in something. That's what we do best.
So far, we've tried
to make the best of things,
but I don't like the idea to see
my people involved in your wars.
Nobody likes the war.
That's why there are so many.
However I reckon
there's some advantage in it.
The Melanesians are standing
united for the very first time.
The people from the Fijis, the Samoa
and Tonga islands are discussing it.
It is as if we should mend a big coat.
I hope you have
a big sewing machine,
because if you have
to do it by hand...
You look tired,
I better leave you.
Thanks for the drink.
We have to find a way to escape.
- Will you help me?
- Yes.
- We'll leave together.
- When?
When the moment is right.
You're too impatient.
You'll never change.
When you want something,
you don't mind what others think.
I've asked you to help me,
not to preach on me.
You're the one who shot, aren't you?
I didn't know
Pandora was in the car!
You wanted
the guilt to fall on me!
Dam you!
That's enough, Rasputin!
If he really did what you say,
the boy's not an idiot.
Will you tell me your name?
Cain Groovesnore, sir,
of the Groovesnores from Sydney.
Rasputin, from now on
you'll be personally responsible
- for Mr. Groovesnore's life.
- Me? But... But actually...
If he dies, you'll die.
Well...
Alright Monk.
Don't get angry. I...
Enough now, leave me alone.
So you're Elijah Groovesnore's son...
Yes sir, and Pandora is the
daughter of my uncle Thaddeus.
Tell me,
you have another
uncle, Renaldo. Do you?
Yes sir, he's a commander
in the Australian Navy.
And is there also a certain Thomas
among the Groovesnores?
He died in a fire on the day
when Thaddeus married aunt Margretha.
But how come you know our family?
Uncle Thomas...
But we never speak of him at home.
- Did you know him?
- And Margretha?
- How about your aunt Margretha?
- She died when Pandora was born.
Uncle Thaddeus raised her.
He adores her.
Listen,
if you have a heart, you should
let our family know we're alive.
A heart is a muscle which pumps
blood, Cain, not sentimentalism.
But...
After all those questions I thought...
Don't think.
And above all, never
do it when I'm there.
I reserve that privilege to myself.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
He got in, stared
at the girl and went crazy.
Take care of her, I'll go and check.
I don't understand, he's
decided to leave immediately.
He wants to leave me here
and go with you? It's not fair!
I've never seen him like that,
we better not leave him alone.
You're right Cranio. I'll go.
You're strange, Monk.
What's happening to you, tell me...
I've seen the Devil, Corto.
I've seen the Devil.
And I was afraid.
Don't leave me alone, my friends.
Don't leave me alone.
No one will leave you, Monk.
You're talking nonsense.
- Do you really want to leave Rasputin here?
- Why not?
Cranio will stay, too.
- He will guard them.
- Cranio?
Sooner or later
he'll need to sleep,
and Rasputin will get rid of him.
He'll steal the money
we've made,
he'll inform the British Admiralty,
he'll bargain over
the ransom for the two youths
- and he'll disappear.
- What if you stay instead?
Do you think I'm stupid, Corto Maltese?
But what do you want?
I don't understand you anymore!
I want you to come with me.
I don't want you to stay here
and flirt with Pandora
- while I'm away.
- Oh, that's it then!
Don't laugh!
I forbid you to laugh!
- You don't know anything! I forbid you!
- Let go of me!
Cranio, you'll take my place here.
I want you to watch over Rasputin,
and the youths to be treated well.
Let's go lieutenant Slütter. It's time.
Do you think it's normal
for us to be equipped like this
just to go and pick up
crabs on a desert island?
- There's no difference...
- Silence, you two!
Why don't they pick up
their own crabs?
And I don't even like them...
Don't you? I do, instead.
Hey, look down there!
Sergeant, sergeant! We've
found a message! It's important!
"We've just been stopped
"by a German submarine
and by an armed freighter.
"They're forcing us to follow them".
The signature is:
"Captain Perez,
embarked on the Bonito.
"November 1914."
The Bonito?
Hadn't it sunk three months earlier?
Goddam Krauts!
But where the hell do
they get the coal?
All the German islands are taken.
My dear, I'll gladly leave that
to the Admiralty.
Submarines in the Pacific...
we'll make them dance.
Good morning Cranio.
- It's a beautiful day.
- Indeed. Good morning Pandora.
Where is Corto Maltese?
It's all right, Pandora.
Corto is wounded
and not far from here, hidden,
but Rasputin doesn't have to know.
What about lieutenant Slütter?
I've heard indirect news.
Many British ships sank
in the roadstead of Papeete
and he and the Monk keep bothering
the cargo boats of the Allies.
But who is this Monk?
The Monk?
The Monk is a defrocked priest.
Well... Actually
he's a Protestant ex-shepherd
who has taken the place
of an excommunicated monk.
Well, something like that.
In any case, we better
not have priests on the island.
We have our wizards
and they're enough for us.
The Monk is okay,
as well as Rasputin is
a brute and an assassin.
But he's also useful.
As regards Corto Maltese...
He's a free man,
he knows many things,
but he never takes
any responsibilities.
Ship!
Sailing ship! War ship!
Halt!
He wanted to warn the Japanese!
He did, but now
he's changed his mind.
Haven't you, Cain?
I haven't! I'm going to... Aah!
Hello?
This island is taboo.
we're initiating the young lads
into magic. What do you want?
We're sorry Chief.
We couldn't know.
We only want some fruit
and some crabs.
Take all the fruit and
crabs that you want,
then return to your ship.
Help! Help!
Who shouted?
What's happening down there?
I'm very sorry, lieutenant.
If the girl hadn't shouted you
could have left for good, but now...
Don't be fool.
You cannot face a war ship.
You'd better...
But what the...
Bravo, Cranio!
Well done, my friend.
Have you seen?
There's nothing left of it.
The ball must have
centred their ammunition store.
- Yes, what a pity.
- A pity? You must be joking.
The Germans will pay us for that.
Now we only have to punish
that little traitoress as she deserves.
You won't punish anybody, Rasputin.
You heard what the Monk said.
Listen Cranio, the Monk
isn't eternal, understand?
Do you know what
I hate about you?
Almost everything.
Idiot!
Stupid cannibal.
Where have you come from?
When have you...
Corto Maltese!
Cain? Pandora?
It's time!
All's ready,
the beach is deserted.
It's the right time.
The pirogue isn't very
big but we can make it.
I have taken some food,
it will last for two or three days.
Wait a moment...
Where's Corto Maltese?
He isn't dead. Cranio hid
him on the island, but he cannot...
If Corto's wounded we can't
leave him here with Rasputin the Mad.
- You two leave, I'll stay.
- Then, I'll stay as well.
No.
You have to go to inform the Admiralty.
They have to send someone here.
It's better this way, Pandora.
- What are you doing here? What's happened?
- Cranio is dead.
- Rasputin?
- Yes.
He's gone completely crazy.
Pandora has run away with Tarao.
Cranio said that you were wounded,
so I've stayed. For you.
For me?
Then I have to think I have a friend?
But it's good for you to have stayed,
because we're going to have much fun.
They came on three big boats.
The man who led the fleet
had tattoos all over his body.
He observed the flight
of the birds to get his bearings,
the direction of the waves and the tides,
and at night he watched the stars.
He was looking for an island.
And when the water and the air refreshed,
Tamatea saw a long
bright cloud on the horizon.
Natoirangi, the wizard,
encouraged the rowers,
and they doubled their effort.
...Why are you laughing?
I'm not laughing at all,
your story is fascinating.
Go ahead, Tarao.
At sunset the cloud
took shape and consistence.
It was Ao-Tea-Roa,
that you call New Zealand.
In those times, its beaches
were infested by giant birds.
Tamatea and his men fought them,
and so they earned
the right to live there.
Now you know why the Maori
are scattered along all the islands,
and don't fear the sea.
Then, I don't have to fear it either.
- How beautiful!
- Yes.
But when they fly like that,
it means it won't
be windy for a long time.
- A shark!
- It's Mao!
He's followed us for a while.
Don't be afraid, Pandora.
Mao is our friend.
He only wants some company.
Now you better sleep.
Alright. But will you?
I'm not tired.
Hey, shark!
Lead me to Ao-Tea-Roa!
Lead me, as you led
Tamatea and Arawa,
our ancestors!
The crew is ready
for the inspection, lieutenant.
Spats aren't a problem anymore.
Don't you think, Mateau?
Well...
The Monk wants to see you.
Alright, I'll go straight to him.
I've tried to call the Escondida
for three days,
but Cranio doesn't respond.
I'm afraid that
something happened.
- What do you think?
- Me?
I think they don't want
to speak to us.
That's impossible. I'm
the Monk, the king of the Escondida.
You've asked me what
I thought, and I've replied.
What are you going to do?
Let’s go to the Escondida.
We'll miss a good prey.
It's a pity. A steamboat full
of women and children.
It would have been
one of our noblest actions.
You're too sarcastic, lieutenant.
We're at war, and the war kills anyone.
You cannot choose your victims...
...only to satisfy
your chivalrous mind.
Shark, I'm looking for an island.
It shouldn't be
too far from here,
it's called...
Bura-nea!
We have arrived, Pandora! Look!
Bye-bye Mao!
Joa-rana!
I couldn't help it!
Cranio wanted to surrender
to the Japanese! Believe me!
I was forced to kill him!
It's the truth!
And the youths? The Groovesnores?
They've disappeared.
We've looked for them everywhere
but they've disappeared.
And you tell me this way?
We need to talk.
- A shark?
- Exactly. It's a friend of his.
I know, uncle Renaldo,
it's hard to believe
but I can assure you it's the truth.
I have seen it with my eyes.
A shark...
If I report that to the Admiralty
everyone will laugh at me.
What matters is to find
the Escondida, right?
Tarao can find the right
direction watching the stars,
and soon it will be night.
Monk!
The British will land here soon.
Come on, you know them...
It will take them
months to find the Escondida.
With such a navigator as Tarao?
They'll find us in a flash.
Then what do you suggest?
Let's abandon the Escondida.
Damn it! This island is mine.
And then the Monk can die,
but he won't run away.
Well, die then.
I can't, I've done it once already.
There has to be a solution.
Maybe you can half
die and half surrender.
Corto, do you know what I like in you?
You always see
the funny side of things.
I'm glad you're safe and sound.
Corto?
Oh, that's you. Good evening.
Good evening Slütter.
The German fleet in the
South Pacific have surrendered.
I have done
shameful things for nothing.
Here Germany
has already lost the war.
So the Groovesnores have escaped?
Yes. Pandora has run away
and Cain is in a safe place.
Very well. Let him stay there.
It's better for
the Monk not to find him.
- Why?
- People speak more easily
when they're locked in a
submarine. Also the Monk.
He told me many
things about Cain,
Pandora and all that family
of nutty billionaires.
- Did I scare you Cain?
- A little.
I didn't hear you come.
The British will land soon.
We'll be forced to abandon the island.
You'll have to come away with me.
I'll be your hostage, won't I?
Not at all.
I'll take you away with me
because I love you.
You mean a lot to me, Cain.
Also Pandora, but
unfortunately she isn't here.
Pandora?
What happened when
you went to her room?
I saw someone
- I thought I'd never see again.
- Who?
Pandora's mother.
- Margretha.
- Aunt Margretha?
Yes, my boy.
I have loved her.
Very much.
But who are you?
I'm the Monk, who do you think I am?
You seem disappointed, Corto.
I've often wondered who was
concealed by the habit of the Monk,
and now that I know I'm afraid
it won't make
my life more interesting.
It's certainly snowing in my hometown,
Lubecca,
and here it's boiling hot.
Look at those girls
dressed in leaves.
It would be a pity
to wait till autumn
to keep them company, don't you think?
You aren't too bad for being a pirate.
I do what I can, Mr. Slütter.
However, you aren't too bad too,
for being an officer.
Now that you've finally had
your kingdom back,
perhaps you should think
of filling its safes.
- What happened?
- The Monk escaped.
He wanted to take me away.
Slütter didn't let him.
The Monk shot him...
then he left.
I think he wants to take
possession of the submarine.
Save... my men...
The British don't have
to find him. Help me.
He... has killed them all.
No, not all. At least not yet.
Resist, I'll try to save you.
I'm going to hurt you.
Stay calm,
or you'll never be credited
in the saga of the Nibelungs.
Try to bandage him.
We'll take the Monk's yacht.
- I'll go set it and be right back.
- But...
Do as I said.
I'll get back for you two.
Halt!
Tarao! You made your way...
from cannibal to soldier
in the New Zealand army.
I've never been a cannibal,
but my grandfather was.
therefore don't force
me to imitate him.
I know. It was so to laugh.
You'll be pleased to hear
that Pandora is safe and sound.
Of course I am.
Cain is safe and sound as well,
therefore you can be happy too.
Now go ahead, and no jokes!
You're so full of piss...
Rasputin! What are you doing
in that beautiful suit?
Sbrindolin has betrayed us.
He had the New Zealanders
land and recognize him as a king.
King of the Escondida?
It's ridiculous. Follow me.
Corto Maltese, born in La Valletta.
- Are you a British citizen?
- Exactly.
Strange. How come you know
this gang of pirates?
Which gang of pirates?
For me they were all friends.
You've got a strange
idea of friendship.
Perhaps,
but that makes life
more interesting.
Come on, move, you bunch of idlers!
Tarao?
I'm happy to see
you again. Is Pandora...
She's well.
She's still on board of the torpedo-boat.
She should land soon.
Perfect. And Corto Maltese?
We know you've hidden
the commander of the German submarine.
For some obscure reason the Admiralty
- wants this gentleman to be...
- He's a lieutenant.
Lieutenant Slütter.
...they want Mr. Slütter
to be tried summarily in a military court.
- Take us to him and we...
- You what?
We'll give you a thousand
pounds and a safe-conduct.
Wow, inflation is galloping!
Thirty pieces of gold used to be enough...
Take him away!
The Victoria's on fire!
Help!
Cheer up, we're coming!
There's another one there!
Be careful.
He could be a German.
Christian Slütter,
you have been recognized
guilty of the following crimes:
piracy, high treason, homicide,
sabotage and espionage.
Accordingly, this court condemns
you to the death penalty.
You'll be shot tomorrow,
19th January 1915.
Have you got something to say?
You can all go to hell!
That's nonsense!
Slütter isn't a pirate,
even less a traitor.
Don't be childish, Pandora.
Slütter has sunk the
Victoria with 15 men on board,
as well as many other merchant ships.
Perhaps it doesn't matter to you,
but it does to the public opinion.
That's why the Admiralty
wants the head of your friend.
What would you do,
uncle Renaldo,
if you senior officers ordered you
to act against your principles?
Unfortunately, I don't have
any more principles.
I prefer the law and the facts.
Answer my question.
What do you want me to say?
It's Slütter who was condemned, not me.
The only thing I can do now
is to grant you
the permission to see him.
Thanks, I don't want your pity.
I know you aren't a pirate
- or a traitor.
- Yes.
But unfortunately it won't be enough.
I understand their point of view.
after all I could have gone
against the orders,
but there were the hierarchies,
the traditions...
all that bullshit.
Prisoner Slütter, it's time.
If you to confess, the chaplain...
Confess what? That I've obeyed
my commander's orders?
Let's put an end
to this hypocrisy.
I'm ready.
Miss Groovesnore, you better leave now.
This isn't the right place for you.
I'll stay here.
I have to inform you that
Commander Groovesnore
had the accusations of high treason
and homicide withdrawn.
Thank him on my behalf.
I wish I could do it in person.
May I say a few
words to my men, captain?
Ready!
Fire!
- It's over, Groovesnore.
- I know, I'm not deaf.
Good, because we need to speak, Renaldo.
Now that the guy
is dead I can tell you:
you've made a big mistake
having the accusations of high treason
and homicide withdrawn.
The public opinion need culprits,
and if Slütter is innocent
they'll demand other heads.
Yours, for example.
What should I do then?
Now Slütter's problems are over.
Let all the accusations be.
It's good to be
generous and chivalrous,
but first of all think of the survivors,
and their career.
In a year you'll be rear-admiral.
Don't ruin everything.
So you haven't left?
No.
But I will as soon
as you have set Rasputin free.
I don't like this island anymore:
there are too many soldiers.
Have no illusions,
Rasputin will be condemned,
- to death.
- You got Slütter,
- I think that's enough.
- Get out of here!
It's easy for you to condemn
those you don't know,
but you're very comprehensive
with your loved ones.
What do you mean? Tell me.
I'll tell you all. I'm sure
you'll find it interesting.
Once upon a time there were four brothers.
We'll call them Elijah, Thaddeus, Renaldo
and Thomas Groovesnore.
Thomas was in love with a girl
called Margretha,
but Margretha had
been promised to Thaddeus.
Shut up, damn you!
Let me end my story.
Your brother Thomas Groovesnore
is also the Monk and
the real father of Pandora.
and that's why
you will release Rasputin,
so the Admiralty won't find out.
You!
You're blackmailing me!
To each their own methods.
Hey, sweet eyes, let's go.
You and I, end of the story.
Come on Rasputin, spare me.
I have done it for Slütter, not for you,
but what is done is done.
Therefore come with
me, and that's it.
Well, if you really care...
After all I like you.
I'll never forget
what you've done for me.
From now on
you'll be my best friend.
Me?
I'd rather be
a friend of a tarantula's.
We'll take the yacht of the Monk.
We'll have to slip away before
Groovesnore changes his mind.
One never knows
with these soldiers...
They never practise
what they preach.
We'll leave with the tide.
Hey!
I'm the one who decides here.
Corto!
I wanted to ask you...
I'd like to sail with you.
With me?
Sure. You're the best
navigator I know.
Here they are, they're setting sail.
Already?
Come on, go!
What are you waiting for?
I prefer to stay here.
I don't like goodbyes.
Corto! Corto Maltese!
She is dying with desire
to say goodbye to you,
but she'll never do it.
Hey... Romantic bijou!
Good morning Corto Maltese.
You look beautiful, Pandora.
You remind me of a tango
I listened to in Buenos Aires
many years ago.
Perhaps you were with
someone who looked like me?
No.
I've always
wanted to meet you
because you don't
look like anybody else.
I cannot come with you.
I know.
Goodbye Pandora.
See you soon, Corto.
- Goodbye Cain.
- Why goodbye?
We live in a big house in Cape
Cod, with a beautiful white gate.
You'll find it easily.
You're invited too, Corto,
and all the people
you want to bring.
See you, my friends.
See you.
That little idiot. Have you seen?
He hasn't invited me.
Of course he has.
What does it mean:
"all the people you want to bring"?
Then you'll bring me?
I've never said that.
# Subtitles: lyliakar
Many thanks to gm88 for his help! #