The Ministry of State has been informed and
they have not observed any irregularities.
What do you suspect that he wants to do?
We don't know yet.
I need to see a list of everybody
who is in the building right now.
That's more than 300.
Everybody has been checked
and we have their IDs.
Any other entrances to the building?
Used by journalists,
maintenance or cleaning staff?
We're sure that everything
is under control.
Even though we only got a very
flimsy description of the suspect.
Excellent, can I see that list?
Sarah,
I have just spoken to my head office
nobody at the DSIS
knew about the Prime Minister's
car being in Jutland that day,
or tearing a page out of the notebook.
No, but somebody must have done it.
Can I get that list now?
Sarah, we have not torn that page out
believe it.
Everything still points to Ussing.
Except that the kidnapper says it's not.
Here is the list.
How about surveillance?
I would like to see recordings
for the past hour.
Sure, but like I told you we have
observed and checked everybody.
That is very reassuring
but I still need to see the
surveillance tapes.
Lund
Brix here,  what is going on?
Goodbye
and good luck on the campaign.
Those 3 can become great ministers
I have decided to carry out
our austerity measures
and show our values.
Why did you fire the Minister
of Finance without informing me first?
Because you wouldn't have agreed.
How about Christopher?
Has he gone ahead to the meeting?
No, he is at a security briefing.
Even if I wouldn't have agreed,
you should still have consulted me.
I can't have a minister who is
working against me,
right?
Let's just get a hold of
Christopher so we can leave.
You are extremely vulnerable
if you try to do it on your own.
The Emilie Zeuthen case
is not closed yet,
you need to calm things down.
I do not want any unrest
and that's why we are no
longer working with Rosa Lebech.
You will agree on that, I'm sure
we are very strong right now,
there are three days to the election
Ussing and the centre party
are down for the count.
We just need to get Emilie
Zeuthen back alive.
We also have irregularities.
I noticed that when I was looking
for the files requested by the police
our vehicle logbook from back then
is missing from the archives.
What vehicle logbook?
The vehicle's logbook..
I've just been told by security
they think the kidnapper is here
in the Parliament building.
The kidnapper is here?
You have to go back to the Ministry.
Go now.
But...
We have checked everybody as you can see
we do a thorough job.
It could take all night
the kidnapper could be deceiving you
and he's chasing Ussing.
No it's not Ussing
he is at the police station with his lawyer
Brix says that he is no longer a suspect.
I am missing the last hour on this list.
What you mean he's no longer a suspect?
Apparently he has an alibi
for that day and time
he was at a hotel together
with a female member of staff
and that has been verified.
This is unacceptable
we need to let them go.
They need to get back home,
catch trains and planes
I can see that you had visitors
from a photocopier service company
this afternoon for a few hours
and then again 20 minutes ago
after normal working hours
and he shows his ID.
We have background checks
on all their employees.
They are here frequently.
But his ID is also cleared for
the Ministry of State.
I need to know where he is right now.
Hey, how do you fast forward on this thing?
The service guy told us that he
forgot to change a toner cartridge
in the administration wing.
Is that the administration wing?
No, that is the Ministry of State's red zone.
What are they saying?
Why is the kidnapper here?
They are not certain, it's
probably a false alarm.
It's really bad if we arrive
late for that election rally.
You need to go to the panic room.
Why?
Just go.
Where is Karen?
She was talking about some missing
files and trying to find a backup.
Excuse me.
Is there something I can help you with?
Hello, I'm talking to you.
The kidnapper has been spotted,
he is wearing a cap.
I'm on it.
You two, come with me.
You saw a guy fiddling with the equipment.
I only saw from the back.
When you catch him...
Stop, everybody out of here except
the guys from the forensic team.
No, no no NO!
Listen here
the kidnapper stole a hard drive.
Apparently.
What's on that hard drive?
We don't know that yet.
Firstly, I would like to know
why the kidnapper was here.
Because he's trying to find out
who was driving the minister's
car on a specific day
during the election campaign
two and a half years ago.
Excuse me,
Sarah Lund from the crime division
and Matias Borch from PET.
The minister's car was not used
during the election campaign.
I believe I explained that to you already.
The car was spotted by a small boy who
wrote down the registration
number in his notebook.
It was on 20 April
on the same day as..
It doesn't matter what date it was,
it can't have been that car.
Why should the kidnapper be
interested in my ministerial car?
I don't get it.
It's Ussing who is involved,
it has nothing to do with the Prime Minister.
Ussing has been cleared of all suspicion.
Our investigation, leads us to believe
that Emilie Zeuthen was kidnapped,
because the old case was closed down
without being solved,
and that is why we need to follow every lead.
So you think that we have
something to do with it?
Not necessarily.
The facts are like this.
We know that the minister's car
was over there on that day.
We just need to know who drove it.
Surely you understand it is in
your own best interest to answer questions.
The hard drive that the kidnapper took
apparently contains all the information
regarding the minister's car,
who drove it, where it was, GPS ...
Am I to understand that I or..
yes
myself or some of my staff are
under investigation for murder?
That is not what we are saying.
I suggest we just calm down and..
The conversation ends here.
We don't know what you're talking about.
One thing is for sure
the Prime Minister was not in
that car that day.
Your car was in that notebook
and that specific page was
torn out of the notebook
I know there is something that
you're not telling us.
You have any idea who you are talking to?
I am sorry about the phrasing...
That car, somebody was putting
pressure on that Deputy Chief Prosecutor
to close down the case.
If you know anything this is
the time to tell us.
We will get back to you.
Great work,  just excellent
We have searched the whole harbour
and all the containers
we have not found anything
suggesting where Emilie might be.
What about the iPad?
Did you send it to the police?
Yes, it is being tested but,
we haven't heard anyhing yet.
They found the place in the harbour
where the kidnapper was hiding.
The police say that she was kept there briefly,
before he left the boat in the harbour.
Any signs to suggest that
she is still alive?
They didn't say.
When did he take her?
Where?
The police believe that she was
taken onto a ship going abroad,
perhaps in a container.
23 ships passed through
during that period.
The problem is
that was three days ago.
The containers have gone on different ships
and therefore the numbers of
ships that Emilie can be on
has doubled.
Plus harbours...
We will check all the ships
and all the harbours.
Many of the ships are on the open sea.
Call them back.
Contact the shipping operators
and tell them we will pay.
It's not enough even if we pay
we cannot buy assurance.
She could have been brought ashore.
What about the people calling
in for the reward,
anything we can use?
No, nothing, I'm sorry
not yet.
Contact those ships.
and keep on taking those calls.
Any news?
I'm going to call and say good night to Carl.
Hear his voice.
It's not your fault.
Did you know about the iPad?
and that she was in the attic
talking to the kidnapper?
She was angry at us,
both of us.
You've told me we will find her,
that's why I know we will find her.
Okay?
Okay
...the calls for them to me.
Lots of people have not managed
to get through to the police.
They have started calling direct to Zeeland.
100 million reward
is going to make them act insane.
I can see what's happening.
Robert
is always the same.
he has been unfair to you
and not paid attention to the children.
The cat, the iPad.
I still don't know if it's
all Zeeland's fault
because they are hiding something.
Robert and Zeeland are not
involved in anything.
That is also what the police are saying.
Hey.
You know I'll do anything for you.
Maja.
I want to go now to Carl.
Maritime maps and container numbers
suggest that she has been put on a ship
but we don't know any more.
Send a copy of of the information
over to Zeuthen.
Okay.
And she has not left any clues
to where she was going?
If she was here then it was
a very short stay
just changing clothes and moving on.
Anything on the kidnapper?
We have plenty of fingerprints
but nothing that matches our database.
Another homeless knows nothing
only that he kept to himself.
What about the connection to
Louise Jelby's mother
anything suggesting who he might be?
He kept a photo of her
So she must have meant something to him
when she was young before she got cancer.
Okay, the kidnapper took a hard drive.
As he no longer has his hideaway
he's going to try and find a computer
so he can check the contents
of the hard drive.
Okay I will try to search libraries
and Internet cafes. I will call back.
Thanks.
Somebody must know something
what about the surveillance?
The photocopier service company?
The kidnapper broke into the company car
and stole a uniform and ID card
while the repair guy was away.
The only thing you can see
on the surveillance tape
is that he walks with a limp
so it's quite amazing that he
managed to get away from you.
Any update?
Nothing new.
The Ministry of State must
tell us what they know.
If they know anything
right now it's just accusations
based on scribbling in a
small boy's notebook.
I would really like to have known
about these scribbles 12 hours ago
when we last sat here
and you told us that PET
knew nothing about it.
We had no knowledge about it.
Obviously not
but you must know whether the
minister's car was in Jutland that day.
It's not exactly helping Emilie Zeuthen
that you are less than f
orthcoming with information.
It was during the election
we had better things to do,
than to watch a car in a garage.
Also the Ministry of State
says it is not true
Dyring,
But the fact that that page was torn out
suggest that..
Speculations.
It could have been the
Deputy Chief Prosecutor
it could been an accident,
maybe the boy did it.
No matter what
we still have to show the kidnapper
that we are working on the case.
We need to focus our investigation
on finding the kidnapper.
For FUCK'S SAKE THAT IS WHAT WE ARE DOING!
Borch, come here
Let me explain.
Borch come here.
You have to bring it up with management.
We need to search the Ministry of State
The small boy collects
licence plate numbers
I don't want to persuade management
Then you have to figure out something.
We risk that the kidnapper
will never call again
if we don't do something.
I made a request that these container
numbers be given to Zeuthen.
I'll check up with them.
I have just received a complaint
from the Ministry of State.
What's going on.
We have a good explanation.
First the opposition party and now this.
It stops now
Ruth
You will apologise to them
We need to talk.
I don't want these accusations hanging.
I want everything regarding that
car investigated, right now.
I'm on it.
The problem is that the hard
drive and information are gone
and so is the vehicle logbook.
I'm trying to contact the
chauffeur of the car.
Okay?
Security has been intensified.
PET  have requested that we cancel
our arrangement for tonight
so I have moved a fundraiser till tomorrow.
What is the chauffeur saying?
They will call back soon and
then we will find out
No, call them in for a meeting right now.
If Emilie Zeuthen's life depends on it,
then I have to ask myself.
You don't need to talk to anybody else.
What?
It was me who removed the
logbook this afternoon.
I didn't want it ending up with the police.
Not before I had a chance to talk to you
because the car was not in
the garage back then.
Who drove it?
What are you talking about?
It was your son.
It was Benjamin who drove the car.
It was during the last election campaign.
There were demonstrations against
the Banks' involvement in the financial  crisis.
It was violent
and Benjamin was recognised as
one of the troublemakers.
He was only 17 so they called me
because they couldn't get hold of you.
I didn't have any option so..
I persuaded one of the chauffeurs
to pick him up in the Minister's car
and drive him to Jutland  where we were at the time.
I arrived at the hotel.
He somehow managed to get hold
of the car keys
and got away in the Prime Minister's car.
It is In the vehicle logbook
20th of April passenger Benjamin Kamper
Wwhy didn't you say anything?
I wanted to but
I did not want you to get involved
with me misusing the minister's car.
Benjamin was embarrassed and
made me promise not to tell.
He was not one to provoke.
He was angry and drunk.
How long was he gone, in the car?
I found him late in the evening.
He called me from some bus terminal.
He was sorry and out of petrol.
Why didn't you say something?
What about the girl? Did he meet her?
No of course he didn't meet her.
He just drove around till he had calmed down,
and then I sent him back to Copenhagen.
You need to make a statement about
everything that happened that day.
What time he came over, what
he did, and when he was found
Any other files that you lied about?
ANSWER.
No
Then you have to go to the police
and tell them everything.
Everything.
If this comes out
then it will look like it's us that
put pressure on the Deputy Chief Prosecutor.
I don't give a fuck.
The police need this information right now.
They better see this
I can confirm that we are currently
investigating events at the Ministry of State
and will continue doing that
until we have satisfactory answers.
Anybody specific?
I can't comment on that.
I want to make it understood
that we are doing everything we can
to get Emilie Zeuthen back alive.
I will man the phones and prepare a press release.
Right.
We need to inform Benjamin's mother, your ex-wife.
I'll take that.
Okay
Karen, can you make sure that
Christopher doesn't get anywhere
near me, I don't want to see him.
Of course
Chairman Gidlsford has heard about
the accusations against the Ministry of State
and he's asking for an orientation
but I'll take care of that.
Somebody from the police is here.
It's that woman
she says it is important.
Okay
Unless you can tell me where Emilie is
we have nothing to talk about.
I just want to know whether you
had time to look at those container numbers
that I sent you.
It was a list of all the
containers in the harbour
three days ago. We have searched most of them
and we are working on the rest...
Please inform us..
...abroad
Are any of the containers of greater interest?
No.
What about the iPad?
Any clues about the kidnapper?
The forensic investigation is still ongoing
It explains how..
Maya
she wants to talk to you,
she's down in the car park.
But I need some information
about some former employees.
It will only take a minute.
We are all very busy.
We still believe that the old case
will lead us to Emilie.
The kidnapper is the biological
father of the girl that got killed
and he could have been employed by Zeeland.
We have already been very helpful,
lists of employees with  photos.
The kidnapper is not somebody
who worked on  an oil rig.
The guy we are looking for
has detailed knowledge
of computers, has a technical background
and knows everything about the harbour.
It must be in Roberts Zeuthen's
best interest..
Do not tell me what is in his best interest
I believe I'm better qualified for that.
Then help me.
We are looking for an engineer
or the equivalent
and something must have happened regarding
his employment when his daughter died.
I..
There were a lot of staff made redundant
2 1/2 years ago and reassignments
Why?
The financial  collapse.
Some of our competitors closed down
and Zeeland took on some of their employees.
But we couldn't take them all.
I will need those records,
maybe we can find something.
I will make sure you get the information
Thank you.
I want to make it clear
it would be unbearable for Robert Zeuthen
if Emilie dies
because the police failed to solve some old case
and it would have ramifications
that go beyond our comprehension.
Hi.
Can we stay at your place?
In the guest room?
Hi dad.
Hi, my lovely boy
Just till we find something else.
Of course.
Come, let's go home.
Thank you.
I'll get somebody to pick up your car.
We have received a written statement
from the Ministry of State.
They now admit that the minister's car
was indeed in Jutland on that day,
but said that it was the Prime Minister's
son that took the car.
The vehicle logbook confirms it
His son, what was he doing there?
The son got angry at his dad
and drove around in the car,
and somehow the logbook just dropped
off the shelf this afternoon.
And how can we believe it is time?
It was witnessed by the brother of
the Prime Minister, Christopher Kamper.
He will make a statement to us tomorrow.
Fridge Note: I have moved in with a friend.
Thank you so much for the help, love Eva.
We need to bring the son in for questioning.
Lund, don't ever read any
newspapers or watch the news?
The son is dead.
Officially it was an accident but
as far as I know it
wasn't, it was suicide.
Only a few weeks after that Kamper
won the election back then,
but of course the head of DSIS doesn't
believe it could have been the son.
Let's pressure them
and I will bring the brother
in for questioning.
Yes.
I waited out here for half an hour,
can we talk?
Sure, come in.
Thank you.
Did you hear about the Prime Minister's son?
They are hiding something.
It's shit.
Of course that's not the whole story.
What do you want?
I have something you need to see.
It is the file on the Prime Minister's son.
I wanted to make sure that you got it.
Couldn't it wait till tomorrow
Well
I will not be there tomorrow.
I'm off the case
and I have to stay away,
and I am sorry I behaved like an idiot.
I should have told you everything
from the beginning,
but I really don't know what happened
to that page in the notebook.
I hope you believe me.
The kidnapping appears to be connected
to an old murder case
that had been covered up.
How did Zeeland respond to that?
I have been told that the Prime Minister's
car is now part of the investigation.
Well hello.
Hi.
What is your name?
Astrid.
Hi Astrid, my name is Christian.
Shall we take some photos?
I have tried to get hold of
Robert Zeuthen's personal assistant.
I want to explain to him what happened
but he hasn't returned my calls.
Christopher's having a meeting
with the police right now.
If anybody finds out about it
then we will call it a briefing.
Thanks, let's just get through this.
How much time?
First up is a tour with Ussing and the press
and then you will talk with
the children downstairs.
There's something we need to talk about.
I know the school needs an upgrade.
Benjamin was found very late.
There's almost half a day that
nobody can account for.
He wanted to be alone, Christopher
already said it was nothing.
He committed suicide
less than two weeks later.
The police will be able to
put two and two together.
Those events are not connected.
He was depressed.
Hello and welcome.
Thank you.
The children are just about to get ready.
I hope you don't mind waiting
just a little bit?
No, that's fine.
It is here.
Yes
Nice drawings by the children.
The walls look better with a bit of colour.
Definitely.
I must admit I was quite surprised to
find out that your car was suddenly of interest.
Don't worry is not something that
I'm going to use for the election campaign.
Thank you.
But do not worry about me.
That's funny, that's what
my advisers told me.
They thought it would only be
fair after what you did to me
with the police and I'm a trustworthy witness.
That's up to you and your conscience.
On the other hand
the facts are, that the old
case was being covered up
and somebody had a really good motive.
Let me tell you something.
That you think your brother was
a bit slow in getting the truth out.
You must also be wondering
whether his good contacts in the ministries
might extend to the Deputy
Chief Prosecutor as well.
No, I will not
listen to you about these kind of accusations.
We will see, it will be bad
for your relationship with Zeeland
and the Emilie Zeuthen case
Aren't we starting soon?
We need to cut this short.
The police need to see you.
What?
I think they suspect that Benjamin
might be behind the killing.
Benjamin Kamper, high school student
mentally unstable
bipolar aka manic-depressive disorder
politically active on the far left wing
closely associated with Communist
newspapers and so on,
but after a trip to Jutland
does his condition suddenly deteriorate
to the level that he leaves home
and jumps out in front of a
freight train a few days later?
Hi you have called Eva, leave a
message and have a nice day.
Benjamin Kamper on the other hand,
told us that
there is no reason to believe that
he was near Louise Jelby back then.
Did you find out anything about
former employees of Zeeland?
They are going to give us more information later,
but we can't wait for that.
Lund
the kidnapper did not contact you
and I'm sure you can figure out
that there is no future for us here.
If we start digging up old
wounds without cause
into the Prime Minister's personal
tragedy in the middle of an election campaign
It'ss got to be him
this would also explain why
you would make a Chief Deputy Prosecutor
cover up the case.
True.
Okay I'll see what I can do
but, it will be the Prime Minister's decision
whether he wants to meet up with us.
Okay.
The file on Benjamin Kamper was very useful
still, I suggest you don't trust
Mathias Borch in the future.
Is that clear?
The kidnapper has not shown up at
any of the Internet cafes or libraries.
By the way what is going on with Borch?
He has been taken off the case.
Did you find out anything about Louise's mother
Monica Jelby?
She lived in Skudehavnen.
There is a woman named Birt
that I'm trying to get hold of.
But, about Borch.
Borch has been taken off the case.
That's all I know.
Did you have something to do with it?
Is it because you are is still
angry about what happened in Jutland,
or is it something else I don't know ..
Listen up, I have no idea.
Then why is his wife sitting
outside waiting to talk to you?
Hi, Sarah Lund.
I'm actually on my way out
so maybe you can call...
He came back late last night.
He didn't go to bed.
I found him in the living room.
At first I thought it was
the case that he was working on,
but that's not the case, is it?
He says that
that he loves somebody else.
It's you I presume?
Were you together
when you were in Jutland?
Are you in love with him?
It might be that you have been lovers before
and still have feelings for
each other or something
but we have two girls together
and he's their father.
Stay away from him.
Lund,  let's go
we got the go-ahead from the Ministry of State.
Okay.
You have our full support
but we do have a business to run.
Can we talk about this some other time?
You are unable to take care of
the daily running of the business.
For good reason I might add,
but it does create an uncertainty
throughout the company.
We need to show strong leadership.
That is the reason why we
would like you to step down
and let the board appoint a new CEO.
I have always been able to count
on your full support.
You still have that.
Then you must know that I cannot
accept that Zeeland moves abroad.
There are reasons to reconsider.
Have you seen today's newspapers?
At this point, we'll stick to the
agreement we made to the government
Zeeland, stays in Denmark.
The Ministry of State is
under police investigation.
My duties can be covered by
the rest of the executives,
and if they can't
then we hired the wrong people.
Make sure it works.
I will make sure that Gidlsford understands
that for now he needs to take
these things up with me.
I will arrange a meeting with him.
Thank you.
Besides that, anything else?
With regards to Emilie
they think they can narrow
the search down to
15 ships and six terminals around Europe
What is missing?
Even with the payment,
it is still difficult to get access
to some ships and terminals.
Rotterdam, Hamburg, Stavanger, and St Petersburg.
The police say that they can't intervene.
I will personally go and talk to
each of the shipping operators.
Please prepare my jet.
I will take care of Hamburg and Rotterdam,
you can take Stavanger and St Petersburg.
Yes, understood
My brother kept the fact that Benjamin
was driven to Jutland in the minister's car,
until yesterday,  hidden from me.
He wanted to protect me and my family.
It was an error of judgement from his side
and that is regrettable
but I have nothing else to add.
Your son took off in the car
at the same time as a local girl disappeared
she was held captive, raped, and killed
at an abandoned shipbuilders.
The Prime Minister has been made aware
of the old murder case, thank you
It is my understanding that
your son was manic-depressive.
How did he feel the following
days after that episode in Jutland
anything other than ordinary?
No, not really.
Were you in contact with him?
Yes
You were talking?
Yes,  of course we were talking.
There were times, he became reclusive
but neither me or my former wife
noticed anything out of the ordinary.
So you just saw it as a depressive phase?
It was a depressive phase.
He had stopped taking his medication
and we only noticed too late
Okay, anything else?
We had a look at what Benjamin was doing
the weeks after he got back from Jutland.
He skips classes significantly
more frequently than before.
He's also absent from his part-time job
and he's buying a lot of  wine
and hard alcohol, according to his classmates.
How did you get this information?
Lots of symptoms indicating
that things were not okay
Still you didn't think it was
anything out of the ordinary?
We just assumed that it was his disease.
My former wife and I are
not trained physicians
I was also absent a lot back then.
Had his condition made him
act like this before?
I believe the Prime Minister
has answered all relevant questions.
The problem is that Benjamin himself
expressed that there was something that
had happened that he couldn't go on living.
He showed up on the psychiatric ward
the night before he disappeared
at Fredericksburg hospital
he expressed distress and wanted
to be checked in by them.
He was informed by the staff that
he was under the legal age
and therefore needed his parents' approval.
He then left the ward, but before that
he repeatedly told the psychiatrist on duty
and I quote
'he had done something that his father
would never be able to forgive him for'.
He was then advised by
the psychiatrist on duty
to go home and talk to his father.
Did he do that?
On this specific evening
I came home very late.
I thought everybody was asleep
but Benjamin
was awake and..
he came downstairs.
Hmm
He asked if we could sit in
the kitchen and talk.
We hadn't done that for very long time
so I was very happy.
He had difficulties expressing
what he wanted to say
and I was very tired.
In the end he said that it didn't matter
and then he went upstairs
to his room.
The next morning when I woke up
I made breakfast
then I went to his room to
try and wake him up.
The bed was empty, he was gone.
It might not be significant,
he was often like that
reclusive, restless..
If your son committed the murder
it is most likely that the evidence
will still be in the car
and our forensic team is capable of
finding evidence that is several years old
even if somebody tried to remove it.
He did not do it.
It is completely ridiculous to sit here and
Stop it!
What did Benjamin say to you that night?
did he say anything that
resembled a confession?
Did he say anything about the girl?
It doesn't matter what Benjamin Kamper said
because he is innocent.
The hard drive that was stolen
from the Ministry of State
was found at an Internet cafe 15 minutes ago.
The kidnapper read the contents of the hard drive
and it confirms that
the minister's car was never near
the crime scene nor the harbour.
And what evidence do you have to support that?
You can see where the car
had been on the map here
the car had a GPS tracker installed
and all the data was on the hard drive.
I'm deeply sorry that you had to go through this.
I expect an official statement from
the police clearing the Prime Minister ASAP
and I trust you won't waste any more time.
What happened?
Did you put pressure on him?
What did they say?
The minister's car was never
anywhere near the crime scene
the GPS proves it
GPS, what GPS?
We don't know the whereabouts of
the kidnapper of Emile Zeuthen.
We have nothing
Stop it, your are not going to
give up just because of a GPS.
Did you ask him about...
Yes, I asked him
and if you have any doubt
then you're more then welcome to
go up there and ask him yourself.
What about the kidnapper?
Do you have the notebook?
We have checked all 13 cars from that day,
there is nothing
Can I have the notebook?
One of the owners of the 13 cars
an old woman
kept insisting that her car was never
anywhere near Jutland on that day.
So we have to go back and verify
everything from the beginning.
Your wife came to see me today.
I don't want that...
don't destroy anything.
Hello
I am outside the Internet café
where we found the hard drive.
The kidnapper has had about
30 minutes to get away
and he has likely found out that the
information on the hard drive is irrelevant
so he's probably not in a very good mood.
Okay.
I'll see if I can find some witnesses.
Birte, the woman who knew Monica Jelby
is at Skudehavnen right now.
I will go out there but I
can't do everything on my own.
Okay, great.
I need to go now
Sarah, the kidnapper's not going to give up.
Neither should you.
I have to go now.
Leading up to when he left,
you saw somebody by the computers?
Sure
lots of people are by the computers
I don't know who they are.
But the hard drive...
What about that girl?
Do think she saw something?
The kidnapper was last seen here
a witness saw him driving
around in a blue estate car.
Check if any have been reported
stolen within the past 24 hours.
He is severely injured he
will seek treatment.
Hospitals, emergency rooms,
we need to check everything again.
The only thing that you will do is
to sit down and wait for briefing from DSIS.
You gave the go-ahead for me to go on TV.
Fom this point on, it will
be DSIS that is in charge
you will do as they ask you to,
and make sure you get Sarah Lund under control
Get her to make the coffee
If I'm going to clean up your mess
Get back to work.
What are you looking at?
We'll continue until we get it in writing.
The plane is ready.
You'll be in Rotterdam before 6 o'clock.
I have notified the shipping
operator of your arrival.
I am going out to see Gidlsford right now
and then I'll go back home to pack.
Thank you,  it's very nice of you.
Annett and the girls are
staying at the house in France
so I might as well do something useful.
I will keep you updated.
Thank you.
Mr. Zeuthen can I disturb you for second?
A witness has shown up at reception.
Who?
A sailor from Sweden.
I think he might have seen something.
He is in a room here.
What is it that you have seen?
I was out sailing four days ago
It was about 3 a.m. and it was freezing.
Suddenly I heard a speedboat
going very fast
and it didn't have any lanterns
and that was a bit strange.
I passed by coastal vessel shortly after.
I saw the speedboat next to the vessel,
and then I saw a man together with
a small child boarding the ship.
Why did you contact us and not the police?
I tried but I couldn't get through
So you claim that you saw my daughter
in the middle of the ocean
in a sail boat in very strong wind
in complete darkness at 3 o'clock?
Yes.
Escort this man out.
150 cm high, 40 kg and long blonde hair.
Black wellingtons, blue raincoat,
and no life preserver.
I could see this because I
was only 30 to 40 m away
a work light was on,  so I
could see everything clearly.
I don't know if I should tell you...
What?
It looked like she was waving.
What was the name of the vessel?
I would like to sort out
some formalities first.
If what you're saying is true
then you will get the reward
without any delays
I would like to get some kind
of assurance of that.
Written agreement and 2% upfront.
We do not have cash here.
I can wait.
I will get the process going, tell me more.
I prefer to wait.
Can I get you something?
A cup of tea with milk.
Okay.
Thank you
Are you Birte?
Who's asking?
Sarah Lund.
You knew Monica Jelby
the mother of Louise
She was my tenant for 10 years
up  there
Monica showed up one day
she was pregnant
with her nose in the air
She said she only needed a place
to stay for three months but
but she just kept on staying?
What about Louise's dad
did you meet him?
No, in the beginning she talked about
a guy who was going to come and get her
but I have heard that story before.
Do know if she had any contact
with the father?
No.
Did a guy ever come here?
After she died
a guy came
Who was it?
He just said that he was an old friend.
What did he want
Information, he asked after Monica
And?
I told him that he could find
her in a grave at the cemetery.
Did he ask about anything else?
No, I just told him that
Louise was in an orphanage.
Can you describe how he looked,
anything special?
No, I don't remember.
Regular guy,
but it didn't sound like he knew
that Monica had a daughter.
I never saw him again.
Hello, this is Eva Laursen's midwife
I don't know if you remember meeting me,
Yes, but the timing is not so good
I just want to know if you could
help us get hold of your son Mark?
Why?
Eva Laursen is at the hospital with cramps.
It's likely that she will deliver prematurely.
Is it serious?
We can't tell yet, but we would
really like to get hold of Mark.
Hello?
I will try to get hold of him.
Thank you, goodbye
I'm sorry but I have to leave now
but I'm sending out a colleague
to hear more about that orphanage.
I don't know much, I only know
that it was a public orphanage.
Monica got that "family fund"
but maybe that's not important.
What "family fund"?
It was some time before she died
Well, she knew she was near the end
she wanted to do something for Louise.
I helped write applications
and when she got a positive reply from
Zeeland's family fund
she was so happy.
What fund?
Zeeland?
Yes
for helping people like Monica
who are alone with a child.
Might be that the family Zeuthen
are loaded with money
but you still feel a
little sad for them.
They help so many children and then
they have to go through this with their own.
No matter what the prime minister claims
he still owes the voters a proper account
of the government's involvement in
the tragic kidnapping case of Emilie Zeuthen.
Look, the government is neither responsible
for the current financial crisis nor the kidnapping
to suggest that is..
There is a cover-up
We can only ask ourselves
if the Prime Minister is actually
interested in the truth.
Could you please switch that off?
Thank you.
I have just heard from Zeeland.
And?
It sounds like they still have confidence in us
and they are still backing the
government's austerity measures.
Karen, back then, in Jutland
did you have any contact with Christopher?
No
he did not tell me anything, why?
The police are right.
Benjamin did change
I do not know why you couldn't see it
in hindsight it's very clear.
Hindsight is always 20/20
don't get yourself worked up
it's only guesswork from the police.
Christopher has accounted for what happened.
You loved your son
and I'm sure he knew that.
We saw the debate on TV.
Great work with Ussing.
What really happened?
I know something happened
with Benjamin over there
I just want to know what?
Well..
Stop it.
For fuck's sake, what happened?
He called me from the bus terminal.
I went over there to talk to him,
but he was out of his mind.
Did he do something to the girl, or..
Of course he didn't
but something had happened
that triggered an episode.
He said he had been driving around
looking for you and the campaign wagon
so he could make a spectacle
in front of the press.
Apparently he saw something that
he thought was important to tell us.
What was it?
It was some incoherent, typical
left-wing conspiracy nonsense
that we are all just kissing
big business arses.
What happened?
Why didn't you let me deal with it?
Because I thought he should leave you alone
he would only fuck things up.
I know he was in difficulties
but you have fought so
hard for this election
and I wouldn't let him ruin that.
What did you do?
He was a risk being near the press.
I put him on a bus to Copenhagen
to get his act together.
Get his act  together?
He threatened to go to the press
they would have eaten it up.
It was for his own sake, he was crazy
What did he see?
Answer.
He had seen Karen.
She was in Zeeland's pockets and held
meetings with them behind your back.
What meetings?
Just some, guy but he didn't even know who.
The money and the contract is on the way.
Thank you.
Reinhart told me to tell you that the
meeting with the chairman went well.
Thank you.
Where is he, I want to speak to him.
He won't say any more until
he gets the money
but we checked out his ID
and everything seems fine.
The police are here.
I've told them about the witness so
they can start the questioning as soon as possible.
I don't believe I called the police
I know, we need to verify the
information with the police
before we..
He gave a description of her blue raincoat
and that's enough for me.
He could not know anything about that
blue raincoat, it was found at
the kidnapper's hide out.
She had likely changed into something else.
Where is he?
He asked direction to the basement parking.
He said he needed to pick
something up from his car.
Seal the building.
Robert, what is happening?
Where is he?
He accessed one of our computers.
Juncker here
we need backup at Zeeleand
the kidnapper might still
be in the building.
I was told I could find you at home.
I've tried calling you.
I'm about to leave
we have sent you the
information you requested.
We did not find anything in them.
I have a few questions that are very urgent
it's about Zeeland's  children's fund.
If we can sort it out while I lock up
Zeeland's  children's fund
is part of our CSR strategy.
We take social responsibility
and helps those in need.
We help children in several countries
but why is that relevant?
Because the girl from the old case
was placed in an orphanage named Mayfarm
the was sponsored by your fund for children.
The orphanage has been closed down so we
have been unable to find information from back then.
The fund must have had good reasons.
They continuously find out what is best for the children
but I need to catch a flight.
I believe the kidnapper contacted that
orphanage in order to find his daughter.
There must be something in
her file from back then.
It might even have his name
and since it was your fund
that ran the orphanage
then there is a chance that they
might have a copy of the records.
It's important, I need this file
if I going to find Emilie
I will try to see if I can find
somebody you can contact.
Thank you
Hello
It's Borch
There is a reason why we
couldn't find that car.
We forgot to take in to account
that those numbers are written
down by a seven-year-old.
He made a mistake.
The first letter was the wrong way around
so instead...
so instead of a Z he wrote S
What that means is that it's a licence plate
that we have never been looking for before
and you will not believe it.
It's a Zeeland car
and the car belongs to Reinholdt
Robert Zeuthen's personal assistant.
Can you hear what I'm saying?
It's Reinholdt.
He has known the whole time that
it was him we were looking for.
Name and phone number.
Where are you?
Sarah?
She is the head of Administration,
she should be able to help you.
I really need to get going now.
You knew Mayfarm
or, you have been there.
I am the chairman of the fund
I try to bring awareness as
often as I can.
Did you know her?
No, not that I can remember.
Who is it?
Excuse me
a window might be open.
Stay where you are.