I wanted to make plans and meet up,
Episode 17
but we're meeting at the last minute.
I know.
I didn't have any appointments today.
If you said that
you had cancelled your appointment for me,
I would've been so happy.
Oh, is that right?
I'll pour you a drink.
Thank you.
So what is it you wanted to talk about?
Let's drink first.
President Baek, will you
treat me as you do your own daughters?
My daughters.
My own daughters, you say?
Since you're younger than my eldest daughter.
I guess it's alright.
What is this about?
Oh, President Baek.
You re a lot more impatient than you look.
Of course, I'd like to ask for advice on
business from a talented and
famous individual, as yourself.
But before I do,
I think we should become closer.
You still have a lot to learn.
Pardon?
Do I seem that easy to you?
I always place my
objective reasoning first over personal feelings.
In the cold battlefield of business,
that's how you're able to survive.
All human relationships are about business.
And you want me to treat you like a daughter?
Those rules apply between parents and
children, too, and that's my creed.
Sir, what I had meant was...
Do you know what my nickname is?
It's viper, a mamushi.
I revel in my nickname.
Let me pour you a drink.
So you're nickname is "viper"?
Fine, I'll show you how a viper
meets its demise.
Yeonhui, you should eat up.
Women who are too skinny aren't attractive.
I prefer plumper women.
Why did you say that to me earlier?
Oh goodness.
You're still dwelling on that?
I told you I didn't mean anything by it.
It's nothing at all.
The Yu Seongbin I know wouldn't say
something without meaning anything by it.
Tell me.
It's really nothing at all.
I didn't mean anything by it.
Seongbin.
Tell me why you said that.
Seongbin!
Do you know a woman named Grace Lee?
Grace Lee?
Your husband, Jeong Byeongguk, is rumored
to be having an affair with her.
But I don't know if that's true.
And because it's not for sure,
I thought I had made a mistake by telling you.
And I didn't want to go into the details.
Where did you hear it from?
Well...
No, forget it.
I'm sure it was a misunderstanding.
I was just worried about you.
Don't worry. I trust my husband.
He would never cheat on me.
Seongbin.
I'm happy now.
I know, Yeonhui.
Is it okay for me to be happy?
You won't think badly of me, will you?
Yeonhui.
There are times when I question
whether it's okay for me to be happy.
Do I have a right to be happy?
No one else may know, but you know why
I'm thinking this.
You know about my past.
I know.
But it's great to see you so happy.
I'm envious, even jealous.
So don't think such things.
You deserve to be happy, Baek Yeonhui.
Have confidence.
Forget about Donghyeon.
I've forgotten him.
I've erased him from my mind.
I can't even remember his face anymore.
Or when his birthday is.
Or even the date we first met.
Or the day of his death.
I didn't mean to forget.
I just forgot naturally.
I had loved him so much, but I started to forget.
I hate myself for being so shameless.
But I'm so scared and concerned that
people might find out about my past.
I'm a really terrible person, Seongbin.
Really terrible...
Is it okay for me to go on like this?
Yes.
You're doing well.
Why isn't she picking up?
The person you are trying to reach is not...
Honey.
Why are you home so late?
I told you I'd be coming home late.
I had an appointment. Is Jinwu in bed?
All you care about is Jinwu. What about me?
Shh! You'll wake up the family.
I went to your shop to treat you to dinner.
What is that on your chest?
Is it a diamond?
Diamond?
It was a gift.
A gift? From whom?
A friend.
Are you talking about Mr. Yu
who works at your father's firm?
You're lucky to get a gift from a guy.
Yes, I'm lucky.
Stop meeting with him.
Now that you're married, stop seeing him.
But Seongbin and I go way back.
Whatever!
Hello?
It's me.
Why couldn't I reach you?
Why? Did you miss me?
Tell me that you missed me.
Then I'll go see you right away.
Oh, really?
It's a little late.
See you tomorrow.
Jinwu, say "Ah".
No, I want my mom to feed me.
Okay, Jinwu. Here you go.
You should eat well to grow up strong.
That's good.
Why did you get home so late last night?
I'm sorry, mother. I had an appointment.
You're a mother.
You should've come home early.
Come on, mom.
You didn't say anything
when Byeongguk stayed out all night.
Be quiet.
Men and women are different.
Yeonhui works, too.
What are you saying?
This is sexual discrimination.
If I report it to the labor ministry,
you'd be in big trouble.
Jeong Yumi, stop it.
If you keep that up...
Byeongguk.
How is the deal With Lasar going?
Grace Lee still hasn't made a decision?
We'll sign the contract soon.
It's taking longer than I thought.
Who is Grace Lee?
Huh?
The Lasar assistant manager from the States.
You should take more interest
in your husband's work.
Do you know how important she is right now?
This is really delicious.
You should try some. It's so tasty.
They should sign the contract already.
Why are they stalling?
I'm so nervous.
Byeongguk?
What happened to the deal with Lasar?
You said it'd go well.
It will go well.
So why is it taking so long?
I'm going mad.
It'll be over soon.
It'll go well.
It'll go well
Do you know Grace Lee?
Byeongguk.
How is the deal with Lasar going?
Grace Lee still hasn't made a decision?
Grace Lee?
Honey, who is Grace Lee?
Can you tell me more about her?
Huh? Why?
Mother said that
I should take more interest in your work.
And I'm curious, too.
She is Lasar's assistant manager.
How old is she? Is she Korean?
Does she come to the office often?
Why are you interrogating me?
It doesn't really concern you.
Honey?
Do you have any spicy soup?
My stomach hurts and my mouth feels dry.
That's why I've made some bean sprout soup.
You shouldn't have drunk so much.
Where is Junhui?
She’s sick. She can't go to work today.
How is she sick?
She's been sick with a cold since last night.
Really?
It's me. Can I come in?
Come in.
What's wrong? You're not well?
It's not a big deal.
You don't have a fever.
I'm fine.
But I don't think I can go to work.
If you're sick, you should take the day off.
Call me later.
Dad?
Do you think I should go overseas to study?
Why would you say that out of the blue?
Why?
Because Yunmi studied overseas,
do you think you're falling behind?
You studied overseas, too.
That was then.
You're talented.
I'm not saying this as your dad
but as the owner of a company.
You're doing very well, so cheer up.
- Good morning.
Oh, Junhui?
Hi, Yeonhui.
Yeongeun, can you get us some coffee?
Okay.
What's up? You didn't go to work?
No, I wanted to see you first.
You should've told me in advance.
I would've come to work earlier.
I just got here.
Enjoy your coffee.
But what are you doing here so early?
Yeonhui.
What is the nature of
your relationship with Yu Seongbin?
What do you mean by that?
I saw you yesterday when you came
to our workplace, driving off with him.
Seongbin and I had a dinner appointment.
Without a single apology,
he cancelled our dinner to go with you.
Do you know how upset I was?
Junhui, that's because...
I know that Seongbin had liked you
for a long time.
And I was relieved it wasn't so anymore.
But now I discover that it was you,
not Seongbin, who is to blame.
Why did you pick Seongbin up from work?
Why did you do that?
Do you like Seongbin?
Do you love him?
Have you forgotten that
you're a married woman?
Junhui, how can you say that?
I've been keeping quiet because of my pride
but I like Seongbin.
No, I love him.
That's why I want to marry him.
So from now on, try not to come between us.
That's what I came to tell you.
Junhui!
Junhui, hear me out, will you?
How can you leave like this?
Seongbin and I
have been friends since college.
But you know this already.
There's nothing going on between us.
How can you take it that way?
Is that what you think of me?
Don't come between the two of you?
Are you saying that I'm having an affair
when I have my husband and Jinwu?
I'm sorry.
But Seongbin only cares about you.
He just feels sorry for me.
Because I've always been such a fool.
You say the same thing.
You call me foolish and clumsy.
When did I say that?
Never mind. Give me my coffee.
I might as well finish it, as long as I'm here.
I want you to pay for it.
I can't offer it for free all the time.
I don't make a lot of money.
A professional dry cleaning
service washed them.
But there still were stains on the napkins?
Yes, ma'am.
That's why I adamantly filed a complaint.
This won't do.
Let's look for another dry cleaning service.
Yes, ma'am.
And Chef Bae?
I know what you're going to say.
I'm glad to hear that.
Don't forget to wear your chef bandana.
It's right here.
And cut your hair short.
I already had it trimmed.
A bit shorter.
I can't cut it any shorter.
Why not? You can trim it a bit shorter.
Are you telling me to shave it bald?
I'm not saying that.
Fine, that would be even better.
Are you telling me to become a monk?
What?
Why would I cut my hair like a monk?
Are you playing with me here?
You want to play around? Fine then.
What? Gosh!
My goodness!
Why did you do that?
What?
Cheese!
Whiskey!
Chansik.
No, I mean Chef Michael.
What's wrong with you today?
Ms. Jeong is in a bad mood.
I'm in a worse mood.
Worse, worse, worse!
What?
What's wrong with the two of them?
I just can't believe him.
Unbelievable!
He must be crazy. Crazy!
I have an awful headache.
Come in.
This is Dutch coffee.
What is this for?
I didn't ask for any coffee.
For 24 hours,
vapors formed drop by drop to create it.
So?
I know you're in a bad mood right now.
A very bad mood.
No, you're feeling worse than that.
So I hope the coffee will comfort you.
Ms. Lee, what's wrong with you?
Are you playing with me?
What's wrong with everyone today?
I'm sorry.
Wait.
Did you get in touch with Lee Hwayeong?
No, not yet.
Okay, you may leave.
Yes, ma'am.
Gosh.
If she finishes up the contract and leaves
for New York, all would be well.
I'm in a bad enough mood to begin with!
Why is that chef making me even more upset?
Geez!
Ms. Baek, are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
I'll clean it up.
- Yeongeun?
- Yes?
Do you know Grace Lee?
Have you heard of her?
Grace Lee? I do know her.
You do?
How do you know her?
She's a regular customer here.
And you two are really close.
We're close?
Who is it?
The person from America.
Hwayeong?
Hwayeong is Grace Lee?
Yes, it's her American name.
Are you sure about this?
I'm pretty sure.
Do you know a woman named Grace Lee?
Your husband, Jeong Byeongguk,
is rumored to be having an affair with her.
Oh.
How do you do?
Hello.
I didn't know I'd run into
your husband like this.
He's so handsome.
You should be on guard always.
Why?
What if someone were to
take him away from you?
Even I want to steal him away.
Ms. Baek!
I think she put in a good word
about us to Lasar's main office.
They're nearly done looking over it.
Only the final decision is left.
That's a relief.
We've been working on this for seven years.
Mr. Jeong, the madam is here to see you.
Who are you talking about?
Your wife is here.
My wife?
Honey?
- Hi.
- Oh, hey.
What are you doing here?
I have something to ask you.
I'll leave you two to talk.
You said you wouldn't come here.
With the coffee shop close by,
it won't do us any good if you're
always paying me a visit.
So Grace Lee is Lee Hwayeong?
Why didn't you tell me?
Huh?
Oh, I didn't?
I didn't think I had to.
We even had dinner together.
Why didn't you say anything then?
That's because...
Wait. Did you come all the way
here to ask me that?
It's not such a big deal.
Honey.
What?
Mr. Kwon from Arabesque is on the phone.
Put him through.
Hello, Mr. Kwon. This is Byeongguk.
Yes.
The person you are trying to reach is not...
My boyfriend gave it to me.
Oh, hello! How are you?
Hello.
I guess you're here to meet your husband.
Bye now!
She doesn't look so well.
Maybe she found out about the affair.
Watch what you say!
You don't know the truth.
You should look after your daughter.
Your daughter will end up in hell that way.
What?
Did you see my daughter having an affair?
Do you have any evidence?
How dare you wag your finger
at me in such a vulgar way?
Vulgar way?
Your name sounds very vulgar.
So I can be vulgar to you.
You're the one that's vulgar.
Do you know that?
I give her an inch and she takes a mile.
Who do you think you are?
Hey, newbie. Bae Chuja!
Good shot!
Let's take a break.
Does your wife play golf, too?
No.
I told her to learn but she's good at such things.
All she cares about is our son.
She's always either at work or home.
Wait, my wife came to my office earlier.
Why?
She asked me why I didn't
tell her you were Grace Lee.
I had forgotten all about it.
So I was very surprised to hear her say it.
I came up with an excuse.
She such an innocent and good woman
that I'm sure she'll just let it go.
Innocent and good?
Do you really think so?
The way I see it,
she's got you wrapped around her finger.
Lee Hwayeong.
Don't say that about my wife.
You don't know her.
Oh, man!
What's wrong with this club?
That fool. That stupid loser.
You've been fooled by Baek Yeonhui.
Mom.
Mom, will you do this for me?
Do it yourself.
Mom!
Mom, mom.
Jeong Jinwu, what s wrong with you?
Why are you whining?
Didn't I tell you not to act like this?
Jinwu, come here.
I'll give you something yummy to eat.
What's wrong?
Grandma!
Who yelled at my dear grandson?
Who gave you the right to scold him?
Mother.
Jinwu keeps whining
even over things he can do alone.
Don't say that.
He rarely gets a hug from you.
So what if he whines a little?
How can you be so cold?
You're his mother!
Did you forget what we went through
to have him?
But mother, I should scold him if he deserves it.
I'm afraid he'll end up being spoiled.
Don't worry.
Why worry about that already?
You're such a worrywart.
I'm home.
Mom, I'm home.
Dad!
Come here, my boy!
Jinwu, what about me?
Say, "Auntie! Welcome home!"
- No.
- Hey!
Did you have a good day today, Jinwu?
How come you're coming home together?
Did you plan on coming home together?
Not at all.
Usually, it's hard to see each other at home.
But we met at the door by chance today.
Did you have dinner?
- Yes.
- Not me.
I'm sorry but can you fix me something?
I'll wash up.
Jinwu, you can come hang out with me.
Let's go.
Jinsuk.
Doesn't Byeongguk look worn out these days?
It's because of that Grace Lee woman.
She's done that to my precious son.
I hope that the deal is finalized soon.
Yeonhui, your mother hasn't been
getting us Oriental medicine lately.
In the past,
she used to bring us some every month.
But after Jinwu was born, that ended.
I'll ask my mother about it.
It's not because I don't want
to buy it myself.
Mothers-in-law are supposed
to be like mothers, too.
Get your husband some tea
so he can unwind a bit.
Okay.
Why is she so down?
What's wrong with her?
Come on.
Okay, okay.
How many times must I tell you
that people like Yeonhui are hard to come by.
She never complains.
Nor does she say she wants to move out.
She grew up like a princess
but she doesn't ask us to treat her like one.
Fine.
Her looks, family and educational background.
They can't be beat.
I said I get it. You can stop now.
But you know what?
There's nothing I lack either.
So why can't I get married?
I'm really tired.
Did you come home early?
Yes.
Come to think of it.
I think I was too hard on you earlier
when you came to see me at my office.
You may be an owner of a coffee shop
but I should've offered you a drink.
It's okay. I'll do it.
Oh, my little Jinwu.
Let's go.
Grace Lee
What are you doing?
What are you doing with my phone?
It was ringing.
You've been acting strange lately.
You never used to act like this before.
It's not that.
It's Grace Lee.
Why is she calling me at this hour?
Why didn't you tell me
that you knew Grace Lee?
That again? How is that important?
It's strange.
What? What's strange?
It wasn't important.
It's true.
You have your own work.
In the same way,
I have my work with Grace Lee.
If I told you about our business relationship,
would you have been able to befriend her?
It'd be awkward for all of us.
I was only trying to be considerate.
So why are suspecting me like this?
Are you really suspicious of me?
Is that it?
You don't trust me?
No, I don't trust you.
Honey.
Hwayeong and I have been close.
But the two of you acted as if you
met for the first time. Does that make sense?
And if it doesn't?
Are you saying I'm having an affair
behind your back or something?
That really doesn't make sense.
I thought you were pure and good.
Why are you acting like this?
You don't trust me?
What did I do wrong?
This is so funny.
Wait.
Turn that down.
Why?
Don't make me out to be the bad guy.
Why are you treating me like a fool?
What's going on?
What are you two doing?
See you next time...