[Star of the Universe Episode 3]
I want to die.
Have you ever thought about what
the world would be like without Wooju?
Are you nuts? Focus
3,2... Go!
Row A, seat 37.
I'm going to see Wooju in person!
That was awesome. Awesome.
Damn!
- I got distracted.
- Bad luck.
You were distracted during
the holiest of holy ticketing hour?
This is the first time
he's had an album flop.
I mean, he's just a man.
He could have just had a low moment.
It's fine if he thinks that way,
as long as he doesn't act on it.
Is he really going to die?
You have insider information,
tell me the truth...
Does he died before or after the concert?
Even if I knew, how am I supposed
to sit by and watch him go?
This job is the worst.
Let's just do it then!
It's not like he can see us!
You know how he is. He hates
clingy fans more than anything.
Then what if he does something
he shouldn't?
You always says he's your
only connection to the living.
Are you just going to let him die
if that's what's going to happen?
Let's just follow him around.
- You can do it because you're a freelancer...
- You can just take some sick days~!
"Sick days?"
I'm dead.
Hello? Helloo, sir.
I was fell of my bike
and hurt my hip...
It's really hard to get around...
I'm sorry for waking you up.
Good night~
Like clockwork, he wakes up
ever morning at 6:30 am.
And he runs the same empty route every day.
He's never missed a workout
since his debut.
For lunch, he eats the organic
lunches his fans send in.
He always eats 2500 calories. Exactly.
He doesn't even touch sweets.
Instant food?
What's the point?
That smell. You forget?
Sorry.
All of those comments were by students.
You really want to sue them?
Yeah. All of them.
Did you even have to ask?
Bolder than I thought.
What!? He might slip and fall in the shower!
We can only protect him so much.
It's been a few days but, he's clean.
Nothing dubious at all.
Beer, cigarettes, women... I mean
he lives alone and he doesn't even watch porn.
If there's nothing to kill him then...
You don't think...?
- Maybe an overdose?
- Hey, no way.
Michael Jackson, Prince...that's how
all the big artist go.
I mean, I thought his latest single
was just too... finished.
What if he has needle marks?
See? Amethysts, germanium ang titanium.
Hyung.
"Healthy jade chair mat."
I hear jade is good for men.
I don't think his health is a problem.
Again!
Let's do it again.
Again.
Let's stop here.
Let's call it a day.
We can keep going. And you could look my way,
we're singing a duet after all.
Go home and get some rest.
Good work today.
Water.
- Hey, do you know how hard it was
to get that thug in here?
- "Thug!?"
Of music!
Thug of music!
- Wasn't that to much!? It's not trot music.
- What do you mean? It sounded fine!
You want me to get the car?
Like you've done anything.
You've never even said thank you to the staff!
Forget that. If you're not going to retire,
then at least finish the song.
Like love songs are hard...
I'll write one.
Hey! You're standing in a studio
that Wooju built and paid for!
- What do you know about music?
- President!
You want me to poke your eyes out?
Who are you speaking like that?!
But he is a son of a bitch when he's working.
More like a puppy...
I only gave you the prescription
because I'm worried about you.
Sleeping pills tend to form habits.
You should try to sleep without them.
You're like a ghost...
It's a woman.
I'm sure sleep is hard,
with your single having tanked.
Having someone next to you
would be the best cure.
- You should at least get a dog.
- You make as much sense as a dog.
Just because you talk like a dog
doesn't mean I'll adopt you.
Hey, I have someone I'm interested in.
And at least I'm trying,
you don't think you're a little strange?
Locking yourself away in that big house.
You'll end up with ghosts.
I'm Hang up.
What Ghosts..
-Sinc & corrected by KieKie Rizkya-