Previously on Dark Matter...
I've got all your memories in my head,
I know it.
I'm Jace Corso.
No, I'm Jace Corso.
I promise I will not rest
until I've done
everything I can to save you.
I'm programmed with various
recreational subroutines,
do you like fun?
Wait!
This runs counter to your programming.
Fun remember?
The search continues
for Emperor Ishida's murderer
purported to be his own son,
Crown Prince Ishida Ryo.
We just murdered 10 thousand
innocent civilians.
You Draves?
Maybe.
I'm looking for someone.
Yeah?
Who?
He's the leader of
the Procyon Insurrection.
They call him The General.
What's so funny?
He's the most wanted man in the galaxy.
What makes you think I know where he is?
Well he's been using
Arrakis Sadr as his base,
and since this is
the closest station to that planet,
it's a good bet his supply line
runs through here.
And to keep below the radar,
he has to be doing business
with the local criminal element.
And you're it, no offense.
And I hope your not offended
if I tell you you're insane.
Do you know how many people he's killed?
I've got an interesting
business proposition for him.
You put me in touch with him
and I'll make it worth your while;
Ten thousand bars transferred
directly into your account.
I can do better.
Twelve thousand.
You misunderstood me.
I said I can do better.
What's going on here?
Griffin Jones.
Wanted for smuggling, piracy, murder.
It's quite the rap sheet.
And a hell of a bounty to go with it.
1x08 - Episode 8
What part of "We need him alive"
didn't you understand?
Sorry, boss.
What are you doing?
I was surprising you with a hug.
Why?
I don't know, I thought you'd enjoy it.
Do I look like someone
who enjoys surprise hugs?
In retrospect no, not at all.
Let's keep it professional, ok?
Okay.
How's she doing?
The corrector nanites in her body
are damn impressive.
I'd say she's about 85% healed.
So, close enough.
We gonna bring her online?
Not yet.
She'll be good to go by day's end.
But we're twenty minutes
out from the space station.
We gonna shuttle in?
No, we'll dock.
Well how're we gonna dock
without the android?
I'll take us in.
Just giving everyone a heads up.
We're about to dock.
If you're looking for a seat belt,
you're out of luck.
Of course not.
I was just - adjusting my seat.
Here we go...
And we're docked.
Never doubted you.
Okay, supply run.
One, you're on infirmary restock.
You got your list?
Got it.
Four, seeds to keep hydroponics going.
Five, you've got gak...
Connectors, adapters,
and three-twelve sprockets.
That's what I said.
Three, you've got juice.
Make sure that...
Where the hell's Three?
In his room.
He says he's not coming.
I'll get him.
Give him some time.
He's had enough time.
Get lost.
What's the point of knocking
if you're just going to come in anyway?
It's polite.
Are you coming?
Naw, I got stuff to do.
Such as?
Cleaning my guns.
Working out.
Alright, well we haven't been
off this ship in a few days.
Who knows when we'll get another chance.
Well, you have a good time.
You need to move on.
I'm thinking "moving on"
is what I've been doing all my life.
Maybe it's time I stopped,
and considered the consequences.
Consequences imply
that you were responsible.
She was relying on me.
I failed her.
She believed in you, with good reason.
You did everything you could.
We all owe you our lives.
Okay, same drill as last time.
We've docked under a false registration.
Just remember,
don't draw any unnecessary
attention to yourselves.
And, yes, I speak from experience.
Think he'll come?
In the interest of us actually
getting some actual R&R,
I hope not.
Oh, come on.
You're all thinking the same thing
I'm just the only one
with the guts to say it.
Alright!
There he is!
Bring it on.
Let's do this boys!
Huh?
Okay, what's up first?
Shops, spa, food...
Food!
Spa!
Seriously, kidding, food.
Alright lets get some grub.
You guys go ahead.
I'll catch up with you.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Alright knock yourself out.
What?
Aren't you going to get something to eat?
No, I'd rather hang with you.
No.
What I mean is,
I just need some time to myself okay.
But we'll hang out later.
Okay.
Garlic?
It's not garlic.
Parsley?
Yes.
Onions, mushrooms...
No, no, no mushrooms.
It's nuts?
What is that flavor?
Nuts.
Mealworms.
When you say mealworms,
is that one of those words
that sounds like something,
but means something completely different,
like "firearms" or "anal-geesic"?
It's pronounced "annal-jezik"
and, mealworms are worms, well larvae.
They're protein-rich
and a hell of a lot less expensive
and easier to source than beef.
Meh.
Excuse me, could I see a menu please?
So you're not gonna eat that?
Cheers.
Griffin Jones.
Wanted for smuggling, piracy, murder.
I had one of my boys run a face recog
when you started asking around about me.
Curious that way.
Hands behind your back.
How do you feel?
Fine.
Why don't I remember what happened?
If your clone returned to its transfer pod,
all new memories should've been sent back
and uploaded into your temporal lobe.
Well, they weren't.
It seems your trip was terminated early.
No bio-mass recycling was recorded.
Your clone died.
Does it say how?
Just that we lost vital signs
at 21:34 hours
which triggered your early wake up.
Could've been an accident...
or natural causes.
What do you mean, natural causes?
Genetic conditions can be
transferred to the clone...
No, it wasn't that.
Put me back in.
Our policy states that
Transfer Travelers have to wait
thirty minutes between travels.
I don't have that kind of time.
It's a precautionary measure to guard
against stress-induced complications.
Come on.
Sorry.
Regulations.
Just, look, I get it.
You're a cog in a big machine.
Keep your head down, put in your time,
retire and hopefully you die
before the savings run out.
It's a solid plan, but I've gotta ask.
Doesn't it ever get to you?
I mean haven't you ever wanted to just,
once, stand up for yourself
and stick it to the big
faceless Corporation?
Break one of their stupid rules?
By letting you transfer
thirty minutes early?
For example.
It's your cerebral cortex.
Thank you.
Wait, wait, wait.
Do you know when I decided I liked you?
When I didn't shoot shoot you
when you tried to steal the ship?
No.
When you abandoned us
on that mining planet.
Yeah?
Yeah, at first,
I thought you'd screwed us over
and I thought, "Damn. I like this girl".
But then, when you came back
and you saved our asses,
I was like:
"Damn. I really like this girl."
Yeah, you guys, I mean.
You guys are great man.
I may not say it enough but...
Or at all.
Ever.
But you guys...
Hey, you!
What's wrong with you guys?
You're leaving me hanging fiver.
What do you mean?
We'll you're all... getting along.
It's weird.
Are you drunk?
Of course we're drunk.
Have a seat.
Here, have some, eat.
No.
And drink something.
What's the matter?
It's Six.
He's gone off the Station.
What?
What!
What do you mean, he's not on the Station?
Where did he go?
That bastard stole our ship!
No, the ship's still here.
And so is he, kind of.
Hang on a second.
What are you drunk?
Is he here, or is he not here?
He's using Transfer Transit.
What's Transfer Transit?
It's state-of-the-art travel tech.
You get into a "transfer pod"
and input a destination.
The pod sequences your DNA
and maps your brain.
Then, that information
gets sent via subspace,
anywhere across the galaxy
where there's a receiver pod,
where they create a clone of you,
complete with your memories
and personality.
It's like flesh and blood 3D-printing.
But the clone has a short life span,
a few days, maybe.
It has to return
to its transfer pod before that time
so all the new memories and experiences
can be sent back to you
before you wake up.
How the hell do you know all this?
I read the brochure.
Hang on.
Just go back.
What the hell's Transfer Transit?
No stop, Six would never
submit to a DNA scan.
Not after what happened last time.
It says all DNA profiles
are kept strictly confidential.
Yeah they would have to be,
otherwise they'd lose
a lot of business fast.
Still, it's risky.
He must've wanted to go
somewhere pretty badly.
Wherever he's going, whatever he's doing,
it can't be good for us.
You're back.
I am.
What'll it be this time?
Merchandise or more information?
Information.
I came in here earlier.
Yeah.
And I needed help finding someone.
And I gave you a name
and sent you on your way.
That name again?
What?
What was the name you gave me earlier?
Draves.
Wanna write it down this time?
Nah, I'm good, thanks.
Sure.
See you around.
Not if I get it right this time.
Yeah?
Yeah, it's me.
He's on his way down.
Are you sure we should be
going through his stuff?
Pretty sure.
Yeah.
It's not right,
it's an invasion of his privacy.
You didn't have a problem invading
my privacy, when you stole my bullets.
That was different.
I thought you were dangerous.
Look, I didn't want to get him in trouble,
I just thought it was weird
that he was keeping something from us.
That maybe he needed our help.
I knew it!
He's been hoarding the green
not-as-crap-tastic protein bars!
He said we were out!
I got stuck eating the blue ones.
It tastes fishy!
What've you got?
Great.
Try "Six".
Try "lying hoarder"?
We can waste all day guessing.
We have to find a way
to bypass the password.
No way.
Look at it this way:
You'll be proving his innocence.
He was researching
a terrorist attack on some space station.
A lot of people were killed.
Breaking news.
We have an update on the bombing
of Station Hyadum Twelve
by the anti-corporate terrorist group
calling itself The Procyon Insurrection.
Over ten thousand lives
were lost in the attack
and today,
investigators released the following video.
Security footage uploaded to the G.A. hub
before the station's destruction
clearly shows one of the suspects
believed to be responsible for the bombing.
If you see this man,
do not attempt to apprehend him,
but call your nearest
G.A. detachment immediately.
And you thought I was dangerous?
It was instinct. I'm sorry.
Well your instincts are terrible.
And nearly cost us a huge pay day.
I'll be careful this time.
I promise.
Nice and simple, right?
We tell him we're taking him
to The General,
then we capture him, alive, torture him,
and then we get him
to give up his real location.
What if he gets suspicious?
There's no reason for him to be.
His first clone took its memories with it.
As far as he knows,
we're meeting for the first time.
- You Draves?
- Maybe.
So what can I do for you?
No wait!
Take it easy.
I had nothing to do with this,
I'm just the girlfriend.
Like hell you are.
You're way out of his league.
Besides your nails
don't quite match your outfit.
They're nice and short,
ideal for handling a gun.
Last time I was here I missed something.
Not sure what it was,
but this time I'm not
gonna take any chances.
And that means shooting you
before you can draw.
Now, I need some information,
and a shuttle.
I don't believe it.
He couldn't have killed all those people.
Why, because he's nice to you?
You think that means anything?
It does seem a little hardcore.
Even for one of us.
It's a mistake.
It has to be.
What about Calchek?
He knows our histories,
maybe we should call him.
No it's too risky.
If we start asking for information
we should already know,
he could get suspicious.
And if he finds out about our memory loss,
he could consider us damaged goods
and end our arrangement.
Or worse, make a move against us.
Other ideas?
We follow Six and find out for ourselves.
That's a damn good idea.
We just go hang out by his pod,
wait for him to wake up,
make him cough up some answers.
I mean we use the transfer technology,
and see what he's up to.
There's no way I'm getting sealed up
in one of those things, all gift-wrapped
and helpless for the G.A, no fricken way.
I'll do it.
He did it for me.
With the Android out of commission,
we need you here,
you're our resident tech expert.
I'll go.
You go with him.
Hang on.
He, uncharacteristically,
makes a good point.
You're pretty damn
vulnerable lying trapped,
in one of those things.
Six respects you.
If there's any confrontation,
you'll be able to reason with him.
You have to go.
For the duration of your travel,
your body will remain here in cryo-sleep.
When your clone returns for
bio-mass recycling at the end of the trip,
its experiences
and memories will be uploaded,
transferred back,
and reintegrated with your own.
- Is it safe?
- Absolutely.
It's the safest way to travel.
With your true body here,
you're never in any real danger.
Your clone could travel
into the center of a star,
and you'd be perfectly fine.
The possibility of any critical
complications is extremely remote.
What do you mean by critical complications?
It's barely worth mentioning.
There have been a handful of incidents,
strokes, heart attacks,
the occasional aneurysm,
but a causal link back to the technology
has never been established.
Well, that doesn't sound so...
Sold.
Excellent, let's see
when we've got a slot available...
How about next...
How about right now.
Right now?
Okay, let's get you signed up.
- Are you a couple?
- No.
- Is there a discount?
- Ten percent.
Well then yes, we are a couple.
Also, a good friend of ours
was in earlier today.
Griffin Jones.
We'd like to meet up with him.
Did he tell you where he was going?
No.
He doesn't know we're meeting up with him.
It's a surprise.
Yeah, it's his birthday.
Well I can't divulge information
about other customers.
It's against company policy.
Also, it's definitely not his birthday.
That's one of the things
you have to provide when you sign up.
Let me ask you something.
Haven't you ever been tempted
to just break the rules, and finally...
Get back at my big
faceless corporate bosses
for making me feel
so small and insignificant?
Send red team to pick up the shipment.
Sir, I've detected an incoming shuttle.
Headed our way.
First squad, with me.
Update us if you hear anything.
Yes, sir.
Okay, I've entered
your destination coordinates
and you're all set.
Just lie back and relax.
Hang on, what if there's
some kind of medical issue?
The system automatically monitors
for signs of physical distress.
At the first indication,
you'll be pulled right out.
Okay.
Good.
Wait!
What if there's a fire?
In all station-related emergencies,
my first priority is to awaken all travelers
and get them to safety.
Ready.
Hang on, what if...
Wait, wait, hang on, wait
wait, excuse me, excuse me, hello?
That's far enough.
You've got some balls coming here.
I'm unarmed.
I'm here to see The General.
Just so happens he's waiting for you.
You ready?
Yeah.
Let's go find Six.
What the hell man?!
Who are you and where is he?!
What are you talking about?!
Oh, crap.
Who are you?
It's me, it's One.
You're Four.
The rest of the crew is back on the Raza.
We just used the transfer tech
to follow Six to this space station
to find out what he's up to.
Three is an asshole.
- It is you.
- Yeah.
A glitch in the transfer process?
Can't be, this body was constructed
on your DNA template, so...
This is my real body.
This is what I look like.
Really look like.
I'm sorry.
You're awake!
My system is 93% restored,
but my corrector nanites are more
efficient while I'm in sleep mode.
Well, welcome back.
Thank you.
Why are you sorry?
You got hurt because of me.
I possess no pain receptors.
I mean you were damaged
by that other android
because I suggested
that you apologize to her.
I apologized because you presented
a reasoned argument to do so.
I had no choice but to respond accordingly.
Of course you had a choice.
In fact, no.
I'm a logic-based entity, therefore,
I act and react in a purely logical manner.
No, no you don't.
I've seen you angry, sad, lonely, happy.
You might not have pain receptors,
but your feelings can get hurt.
I've seen it happen.
You were jealous of Wendy.
I was not jealous.
Think of the impression
that she made on you,
when you saw her with us.
Now that I think of it,
I did experience a sensation
that could be misconstrued
as human resentment.
No.
That was jealousy.
And you know what that means.
My programming is flawed.
No, you have feelings.
Congratulations.
Hopefully this Draves fellow shows up.
Look, I'm sorry.
I should've just come clean sooner.
True.
I don't know why
I was posing as Jace Corso.
I don't remember.
So whatever hidden agenda I might have had,
it's gone now, right?
I know you can't speak for anyone else,
so I just want to know
where I stand with you.
We cool?
At the moment,
I think I'm the least of your worries.
You wanted to talk to me?
We're looking for someone.
Seems a lot of people are doing that today.
Big guy, came through about an hour ago.
Last we heard,
he was headed in your direction.
Yeah, I know where your friend is.
He's no friend of ours.
Then what business do you have with him?
Payback.
Well, why didn't you just say so?
Hey, Griff.
Good to see you again.
So what brings you back
after all this time?
Unfinished business.
Thought you were just tired of running.
It must get really exhausting,
always having to look over your shoulder,
never to be sure who you can trust.
I imagine it's hard making new friends
when you have a reputation
for killing the old ones.
They weren't my friends.
They were your brothers in arms
and they trusted you.
And I trusted you when I flew that shuttle
onto the station to take that G.A. cruiser.
You manipulated me,
made me complicit in mass murder.
You were a soldier.
My soldier.
And we were at war and that station,
that was a legitimate target.
Over ten thousand lives were lost,
including children.
Hundreds die every day
under corporate rule,
and the Galactic Authority,
our protectors,
they stand by and let it happen.
There's no such thing
as a bloodless revolution.
You know you were a good soldier, Griff.
Determined.
Relentless.
The very qualities
that now make you a threat.
You'll be dead before your friends arrive.
Apparently they're on their way.
And my men, they are
more than ready to welcome them.
You keep checking the time.
You waiting for something?
Sonovabitch.
Well, Griff. Timing:
not really your strong suit.
What the hell was that?
I figured this was a one-way trip,
so I set my shuttle to go critical.
Though it did take
a little longer than I thought.
Timing not being my strong suit, right?
Are you kidding me?
What have you done?
He was a clone.
I know.
So am I.
So shoot, don't shoot.
It's not gonna make
much of a difference in the long run.
How'd you find me?
We asked around.
Who's your friend?
Long story.
You lied to us.
I didn't so much lie as...
slightly delay telling the truth.
Oh, really?
And when exactly were you
planning to tell us that truth?
Honestly?
I don't know.
I was looking for
the right opportunity but,
when's a good time to tell your friends
you're not who they thought you were?
Hell, you're not who you thought you were.
All I know is I assumed an identity
to get on board this ship.
As to why,..
I have no idea.
Right after that incident
with the real Jace Corso,
you should have told us everything.
Hiding the truth makes us vulnerable.
If Corso had come back at us,
we never would have seen him coming.
I know.
I didn't think it through.
Is there anything else
you'd like to tell us?
Now's the time.
And you!
You knew, and you kept it a secret.
That's just as bad.
It's not as bad.
It was strictly for blackmail purposes.
We don't keep secrets,
and we don't blackmail each other either.
Fine.
And you.
What reason do you have
for putting us all at risk?
It was something I had to do alone.
I didn't want any of you
talking me out of it,
or screwing it up.
That's an apology?
No.
It's me being honest.
That's what you want, isn't it?
What I want is for us
to be able to trust each other.
Moving forward,
no more lies, no more secrets.
We have to have faith in each other
if we're going to survive.
But despite everything that we've
been through, we just can't seem to do it.
Whoever wiped our memories,
probably did it to make it
harder for us to work together.
Guess what?
It worked.
It all looks good.
Are you sure?
No discernible abnormalities?
None that I can see.
Why?
Are you worried about something?
You're implying that I experience anxiety.
What are you suggesting?
Nothing.
Touchy.
Suggestive of hypersensitivity.
All the diagnostics show normal.
You're fine.
Which is more than I can say
for the rest of the crew.
What's wrong with the rest of the crew?
The atmosphere on this ship is bad.
The atmosphere is optimal.
It's 78.084% Nitrogen,
20.9476% Oxygen, 0...
Morale.
I mean morale is bad.
Yes, that is suboptimal.
We have to find a way to trust each other.
I mean, if we can't even do that,
how can we possibly hope to survive?
How indeed.
You look like you want to say something.
If you honestly feel this way,
why don't you tell them?
Tell them what?
The truth.
About yourself.
How was your workout?
It was good.
We've got another three hours or so
before they finish repairs on the ship.
And some of us were thinking of
heading into the station to catch a movie.
Do you wanna come?
No thanks.
But it's Star Wars 36.
Remastered in full VR,
they say it's a classic.
Naw, I'm good.
Have fun though.
But you said we would hang out later...
This is the Ishida Directorate.
How may I help you?
You know who I am.
I wish to speak with Hiro.
One moment.
Ryo?
Hello, brother.
There was a dramatic development today
in the investigation into the death
of Catherine Moss,
the wife of CoreLactic Industries'
new CEO, Derrick Moss.
The Galactic authority identified this man,
Marcus Boone, as a suspect in the case.
Boone is a career criminal
already wanted on dozens
of unrelated charges.
He is considered armed
and extremely dangerous.
Original sync by kategreen
WEB-DL resync by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
subs improved and approved by MacRellen