ANNOUNCER: The National
Football League welcomes you
to the Pepsi Super Bowl
XLIX Halftime Show.
(music playing)
Sync and Corrected by er1ck9
www.addic7ed.com
("Roar" by Katy Perry)
(music continues)
Super Bowl, are you ready to rock?
KATY PERRY:
Come on!
♪ I used to bite my tongue
and hold my breath ♪
♪ Scared to rock the boat
and make a mess ♪
♪ So I sit quietly ♪
♪ Agreed politely ♪
♪ I guess that I forgot I had a choice ♪
♪ I let you push me past
the breaking point ♪
♪ I stood for nothing ♪
♪ So I fell for everything ♪
♪ You held me down but I got up ♪
♪ Already brushing off the dust ♪
♪ You hear my voice,
you hear that sound ♪
♪ Like thunder gonna shake the ground ♪
♪ You held me down but I got up ♪
♪ Get ready 'cause I've had enough ♪
♪ I see it all ♪
♪ I see it now ♪
♪ I got the eye of the tiger, a fighter ♪
♪ Dancing through the fire ♪
♪ 'Cause I am a champion ♪
♪ And you're gonna hear me roar ♪
♪ Louder, louder than a lion ♪
♪ 'Cause I am a champion ♪
♪ And you're gonna hear me roar ♪
♪ You're gonna hear me... ♪
(roaring)
("Dark Horse" by Katy Perry and Juicy J)
(music playing)
♪ I knew you were. ♪
♪ You were gonna come to me ♪
♪ And here you are ♪
♪ But you better choose carefully ♪
♪ ‘Cause I, I’m capable of anything ♪
♪ Of anything and everything ♪
♪ Make me your Aphrodite ♪
♪ Make me your one and only ♪
♪ But don’t make me your enemy, ♪
♪ your enemy, your enemy ♪
♪ So you wanna play with magic ♪
♪ Boy, you should know ♪
♪ what you're falling for ♪
♪ Baby do you dare to do this? ♪
♪ Cause I’m coming at
you like a dark horse ♪
♪ Are you ready for, ready for ♪
♪ a perfect storm, perfect storm ♪
♪ Cause once you’re mine,
once you’re mine ♪
♪ There’s no going back ♪
KATY PERRY:
Ladies and gentlemen, Lenny Kravitz!
("I Kissed a Girl" by Katy Perry)
♪ This was never the way I planned ♪
♪ Not my intention ♪
♪ I got so brave, drink in hand ♪
♪ Lost my discretion ♪
♪ It's not what, I'm used to ♪
♪ Just wanna try you on ♪
♪ I'm curious for you ♪
♪ Caught my attention ♪
♪ I kissed a girl and I liked it ♪
♪ The taste of her cherry chap stick ♪
♪ I kissed a girl just to try it ♪
♪ I hope my boyfriend don't mind it ♪
♪ It felt so wrong
It felt so right ♪
♪ Don't mean I'm in love tonight ♪
♪ I kissed a girl and I liked it ♪
♪ I liked it ♪
("Teenage Dream" by Katy Perry)
(music playing)
♪ You think I'm pretty ♪
♪ Without any make-up on ♪
♪ You think I'm funny ♪
♪ When I tell the puch line wrong ♪
♪ I know you get me ♪
♪ So I'll let my walls come down, down ♪
♪ Before you met me ♪
♪ I was a wreck but things ♪
♪ were kinda heavy ♪
♪ You brought me to life ♪
♪ now every February ♪
♪ You'll be my valentine, valentine ♪
♪ You make me ♪
♪ Feel like I'm living a ♪
♪ Teenage Dream ♪
♪ The way you turn me on ♪
♪ I can't sleep ♪
♪ Let's runaway ♪
♪ And don't ever look back ♪
♪ Don't ever look back ♪
♪ My heart stops ♪
♪ When you look at me ♪
♪ Just one touch ♪
♪ Now baby I believe ♪
♪ This is real ♪
♪ So take a chance ♪
♪ And don't ever look back ♪
♪ Don't ever look back ♪
♪ I might get your heart racing ♪
♪ In my skin-tight jeans ♪
♪ Be your teenage dream tonight ♪
♪ Let you put your hands on me ♪
♪ In my skin-tight jeans ♪
♪ Be your teenage dream tonight ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ Tonight. ♪
Make some noise, Super Bowl!
("California Gurls" by Katy Perry
Ft. Snoop Dogg)
♪ I know a place ♪
Sing that!
Where the grass is really greener
♪ Warm, wet and wild ♪
♪ There must be something in the water ♪
♪ Sippin' gin and juice ♪
♪ Laying underneath the palm trees, undone ♪
♪ The boys break their necks ♪
♪ Tryin' to creep a little sneak peek ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ California gurls, we're unforgettable ♪
♪ Daisy dukes, bikinis on top ♪
♪ Sun-kissed skin, so hot, ♪
♪ will melt your popsicle ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ California gurls, we're undeniable ♪
♪ Fine, fresh, fierce, we got it on lock ♪
♪ West Coast represent, ♪
♪ now put your hands up ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
California!
(music playing)
("Get Ur Freak On" by Missy Elliott)
♪ Gimme me some new... ♪
Let's go.
♪ Missy be puttin it down ♪
♪ Im the hottest round ♪
♪ Ill told yall mutha... ♪
♪ Yall can stop me now ♪
- Come on!
- ♪ Listen to me now ♪
- ♪ I'm lastin twenty rounds ♪
- Come on!
♪ And if you want me, nigga ♪
♪ then come and get me now, bounce ♪
♪ Is you with me now, bounce ♪
♪ The biggie biggie bounce, bounce ♪
♪ I kno you dig the way ♪
♪ i sw..sw...switched ma style  ♪
- Holla.
- Come on, Missy.
- ♪ People sing around ♪
♪ Now people gather round ♪
♪ Now people jump around ♪
♪ Getcho freak on.. go... ♪
♪ Getcha Getcha Getcha
Getcha Getcha freak on ♪
♪ Getcho freak on.. go... ♪
♪ Getcha Getcha Getcha
Getcha Getcha freak on ♪
If you a fly gal get
your nails done
Get a pedicure,
get your hair did
("Work It" by Missy Elliott)
♪ Is it worth it, let me work it ♪
♪ I put my thing down,
flip it and reverse it ♪
♪ ti esrever dna ti nwod gniht ym tup i ♪
♪ If you got a..., let me search it ♪
♪ and find out how hard I gotta work you ♪
♪ ti esrever dna ti nwod gniht ym tup i ♪
♪ Is it worth it, let me work it ♪
♪ I put my thing down,
flip it and reverse it ♪
♪ ti esrever dna ti nwod gniht ym tup i ♪
♪ If you got a..., let me search it ♪
♪ and find out how hard I gotta work you ♪
♪ ti esrever dna ti nwod gniht ym tup i ♪
Music make you lose control.
Let's go!
("Lose Control" by Missy Elliott
Ft. Ciara, Fatman Scoop)
(music playing)
♪ I've got a cute face, Chubby waist ♪
♪ Thick legs in shape ♪
♪ Rump shaking both ways ♪
♪ Make you do a double take ♪
♪ Planet Rocka show stopper ♪
♪ Flo froppa head knocker ♪
♪ Beat stalla tail dropper ♪
♪ Do my thang motherf.... ♪
♪ Everybody here, Get it outta control ♪
♪ Get your backs off the wall ♪
♪ Cause misdemeanor said so ♪
♪ Throw your hands in the air ♪
- Everybody
- Music makes you lose control.
("Firework" by Katy Perry)
(music playing)
♪ Do you ever feel like a plastic bag ♪
♪ Drifting through the wind ♪
♪ Wanting to start again ♪
♪ Do you ever feel, feel so paper thin ♪
♪ Like a house of cards ♪
♪ one blow from caving in ♪
♪ Do you ever feel already buried deep ♪
♪ Six feet under scream but no ♪
♪ one seems to hear a thing ♪
♪ Do you know that there's ♪
♪ still a chance for you ♪
♪ Cause there's a spark in you ♪
♪ You just gotta ignite the light ♪
♪ And let it shine ♪
♪ Just own the night ♪
♪ like the Fourth of July ♪
♪ Cause baby you're a firework ♪
♪ Come on show 'em what you worth ♪
♪ Make 'em go "Oh, oh, oh!" ♪
♪ As you shoot across the sky-y-y ♪
♪ Baby you're a firework ♪
♪ Come on let your colors burst ♪
♪ Make 'em go "Oh, oh, oh!" ♪
♪ You're gonna leave 'em ♪
♪ fallin' down-own-own ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Even brighter than the moon, moon, moon ♪
♪ It's always been inside of you, you, you ♪
♪ And now it's time to let it through ♪
♪ Cause baby you're a firework ♪
♪ Come on let your colors burst ♪
♪ Make 'em go "Oh, oh, oh!" ♪
♪ You're gonna leave 'em going "Oh, oh, oh!" ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Even brighter than the moon, moon, moon ♪
Thank you, God Bless America!
ANNOUNCER: The National Football
League thanks you for
watching the Pepsi Super
Bowl XLIX Halftime Show.
Sync and Corrected by er1ck9
www.addic7ed.com