Can you just listen up?
Guys?
We got 2,000 feet, 600 vertical meters
to Camp Four.
It's roped all the way,
so I know you can make it.
Once we get to the yellow band,
-(COUGHING)
-we're gonna regroup
put on the masks, turn on the gas.
Make sense?
(WIND WHOOSHING)
325 dollars a bottle.
For oxygen?
That's daylight robbery!
Yeah, well, he's cornered the market,
he's got it.
He reckons there's gonna be 20 teams
at Base Camp this season.
Twenty teams?
HAROLD: I mean, with all
the Sherpas and porters,
it's gonna be a squeeze up there.
Well, that's a scrum on the ropes, right there.
-HAROLD: What is this?
-It's Helen's.
It's a little decoration for the mess tent.
You can wear them in your hair.
I'll have that. Thank you.
Okay, I got some news.
-We got Krakauer.
-(HAROLD EXCLAIMING)
You stole him from Scott Fischer?
No, he made up his own mind.
HAROLD: Good job, Rob!
How much is he paying you, Rob?
Well, he's only paying for his airfare
-(SIGHS)
-but we get 5,000 words in the magazine
and our picture on the front cover. Huh?
That makes it all worthwhile. Right there.
Well, if you get him to the top.
ROB: If?
If? How can you say that to me?
There you go. You all right?
ROB: Thanks, Guy. Cheers, mate.
-HELEN: Hey!
-Hello!
-JAN: You all right?
-Oh, yeah, how are you?
-Me? I'm good.
-Oh, look at you!
I know, I'm big.
-ROB: Here you go.
-You good?
Yeah, you know, I'm just gonna miss you.
HELEN: Come on.
-Let's go, Guy.
-GUY: Mmm-hmm.
Just go careful, all right?
-It's...
-Please, my love.
Come on. Please don't worry.
It's just the doing nothing back here
that's making me worry.
You're not doing nothing.
No, but...
What?
It's the waiting for you.
-For him.
-Her.
Just be back for the birth, Rob Hall.
You try and stop me.
WOMAN: (ON PA) This is a final call
for Air New Zealand
Flight 7419 to Kathmandu.
-Okay, I love you.
-Go, or I'll cry.
Go.
(SNIFFLES)
(INAUDIBLE)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Yeah.
That all you got?
Yeah, that's it.
DOUG: I think we're over here.
Hey, what outfit you guys with?
Uh, Adventure Consultants.
Ah, good. Me too.
-DOUG: Ah.
-I'm Beck.
-Beck Weathers.
-Doug Hansen.
-Jon Krakauer.
-How you doing?
-Good.
-Are you, uh...
-Krakauer from Outside magazine?
-Yep.
Really?
What are you doing?
Writing or climbing or what?
-Little bit of both.
-Hmm.
Well, I'll let you know
how the summit goes, okay?
No need. I'll be there.
Ah, we'll see.
What do you do
when you're not climbing, Doug?
-What, for work?
-Yeah.
Uh, different things. Carpenter, mailman.
Carpenter, mailman?
DOUG: Yep.
Seriously, you deliver the mail?
Yeah, I deliver the mail.
Mailman on Everest?
(CHUCKLES) Hope so.
(CHUCKLES) I like that.
Mailman on Everest.
BECK: There we go.
JON: Beck.
BECK: Yeah?
You know he made it
to the South Summit on Everest last year?
-Who, Doug did?
-Yeah.
That's pretty high for a mailman.
Yep. Longs Peak, McKinley.
I never made it up to
the top of McKinley myself.
-I know.
-Well, how do you know that?
'89, right?
Oh!
You've done your research.
That's what we do.
You, my friends,
are following in some very famous footsteps.
A history made famous by George Everest,
George Mallory,
Tenzing Norgay, Edmund Hillary.
HAROLD: And Rob Hall!
(PEOPLE CHUCKLING)
(STUTTERING)
-Legends all of them!
-(ALL CHUCKLING)
That's right.
For those of you who dare face their dreams,
Adventure Consultants offers something
beyond the power of words to describe.
And why don't we describe it in the brochure?
Because it's mostly just pain.
HAROLD: Yes.
BECK: Ain't that the truth?
ROB: And the odd, if you don't mind, Mike,
and the odd missing toe.
-There we go.
-(ALL GROANING)
ROB: To put it simply, guys, human beings
simply aren't built to function
at the cruising altitude of a 747.
Okay, once we get above here,
above the South Col
our bodies will be literally dying.
And I mean literally dying.
It's not called
the Death Zone for nothing, guys.
So the game is,
can we get you up to the top
and down to the bottom
before that happens?
-You sure can.
-ROB: Oh!
(CHUCKLES) Beck Weathers,
ladies and gentlemen.
You might have noticed
a bit of the Lone Star State?
100% Texan right here, people.
100% Texan.
You've met Mike Groom.
I'd like to introduce you to Andy Harris.
-Harold.
-ROB: Our other guide out of Queenstown.
Taranaki, actually, originally. Kia ora.
ROB: Helen and the rest of the team
are already on the way up to Base Camp.
They're setting it up for when we get there.
Today's March 30, people.
I plan on going for the summit May 10.
It's been a lucky day for me
and Adventure Consultants
and the weather's usually
pretty stable around then.
So that means,
we have 40 days
to train your bodies and your minds
to go for it.
Now, I know there's a lot of mountaineering
experience in this room.
You wouldn't be here without it.
-Stu, K2, Broad Peak.
-(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
John Taske.
1,192 meters of Mount Kosciuszko.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
And... I mean, Yasuko Namba.
Six of the Seven Summits
and the only woman.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
BECK: There you go.
-HAROLD: Let's make it seven.
-Thank you.
But Everest, though, is another beast,
another beast altogether.
That's why you're here,
isn't that right, Dougie?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
So, listen. Tonight, that's it from me.
Eat, drink, be merry.
Tomorrow, we trek.
-We good?
-You ready for this?
(CHUCKLING)
Dougie.
ROB: All right, folks, hang on.
YASUKO: Okay.
ROB: That's it, here we go, Colonel.
MIKE: All right, everybody, earbuds.
ROB: Take your seats, buckle in, everyone.
BECK: Thanks, Mike.
Do or die. Here we go.
YASUKO: Okay.
BECK: Can you believe it?
PILOT: Bravo 270 en route, request Bravo 410.
Keep 'em all in a nice group.
Hey, guys, take it easy.
YASUKO: Yes, I'm ready.
DOUG: Ready.
ROB: We're kicking it off, let's go.
DOUG: You lead the way, pal.
You all right?
Yes.
ROB: Guys, man wants to
see your climbing permits.
Need to see all your climbing permits!
-(SPEAKING NEPALI)
-Namaste.
ROB: Thank you very much,
we'll see you on the way back.
MAN: Thank you very much.
-All good?
-DOUG: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, you?
-Yeah.
-Hey, uh...
Thanks, Rob.
Thanks for what?
You know, the discount.
Well, you're working three jobs, Doug.
It was the least I could do, mate.
I know, you didn't have to do it, though,
and I appreciate it.
Let's just get you to the top this time.
Yeah.
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-How you feeling, Beck?
Fair to middling.
Come on, buddy, you can do it.
Thought I was
gonna acclimatize faster than this.
Uh, you'll be all right.
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
Darn critters.
Whoo!
-Wow.
-Yeah.
BECK: How close did you get?
DOUG: Well, I got real close
but it got late and I was
pretty shot anyways.
Well, I think I would have made a run for it.
Every day I wake up thinking that.
Then why didn't you do it?
ROB: 'Cause I turned him around.
Morning 15 at the South Summit,
bad conditions,
we weren't gonna make
our 2:00 p.m. turnaround.
See, it's all good and well
to make the top, Beck
but you pay me to bring you down safely.
Remember that.
Okay.
What's eating him?
One of our Sherpas, Tenzing.
He had an accident.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Fell while fixing
one of the ladders on the Icefall.
It's not good. They had to bring him down.
(DRUM BEATING)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Namaste.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
ROB: Congratulations, you all made it.
Welcome to Base Camp!
We got the United Nations here this year.
Got the IMAX team, South Africans.
And right up here
in the best spot of all
we have the Adventure
Consultants Base Camp.
-MIKE: Hey, Helen.
-Hey. Hi, how are you?
-Good to see you. Thank you.
-Welcome, nice to see you.
-Hi, Rob.
-Hey.
Well done, you all right?
ROB: Yeah, good. You?
-Yeah, no, we're good.
-ROB: It looks good.
For those of you that haven't met,
this is Helen Wilton,
Base Camp manager.
She will be your mom for the next few weeks.
Any problems, take it to her and she'll sort it.
All right, well, it's very nice
to finally meet you all in person.
Ang Dorjee, come here.
This is Ang Dorjee, everyone.
He's your climbing sirdar, your lead Sherpa.
Hey, how are ya?
You speak English?
Better than you, Mr. America.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
-Bet you climb better than I do, huh?
-Yeah.
-(ALL CHUCKLING)
-Yeah?
Summited three times, Beck.
All right, all right. I hear ya, I hear ya.
All right, well, there's tea in the mess tent
when you've dumped your sacks
and the comms tent's down the back,
that's the cooking tent, and over there
is the toilet.
It's a little bit drafty, but just remember that
when the wind gets up here, you've got
the same view that George Everest did.
IAN: For those of you
who haven't used crampons before
the left and rights
are marked with an "L" and an "R,"
so you can't get it wrong.
All right? So, simple.
First of all,
you push it into the shoe with this.
Unbelievable.
If it isn't the mayor of Base Camp!
ROB: Scott Fischer, Mr. Mountain Madness.
In the flesh.
SCOTT: You want a cup?
Sit down, man. Acclimatize!
Okay. I'm normally a tea man myself,
but let's give it a go.
Thank you so much.
Wow. It's crazy this year, eh?
I know, man.
Some idiot Kiwi goes
and invents Himalayan guiding
and look what happens.
Yeah, it didn't
take you too long to get in on the act.
Gotta make a living, man.
You went ahead and fixed the icefalls, I see.
Yeah, yeah.
-It's pretty messy up there this year.
-Yeah?
Crevasses are pretty big.
Strung four or five ladders across.
ROB: You used good ropes though,
didn't you?
SANDY: You ready? Okay.
This is, um, April seventh, about 10:30 a.m.,
this is Sandy Hill Pittman,
reporting for NBC Interactive Media
-and we are officially at Everest Base Camp!
-(CHUCKLING)
-She one of yours?
-Oh, yeah.
Someone went and stole my journalist
-so I had to get another one.
-Hmm.
She's a lot easier on the eye
than Jon Krakauer
-that's for sure.
-Listen, just to be clear,
I didn't steal your journalist.
Hey, man, it's all good.
Outside magazine gave me a call.
-Hey. Hey!
-They gave me a call.
-Said they wanted to...
-SCOTT: It's all good, man.
They were gonna send a journalist up the hill
and asked me if I was interested.
It was his call in the end.
All right, Caroline MacKenzie, team doctor.
Why don't you kick it off, Caro.
-Hi, everyone.
-DOUG: Hey, Caro.
Hi there.
-Sorry.
-That's fine.
Um...
So Rob and Harold and Mike will tell you
all sorts of stuff about mountaineering,
but from a medical standpoint
getting you to the top of Everest
is really about oxygen.
And the lack of it.
To give you the best chance of summiting
you need to prepare your bodies
for the thin air up there.
So, over the next month,
before the final ascent
you're gonna make
three partial acclimatizing ascents
returning here to Base Camp after each one.
ROB: The bad news is that each ascent
begins and ends with the Icefall.
I'm sorry, but there is no way around it.
There are millions of tons of glacial ice
continually moving day and night.
You got seracs the size of tower blocks,
you got crevasses so deep
they probably don't even have a bottom.
It is not a place that
you wanna get caught hanging out in,
especially when the sun hits it.
So we're gonna be up nice and early
and through that as soon as possible.
Now the Sherpas have gone ahead
and fixed the ladders across the crevasses
and we've made it as safe as we possibly can.
But that is not to say
that it is completely safe.
19 people have died in that Icefall.
BECK: Whoa! Whoa! Hold on!
Steady.
HAROLD: You all right, Jon?
You all right?
-I'm good.
-DOUG: Okay.
-All right, steady up.
-Whoo!
ROB: So remember, we're a team.
Let's look out for each other.
CAROLINE: Look out for hypothermia,
things like slurred speech
and irrational behavior.
I've seen hypoxic climbers rip off
all their clothes at 8,000 meters
because they're feeling hot.
You all know about cerebral edema,
the swelling of your brain
to the point of loss of motor function
and eventually death.
And pulmonary edema,
which is your lungs filling with fluid
-so you effectively drown.
-(COUGHING)
The only cure is to get
down the mountain, fast.
-All right, okay.
-NEAL: All right, buddy.
ROB: But it is not
all doom and gloom here, okay?
Myself and the whole AC team are here
to make sure you get up and down safely
and you will acclimatize naturally.
So why don't we all
give Caro a nice big thank you,
it's her first time here.
DOUG: All right.
BECK: Nice job.
Well done.
HAROLD: See, you want to
get on the regulator.
You want to hear that hiss.
(GAS HISSING)
Connect your hose.
-Yasuko.
-YASUKO: Beck.
-How'd you do, darling?
-Okay.
BECK: Good?
HAROLD: Well done.
JON: Can I get a hit of that?
HAROLD: Have a suck on that.
In a situation like this, you just wanna
catch your breath, throw it up to four.
You should start feeling pretty good.
BECK: I can feel it already.
How did you boys go?
-Hey.
-Instant happiness.
-It's amazing.
-JON: Very happy.
(DOUG COUGHING)
ROB: Doug, you okay?
Well, when we get back to Base,
I want you to get Caro to take a look at you.
-No. I'm all right, I'm okay.
-ROB: No, no.
And do me a favor,
spend your night on oxygen.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
We got enough?
-We got plenty.
-All right.
Get some tea into ya.
Just lift your shirt up a bit.
Thank you.
And take a deep breath for me?
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(COUGHING)
Just take one of those in the morning
with a bit of water, before breakfast.
Okay, thanks.
-Right, Beck, you're up.
-Sorry. Here, go for it.
Read it and weep.
CAROLINE: Take it easy, Doug.
-Right, you can stop.
-Yeah?
You're in great shape, Beck.
I am in great shape.
-You are.
-ROB: Six days a week in the gym.
-Ought to do it.
-Your wife must love that.
Yeah, she does.
Oh, no. What's the date today?
April 25th.
No!
BECK: I need to send a message to my wife.
Can I use your fax?
You might wanna look at this one first.
It came in for you last night.
(BECK SIGHS)
-Lord.
-ROB: What?
-BECK: Can I use your sat phone?
-Ooh!
Well, if this did come in last night,
it's an emergency.
HELEN: It's 25 bucks a minute, Beck.
Yep, fine.
No, this one's on us.
BECK: Seriously?
Thanks.
Rob!
-Beck?
-BECK: Peach, it's me.
What's happened?
Nothing, nothing. I'm fine.
Where are you?
Uh, I'm at Base Camp right now.
You're calling me from Everest?
Yeah, it's a satellite phone, honey.
PEACH: Oh, my God, how much
is that costing? What's the problem?
There is no problem, Peach.
Uh...
I'm sorry, we were up at Camp Two
and that's why I didn't
send you a fax yesterday.
Happy anniversary! Okay?
How are the kids?
Fine.
Peach?
Bub's here
doing his homework
in the morning, as per usual.
You wanna say hi to him?
Well, yeah, of course I do.
-Hang on.
-Okay.
-Say hi.
-Hey, Dad!
-Hey, bud!
-MEG: Hi!
I miss you, buddy.
Oh! And Meg went on her first date
last weekend.
(EXCLAIMS)
Well, you did!
-Wow! Really?
-Mmm-hmm.
-BUB: Get off!
-Peach?
I miss you, honey.
Mom? Mom?
I miss the kids.
A lot.
Peach?
Listen, I gotta get the kids to school
so I gotta run.
Okay.
PEACH: Yeah, go careful.
Bye-bye.
Is Dad okay?
Just, he never calls.
I think he's scared.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Here, come in, mate, come on!
-Come on.
-TASKE: Come on, Beck.
You don't dance, you don't climb!
Come on, guys, Beck Weathers!
ALL: (CHANTING)
No dance, no climb! No dance, no climb!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
NEAL: Hey, man. Breaking into the rations?
Yeah, you want some?
NEAL: No. I'll wait till we summit.
I don't know about that, Neal.
We'll get there.
I'm excited.
Anyway, me and Anatoli
are here to help you, you know?
There's too much competition, Toli.
We don't need competition between people.
There is competition
between every person and this mountain.
The last word
always belongs to the mountain.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
-Ang Dorjee!
-ANG: Yeah?
Stay there, Beck, stay there.
ANG: Okay, I'm coming down!
(ANG SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Harold, Mike, this is Rob.
-(ON RADIO) Mike here.
-This isn't happening, guys.
Let's turn 'em around,
let's get 'em off the face and back
down to Base Camp. Turn around.
-Ang Dorjee, come on, we're going down.
-ANG: Okay.
My hand.
Okay, make a fist again.
Keep clenching, just keep the blood flowing.
What's going on, man?
We're still waiting for the South Africans.
Taiwanese took forever as well.
SCOTT: Hey, Ian.
You haven't paid for these ladders.
Yeah, yeah. Your Yak Fund money's coming.
SCOTT: You serious, man?
Come on, get a move on.
How long you been waiting here?
Good 45 minutes.
Man, it's freezing.
-Yeah.
-HAROLD: It's stinging, huh?
Yeah. Right at the tips.
Hey, Rob, we gotta get 'em over.
ROB: We're working on it.
HAROLD: He's freezing, mate.
ROB: Are you set?
MIKE: Clear.
ROB: Sending him over, Mike!
MIKE: Yeah, all right.
ROB: Looking good, Beck.
Looking good.
That's it. No, head up, mate, head up.
Steady yourself!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
BECK: Little help? Help! Help!
ROB: Mike, you good?
Are these ladders gonna take two?
Yeah, I'll get a rope, I'll belay you.
ROB: Just stay right where you are, mate.
BECK: I can't pull myself up!
-(GRUNTING)
-ROB: I'm gonna come out to you.
BECK: Okay.
You're good, Beck, you're okay.
Got it for you.
ROB: Right, tie me in, Scott, tie me in.
BECK: Come and get me!
ROB: On belay?
SCOTT: Got it. On belay.
ROB: Let's go.
Right, I'm coming out to you, Beck.
Here I come, mate.
(BECK GRUNTING)
ROB: Nice and easy, you're tied in, mate.
BECK: I can't feel my hands.
ROB: You're looking good.
-BECK: Grab me.
-Beck, Beck, Beck.
-BECK: Grab me!
-Stay right where you are, mate.
I'm right here, I'm coming to you.
I can't pull myself up!
I got ya.
You okay?
There's no guarantee to the summit, I get it.
But to get killed because I'm waiting in line
like I'm in freaking Walmart.
That's not why I paid you 65,000 dollars.
Now get me off of here.
ROB: That's it. Plant your feet one at a time.
ROB: All right, thanks for coming by.
Uh...
Look, Base Camp's, you know,
chockablock full this year, so,
I think it would all benefit us greatly
by coming together like this
and, you know,
working out some kind of plan and schedule.
What, like some kind of rota?
Yes.
On Everest?
IAN: Everyone knows Everest is a business
for you, Robert, are you kidding?
What gives you the right to tell us
when we can climb and when we can't?
I'm not telling you, mate. I'm asking.
If we know when everybody's
planning to summit, for instance,
you know, we can avoid the chaos
that happened in the Icefall today.
Adventure Consultants are aiming for May 10.
-So are we, man!
-Us too.
May 10.
Okay, that's bumper-to-bumper traffic
on the Hillary Step.
ROB: Yes, it is, that's my point.
Look, this is ridiculous.
We're summiting when we want.
All right?
And I don't need
your permission to climb the mountain.
ROB: Ian, have you seen
how many people are here at Base Camp?
-We're finished here. Come on, guys.
-Ian! Hey, man.
(SINGING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
SCOTT: Oh, Rob!
-Ah! Come in, man!
-ROB: Hi.
SCOTT: Have a drink, Rob! Come on, man.
Na zdorovie.
ALL: Na zdorovie!
-Can we have a word?
-Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
You feeling a little crook, huh?
No, it's just a little...
Little touch of the Delhi belly.
SANDY: He means Buddha belly.
-SCOTT: Maybe Sandy's caviar.
-(SANDY LAUGHING)
SANDY: I told you not to have
the Dom Perignon with it!
What's going on, Roberto?
I don't like the look
of the crowds on the ropes.
I think we're gonna have some trouble
once we get above Camp Three.
I mean, you wanna top it on the 10th, yeah?
-Yeah.
-So do I.
What, are you saying we should team up?
Well, it's an idea, yeah.
Oh, man.
I don't know, man.
We have different styles, man.
All due respect, you're a hand-holder.
I mean, the best, but...
I just believe
that if you can't get up there yourself
you shouldn't be on the mountain at all.
You guide your team, I guide mine.
I'm just suggesting that we work
with each other instead of against.
The only way we both summit, mate,
is if we work together.
Particularly fixing the ropes.
It's gotta make sense.
(SIGHS)
Whoo-ie! Why not?
-Yeah?
-Yeah, I see the sense in it.
Good man. That was all.
All right.
Who's gonna lead when we get up there?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Rob. If I say I will do it, it will be done.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
SCOTT: You gotta work with Ang Dorjee,
because we're working together now.
ROB: I'm just saying, if both of us...
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Okay?
Ang Dorjee.
We're all professionals here.
We'll work together
and we'll get the job done. Yes?
-SCOTT: All right.
-Yeah.
We're planning on stashing,
what, eight bottles of O
up at the South Summit.
ANATOLI: Well, I'm not using O.
ROB: What do you mean?
You're not using oxygen at all?
Come on, man. You know you want to.
English air. Don't need it.
ROB: Yeah, but Anatoli,
you're guiding for Scott this year.
You have people's lives in your hands.
It's a job.
Never used it. Never will.
Bigger problems if you run out.
Okay.
I'll put some more bottles of O up there.
-ROB: All right, that'll be good.
-All right.
Just so long as you guys are clear.
If you work for me, you use oxygen,
otherwise you don't work for me.
You don't have to ask, mate.
I've been up there before without O's, Rob.
I don't need to do it with clients.
ROB: All right, next we have to fix ropes.
-SCOTT: Yeah.
-Particularly above the Lhotse Face.
Hillary Step need new fixed rope.
And South-East Ridge as well.
ROB: Yes, it does. Well...
My idea is that we work together
and we fix ropes together.
We share the duties.
-Okay?
-SCOTT: Sounds good.
ROB: All right,
you and Lopsang maybe get together.
Talk about who wants
to fix what and where, okay?
Only essentials. I'm not
gonna tell you what to pack,
but be brutal. Okay?
One pound down here is like 10 up there.
Light and fast.
What, and just like that,
you kill my summit cappuccino.
Go, go, go! Run!
-That camera's totally dying.
-ROB: Okay.
All right, it's gonna be a tough week.
But it is gonna be
the best Friday of your lives.
Yeah, what are we doing again on Friday?
-ALL: Summiting!
-(CAMERA CLICKS)
BECK: Now it's up to me, right?
JON: Yes it is, yes it is.
BECK: I'll take three.
It's from Jan.
(CHUCKLING)
I knew it was gonna be a girl. I can't believe it.
It's a girl!
(ALL CHEERING)
BECK: All right, good on you!
I knew I was.
-I knew she was.
-Congratulations.
Thank you, thank you, Doug. Cheers, mate.
When's she due?
Mid-July, as soon as I get back.
DOUG: You better sleep now, buddy.
BECK: Yeah, that's true.
Hey, Rob.
-Yeah?
-So...
Jan doesn't mind you being here?
Uh-oh.
Krakauer's sword is unleashed.
It's okay. Jan's a climber, Jon, she gets it.
HELEN: Yeah!
ROB: Cheers, Helen.
What about you, Doug?
What about your wife?
Oh, she's been fine with it,
ever since we divorced.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
DOUG: She's been great
with everything since then.
I'm so sorry, buddy.
No, no.
No, no, no, I ask because Peach said to me,
"If you climb one more mountain,
I will divorce you."
And you went ahead
and then booked this trip!
BECK: No, no, no, the worst part of it
is that I kind of forgot to tell her.
You don't forget
to tell her you're climbing Everest!
I forgot to tell her, I did.
JON: All right. It's all on the table, here.
It hurts, it's dangerous,
it destroys relationships,
it's costing you all a small fortune.
DOUG: Are there any
negative aspects to this game?
I gotta ask the question, you know I do.
Why?
Why.
Because...
It's there!
BECK: That's why. Thank you, Mr. Mallory.
-Come on. Guys, I'm serious.
-(COUGHS)
Yasuko. Why are you climbing Everest?
YASUKO: Uh...
I'm 47 years old,
I have reached six of the seven summits, so...
Of course, now I have to reach the seventh.
That's not an answer.
-No. Why any summit?
-(YASUKO STAMMERS)
JON: Doug.
-Me?
-Why?
HELEN: Come on, tell 'em about the kids.
What?
Tell 'em about the kids.
-MIKE: Whose kids?
-Oh...
HAROLD: You have kids?
Yeah, I have kids, but, I thought I told you,
there's an elementary school, back home.
And I've been going
and talking to the kids there
and they actually helped me
raise some of the money to come
and gave me a flag
to plant on the summit, and...
So, I was thinking, maybe it's...
They see a regular guy can,
you know, follow impossible dreams,
maybe they'll be inspired
to do the same, I guess.
I'm climbing Mount Everest
because I can.
Because to be able to climb that high
and see that kind of beauty
that nobody ever sees,
it'd be a crime not to.
Hear, hear, Dougie.
JON: There you go.
BECK: I like that.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
ROB: Hey. Did I wake you?
No.
I did too, you liar.
Huh?
-JAN: You okay?
-Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I'm good, I'm better.
I'm better now, I'm...
I miss you.
We go for the final ascent tomorrow.
So, you summit Friday?
Yeah, the 10th.
It's your lucky day.
It is.
How's the weather?
It's good.
Yeah, I think we're gonna get a good window.
So, it's a girl.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
And did you go to the doctor,
did you get a scan done?
Did you see her?
Yeah, sure did.
And? Come on. What did she look like?
Oh, you know. Blonde hair, nice smile,
perfect height-to-weight ratio,
she's gonna be a great climber. (CHUCKLES)
She's there, Rob.
-Already.
-Wow.
A little me, a little you.
A little bear, huh?
And then, one day, you
and me
and our little Sarah,
we'll all go climbing together. Hmm?
Sarah?
Yeah, what do you think?
-No way!
-Come on.
No!
Please? Think about it.
-No. (CHUCKLES)
-Huh?
You still there?
Of course I'm still here.
I love you.
Love you, too.
Sleep well, my love. (KISSES)
All right. Bye.
(PRAYING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
NEAL: Take it easy, now.
You're gonna be okay.
We're gonna get you down the hill. All right?
Hey, Neal, you okay?
Yeah, Dale, he doesn't look too good.
We need to take him down.
ROB: Yeah.
You can't get Scott on the radio?
Nope. Nah, I think he's up ahead.
ROB: Best not to stare too long at the summit.
JON: That's a long way to go, man.
Head down, one step at a time.
You got it, boss.
You seen Dale?
Yeah, I did, he wasn't looking too good
but Neal seemed
to have a handle on the situation.
Tried to get you on the radio.
-You're kidding me.
-No.
This thing's not working, huh?
I'm going down to Camp One.
If he's not doing so well,
I'm gonna take him down to Base Camp
and I'll head back up. You guys all right?
Yeah.
He can't be too far ahead of you, mate.
Yeah, I'll make it down in half the time.
I'm gonna catch you! Whoo!
(COUGHING)
Rob to Guy.
Rob to Guy, you up there, mate?
Yeah, Guy to Rob. I'm here.
ROB: Good to hear you, Gee.
Where are you?
Camp One, Pumori.
Yeah.
There you go, I got the old sly rotter.
Listen, I think you're on
the wrong mountain, there.
Look, I can't talk, we gotta get out of here.
All right, mate.
Well, listen, you take care on the kiddie slope.
I'm gonna get back to the real thing.
GUY: Yeah, don't worry, Rob.
I'll keep an eye on you.
Ice!
(GRUNTS)
Rob!
ROB: I got you!
Harold, you okay?
(HAROLD GROANING)
ANG: Is everyone okay?
We're okay!
Come here, sit down, sit.
I'm fine.
Look at me.
-Look at me.
-I'm fine, mate.
Look at me, Harold!
Look, I'm telling you, I'm all right.
-Okay.
-I'm all right.
-There you go.
-Thank you.
Don't do that to me again, eh?
I'm sorry.
Okay, mate.
I'm gonna drop back with Frank,
he's struggling a bit, all right?
All right.
(MAN WHIMPERING)
Straight down.
Let's get him on the oxygen.
Rob Hall to Scott Fischer,
Mountain Madness, how do you copy?
Hey, man! Scott, here.
I've been down to Base Camp,
and I'm back at Camp One.
I'm gonna catch you tomorrow.
What, you're not gonna
rest up a day first? No?
Scott, you sound a little rough.
Mate, take an extra day.
No way, Jos, what, miss out on all the fun?
That's a lot of up and down in one day,
even for you, Scott.
You know what they say, man.
It's not the altitude, it's the attitude.
Are you sure you're gonna be okay?
-Scott?
-I'll be good.
Just taking a shot of dexamethasone now.
Well, just don't push yourself
too hard, okay? Over and out.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
HELEN: Rob, I've just been over to Mal's
to get a weather update.
It's moving fast.
It's changed course slightly.
And it could still go north, but, if it doesn't
it's gonna hit sometime on the 11th, I reckon.
It's a weather forecast, Helen.
This mountain makes its own weather.
We're keeping an eye on it.
Yeah, sure, just letting you know.
Appreciate it, Helen.
BECK: Why do we do this to ourselves?
-(CHUCKLING)
-(COUGHING)
Oh, this is crazy.
You know, I never told Krakauer this
when he was asking us why we climb Everest.
When I'm at home
I just got this big
black cloud following me.
You know, like a depression?
And when I'm out here
on a mountain, any mountain...
DOUG: Yeah?
It's just like it's a cure.
I feel like I'm reborn.
So, you're happy now?
No, I'm starting to wonder.
This is suffering, man.
-Yeah.
-This is suffering.
Yeah.
Suffer a few more days,
for the rest of your life you'll be a guy
that got to the top of Everest.
-Mmm. (CHUCKLES)
-Huh?
I just hope I get there.
Yeah.
Just hope I get there, and get home.
What do you think, Mike?
MIKE: Looks pretty good.
Little bit of wind, up higher.
I mean, if it picks up,
we can always come back down.
-Exactly.
-It's your call, Rob.
Let's get 'em all going.
(WIND HOWLING)
ANATOLI: Rob!
ROB: You okay?
Not good!
Ah.
I'm hoping it's gonna
die down after sundown.
It's been doing that.
I don't like this.
Well, we don't go if it doesn't calm.
I talk to Scott when he comes here.
ROB: Okay.
-(COUGHING)
-(YASUKO COUGHING)
Scott! Scott!
-Toli?
-Here!
Toli!
Where's Rob? Where are they?
-We go down!
-No.
What's Rob's... What's Rob's team doing?
He wants to see if this passes.
If he waits,
we wait.
Okay.
Hey, guys.
Come out and take a look.
At least somebody up there loves us.
Nothing?
Where'd the storm go?
Exactly.
That's crazy.
You ready to saddle up?
Okay, everyone. We got a window.
We don't know how long it's gonna last,
but we're gonna go for it.
Be ready in half an hour.
We'll have a 2:00 p.m. turnaround,
let's climb this thing.
BECK: Okay.
So, today's the day, huh?
Yep.
Now or never.
Oh, boy.
ROB: Now the South Africans
were late out of Camp Three.
They never made it into Camp Four.
Probably got caught up in it.
HELEN: (ON RADIO)
Maybe it blew through early.
ROB: Yeah, well, it hit us all night,
but now there's nothing. Absolutely nothing.
So, it's definitely worth a shot.
I'll radio out and tell everyone the news.
Any messages?
ROB: Yeah, ring Jan
and tell her that we're heading out.
I'll call you, Helen, in 12 hours
when we get to the summit.
Turnaround's 2:00 p.m.
Good luck, and Godspeed to you all.
ROB: Okay, thanks, Helen. Bye-bye.
SCOTT: I'll see you guys up there.
NEAL: Take it easy, Scott.
SANDY: Let's do it.
SCOTT: Gonna get a couple hours of sleep,
and I'll be right behind you.
NEAL: Yeah, okay.
SANDY: See you at the top.
Have fun, Pittman.
You get some rest, okay?
See you there.
You got the ropes for the Hillary Step?
Yeah.
-Okay.
Okay. Yeah.
Can we go any faster?
Not a chance we can go faster here.
It's too difficult.
This could take a while.
We're losing time.
(GRUNTING)
Beck. What's wrong?
I don't know.
I had an operation a couple years ago,
on my eyes.
That might be it.
-I don't know.
-ROB: Okay.
You guys go in front of us.
All right, Beck, let's sit you down.
Beck. Look at me.
I need to send you down with someone.
No, I don't wanna go down, Rob.
-No, you gotta go down.
-I don't wanna go down.
Okay.
Right, Beck, listen.
You can wait here for half an hour.
Beck, listen to me.
If it gets better by then
join in the queue and keep going up.
But if it doesn't get better, Beck,
I'm sorry, mate, it's over.
Okay.
The Sherpas are gonna go up and drop off
the extra oxygen at the South Summit
then I'm gonna send
one of them down for you.
-Is that clear? Yeah?
-Mmm-hmm.
Okay, mate.
All right.
See you.
LOPSANG: Sandy, do you want to go down?
What? No. No way.
Look, Lopsang, I'm gonna make it to the top.
Do you understand?
-Okay.
-I'm not going back.
-Okay?
-Okay.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
HAROLD: Where are the ropes?
There is no rope! No rope.
HAROLD: Yeah, they should have been fixed.
Do you have more in your pack?
ANG: Lopsang has the rope. He's not here!
Harold. No ropes?
No.
Neal.
Hey, Rob.
Listen, we got a problem, here, mate.
There's no fixed ropes on the traverse
to the Hillary Step, over.
ROB: Where's Ang Dorjee and Lopsang?
HAROLD: Yeah, I've got Ang Dorjee here,
but there's no sign of Lopsang.
So me, Neal, and Toli are gonna
have to set some new ones, over.
ANATOLI: Find them?
NEAL: Yeah.
-ANATOLI: Good.
-Let's do it!
YASUKO: What's going on?
No fixed ropes.
What?
(SANDY BREATHING HEAVILY)
-ROB: That's it.
-(GRUNTS)
One step at a time, Doug.
(COUGHING)
Come on, Dougie. Deep breaths, Dougie.
Come on, mate, keep it on, keep it on.
Deep breaths, Dougie, hang on. Hang on.
(GAS HISSING)
You can do this, Dougie.
I know you can, pal.
DOUG: Yeah.
I don't wanna see you
back here a third time, mate.
Huh?
John. You headed back down?
There's a holdup.
There's no fixed ropes
above the South Summit.
Yeah, I know, mate,
but we're sorting that situation out now.
Ran out of juice, waiting. Cold.
I'm sorry, Rob.
It's your call, pal.
LOU: I don't wanna
run out of oxygen up there.
Sorry, Rob.
ROB: (ON RADIO) Yeah, bit of a setback.
Lou, Stuart, and John Taske just turned back.
Just below the South Summit.
How are the conditions, so far?
Cold and windy.
Okay, let me know, Rob.
Okay, Helen, thanks, bye-bye.
I hope we're not looking at another year
with no clients at the top.
Well, if they don't get a move on pretty soon
they're out of time, aren't they?
Yeah.
And what's Jon gonna say
about that in his article?
(ON RADIO) It's Rob. Guys...
We just lost Lou, Stu, and John Taske.
What's going on, what's the holdup?
Yeah, mate, we're...
We still have Toli and Neal
at the top of the Step
fixing the ropes.
We're at the base of the Step, over.
(ON RADIO) Rob, it's Mike.
How's Doug faring?
Doug's just behind me,
I left him behind to scoot forward.
Yeah, I got eyes on you right now,
yep, that's me. Let's move as...
As quickly as possible, over.
HAROLD: We'll start moving everybody up,
as soon as we get the all clear.
Rob to base, Rob to base, how copy, Helen?
-HAROLD: You all right?
-HELEN: Copy, Base Camp to Rob.
Have you heard from Scott?
Anyone managed to find out
where he is, over?
SCOTT: Whoo-ie! Yo, dude!
Look, where are you, mate?
We got a real logjam,
here at the Hillary Step, over.
We're more than an hour behind!
Just chill.
People are just sitting here,
using up their oxygen.
Get here as soon as you can.
You feeling okay, Beck?
Yeah, I got a little problem with my eyes.
You guys turned back?
STUART: There's a logjam
below the Hillary Step. It's crazy.
Come down with us.
Nah, I can't, promised Rob I'd wait for him.
LOU: Your call.
BECK: I'm good.
LOU: See you down there.
ANATOLI: Neal, ready!
NEAL: Okay, Toli! I'm done.
Off rope! Safe to climb!
HAROLD: Okay, we're climbing up!
-JON: Hey, Mike.
-What?
-You mind if I go first?
-Why?
I'm running pretty low on O.
Rob, it's Mike, here.
We've had the all-clear on this end.
I'm gonna stay here with Yasuko,
until we get a clear line.
ROB: I'll be here till I get a visual on Doug,
over and out.
(YELLING)
Come here.
(CHUCKLING)
We did it!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
ANATOLI: You did it!
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
ROB: Yasuko.
-Seven.
-Seven Summits.
Come here. I'm so proud of you, Yasuko.
So proud.
Thank you.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(ON RADIO) Rob to Base, Rob to Base.
Rob, this is Helen, hello? Where are you?
I'm on the top of Everest, Helen, we made it.
(ALL CHEERING)
How copy us, over?
We copy you loud and clear, Rob.
It's wonderful to hear your voice up there.
Who are you with, again, say?
At the moment, I'm with Mike and Yasuko.
MIKE: Headed down, Rob.
ANG: Now you have to go.
YASUKO: Rob. See you. Thank you.
Jon K has already been and gone.
Doug is just coming over the horizon.
And what about Beck?
Beck was having a problem with his eyesight.
He waited on the southeast ridge,
on the Balcony
for the first people that came back, over.
And I guess you'll be leaving right away, yes?
We'll be off in a few minutes.
Just as soon as I see Doug,
we'll be heading back down, over.
Right, understood.
Well, that's terrific, Rob.
We're all keeping
our fingers crossed for Doug.
ROB: Over and out, Helen.
(DOUG GRUNTING)
LOPSANG: Congratulations.
ROB: Welcome!
SCOTT: Yeah, Lopsy!
LOPSANG: You did it!
Whoo-ie!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You look terrible.
My stomach's not so good, man.
See Doug?
Oh, yeah. He's way, way,
-way back there, man.
-(SIGHS)
Hey, Roberto.
Where are the rest of your guys?
'Cause I'm pretty sure my whole team
made it up, yeah?
ROB: (CHUCKLING) I saw 'em.
Don't worry, I won't tell Krakauer.
Well done, mate. I had a mixed bag.
I'll have to give you this year.
-Scott, you really don't look too good.
-(COUGHING)
-Lopsang.
-LOPSANG: Yeah?
Come on, mate, let's get him down.
SCOTT: All right. Let's go.
(YASUKO GRUNTING)
Harold. What are you doing?
I'm just trying to sort the O.
I can't find any full ones.
There's full bottles, I saw 'em on the way up.
No.
No, I'm pretty sure
you should have another look.
No, I just have, they're not full.
Harold, listen, I saw...
Look, mate, I checked twice, all right?
Yeah. All right, man.
I'm going down.
Harold?
Doug, Doug, Doug.
-It's over, mate.
-What?
I'm sorry. No, no, no.
Doug, you're too late, okay?
(DOUG COUGHING)
You guys keep going, mate, I'll catch up.
ROB: Doug, Doug. Doug, listen to me.
-It's way too late. It's over.
-DOUG: No, come on!
Listen to me, mate, I'm sorry,
but I gotta turn you around.
Okay?
I can do it.
It's right here, man. It's right here.
I'm not coming back next year, man,
it's my last chance.
You gotta let me do this.
Let me do this.
-Okay.
-Please, Rob.
Let's do it.
-Let's get it done.
-All right.
-Come on.
-Thanks, man.
ROB: Come on, Doug.
(SINGING) There ain't no hope of getting
My double-wide trailer
There ain't no...
Beck?
Are you okay?
Who is that?
It's Jon.
I'm not seeing too well, Jon. I'm freezing.
Mike's just behind me.
He's back there with Yasuko.
You'll be okay. Mike's right behind me.
You're okay?
I'll see you down there.
ROB: There she is.
Ten more steps, mate.
-(COUGHS)
-Dig deep, Doug, dig deep.
There you go.
(GRUNTS)
There ya go.
(YELLING)
You made it!
Huh?
You did it!
Because of you, man.
(THUNDER CRACKLING)
Guy to Rob, you read me, mate?
Guy to Rob, are you there?
ROB: For the school kids.
Good on you, Doug. Come on.
Easy.
Here, I got it.
Come on, let's get you up.
Need more O.
No, Doug, we can't give you more O.
We gotta get down
to the South Summit, come on.
Guy Cotter to Everest Base Camp.
You there, Helen?
Guy, this is Helen, how's it going?
Yeah, fine.
I got a clear view of the summit
and we've still got climbers up there.
They're not any of ours, right?
We got three up,
and they're all on their way down.
Well, what are they doing there so late?
They had a 2:00 turnaround time,
they're way past it.
Yeah, we got cloud coming up
through the valley,
it's a lot of it.
Thanks, I'm calling them now, Guy.
Rob, come in, this is Helen.
ROB: Whoa!
Easy, easy, easy, Dougie! There you go.
There you go.
Looking good. Round the corner. (GRUNTS)
-That's it.
-(DOUG COUGHING)
BECK: Rob, is that you?
MIKE: Beck?
It's Mike, Beck. What are you doing here?
BECK: I can't see, it's bad.
You guys all right?
We got a problem with Beck.
NEAL: Hey, Mike, we're getting low on O.
We gotta move.
Gonna get you to stand up, okay?
NEAL: I'll take Yasuko.
MIKE: That's it.
NEAL: I got you.
You're okay.
ROB: Doug, come on!
Come on!
DOUG: I'm cold.
(ROB SIGHS)
Mike, Harold, Ang Dorjee,
put the brakes on, guys,
we got a problem.
We're out of gas, Doug.
We're out of gas.
Need to keep moving, come on.
Come on!
ROB: (ON RADIO) Mike, Harold, do you copy?
I need someone...
I need someone to come back up
with oxygen, over.
Somebody, please, I'm begging you.
Doug, come on, mate, come on!
Harold, do you copy, over?
Has anyone got eyes on Ang Dorjee?
HAROLD: Mate, I've just had Ang Dorjee
go past me, heading down, over.
He's going down.
ROB: Can you stop him,
can you turn him around?
I need someone to come back up now.
Hey, Ang Dorjee!
Ang Dorjee!
Base Camp, do you copy, over?
HELEN: Helen to Rob, go ahead.
Helen, please. I need a bottle of gas
at the top of the Hillary Step.
I can't get him down without it.
I'm really stuffed.
Understood that you need a bottle of oxygen
at the bottom of the Hillary Step.
We are sending it up to you,
as soon as we can.
At the top, at the top.
The last thing I said to Ang Dorjee was
"Please, leave two bottles of gas
at the South Summit."
Yes.
Copy that, Rob.
Boys,
there's oxygen at the South Summit, right?
(ON RADIO) No, Rob, this is Harold.
There's no oxygen at South Summit.
Repeat, no O.
Ang Dorjee stashed four bottles there, Harold.
Harold, where are you?
Can you hear me, Harold?
Harold!
Harold, can you hear me?
Think it'll take me about
half an hour to get back up
to the South Summit.
Okay, I'm coming.
ROB: If you don't have oxygen, mate,
don't come up, don't come up.
We're moving on.
HAROLD: I'm coming up to you, Rob.
ROB: Doug, come on, mate, come on!
(ROB GRUNTING)
Rob, this is Base Camp.
ROB: I copy you, Caro.
Rob, can you get yourself down?
Caro, we're not at that point, yet.
Rob, can you let us know who you're with?
I'm with Doug.
We're both listening.
Come on, Dougie, come on, mate.
One more effort, come on.
CAROLINE: Rob, what is
Doug's state of consciousness?
He's really weak.
He collapsed after we ran out of oxygen.
Okay, give him
eight milligrams of dexamethasone.
That's two tablets, Rob.
(ON RADIO) Guy to Rob.
ROB: Go ahead, Guy, I got you, mate.
Rob, I suggest you get yourself down.
You know you're doing no good up there.
Now, we've got people
that we can send up to help Doug
but you've gotta get yourself down,
do you understand?
I mean, come on, man,
we're playing with a man's life here.
There's no way I'm leaving Doug behind.
We gotta keep moving, mate.
No, we gotta keep moving,
we're in some trouble.
Yeah, Helen's gonna need some help
so I'm gonna try
and make my way back. Okay?
All right. Go on.
(SCOTT GASPING)
LOPSANG: Hey, Scott.
Scott! You okay?
SCOTT: Lopsang.
Lopsy!
I'm done, pal.
I'm done.
You go, send Anatoli...
Send Anatoli back with some O.
Okay.
-Go!
-Okay.
I will send back Anatoli.
-ROB: Let's go.
-You go down.
No, mate.
No, I'm not leaving you behind, Doug.
-Come on!
-Gotta rest.
No, Doug, come on, you're coming with me!
I need 10 good minutes, Doug, come on!
(ROB GRUNTING)
Please, Dougie, come on, mate.
Ten minutes.
We'll get to the bottom of the Step.
Come on, this leg.
This leg, Dougie, come on!
Come on.
There we go.
(GRUNTING)
(THUNDER CRACKLING)
HELEN: Oh, no.
Oh, no.
Hold that down.
Come on, come on! Get those chairs!
(THUNDER CRACKLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(HAROLD GRUNTING)
(THUNDER CRACKLING)
No, no, no, no. Come on, Dougie!
Doug, let's go, hurry up!
Doug! I'm gonna go
to the South Summit to get oxygen.
Okay, mate? Gonna find oxygen.
But you've gotta stay here!
Okay? Stay here!
Don't move! I'll be back!
(GRUNTING FEEBLY)
DOUG: Hey, Rob.
(ROB GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
MIKE: Beck! Stop! That's the wrong way!
Stop!
Back! Turn back!
MIKE: Beck, easy!
(ALL SCREAMING)
GUY: Rob!
Harold!
HAROLD: Rob!
ROB: Harold?
HAROLD: I've got oxygen!
Here, I found some half-empty ones.
Where's Doug?
Doug's gone.
He's what?
(STRAINING) Gone!
KLEV: Camp Four's that way!
TIM: Get up!
KLEV: Let's go!
MIKE: Come on! Beck!
MIKE: I'll get help!
(SHIVERING)
(GRUNTS)
-(METALLIC CLANGING)
-ANATOLI: Here!
-Toli!
-ANATOLI: Where are the others?
They're still out there.
ANATOLI: Jon! I need help!
What?
They're out there, I need help!
JON: I can't see, Toli.
I'm snow-blind.
Beck, Doug.
They need help.
They're still outside...
ANATOLI: I go find them! You stay here!
ROB: Good job.
(ANATOLI YELLING)
TIM: Toli! Sandy needs O!
ANATOLI: Sandy, here!
-Can you walk?
-I can't.
ANATOLI: I'll come back!
TIM: I'll stay!
Here, give me that, come on.
It won't go, it's frozen!
Take this.
The glove.
I'm sorry.
(SIGHS)
Come on, mate.
Come on, Harold.
Thanks for coming back.
(DIALING)
HELEN: Hello, Base Camp.
Helen, it's Jan.
Why haven't I heard from you?
Why isn't anybody calling me?
They've been hit by a storm, Jan.
It's really bad.
Where is he?
We don't know, exactly, but
he was still on the summit at 4:00.
Oh, no. Can he get down?
Rob can, but Doug can't.
There's at least 13 people stranded up there
and, well, the storm is getting worse.
JAN: Get Ang Dorjee up there.
He'll bring them down.
-Helen, do you understand?
-GUY: Helen! Give me an update!
Get Ang Dorjee up there.
HELEN: Jan, yeah, we will get him.
And I will call you, the minute I hear from him.
As soon as I hear from him.
-Thanks, Helen.
-All right?
Okay.
-Where is he?
-Guy, I haven't heard from him.
GUY: Okay, I'll get him.
HELEN: I've been trying.
-Guy...
-GUY: Just hang on, hang on.
Rob? It's Guy, where are you?
Guy, I've been doing that
for the last two hours.
All right. Rob, it's Guy.
-Just keep your energy, mate.
-CAROLINE: Helen.
Once you catch a break,
you move, you know the drill.
We've got a stash of oxygen on the South Col.
Whoever needs it can have it.
That's the way, thank you.
Mal's team are gonna go up, they're gonna
mount a search as soon as they can.
Anyone who's going, we're gonna leave
at dawn, weather permitting.
Of course, Helen. At dawn.
HELEN: That's great, David.
Go let Ed know what's going on,
I'll be right behind you.
Camp Four, come in.
Rob. Rob, can you hear me?
HELEN: David Breashears
has a stash of oxygen
at the South Col that we can use.
GUY: All right, mate, we're organizing a team,
we're coming to get you.
Hot.
Burning up.
ANATOLI: No, no.
Yasuko.
(GROANING)
Sandy?
(ANATOLI GRUNTING)
Come on!
(DEEP RUMBLING)
Rob, talk to me, please. Pick up.
Pick up, mate, please.
Is there any word on the others?
Anatoli managed to get three clients back
from the South Col last night,
but Beck and Yasuko are still out there.
They're trying to mount a search
but everyone who's been up there
is exhausted.
(FEEBLE GRUNTING ON RADIO)
Rob, is that you?
Rob, where are you?
We're sending people for you.
Rob, this is Base Camp.
ROB: (FEEBLY) I can't... I can't move...
I can't move anymore. Anymore.
Hey, mate. Yeah, I know. I know, mate. I know.
But you gotta keep on moving.
ROB: My hands...
I can't feel my hands, they're frozen.
Gotta de-ice my mask.
I gotta de-ice my mask.
That's good. Yeah,
you gotta get that mask working. Yeah?
The sun's gonna come up and,
you know, you can get warmer,
you can get moving.
-Guy.
-Yeah?
Guy. Harold was here.
Where's he gone?
Rob, is Doug with you?
ROB: Harold...
Doug... Doug's gone.
Harold's gone.
I'm gonna need a little help.
GUY: Okay, Rob, you gotta get yourself down.
Where are you?
ROB: Guy...
I'm in that little...
In that little dip just below the South Summit.
GUY: All right. You can do this.
You just gotta, you know,
pull yourself up out of that dip
and slide the rest of the way.
Guy, send the boys.
Okay?
I'm gonna need a little help.
GUY: We've got some
Sherpas coming up there
with tea, oxygen.
You just gotta come on down, mate.
Yeah? Come on down.
Rob.
Can you patch Jan through?
HELEN: To Rob?
Patch her through, yeah?
Let's just try it. Let's just...
Put the sat phone next to the radio.
Yeah, if anyone can motivate him to move,
then Jan will.
(ON RADIO) Guy to Rob.
Guy to Rob.
Guy to Rob. Can you read me?
-We're just getting...
-Rob, are you there?
-We're getting him now.
-Here.
Rob, this is Helen.
ROB: Copy.
Rob, I've got Jan for you.
My Jan?
Yeah, she's just here.
Jan, you're on.
JAN: Okay.
Hi, sweetheart, how are you doing?
ROB: Hi, my love.
I'm a bit...
A bit cold
but I'm okay.
I know you are.
But the sun'll warm you soon.
Sweetheart?
You've gotta get moving.
You've gotta come on down.
ROB: My hands
are frozen.
My feet are frozen.
JAN: We're sending people
up to you with tea and O's.
But you've gotta get moving.
Rob? Can you hear me?
You've gotta get your circulation going.
Okay, my love.
You do it... You do it right now.
I love you.
Over and out.
Come on, Rob.
(WHEEZING)
We can't carry them.
It's not possible.
JON: It's gonna...
It's gonna take all we got
just to get ourselves down.
I don't wanna die, man.
(ON RADIO) Helen, it's Mike here.
Do you copy?
Come in, Mike. What do you got?
Yasuko and Beck
did not make it back to camp.
Okay, Mike. Thanks for letting us know.
PEACH: Meg?
Bub?
(WHEEZING)
Helen Base Camp. Helen Base Camp.
Helen Base Camp.
Ang Dorjee, this is Helen.
We have to turn back!
There is a very bad storm again.
(HELEN SOBBING)
-Your call, Ang Dorjee.
-Sorry.
We'll try to again when the storm's passed.
We'll leave some tea and oxygen here. Sorry.
We have to tell Rob they're not coming.
Okay.
(ON RADIO) Hey, Rob, it's Guy, mate.
Guy.
Can't stop shaking, mate.
The boys have hit a bit of high wind.
And your best shot is gonna be to get lower.
(SNIFFLES)
Let me think about it.
I think I can hang out here another night.
We'll try again first thing, okay?
(GRUNTS)
(PHONE RINGING)
-Helen?
-Yeah.
Yeah, he's still there.
He's just below the South Summit.
He's got oxygen, but it's iced up.
We don't know whether
he's been able to free it.
Is anybody with him?
No.
You have to get him down before dark.
He won't survive another night.
We know.
But the storm's come back, real bad.
We can't get anyone up to him tonight.
We tried.
He might as well be on the moon.
Uh...
Can you put me on with him again?
Of course.
Guy, get Rob.
Hey, Rob, it's Guy.
I've got Jan for you.
ROB: Hold on. Give me a sec.
Okay.
Hi, sweetheart.
How are you?
(SNIFFLES)
I'm thinking about you.
You sound good.
Are you warm, my love?
I might have a little frostbite.
I'm looking forward to making it all better.
I can't wait for you to come home.
ROB: How's Sarah?
(SOBBING) Sarah?
Yeah.
Yeah, Sarah's good.
Will you call her that for me?
JAN: Yes, I will.
I don't think I'm gonna get to meet her.
I'm so sorry.
Don't say that.
If anyone can make it, you can.
Remember?
I love you.
Please don't worry too much.
Good night, my love.
I love you, Rob.
I love you.
(GASPS)
(INAUDIBLE)
(GROANING FEEBLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INAUDIBLE)
(GRUNTING)
Beck?
(ON RADIO) Helen, it's Mike here.
Helen, do you copy?
Mike, come in.
Beck's still alive.
He walked himself into camp.
David Breashears and the IMAX team
are gonna get him down to Camp One.
Thanks, Mike.
HELEN: We don't even
know how, but he is alive.
The thing is, Peach,
we can't get him down the Icefall.
PEACH: Oh, no, I'll get him down.
I'll get him down. Okay.
Okay, what do we need?
We need a helicopter, right?
Yeah, but they can't take
a helicopter up that high
because the air is too thin.
We should try, but it is one heck of a risk.
And he's not in a good way, Peach,
so I don't want you to get
your hopes up too high.
One step at a time.
-You gotta keep moving.
-Tired.
-I know.
-I'm tired.
I know you are. Come on.
Slow and steady.
Come on, keep moving.
Yes, I'd like the number
of the American Embassy
in Kathmandu, Nepal.
-Yes, Nepal.
-Ambassador, please.
No, sweets, I can't hold.
No, you listen, sir,
my husband's already died once
as you'll have seen on the news.
Trust me, having him die a second time
is not gonna play well on CNN.
DOCTOR: There we go, buddy.
That's it, all right.
Mike.
Mmm-hmm.
How you doing?
Oh, you know, fair to middling.
Warming up?
I'm not sure yet.
Look like you are, a little bit.
How's Rob doing?
Rob's still up there right now.
And Doug? What's he up to?
Doug's gone, Beck.
I don't know, no one's ever tried
to fly higher than Base Camp before,
they're gonna give it a go.
You find an LZ,
just mark it out with whatever you can.
Okay, worth a try. Thanks, Guy.
-Yeah?
-Grab a Gatorade.
Got a chopper coming in,
we need to make an LZ.
We got a chopper coming in!
Clear everyone back to the tents!
Thanks.
Keep it clear, keep this whole area clear.
MAN: Back away.
DAVID: Come on, come on.
MAN: (ON RADIO) Army 45, keep updating.
MADAN: Lukla Tower, we're doing fine.
-It's not possible!
-(INSTRUMENTS BLARING)
You land here, we'll never get back up.
Gonna kill us!
Okay, Major, let's go back.
CO-PILOT: That's it!
We can't get any more out.
It's as light as we're gonna get it!
MADAN: Time to go then, Major.
(BOTH SPEAKING NEPALI)
DAVID: Right here, right here!
Come on! You can do it!
ED: Come on, buddy. You're nearly there.
Okay, come on.
(GROANING)
MADAN: One person. Only one person.
DAVID: Yeah, it's just him, just one! There.
ED: There you go.
You're good!
I'm going to lift the tail up,
to fly us over the edge.
Fall a bit, until the blades catch on the air.
Is that okay with you?
BECK: I'm with you.
MADAN: Good man.
Get yourself inside, go on.
Oh, Anatoli.
(SOBBING) I'm so sorry, Helen.
Come on, let's get you inside.
-(GASPS)
-(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
Hi, Peachy.
Hey.
(SOBBING)
Thank you so much, darling.