do you know why people hate
to admit they're lonely?
it's because when you do,
everyone thinks
something's wrong with you.
They think,"I have people in my life.
Why don't you?
" But the strange thing is,
you can have people in your
life and still be alone.
No one knows that better than I do.
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-
Proudly Presents
Sync: ¿¨»Ò
the forgotten 2009
s01e04
Jane doe.
She just collapsed?
In a local park.
We're thinking no foul play.
The M.E.  'S finishing the autopsy,but
we got a heads-up on the cause of death--
too much insulin in her system.
Was she diabetic?
Well,they found recurring
injection marks in her stomach.
Looks like an overdose.
Suicide.
Her problems got so bad,she
couldn't see any other way out.
Or an accident.
Hard to know why,but
maybe she didn't realize
she had already taken her shot.
Either way,our investigation's limited.
Department policy.  They won't assign more
manpower unless it's declared a homicide.
- Right.
- We need your help giving her a name.
I understand.  We'll do
what we can to get her home.
She just died in the middle
of the park like that,
in front of a bunch strangers?
And she was young.
Those are always the hardest to take.
Probably mid-20s,based on the
photo and what she was wearing.
She had a purse with
her,but no wallet,no I.D.
What kind of woman carries
a purse with no wallet?
That's like a telephone repairman
not carrying his echo sensitizer.
Right.
And when she fell,her purse
spilled onto the grass.
If she had a wallet,it's
possible somebody
at the scene swiped it in all the chaos.
Wow.  Swiping a dying wan's
wallet.  Man,that's cold.
Whatever was in her
purse is at the princt.
Candace,lindsey,maybe you
guys could take a look.
There might be something in
there that helps us identify her.
What about the databases?
Police ran the prints and the D.N.A.
No criminal record,no missing
persons,but it's only been about 48 hours.
There's no wedding ring.
If she lived on her own,it might take
a few days before somebody reports her.
It might,but maybe we can
I.D.  Her a little sooner.
The police found this
in our jane doe's pocket.
Looks like a hotel key.
I don't think it's a hotel.
You're late.
Huh.  Did you miss me?
Most hotels put a name
or a logo on their cards.
But if it's blank like that,could
be a corporate apartment.
- Why corporate?
- They change 'em out.
Companies keep apartments in town.
When a client comes
in,they print him off a key.
My dad's company does it a lot.
Couldn't the cops just
hack the strip on the back?
Yeah,but it's just an entry code.
There's no address.
So if you lose it,nobody
knows what it's for.
She was pretty well-dressed.
Maybe our jane doe was
in town for business.
If she was,maybe she
was staying in the area.
The police already checked two
the blocks around the scene.
I think we should expand it to ten.
Tyler,walter,you're with me.
Quality time,boys.
Nothing.  Any luck?
Six more blocks to go.
Swing and a miss.  Wrong building.
But the guy said he recognized the gold
card from a building a few blocks up.
It's called the gold standard.
Thanks so much.
Russell said the police took a look,but
they didn't see any contact info.
It still helps.
Just want to get to
know her a little bit.
I mean,a woman's purse is
like a time-space continuum--
next week's concert
tickets,last year's chewing gum.
Yeah.
It just feels strange
going through her stuff.
Okay,we got one lip gloss,coloR...
pink.
And that is not a high-fashion pink.
Now this-- this
is high-fashion.
- It's classic.
- Yep.
The clasp is broken.
That's beautiful.
For a woman in her mid-20s,she
was obviously making good money.
Hey,here's something.
She didn't have a cell
phone,but she had a music player.
I don't see any names or addresses,
but there are some
friends' photos in there.
We should get those to alex.
You know what?  Maybe we can
get their names another way.
Thanks f bringing this over.
We have permission for this?
- All clear from detective russell.
- Great.
Okay,here we go.
Well,it certainly
looks like one of ours.
We had them specially
made for the color.
Gold is our trademark.
ah,yes.  We coded this key about
three weeks ago for apartment 42.
And is this the woman who
was staying in that unit?
I remember her face.
She was here.
She ave st h abeen guest
of one of our residents.
She looked me in the
eye when she said hello.
A lot of our visitors just can't
be bothered,but she was nice.
here we are.
That unit's owned by
the wellman corporation.
The only tenant to use it in the
last month was a mr.  Roger turow.
Thank you.
Mr. Donovan?
I'm roger turow.
I appreciate you meeting me out here.
I'm certainly not looking for trouble.
Trouble?  Why would there be trouble?
Well,it's my job to book all the
corporate apartments for the firm.
I make them available to
out-of-town clients or guests.
And sometimes when I see they're
not being used,I use them myself.
Use them for what?
For gatherings,parties.
It's nothing shady,I assure you.
It's all perfectly normal.
I host wine tastings or book readings.
I have a number of guests.
Was she one of 'em?
Uh,no.
Well,possibly,but I don't recognize her.
She had a key to the apartment
made only three weeks ago.
Really?  Well,I have a number of
keys printed before each event.
I make them available so people
can come and go as they please.
I'd like to have the
names of those people.
I'm not sure I have them all.
You see,it's not just my guests.
It's their friends and
friends of their friends.
Mr. Turow,I'm not looking have
you fired,but this woman is dead.
I need to have the names of every
guest who might have one of those keys.
Of course.  Um,I'll-- I'll
write them down for you.
And I appreciate you not mentioning
anything to my boss abt this.
we're making progress.
So are we.  I just got a call from
the M.E.'S office.  Meet me there.
We called you as soon as we saw it.
Well,why didn't you see this before?
Because it didn't exist.
It can take up to two days for
bruising like this to emerge.
Okay,surprise number one.
After autopsy,we noticed a
bruise forming in the middle back.
After looking closer,we realized
it was an injection site.
She was injected in the back?
Definitely,and with a lot of
force,like a stabbing motion.
This was a homicide?
You said surprise number one.
Is there another one coming?
This is
number two--
routine dental x-rays
of the wisdom teeth.
Guys,they aren't developed at all.
what are you saying?
I'm saying your jane
doe isn't in her mid-20s.
She couldn't be any older than 15.
15?
I mean,what was she doing at a wine
tasting in a corporate apartment?
When I was 15,I did my
wine tasting in private.
In the backseat of
the quarterback's car?
And where are her parents?
They must know she's missing.
I mean,why haven't they reported it?
Maybe they don't know.
Or maybe they think she's fine.
You'd be surprised at what kids
can hide from their parents.
And you'd be surprised
at the number of parents
who don't really care
where their kids are.
Well,I'm sure they would have at
least expected her to check in,
but he may be right. ****
It's in the fridge.
You can heat it up later.
Just got back from the chicago P.D.
With the insulin shot in the back,
the case is officially a homicide,but
the "who is it?  " Is still on us.
We need to figure out this girl's story.
Maybe she's a runaway.
Yeah,maybe she's one of those kids
who got her education
from the streets,right?
Not from the schools.
It happens.
We can still find jane doe's friends.
There were photos on the music player.
Lindsey and I got one of the names
from the midsummer night's ball
and tracked down an address.
So we'll go talk to her tomorrow.
Good,and we'll start calling
schools in the morning.
She had to be a student somewhere,rig?
A charity ball
for heart disease--
is that really something
a tenth grader wants in on?
I don't get it.
If we just found out she's 15,she
did a pretty good job of hiding it.
So I wonder who else
in her life didn't know?
Or got angry when they found out.
here she comes.
Erin ingall?
We're trying to track
down a friend of yours.
Excuse me?  Who are you?
We're from the forgotten network.
We're volunteers that help
identify jane and john does.
That's from the midsummer night's ball.
That's lisa.
Her name is lisa?
Oh,my god.  Did something happen to her?
She was killed a few days ago.
we don't know her that well.
I-I don't even know her last name.
She's dylan's girlfriend.
- Who?
- Dylan dreslan.  He's an old friend.
He told us about these get-togethers,
like mixers,at this building downtown.
- The gold standard.
- Yeah.
Dylan's a regular.
He's brought lisa as
his date a few times.
Yeah,that's dylan.
We've known him since high school.
Did you know lisa was still
young enough to be in high school?
What?
I really thought dylan would
make things better for me.
Most of the boys I knew were
still figuring out who they were.
But dylan...
he me me want to fit inthis world.
you're here about lisa?
Yso da ago,your girlfriend
lisa was murdered.
U didn't know that?
- Murdered?
- Yeah.
How?
Okay,w-wait.
First of all,she wasn't my girlfriend.
Careful,mr.  Dreslan.
I promise you,you do
not want to lie to me.
No,I'm not lying.
We went out a few times.
I-I took her to a few parties thrown
by a friend of mine.  That's it.
We need to know lisa's full name.
Chang.  Lisa chang.
When was the last time you saw her?
Two days ago,here.
She came to my office,said
that she didn't think
that we should see each other anymore.
Well,did she say why?
No,she just said she wasn't ready
to be in a relationship,and I agreed.
I mean,we only met a few
weeks ago at a museum exhibit.
Do you know where she lives,where
her parents might live?
No.  We never talked about that.
Uh,she said one time that her
mother was a hairstylist,I think.
You think?
Look,we never talked about that.
It turned out we didn't
have a lot in common.
yeah,well,maybe that's
because she was only 15.
I don't know what that means.
It means lisa chang
was only 15 years old,
which at minimum makes you
a suspect for statutory rape.
That's not possible.
It is possible.
She was young enough
to be in high school.
No,no,no.  She teaches high school.
That's what she said.  I-I
dropped her off a few times.
- Where?
- Uh,lincoln rhodes prep.
The last time you saw her,
we need to know where you
were for the rest of the day.
I was in meetings with a client
all afternoon.  You can check.
Trust me,we will.
"Trust me,we will"?
Too much?
You know,you may not be a cop a,more
but you still know how to act like one.
lisa chang?
No,her name is li wen.
And she wasn't a teacher.
She was a sophomore.
We need to contact her parents.
Li lived with her aunt.
We've left her several messages,
and if we didn't hear
back in the next two days,
it's our policy to call the police.
Li also has a brother.
He graduated here three years ago.
He's in college now--
northwestern,I think.
No mother or father?
Well,I'm sure they're back in taiwan.
It's common for our
international students
to live with a relative or guardiaN.
It's the guardians that
register them here at school.
But to be perfectly honest,we don't
always know the family situation.
If a student lives
with a legal guardian,
we don't pry into personal history.
I know you can't get close to
every student,but did you know li?
Only a little.
I do think she was
having trouble adjusting.
Adjusting?
Socially.
Well,the kids here-- some
are from down the block.
Some are from all over the world.
It's--it's hard to figure
out where you fit in.
School was exciting at first--
a fresh start in a new country,
the english textbooks,the
new clothes,fr new iends.
My brother quon loved it here.
D saiI would,too,but he was wrong.
Hey,you ready?
We need to find the aunt.
How come she never reported li missing?
The address in li's file
is 33 hayworth.  Let's go
they didn't answer the phone.
When was the last time
you saw the tenants?
It's been a while.
Thank you.
Nothing.
This has to be hers.
And she was all alone.
I was happy when I came here.
But sometimes when
you're in a strange place,
you never stop feeling like a stranger.
Alex,they found insulin
in the refrigerator.
Li wen was living here.
How does this happen--
a 15-year-old girl
living by herself on lake shore drive?
Where's her guardian?
Who pays for this place?
The name on the lease
is mei chen,li's aunt,
but she doesn't pay for the rent.
The landlord says the money gets
wired into his account every month.
It'll take a minute,but
we're tracking from where.
Probably her parents in taiwan.
The school paperwork lists
her brother as quon wen.
We called his dorm at northwestern,
but he didn't answer,so
we're sending a unit.
Well,lindsey knows
northwestern pretty well.
Maybe she can help.
Yeah,I'm sure she can.
What?
Nothing.
Nothing?  I thought you liked lindsey.
I think lindsey's fine.
You know what I think?
I think maybe you're a little jealous.
- I mean,lindsey and I do spend an awful lot of time together.
- Oh,my goodness.
- And we used to be partners.  It's only natural...For you to feel a little threatened.
- I am not jealous,and you can spend time with whoever you want.
Are we done now?
Can we go back to work now?
I'll send candace and
tyler to li's school.
Maybe some of the students
can help us fill in the gaps.
Hey,hold on.
Didn't li's boyfriend dylan
say something about her mother?
He said she was a hairstylist.
The white lotus salon.
Maybe it wasn't her mother.
Maybe it was her aunt.
how's she doing?
She seems devastated.
When patrol picked her up at the
salon,she had no idea li was gone.
Maybe she didn'T.
Ms. Chen,uh,if you're ready,we would
like to ask you a few questions.
- You're li's aunt?
- Yes.
Not by blood,but I take care of her.
When her parents sent her
here from taiwan,they hired me.
My god.
When they see she's gone...
I need to call them.
But I still don't know what happened.
Forgive me,but I'm trying
to see how that's possible.
You're li's legal guardian.
You had to know she was missing.
No,she was traveling
with the school choir.
They were performing at
a school in grand rapids.
She's coming back on the weekend.
That's what she told you?
Of course.  I just assumed it was true.
Li never lied to me.
Ms. Chen,with all due respect,I
think you're the one who's lying.
We went to li's apartment.
The apartment?
She was living there
alone-- a 15-year-old girl.
- No,that's not right.
- It is right.  We were there.
Please listen.
I don't stay at the
apartment,but neither does li.
She lives with me.
At first,it was my
hope to stay with her.
But I have my own family.
They need me closer to them.
So li understands.
We saw her room.
Yes,that's the apartment
her parents arranged for us.
My space isn't big
enough for her things.
I think every teenager
needs a room of her own.
Li goes there during the day
to play music and be a teenager.
She was dating a 25-year-old
man.  Did you know that?
No.  I don't believe that.
Her school's been leaving messages.
You haven't returned any of those calls.
I didn't know.
They must have been
calling the apartment.
Li was on her trip.
I never thought to check.
Please...
li was like my own daughter.
excuse me.  What's going on?
Cops are searching one of the rooms.
- You know who?
- Quon wen.
Someone said he killed his sister.
- Where'd you hear that?
- Just around.
I bet it's true,thoug 'cause his
girlfriend kate's really freaking out.
Excuse me!
Excuse me,kate,are
you quon's girlfriend?
- Do I know you?
- It's okay.
We're not with the police.
We're with a group called
the forgotten network.
I don't know where quon is.
We really need to talk to him,kate.
I can't help you.
Kate,you know what
happened to his sister li.
It's not about helping us.
If you want to help him,tell
us where we can find him.
So where does your boss
think you are right now?
Nsuran iance seminar.
You ever been to one?
Yeah,it's like being shot
with a tranquilizer dart.
Oh.  So you just blew it off?
Aren't you worried he'll find out?
Well,I mean,the seminar
was on avoiding risk,
so yeah,maybe I should've gone.
I went to a school like
this-- eastlake prep.
Nothing but a holding pen
for out-of-control rich kids--
somewhere for their parents to park them
until they're old enough to
send them away to college.
You know,the whole out-of-control
thing I get,but rich?  Really?
I mean--I-I just-- I can't picture
you in the blazer and tie getup.
I'm not rich.  My parents are.
There's a big difference
and I burned the blazer and
tie the minute I graduated.
Li wen she was a sophomore.
Yeah,I knew her.
Didn't talk to her much.
We didn't exactly roll
with the same crowd.
And what crowd did li roll with,exactly?
Who's asking?
Name's tyler.
- You're not a cop?
- No.  I'm a volunteer.
I'm just trying to learn about her life.
And you're not worried?
Why would I be worried?
I'm just saying,whoever
killed that girl,
they might not want
you asking questions.
Honestly,li didn't talk to too
many people,but we were friends.
Must have been hard trying
to be an american teenager.
I guess,but...
a lot of students at lincoln
rhodes are from taiwan,
and she could have hung out
with them if she wanted to,
but they have a whole
social thing going on.
What kind of social thing?
I can't really talk about it now.
Okay.  Then when?
Li was a cool girl.
You know,'te didn deserve
what happened to her.
You guys ever eat komodo dragon soup?
No.
Well,if you get hungry
later,around 11:00,
that's the place to get it.
And we can talk then?
What is this?
I think it's what
we're having for dinner.
so what about the boyfriend
dylan?  His story checked out?
He was with clients the
afternoon li was murdered.
- What about the guardian?
- Looks good,too.
Russell sent a unit to the apartment.
The aunt said that li was
living on a pullout couch.
And what about the choir trip?
Never happened.  If that's
what she told her,she was lying.
I wonder if her parents know something.
We can ask 'em. They're
on their way from taiwan,
but when they get here, I'd like
to be able to tell them wt happened.
You sure about this?
Definitely.
My friends used to do this
all the time in high school.
So you're gonna order a soup
made from an endangered species?
Trust me.  There's no soup involved.
I'll have the komodo dragon soup.
You want fries with that?
so what did he give you?
The address of the party.
so what is this?
during the day,it's
an abandoned theateR.
I think that proves thwe I
nt to the wrong high school.
allright that's
dana hayes--
the girl who tipped us
off about this place.
Well,maybe now she'll tell us why.
li was a P.K.
What is that?
P.K. Stands for parachute kid.
We have a lot of
them at our school--
kids from taiwan or china who get
dropped into the united states.
Dropped by who?
Their parents.
They want them to have
an american education,
so they send them here alone
and arrange for a guardian.
How do you know all this?
From li.  Her brother quon did it.
Now he's in college.
Li's parents sent her over a year
ago,but she never liked it here.
Why not?
This is why not.
Some P.K.  S are pretty
much on their own.
Seems to me like most kids
would want that kind of freedom.
No.  Li wasn't like that.
I tried to like them-- the
other kids e nt herlike me.
But I just wasn't re
y to grow up that fast.
Alex!
Alex,you seeing this?
If you don't know,somebody
knows.  No,honestly.
That's quon--
li's older brother.
- I'm a t gonncalm down!  I'm not leaving!
- What are you talking about?
Quon wen?
russell thinks li's brother
was involved in the murder.
Yeah,but why would he
kill his own sister?
Good question.  He's four years older.
They don't live together,it doesn't
even seem like their lives intersect.
Yeah,but people have all kinds of
baggage when it comes to siblings.
That was a general
statement.  I love my sister.
Maybe it wasn't some preplanned thing.
He got angry about
something,and it just happened.
Well,that fits with the insulin.
It was the only weapon around,so he
grabbed it and stabbed her in the back.
I just don't want us assuming anything.
The way we work is by learning about
li,and right now I don't see the connection.
Okay,so we stay open to everything.
Li was living in two worlds--
her school and hanging with dylan.
And we know dylan checked out.
I took a ton of pictures at the rave,
and I'll bet that some of those
other kids there were P.K.S.
We should look into that.
Sounds like a plan.
I' talk with russell about quon.
You guys start with these.
If they knew our girl,we
need to get to know them.
I'm not saying it's him.
I'm saying most people who run
from the cops are criminals.
- Any luck finding him?
- Not yet,but we will.
I mean,think about it--
if quon was innocent,
why wouldn't he come
in,ask for our help?
I don't know.  He might be
guilty.  It just feels wrong.
What?
You're the one who tells me I should
get more in touch with my feelings.
Okay,no rush to judgment.
Co I just got the voice mails from li's
apartment put on disc.  Have a seat.
The first two are from the school
principal,asking why li was absent.
Then this...
mei,it's quon. I can't
reach li. Call me.
It's quon. Where are you?
Is li okay? Please call me.
You still think he's involved?
yes,ms. Chen,my name is hal gordon.
I'm with the department of
social services here in chicago.
We received a report
regarding child neglect
for a young woman named li wen.
I've been out to see you
twice now,but you weren't home,
and you haven't responded to
my notes asking you to call.
social services?
Someone filed a complaint for neglect,and
a few days later li was murdered?
We need to find the person
who filed that complaint.
She's right over there.
Dana.
Just want to ask you a couple
more follow-up questions.
You never told us that you
reported li to social services.
Don't deny it.
You made an anonymous call,but
that call was recorded.
Social services sent us the
tape,and I recognized your voice.
I couldn't tell you.
So what happened?  Did li
find out that you reported her?
Was she upset?
- Dana,if you hurt li
in self-defense-- - no.
I didn't report li because I wanted to.
I reported her because she asked me to.
she wanted to go home.
She couldn't do it herself,
not after everything her
parents gave up to send her here.
She told me they would never understand.
I helped her.
I reported her,and it got her killed.
Well,then who killed her?
The P.K.S.
They don't want investigations.
they don't want anyone going to
the authorities about anything.
Nobody threatens their freedom.
Dana,you were just at a party with them.
I had to go.
I have to be exactly the
same as always around them.
Why?
b-- they must have found out
about li and social services.
I don't want them to
know that I was involved.
Why didn't you tell
us any of this before?
'Cause I'm scared.
I mean,if they killed li,what do
you expect they're gonna do to me?
I never wanted that
kind of freedom--
staying out all night,partying.
I tried.
I just never felt like I belonged.
I couldn't tell them
I wanted to go home.
They would never have understood.
Okay,wang feng is a
sophomore,sun zhizhi,
senior,and chen shipeng is a freshman.
And there's nine boys in all.
And ten girls.
These are the parachute kids at
the rave who went to school with li.
Now li didn't hang out
with the P.K.S as much,
but these are the ones who
saw her on a daily basis.
Nice job.  So 19 kids.
Which means 19
suspects,assuming one of them
found out about li and social services.
It's hard to believe.
They're just kids.
It's one thing to like your freedom.
It's another thing
to kill to protect it.
What,you think we're on the wrong track?
Let's find out.  We gotta
look at this from both sides--
social services and these kids.
I know social services.
I've dealt with them once in
a while with my own students.
They didn't write up any findings?
They never got a chance.  Li was killed
two days after the complaint was received.
Okay,lindsey,you take social services,
find out what they did on this case.
Walter,you're with lindsey.  Everybody
else,we're going back to that school.
Uh,what if they won't talk to us?
'Cause I thought that P.K.  S don't
talk to anyone outside their own circle.
Li talked with dana.
Somebody will talk with us.
Parachute kids--
I-I've heard the term,
but all of the kids here at lincoln
rhodes have registered guardians.
From what we hear,those guardians
may not be doing their jobs.
They're doing fine in their classes.
There's no problem with
attendance or G.P.A.S.
We found 19 of your students at a rave
in an abandoned theater on a school night.
With all due respect,there
may be more problems here
than you're actually aware of.
- Nothing.
- Dana was right.
These kids won't talk about li.
They won't talk about anything.
They're scared.  If they're
living without supervision,
they know they can be
sent back to taiwan.
I think you should pick 'em up.
- Which ones?
- All of them.
I mean,think about it.  These
kids could be living alone.
If that's true,it's endangering
the welfare of a child.
You have an obligation to investigate.
According to the principal,these
kids have guardians.
Fine.  So let them prove it.
Ifne of these kids killed li wen,
we need to know which ones
have something to hide.
hey.  Okay,so far only three loolegit.
Two live with grandparents,one with an
uncle who had all the right paperwork.
- We're still contacting their other guardians.
- Let's keep going.
Alex,this is hal gordon from
social services,a friend.
Thanks for your help.  You didn't
have to come all the way down here.
Hal was assigned to li's case.
I was out at the house a
few times but got no answer,
so I took a ride to see
li's brother at northwestern.
- Juan?
- Uh,quon.
Oh,right.  Well,he was out,but I
did speak to his girlfriend kate.
So kate knew that you
were investigating li?
Well,I told her.  Does that help you?
Yeah,I think it does.
I haven't seen quon.
I told you,I don't know
anything about this.
You're lying,kate.
You knew li was being
investigated by social services.
You knew she could have been sent home.
Did you think quon might
have to go with her,
that if the police thought
li was being neglected,
that quon could get into
some kind of trouble?
Maybe even deported?
How much do you love
your boyfriend,kate?
Would you kill to keep from losing him?
it wasn'T...
I can't hear you.
I wasn't worried about the government.
I was worried about his parents.
I know them.
If li was being neglected,they
would blame quon.
they would order him to come
home,and he would listen.
I just didn't know what to do.
And so I went to see mei.
Li's guardian?
I went to the salon where she works,
and I told her that social
services came to see quon.
Mei was upset.
Why didn't you tell us this before?
Not tell you what?
That I'm the one that
started all of this?
That I'm the one that got li killed?
I went to mei,and she told
me she would take care of it,
and I-I don't know what she did.
Did you tell this to quon?
Kate,does quon know it was mei?
Mei's apartment's at t end of the hall.
I liked this part much
better when I carried a gun.
I kinda like you better without one.
miss chen?
Miss chen?
Either this place was tossed
or someone left here in a hurry.
Who are you?!  What do you want?!
- All right,take it easy.  - Why are you chasing me?
What do you want?  - Chicago police!  - Drop the gun!
Drop the gun!  Do it now!
- Who are you?  What do you want? Why are you chasing me?
- Drop the gun!  Do it now!
Last chance!  Put it down right now!
- Nobody's gonna do anything.
- Alex,step back,right now!
Quon,just listen.
We're not here for you.
We're trying to find mei chen.
You're not the police.
I saw you the other
night.  You chased me.
That's right.  My name's alex donovan.
I'm not a cop,but this
is detective russell.
There's a badge on her belt.
We're tying to find out
what happened to your sister.
my sister was murdered.
That's right.  We think
we know who did it.
Mei.
That's who we're trying to find.
We kw it wasn't you.
Grace,please.  We're fine here.  Okay?
Quon,think about your parents,all right?
They've already lost one child.
Please don't do this.
Please.
come on.
I know you want revenge,quon,
but you have to know this was wrong.
Mei killed my sister.
If you knew that,
why didn't you go to the police?
Why did you run?
You don't understand.
My sister and I are P.K.S.
There are people who
take advantage of that.
They kidnap us and ransom
us back to our parents.
You thought she was kidnapped?
I thought maybe someone grabbed
her,then she tried to escape.
Did you call your parents?
No.  I couldn't face them.
They'd blame me for not
protecting li,and they'd be right.
MeI chen said that li
was living with her.
Is that true?
No.  Li was living alone.
You knew that?
I didn't know in time.
when li died,I couldn't find mei.
I started asking around,trying
to find out about her.
She lied to me and my parents,and
not just about taking care of lI.
About what?
She wasn't just li's guardian.
She was the guardian for a lot of
kids-- P.K.  S all over chicago.
It was a business for mei.
If li had reported
her to social services,
her whole enterprise
would have collapsed.
That gives us motive.
Now we just have to find her.
I'll call it in.  I'll get
airports,trains,buses covered.
She has a car.
What kind?
A new cadillac.  I've seen it.
Well,if it's new
enough,maybe we can stop her.
technology,miss chen.
That car of yours has a lot of features.
One is a service that can start and
stop your engine from a company computer.
Comes in handy when you lose your key,
not so handy when you kill someone.
I told you.
I don't know what happened to li.
I remember what you told us.
You're here because of
what you didn't tell us.
You knew li was being
investigated by social services.
In other words,you were being investigated
for criminal neglect of a child.
I never neglected li.
The fact is,you're no
just li's guardian,are you?
That's why you ran.
Once we started questioning P.K.
S,you knew we could find out.
You're listed as guardian
for 11 kids in chicago.
You took their parents' money,and
then you abandoned their children.
I guess most of those
ki like their freedom,
but li--she wasn't
like them,was she?
It was her.
The problem is,I'm not
sure we can prove it.
We still can't put her at the scene.
I think I know how.
I need to see the stuff
that we found in li's purse.
It's right here.
All right.
I knew when I saw this before that it was
a sophisticated choice for a young woman.
Now I know why.
It's not li's necklace.
It's mei'S.
It was on the ground.
We thought it was one of the things
that fell out of li's
purse,but it wasn'T.
Li must have ripped it off your
neck right before you killed her.
I warned her.
But she wouldn't listen.
she never listened.
I just wanted to go home.
she came from a small town,like I did.
She said all the right
things to my parents,
and they believed she
would keep us safe.
But I never thought she'd
go as far as she did.
For so long,I felt powerless.
But that day,I stood up for melF.
I grew up,
even if it was just for that moment.
In the end,
I didn't get to go home after all.
But in a way,home came to me.
My name is li wen.