You can't ask a devout people
to disregard a precious teaching.
Yes, but Your Holin ess...
with true respect,
we can't possibly--
I'm sorry, but we can't
possibly rescue all the worms...
not if you want a theater
finished in this lifetime.
You have a clever mind.
Think of a solution.
And in the meantime, you can
explaln to me what is an elevator.
Antarctica.
That's down below.
Here.
Fantastic.
Englan d.
Don't look at me for h elp.
Here?
Shift.
Oh, I know him.
Honk. Hello!
Turn !
Brake!
The robe of a minister is so much finer
than your old brown robe, i sn't it?
Please.
Everyone, please.
You must be very clever
to get such a good promotion.
I did not intend to be
a secretary forever.
Apparently so.
Well , congratulations.
Evil omen !
From his headquarters
in Peking...
the Chairman, Mao Tse-tung,
was triumphantly proclaimed leader...
of the new
People 's Republic of China.
Chairman Mao vowed that the first task
of the Communist regime...
is to reunite
the Chinese motherland.
He declared that
the remote kingdom of Tibet...
Is an lntegral part
of the Chinese territory...
and must join
the great new republic.
"...and must join
the great n ew republic."
People's Republic of China
is advised...
the government of Tibet
recognizes no foreign sovereign.
We are an independent nation.
All the Chinese officials will be
expelled from the borders of Tibet.
We wish you a happy return
to your h omeland.
Have a safe and pleasant journey
back to China.
May you have a safe and
pleasant journey back to China.
We wish you a happy return
to your homeland.
May you have happiness
and prosperity.
Let me see.
You have a very long lifeline,
unlike others here.
When we are faclng the light,
it's day, yes?
When we are in shadow,
it's night.
So if the sun is just rising
in Lhasa...
that means it is just setting...
in New York City, perhaps.
That's why it can't be the same time
in every place.
- Does that answer your question?
- Yes!
Tell me more.
What else do you want to know?
In a few moments, you wIll be
entering the world of mass media.
I can hear news
from all over the planet?
I don't know if they have live
broadcasts from the Tonga lslands...
but generally speaking, yeah.
Do you listen to news
from your country?
From Austri a?
No, not really.
Give me some light, Ku-Dun.
- Why? It's your home.
- Not anymore It isn't.
But don't you have
friends and family there?
A few friends, no family.
Keep the light steady,
Your Holiness.
Why? ls everyone dead?
Do you know there's another sentence
construction aside from the question?
I was married,
but I'm divorced.
What did you do?
I didn't want a child,
so I ran away to climb a mountain.
You h ave a child?
Although I've never seen hlm.
All right. Let me show you
how this thing works.
- Glve it all you've got.
- Yes, Mr. Harrer.
Happy Christmas.
Thank you.
- What is this special occasion?
- This is Chrlstmas.
And this is for you, my friend.
Go on.
"I found it in a shop
in the Barkhor.
It has traveled a long way
and finally come back home.
Thank you for your friendshlp.
Heinrich. "
It is incredible.
Thank you for saving my life.
...must be liberated
from religlous oppressors.
Tibetans must be reunited...
- with their brothers and sisters...
- Turn that off.
- of the great family of new China.
- I'm very sorry.
Foreigners control
Tibet's corrupt government.
Our Tibetan comrades must be liberated
from foreign imperialists.
Tibet 's million serfs
must be freed.
How many foreigners
are there in Tibet?
You, Heinrich.
Tibet will be liberated.
He asked for you, Mr. Harrer.
They were destroying the village
I was born in, Takster in Amdo.
It was terrible.
It was just a dream.
You had a bad dream. That's all.
But it was so real.
Where did it come from?
My mind could never imagine
such terrible things.
I can't sleep.
I'm afraid the dream will come back.
A couple of insomniacs.
Tell me a story.
Tell me a story
about cllmbing mountains.
That's one way to fall asleep.
Those stories bore even me.
Then tell me
what you love about it.
What--
The absolute simplicity.
That's what I love.
When you're climbing,
your mind is clear...
freed of all confusions.
You have focus.
And suddenly
the light becomes sharper...
sounds are rlcher...
and you are filled with...
the deep, powerful presence of life.
I've only felt that way
one other time.
When?
In your presence, Ku-Dun.
The Chinese have already secured
much of the northern border regions.
They have ransacked a village,
destroyed the monasteries...
burnt scriptures
and defaced holy relics.
We've been told they've
even killed some monks--
- Which vill age?
- Takster in Amdo.
It's where His Holiness was born.
Go ahead.
When you were defense minister
to the previous Dalai Lama...
then you wanted to
reorganlze the army.
Can you do it now?
The People's Liberation Army
is one million troops strong.
We have 8,000 men
with 50 pieces of artillery...
and a few hundred mortars
and machine guns.
The task is hopeless.
Then you refuse
the appointment, do you?
No. I accept it with honor.
You two gentlemen know about wars.
What type of weapon
do you recommend?
It seems the Chinese troops are
advancing toward our northern borders.
Where's His Holiness?
The glory of
a British coronation.
Nowhere in the world
is there anything half so wonderful.
Only once or twice in the life of each
one of us comes such a day as this...
when we know that we are watchlng
history in the making...
when we know that generations to come
will look back on this day...
for May 12, 1937, wIll be
one of the dates in hlstory...
that schoolchildren will learn about
maybe a thousand years from now.
Every moment
the thrill of excitement--
Do you thlnk someday people will
look at Tibet on the movie screen...
and wonder what happened to us?
The coronation coach moves forward.
I don't know.
Don't you have all the answers?
I don't.
On the same field where Tibetans
traditionally gathered for picnics...
ground was cleared
to build an alrstrip...
so that the plane carrying
three Chinese generals could land.
Nearby, the Tibetan army
practiced its maneuvers.
Some of the soldiers
wear ancient mesh armour.
They bring old muskets
and spears as artillery.
The spectacle of a peace-lovlng nation,
vainly attempting to create a mllitary.
The fears of war
on my friends ' faces...
strike a deeply burled
personal chord.
Echoes of the aggressions
of my own country...
the will to overpower
weaker peoples...
bring shame to me.
I shudder to recall how once long ago
I embraced the same beliefs...
how at one time I was, in fact...
no different from
these intolerant Chinese.
The Tibetans say an enemy
is the greatest teacher...
because only an enemy can help
develop patience and compassion.
They believe with rock-llke faith
that the power of their religion...
will protect them
against these Chinese.
In preparation for
the generals ' visit...
sacred ceremonies are performed
throughout Lhasa.
Sculptures of deities have been carved
with great care in butter.
As the sun melts them, they become
a reminder that nothlng lasts.
The rising star of the cabinet,
Minister Ngawang Jigme...
made an offering of his own
to greet the Chinese generals...
and lead them through Lhasa.
Raising their flag is an honor
the Chinese don't deserve.
When you are not strong enough to fight,
you should embrace your enemy.
With both arms around you,
he cannot point a gun at you.
Nothing in politics
is a matter of honor, my friend.
History repeats itself,
even in paradise.
General, we shall have
our audience with His--
General, the monks have been making
this mandala of sand for many days.
It is a symbol of
enlightenment and peace.
General !
We do not sit lower than he does.
But, General,
It is our custom.
I can sit down there.
Your Holiness,
this is General Chang Jing Wu...
General Than Gua,
General Than Gua San.
They wish to have
an audience with you.
May you have happiness
and prosperity.
They are promising regional autonomy
and religious freedom...
if Tibet accepts that China
be its political master.
Until I attain my majority, the
regent ls the political leader of Tibet.
You should have requested
an audlence with him...
to discuss these important matters
of the world.
My experience of such things
is limited.
I am a simple Buddhist monk.
All I know is the scripture
and the words of Lord Buddha.
He sald, "All beings tremble
before danger and death.
Life is dear to all.
When a man considers this,
he does not kill or cause to kill."
You must understand.
These words are ingrained
in the heart of every Tibetan.
It ls why we are a peaceful people
who reject violence on principle.
I pray you will see this is
our greatest strength...
not our weakness.
I thank you for your vislt.
An offering
to the Enlightened Ones.
Rellgion is poison.
The Chinese have attacked
the Tlbetan frontier near Den-Go.
"Today at the dawn, 84,000 troops
of the 1st and 2nd Field Armles...
under the overall command
of General Chang Jing Wu...
attacked the Tibetan frontier
near Den-Go.
The Tibetan army believes
an attack on Chamdo is imminent.
Ngawang Jigme,
our newly appointed governor...
is preparing to send troops
toward the Chinese column...
In order to stop
their progresslon. "
As you know, Chamdo
is the gateway to Tibet.
If Chamdo falls.
If I did not know that, I would not
have been appointed governor.
You do realize our troops are committed
to fighting the Chinese to the last man.
They would rather die than surrender.
Rest assured. there will be no surrender
Radio Lh asa.
Now.
We request permission
to surrender.
- But there will be no surrender--
- I said, "Radio Lh asa."
Permission to surrender now.
We lost the war in 11 days,
Heinrich.
This surrender is
our death sentence.
And I'm afraid our friend
Ngawang Jigme has issued it.
He abandoned Chamdo and then
destroyed the ammunition dumps.
Without weapons and ammunition...
there was no hope for
the troops who wanted to fight.
Our guerrillas could have held
the mountain passes for months...
even years.
It would have bought us time to make
appeals for help to other nations.
Now it's lost.
They broke down the gates.
Hello, my friend.
We did what was the best
for our country...
for Tibet.
On the way to Lhasa, I would see
Tibetans wearing these jackets.
"Chinese soldiers.
Very nice.
Glve food, clothes, money.
Very nice."
It's strange to me that something
so harmless as a jacket...
could symbolize
such a great lie.
After all these years, you still
do not understand Tibetan ways.
To return a gift is unforgivable.
A man who betrays his culture
should not preach about its customs.
There was a time
I would have wished you dead...
but your shame
will be your torture.
And your torture
will be your life.
I wish it to be long.
We pray that His Holiness,
the Dalai Lama...
will be granted the power
to unify his people.
We humbly ask the Tibetan government
to honor our request...
and let the Dalai Lama
attain his political majority.
You have the entire palace
in a panlc.
I'm hiding from the world
for a day.
Kind of difficult
in a glasshouse, no?
It's The Moonlight...
by Debussy.
What else do you know
about this song?
Him, him and him.
I hope you've received your invitation
to the enthronement ceremony.
Yes. Thank you.
- It's next week.
- Th ank you.
Do I look like an egghead?
No, they suit you.
We have a saying in Tibet...
"If the problem can be solved,
there is no use worrying about it.
If it can't be solved.
So stop worrying.
You have to leave Tibet.
Your life's at great risk.
Forgive my presumption, but I made
arrangements to get you out safely.
We should leave after the enthronement.
The Chinese would never expect it--
How can I help people if I run away from
them? What kind of leader would I be?
I have to stay here.
Serving others
is my path to liberation .
- Then I don't go either.
- Why not?
Because you are my path
to liberation.
The Buddha sald. "Salvation
It demands strenuous effort
and practice.
So work hard and seek
your own salvation diligently."
I am not your son...
and I never thought of you
as my father.
You were much too informal
with me for that.
Do you ever think about him?
And wh at do you think about?
It's not the conscious thought
really.
It's just always there.
When I crossed Tibet,
he was with me.
When I came to Lhasa.
When I sit beside you,
he's...
there with me.
I can't even imagine how I pictured
the world without him in it.
Then you should go home
and be his father.
I know.
You have finished
your job with me.
But you have to stay
for my enthronement.
I want you to see me
in all my pomp and glory.
It'd be a pleasure, my friend.
From the government of Tibet...
to Your Holin ess,
the fourteenth Dalai Lama...
we ask you to rule your people...
as the spiritual and
temporal leader of Tibet.
By your prayers and wishes,
I humbly accept.
Butter tea.
It was never my cup of tea.
- One was enough.
- Yes, we must follow the custom.
A fresh cup of tea is poured
for the loved one departing.
It sits untouched,
walting for hls return.
May all travelers find happiness
wherever they go.
Without any effort may they accomplish
whatever they set out to do.
And having safely
returned to the shore...
may they be joyfully reunited
with their relatives.
Mr. Harrer...
from His Holiness.
- Hello, Horst.
- Hello, Heinrich.
Rolf, come out to meet him.
No, I don't want to.
May l?
Rolf, take your time.
Well done, son.
Well done.
THE END
Subtitles by: