Have you ever thought about
how we would be right now
if we had never met?
Are you saying...
if I hadn't met you?
If I hadn't met you, the current me
would probably be like any other woman,
and find a man who loves
me more than I love him.
I would be blandly dating
him, without any worries.
Stop pushing me.
Mom, can you stop forcing me?
What about you? If you hadn't met me,
what would the current you be like?
Hello, I'm Xiao Min.
Hello, I'm Hao Meng.
Perhaps I would be like you,
going by every man's advice,
and finding a woman who cares
more about me than about herself.
A kind and honest
woman who doesn't have any particular strengths, but
a good woman who's understanding of all my flaws.
If you want to take a picture...
Perhaps I wouldn't have
the urge to marry her.
Really?
But I also wouldn't think
about breaking up with her.
Subtitles brought to you
by The Eligibles @ Viki
Even if I my heart doesn't
beat crazily anymore,
I will still tell myself that having no
frustrations is a type of happiness.
Even if, in my heart, I feel like I have
lost something, I will still reassure myself
that having no regrets
is a type of happiness.
Because...
we are not together.
Why are you here?
It was me who sent a text
with my father's phone.
Other than him, I don't think
you will meet with anyone.
Whether you believe it or not, your father and
I do not have that kind of a relationship.
That's what all the
mistresses say in dramas.
Miss Cai, are you humiliating me?
That's not what I mean. Why
would I humiliate you?
Didn't you say that you and my
father have a clean relationship?
That's exactly what he said.
He said that even though you're his first love,
the person that he loves now is my mother.
He's only friends with you.
What he said is true. We're only friends
who've reunited after many years.
He really does love your mother.
Really?
Of course! He told me himself how much he
loves your mother and you, his daughter.
You can choose not to believe me, but
you have to believe your father.
Okay. If it's really how you say
it is, then prove it to me.
That's right! You better prove to me that there's
nothing going on between you and Cai Hong Li.
- We are really—- Kneel!
I'm sorry. Recently, my husband and I are
living separately and arguing about divorcing,
but both my son and daughter
don't support my decision.
So I've been feeling suffocated
and wanted to talk to someone.
That's why I asked Hong
Li to come out and talk.
It's true.
Don't misunderstand. There's really
nothing going on between Hong Li and I!
I never thought to steal
someone else's husband.
Plus, I can tell that Hong
Li is sincere towards you.
In his world, you and your daughter
are what's most important.
Before I met up with Hong Li,
I had already seen you
two at the supermarket.
What?
I saw you two pushing the cart,
talking and laughing while buying wine.
It was clear that you two were happy.
After seeing you two leave,
I was really envious.
- Because my husband and
I—- Okay, okay, okay.
We still need to take care of this issue.
- Cai Hong Li! - Yes!
- Go buy wine.- What?
-What? (Huan Zhen)
What do you mean what? Do you want
to keep kneeling or go buy wine?
Oh, oh, okay. Report:
Yes, I'll go buy wine!
Tonight...
is lady's night! You can't
leave until you're drunk.
What? You're saying my mom
is drinking with your mom?
Really? I've never seen my mom drink.
Yeah.
Not only can she drink, her tolerance is quite high. She's
having a good time with my mom, talking and laughing.
They might even become drinking buddies.
It was only hours ago when that unsightly scene
happened, now they're happily drinking together?!
What is she thinking? I'm really starting
to have trouble understanding my mom.
Perhaps what she feels most hurt about is not being
misunderstood, but rather having no one understand her.
The people who appear the strongest
are often the loneliest.
Just like how I misunderstood you before.
Perhaps.
Anyway, don't worry. I'll take care of her.
When she feels better, you can take her home.
Alright.
Hey, I have a question.
What question?
How come when you found out
that my mom had no money
and didn't know where to go,
you contacted me first instead
of calling my brother?
I've already broken up with him.
Wouldn't it be weird to call him?
If you guys have already broken up, then
why are you still doing so much for him?
I'm not doing if for him, it's for you.
Me?
Yeah. Don't forget that I'm
not only your brother's ex,
I'm also your best friend.
Of course I need to help your family.
It better be like that.
Cai Huan Zhen!
Oh, coming!
I'll talk to you later. Your mom's
calling me. That's all for now. Bye-bye.
Okay, bye.
Who were you talking to?
I was talking to...
Ohoho! Ohoho!
Ahh! Ahh!
What are you doing?
Mrs. Hao, Mrs. Hao! Are you alright?
I want to drink, let me drink!
Xia Yu He!
Go die!
Ah, Auntie, do you want to rest first?
You can come to my room to rest.
Stop pretending to be nice!
You're the happiest seeing
me this way, right?
Don't think that if you treat me well,
- I'll let you and Hao Meng be together.
That's impossible!  -That's not right!
Ahh, hold on.
Why are you laughing?
I'm laughing because I'm
happy to drink with you.
Auntie! Ah, A-Auntie!
Hello? Sheng Nan, where are you?
I didn't see you.
About that...
I'm almost there, I'm almost there!
I'm on the way. I'll be there soon!
Wait for me, uh, outside by the door.
Okay, okay. Bye-bye!
Cai Huan Zhen, sorry.
I wasn't trying to trick you.
I'm not just your best friend,
I'm also my brother's good sister.
Why are you here?
My sister said that my mom's drunk,
and she wanted me to take her home.
Come in.
Why did she drink this much?
- Actually, your mom drank most
of the alcohol herself.  -Huh?
It's probably that she
normally has a lot of
pressure, so when she drank,
she became like this.
Even my mom and my dad who
drank with her are drunk too.
She normally never drinks in front of me,
I didn't think that she'd be like this now.
Sorry.
I said I'd take care of her well
but I let her drink so much.
The person who should apologize is me.
I didn't consider her mood
and let her leave alone.
Thankfully you were there. Thank you.
-No-no-no-no-no.  -Let's go.
There's no need. There's no need to go.
I don't want to go back.
Do you want... to just let
your mom sleep here for today?
And then come get her tomorrow?
Will that be too bothersome?
I was just thinking, that at this time
if she has to go home to face the people
she's the closest to and cares most about,
she will probably need some more time.
Yeah.
That hurts.
This is okay for now.
When she wakes up tomorrow, I'll call you.
Turn on the lights...
turn off the lights...
Then I'll just have to inconvenience you.
Hao Meng, Hao Meng, go tell him.
I, Xia Yu He, will never
go back in this lifetime.
I'll never go back!
Really, don't come look for me!
Even if you beg me there's no use!
I'm telling you, I won't go back!
Tell him I won't go back.
Auntie, Hao Meng isn't here. I'm Huan Zhen.
- Auntie, just lie down first, okay.
-There's no problem, no problem.
I'll tell you.
Actually these past dozens of years,
I've suffered through many hardships.
I...
I really tried hard to be
Hao Yi Sheng's good wife.
And be Hao Meng's and Hao
Shen Nan's good mother.
But what's the use?
My husband sees me and
thinks I'm transparent!
My daughter gets scared when she sees me!
And when my son sees me he avoids me!
Everyone thinks
that Xia Yu He only cares about
her own honor and reputation.
You guys are all wrong.
Actually, what I care most about
is whether or not my Hao
Meng is living well or not.
Do you know that when Hao Meng
first graduated from school
he had to be some environmental lawyer?
And what was the result?
He had piles of debt!
His father said kids had to fall to grow.
Unless Hao Meng himself begged his
father, his father wouldn't help him.
I wasn't willing to let
Hao Meng suffer hardship
so I begged him and really
even kneeled in front of him.
As long as I could help Hao Meng,
what does my honor count for?
Because in my heart,
Hao Meng is the best child
in the whole world.
In this whole world, there is no woman
who is good enough for our Meng Meng.
But to tell you the truth,
I actually don't even
want him to get married,
because I'm really scared,
that if he has a wife, he'll forget me.
So his girlfriend needs to be picked by me.
I want to pick one that
is willing to listen,
a daughter-in-law who won't steal my son.
What now?
What are you looking at me for?
Do you think I'm really scary?
Is a mother like me really scary?
No, not at all.
You're not scary at all.
I understand your feelings.
You understand?
-Really, I understand.
Because I feel the same way as you do.
Because I'm afraid that
other people will worry,
I always pretend to be strong and smart,
but really, the two of us
are actually quite stupid.
Even if the two of us
clearly really love him,
we don't know how to express it.
We grasp the things we care
about tightly in our hands.
Sometimes, though, they get crushed.
But even so, we hold onto them
tightly and protect them.
Because Hao Meng and Sheng
Nan have a mother like you,
they are really happy and content.
You're not scary at all.
Really? Having a mother like me,
they are actually happy?
Really. They're really really happy.
Subtitles brought to you
by The Eligibles @ Viki
Your mother, she's already asleep.
What are you thinking?
I think I don't really
understand my mother.
I thought back earlier,
I don't think I've ever, like you,
sat by her side and calmly
listened to her talk.
Earlier I carefully thought back,
and realized that I never
once had this type of memory.
If being with the one I
loved for my whole life
is an extremely happy and
deserving of anticipation event,
then my mother, who, for the
sake of her own children,
became tied together with
someone she didn't love,
isn't she even more unfortunate
and full of despair?
But I think... that your mom, even
more than you think, loves your dad.
How is that possible?
Sheng Nan and I have watched the two of them
argue almost every day since our childhood.
Compared to your parents,
they are like... two people
who cannot stand each other
and, they are, at most, roommates.
From a woman's perspective,
your mom often argues with your dad in
hopes of being cared about a bit more.
Just like my mom, she
often argues with my dad.
But that's because she cares
too much about my dad.
Their generation of women doesn't know
how to express their feelings well,
so they often use this method
to tell their other half
"I care very much about you. Could
you also care more about me?"
Even if it's a bit dumb and a bit
like they are appearing to be strong,
that's just considered part of their love.
If you look closely at their daily life,
you will realize that there's a lot
of clues that they're in love.
What's wrong?
Did I say something wrong?
No.
I just think that being like this right now
and chatting with you feels really good.
Me too.
It has gotten late now.
I'll leave first.
Good night.
Earlier when we first got
together, I had a dream.
I dreamed that the two of us
woke up under a huge tree
and in the dream the two of us were like a
couple who've been together for a long time.
We brushed our teeth together
and ate breakfast together.
We were on the sofa together
watching a movie that had been
rerunning for god knows how long.
Good night.♫ Heaven knows how many
misunderstandings there must be... ♫
Hao Meng.
Have a safe trip back.
Subtitles brought to you
by The Eligibles @ Viki
Dad! Didn't I tell you it's
not what you're thinking?
So why do you have to do this?
What's wrong now?
Dad just took all of mom's things and
wants me to take them to your place.
You didn't tell him that all of
this was a misunderstanding?
Of course I did, but he doesn't listen!
Now what do we do?
If they want to divorce,
then just let them divorce.
Huh?
First take these clothes
and put them on the car.
O-oh.
Brother, what if they really want to
divorce, then wouldn't the two of us—?
Auntie.
I prepared some honey water.
It's good for hangovers.
Actually, I am just scared
that our Meng Meng, after getting married
and having a wife, will forget me.
I want to find a woman who listens
and a daughter-in-law who
will not steal my son.
In the bathroom, I put a new toothbrush and bath-towel,
so you could stay for breakfast then leave.
Is this your room?
That's right.
Is there something wrong?
A woman's room can be this messy?
I don't understand how Hao
Meng can like a girl like you.
And, uh, last night I drank
a bit too much, so
that's why I stayed for the night.
So, tell your mother
I caused much trouble for her
so later I'll go back. Oh my...
Auntie, are you okay?
Nothing is wrong. Can I ask
where the bathroom is?
If you walk out, you'll see it.
Uh... do you want to stay and have dinner?
You really don't have to. Sorry for the
inconvenience, but I'll leave first.
Mom.
Before you go home, I want
to take you somewhere.
Subtitles brought to you
by The Eligibles @ Viki
Did the two of you ask me here to meet him?
Hao Meng, I told you.
If she wants to leave, let her leave.
I have nothing to say to her.
The two of you don't need to misunderstand. I asked you
to meet here to go through with the divorce proceedings.
I have five copies of the divorce papers. The man and woman
both have a copy. Each side's witness both also get copy.
The last copy is for the Household
Registration Office for proof.
The divorce agreement only had
a signature on one paper.
So I can't help you get the divorce
passed if it's not complete.
As for the witnesses,
Sheng Nan and I will take those positions.
Both of us have signed the papers.
As for the property and retirement fees,
I have already used your situations and
your needs to decide how to divide them.
There shouldn't be too many problems.
Now.
Divorce, please.
Okay.
Since Brother already said so.
It's better to be clear.
Just make it as if we don't owe anyone.
I agree, I'll sign.
Then sign! Who cares?
Okay, after this, Sheng Nan and I
will go to the office with you
and end your marriage.
It will end.
Wait a second brother.
When we were going through
the assets of you two,
There is one more thing
that hasn't been split.
What is that?
This thing is not mentioned,
because it's not considered anything.
So I need to point it out
in front of both of you.
Wait.
This accessory box is my marriage
gift, it has nothing to do with him.
Yes, it used to belong to you.
But everything in the box is not yours.
Since you want to divorce,
What is there not to split up?
What is it that you can't show me?
Dad, these are things that can't be seen.
These are your memories with Mom.
There's rain.
Remember to bring an umbrella.
November 3, 1996.
Since I saw you coughing
for the whole night,
I got you medicine,
remember to take it after eating.
March 12, 2001.
This medicine pack is the medicine
mentioned on the post it.
I didn't think Mom would save it,
and not take it.
To be honest, before today,
I believed what you told me.
You said you never wanted to marry dad.
You even said you've never loved him.
And I believed all of this,
but the Cai Huan Zhen that
you hated the most told me,
that I need to look at your day-to-day life
and I will find evidence that
the two of you love each other.
And reality proved that she was right.
I think that no matter if it's
me, Sheng Na, or Dad, or you,
we were all were tricked by your pride.
In your heart, you must still love Dad.
Otherwise, you wouldn't
save any of these things.
Dad.
When mom first married you, she may
have had someone else in her heart.
But you chose to use coldness and
detachment to face your marriage.
You let a woman use this petty and low way
in your detachment, saving all the next-to-nothing
pieces of evidence that there was concern and care.
In this box, it contains
Mom's yearning for you.
And the detachment you
exhibited towards her.
This is the evidence that
you gave her a tragic love!
If you put no care in your
attitude then let me say this,
should you still be considered as a man?
As your son,
I couldn't have not said these words.
But as your divorce lawyer,
I really think that your marriage,
really has not gone to
a point of no return.
I hope the two of you can
give yourself and each other
a last chance.
Let them calm down first.
Then, what do you plan do to now?
I never thought that
you would have kept all these things.
Even movie tickets...
1997 Titanic.
That was our
last time watching a movie together.
Yu He, we haven't watched a
movie together in twenty years.
Do you want to watch a movie together?
Do you have time later?
Yes.
I feel really good. I want
to go to the place...
Do you remember the last time
the two of them held hands?
Please.
From childhood until now, I've never seen
them as close as they are right now.
- Then what do you plan to do
with Cai Huan Zhen?  -Huh?
- Dad and Mom argued for thirty years and have managed to
reconcile, what impossibilities do the two you have?  -I...
You are the man. I beg of you, take
the initiative already! Can't you?
- The timing isn't right.  -Then
when is the timing right?
When the timing is right,
you'll naturally know.
Huan Huan Jie, Busan City Hall just called to ask if you have
finished making the fixes to the collaboration project plan.
I'm correcting it right now. Let them know that
before I get off work I'll send it to them.
Okay, no problem.
-Hey.  -Hmm? -Are you okay?
I'm very good.
My brother, these days,
did he not call you?
No.
Uh, I really don't know what he's thinking.
He clearly wants to reconcile with you, but he's
just putting on a facade and not doing anything.
Right now he probably doesn't
want to reconcile with me.
Or... are you saying,
that in your heart, you actually also
really want to reconcile with him.
I never said that.
Huan Huan Jie, someone is here to see you.
Auntie, you coming to see me today...
is there something wrong?
Huan Huan, coming here, I wanted to ask you
do you have a partner now?
-Huh?  -Huh?
Are you still single? Do
you have a boyfriend?
Mom.
Are you coming here today to say nonsense
like you can't be together with brother?
Stay quiet please, I'm here
to speak with Huan Huan.
Ah, what's the matter?
Do you have a boyfriend?
-No.  -Ah, perfect!
I have a single man with
good qualifications.
Did I hear wrong, Mom? You want to set
Cai Huan Zhen up on a blind date?!
You are really strange and noisy!
Ah, I'm here to find Huan Zhen.
What are you doing here right now?
Mom, aren't you being too over the top? It's not like
you don't know Cai Huan Zhen and brother's situation.
You doing this and you're even
setting up a blind date for her?
Huan Huan, let's not listen to her.
Here, this is the man's photo and information.
Take a look at it first. If you're satisfied,
Auntie can arrange for you to go
out to dinner to meet this person.
Auntie, thank you, but I really don't
have this intention right now.
Are you sure? This man's
qualifications are really good.
- I'm really okay, thank you. -Look at it first. If you really
are not satisfied, we can talk about it, it's not too late.
Okay, okay, okay. I'll look at it to see if this man's
qualifications are that good. Just wait a moment, okay?
Ah, you're really strange. I already told you
this isn't for you. What are you looking at?
- No, you— - Let go. You're really strange. It's
not your type so why are you fighting for it?
- Because—- Stop fighting!
I'll look, I'll look!
What do you think?
This should be the type you like, right?
Huan Zhen,
relax, don't be nervous.
Subtitles brought to you
by The Eligibles @ Viki
Okay. I won't bother you guys anymore.
You two can talk by yourselves.
I'll be leaving first.
Brother, I did what you wanted me to.
It'll be up to you now. Don't
forget what you promised me.
Don't make me disappointed.
You asked your mom to take me out?
That's not the main point.
The main point is that you're
sitting in front of me,
so in my mom's mind, you're the woman most
suited to be with me in the entire world.
When we separated,
I couldn't understand many things.
Why can't we be together even
though we love each other?
Why are you pushing me away even
after everything I did for you?
Do you not love me anymore?
It's not that I don't love you.
I just don't think we're
suited to be together.
To find this answer
I went back to the place where we broke up.
I stood on the streets of Busan,
and remembered the words you told me.
In that instance, I understood.
No matter how much we love each other,
no matter how much we want to be together, the
problem between us is still not solved, right?
So in your heart,
what you're most afraid of
are those things that might disappear.
That's why I told myself
that if I can't solve
the problem between us,
if I can't destroy all those things you're afraid of,
then I don't have the right to say that I love you.
In Korea,
you said that my sister dislikes you.
Right now, you two have reconciled.
So you can't use this excuse anymore.
You said that my mom dislikes you,
that we're not suited to be together.
Right now, she's no longer
against us being together.
So you can't use this excuse
to reject me either.Lastly,
it's also what you're most afraid of.
You think that being with me
will make me lose many things.
Why do you have this?
Teacher Yu E gave it to me.
This note made me realize your emotions.
But what I want to tell you is that
being with you never
made me lose my dreams.
Because rather than being afraid of those things
that might disappear, I'm most afraid of losing...
I'm most afraid of losing you.
So right now you don't have
any excuses to reject me!
Can you return to my side?
Do you remember what you told me?
When we first got together,
you had a dream.
In the dream, we were like a couple
who've been together for a long time.
Watching a movie that's been
rerunning for a long time,
sleeping together, waking up together.
I still remember.
Me, too.
Because I've dreamt the exact same dream.
It's a pleasant dream, but for some reason,
I felt afraid after waking up.
The me in the dream
was not the Cai Huan Zhen who has
had many failed relationships.
It was a Cai Huan Zhen who was
really happy and really blissful.
I suddenly felt so scared. I was scared
that we would work too hard for this dream,
but then one day, we would wake up
and realize that this relationship
was not as pleasant as we imagined.
What would we do then?
It's not that I don't want
to return to your side.
It's just that I'm really not certain
if I can achieve happiness like this.
If I can't be like you, saying "Yes!
This time, we can be happy until the end."
Wouldn't it be unfair to you?
Give me a bit more time.
After I've sorted out myself,
after I find the answer, okay?
What if you still can't find the answer?
Do you still not understand what I want?!
I felt afraid after waking up.
The me in the dream
was not the Cai Huan Zhen who has
had many failed relationships.
It was a Cai Huan Zhen who was
really happy and really blissful.
I suddenly felt so scared.
I was scared that we would
work too hard for this dream,
but then one day, we would wake up
and realize that this relationship
was not as pleasant as we imagined.
What would we do then?
♫ Why must I lose the
courage to become weak ♫
♫ What kind of love and
ending was I expecting? ♫
♫ That would complicate my simple heart and
make me immeasurably self-satisfied? ♫
If I can't be like you, saying "Yes!
This time, we can be happy until the end."
Wouldn't it be unfair to you?
♫ Why am I always so attentive to love? ♫
♫ Just how much backbone
and pride must I have? ♫
♫ Knowing that love is about to shatter ♫
Give me a bit more time.
After I've sorted out myself,
after I find the answer, okay?
Do you still not understand what I want?!
Cai Huan Zhen!
Aren't you going to work?
You're going to be late.
I'm already up.
Then what are you doing?
Are you calling Meng Meng?
I'm not.
Cai Huan Zhen, let me tell you something
very important. Please pay attention.
Earlier I calculated yours
and Meng Meng's lives,
today your luck with
romance is very unsteady.
So today,
you can't take your phone to work.
How do I go to work if you take my phone?
You won't die for being without
your phone for one day.
You two can't contact each today!
Hey!
How can you take someone's phone like that?
Hey, wife, did you take her cell phone?
You don't have to worry
if I'm the one doing it.
Hurry and give it to me.
Otherwise we'll run out of time.
Subtitles brought to you
by The Eligibles @ Viki
Follow me.
Electro
♫ L. O. V. E. Baby ♫
♫ L. O. V. E. ♫
♫ Love, love, love ♫
♫ Why don't you be with me tonight? ♫
♫ Cause I've got you all over my mind ♫
♫ And baby we celebrate in life ♫
♫ We've got so much love inside ♫
♫ So come and give me love ♫
♫ Love ♫
♫ Come and show me love ♫
♫ So come and give me love ♫
♫ Baby, give it to meLove ♫
♫ Baby, tell me one more Love ♫
♫ Love you, babyLove ♫
♫ Why don't you be with me tonight? ♫
♫ Cause I've got you all over my mind ♫
♫ And baby we celebrate in life ♫
♫ We've got so much love inside ♫
♫ So come and give me love ♫
♫ Love ♫
♫ Pass by the school's flower shop.
The vacantness reaches the shores ♫
♫ Until forever~ Every second, we love
while fighting, without stopping ♫
♫ Why don't you be with me tonight?Cause
I've got you all over my mind ♫
♫ And baby we celebrate in life
We've got so much love inside ♫
♫ So come and give me love ♫
♫ Come and show me love ♫
♫ L. O. V. E~ Love ♫
You said that you can't be with me
not because you don't love me,
but because you're not certain
if we can find happiness
by continuing to be together.
To be honest,
I can't answer you.
Because the answer
needs to be found
by the both of us.
What if
we still can't find it in the end?
What if I'm not the person that's
supposed to find the answer with you?
Impossible.
We will definitely find the answer.
Because our meeting
was destined.
It was destined before we even met.
Whether it was the silhouette that made my
heart mysteriously pound for the first time...
- I don't want to.- Just try it.
- I don't want to!
- I don't care!
I'll bring the dress to you tomorrow.
Bye bye!
No! Bye bye!
Hey.
Why are you here?
The second time you made my heart palpitate...-
Who is she?- She's my best friend, Cai Huan Zhen.
Why is your hair so ugly?
Or the time you made my heart beat
to the point that I forgot myself...
All those innumerable times
you made my heart beat...
all this time...
it was only one person.
Will you marry me?
To find the answer...
together.
I will.
♫ Forever ♫
Yes, I do.
I know, he's really popular.
Who?
You all think he's good at basketball?
A sandwich and bubble tea.
Please wait a minute.
Cai Huan Zhen, let's go.
Alright.
Come on, come on.
I can't believe...
Cai Huan Zhen!
Perhaps we're not all perfect.
But that doesn't mean we can't
have a perfect relationship.
Because happiness is
earned by fighting for it.
To every woman... marry me, or not?