When I open my eyes, Irie-kun is right next to me.
I'm so happy!
Perhaps... I am the most happiest person in the world?
It's already been 2 and a half years since the marriage,
and still my love for Irie-kun reaches a new record everyday!
Good morning.
Don't look at me with your swollen face.
It's not good to look at.
Forget about what he said now.
I love you.
Good morning.
Good morning, Kotoko-chan.
You could have slept a bit more since it's the spring holidays.
I'm your unchanging Daughter-in-law...
Oh my.
Nice Mother-in-law!
Good morning, Mama.
And Kotoko-chan.
Good morning.
Good morning, Father-in-law.
Shall I make you some coffee?
Oh~! Thank you, Kotoko-chan!
Nice Father-in-law!
Kotoko!
You washed my shirt with my student handbook in a pocket.
You noticed that?
It won't fit into a pocket now!
Forget about him, too.
- Good morning- Good morning!
Kotoko, can you make me some coffee?
Of course~!
And... And...
The coolest person in the world - my husband!
This happiness will never end... was what I thought.
Until that time.
Oh, I forgot to mention,
but Rika-chan will stay with us for a while starting tomorrow.
Rika?- Rika will?
So she came back.
That's right! In 7 years!
Who is Rika-chan?
That's right. You didn't know, right?
She is Naoki and Yuki's cousin.
You're incomparable to her.
She is really smart and pretty.
Until she went to America because of her dad's job 7 years ago,
she used to come here and play with these two.
Why will she stay here for a while?
Oh, her family will come back in May,
but Rika-chan will go to a high school here in April and came back by herself.
So, for a month, until her family comes back here,
we agreed to let her stay here with us.
That's how it is. So Rika is coming back.
What kind of girl is Rika-chan who makes woman hater Yuki-kun this happy?
As I recall, Rika-chan used to win
piano competitions and cooking competitions, right?
She is cheerful and nice, isn't she?
Yes, she has been bright ever since she was little.
So Rika-chan is like a perfect person.
So different from idiot Kotoko.
Think of her as your little sister. Please take care of her.
Okay.
So heavy!
It feels like my arms are being torn.
I'm almost there.
I'm sorry!
No, I'm sorry!
Sorry.- Sorry!
Thank you.
So you were coming to our house, right?
Are you Rika-chan? You're Rika-chan, right?
No, I'm not.
You're not...
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
Perhaps you're Yuki's friend?
What?
Excuse me, then!
Wait a minute!
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Seriously.
Look in front of you.
I was.
You suddenly ran into me.
She seems to be about the same age as Yuki-kun.
Onii-chan!
Oh, Yuki.
Yuki, there was...
Rika. Rika is here!
Hey Rika!
Wow. She is so cute!
Naoki!
Naok, you've become more handsome again.
You too. You've become prettier as well.
What is this?!
♫KISS what I've longed for♫
♫the complicated kiss from you♫
♫Mischievous Kiss♫
♫On the sloping path♫
♫The wind passes through. If I look up at the sky♫
♫The sun is shining brightly♫
♫With an innocent expression♫
♫I catch up and naturally our eyes meet SPARK♫
♫No matter if I cry or laugh, or if things are difficult♫
♫Even if I want to escape reality♫
♫This feeling is the only thing♫
♫I can't control♫
♫KISS the greedy kiss♫
♫The kiss I remember♫
♫The kiss that awakened me♫
♫Mischievous Kiss♫
♫KISS the kiss I've waited for♫
♫The kiss that betrayed me♫
♫It started with a kiss♫
♫Mischievous Kiss♫
♫Oh Kiss♫
Mischievous Kiss 2 ~Love in TOKYO~
Thank you for doing this for me today.
I'm so happy nobody has changed.
Let's toast for Rika-chan who came back safely
and stays here as a part of our family for a while.
Cheers!
Thank you.- Yes, welcome back.
Cheers! Thank you.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you, Kotoko-san.
Nice to meet you.
So you go to school from tomorrow, right?
Yes, I'm going to Sumiregaoka Gakuin.(gakuin: school)
Sumiregaoka Gakuin?
The one that's very famous and for the intelligent...?
Yeah, well because it's kind of in my neighbourhood.
It's not the kind of school that you can enter...
just because it's in you neighbourhood right...
I heard you scored full marks for the transfer admission test.
Full marks?!
Kotoko, you should learn from Rika.
Ah, but Kotoko-san is more amazing, don't you think?
Which part of Kotoko? Better than you?
Well, I think capturing Naoki's heart is a hundred times harder than getting full marks on a test.
Now that you mention it, that seems true!
Oniichan is stubborn.
We were so surprised to learn Naoki got married.
Kotoko-san is great to win the heart of Naoki who's been known as woman hater.
I did try my best.
But you approached him, right?
Yes.
I thought so. Otherwise...
Bummer. I should've claimed him before going to America.
I know she is his cousin, but she is getting too clingy.
Rika-chan!
Enough with touching Naoki!
Why don't you eat my special lasagna?
Wow, it looks delicous!
I missed your cooking so much!
Here you go.
Subtitles and timing by the Mischievous Kisser Team @vik.com
Isn't that...
a serious crisis?
I thought so.
She's a lively high schooler.
Face, style and brain. They're all perfect, right?
-Yes.- And...
They're cousins who grew up together.
She has a past with Irie-san that you don't know anything about.
They hugged each other suddenly...
"Naoki~!"
She called his name so casually.
She's not bad. Such an admirable enemy.
What do you mean an enemy?
She is, isn't she?
To you,
and to me, too.
But there is no way that she would have feelings for Irie-kun.
Yeah. Probably.
It's obvious! What are you saying?
Hey, we're talking about Irie-san here!
-Are you sure?- I am absolutely sure.
This cream parfait is delicious.
She really is cheerful and seems like a good girl, doesn't she?
It's just, I feel a bit left out.
Like I'm being alienated.
I see.
You're biggest problem this time...
is his family.
What?
Up until now they were always on your side,
but now they're all on her side.
Don't exaggerate.
You're too soft.
This is no time to be talking so complacently!
While everyone is making such a fuss of her,
Irie-san...
may be taken from you before you know it.
N-No way.
You will be completely forgotten.
Moto-chan!
Thanks for the dessert.
What?
Kotoko-san.
Rika-chan.
So many guys have been trying to pick me up until now.
Pick you up?
Guys here are so immature.
Is that okay?
The guys in my class aren't great either. Not one of them is good-looking.
I grew up with Naoki, so no one else measures up.
I have high standards.
Poor things. Being compared to Irie-kun.
Hey, Kotoko-san...
Naoki...
Could you give him to me?
What?
It's fine, right?
Give him to me.
R-Rika-chan...that's...
Just look at your face! I'm kidding.
Kidding. Just kidding.
Maybe I should just let it go...
Who is it? Mother might be doing laundry?
Kotoko-san.
Rika-chan! What is it?
Let's take a bathe together!
Rika-chan..that's a little...
We're both girls, so it's fine!
That's a bit...
She has a great figure.
Hey, Kotoko-san...
you're the one who proposed, aren't you?
Of course not.
Really?
I always seem to end up following Rika-chan's pace.
No, no, no! Don't get caught up!
I have to be confident! confident!
She's just a high school girl.
And I am Irie-kun's wife!
Can I ask one more question?
What is it?
Is Naoki good at kissing?
What?!
Well...
I don't know...
I've really only kissed Irie-kun, so...
Really?
Then you wouldn't really know.
I had lots of boyfriends while I was in the US,
so I kissed quite a bit.
No.
I feel dizzy now.
I think I'm done for now.
But,
the best kisser so far
is Naoki.
Naoki's really good...
at kissing.
What did she say?
I'm jealous. You can kiss Naoki whenever.
I really want to kiss him one more time.
But I don't think it was that kind of kiss.
Like the kind of kiss you give your childhood friend on their cheek.
I was in 5th grade and Naoki was a junior in high school.
It was on the lips, of course.
What?!
I think it was both of our first kisses.
This can't be true!!!
Kotoko-san?!
Irie-kun's first kiss...
wasn't with me but with Rika?
Kotoko-san!
Somebody...tell me it's a lie...
Irie-kun...Irie-kun...
Irie...
Kotoko-san, I started dating Naoki.
What?
What are you saying?! Irie-kun's married to me!
No matter how you look at it, I and Naoki look better.
And I kissed Naoki first.
-Right, Naoki?-Yeah.
That's right.
Naoki and I, we were both our first kiss.
Hey, Naoki.
Let's kiss in front of her.
Sure.
Stop it!
What? It was a dream?
I slept in!
Oh, good morning, Kotoko-san.
Are you alright?
You fainted last night. You could have slept some more.
Oh, I borrowed your apron.
Naoki, you like omelet. Do you want some?
-Yes.- Me too.
-Okay, leave it to me -Rika-chan, it's okay! I will do it!
But I am better at making this.
You don't know until you do it, right?
It's okay. You can rest, Kotoko-san.
What's up, you two?
I said I will do it!
You want to know about Rika?- You would know, right?
Yeah. We were close since we were young.
So we three were like siblings.
Does Rika-chan like...
Irie-kun?
Not sure.
But I really like Rika.
When I told her I wanted her to stay here forever and made a scene,
Rika said this to me before;
If she gets married to my brother, then she will become my real sister.
Marriage?
Yeah. I wanted her to be my sister, so...
She asked for me to help to get her married to my brother.
And I promised her...
Kotoko-san, can you give Naoki to me?
She liked Irie-kun since she was young.
Is she serious about it?
Alright. This should do.
Wow, Kotoko-san. You're early.
You too.
What happened this morning?- You guys are getting along!
That's great!
Good morning.
Irie-kun!- Naoki!
Naoki! This is really good. Eat it.
Irie-kun! I made this myself. Have it.
I am not going to eat all that in the morning.
No way. Please~
So cruel. I made this for you.
Seriously. What should I have first?
Fish, fish. Here you go.
So bad.
Naoki, eat this too.
It's really good. - Really?
Kotoko-chan. Don't be discouraged!
Why?
Kotoko. Coffee.
I will bring you some.
It's okay.
I like her coffee.
I will bring it to you!
Kotoko-san.
Rika-chan, What's up? What about school?
I...
like Naoki.
I liked him from the start.
Give Naoki back.
What are you saying?
She is serious. She is serious about this.
If I didn't go to America,
Naoki wouldn't have married you.
How would you know that?
Naoki liked me!
We exchanged a kiss, too.
Naoki was holding me tight.
We were in a good mood.
That doesn't matter. I don't know how he felt at that time.
All I could do was watch him.
But Naoki slowly started looking at me,and asked me to marry him.
What do you mean he slowly started looking at you?
What is this?
Give that back! Give that back!
This thing.
Enough!
Rika!
Naoki!
Naoki, it hurts.
Rika, let me see your leg.
Irie-kun...- Enough!
What are you trying to do against a high school student?
You have been acting weird, recently.
Can you stand up? I will take you home.
Subtitles brought to you by The Mischievous Kisser Team @ Viki
That's not it...
Kotoko-chan!
So you're Kotoko-chan's friends.
Yes.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
She's been crying since the morning, saying she injured a kid named Rika so she can't go home.
We tried to comfort her and went out for a drink but...
Hey, hurry and get off, you're too heavy!
Really... What are you doing?
Irie-kun!
No, it's no problem.
Hey, let's go.
No!
You hate me, don't you?
Let me go!
But you, you like...
Rika-chan... Rika-chan... more than me!
Seriously.
Did kotoko-san fall asleep?
I don't want you to apologize.
Don't taunt her too much.
What? When did I?
Good night.
Hey, it's done!
Eat a lot!
Naoki, this looks good. Try it.
Thanks.
Is it good?
Yeah. It's good.
It's good when I eat here!
Irie-chan. You're eating too much!
It's okay.
Kotoko, bring some beer.
Yes.
I am coming too.
Kotoko-san.
When did you start liking Naoki?
It was first year in high school, so 8 years ago I guess.
That's pretty long, huh?
For me, I liked him when I was two, so it has been 15 years.
Rika-chan.
You told me to give Naoki back last time, right?
Hey, is beer ready ye...
This is dangerous.
I can never do that.
Never.
Okay.
But that's your opinion, right?
What?
I wonder what Naoki thinks.
If Naoki says he likes me,
you can give him to me, right?
Sure. You better ask him, then.
So...
You were listening, Naoki?
What?
Yeah, somewhat.
I have always liked you.
I don't understand how you like her!
I suit you better.
Then why? Why did you marry her?
Do you know how shocked I was when I heard it, while in America?
Then...
You shouldn't have gone to America!
Why did you stay away from the one you loved for so long then?
I had no choice!
I was only in primary school at that time, my parents...
That doesn't matter!
If I were you,
I wouldn't have gone to America.
For me,
I was okay with just looking at Irie-kun.
You might have loved him longer, but...
Then...
I don't know how Irie-kun feels though.
About that...
Then...
Kotoko-san!
That's why I fell in love with her.
She can't do anything right,
unlike you, but
I like that power of her.
You like her over me?
Yeah. Over you.
Okay.
If it were Kotoko-san,
she wouldn't have gone to America, I guess.
I guess so.
Why are you crying?
I chose you.
So be more confident.
Rika.
You betrayer.
Hm?
You betrayer!
Didn't you promise me?
That you would help me become your sister!
That you would help me get married to Naoki!
This is your fault!
You're such an idiot!
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
Sorry.
Rika.
Uncle, Aunt.
Come again.
Of course!
I will come with a boyfriend much cooler than Naoki next time and hang out.
Well, there is no one like that.
My, my. These two girls.
Rika.
See you. - Yeah.
That time?
The day I left for America.
When Naoki and I kissed for the first time.
Then do you want me to show you?
No!
This is what happened 7 years ago.
Sorry.
Dramatize?
But the the kiss doesn't change, right?
So that's how it was...
Here.
This is... for me?
I had no choice.
I will recognize you as Naoki's wife.
See you again.
Be careful.- Seeya.
See you!- Bye!
Rika-chan! See you again!
Bye, bye!
Seriously. She is such a noisy person.
Bye bye, Naoki.
In fact, I'm the one who really understands how Rika-chan feels.
Rika-chan, next time we meet, we must become closer alright?[Sorry about it--Rika]
#10 Naoki-san, please take good care of Kotoko
You like Yuki-kun right?
Those cold eyes!
I'll support you!
Next week is the death anniversary of Kotoko's mother, right?
-This year I'll go with you too.-What?!
It's...it's ok, you don't have to go out of your way to!
Is there something you're hiding from me?
You'll see when we arrive...
Thank you for your warm reception.
But...the character for 'ki' in Naoki has been spelt wrongly...