All because of us...
It doesn't even concern you.
It does concern me.
Don't say that it doesn't.
You should...
leave him.
You're jealous.
Jealous? Me?
You don't love me anymore, do you?
That's not it...
You never loved me!
- Calm down!
- No! Why...
Why...
Why did you marry me?
I'm the only one... that loves you.
I can't do this!
Kotoko!
Something I was always
too scared to ask him about.
But the question was always in my heart,
and I finally let it come out.
I put an end to it myself...
Are we... finished?
Another busy day.
Sorry, we're closed.
Kotoko?
- What's wrong, Kotoko?
- Kotoko!
Hey, hey...
Are you okay?
Have some tea, eh?
Are you fighting with Naoki again?
I told him he'd better not
make you cry anymore.
How pitiful.
You're going home with me.
No, I'm not!
Naoki will be worried.
He doesn't care
what I do or how I do it.
I don't know what happened,
but it's late.
Please!
Don't tell him I'm here.
I...
can't go home.
Kotoko! Come stay with me.
- Really?
- Yes, of course!
Or my apartment.
Stay as long as you like.
Kinnosuke!
Hello? Kotoko is here.
Don't worry. It'll be fine.
She's going to stay
with Chris tonight.
Give her time.
She'll calm down.
Sorry to worry you.
Thank you.
See you.
Subtitles provided by
SPO Entertainment
Episode 07
[A Vow with A Nurse Cap]
Aren't you eating?
Not right now...
Are you okay?
She had a fight with Mr. Irie,
ran away, and got smashed.
Poor Kotoko!
Girls with hangovers are so unseemly.
Here!
Keita.
This works the quickest.
Drink it.
Thanks.
Hey, Chris!
I can't see!
What are you doing?
It's him! Him!
You're so sweet to Kotoko.
It's bitter!
Did you really run away?
Huh?
We can hear everything in here.
Lecture her for me, will you?
You fought with Irie, right?
Want to stay with me?
Huh?
It's a small apartment.
Wait a minute.
Are you kidding?
I told you I was serious.
I love you.
That idiot! What is he...
Where are you going?
Kinnosuke!
I can't keep my mind off of you.
But... I'm Naoki's...
So leave him!
Has he come running after you?
He's not even jealous.
What has he done for you?
That's not a marriage.
Married couples need each other!
You need me.
Wrong.
Totally wrong.
Naoki...
You're too late.
You only made Kotoko suffer.
You can't make her happy.
You had no right to marry her!
What's going on?
Kamogari and Kotoko?
An affair?
That may have been true.
Not "may have been"...
It was true!
I was jealous.
I was jealous of you.
Huh?
I've never been jealous or envious...
I've never been dejected or
experienced any of those
disgraceful, messy
human emotions before.
But...
that all changed when
Kotoko came into my life.
All those hidden emotions
made me lose control.
I didn't know how to handle it.
They bewildered and irritated me.
So what?
Kamogari, you have
more than your share
of messy, disgraceful emotions.
What? Are you picking a fight?
I was paying you a compliment.
I don't envy you, though.
That's why you don't need Kotoko.
She's for me. I need her.
What?
I can only be my true self
when I'm with Kotoko.
Really? Naoki.
Yes.
I didn't even realize it until...
Kinnosuke told me.
Kin-chan?
He came running over to get me.
I can't believe...
he felt this way for 6 years.
He's amazing.
I'm just a better human being.
Naoki...
Is it...
Is it really okay for me to stay?
I just told you so.
I'll never...
leave you until the day I die!
I'm counting on it.
- Congrats!
- How romantic!
Oops... we're in the cafeteria!
I guess I lack modesty, too.
You...
How sweet.
What, Motoki!
What have you done?
You just strengthened
their marital bond.
Just for now...
You...
love rescuing people in need.
That's what it was.
You wanted to rescue Kotoko...
Right, Keita?
That's one way to look at it.
There will be plenty of patients
for you to rescue.
Don't focus on just one.
I'm not giving up on
Mr. Irie, though.
We're home!
You're home, Kotoko!
Oh... my!
What happened?
You made up?
Sorry to worry you, Mother.
But we made up.
Oh...
I'm so glad.
Stop hanging on me.
Come on.
So what happened?
In front of everyone... Naoki...
professed his love for me!
Naoki! You come through
when it counts!
You! You! You!
You did?!
"I can only be my true self
when I'm with Kotoko."
- Yes!
- Hey!
What a great line!
He loves you so much!
Now that you made up,
you'll be a real husband and wife!
Thank you, Kotoko.
Huh?
Naoki has matured so much
since he's been with you.
He understands how other
people feel.
I think your love melted
his cold, icy heart.
My love? Well...
Don't ever give up on him.
No. Of course not.
We have to celebrate
your getting back together.
Let's! What should we do?
- Shall we bake a cake?
- Yes! I'll help you.
Ms. Irie.
You failed the injection,
vital sign checks
and wheelchair exercises.
It's not looking very good.
Training at the hospital
begins next month.
Yes...
I'll retest you tomorrow.
If you don't pass,
you'll have to repeat a year.
Okay?
Oh, no!
[The Next Day]
Kokoto!
What are you doing here?
Oh... Keita.
I'm being retested today...
A spot check on everything
we've learned.
I've been practicing since 6 am,
but I still can't do it.
You wasted so many syringes.
I can't do anything right.
No even an injection...
I don't even know if
I can become a nurse.
And...
This is no time for blubbering.
Huh?
Here. Use my arm.
It's easy, once you get the
hang of it.
Don't worry about messing up.
Just go for it.
Really?
Yeah.
Okay...
Here I go.
Hey!
Use the rubber arm!
Sorry...
I'll get it this time.
Look at the needle.
Yes.
Kotoko, relax!
You're always telling me that.
Your anxiety will only make
the patient nervous.
Relax!
Okay, one more time!
Okay.
I did it! I did it!
You did it, Kotoko!
I finally did it! Thanks, Keita!
And while we're at it...
can I ask you one more favor?
Huh?
Kotoko, you're too tense.
Okay...
Take your time.
Yes.
Hey! Focus!
Don't panic.
- Gentle and slow.
- Okay.
You got it...
I did it! Yes!
Congratulations.
It's all thanks to you.
I'll never forget this feeling!
Why do you want to become a nurse?
You know...
was it a childhood dream?
Do you want to help the sick?
Well...
I...
want to help Naoki because
he's going to be a doctor.
Is that all?
No...
I'm a klutz and I'm not
good at anything.
I'm a burden to you all.
But if I could be of help
to someone
like provide moral support
to a patient feeling scared...
But, Naoki still comes first.
You're incredible.
I guess you're happy with him.
Yes.
Good luck on your test.
Thanks... Keita.
Hey!
What are you doing here so early?
I was being a pin cushion
for your wife.
She's being retested today.
Well, thanks for your help.
You're something else.
I decided not to pursue
Kotoko anymore.
No matter how terrible
a husband you are.
As long as Kotoko is happy...
I'll keep my mouth shut.
So you accepted the fact
that you can't compete
with her strong feelings for me.
Too bad it took you so long.
Is this how you treat a guy
who just conceded?
You conceited jerk!
Take care of her.
What's this?
A special omelet. I told
Kin-chan I passed the test.
Now we can all train together!
Yes!
But before that...
It's almost here.
What is?
The capping ceremony, of course.
What's a capping ceremony?
What?
You've never hear of
the capping ceremony?
I transferred mid-term.
So what?
A capping ceremony is...
the first step in becoming
a real nurse.
Like a coming-of-age ceremony
for nurses.
I see.
We get "capped" by the head nurse.
Holding candles! How romantic.
I've dreamt of this day for
so long...
My own nurse's cap...
My first step towards
becoming a "nightingale".
It's not an exaggeration...
to say I chose this path just
for this auspicious event!
Is it that great?
And there's something else.
What?
A guy from the medical school
presents you with flowers!
- Flowers?
- Yes!
It's a tradition unique
to Tonan University.
When we finish the ceremony,
a med student is waiting for you
with a bouquet of flowers!
A once in a lifetime event.
Everyone is...
desperately looking for someone
to give them a bouquet.
I'm so lucky!
Kotoko!
Congratulations.
The cap looks good on you.
I love you.
Naoki...
Just imagining it--
it's too wonderful to be true!
I'm getting a bouquet from Naoki.
It's no use.
She's in dreamland.
Who should I ask?
What about Mr. Funatsu?
He'd be happy to.
Are you kidding me?
I haven't seen Mr. Funatsu lately.
The parasite museum
was closed yesterday...
Speak of the devil...
Mr. Irie?
Are you listening? Mr. Irie?
You complain too much.
Mr. Irie!
Naoki!
I don't feel well.
Naoki! Where's Mr. Funatsu?
He's not feeling well.
He's lying.
What?
You were number one again,
weren't you?
Yeah.
You said you bombed the test,
but you still...
My husband is amazing.
What are you doing?
I knew it...
Mr. Funatsu...
He talked all big, but he's
still number two.
That's why he can't face me.
What a coward!
Is he a man or what?
Naoki, I have a favor to ask...
The capping ceremony is coming up.
There's a tradition of
giving flowers to the nurses...
I'm so happy... Oh!
I'll appreciate anything,
but I prefer roses...
- I can't.
- Huh?
I'll be at a conference in Nagoya
with my professor.
What?!
But... but!
We'll probably stay overnight.
In any case
I have no interest in participating
in such an embarrassing tradition.
It's ridiculous.
See you.
So mean!
Mr. Irie was so popular last year...
so many of the nurses asked him,
but he rejected them all, so...
So?
Everyone, the capping ceremony
is just around the corner.
Today, I've asked the head nurse
of Tonan University Hospital
to say a few words.
I'm Nurse Hosoi.
Nice to meet you.
What presence!
She's famous for her "big presence".
She's also known for picking on
nurses she doesn't like.
I hope I'm never on her black list.
I heard there's a Mrs. Irie
in this class.
Yes. I'm Kotoko Irie.
You're Mrs. Irie?
Your husband is an intern
at our hospital.
He's so capable!
He's the talk of the ward.
I expect you to be just
as capable.
Well... I...
Yes, she is.
Oh, how promising!
Let's get down to business.
At the upcoming ceremony
I'd like 4 of you to recite
the "Nightingale Pledge."
Me! Me! Me!
Yes?
My name is Motoki Kikyo.
May I volunteer?
Are you a man?
You cannot!
Why? Nurse Hosoi!
At Tonan, the Nightingale Pledge
has always been recited
by female students.
Unfortunately, I have no use for you.
Furthermore, male students
don't get capped.
They get a badge.
My... dream...
I lived for this day...
I choose Miss Ogura.
Yes.
- Miss Mori.
- Yes.
- Miss Shinagawa.
And lastly, Mrs. Kotoko Irie.
Huh?
I'm counting on you.
Moto-chan, slow down!
Why do you two get to recite
the Nightingale Pledge?
You asked us that already!
I don't even want to do it.
Me neither.
It's your fault.
You told her I was capable.
Now I have to recite
the last and longest part!
I don't even get a nurse's cap.
My phone.
Hello?
"I will hold in confidence..
all personal matters
committed to my keeping...
and all family affairs
coming to my knowledge...
in the practice of my calling."
Wow, Moto-chan!
You're really bad
at remembering things.
But you'd better memorize this!
You have to make me proud.
And don't embarrass your husband.
I know but, there's a lot of pressure.
"I will endeavor to aid the physician...
and devote myself to the welfare
of those committed to my care."
Moto-chan!
What?
I have a great idea!
At the capping ceremony...
What?
One week later, the day of
the capping ceremony finally arrived.
And now...
the Tonan University Nursing School
Capping Ceremony will begin.
Marina Shinagawa.
Yes.
Good luck.
Tomoko Ogura.
Yes.
Hey. Where's Motoki?
Keita Kamogari.
Yes.
Kotoko Irie.
Good luck.
Naoki...
I'm one step closer to you now.
I wish you could see me
in my nurse's cap.
Motoki Kikyo.
Yes.
Huh?
Motoki!
W-wha...
What is this?
Go change immediately! You'll
desecrate the capping ceremony!
Nurse Hosoi! Please don't!
Moto-chan worked so hard for this!
Men and women care equally
for their patients. Please!
Kotoko...
Please let him do this!
We beg of you!
I don't want a nurse's cap...
but please let Motoki wear one.
- I agree.
- We all do!
Fine.
You win. I'll make an exception
and give Mr. Kikyo a nurse's cap.
Really?
Congrats, Moto-chan!
Thank you, Kotoko!
You did it.
Thank you everyone!
I love you!
Good luck.
Thank you, Nurse Hosoi.
An exception was made
and Moto-chan got a nurse's cap.
"I solemnly pledge myself before God
and in the presence of this assembly.
To pass my life in purity and
to practice my profession faithfully. "
"I will abstain from whatever is
deleterious and mischievous
and will not take or
knowingly administer
any harmful drug.
I will do all in my power
to maintain and elevate
the standard of my profession and..."
"will hold in confidence all personal
matters committed to my keeping
and all family affairs coming
to my knowledge
in the practice of my calling."
"With loyalty I will...
Naoki.
endeavor to aid
the physician in his work...
Can you hear me?
...and devote myself to the welfare
of those committed to my care."
I'll do my best to help you.
Naoki's not coming home
tonight anyway.
Maybe I'll just sit here
a while longer.
Nursing is demanding. Academically,
emotionally and physically.
But I think I can do it.
When I feel discouraged,
I'll look back on this day...
Who is it? A ghost?
Idiot.
Naoki?!
What are you still doing here?
What about your duty in Nagoya?
Huh?
I took the Shinkansen train back.
You came back for me?
I didn't make it in time, though.
The florist was closed.
I don't care.
I don't need flowers.
You came...
Say it.
The part you recited.
Okay.
"With loyalty...
I will endeavor to aid
the physician in his work...
and devote myself to the welfare...
of those committed...
to my care."
Again.
"I will endeavor to aid the physician...
and devote myself...
to the welfare...
of those...
committed...
to my care."
Miss Nightingale.
No matter what hardships await me
I will never forget this day.
Subtitles provided by
SPO Entertainment
We start training at
the hospital next week.
I'm so nervous...
I'm sure she's a really sweet old lady!
You two may get along well.
I can't be remembering trainee's names.
She called me 8 times
this morning alone!
She's a bully!
I'm losing confidence.
Are you going to quit?
My chest... my chest hurts.
What's wrong, grandma Toyo?
So you accepted the fact...
Hey!
What are you doing here so early?
I was being a pin cushion
for your wife.
She's being retested today.
Well, thanks for your help.
You're something else.
I decided not to pursue
Kotoko anymore.
No matter how terrible
a husband you are.
As long as Kotoko is happy...
I'll keep my mouth shut.