-SupunWe- | supun@zoom.lk | supunwee@facebook.com
I think it's safe to say the maze trials
were a complete success.
It's to soon to say,
but they could be the key to everything.
It's time now to begin phase two.
Welcome to the Scorch!
The world outside is hanging on
by a very thin thread.
Beyond this door
lies the beginning
of your new lives.
- Hey, Thomas!
- We weren't he only maze.
What do you remember about Wicked?
I remember they sent me to the maze.
I remember watching my friends die
in front of me.
- Don't you want to understand?
- Understand what?
Why this all happened?
I just need to know,
whose side are you on?
- They're hiding something.
- Come on, you don't know that!
They lied to us.
We never escaped.
It's all just been part of their plan.
What do they want from us?
Thomas!
The maze is one thing.
But you kids won't last one day
out in the Scorch.
What the hell?
The course of your lives
will determine the course of humanity.
Into light,
or darkness.
-SupunWe- | supun@zoom.lk | supunwee@facebook.com