( orchestral music playing )
At rare intervals
there appears among us
A person whose virtues
Are so manifest to all,
Who has such a capacity
For relating to every sort
of human being,
Who so subordinates
his own ego drives
To the concerns of others,
Who lives his whole life
in such Harmony
With the prevailing
standards of the community
That he is revered and loved
By everyone with whom
he comes in contact.
Such a man
Dalton Trumbo was not.
( crowd chuckles )
During the second world war
277 members of the guild
entered the armed services
To fight what was then called
The war against fascism.
Five of them did not come back.
Within six years
43 of those who did return
Were denounced
as un-American,
Stripped of their
names and passports
And blacklisted.
I presume that over half
of our members
Have no memory
of that blacklist
Because they were children
when it began
Or not yet born.
To them I would say only this:
That the blacklist
Was a time of evil
And that no one
on either side who survived it
Came through untouched by evil.
Caught in the situation
that had passed
Beyond the control
of mere individuals,
Each person reacted
as his nature,
His needs, his convictions
And his
particular circumstances
Compelled him to.
There was bad Faith and good,
Honesty and dishonesty
Courage and cowardice,
Selflessness and opportunism,
Wisdom and stupidity,
good and bad
On both sides.
And almost every
individual involved,
No matter where he stood,
Combined some or all
Of these antithetical qualities
In his own person,
in his own acts.
Interviewer:
Dalton Trumbo... he's a very
distinguished film writer.
He's won academy awards.
He's a letter writer too.
And they're obstreperous.
They're funny.
- They're eloquent.
- Trumbo: Well, I suppose so.
Interviewer:
And so these letters
that you wrote
Dealing with yourself,
your independence,
your stubbornness...
Trumbo:
Words are lost on the air...
the spoken word.
You never know
really what you said
in the last conversation,
Whereas if you sit down
and write
A concise definition
of your problem,
It commands
the man's attention.
Interviewer:
So your letters
to all variety of people,
Friends and enemies
In 1942 to 1962,
You almost tell us
the story of our country
Through the eyes
of this very stubborn man
Dalton Trumbo.
Trumbo:
It was very lively
two decades...
Very lively.
One was rarely bored.
Interviewer:
All your warts
are here too,
'cause you're pretty...
you're rough, you know,
at times.
"warty warty"...
I prefer the word
"abrasive."
- Abrasive.
- But "warty"
is just as good.
Helen Manfull:
I discovered
the correspondence
As a processor
At the Wisconsin center
for theater research.
And they were collecting
the materials
Of the Hollywood 10.
One of the collections
that I got to process
Was the collection
of Dalton Trumbo...
Box upon box upon box.
It's the story
of an absolutely devoted
And passionate family man,
Trumbo's love of his wife Cleo,
Of their three children.
It's the story of the blacklist
And what it did to people.
It also made me aware
Of what it means
To be true to your principles
And to be willing
to stand up for what
you believe
No matter what
the consequences are.
Trumbo's this person
With an unbelievably strong
sense of Justice, you know,
And what's right.
And the letters for him
Are his, as it were, forum
To express that.
He was so opinionated
and so passionate
And so inventive
and sharp and funny
That you just didn't
win an argument with him.
He would be one of our heroes
Because he was an iconoclast.
He just plain was
a little grandiose, I think.
He wasn't confrontational
in the sense
He went out
looking for trouble.
It seemed to come to him.
Dalton was a contrarian,
you know.
He had fights.
I'm just glad he never
had a fight with me.
Trumbo:
I think of myself
as an extremely peaceable man.
God knows I never wanted
to fight in my life,
But sometimes I think
they're forced upon
a peaceful man.
My father
always had an ambition
to become a writer.
And once he gets started,
Publishing his first book
In 1933 or 1934,
By 1940 he's published
three novels,
Won a national book award
And written
about 20 screenplays.
And he's been nominated
for an Oscar also.
So he has, you know,
sort of a brilliant
Seven-years beginning.
Up to about 1945
He was the highest-paid
screenwriter in Hollywood.
He had a contract
without a morality clause.
He was very very successful.
Everybody wanted
To use the name
of Dalton Trumbo.
He probably was the best writer
At that time.
And then it all fell apart.
Newsreel announcer:
In Washington, the committee
on un-American activities
Opens new hearings
in a jam-packed caucus room.
Here charges of red influence
Directed against
the motion picture industry
are aired.
This committee
under its mandate
From the house
of representatives
Has the responsibility
of exposing
And spotlighting
subversive elements
Wherever they may exist.
McCarthy was seeing communists
In congress,
In the white house,
in the army,
And especially in
the movie industry,
And especially
with the writers.
Man:
What about Mr. Dalton Trumbo?
Do you know Mr. Dalton Trumbo?
Yes, I know
Mr. Trumbo.
Mr. Trumbo was the editor
of the official
- Publication of the guild,
was he not?
- Yes, that's true.
Yes, at one time
Dalton Trumbo was editor
of "the screenwriter,"
The monthly publication of
the screenwriters' guild.
Do you think
that Dalton Trumbo
was a communist?
Well, certainly I have
no information on that
Beyond what I've heard
here this week.
People joined
the communist party
because it was doing something.
It was an effective instrument.
It was doing things
That they felt should be done.
It was opposing
the rise of fascism
All through Europe.
It was helping those
who were refugees.
I remember as a kid
The conversations would be
about the soviet union.
This was the depression.
The country was
in a depression.
Socialism, communism
seemed like somewhat
of a solution
To everybody being out of work.
Russia had been our allies
through the early 1940s.
And then all of a sudden
they became our enemy.
It is my duty
to place before you
Certain facts
About the present
position in Europe.
An iron curtain has
descended across the continent.
Newsreel announcer:
A growing struggle
between two great powers
To shape the postwar world.
On orders from the Kremlin
Russia had launched
one of history's
Most drastic political,
moral and economic wars...
A cold war.
Trumbo:
We were ready for war
And felt it was coming.
And people didn't want it,
But they were frightened.
And with the public
that frightened
One can understand
How things like this
could happen.
If you want to scare a country,
You go after its royalty.
And Hollywood was our royalty.
And they had two rounds
of witnesses.
And the first round were mostly
Either friendly witnesses
or executives.
The committee wanted
to bask in the publicity glow
And fame of the stars
and of Hollywood.
This is a foul philosophy...
this communistic thing.
I would move
to the state of Texas
if it ever came here
Because I think that Texans
would kill them on sight.
( crowd laughs )
If I had my way about it
they'd all be sent back
To Russia or some other
unpleasant place.
( applause, gavel pounds )
I don't believe
it's a political party.
I believe
it's an un-American thing.
And I feel that they really
ought to be smoked out
And shown up for what they are
So that all the good
free causes in this country,
All the liberalisms
that really are American
Can go out without
the stain of communism.
And then they called...
I believe it was 19 people.
And eventually
It boiled down
to the Hollywood 10.
Trumbo:
Well, we were called
originally
"the unfriendly 10."
And I like that much better.
Interviewer:
Unfriendly to what?
Trumbo:
To that committee
and to anybody else
Who interfered...
Who tried to force
a compulsory confession
Of beliefs, Faith,
anything else.
An official purpose of theirs
Was to discover
communist propaganda
In the films that
these folks had written.
It's a fallacy to think
that they got
Overtly leftist themes
into films,
But as many scholars before me
Have noted quite elegantly,
What they did is
They were able to shift subtly
Some of the archetypes
That were really important
in American films
of that era.
You wrote from a particular
point of view, you know.
The irony to me
Of all these
radical communist writers,
You know, was that
what they were trying
to do really
Was to be good liberals.
What is democracy?
Well, I was never
very clear on it myself.
Like every other
kind of government,
It's got something to do
With young men killing
each other, I believe.
Why don't old men
kill each other?
Well, the old men
are needed to keep
the home fires burning.
Couldn't the young men
do that just as well?
Young men don't have homes.
That's why they must go out
and kill each other.
When it comes my turn,
Will you want me to go?
For democracy
Any man would give
his only begotten son.
That was it.
He understood it now.
He had told them his secret.
And in denying him
They had told him theirs.
He was the future.
He was a perfect picture
of the future.
And they were afraid
to let anyone see what
the future was like.
Already they were looking ahead.
They were figuring the future.
And somewhere in the future
they saw war.
To fight that war
they would need men
And if men saw the future
they wouldn't fight.
So they were masking
the future.
They were keeping the future
a soft quiet deadly secret.
They knew if all the people
all the little guys,
saw the future,
They would begin
to ask questions.
They would ask questions
and they would find answers
And they would say to the guys
who wanted them to fight
They would say,
"you lying thieving
sons-of-bitches,
We won't fight.
We won't be dead.
We will live.
We are the world.
We are the future.
And we won't
let you butcher us
no matter what you say,
No matter what speeches
you make,
No matter what slogans
you write.
Remember it well,
we we we are the world.
We are what makes it go round.
We make bread
and cloth and guns.
We are the hub of the wheel
and the spokes and
the wheel itself.
And without us you would be
hungry naked worms.
And we will not die.
It will not be us who die.
It will be you.
It will be you...
You who urge us on to battle,
You who incite us
against ourselves,
You who would
have one cobbler
kill another cobbler,
You who would have
one man who works
Kill another man who works,
You who would
have one human being
who wants only to live
Kill another human being
who wants only to live.
If you tell us
to make the world
safe for democracy
We will take you seriously
And by God
and by Christ
we will make it so.
Make no mistake of it
we will live.
We will be alive
And we will walk and talk
and eat and sing
And laugh and feel and love
And bear our children
In tranquility, in security,
In decency,
in peace."
Very much what my father
took to be his politics
Was the constitution
of the United States
And the first 10 amendments.
That for him outlined
A reasonable way
That human beings could live
Within a society,
That it guaranteed
the individual specific rights
And that it limited
the rights of the state,
It limited the influence
of religion.
And that very much
was his idea about
what the west was.
It was an open place.
The ranch was fairly isolated.
There would be days on end
Where you do not see
any kind of automobile.
So the sighting
of an automobile
Is really exciting
for my older sister and me.
It doesn't mean
that the car is
coming to us,
But there's a possibility.
And this one did.
And so we went out
and we opened up
A rather large, heavy gate
And brought the man
into the house.
And he was the process server.
So that's how my father
received his subpoena...
With the help of his children.
The man knocked on the door
And you got that pink slip.
The first thing
you did was go out
And try to sell your house
before anybody discovers,
So you could at least
get a fair price for it,
Or as fair as possible.
Don't let anybody know.
Keep it quiet.
Get as much work as you can in
Before it becomes public.
Save every penny you have.
Sell what assets you have.
And get ready
To become nobody.
Man: Do you solemnly swear
that the testimony you're
about to give
Is the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth,
- So help you God?
- I do.
Sit down.
Could you state your full name?
Dalton Trumbo.
When and where
were you born, Mr. Trumbo?
I was born
in Montrose, Colorado,
On December 9th, 1905.
What is your occupation?
My occupation is
that of a writer.
I have some other questions,
Mr. Trumbo,
I'd like to ask you.
Are you now or have you
ever been a member of
the communist party?
Mr. Stripling, you must
have some reason
For asking me this question.
You can address the committee.
You do.
I understand
That members of the press
Have been given an alleged
communist party card
Belonging to me.
Is that true?
No, that's not true.
- You're not asking
the questions.
- I was.
- The chief investigator
is asking the questions.
- I beg your pardon.
Now are you or have you
ever been a member...?
A number of Hollywood
personalities
Took the first amendment...
Not the fifth amendment
against self-incrimination,
But the first amendment
To refuse to answer
their questions
About their political
backgrounds.
Well, Mr. Stripling,
I think that there's
A question of
constitutional rights
involved here.
I don't believe
that you have...
When did you learn
about the constitution?
Now just tell me
when you learned
about the constitution.
Stripling:
Mr. Scott, could you
tell the committee
Whether or not
you are now or have ever been
A member
of the communist party?
I believe that question
also invades my right
as a citizen.
I believe it also invades
the first amendment.
I believe that I should not
engage in any conspiracy
With you to invade
the first amendment.
Man:
Well, now we can tell
even from that answer
- Whether you're a member
of the communist party.
- ( Laughter )
Victor Navasky:
If you take the fifth
amendment
You're talking about
your right not to be
incriminated.
Well, they didn't feel
they had committed
any crime.
Well, they believed
that their freedom of speech
Was being abridged.
I believe I have the right
to be confronted
With any evidence
which supports
this question.
I should like to see
what you have.
- Man: Well, you would?
- Yes.
- ( laughter )
- Well, you will
pretty soon.
The witness is excused.
Typical communist tactics.
"dear Sam, it's 4:00 am.
And I've been working
since 10:00 last night...
Back at last
to the hours I love.
And all night
it's been snowing.
I just flash the spots on
And the sight is
wonderfully soothing
and beautiful.
No corners
anywhere in the world,
Everything round
and smooth and immaculate.
The kids and Cleo are asleep.
The house is in order.
The machines all
function smoothly.
The larder is full.
And I feel,
For the moment at least,
That I am the luckiest
and most contented man
in the world.
If you were here
we would break a bottle
And light the fire
and watch the falling snow.
And I would tell you
all about it.
That being impossible,
I shall write.
First I shall
tell you something
Which would embarrass
us both greatly
If I were to speak it.
Separated from people
as I have been,
I have had a great deal of time
To observe the reactions
to the present troubled times
And I have seen many
betray themselves.
I have seen many fail
at any decent test
of conduct,
Some of them my friends.
And I have shucked them off
With as little feeling
as I would toss away
a nail paring
And have experienced
no sense of loss
in the process.
But through this whole
interesting experience
My respect for you has deepened
And my affection
has grown more profound,
Not only for the money
you lent me,
Although that was
a life-saver
And a great
demonstration of Faith,
But for your attitude toward me
And other persons
and toward life itself,
For your willingness
To Grant me
any belief I cherish
So long as it is not
harmful to others,
Even when you disagree with it,
And for your personal
sense of outrage
When that right is denied.
This and this alone
Makes decent men
and decent society
And is rare
And is why I feel warm
in the knowledge
That we are friends.
Perhaps I should not be
as angry as I am
Against the weaklings,
Cravens and liars
who have succeeded
In banning me
from motion pictures,
For I feel the sense of relief
And a sense of buoyancy
At no longer being an employee.
I'm sure I should never
have had the courage
Or perhaps one should say
the foolhardiness
To have left it voluntarily.
My feeling now,
as of today that is
With the hope
of succeeding elsewhere,
Is still strong in me
that I shall never
return to films,
That if metro
asked me back tomorrow
With all forgiven,
I should refuse.
Hunger, of course,
could in time alter
that decision,
But for the present it stands.
Well, now enough.
I hope all things
go well with you.
Cleo and I send you our best.
And the children
have just risen.
They've started shouting
through the house
At the discovery of the snow.
Oh, say hello to my friends
And piss on my enemies."
I've learned that
total adjustment to society
Is quite as bad
as total maladjustment,
That principled disobedience
of unjust law
Is more Christian,
more truly law-abiding
Than unprincipled respect,
That only freedom can tame
The wild, rebellious,
Palpitating heart of man.
Encagement... never.
- ( air raid sirens blaring )
- Trumbo: Wherever there's
fear, there's hysteria.
And wherever there are people
who whip up fear
For their own purposes,
They will produce the hysteria.
And they will try
to do it again.
The fact that he followed
The usual communist line
Of not responding
to questions of the committee
Is definite proof
that he's a member
of the communist party.
Therefore, by a unanimous vote
The subcommittee recommends
to the full committee
That Dalton Trumbo be cited
For contempt of congress.
The committee recommends
That appropriate action
be taken
By the full committee
without delay.
Navasky:
After the hearings
There was this meeting
at the Waldorf.
They united on a policy
Which basically was,
"we don't believe
in a blacklist,
But we're not going to
employ anyone
Who has been involved
in any way, shape or form
With the communist party.
Eric Johnston:
We will forthwith discharge
Or suspend without compensation
Those in our employ
And we will not reemploy
any of the 10
Until such time
as he is acquitted
Or has purged himself
of contempt
And declares under oath
That he is not a communist.
You have the scapegoat.
You have the communists.
There were about 80,000
communists in the country
At the peak
of the party's success.
You know, they weren't
as dangerous as the elks
And didn't have nearly
as many guns.
Christopher Trumbo:
After the Waldorf agreement
is signed
By the various producers
and studios
And the blacklist
is established,
My father's position became
That he would have
to accept the idea
That the blacklist existed
And operate under
those conditions,
Which meant finding work
in another way.
They lost their jobs.
They were personae non grata
in Hollywood.
And they began writing
under assumed names.
And it was really,
you know, contrary
To what this country
is all about.
I have the feeling
That if you give
Most people
In the world
A choice between
enough food for
their children
And shelter
And clothing
In return for their
freedom of speech,
That they will go
For the food, the shelter
And the necessities.
And freedom of speech
Becomes a luxury
For which few fight
at the most.
"dear guy,
I have had several days
to ponder our discussion
Of the Saturday
before Christmas.
Though I have not yet
had the opportunity
To talk it over
with the others,
I have had second thoughts
of my own
And a strong impression
I didn't make myself clear
As to my real opinions.
That day a prominent
and liberal producer
Whose motives
I do not at all doubt
Was quoted as saying
to one of us:
'look, you people
are simply stubborn
and foolish.
The committee
and its requirements
Are a part of our time;
They are the law;
They are the country;
They are the flag.
That's the way it is,
And those who refuse
to recognize this
No longer arouse sympathy;
They only isolate themselves
And prevent their voices
from being heard.'
I know and can read
the first amendment
As well as anyone else.
I know it is
the basic law of this country.
I know that if it goes,
All will go.
Thus, the court has
presented us with a dilemma
That lies at the heart
of all philosophies
and religions,
The dilemma best symbolized
In the Faustian legend:
Yield up your principles
and you shall be rich;
Cling to them and you shall be
Less prosperous
than you presently are.
That's the problem:
Choice.
Not compulsion: Choice.
Committee or no committee,
law or no law,
Capitalism or no capitalism,
movies or no movies,
It is the constant
necessity to choose
That dogs every action
of our lives,
Every minute of our existences.
Who is it then
Who compels us to inform?
Who is it that denies us work
Until we seek out the committee
and abase ourselves before it?
Since it is neither the court
Nor the law nor the committee,
The man who compels informing
Can only be
the employer himself.
He is the one
who urges us to inform,
And he is the one
who withholds work from us
until we do.
He is, in fact,
that same liberal producer
Who was quoted
at our Saturday discussion.
It is he and not the committee
Who applies the only lash
that really stings...
Economic reprisal:
He is the enforcer
who gives the committee
Its only strength
and all its victories.
Disliking the nasty business
of blacklisting
But nonetheless practicing it
every day of his life,
He places upon his country
and his flag
The blame for moral atrocities
That otherwise
would be charged
directly to himself.
And thus, since informing
has nothing to do
With the law
and the country
and the flag,
And since the necessities
of his life as he sees them
Oblige him to enforce
what the committee
can never compel,
And since
without his enforcement
The committee would have
no power at all...
What he actually said
Is that he is the law
And the country and the flag.
Thinking back to our producer
And his concept
of country and flag,
I am more than ever bewildered.
I wonder if he has
really seen this country,
If he has really seen
these American people,
If he has really
seen that flag.
If he has, and his
conclusions are honest,
He has seen something
I never imagined
And don't believe
exists."
Trumbo:
My mother and father
always refused...
Declined to state
their political affiliation
in primaries.
And I learned
to decline to state.
I learned that certain things
were not anybody's business,
And that if you allow them
To encroach upon this area
Then they can
ask you anything...
About your wife,
about your children
About your politics.
They might even...
and I can imagine
a time in this country
When they may
bring democrats up
to the platform
And say, "have you now
or have you ever been
A member of
the democratic party?"
Mitzi Trumbo:
My father loved it
when he could be
In some kind of
magnificent battle
with somebody.
I always loved
hearing his perspective
on anything,
But especially political,
because he was just
so astute.
He was really smart.
He was very funny.
He was charming.
He was very charming.
He would enchant people.
He could also be difficult,
Grumpy and cantankerous
And had a temper.
He was a terrible
money manager.
As soon as money
came in for a script,
He'd spend it
is the only way
I can think about it.
My father's relationship
to money is
He never managed to save any.
( chuckles )
this was always
the problem.
He was consistently
catching up.
So all of his plans,
You know, or all of his dreams
To actually become
financially independent
Never had a Chance
in the face of the things
That he was interested
in doing with the money
At the time, which was like,
"maybe we should put
a lake in there,"
That kind of thing.
And so, as he was being
unemployed by the studio
And his contract canceled,
he was in the middle
Of improving the ranch again.
"dear burglars:
Our baby sleeps in one bedroom
And we sleep in another.
When she yelps at night
we cannot hear her.
A man said you were the people
To see about such things.
Can you install a speaker
in her room and one in ours
So we can gossip
back and forth with her
During the wee small hours?
Not one of your
solid gold outfits,
Something sensible
and serviceable.
I am not a rich man anymore.
Now let's all get together
and see if we can arrange
A decent, modest little
outfit for an old customer
Without screwing him
to death in the process.
Irritably yours,
Dalton Trumbo."
"my dear Mr. Fourness:
Your letter has arrived
And been put to the only
sensible use I could think of.
When we reds come into power
We are going to
shoot merchants
in the following order:
(1) those who are greedy,
and (2) those who are witty.
Since you fall
into both categories
It will be a sad story
When we finally
lay hands on you.
I had hoped time might have
improved your character,
But the prices you quote
convince me otherwise.
You still cannot imagine
a happy moment
Which does not find your fist
In somebody else's pocket.
Since I have
little choice in the matter,
I must yield.
Send the set described
and with it
A man for installation.
I have no intention
of creeping about the house
on all fours
With a wire in one hand
and a hammer in the other
And my larynx
clogged with tacks.
The Bill should be sent
to my business manager
Whose name is Rex Cole.
I have employed him
because he hates creditors
And does not pay them
too promptly.
You will feel better
over the Thanksgiving
and Christmas season
If you have something
to look forward to
During the hangover period
which follows;
And I tell you quite frankly
That it will probably be
60 days
Before you get your money.
Considering what
you've done to me,
I ought to make you wait
the full nine months.
Please extend my good wishes
for the holiday season
To everyone
in the thuggery."
My father's poem
for my birthday
In 1951, I'm 10 years old,
Is precisely the kind of fun
That he likes to have
with language,
With, in this case, meter.
So there is
an enormous playfulness
That really has
no outlet, you know,
In any other way.
"about 10 years ago today
(or rather, in the night)
Your mother turned to me to say
A thing that gave me fright.
She whispered
with surpassing Joy,
'my darling husband dear,
We're going to have
a little boy.
In fact,
he's almost here!'
I leaped at once
onto the floor,
Fell flat upon my face,
Jumped up and ran
against the door,
Fell down again...
same place.
I scrambled into suit and hat,
Fell down the stairs,
slid through the hall,
Did handsprings like an acrobat
To where the car stood
in its stall.
I packed your mother into it
And started through the night
To-whoop, to-whee,
to-lickety-split,
To-wheedle-de-wham,
what a sight!
Then halfway to the hospital
The engine's feeble pop
Brought mother and me
and unborn you
To an absolute dead stop.
"oh dear, oh me,
oh double-alas
And mercy," cried my heart,
"the car has just
run out of gas,
And having stopped,
won't start!"
I raced away to a standard sign
For a bucket full of gas,
Filled up the tank
with an old hose line,
Which I threw away
on the grass.
Then off again
with the speed of light
(the tires and mother whining)
Like a startled baboon
through the dark of night,
My eyes all wild and shining.
We got to the place
in a mile-long slide,
And seven minutes later
You arrived
with a mouth as wide
As a full-grown
alligator.
Your mother looked at me,
And I looked grimly
back at her.
'what'll we name it?'
I said with a sigh,
And she said,
'Christopher.'
And that's how it happened,
my little son,
My grim and glare and starey,
My gloom and glum
and fearsome one,
My beautiful and scarey!
Happy birthday from daddy.
Dalton Trumbo...
prisoner #7551."
The guys went to jail in '50.
And that was a big shock.
That was a real shock
to all of us.
Only two people stood trial.
Jack Lawson stood trial first,
And then I.
Both Jack and I were judged
Guilty of contempt
Of the 83rd congress
I think it was.
And as far as I'm concerned,
It was a completely
just verdict.
I had contempt
for that congress
As I've had contempt
for several since.
All through the appeals
things got very tight.
Everybody was working,
scrambling terribly hard.
Navasky: It went all the way
up to the supreme court.
By the way, they thought
they were going to win.
Trumbo:
Every law review
in the country
Thought we would win.
Now we didn't win.
Others saw something
That we had not had
the advantage of seeing.
They saw 10 men
sell their houses,
Say goodbye to their kids
And go off to jail,
lose their jobs
And then be subjected
To public disgrace
and punishment.
I have three children.
I have a nice wife.
Why should I go to jail?
"my darling,
You know what I was
thinking last night?
I was thinking of the night
A weary, frightened,
Tearful girl
climbed into my car
And let me drive away with her.
And I was thinking
Of the truly remarkable person
She has turned into.
And I came to the conclusion
That the night in question
Was the luckiest one
of my life."
Mitzi Trumbo:
Yes, my parents' courtship
was a famous family story.
( chuckles )
he had a friend
named Earl Felton
Who told him that he had met
The woman that my father
should marry.
And my mom worked
in a drive-in stand.
Christopher Trumbo:
My mother came out,
Served them dinner,
whatever it was,
And my father proposed to her.
My mother rejected him.
She married...
I believe he was the cook
at the drive-in stand.
I don't know
if she did this
in defiance or what.
Jean Rouverol:
Trumbo was dismayed
When she married this fellow
Whom he had met somehow
And didn't trust worth a darn.
So he put a detective
on this other man
And in due time discovered
That the man was
already married.
So to his great delight
This invalidated
Cleo's marriage
To his competitor
And before too long
Cleo had chosen Trumbo.
"two days hence
will be our 13th
Wedding anniversary.
I have been lying here
on my bunk
Thinking about it.
The 13 years
Seem so short a time
Because it has been
so happy a time for me.
All that is any good in my life
Has grown out of it.
I think back on each year
of it with pride.
I think our children
take pride in it,
And will take more pride
as they grow older.
I think the three things
I want most
when I get out of here:
I want (1) a good drink,
(2) a rare steak,
And (3) a symphony.
More and more I realize
that when I emerge
from here
I must make the choice
of what kind of writer
I want to be.
And I think it would be
better for all of us
If I returned
to writing novels,
With the occasional foray
into the theater.
It will probably
take years to recover
From the blow dealt
by the blacklist.
But the discovery of friends
who would rally around
With such incredible generosity
Perhaps makes the whole
experience worthwhile.
Much love...
Dalton Trumbo...
prisoner #7551."
( chuckles )
"p.s. As for the problem
of your children,
I have no solution,
Except that I will adapt
myself to the solution
Which you conclude
is reasonable.
It is your problem.
They are, after all,
The fruits of your own
unbridled lust.
And if they now
appear inconvenient,
Remember the Joy
of their conception."
Christopher Trumbo:
In 1951 when he gets out
of jail
My father came back
to the ranch
And all the attendant
problems of
"how do we start again?
What are we going to do?
What's the world
look like now?"
Is it your opinion, senator,
that we're any nearer
A war with soviet Russia
than we were a year ago?
As far as war is concerned,
we're at war
With the communist
half of the world.
That war wasn't started by us.
It can't be ended by us
except by ultimate victory.
It wasn't only McCarthy.
It was an attitude
in the senate,
In the house un-American
activities committee.
Communism in reality
is not a political party.
It is a way of life,
An evil and malignant
way of life.
It reveals a condition
akin to disease
That spreads like an epidemic.
And like an epidemic,
a quarantine is necessary
To keep it from infecting
this nation.
Jean Rouverol:
About this time
the government was beginning
To recondition
the relocation centers
That the Japanese had been
interned in during the war
For members of the left...
In other words,
concentration camps
For American radicals.
And that was
really frightening.
We had had a long period
of unemployment,
Which had scared
the living dickens out of us.
So we realized
That there was a gray list
That was beginning
to affect us.
But I had dinner with the kids
And the doorbell rang.
I went to the door
knowing exactly what
I would find.
And I looked through
the Judas hole
And it was two men in hats
on the front porch.
And they asked for Hugo
And I said
that he wasn't there.
And they asked where he was
And I said I didn't know.
And they looked
at each other and
off they went.
And, oh, I was a wreck.
And I came back to the table
And I telephoned Hugo.
He came on the phone
and I said,
"honey, get on your horse."
And there was a pause
And he said, "no shit."
And we were on the run.
We all agreed
that maybe we should all
leave the country
Because we couldn't see
any way out.
We couldn't see
what lay in store for us.
"old boy, my limited view
of the economy of Hollywood
Indicates it's not too good.
Employment extremely low,
Many deserving hacks starving.
I find enough to do
but don't enjoy doing it,
Stall a great deal of the time.
I just slunge around
and bipper at people,
And dream of the time
I'll be shed of everything.
I'm impatient
for something to happen,
Good, bad or indifferent.
I want to move somewhere.
I think we might
live handsomely
And grow rich in Mexico.
Don't you?
I'm perfectly willing
to go anywhere
That I can live
not, perhaps, in peace,
But certainly in luxury.
If I could spend
the next five or 10 years
In Mexico city or its environs
And earn say
40-50,000 a year,
Which isn't at all improbable,
And pay Mexican income taxes
And stash enormous
sums of cash away...
Hell, I'd go for it instantly.
Cleo and I intend to
swoop into Cuernavaca
And quiz Gordon Kahn
about living costs,
Schools, rents,
mordito, inmigrantes
And the virgin of Guadalupe...
All of which he is said
to know more about
Than any other living person.
Naturally, we shall share
our findings with you.
We all send you felicitaciones,
Y 'misereres', y fraternidades
Y 'comisereres'."
Ring Lardner
And Hugo butler and Ian Hunter
Were my father's
closest friends
And had been during the '40s.
And all of the families
Ended up at some point
In Mexico city.
We all moved to Mexico.
First it was...
The butlers and the Trumbos
Went down in this
caravan together.
And we followed in January.
I think they went down
in November.
I've heard stories
about ring and Hugo
And Ian and pop.
And there are actually
Some photos somewhere
of them wrestling.
So this is the wrestling.
This is my dad...
This is ring.
And that's Hugo.
And this unflattering
picture here...
This is Trumbo.
I think these are legs,
and they would be Ian's.
Rouverol:
Somehow or other
these four writers,
Young writers,
all got together,
All had a wonderful
time together
And made up a band,
a little band of brothers.
They were adorable together.
They were terribly funny.
Mostly what they did
was have fun.
They would think of pranks.
They would drink,
Which was, you know,
a primary occupation.
Kate Lardner:
They were all
probably drunks.
I'm not sure about Hugo.
Trumbo seems to have been
the most successful
In being able
to drink and write.
"my dear son,
I am sending you two books
I think appropriate
For a young man spending
five-sevenths of his time
In the monkish precincts
of John Jay hall.
The first is
'education of a poker player, '
By Herbert O. Yardley.
Read it in secret,
hide it whenever you
leave quarters,
And you'll be rewarded
with many
Unfair but legal advantages
over friend and enemy alike.
The second book
I think you should share
With your young companions.
It is "sex without guilt,"
By a man who will
take his place in history
As the greatest humanitarian
Since Mahatma Gandhi...
Albert Ellis, PhD.
This good man has written
what might be called
A manual for masturbators.
The result
(mailed in plain wrapper
under separate cover)
Is one of those
fortuitous events
In which the right man
collides with the right idea
At precisely the right time.
This whole new approach...
this fresh wind
Blowing under the sheets,
so to speak...
This large-hearted appeal
for cheerful self-pollution,
Invokes perhaps
a deeper response
In my heart than in most.
For I (sneaky, timorous,
Incontinent little beast
with my paphian obsessions)
Was never wholesomely at home
With my penile problem...
All because of that maggoty,
Mountainous pustule
of needless guilt
That throbbed
like an abscess
in my young boy's heart."
This is an exercise
of language and style.
He's just read Nabokov.
He's playing with it.
He's entertaining me.
He's entertaining himself.
"on warm Summer nights
While exuberant
girl-hunting contemporaries
Scampered in and out
of the brush
Beneath high western stars,
I, dedicated fool,
lay swooning in my bed
With no companion
Save the lewd
and smirking demons
Of my bottomless
guilt."
The first thing I did
was start laughing,
And the second thing I did
was get a dictionary.
"cowering there
in seminal darkness,
Liquescent with
self-loathing,
Attentive only
to the stealthy rise
and crafty-ebbing
Of my dark scrotumnal blood,
Fearful as a lechwe
Yet firmer of purpose
than any rutting buffalo,
I celebrated
the rites of Shuah's son
With sullen resignation.
Poor little chap
on a Summer's night,
Morosely masturbating...!
( clicks tongue )
Even now, more than
three decades later,
Even now when I forget
a friend's name,
Or mislay my spectacles,
Or pause...
In mid-sentence idiocy...
Even now such lapses
Set a clammy chill
upon my heart.
It's then,
While panic tightens
my sagging throat,
That I whisper to myself:
'it's true after all.
It does make you crazy.
It does cause
the brain to soften.
Why, oh why did I
like it so much?
Why didn't I stop
while I was still
ahead of the game?'
Ah well...
little good to know it now:
The harm's done, the jig's up,
You're thoroughly rattled.
Better you'd been born
with handless stumps.
I recall
A certain chill winter night
On which my father took me
To one of those
Calvinist fertility rites
Disguised as
a father-and-son banquet.
Master of the revels
was an acrid old goat
Named Horace T. McGuiness.
He opened his discourse
With a series
of blasphemous demands
That the almighty agree
with his ghastly notions,
And then got down
to the meat of the program
Which, to no one's surprise,
was girls.
When you go out
with a young lady,
he slavered,
You go out
with your own sister.
It seemed plain to me
That if one day
I did burst upon the world
As the hymeneal Genghis khan
of my dreams,
I would be in
for an extremely
incestuous time of it.
I can still hear
that demented old reprobate
Howling his
bill of particulars
against poor Onan,
The bible's first
recorded masturbator,
Shaking his fist at us
And sweating like
a diseased stoat.
'he wasted his seed!
Oh monstrous, shameful,
nameless act...
He spilled it right out
onto the ground!
All of it!'
And this displeased the Lord,
And the Lord
slew him!"
Yet the more I think on it,
The more positive I become
That you will never
truly be able
To comprehend in all its horror
That interminably
sustained convulsion
Which was your father's youth.
It's only reasonable
that this should be so,
Since you had
so many advantages
That were denied to me.
To name but three of them...
A private room,
A masturbating father,
And Albert Ellis, PhD.
I carried the ball
for all of us,
And carried it farther
Than anyone had a right
to expect.
I was the Prometheus
Of my secret tribe...
A penile virtuoso,
A gonadic prodigy,
A spermatiferous thunderbolt;
In fine,
A masturbator's
masturbator."
( blows air )
I dreamed of living
In luxurious exile
in Mexico city.
Well, it was luxurious
for the first year.
It was absolutely hellish
for the second year
Because I had assumed
That I could get
a little underground work
from the north.
It turned out
that I could get none.
And I was sort of
heroically broke.
Rouverol:
Cleo was staunchly loyal
to Trumbo...
Staunchly loyal...
And everything
that he stood for.
So she accepted what had to be.
By now the Trumbos
had kind of used up
Most of their reserves
And they knew that it was...
They were going to have to
sooner or later come back,
And it had better be sooner.
There were ideas that
perhaps there were ways
Of breaking into
the Mexican film industry
Or something like that.
For my father none of this
ever paid off.
"dear Dorothy and Seniel:
To start in,
I was a fool for moving
south of the border.
The line of supply
to my living source
Was so tenuous
that when I did work
The people who owed me for it
Mistook my absence
for my death,
And simply did not pay
Without the strongest
kind of pressure
Being exerted.
We lived out an old truism:
'the first time you see Mexico
You are struck
by the horrible poverty:
Within a year you discover
it's infectious.'
I'm as broke
as a bankrupt's bastard.
When I arrived from Mexico,
I pulled into town
With a wife,
three children,
a dog, a cat,
One mortgaged jeep,
And $400 in my pocket.
There were other problems.
I had lost all my
life insurance
During that disastrous
Mexican holiday.
I lived on borrowed money
For the last nine months
of the visit.
I couldn't even get
my furniture out of storage
Because of a $1,200
storage Bill I couldn't pay.
I sat down
in a motel in Pasadena
With a dog, cat and one child,
While Cleo and the two girls
Moved in with my sister.
Most of my black market
connections
Had dissolved
during my absence,
And it was like trying
to find work at midnight
In a thick fog among strangers.
Hence I started at the bottom,
Like any newcomer,
For as little
as $1,000 a script.
In the first 18 months
I wrote 12 scripts...
Which normally would take
between four and six
years to do.
The necessity of keeping
the money grinding in
Made it impossible for me
to take as much as a month off
And gamble on an original
which might sell for enough
To give me more gambling room.
Also, I am overly timid
and evasive
When I owe money
And I can't see
just how I'm going to
pay it back.
This letter, then,
is an apology
Which I hope you will be
generous enough to accept.
I enclose a check for $50,
Which I shall now be able
to repeat every month
Until the money
you so very graciously
lent me
Is paid off in full."
One of the objects
of a blacklist
Is to deprive the victim
Of economic security
And to drastically lower
his living standards
To the point
where he will yield.
Well, that being
their objective,
My objective is to maintain
those living standards
in spite of it.
Trumbo began to work
very very hard
and very fast.
And he would have
three stories
going at once
Because he was beginning
to have to sell stuff
Under other names
or with a front.
So there were a lot of secrets.
He had many, you know,
different names.
And the phone would ring
And it was never
the wrong number
As far as I was concerned.
I'd always just
call my dad.
Trumbo:
I had 13 pseudonyms,
all told.
I had Irish names.
I had Jewish names.
I had Anglo-Saxon names.
Give them their preference.
So you say
Sam Jackson calling
or Doc Abbott
Or Theodore Flaxman
or Evelyn Dumain.
My dad...
his best friend,
One of the members
of this group, was Ian hunter.
And Ian had an academy award.
Ian's was for this
beautiful movie called
"Roman holiday."
It wasn't until I was
in my early 30s
That I learned
that Ian had not written
"Roman holiday."
Trumbo had written
the original story.
Ian had fronted for Trumbo.
Ian hadn't been
blacklisted yet.
And when the credits
were redistributed
Sometime in the '90s to Trumbo
The whole experience
was embarrassing.
Just the blacklist
is a little bit more
complicated.
It just has these
repercussions.
I thought a little wine
might be good.
Shall I cook something?
No kitchen.
Nothing to cook.
I always eat out.
Do you like that?
I like this knowledge
what one likes.
Is it...?
No, it isn't.
Ray Murphy was a young man
My father met
in the south pacific.
Ray later became
a front for my father.
And we needed
the money as usual
When the script sold.
And my father was expecting it
And it wasn't coming.
So he made inquiries
And a few weeks later
discovered
That Ray Murphy
had died suddenly.
"dear Mrs. Murphy,
I want to tell you
about your son
And my relationship with him,
And of my wife's sorrow
and my own
That he is no longer living.
It has been
my privilege, since 1945,
To be Ray's friend.
It came about
in the following manner:
In June of 1945
A party of six or seven
war correspondents
Embarked from
San Francisco by air
On a three-month tour
of pacific battle areas.
Among the correspondents
were Ray and I.
During the invasion of Borneo,
Ray and I went ashore
in a landing craft
Between the first
and second waves,
Dodging mortar fire
As we sprinted across the sand.
From a slit trench outside
the governor's palace
Ray and I spotted a hilltop
Which we believed
would give us a better view
Of what was going on,
and decided to climb it.
When we finally reached
the top of the hill
We found an abandoned AA Gun
That had been knocked out
by naval fire,
And no sign of a human being.
We took what cover we could
When we heard sounds
of approaching troops,
Thinking the Japanese
were returning.
Moments later a grim-looking
Australian assault group
With fixed bayonets appeared
Expecting to meet the enemy.
Well in advance
of our armed forces,
As it turned out,
Ray and I had accidentally
captured the hill.
On the fourth day
of the campaign,
The outcome being beyond doubt,
Our group decided
to return to Tawi Tawi.
Once off we retired
into the main cabin.
Somewhere off Japanese
occupied celebes,
The alarm signifying
an air attack
Went off in the cabin.
It could only mean that a zero
Had risen from celebes
and was attacking.
I was on the top bunk.
I looked down.
Ray was lying full length
on the floor
Between two other men,
his helmet on.
He looked up at me
And although his face was,
I daresay,
As pale as my own, he smiled.
Then he said,
'goodbye, Trumbo.'
I cannot quite describe
My emotions at that moment.
Perhaps I thought of
my own son, then only four;
Perhaps I thought
of my father long dead;
I certainly felt that a son
not my son
Had chosen me
from among that company
As the one he wished
to say goodbye to,
And that a father
not his father
Had responded.
The fact,
as it later turned out,
That there was no zero
within a hundred Miles
and no danger.
That the whole incident
was a ludicrous mistake
of nerves
On the part of the crew
In no way diminishes
my memory of that moment,
Nor the surge of love
I felt for your son.
We managed to correspond
intermittently ever since.
Ray went to India,
And later published
his first novel;
I went before
the house committee
on un-American activities
And later
served my first term
in a penitentiary.
I was at that time,
as I am now,
Blacklisted
by motion pictures,
publishers, and magazines.
It was typical
of his generous nature
That he offered
to collaborate with me
for motion pictures,
And to put his name alone
To the product of our
mutual endeavors.
It was typical of my need
that I accepted.
During our last visits,
In a moment
of temporary depression
Common to young men
who are both sensitive
And intelligent
beyond their years,
Ray told me
That he thought
he believed in nothing;
He felt himself
a complete cynic.
It was, of course, not true.
A day or two later
When he brought a copy
of my novel
'Johnny got his gun'
for me to inscribe,
I wrote in it
what I really felt
About him and his future.
He telephoned me
the next day to thank me.
He said, 'I hope
I can live up to it.'
I should have told him then,
And now have only you to tell
That he already had."
Man:
Prisoner, show yourself.
( coughing )
Give me the name
and you're back
on full rations.
Just one name.
I was born skinny.
Then you'll die.
Christopher Trumbo:
In 1957 or '58
The situation
in Hollywood in terms of
blacklisted writers is
Unless you cooperate
with the committee,
Unless you, you know,
do what it asks you to,
You won't be employed.
Navasky:
The next generation
of witnesses
Faced a different
sort of choice.
They could take the first
amendment like the 10
And then their assumption was
they'd go to prison;
They could take
the fifth amendment
Which would keep them
out of prison,
But they would then
be blacklisted;
Or they could cooperate
with the committee.
If they did that and admitted
That they had been members
of the communist party,
The next question was, "and who
else was a member with you?"
Larry parks was
the first witness
In the new round
of witnesses in 1951,
And parks was ready
to talk about himself.
He was ready to talk about
why he joined the party,
Which he said was
because it was the most
liberal thing around
And then he got out.
And he said,
"but don't make me name names.
Don't make me play
the informer."
Don't present me
with the choice
Of either being in contempt
to this committee
And going to jail
Or forcing me
To crawl through the mud
to be an informer.
I beg you
Not to force me
to do this."
Navasky:
They insisted
that he name names
And from then on
you had to name names
In order to get cleared
by the committee.
It is only a matter of time.
You think so?
He's on half rations now.
You can't exist on that.
Forced to choose between
starvation and telling,
What would you do?
We're not talking about me.
I looked hard at Dalton
and I thought,
What is it about this Guy
that would not...
Which would make him say,
"no, I'm not giving names."
And that was
a psychic death kind of.
Because you just
lost everything.
You were never to work again.
You were never to have
any money.
You went to jail.
I remember doing an interview
With Adrian Scott
Who was one of
the Hollywood 10.
I visited him in his home
And all of the furniture
was gone.
He was sitting on the floor
With a crate in front of him
And a typewriter
on top of the crate,
And on the wall was
A photograph
of Franklin Roosevelt.
And that was all there was
in this house.
I'm really speaking
of the personal experience
Of a man who was fortunate
during this period.
It was a matter of total
disaster for others...
Financial, matrimonial,
For some of their children.
Wherever you are,
at some point somebody
discovers
That Dalton Trumbo
was Dalton Trumbo.
Mitzi Trumbo:
We clearly stood out.
We were a different
kind of family.
Dalton Trumbo:
It is that we were
thrust inward as a family.
We were thrust upon ourselves.
And we relied
upon each other more
And trusted each other more
and helped each other more.
Mitzi Trumbo:
I felt we were
a very close family.
Christopher Trumbo:
What you need is a person
who is outraged
By the fact
that Dalton Trumbo lives
in the neighborhood
And, two, that his daughter
Actually goes to school
with their children.
Mitzi:
It was beginning
fifth grade.
I think I was 10 years old.
And it was pretty awful
at school.
And I didn't tell them
about it,
Because when you're a kid
You pretty much think
it's your problem
to deal with,
Until it got to the point
Where I just couldn't go
to school anymore
And finally let them know
what was happening.
"to Mrs. Eleanor
Barr wheeler,
Principal,
Annandale elementary school.
My dear Mrs. Wheeler,
We entrusted to your care
A happy, healthy,
Comparatively
well-adjusted
And demonstrably
intelligent child
Who loved school,
adored her teachers
And enjoyed the friendship
Of her small circle
of contemporaries.
Eight months later
you have returned to us
A spiritually devastated
human being
Who begs us not to send her
to school.
I am informed
that within the P.T.A.
And the bluebirds
There have been a series
of small secret meetings
Devoted to a discussion
Of Mrs. Trumbo's character,
and of mine,
And what to do about us.
Since no one
has come to our home
to discuss at first hand
The problems which
so deeply trouble them,
We have obviously been tried
and condemned in absentia,
And the verdict
has filtered down
From parent to child.
Mitzi,
Who started out
the school year
with many friends,
Has found herself
in the past three months
The object of the scorn
And ridicule and hatred
Of those she liked most.
Small childish conspiracies
Are directed against her...
Patterned in secret
After the conspiracies
of the parents...
And she is quietly
and incessantly persecuted
And boycotted and shunned
As long as
the school day lasts.
This slow murder
Of the mind
and heart and spirit
of a young child
Is the proud outcome
Of the patriotic meetings
held by a few parents,
Under the sponsorship
of the P.T.A.
And the bluebirds.
I should like you to watch
How decently and bravely
our daughter tries
To suppress her bewilderment
At her first encounter
with barbarism
Parading as American virtue,
Barbarism which began
At your school
among adult persons.
Now that we have discovered
The source of matzo's agony,
We shall naturally secure
competent treatment
To rid her of the scars
already inflicted.
If it then seems advisable
We shall employ
competent counsel
To seek a court test
Of the responsibilities
of the school
And of school organizations
For the mental health
of the children
entrusted to it.
For it is within these
school organizations
That Mitzi has suffered
an assault.
That the assault has been
upon her personality
And that the injury
she has sustained is psychic
Makes it no less real than if,
in a physical sense,
The men and women
of the P.T.A.
And the officials
of the bluebirds
Had incited their children
to trample her senseless
On the blacktop
of the playground."
Dalton Trumbo:
That was the quality
of hatred.
It wasn't just against me
or our daughter.
It was against everything
that is strange,
Everything that is different.
And that of course is...
Is the beginning
of the apocalypse.
( crowd cheering )
Rouverol:
One Sunday Hugo and I
and Trumbo and Cleo
Went to a bullfight.
Hugo identified
with the bullfighter
And Trumbo identified
with the bull.
So in this case
it was a bad kill.
The bull was stabbed
through the throat
And bled profusely.
And Trumbo and Cleo
were absolutely livid.
They were simply horrified.
They could hardly speak.
And within a couple of months
Trumbo has gotten the idea
for an original,
Which emerged finally
as "the brave one."
Trumbo: On the day that
the academy nominations
were announced,
It was announced that
Robert rich was nominated.
Robert rich was one
of my father's fronts.
Robert rich was
an actual person.
He was the nephew
of the king brothers
who had produced the picture.
( fanfare )
Announcer:
...Night of nights in Hollywood
as the film industry presents
The 29th annual
motion picture academy awards.
Christopher Trumbo:
In 1957 at the academy
awards
"the brave one" received
the academy award
For best original story...
For "the brave one."
And the academy award
was given to Robert rich.
Dalton Trumbo:
That night no one appeared
to pick up the award.
The next morning six other
Robert riches announced
That they had written it
and demanded the award.
That Oscar became
The only unclaimed Oscar,
I believe,
In the whole history
of the academy awards.
I remember as a child
Seeing a photo composite,
That they were
trying to reconstruct
who Robert rich was.
Christopher Trumbo:
As a result there
came to be
A search for Robert rich.
This was an opportunity
that my father seized upon
And used
To bring the idea
of blacklisted writers
to a head,
That it couldn't be
ignored anymore.
Mr. Trumbo, did you write
"the brave one"?
Well, you see,
I've been accused
Of writing many pictures
in the last 10 years
During the period
of the blacklist.
So I've had to make a policy
about such questions.
My policy is
That I modestly refuse
Either to confirm or to deny.
In this way I receive
just a little bit of credit
From almost every
good picture that's made.
And for some reason
I never get blamed
for the scamps.
"the name Robert rich
Lends itself
magnificently to jokes
And may even be
The invention of a jokester.
But it nonetheless contains,
As every really good joke must,
An essential element of tragedy
Or horror or disgrace
Or doom.
Robert rich
is the unknown artist.
He is the fugitive American
of our time.
And it is my purpose
and determination
That his name
shall be remembered
As a symbol
of this national disgrace
Long after the blacklist itself
Has been destroyed.
For I have seen the blacklist
That produced Robert rich.
I know its pain
and its frustration
And its horror
And its shattering cruelties.
I have seen families
Rendered by it
destitute overnight.
I have seen broken homes
And heartbroken children
and sorrowing friends.
I have seen its hideous
waste of talent
And of love,
Of friendship and of life.
I have long served
In this lowly marching army
of the anonymous.
And walking among its ranks,
I have seen
The figure of death.
And helplessly I have watched
Decent men and women die
Before their stories
had been told,
Before their work was finished
Before their normal span
of years had been lived out.
Every trade,
every profession now has
Its roll call of honored dead.
I can make no more jokes
about Robert rich.
They turn sour on my tongue.
I can invent no more witticisms
About the Oscar
he dares not claim
Because that small,
worthless golden statuette
Is covered with the blood
of my friends.
I cannot laugh about it
any longer
Because my belly is filled
With the poison
of this blacklist
And my heart is filled
with its grief
And my ears roar with rage
At its injustices.
And my heart for the first time
Is filled with something
very close to hate."
I have a daughter.
She's 13 years old.
I've been blacklisted
since she was three.
She's known the title
Of every motion picture
I've written in this study
And she's kept
that title secret.
My parents and I
watched the academy awards
The night that Robert rich won
And I was so thrilled.
And I was saying,
"daddy, let's go
get it tomorrow.
Let's go pick it up."
And he said,
"well, you know, we can't."
When her friends say to her,
as children do,
"my father does so and so;
What does your father do?"
This has confronted her
with a very real problem.
It confronts her
with the problem...
And has since she was three...
Of who her father really is
And what her father
really does.
I think
I will give this Oscar,
if I get it, to that girl.
I think I will tell her,
"well, here is one secret
You no longer need
to be burdened with."
I'll tell her,
"we have our names
back again."
I bring a message
from your master,
Marcus licinius Crassus,
Commander of Italy.
By command of his most
merciful excellency,
Your lives are to be spared.
( crowd muttering )
Slaves you were
and slaves you remain,
But the terrible penalty
of crucifixion
Has been set aside
On the single condition
That you identify the body
or the living person
Of the slave called Spartacus!
- I'm...
- I'm Spartacus.
I'm Spartacus.
All:
( slaves continue shouting )
You know, when you get close
To 90 years of age
You look back
And you try to remember
The things that you're
not quite proud of
And if there are the things
that you're proud of.
I find one thing
That I was very proud of.
I employed Dalton Trumbo
To write the screenplay
of "Spartacus."
Trumbo's name appears
on two films in 1960...
On "exodus" and "Spartacus"...
After years in which
none of his peers
Could get credited on films.
I had lunch with Mr. Krim
and Benjamin
And I said that I want
to give Trumbo credit...
You know,
official screen credit
as Dalton Trumbo.
And they said to me,
"you have autonomy
of contract."
If you want to give him
screen credit,
We won't publicly
agree with you
For certain reasons.
But we will not stop you.
Do whatever you like."
I know it. I feel it.
Either you compromise
or you lose.
We won't lose.
Kate Lardner:
And I remember going
to see "Spartacus"
And I remember
going to see "exodus"
with my family.
I sensed the family pride,
The pride of the community,
You know, that this man's name
Was on the work
And it might make it
easier for the others.
Christopher Trumbo:
Everything for him
comes down to
Some very simple attitudes
And some very simple beliefs.
And he just doesn't
stray from those,
Which goes back to his ideas
About the first amendment,
Freedom, what it is,
The way a man operates
in society.
Donald Sutherland:
We were talking and he
looked at us and he said,
"don't forget
to be happy."
And I thought,
"God, reflected in that
Must be so much pain
and suffering
For the political
commitment he made
That put him
on that blacklist."
All over the world...
Here, there and everywhere...
Is this immoral
assertion of power
Over the most private
thoughts of men
And the assertion by government
That it has the power
to compel men to tell,
To recant,
to disgrace themselves,
To swear they were idiots,
To revoke their past
and to spit on their work.
This is what government wants
In greater or less degree
all over the world.
And this is what nobody...
Nobody can do.
"I've delivered newspapers,
Peddled vegetables,
clerked in stores,
Waited on tables,
washed automobiles,
Picked fruit, hosed down
infected cadavers,
Shoveled sugar beets,
iced refrigerator cars;
Laid rails with a section gang,
Reported for newspapers,
Served an eight-year hitch
on the night shift
Of a large industrial plant.
I looked at many
American faces:
I've seen them
as flack burst around them
9,000 feet over Japan;
In a slit trench on Okinawa
watching the night Sky
To see where the next
bomb would fall;
In an assault boat as they
moved toward a beach
That tossed more violently
than the surf through which
they rode.
I've counseled with
a paroled prostitute
On how she might escape
the clutches of a policeman
Who had caught her
and was stealing
half her earnings
And sending his friends
to her with courtesy cards
That entitled them
to take her without pay.
I've been asked
by Louis B. Mayer
why I had no religion,
And by a ranking member
of the state department
How I could bring myself
to work with
'all those
Hollywood Jews.'
I've seen American faces
in a congregational church
in New Hampshire,
Where a colleague and I
traveled with a bodyguard
of students.
I've seen their faces
in a miners' union hall
in Duluth
On a night when
the wind off the lake
Blew the snow
so killingly and so deep
Cars couldn't be used
and everybody walked
to the meeting.
I've seen their faces
in the banquet room
of a new York hotel
When the American
booksellers' association
Gave me a national book award;
And I've seen them again
in the jury box
As each of them twice said
'guilty as charged, '
While one of them wept
as she said it.
While one of them
wept as she said it.
I've been stripped by Americans
And paraded naked
with them and before them
And obediently bent over
on command
To present my anus
for contraband clearance.
I've lived with and trusted
And been trusted by
car thieves and abortionists
And moonshiners
and embezzlers and burglars
And Jehovah's witnesses
and Quakers.
I've stood on a gray day
In the fifth marine division
cemetery on Iwo Jima,
And looked off at the graves
Of 2,198 Americans.
In the center
of all those graves
On a slim white pole
On a concrete pedestal
flew the American flag.
And I swear it was not
the flag of informers.
And if I could take a census
Of all the American faces
I have seen
And of all the dead
whose graves I have
looked on...
If I could ask them
one simple question:
'would you like a man
who told on his friend?'...
There would not be
one among them
Who would answer yes.
But, show me the man
who informs on friends
who have harmed no one,
And who thereafter
earns money he could not
have earned before,
And I will show you
not a decent citizen,
not a patriot,
But a miserable scoundrel
who will,
If new pressures arise
and the price is right,
Betray not just his friends
but his country itself.
I don't know
one Hollywood informer
Who acted
except under duress
and for money;
Such men are to be watched.
I cannot imagine
they are not watched.
I've been noticing lately
that I sneak small naps
In the afternoon.
It's just a little
more difficult
To summon the energy
to write this letter
Than it was five years ago.
Wine goes to my head
more quickly than it used to.
I walk forward
instead of running,
And although there is
much life in me,
Much is also gone.
So to sum up, I evaluate,
I calculate my course
more thoughtfully.
There are certain men
at my time
Who have waged great battles
And now look out upon the world
From hilltops or from peaks
Where the horizon
must be immensely wider
and more revealing.
But I, who have
only skirmished,
Stand on a Ridge,
Lower than I had hoped for
And yet perhaps higher
than I deserve.
The horizons
I had thought to see
Will probably be denied.
I still hope
(if I conserve energy
And absorb the meaning
of my experiences)
That I shall be able to ascend
One of the middle hills...
a little hill,
But still a hill
and not a Ridge.
Be that as it will be,
Even from my Ridge
I look back on two decades
Through which good friends
stood together,
Moved forward a little,
Dreamed that the world
could be better
And tried to make it so,
Tasted the Joy
of small victories,
Wounded each other,
made mistakes,
Suffered much injury,
And stood silent
in the chamber of liars.
For all this I am grateful:
That much I have;
That much cannot be
taken from me.
Barcelona fell,
And you were not there,
and I was not there.
And perhaps if we had been
The city would have stood
And the world been
changed and better.
But we were here,
And here together we remain.
And our city won't fall.
And if it should,
Better that we lie
buried in its ruins
Than found absent
a second time."
Dalton Trumbo:
We are not guaranteed
happiness.
We are only guaranteed
the right to pursue it,
Which does imply that
we all have adversity.
And it's not too bad.
"I always thought of my life
As a sequence of conflicts,
Each separate battle
segregated in my mind
Under the heading,
'my fight with these guys'
Or 'my fight
with those guys.'
In thinking back, I now realize
I have regarded each fight
As distinct and unrelated
to the other,
And have sometimes marveled
How one man can have
so many of them.
I now realize
it was all one fight;
That the relation of each
to the other was very close;
And that I am
really no more combative
than any other man.
It just happened in my case
That the original fight
once undertaken,
Expanded marvelously into
what seemed like many fights,
And that the most recent
in a sequence of fights
Is actually no more
than the current phase
Of the primary engagement.
Since all men have at least
one fight in their lives
And are not considered
Professional troublemakers
because of it,
The longer view reveals in me
A citizen no less peaceful
than his neighbors."
( instrumental music playing )
}}