My mommy always said
there were no monsters.
No real ones.
But there are.
She's perfect.
Careful.
Two centimeters.
OK.
Yeah. Ready with that amnio.
And..
there it is.
Be careful.
Jesus..
Clamp.
What about her?
Can we keep her alive?
How's the host?
Doing well.
Sew her back up.
Excellent work.
Everybody.
How is our Number Eight today?
Appears to be in good health.
- How good?
- Excellent.
As in completely off our projected charts.
Look at the scar tissue.
See the recession?
- This is from three days ago?
- Exactly.
Well, this is good.
This is very good.
You're going to make us all very proud.
Don't! I'm all right!
Now try this.
Hand.
Close.
Glove.
Number Eight?
Fruit.
Good. Cherries.
- It's unprecedented.
- Totally.
She's operating at
a completely adult capacity.
- What about her memories?
- There are gaps. Synaptic dissonance.
She's freaked.
It has difficulties,
caused by a biochemical imbalance,
causing emotional autism..
Wait.
It has memories!
Why does it have memories?
I'm guessing, but.. inherited memories,
passed down generationally
by the aliens, like its strength.
Plus a
highly evolved form of instinct.
An unexpected benefit
of genetic crossing.
Oh..
I see.
Stupid me. Of course.
An unexpected benefit
of the genetic process!
I didn't even think of that!
- You're not thinking termination?
- Oh, boy, am I?!
General, this is not a problem.
Ellen Ripley died
trying to wipe this species out.
She practically succeeded.
I don't want her
taking up old hobbies.
- That won't happen.
- We won't tell her.
Oh, I see,
and that's supposed to comfort me.
Identification, please.
Please try again.
Thank you, General Perez.
The bottom line is,
she looks at me funny one time,
I'm putting her down.
OK, as far as I'm concerned
Number Eight is a meat..
by-product.
Her Majesty here is the real payoff.
- When does she start producing?
- Days.
Less, maybe.
- We need the cargo.
- I told you, it's on its way.
Fork.
Fuck.
It's a fork.
How did you..
How did
we get you?
Yes.
Hard work. We used
blood samples,
from Fiori 16, on ice.
Where you died.
We've remade you. Cloned you.
Does it grow?
Yeah.
Very rapidly.
It's a queen.
How did you know that?
She'll breed.
You'll die.
Everyone in the company will die.
In the.. in the company?
Weyland Yutani.
Ripley Eight's former employers.
Terran growth conglomerate.
They had.. defense contracts
under the military.
I think you will find that
things have changed a great deal
since your time.
I doubt that.
We're not flying blind here.
This is United Systems Military,
not some greedy corporation.
Oh.
It won't make any difference.
You're still gonna die.
How do you feel about that?
I wish you could understand
what we're doing here.
The potential for this species
goes way beyond urban pacification.
New alloys, vaccines.
Nothing like this,
we've ever seen before.
You should be proud.
Oh.
I am.
And the animal itself,
wondrous.
The potential,
unbelievable. Once we've tamed him.
Roll over? Play dead?
Heel?
You can't teach it tricks.
Why not?
We're teaching you.
Time to enjoy some of
the General's hospitality, Christie.
Great. Army food.
Yeah, it'll do till we get
the family wagon up to spec.
Yeah.
That is, if the natives are friendly.
How's that?
Good.
Are we expecting any, uh, trouble?
From Perez, I doubt it, but you never know.
We've been there before.
- Where are the others?
- In the cargo bay.
What is wrong with you?
Just a little target practice.
Vriess isn't complaining.
Goddamn it!
Johner, you son of a bitch!
Come on, man, you didn't feel a thing.
Whoa..
The knife.
Son of a bitch!
Don't push me, little Call.
You hang with us for a while,
you'll find out I am not the man
with whom to fuck.
Hey, son, I'll give you
my authorization code.
It's E, A, T, M, E.
I'm sorry, sir.
Could you repeat that?
Prick.
You know, no matter
how many times you see it,
the sight of a woman all strapped up
in a chair like that just..
What?
Just bring us in on a 3-0 descent.
And ride the parallel.
Darling, it is done.
Good girl.
Hey, don't cut thrust
till about 600 meters.
It'll give 'em a little scare.
I am Father.
Welcome to the USMAuriga.
Step forward for contraband
and weapon search.
Please report any infectious diseases
to the medical officers.
Levels seven through twelve
are off-limits to civilians.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Go.
- Hands up, please.
- What?
Could you get your hands up, please?
No weapons allowed on board, sir.
My own recipe.
Way more dangerous.
Nice welcome, Perez.
What the hell is this?
Are you afraid the six of us
will hijack your damn ship?
Just making sure none of your
asshole crew members
gets drunk and puts a bullet
through the hull.
We happen to be in space.
No shit.
How you been?
Wanna check the chair?
Elgyn, these were very,
very hard to come by.
So was our cargo.
You're not about to plead poverty on me,
are you, General?
Few people deal in cash now.
Just the ones
don't like to keep business records.
Yourself, for example.
Drink?
Constantly.
I'm gonna take a.. wild guess here,
General, but I'm thinking
whatever you got going on here,
it ain't exactly approved by Congress.
Who's the
new filly you got on board?
Call?
Little girl playing pirates.
She makes an impression.
She is severely fuckable, ain't she?
Mind you, I think she's just a tad curious
about this transaction of ours.
I can't say as I blame her.
It's awfully cloak-and-dagger stuff.
It's a military operation.
Really?
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but I was under the impression that
most army medical labs don't operate
outside of regulated space.
What do you want?
Me?
Yeah.
Two days bed and board.
Vriess might want to snag
a part or two. I mean,
if it's not imposing.
Mi casa es su casa.
Please direct cargo
to med-lab centre, area G.
Follow the lit path.
Do not deviate.
Cargo status stable.
Life forms intact.
Stasis uninterrupted.
Med-lab centre
is off-limits to civilians.
Thank you.
Oh..!
Oh, hey!
- Oh, please.
- You know I can't lay off the tall ones.
How ya doin'?
How about a little one-on-one?
Whad da ya say?
You got some moves on you, girl.
Oh, man!
If you don't wanna play basketball
I know some other indoor sports.
Give me the ball.
OK, I got a new game.
Tag.
Ripley!
Ripley.
You've had enough fun.
What the hell are you?
Something of a predator.
Yes, she continues to make us
very proud.
There's just one minute
and 30 seconds left
to order this collector's item.
Jesus Christ, Johner, what did you
put in this shit? Battery acid?
Just for color.
So, we're a fast learner.
This is a really good show, man.
Hey, that shit is not easy to come by.
Why don't you take a walk outside!
Great!
I'm so sorry.
Stay away from this shit!
Identification, please.
Please try again.
Thank you, General Perez.
Well?
Are you gonna kill me, or what?
There's no point, is there?
They've taken it out of you.
Where is it?
Is it on the ship?
You mean my baby?
I don't get it.
If they took it out, why keep you alive?
Well, they're curious.
I'm the latest thing.
Look, I can make it all stop.
The pain, this nightmare,
that's all I can offer.
What makes you think
I would let you do that?
Who are you?
Ripley, Ellen, Lieutenant First Class.
Number 36706.
Ellen Ripley died 200 years ago.
You're not her.
I'm not her?
Who am I?
You're a thing.
A construct.
They grew you in a fuckin' lab.
And now they brought it out of you.
Not all the way out.
I can feel it.
Behind my eyes.
I can hear it moving.
Help me stop this thing
before it gets loose.
It's too late.
You can't stop it.
It's inevitable.
Not as long as I'm around.
You'll never get out of here alive.
I don't care.
Really?
I can make it stop.
Go on.
Get out of here.
They're looking for you.
I think you're gonna find
that this was very ill-advised.
Where are her friends?
- They're in the mess hall, sir.
- Well, you find them, now! Quietly.
What the hell's going on?
Smells like a double-cross, boss.
Where's the other one?
With the chair.
Don't ever touch me.
Ever!
- Wanna tell us what this is?
- Wanna tell me who you're working for?
Wren, they're not involved.
With what?
Do you know the penalty
for terrorist activity?
There are no terrorists in my crew.
Call, you got something to say?
I don't care if you knew.
You brought a terrorist on board.
As far as I am concerned,
you all die with her!
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I understand.
Christie.
Freeze!
Stop! Drop your weapons!
And you, drop that piece of shit!
Or I blow his head off!
- I can't do that, man.
- Drop it now!
They're attached.
You're all under arrest for a Code 8,
concealed weapons,
and a Code 12, which is murder!
Kiss my ass.
Put down your weapons!
Everybody OK?
Real easy, soldier boy.
Security!
There is a serious problem
in the mess hall.
You lie to me now, little girl,
I will cut your throat
and leave you to die. Understand?
- This is Security..
- Hello?
- We do not read you.
- We do not copy you. Please repeat.
- Hello?
Gediman!
He's conducting illegal experiments.
He's breeding..
- lce the goddamn mole!
- Listen! He is breeding an alien species.
If it gets loose,
it'll make the Lacerta Plague
- look like a fuckin' square dance.
- Shut up!
Listen.
Your attention, please.
Security breach.
Med-lab, level 15.
Girls, get back to the Betty.
The doctor and soldier boy can escort us.
- What about Vriess?
- Fuck Vriess.
Your attention, please.
Unauthorized opening of cage three.
Unauthorized opening of cages five,
seven, eight, ten.
- Move it!
- Evacuation.
- Go! Go! Go!
This is nota drill.
- Evacuation.
- Get on board!
Your attention, please.
Non-human presence detected.
Levels 21, 23,
27,
14,
level 38,
level 39.
Evacuation. Proceed to lifeboats.
This is nota drill.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Loll give you holes,
you slimy bastard!
Move it! Go!
- Final vessel ready.
- Get aboard!
Go!
Complete evacuation now.
Grenade.
Alert. Alert.
Evacuation incomplete.
Civilian presence detected
in area H. Warning:
Main vessel declared uninhabitable.
- Elgyn, come on, let's move, man.
- Yeah.
Elgyn! Elgyn, where are you!
Elgyn!
Easy, Hillard!
- Give me a hand here!
- Get him up!
- Come on, let's get him up!
- Move out of the way!
- Oh..
- Aw, shit.
- What the fuck did this!
- What's in this place!
Call, get down!
- What the fuck is that!
- Don't shoot!
It's in front of the hull!
What is that!
Come on, man. Time to go. Time to go!
Get back!
Time to go!
Come on, Call!
Open the goddamn door!
We can't open it!
We can't open the door!
We gotta go back!
I'm not going back. You go back.
What the fuck?
Was it everything you hoped for?
Leave him alone.
What do we do now, man?
What we were doing.
We get the hell outta here.
What if there's more?
I say we stay here, man.
Let the army guys deal.
Where the fuck are the army guys?!
They're dead.
Then we don't need this asshole.
Step back!
You!
Stop!
You got no authority!
Doctor, that thing
that killed my partner,
that's your pet science project?
Yes.
- Let me do him!
- I should do you right now.
How many more are there?
How many more are there?!
Twelve.
Twelve?
There'll be more.
So,
who do I have to fuck
to get off this boat?
I can get you off.
Maybe not the boat.
Let's go.
No, wait a second.
She was the host for these monsters.
Wren cloned her
because she had one in her.
She's not human.
She was part of his experiment
and she will turn on us in a second.
I don't give a shit what she is.
- We have to leave her.
- She comes.
We can't trust her.
I don't trust anyone.
If we're gonna survive this mess
we all stick together. Agreed?
Hillard, we gotta go.
It's not over.
We gotta get to the Betty.
Make a nice souvenir.
I can't believe you did that.
Did what?
Killed one.
It's like killing your own kind.
It was in my way.
Oh, man!
Who did you expect?
Santa Claus?
I thought you were toast,
for certain, man.
Where's Elgyn?
Shit.
- What if they're at the Betty?
- The activity was in
- the F sector. Why would they move?
- They won't.
If they send anyone out, it'll be
here.
Where the meat is.
Yeah.
To make decent time,
let's ditch the cripple.
- No of fence, man.
- None taken.
Nobody is left behind.
Not even you, Johner.
- What's the quickest way out?
- After the cooling tower, there's an elevator.
It goes from the top of the ship
down to level one.
- Straight to the dock.
- Sounds reasonable. Let's do it.
We're moving.
What?
The ship's moving. I can feel it.
The ship has stealth run.
There's no way you can tell.
She's right.
- It's been go since the attack.
- It's a standard emergency procedure.
Any serious problem,
the ship autopilots to home base.
And you were planning on telling us?
Nobody asked.
What's home base?
Earth.
- Great!
- Bastard!
Earth? I'd rather stay here
with the things, man.
How long until we get to Earth?
Three hours almost.
We gotta blow the ship.
Call! You're not blowing this ship.
Not while we're on it, OK?
You get out of the ship
you do as you please, all right?
Earth, man. What a shithole.
It's clear.
Hey, Ripley.
I heard you, like,
ran into these things before.
That's right.
Wow, man.
So, like,
what did you do?
I died.
Not that way!
Ripley.
Ripley, come on.
Ripley, we got no time
for sightseeing here.
Ripley, don't.
Kill..
me.
Don't do it.
Don't do what?
What's the big deal, man?
Fuckin' waste of ammo.
Let's go.
Must be a chick thing.
Am I dreaming? Isn't this
the shit we brought with us?
Yeah. It's the same shit.
It stinks in here.
Let's keep moving.
Get away from me!
Get away!
- Drop the rod.
- Get away from me!
Do it!
Get away from me.
Who are you people?
What's happening here?
Calm down.
We're getting the fuck
off this ghost ship.
Ship?
What ship?
Where am I?
I was in cryo, right?
On my way to Xarem.
Right? Work crew
for the nickel refinery.
I wake up..
I know I don't understand.
Oh, God. I saw..
I saw horrible things.
Look, you're coming with us.
It's too dangerous for you here.
Leave him.
Fuck you! We're not leaving him here.
He's got one inside.
I can smell it.
Inside me?
Inside me? What's inside me?
I don't want one of those things
birthing anywhere near my ass.
It's a bad risk.
What's inside me?
- We can't leave him.
- You came here to stop them spreading.
- What's inside me?
- Can't you stop it?
We've got no time.
The lab's out of order.
I could do him. Back of the head.
Painless. Might be the best way.
What's inside me?
There must be another way.
- What if we freeze him?
- What's in-fucking-side me?!
There's a monster in your chest.
These guys hijacked your ship,
and they sold your cryotube
to this.. human.
And he put an alien inside of you.
It's a really nasty one.
And in a few hours
it will burst its way
through your ribcage.
And you're gonna die.
Any questions?
Who are you?
I'm the monster's mother.
Look, if we freeze him on the Betty,
then the doctor can remove it later.
It's a mess down there.
Is this the only way?
Vriess!
We gotta lose the chair.
I know.
Kawlang manoeuvre, right?
Yeah. Just like old times.
Yeah.
Must be the cooling tanks.
Somebody must have opened the valves.
The nasties couldn't do that, could they?
We're at the bottom of the ship.
We have to go through the kitchen.
Maybe 90ft.
To the elevator on the other side.
I don't like it.
What's to like?
This sucks!
Are you sure about the distance?
Yes!
You ready to get wet, partner?
Yeah.
Hey, Christie, do me a favor.
When we hit the surface,
no backstroke, OK?
Jesus Christ!
It set a goddamn trap.
It's a goddamn ambush!
Distephano!
It won't break.
Give me your weapon.
You really are way too trusting.
No!
You killed her!
You bastard!
I'll get you!
Father, lock the door!
Christie!
Climb!
Climb! Come on!
Come on!
Move it!
It's jammed!
Get off!
Johner!
Help me!
Die, motherfucker!
Oh, man!
Real nice party, ain't it?
Christie!
No!
What are you doing?!
Don't do it!
Don't!
We can make it!
No!
Damn!
This way!
Come on!
Baby, am I glad to see you!
I thought that asshole got you.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
You got body armour on?
Yeah. Come on.
You took it in the chest.
I saw it.
You're a robot?
Son of a bitch!
- Little Call is full of surprises.
- I should've known.
No human being is that humane.
I thought synthetics were logical.
You just a big old psycho, girl!
You're a robot?
You're a Second Gen, aren't you?
You're an Auton?
Robots designed by robots, right?
I remember.
They were meant to revitalize
the synthetic industry.
Instead they buried it.
They don't like being told what to do.
Government ordered a recall.
Now, I heard..
I heard that only a few
had gotten out in time.
Man, I never thought
that I would see one!
Great. She's a toaster oven.
Can we leave now?
How long before we land?
Under two hours.
Vriess, you got a wrench?
Maybe she just needs an oil change.
Sorry. Access denied.
And I almost fucked it.
Like you never fucked a robot!
If Wren gets in the computer
he could really screw us.
- We gotta find a terminal.
- Not on this level.
We'd have to go back.
We can't go back.
- I don't know Wren's access codes.
- Help me.
Call..
No.
I can't.
You're the new model.
You can access the mainframe.
No, I can't.
I burned my modem. We all did.
Call,
you can still patch in manually.
You know that.
There's ports in the chapel, up there.
Call..
You're programmed for that?
Don't make me do this.
Don't make me make you.
I don't wanna go in there.
It's like my insides are liquid.
It's not real.
Get over it. You can blow this ship
before it reaches Earth,
and kill them all.
Just give us time to get out first.
Damn it!
Anything?
Hold on.
Breach in sector seven,
sector three.
Sector nine unstable.
Engines operating at 41%.
86 minutes until Earth dock.
We burn too much energy.
I can't make critical mass.
I can't blow it.
Then crash it.
I'm OK. I'm OK.
Really.
I feel good.
Ground level recalibrated.
Time till impact
43 minutes, 8 seconds.
Clear a path to the Betty.
And start her up.
Please wait.
Emergency override
in console 45V, level one.
It's Wren. He's almost at the Betty.
Father, locate the power drain. Report.
Father?
Father?!
Father's dead, asshole.
Intruder on level one.
All aliens, please proceed to level one.
You got a mean streak.
Damn it!
- Let me see.
- Don't touch me.
Come on.
You must think this is pretty funny.
I'm finding a lot of things funny lately.
But I don't think they are.
Why do you go on living?
How can you stand being what you are?
Not much choice.
At least there's a part
of you that's human.
I'm just..
Look at me.
I'm disgusting.
Why did you come here?
To kill you. Remember?
Before the recall,
I accessed the mainframe.
Every covert op the government
ever dreamed up is in there.
And this, you, the aliens,
even the crew from the Betty. I knew
if they succeeded it'd be the end of them.
Why do you care what happens to them?
Because I'm programmed to.
You're programmed to be an asshole?
You're the new asshole model
they're putting out?
Come on!
I guess we're almost there.
It's not so far now!
- I'm so tired!
- You can sleep when you die!
Oh, no. This is bad, right?
I think we're near the nest.
- We'll go another way.
- We don't have time.
- We got 90 minutes.
- Not any more.
What?
- What did you do, robot?
- Let's go. Come on.
Hey! You wanna die here,
with your family, that's cool.
But I plan to live past today.
If this hunk of plastic
pulls any shit,
I'm gonna kill her!
Kill you!
Does that compute?!
Or do I have to draw you a schematic?
Hey!
You want another souvenir?
How far are the docks?
100 yards.
Ripley?
Ripley?!
Come on!
Ripley, we have to go.
I hear them.
I hear them. They're so close.
- Ripley..
- it's the queen.
She's in pain.
Ripley!
Wait!
Oh, my God.
We gotta be moving.
The best thing we can do
is pray for a quick death.
Come on.
It's not right.
I've been saying that all day.
Call, I need you to patch into the ship,
and open the hatch.
Johner, we should put Purvis
in the freezer now.
All right, little buddy.
Nap time.
Oh..
Nobody moves, or I put a cap
right where this little droid's brain is.
Distephano, take the weapons.
Excuse me, sir, but.. fuck you!
Fine. Then I kill her,
and you kill me, and we all die,
and nobody goes home!
Now drop the weapon!
Then this little synthetic bitch
is gonna plug into the Auriga,
and take us back to home base,
according to standard procedure.
No, she's not!
Are you crazy?
You'd bring those things back to Earth?
- Haven't you been paying attention?
- Ah, the intellectual speaks!
- Listen, if..
- Don't you ever shut up?
Why does nobody listen to me?
I told you,
at first everything was normal.
The queen laid her eggs.
But then she started to change.
She added a second cycle so..
So..
this time there is no host.
There are no eggs.
There is only her womb
and the creature inside.
That is Ripley's gift to her:
A human reproductive system.
She is giving birth for you, Ripley.
And now she is perfect!
You.. are..
a beautiful,
beautiful
butterfly.
No!
No! No..
Ah, look,
your beautiful, beautiful little baby.
Look, it thinks you're its mother.
Come on.
Civilian vessel on-line.
Emergency departure authorized.
All right, she's hot. I'll open the air locks.
Pull the holding clamps.
Right, I, uh, just need to find, uh..
the, uh.. the vertical thrust lock.
- Are you sure you can fly this thing?
- Yes!
Launch status is go!
No!
Ripley!
Hey.
- I thought you were dead.
- Yeah, I get that a lot.
- Why are we still here?
- I-l.. I'm just..
finding the.. manual override.
- For Christ's sake!
- Hey, Ripley.
Good memory. Excuse me.
- Ripley's back.
- Is that it?
Nope.
You can't fly one of these things?
Are you kidding?
This piece of shit is older than I am.
Goddamn it!
We still got breach. The hatch.
I closed it.
- I've fixed it a hundred times!
- I'll get it.
Approaching Earth's atmosphere.
Window of departure now46 seconds.
Call?
We have to go.
Call.
We've gotta get out of here.
Window of departure now 20 seconds.
Grab on to something, Call.
We're outta here.
Come on, baby.
This thing is gonna fall apart!
Pressure's unstable!
Go help Call turn on the auxiliary pump!
Distephano?
Come on! Step on it!
Hey! I'm not the mechanic here, lronside!
I mostly just hurt people!
Shit!
Call!
Call, get back up here!
Call! Call!
Ripley!
Hey, Ripley!
Johner, you son of a bitch!
Get on it, bastard!
What am I supposed to do?
Grab the sticks!
Put her down.
Ripley!
I'm sorry.
USM Auriga wil limpact in
five seconds. Four,
three,
two,
one.
Thank you.
- What's burning?!
- Us!
Shit! You're right!
You did it.
You saved the Earth.
You sound disappointed.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
I didn't expect it to be.
What happens now?
I don't know.
I'm a stranger here myself.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326