Woody Allen: I said this in a movie once:
Everyone knows the same truth
and our lives consist of
how we choose to distort it.
Bill Pullman: I am kind of amazed at what
Lawrence and Richard are doing
because they are walking
into some pretty prickly arenas
and they have no armour other
than their own mental faculties.
Werner Herzog: I think what these
two men are doing out there
promoting a scientific
world view
is something of great value
because it is part of
what humanity's all about.
To be curious, to understand
what is the real world
surrounding us.
And this is what I love
about science is that
it's knowledge
and knowledge is power
and it empowers you
and it frees you
because then you're not stuck.
You're no longer stuck where you've been
or where somebody else has been stuck.
There are no scientific authorities.
There are scientific experts.
Richard knows a lot about zoology;,
I know a lot about physics.
But there's no one whose views
are not subject to question.
Science just seeks the truth without
prejudice, for better or worse.
It doesn't say 'Should I find
this out?? It says 'Can I??
And that's the point about beliefs:
they don't change the facts.
Facts, if you're rational,
should change your beliefs.
Throughout history new discoveries.
Have challenged existing beliefs.
Religion is no exception.
Religion is just like
any other topic
and should not be
sacrosanct at all.
You should be able
to discuss religion.
Why not?.
Sarah Silverman: I think religion
should be open to discussion.
I think everything
should be. I think
when you make things taboo
even when feel like
you're protecting it
it's not for the greater good.
We cannot close down
a conversation
about a set of
beliefs that lead to actions
which affect all of us.
All this stuff I was
taught about evolution
and big bang theory and all that
is lies straight
from the pit of hell.
This is the trouble with ethics and
morality and the big questions
and the fact that religions think
they own that conversation.
Quite the contrary.
They kill that conversation.
Bill Pullman:
And I think we follow people
who have courage, you know,
to think about things
that we haven't
thought about before
and in these times
where intolerance
is kind of championed
I'm pretty impressed
that someone is
taking on the quest.
That's what I get
from these guys:
The permission to
question everything.
Lawrence Krauss: Richard, ten years ago,
I asked you the question
in the popular writing and
speaking that you do which is:
what's more important
in some sense
if you had a choice which is to
explain science or destroy religion?.
Oh I think that
they go together
because 'destroy religion'
makes it sound negative.
Yeah.
To me it's a positive thing.
Science is wonderful.
Science is beautiful.
And religion is not wonderful.
It's not beautiful.
It gets in the way. There are all
sorts of other things wrong with it
but I mostly care about
truth, the beauty of truth,
the poetry of reality
which is science
and the fact that religion
as a scientific explanation...
It is a competing
scientific explanation...
It's so dull, it's so
boring, it's so petty.
It's wrong too.
And it's also wrong, yes.
Which I think is a bit more...
More important, yeah.
I think the same as you.
I want people to understand
how the universe really works.
As an aside, ultimately,
is this other incompatibility
between science and religion
that when empirical evidence tells you
something you have to accept it...
When you give up that by saying 'I can
believe this myth and fairy tale'
then it opens you up
to lots of other things.
So it's not innocuous. Inevitably when
you have to deal with the real world.
You inevitably make
bad decisions.
If we can get people
to believe that
then it's easier...
Or should be easier to convince
people that evolution is true
because the evidence
is so strong.
Once you tell them
the evidence for evolution
they say 'Oh right, okay.
So much for God.'
Well tonight, Richard is in
Sydney while I'm in Canberra
and he's going to debate on a
television program called Q&A.
The Archbishop of Sydney
and I'm here in Canberra debating
in a Muslim debate initiative.
We're both sort of
launching out
against the forces of evil
in different places
and that poetry was
to compelling to resist.
As far as I can see
this event has been advertised
only in the Muslim community.
Except for the few people
I've told about it
no one will know about it
except the Muslim community
so it'll be
an interesting audience.
Oh look over there.
That's fascinating.
That may be our audience
right there, by the way.
That could be it.
Hi, how ya doin'?.
- Nice to see you.
- Morning Professor.
- How are you?.
- Hi.
I'm the uh... Uthman. Uthman Badar.
Oh okay.
You're the other person that's
going to talk. That's right.
It's interesting... I looked online and
didn't see any advertisements for it.
It'll be interesting to see.
We'll see how that goes.
But I have a rule... if there's less than
five people, we just go for coffee.
Does that sound good?.
I'm gonna sit in the back now
and read my Bible
which is...
I just thought I'd pick
it up for inspiration.
Christopher always inspires me.
Richard Dawkins:
Cardinal George Pell is the
most senior Roman
Catholic in Australia.
He's the Archbishop of Sydney
and I know rather little
else about him I'm afraid.
And he is sometimes talked about
as a possible candidate for Pope.
I have always refused to debate
religious fundamentalists.
It is my understanding that a
Cardinal of the Roman Catholic Church
is not a fundamentalist.
If he is, I've made a mistake.
MC: We're very excited to have these
two gentlemen here this evening
for this discussion.
We know them already but please
let us introduce them properly
and make them feel very welcome.
Please help me welcome
the author of The God Delusion
the evolutionary biologist
Richard Dawkins.
The Archbishop of Sydney
please welcome
Cardinal George Pell.
(Cheering)
Woman: Five, four, three...
(Theme music plays)
(Audience applauds)
George Pell, do you accept
that humans evolved from apes?.
Yeah probably.
From neanderthals yes.
From neanderthals?.
Probably. Why from neanderthals?.
Who else would you suggest?.
Neanderthals were our cousins.
We're not descended from them.
These extant cousins?.
Where would I find a neanderthal
today if they're my cousins?.
They're not extant. They're extinct.
That's my point.
Your point is that
because they're not...
That because they're extant
they can't be our cousins?.
I'm really am not much fussed.
That's very clear.
Ignoring the limitations
of science
also leads to sloppy
and arbitrary science.
Agood example is the field
of quantum mechanics.
The evidence of logic derives
from the evidence of reality.
Is it logical that I can be
in two places at once?. No.
But if I am an electron,
I certainly can be.
Because while you refer to quantum
mechanics, I actually understand it.
Most evolutionary
biologists today
don't believe that.
Don't believe what?.
They don't believe in
this crude fundamentalist version of
random selection that you propose.
I do not propose it
and I strongly deny
that evolution is
random selection.
This idea that we should
challenge our beliefs
I agree, in some areas,
and this is the point
I tried to touch upon the difference
between science and religion...
Only when you appreciate the
difference can you ascertain whether
different propositions
apply or not.
Anything about higher truth
morality for example
do you want me to challenge my belief
every day that murder is wrong?.
Well if any of you stopped
believing in God I would ask you,
would you go out tomorrow
and murder your neighbour?.
Well some of you say yes.
Evolution is
non-random selection.
Oh there's a purpose
to it, is there?.
No.
But... (Audience laughing)
Could you explain
what non-random means?.
Yes of course I could.
That's my life's work.
((Laughter, applause)
No idea should be
above ridicule.
Ridicule is a very
important tool.
And why should religion
not be subject to ridicule?.
If politics is subject
to ridicule, if science,
if sex, if everything else in the
world is subject to ridicule
as a way of illuminating
reality, why shouldn't religion?.
It's part of being human
to ask why we exist.
Richard: The question why
is not necessarily a question
that deserves to be answered.
There are all sorts of
questions that people can ask
Iike 'What is
the colour of jealousy??
That's a silly question.
Exactly.
Why?. is a silly question.
You can ask 'What are
the factors that led
to something coming
into existence??
That's a sensible question.
But 'What is the purpose
of the universe??
is a silly question.
It has no meaning.
And so I hope that every student,
who ever goes to
university at one point
in their life has the
opportunity to have something
that is at the heart
of their being
something so central to their
being that if they lose it
they won't feel that they're human
anymore, to be proved wrong.
Because that's the liberation
that science provides:
The realisation that
to assume the truth,
to assume the answer
before you ask the questions
leads you nowhere.
We do have a scientific
understanding of why we're here
and we therefore have to
make up our own meaning to life.
We have to stand up,
look the world
in the face, face up to the fact
that we are not going to last
forever, we have to make
the most of the short time
that we have on this planet,
we have to make this planet
as good as we possibly can
and try to leave it a better
place than we found it.
And if we live in a world where certain
things are not subject to question,
we live in a world
where thinking has stopped.
((People applauding)
MC: Final results
of tonight's vote:
W;ith more than 20,000
of you voting, we have 76%%%
saying no, religious belief
does not make the world
a better place.
Please thank our special guests,
Professor Richard Dawkins
and Cardinal George Pell.
(Applause)
((No audible dialogue)
* Hey now little speedy head *
* The read on the speed meter says *
* You have to go to task in the city *
* Where people drown and people serve *
* Don't be shy you just deserve *
* It's only just *
* Light years to go *
Richard: Well I got
thoroughly fed up with
BBC-type interviews
where you have a chairman
in the middle
and you get an interesting
conversation going on between...
there might be five people
around the table,
and A and B are having
an interesting conversation
and so the chairman suddenly says 'and
what do you think about this C??
totally breaking the flow,
spoiling the conversation
all in the interest of balance and
things like that and it occurred to me,
why on earth do we bother with chairmen?.
They're not necessary.
Certainly my recent encounter
with the Archbishop of Canterbury
in the Sheldonian Theatre
in Oxford,
that was completely ruined by the
chairman, who was a philosopher
and felt it was his role
to clarify things
and, of course,
that meant obscuring things.
* We're closer now * "
* Than light years to go *
Lawrence: Yeah I think
it's... I think conversations
and conversations
that aren't planned
are fascinating for people
to watch and listen to.
Richard: Yes.
Lawrence: I think it works.
((Crowd murmuring)
Woman: We should probably go.
Richard: Okay.
So to fill it up...
we'd sometimes begin late...
From my experience, if it's really
full it begins a little late.
Usually three
or four minutes, yeah.
((Indistinct chatter)
Woman: Would you welcome these two
great scientists to the stage?.
Please join me... Richard
Dawkins and Lawrence Krauss.
(Audience applauding)
I think it's
appropriate to begin...
Did any of you see Q&A?.
I was amazed... Cardinal Pell
who was on the programme
manifestly didn't
understand evolution.
Actually he didn't manifestly
understand anything
as far as I could see.
Why don't you elaborate a little
bit about that real problem?.
Because I think it's
a fascinating issue of
if speciation occurs,
if species change,
was there a first person?.
At first sight, it seems obvious
that there has to have
been a first person
and there has to have
been a first rabbit
and a first rhinoceros
and things.
After all people are
people, aren't they?.
And their ancestors
were not people.
If you go back sufficiently
far, your ancestor was a fish.
Mustn't there have been a
time when so to speak,
the last homo erectus parents gave
birth to the first homo sapiens baby?.
And the answer is no.
There never was a first person.
There never was a first
rabbit or first rhinoceros
because every organism ever born
belonged to the same
species as its parents.
And yet because
it was so gradual
and because it was so slow
not only was our 200 million
great grandparent a fish
but if you go back
further still
they were worms and so on.
And one suggestion that's
been made is that people
really have difficulty
grasping the idea
that animals turn into other
animals so imperceptibly
that you can hardly notice it.
It's not actually
that paradoxical.
It all happened
very very gradually.
And you can think of
parallels like the fact that
you can't see the hour
hand on your watch moving.
At some point we cease to think
of ourselves as middle-aged
and we start to think
of ourselves as old.
But nobody ever goes to bed
middle-aged and wakes up
and says 'I'm old.'
Lawrence: We had a
meeting at my institute
where we were trying to get
at the origin of life
and it's fascinating to learn
how much closer we're getting.
I don't know if you think we'll get to
the beginning in your lifetime or my lifetime.
Well it's an exciting thought and
I'm pretty hopeful that we might.
You'll never be able to prove
it for certain I suspect
but to come up with
a plausible theory
that people say 'Of course!.
That's so elegant
and so simple.'
Either it's true or it ought to be true.
I mean it could...
I think the key point
is plausibility.
It is amazing
and fascinating to me
and worth celebrating that the laws
of physics as we now understand them
have given us a plausible
story to answer questions.
That's amazing. Which is, how could
something arise from nothing?.
How could a complex
universe arise
from a universe in which
there was nothing?.
No particles and maybe
not even any space?.
And it's amazing to me
in cosmology now
that we are beginning
to get back and realise
that even something as
complex as a whole universe
could plausibly be created.
But that's all we ever claim.
And yet whenever we claim
that, we are called strident.
Do you notice that?.
Yes I do.
It came up in
the Q&A debate
and I tried to
very briefly expound
Lawrence's thesis
that you could get something
from literally nothing.
The audience just laughed. It
was obviously to them absurd.
How could you possibly
get something from nothing?.
It does violate common sense.
But as I said earlier this evening,
you can't go by common sense.
If we could do things
by common sense
we wouldn't need physicists.
((Laughter)
Common sense,
of course, comes from
what was necessary
for our brains to survive
in the pleistocene of Africa.
So they had to know
how to catch a buffalo
and how to find a water hole
and how to climb a tree
when being pursued
by a lion or something.
So our brains were never shaped by
natural selection to understand
either quantum mechanics,
the theory of the very small,
or relativity the theory
of the very fast.
And it's actually an astonishing
compliment to the human brain
that at least some humans
are capable of understanding.
No it is really remarkable that we've
been able to get as far as we can,
but you hit on another point:
Our brains not only
didn't evolve to understand
those aspects of the universe that
it couldn't experience directly
but another aspect of the universe it
can't experience directly is long time.
Absolutely.
And I think that's another reason
why evolution is
such a hard concept.
Because we can just see... we have
a slice of 1 00 years or less.
We can do seconds,
minutes, hours, days,
years, centuries...
Even millennia
we have trouble with.
You cannot grasp
the immensity of time
that is 1 00 million years.
Exactly.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very very much.
**
* The walls abandon shape *
* They got a cheshire cat grin *
* All blurring into one *
* This place is on a mission *
Lawrence: Alot of people think that just
because there's a lot we don't understand
at the edge of science that everything
we know is going to go out the window
and that's not true.
Evolution happened.
The big bang happened.
If I take a ball and drop it,
it's going to fall.
There are lots
of things we do know.
For me the only
solution I can see
is to try and educate people.
Because if you don't
have an informed public
that's the greatest
threat to democracy.
So it's incumbent on scientists
to do a much better job
and then it's up to the public
to make the decision.
They can decide that they don't want
to do anything about global warming.
But they should at least be presented with
the evidence and understand the facts.
MC: Ladies and gentlemen,
the dynamic duo of science!.
* Before you run away from me *
* Beore you're lost between the notes *
* The beat goes round and round *
Richard: It's such a privilege
to be alive in the 21 st century
and to look out at the stars
to look down a microscope, to
look down an electron microscope
to look into a single cell
and see the prodigious
stupeying complexity
of a single cell and then
realize that there are
trillions of those cells
in your body
all conspiring together
to produce a working machine
which can walk and run
and eat and have sex and think.
What a privilege it is for each
of us to have in our heads
an organ which is capable of
constructing a model
of the universe.
It is sad that that model
will die when our brain dies
but my goodness what a privilege
it is before we do die.
* Jigsaw's falling into place *
*There is nothing to explain *
* You eye each other as you pass *
* She looks back you look back *
* Not just once *
* Not just twice *
* Wish away the nightmare *
* You got a light you can feel it on your back *
(Audience cheering) Stephen Colbert:
Welcome back everybody. My guest tonight:
please welcome, Lawrence Krauss.
Hey Dr. Krauss, thank you
so much for coming on.
All right Sir.
Why does what you're saying
have to be an attack on my God?.
It doesn't have to be an attack...
But that's all you've done.
You've attacked my God
for the last six minutes.
No, you have. All I've said
is you don't need him.
That's an attack.
We've changed our minds about the universe.
We've learned that the universe is more
remarkable than anything we ever thought before
and in fact
changing your mind and, in fact,
being wrong is wonderful.
You should try it sometime.
It's really amazing.
Hmm-mm. It means
that... it means that...
If there is no God, okay
if there is
no thing called God
if he is nothing, can't
something come from him?.
(Audience laughing, cheering)
Lawrence Krauss,
thank you so much.
* You can feel it on your back *
* Jigsaw's falling *
* Into place *
Lawrence: ((Chuckling)
This makes my day.
Miley Cyrus just tweeted
a picture of me
along with my quote
about stars where I say
'Forget Jesus. Stars died
so you could be born.'
And underneath,
she put the word 'beautiful'.
And she seems to have gotten
a lot of hate mail for that.
I actually think they don't
understand this too because,
you know, they think she's
saying the quote is beautiful
but clearly what she's saying is
that the picture of me is beautiful.
(Audience applauding)
Lawrence: I think we both agree
that what people want to do
is they want to believe, to take
that line from The X-F;iles...
(Audience laughing)
They want to believe in
believing and so most people
of faith, I think,
in our society
naturally pick and
choose from the doctrine
those things they find
absolutely ridiculous
and throw out.
Yeah.
And the Pope would say
that's not palatable.
And I would tend
to agree with the Pope.
I think, if you can't
believe some of this stuff
and need to throw it out,
just forget the whole thing.
Yeah.
That would be my view
and I suspect that
well there are, what, 535
members of the U.S. congress
and 1 has said that he doesn't
believe in a supreme being?.
That's statistically
not possible.
(Audience laughing)
I mean
a fair number of those members of congress
presumably have had some sort of education.
There have got to be
a very substantial number
of atheistic members
of the United States congress
probably more than a couple
of hundred would be my guess.
And yet they cannot admit it
and so in order to get elected
you have got to lie
about your belies.
I think that's right and I think
it's good to call them on it.
I disagree with you
slightly maybe because
I've spent a lot more
time in this country.
I would say
if people don't hold their
religion on their sleeve
then it's not relevant to them
then it's not in
the public domain
and journalists needn't
ask questions about it.
But if they do hold their
religion on their sleeve
then it becomes in the public
domain and it becomes
appropriate for journalists
to bring it up.
Because then it's an action.
They're saying 'Elect me
because I'm a person of faith.'
But I'm coming back
to the nub of the
question which is that
even if they don't take
any action based upon it...
I mean, an extreme example
which I actually published
on a blog somewhere
was a hypothetical doctor
who doesn't believe
in the sex theory
of reproduction
believes in
the stork theory of...
of reproduction.
I thought I was pushing
to the limit,
I assumed that everybody would
agree with me at least here,
that you would not wish
to consult such a doctor.
Not a bit of it.
I was kicked around the room.
'The doctor's private beliefs
are his private beliefs.
They're no business of yours.
So long as he can
take your appendix out
or whatever he has to do
then it doesn't matter that
he doesn't believe in sex.
He believes in
the stork theory.'
That's where we're
disagreeing because...
Because the stork theory is relevant
to his career as a doctor...
Make him an eye doctor then.
Then I'd have to say
for a politician
(Audience laughing)
I think there are rights to privacy.
I mean, I think
if someone believes
that it's okay for them
to have sex with animals
I shouldn't ask that question as long as
they don't make it a campaign platform.
And and and...
And so I happen to think that
there some a right to privacy
in the sense that, if you don't
wear it on your sleeve,
and these candidates do wear it
on their sleeve, including Obama.
And I think once
you bring that up
then it becomes fair game.
Now let's end with...
Because you pointed out
that there's one
member of congress...
And I didn't know there were that many...
(Audience laughing)
who argue that he doesn't
believe in a supreme being.
I just wrote an article
about a study
that's been done by a
group of psychologists
in Canada
and the United States...
It's just been published...
That asks what groups
people distrust
and it turns out
the group that is distrusted
the most are atheists.
Well they're not quite the most.
They're on par with rapists.
(Audience laughs)
And I wonder
if you could comment.
Well that seems to me
to be an adequate explanation
for why so many members
of the United States congress
are obviously lying
about their private beliefs.
I mean, if you're
on a par with rapists...
I suspect that
we've already had
in this country quite a number of
atheist presidents. I suspect.
It wouldn't surprise me in the
least if Kennedy was an atheist.
It wouldn't surprise me
if Clinton was an atheist.
if Obama's an atheist.
But you cannot admit it or you
simply don't get elected.
I would like to start
a campaign for
Iame-duck presidents and senators
and people to say
'Okay I'm not standing
for election anymore.
I'm an atheist. I've been
an atheist all along.'
(Audience applauding)
((Man over telephone)
((Indistinct)
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
((Indistinct conversation)
And here we've got
Darren waiting for you.
Hi how are you doing?.
Hi Lawrence. Darren. How's it going?.
Hi nice to see you.
Woman: So if you want
to have a seat...
((Indistinct)
She said 'It's never
been so hard
never been so challenging.'
Oh no.
((Man over telephone)
((Iindistinct)
Okay we're heading out eh?.
Yes let's go. Yep.
We're set up.
What do you know?. It looks like
a real place to interview.
And so these mics work?.
I don't have to wear one?.
That's right. That's good.
Man: Ready in three, two...
(Theme music plays)
Lawrence Krauss welcome to One Plus One.
It's great to be here.
Albert Einstein was once
quoted as saying
'If you can't explain it
to a six-year-old,
you don't
understand it yourself.'
Your latest book
A Universe From Nothing
deals with some
fairly weighty topics.
How would you explain
to a six-year-old
that the universe
came from nothing?.
Oh well...
((Man chattering)
I see what you mean
but it's very unjust.
I mean, telling children
they're going to hell
is surely by any standards wicked.
I mean that's just evil.
But I am not
doing anything remotely
comparable to that.
What I'm doing is telling
children 'think for yourself.'
'Look for the evidence.'
I'm not saying 'This is the way it is.
Youd better believe it or else.'
Well it's funny
because six-year-olds
are a lot less biased
than adults often
and the neat thing is
I'd try and tell them that
nothing is not exactly
what they thought it was.
It was a little bit different.
That the laws of physics
tell you that even empty space is much
more interesting than you thought.
Empty space is a boiling
bubbling brew of stuff
that's popping in and out
of existence every second.
And what's more amazing is that
we've learned that if you take
just a bit of space and get
rid of all the particles
and all the radiation
and everything
that it still weighs something
and we don't understand why.
Lawrence Krauss, thanks for
joining us on One Plus One.
Thank you very much.
It's been a pleasure.
(Theme music plays)
Excellent. Wonderful.
Thank you very much. Thanks a lot.
It was nice doing it.
There's a dot.
((Man continues indistinct)
What a disgusting idea.
I mean, the idea that the
only way to forgive somebody
is to have a scapegoat,
to have your own son
tortured and killed
because there's
no other way to forgive.
The idea that there
can be no forgiveness
without bloodshed,
without punishment
is an ancient idea
and it's a horrible one.
In the particular case of the
doctrine of original sin
the original sin is suppose to
have been committed by Adam
who as we now know
never existed.
So we now have the preposterous
idea that Jesus was sacrificed
the scapegoat was sacrificed
for the sin of
a nonexistent forbear.
((Man speaking)
((Over intercom, indistinct)
That's the fellow who finally let me in.
He was out having a phone call.
Yes yeah. Hi I'm Jenny.
How are you?.
Hi. Good. I'm glad there's someone
here to actually do this.
Man: 26 to 8.
Hop over there Lawrence.
There you go.
It's good to see you again.
It is 26 to 8 on 702.
Lawrence Krauss is our guest.
His latest book is called
A Universe From Nothing.
You say the universe continues
to get weirder. Are there moments when
we might break through and things
suddenly make more sense for you?.
'cause some of the stuff you
do really upsets some people
and really inspires other people
to back their own belies.
Would you prefer that it was just
an esoteric academic discussion?.
No it's not esoteric.
These are wonderful things.
Everyone should be
talking about them.
It's some of the most beautiful ideas
and discoveries humans have ever made.
And if it upsets people,
how can learning about
how the universe really
works upset people?.
And it is a shame that it does.
Instead of being threatened
or having our faith threatened
by the discoveries of science
we should realise that we
should force our beliefs
to conform to the evidence of reality
rather than the other way around
and we should take joy in the
fact that we are actually here
in this random moment able
to even ask those questions
and get close enough
to the answers.
We don't have the ultimate answers.
I don't claim in the book
that I have
the ultimate answers.
I talk about what's plausible and
the fact that we're learning
we're getting closer
and closer to even
potentially answering
these ultimate questions
is something that
we should all celebrate.
People shouldn't be
threatened by science.
((Man continues, indistinct)
Um no, I think that's fine.
Thank you very much.
Well it's been nice
talking to you.
All right. Bye bye.
Lawrence Krauss as always a
pleasure speaking to you.
Lawrence: Same here. Thanks.
((Religious programme on TV)
This is the nicest thing I've
seen in any library recently.
Can I do that?.
Is that Pooh over there?.
I got to go...
Man: Professor Dawkins,
what do you see
or rather hope for the
future of atheism
in the public sphere?.
My hope for the future of atheism is
that it will no longer be necessary.
We don't call ourselves
a-Thor-ists and a-Zeus-ists
and a-Leprechaun-ists
because it's not necessary.
And my hope is that
the day will come
when it's simply
taken for granted
that everybody doesn't
believe in yahweh
any more than they believe
in Thor and Jupiter.
I think there's some indication
that the religious lobby is
getting increasingly desperate
and is increasing
the venom and the vitriol
with which they fight back.
And I think what we may be seeing is
the beginning of the death throes.
And when you see a wounded
animal in its death throes
it tends to lash out.
((People clamouring)
((Shouting)
Excuse me, gentlemen,
can you be quiet for one second?.
Nice to see all you
fine, strapping,
young, gentlemen here to
protest for your religion.
But like I've been asking,
where are all of your women?.
((People cheering)
((Chanting) Where are all the women?.
Where are all the women?.
Men: ((Chanting)
Infidels! Infidels!
Infidels! Infidels! Infidels!
* Follow me don't follow me *
* I've got my spine I've got my orange crush *
* Collar me don't collar me *
* We are agents of the free *
* I've had my fun and now it's time to serve *
* Your conscience overseas *
* Coming in fast over me *
This is a demonstration of what a
secular society is supposed to be ((People cheering)
It's not one that
excludes religious people.
It's one that is inclusive
of all points of view.
Woman:
It's definitely exciting.
It's definitely exciting
and it re-enthuses you
to go out and do your thing
and stick to your guns.
We've made so many
amazing friends.
Man: Fantastic people here.
* orange crush *
* collar me don't collar me *
Oh I've talked to
all sorts of people.
Sit down with someone and you get up
a conversation without any trouble.
They're the friendliest
lot you'll ever meet.
* I've had my fun *
* And now it's time to serve *
* Your conscience overseas *
* Coming in fast over me *
Lawrence: There is a similarity...
My friend Richard Dawkins
who is here was kind enough to
write the afterword for the book
and he made a wonderful comparison
which is that there's some similarity.
Beore Darwin,
life was a miracle.
You couldn't ask 'Where did the diversity
of life come from?? It was a miracle.
It was designed.
What Darwin showed
were very simple
laws of biology.
Natural selection and genetic
mutation essentially
could produce all
the diversity of life,
the complexity we now see,
from very simple beginnings
with no miracle.
Now at the time he did it,
did it prove it?. No.
But it was plausible. Now there's
been 1 50 years of proof.
Now we take it the next step. Do we know
how the first forms of life started?.
Absolutely not.
But it's certainly plausible
that given everything we know
about genetics biochemistry
that chemistry by natural
processes can turn into biology.
Do we know that?. No.
But it's plausible.
And that's worth celebrating...
That you don't need miracles.
And the same is true
for the universe.
We've taken from biology
to that fundamental question
which was the last bastion
for many people of God:
'Why is there something rather than
nothing?? And said 'You don't need him.'
If this is the case,
and our universe
just popped into existence,
and space and time
were created in our universe the
moment it came into existence
along with the laws
of physics we measure
then there's an object,
if you want to call it that,
that is greater
than our universe.
We call it in physics now
the multiverse,
in which case there are
many possible universes.
From a philosophical
perspective
people have a problem with a
universe that had a beginning.
That's why they invented God:
'cause they want something eternal,
with no cause... first cause,
prime mover... you pick
your philosophy or theology.
The point is that the multiverse
now serves the role
of the prime mover.
From a philosophical
perspective
It could be eternal and
certainly beyond our universe.
But the thing I also want to point out... I've
debated with Christian apologists often
and they say 'You invented the
multiverse cause you don't like God.'
Well it's true,
I don't like God.
But the multiverse was proposed
because the laws of physics
are driving us to it.
I don't even like the multiverse but
if nature tells me that's the case
and the laws of physics are
accidental, I've got to live with it.
So to conclude,
I've told you today the
universe can come from nothing.
More importantly I've told you
that you were far more insignificant
than you ever thought
and that's what I want you
to celebrate here today.
But instead of taking...
People say science takes away
spiritual fulfilment
and wonder and awe
and happiness.
You should be happier because you're
insignificant and the future's miserable
'cause you're here today
and you're endowed
by evolution with a conscience
and an intelligence
and you can ask these questions.
So instead of being depressed
and requiring meaning
in the universe
beyond your own existence
you create your own meaning
and enjoy your brief moment in the sun.
Thank you very much.
But the problem is that
most people, most of the time
are desperate to
believe ridiculous
and divisive ideas for
patently emotional reasons.
And while rarely explicit
what they're really
worried about is death.
When we're arguing about teaching
evolution in the schools
I would argue that we are
really arguing about death.
It seems to me
the only reason why
any religious person
cares about evolution
is because if their holy books
are wrong about our origins
they're very likely wrong about
our destiny after death.
Ex-Muslims like me
in Europe and in North America
are growing in number.
We give speeches, we publish
articles and books
and we communicate
with one another.
'Infidel' was the
epithet, an insult
that was thrown at me
over and over again
by family and former
Muslim friends.
It is a label that I now wear
with pride and joy.
We're in a brand new
age for religions.
For millennia, religions
did not have to worry
about the flock
acquiring lots of information
about other religions
or about their own religion.
These religions evolved
culturally in a world
of easy-to-maintain ignorance.
But the new transparency
of information brought about
by technology, cell phones,
the Internet and all the rest
is the first
really drastic change
in the epistemological
environment that religions
have had to face
in several millennia.
Thanks for your attention.
Man: To many he's more than
an evolutionary biologist.
He's a champion
of science and reason.
He's convinced many around the
world that it's more than okay
to come out as an atheist.
Please welcome to the stage
our final speaker of day two
of the Global Atheists
Convention, Richard Dawkins.
(Audience cheering)
Richard: I want to take
back intelligent design.
I want to take back
other hijacked words.
Just as the feminists have
rallied around the phrase
'take back the night'
maybe we should take back
intelligent design
in the true sense of the word.
Let's take back morality.
Let's redesign our morality
rather than trying to read
what's right and wrong
in a 3,000 year-old book.
Religion has hijacked
morality for centuries.
Let's take it back
and intelligently design it.
Let's intelligently
design our lives
rather than be dictated to
by priests and mullahs.
Let's intelligently
design our future
using the gift of foresight
something that never
existed before brains...
And for practical purposes that
means human brains... evolved.
The ability to design
is one of the crowning
glories of our species.
Bridges, planes, buildings,
all sorts of
ingenious contraptions.
The essence of design, in
this true sense of the word,
is deliberate foresight.
Human designers can
look into the future
and see the possible mistakes
see the possible pitfalls
try things out in imagination...
Above all, look into the
future, which is something
natural selection cannot do.
This is one of the major
misunderstandings of evolution.
People are so used to the idea
that natural selection produces
apparently good design
that they think that natural
selection must be capable
of peering into the
future of taking steps
to stop the species going
extinct, for example.
Never happens. It cannot happen.
Nature cannot plan
for the future;,
the human brain can.
We can look at trends
in the present
and extrapolate into the future.
We can foresee
possible scenarios
that might lead to
our species going extinct
and take steps to avoid it.
Thank you very much.
((People shouting, clamouring)
Man: How many people do you
have to kill to be a murderer?.
Just one. Just one.
How many lies do you have to
tell to be a liar?. Just one.
The Bible says...
The Bible says 'You shall not take
the name of the Lord in vain.'
((Shouting)
What I find humorous is you will
not curse Allah or Muhammad
but Jesus is in every one
of your conversations.
((Clamouring)
Science means knowledge?.
When you take the name of my
saviour Jesus Christ in vain
you do it with
an inherent knowledge
an intuitive knowledge
that it is wrong
that it is born
out of your sinful heart.
My friends what I'm saying
is you're not just atheists
you're liars.
((People booing, jeering)
((No audible dialogue)
People: Whoo!
Lawrence: I guess the best
part of communicating
is the excitement.
Science turns us on. Science is fun.
Science excites us.
You can't communicate unless you're
excited but on the other hand
I feel it's so
fascinating for me
that I want to tell
people about it.
Carl Sagan said
'When you're in love
you want to tell the world.'
I'm in love with science
and I have to tell the world.
But we mustn't run away with the
idea that science is just fun.
Science is hard.
Yeah.
And so it's not fun in the sense
that it's just sort of...
Easy and you can laze around doing it.
It is hard.
It's hard work.
But it's worth it.
Lawrence: Something I didn't
know... I don't know if you knew...
That the Royal Society has a
Patron Saint: St. Andrew.
St. Andrew?.
Yeah.
Why not Doubting Thomas?.
He'd be the proper Patron Saint of Science.
That'd be perfect. "
Doubting Thomas because
that's what it's all about.
Lawrence: For me, this is the
legacy of modern civilisation.
This is what it's all about
and this is the legacy
that's worth preserving
and sharing more broadly
and it's under attack.
Richard: Yes, I see the history
of science, modern science,
as weaning off
the wisdom of old books
and onto the wisdom
of observation and experiment.
There's a lovely story about
Galileo being
visited by somebody
and Galileo showed this person
something through his telescope
and it contradicted
what he thought before
and eventually he said
'Mr. Galileo your demonstration
is so convincing
that were it not
that Aristotle positively
states the contrary,
I would believe you.'
He was actually looking
through a telescope.
Lawrence:
It's surprising in some sense,
that we're talked about as being
arrogant for somehow saying
we create our own importance
that our knowledge
and our understanding
and the way we live our lives
is what makes our importance.
People don't seem to recognise that
a universe that's created for us
is a little more arrogant.
Richard:
Incredibly arrogant yes.
Lawrence: And for me
that's the most powerful
and enlivening thing
is the fact that more
unimportant we become
the more powerful
is the importance of science
for pointing out that
the universe exists
whether we like it or not.
Richard: That cosmic humility is the exact
opposite of what we're often accused of.
Science is responsible
for the justified
humility of humanity
which is a new thing.
Lawrence:
Richard I remember vividly
the very first time we had a
discussion that we disagreed.
I argued to you
that I thought that
if you were trying to convince
people of your point
the first thing you shouldn't say is
'Everything you believe is wrong
and you're really stupid'
and it's better to try and
sort of go where they are.
Yeah, I mean, I think
I, myself, have been convinced
of somebody telling me
'Everything you believe
is rubbish.'
As a student I was
very persuaded by
that old French theologian
Teilhard De Chardin
who wrote a book called
The Phenomenon Of Man
which is...
pretentious gibberish
but it fooled me
when I was a student.
And then I read Peter Medawar's
brilliant review
of the book which is
almost certainly the best negative
book review ever written.
And I was completely
turned around by that
even though you might think
I'd have pushed back
and said 'Wait a minute. You're
insulting my intelligence.'
Well yes, maybe you are
insulting my intelligence.
I deserve to have
my intelligence insulted.
People get...
In fact there's a lot of...
There's a lot of research
that says pedagogically
the only way you can
really get people to learn
is by confronting their own
misconceptions and using them.
I use it in physics
all the time.
Kids learn stuff on...
You write stuff on the blackboard it
goes in one ear and out the other
but if you confront a belie they
have and show them immediately
that they can see for themselves
it's crazy, then they remember it.
Richard: Yes.
Woman: This weekend the Reason
Rally took over the National Mall
here in Washington D.C.
Billed as the largest gathering of the
secular movement in world history
National Mall Parks Service estimated that
over 30,000 people were in attendance.
And despite the rain, the
participants waited for hours
to see speakers
like Lawrence Krauss,
Richard Dawkins, Adam
Savage, so we have to ask
what the largest gathering
in history of atheists,
humanists, secularists,
free thinkers, skeptics...
What does it really mean?.
Man: I'm David Silverman
president of American Atheists
and I would like to
welcome you all to this
the largest atheist gathering
in world history.
((Cheering)
But I don't believe in God.
I have two proofs
for not believing in God... First
of all, God, if you're there,
we're here in Washington.
Come down now.
If you're there,
this is a pretty good time.
I'm sure Fox News would love it.
Just come down, say hello.
We are the people
who believe in this life.
who believe in morality.
If you are doing something
for reward or punishment,
you do not have morality.
Let's make it
so they're as embarrassed
to say something bad
about atheists
as they are to say
something bad about Mormons.
Mormon.
Mormon. ((Cackling)
* Thank you God
for fixing the cataracts *
* Of Sam's mum *
* I didn't realise
that it was so simple *
* But you showed a great example
of just how it can be done *
* They only need to pray
in a particular spot *
* To a particular version
of a particular God *
* And if you pull that off
without a hitch *
* He will fix one eye of one
middle-class white bitch *
They are ruled by fear.
That's not my style
and it's not yours either.
Folks it's certainly time
that we all grew up.
Instead of forging ahead
into the 1 4th century
we should be embracing
the 21 st by writing fini,
to the belie in the
bigoted, capricious, cruel,
deceitful, genocidal,
homophobic,
misogynistic, racist,
vindictive and violent bully.
((Cheering)
Ladies and gentlemen thank you.
Folks, Professor
Richard Dawkins.
((Crowd cheering)
((Chanting) Richard! Richard!
Richard! Richard!
((Chanting continues)
What a magnificent,
inspiring sight.
I was expecting great things
even in fine weather.
In the rain look at this.
This is the most incredible sight
I can remember ever seeing.
How is it necessary
to have a rally
for reason?.
How could anyone rally
against reason?.
I am often accused of
expressing contempt and
despising religious people.
I don't despise
religious people;,
I despise what they stand for.
There are too many
people in this country
who have been cowed into fear
of coming out as atheists
or secularists or agnostics.
We are far more numerous
than anybody realises.
((Cheering)
What I want to suggest you
do when you meet somebody
who claims to be
religious, ask them,
'Do you really believe
that when a priest
blesses a wafer
it turns into
the body of Christ?.
Are you seriously telling me
you believe that?'.
Don't fall for the convention
that we're all too polite
to talk about religion.
Religion is not off the table.
Religion is not off limits.
Religion makes specific
claims about the universe
which need to be substantiated
and need to be challenged
and if necessary
need to be ridiculed
with contempt.
Thank you very much.
Lawrence?. Yes yeah?.
Do you mind if we get a picture?.
No problem.
Hi. It is so good to meet you.
Can I get a picture of you real quick?.
Sure yeah.
I seen you on the TV.
Yeah.
Hey Dr. Krauss. Hi.
Could I shake your hand too?.
Sure.
Can I shake
your hand really quick?.
Your Universe Of Nothing speech
started my road to atheism.
Hi how are you?.
I'm Kenny Hibb
from Tulsa, Oklahoma.
Oh okay.
Went back to school for science becasue of you.
I'm a big fan.
It's not like a pancake.
It's like the space...
With the x-y-z axis
just remain perpendicular.
And light travels in a straight line.
Oh okay.
Bill Maher: Hi everybody
out there on the mall.
It's a great honour to be
addressing the Reason Rally.
And when you look at the who's
who lists throughout history
of people who were either
declared atheists
or who voiced publicly their opinion
that religion was bullshit
you can feel a swell of pride as you
stand out there on the mall today.
Let's let everybody know
that they can come out of
the closet if they're afraid to
because we're here to support
them and embrace them
because this is an amazing
community of people
who are non-believers
and I think it's wrong
that the religious right
and various belief systems
have gotten a monopoly
on morality and patriotism.
We are Americans and we're
moral and righteous Americans
and we don't need
a God to prove it.
Come on out and join us.
I have concluded through
careful empirical analysis
and much thought that somebody
is looking out for me
keeping track of what
I think about things
forgiving me when I
do less than I ought
giving me strength to shoot for
more than I think I'm capable of.
I believe they know everything that I
do and think and they still love me
and I've concluded
after careul consideration
that this person
keeping score is me.
((Laughter, cheering)
Immanuel Kant was asked
'What is the enlightenment?'.
He said 'Sapere aude:
Dare to know.'
The age of reason then
was an age when humanity
was born again
not from original sin
but from original ignorance
and dependence on authority.
Never again!
((Cheering)
Man: Folks you're
in for a treat.
The author of
the New York Times bestseller.
A Universe From Nothing
((crowd cheering)
Please welcome physicist
Dr. Lawrence Krauss!
((Cheering)
As was just pointed out
a few years ago,
my friend Richard Dawkins asked
me to give a talk at a meeting
called The Universe From Nothing, so I did.
Today I want to talk about
something that's equally plausible
but much more tragic:
How to get nothing
from something.
It's happened a number of
times in human history.
It happened during
the medieval era
when religious dogma
erased the enlightenment
of the Greeks.
Measuring the circumference of the
earth all of that was forgotten.
It happened in the Arabic world
in the 11th century when
what was then the centre
of culture and mathematics became
an economic and intellectual backwater
because of Islamic fundamentalism.
And it can happen today.
But the 21 st century
is placing challenges
on us like we've never had:
Global climate change,
over population,
the energy crisis,
the need finally to educate
and stop the subjugation
of women around the world.
Einstein said 60-odd years ago
after we exploded
the first atomic weapon
that everything has changed,
save the way we think.
And unless we change
the way we think
and unless we're willing to revere
open questioning, discussion,
and a public policy
based on reality,
we can take this wonderful
world we have now in many ways
and turn something into nothing
and we all have to make
sure that doesn't happen.
Thank you very much.
Man: Dr. Lawrence Krauss!
I do see a problem
that you can't live a life
based on delusion.
You can't hold out reality
all the time
and just exist in a fake world.
You've got to constantly,
not only be challenging
your own belies
but be willing to
say that you have been
wrong and misinformed
for your whole life
and change your views.
Otherwise, you know,
it's a mindless existence.
And that's not to say they don't
have the right to believe.
I believe everyone has
the right to believe anything.
They have the right
to believe anything
but I have the right to find
that belief ridiculous.
I've had people on
Twitter say things like
'Everyone has the right
to their own opinion
so just keep quiet
about your atheism.'
Brilliant. There it is.
You've summed it up for me.
Well done.
I did a courtroom
scene on a show
and I look at the judge
and right above his head
it says In God We Trust.
I mean, this should've hit me
before being on The Good Wife.
But I just can't believe it.
I just can't believe
that in 201 2
that's in our courts system.
These notions aren't shared
by everyone in America.
W;ith religion the stories
have been told over centuries
and science is always
telling a new story.
And I think that that's
what's hard for people
who hold religion as the truth
to understand that
science is something
that's broader.
It doesn't start
6,000 years ago,
it starts 4 or 5
billion years ago
and that is a really...
there's a lot more information
in there, in the book,
if we had a book,
it'd be a lot thicker.
And of course
we have seen backlash
against scientific
understanding of reality.
We have seen it
in many religions
not only in the United States.
So I believe
there's a great value
in promoting this kind of work.
People who like science are all
drawn to it for the same reason:
It explains the physical world.
What is this stuff?.
Is it the last word
on what reality is and what
the physical world is?.
I don't know
but if it's not the last word
it's at least the best word.
In our increasingly
complex scientific
and technological civilisation,
many policy issues require
scientific knowledge.
How then can the public
exercise democratic control
if it doesn't
understand science?.
I think it's very
important to advance
the pro-science view
in the modern world.
What could be bad
about advancing
knowledge and enlightenment?.
It can only be a good thing.
If you don't get that there's
some objective place
from which we can all start,
which we call science,
a place where we get rid of our biases
and get back to what we can observe
if you don't think that's
the best place to start
these conversations from
then where do you
start them from?.
You have to start from
'Well my evidence shows
that gay people are just like
me and they love each other
or that women are smart.'
The magic book kills discussion.
I went to Israel for the first
time the summer beore last.
People always say 'Oh you go to
Israel, you're gonna be changed forever.
You're gonna feel
so connected.'
And I just... I didn't
feel that at all.
I went... it just was so...
When I saw the Western
Wall especially,
and that this much room
was for the men
and this much room
was for the women
and they said 'Cover your
shins and cover this up
or people will throw
rocks at you'
and I just felt like
'(beep) you!'
All I felt was '(beep) you!'
I didn't feel
connected to anything
because it wasn't
including me as an equal.
It's the rules.
It's the arbitrary rules.
He gave you free will.
Well then why is he sending
me to hell for using it?.
He moves in mysterious ways.
I mean 'moves in
mysterious ways...'
That is the philosophical
equivalent of going... running away.
You know?. It's strange
'moves in mysterious ways.'
What's the difference between a
random God and no God at all?.
That's what I'd say.
I think people don't really
believe the myths they invent.
I've been to many
funerals in which
the priest has spoken
of an afterlife
and even the people
who are there
are sobbing profusely.
They don't really think
they're gonna meet
their loved one
in five years time.
If, on the other hand,
you stood on the quayside
and watched the Queen Mary
set off for New York
the people on the quayside are
not crying because they know
they're going to see those
people again fairly soon.
A funeral is fundamentally different
yet it should be the same.
I think myths are like a drug.
I think a lot of people
would rather just
take the myth pill
that makes them feel
nice and cozy and warm
and fuzzy and okay
with everything
rather than have to
look at the reality
of what the world actually
is because it's so big.
But then I think what's
so great about the world
being so big or the
universe being so big
is that it's so big
and that is so cool.
Early Christians were called
atheists by the Romans
'cause they didn't
believe in all the gods.
I love that. That's what
atheism is really.
It's the belief in one
less God than you.
The whole forward movement of
trying to do this thing, give
the people the opportunity
to be educated to a point
where they don't have to
Iean on stuff that's
probably not there
is a worthy cause.
You have to be able to
offer someone alternatives
to the way they view the world
or how can they learn something?.
You can't keep teaching someone
something they already know.
If you are so attached to your belie
system that you stop listening
out of fear of that
being challenged
or shaken
you're dead.
Most scientists are
not up for this game
of taking on these things
and having it become a forum
but once you start to step
up in front of doubters
it becomes this idea of really
can you change people's
minds from this debate
or are you just
taking rocks
and bashing each
other's brains out?.