Cleaned & corrected by Tronar
You're a thief, right, Nate?
- Mr. Thompson...
- Who was your wheelman?
Rowland Smith.
It was settled, Dean...
the territories.
- Jake says you're encroaching.
- Is that what Jake says?
- You deny it?
- Without equivocation.
You gotta respect
the boundaries.
- I'm asking you are you deaf?
- Hey, his kid's deaf.
I play the mandolin.
And sing to him
with his hand right here.
Dr. Landau is trying
to convince
my husband and I to sponsor
a women's health clinic
at the hospital.
There are some delicate topics
which would have to be avoided.
Let's set the table over again.
I'll send you home tomorrow
with a full month's supply.
Square enough deal.
Masseria we need to settle with.
He's gonna come looking
for his piece.
We're sending Benny
up to Harlem.
We're dealing in Midtown.
I sell two bindles of powder
on Elizabeth Street,
Joe Masseria gets cut in?
That's how he'll see it.
Hey, kid.
Joe Masseria says hello.
Hey!
I understand you boys
are heading back to New York.
- Where'd you hear that?
- Nucky's man.
I think we're gonna
stick around awhile.
What the hell are you doing?
Sync and correction by Bellows
www.addic7ed.com
Don't.
Should I answer it?
Should I? Well?
- Oh, just answer it already.
- Hello?
Katy. I'm looking for Owen.
- No, no, no, no.
- Yes, Mr. Thompson.
- Hello?
- Where the hell were you?
I was just in the loo.
I didn't hear the phone.
Jesus.
- The two of you?
- Sir?
- Where in the bathroom?
- No. No, no, I...
- Have you read the paper?
- No, I have not.
Well, read one
and meet me at Mickey's.
I'd have kept speaking
had I known you'd stop.
I don't have to.
I'd better go.
He's in a bad humor again.
Well, then it won't
matter if you're late.
Will it, Mr. Poofles?
Mr. Poofles.
There's some fresh rolls
if you want.
I like the poppy.
These are sesame.
Why ain't he at school?
Bellyache.
Let me take
a look at you, champ.
Hey.
What the hell's this?
Sonny, go play.
- Hey, your ma's talking to you.
- Go play.
Go play.
Come on.
Go on.
He came home with it yesterday.
I rang the headmaster.
Some new boy, he's a bully.
Picking on a kid
almost stone-cold deaf?
They all are, Al.
That's why he's there.
Boys will be boys, whether they
can hear each other or not.
Kid's got to toughen up.
Coming through. Coming through.
All right, pipe down.
Mr. Thompson wants a word.
As some of you may know, our
contact at Tabor Heights...
Sheriff Victor Sickles
died recently
as a result of what
the "Atlantic City Press"
has deemed a tragic accident.
Given as how the chief witness
to this unfortunate occurrence
was a Mr. Gyp Rosetti
of New York,
it's quite possible there's
a bit more to the story.
That being the case,
until further notice,
all shipments
to Mr. Rothstein
will use back roads only,
avoiding Tabor Heights
altogether.
In the middle of January?
The roads are sheets of ice.
And where are we gonna get gas?
That's your problem, isn't it?
You sure this is a good idea?
What the fuck
you asking him for?
I just thought
when it comes to...
You just what?
I already said how it is.
All right, Nuck.
I'm sorry.
Get up to Tabor Heights, find
out what the fuck is going on.
Yes, sir.
You know that coast road
that heads through Hammond?
Head up there,
check out the roads.
See how icy they actually are.
- You know the one I mean.
- Okay.
What's being done
about Rowland Smith?
- Who?
- Rowland Smith.
Nate Honig's wheelman.
The sack of shit who
robbed this place.
That job was left
to Manny Horvitz.
Oh, where's he been lately?
I don't have enough on my mind?
I have to start checking
your fucking work, too?
Make sure things
are being handled?
It won't happen again, sir.
Find this guy.
Use Agent Sawicki if you have to.
You want the feds involved?
He's on the goddamn payroll.
Make him earn it.
Any more second-guessing?
I'll get on it straightaway.
- Nucky, can I have a word?
- About what?
This Rosetti business,
the whole Tabor Heights thing.
If you've got a complaint,
talk to Mickey.
I don't.
It's just that I'm back now.
I'm well aware of that.
Then let me earn, Nucky.
I did my time like you asked.
Let's get something straight.
Allowing you to simply go to jail is
the last gift I'll ever give you.
This is rather infelicitous
language, isn't it?
- Vagina?
- It is a medical term.
I've never enjoyed
the sound of it.
I've never liked brussels sprouts,
but I don't deny they exist.
What a peculiar analogy.
What term would you prefer?
The entire area
is problematical.
You do acknowledge
certain subjects
would be difficult
to discuss without it?
Intercourse,
fertilization, birth.
You imagine yourself quite
wicked, don't you, Doctor?
The jackanapes at the back
of every classroom,
mistaking his sniggering
for the wit of the world.
That sounds more like
my cousin Francis.
"Pregnant."
Another problematical area?
"Gravid" has a noble ring.
Will they even know
what that means?
Is it not your intention
to instruct them?
"With child"?
Ah.
"Monthly time."
You are at odds
with "menstruation"?
- It's good Latin.
- A regrettable neologism.
The Federal Children's Bureau
has already published a series
on prenatal care and
"menstruation" is what they use.
The indiscretion of politicians
is of no concern to me.
I will be attending the class
to make sure my instructions
are followed.
And these are?
Gifts for the women.
"Kotex."
Sanitary napkins, Sister.
These are sold openly in stores?
They are a relatively
new product.
Perhaps you yourself...
Well...
let's hope our evening students
aren't quite so sensitive.
Looks like you've stepped
straight into my trap.
What?
You know, like I was
gonna arrest you.
Why would you do that?
Just making a little joke.
Mr. Thompson's a busy man.
I have nothing better to do?
Came out here in the middle
of the day, didn't you?
Is this Rowland Smith's
place or not?
That's what the Philly
office says.
You spoke to other
agents about this?
Just the one
that I can trust.
You mean the one that's crooked.
Looks like it's locked.
Thanks for clearing that up.
Rowland Smith's
been a busy fella.
At least half of this is ours.
It's all ours now.
You sure he's showing up?
This is his main drop.
Says your man in Philly.
Well, he would know,
wouldn't he?
And what's stopping him
from tipping Smith off?
Why would he do that?
Because he's never
bothered to catch him.
Call me when he gets here.
I'll take care of it.
You've my word.
You needn't involve yourself.
Is that what I asked you?
You've mentioned low profiles.
I'm trying to oblige.
Ahem.
Go buy a personality.
Let me get this straight.
Rosetti's gassing up,
Sickles is at the next pump.
He completely douses
himself with gasoline.
Then for some fucking reason,
decides that it's a
good time for a smoke.
Look, what's the difference?
The man was your partner.
What I'm saying is,
it don't matter.
The situation's being handled.
Meaning what?
Me and the boys,
we're taking care of it.
You just said
you couldn't arrest them.
I'm not talking
about arresting them.
I'm talking about handling them.
I got a load coming through here
tomorrow night, Deputy Ramsey.
I'm the sheriff now.
And I still got a load
coming through.
It's fine.
Same as always.
You boys go about your business.
Leave these dagos to us.
I don't like this.
Let the man do his job, Eli.
You ain't the only
sheriff ever lived.
Get in the car.
Postcard from Johnny.
"Greetings from Naples.
I haven't seen this many Italians
since we were back in Brooklyn."
What the fuck is this?
Cash.
What do you mean?
It's sticky.
Little schmutz.
I don't know, I just ate.
Even your money reeks.
Fuck you talking about?
Would it kill you to pony up for
a decent shave once in a while?
A little Bay Rum.
Gives me a rash.
Jake, I'm serious.
You know I love you, but you
smell like a sardine's twat.
I mean, what does your wife say?
"Why didn't I marry
Milton Korntragger?"
Your whores, then.
I pay 'em not to notice.
18th up to Harrison.
I got the rest of
my collections tonight.
- Where you going?
- Take a leak.
That's why beer
is so profitable.
We don't sell it,
we only rent it.
Personal hygiene, Jake.
It makes a big impression.
"How was
your day, honey?"
I love her and all, but my day?
This happened
and then that happened
and then the next thing.
That's the day.
Now you gotta go
through this whole...
Hi there.
Don't move.
Check him.
Just for coneys.
Who are you?
Ask you the same question.
You friends of my folks?
Do we look friendly?
You seem okay.
Don't know about him, though.
They don't like it
if I'm late for dinner, so...
- What's your name?
- Lon Chaney.
Norma Talmadge.
Baby Peggy.
Rowland Smith.
You're mean to children.
Aren't you the dog's bollocks?
Is that a good thing?
Yeah, I need
the Ritz-Carlton.
What used to come up
from Atlantic City
comes right through here,
straight in off the ocean.
Cut out the middleman.
We sail out, load up, off-load
here right on the beach.
Gonna have to do it at night.
We'll probably need
some boats, too.
I'm new to this.
I'm sorry.
You've been with us a year.
What do I know about the ocean?
I'm from Yonkers.
- Excuse me, miss.
- Sir?
One of these days I'm gonna
take you in the back,
show you how to
really make sauce.
But I don't know how to cook.
You stir, I'll provide the heat.
Could I have one?
How old are you?
16 next month.
Sir.
- You shouldn't smoke.
- I don't.
Then why do you want
a cigarette?
See what all the fuss is about.
You trying to charm me, kid?
Is it working?
What do you think?
You gonna hit me again?
I'm not opposed to it.
You know who I am, Rowland?
Answer straight.
You're Nucky Thompson.
You gave us
a Christmas turkey once.
When did I do that?
1914.
I was six.
Boy, was Ma grateful.
Is this how you thank me?
How do you mean?
Stealing my merchandise.
I guess I didn't think
you'd mind.
Why the hell
would you think that?
I don't know.
Whenever I see you in the paper,
it looks like
you're having a good time.
Anyway, I didn't steal
it all from you.
Who else?
A lot of it belongs to
Waxey Gordon in Philadelphia.
Did he give your mother
a turkey, too?
Heck, no.
He's a crook.
Tell me what you want
to happen here.
What's that mean?
It's not as expected. The fault's
mine for letting it get this far.
I'll take responsibility
and your hands stay clean.
Have one on me.
Need a light.
Expecting someone?
Federal agents.
Get your hands up.
Get 'em up.
Hands up.
All right, boys. Nice and slow.
Nice and slow.
Go around front.
What's the story, Rowland?
Beats me.
They're Prohees out of Philly.
They've kind of
been following me.
Arsed-out little shite.
- Just trying to get a leg up.
- You know any of them?
That tall fed
with the 12-gauge,
he's in Waxey Gordon's pocket.
- Anything else?
- Pretty sure they're here to kill me.
Enough with the bull...
Jeez, it's not our...
All right, let's go.
Do what you have to do.
Watch the windows, boys.
I'm gonna check the cellar.
Anything?
Just cobwebs and squirrel turd.
Squirrel turds?
That's rat shit.
Hit me again.
Picking up for Mr. Torrio.
Give me a short one.
Guzik, right?
Torrio's man.
Yeah. I know you?
Joe Miller.
I'm with Deanie O'Banion.
Uh-huh. Okay.
- Beer's better here, huh?
- How's that?
I say the beer's better here
down on the South Side?
Tastes the same to me.
Well, can't trust
the water anyway.
What water?
Any water.
I don't know, I'm just...
look, you drink, I'll drink.
We're fine, right?
Sure, we are.
You called Dean O'Banion a liar.
- Huh?
- That day at Torrio's.
- I don't really...
- You got a big mouth to match that big gut.
Enjoy your beer, Joe.
How can I with the stink
coming off of you?
Walk away from me, Jumbo?
I'm talking to you,
you fat fuck.
Came to collect?
Here.
Have some more.
How you holding up, huh?
Come on, get it on.
Get it on.
Hurry it up, guys.
We don't have all night.
Taking their sweet time.
Wait it out.
And if they decide to
look down here again?
Well, we're all in this
together, ain't we?
The mouths of babes.
What did we leave in the car?
Nothing.
I always keep it clean.
- The plates?
- In Tunney's name.
Don't expect
he'll much mind now.
I got maybe 50 if you need any.
Got 50 what?
License plates.
Swap 'em around.
That way, they can't
ever track us.
That's your system, is it?
Worked it out myself.
Then what are they
doing out there?
Just coincidence, I reckon.
Pretty good run, though, huh?
Kept us guessing.
Not that hard, really,
if you don't mind me saying.
- Why's that?
- Drive fast, flash the pistol.
I mean, who wants to get all
killed over a few crates of booze?
No one.
That's how I see it, too.
Shame about Nate, though.
He was my partner.
Oh, aye?
What happened to him?
Feds got him.
Guess he didn't have your luck.
Anyone check the cellar?
Mr. Thompson.
Yeah, I did.
Well, check it again.
What the fuck are you doing?
Like you said.
One part laxative, Benny.
You want them shitting themselves
all over Hester Street?
Anything?
Charlie and I need to talk.
I think it's time
I got included.
- Based on what?
- I stepped up.
I did what I had to.
That means I stay in the room.
You shot your wad off
in the middle of the street.
- They went back minus one.
- Meyer did that.
- I fucking gave him cover!
- Benny.
We are certainly
gonna discuss this,
but not right now, so...
I'm summoned.
At noon.
I'll come with you.
Meyer, Masseria hates that
shayna punim of yours.
Now more than ever.
You turn up,
who knows where this goes?
He needs to understand
the way the world's heading.
You're the one who said
come to terms.
- That was before.
- Well, you see?
This is the problem with you.
Always very headstrong.
Good thing I'm here
to talk some sense.
Offer two.
Settle at five.
Nothing west of Broadway,
nothing south of Grand.
Anything else?
Try not to sit by the window.
Tonight, 10:00 P.M.
All set on our end.
Some tough customers,
these boys.
You sure you want to do this?
Think I'm gonna let
you fellas have all the fun?
We'll meet by
the filling station.
Pull the truck around back
and bring plenty of rope.
All right, let me roll.
Let me roll.
Look at that, baby.
All mine.
Hit me, tough guy.
Come on.
Come on, hit me.
Hit me.
Come on, tough guy.
Come on. What was that, huh?
Come on, hit me harder.
What was that?
Harder than that.
Come on, put your hands up.
Put your hands up.
Like this in front of your face.
In front of your face like this.
Okay? And you're gonna
throw your punch.
You're gonna throw
your punch like bang!
Come on, let me see what you got.
Come on.
Come on!
Hit me!
You got to hit me.
You gonna let people bully you, huh?
Come on and hit me, huh?
Come here.
Come here. Shh.
It's okay, Sonny.
Shh. Come on.
Shh.
It's okay.
Come here. Come here.
Come on. Shh.
Papa's got you.
Yes. Yeah, yeah.
Yes, missus.
Thank you.
Mrs. Thompson
has no information.
- Try over at Chalky's.
- I did.
Lolly Steinman as well.
Chippy in New York, then.
Miss Kent has not
seen him either.
How many for Rothstein?
800.
Same as last time.
I wouldn't do this, Mickey.
Of course you wouldn't.
'Cause you're not in charge.
Use your head, will you?
There's no way through the back
roads and Tabor Heights is off-limits.
Sheriff's on it.
You heard him yourself.
The sheriff's been on
the job less than a week.
And the last one got burned...
Don't you have
some trucks to load?
Sure thing, boss.
- What, you hear something?
- No, I didn't hear anything.
Couldn't sleep either?
Not exactly a featherbed.
Although that hasn't
been helping either.
Doesn't seem to bother him.
I'm not sure what does.
More than a few nights
spent like this
back in Ulster.
How's that?
You'd get your orders,
this or that address,
and then count off the hours
till you finish the business.
Wasn't the work, though.
It was the waiting.
Must have had your way
of getting through it.
Oh, aye.
Walk through the streets
of Coleraine
in my head.
Steps to the school.
Steps to the church.
Steps to the greengrocer.
That what you've
been doing all night?
I have not thought
on the place in months.
Sounds like
you're feeling at home.
I know who's in charge,
Mr. Thompson.
Maybe you're not happy about it.
It's not my satisfaction
that matters.
And what have I done
to earn your loyalty?
You made a place for me.
Now minus the soft soap.
You pay me.
Jesus.
What the fuck happened?
- Joe Miller.
- Who?
O'Banion's man.
Last night
I was making my collection,
he dry-gulched me.
What, he hit you when
you wasn't looking?
I was leaving the bar
at Keller's.
- He's on the South Side?
- Cracked me with a beer mug.
Split my head open.
Irish fucking prick.
Al, he made fun of me.
- What?
- I mean, he...
in front of everybody.
You think it doesn't bother me?
I can't help how I smell.
Hour after I wash,
I already got to change my...
Al?
Women's health clinic.
St. Theresa's Hospital.
Free to all.
Women's health clinic.
St. Theresa's Hospital.
Free to all.
Ma'am, may I give
you one of these?
- Miss.
- Pardon?
Miss.
It's not my baby.
You're welcome in any case.
Excuse me, I'm from
St. Theresa's Hospi...
Mrs. Shearer.
Hello.
Yes?
Margaret Thompson.
We met...
I remember you.
What do you want?
Something that might
interest you.
It's a series
of classes intended...
- I know about it already.
- The class?
All of it.
I thought the same thing myself.
And truthfully I'm ashamed
by my ignorance.
Then who are you
to lecture people about it?
I'm not. We have a doctor
from the hospital staff.
Please come if you can.
Your own experience
will be valuable for...
A two-cent piece
for each of them?
It's only once a month.
Who's this?
A lady from the hospital.
- Is it Mr. Shearer?
- Yes, ma'am.
This isn't about
our bill, is it?
We got ourselves a little
behind, but I promise...
No, not that at all.
I just wanted to
tell your wife that...
that I'm glad to see
she's doing so much better.
Well, we've said our prayers,
but that's how the Lord
must have wanted it.
Yes, of course.
But He spared Edwina
and we're blessed for that.
The doctors had some hand in it.
I took the week off
to see her through.
You just wanted to put your feet
up and smoke those awful cigars.
And when she's up to it,
we'll try again.
We do appreciate
your good wishes, though.
Are we gonna spend
the whole day out here?
Lead on, Mother.
Ready, boys?
Women's health class.
St. Theresa's Hospital.
Free to all.
Women's health class.
St. Theresa's Hospital.
You get a cut of the card game,
a cut of the fence,
a cut of the booze.
What's to give?
It's a sideline.
"We."
Have a look around.
There's just you and me.
I have partners.
No.
With your partners.
Gonna look very cheap.
Mr. Doyle.
Why am I talking to you?
'Cause you called me.
- But why am I calling you?
- Uh...
Why is that even occurring?
If I had my liquor on the timely
basis your employer promised,
if, in fact, I could
reach your employer,
who now seems to think
acceptable business practice
to disappear for days on end,
this conversation
would not be taking place.
And that would make me...
very happy.
Yeah, I understand.
- Listen, Mr. Rothstein.
- I want what I paid for.
- I want it now.
- Okay, sir.
And I don't ever want to find
myself chatting with you again.
- Of course.
- Is that clear?
You'll have it
by tomorrow morning.
That Rothstein,
warm as a lizard.
What did he say?
That he's expecting
his delivery.
And what did you tell him?
That it's coming.
What do you think?
What do I think?
That you're a fucking idiot.
Watch your step, Eli.
I'm your boss.
Nucky explicitly said
to avoid Tabor Heights.
I heard. There's no way
to use the back roads.
Not till May at the earliest.
So hold off making the delivery.
And get your brother's foot
up my ass? No, thanks.
I'm telling you
not to do this, Mickey.
I'm not doing nothing.
They are.
You're straight through
to New York.
Gas up in Tabor Heights
and that's it.
You stop for nobody.
Not even the law.
Tonight is my night.
Hey.
- He's got a gun.
Easy!
Stop!
Oh!
You want to pick on people
who can't defend themselves?
Huh?
Pay for his funeral.
What are they saying?
I think they're wrapping it up.
They're gone.
Nearly shit your breeches
there, didn't you, son?
Heck, I wasn't scared.
I was.
Okay, I was, too.
There'll not be a peep from me.
He always this much fun?
You should hear him
on the phone sometime.
- Canoodling with his girlfriend.
Well, I got bacon
and eggs in the icebox.
I can fry 'em up
if anyone's hungry.
Maybe they left
a bottle upstairs.
Here we are.
Come on.
Hey, fellas.
Ready to make some dough?
Don't make a move
until Gyp says so.
You're gonna help us
block the road.
First shot, then you move.
Just keep the road blocked.
- Don't be yellow now.
- Down in the shadows.
Rothstein's shipment
is on its way.
By which route?
Tabor Heights.
Word came back it's clear.
Did anyone wonder where we
were for the last 24 hours?
If they did,
they were quiet about it.
Well?
You see this?
See what?
There's nothing here.
That's my point.
We've both got empty hands.
What's that say to you?
Find a better hideout?
Mr. Thompson,
you got to admit
I'm pretty good at this.
I wouldn't go boasting about it.
Yeah, and I could say
I'd never do it again,
but you wouldn't
believe me, would you?
Probably not.
So...
so how's about
I come work for you?
How would that go, Rowland?
Well...
put me behind the wheel,
box of shotgun shells,
just let them try stealing then.
He doesn't like me.
Can you blame him?
Ain't I cool in a tight spot?
You'll do.
I know all the roads
around here.
Best places to lie low.
Best places to keep your stash.
They won't ever catch me.
We caught you, Rowland.
Okay, but it wasn't easy.
And Waxey Gordon, he ain't
nearly as smart as you.
You could take as much
of his booze as you'd like.
It's apples off a tree.
Just tell me
what you want to do.
You've sure got a lot of moxie.
How else are you
supposed to get ahead?
I thought you didn't smoke.
Did I say that?
- How old are you really?
- 19.
So legally I'm allowed to drive.
Isn't that better?
Have one of mine.
- Mr. Kessler.
- Who's Mr. Kessler?
He's Mr. Thompson's driver.
I thought you were
letting him go.
Why would you think that?
I misunderstood.
As long as you understand now.
Stop!
- Is that Eli?
- Looks like it.
Fuck that.
Mickey said don't stop for nobody.
Stop!
It's an ambush!
Wait!
Stop!
It's an ambush!
It's a fucking ambush!
Come on.
Oh, right there.
Right under his coat.
Look at this.
You want that?
Where we dumping these?
Boss says dig a pit
in the woods.
That'll take all night.
Get the podunks to do it.
Jeez, this one
crapped his pants.
I need a wallet.
Which one of them waitresses
do you think is cuter?
The little one
with the bobbed hair.
I'm gonna fuck the redhead.
Hey. Hey.
Shh.
Look.
Come on.
Here we go.
♪ Nights are long ♪
♪ Since you went away ♪
♪ I think about ♪
♪ You all through the day ♪
♪ My buddy ♪
♪ Nobody quite so true ♪
♪ Life is a book
that we study ♪
♪ Some of its leaves
bring a sigh... ♪
Nucky.
♪ There it was
written, my buddy ♪
♪ That we must part,
you and I ♪
♪ Buddies through all
of the gray days ♪
♪ Buddies when something
went wrong... ♪
I have to talk to you.
We've had our conversation.
This is about something else.
And you're gonna
need to hear it.
♪ Miss your voice ♪
♪ The touch of your hand ♪
♪ Just long to know ♪
♪ That you understand ♪
♪ My buddy ♪
♪ Your buddy misses you. ♪
Good night.
♪ Life is a book
that we study ♪
♪ Some of its leaves
bring a sigh ♪
♪ There it was
written, my buddy ♪
♪ That we must part,
you and I ♪
♪ Nights are long ♪
♪ Since you went away ♪
♪ I think about you ♪
♪ All through the day,
my buddy ♪
♪ My buddy ♪
♪ Nobody quite so true ♪
♪ Your buddy ♪
♪ Misses you. ♪