THE UNKNOWN SOLDIER
Translated from the Finnish subtitles
by thumos - v5
Rokka!
PALOAUKEA
June 1941
Goddamn war-crazed lunatic!
(Captain Kaarna) Hmph, perkele.
Goddamn fucking hell.
Machine gun company!
At ease.
(Koskela) The battalion will be transported to another location by trucks.
Thus, all extra equipment will be relinquished.
Put another set of underwear, footwraps
and your overcoat in your pack.
And weapons, of course.
Rest to storage. Hietanen oversees. Be quick about it.
(Hietanen) Where are we headed? All the way to hell, I guess?
You'd better hurry.
(Lahtinen) Boys, there's going to be a fight.
That nutcase is going to take off from Germany,
and then our idiots will follow after him.
The brass are afraid that Russia will come here
if they start fighting with Germany.
What would they do here?
As far as I know, they've not attacked anybody.
But we've already got Krauts here.
Vanhala, battalion horse drivers said that
we're going to be sent to garrison Helsinki.
All old rags will be changed to new ones.
Every man will get riding breeches.
That's what I heard.
Attention!
- As you were.
Do you know what it says on a boy scout's belt?
"Be prepared."
Coffee and a pretzel, please.
What would you like?
(Rahikainen) - What would the girl sell to Rahikainen on this last night?
A cup of coffee, and a pretzel.
We're selling as many pretzels as you want.
The cantina will be sold empty tonight.
There it is. War is coming,
signs are in the air.
I wonder if I'll get to see
the girl's pretty eyes ever again?
(Lammio)
Finish your business so others have a chance as well.
Lieutenant, let's not get too hasty.
How much tobacco am I allowed?
How much do you want?
- Let's say a packet. And around ten pretzels.
Move your feet.
Looks like that girl ain't gonna be the mother of your children.
You need pins on your collar for that.
(Rahikainen) Well, as long as there's something under the collar.
(Sirkka) I'm going to miss you.
(Kariluoto) I'll return.
- You certain?
Of course, if you wait.
- I'll wait.
Will you?
I will.
I shall not abandon my squad, ship or flag -
but as commanded,
and as long as there's strength in me -
I will follow it with manly seriousness,
and defend it to my last drop of blood.
...A Bulwark never failing;
Our Helper He amid the flood
For still our ancient foe
Doth seek to work us woe;
His craft and power are great,
And, armed with cruel hate,
On earth is not his equal.
Did we in our own strength confide...
(Kaarna) A fine beginning.
(Koskela) First half squad to this truck, second to the next one.
First and third squads, mount up!
Second and fourth, wait for the next free truck.
Eki goddammit!
- Someone is sitting on my pack!
Goddammit.
- Watch it.
Move a little.
Last greetings to you, Paloaukea!
Farewell forever, you sweat sponge!
Be a very shitty place
for all new recruits!
(President Ryti) Citizens.
Our peace loving people -
who for a second year already,
has stretched to the end of its strength -
to rebuild our country to prosperity
after the last war -
has once again been brutally attacked.
Once again the same enemy,
who for more than 500 years -
by destroying, crushing and murdering,
has warred against our small nation.
(Salo) When those guns start glowing,
our neighbour is going to get a beating.
Herrings are a little slim for a Christmas dinner.
They've got guns on the other side too.
It's not going to be as easy as they say.
I don't know. Ostrobothnian boys had to be tied
to trees so they wouldn't rush off.
NORTHERN KARELIA
4th of July 1941
Wake up. It's begun.
Guns are already singing their tune. Hurry up.
They're firing with a cannon.
Still going far. Can't even hear the whistle.
Cannons are singing.
(Koskela) We go with third company.
Nothing much to it,
but you have to take it calmly...
Aim at the belt, that's the best way.
Just remember they're
no different from other people.
They obey lead,
just like everyone else.
All right, get moving.
Autio promised me two of your machine guns.
- I know.
Fire as fast as you can then, Ville.
See you there.
(Koskela) Move.
(Lahtinen) Men are already getting cold there.
(Autio) Kariluoto.
Artillery will fire a barrage in front of the second.
After that, advance without a separate command.
Don't let 'em stop, try to make it in one go.
Under no circumstance can you let 'em lie down under fire.
Good luck.
Fire!
Fourth, forward!
- Forward!
Don't lie down under fire. Forward!
Don't stop!
Machine guns into position.
Forward!
Forw...Forward.
Shoot for their nuts!
- Shoot for their nuts!
It's a tank.
(Mielonen) I doubt it.
(Kaarna) Sure you can doubt it, it's still a tank.
Well, well. Berries are coming along nicely.
They're blossoming beautifully.
What's...?
What's this?
No, no, no, boys, boys, boys.
You're mistaken.
You don't fight a war like this.
Our neighbouring company has already
advanced to the enemy's positions.
Let's cross that damn bog in a hurry.
Let's try it again, 2nd Lieutenant.
You'll get the hang of it.
Cut them down, son of the North!
Move it!
Get moving!
Cut them down, son of the North!
Medic, medic!
Cut them down, son of North!
- Fourth, forward!
Not a single dead Russki. Not a single one,
I checked when we came.
(Sihvonen)
Hey, one's lying down here.
(Lahtinen) I guess they don't care much for each other.
They left him here to crawl.
Goddammit.
Hello. Say, is it cold in Russki's hell?
(Hietanen) What you got there?
Show me.
- These are mine.
(Hietanen) Give me.
What's this? "Konek, konek."
Who the hell is that beard fellow?
That's Lenin.
Such a slant eye that he sees both Sundays on a Wednesday.
Oh. Hey boys, a little lavender perfume?
(Ukkola) Lieutenant.
(Autio) - Kariluoto.
A brisk start.
How did it feel?
Good, as soon as I got going.
Couldn't almost get 'em moving.
Captain Kaarna...
- I heard.
But, great thanks. You did well.
(Koskela)
Form up and get moving.
(Sirkka)
Now is our time. Finland's time.
To demand back what was lost.
That's our right.
Isn't it?
"Say, is it cold in Russki's hell?"
(Hietanen) If I was God,
I wouldn't have made stars.
If I could, I'd break 'em.
What's the point of them when they don't do anything?
God didn't create them, that's just talk.
Neither were people.
People were born in the sea.
People are made out of carbon and other things.
The simple man is kept in ignorance so he’ll be
more submissive to the capitalists.
Carbon?
In the sea? Carbon?
Lahtinen. You're talking crazy stuff.
How the hell could people be born in the sea?
If you're underwater for half a minute,
you're out of breath.
You can be underwater if you have gills.
People are made out of meat and bones,
anyone can tell you that.
People were fish in the beginning.
- Fish?
Even a capitalist scientist has recognized that.
Goddamn. A fish?
Vanhala, I'm a perch.
I'm a perch made out of carbon. A perch, yeah.
Nature is what creates, that's how it is.
Everything else is hogwash.
Rich people know what tune to sing,
when it's about their money.
And off we go again,
we'll see how this pans out.
We'll see.
There's a lot of men they can throw against us.
But a Finnish soldier is worth ten Russkis.
- I guess so.
But what do you do when the eleventh comes?
Crawl forward, goddammit!
Boys, get fucking moving!
Boys, forward!
Forward!
Whole battery, fire three times,
targets one and two.
Three men have fallen,
I just lost my best squad leader.
Whole battalion is already in it.
If you get through, this will be your day.
You know I won't be spareful with the praise.
I'll do everything I can,
as long as I get the men moving.
Fourth, forward!
Forward!
Forward, fourth!
(Koskela)
Let it be. You'll get yourself killed for no reason.
If one man could get close with a satchel charge.
I'll try.
- I'll go.
That's my job, not yours.
- Your job is to get the men moving.
(Koskela) Lehto! When I go, the machine gun has to fire nonstop!
- Got it!
Make room for Lehto!
- Take him away!
Lehto!
(Kariluoto) They're falling back!
First squad...Viirilä!
First and second to the right!
Third and fourth to the left! Mäntynen!
Mäntynen!
Viirilä!
(Kariluoto)
Let's keep moving.
We don't have time for looting.
Let's go forward.
No human is truly evil,
but many of us are weak.
There's much good in everyone,
even though it may be hidden today.
Well...
Have you gotten food?
- Yes, we have, Major.
I see. Do you boys have tobacco?
- Yes, Major.
(Hietanen) We're rolling mahorka cigarettes, Major.
I see, and how do they taste?
Like home-grown tobacco, Major.
Tastes the same everywhere.
Well, of course.
I found potatoes!
- Potatoes?
(Hietanen) Change carriers.
- Vanhala.
(Vanhala) I just carried it the longest.
(Lehto) - Don't whine, goddammit. Give me that stand.
(Ukkola) Can you believe that I'm hungry?
(Vanhala) How long do they think
us forest warriors will march with these rations?
They don't think,
they know.
They've counted the calories,
or whatever the hell they are.
Go complain and they'll show you such a calculation -
that proves that you can't be hungry.
Lehto. Don't you know that's forbidden?
So is killing.
I've never seen such gluttons.
(Hietanen) Boys...
I don't believe in calories -
or in anything else supernatural,
but I know one thing for certain.
Lahtinen thinks for sure that calories
were invented by the capitalist.
I don't know anything about capitalists -
but if my old man dies before me,
I'll get 9,5 hectares...
He's running there.
(Lahtinen) Rukiver!
Stoi!
Rukiver.
(Koskela) Check if anyone else is around.
Search his pockets.
Superpower's gear doesn't look that great.
(Rahikainen) Tavaritsia, tavaritsia?
Anyone else? Bonimai?
He could've blown us up with himself.
He's not that kind of a man.
You can see that.
Vanja boy, rastui.
He needs to be taken to the command post. Who will go?
(Lehto) - I'll go.
Walk that way.
Go, go.
What did he do?
- Died.
Did he try to escape?
- Yes.
That wasn't necessary.
He wasn't that sort of a man.
Damned if I'm going to sort 'em out?
- You shot him in the back. He didn't try to escape.
"In the back!" Better that than from the front.
Easier for him. Start crying, goddammit.
Shoot for all I care.
I'm no military judge.
But that man was afraid enough as he was.
We don't start to cry for one Russki.
Well then, let's keep moving.
How many days will the march last?
(General) - Infantry is used to this.
A Finnish soldier will march for a week.
Out of the way!
Don't touch the car!
Throw up some dust on a grunt's eyes, goddammit.
No sign of a fuel shortage,
when they take their field whores for a ride.
(Hietanen) Boys, the old border.
We're in Russia now.
Right now, at this moment,
this lad stepped into foreign soil.
Our rights end here. From now on,
we're a pack of bandits.
(Ukkola) Sure, we're the bandits,
when we cross borders.
But the others are just protecting their security,
when they redraw borders.
We've marched across Karelian song country.
Weren't there some old men and women here,
who sang sad laments?
We have reason for a few laments ourselves.
Now that we've crossed the border,
they'll start fighting back for real.
There's a few troops ahead of us,
we won't be sent to the line right away.
(Lahtinen) We're building that Greater Finland.
Got their heads so hot they got steam coming out their noses.
(Vanhala) Suhna superpower in the making!
(Salo) They're saying it's three weeks,
and we'll be back in the hayfields.
HOME FRONT
August 1941
(Rokka) So, I guess this here
is the company commander.
We're replacements.
I guess the Major called that we're coming.
There's papers for the both of us.
- So, what's... You're a Corporal.
That I am.
They gave me these stripes in the Winter War.
For what reason, I don't know,
as I've never hurt anybody.
Listen Lieutenant,
put us in the same squad.
We're neighbours,
and we've been together since the Winter War.
You have to remember that
this is not a reserve regiment.
We don't address superiors informally here,
because it would weaken discipline among conscripts.
Is that so? Well I didn't know that.
But I'm just saying that make sure we're
put in the same group with Sus' Paw here.
Who?
- Sus' Paw.
What's your name?
Pr-pr-private Sus is my name.
So Susi?
And what's your name?
- I'm Rokka. Antero is my first name.
But I've been called Antti my whole life,
and I even say so myself.
That fella thinks highly of himself, if there's
any more like him, we'll not like it here.
We'll always manage.
Don't you worry at all.
He's very young still. We've managed before.
- Su-sure we have.
Goddamn how they're firing with the cannons.
That's where we're headed soon.
Listen here 2nd Lieutenant, we're leaving today.
- Have you been at the front before?
In Taipale, dreadful place.
We're from the Isthmus.
They took our farms,
but not our lives, no matter how they tried.
We'll see if they manage to get us now.
I wanted to go to the Isthmus. That's where I have
unfinished business with the neighbour.
It doesn't matter where we fight.
There’s cabins up for the taking
all the way to Smolensk.
I don't know about Smolensk,
they've praised the Fritz -
but on the way here, I saw them
clicking their heels a bit too much.
But we don't care about that,
Europe can go to hell.
We'll take back Karelia,
and then we're going home.
Get ready.
- For what?
Well, to attack.
(Rokka) Assault boats.
They want to make marine animals out of us.
(Susi) We're in the shit now.
- Oh, don't fret. It's just water.
What does it matter if you die
on water or on land?
Don't speak of death,
I'll get a bad stomach.
Listen 2nd Lieutenant.
- Yes?
We're crossing that river in a bit.
I know.
- Well, all right then. Just take it calmly.
Mount the machine gun with the stand on the bow.
Why, my friend, surely you see it's pointless
to use the stand for that crossing.
It will just slow us down
during the landing.
I'm not your friend,
I'm your company commander.
Don't think so.
At most we'll mount it without the stand.
You'll do as you're told!
Move!
- Move!
Second wave, get ready!
Forward!
Sarge!
- Forward!
Give me that belt.
(Rokka) That goddamn machine gun.
All right! Let's rush 'em now!
Paw. You come feed the belt.
Give me that rifle.
Assault!
Jeesus perkele!
Give me that submachine gun. You take grenades.
- Grenades.
As the grenade explodes, I go around the corner and finish them off.
Then we advance to the next corner.
Go ahead.
New magazine!
Give me a submachine gun!
This is a damn good gun.
We only had a few of these in the Winter War.
Don't you try aiming at me.
That means death, I'm a hasty man.
Corporal.
What's your name?
- I'm Rokka.
Antero is my first name.
I already reported to our 2nd Lieutenant.
That was excellent work.
- Don't you try praising me.
You want to do heroic deeds,
I don't give a damn about none of that.
You go when the situation demands it,
otherwise you keep low.
We're not here to die,
we're here to kill. All right, off we go.
Paw, take that tent tarp from that fallen guy.
It'll make a good blanket.
Autumn rains will start soon.
- Move it!
Everyone alive?
- We are, no worries here.
Next we'll take Petroskoi.
And then we'll go home.
What do you think of that, Vanhala?
Petroskohoi...
- Kihi kihi.
Saatana...
That has to last for three days.
- Of course it has to, when you don't give more.
Yup, it's a horse.
You can see a whip mark here.
- Don't whine about the food.
The meat is up to the standards.
- Who can say something like that?
First Sergeant Sinkkonen,
company's new Master Sergeant.
The food is good,
considering the circumstances.
Considering the circumstances,
I'd prefer that you don't kick over my mess kit.
Well sure, I guess it isn't the horse's fault
if it gets tougher as it ages.
Better men have fulfilled their duties
without complaining.
You're quite something.
You crack jokes like they was serious.
We have to have fun here.
Join our group, we'll put together an orchestra.
Take a pot and start drumming.
The boot hits the floorboards,
like you hit an ace on the card table
The children can't stay put,
unless you tie 'em down
The violin screams hiitula-hiituu,
the accordion goes halapata-paa
Do you hear how the violins sing?
- What kind of circus is this?
The new Master Sergeant,
he has a gloomy mind.
We thought we'd give him some joy,
but apparently he's not fond of music.
Quit your antics.
The company has to be ready to march in an hour.
Those without a white handkerchief,
get a piece of white paper.
Get to work.
Sinkkonen.
We're going deep into the forest,
all through the night.
Paw, eat your porridge.
Eat it all so you'll have enough strength.
(Lahtinen)
When are the Krauts getting to Moscow?
(Hietanen) Big thing happening, boys.
Whole regiment is moving.
(Rokka) Take my hand.
Flanking is proceeding well.
No sign of the enemy.
(Rahikainen)
Try to carry the clothes you've got on.
My comradeship
has its limits, Riitaoja.
Give me your backpack and get up.
Fucking get up!
Give me that backpack, goddammit!
You're one cross to carry!
Get up!
- Don't kick him!
You should get a string of bullets through you.
- Try your luck, asshole.
Let it be.
Of all the motherfucking pansies,
I have to drag you along.
Who will go?
- First will go.
There's almost certainly something there.
If our second has left,
you return to the road.
Vanhala and Rahikainen with me. I won't take Riitaoja.
- Lahtinen will give one of his men.
Sihvonen.
- Me, why of course!
(Lammio) Quit grumbling.
Riitaoja must fulfill his duty.
Where the hell is second platoon?
(Vanhala) - What if we all headed back to Finland?
We'd go home and say we got lost.
Quit your yapping.
I'll go ahead a bit.
Riitaoja!
Let's leave, boys.
Let's not stay here to be killed.
And Lehto was dead?
- I don't know, he didn't answer when we yelled.
I'm just so damn puzzled.
So damn puzzled.
This looks like a grand mystery.
A true mystery show.
How can a dead guy shoot himself?
Rokka. You take command of first squad.
Sihvonen to Lahtinen. Take Susi to your squad.
- That'll suit me fine.
All right. Start checking positions.
All right, boys. We're not leaving here,
no matter what.
Vanhala, let's wait a bit.
Fire!
It doesn't work on that!
Boys, the tanks are coming now!
- Let's leave, quickly!
Run!
- Get back!
(Sarastie) Thank you.
They got a bloody nose just now.
Let’s go and give a kick to their butts next.
They're after that nickel up in Petsamo.
Well, we're generous fellows.
Let's go and give them as much as they want.
That's the way. Koskela.
Get ready.
(Rahikainen)
Aren't they running out of men?
(Lahtinen) Listen, they won't run out of men.
Plenty of men and stuff up there.
And if the men are spent -
they've got 15 million female soldiers.
Everyone's received training, even the old hags.
(Vanhala) That would lead to some intense close combat.
Even Rahikainen would get awarded
with the Mannerheim Cross.
SOVIET KARELIA
September 1941
Medic!
- Medic!
Soldiers!
Remember who you are!
Not a step backwards!
Men!
Petroskoi awaits!
Mäntynen! Let's go!
I'm going to Father!
- Don't move, It'll just hurt worse.
You pray! I can't do it!
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread...
...and forgive us our trespasses...
...as we forgive those who trespass against us...
...and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, the power and the glory...
for ever and ever.
Amen.
We're in Russia.
- Petroskoi, Petroskoi...
We're not leaving from there, not anywhere.
Perkele!
For home, religion and Fatherland,
goddammit.
We've been fighting for that damn dump.
Other troops are already there,
grabbing all the good stuff.
(Hietanen) Boys, this is a historical event.
There lies a new city of Finland.
PETROSKOI
1st of October 1941
Booze factory has been taken!
Mannerheim said...
- Piss in your bottles!
(Lautsalo) Booze factory has been taken!
Walk, what you mean walk? Hellurei!
2nd Lieutenant Kariluoto,
8th infantry regiment, 1st battalion, 3rd company.
Welcome to Hermanni's youth club!
I'm in command here!
We conquered Petroskoi.
Objective has been reached.
It fell quickly.
Are you running around here by yourself?
Äänislinna, former Petroskoi
12th of October 1941
Machine gun company!
Eyes - right!
Eyes - front!
(Hietanen) What kind of flailing is that?
Scrub it well.
One of Stalin's messes.
- "Welcome to Hermanni's youth club!"
We're abroad now.
As the fighting ends in Aunus
and as the Svir river has been reached -
Finnish troops were reorganized for a new offensive -
towards Äänisjärvi and Äänislinna -
which still at that time carried
the Russki-sounding name of Petroskoi.
The glorious Blue Cross Flag of Finland
is now flown over this liberated land.
(Rahikainen)
Which one does the pastor want?
I'll take this.
I also have canned goods from America.
- No thanks.
Maybe next time.
Was the girl good?
- Yes.
Shoot the Russki between the eyes,
that ought to bring them down.
Between the eyes, between the eyes,
shoot the Russki between the eyes!
A Russki shall give us no trouble,
we are used to their kind.
Between the eyes, between the eyes,
shoot the Russki between the eyes!
Shoot the Russki between the eyes,
that ought to bring them down.
Between the eyes, between the eyes...
We've got girls as well.
"Gogol's street."
"Maksim Gorj-jiki"... "Gorjiki street."
Lenin's hill.
Hey, Aleksi!
- Hey!
Aleksi, down with the Russki.
- Down with the Russki, Finland good!
Say again: down with the Russki.
- Down with the Russki.
Say it again.
Tanja...
Aleksi, down with the Russki!
- Down with the Russki, Finland good!
Hello.
- Hello.
Come inside.
Here again.
Did you bring that tea?
- Tea and chai.
We've got music.
A disc.
Spasiba.
What are you grieving, Veerukka?
Don't talk. She misses her fiancé.
Veruka doesn't have a fiancé.
Why did you come?
Why didn't you leave us be at peace?
You started this.
You took my farm. Go look
at the state of the Isthmus.
We wouldn't be here if you had left us alone.
- Oh, look at that!
Who came? Hitler!
But he'll be met with death.
Then why did you aim your rifle at me?
How could I know who was coming?
I confess, war is pure evil, on both sides.
No matter who starts it.
Everyone has to suffer...
...even those who haven't hurt anybody.
Like kids for example.
You said we're evildoers.
But Hietanen brought our tomorrow's
bread ration for Aleksi and Tanja.
Our boys are sharing their
own rations with the children -
of the kindred nations, who have been
suffering from hunger under Bolshevik rule.
You don't give to children. You eat everything yourself,
as you're such a young fat man.
(Vanhala) Music...
Stalin's speeches. Stalin...
Should we?
Kalinka, kalinka, kalinka moja
Sadu jagoda malinka, malinka moja
(All women together)
Kalinka, kalinka, kalinka moja
Sadu jagoda malinka, malinka moja
I guess I can keep this,
for memory's sake.
Take it.
You should've stayed.
Finnish tribes could've united.
We can't take Hietanen there anymore.
He'll get a wound in his heart.
Don't think I'll be the first one to thaw.
- We're just joking.
I'm a regular sorrowless fellow.
I don't care about anything.
(Sinkkonen) Perfect cleanliness has
to be maintained.
Barracks regulations, with all its clauses,
is in effect.
NCOs will lodge separately
in their own quarters.
Your job is to oversee that
good order is maintained.
That's not fine by me. Paw and I take our tea
together, and everything else as well.
I'll bunk with him,
or maybe Paw will lodge in the NCO quarters.
Be quiet. You'll go
where you're ordered.
Is that clear? - Well, no. Don't try
to flaunt yourself, you know how that'll end for you.
Do you fucking horseman think that
I'll jump according to your whims like recruit?
Attention!
At ease.
Corporal Rokka.
- What's the matter?
You'll stay in the NCO quarters like everyone else.
Is that clear? - We'll see about that later.
That's not something I want to argue about.
But when will we start getting furloughs?
I'm a family man and we've been here for months.
If I leave an application, will you approve it?
We're not on a first name basis.
- Well sure, but let's be.
I'm Antero. You can call me that anytime you like.
And I'll address you informally in any case,
since you're younger than me.
Attention!
I discipline Corporal Rokka
for disobeying a superior officer -
with four days of labor without relief.
The punished will carry out
four extra guard duty shifts.
At ease.
(Hietanen sings)
So once sang black Saara...
little happy nigger child...
In Heaven the Lord will relieve
you of your pain...
Company, get ready! We're moving out!
- No we aren't.
Company, get up!
For the last time, get ready.
Koskela for company commander.
- Koskela for company commander. Then we'll go.
This is not some Red Guard -
that elects its company commanders
by shouting out votes. Is that clear? - No.
I am ordering you for the last time.
After that, other measures will be taken.
I think there's reason to hurry up.
Don't take too much extra junk.
Sure, musical instruments are nice. I guess
we'll manage with them somehow.
Where are they taking us?
- To Svir river.
What the hell?
- Why couldn't we stay?
To Svir?
- Tighten up a bit.
Fucking go.
- Go ahead, quickly.
(Hietanen) I made it!
Goddamn, where are we going?
Private Korhonen and Private Peltola
had during the 3rd day of this month -
in the enemy's vicinity,
refused to obey their superior's orders.
A military tribunal has sentenced
Private Korhonen and Private Peltola, -
to suffer the death penalty
for these crimes.
Load!
Aim!
Fire!
Right...
The sentence has been carried out,
so that insubordinates will see -
that this army doesn't have time for games.
I hope, and I believe -
that I won't have to read out
something like this again in this battalion.
SVIR
January 1942
Alarm!
Enemy ahead!
Who's there?
What do you think?
Who might it be?
We're toast. If we have to flee,
the machine gun better not get left behind.
Sure, I'll take the gun-stand.
(Lahtinen)
Meet you back on the tanner's rafters.
Stay put! Get back!
Who the fuck told you to fall back?
They're running! We'd better go, too!
- Back to the line!
Not before the others! Sihvonen!
Hentinen is dead!
- Perkele!
Määttä! Go help!
I'll hold them off for a while.
Pull, pull!
Lahtinen!
- Leave the machine gun!
Perkele!
Fucking sheep! You run off like cowards
and leave the wounded!
Where's Lahtinen and the machine gun?
They're lying back there. Side by side.
Nothing to be done about it. This man did what he could.
No reason to blame him.
I'm not looking for anyone to blame.
Lahtinen and his machine gun is what I was looking for.
Let's put our line back together.
They'll be here soon.
Listen, 2nd Lieutenant. Where do you need a real top-notch fella?
'Cause you've got one here.
Ends of the line are the worst.
Go secure our left flank and keep an eye on the situation.
Sihvonen, come with me.
Paw, give him your skis.
You're going to have so much fun with me!
Goddamn, what a ploy.
They sent troops to flank us.
Some damn instinct I've got.
Come on now.
What's taking you so long?
There's full magazines in the pack.
As I empty them,
you refill them.
Keep the full ones in one pile,
so they don't get mixed.
Be calm. Just like me.
We're in no trouble here.
They're about to have it rough, and not us.
If you can sing, then hum by yourself.
That keeps the mind at ease.
Think about all kinds of crazy stuff,
they're good in a spot like this.
Little strategy for the mind.
Officer in front.
When his head's shadow hits that small spruce,
he'll meet his maker.
That's how I've decided for him.
And after that, the others will start getting it as well.
They don't know what awaits them.
Soon you'll see how the Lord calls for His own.
If they have sinned, then,
Lord, forgive them.
But be quick about it,
they'll start coming real soon.
Where are you going?
- Nowhere.
Back to your post then.
Magazines are getting empty.
It was that devil, behind that small spruce!
You don't fucking cross Antti Rokka!
Goddamn!
Perkele!
Dad's coming home!
Dad, dad!
(Rokka) Well, well? I'm back home for a week.
(Lyyti) We've been waiting for you.
Oh, you smell of something horrible.
- Dad, don't go to war again.
It's good that you came. The horse needs to be shod
and we need a new load of wood.
Well then, it has to be done.
- We'll go inside.
Get your spirits up, hmh?
Dad, we're making Finland Great.
- You think so?
What you got there?
(Lyyti) Do you need to bother
an old man like that anymore?
4th of June 1942
The Marshal of Finland's 75th birthday -
turned out to be the grandest and
most unforgettable celebration in Finland's history.
The celebration's culmination was when
the leader of Greater Germany, Adolf Hitler -
personally arrived to congratulate
the Marshal of Finland -
on his and the Reich's behalf.
Here you are.
Cut cognac.
- Cut.
Mannerheim's liquor.
- Well, cheers.
Drink it with good luck.
- With good luck.
This is nothing. Get the Boy.
- Go get the Boy!
All right, hooch!
But Ville, maybe I ain't the best, but I've
still done pretty good. Haven't I?
Tough lads.
- I'm off to the village.
Across Svir? How will you manage that?
- There's women there, building roads.
What do you say, boss?
- A man goes and a man comes.
We're leaving tomorrow. If you want to go AWOL,
that's none of my business.
The things we have to do, we do.
Otherwise, you can do as you please.
You can go, as long as you remember that.
- I'll be here if I'm alive.
(Rokka) What the hell are you doing with that blanket?
Well, one needs a bed.
Who the hell lies on bare ground?
I think he'll succeed. He'll get
through this war without a scratch.
Too crooked a man for even a bullet to hit.
- I'm just saying.
And I mean no offense.
but Rahikainen hasn't exactly
put himself on harm's way that often.
I don't know about that,
but I guess every man is scared.
There's no man who isn't
scared of death.
("Kalinka" playing on the gramophone)
Jokkatii, jokkatii, jokkatii, jokkatii,
jokkatii, kamaja
Hietanen, dance.
Hostess of the bunker is dancing now.
The poor Finnish people
is breaking its chains
The chalice of suffering is filled to the brim
Goddamn, songs of the Rebellion!
- Let him sing!
The best sons of the noble people to the battle.
The poor Finnish people
is breaking its chains
The chalice of suffering is filled to the brim
I'm an aircraft!
An emblem of the Soviet Republic.
Boys, look!
Hietanen, the plane is going down!
(Rokka) Koskela, where are you going?
- To Jerusalem.
Mielonen.
Mielonen, perkele.
What kind of a doorman are you?
(Singing together: "Die Fahne hoch")
Marschier'n im Geist
In unser'n Reihen mit
Kam'raden die Rot geschlossen
SA marschiert
mit ruhig festem Schritt
Splendid is death, when courageous,
the first in battle, thou fallest,
Fallest in war for thy land,
dying for city and home.
Therefore, with fiery mind,
arise to fight for thy country,
Hasten to yield up thy life,
gladly, for races to come!
This behoves, above all,
a youth while still he is wearing
Wreaths on the curls of his head,
sweet-scented flowers of spring.
Handsome to women, stately to men,
he may seem in his life-time;
Handsomer is he in death,
fall’n in the thick of the fray.
An officer's toast. Gentlemen.
Forth without hesitation,
where the Marshal's sword points.
Hey, Ville. Old pal!
Die Fahne hoch
Die Reihen fest geschlossen...
- Rastui!
Siperia, polsoi, taika. Topra huja!
(Kitunen) Who's talking Russki?
Koskela from Finland.
Eats iron and shits chains.
Do you have something against me?
- Socialist-tis-tis...
I can speak Finnish too. Might be best
for you to stick with it as well.
Gu...gu...gun...
Shot coming...
Bear hunter Martti Kitunen.
Riti rati ralla
winter's frost came
hoary-beard, blizzard-hair
snow-cloak, gray-sock
Perkele, I'm shifting to second gear!
Ville, calm down!
(Koskela) Perkele! You don't dance humppa like this!
- Calm down!
What's...what's...what's up guys?
(Koskela sings)
I found a girl from Karelia
found a little cute thing.
Ville, calm down.
Ville!
Take it easy!
(Koskela) Cold, it's cold, boys...
Two coffins at the same time.
My brothers are gone...
Hot.
Try to get him to sleep.
- Old solo warrior.
Beautiful, very beautiful.
What have you been drinking here?
Hooch.
You will be responsible for this half-squad,
until Koskela and Hietala...
...Hietanen...sober up.
Hello.
Hello, old solo warrior.
Take him to bed.
- That we'll do.
Try at least.
- We'll try.
We're home.
Old grandpa, what's new?
Go home.
But don't you dare come back.
Is this Lieutenant Koskela's bunker?
It is. - Is the Lieutenant
Lieutenant Koskela himself?
Yes.
- Lieutenant, might I have a word?
Don’t see why not.
Private Honkajoki A, A1 -
first A is short for Aarne,
second A and 1 denotes my fitness grade -
reports to the Lieutenant's
platoon as a replacement.
Served before in
the 50th infantry regiment's -
2nd machine gun company -
after being wounded, was reassigned here
by the Personnel Replenishment Center -
Hereby reporting for active military duty,
firmly prepared to sacrifice my own blood -
and the blood I received at the hospital,
for the Fatherland and for the freedom of our people.
Well, welcome then.
Two others to the other half-squad.
I guess you don't trust foreign weapons?
In light of the rapid development of weaponry and technical
equipment that is currently in use in this great war -
I find that from the point of view of the nation’s defense,
the adoption of new weapons is essential.
What did you do for work?
- Forestry is my livelihood.
More specifically,
collecting pine cones.
I am an inventor.
My most immediate goal is a perpetual motion machine.
No one can invent such a thing.
- Well, maybe I'll rest a bit.
Well. What's your name and age group?
Private Hauhia, Lieutenant.
I just turned 19, Lieutenant.
Rokka. Take the boy with you the next time
you go on guard, show him the ropes.
Anything to ask?
No, Lieutenant.
We're not in the habit of formally addressing folks here.
This of course only applies to me,
other officers are a different case.
Yes, Lieutenant.
All right. You'll figure it out.
I've been in an air raid,
but that's nothing compared to real war.
There's no more real war than that.
This is the outhouse.
Are those flyers?
- Yes. They even provide us with toiler paper.
Have you lost many men?
- Every few days some guy kicks the bucket. Go!
All right, come now,
so your elder can teach you to fight.
Never go out alone,
remember that.
(Russian megaphone)
Soldiers, don't believe your officers...
Positions for riflemen.
This is their guard. You see anything?
Your officers are your archenemies!
Don't read while on guard duty,
even if that Ukkola is doing it.
Get this through your skull:
never raise your head from the trench.
Almost everyone who has died
held their head too high for an extra second.
Just look through the periscope.
You see? Like so?
(Russian megaphone) Kill your Lapuan officers
and come over!
Lapuans have been killed way back already!
Now it's the Laihians' turn!
Sons of Finland! Come get some bread!
You come and get some butter for your bread!
He does that damn thing all the time.
- Finnish working class soldiers!
You must shed your blood while -
the Germans are raping your wives and sisters!
Yes, and the mothers of the younger ones
are getting what they badly need!
Vanhala, don't you keep yelling here.
- They started it.
There's 14 dead there.
Remember their places.
If they come,
don't mix the living with the dead.
Right, take a look yourself.
Like that.
Remember to keep your head down -
Just like that.
If they come, pull from this wire.
It goes to the bunker.
Remember to keep your head down.
- Yes.
What's it like to shoot at another human being?
I don't know,
I've only been shooting at enemies.
Are they not human at all?
- No, they're not.
I don't know. The wise say so –
that an enemy is not human.
I don't think about such things.
Antti Rokka just shoots and
makes rings. You do that as well.
(Rahikainen sings)
As our way headed for battles
Where only the song of the bullets played,
We never knew as we departed...
Alarm!
(Koskela) Salo and Sihvonen,
take the boy away. - Right.
You can't say that the boy wasn't told.
"Suddenly a great company of the heavenly host
appeared with the angel, -
praising God and saying:
“Glory to God in the highest heaven,
and on earth peace to those -
on whom his favor rests.”
Merry Christmas, soldiers.
- Merry Christmas, Major!
Fair is creation,
Fairer God’s heaven,
Blest is the marching pilgrim throng.
Onward through lovely
Regions of beauty
Go we to Paradise
with song.
Ages are coming,
Ages are passing
Nations arise and disappear.
Never the joyful
Message from heaven
Wanes through the soul’s brief sojourn here.
Merry Christmas then.
Merry Christmas.
(Sarastie)
Fleeting is life in this earthly frame.
Let us, then, burn with a roaring flame,
in fire let’s soar on a heaven-bound road.
Dust to dust,
but heaven is spirit’s abode.
Soldiers,
don't believe your officers' lies!
Your officers are your archenemies!
SVIR
July 1943
What's this?
What sort of a man are you?
I'm a guard. And a guard is someone
you shouldn't rumble at.
As he has been entrusted with great powers.
What are you doing?
- I'm carving a lamp-stand, can't you see?
This is looking a bit like it already.
This is going to be a lamp-stand like no other.
Don't you understand you're on guard duty?
- Of course, why else would I be here?
You can see yourself that I'm a guard,
as I'm looking through the periscope all the time.
What's your name?
Right. I'll relay the order. Out.
Rokka. It was Lammio.
He commanded you to clean
the command post's surroundings.
The paths should be decorated with round stones.
(Vanhala) Round stones...
(Koskela) - So you're not going?
Evening.
Goddammit. Me cleaning your lawn
and decorating your paths with stones.
I chose that assignment to see
whether you'll obey or not.
You think I'll obey?
- I'd suggest you do.
You think I'm afraid?
Not at all.
If you behaved like a soldier -
especially in front
of a superior officer -
I could straight up promise
you the Mannerheim Cross.
I'd offer you a smoke.
You're the best fighter I know.
- That I am.
But don't let that illusion continue,
that because of that, everything is forgiven.
By completing the task I gave you,
you have a chance to make everything right.
You know what?
I'm not doing it.
That means court martial.
- That means a whole fucking lot else too!
Don't you fella
try playing with me.
My pregnant old lady is cutting down rye
all by herself in the Isthmus -
and you goddamn idiot -
try to make me lay
stones on the sides of your paths!
I'm not going to do that!
You believe me?
Of war, I know what needs to be known,
but I'm not here to play.
Court martial me if you wish,
but I'll not die like a dog.
A few guys will meet their demise before that.
Get that through your skull.
Who is it?
Who's there?
Don't go anywhere.
Just calmly stay there.
Go get some sleep.
Just us.
- Well, all right then.
Want a smoke? - I don't smoke.
You shouldn't either, it's a hell of a poison.
Alarm, alarm!
Get up. We had a small
wrestling match here.
Goddamn.
(Question in Russian)
Baranov.
(Answer in Russian)
What did he say? - They were meant to take a prisoner,
but that didn't work out.
Captain.
- Ville...
A Captain, this lad.
- He's a a big shot.
Don't call this in yet, Ville. They've
promised a furlough for taking a prisoner.
Vanhala!
Turn on the gramophone!
("Kalinka" plays)
Cheer up. We'll go to prison together,
we'll have no worries there.
We'll carve lamp-stands.
I'll show you how it's done.
Who's this?
- Him? He's the Baranov boy.
The Baranov boy? - Since we're doing this inquiry,
I thought we might get his over with too.
How did you get the prisoner?
- They tried to take me to Russia.
I told them that's not going to work out,
since I gotta go to this court martial.
Three of them died in the scuffle, but him I captured.
Baranov here is a big shot. He's a Captain.
How do you know that? - Boys at the bunker already
questioned him. He was leading the commando.
What kind of a man are you, anyway?
- Don't you know me? I'm Antti Rokka.
Farmer from the Isthmus.
These days, a poster boy for Tikkakoski submachine guns.
Ossi.
- Major.
Take the prisoner outside.
- Yes, sir.
All right. They'll take good care of you.
Sit.
Why do you have to go against
military discipline at every turn?
I don't know a damn thing about discipline.
I've never needed it.
I was happy to come and fight,
I want the Isthmus back.
And I'm such a man,
that none of you are a match for me.
I'm not out here because of you,
I've got a wife and kids.
And you want me to jump like a dog
whenever you say jump?
That's not going to fucking happen, you hear?
You think that's why we're here -
so that there's always someone fawning before you
clicking their heels and blabbering:
"Yes, sir,
yes, sir!"
Not for that.
But what you refer to as fawning,
is an external sign of discipline.
and its absence means
the absence of discipline.
Take into account,
that not everyone is like you.
(Lammio) Be reasonable.
Where do you think you'll find a commander,
who would tolerate as much as I have? - Reasonable.
Goddamn. You've been following your own whims,
not some principles.
Get that 2nd Lieutenant, let's get that
fucking inquiry going! I've had enough.
The battalion will manage just fine without you.
No man is indispensable in a war,
no matter who he is.
I'll forgive you. For now.
From now on,
you'll follow the rules like everyone else.
If you go singing this in the streets,
then it becomes a question of authority -
and if that happens,
I will set the mill to grind.
Your behavior will determine how
your case is handled henceforth. Dismissed.
I just remembered.
We're promised a furlough in exchange for a prisoner.
I'm due an extra 14 days then.
Specially seeing I got me a Captain.
Well, you'll get it. No denying it belongs to you.
Leave a request as soon as possible.
Dismissed.
- Major.
Dad, don't go there anymore.
It should end soon. The war.
Eat your soup.
(Lyyti hums a Karelian song,
remembering words here and there.)
I'm going now.
SVIR
December 1943
We-were going to lose this war, Antti.
They'll take everything from us.
Paw, don't you worry.
Let the big shots worry.
Attention. Right - face!
Goddammit, men. Behave yourself!
Right - face!
Dismissed - on the double!
(Susi) They'll take it all.
Since it has already grown late, I see it fit
to read a prayer to this humble abode as well.
Protect us from
the ploys of the enemy -
and especially from their snipers
and direct-fire artillery.
The rations could also
be a little larger -
if you can spare any more
for your children's needs.
Make the weather tolerable -
so that it would be more pleasant
to stand guard for your cause.
Moonlight would be welcomed
to ease tensions
and to save our
few flares.
Protect the rangers, guards,
seafarers and horse drivers.
Artillery men aren't that important.
Protect the Commander in Chief,
Chief of the General Staff -
and smaller big shots as well,
if you have time to spare.
Protect the corps, division,
regiment and battalion commanders -
and especially the commander
of the machine gun company.
And finally, in general and separately:
Protect the leaders of Finland.
So that they wouldn't, for the second time,
strike their heads on a Karelian pine tree.
Amen.
RETREAT FROM SVIR
June 1944
Greetings. We have to depart now.
(Sarastie) The enemy has launched a grand offensive
in the Karelian Isthmus.
It is advancing rapidly
on both flanks.
Consequently, our regiment
will now start withdrawing towards our old border.
Battalion departure time: 06.00
Get to work.
(Rokka) Get this backpack on.
Good now?
Where do I pack these?
- Take them back. They can wait us here.
We're coming back?
- Sure we are.
We are going to a very nice place.
Hurry up now.
Bring the cows to the yard, they're coming with us.
Some waves from Ääninen.
This stream didn't end up
as Finland's new border.
Air attack!
To cover!
Right.
- Salo was hit.
Get moving, boys!
- Forward!
Get moving!
I'm running.
Before the eyes of the almighty God
and in the presence of this assembly -
I ask you, Jorma Juhani Kariluoto:
will you take Sirkka Linnea Klenberg to be your wedded wife -
and will you be faithful to her and to
love her in days of joy and of adversity,
as long as you both shall live?
I do.
Hey!
- Don't go.
(Sirkka) Would you apply for a transfer to Helsinki?
You'd get it easily.
(Kariluoto) Right...
You've already done your part.
They need me back there.
Every officer is needed at the front.
It is my duty to fight for Finland.
For Ingria and Karelia.
(Kariluoto) Hello there!
Old Ville, you're still around.
But who'd take you out?
God won't have you and the Devil knows he's due.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
How are things? - We're here.
Been moving a lot while you've been away.
2nd platoon is across the road,
1st and 4th are on this side.
3rd is in reserve.
Jaeger platoon is patrolling on both flanks,
we have no other reserves.
Sarastie believed the line along the brook will hold.
- Perhaps.
But both flanks are open.
I’ve got a thing or two in my bag.
I'll change my gear and
take over the company after that.
It's all over.
As over as it can be.
There's no hope, not a trace.
Then we'll fight hopelessly.
That’s what we’ve been doing this whole time.
How old are you?
- Born in 1925, Sergeant.
Nineteen. I'm astonished.
We were young as well in the beginning,
but not children.
Sergeant. Where are the Russkis,
so that I can start killing them?
Don't yell so loudly.
They'll hear you and flee
when they realize you've come.
Get down! Get down!
Stay in your foxholes. Stay low!
I told you to stay in your foxhole!
But you...
You got hit on your nose a bit.
It hurts...
Take it easy.
Your life doesn't
depend just on your eyes.
If we make it out alive, we'll certainly meet again.
I'll visit sometime. - See you then.
Say hello to the guys.
Take care of yourself.
I can walk.
Who's shooting? Our guys?
Help! I'm burning!
Help! I'm on fire!
- I'm not leaving you! I'm not leaving you!
Take my hand.
I'm not leaving...
Help! Help!
Why did you leave me?
Captain, the enemy has
cut the battalion in two.
Captain Lammio has ordered us to fall back.
You're now the senior company commander
on this side of the cutoff.
Get me the commander
of the Battle Group.
Connect me to
the Lieutenant Colonel.
Captain.
First.
- Cut to minimum edge.
The position has to be held.
- I can go around.
Perkele! The point is not to go around,
but to hold the position.
Fucking goddammit.
A quick strike will solve the situation.
Hit hard. You choose the method.
- Understood, Colonel.
We'll quietly withdraw through these swamps,
we can slip out that way. - The order was clear.
The line can barely hold now.
- The commander knows the situation.
Excuses are of no use now.
- Karjula doesn't know what he demands of us.
The enemy has been there for three hours.
You can be fucking sure they've dug their heels in.
It'll hurt only once.
You know the order.
We need to put together a strike squad.
Russki has flanked to the command post.
We'll counterattack.
- Well I'm a strike squad all by myself, you don't need much more.
Kariluoto attacks on the other side of the road.
- Got it.
Asumaniemi, come here.
Corporal?
- You're coming with me.
Forward!
Jeesus perkele!
Fire at that heap next to the pine!
Shoot like hell! And you, cover me!
Cover me!
Jeesus perkele!
Bread.
Let's empty a couple foxholes to clear an opening.
Then we take 'em out.
Saatana!
You can't get through here!
You have grenades?
- No.
Then we rush!
- Goddammit!
Koskela! Get up here!
Boys, forward!
Private.
- Lieutenant.
Tell Captain Kariluoto that
the command post has been reclaimed.
And that Major Sarastie has fallen.
- Understood.
Ukkola! Ukkola!
Line! Get in a line!
We hit 'em now!
Don't give up!
Fourth, forward!
Hit 'em now! Forward!
- Forward!
Forward!
Runner! - Captain, Koskela can't
continue with the attack immediately.
The Lieutenant suggests that you wait...
- Wait for what?
If we can't get through here now,
then it's not going to happen later.
Say to Koskela that we'll advance.
Leaders, lead by example!
Fall back!
- Fourth platoon, forward!
Forward!
Under my command, the battalion will not
continue with the attack.
Fucking goddammit.
The positions will not be abandoned.
Lieutenant, the enemy is
attacking at the brook line.
The enemy is attacking at the brook line.
The whole battalion can get encircled.
We're falling back.
- Equipment must be brought with you.
I'll bring the battalion. Over.
You don't open the radio for a while then.
Wounded to the northern side of the road.
What of the dead? We even brought out the Captain's body.
- The living are enough.
Gather the companies. Move out!
The machine guns will be
tossed into the pond.
We’ll just keep one as a souvenir.
Will you bring yours?
Whatever.
- Just toss?
Just toss.
Like this.
Good riddance, goddamn bitch.
Get the wounded up and moving.
Viirilä, take point.
March after me.
Boys, try to hurry up.
(Ukkola)
Vanhala... Cover me with something after.
Load the wounded,
get rid of all the other stuff.
Perkele. Where was your reserve?
You're squatting by the road with no cover at all.
- Lieutenant Colonel.
We lost our best possible position because
of your hasty assessment of the situation.
The men were disheartened by the losses.
- I know the situation, you don't have to explain it to me.
You handle the battalion until Lammio arrives.
Lieutenant Ovaska gets the machine guns.
I told the men to toss the machine guns into the pond
to get them to carry the wounded.
I left only one.
Into the pond? Tossed the machine guns?
Goddammit, Lieutenant.
This is deliberate sabotage,
you're aiding the enemy!
I told you to bring the equipment.
Machine gunners are machine gunners,
not medics.
You were the battalion commander,
not a goddamn nurse.
And men! Attention!
Are you sheep or Finnish soldiers?
The positions are either held,
or you die in them.
Be ashamed, goddammit!
I wouldn't dare call myself a Finn,
if I behaved like you lot.
And now, man the positions.
Stay put!
They'll steamroll us!
- No they won't.
There's a minefield there. Stay put!
Sergeant! Grab a satchel charge, we're going.
- You can't get there!
Satchel charge.
Let's go!
Go, go!
Positions lost. Third company is
partly fleeing in panic.
Perkele! Perkele!
Goddamn flock of sheep!
Not a step further!
Man the positions! Those who still flee,
have forfeited their lives.
Not a step further!
Boys, they're coming. Tanks!
Stop! Where are you going?
Stop!
For the last time, where do you think you're going?
To Inari to fuck some wolves.
Under military law,
I sentenced the traitor to die.
This is about Finland.
Goddammit!
Everyone, man your positions!
Man your positions! Perkele!
Get down!
- Go!
Don't flee!
Everyone to your positions!
Get to positions!
Help!
Positi...
Keep your distance.
More distance!
(Lotta)
I can't ride with this. Can I hop on?
(Korpela)
We don't haul horse shit on Sundays.
That's how it fucking is.
(Lammio) Leave your bicycle,
get on the next vehicle.
Private Korpela. What did you just say?
I said what I said. What kind of
fancy pants are you, following me around?
Flies have usually swarmed around horses.
Are they swarming around people now too?
Get to cover!
Go away!
You fuckers just keep on shooting!
Well shoot away!
LAST DEFENSIVE POSITIONS
July 1944
You remember how we swam in Vuoksi as kids?
- Antti, we're never seeing that river again.
Nothing but corpses swimming there now.
- We're gonna be swimming in that river, you believe me?
If anybody gets that far.
Boys, don't save your sugar.
It'll just get all wet and then it'll be ruined.
We're swimming soon.
We’ll hop that stream if it comes to it.
- Damn it, boy! You hush up now, you hear?
Swallow that sugar,
don’t leave it to get wet!
The officers keep babbling that
these positions are going to hold.
I don't know what it is, but I just don't get along
with those officers. - I don't know.
Have you ever thought
that you might be at fault?
Me?
- Yep.
I'm always speaking sense.
They just keep on babbling about nothing.
Karelia is gone. The war is lost.
I don't have anything to lose anymore.
I'm just trying to make them pay for taking the Isthmus.
(Asumaniemi)
All right guys, we'll get to fight soon!
Antti, get away from there.
Antti, Antti, get in this pit.
We leave now.
Fall back.
- Paw, you go ahead.
Boys, get back!
Okay, young guys go over first, we'll hold them off.
Määttä, take the machine gun.
Go!
(Vanhala) They're on the other side! I'm going!
- Fall back!
Paw, get across! Go!
Antti, I'm hit!
- How bad?
Leave me!
(Honkajoki) Rokka!
Cover them!
Antti, you've been hit,
I heard it.
(Jalovaara) Vanhala, gather a strike squad.
We have to recapture the positions.
You see that body?
- Yes.
There's a light machine gun next to it.
Get to the grave and take it out.
I can get to the grave.
If not there, then at least to my own.
I better take Asumaniemi and Honkajoki,
no more.
We'll provide cover fire.
I don't dare to volunteer.
You have to order me to go.
Well, then I order you to go.
- Well, that's a different story.
Submachine gun.
(Asumaniemi) Let's go!
Goddammit, boy!
- You got the grenades ready?
(Asumaniemi) Throw right.
(Asumaniemi) Ding ding.
(Asumaniemi) Slobos are leaving.
Get moving!
(Asumaniemi) We succeeded.
- Strike squad Vanhala, excellent work.
Your native land won't forget you.
I'm out of magazines. Hey guys -
ARMISTICE
4th of September 1944
No more...
No more...Stop it!
- Get to cover!
Have to get out!
Let me go!
The loser will get the shit kicked out of it,
and that's that.
If we had that bow now.
(Radio speech) Honorable citizens,
this is a summary of the situation:
We have taken the first step -
towards peaceful relations -
with our great eastern neighbour.
We have taken a step in a road,
which might hold unexpected dangers.
We do not yet know the terms,
that will be placed upon us -
but because our great eastern neighbour
has not demanded our unconditional surrender -
we have seen it as our duty -
to fulfill the preconditions set by
the Soviet government and her allies -
and thusly demonstrate
our sincere desire for peace.
("Finlandia hymn")