I used to work in the old city
as a coolie.
I used a pushcart
to carry luggage
from the boats
that docked next to the shore.
After the old city moved
across the river
they took down your old house,
no matter who you were.
I had to find a place on my own
so I built a hut
next to the shore.
Right here where no one lives
I can plant some vegetables.
There are dots in this one.
That doesn't look so good.
Let's move on.
I think my family is living
a pretty good life.
I think the downside would be
that the house we're living in
is not in very good condition.
But the good side
is that we have good food.
Because I know
that many of my classmates
don't eat as well as we do.
I want to go to high school
after middle school.
High school?
Where's the money for that?
Many of my classmates
are going to high school.
Now we're in a socialist society
that demands knowledge.
We need to go to high school.
Besides, the country needs
well-educated talent.
So middle school is not enough.
It's not that
I don't want you to go.
Because if you go alone,
do we just forget about
your little brother and sister?
It's better
if you go and earn some money.
Then you can afford to go later.
How can I make that much money?
We'll see then,
if you can't make that much...
The water will soon rise
when the Three Gorges Dam
closes.
I'm really worried.
But even if my heart worries,
there is nothing I can do.
The Three Gorges Dam is
a national project, not private.
The higher level of government
distributes the money.
But when the money trickles down
through the hands of the people,
like corrupt officials,
it just disappears.
My father was
a minor village official
for the old government,
so after liberation
he was labelled
a counter-revolutionary.
Our farm collective
persecuted my family,
so we fled from my hometown.
My mom starved to death in
the Great Famine of the 1960s.
It was like this
during Mao's time.
Before I think my dream
was to go to university
and be a scientist.
But now i think it's impossible.
I'd say maybe let Yu Shui...
... go to work.
I think that's what
she should do.
We can't make enough money
for her to study.
How can she go to school
when she only scored 400 points?
She can only go to work.
Let her go to work first...
Of course
I'm worried that
if we let her go study
then we'll be short of money.
But if we don't
she may blame us later.
When the water rises and
the Three Gorges gate closes,
where can you farm?
You can't even have a life.
She'll be fine
working on the boat.
Some of her classmates
are working on the Fengdu boats.
Let's go dance!
Hello?
If you have nothing to do,
Chen Bo Yu is leaving.
Come and join us.
The mood's not right!
Let's go to Wild Cat to dance.
Don't be like this,
lingering in my mind,
you'll find out how lonely I am.
In my dreams, I've kissed you
a thousand times...
When the boat managers
came to our school,
they told me they hired me
because I have two advantages:
First I'm good-looking,
and second I'm good at English.
I am abitious, I'm never
satisfied with what I have.
I don't want
a flat and tasteless life.
Tonight's about having fun.
Tomorrow will be about
my career.
Career is the top priority!
When I come back
in the New Year,
I guarantee you guys
more fun than you can handle!
In my opinion
you are still students.
Whenever you have difficulties
in your life, give me a shout.
Soon I'll be earning
my own money.
I'll have more than you guys.
Let's fill it up.
Drink up to show that we share
the same passions, right?
Okay, brothers forever!
Whoa, what the fuck?
Remember when you leave
to listen and obey.
Otherwise, it's no good.
Go get me some more rice.
Go get it for your father.
C'mon, be quick.
Be good.
Mom, can you see me off?
See you off?
There's no need.
You know your way.
You know you way.
Besides, you're a grown-up now.
You're a middle school graduate.
I don't read. I might take you
to the wrong boat.
You're not a real mother!
It's not worth it!
Stubborn temper!
Come and collect the plates!
It's your responsibility!
Hurry up!
You're having too much fun,
It's your turn to clean!
Remember to
clean the table later.
Remember that.
You know our family is poor.
You can't compare us to others.
You understand
the situation, no?
We don't even
have anything to eat.
How can we
afford to rent a house?
I know you don't want
your parents to suffer.
Your hard work will pay off.
I know it's because your father
and I don't have the skills
that we have to exploit you.
If we had a choice,
how could we do this to you?
You know your father
isn't educated. He can't read.
Whatever clothing you need
buy a little bit.
The rest of the money
send back to your parents.
We'll put it aside.
In your daily life, eat well.
Don't save money on that, okay?
When you spend money on food,
don't worry about us too much.
I'm going to give you
an English name.
We'll call you Cindy.
- What's your name?
- Chen Bo Yu.
- What's you English name?
- Jerry.
He's Jerry. Cindy.
This is our operations manager,
Michael.
You have two long-sleeves,
two trousers and two t-shirts.
Here are two long trousers.
Here is a tie and apron,
one for each.
Here is a tie clip.
How do you like it?
Eyes front!
Stand to the right!
Who's still moving?
You can't hold still
for a short time?
Quality service.
Do we have the confidence?
Yes.
I can't hear the confidence
in your voice.
- Do you have it or not?
- Yes!
That's better.
Let's talk about
studying English.
Twenty years ago,
when I first brought
foreign tourists,
people in Hong Kong
would call them
"foreign devils".
So now, let's invite Cindy.
You can try speaking slower.
My "University of Life"
has just begun.
You should greet guests
wherever you meet them,
even by the staircase.
No! Don't say, "Hello"!
Normally you say:
That's the proper way.
Most of the tourists are French
this time.
At lunch you let out the water.
When you come back at dinnertime
you add water.
You have to
keep plates and bowls seperate.
Otherwise, you damage them.
Here's the daily cleaning fluid.
Press that to wash.
If you don't do this properly,
the water leaks out.
It'll be messy.
Have a look.
This is the sink.
Here's the electricity switch
The first thing you do
every morning is switch it on.
The whole place will light up.
Plates with a blue circle
belong to the kitchen.
When the time comes,
I will set you up
with more complex work.
Okay.
So tired!
Pay attention
when talking to Americans
to not be overly modest
or polite.
Too modest
or a even little bit humble,
they might think
you're a bit fake.
Don't compare Canada to
the United States.
Don't talk about
Quebec independence.
Avoid the issue
of Northern Ireland.
Don't talk about this issue.
Don't talk about monarchies,
royalty or royal families,
or any relevant serious
political issues.
Don't call anybody
old, pale or fat!
In English you will say "plump".
Drain the water
after you take out the garbage.
Make sure everything is clean.
That's it.
You shouldn't say
that is good enough.
You need to finish it.
Make sure you clean the mess
thoroughly and properly.
You can't leave things
half-done.
If you have to clean this place,
then make it clean.
Don't cry.
Just do it slowly, okay?
You will learn more
by toughening up.
Don't be upset.
This is not difficult.
All you need to do
is to clean this up.
That's our duty.
It's not any easier
to serve in the dining hall.
You still need to work hard.
And this is straightforward work
and easy to do.
You always have to remind her
at work.
Yes, always have to remind her.
She doesn't know enough,
especially when
it comes to hygiene.
And communicating with people.
I got blisters on my hands
when I first came on the boat.
Nobody can help you.
If you're doing guest rooms,
you have to do
your own work.
Everybody has
their own duties to cover.
She really has to change a lot.
Is she afraid of asking?
No, I don't think she realizes
that she needs to ask.
She should be more hunble
when she's working
in the kitchen.
I think she's a bit shy, though.
She lives by the river
and her family is really poor.
If her family is poor then
she should work even harder.
Oh, this one!
I was wondering what it was.
Yu Shui, what are you doing?
I'm writing some stuff.
Writing your diary?
Yeah, sort of .. diary.
I'm worried
if the river rises back home
and floods our land and house.
I'm worried that my father
can't find a place to move to
and what will he do afterwards?
I'm just worried about them.
I miss them every day.
We'll eat as soon as your mother
cooks the winter-melon.
It's still early.
It's not even
6:00 in the morning yet.
- What dynasty is it?
- Ming dynasty!
- Ming dynasty?
- Yes, Ming era!
How much for that one?
Sell it if you like my offer.
Don't be so difficult!
We're moving. The prices
are already the lowest!
There will always be people
who need to make sacrifices.
It's impossible to stop
the building of
the Three Gorges Dam
because of my own needs.
Sacrificing the little family
for the big family.
If you house will be flooded,
then don't stay here!
I will report to
a higher-level government.
Look, they're fighting
about resettlement again.
You just can't help it.
Go take a look!
We did all the calculations,
signed all the papers,
and had the house demolished.
After all these months,
we still didn't get
the promised compensation.
The Zhan village got 300 yuan,
while we only got
200 yuan compensation.
They had people
come and beat us!
What can you say about us
getting beaten up?
They tore down our machines
and threw them on the ground.
It's hard being a human
but being a common person
in China is even more difficult.
China is too hard
for common people.
Some officials are like bandits:
Beating, smashing, robbing...
Even wanting a roof
over our heads is difficult.
When we had to move,
we were dragged and beaten.
No money to bribe the officials,
so they gave us a hard time.
For common people
living day-by-day...
...it's really not easy.
Ladies and gentlemen, you know,
after this dam is finished
the most important thing
is the relocatee.
How about the relocatee?
Would you like to have a look?
This is the new apartment
of the relocatees.
Where is the old house?
The old house
is already underwater.
Ladies and gentlemen,
shall we get off the coach?
If you have
any questions or issues,
you can ask the farmer directly.
I will just do
the job of the interpreter.
In the farmer's house, they have
the refrigerator, colour TV,
air conditioning.
I think the house is okay.
Seeing is believing.
Would you like to have a look
with your own eyes?
I have been doing this
for almost half-a-month now.
The weather has been dry.
You can't get any income
from farming.
You can't grow anything
in the land.
When the Three Gorges gate
closes,
the water level will soon rise
and the farmland
will be flooded.
I'll have to earn
some extra cash
to pay for my kids' studies
and to live.
No money if I stay home.
It's coming, coming, coming.
Watch out!
Watch out, watch out!
I don't like these
with the hood.
Let me find you a larger one.
That's kind of small.
How about you just try it on?
Just put it on, okay?
Just put it on.
Can we try it?
Here we go.
Just hang your clothes up there.
It's kind of tight.
It's not revealing!
That's not revealing.
She didn't
clip the button properly.
Don't slouch.
You have to put the sleeves
like this. To this side.
That's nice.
Yes, it's better
than the other one.
Like that!
She should straighten
her shoulders!
That will look much better.
Yeah, that's better.
It's nice. How much is it?
It's 148 yuan
with a 20 percent discount.
20 percent discount?
Help me calculate.
How about a little cheaper?
How about 100 yuan?
Okay.
Mom!
You're early.
When did you come?
- I've just come down.
- Just come down.
This must be your father!
Your parents, right?
Nice to meet you.
My name is Zheng.
How about we go on the boat
for a little sit-down?
- That's not necessary.
- It's nothing. Let's go.
Let's go have
a look around, okay?
- Okay.
- Yes, come. Come.
I'm sorry if my daughter
is too young and disobedient...
Hopefully you can tolerate her.
You have a nice view
from the bar.
Employees need to speak English.
Little Yu
is working hard to learn.
Yes, that's for sure.
The kind of thing
she always wants to learn.
The situation is impossible
because of
our family's condition.
Now that she's on the boat
she might need
a lot of help from you.
As for herself, unlike others,
she doesn't mess around
that much.
She's never had
a chance to go out
and see the world before.
This is her first time.
It's a big step forward.
To deal with Western customers,
from developed countries,
that's a big change.
You should have confidence
in yourself and your daughter.
Confidence to believe
that things are changing.
The dreams you cannot fulfill
can be fulfilled
through you daughter,
through her hard work,
and the progress of society.
Don't worry!
- Say goodbye to your parents.
- Goodbye.
- Be good!
- Okay.
Listen to your manager.
Work hard.
Let's go.
I'll see you later.
I pray to the Holy Father
It's a blessing
to believe in God
I pray everyday
that God comes to help me
I pray for the youth
The youth should also
come to God
To learn how to be
and how to tolerate
Don't quarrel
Praise God
God, I beg for your blessing.
Your humble daughter
with many troubles.
Tears in my eyes,
thoughts stuck in my mind,
as if someone is clawing
at my heart.
I'm God's child. I depend on you
to eat, drink and live.
Wherever you go I will
follow forever. Praise God.
If you are satisfied
with our service,
we feel very cheerful.
Welcome to our boat again.
Whoa. Thirty. Thirty!
I'm so happy.
Fuck, 30 US dollars!
I can't believe it.
You did nothing
and she gave you 30 dollars!
They're out of their minds!
Now, since
I'm earning my own tips,
I've learned
how to handle rich people.
You have to know
how to use your eyes, right?
Normally I don't help
the elderly.
Even if they ask I won't go.
I would ask someone else
because I know that they're
the fucking poorest.
They are the stingiest.
They only give two yuan tips.
What the fuck do I do
with two yuan?
If they're too young or too old,
they won't give tips.
The best are the middle-aged men
or women.
I earn the most.
Fuck, think about it.
My mom only earns
1000 yuan a month.
My father makes about 2000 yuan.
Actually less than that.
How's life on the boat?
Life is pretty good.
Do you eat meat everyday?
Everyday we always have
meat and vegetables.
Do they have television?
Yeah, there's television,
fans...
The tour guides' cabins
are even air conditioned.
Did you meet any friends
on the boat?
I've gotten to know
quite a few.
One of them is called Xie Juan.
Her English name is Yo Yo.
She actually treats me
pretty well.
We're always joking around
and laughing together.
She gives me nicknames.
Because I have darker skin,
she calls me
a little grey rabbit!
I don't know
whether to laugh or cry.
Do you feel homesick?
Yeah, I do. Everyday.
You still want to come back
and see us, right?
Yeah.
Girls should know
how to pamper themselves.
Will you blame me
if I hurt you with this?
What do you think?
You need to dress-up
so you're more pleasant
to the eye.
It's easier to be with them.
Is that right?
That's right.
I'm drawing you
to look like a panda.
You're laughing all the time.
Got to put on lipstick
to bring out the shape.
Now you look so womanly!
It'd be better
if you hair was longer.
You'd look like a doll!
Now smile.
Isn't that cute?
Please welcome Chen Bo Yu.
I dedicate this song to you.
Enjoy your vacation.
Thank you.
When the earth rotates,
it's a day
That means I'm missing you
for another extra day
Forever the same horizon
My heart
will never change
Love you for then thousand years
That love can overcome
all obstacles
Surpass the limitations of time
Bring closer
another part of the world
Stay with eacht other,
close together forever
I told Chen Bo Yu that if he
wants to learn I can teach him.
But he doesn't respect me.
I hate these types of people.
He's so arrogant.
He's like an actor.
Not someone who goes to work.
So we've never taken him
as one of us.
He's a superstar.
- Look at him.
- Just eat your food.
Don't make me choke.
Chen Bo Yu,
what are you thinking?
I'm asking,
I'm going to cry.
Self-criticism. Heping and I carried suitcases to room 332.
As usual we went in,
put down the luggage
and said hello to the guests.
We stayed for several minutes
and the customer gave us
20 US Dollars for tips.
Then we left
and closed the door.
I didn't ask her for it.
I never said: "You need
to give me some personal tips".
I never said this at all.
We closed the door and left.
She complained.
She complained and said
we asked her for tips.
I don't think
I'm suitable for this job.
I'm too arrogant.
I look down on everything.
I think I was born
with a silver spoon.
My parents
keep me in the future.
I'm very young.
I'm 19 years old.
This is their responsibility.
But Yu Shui is only sixteen.
We're different.
I come from a richer family.
I can continue my studies but
does she have the opportunity?
Can her family support her
to go to school?
Well, my family can.
First, when
the customer come in
you need to smile, got it?
Do you know how to smile?
A gentle smile?
You can't smile like that!
You have to be natural.
Not a silly smile.
Then let the guests
remember your name.
Your English name.
Introduce yourself to them.
My name is Cindy.
Do you know any tourist spots
along the Yangtze?
For example, do you know where
we are now?
No, I don't know.
From now on,
you need to know them, okay?
You have to work harder
and maybe later on
you'll be promoted to server
out here and earn tips.
The situation now
is that there's no way
I can get compensation
In the end it feels like
the rock I carried
has smashed my foot.
As a peasant who doesn't read
or watch television
I can't make any judgment on it.
I believe this business belongs
to the upper government.
Nobody cares about me.
Like people say,
"I'm like an illegal citizen".
Jerry, you've been here
for a while now, right?
Yeah, it's been
three months already.
The probation period.
So for
the three months probation
I think you've somehow
learned things and advanced.
However, in other words...
That means both your performance
and your capability
are below the standards
of our ship's requirements.
That means you will have to
leave our company
and find another job.
Over-confidence, self-conceit,
and self-centeredness
for a young man,
especially for a single child,
are the characteristics
you need to overcome.
That's how I feel about it.
Do you think the construction
is benficial to you?
There must be some benefits.
It's beneficial to our country,
but for individuals,
I don't think
it will do me any good.
- You carry this with you?
- Yeah.
- What's that?
- It's my clothes.
I can tell you are from Fengdu
from this.
I'm going to show you.
Come here.
Have you ever seen this?
This is the dam.
- Do you have a dam in Fengdu?
- No.
What's this?
This is part of
the Yangtze river
and the dam
cuts it into two pieces
cuts it into two pieces.
This is what we call damming.
We did it back in 1997 and 2003.
Have you seen it on TV?
Yeah, but it's better
to be here myself.
Electricity is transmitted
through wires.
Maybe it goes to Fengdu.
I don't know.
I have no idea about that.
So these are all electric?
Yes, now it's all electrical.
Keep it low so
it's easier for me to lift it.
Don't you get it?
- There's a big crack here.
- Where?
Push! Yeah, push it forward
a bit.
- Do you want me to hold it?
- No, it's not necessary.
Here's our new home.
Before in the little hut,
even though it didn't look good,
you didn't need money
for vegetables or water.
Up here, you have to buy them.
Go and make your own bed.
I'm looking for
the palm mattress.
Stretch the corner a bit.
Our country is really strong
and prosperous now.
So strong and prosperous
that it can actually stop
the gigantic river.