Marta.
Curtain!
High on a hill was a lonely goatherd
Loud was the voice
Of the lonely goatherd
Folks in a town
That was quite remote heard
Lusty and clear
From the goatherd's throat heard
Marta. Marta!
Gretl, the prince!
A prince on the bridge
Of a castle moat heard
Men on a road
With a load to tote heard
Men in the midst
Of a table d'hôte heard
Men drinking beer
With the foam afloat heard
One little girl
ln a pale pink coat heard
She yodeled back
To the lonely goatherd
Soon her mama
With a gleaming gloat heard
What a duet for a girl and goatherd
One little girl
ln a pale pink coat heard
She yodeled back
To the lonely goatherd
Soon her mama
With a gleaming gloat heard
What a duet for a girl and goatherd
Happy are they
Soon the duet will become a trio
-Bravo!
Very good!
Wonderful!
-Can we keep the puppets, Uncle Max?
-Yes, can we?
Of course you may, my darlings.
Why else did I tell Professor Kohner
to send the bill to your father?
Well done, fräulein.
I really am very much impressed.
They're your children, captain.
My dear, is there anything
you can't do?
Well, I'm not sure
I'll make a good nun.
If you have any problems,
I'd be happy to help you.
Attention, everyone!
I have an announcement to make.
Surprise! Surprise!
Today, after a long
and desperate search. . .
. . .I have found a most exciting
entry for the Salzburg Folk Festival.
Congratulations, Max.
And who will you
be exploiting this time?
-The Saint lgnatius Choir?
-Guess again.
Well, let me see now.
The Klopmann Choir?
-No, no, no, no.
-No, no?
Tell us.
A singing group all in one family.
You'll never guess, Georg.
What a charming idea!
Whose family?
Yours.
They'll be the talk of the festival.
-Well, now, what's so funny?
-You are, Max.
You're expensive, but very funny.
-They'll be a sensation!
-No, Max.
It's a wonderful idea.
Fresh, original.
Max! My children
do not sing in public.
You can't blame me for trying.
Children, who shall we hear
from next?
Who?
Yes.
The vote is unanimous.
You, captain.
Me?
-I don't understand.
-Please.
No, no, no, no.
I'm told that you were quite good.
-That was a very, very long time ago.
-I remember, Father.
-Play us something we know.
-Oh, please, Father.
Well. . . .
-Why didn't you tell me?
-What?
To bring along my harmonica.
Edelweiss
Every morning you greet me
Small and white
Clean and bright
You look happy...
... to meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
-Edelweiss
Every morning you greet me
-Small and white
-Clean and bright
You look happy...
... to meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
Anytime you say the word, Georg,
you can be part of my new act:
The von Trapp Family Singers.
I have a wonderful idea, Georg.
Let's really fill this house
with music.
You must give a grand
and glorious party for me.
-A party?
-Yes, Father, please!
It's high time
I met all your friends. . .
. . .and they met me.
Don't you agree?
-I see what you mean.
-Oh, please!
Children, it's bedtime.
Come now, say good night.
Good night, Father.
-Good night.
-Good night, Baroness Schraeder.
Good night, Father.
Good night, Uncle Max.
It'll be my first party, Father!
-Captain.
-Herr Zeller. Baroness Schraeder.
-Good evening, Herr Zeller.
-Baroness.
How do you do? Good evening.
Did you notice the obvious
display of the Austrian flag?
The women look so beautiful.
I think they look ugly.
You're just scared of them.
Silly, only grown-up men fear women.
-I think the men look beautiful.
-How would you know?
Liesl, who are you dancing with?
Nobody.
Oh, yes, you are.
May I have this dance?
I'd be delighted, young man.
Why didn't you tell me
you could dance?
We feared you'd make us all dance.
The von Trapp Family Dancers.
What are they playing?
It's the Laendler.
An Austrian folk dance.
-Show me.
-I haven't danced since I was little.
You remember. Please?
-Well. . . .
-Please.
All right. Come on over here.
Now you bow and I curtsy.
-Like this?
-Fine. Now we go for a little walk.
One, two, three. One, two, three.
One, two, three, step together.
Now, step hop, step hop.
Now turn under. Not quite.
This way. Hop step, hop.
And under.
Kurt, we'll have to practice.
Do allow me, will you?
I don't remember anymore.
-Your face is all red.
-Is it?
I don't suppose I'm used to dancing.
Why, that was beautifully done.
What a lovely couple you make.
It's time the children
said good night.
We'll be in the hall.
-We have something special prepared.
-Right!
Yes, come on!
All that needless worrying, Georg.
You thought you wouldn't find
a friend at the party.
-A bit chilly out tonight, isn't it?
-Oh, I don't know.
It seemed rather warm to me.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The children of Captain von Trapp
wish to say good night to you.
There's a sad sort of clanging
From the clock in the hall
And the bells in the steeple too
And up in the nursery
An absurd little bird
Is popping up to say "coo-coo"
Coo-coo
Regretfully they tell us
But firmly they compel us
To say goodbye
To you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, good night
I hate to go
And leave this pretty sight
So long, farewell,
Auf Wiedersehen, adieu
Adieu, adieu
To you and you and you
So long, farewell
Au revoir, auf Wiedersehen
I'd like to stay
And taste my first champagne
-Yes?
-No.
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
I leave and heave a sigh
And say goodbye
Goodbye
I'm glad to go
I cannot tell a lie
I flit, I float
I fleetly flee, I fly
The sun has gone to bed
And so must I
So long
Farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
Goodbye
Extraordinary!
What they'd do at the festival.
Young lady,
I must have a word with you.
Georg, you won't let this girl
get away. She must join the party.
-No, really l--
-Stop. Stop it now.
-Georg, please.
-You can if you want to, fräulein.
I insist.
You will be my dinner partner.
This is business.
Franz. . .
. . .set another place next to mine
for Fräulein Maria.
-Whatever you say.
-It appears to be all arranged.
-It does.
-I'm not suitably dressed.
You can change. We'll wait.
Captain, you must be very proud
of your youngsters.
I am, thank you.
Is there a more beautiful expression
of what is good in our country. . .
. . .than the innocent voices
of our children?
Oh, come now, baron.
Would you have us believe that Austria
holds a monopoly on virtue?
Herr Zeller, some of us prefer
Austrian voices raised in song. . .
. . .to ugly German threats.
The ostrich buries his head
in the sand. . .
. . .and sometimes in the flag.
Perhaps those who would warn you that
the Anschluss is coming, and it is. . .
. . .would get further with you by setting
their words to music.
If the Nazis take over Austria, you
will be the entire trumpet section.
You flatter me.
Oh, how clumsy of me.
I meant to accuse you.
It's very kind of you
to offer to help me, baroness.
I'm delighted, Maria.
I really don't think I have anything
that would be appropriate.
Now where is that lovely little thing
you were wearing the other evening?
When the captain couldn't keep
his eyes off you.
Couldn't keep his eyes off me?
Come, my dear, we are women.
Let's not pretend we don't know
when a man notices us.
-Here we are.
-The captain notices everybody.
There's no need to feel
so defensive, Maria.
You are quite attractive, you know.
The captain would hardly be a man
if he didn't notice you.
Baroness, I hope you're joking.
Not at all.
I've never done a thing to--
You don't have to, my dear.
Nothing's more irresistible to a man
than a woman who's in love with him.
-In love with him?
-Of course.
What makes it so nice is
he thinks he's in love with you.
But that's not true.
Surely you've noticed the way
he looks into your eyes.
And you know, you blushed in his arms
when you were dancing just now.
Don't take it to heart.
He'll get over it soon enough,
I think.
Men do, you know.
Then I should go.
I mustn't stay here.
-Is there something I can do to help?
-No, nothing.
Yes.
Don't say a word to the captain.
No, I wouldn't dream of it.
Goodbye, Maria.
I'm sure you'll make a very fine nun.
Champagne, darling.
I feel like celebrating. Cheers.
-You know something.
-Perhaps.
If you're so clever, tell me how to
get fräulein to influence Georg.
I want those children in the festival.
Elsa, this is important to Austria.
Wouldn't do you any harm either.
I thought of that.
Well, if it's a matter of influence. . .
. . .maybe the one you have
to be talking to is me.
-Two.
-Three.
-Four.
-Five.
-Six.
-Seven.
Eight.
-Four.
-Two.
-Seven.
-Five.
-Two.
-Six.
Isn't this fun?
-Four.
-I'm number five.
-Oh, yes.
-Eight.
-Two.
-Four.
Six.
Two.
Baroness Schraeder, do you mind
if we stop now? We're tired.
Whatever you want, dear.
We'll do it again tomorrow.
The country's so restful, isn't it?
Have some lemonade.
There must be an easier way.
I get a fiendish delight thinking
of you as the mother of seven.
How do you plan to do it?
Darling, haven't you ever heard. . .
. . .of a delightful little thing
called boarding school?
Baroness Machiavelli.
Uncle Max, where's Father?
I think he's in the house.
What's the matter
with all you gloomy pussies?
-Nothing.
-I know. Let's have a rehearsal.
What for?
Let's make believe we're on-stage
at the festival.
-I don't feel like singing.
-Not without Fräulein Maria.
Liesl, get the guitar.
Come on, Marta.
Everybody into the group.
Get in your places.
Now be cheerful, right?
Give us the key, Liesl.
Now, impress me.
Gretl, why don't you sing?
I can't. I've got a sore finger.
But you sang so beautifully
the night of the party.
Come on, all of you.
Try something you know.
Enjoy it. Be cheerful.
All right, Liesl.
The hills are alive
With the sound of music
With songs they have sung
For a thousand years
The hills fill my heart
With the sound of music
They wanted to sing for me,
bless their hearts.
That's lovely, lovely.
Don't stop.
-Something long and cool, Georg?
-No, thank you, darling.
-Father?
-Yes, Brigitta?
Is it true Fräulein Maria
isn't coming back?
Yes, I suppose it's true.
What have we got here?
-Pink lemonade.
-Laced with lemonade.
I don't believe it, Father.
-What?
-About Fräulein Maria.
Oh, Fräulein Maria!
Didn't I tell you what her note said?
I'm sure I did.
She said she missed her life
at the abbey.
She had to leave us.
And that's all there is to it.
I think I'm brave enough to try
some of that.
-She didn't even say goodbye.
-She did in her note.
That isn't the same thing.
Not too sweet, not too sour.
Just too pink.
Father, who is our new governess
going to be?
Well. . .
. . .you're not going to have
a governess anymore.
-We're not?
-No.
You're going to have a new mother.
A new mother?
We talked about it last night.
It's all settled.
And we're all going to be very happy.
Well, all right, all right.
Run off and play.
Yes, my children?
-My name is Liesl.
-Yes, Liesl?
We, my brothers and sisters,
want to see Fräulein Maria.
Fräulein Maria?
Oh, Maria.
Come in, please.
Wait here.
I'm Sister Margaretta. I understand
you inquired about Maria.
We have to see her.
Will you tell her we're here?
-I'm afraid I can't do that.
-But you've got to!
-She's our governess.
-We want her back.
She didn't even say goodbye.
All we want to do is talk to her.
I'm very sorry,
but Maria is in seclusion.
-She hasn't been seeing anyone.
-She'll see us.
I want to show her my finger.
Some other time, dear.
I'll tell her you were here.
-It was sweet of you to call.
-We have to speak to her!
Run along, children.
Run along home.
I'm sure she'd like to see us.
Sister Margaretta, please.
-Goodbye, children.
-Sister Margaretta, may we, please?
What was that about, Sister?
The von Trapp children,
Reverend Mother.
They want to see Maria.
Has she spoken yet?
Has she told you anything?
She doesn't say a word,
Reverend Mother, except in prayer.
Poor child.
It's strange.
She seems happy to be back here. . .
. . .and yet she's unhappy too.
Perhaps I have been wrong
in leaving her alone so long.
Bring her to me,
even if she's not yet ready.
Yes, Reverend Mother.
Sister Augusta, take our new postulant
to the robing room.
God bless you, my daughter.
Yes, bring her in.
You've been unhappy. I'm sorry.
Reverend Mother.
Why did they send you back to us?
They didn't send me back.
I left.
Sit down, Maria.
Tell me what happened.
I was frightened.
-Frightened? Were they unkind to you.
-Oh, no!
No, I was confused. I felt. . . .
I've never felt that way before.
I couldn't stay. I knew that here
I'd be away from it. I'd be safe.
Maria, our abbey is not to be used
as an escape.
What is it you can't face?
I can't face him again.
Him?
Thank you, Sister Margaretta.
Captain von Trapp?
-Are you in love with him?
-I don't know!
I don't know. I--
The baroness said I was.
She said that he was in love with me.
But I didn't want to believe it.
There were times we looked
at each other.
I could hardly breathe.
-Did you let him see your feelings?
-I don't know.
That's what's torturing me.
I was on God's errand.
To have asked for his love would have
been wrong. I just couldn't stay.
I'm ready at this moment
to take my vows.
-Please help me.
-Maria.
The love of a man and a woman is holy.
You have a great capacity to love.
You must find out how God
wants you to spend your love.
But I pledged my life to God.
I pledged my life to his service.
My daughter, if you love this man,
it doesn't mean you love God less.
No.
You must find out.
You must go back.
You can't ask me to do that.
-Please let me stay. I beg--
-Maria.
These walls were not built
to shut out problems.
You have to face them.
You have to live the life
you were born to live.
Climb every mountain
Search high and low
Follow every byway
Every path you know
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find your dream
A dream that will need
All the love you can give
Every day of your life
For as long as you live
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find your dream
A dream that will need
All the love you can give
Every day of your life
For as long as you live
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find...
... your dream
Now, it's not like my children
to be secretive.
We're not being secretive, Father.
And it's not like my children
to be late for dinner.
-We lost track of the time.
-I see.
Who's going to be the first one
to tell me the truth? Friedrich.
Brigitta. Liesl.
Where do you think we were, Father?
If you don't believe us, you must have
some idea of where you think we were.
-Marta.
-Yes, Father.
You tell me.
Friedrich told you, Father.
We were berry picking.
-I forgot! You were berry picking.
-Yes, we love berry picking.
All afternoon?
-We picked thousands.
-Thousands?
-They were all over the place.
-What kind of berries?
-Blueberries, sir.
-Blueberries.
It's too early for blueberries.
-They were strawberries.
-Strawberries?
It's been so cold lately,
they turned blue.
Very well. Show me the berries.
-We. . . .
-Well. . . .
-Show me the berries you picked.
-We don't have them.
You don't have them?
What happened to them?
-We. . . .
-We ate them.
-You ate them?
-Yes!
-They were so good.
-Delicious.
Very well.
Since you've obviously stuffed
yourselves on thousands of berries. . .
. . .you can't be hungry anymore,
so I'll have to tell Frau Schmidt. . .
. . .to skip your dinner.
It's your fault.
We should have told him the truth.
And made him boiling mad at us?
It's better than starving to death.
We didn't do anything wrong.
We just wanted to see her.
My stomach's making noises.
The least they could have done
was to let us say hello.
-I wonder what grass tastes like.
-I feel awful.
When Fräulein Maria wanted to feel
better she used to sing that song.
Let's try it.
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
Bright copper kettles
And warm woolen mittens
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
These are a few of my favorite things
Why don't I feel better?
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
-Silver white winters...
-Fräulein Maria's back!
... that melt into springs
These are a few of my favorite things
When the dog bites
When the bee stings
When I'm feeling sad
I simply remember my favorite things
And then I don 't feel
So bad
-Children, I'm so glad to see you.
-We missed you.
I missed you.
-Kurt, how are you?
-Hungry.
-What happened to your finger?
-It got caught.
-Caught in what?
-Friedrich's teeth.
-Liesl, you all right?
-Just fair.
-Any telegrams been delivered lately?
-None at all.
But I'm learning to accept it.
I'll be glad when school begins.
Liesl, you can't use school to escape
your problems. You have to face them.
I have so much to tell you.
We have things to tell you too.
The most important thing is
that Father is going to be married.
Married?
Yes, to Baroness Schraeder.
Oh, I see.
Father, look!
Fräulein Maria's back!
Good evening, captain.
Good evening.
Everyone inside for dinner.
Dinner!
You left without saying goodbye.
Even to the children.
It was wrong of me. Forgive me.
Why did you?
Please don't ask me.
The reason no longer exists.
Fräulein Maria, you've returned.
Isn't it wonderful, Georg?
I wish you every happiness,
baroness.
You too, captain.
The children say you're to marry.
Thank you, my dear.
You are back to stay?
Only until arrangements can be made
for another governess.
There you are.
I must speak to cook
about the schnitzel.
It is entirely too delicious
for my figure.
And it makes you much too quiet
at the dinner table.
Or was it the wine?
Undoubtedly the wine.
You have no idea
the trouble I'm having. . .
. . .trying to decide on
a wedding present for you.
Oh, I know. I'm enough.
But I do want you to have
some little trifle for the occasion.
At first I thought
of a fountain pen. . .
. . .but you've already got one.
Then I thought perhaps a villa
in the south of France. . .
. . .but they are so difficult
to gift-wrap.
Oh, Georg, how do you
feel about yachts?
A long, sleek one
for the Mediterranean. . .
. . .or a tiny one
for your bathtub, huh?
-Elsa.
-Where to go on our honeymoon?
Now, that's a real problem.
A trip around the world
would be lovely. And then I said:
"Oh, Elsa, there must be
someplace better to go. "
-But don't worry, darling, I'll--
-Elsa.
Yes, Georg.
It's no use. . .
. . .you and l.
I'm being dishonest to both of us. . .
. . .and utterly unfair to you.
-When two people talk of marriage--
-No, don't.
Don't say another word, please.
You see, there are other things
I've been thinking of.
Fond as I am of you, I really don't
think you're the right man for me.
You're much too independent.
And I need someone
who needs me desperately. . .
. . .or at least needs
my money desperately.
I've enjoyed every moment we've had
together and I do thank you for that.
Now, if you'll forgive me. . .
. . .I'll go inside,
pack my little bags. . .
. . .and return to Vienna
where I belong.
And somewhere out there. . .
. . .is a young lady who, I think. . .
. . .will never be a nun.
Auf Wiedersehen, darling.
Hello.
I thought I just might find you here.
Was there something you wanted?
No, no, no. Sit down, please.
Please.
May l?
You know, I was thinking
and I was wondering two things:
Why did you run away to the abbey?
And what was it
that made you come back?
Well, I had an obligation
to fulfill. . .
. . .and I came back to fulfill it.
Is that all?
And I missed the children.
Yes.
-Only the children?
-No. Yes.
-Isn't it right that I missed them?
-Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
I was only hoping that perhaps you. . . .
Perhaps you might. . . .
Yes?
Well, nothing was the same
when you were away. . .
. . .and it'll be all wrong again
after you leave. . .
. . .and I just thought perhaps
you might change your mind.
Well, I'm sure the baroness will be
able to make things fine for you.
Maria. . . .
-There isn't going to be any baroness.
-There isn't?
No.
I don't understand.
Well, we've called off our engagement,
you see, and--
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Yes. You are?
-You did?
-Yes.
Well, you can't marry someone
when you're. . .
. . .in love with someone else. . .
. . .can you?
The Reverend Mother always says:
"When the Lord closes a door,
somewhere He opens a window. "
What else does
the Reverend Mother say?
That you have to look for your life.
Is that why you came back?
And have you found it. . .
. . .Maria?
I think I have.
I know I have.
I love you.
Oh, can this be happening to me?
Perhaps I had a wicked childhood
Perhaps I had a miserable youth
But somewhere
ln my wicked, miserable past
There must have been a moment of truth
For here you are
Standing there loving me
Whether or not you should
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
I must have done something good
Nothing comes from nothing
Nothing ever could
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
I must have done something good
Do you know when I first
started loving you?
That night at dinner, when you sat
on that ridiculous pine cone.
What?
I knew the first time you blew
that silly whistle.
Oh, my love.
For here you are
Standing there loving me
Whether or not you should
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
I must have done something good
Nothing comes from nothing
Nothing ever could
So somewhere in my youth...
...or childhood
I must have done something
Something good
Maria.
Is there anyone I should go to,
to ask permission to marry you?
-Why don't we ask--
-The children?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
A flibbertigibbet
A will-o '-the-wisp
A clown
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
Many a thing she ought to understand
But how do you make her stay
And listen to all you say?
How do you keep a wave upon the sand?
Oh, how do you solve
A problem like Maria?
How do you hold a moonbeam
ln your hand?
Herr Detweiler!
-Heil Hitler.
-Oh, good afternoon, Herr Zeller.
Perhaps you've not heard.
I am now the Gauleiter.
Heil Hitler.
I've come from
Captain von Trapp's house.
The only one in the area
not flying the Third Reich flag. . .
. . .since the Anschluss.
-But we have dealt with that.
-I don't--
The housekeeper told me
that I would find you here.
The only thing she'd tell me.
What kind of information
are you looking for?
When will the captain return?
Well, he's on his honeymoon trip.
He's not been in touch with us.
Am I to believe he hasn't communicated
with his children in over a month?
How many men do you know. . .
. . .who communicate with their children
while honeymooning?
Upon his return, he'll fill
his proper position in the new order.
Naturally.
And may I congratulate you. . .
. . .and your people in allowing the
festival to go on tonight as planned.
Why should it not go on?
Nothing in Austria has changed.
Singing and music will
show this to the world.
Austria is the same.
Heil Hitler.
Come, let's go home.
-Why was he so cross?
-Everybody's cross these days.
Maybe the flag with the black spider
makes people nervous.
-Will Father be in trouble?
-He doesn't have to be.
The thing to do
is to get along with everybody.
Remember that tonight at the concert.
Are we really going to sing
before a lot of people?
Look. The von Trapp Family Singers:
Liesl, Friedrich, Louisa, Brigitta,
Kurt, Marta and Gretl.
-Why am I always last?
-Because you are the most important.
There we go.
Are you sure Father will approve
of our singing in public?
He'll be pleased and proud.
-Liesl, do you think so?
-Don't you trust me?
No.
You're a very intelligent girl.
Liesl. Liesl!
Rolf!
I'm so glad to see you.
It's been su--
Good afternoon.
Give this to your father
as soon as he's home.
-He's on his honeymoon.
-I know.
-You do?
-We make it our business to know all.
-Who's "we"?
-See that he gets it.
-What is it?
-It's a telegram from Berlin.
Don't you want to deliver it yourself?
I'm occupied
with more important matters.
And your father had better be too.
But, Rolf!
Father!
-We didn't expect you so soon.
-Hello, hello!
We didn't expect you home
until next week!
-Did you bring souvenirs from Paris?
-Hello! How are you?
Why didn't you call us?
We couldn't get through.
I had nothing to do with that.
We came back as fast as we could.
Well, well, well! We missed you!
-We missed you!
-We missed kissing you.
We missed all the noise
in the morning.
-Mostly, we missed hearing you sing.
-Oh, you came back just in time.
Look, Fräulein Maria--
I mean Mother.
We're going to sing
in the festival tonight.
We've been having a lovely time!
We've been rehearsing all--
Surprise! Surprise!
Surprises for you on the terrace.
We'll talk about this.
I would've told you but you were away.
I had to make a last-minute decision.
I was fortunate to enter them at all.
They'll be the talk of the festival.
Imagine, seven children in one family!
Max!
Somehow I recall having made it
quite clear to you. . .
. . .how I feel about my family
singing in public!
The committee was enchanted.
-What did they say?
-I have never heard such enthusiasm.
-Don't you think just this once--?
-Absolutely out of the question.
-Georg, this is for Austria.
-For Austria?
-There is no Austria!
-But the Anschluss was peaceful.
-Let's at least be grateful for that.
-Grateful?
You know, Max. . .
. . .sometimes I don't believe
I know you.
Father, I forgot.
This is for you.
Maria, he has got to at least pretend
to work with these people.
You must convince him.
Max, I can't ask him
to be less than he is.
Then I'll talk to him.
If the children don't sing, well. . .
. . .it will be a reflection
on Austria.
Oh, I know.
It wouldn't do me any good either.
Mother? That sounds so nice.
-I like calling you "Mother. "
-I like hearing it.
You love Father very much.
I can tell you do.
Very much.
Mother, what do you do when you
think you love someone?
I mean, when you stop loving someone
or he stops loving you?
Well, you cry a little.
Then you wait for the sun to come out.
It always does.
There are so many things I think
I should know but I don't.
-I really don't.
-How can you?
Sometimes I feel the world is ending.
-Then you feel it's just beginning?
-Yes!
It was that way with me. And for you
it will be just as wonderful.
Do you really think so?
When you're 16 going on 17
Waiting for life to start
Somebody kind
Who touches your mind
Will suddenly touch your heart
When that happens
After it happens
Nothing is quite the same
Somehow I know
I'll jump up and go
If ever he calls my name
Gone are your old ideas of life
The old ideas grow dim
Lo and behold
You're someone's wife
And you belong to him
You may think this kind of adventure
Never may come to you
Darling, 16 going on 17
Wait a year...
-I'll wait a year
-...or two
Just wait a year...
...or two
Liesl.
What is it?
Berlin.
They've offered me a commission.
I've been requested
to accept immediately. . .
. . .and report to their naval base
at Bremerhaven tomorrow.
I knew this would happen.
I didn't think it would be so soon.
To refuse them would be fatal
for all of us.
And joining them would be unthinkable.
Get the children all together.
Don't say anything to worry them.
Just get them ready.
We've got to get out of Austria. . .
. . .and this house. . .
. . .tonight.
This strains my back
and breaks my heart. . .
. . .when I think of the children
missing the festival.
By your announcement
we'll be over the border.
Do you appreciate
the sacrifice I'm making?
You have no choice.
I know. That's why I'm making it.
Why doesn't Father turn the motor on?
Because he doesn't want anyone
to hear us.
What will Frau Schmidt and Franz say?
They'll be able to answer honestly
they didn't know anything.
-Will we be coming back here?
-Someday, Liesl. I do hope someday.
Are Father and Uncle Max going to push
the car all the way to Switzerland?
Something wrong
with your car, captain?
Yes, we couldn't get it started.
Karl.
Fix Captain von Trapp's car
so that it will start.
Excellent, Karl.
I've not asked you where you
and your family are going.
Nor have you asked me why I'm here.
Apparently we both suffer
from a deplorable lack of curiosity.
You never answered the telegram. . .
. . .from the Admiral of the Navy
of the Third Reich.
I was under the impression,
Herr Zeller. . .
. . .that the contents of telegrams
in Austria are private!
At least, the Austria I know.
I have my orders. . .
. . .to take you
to Bremerhaven tonight. . .
. . .where you will accept
your commission.
I'm afraid that's going to be
quite impossible.
You see, we. . .
. . .all of us, the entire family,
will be. . .
. . .singing in the festival tonight.
As a matter of fact, we're going now.
We couldn't possibly
let them down now.
-I just hope we're not too late.
-Yes.
You ask me to believe that you,
Captain von Trapp. . .
. . .are singing in a concert?
Believe me, it will be a performance
beyond anything even I've dreamt of.
Like you, Herr Zeller,
l, too, am a man of hidden talents.
Yes.
Here, program.
It says only the names
of the children.
It says
the von Trapp Family Singers. . .
. . .and I am the head of
the von Trapp family, am I not?
And these travel clothes
that you're all wearing?
Our costumes, naturally.
This night air is not good
for the children's voices.
Well, a slight delay in my orders
will not be serious.
Therefore. . .
. . .you will sing.
You will all sing.
But only because that's what I want.
It will demonstrate that nothing
in Austria has changed.
And when you have finished singing. . .
. . .you, Captain von Trapp, will be
taken to Bremerhaven.
Now, if you will all get
into your car. . .
. . .we will escort the von Trapp Family
Singers to the festival.
No escort will be necessary.
Necessary? A pleasure, captain.
After all, we would not want you
to get lost in the crowds.
Would we?
No.
Sew, a needle pulling thread
La, a note to follow sew
Tea, a drink with jam and bread
A drink with jam and bread
Tea with jam
Jam and bread
-With jam
-A, B, C
-Do-re-mi
Tea with jam and bread
With jam and bread
With jam
With jam...
...and bread
My fellow Austrians. . .
. . .I shall not be seeing you again,
perhaps for a very long time.
I would like to sing for you now. . .
. . .a love song.
I know you share this love.
I pray that you will never let it die.
Edelweiss
Every morning you greet me
Small and white
Clean and bright
You look happy to meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
Edel....
Small and white
Clean and bright
You look happy to meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
I think it'll work.
I shall miss all of you.
I shall miss the money
I could have made with you.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
The competition has come
to its conclusion. . .
. . .except, we don't know
yet what that conclusion will be.
And while the judges
arrive at their decision. . .
. . .I have been given permission
to offer you an encore.
This will be the last opportunity
the von Trapps will have. . .
. . .of singing together
for a long, long time.
Even now, officials are waiting
in this auditorium. . .
. . .to escort Captain von Trapp
to his new command. . .
. . .in the naval forces
of the Third Reich.
And so, ladies and gentlemen,
the family von Trapp again. . .
. . .to bid you farewell.
There's a sad sort of clanging
From the clock in the hall
And the bells in the steeple too
And up in the nursery
An absurd little bird
Is popping out to say "coo-coo"
Coo-coo
Regretfully they tell us
But firmly they compel us
To say goodbye
To you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, good night
We hate to go
And miss this pretty sight
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, adieu
Adieu, adieu
To you and you and you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
We flit, we float
We fleetly flee, we fly
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
The sun has gone to bed
And so must I
Goodbye
Ladies and gentlemen, I have here the
decision of our distinguished judges.
We will start with the award
for third prize.
For this honor,
the judges have named. . .
. . .the first soloist of the choir
of St. Agatha's Church in Murback.
Fräulein Schweiger.
Second prize
to The Toby Reiser Quintet.
And the first prize,
the highest honor in all Austria. . .
. . .the von Trapp Family Singers.
The family von Trapp.
They're gone!
Come with me.
Quickly, quickly.
I have a place you can hide.
Slowly, slowly.
Open this gate.
Good evening.
Hurry up, woman.
Two men in there.
Six of you cover the yard.
You two, cover the corridor.
Reverend Mother, we didn't realize
we put the abbey in this danger.
No, Maria, it was right for you
to come here.
We thought we might borrow
your car.
I'm afraid our car will do you
no good now.
I've been listening to the wires.
The borders have just been closed.
All right,
if the borders are closed. . .
. . .then we'll drive up into the hills
and go over the mountains on foot.
-The children--
-We'll help them.
We can do it without help, Father.
Maria.
You will not be alone.
Remember:
"I will lift up mine eyes unto
the hills from whence cometh my help. "
Yes, Mother.
-I'm scared.
-Me too.
God be with you.
-Mother.
-Yes?
Would it help if we sang
about our favorite things?
No, darling.
This is one time it would not help.
You must be very quiet.
Hold tight to me.
Let's try the roof.
Rolf, please.
No, wait.
Maria.
Children.
It's you we want, not them.
Put that down.
Not another move,
or I'll shoot.
You're only a boy.
-You don't really belong to them.
-Stay where you are.
Come away with us.
Before it's too late.
Not another step.
I'll kill you.
-You give that to me, Rolf.
-Did you hear me?
I'll kill you.
Rolf.
You'll never be one of them.
Lieutenant!
They're here!
They're here, lieutenant!
Reverend Mother.
I have sinned.
I too, Reverend Mother.
What is this sin, my children?
Subtitles by
Gelula/SDI