Reality?
You mean
this is the real world?
Huh?
I never thought of that.
My mother and I,
we had a house in Chicago.
We figured, well...
we'd get out of there, you know,
while the getting's good.
And so then
when I got to Vernon...
well, I called up
these real-estate people.
They sent me
their phone number.
So then I seen a picture.
Well, the property was $2,200.
Of course...
they claim it was too much.
But, well, it wasn't too good.
It wasn't a castle, you know.
But it was a house, you know.
Five lots.
So, okay, bought it.
Had a mortgage for four years,
paid off...
and so I don't have
to pay no rent, see?
No taxes.
Old age.
You got to like outdoor sports.
And I've always loved it.
Especially turkey hunting.
I killed my first turkey
when I was 10 years old.
I can't tell you
how many I've killed...
but I've killed a lot of 'em.
I run a business. I close the business
down if I have to to go turkey hunting.
It's just something I like.
It's just in me.
I can't tell you how I feel.
It's just a hell of a sport,
that's all.
Sometimes you can be
standing around...
and hear one jar the ground.
And you just look
at the roads, the fire trails...
until you pick up fresh tracks,
and you know which way he's going.
You just go to that area...
stop, listen,
and hope that you hear one.
Sometime they gobble
quite often early.
And sometime
it's five, 10, 15 minutes.
And later on in the morning,
sometime it's every 30 minutes.
You just can't tell.
They a smart bird.
The smartest we got
in this country.
See, we spend time like this
day in and day out...
day in and day out,
not hearing nothing.
But you know they're here.
I sent 'em two checks.
One check for $12...
a three-year membership -
And three dollars' insurance.
So I waited ab- I don't know,
I waited a month or longer...
and I didn't get
no answer from 'em.
So then I had this lady
copy the checks...
you know, on a copier.
So then I sent
the copies to them...
and now they sent me
the jewel, see?
I don't know if the jewel
is genuine or not. Take a look.
I don't know
what I'm looking for.
I don't know.
What does a jeweler look for?
You know, those guys,
when you go into a jewelry store...
and if you want something examined,
they look through a lens?
And what are they looking for?
If you ask 'em, they'd go -
You ever seen a man's brains?
I've seen 'em.
I've picked 'em up, scooped 'em up...
and put 'em in -
do them up like brains -
you're buying brains.
But there's a bowl right here,
and there's a bowl here.
There's a bowl here
and a bowl there.
Now, they're connected
to the spine.
The spine goes
down the backbone.
And, uh, if all four...
of these, uh...
bowls or brains, if all four
of 'em is functioning, you can -
You are not a one-track mind.
You're a four-track mind.
And you can - You can -
I've seen a lot of folks.
They could type...
one letter -
Write me a letter and you a letter
on a typing machine...
and writing one way
with this hand -
writing your letter with this hand
and my letter with that.
And I can take a pencil
and sit down...
and write "cat shit" with this hand...
and "dog shit" with that one...
at the same time.
Two pencils.
I've done that lots of times.
These brains -
Now, what I was -
what I was telling you -
I can't stand up...
I don't believe,
without propping against something.
It gets me out of balance.
I got to get something.
You run one -
Now, if you ain't got that -
and I've often,
all over this town...
time and again, pointed it out,
see if anybody could do it.
If you run that foot
in a circle this way...
and then your hand
right the other way...
then just pick up your pistol
and keep wiggling your arm...
and singing a song.
That's four -
in other words, that's five things.
That's five things
I can do on this -
on one,
with this old knot up here.
Looks okay.
- Looks pretty close.
- Huh?
You're close. You're right on it.
Right between 'em.
I don't know if this is where
the valve stem was yellow.
That's a good tire.
Vernon 30 to Control.
Go ahead.
Quincy, can you give me
the correct 10-36?
By my watch,
it's heading to 17:31.
That's a big 10-4.
Appreciate it.
We don't have too much traffic
coming through now.
Sit and watch 'em come shooting
off the end of that bridge a little bit.
About the only thing I do
this time of day. I just...
sit around and wait.
You have to do this in a hurry...
'cause you gonna cover
several places at one time.
Not at one time, but...
as quick as you can,
'cause they gobble better...
earlier part of the morning.
The later in the morning it get,
the less they gobble.
So you usually -
you usually kill by...
oh, 6:00, 7:00 at the latest.
There's been a lot killed
after that, but...
that's the cream of the huntin' -
from daylight to 6:00, 7:00.
And he's looking
for a fresh track now.
And if he finds a fresh track...
he'll stop, listen,
and go in on it.
That's what he's doing -
walking and listening right now.
Looking for a fresh sign
that's crossed the graded road.
Where there's smoke,
there's fire, you know.
You find a fresh track,
you know there's a gobbler there...
'cause this is
a prime area for turkey.
Look how that one's
bogged down there.
Bogged an inch deep
there in that dirt.
He weigh 18, 20 pounds.
Look at the size of the track.
Look how he's bogging up
that hard dirt.
He probably crossed there
late yesterday afternoon...
and roosted right back down here
in these woods.
And if he's got a hen with him,
it's very hard to call him away.
You can believe that.
Anybody that'll tell you they can
call a gobbler away...
from a pack of hens,
just anytime -
Did you hear that?
Sounds almost like a turkey gobbling,
but it's not.
It's one of them
big woodpeckers pecking.
It'll fool you a lot of times.
Occasionally
you'll call a big gobbler...
away from some hen,
but very seldom.
I... I...
I'd rather not even try
to call one away.
Well, you always try,
but you can't do it.
I never have.
Very, very, very seldom.
I have different areas...
I like to sit around and wait.
I sit here a lot of times.
Since this car
was sitting around so much...
why, the people,
they don't know for sure...
if we have a police officer
on duty here or not.
So I can catch a lot of them
as they come across the bridge...
or come down through town.
Like this tanker.
He sounds like he's getting on it now.
You try to hold 'em down.
I hate to have to get out
and chase every one of 'em down...
but I try to let 'em
see me sitting here.
So then if I have
to write 'em up, why...
it's their own fault,
because they can see me sitting here.
I'm not trying to hide now.
But there is a few places where I sit
around where you can't hardly see me.
And that's why my radar gun,
when I have it-
I don't have it with me today.
I had to send it back in
and get it recertified.
So I'm waiting for it
to get back here.
It should be in
Friday or Saturday.
Then I can sit out here
and catch a bunch of 'em.
They said he was 65 years old.
I don't know about' that', now
That's a long life for a mule.
But he eventually died.
They rooted him
over into that pond.
That old skeleton lying there
with the hide all on him...
just as tough
as anything you ever seen.
And a big hole
in his throat here...
where the buzzards
and things...
had eaten every bit
that they could.
They couldn't eat him all.
I was a-fishing in there one day...
and dropped my bait
down there at that hole.
That old mule was laying in there,
you know, all puffed up.
Yeah, all dried up
on the skeleton.
And there was
a big warmouth perch...
run out of him up here
and bit my hook.
Took it in that old mule
right that quick, you know?
And, uh, he got off of there.
Got loose.
And I went to pull the hook out...
and I must have hung it
on one of his ribs.
I had to break it off,
but I put on another hook...
and dropped it down there,
and I caught a big one, you know.
The bones
had come out of his legs.
The skin was laying there,
you know, and it was tough as a -
just tough as a bear,
you know.
And I got over -
it was about this deep in the water -
and went down in there
and got a hold of them legs...
and drug that old mule
out on the hill...
and there was 114 warmouth in him,
warmouth perch.
I could hear 'em a-flutterin'.
Just as I run out on the hill with him...
the water run out of him...
and I could hear 'em a-flutterin'
in there, you know.
It was in planted pines...
but he'd roosted in a branch,
other side of planted pines.
And I eased in a row
of planted pines, you know.
Planted pines -
they're not exactly
in a straight row like that.
They'll be, you know, offset.
So you got a variation
of about two foot, maybe.
I'd get in them planted pines,
and I'd walk across the rows...
crossways to the rows, till I got right
even with where he was at in the swamp.
And I knew.
I said, "Right yonder he's at".
I'd walk crossways to the rows
till I got to that row.
I knew he was at the end of it.
I was working my way in and out.
And I slipped up there.
I slipped up close enough to the branch.
I could see the turkey...
in a pine tree.
He was a-gobbling.
And I got to that pine,
and I looked.
It was about 30 foot
over there to that other pine...
and it was about
25, 30 foot more to the turkey.
I looked at that turkey,
and I looked at that open spot.
I says, "There ain't no way
I can get no further".
I just eased
that gun up real slow...
behind them pines,
then eased down.
And there he is, right there.
I think he's got
about an 11-inch beard.
He hit the ground.
It sounded like a ton of bricks.
Now, this here is a gopher.
He's not a turtle.
He's harmless.
He won't bite you.
I don't know just how come him
to be way down in here.
He don't like
this kind of land here.
He's, uh -
High, dry,
sandy land for him...
and he'll dig his den to be...
as far as
20 feet deep sometimes.
And he's good to eat too.
I don't eat him,
but people do eat him.
He's just a fine piece of meat
for the dining table.
I believe he wants to walk now.
His motor's slow-paced.
I said, "Y'all just leave my gun here.
I got to use the bathroom.
You got to come back
this same way. "
They said, "Yeah".
All right.
L 901 my gun.
I didn't get to use
the bathroom, though.
I was fixing to...
but right out in them pines,
I heard one gobble.
And they'd done left.
And I said, "My God".
Boy, that's the best diarrhea
medicine in the world.
Mm-mm!
You hear a turkey gobblin'...
you forget all about diarrhea
and everything.
Headaches, anything.
That'd cure anything.
I grabbed my gun,
and I tore out.
Must have went a quarter mile.
Went through a bunch of pines...
and he double-gobbled.
I knew right then that I had
a pretty good chance of killing him.
Man, it hadn't been 30 minutes
since one had been killed.
Bless your heart.
The next time he gobbled...
there he was, right out there...
in that wiregrass
and broom sage.
I just yelped real low to him.
He gobbled.
He was coming straight toward me.
He wasn't walking, he wasn't running.
It was sort of a little fast trot.
And I had a good blind in some palmettos,
sitting behind some palmettos.
I done had my gun on him.
When he got up there -
He was walking...
a little too fast to shoot him,
'cause I wanted a sure shot.
And what I done, I just whistled.
And he stopped,
and he looked...
and when he looked up,
that was the end of it. Pow.
And that's him
right there in the middle...
with about an 11-inch beard.
Now, this possum -
I didn't catch him myself.
But another feller did.
He was eating his chickens.
And he caught him
and brought him down here to me.
He said I was the only fellow...
that knew what to do with a possum.
I'm a-gonna keep him
for the Fun Day in Wausau...
and sell him to -
sell him to the fellows.
They auction 'em off over there
for $1,200 to $1,500.
That's a great price for a possum,
don't you know.
Uh, I'll put him -
put him back.
You've got to be careful
with one of them things.
They'll bite you.
I've been bit by 'em.
I've been bit by everything
there is in the country,
wild game, you know -
except a rattlesnake.
I was sure enough
watching for him.
He just walked.
No rain in it.
Got to looking...
and his track
was in that track...
that trailer track...
which we'd just talked to the man
five minutes behind us.
The trailer made a track.
We come out the same way he come in.
And you know
that's got to be a red-hot track...
'cause it's on top
of that trailer track.
You understand what I'm talkin' about?
That we'd just talked to back behind us.
"Shh. " He's right out here.
Stepped outside
and yelped one time...
and he come right back, gobbling.
Hot daggone!
We started grabbing guns...
and getting into position.
And I told Snake,
I said, "Snake...
that turkey's not coming back
across the road.
There ain't no way
he's coming back across the road.
He's going the other way. "
We'd sit there and we'd yelp to him,
and he'd gobble.
He'd go over this way,
Go back that a-way, and he'd gobble.
He's wanting us to come on.
But we wasn't going on.
We was expecting him to backtrack.
And I told Snake he wouldn't backtrack
and come back to us.
This went on
for about half an hour.
I told Snake, I said...
"I'm tired of this.
I'm gonna kill that turkey. "
And I yelped one time...
and he double-gobbled.
And that's all I yelped.
And the next thing you know,
here he comes -
just a-gobbling all the way.
I shot him,
and he hit the ground.
I mean, he was doing a da-do...
bouncing around
about three, four foot high.
I run down there to pick him up,
and he got up.
He had a broke wing,
and I knocked him down.
I said, "My God,
he's fixin' to get away".
I just tried to shoot his head.
I shot a big hole in the ground.
I missed his head...
because if I'd shot the whole turkey,
I'd have tore him to pieces.
And I missed him.
He was going down the pine run...
and I said,
"Well, one more shot".
And I shot him
and just rolled him over.
And it was cloudy, like I said.
And during all this time
and around in them pines...
everything looks alike.
To me it does. Anybody else
that's ever been in there -
You can't - Excuse me.
You can't tell where you're at.
I got in there...
and when I killed the turkey,
I didn't know where I was at.
I walked around and...
I'd got lost.
I was hollering for Snake.
I'd walk the direction I thought it was.
I was going in the right direction,
but them pines, everything looks alike.
And I started hollering "Snake!"
just as loud as I could.
They knowed I was turned around.
They was settin' up there...
just a-laughing like the devil at me.
They wouldn't answer me.
But anyway, I drug that one out
the next morning...
after them two
the morning before.
And there his beard is.
About the same length.
About an 11-inch beard.
The one on the far right here.
Thirty-five, 40 years ago...
there wasn't no wigglers.
There wasn't no wigglers.
These wigglers is a -
is kind of a new thing
in this country.
These wigglers
have been in here...
about 20-something years there.
These wigglers is a new -
a new thing come in here.
I reckon they was here,
but, uh...
I don't know
where they accumulated from.
I got the seed of these
from south Florida...
is where I got them.
This is not a regular-
regular wiggler
like everybody's got here.
This here is what they call...
an orchard-worm wiggler,
that I got here.
That's the reason
people come here...
and wants to beat me
out of 'em like they do.
I don't know
where all this water comes from.
They must have
a lot of ditches up there.
Well, of course, if you're taking
a history of the, uh -
of Vernon,
well, I can't tell you.
All I can tell you
about the river is...
somebody told me
boats used to come down here.
And I says, "That river
must have been wider," you know.
The creek, they call it.
But they said no.
So, I mean, freight boats
used to come down.
Just like freight
on the Mississippi River.
And, uh -
But I don't know.
I can't figure it out.
Maybe they used big canoes.
There's a big red wiggler...
and there's a wiggler
that they call the eel worm...
and this orchard-worm wiggler.
And then they got
a big ringneck wiggler.
Then they got one
they call the night crawler.
He gets -
He weigh like that.
I got some of 'em...
from up in Joplin, Missouri,
and brought 'em down here.
They up there.
I brought 'em down here
and put 'em in a bed -
little old bed I had yonder -
and they all left.
They crawl at night.
You can't keep them in a place.
They stay around
in the edge of the swamp.
Out there
there's a lot of muddy water.
That reminds me of the story
about the two sailors.
They were looking at the water,
and one says...
"It's a lot of water out there,"
and the other guy says...
"Yeah, that's just the top of it. "
Hey, those snakes out here,
they can swim.
Be careful of that.
Those snakes can crawl
over that water...
just like they're crawling
over the ground.
My! 1-
And some people, they says,
"You going swimming?"
"Uh-uh. "
You're swimming around,
and then you look up...
and you see this snake
coming toward you?
Oh, brother!
See that jump?
You know what kind of fish that was?
That could've been a garfish.
Usually the garfish,
they feed on top...
and if there's little minnows on the top,
they snap 'em up.
You ever see a garfish?
He's got a bill about like that -
you know, his nose.
And when he -
He usually catches
what he goes after, you know.
I've never studied no book
on these wigglers.
What I know about 'em
is just self-experience.
They got books on 'em,
but them books is wrong.
They don't teach you right.
They don't teach you right
on 'em.
Teach you what kind of feed
to feed 'em, and...
how to do 'em and all that...
and it's all wrong,
in my book.
Why he wanted to take his shoe off
to pull the trigger, I don't know.
The very next damn day
after we was workin'.
And that day, he says...
"That'll be the last thing I ever do,
is to shoot myself. "
- Which it was.
- Well, they weren't none of his -
weren't none of his brains
a-working, period.
Yeah, he was -
I tell you, he had two shells...
laying under the sill
of the house.
He crawled under there
and got them.
Come out and told his wife,
"I've got one for you and one for me.
We're going. "
She run him down and take
one of 'em away from him.
He sat down in his old
homemade straight chair...
and he taked his -
pulled his shoe off...
and he set that gun barrel
right there...
and pulled the trigger.
He pulled his shoe off
to use his big toe to -
Yeah, but hell, if I was gonna do that,
I'd just reach down with my finger.
Well, it'd have moved his head
from the gun barrel.
- No, it wouldn't.
- He'd have had to stoop over.
He pulled his shoe off
in order to use his big toe to -
Everybody don't do things alike,
but that's the way he done it.
Knowing that the Lord
had called me to preach...
I had to pursue what the Lord
placed me on this world to do...
so I started back
into the ministry.
Sometimes in this line of work...
you don't have the finances
you'd like to have.
You see things
you'd like to have...
and you sometimes wish
you were back in a secular position...
making better money.
But then I have a better situation
than most people realize.
When I have a need,
I just pray for it.
Just like the van
that I have now.
I felt I had a need for it...
and so I began to pray,
and then I began to go price vans.
But I didn't feel like my prayers
and the prices I found on the vans...
coincided exactly the way
they ought to...
because they were
far out of my reach.
But still, I felt like if the Lord
wanted me to have a van, I'd get one.
So in the process, a couple of weeks
after I'd given up the idea...
of finding one I could afford...
I ran into a man,
and he had a van.
I was looking at it,
and he gave me the price on it.
I told him that was
out of my range.
He said, "Well, I've got
a friend over in Marianna...
that has a brand-new '79 van.
It's been on his lot
for eight months...
and he's priced it down to $5,000,
where it can be bought.
I know it can be bought
for $5,000."
I said, "That's the range
I was looking for".
Sure enough, I called the man.
He brought it to me...
and in three hours,
I owned the van.
God made all things...
that was made.
All things that was made.
And he looked on it
and pronounced it...
good and very good!
He made all these things
that we've got today.
And he said it was good
and very good.
But you could go
to the extreme on anything.
You can go
to the extreme on anything...
and make a hog of yourself.
But as long as you let it go
like God intended it...
you need never worry.
He'll give you power
and strength and wit...
to take care of the deal.
There was a huge oak
right on the bank of the creek.
I stood under the oak,
and I said...
"Lord, I don't know if you want me
to have this lot or not.
But if you do, then make it
possible for me to have it. "
So I went along for over a year...
and I didn't know
if the lot had sold or anything.
But over a year later,
I had as much money...
as the man was asking
for the lot.
I went to him to find out
if he still had it...
and sure enough, he did.
He said,
"But it's really ironic.
I've had this thing sold
three times...
and every time I've had it sold,
something's come up...
and the party going to buy it
didn't go through with the deal.
I hope yours goes through. "
I says, "It's gonna go through.
I know this is an answer to prayer".
# Sing the wondrous love
of Jesus #
# Sing his mercy and his grace #
# In the mansions
bright and blessed #
# He'll prepare for us a place #
# When we all get to heaven #
# What a day of rejoicing
that will be #
# When we all see Jesus #
# We'll sing and shout
the victory #
I was reading Romans
not too awfully long ago...
and over and over,
this word "therefore" -
which is the first word
in our scripture this morning -
began to pop out at me.
And I begin to think about it...
because I remembered somewhere
back yonder when I was in school...
that an English teacher
taught me something...
about the meaning of words.
And this word "therefore"
had a specific meaning.
And I think, "Well, if Paul
is using this word so many times...
there must be a reason for it. "
So immediately,
I went to Webster's Dictionary...
and I began to look up what the word
"therefore" was all about.
And I found the word
to be a conjunction.
Now, I had long forgotten
what a conjunction was.
And so as soon as I realized
it was a conjunction...
I thumbed back through the dictionary
to the word "conjunction"...
to see what a conjunction was,
and Webster? Dictionary said...
that a conjunction
is an indeclinable word...
that connects
two thoughts together.
And so I said, "Well, what does
this word 'indeclinable' mean?"
So I looked up
the word "indeclinable"...
and found out that it meant
that it was unchangeable.
And so I found out
that "therefore" was a conjunction...
that could not be changed...
that connected
two thoughts together.
And so therefore,
whenever I found this out...
I looked at that word again
in the first verse of our scripture...
and I said, "Well, certainly,
Paul must have said something...
that this word is connecting together,
so let's see what it was. "
And when I began to look back,
I found out that Paul...
had used that word "therefore"...
many times in Romans
before this...
and many times
in Romans after this.
And so I really got interested,
so I looked in my concordance...
and I found out that Paul
used the word "therefore"...
over 119 times...
in his writings.
And so I think,
"If he used the word 'therefore'...
over 119 times, I need to find out
what the Greek says about it. "
So I looked up
what the Greek meaning was...
and the Greek word was "on"...
which had a triple meaning.
The first one was "accordingly"...
the next one was "likewise then,"
and then "therefore".
Paul says,
"Therefore you receive the peace".
So if you're here this morning,
you're Christian...
and you don't have that peace,
I'll tell you what's happened:
You have taken back over...
the controls of your life...
and you're holding on to that...
which you ought to leave
in God's hands.
As a result, you've lost
the peace of your salvation...
and you won't gain it back
until you have...
another "therefore" experience.
I thank God this morning
for the "therefores"...
of Paul here in Romans.
Perhaps there's someone here
this morning who's never received Christ.
They've never let him come
into their hearts by faith.
They've never said, "Lord, I want you
to have your way in my heart".
You know what God's way
in your heart is?
God wants to come and cleanse you
from your unrighteousness...
and make something beautiful
out of your life.
He wants to forgive you
of your sins.
And God says, "You come on.
Just believe, and I'll forgive you. "
The most important thing
about turkey hunting...
is knowing your woods.
You can snatch me or Snake up...
and carry us off to a place
that we're not familiar with...
we don't know the woods,
the country.
Hey, man, you're lost.
You're lost.
Be just like taking me out of Vernon
and sending me to New York City.
I mean, you just can't
do nothing with 'em.
Knowing the woods.
Knowing which way they travel.
So in fact,
just knowing the woods...
is one of the -
Know the terrain, man.
And just knowing the range.
And when you go
to a new part of the country...
hey, man, you're lost -
or I am.
Any turkey hunter's lost.
I don't, uh...
really know of any crimes
that's going on here.
Just like any town,
anywhere you go...
you're gonna have
little incidents...
of, you know,
things popping up.
Like someone will walk in
one of the stores...
and they might
pick up an apple...
or a package of clothespins
or bobby pins...
or razor blades
or something like this.
But this goes on in all towns.
And, uh - Nothing really
more serious than that.
Not at this time, that I know of.
I traveled along the road with a fella -
in a car, of course -
and I was looking,
and I said...
"Hey, Barney,
you see that water over there?"
And he says, "Yeah".
So then we come right up to it,
and there was no water there.
That was just a mirage.
In other words, uh -
Well, to be, uh...
scientific about it, uh -
the lights -
you know, the rays or the -
the light bends, you know.
And, uh - So I mean...
if you get a different reflection,
say, for instance...
maybe a diamond
don't even shine.
Maybe it's just the way it's cut...
and the way the light hits it.
It's just like some day
after the rain.
You take a picture
of those drops on the trees...
and you can see 'em.
It's almost more beautiful
than the diamond.
I was out here
in these woods one night...
and I just had a feeling
that someone was out there...
and I heard that someone had fired
a couple shots out there.
It kind of had me worried...
that someone was out there.
I didn't know whether my walkie-talkie
was working right or not.
But one time
I was kind of worried...
or scared,
whatever you might want to call it.
But this'll happen
to the best of 'em.
Sometimes you just have
that feeling that there's someone...
up close to you
or trying to get to you...
when you're out
like that by yourself.
I had the camera,
and I was lucky.
And I held the opera glasses...
against the lens of the camera
and snapped it.
Of course,
I just about judged...
you know, where the -
I couldn't line it up
any other way because...
when you had the opera glass
on the lens, you couldn't see nothing.
And I held it up,
and it turned out.
I don't know
if this is the moon or not.
It looks like some clouds.
I don't know
if this is a star or what.
Well, no, it couldn't be that...
because, uh -
Well, that's a picture of the star.
I just took the camera...
and pointed it up there -
I didn't even sight it -
and then took
the picture that way.
Of course, as you can see,
that picture ain't too good.
It's a cheap camera.
You get a cheap picture.
Luck. Luck, you know.
When something turns out,
you say, "Gee, I'm lucky".
Right?
Of course, you see,
when you have a camera -
you have a camera,
and you point it at a certain -
Just like if you had a gun.
You don't shoot, do you?
If you had a gun
and pointed it at something...
you're liable to hit
what you're pointing at...
and then again
you might not, see?
The bullet came in...
at just about this angle...
and went into my seat here.
You can see
I haven't had that repaired yet.
Small hole there.
It went in there...
and lodged in the back
of the seat.
The county sheriff's office
came out to investigate...
and they had to dig it
out of the backseat -
out of the back part of the seat.
It came in at an angle
from the road.
I still don't know why they did it.
Probably just to frighten me a little bit.
But I'm not one that's gonna
frighten easy about things.
It don't bug you too much...
but the closer you get on him -
You want to make
the kill so bad.
It's in your blood,
or you wouldn't be out here huntin'.
And believe me, it's in mine,
and Snake's too.
And the closer it gets...
it's just like you're gonna
be electrocuted.
Each day, it comes closer -
- The tension goes on -
- Tension builds up.
And tension builds up.
It builds up in me.
I don't realize it...
but it's always a-building up.
Building up, building up,
building up.
And the closer it gets,
the worser it gets.
And after a while,
it comes to a point...
that you forget about it
when it gets right there on you.
You go blank.
You're concentrating on making the kill.
And once you make the kill...
you shoot, run, get the turkey...
or run him down or miss him.
Then all that tension...
that's built up in you, I mean...
it-it makes me sick.
You get the dry heaves,
like you got up on a morning...
after a Saturday night...
with the dry heaves
from a drunk?
Gag and puke.
Just gag, you know.
It's nothing but your nerves built up
that's dying down.
That's all it is.
In four, five minutes,
I'm all right.
Every star you see up there,
maybe it is a world.
I mean, it was made
for some purpose.
It's just up there, see,
and then maybe...
in the future
maybe there'll be one Irish world...
one German world,
one Russian world...
and one colored world,
you know.
I mean, each party has
their own world, you know.
But who knows?
You don't know God's plan.
Even Jesus Christ didn't know,
you know.
It says right in the Bible
that no man knows that -
can find out
the answer to that -
when the end of the world is.
Well, not the end of the world,
but the end of our -
our world, you know -
I mean our-
our scheme of things -
politicians, you know.
In a little town
when you talk to somebody...
and you tell them about...
the lights on the road,
they're not blinking...
well, they don't want to take
no responsibility.
I says, "Who do you call?
D.O.T. or -"
Well, they didn't know, see?
They don't care.
They should run 'em
out of town on a rail.
Tar and feathers.
Yeah, I like that.
That tar and feathers, boy.
Wouldn't you like that?
To see some old -
some guy or some kid
that did something wrong...
and they'd tar and feather him?
He'd have something
to think about, wouldn't he?
"The next time, we'll give you
the hot seat, buddy. "
I never saw anything
more perfect in my life...
than to see
the perfection of God himself.
"That thing just happened".
"That just happened. "
Folks thinks that way
all the time.
"That just happened. "
There was an old feller talking to me
in that house up yonder.
He said,
"There ain't no such thing as a god".
Well, I said, "Mr. Day... "
I said, "You believe you're here,
don't you?"
"Yeah, I believe I'm here. "
I said, "Do you believe
any man on earth made you?"
"No, I didn't make me. "
I said, "Do you believe any man
on earth made Adam and Eve?"
He said,
"No, I don't believe it".
I said, "What made 'em?
How come I'm here?"
He said,
"That just happened".
I said, "You saying 'just happened,'
let's call that God.
Let's give it another name...
and say, 'that just happened,'
'just happened".'
Whenever I got through
with work, I -
- You had a vacation coming in.
- had a vacation coming in.
The boss man give me a bonus.
So I come in home, and we left
that evening and went to - started out.
We drove all night and all day.
We didn't stop.
1,413 miles out there.
White Sand Missile Base, out there.
That's where the first atomic bomb
was ever dropped.
Sand dunes, you know.
There are sand dunes in there.
And that sand, it crawls,
and it crawls over the roads.
They're sweeping it
with a sweeper all the time...
to keep it
from covering up the roads.
It's growing sand.
That sand grows until -
The desert runs out
an average of 14 feet a year.
They got graders.
They keep it graded off the road.
It get bigger by 14 feet a year.
There's graders out there all the time
grading that sand off the road.
Pushing the sand back off of the roads
where you get in there.
Build new roads every day.
Wind come.
You know, that dry sand...
and it wraps up so deep
with sand overnight.
I reckon it' run
as high as a telephone pole.
Paid and went in there...
and got in there
where the white sand's at...
and, uh...
we got us some white sand.
I got a jar here
where it grows in it.
See, I had just
a little bit of this in this jar...
whenever I brought it out.
And now, you see,
my jar is nearly full.
It grows. It grows. It crawls.
It crawls up the side
of the jar, you see?
I reckon it gonna fill up the jar.
In two more years
it will fill up this jar.
They say it grow 14 feet a year...
out towards the town
where Billy the Kid got killed.
They say it'll cover that town
in a year to come.
This century, they say.
Less than a hundred years...
- Cover that town.
- that desert will eat it up.
Would you look at that tree?
There's one, two, three, four...
five, six...
seven, eight...
nine,10,11, 12,13...
14, 15, 16, 17, 18...
19, 20, 21, 22...
23, 24, 25...
26, 27, 28...
29...
30, 31, 32, 33...
34, 35.
Thirty-fifth one flew.
Thirty-five on one cypress top.
Listen to that sound, that -
Hear that sound?
Getting in and out of trees?
That "flop-flop" sound?
Mm, that sound will sure
mistake you for turkeys.
Listen.
Hear that "flop-flop"?
Limbs breaking.
Hear that good flop then?
Listening to that
gives me the turkey fever.
Mm-mm!
I wish there were as many turkeys
as there are buzzards.