Original subtitles by NizarEzzeddine.
- See you later Laaksonen.
- Yeah, see you soon.
- Good evening.
- Come here.
- Fire!
- Fighter jets, two groups. Shoot.
- Laaksonen!
- Yes Captain.
- Heikki Alijoki. Call me Heikki.
- Touko Laaksonen. Touko.
- Thank you.
- Do you have any dreams for the future?
- Well... I don't know.
- What would you like to do after the war?
- In addition to visiting parks of course.
- Play the piano.
- And draw.
- So you are an artist?
- Nah.
- In the Louvre:
- all the great artists and then Laaksonen, eh?
- Nobody from my town never even visited Paris.
- But think about it. A grand opening.
You'll invite me to there as well.
- There I will be telling everyone how I know you.
- You must have big dreams in life.
- The Eastern Front will fall.
We will be relocated there soon.
- There are just so many Russians. Way too many.
- I will tell the boys that they must dream big..
- ..and think about victory.
- Oh well.
- Captain. Heikki.
- You can keep it.
- Let's go.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- I spoke with my boss.
- He promissed you could try working at the firm.
- What do you mean?
- I showed him your art work.
- That landspace that you painted for dad.
- He will probably change his mind when he sees me.
- We really need the money.
- Your veteran discount isn't helping much.
- Do you have any idea how expensive
cheese is in the black market?
- Do you feel better?
- You are starting to look like youself again.
- Oh really?
- A little. You do distantly resemble my brother.
- I got a straight flush.
- What do you mean by that?
- I crossed over everyone I know who
quit smoking since the war began.
-Born in 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925.
- Dear brother, the war is over.
- A fucking Russian.
- Touko. Touko.
- I'm here, you have nothing to worry about.
- Listen, don't worry.
- Nothing to worry?
- Nothing to worry, nothing.
- What would I have to be worried about?
- Give me one as well.
- You just need to find someone.
- Someone to look after you. Someone special.
- I had someone special during the war.
- Oh really? What happened?
- As usually happens during a war.
- She was a war nurse?
- No.
- You are not in your right mind.
- It's because the war. But it will pass.
- You just need to get a job and meet new people.
- Many girls would be interested of
a handsome Officer such as you.
- You received the medal because you fought bravely.
- Right?
- I guess.
- Just get a hold of yourself and start living your life.
- Good night.
- He is a fagg!
- Get out now. Or I'm calling the police.
- Learn to behave.
- You will be banned for a month. At least!
- Better make it lifelong.
- Thanks love.
- What's your name?
- Nipa.
- Would you like to see something?
- I would prefer doing something.
- Wow.
- Can I keep this?
- Stop!
- Police!
- Halt!
- Stay were you are!
- Police!
- Stop in the name of the law!
- You two in there! Stop that immediately!
- Stop!
- I got one.
- We are the police, stay still.
- Get him!
- And who do we have here?
- Good evening. What is going on in here?
- We are cleansing the park from criminals.
- Why does it need be cleansed?
- For the Olympics.
- I see. Are you interested in spearing, stake jumping..
- ..or perhaps a friend of wrestling?
- Well I am interested in spear throwing.
- Good. Hurry then. Before the they arrive.
- We will do our best.
- Get into the car.
- What's your name?
- "Kake".
- Did you sleep well?
- Fantastically. What about you?
- Fantastically.
- Great.
- Let's go.
- Laaksonen.
- I can't show this to the client.
- Make something out of it.
- Jansson, about this winter's long johns -campaign.
- What is your situation with that?
- Excuse me.
- Could you come with me for a moment, please?
- If you could sit down.
- Maria, can I borrow you for a moment as well?
- Just a moment.
- Um..
- Look into the eyes. No, not mine. Each others.
- Good. Now think about a morning..
- The first morning after you first, you know.
- Think naughty things.
- Now think about how it feels to touch one another.
- Just like that. Gabriel, think a little further.
- Touch each other so you feel the sparks.
- Good.
- Guess what?
- What?
- Our boss said he is very satified with you.
- Oh great.
- What are you doing?
- Work. Just work.
- Promoting the sales of useless products with immoral means.
- Ha-ha. Show me.
- I won't.
- Are you afraid that I'll laugh?
- No, don't.
- But I'll promise.
- I'll have a look.
- No.
- What is it?
- Have a seat.
- Sit!
- Would you sit already!
- No, please don't.
- Don't be like that! You have a beautiful face.
- No I don't.
- You do. Let me.
- Well?
- I'm done.
- I'm not sure if I want to see it.
- I don't look like that.
- I think you do.
- I'm not that pretty.
- You are.
- Those legs?
- You never learned how to draw legs. Those look like sticks.
- Let me show you how it's done.
Can you hand me the drawing pad?
- Well?
- Thank you.
- You are welcome.
- Be careful not to break a sweat.
- Ten seconds.
- No, no..
- Ready..
- No, not yet.
- Set, go!
- Go!
- You are incredibly good.
- No, I'm not.
- But you are.
- I have been thinking, that maybe sometime..
- ..someday, I would have my own exhibition.
- Why someday? Why not tomorrow?
- No.
- What kind of artist you are..
- ..if nobody sees your work?
- Nobody wants to see them anyway.
- Look who's talking. You won't show your work even to me.
- Passports please.
- Hi sweety.
- Are you lost?
- How is the pheasant hunting?
- You should ask him.
- Thank you.
- In English or German?
- Depends.
- Are you going out?
- Name three different streets..
- ..that across with Helsinginkatu and Runeberginkatu.
- Apollonkatu, Hesperiankatu and Topeliuksenkatu.
- If you are originally from Kaarina,
why don't you speak a dialect?
- My parents were teachers.
This is how we spoke at home.
- Why there was an unknown man in your room..
- ..who also, according to you, stole
your travel documents and wallet?
- We were discussing about pheasant hunting.
- Is this yours?
- It was found in your room.
- I'm going to return to Finland..
- ..and based on these answers, I cannot
confirm that you are a citizen of Finland.
- The Germans will see you as a
spy or at least as a criminal.
- But I know what you are..
- ..and I'll report back to counsil..
- ..that the man the Germans arrested is not Finnish.
- I will leave you here for them to interrogate you.
- Heikki.
- What now?
- Heikki Tapio Alijoki.
- Captain Heikki Alijoki.
- Worked in the air force of Helsinki during the war.
- What about him?
- I know him.
- Could a meeting be arranged?
- Regarding what?
- Pheasant hunting.
- Do you know this man?
- No.
- I'm Lieutenant Laaksonen.
- We fought together in Sky Observation park in Helsinki.
- There were some close calls.
- There were no battles in there!
- I meant the air forces in Helsinki during the war.
- We fought together. I served under you command.
- I see.
- Could you give us a moment alone?
- Certainly.
- Is this a somekind of a trap?
- Are you trying to get me caught?
- I'm the one trapped here.
- How did you know I'm in Germany?
- I didn't.
- Your name was merely mentioned.
- I see.
- We know each other, right? We are both..
- Shh, please.
- Both war officers.
- This is ridiculous. Such a fuss over nothing!
- You are creating this yourself.
With drawings such as this.
- It's a piece of paper!
- A naughty picture somebody drew for amusement.
- It is not just a piece of paper!
- It's an atomic bomb which can land you in jail.
- There will be an investigation.
They will search your home.
- They will interrogate your
family members and co-workers.
- I don't care about what happens to me. But my family..
- Could you help me out?
- I can't.
- Okay. Let's make a deal.
- You have to swear on your officer honor..
- ..that you have never done anything inglorious.
- Gentlemen.
- Mr. Laaksonen here is..
- ..an honorable Finnish war Officer.
- Let's hear from Mr. Laaksonen.
- Yes. I thank you.
- And..
- I didn't do anything wrong.
- We are happy to help Finnish nation.
- The case is closed.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Laaksonen, my wife and I would be..
- ..delighted to have you over for a lunch sometime.
- Are you married?
- Of course.
- I live in Helsinki and sometimes invite the
right kind of people over for a small party.
- You could join us sometime.
- It needs to be kept low-key.
- Artists are always welcome.
- Thank you.
- My wife is very understading about the matter.
- Hey.
- Did you enjoy your time in Berlin?
Did you bring any souvenirs?
- They didn't get past the Customs.
- What are you wearing?
- It's a new hobby of mine.
- What?
- You were the one who told me to have fun and live my life.
- I found a tenant for us, who will be here shortly.
- Some religious girl from the countryside?
- No need to get up for me. I'm
Touko Laaksonen, Kaija's brother.
- Veli. I mean my name is Veli Mäkinen.
- People also call me Nipa.
- You have a very beautiful home.
- How did you find this place?
- Thank you. A war widow sold us the house.
- We have met before!
- You are mistaken.
- Would you like to see your room?
- I would be happy to.
- Touko! You are here as well?
- Of course, I like these performances.
- You like dance performances?
- Yeah. I have a season ticket.
- Weren't you supposed to be working on the campaign?
- It's done. It's perfect.
- Oh? What's the slogan?
- It's "yum yum, chocolate it's good".
- Doesn't sound so ready yet.
- Oh well.
- Could you fetch me some sparkling wine?
- Of course.
- Would you like some as well?
- I would, thank you.
- You know, you solo part was..
- I forgot my wallet home.
- And how did you pay for your ticket?
- The season ticket, you rememeber?
- Kaija, could you go get them?
I'll pay you back at home.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- We have met before.
- If we have, I was drunk at the time.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Thank you for inviting me here to see the performance.
- Well, thank you for coming.
- Cheers.
- Cheers!
- Very rarely these own projects come
true. My writings in example..
- ..nobody wants to publish them.
- Finland might not be ready for this yet.
- You know how it is in here.
- I was told that now it's a
great time to be in marketing.
- And I am a good advertiser. As are you Touko.
- Which is why you are now our main drawer.
- Congratulations about that by the way.
- Thank you.
- So you are interested in motorcycles?
- Yes.
- Riding on top of that..
- Yeah, would be nice to ride it.
- Indeed.
- Gentleman, may I take a photo with you?
- Alright, let's take one.
- Grab the handle.
- From here?
- Yeah.
- Just think how the power is controlled by it.
- Touko join us.
- It's a children's game.
- We are all children of God.
- Come on!
- Touko! Touko! Touko!
- Are you a virgin?
- No.
- Touko, truth or dare?
- Pick truth.
- Truth.
- No! Dare.
- Kiss Heidi.
- Kiss!
- Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
- Seems like it's my turn.
- Oops! It stopped at Kaija.
- Truth or dare?
- Truth.
- So dare it is.
- Kiss Heidi.
- Touko dear, it's forbidden by the law.
- Just do it this time.
- Almost, Kaija, almost.
- During the war, there was a blackout in Helsinki.
- You might be too young to remember. Or maybe not.
- But the atmosphere was electric.
- A plane roared in the sky over the city.
- It was so dark that we couldn't see anything.
We were asking who are you? Who is touching me?
- Hey dad.
- Hey.
- It's nice to see you again.
- Hey. Welcome.
- Hey. I'm Nipa.
- Welcome. Nice to meet you.
- Where is my godson Aaro?
- What?
- Come!
- One. Two. Three. Four.
- Five. Six. Seven. Eight.
- Nine. Ten! Here I come!
- Ha! Found you.
- I enjoyed coming here as a child.
- What were you doing here?
- Polished boots.
- Before it was believed, that if unmarried woman..
- ..would roll around in the meadow on Mid-Summer's Eve..
- ..she would be able to see her future
husband's reflection on the lake's surface.
- The meadow behind the house is a perfect place for that.
- How do the Mid-Summer spells really work?
- You see, it's because during the Mid-Summer
night, the sun doesn't set beyond the horizon.
- And then the men couldn't hide. Like
your father tried to hide from me.
- I tried to hide? No I didn't.
Your mother is trying to fool you.
- I would only destroy everything. Your family..
- You wouldn't.
- I'm not good. I'm rotten.
- No you are not.
- Good evening.
- Everyone should see these.
- Yes?
- We are here for the gathering.
- Good day.
- He is so handsome.
- I know. And waiting for you. Go!
- Darling.
- Darling..
- There is someone at the door!
- Oh fuck! It's the police!
- Fucking hell! Take everything with you.
- Heikki, let's go.
- No.
- No, I'll stay to delay them.
- It's the police! Open the door!
- Just go without me.
- Open the door right now!
- Vieno..
- Open this door at once or we will break through it!
- This is the police. Open!
- No! Don't take that route! This way.
- We should have parties like that as well.
- I don't think Kaija could handle it.
- I wan't an apartment of our own, together.
- With big windows and yellow curtains.
- Yellow colour is for sissies.
- I want the windows to be open. And us to
be able to dance there with our friends.
- With what money?
- If you would start selling you art.
- Where?
- Out there in the world.
- Maybe somewhere in the world. But never in Finland.
- Let's just get our own aparment.
- And just throw my little sister on the streets?
- Yeah, little sister. She is only thirty.
- Stop dreaming the impossible.
- I want you to hold my hand during day light.
- I want the curtains to be open.
- It's a nice idea, but still totally unrealistic.
- Want to bet on it?
- Sure. For a whisky bottle.
- It's a deal.
- You practically lost already.
- You know, you're the sissy.
- What the?
- No wonder we lost the war..
- ..since we had a gay sissy like you shooting there.
- I'm tired of fighting. I fought my wars.
- I'm not a freaking freedom fighter.
- Yeah. "I'm just a willy artist who
only wants to fuck and have fun!"
- Yellow is a colour for sissies.
- They almost didn't let me visit.
- Told them that I'm your brother.
- They are taking a good care of me.
- Fantastic.
- Because I need help.
- The only help you need is with mixing the gin and tonic.
- And I could help you.
- You can get better too.
- Except that I'm not ill. Just like you aren't.
- I will get better and have children.
- Come with me. Let's get out of here.
- Did you hear that we founded a new club?
- A motorcycle club.
- Without the motorcycles.
- Touko.. Thank you for visiting me.
- But I want to get better.
- I already lost my job. I don't want to
loose everything else I still have.
- Heikki..
- Goodbye my friend.
- Lieutenant.
- Captain.
DIPLOMAT TURNED OUT TO BE A HOMOSEXUAL
- I read the article.
- Poor Heikki.
- What could we do?
- Hey. It's a terrible weather outside again.
- You got mail from America.
- Again in the cover?
- And a letter from that Doug.
- Your number one fan. How is he?
- They want me to go there.
- They would like to organize one or two exhibitions.
- He wants to help me.
- To America?
- Yeah.
- Congratulations.
- You know, I could fall for someone as successful as you.
- Watch out. You could get hurt.
- It's Kaija.
- Is the food ready?
- Not yet.
- Evening.
- Good evening. I'm so hungry already.
- You are always on time.
- Yeah.
- I knew the place was in chaos.
- You guys can be such pigs.
Should I clean here quickly?
- Just hire a cleaner already.
- Are you having a party?
- Just celebrating a little.
- It isn't even six o'clock yet.
- It's good to be on time my darling.
- What are you celebrating then?
- Life. That it's fun to be alive.
- And that we are leaving for America.
- Oh?
- Well it doesn't concern me.
- How about some dancing? Maybe a little bend?
- I don't know.
- Stop! I'll pee myself.
- These are sexy. You will loo amazing in these.
- You should go see a doctor.
- I did. It will pass on it's on, don't worry.
- Was he certain?
- Yeah, completely.
- Go and conquer America for us.
- Which one?
- Take them both. Always take both.
- You should come with me.
- Next time.
- Next time then.
- That would be twelve marks.
- Good evening.
- You still have that cough?
- Yeah.
- "Kake" made it to America.
- He did it.
- Were there handsome people in America?
- Like the ones you always draw?
- Yeah.
- Many of them?
- Nah, just a few.
- But none so..
- ..smart, cheerful and sexy
than this one dancer I know.
- Where everyone there so syrupy as you are right now?
- Yeah.
- I'm sick.
- L.A. has the best doctors in the world.
- For them, throat cancer is just like flu.
- We can get a house with a garden
and parrots in there.
- I like the idea of parrots.
- The weather is always warm in there.
Sun is shining and sea glowing blue.
- Almost everyone is like us in California.
- Sometimes heterosexuals suffers from harassment.
- And I have to defend them. They
also have the right to exist.
- And the right to live the way they want to.
- Oh how noble you are.
- Why didn't you tell me that you are sick?
- I didn't want you to see me die.
- I want nothing more than.. I mean..
- It's alright.
- Let's make underwear for you from this fabric.
- From this?
- It feels comfortable. And it would be see-through.
- Good evening.
- We would like to order curtains from this.
- How long would you like them to be?
- Two-seventy?
- Two-seventy.
- Two metres and seventy centimeters.
- Colour for sissies.
- Hah. You owe me a whisky bottle.
- Well..
- ..I owe you so much more than that.
- Would you like sewed rings in the curtains?
- I do.
- Would you like rings such as these?
- I wan't people to know about us.
- Do you promise to tell them?
- I promise.
- Tell it to everyone.
- You had to take the elevator?
- What are you saying?
- Elevators are for old people.
- How have you been?
- Just great.
- I miss Nipa everyday.
- Yeah.
- Let me see the new ones.
- I don't know if they are even worth seeing.
- You will see.
- Here.
- You have made a lot of progress.
- Oh really?
- You have.
- These are good.
- This is my favourite.
- You should have a exhibition.
- I won't be having one.
- My work is nonsense. Terrible.
- They are, just look at them.
- Neither of us grew into a real artist.
- You nor me.
- You think so?
- Well I doesn't seem like it.
- Let's clean already. Are you throwing this one away?
- Nipa loved this book.
- I guess it's finally my turn.
- I see.
- I'm appreciated.
- Where are you showing these?
- Around the world.
- These willy drawings?
- They are liked.
- Sure..
- At least you are using that silly nickname..
- ..and not ruin the family name.
- Scruffy, cheap sex magazines.
- Where is the vacuun cleaner?
- You could have signed the guest book.
- Kaija, the phone is ringing.
- Touko Laaksonen.
- Would you like me to make food?
- Umh. I'm on the phone.
- Sorry. Can you wait?
- No need. I'll go dine later.
- This call is from America, could you?
- We are losing the war..
- We will die..
- Isn't it so Lieutenant?
- Jalonen.
- You are a tenor, right?
- You as well, Lahtinen?
- And you were basso, Toikka?
- Correct.
Listen how the music echoes..
..from the kantele of Väinö.
Song of Finland..
Song of Finland!
Listen how the trees sigh..
Listen how the rivers roar.
Song of Finland..
Song of Finland!
Original subtitles by NizarEzzeddine.