Subtitled by Dr.Abkar Khristo
abkars@yahoo.com
Then some Pharisees and teachers of the law came to Jesus from Jerusalem and asked
"Why do your disciples break the tradition of the elders?
They don't wash their hands before they eat!"
Jesus replied,
"And why do you break the command of God for the sake of your tradition?
For God said, 'Honor your father and mother'
and 'Anyone who curses his father or mother must be put to death.'
But you say that if a man says to his father or mother,
'Whatever help you might otherwise have received from me is a gift devoted to God,'
he is not to 'honor his father' with it.
Thus you nullify the word of God for the sake of your tradition.
You hypocrites!
Isaiah was right when he prophesied about you:
" 'These people honor me with their lips,
but their hearts are far from me.
They worship me in vain;
their teachings are but rules taught by men.
Jesus called the crowd to him and said,
"Listen and understand.
What goes into a man's mouth does not make him 'unclean,'
but what comes out of his mouth, that is what makes him 'unclean.' "
Then the disciples came to him and asked,
"Do you know that the Pharisees were offended when they heard this?"
He replied,
"Every plant that my heavenly Father has not planted will be pulled up by the roots.
Leave them; they are blind guides.
If a blind man leads a blind man, both will fall into a pit."
Peter said,
"Explain the parable to us."
"Are you still so dull?" Jesus asked them.
"Don't you see that whatever enters the mouth goes into the stomach and then out of the body?
But the things that come out of the mouth come from the heart,
and these make a man 'unclean.'
For out of the heart come evil thoughts,
murder, adultery, sexual immorality, theft, false testimony, slander.
These are what make a man 'unclean';
but eating with unwashed hands does not make him 'unclean.' "
Leaving that place, Jesus withdrew to the region of Tyre and Sidon.
A Canaanite woman from that vicinity came to him, crying out,
"Lord, Son of David, have mercy on me!
My daughter is suffering terribly from demon-possession."
Jesus did not answer a word.
So his disciples came to him and urged him,
"Send her away, for she keeps crying out after us."
He answered, "I was sent only to the lost sheep of Israel."
The woman came and knelt before him. "Lord, help me!" she said.
He replied, "It is not right to take the children's bread and toss it to their dogs."
"Yes, Lord," she said, "but even the dogs eat the crumbs that fall from their masters' table."
Then Jesus answered,
"Woman, you have great faith! Your request is granted."
And her daughter was healed from that very hour.
Jesus left there and went along the Sea of Galilee.
Then he went up on a mountainside and sat down.
Great crowds came to him,
bringing the lame, the blind, the crippled, the mute and many others,
and laid them at his feet; and he healed them.
The people were amazed when they saw the mute speaking,
the crippled made well, the lame walking and the blind seeing.
And they praised the God of Israel.
Jesus called his disciples to him and said,
"I have compassion for these people;
they have already been with me three days and have nothing to eat.
I do not want to send them away hungry, or they may collapse on the way."
His disciples answered,
"Where could we get enough bread in this remote place to feed such a crowd?"
"How many loaves do you have?" Jesus asked.
"Seven," they replied, "and a few small fish."
He told the crowd to sit down on the ground.
Then he took the seven loaves and the fish,
and when he had given thanks, he broke them and gave them to the disciples,
and they in turn to the people.
They all ate and were satisfied.
Afterward the disciples picked up seven basketfuls of broken pieces that were left over.
The number of those who ate was four thousand, besides women and children.
After Jesus had sent the crowd away, he got into the boat and went to the vicinity of Magadan.
The Pharisees and Sadducees came to Jesus and tested him
by asking him to show them a sign from heaven.
He replied,
"When evening comes, you say, 'It will be fair weather, for the sky is red,'
and in the morning, 'Today it will be stormy, for the sky is red and overcast.
' You know how to interpret the appearance of the sky,
but you cannot interpret the signs of the times.
A wicked and adulterous generation looks for a miraculous sign, but none will be given it
except the sign of Jonah."
Jesus then left them and went away.
When they went across the lake, the disciples forgot to take bread.
"Be careful," Jesus said to them.
"Be on your guard against the yeast of the Pharisees and Sadducees."
They discussed this among themselves and said,
"It is because we didn't bring any bread."
Aware of their discussion, Jesus asked,
"You of little faith, why are you talking among yourselves about having no bread?
Do you still not understand?
Don't you remember the five loaves for the five thousand,
and how many basketfuls you gathered?
Or the seven loaves for the four thousand, and how many basketfuls you gathered?
How is it you don't understand that I was not talking to you about bread?
But be on your guard against the yeast of the Pharisees and Sadducees."
Then they understood that he was not telling them to guard against the yeast used in bread,
but against the teaching of the Pharisees and Sadducees.
When Jesus came to the region of Caesarea Philippi, he asked his disciples,
"Who do people say the Son of Man is?"
They replied, "Some say John the Baptist;
others say Elijah;
and still others, Jeremiah or one of the prophets."
"But what about you?" he asked. "Who do you say I am?"
Simon Peter answered, "You are the Christ, the Son of the living God."
Jesus replied,
"Blessed are you, Simon son of Jonah,
for this was not revealed to you by man, but by my Father in heaven.
And I tell you that you are Peter,
and on this rock I will build my church,
and the gates of Hades will not overcome it.
I will give you the keys of the kingdom of heaven;
whatever you bind on earth will be bound in heaven,
and whatever you loose on earth will be loosed in heaven."
Then he warned his disciples not to tell anyone that he was the Christ.
From that time on Jesus began to explain to his disciples
that he must go to Jerusalem
and suffer many things at the hands of the elders, chief priests and teachers of the law,
and that he must be killed and on the third day be raised to life.
Peter took him aside and began to rebuke him.
"Never, Lord!" he said.
"This shall never happen to you!"
Jesus turned and said to Peter, "Get behind me, Satan!
You are a stumbling block to me;
you do not have in mind the things of God, but the things of men."
Then Jesus said to his disciples,
"If anyone would come after me, he must deny himself
and take up his cross and follow me.
For whoever wants to save his life will lose it,
but whoever loses his life for me will find it.
What good will it be for a man if he gains the whole world, yet forfeits his soul?
Or what can a man give in exchange for his soul?
For the Son of Man is going to come in his Father's glory with his angels,
and then he will reward each person according to what he has done.
I tell you the truth, some who are standing here
will not taste death before they see the Son of Man coming in his kingdom."
After six days Jesus took with him Peter, James and John the brother of James,
and led them up a high mountain by themselves.
There he was transfigured before them.
His face shone like the sun, and his clothesbecame as white as the light.
Just then there appeared before them Moses and Elijah, talking with Jesus.
Peter said to Jesus,
"Lord, it is good for us to be here.
If you wish, I will put up three shelters—
one for you, one for Moses and one for Elijah."
While he was still speaking, a bright cloud enveloped them,
and a voice from the cloud said,
"This is my Son, whom I love; with him I am well pleased. Listen to him!"
When the disciples heard this, they fell facedown to the ground, terrified.
But Jesus came and touched them. "Get up," he said."Don't be afraid."
When they looked up, they saw no one except Jesus.
As they were coming down the mountain, Jesus instructed them,
"Don't tell anyone what you have seen, until the Son of Man has been raised from the dead."
The disciples asked him,?"
"Why then do the teachers of the law say that Elijah must come first
Jesus replied,
"To be sure, Elijah comes and will restore all things.
But I tell you, Elijah has already come,
and they did not recognize him, but have done to him everything they wished.
In the same way the Son of Man is going to suffer at their hands."
Then the disciples understood that he was talking to them about John the Baptist.
When they came to the crowd, a man approached Jesus and knelt before him.
"Lord, have mercy on my son," he said. "He has seizures and is suffering greatly.
He often falls into the fire or into the water.
I brought him to your disciples, but they could not heal him."
"O unbelieving and perverse generation," Jesus replied,
"how long shall I stay with you? How long shall I put up with you?
Bring the boy here to me."
Jesus rebuked the demon, and it came out of the boy,
and he was healed from that moment.
Then the disciples came to Jesus in private and asked,
"Why couldn't we drive it out?"
He replied, "Because you have so little faith.
I tell you the truth,
if you have faith as small as a mustard seed, you can say to this mountain,
'Move from here to there' and it will move.
Nothing will be impossible for you."
(But this kind does not go out except by prayer and fasting.)
When they came together in Galilee, he said to them,
"The Son of Man is going to be betrayed into the hands of men.
They will kill him, and on the third day he will be raised to life."
And the disciples were filled with grief.
After Jesus and his disciples arrived in Capernaum,
the collectors of the two-drachma tax came to Peter and asked,
"Doesn't your teacher pay the temple tax?"
"Yes, he does," he replied.
When Peter came into the house, Jesus was the first to speak.
"What do you think, Simon?" he asked.
"From whom do the kings of the earth collect duty and taxes—
from their own sons or from others?"
"From others," Peter answered.
"Then the sons are exempt," Jesus said to him.
"But so that we may not offend them, go to the lake and throw out your line.
Take the first fish you catch; open its mouth and you will find a four-drachma coin.
Take it and give it to them for my tax and yours."
At that time the disciples came to Jesus and asked,
"Who is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven?"
He called a little child and had him stand among them.
And he said: "I tell you the truth,
unless you change and become like little children, you will never enter the kingdom of heaven.
Therefore, whoever humbles himself like this child is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven.
"And whoever welcomes a little child like this in my name welcomes me
But if anyone causes one of these little ones who believe in me to sin,
it would be better for him to have a large millstone hung around his neck and to be drowned in the depths of the sea.
"Woe to the world because of the things that cause people to sin!
Such things must come,
but woe to the man through whom they come!
If your hand or your foot causes you to sin, cut it off and throw it away.
It is better for you to enter life maimed or crippled
than to have two hands or two feet and be thrown into eternal fire.
And if your eye causes you to sin, gouge it out and throw it away.
It is better for you to enter life with one eye
than to have two eyes and be thrown into the fire of hell.
"See that you do not look down on one of these little ones.
For I tell you that their angels in heaven always see the face of my Father in heaven.
(The Son of Man came to save what was lost.)
"What do you think?
If a man owns a hundred sheep, and one of them wanders away,
will he not leave the ninety-nine on the hills and go to look for the one that wandered off?
And if he finds it, I tell you the truth, he is happier about that one sheep
than about the ninety-nine that did not wander off.
In the same way your Father in heaven
is not willing that any of these little ones should be lost.
"If your brother sins against you, go and show him his fault, just between the two of you.
If he listens to you, you have won your brother over.
But if he will not listen, take one or two others along, so that 'every matter may be established by the testimony of two or three witnesses.'
If he refuses to listen to them, tell it to the church;
and if he refuses to listen even to the church,
treat him as you would a pagan or a tax collector.
"I tell you the truth,
whatever you bind on earth will be bound in heaven,
and whatever you loose on earth will be loosed in heaven.
"Again, I tell you
that if two of you on earth agree about anything you ask for,
it will be done for you by my Father in heaven.
For where two or three come together in my name, there am I with them."
Then Peter came to Jesus and asked,
"Lord, how many times shall I forgive my brother when he sins against me?
Up to seven times?"
Jesus answered,
"I tell you, not seven times, but seventy-seven times.
"Therefore, the kingdom of heaven is like a king
who wanted to settle accounts with his servants.
As he began the settlement, a man who owed him ten thousand talents was brought to him.
Since he was not able to pay, the master ordered that he and his wife and his children
and all that he had be sold to repay the debt.
"The servant fell on his knees before him.
'Be patient with me,' he begged, 'and I will pay back everything.'
The servant's master took pity on him, canceled the debt and let him go.
"But when that servant went out,
he found one of his fellow servants who owed him a hundred denarii.
He grabbed him and began to choke him. 'Pay back what you owe me!' he demanded.
"The servant fell on his knees before him. 'Be patient with me,' he begged, 'and I will pay back everything.'
"But he refused. Instead, he went off
and had the man thrown into prison until he could pay the debt.
When the other servants saw what had happened, they were greatly distressed
and went and told their master everything that had happened.
"Then the master called the servant in.
'You wicked servant,' he said,
'I canceled all that debt of yours because you begged me to.
Shouldn't you have had mercy on your fellow servant just as I had on you?'
In anger his master turned him over to the jailers to be tortured,
until he should pay back all he owed.
"This is how my heavenly Father will treat each of you
unless you forgive your brother from your heart."
When Jesus had finished saying these things, he left Galilee
and went into the region of Judea to the other side of the Jordan.
Large crowds followed him, and he healed them there.
Some Pharisees came to him to test him.
They asked, "Is it lawful for a man to divorce his wife for any and every reason?"
"Haven't you read," he replied,
"that at the beginning the Creator 'made them male and female,'
and said, 'For this reason a man will leave his father and mother and be united to his wife,
and the two will become one flesh'?
So they are no longer two, but one.
Therefore what God has joined together, let man not separate."
"Why then," they asked,
"did Moses command that a man give his wife a certificate of divorce and send her away?"
Jesus replied, "Moses permitted you to divorce your wives because your hearts were hard.
But it was not this way from the beginning.
I tell you that anyone who divorces his wife, except for marital unfaithfulness, and marries another woman commits adultery."
The disciples said to him,
"If this is the situation between a husband and wife, it is better not to marry."
Jesus replied, "Not everyone can accept this word, but only those to whom it has been given.
For some are eunuchs because they were born that way;
others were made that way by men;
and others have renounced marriage because of the kingdom of heaven.
The one who can accept this should accept it."
Then little children were brought to Jesus for him to place his hands on them and pray for them.
But the disciples rebuked those who brought them.
Jesus said,
"Let the little children come to me,
and do not hinder them, for the kingdom of heaven belongs to such as these."
When he had placed his hands on them, he went on from there.
Now a man came up to Jesus and asked,
"Teacher, what good thing must I do to get eternal life?"
"Why do you ask me about what is good?"
Jesus replied. "There is only One who is good.
If you want to enter life, obey the commandments."
"Which ones?" the man inquired.
Jesus replied, " 'Do not murder, do not commit adultery, do not steal, do not give false testimony,
honor your father and mother,' and 'love your neighbor as yourself.'"
"All these I have kept," the young man said. "What do I still lack?"
Jesus answered, "If you want to be perfect, go, sell your possessions and give to the poor,
and you will have treasure in heaven.Then come, follow me."
When the young man heard this, he went away sad,
because he had great wealth.
Then Jesus said to his disciples,
"I tell you the truth, it is hard for a rich man to enter the kingdom of heaven.
Again I tell you, it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich man to enter the kingdom of God."
When the disciples heard this, they were greatly astonished and asked,
"Who then can be saved?"
Jesus looked at them and said,
"With man this is impossible,
but with God all things are possible."
Peter answered him,
"We have left everything to follow you! What then will there be for us?"
Jesus said to them, "I tell you the truth,
at the renewal of all things, when the Son of Man sits on his glorious throne,
you who have followed me will also sit on twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel.
And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or fields for my sake
will receive a hundred times as much and will inherit eternal life.
But many who are first will be last,
and many who are last will be first.
"For the kingdom of heaven is like a landowner
who went out early in the morning to hire men to work in his vineyard.
He agreed to pay them a denarius for the day and sent them into his vineyard.
"About the third hour he went out and saw others standing in the marketplace doing nothing.
He told them, 'You also go and work in my vineyard, and I will pay you whatever is right.'
So they went.
He went out again about the sixth hour and the ninth hour and did the same thing.
About the eleventh hour he went out and found still others standing around.
He asked them, 'Why have you been standing here all day long doing nothing?'
" 'Because no one has hired us,' they answered.
"He said to them, 'You also go and work in my vineyard.'
"When evening came, the owner of the vineyard said to his foreman,
'Call the workers and pay them their wages, beginning with the last ones hired and going on to the first.'
"The workers who were hired about the eleventh hour came and each received a denarius.
So when those came who were hired first, they expected to receive more.
But each one of them also received a denarius.
When they received it, they began to grumble against the landowner.
'These men who were hired last worked only one hour,' they said,
'and you have made them equal to us who have borne the burden of the work and the heat of the day.'
"But he answered one of them, 'Friend, I am not being unfair to you.
Didn't you agree to work for a denarius?
Take your pay and go.
I want to give the man who was hired last the same as I gave you.
Don't I have the right to do what I want with my own money?
Or are you envious because I am generous?'
"So the last will be first, and the first will be last."
(for many be called, but few chosen.)
Now as Jesus was going up to Jerusalem, he took the twelve disciples aside and said to them,
"We are going up to Jerusalem,
and the Son of Man will be betrayed to the chief priests and the teachers of the law.
They will condemn him to death
and will turn him over to the Gentiles to be mocked
and flogged
and crucified.
On the third day he will be raised to life!"
Then the mother of Zebedee's sons came to Jesus with her sons and, kneeling down, asked a favor of him.
"What is it you want?" he asked.
She said, "Grant that one of these two sons of mine may sit at your right and the other at your left in your kingdom."
"You don't know what you are asking," Jesus said to them.
"Can you drink the cup I am going to drink?"
"We can," they answered.
Jesus said to them,
"You will indeed drink from my cup,
(and be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with:)
but to sit at my right or left is not for me to grant.
These places belong to those for whom they have been prepared by my Father."
When the ten heard about this, they were indignant with the two brothers.
Jesus called them together and said,
"You know that the rulers of the Gentiles lord it over them,
and their high officials exercise authority over them.
Not so with you.
Instead, whoever wants to become great among you must be your servant,
and whoever wants to be first must be your slave—
just as the Son of Man did not come to be served, but to serve,
and to give his life as a ransom for many."
As Jesus and his disciples were leaving Jericho, a large crowd followed him.
Two blind men were sitting by the roadside, and when they heard that Jesus was going by, they shouted,
"Lord, Son of David, have mercy on us!"
The crowd rebuked them and told them to be quiet,
but they shouted all the louder,
"Lord, Son of David, have mercy on us!"
Jesus stopped and called them.
"What do you want me to do for you?" he asked.
"Lord," they answered, "we want our sight."
Jesus had compassion on them and touched their eyes.
Immediately they received their sight and followed him.
As they approached Jerusalem and came to Bethphage on the Mount of Olives,
Jesus sent two disciples,
saying to them:"Go to the village ahead of you,
and at once you will find a donkey tied there, with her colt by her.
Untie them and bring them to me.
If anyone says anything to you, tell him that the Lord needs them, and he will send them right away."
This took place to fulfill what was spoken through the prophet:
"Say to the Daughter of Zion,
'See, your king comes to you,
gentle and riding on a donkey,
on a colt, the foal of a donkey.' "
The disciples went and did as Jesus had instructed them.
They brought the donkey and the colt,
placed their cloaks on them, and Jesus sat on them.
A very large crowd spread their cloaks on the road,
while others cut branches from the trees and spread them on the road.
The crowds that went ahead of him and those that followed shouted,
"Hosanna to the Son of David!"
"Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord!"
"Hosanna in the highest!"
When Jesus entered Jerusalem, the whole city was stirred and asked, "Who is this?"
The crowds answered, "This is Jesus, the prophet from Nazareth in Galilee."
Jesus entered the temple area and drove out all who were buying and selling there.
He overturned the tables of the money changers and the benches of those selling doves.
"It is written," he said to them, " 'My house will be called a house of prayer,'
but you are making it a 'den of robbers.'"
The blind and the lame came to him at the temple, and he healed them.
But when the chief priests and the teachers of the law saw the wonderful things he did
and the children shouting in the temple area, "Hosanna to the Son of David," they were indignant.
"Do you hear what these children are saying?" they asked him
"Yes," replied Jesus,
"have you never read," 'From the lips of children and infants you have ordained praise'?"
And he left them and went out of the city to Bethany, where he spent the night.
Early in the morning, as he was on his way back to the city, he was hungry.
Seeing a fig tree by the road,
he went up to it but found nothing on it except leaves.
Then he said to it, "May you never bear fruit again!" Immediately the tree withered.
When the disciples saw this, they were amazed.
"How did the fig tree wither so quickly?" they asked.
Jesus replied, "I tell you the truth,
if you have faith and do not doubt,
not only can you do what was done to the fig tree,
but also you can say to this mountain, 'Go, throw yourself into the sea,' and it will be done.
If you believe, you will receive whatever you ask for in prayer."
Jesus entered the temple courts,
and, while he was teaching, the chief priests and the elders of the people came to him.
"By what authority are you doing these things?" they asked. "And who gave you this authority?"
Jesus replied, "I will also ask you one question.
If you answer me, I will tell you by what authority I am doing these things.
John's baptism—where did it come from? Was it from heaven, or from men?"
They discussed it among themselves and said,
"If we say, 'From heaven,' he will ask, 'Then why didn't you believe him?'
But if we say, 'From men'—we are afraid of the people,
for they all hold that John was a prophet."
So they answered Jesus, "We don't know."
Then he said, "Neither will I tell you by what authority I am doing these things.
"What do you think? There was a man who had two sons.
He went to the first and said, 'Son, go and work today in the vineyard.'
" 'I will not,' he answered, but later he changed his mind and went.
"Then the father went to the other son and said the same thing.
He answered, 'I will, sir,' but he did not go.
"Which of the two did what his father wanted?"
"The first," they answered.
Jesus said to them, "I tell you the truth,
the tax collectors and the prostitutes are entering the kingdom of God ahead of you.
For John came to you to show you the way of righteousness, and you did not believe him,
but the tax collectors and the prostitutes did.
And even after you saw this, you did not repent and believe him.
"Listen to another parable:
There was a landowner who planted a vineyard.
He put a wall around it, dug a winepress in it and built a watchtower.
Then he rented the vineyard to some farmers and went away on a journey.
When the harvest time approached, he sent his servants to the tenants to collect his fruit.
"The tenants seized his servants;
they beat one,
killed another,
and stoned a third.
Then he sent other servants to them, more than the first time,
and the tenants treated them the same way.
Last of all, he sent his son to them. 'They will respect my son,' he said.
"But when the tenants saw the son, they said to each other, 'This is the heir.
Come, let's kill him and take his inheritance.'
So they took him and threw him out of the vineyard and killed him.
"Therefore, when the owner of the vineyard comes, what will he do to those tenants?"
"He will bring those wretches to a wretched end," they replied,
"and he will rent the vineyard to other tenants,
who will give him his share of the crop at harvest time."
Jesus said to them, "Have you never read in the Scriptures:
" 'The stone the builders rejected
has become the capstone;
the Lord has done this,
and it is marvelous in our eyes'?
"Therefore I tell you that the kingdom of God will be taken away from you
and given to a people who will produce its fruit.
He who falls on this stone will be broken to pieces,
but he on whom it falls will be crushed."
When the chief priests and the Pharisees heard Jesus' parables,
they knew he was talking about them.
They looked for a way to arrest him,
but they were afraid of the crowd because the people held that he was a prophet.
Jesus spoke to them again in parables, saying:
"The kingdom of heaven is like a king
who prepared a wedding banquet for his son.
He sent his servants to those who had been invited to the banquet to tell them to come,
but they refused to come.
"Then he sent some more servants and said,
'Tell those who have been invited that I have prepared my dinner:
My oxen and fattened cattle have been butchered,
and everything is ready. Come to the wedding banquet.'
"But they paid no attention and went off—
one to his field,
another to his business.
The rest seized his servants, mistreated them and killed them.
The king was enraged. He sent his army
and destroyed those murderers and burned their city.
"Then he said to his servants, 'The wedding banquet is ready,
but those I invited did not deserve to come.
Go to the street corners
and invite to the banquet anyone you find.'
So the servants went out into the streets
and gathered all the people they could find, both good and bad,
and the wedding hall was filled with guests.
"But when the king came in to see the guests,
he noticed a man there who was not wearing wedding clothes.
'Friend,' he asked, 'how did you get in here without wedding clothes?'
The man was speechless.
"Then the king told the attendants,
'Tie him hand and foot,
and throw him outside, into the darkness,
where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.'
"For many are invited, but few are chosen."
Then the Pharisees went out and laid plans to trap him in his words.
They sent their disciples to him along with the Herodians.
"Teacher," they said,
"we know you are a man of integrity
and that you teach the way of God in accordance with the truth.
You aren't swayed by men, because you pay no attention to who they are.
Tell us then, what is your opinion?
Is it right to pay taxes to Caesar or not?"
But Jesus, knowing their evil intent, said,
"You hypocrites, why are you trying to trap me?
Show me the coin used for paying the tax.
" They brought him a denarius,
and he asked them, "Whose portrait is this? And whose inscription?"
"Caesar's," they replied.
Then he said to them, "Give to Caesar what is Caesar's, and to God what is God's."
When they heard this, they were amazed. So they left him and went away.
That same day the Sadducees, who say there is no resurrection, came to him with a question.
"Teacher," they said,
"Moses told us that if a man dies without having children,
his brother must marry the widow and have children for him.
Now there were seven brothers among us.
The first one married and died, and since he had no children, he left his wife to his brother.
The same thing happened to the second and third brother, right on down to the seventh.
Finally, the woman died.
Now then, at the resurrection,
whose wife will she be of the seven, since all of them were married to her?"
Jesus replied, "You are in error because you do not know the Scriptures or the power of God.
At the resurrection people will neither marry nor be given in marriage;
they will be like the angels in heaven.
But about the resurrection of the dead—
have you not read what God said to you,
'I am the God of Abraham, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob'?
He is not the God of the dead but of the living."
When the crowds heard this, they were astonished at his teaching.
Hearing that Jesus had silenced the Sadducees, the Pharisees got together.
One of them, an expert in the law, tested him with this question:
"Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?"
Jesus replied:
" 'Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.'
This is the first and greatest commandment.
And the second is like it: 'Love your neighbor as yourself.'
All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments."
While the Pharisees were gathered together, Jesus asked them,
"What do you think about the Christ? Whose son is he?"
"The son of David," they replied.
He said to them, "How is it then that David, speaking by the Spirit, calls him 'Lord'?
For he says,
" 'The Lord said to my Lord: "Sit at my right hand  until I put your enemies under your feet." '
If then David calls him 'Lord,' how can he be his son?"
No one could say a word in reply,
and from that day on no one dared to ask him any more questions.
Then Jesus said to the crowds and to his disciples:
The teachers of the law and the Pharisees sit in Moses' seat.
So you must obey them and do everything they tell you.
But do not do what they do, for they do not practice what they preach.
They tie up heavy loads and put them on men's shoulders,
but they themselves are not willing to lift a finger to move them.
"Everything they do is done for men to see:
They make their phylacteries wide and the tassels on their garments long;
they love the place of honor at banquets
and the most important seats in the synagogues;
they love to be greeted in the marketplaces
and to have men call them 'Rabbi.'
"But you are not to be called 'Rabbi,'
for you have only one Master
and you are all brothers.
And do not call anyone on earth 'father,'
for you have one Father, and he is in heaven.
Nor are you to be called 'teacher,' for you have one Teacher, the Christ.
The greatest among you will be your servant.
For whoever exalts himself will be humbled, and whoever humbles himself will be exalted.
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You shut the kingdom of heaven in men's faces.
You yourselves do not enter, nor will you let those enter who are trying to.
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You travel over land and sea to win a single convert,
and when he becomes one, you make him twice as much a son of hell as you are.
"Woe to you, blind guides!
You say, 'If anyone swears by the temple, it means nothing;
but if anyone swears by the gold of the temple, he is bound by his oath.'
You blind fools!
Which is greater: the gold, or the temple that makes the gold sacred?
You also say, 'If anyone swears by the altar, it means nothing;
but if anyone swears by the gift on it, he is bound by his oath.'
You blind men!
Which is greater: the gift, or the altar that makes the gift sacred?
Therefore, he who swears by the altar swears by it and by everything on it.
And he who swears by the temple swears by it and by the one who dwells in it.
And he who swears by heaven swears by God's throne and by the one who sits on it.
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You give a tenth of your spices—mint, dill and cummin.
But you have neglected the more important matters of the law—
justice, mercy and faithfulness.
You should have practiced the latter, without neglecting the former.
You blind guides!
You strain out a gnat but swallow a camel.
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites! .
You clean the outside of the cup and dish,
but inside they are full of greed and self-indulgence.
Blind Pharisee!
First clean the inside of the cup and dish, and then the outside also will be clean
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You are like whitewashed tombs, which look beautiful on the outside
but on the inside are full of dead men's bones and everything unclean.
In the same way, on the outside you appear to people as righteous
but on the inside you are full of hypocrisy and wickedness.
"Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites!
You build tombs for the prophets and decorate the graves of the righteous.
And you say, 'If we had lived in the days of our forefathers,
we would not have taken part with them in shedding the blood of the prophets.'
So you testify against yourselves
that you are the descendants of those who murdered the prophets.
Fill up, then, the measure of the sin of your forefathers!
"You snakes!You brood of vipers!
How will you escape being condemned to hell?
Therefore I am sending you prophets and wise men and teachers.
Some of them you will kill and crucify;
others you will flog in your synagogues and pursue from town to town.
And so upon you will come all the righteous blood that has been shed on earth,
from the blood of righteous Abel to the blood of Zechariah son of Berekiah,
whom you murdered between the temple and the altar.
I tell you the truth, all this will come upon this generation.
"O Jerusalem, Jerusalem,
you who kill the prophets and stone those sent to you,
how often I have longed to gather your children together,
as a hen gathers her chicks under her wings, but you were not willing.
Look, your house is left to you desolate.
For I tell you, you
will not see me again until you say, 'Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.'
Jesus left the temple and was walking away
when his disciples came up to him to call his attention to its buildings.
"Do you see all these things?" he asked.
"I tell you the truth, not one stone here will be left on another; every one will be thrown down."
As Jesus was sitting on the Mount of Olives, the disciples came to him privately.
"Tell us," they said, "when will this happen,
and what will be the sign of your coming and of the end of the age?"
Jesus answered:
"Watch out that no one deceives you.
For many will come in my name, claiming, 'I am the Christ,'
and will deceive many.
You will hear of wars and rumors of wars,
but see to it that you are not alarmed.
Such things must happen, but the end is still to come.
but the end is still to come.
Nation will rise against nation,
and kingdom against kingdom.
There will be famines and earthquakes in various places.
All these are the beginning of birth pains.
"Then you will be handed over to be persecuted and put to death,
and you will be hated by all nations because of me.
At that time many will turn away from the faith
and will betray and hate each other,
and many false prophets will appear and deceive many people.
Because of the increase of wickedness, the love of most will grow cold,
but he who stands firm to the end will be saved.
And this gospel of the kingdom will be preached in the whole world as a testimony to all nations,
and then the end will come.
"So when you see standing in the holy place 'the abomination that causes desolation,'[b] spoken of through the prophet Daniel—
let the reader understand—
then let those who are in Judea flee to the mountains.
Let no one on the roof of his house go down to take anything out of the house.
Let no one in the field go back to get his cloak.
How dreadful it will be in those days for pregnant women and nursing mothers!
Pray that your flight will not take place in winter or on the Sabbath
For then there will be great distress, unequaled from the beginning of the world until now—
and never to be equaled again.
If those days had not been cut short, no one would survive,
but for the sake of the elect those days will be shortened.
At that time if anyone says to you,
'Look, here is the Christ!' or, 'There he is!' do not believe it
For false Christs and false prophets will appear
and perform great signs and miracles
to deceive even the elect—if that were possible.
See, I have told you ahead of time.
"So if anyone tells you, 'There he is, out in the desert,' do not go out;
or, 'Here he is, in the inner rooms,' do not believe it.
For as lightning that comes from the east is visible even in the west,
so will be the coming of the Son of Man.
Wherever there is a carcass, there the vultures will gather.
"Immediately after the distress of those days " 'the sun will be darkened, and the moon will not give its light;
the stars will fall from the sky,
and the heavenly bodies will be shaken.'
"At that time the sign of the Son of Man will appear in the sky,
and all the nations of the earth will mourn.
They will see the Son of Man coming on the clouds of the sky, with power and great glory.
And he will send his angels with a loud trumpet call,
and they will gather his elect from the four winds, from one end of the heavens to the other.
"Now learn this lesson from the fig tree:
As soon as its twigs get tender and its leaves come out,
you know that summer is near.
Even so, when you see all these things,
you know that it is near, right at the door.
I tell you the truth,
this generation will certainly not pass away until all these things have happened.
Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will never pass away.
"No one knows about that day or hour,
not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father.
As it was in the days of Noah, so it will be at the coming of the Son of Man.
For in the days before the flood, people were eating and drinking,
marrying and giving in marriage, up to the day Noah entered the ark;
and they knew nothing about what would happen until the flood came and took them all away.
That is how it will be at the coming of the Son of Man.
Two men will be in the field; one will be taken and the other left.
Two women will be grinding with a hand mill; one will be taken and the other left.
"Therefore keep watch, because you do not know on what day your Lord will come.
But understand this: If the owner of the house had known at what time of night the thief was coming,
he would have kept watch and would not have let his house be broken into.
So you also must be ready,
because the Son of Man will come at an hour when you do not expect him.
"Who then is the faithful and wise servant,
whom the master has put in charge of the servants in his household
to give them their food at the proper time?
It will be good for that servant whose master finds him doing so when he returns.
I tell you the truth, he will put him in charge of all his possessions.
But suppose that servant is wicked and says to himself,
'My master is staying away a long time,'
and he then begins to beat his fellow servants and to eat and drink with drunkards.
The master of that servant will come on a day when he does not expect him
and at an hour he is not aware of.
He will cut him to pieces and assign him a place with the hypocrites,
where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.
"At that time the kingdom of heaven will be like ten virgins
who took their lamps and went out to meet the bridegroom.
Five of them were foolish and five were wise.
The foolish ones took their lamps but did not take any oil with them.
The wise, however, took oil in jars along with their lamps.
The bridegroom was a long time in coming, and they all became drowsy and fell asleep.
"At midnight the cry rang out: 'Here's the bridegroom! Come out to meet him!'
"Then all the virgins woke up and trimmed their lamps.
The foolish ones said to the wise, 'Give us some of your oil; our lamps are going out.'
" 'No,' they replied, 'there may not be enough for both us and you.
Instead, go to those who sell oil and buy some for yourselves.'
"But while they were on their way to buy the oil, the bridegroom arrived.
The virgins who were ready went in with him to the wedding banquet.
And the door was shut.
"Later the others also came. 'Sir! Sir!' they said. 'Open the door for us!'
"But he replied, 'I tell you the truth, I don't know you.'
"Therefore keep watch, because you do not know the day or the hour.
"Again, it will be like a man going on a journey, who called his servants and entrusted his property to them.
To one he gave five talents of money,
to another two talents, and to another one talent,
each according to his ability.
Then he went on his journey.
The man who had received the five talents went at once and put his money to work and gained five more.
So also, the one with the two talents gained two more.
But the man who had received the one talent went off,
dug a hole in the ground and hid his master's money.
"After a long time the master of those servants returned and settled accounts with them.
The man who had received the five talents brought the other five.
'Master,' he said, 'you entrusted me with five talents. See, I have gained five more.'
"His master replied, 'Well done, good and faithful servant!
You have been faithful with a few things;
Come and share your master's happiness!'
"The man with the two talents also came. 'Master,' he said,
'you entrusted me with two talents; see, I have gained two more.'
"His master replied, 'Well done, good and faithful servant!
You have been faithful with a few things; I will put you in charge of many things
Come and share your master's happiness!'
"Then the man who had received the one talent came.
'Master,' he said, 'I knew that you are a hard man,
harvesting where you have not sown and gathering where you have not scattered seed.
So I was afraid and went out and hid your talent in the ground.
See, here is what belongs to you.'
"His master replied, 'You wicked, lazy servant!
So you knew that I harvest where I have not sown and gather where I have not scattered seed?
Well then, you should have put my money on deposit with the bankers,
so that when I returned I would have received it back with interest.
'Take the talent from him and give it to the one who has the ten talents.
For everyone who has will be given more, and he will have an abundance.
Whoever does not have, even what he has will be taken from him.
And throw that worthless servant outside, into the darkness,
where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.'
"When the Son of Man comes in his glory, and all the angels with him,
he will sit on his throne in heavenly glory.
All the nations will be gathered before him,
and he will separate the people one from another as a shepherd separates the sheep from the goats.
He will put the sheep on his right and the goats on his left.
"Then the King will say to those on his right,
'Come, you who are blessed by my Father; take your inheritance, the kingdom prepared for you since the creation of the world.
For I was hungry and you gave me something to eat,
I was thirsty and you gave me something to drink,
I was a stranger and you invited me in,
I needed clothes and you clothed me,
I was sick and you looked after me, I was in prison and you came to visit me.'
"Then the righteous will answer him, 'Lord, when did we see you hungry and feed you,
or thirsty and give you something to drink?
When did we see you a stranger and invite you in, or needing clothes and clothe you?
When did we see you sick or in prison and go to visit you?'
The King will reply,
'I tell you the truth,
whatever you did for one of the least of these brothers of mine, you did for me.'
"Then he will say to those on his left,
'Depart from me, you who are cursed, into the eternal fire prepared for the devil and his angels.
For I was hungry and you gave me nothing to eat,
I was thirsty and you gave me nothing to drink,
I was a stranger and you did not invite me in,
I needed clothes and you did not clothe me,
I was sick and in prison and you did not look after me.'
"They also will answer, 'Lord, when did we see you hungry
or thirsty or a stranger or needing clothes or sick or in prison, and did not help you?'
"He will reply, 'I tell you the truth,
whatever you did not do for one of the least of these, you did not do for me.'
"Then they will go away to eternal punishment,
but the righteous to eternal life."
When Jesus had finished saying all these things, he said to his disciples,
"As you know, the Passover is two days away—
and the Son of Man will be handed over to be crucified."
Then the chief priests and the elders of the people assembled in the palace of the high priest, whose name was Caiaphas,
and they plotted to arrest Jesus in some sly way and kill him.
"But not during the Feast," they said, "or there may be a riot among the people."
While Jesus was in Bethany in the home of a man known as Simon the Leper,
a woman came to him with an alabaster jar of very expensive perfume,
which she poured on his head as he was reclining at the table.
When the disciples saw this, they were indignant.
"Why this waste?" they asked.
"This perfume could have been sold at a high price and the money given to the poor",
Aware of this, Jesus said to them,
"Why are you bothering this woman?
She has done a beautiful thing to me.
The poor you will always have with you, but you will not always have me.
When she poured this perfume on my body,
she did it to prepare me for burial.
I tell you the truth,
wherever this gospel is preached throughout the world,
what she has done will also be told, in memory of her."
Then one of the Twelve—the one called Judas Iscariot—went to the chief priests and asked,
"What are you willing to give me if I hand him over to you?
So they counted out for him thirty silver coins.
From then on Judas watched for an opportunity to hand him over.
On the first day of the Feast of Unleavened Bread, the disciples came to Jesus and asked,
"Where do you want us to make preparations for you to eat the Passover?"
He replied, "Go into the city to a certain man and tell him,
'The Teacher says: My appointed time is near.
I am going to celebrate the Passover with my disciples at your house.' "
So the disciples did as Jesus had directed them and prepared the Passover.
When evening came, Jesus was reclining at the table with the Twelve.
And while they were eating, he said, "I tell you the truth, one of you will betray me."
They were very sad and began to say to him one after the other,
"Surely not I, Lord?"
Jesus replied, "The one who has dipped his hand into the bowl with me will betray me.
The Son of Man will go just as it is written about him.
But woe to that man who betrays the Son of Man!
It would be better for him if he had not been born."
Then Judas, the one who would betray him, said, "Surely not I, Rabbi?"
Jesus answered, "Yes, it is you."
While they were eating, Jesus took bread,
gave thanks and broke it, and gave it to his disciples, saying,
"Take and eat; this is my body."
Then he took the cup, gave thanks and offered it to them, saying,
"Drink from it, all of you.
This is my blood of the covenant, which is poured out for many for the forgiveness of sins.
I tell you, I will not drink of this fruit of the vine from now on until that day
when I drink it anew with you in my Father's kingdom."
When they had sung a hymn, they went out to the Mount of Olives.
Then Jesus told them,
"This very night you will all fall away on account of me, for it is written:
" 'I will strike the shepherd, and the sheep of the flock will be scattered.'
But after I have risen, I will go ahead of you into Galilee."
Peter replied, "Even if all fall away on account of you, I never will."
"I tell you the truth," Jesus answered,
"this very night, before the rooster crows, you will disown me three times."
But Peter declared, "Even if I have to die with you, I will never disown you."
And all the other disciples said the same.
Then Jesus went with his disciples to a place called Gethsemane,
and he said to them, "Sit here while I go over there and pray."
He took Peter and the two sons of Zebedee along with him,
and he began to be sorrowful and troubled.
Then he said to them,
"My soul is overwhelmed with sorrow to the point of death.
Stay here and keep watch with me."
Going a little farther, he fell with his face to the ground and prayed,
"My Father, if it is possible, may this cup be taken from me.
Yet not as I will, but as you will."
Then he returned to his disciples and found them sleeping.
"Could you men not keep watch with me for one hour?" he asked Peter.
"Watch and pray so that you will not fall into temptation.
The spirit is willing, but the body is weak."
He went away a second time and prayed,
"My Father, if it is not possible for this cup to be taken away unless I drink it, may your will be done."
When he came back, he again found them sleeping, because their eyes were heavy.
So he left them and went away once more and prayed the third time, saying the same thing.
Then he returned to the disciples and said to them,
"Are you still sleeping and resting?
Look, the hour is near,
and the Son of Man is betrayed into the hands of sinners.
Rise, let us go!
Here comes my betrayer!"
While he was still speaking, Judas, one of the Twelve, arrived.
With him was a large crowd armed with swords and clubs,
sent from the chief priests and the elders of the people.
Now the betrayer had arranged a signal with them:
"The one I kiss is the man; arrest him."
Going at once to Jesus, Judas said,
"Greetings, Rabbi!"
and kissed him.
Jesus replied,
"Friend, do what you came for."
Then the men stepped forward, seized Jesus and arrested him.
With that, one of Jesus' companions reached for his sword,
drew it out and struck the servant of the high priest, cutting off his ear.
Put your sword back in its place," Jesus said to him,
"for all who draw the sword will die by the sword.
Do you think I cannot call on my Father, and he will at once put at my disposal more than twelve legions of angels?
But how then would the Scriptures be fulfilled that say it must happen in this way?"
At that time Jesus said to the crowd,
"Am I leading a rebellion, that you have come out with swords and clubs to capture me?
Every day I sat in the temple courts teaching, and you did not arrest me.
But this has all taken place that the writings of the prophets might be fulfilled."
Then all the disciples deserted him and fled.
Those who had arrested Jesus took him to Caiaphas, the high priest,
where the teachers of the law and the elders had assembled.
But Peter followed him at a distance, right up to the courtyard of the high priest.
He entered and sat down with the guards to see the outcome.
The chief priests and the whole Sanhedrin were looking for false evidence against Jesus
so that they could put him to death.
But they did not find any, though many false witnesses came forward.
Finally two came forward and declared,
"This fellow said, 'I am able to destroy the temple of God and rebuild it in three days.' "
Then the high priest stood up and said to Jesus,
"Are you not going to answer?
What is this testimony that these men are bringing against you?"
But Jesus remained silent.
The high priest said to him,
"I charge you under oath by the living God: Tell us if you are the Christ, the Son of God."
"Yes, it is as you say," Jesus replied.
"But I say to all of you:
In the future you will see the Son of Man sitting at the right hand of the Mighty One
and coming on the clouds of heaven."
Then the high priest tore his clothes and said,
"He has spoken blasphemy!
Why do we need any more witnesses?
Look, now you have heard the blasphemy.
What do you think?"
"He is worthy of death," they answered.
Then they spit in his face and struck him with their fists.
Others slapped him and said,
"Prophesy to us, Christ. Who hit you?"
Now Peter was sitting out in the courtyard,
and a servant girl came to him. "You also were with Jesus of Galilee," she said.
But he denied it before them all.
"I don't know what you're talking about," he said.
Then he went out to the gateway, where another girl saw him
and said to the people there, "This fellow was with Jesus of Nazareth."
He denied it again, with an oath:
"I don't know the man!"
After a little while, those standing there went up to Peter and said,
"Surely you are one of them, for your accent gives you away."
Then he began to call down curses on himself and he swore to them,
"I don't know the man!"
Immediately a rooster crowed.
Then Peter remembered the word Jesus had spoken:
"Before the rooster crows, you will disown me three times."
And he went outside and wept bitterly.
Early in the morning, all the chief priests and the elders of the people came to the decision to put Jesus to death.
They bound him, led him away and handed him over to Pilate, the governor.
When Judas, who had betrayed him, saw that Jesus was condemned,
he was seized with remorse
and returned the thirty silver coins to the chief priests and the elders.
"I have sinned," he said, "for I have betrayed innocent blood."
"What is that to us?" they replied. "That's your responsibility."
So Judas threw the money into the temple and left.
Then he went away and hanged himself.
The chief priests picked up the coins and said,
"It is against the law to put this into the treasury, since it is blood money."
So they decided to use the money to buy the potter's field as a burial place for foreigners.
That is why it has been called the Field of Blood to this day.
Then what was spoken by Jeremiah the prophet was fulfilled:
"They took the thirty silver coins, the price set on him by the people of Israel,
and they used them to buy the potter's field, as the Lord commanded me."
Meanwhile Jesus stood before the governor, and the governor asked him,
"Are you the king of the Jews?"
"Yes, it is as you say," Jesus replied.
When he was accused by the chief priests and the elders, he gave no answer.
Then Pilate asked him, "Don't you hear the testimony they are bringing against you?"
But Jesus made no reply, not even to a single charge—to the great amazement of the governor.
Now it was the governor's custom at the Feast to release a prisoner chosen by the crowd.
At that time they had a notorious prisoner, called Barabbas.
So when the crowd had gathered, Pilate asked them,
"Which one do you want me to release to you:
Barabbas, or Jesus who is called Christ?"
For he knew it was out of envy that they had handed Jesus over to him.
While Pilate was sitting on the judge's seat, his wife sent him this message:
"Don't have anything to do with that innocent man,
for I have suffered a great deal today in a dream because of him."
But the chief priests and the elders persuaded the crowd to ask for Barabbas
and to have Jesus executed.
"Which of the two do you want me to release to you?" asked the governor.
"Barabbas," they answered.
"What shall I do, then, with Jesus who is called Christ?" Pilate asked.
They all answered, "Crucify him!"
"Why? What crime has he committed?" asked Pilate
But they shouted all the louder, "Crucify him!"
When Pilate saw that he was getting nowhere, but that instead an uproar was starting,
he took water and washed his hands in front of the crowd.
"I am innocent of this man's blood," he said. "It is your responsibility!"
All the people answered, "Let his blood be on us and on our children!"
Then he released Barabbas to them.
But he had Jesus flogged, and handed him over to be crucified.
Then the governor's soldiers took Jesus into the Praetorium
and gathered the whole company of soldiers around him.
They stripped him and put a scarlet robe on him,
and then twisted together a crown of thorns and set it on his head.
They put a staff in his right hand
and knelt in front of him and mocked him. "Hail, king of the Jews!"they said.
They spit on him, and took the staff and struck him on the head again and again.
After they had mocked him, they took off the robe and put his own clothes on him.
Then they led him away to crucify him.
As they were going out, they met a man from Cyrene, named Simon,
and they forced him to carry the cross.
They came to a place called Golgotha (which means The Place of the Skull).
There they offered Jesus wine to drink, mixed with gall;
but after tasting it, he refused to drink it.
When they had crucified him, they divided up his clothes by casting lots.
And sitting down, they kept watch over him there.
Above his head they placed the written charge against him:
THIS IS JESUS, THE KING OF THE JEWS.
Two robbers were crucified with him,
one on his right and one on his left.
Those who passed by hurled insults at him, shaking their heads
and saying, "You who are going to destroy the temple and build it in three days,
save yourself! Come down from the cross, if you are the Son of God!"
In the same way the chief priests, the teachers of the law and the elders mocked him.
"He saved others," they said, "but he can't save himself!
He's the King of Israel! Let him come down now from the cross, and we will believe in him.
He trusts in God. Let God rescue him now if he wants him, for he said, 'I am the Son of God.' "
In the same way the robbers who were crucified with him also heaped insults on him.
From the sixth hour until the ninth hour darkness came over all the land.
About the ninth hour Jesus cried out in a loud voice,
"Eloi, Eloi lama sabachthani?"
—which means, "My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?"
When some of those standing there heard this, they said, "He's calling Elijah."
Immediately one of them ran and got a sponge.
He filled it with wine vinegar, put it on a stick, and offered it to Jesus to drink.
The rest said, "Now leave him alone. Let's see if Elijah comes to save him."
And when Jesus had cried out again in a loud voice, he gave up his spirit.
At that moment the curtain of the temple was torn in two from top to bottom.
The earth shook and the rocks split.
The tombs broke open and the bodies of many holy people who had died were raised to life.
They came out of the tombs, and after Jesus' resurrection
they went into the holy city and appeared to many people.
When the centurion and those with him who were guarding Jesus
saw the earthquake and all that had happened, they were terrified,
and exclaimed, "Surely he was the Son[e] of God!"
Many women were there, watching from a distance.
They had followed Jesus from Galilee to care for his needs.
Among them were Mary Magdalene, Mary the mother of James and Joses, and the mother of Zebedee's sons.
As evening approached, there came a rich man from Arimathea, named Joseph,
who had himself become a disciple of Jesus.
Going to Pilate, he asked for Jesus' body,
and Pilate ordered that it be given to him.
Joseph took the body, wrapped it in a clean linen cloth,
and placed it in his own new tomb that he had cut out of the rock.
He rolled a big stone in front of the entrance to the tomb and went away.
Mary Magdalene and the other Mary were sitting there opposite the tomb.
The next day, the one after Preparation Day,
the chief priests and the Pharisees went to Pilate.
"Sir," they said, "we remember that while he was still alive that deceiver said,
'After three days I will rise again.'
So give the order for the tomb to be made secure until the third day.
Otherwise, his disciples may come and steal the body
and tell the people that he has been raised from the dead.
This last deception will be worse than the first."
"Take a guard," Pilate answered. "Go, make the tomb as secure as you know how."
So they went and made the tomb secure
by putting a seal on the stone and posting the guard.
After the Sabbath, at dawn on the first day of the week,
Mary Magdalene and the other Mary went to look at the tomb.
There was a violent earthquake, for an angel of the Lord came down from heaven
and, going to the tomb, rolled back the stone and sat on it.
His appearance was like lightning, and his clothes were white as snow.
The guards were so afraid of him that they shook and became like dead men.
The angel said to the women,
"Do not be afraid, for I know that you are looking for Jesus, who was crucified.
He is not here; he has risen, just as he said.
Come and see the place where he lay.
Then go quickly and tell his disciples: 'He has risen from the dead
and is going ahead of you into Galilee. There you will see him.'
Now I have told you."
So the women hurried away from the tomb, afraid yet filled with joy,
and ran to tell his disciples.
Suddenly Jesus met them. "Greetings," he said.
They came to him, clasped his feet and worshiped him.
Then Jesus said to them,
"Do not be afraid.
Go and tell my brothers to go to Galilee; there they will see me."
While the women were on their way,
some of the guards went into the city
and reported to the chief priests everything that had happened.
When the chief priests had met with the elders and devised a plan,
they gave the soldiers a large sum of money,telling them,
"You are to say, 'His disciples came during the night and stole him away while we were asleep.'
If this report gets to the governor, we will satisfy him and keep you out of trouble."
So the soldiers took the money and did as they were instructed.
And this story has been widely circulated among the Jews to this very day.
Then the eleven disciples went to Galilee, to the mountain where Jesus had told them to go.
When they saw him, they worshiped him;
but some doubted.
Then Jesus came to them and said,
"All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me.
Therefore go and make disciples of all nations,
baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit,
and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you.
And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age."
Subtitled by Dr.Abkar Khristo
abkars@yahoo.com