TM by GLOBEPLUS
Silent Hill: Revelation
You cannot defeat me.
Do not go to Silent Hill.
Honey, it's okay.
I'm here...
Yes?
- I was burning...
- Hey come on, kiddo, it was just a dream.
Just like this morning...
- This feels different...
- Hey look...
Once we've unpacked and give this
place a lick of paint...
This will be our home.
- The dreams will fade.
- They're calling me.
Do not listen.
Do you hear?
I want you to promise me that whatever happens,
you'll never go there...
Okay.
Rough night?
Yeah.
Daddy, I don’t want to do this again.
I know, honey.
Spoons...
"Heather."
Why Heather?
It was my grandmother's name.
You can change it if you don’t like it.
No, no.
Heather is fine.
I was Sharon, then Mary, then Cathy.
Now Heather.
And you were Christopher and now you're Harry.
Names don't matter.
I'm still me.
Happy birthday!
Dad, thank you! But you’re, you’re early.
Just a little.
Can't believe that today I have
a soon-to-be 18 year-old daughter.
- What’s wrong?
- Nothing.
I love it.
- Really?
- Yes
It is the one I saw you're looking at in the mall.
Yes, yes. Thank you.
I love it.
You're welcome, honey.
You're getting all that gray there, dad.
Hmmm, your fault.
- You know, yours are showing.
- Yeah, I know. I'll fix it.
I think this place will be good for us, you know?
What do you think?
Yes
Hey, come on. What's say we unpacked,
give the new place a lick of paint...
- I think...
- Don't, Dad.
What?
It's just what you said
in my dream. Just, don't.
I got to go.
Do not want to be late on the first day of school.
Hey, remember the rules.
- New town, new school.
- Yes
I've done this before.
I know you have, I'm just...
- You know I worry.
- Don’t worry.
I'm careful.
I'll be fine.
I love you.
I love you too, honey.
Hey, Rose.
I wish you were still here.
It's been so hard since you
brought Sharon back to me.
Christopher, my love,
Rose
I tried to find you
I searched for so long
My love, I don’t have a lot of time
I'm trapped here. There's nothing you can do for me,
protect her.
- She's the one that matters now.
- Why can't you come back?
I found a Seal. Part of it is missing.
Only one of us could come through.
I made a choice.
- Where is our daughter?
- They'll come looking for her.
They'll come looking because they need her.
Never let them take her.
No matter what happens, no matter
what you have to do, swear to me.
Swear to me you will never let them take her.
- I swear.
- I brought her back to you.
She is yours to care for now.
Don't go.
Goodbye, my love.
Rose…
Daddy…
Sharon?
Oh, my God, Sharon!
- You are here.
- Daddy!
It's Okay.
You are safe now.
What happened?
I don't remember anything.
It's Okay…
You. ..
You had an accident.
Where's Mommy?
- Mommy saved you.
- Where's Mommy?
She's gone, honey.
Sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
- Sorry, what?
- Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
It's just that you don't wanna
be messing with the vagrants, miss.
I just wanted to see
if he needed some help.
Some people are beyond our help.
Have we met?
- No, no, I don't think so.
- No ?
I'm sure we have.
- What is your name?
- I have to catch my bus.
Welcome back, everyone. I hope you
had a good Christmas vacation.
I would like to welcome some new
students who will be joining us this semester.
Heather Mason.
Could you say hello to the class, Heather?
Hi. I'm Heather.
I'm new.
I just moved to town, so...
Come on, Heather, share a
little bit of yourself.
Everyone has a story.
Tell us yours.
What is this, third grade?
What do you wanna know?
Do you get all of your clothes from goodwill?
Okay, you know what?
Let me make this sincere for you.
This is the fifth school
I've been to since I was 11.
Me and my dad, we move around.
So I do this, a lot.
So don't bother trying to remember my name
because I'm sure as hell not gonna remember yours.
Do not talk to me.
We won't be friends.
I won't I.M you or,
Facebook you or Tweet you,
read your blog.
And whatever you're thinking of
saying or doing, don't bother, because
I've seen it before, and I'm just guessing here, but...
I don't think there are too
many original thinkers in this room.
And by the time any of you have found
out anything about me that’s worth knowing...
I have moved on.
- How's that?
- Very impressive.
Now the next addition to our class,
... Vincent Cooper.
Are you kidding me?
I can't follow that.
Shit!
Burn the witch!
- Burn the witch!
- No.
- Please leave me alone.
- Burn the Witch!
Please!
Leave me alone…
Are you alright. .?
- What?
- Are you okay?
What are you doing out of class?
You know what?
I'm lost.
I can't find Math.
Any ideas?
No, no.
I - I'm lost too.
Hey look, you wanna get a coffee?
- No, we have class.
- I mean, later.
- No.
- Why not?
We're both new.
We don't know anyone else.
That speech I gave in class, I gave it for a reason.
I really do not want to know anyone here.
Hey, honey.
How was your day?
I think there's someone following me.
What do I do?
Okay. Uhh..
Don't come back here. Not yet.
I'll meet you somewhere.
Central Square Mall.
- You need to make sure.
- Okay, I’ll meet you at Happy Burger place.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Do you think someone knows?
No.
No one knows.
I'll see you soon.
- I love you, Daddy.
- I love you too.
Happy birthday, Heather!
Make a wish!
"Happy birthday, HEATHER"
"Happy birthday, ALESSA"
Sharon.
Sharon !
Please, sir...
Sharon, wait!
Daddy, Daddy...
Father ..
Sharon, wait.
Sharon!
Keep away from me!
- It's okay.
- No, it's not okay.
Nothing is okay.
Who are you?
My name is Douglas Cartland, I'm a
private investigator.
What do you want from me?
I'm paid to find people.
Someone wanted you found, Sharon.
- That's not my name!
- You're Sharon Da Silva.
Or at least you think you are.
Tracked you down after you left Portland.
You and Harry got away
from the police, but I found you.
What my dad did there...
That was self-defense.
I don't care who Harry killed.
- I'm trying to help.
- Get back! Why?
Because I didn't know who I
was working for then, but I do now.
They call themselves the Order of Valtiel.
And they want you.
You're lying.
You do not understand.
They know where you are.
I told them where you are.
They're coming.
You gotta get away.
Don't worry, I will.
Keep away from me!
Everything your dad ever told you was a lie.
Fuck you!
He told me the truth.
You know why you don't remember
anything from your childhood?
I was in a car crash. My mother died.
I lost my memory.
No! There was never any accident.
You were trapped in a place called Silent Hill.
But your mother saved you.
She got you out.
But they want you back.
Ask your dad.
He knows that...
Tell me who I am.
No!
Please tell me.
It's gone. It's gone.
I'll help you, come on.
"Garbage"
You two, move back now.
Hey, Miss, you can't be back here.
Come on, back behind the tape, please.
Hey come on, folks, I need you back,
everybody get back.
Whoa, whoa, one second.
There’s a wallet in his pocket.
Sir, please stand back.
Douglas Cartland.
Some P.I. from out of town.
- What do you got there?
- The boys found this jacket down there.
- There’s blood on it.
- Go hand it over to forensics,
just find out whose blood it is.
Heather Mason, Sharon Da Silva.
- This girl?
- Maybe this is her.
Well let’s find her and ask her.
See what we got on this Cartland,
pull the security tapes,
I want to see what happened
here tonight.
Hey.
They found a guy dead in there,
did you see it?
Yeah, uhh…
What’s wrong?
- I can’t tell you.
- It's okay. You can tell me.
No, I can’t, because, I have no idea
what’s going on in my head now.
Harry’s voice on phone:
It’s me. Leave a message.
Dad, dad, call me when you get this, please.
Look, you’re cold.
Where's your coat?
Come here.
Thanks.
What's the matter?
Do you see them?
- Yeah, who, the runner?
- No.
Never mind. It’s just another thing that
prove that I’m going crazy.
So, where’s home?
A couple of blocks away.
No, I mean before.
Where did you come from?
Nowhere, really.
I travel a lot with my dad.
Do you think there is a
difference between dreams and reality?
(Chuckles)
What happened to the small-talk?
No "what’s your favourite band",
"do you Facebook", nothing like that?...
Fuck Facebook. Do you?
I never think about it.
- Everybody thinks about it.
- Not me.
Look, my life is complicated enough.
You should talk to my grandfather.
That's all he ever thinks about.
It drove him crazy.
- It's driving me crazy.
- No, no, I mean he’s insane.
Bat-shit nuts.
Back in my sweet, little hometown,
Old man Leonard drools in a padded cell.
He will tell you there are no such things as dreams,
just endless realities all piled on top of each other.
Some people see monsters,
Other people just see... people.
- And they locked him up for that?
- My mother had him committed.
- Jesus.
- Yeah, she's kind of intimidating, my mother.
No difference between fantasy and reality.
- I don't think I like my reality.
- You think anyone does?
At least I'm, who I think I am.
And you…
Yeah, pretty real...
... and just, pretty.
Oh, a lousy pick up line.
Does it often work?
I never tried it before.
How did it go down?
It was a crime against pick-up lines.
You're kind of funny, Heather.
You're pretty fucked up,
but I don't know, I ...
I think you're goofy fun inside.
Goofy fun...
That would be nice for a change.
Anyway, this is my street.
- Thanks for walking me back.
- I'd like to do it again sometime.
Vincent, you're nice, but...
- I don't think you wanna know me.
- I do.
No, you don't.
I'm gonna call you later.
I didn't give you my number.
See you around!
Dad?
Dad!
"COME TO SILENT HILL"
Dad…
Dad!
Heather, it's Vincent.
I heard you yell. Is everything alright?
I need your help.
Look,
Is that blood?
- Did you call the police?
- I can’t.
- Why not? They can help.
- I just can't!
- Okay?
- Okay.
Well, do you know where this Silent Hill is?
No, it's ..
It's something that I dreamt about. My dad, he...
He warned me never to go there.
But I know that symbol.
This is it.
He kept it all in here.
"SHARON"
- Is this your mom?
- My adoptive mom, Rose.
You were adopted?
Yeah, I never knew my real parents.
- Did you write all of these?
- Yeah…
- Do you know what that is?
- No.
Looks like there's another
side that fits in here.
A gun?
Why do you need a gun?
- Miss Mason, it's the police.
- I thought you said you didn't call.
- I didn't.
- Then why are they here?
- What is going on, Heather?
- I have to go.
If they catch me,
I'll never find my dad.
Catch you?
Why would they catch you?
- What have you done?
- Nothing! I haven’t done anything, I swear.
- Help me.
- What do you want me to do?
- Can you drive?
- What?
I can’t drive. Can you?
Santini, come here.
You want a probable cause?
This is it.
What the hell happened here?
That look like a gang tag to you?
I don’t think so.
But I've never seen anything like it.
Call Crime Scene, get them down here.
- What about the girl?
- She’s a murder suspect.
"My dearest Sharon,
If you are reading this then
something has happened to me.
You're on your own now.
Don’t try to find me.
And whatever you do,
don't go to Silent Hill.
I promised your mother I'd
keep you safe, but I failed.
I know you think we're
running from the police,
because of the man I killed
in Portland two years ago.
(You can't protect her forever!)
Dad!
But the truth is...
He wasn't just a random thief.
(Get your things, we're leaving.)
He was sent to take you back to Silent Hill.
He was a member of the Order.
These people want you, they need you.
I don't know why, but they will do everything
in their power just to draw you back.
You must resist it.
I tried to keep you safe.
And I never meant to lie to you,
but I had to.
You'll find the truth in my notebooks.
As much as I could find out.
I hope that when you read what I learned,
you can finally begin to understand who you really are.
Please forgive me for not
telling you the truth.
But I did it to protect you.
I love you, Sharon."
Are you okay?
Do you wanna stop?
No.
What does it say?
So much.
I know his writing, but this is crazy.
It says:
"Silent Hill was originally a prison colony,
built on ground taken from the native Indians.
They called it
'The Place of the Silent Spirits'".
Never build on the ancient Indian burial grounds.
I thought everyone knew that.
It says here:
"Religious zealots called the Order of Valtiel,
secretly ran the town for the last 100 years.
They were waiting for a child to be born
to be a vessel for their god.
Who would then be resurrected and make the world anew."
It sounds like one of those crazy doomsday cults.
Yeah. Sounds like it.
There is a newspaper article.
"Fire in the coal mines got out of control"
"The whole place is still burning, deep underground.
Everyone had to leave."
My dad doesn't believe that, though.
No?
He says the town was cursed by
the power of a demon child.
Her name was Alessa. This Order
tried to cleanse her with fire.
But they failed. And
Alessa's revenge
was to summon a world of darkness,
filled with terrifying creatures.
This one, it says, is her "guardian and executioner".
We should stop.
- No, I want to keep going.
- I'm tired.
I need rest, you need rest.
Do you think they'll find us?
Someone will, eventually.
- You think we're far?
- No.
No, I think we're very close.
And I don't think you should go...
- What?
- I think your dad is right.
I don't think you should
go to Silent Hill.
I need to find him.
You read his notebooks. He wants you to run.
- Vincent...
- No, listen to me. The Order, they want you.
I think that's why they took Harry.
- To make you come back.
- I don't have a choice.
- Don't you understand that?
- I understand.
I just...
I just don't want anything to happen to you.
You didn't sleep?
No.
We can't go any further.
We already talked about this.
I have to.
- Why can't you just trust me?
- It's for my dad. You don't understand.
- I do.
- No, you don't.
How could you?
Because I am a child of the Order.
What?
I was born and raised in Silent Hill.
I was chosen to come into this world,
to make sure you return.
No…
No, that's not possible.
The Order are trapped in
Silent Hill. The notebook says so.
It is possible for a few to escape
just for a while,
but it requires,
it requires sacrifice, and
suffering…
You have been chosen for this!
- How could you do this to me?
- My whole life all I've been taught,
All that any of us have taught is that
Alessa is the great evil of the world.
She trapped us, she brings the darkness.
And you... you are part of that evil.
But I, I know that's not true.
After seeing you, after spending this time
with you, I know you're not evil, I ...
If you are part of Alessa...
… you're the innocent part.
- Every step of the way, you lied.
- I had to.
They were watching, protecting their
spirits into the world. You saw them.
You took my dad.
Please believe me, I had nothing to do with that,
- I'm sorry.
- Why take him, why not just take me?
Because you have to return of your own free will.
Taking him, they knew you'd follow.
Why do I matter so much?
Because the Order can't be
free until Alessa is gone.
Her power keeps them trapped, and she can't
be destroyed until she's whole again.
- You will make that happen.
- What about my dad?
- Is he still alive?
- Yes, but not for long.
My mother, Claudia, won't keep him
alive after she has what she wants.
- Where is he?
- In the sanctuary beneath the town.
- Wait, Heather, stop...
- No!
You need this.
You have to find the other half. It's the only
way you'll be able to save your dad.
My grandfather has it.
The one in the asylum?
Yes, Leonard Wolf.
- It's dangerous. Let me help you.
- No! Get off of me!
- Listen!
- No...
- What is happening?
- The Darkness is coming.
Heather...
What's going on?
Stop! Make it stop!
- You did this.
- No.
It's not me.
How could it be me?
Because you are part of Alessa.
You're so close, you allowed
the darkness to break through.
Vincent, what is going on?
I don't know.
Vincent!
WELCOME TO SILENT HILL
Burn the Witch!
You should not be here.
They will use you.
We will all suffer now.
I know who you are.
You're her mother.
Alessa's mother.
How could you let them burn her?
No, I loved her.
It's alright, sweetheart.
It's okay. It's alright
I was deceived.
I never wanted this for her.
Alessa: Where are you taking me?
Mommy! Mommy!
Alessa was special.
She was the only one who could
survive the fire, that's why she was chosen.
No, no!
But it only led to our damnation.
You all got what you deserved.
Yes, and I became the mother of the demon.
But you are her daughter.
What are you talking about?
Alessa didn't die in the fire,
but she suffered so much.
For pain was only matched by the rage.
And with that rage, her powers grew…
... beyond all comprehension.
Alessa knew there was a part of her,
that could still be free from pain.
So she took that last,
innocent part of her soul
and placed it into a
new born, orphan child.
You.
You were secretly taken from here,
to be raised by loving, but unaware parents.
You're the only part of Alessa
that feels love.
You have the balance of hate.
You should never have come back.
Because now you have given the order
what they could never have...
A way to destroy Alessa.
And you.
Where is my father?
There is nothing you can do to
save him without damning yourself.
I don't care.
Just tell me what you know.
I know the darkness is coming.
It's safer to be inside.
Run.
Run!
No!
What?
Help me.
No…
Run.
I'm here, I'll help you!
- What happened?
- Run, she's coming.
Who's coming?
Come on! Run!
- Where did you come from?
- I took a wrong turn...
Got lost in the fog...
"EXIT"
Go! Come on!
No!
This way.
Run!
Go!
My own son...
Mother, please...
... betrayed us.
She is not evil.
Your mind is corrupted by her darkness.
You were young to be given this task...
I understand.
You created Alessa.
The darkness is your evil reflected back at us.
- She is innocent.
- She is innocent?
- You are insane, just as your grandfather is insane.
- Kill him! Burn him!
Make him suffer!
- Let the God judge him!
- No!
You succeeded.
Even in your madness,
you guided her back to us.
- And a broken mind can be mended.
- No.
Mother, please don't.
- Take him to the asylum. Cure him.
- No.
No!
"Brookhaven Asylum"
Leonard.
(Do you think someone knows?)
(No.)
(No one knows.)
(Okay.)
(I love you too.)
Leonard Wolf.
Okay.
S-12.
12.
Leonard.
Hello, child.
Please come closer,
so I could touch you.
I don't think so.
- Did Claudia send you?
- Claudia?
- Yeah.
- No. She put you here.
My own daughter says that I'm
corrupted by the darkness.
She says that I’m a monster.
She's far worse than I am.
She is also corrupted by the same darkness.
- I am looking for my father.
- Is he lost?
He's in Silent Hill.
There are many Silent Hills.
Are you sure it's this one?
Vincent said you know how to...
Vincent, that little traitor…
My own flesh and blood turned against me!
Listen. Ahh.
You may be able to hear
the cries of his torment.
He's here?
Where else would you go to mend your mind?
Like yours is?
Why ..
I'm just...  an ongoing project.
I have half of this.
- Will it help me?
- Listen...
I'm blind, child.
I cannot see what you have there.
Place ​​it in my hand
and I will try to help you.
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
- You know what it is.
- I was the Master of the Order.
How could I not know
the Seal of Metatron?
It was stolen from me and used
by her to escape with the child.
Without it we cannot summon the god.
It is a key. What does it unlock?
The true nature of things.
I need to find the other half.
But you've already found it.
The other half is in me!
What are you doing?
No!
Stop!
Now...  I see the truth of you.
You're a demon!
You must be destroyed!
Not today.
Two halves coming together.
It's complete.
Alessa?
Can you feel me?
You know I'm here, don't you?
You know I've got the Seal of Metatron.
Somebody help me.
No.
Get back! Get back!
And you!
Get back!
- Look out!
- Get back!
Do it! Do it!
How can I find my dad?
- Heather, help me.
- Tell me where he is.
In the sanctuary, beneath
the amusement park.
I can help you.
Okay.
Hurry!
I am hurrying!
Damn .
Stop!
- Heather, stop.
- We need a knife.
How can you live like this?
This darkness, those creatures?
That's all I've ever known.
My reality.
Darkness should have faded by now.
- Why hasn't it?
- You're so close to Alessa,
two halves coming together again,
it's changing the world.
What's gonna happen?
That's up to you.
Lakeside Amusement Park is over there.
And the entrance to the sanctuary.
Do you think you can save him?
I have to try. My dad gave up
his life to protect me.
- I think he'd want you to leave.
- You don't know that.
If he loved you, he wouldn't
want you to be in any danger.
And if you love someone, you know
that you will never give up.
No, wait!
Get down.
- Look.
- Are they soldiers?
Not really.
We call them "the Brethren".
The most devout servants of the Order.
See the masks? They won't breathe
the air of the darkness.
They think it corrupts them.
I hope you find him.
I hope live free and happy,
It's more than I ever did.
What are you talking about?
Vincent, no!
- Alessa?
- Daughter.
Sister.
- Self.
- No.
I gave you life so you
could live my dream.
You're the part of me that
can be free of this pain.
Live, and feel love.
Do you feel nothing?
Nothing but hate.
They say you are a demon.
- They are right.
- You created this nightmare.
Everyone has a different nightmare in Silent Hill.
- I am theirs.
- I have to save my father.
He's not my father, or yours.
And sacrifices, have to be made.
Go to hell!
Don't you see?
We're already here.
And you're not welcome!
Do you think, I won't destroy you?
I don't care.
I am you.
Time to take back what I gave you!
Stop!
We are one, Heather.
Dad!
Sharon!
Sharon...
Don't hurt her!
What do you want from me?
Look around you.
This was our sanctuary.
A last, safe place from the darkness.
And now, even here, has fallen to her evil.
But praise the god,
that you are here, finally.
- You have delivered us.
- I have done nothing for you.
You have done everything.
Defeated Alyssa.
Re-joined the seal.
You are the savior.
If I've done so much,
Then let my father go.
He cannot go. His blood
will feed the newborn god ..
Just as your body will be its incubator.
Why?
- Why me?
- It is your destiny.
You have been chosen many
years ago to be the vessel.
The god can only be born through your flesh.
And then we will be free from this prison
to cleanse the world of its sins.
And all we need... is your body.
No!
You leave her alone!
You have the Seal of Metatron.
With it, I can summon the god.
Give it to me.
Take it, I want to see
the truth of what you are.
- Dad!
- Sharon.
The ash…
It’s stopped!
- Was it you?
- No, it's not me.
I think things are gonna be
different around here from now on..
The Order's power is broken.
Alessa's nightmare is over.
- She's gone.
- Another one will come.
This is the place of lost souls.
What's wrong?
- I can't leave.
- Why?
- I have to stay here.
- But dad, we're free.
We're safe.
- For the first time.
- I'm gonna find your mother.
You saved my life.
And I can never repay you.
But Rose is still trapped here somewhere .
- I'm gonna find her.
- Let me help you find her.
No. I promised her, once you
were safe, I’ll come back.
This is my task.
You've done what you had to do.
Now, I want you to be free, finally.
Do you understand why I have to do this?
You're everything I could've ever wished for.
- I love you, baby.
- I love you too, Dad.
Vincent, look after my little girl,
do you hear?
I don't think she needs me for that.
Come on.
Yeah.
Come on in.
Watch your step.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
You're lucky I came by.
I haven't been this way in a long time.
- Travis Grady.
- Vincent.
- Sharon.
- Nice to meet you.
So where're you two lovebirds headed?
Just take us as far away
from here as you can.
- Amen to that!
- Got it.
By TM  GLOBEPLUS