The Parent Trap (1998)
Subtitle re-arranged by Tanveer
‘L’ is for the way
you look at me
‘O’ is for the only one I see
‘V’ is very,
very extraordinary
‘E’ is even more
than anyone that you adore can
Love is
all that I can give to you
Love is more than
just a game for two
Two in love can make it
Take my heart
and please don’t break it
Love was made for me and you
Love is
all that I can give to you
Love is more than
just a game for two
Two in love can make it
Take my heart
and please don’t break it
Love was made for me and you
‘L’ is for the way
you look at me
‘O’ is for the only one I see
‘V’ is very,
very extraordinary
‘E’ is even more
than anyone that you adore can
Love is
all that I can give to you
How about a souvenir picture?
Can you turn towards each other?
My God ! My phone just
does not work out here.
Oh, my God !
How are we ever gonna live?
Uh ! Thanks.
There's a counsellor. Oh, excuse me.
Um, can you tell me where
the Navajo bunk is?
- It's right over there.
- Thanks.
Now, girls, let's find our duffles
as quickly as we can.
We have a big first day
ahead of us.
I'm going to turn the bullhorn
over now to my daughter,
and right-hand man,
Marva, Jr.
Marva, bunk assignments,
if you please.
All right, ladies,
here we go. Listen up.
Wait a minute.
I thought this was a boy's camp.
Okay, found my duffle.
Now the question is...
how do I get it out?
Okay, I can do it.
Okay... no, I can't.
- You must be new.
- How could you tell?
- You didn't know how
to grab your duffle...
before the aides tossed
it into the heap.
-I would say you need some serious help.
-Thanks.
It's the big, yellow one.
Whoa ! Now,
that's my kinda woman.
- Yo, tie-dye girl !
- Hmm?
Could you give me an hand
with my duffle? It's the yellow one,
- buried way in there.
- Sure.
Oh, that?
No problem.
Hey, you're
from California?
Do you, like, live in Hollywood?
Do you, like, live next door
to a movie star?
What are you two,
Lucy and Ethel?
I've never even been
to Hollywood.
I live in Napa.
That's northern California.
And I live next door to a vineyard.
- A what-yard?
- A vineyard.
It's where you grow grapes
to make wine.
That's what we do.
Me and my dad, we own a vineyard.
- Parker, Hallie !
- Right here.
- Arapaho.
- Same as me.
That's where I am.
- Yes ! Come on, you guys.
So, ah, either of you, by any chance,
know how to play poker?
- No.
- Never played it before.
No? Gee,
what a shame.
So, ah, how much cash did you guys
bring with you this summer?
- How much?
- A lot.
- Whoa ! Who is in there?
Come on. Let's go.
Well, here we are.
Camp Walden for Girls.
We travelled all the way
from London for this?
Well, it's rather picturesque.
Don't you think?
- Eh, um--
Not exactly the term
I think I would have used.
- All right. Shall we review
your mother's list?
- Mm-hmm.
- Now, let's see. Vitamins?
- Check.
- Minerals?
- List of daily fruits and vegetables.
- Check. Check.
Check for fruits,
check for vegetables. Go on.
Sun block, lip balm,
insect repellant,
stationery, stamps, photograph
of your mother, grandfather...
and, of course,
your trusty butler, me.
- Got it all, I think.
- Oh, and, um--
Here's a little something
from your grandfather.
A spanking-new deck
of cards.
Maybe you'll actually find
somebody on this continent
who can whip your tush at poker.
Well, I doubt it.
But, thanks.
And thanks for
bringing me here, Martin.
Now, you remember,
if you change your mind...
and want me to come here and
collect you at the end of camp,
I'm only a phone call away.
Thanks,
but I'll be fine.
Really. See you in eight weeks,
Marty ol' pal.
Missing you already,
queen of my heart.
- Have fun, old bean.
- I will.
- Toodle-oo.
- Airport, please.
- Okay, hurry up.
She brought a date.
She didn't.
Mom ! Mom ! Are you there?
Pick up ! Mom !
Whoa ! Whoa ! Whoa !
Slow down. Thank you.
- Have some too, okay?
- It's something.
- It smells good.
- I'll save ya a seat, Annie.
- Okay, thanks.
Excuse me, girls. I've just got to have
a scoop of these gorgeous strawberries.
- Would you care for some, dear?
- Oh, no thanks.
Can't. I'm-- I'm allergic.
Oh, that's too bad.
How 'bout you, dear? Strawberries?
Oh, sorry, wish I could, but I can't.
I'm-l'm allergic.
Yes, allergic.
You just... told me that.
How did you get over there?
Oh, well. First day of camp.
You'll have to excuse the old girl.
At least I'm not putting
salt in the sugar shakers.
Ah, well, I mean, you know.
Sugar in the salt shak--
Now where did she go?
Touche.
Good job.
All right !
Excellent, kid.
The winner, and still undefeated
champ from Napa, California,
- Miss Hallie Parker.
- Yeah, Hallie.
Do we have
any challengers?
Oh, come on. Ladies,
let's not be damsels in distress here.
I'll take
a whack at it.
Okay. We've got ourselves
a chal-len-ger. Suit up.
Cool.
Ooh, thanks.
Here I go.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Go, Annie. Whoa !
Fencers ready?
- Ready.
- All set.
En garde ! Fence !
- Oops.
- Ah !
Touche !
- Nice catch.
- Thanks.
Touche !
- Sorry, let me help you.
- No, let me help you !
- What'd ya do that for?
- Me? You pushed me in.
- I did not.
Okay, that was
quite a show.
All right. I think we've got ourselves
a new camp champ from London, England,
Miss Annie James.
All right, girls.
Shake hands.
Come on, girls.
Oh, my !
Why's everyone
staring?
- Don't you see it?
- See what?
- The resemblance between us.
- Resemblance? Between you and me?
Let me see.
Turn sideways.
Now the other way.
Well, your eyes are
much closer together than mine.
Your ears, well, don't worry,
you'll grow into them.
Your teeth are a little crooked.
Ah ! And that nose ! Well, don't worry,
dear, those things can be fixed.
- Want me to deck her for ya?
- Hold on. I'm not quite finished yet.
You wanna know
the real difference between us?
Let me see.
I know how to fence and you don't?
Or, I have class and you don't.
Take your pick.
- Why, I oughta--
- Ladies, it's time
to break up this little lovefest.
Annie, Hallie.
I mean, Hallie, Annie.
I-I-I mean-- Whoa !
Sorry, ladies. Two pair.
Read 'em and weep.
Aah ! I'm out.
- So that's it? No more takers?
- I have nothing left.
I'll take
a whack at it.
Take a seat,
Parker.
Deal me in.
Tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'll make you a little deal.
Loser jumps into the lake
after the game.
- Excellent.
- Butt naked.
Even more excellent.
Start unzipping, Parker.
Straight.
In diamonds.
You're good, James.
But, you're
just not good enough.
In your honour,
a royal flush.
- Love the birthday suit.
- Lookin' good.
Oww, baby !
Grab her clothes.
Oh, right. Fine.
If that's the way you want it,
then let the games begin.
I swear I heard your evil clone
sneaking all the way up toward
the mess hall this morning.
I am so tired. I'm going back
into bed and sleeping till lunch.
That does not seem like
a possibility, babe.
- Why not?
- That's why not.
No... way.
- Be quiet.
- Oh, I hope they're sleeping.
The coast is clear.
Okay, let's go in.
- Payback time.
- Don't wake her.
- Careful.
Got milk?
Oh, my God.
She didn't get me.
Ah ! That girl
is without a doubt...
the lowest, most awful creature
that ever walked the planet !
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Morning, girls.
- Morning, Marvas.
Marvas !
Surprise inspection.
Attention !
No, no, Marva.
Do not go in there.
One of the girls got sick last night,
and it is a big, big mess.
Save yourself the aggravation.
It's really disgusting.
Oh, well, if someone's sick,
dear, then I must go in.
- Move aside, dear.
- No, no, really. I insist.
I can't let you go in there.
She's highly contagious.
Honest.
Actually, we're all
quite fine in here,
unless Hallie Parker knows
something we don't know.
Really. I insist. Open the door
and come see for yourself, ma'am.
Stand aside, Hallie.
Mommy !
No ! No !
No !
- I told you it was a mess in here.
- She should know. She did it !
You !
And you !
Pack your bags !
Okay, girls.
The rest of you...
back to your activities.
You two...
the isolation cabin.
Oh, gosh,
it's stuck.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Ah ! Oh, man !
- Oh, here's your--
- Cuppy.
Any of your
pictures ruined?
- Only the beautiful Leo DiCaprio.
- Who?
You've never heard
of Leonardo DiCaprio?
How far away
is London anyway?
Well, from here
it's 3,000 miles,
but sometimes
it seems much further.
- How far away is your home?
- Oh, California is way at
the other end of the country.
Actually, here's a picture of my house.
- Wow ! It's beautiful.
- Yeah.
We built it when I was little.
We've got this incredible porch...
that looks over
the entire vineyard.
- And then--
- Who-- Who's that?
Oh, that's my dad. He didn't know
I was taking the picture then...
or else he would have
turned around.
He's kinda like my best friend.
We do everything together.
- What's the matter?
- Oh, it's chilly in here, that's all.
- Want one?
- Oh, sure, I love Oreos.
At home I eat them with--
I eat them with peanut butter.
You do?
That is so weird. So do l.
You're kidding. Most people
find that totally disgusting.
I know.
I don't get it.
Me either.
What's your
dad like?
I mean, is he the kind of father
you can talk to,
or is he one of those
workaholic types who says,
"I'll talk to ya later, honey,"
but, you know,
never really does?
- I hate that.
- I don't have a father, actually.
I mean, I had one once,
I suppose.
But my parents
divorced years ago.
My mother never even
mentions him.
It's like he evaporated
into thin air or something.
It's scary the way nobody
stays together any more.
- Tell me about it.
- How old are you?
- I'll be 12 on October 11.
- So will I.
- Your birthday's on October 11?
- Yeah.
- How weird is that?
Extremely.
Oh, hey.
It stopped raining.
You wanna go get
a Popsicle or something?
- What's the matter?
- Hallie, what's your mother like?
I never met her. She and my dad split
up when I was a baby, maybe even before.
I'm not sure.
He doesn't like to talk about her.
But I know she was
really, really beautiful.
How do you know that?
Well, because my dad
had this old picture of her
hidden in his sock drawer,
and he caught me looking at it,
like, all the time,
so he gave it to me to keep.
Look, I'm-l'm really thirsty.
Sure you don't want to go to
the mess hall and get a lemonade?
Will you stop thinking about
your stomach at a time like this?
- At a time like what?
- Don't you realize what's happening?
I mean,
think about it.
I only
have a mother,
and you only have
a father.
You've never seen
your mom,
and I've never
seen my dad.
You have one old picture
of your mom,
and I have one old picture
of my dad.
But at least yours
is probably a whole picture.
Mine is a pathetic
little thing,
all crinkled and ripped
right down the middle and--
What are you rummaging
in your trunk for?
This.
It's a picture
of my mom,
and it's
ripped too.
Right down
the middle?
the middle.
This is so...
freaky.
Okay.
On the count of three,
we'll show them to each other, okay?
Okay.
One.
Two.
- Three.
- That's my dad.
- That's my mom.
That's the lunch bell.
I'm not so
hungry any more.
So if--
if your mom...
is my mom...
and my dad
is your dad...
and we're both born on October 11...
then you and I
are like--
like sisters.
Sisters?
Hallie, we're
like twins.
I just don't know what to say.
What's that
you're holding?
My locket.
I got it when I was born.
It has an "H"
on it.
[ Chuckles ]
I got mine when I was born, too,
except mine has
an "A" on it.
Ooh, now I've got goose bumps.
My God, so I'm
not an only child.
I'm a twin.
I'm a twin-- there's two of me.
I mean,
two of us.
- This is like--
- Mind boggling.
- Totally.
- Completely.
- Oh, my God.
Tell me, what's Mom like?
Well, she designs wedding gowns.
Really?
She's becoming
quite famous, actually.
A princess in Greece
just bought one of her gowns.
Wow.
Y-You know what's
interesting?
Neither one of our parents
ever got married again.
Has Dad ever been close
to getting remarried?
Never. He always says
I'm the only girl in his life.
Yeah, Mom's never
come close either.
I have a brilliant,
beyond brilliant idea.
I'm serious.
I am a total genius.
You want to know
what Dad is like, right?
Right.
And I'm dying
to know Mom.
So what I'm thinking is--
Don't freak out, okay?
I think we should switch places.
When camp's over
I'll go back to London as you,
and you go back
to California as me.
- What?
- Annie, we can pull it off.
We're twins, aren't we?
Hallie, we're totally
and completely 100% different.
So, what's the problem?
I'll teach you to be me...
and you teach me
to be you.
Look, I can
do you already.
Yes, you want to know
the difference between us?
I have class
and you don't.
Come on, Ann. I got to meet my ma.
The truth is, you know,
if we switch,
sooner or later
they'll have to unswitch us.
And when they do,
they'll have to meet again,
- face to face.
- After all these years.
Thank you. I told you
I'm brilliant.
Okay. 'Tis grandfather.
- He's so cute. What do we call him?
- Grandfather.
Why didn't I think of that?
This is Martin,
he's our butler.
- We have a butler?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay. Living-room's first.
Then over here is the dining room.
But we never eat in there
except for Thanksgiving...
and Christmas and,
of course, October 11.
Okay. I-I'm ready.
- Don't shut your eyes !
- Oh. Okay. Right.
Sorry. Just got
a little nervous.
You're nervous?
An 11-year-old is cutting my hair.
Hey, you sounded just like me.
Well, I'm supposed to, aren't I?
Go on, just do it.
Don't panic.
You look great.
Looking good.
This is so... scary.
Honey, you never
looked better.
Oh, my God !
What?
I have
pierced ears.
No. No, no and no.
Not happening.
Sorry, wrong number.
I won't.
I refuse.
Then cutting your hair
was a total waste,
'cause, I mean, there's no way
I can go to camp...
with pierced ears
and come home without 'em.
I mean, come on.
Get real.
Needle sterilized.
Y-You-- You sure you know
what you're doing?
Relax. I've gone with all my friends
to get their ears pierced.
It's nothing.
Just close your eyes,
and it will be over
before you know it.
- Earring ready?
- Yes.
Good.
Hand me the apple.
Thank you.
Just relax. I'm telling you,
this is not a big deal.
On the count of three,
remove the ice.
One... two...
three.
Girls, time to say
your last goodbyes.
- The busses are loading.
- Busses one and two leaving.
I'll see you guys
next summer, I promise.
Okay, so call me every single day.
All right. And write me.
Don't forget.
I won't.
Okay. This is it.
So remember, you're going
to find out how Mom and Dad met.
- And you're going to find out
why they broke up.
- Annie James,
- your car is here.
- That's you.
Here's your ticket and passport.
Martin will pick you up
at the airport tomorrow morning.
- What time do you leave?
- Oh, not for a couple of hours.
Give Mom a kiss for me.
- Give Dad one for me.
- Annie James, front and centre.
Bye.
- Bye.
- Last call, Annie James.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Good luck.
Okay. This is it.
God, I hope
she likes me.
Please like me.
Please.
- Annie !
- Martin.
- Missed you.
- What have you done to your hair?
- Cut it. Do you like it?
Love it. It's the new you.
And you've had
your ears pierced.
Give me five,
girlfriend.
- Home again.
- Thank you.
This is it.
7 Primbrook Lane.
Hello.
Grandfather?
- I'm home.
- Is that my little girl?
That tall, gangly thing?
Yes, it's me.
Oh, welcome home.
- Did you have a good time, sweet pea?
- Uh-huh, great.
What are you doing?
- Just smelling.
- Smelling?
- I'm making a memory.
- Oh.
Years from now,
when I'm all grown up,
I'll always remember
my grandfather...
and how he
always smelt of...
peppermint
and pipe tobacco.
Good to have you back.
Annie?
- Mother.
- You're back.
- I can't believe it's you.
- And I can't believe
it's you.
And with short hair.
Who cut it for you?
A girl I met at camp.
Do you hate it?
No, I absolutely
love it.
You got your ears pierced?
Well, are there any other surprises?
Belly button rings,
tattoos?
Ah, darling,
what is it?
I'm sorry.
It's just--
I've missed you
so much.
I know.
- It seems like it's been forever.
- You have no idea.
So, come on. Tell me,
did you like everyone? Was it fun?
- Ah, Martin.
- I found a stowaway in your suitcase.
Oh, my God. Cuppy !
- Cuppy?
- He-- He belongs to my friend,
the one I was, umm,
telling you about.
I can't imagine
how he got into my suitcase.
Well, since he's not our Cuppy, shall
we dispose of the little creature?
No ! I mean, no.
I'll-- I'll mail him to her.
She loves this thing a lot--
a lot, a lot.
And she's, like,
slept with this thing her entire life,
And she could never be, like--
Stay in a foreign country without him.
No, no. I'll take care of it.
That will be all, Martin.
Thank you.
Hello.
Oh, hi.
How's the photo shoot going?
Hmm. Well, can't you
manage without me?
I mean, Annie just
got home from camp.
Hmm. Yeah.
Okay. Hold on a moment.
Annie, would you hate very much
running down to the studio with me?
No, I'd love it.
Wow. That's incredible.
You designed that?
Well, I had to do something
while you were at camp.
- You don't think it's too--
- No, it's gorgeous. I love it.
You know who would look
really beautiful in that gown?
- I mean, like, really beautiful?
- Who?
- You.
- Me?
You know what? I think that time
change has made you a little loopy.
Come on. Let's see
what all the fuss is about.
Okay. I'm here.
Ah, we're saved.
- Hi, Angela.
- Hi. Sorry, we don't know
what to do with the veil.
If she wears it, it covers the back
of the dress, and if she doesn't,
- the dress looks--
- Incomplete, you're right.
Can you try turning sideways
with your chin up?
Yeah, I see the problem.
Can I have the veil? Annie, darling,
pass me one of those hats
on display in the window.
- Me?
- Yes.
- Which one do you like?
- The white one.
Me too.
Try this.
Now, throw the veil
straight back.
That's it. Now spin around.
I want to see the back of the dress.
That's beautiful. Did you get that?
Just how it falls. Just down there.
Don't worry about the bouquet.
You're married now.
You've got to learn to juggle.
- Don't forget you look happy.
It is your wedding day.
- My mom is too cool.
So, doesn't designing
all these wedding gowns
ever make you think about...
getting married again, or at least
make you think about the "F" word.
The "F" word?
- My father.
- Oh ! Oh, that "F" word.
Well, no, actually,
because I didn't even wear a wedding
gown when I married the "F" word.
- You didn't? Why not?
- Why the sudden curiosity...
about your dad,
huh?
Well, maybe because
he's never mentioned.
And you can't blame
a kid for wondering.
Mother, you can't avoid
the subject forever.
At least tell me
what he was like.
Okay. He was quite lovely,
to tell you the truth.
When we met he was...
actually, entirely lovely.
- All right?
- All right.
So, did you meet
him here in London?
- We met on the Q.E. 2.
- Q.E. what?
The Queen Elizabeth 2.
It's an ocean liner that sails
from London to New York,
'cause I wasn't keen on flying then
and neither was your father.
We met our first night
on board ship. We were seated
next to each other at dinner.
- He's an American, you know.
- No kidding?
So, was it love at first sight?
I knew you were going to ask me
all these questions one day. Taxi !
Dear ol' Dad.
I wonder what he's doing
at this very moment.
Thanks.
- Got it?
- Oh, gosh.
It's him.
Hey, Hal !
Welcome home,
kiddo.
Get into these arms,
you little punk.
Dad. Finally.
Oh, I hope you had a lousy time at that
camp, because you are not going back.
I missed you too much.
What happened
to you, Hal?
Something's changed.
Are you
getting taller?
So, what's up,
Dad?
I mean, how's Chessy
and everybody?
Great. Everybody's great.
Can't wait to see you.
Eight weeks really
is too long, Hal.
- A lot's been happening around here.
- A lot's happened to me too, Dad.
I mean, I feel like
I'm practically a new woman.
What's the matter?
I cut myself shaving?
No, it's just-- just seeing you
for the first time.
I mean, you know,
in so long.
You look taller to me, too, Dad.
Come on, squirt.
Let's get home.
Oh, by the way,
thanks for all those newsy letters.
I'm really glad I bought you
that personalized stationery...
you just had
to have.
- Well, we meant to write,
Dad, but we just got so--
- We?
Oh !
Oh, me and my friend.
I-I met this girl at camp
and we got really close.
- Great.
- Practically like sisters.
- She was a lovely girl.
- Lovely girl?
All of sudden
you're so proper?
You're still biting those nails, I see.
- Dad, you noticed.
- What do you mean noticed?
You've been biting
them since you could chew.
But I've decided to stop, Dad.
It's a horrid habit.
Lovely girl, horrid habit.
What did I do, send you
to summer camp or finishing school?
And why do you keep saying "Dad"
at the end of every sentence?
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
I was doing it, Dad.
Sorry, Dad.
Do you want to know
why I keep saying "dad"?
- The truth?
- Because you missed your
old man so much, right?
Exactly. It's because
in my whole life,
I mean, you know,
for the past eight weeks,
I was never able to say the word "dad."
Never. Not once.
And if you ask me,
I mean,
a dad is an irreplaceable
person in a girl's life.
Think about it. There's a whole day
devoted to celebrating fathers.
Just imagine someone's life
without a father--
never buying a Father's Day card,
never sitting on their father's lap,
never being able to say,
"Hi, Dad" or "What's up, Dad"
or "Catch you later, Dad."
I mean, a baby's first words
are always "dada," aren't they?
Let me see if I get this--
You miss being able to call me dad?
Yeah.
I really have, Dad.
Oh, my God.
Now you're starting to sound
like your old self.
Hello, gorgeous !
Oh, look at you !
Oh, you grew.
Oh, we missed you
so much.
Hey, don't you dare let
your old man talk you out of
going back to camp. Okay?
You're a growing girl.
You need adventure.
- Okay.
- Oh, you hungry?
I made corn bread
and chili.
- Why are you so quiet? What's wrong?
- Nothing, it's just--
I'm so happy
to be home.
Hey, did I hear somethin' about
corn bread and chili?
Yeah, it's on
the stove. So...
something's changed
about you, Hal.
Umm, I can't
put my finger on it,
- but something about you
is definitely changed.
- Really?
Well, it's just
the same old me. Honest.
- Hi, Sammy.
What is wrong with you,
you goofball? It's Hallie.
Oh, I-I probably just smell
like camp, that's all.
What's the matter
with you?
It's like you didn't
even recognize her.
Wow !
It's even better than the pictures.
Okay, kiddo.
What do ya wanna do first, huh?
You wanna eat and then unpack?
Or, uh, we could unpack and then eat.
- Or we could eat while we unpack.
- Do you mean I can eat in my room?
Yeah, I'd say it's
a definite possibility.
Hey, Hal,
when you're done, come on down.
There's someone I want you to meet.
- Okay, Dad.
- Okay, Hal.
Look at you. Always eating.
- Did you tell her?
- No.
Nicky.
- I will. I will.
- Tell me what?
Hal, it is none of my business
how your father makes a fool
out of himself. Okay?
He's a big boy.
He can do what he wants.
Okay. Okay.
So, who is she?
Her name's
Meredith Blake.
She's a publicist
from San Francisco.
Your father hired her
at the beginning of the summer...
to do some publicity
for the vineyard.
If you ask me, she's doin' a better job
of sellin' herself than the grapes.
What do you mean?
Look, you and I both know
your father's...
not some kind of suave, debonair
bachelor-of-the-month type.
So, I gotta ask myself, "What does
a hot, young thing like that...
see in a guy who walks around
with his shirttail hangin' out...
and his cereal bowl
full of chili?"
Then, I realized there's about a million
reasons why that girl's gigglin'.
And all of them are sitting at
the Napa Valley Community Bank.
You mean, you don't think
she even really likes him?
Eh, what do I know?
But I'll tell you one thing.
This one's got your father
eating out of the palm of her hand.
They do everything together.
They ride together.
They swim together.
They go out to eat dinner every night.
But, you know what? Meet her. See for
yourself. Don't let me influence you.
There's my girl.
Honey, I want you to meet
a friend of mine. Hal,
this is Meredith Blake.
Hi.
Hi,
Meredith Blake.
Wow. I can't believe I'm finally
meeting the famous Hallie.
I have looked forward
to this all summer.
Really?
Well, here I am.
Oh, Nicky,
she's adorable !
You know, the way your father
talked about you,
I expected to meet a little girl,
but you are so grown up.
I'll be 12 soon. How old are you?
Twenty-six.
Only 15 years older than me.
How old are you, again, Dad?
Wow ! Suddenly, you're
so interested in math.
Look, I'm gonna go inside.
I'm gonna get some more chili,
maybe a bottle of champagne
to celebrate.
- What are we celebrating?
- Your homecoming, of course.
Be right back.
Meredith Blake.
Hello, Reverend Mosby.
Mm-hmm. Of course. No, I understand
it's for a local charity?
Oh, yes.
I am writing it all down.
Okay, it sounds
very worthwhile, I agree.
But, unfortunately,
I see that Mr Parker...
is going to be
out of the country on those days.
Yes. Absolutely.
I will be sure to mention it to him.
Thank you.
So, how was camp, Hal?
Was it fabulous?
My dad's going
out of the country?
Oh, no.
I just had to tell a little
white lie to get him out of something.
You know, I have never heard a man
talk about his daughter...
the way Nicky
talks about you.
You two are obviously
incredibly close.
Well, you know,
we're closer than close.
We're all
each other has.
Ohh !
Sorry. Did I
get you wet, Mer?
Just a little, Hal.
Hey.
Guess what?
Your daddy took me riding the other day,
and he let me ride your horse.
I hope that's okay
with you.
Oh, sure. She's probably used
to strange women riding her.
Not that you're
strange or anything.
Actually, compared to the others,
you are relatively normal.
Others?
What others?
- Do you want the 411?
- What's the 411?
The information--
the lowdown on other women.
Can't say
I blame you.
I'd wanna know if I was number 28--
I mean, 29 in a man's life.
I'm number 29?
Yeah. It's always
the same routine--
horseback riding
through the vineyards,
romantic dinners with
his special reserved-label wine,
- moonlight swims--
- Here we go--
a bottle of my special
reserve-label.
So, did you girls find something
to talk about while I was gone?
- Does that mean yes?
- It sure does.
Will somebody
grab that, please?
James residence.
Annie?
- Yes, Martin.
- Oh, dear. It sounds
just like you on the phone.
I'm sorry.
To whom did you wish to speak?
Annie?
Of course.
One moment, please.
A Mildred Plotker
for you.
Sounds just like
your twin.
My twin?
Very funny.
Good one, Martin.
Hello.
Oh, Mildred, darling.
Hi. How are you?
- Hey, how's it going over there?
- Oh, everything's quite lovely here.
W-We're expecting
a bit of rain today.
But, Mildred, can you--
can you hold on for a moment?
Okay, but hurry, Hal.
I've got to talk to you.
Okay. Now I can talk.
Oh, my God ! Mom's incredible.
I cannot believe I lived
my entire life without knowing her.
Sh-She's beautiful
and fun...
- and smart, and I love
the gowns she designs.
- But--
And I got her talking about how she
and Dad first met. And, if you ask me,
- there's like
a whole possibility, like--
- Hallie, stop !
We've got a major problem.
You're going to have to bring
Mother out here immediately.
Immediately? Are you nuts?
I've only had one day with her.
I'm just getting to know her.
I can't. I won't.
But this is an emergency !
Dad's in love.
Get out of here !
Dad doesn't fall in love.
I mean,
at least not seriously.
Trust me.
He's serious about this one.
He's always holding her hand
and kissing her neck...
and waiting on her
hand and foot.
- He is?
- It's disgusting.
Well, you'll just have to break 'em up.
Sabotage her. Do whatever you have to.
I'm trying, but, I mean,
I'm at a slight disadvantage.
I only met the man
12 hours ago.
Hal, you've got to get
back here to help me.
Annie, I can't.
I want more time with Mom.
What's going on?
Ann, are you still there?
I can barely hear you. Ann.
- I'm here. What do you--
- Operator. Operator.
- I think I lost you, Ann.
- Hello?
Thanks for all the help, Hal.
Hi. I had a phone call
from a friend at camp.
Yeah. I-It's
an old camp tradition.
Talk to your friend from
inside a closet. [ Laughs ]
Kinda stupid, I know, but--
So, breakfast anyone?
Okay. Here we go.
Most important meal of the day.
Eggs sunny-side up,
bacon, side of toast...
and, in case you're
really hungry,
a stack of humongous chocolate chip
pancakes, which smell incredible,
- if I do say so myself.
- Thanks, Chessy.
You're not hungry again?
You hardly touched your chili,
your favourite food in the world.
And now you don't want breakfast?
Are you sick, honey?
I'm fine.
I promise.
Where's Dad?
Oh. He and Miss "I'll Just Have
Half A Grapefruit, Thank You"...
left about
an hour ago.
You overslept,
and he didn't want to wake you.
Of course, I'd probably oversleep, too,
if I were up until midnight...
making mysterious phone calls
from my bathroom.
Oh. Oh. That.
I was calling a friend
from camp, Mildred.
She lives
in New York.
Oh, I see. So, you wanted
to wait and call Mildred...
at a time that was convenient for her
because of the time difference.
Exactly. Because--
Because of the time difference.
Uh-huh. So, you waited until it was
3:00 in the morning her time?
- That makes perfect sense.
- Actually--
It was 7:00 at night
her time.
You see, she lives in New York,
but she was on vacation...
with her family
in Bora Bora.
Very smooth.
Okay, look, smarty pants,
your father wants you...
to meet him at his office as soon
as you're done with breakfast.
He does?
Thanks.
I'm done.
That dog
has gotten so weird.
Bye, Chessy. Thanks again
for breakfast. It was great.
Push, Hal.
Sorry. I... forgot.
Honey, I'm really glad
you're here,
'cause there's something really
important I want to talk to you about.
That's funny, because there's
something really important that
I want to talk to you about.
- Yeah? Well, you go first.
- No, you.
Okay. I want to talk to you
about Meredith.
And I want to talk to you
about my mother.
- What about Meredith?
- Well, what about your mother?
Dad, I'm almost 12.
How long do you expect me...
to buy that story that the stork
dropped me on your doorstep?
Oh, come on, Hal.
We've talked about your mother.
No, we haven't.
Not really.
A girl needs more in life than
a half a crumpled old photograph.
Dad, I'm almost
a teenager.
Face it.
I need a mother.
You know what?
You're right.
You're absolutely right. You do need
a mother. Which brings me to--
- Meredith.
- Hi. Hello, Hal.
Hi.
Hallie, this is
my assistant, Richard.
Richard, this is Nick's daughter, the
one I've been telling you so much about.
- Oh, hello. How are you?
- Hi there.
- Did you tell her?
- Almost.
- [ Sighs ]
- Hey, if you're free later,
why don't we all
have lunch on the terrace?
Well, actually, I promised Hal
we'd hang out together this afternoon.
Oh, no problem.
I've got plenty to do.
I'm working on a new label design,
Nicky, featuring Y-O-U.
You're gonna love it.
See you for dinner, darling.
- Bye, Hal.
- Bye.
The first change I make is to send
that two-faced little brat...
off to boarding-school
in Timbuktu.
Ooh. Ice Woman !
And proud of it, babe.
Come on, Dad.
Okay. Okay. You win.
Pull up.
Give that horse a rest.
Whoa, Sprout.
So, honey, are you excited
about our camping trip?
- What camping trip?
The one we take every summer
before you go back to school.
Oh. Oh. That camping trip.
Yeah. Sure. I can't wait.
So, uh, Hal.
What do you think of Meredith?
As what, Dad?
Your... Your publicist,
your friend, your...
No. Just what do you think
of her as a person?
Oh. She's cute.
She has nice hair, good teeth.
She can spell the word "you."
Honestly, Dad, the woman is
a complete stranger to me.
Why do you
want my opinion, anyway?
Well, I'll tell you why, Hal.
- Because, believe it or not--
- Race you back to the ranch, Dad.
H-Hal.
Hal, I'm trying
to tell you something.
Hey !
Slow down.
I'm in so over my head here.
I can't handle this, I just can't.
I'm only one kid. (gasps)
You got something you want to
share with the class  there, Hal?
Chessy, you gave me a fright.
I gave you a fright?
You scared me.
I didn't know you were, like, in here.
Are you sure there isn't anything
you want to talk to me about?
Like why Sammy
never comes near you anymore.
or why your appetite's
changed.
Or why all of a sudden you're
neat as a pin
and using expressions like,
"You gave me a fright."
Chessy, I changed a lot
over the summer, that's all.
OK.
Boy, if I didn't know
any better, I'd say
it's almost like you were...
Forget it. It's impossible.
Almost as if I were who,
Chessy?
Nobody. Nobody. Forget
I mentioned it.
Almost as if I were... Annie?
You know about Annie?
I am Annie.
(Nick)  Hal.
Hal, why did you take off
on me like that?
I told you I wanted to
talk to you about something.
Chessy, why are you looking at her like that?
Like what? I'm not looking
at her any special way.
I'm looking at her like I've
looked at her for 11 years.
Since the day she came home
from the hospital.
Six pounds, 11 ounces. 21 inches long.
This is how I look at her.
Can I hug her?
Oh, she's so beautiful.
And so big.
I'm going to make you
something special to eat.
What would you like? Anything?
You know what,
it doesn't matter.
I'm just gonna go whip up
everything we've got. OK?
Hal, come here.
- We have to talk.
OK. Shoot.
OK.
Honey...
I want to know what you think
about making Meredith
part of the family.
Part of our family? - Yeah.
- I think
it's an awesome idea.
- Yeah?
- Inspired! Brilliant!
- You do? Really? You do?
Totally. I mean, like it's
a dream come true. I've always
wanted a big sister.
Oh.
Um... Honey, I think you're
kind of missing the point.
No, I'm not. You're going
to adopt Meredith.
- That is so sweet, Dad.
- No, I am not going to adopt her.
I'm... going to marry her.
Marry her? That's insane.
How can you marry
a woman young enough
to be my big sister?
Mais tu plaisantes, j'espère.
Meredith, ce n'est pas
une fille pour toi.
Mais c'est pas possible,
je rêve. Qu'est-ce qui...
Calm down. Hal!
Are you speaking French?
I learned it at camp.
OK. I'm sorry.
Let's discuss this calmly.
Calmly and rationally.
Yeah, and in English,
if you don't mind. Right?
OK.
Sweetheart,
what has gotten into you?
Nothing. Nothing. Just...
Dad, you can't get married.
It'll totally ruin
completely everything.
Hal. Hal.
Hallie.
Don't look at me.
I don't know a thing.
(music blasts from car stereo)
She thought I was going to adopt her?
Hi, doll. - Hi.
Oh. You look stressed, baby.
How about a martini? - How about a double?
Coming right up.
Chessy!
Don't you love it?
It's just what we need,
it's such a big house. Chessy!
You rang?
Two martinis, please.
And make Mr. Parker's
a double.
Chess, please.
I'm getting a migraine.
- I told Hallie.
- You did? And?
She went ballistic.
She started yelling in French.
I didn't even know
she spoke French.
- I don't know what's gotten into her.
- Oh, Nicky.
This reaction
is totally classic.
It's "Daddy's
Getting Remarried 101."
I'd be worried
if she didn't act this way.
Look.
Why don't I go talk to her?
You know, woman-to-woman.
I think she's a little
sensitive about you right now.
That's why I need to do it.
We've got to
break the ice sometime.
Wear your shirt like this.
I like it when
I can see a little chest hair.
Knock, knock. Can I join you?
Sure.
Guess the news of the
engagement came
as a bit of a shock, huh?
Basically.
You know, I remember
what it was like to be 11.
I had my first beau at 11.
It's a wonderful age.
You're just starting to feel
like a woman and,
believe it or not,
soon you'll understand
what it's like to be in love.
Me? I don't think so.
I don't even have
my 12-year-old molars yet.
Well, take it from someone
who got their molars
very early in life,
being in love is a fantastic
mystery that takes a man
and a woman...
I don't mean to be jerky when
you're trying to be all mushy
and everything,
but I know what mystery
my dad sees in you.
You do?
You're young and beautiful and
sexy and, hey, the guy's
only human.
But if you ask me,
marriage is supposed to
be based on something more
than just sex, right?
Boy, your father
underestimates you.
But you won't.
Will you, Meredith?
Being young and beautiful's
not a crime, you know.
And for your 411,
I adore your father.
He's exactly the kind of man
I always planned on marrying.
This is the real deal, honey.
And nothing you do is going
to come between us.
Hate to break it to you, angel
but you are no longer the only
girl in Nick Parker's life.
- Get over it.
- If this is the real deal,
then my dad's money has
nothing to do with you wanting
to marry him, right?
OK, puss. You listen
and you listen good.
I am marrying your father in two weeks
whether you like it or not.
So I suggest you do not tangle
with me anymore.
You are in way over your head.
Is that clear?
Crystal.
(Grandfather) Martin!
A refill, please.
- Lovely choice of wine, by the way, Martin.
- Thank you, sir.
- May I have a sip?
- I don't think
you're going to like it.
Well, if you ask me, the bouquet's a little
too robust for a Merlot,
but then again I'm partial to
the softer California grape.
Has she learned about wine
at the summer camp?
She must have.
Darling! Are you all right? - I had one sip too many,
I guess.
You know, Mother,
I feel like I could use
a bit of fresh air.
Would it be OK if I stepped
outside for a moment?
Are you OK?
Would you like me
to go with you?
No, no, no. I'll be fine. Just
got a touch woozy, that's all.
Woozy, huh?
I'd like to place a collect call to America,
please.
(rings)
- Hello?
- What's up?
Hal, I'm desperate.
Dad's getting married.
What do you mean,
getting married?
I mean black tie, white gown,
the whole enchilada.
- What?
- The wedding's in two weeks.
If there's any hope of getting
Mum and Dad back together
we've got to do it fast.
And I mean really fast.
OK. So Mom and I are going out
to the theater tonight.
I'll drop the bomb on her
first thing in the morning.
OK. Thanks.
- And, Hallie, hurry!
- OK. I will.
Oh, excuse me, sir.
- Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh. Yes.
Now, what say you and I take
a little stroll in the park,
eh, young lady?
OK.
Now...
Come on,
what's this all about?
Well, it's a long story.
Well, it's a very big park
and we've got plenty of time,
you know.
Well, first of all...
(Elizabeth) Féminine?
Vraiment... Je ne sais
pas comment expliquer
mais vous aurez
le dessin demain, en tout cas.
En satin? Non, non, ce sera
quelque chose plus moderne
avec de la dentelle, du tulle
blanc très, très jeune,
très léger.
Just do it, sweet pea.
Non, c'est trop, non. Oui,
mademoiselle, vous aurez
le dessin demain matin.
Oui, tout à fait. Ne vous
inquiétez pas. Allez,
au revoir.
Darling, come in. I just
have to finish this sketch
and fedex it off to Paris.
Then how about you
and I go out to lunch
and spend the rest of the day
getting lost in Harrods. Hm?
I can't, Mum, I'm sorry.
I have to go
out of town today.
Oh, you have to go
out of town?
(laughing)  And where,
may I ask, are you going?
Annie. Annie.
(American accent)  That's where
I have to go.
I have to go see Annie.
I see.
And where might Annie be?
In Napa.
With her father Nick Parker.
You're not Annie.
That would be correct.
You're Hallie?
I am.
Annie and I met up at camp and
we decided to switch places.
I'm sorry, but I'd never seen you, and I dreamt of meeting
you my whole life.
Annie felt the exact same way about Dad, so we sorta
just switched lives.
I hope you're not mad, because I love you so much
and I just hope that one day
you can love me as me,
and not as Annie.
Oh, darling.
I've loved you
your whole life.
(sobbing)
I've never been so happy
in my entire life.
(wails)
So, I...
I guess you have
to switch us back now, huh?
Well, technically, you belong
to your dad and Annie
belongs to me.
His and hers kids. No offense, Mom, but this arrangement
really sucks.
I agree. It totally sucks.
Then I say we fly to Napa,
see Annie and Dad, and work
this whole thing out.
And I say you're right.
Not to worry, darling.
I'll take care of everything.
You're not to worry, OK?
I'm sorry.
I can't handle this.
I mean, I haven't seen
or heard from Nick Parker
in over 11 years,
and suddenly I'm flying
halfway across the world to...
I'm not mature
enough for this.
If the man didn't make me so nuts,
I'd still be married to him.
I mean, we came up with this
arrangement so that
we'd never have to see each other again. I mean, look at me, Martin.
Have you ever seen me like this?
- Well...
- Don't answer that.
I mean, what if he doesn't
recognize me?
No, don't answer that, either.
So, Hallie said
he was a... a hunk.
He was rather dishy.
He had a smile that made me
go weak at the knees,
if you can imagine that.
- OK. I'm all set, Mom.
- Great. Me too. Almost.
Mom, your suitcase is,
like, totally empty.
Oh. Right. Sorry. Um...
Did you speak to your father,
dear?
Um... Yeah, yeah.
I just hung up with him,
actually.
He said he's really anxious
to see you.
Anxious nervous,
like he's totally,
completely dreading it?
Or anxious excited,
like he's looking forward
to it?
- Anxious excited. Definitely.
- Oh.
He said he'll meet us tomorrow
at noon at the Stafford Hotel
in San Francisco.
My, my, my. That's incredibly
soon, isn't it? Well. Um...
Why don't you run downstairs
and gather up our tickets
from your grandfather
while I finish up here?
OK.
- (whispers)  Liar, liar,
pants on fire.
Sh! Oh, Martin, I have a really
ridiculous, somewhat childish
request to make.
Martin, you know that you're
more than a butler to me.
You're more like a lovable
brother who just happens
to wait on us and...
Anyway, I was wondering if...
I'd accompany you on the trip?
Make it a bit easier for you?
Would you, Martin?
Thank you so much.
I'd be so grateful. And you
don't even have to come as our
butler, just as a friend.
Madam, I'd be honored.
And may I say, as a friend,
if I was seeing my ex,
after 11 years,
and I had your legs...
I'd wear this little baby.
You'll kill in it.
Bye, Daddy, darling. - Bye, darling.
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
- Bye, Pop.
- Bye, Hal.
So you're coming to Napa
for Thanksgiving, right?
I wouldn't miss
it for the world.
Bye.
Oh, and say hello
to your father for me.
I will.
Airport, please.
( "In the Mood"
by Joe Garland)
OK. They'll be here any minute.
Now, be nice, Daddy.
He's everything you ever
wanted for your little girl,
plus millions more.
Then you know I'll be nice.
Oh, OK. There he is.
(Sammy barks)
With the whole motley crew.
Hi, darling.
Hallie. Chessy. And Sammy.
What in the world are you doing here?
Honey, a dog at the Stafford?
- Hal begged me to bring him.
- Oh, you're such a softy.
(Sammy growls)
- Oh!
Good doggy. So, Meredith,
these the folks?
Yes. Mom, Dad,
you finally meet.
This is my fiancé and the love
of my life, Nicholas Parker.
Hello, Nicholas.
I'm so pleased to meet you.
- I'm Vicki.
- Hi.
And this is Nick's adorable
daughter Hallie.
This entire prenuptial
get-together was her idea,
I'll have you know.
How are you, young lady?
We've heard nothing but
wonderful things about you.
Hello, pet.
You may call me Aunt Vicki.
Other end, madam. - Whoops.
That was a great flight, wasn't it? I mean,
it was so quick.
I've never seen you quite
so thirsty before, madam.
Well, would you believe,
Martin, darling, I've never
tasted vodka before this trip?
Could have fooled me, ma'am.
(Elizabeth)  Come on.
Let's rock and roll.
I am in such major
trouble here.
If the hotel can do it,
I think that room is perfect
for the wedding.
Not too big, not too cramped.
And not that I don't like
the idea of having the wedding
at the house,
it's just that this
could be amazing.
So I've already checked us in.
Why don't we go upstairs,
freshen up,
and then rendezvous for lunch?
- Great.
- Meet you in the bar in ten.
OK?
Perf.
Sweetheart, now that we're
here, why don't we go check
out the honeymoon suite?
I bet it is to die for.
( "In the Mood")
Oh, whoops.
I forgot my bag.
Hang on.
Sammy.
Sammy!
Excuse me.
Did you find a beige...
Thank you.
- Ooh.
- Mum!
Darling, you didn't have
to wait for me. I could have
found the room by myself.
Besides, I need to get
a little fresh air.
Go on, sweetie.
I'll meet you upthairs.
I like that jacket,
by the way.
Were you wearing that
the whole time we were
on the plane?
- Mum, watch out!
- (bellboy) Sorry, sorry.
She's drunk. She's never
had more than one glass
of wine in her entire life,
and she chooses today
to show up totally zonked.
Yeah, well. Just do what the
woman says and meet
her "upthairs."
Maybe that's why they make "do not disturb" signs.
Alone at last.
Hallie Parker.
Oh, don't do this to me.
I'm already seeing double.
- It's me, Mum. Annie.
- Oh, darling.
You look wonderful.
Oh, my girls.
I can't believe you're
together. But how could you
do this to me?
(clears throat)
Excuse me.
I hate to interrupt, but...
might I suggest that
we continue this little
powwow inside?
- Hi. You probably
don't remember me.
- Chessy.
I knew I always liked her.
One of you... I'm not sure
which one at the moment,
but one of you told me
your father knew I was
arriving here today.
And I'm here to tell you
that the man I just saw
in the elevator
had absolutely no idea
he and I were
on the same planet,
- let alone in the same hotel.
- You saw Dad already?
Yes, I did.
The man went completely ashen,
like I was the bloody
Ghost of Christmas Past.
Can one of you get something
cold for my head?
I mean, don't you think I've
pondered what it was going
to be like
to see your father
after all these years?
Well, let me tell you, me
waving like a mindless idiot
while Nick Parker's wrapped
around another woman's arms
is not exactly the scenario
I had in mind. No, sirree.
(whistling)
- (gasps)
Martin! What are you doing?
Going for a dip, madam.
Do you mind?
No, no. No, that's perfectly
perfect.
Have fun.
Someone ought to.
Hello.
Hello. Hello to you.
(Elizabeth)  Chessy,
this is our butler, Martin.
How do you do?
I'm her butler.
Enchanté, mademoiselle.
Gee. The pleasure's all mine,
monsieur.
Girls, you were going to tell me why you lied
and brought me here
without telling your father.
Were they?
OK, that's good. Uh...
Well, I'm just gonna go back
to my room and check out the
old mini-bar situation.
- Allow me to assist you.
- (Elizabeth)  Wait.
Does everyone here
know something I don't know?
Mum, Daddy's getting married.
To Cruella De Vil. She's awful, Mum. We can't let
him go through with it.
She's all wrong for him, Mom,
and the only way he won't
marry her is if...
You tell her.
She knows you better.
Is if he sees you again.
Wait a minute. You're
not trying to set me up
with your father?
(Hallie)  Actually, we are.
You're perfect for each other.
Hold it!
You two knew about this?
- What? Oh! No.
- No.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- Madam, no, absolutely. I had no idea.
Yes. Yes, I did know something.
Yes. Technically, yes.
I had an inkling.
- Hallie told me the story.
- It was their idea.
It was so sweet.
I just fell for the story.
I'm an old romantic.
Yeah, so am I.
OK. OK.
Let me say this
loud and clear.
Nick Parker and
I have absolutely nothing
in common...
anymore.
Plus, in case you haven't
noticed, he seems
extremely content
with his leggy, tight-skirted,
bare-backed fiancée.
And I want the two of you
to explain to your father
that I am here for one
purpose, and one purpose only.
And that is
to switch the two of you back.
Now, let's do what we have
to do and be done with it.
Understood?
- Hey, Dad. What's up?
- Hi. Just running down
to the lobby.
- Hey, Hal.
- Huh?
Do me a favor, will ya,
while I'm gone?
Will you just look after
Meredith for me?
Huh? Thanks.
- Hallie. Hallie.
- Yeah?
How do I look?
Like, presentable
and everything?
- Not too old?
- You look fab, Dad.
Young and fab.
Dad.
I thought you were gonna
keep Meredith company.
I was? I mean, I am, yeah.
I was just looking for her,
actually.
It's great to see you, Dad.
It's great to see you too,
squirt.
- Nice outfit.
- Oh, thanks.
Well, go on.
Get up there. Come on.
Let's get together, yeah,
yeah, yeah
Why don't you and I combine?
Let's get together...
- Have you seen your father?
- You talking to me?
What, are you Robert De Niro?
Yes, I am talking to you.
Oh, Meredith.
- Uh... Yeah. I just saw him.
- Well, hello. Where was he?
Uh... He went that way.
I think.
What are you staring at? - Oh, nothing. Nothing.
You're just really very pretty.
That's all.
Oh...
Don't tell me you're gonna
break your rotten streak and
suddenly be nice to me.
If you see your father,
tell him he's late
and I'm waiting.
Whatever you say, Cruella.
( piano jazz)
Here you go. This'll cure anything you've got.
- Just don't ask what's in it.
- OK.
Here's to...
Here's to you.
May your life be far less
complicated than mine.
Thank you.
Ugh.
- Martini, dry, please.
- (burps)
I beg your pardon.
I think I just drank tar.
There's your martini,
and your bill, Miss James.
Thank you.
You're Elizabeth James?
- Guilty.
- Oh!
I just saw a wedding dress you
designed in Vogue and fell
completely in love with it.
I faxed your office just
yesterday, and they said that
you were out of town
and didn't know
if you could make another.
I can't believe it. It's fate.
- I'm Meredith Blake.
- How do you do?
( Caribbean-style music)
Sorry.
Excuse me. - Excuse me.
Where have you been?
We've been looking
all over for you.
Nicholas, I think this hotel
is perfect for the wedding.
The more I see of it,
the more I like it.
Me too.
Absolutely.
Now, tell me, dear. How many
are we expecting from your
side of the family?
Just a guesstimate.
Uh... Can I get back to you
on that? I... I'm not sure
at the moment.
Excuse me.
Pardon me. Sorry.
Oh! Boss, you OK? - Yeah, I'm fine.
- (man)  Uh... Sir.
- Dad, watch out!
- Oh! Careful!
- Argh!
Hello, Liz. - Hello, Nick.
Well, gosh. There you are.
What do you know?
Uh... Is there something going
on here that I should know
about?
Because I'm stunned
to see you.
But, uh... you don't seem
as stunned to see me.
I mean, I haven't seen or
heard from you
in, what, ten, eleven years.
- All of a sudden, on the very day that...
- Dad.
I can explain why she's here.
Hallie, you know who this is?
Actually, yes.
And, actually, I'm not Hallie.
Actually, I am.
Both of them?
Annie?
Hallie?
I guess you and Mum kind
of think alike, 'cause you
both sent us to the same camp.
We met there,
and the whole thing
just sort of spilled out.
They switched places on us,
Nick.
You mean I've had Annie
with me all this time?
Well, I wanted to know what
you were like, and Hallie
wanted to know Mum, and...
Are you angry? - Oh, honey. Of course not.
I just can't believe it's you.
Last time I saw you, you had diaper rash.
Oh, sorry - you're all wet.
- It's all right.
- Look at you.
Well, I'm quite grown-up now,
and quite without a father.
And I'm headed into my crazy,
mixed-up teenage years,
and I'll be the only girl
I know without a mother
to fight with.
Hallie, you've been in London
all this time?
Come here, squirt.
Mom's amazing,
Dad. I don't know how you ever
let her go.
Girls, why don't you let your
father and I talk alone for
a couple of minutes, OK?
- Sure, fine.
- Take your time.
I don't believe this.
Seeing them together,
seeing you.
- Ow.
- Ooh.
Let me help you with that.
Oh, excuse me.
Do you have a first-aid kit?
Yeah, of course.
Why don't you lie down?
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
So... how are you, Lizzie?
Or does everyone
call you Elizabeth now?
Oh, no, no. Lizzie's...
Lizzie's fine.
- My dad still calls me
Lizzie.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I've been...
uh, been terrific.
- Oh.
You know,
you haven't changed a bit.
Finally. There you are.
Oh! Uh... Oh, good.
You've met.
Honey, Elizabeth
designs wedding gowns,
and she's going to make my...
Wait, um...
I don't understand.
How did you two meet?
And, Nicky,
why are you all wet?
You're making
my fiancée's wedding gown.
- Well, I didn't know
she was your fiancée.
- Well...
How did we meet?
How did you two meet?
- Am I missing something here?
- Know what? This is one small world.
How small?
- Hi, Mer.
- Hello.
- How you doing?
- (shrieks)
Honey, did I ever mention
to you that Hallie was a twin?
No, I'm afraid you forgot
that little detail.
Don't feel bad, Mer,
he never mentioned it to me,
either.
By the way,
I'm the real Hallie.
This is Annie.
She was pretending to be me,
while I was pretending
to be her.
And this is our mother,
Elizabeth James.
This is your mother?
(both)  Yes.
You were married to him?
- Yeah.
- Guilty again.
- Oh, well.
This is a small world.
- And getting smaller.
And what a coincidence that
we're all here on the exact
same weekend.
My, my, my. How sweet.
Hal, I've had enough surprises for one day.
Will you please just tell me
where we're going?
You're gonna love it, Dad.
Trust me.
Hello.
Hey.
So...
Do you have any idea
where they're taking us?
- Not a clue.
- Right.
Where are we?
This is where we're eating?
No, actually,
that's where we're eating.
She's ours for the night.
Wow!
So how exactly are we paying for this?
Well, we pooled our allowances.
- Yeah, right, Annie.
- OK. Grandfather chipped in a bit.
- Annie.
- OK. He chipped in a lot.
(Hallie) Come on.
You guys are gonna love it.
(Nick)  Pretty snazzy.
Elizabeth and Nick, your dinner awaits you.
Girls.
The table's only set for two.
- Oh. That's the other part of the surprise.
- We're not joining you.
-You're not?
- No, but I am.
Good evening. I'm Chessy, and I'll be your server this evening.
- No wisecracks, please.
- And I am Martin, your sommelier.
May I offer you both a taste
of the bubbly in the hope that
you'll get a bit schnockered
and not fire this lovely lady
and myself
for following
the orders of these
audacious 11-year-olds?
Annie, mood music, please.
( "I Love You
for Sentimental Reasons"
by Linda Ronstadt)
Just relax.
Sail through time.
(Hallie)  Back to yesteryear.
- You do get all this, don't you?
- Yes, I'm beginning to.
They're recreating the night we met.
The boat, the music...
The help.
It's so sweet.
Martin,
I think I'll take that drink.
Thank you, Martin.
Oh. Yeah.
To tell you the truth, I haven't been on a boat
since the QE2.
Neither have I.
Well, then, here's to, uh...
Our daughters.
Now I know how a goldfish feels.
(groans)
You know, sometime
if we're ever really alone,
maybe we could talk about
what happened between us.
It all feels a bit hazy to me now.
It ended so fast.
It started so fast.
Well, that part
I remember perfectly.
Looks like things are heating up quite nicely.
I'd say it's safe to serve
the vichyssoise.
You ladle, I'll serve.
I'm sorry.
Yes, I'll...
uh, ladle.
Right.
And then I'll--
- Serve?
- Right.
Right.
So... you've done
fantastically well. Um...
your dream of owning your own
vineyard actually came true.
What about you?
You were always drawing...
on napkins
and corners of newspapers.
- Now you're this major designer.
- Yeah, it's great.
We both actually got
where we wanted to go.
Yeah, we did.
Anyway, what are we going
to do about the girls?
Well, now that they met,
we can't very well keep them apart.
Well, I could keep them for half of
the year, and then you could keep them.
- Well--
- Guys. They can't go to
two different schools every year.
- That's nuts.
- I agree.
Well, then, I could keep them both for
a whole year, and you could keep them...
Liz.
That's why we came up with--
Oh, G-- Sorry. Ignore me.
Enjoy your soup.
That's why we came up
with the solution that we have.
Really?
I thought it was because...
we decided never to see
each other again.
Not we, Liz.
Well, you know, that part's become
a bit hazy to me, too, over the years.
- You don't remember the day you packed?
- No, that day I remember perfectly.
Did I hurt you when
I threw that, um...
- What was it? Uh, uh--
- It was... a hair dryer.
Oh, right.
Sorry.
You know, I may never
be alone with you again.
So, about that day that you packed--
Why'd you do it?
Oh, Nick.
We were so young...
and we both had tempers.
We said stupid things
and so I packed.
Got on
my very first 747,
and... you didn't
come after me.
I didn't know that
you wanted me to.
Well, it doesn't
really matter any more.
So, let's just
put a good face on...
for the girls and get the show
on the road, huh?
Yeah, sure.
Let's...
get the show
on the road.
Your passport, Ms James.
Have a safe trip home.
Thank you.
- All set then. Where's Annie?
- I just rang up. She's on her way down.
Right.
So, I'll send Hallie
back to you over Christmas.
And Annie will spend Easter with you.
Honey, what are you doing in those
clothes? We've got a plane to catch.
Here's the deal, Mom.
We thought it over, and
we decided we're being totally gypped.
Dad promised we'd go on our camping
trip. And we want to go... together.
What camping trip?
The one we go on every summer
before school starts.
Annie, this is ridiculous.
Go upstairs and put your clothes on.
- Are you sure I'm Annie?
- Well, of course, I'm sure.
But, it's kind of hard
to be 100% positive, isn't it?
Girls, this is totally unfunny.
You're gonna make your mother
miss her aeroplane.
- Annie !
- Yes !
This one's Hallie.
I'm positive.
You know, I hope
you're right, Dad.
Because you wouldn't want to send the
wrong kid all the way back to England.
Would you?
Here's our proposition.
We go back to Dad's house,
pack our stuff,
and the four of us leave
on the camping trip.
- The four of us?
- And when you bring us back,
- we'll tell you who's Annie
and who's Hallie.
- Or you do as we say,
and I take one of you back with me
to London whether you like it or not.
And what am I supposed to do
for three days? Sit home and knit?
Honey, we have kind of
a sticky situation.
- Sticky situation? What do you mean,
"sticky situation"? What exactly--
Excuse me.
What is she doing here?
You see, that's part of the deal.
The four of us--
We... go together.
- What are you suddenly,
the Brady Bunch? This is ridic.... Hello.
Everything all right?
Well, no. Actually it isn't.
I didn't realize that
you were going on this little outing.
- And to tell you the truth, I'm not
so sure that I'm okay with it.
- I agree.
I think the ex-wife in
the next sleeping bag is a little weird.
- Thank you.
- I absolutely insist that you come with us. Really.
Liz--
No, honestly, Nick.
I've messed up your entire weekend.
It's the least I can do.
Really, please.
Dad, what's Meredith
doing here?
- Your mother invited her.
- What?
Be nice.
- Okay. All set? Have fun, everyone.
- What?
Liz, what are
you doing?
Well, I really think that
you and Meredith need some time
alone before the big day.
Mom, come on !
That's not the plan.
Ah, honestly, you'll have
much more fun without me.
Wait, wait. If you're not going,
I certainly don't have to go.
I mean, trust me,
I'm not a big nature girl.
But this is your chance
to really get to know the girls.
I mean after all,
starting next week, they're--
they're half yours.
Have fun all of you !
Bye-bye !
Oh, I would pay big money
to see that woman climb a mountain.
Whoa !
- Come on, you guys.
- Whoa ! Oh !
Oh, I'm gonna
kill my trainer.
He says I'm in such great shape. I can't
believe people actually do this for fun.
Hold on.
We're stopping.
Again? Dad, at this rate,
it'll take us...
three days just
to get to the lake.
Meredith isn't used to the altitude.
Just chill, okay?
Ooh.
Ah, I'm in serious pain.
Somebody hand me my Evian.
I can't move.
Sure.
Brilliant.
Here you go, Mer.
Honey, you okay?
What happened?
This little guy was
on her Evian bottle.
Oh, he won't hurt you, Meredith.
Oh, right, right, right. Right. I know.
You, uh, go ahead.
I'll be fine.
Get that thing away from me.
I hate things that crawl.
Aagh ! How can you touch that?
Just put it down.
Okay. Okay.
I'll put it down.
- Girls?
- What?
I'm going to take the lead. The two
of you help Meredith. All right?
Sure, you'll help me.
Right over a cliff,
you'll help me.
- Not a bad idea.
- Yeah. See any cliffs?
- Aah, my backpack.
- Need a hand, Mer?
Not from you, thank you.
Don't think I can't see
right past those angelic faces.
One more trick from you two,
and I promise...
I will make your lives miserable
from the day I say "I do."
Got it?
Got it, Cruella.
What did you call me?
Nothing, nothing.
Not a thing, Cruella.
Oh, by the way, Mer, I think there's
something on your head.
Are you all right?
- Aah !
- What... happened?
Ask... them.
What did we do, Dad?
We were right behind you.
Here we go, girls.
This will hold us for a while.
Sure you don't want some trout, Mom?
Is that okay, by the way,
if we start calling you mom?
I think your mother would prefer if you called me Meredith.
And no thank you.
I do not eat... trout... for the thousandth time.
I will wait until breakfast.
- What are we having?
- Trout.
Come on. It's part of the experience.
Mmm. And what's the other part?
Being eaten to death by mosquitoes?
God, you'd think
they actually like this stuff.
Well, what's that you're using?
Let me see that.
Well, you're gonna attract every mosquito in the state with this stuff,
It's sugar and water.
Where'd you get it?
That's it.
I am taking one large sleeping pill...
and going to bed.
Meredith,
what are you doing?
I don't want the mountain lions to--
There are no mountain lions
up here, are there?
No.
Good night.
Girls, I'm telling you.
Lay off.
This isn't her thing, okay?
I'm not marrying her because she's Annie Oakley.
Who's Annie Oakley?
Just cool it.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
I hope that
one large sleeping pill worked.
You take that side.
- All right.
- Gosh, she's heavy.
- She's also like... snoring.
Nicky?
Sweet dreams, Mommie Dearest.
Mmm.
That feels nice.
Nicky !
Oh, man.
Ooh !
Ugh !
Ugh ! Ugh !
- What's goin' on?
- Here's what's going on, buddy !
The day we get married is the day
I ship those brats off to Switzerland.
Get the picture?
It's me or them. Take your pick.
- Them.
- Excuse me?
- T-H-E-M, them.
Get the picture?
Hello.
You're back so soon.
- Did you have fun?
- Well, I wouldn't go right to fun.
- You wouldn't?
- We've been punished to the end of the century.
- Starting now. Go !
- Where's Meredith?
We played a couple of harmless tricks on her and she kind of freaked out a little.
A little?
Hmm.
She threw this at my head.
At least it's smaller than a hair dryer.
Oh, Nick, it's all my fault.
If I hadn't suggested she go--
Or tricked!
Tricked would be more like it.
Like mother,
like daughters.
I-I really am sorry.
- We are too, Dad. Really.
- Yeah.
Up to your room...
now.
I gotta remember
to thank them one day.
So, where's Chessy?
I'm starving.
Well, she and Martin went off on a picnic around noon... yesterday.
Really ! Who would
have thought-- my nanny, your butler !
Well, what do you say,
I whip us up something to eat?
- You can cook now?
- Oh, yeah. I can, uh, make pasta and pasta and, uh--
- Mmm, pasta sounds good.
- Well, pasta it is.
Okay, I'll take two.
- Hey, Dad!
- Wow! You look so nice!
- Where are you going?
- Good night, ladies.
- Oh, wow !
- This is where I keep my private stash.
Did you know
I also collect wine?
- Really?
- I'm a man of limited interest.
Come here.
This...
is a 1921 Burgundy.
- They say the rain that year made this
the best Burgundy ever harvested.
- Oh.
Now, you will appreciate this.
Come here.
Look.
"VJ day, 1945."
- That's incredible.
- I love that.
Now, this is the same wine that
was served at my parents' wedding.
A Bordeaux-- '52.
I think my sister
was conceived on this baby.
What's this one?
"Where dreams have no end--
- 1983."
- That one actually
took me years to track down.
Why?
Where's it from?
It's the wine that we drank
at our wedding.
I know. I have
every bottle ever made.
You do?
I do.
- Can we open one?
- You're the only one I'd drink it with.
- You okay?
- Oh, yeah. I just got
a little dust in my eye.
Hmm?
I can offer you a clean sleeve.
No, no.
I'm fine really. All better.
You don't always have
to be so brave, you know.
Oh, but I do actually.
That will be Chessy.
She has a key.
Hello. Anybody home?
We'll be right up.
- Take care of yourself.
- Yeah, I will. You too.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Hello.
We're home.
- Grandfather?
- I'll check the study.
Hey, stranger.
Hey, Mom, did you know the Concorde
gets you here in half the time?
Yes, I-I've heard that.
Huh !
What are you doing here?
It took us around 30 seconds
after you guys left...
for us to realize we didn't
want to lose you two again.
We?
We.
I made the mistake of not coming
after you once, Lizzy.
I'm not going to do that again
no matter how brave you are.
And I suppose you just expect
me to go weak at the knees...
and fall into your arms and cry hysterically...
and say we'll just figure this whole thing out-- a bicontinental relationship...
with our daughters being raised here an-and there and...
and you and I just... picking up where we left off, and--
and growing old together and--
and--
Come on, Nick.
What do you expect?
- To live happily ever after?
- Yes...
to all the above.
Except you don't have to cry hysterically.
Oh, yes, I do.
We actually did it.
This will be the one
I've waited for
This will be
The first time anyone
has loved me
I'm so glad you found me
in time
And I'm so glad that
you rectified my mind
This will be
An everlasting love for me,
yeah
Whoa
Loving you
is some kind of wonderful
Because you've shown me
just how much you care
You've given me
the thrill of a lifetime
And made me believe
you've got more thrills
to spare
Oh, this will be
An everlasting love
Oh, yes, it will, now
You've brought
a lot of sunshine into my life
You've filled me
with happiness I never knew
You gave me more joy
than I ever dreamed of
And no one, no one
can take the place of you
This will be
You and me
Yes, sirree
Eternally
Hugging and squeezing
and kissing and pleasing
Together, forever,
through rain or whatever
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
you and me
So long as I'm living,
true love I'll be giving
To you I'll be serving
'cause you're so deserving
Hey, you're so deserving
From now on