The defeat and breakup
of the Soviet empire,
culminating in the crumbling
of the Berlin Wall,
is one of the great events
of world history.
There were many heroes
in this battle,
but to Charlie Wilson
must go this
special recognition.
Just 13 years ago,
the Soviet Army appeared
to be invincible.
But Charlie, undeterred,
engineered
a lethal body blow
that weakened
the Communist empire.
Without Charlie,
history would be hugely
and sadly different.
And so,
for the first time,
a civilian is being given
our highest recognition,
that of Honored Colleague.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the Clandestine Services,
Congressman Charles Wilson.
It'd be like Dallas.
That's right.
You know what I'm saying?
Like Dallas but set
in Washington.
Yeah.
And you should
say it just like that.
When I pitch it.
You should say it just...
"Oh, this is fucking great."
You should say it
just like that.
Dallas set
in Washington D.C.
You know,
with the intrigue
and the power plays
and the overt
natural sex.
The glamour,
the power.
Do you know
what I'm saying?
It's fucking Dallas.
Or,
or Falcon Crest.
Yes.
That's set in Washington.
Say it to Charlie
like that.
The resistance fighters
disguised us as one
of them.
Charlie.
It's like Dallas
but in Washington.
With Crystal
in the starring role.
Yeah.
You tell me when to watch.
I'll make sure I'm home.
You don't think
I can make it happen?
I don't know anything
about how any
of that works.
I do.
You said that
you would listen to him.
That's why we're here.
Do they routinely
give starring roles
on network programs
to people who haven't
acted professionally
before?
She was just on
the fucking cover
of Playboy, Charlie.
Well, I guess
that's just the
same thing.
Would you take
this seriously, please?
I am taking it seriously,
hon, but can you all
tell me something?
What is...
What is Dan Rather
wearing right now?
What?
Dan Rather.
What is he wearing?
You're watching TV?
Why hasn't he shaved?
Well, who gives a damn?
Excuse me! Hey! Excuse me,
could you turn that up?
Could you just turn up
the volume on the TV?
Oh, I'm completely high.
Yeah. Okay.
Still, could you just
grab the remote there
and find
the volume button?
Charlie, are we
gonna do business?
Dan Rather is wearing
a turban, Paul. Don't
you want to know why?
He's doing a thing
from India.
No, that's Afghanistan.
Got it.
Appreciate it.
We got it...
We captured it
from the Afghan,
the Afghan army.
Thank you.
Does he have
ammunition for this?
He has three.
But does he have ammunition?
A lot of ammunition?
Well, he's talking
about the mujahideen.
No, we don't,
we didn't capture any.
Priests?
No, mujahideen means,
like, holy warriors.
Priests!
How the hell am I
supposed to know?
Paul.
And he was... He is saying
that, you know, America
seems to be asleep.
It doesn't seem to realize
that if Afghanistan goes
and the Russians
go over to the Gulf,
that in a very short time,
it's going to be the turn
of the United States as well.
I'm sure he knows
that in Vietnam...
Excuse me.
We were just wondering
what you do for a living.
I'm not a police officer,
if that's what you're asking.
No. We just... We don't
meet a lot of guys here
who both, you know,
know about the world
and like to party.
No.
I'm a member
of the U.S. House
of Representatives.
I'm sorry?
I'm a Congressman.
Are you kidding?
No. No,
I'm absolutely serious.
I'm Charlie Wilson.
I represent the Texas
Second Congressional.
Texas. And this
is Crystal Lee.
This is Paul Brown.
What are your names?
Stacey.
Kelly.
Kelly. Well, it's nice
to meet you both.
If you are a Congressman
should you be in here
with strippers and blow?
Hey, I'm not a stripper.
I am a stripper.
I'm a stripper.
Yes, see, they were
talking about themselves.
You know, you do
have a point there.
I really should get going.
A little pruney.
Look, Charlie,
I need $29,000
to make it happen.
And you know I can make
it happen, and you know
you want in on this.
Hey, who wants
to take a ride with
me to the airport?
Oh, me!
Paul?
Okay.
A holy war
against the Soviets.
A war they say that,
if they get weapons,
from us or anyone else
in the free world,
they will win.
Yeah, I'm with
Congressman Charles Wilson
and Crystal Lee.
I wish
he wouldn't do that.
From Texas.
Has there ever been
a show about
Washington?
I don't think there has.
Me, neither.
Thank you. We got the suite
another night. Comped.
Should I go back?
No.
You can't stay
another night?
No. No.
Stay another night.
I can't.
I have a vote.
What, an important one?
Yes.
What is it?
Well, it's a
non-binding resolution
expressing the sense
of the Congress
that the Department
of Defense should continue
to exercise its authority
to support
the Boy Scouts
of America.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Come on, Charlie,
call, raise or fold.
I want to get an answer
on this thing
that Crystal
and I want to do.
First off,
I'd appreciate it
if you didn't throw my name
around quite so much,
'cause, from time to time,
I use it myself, and I need
it in good condition.
Second, I'm
from Lufkin, Texas.
I'm the son of an accountant
for a timber company.
I take home about
700 bucks a week,
and I pay alimony,
so the idea that I got
$29,000 in the bank
is pretty hysterical.
That said,
I love your idea.
Crys, I'll call you
this week.
Okay.
All right.
Stacey, Kelly,
nice to meet you both.
Are you Nevada residents?
Yeah.
Well, don't forget to vote.
Bye. We love you!
We love you!
Oh, it helps not to know me.
Oh! That is for you.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Bye!
Bye, Charlie.
I love Las Vegas!
All right, what else?
That Dairy Queen guy,
Larry Liddle,
is sitting
in your office.
Hey.
Yeah, I told him
he could come in.
He wants to talk
to you about a creche.
What, a nativity scene
with baby Jesus?
Yeah, it's on public property,
and the city's making
him move it.
Shit. I thought
he was just coming in
to get his picture took,
you know?
Congressman.
Yeah?
You're exactly
who I need to speak to.
You have a moment?
Sure.
Tip asked me
to talk to you.
Okay.
He wanted me to talk to you
about John Murtha.
Go ahead.
The prosecutor's
gonna go after him.
Well, they ain't
gonna find anything.
John Murtha's as clean
as my mother's kitchen floor.
Yeah, but Tip would
like to put you
on the Ethics Committee
just the same.
You're kidding.
No.
Well, Jesus, Donnelly,
everyone in town knows
I'm on the other side
of that issue.
Ethics?
Yeah!
Well, the Speaker would
like to put you on the
committee anyway.
Okay. Well, if anyone asks
what the hell I'm doing
on the Ethics Committee,
we'll just tell them
I like chasing women
and drinking whiskey
and the Speaker felt
we were underrepresented.
One man, one vote.
Exactly.
Tip's gonna want
to return the favor.
Tuesday, right?
That is Tuesday, yes.
So if anything comes up
that you'd like me
to speak with him
about, please...
Yes.
Yes!
I'd like to be on
the Board of Directors
of the Kennedy Center.
Charlie.
I'm sorry?
Turns out Congress appoints
the Board of Directors
of the Kennedy Center.
It's a great place to take
a date, and I can never
afford the tickets.
Consider it done.
Excellent.
Go vote.
Another few minutes.
Let's see what's
on the wires.
Why can't you wait
for newspapers like
everybody else?
'Cause I think it's productive
to know today's news today.
And it makes me one day
smarter than you,
which I enjoy as well.
I know you do.
You don't think
that's a little crazy?
Pan Am and Eastern
are lowering their fares.
'Cause of Braniff.
What's a little crazy?
Joining the Board
of the Kennedy Center
so you can get free tickets
to the Royal Ballet of...
Hold on.
What?
AP story out of Kabul.
Uzbekistan?
Afghanistan.
Russia, Afghanistan,
Pakistan, Iran, Iraq,
Kuwait, Saudi Arabia,
Jordan, Israel, Egypt.
Jim Van Wagenen's
our point man
on black approps
for the Defense
Subcommittee?
Yeah.
Have him come to my office
as soon as possible.
How am I voting on this?
Yes.
You sure?
The Boy Scouts?
Jim Van Wagenen.
Get him and show him
that wire story.
Yes, sir.
You are the man
I wanted to talk to.
The Congressman will
be here in a moment.
He's just coming up
from a vote.
I'm sure it's
an important one.
No. Not really.
So, Marla, can you
fit this into his schedule
next week?
Charlie Wilson's office.
Good morning.
The third...
It is? How are you?
Suzanne, can you
help me with this?
Okay.
I'll be right back.
I'll have
him do it.
Okay, bye-bye.
Miss?
Yes, sir?
It seems to me, looking
around, that it's almost
all women working here,
and that they're
all very pretty.
Is that common?
Well,
Congressman Wilson,
he has an expression.
He says, "You can teach them
to type, but you can't teach
them to grow tits."
Well, that's charming.
Larry!
Congressman!
No, no, no. For $5,000
every two years you get
to call me Charlie.
And for 10,000, you can call
me Betty Sue and I'll clean
out your rain gutters.
This is my daughter, Jane.
Well, now I remember Jane.
Two-L at SMU.
Charlie Wilson's office.
Good morning.
Welcome to the
United States Congress.
Hey, I'm gonna
talk to your daddy
for a couple of seconds.
Larry, can we
get you a drink?
It's 10:00 in the morning.
Well, fair enough,
I guess.
Grab a seat.
Now, this situation
with the creche, I want
to know all about it.
Well, sir,
Every single year
since the world was young,
the firehouse in the
Nacogdoches Township
has displayed a creche.
Now, the ACLU has filed suit
against the township
for displaying
a religious symbol
on public property.
It's Christmas time.
It's a creche.
I could understand
if we were in
gosh-darn Scarsdale,
but this is east Texas,
and I want to know
who we're offending.
Except two lawyers
from the ACLU.
That is a terribly interesting
and complicated question.
Let me make
this suggestion, though.
There's a church about
a block and a half
from that firehouse,
First Baptist Church
of Nacogdoches.
They've got
a beautiful rolling lawn
out there in front.
No, no. This
is a Christian
country, Charlie,
founded
on Christian values.
Sure.
We welcome other faiths
to worship as they wish,
but when you can't
put a nativity scene
in front of a firehouse
at Christmas time
in Nacogdoches Township,
something's gone
terribly wrong.
Well, that's not
really true, Larry.
You could move that creche
over to that church
and everything's just fine.
That's not the point!
Okay. Why don't
we just start back
at the beginning?
What can I do for you?
You can intervene
in the case against
the creche committee.
Intervene? How?
You appointed the judge.
I don't appoint judges.
I just made a recommendation
to the President.
Uh-huh.
I think you and I both know
what that means.
I cannot just call up
a judge and tell him
what to do.
Why?
Well, 'cause
it's against a shitload
of really good laws, Gary.
Larry.
I got to go talk to this guy
out here for a second.
Will you excuse me?
By the way,
I love Jesus Christ
and his mother Mary
as much as anybody.
About 38 churches you could
move that creche to,
everybody lives.
Give me a call.
Okay.
I love Chivas.
Jane, how are you?
You need a cup of coffee?
Something to drink?
Anything like that? Okay.
Mmm-mmm.
Jim.
Congressman.
You see Lederer's
AP story out of Kabul?
Yeah.
We're reading this
story every day now.
You see Dan Rather
last night?
Yeah. I did.
Tell me something.
What is the Defense
Subcommittee's budget
for covert ops against
the Communists
in Afghanistan?
All in?
All in.
It's 5 million.
Well, they can't
shoot down helicopters
for $5 million, Jim.
Though they're trying to.
Which is more than
I can say for us.
Get everybody together
for me, would you?
And double it.
Charlie Wilson's office.
Okay, I'm sorry, sir?
The covert ops budget.
Double it.
Okay.
This ain't gonna
be much longer, okay?
Here's what
I'm gonna do, Larry.
Charlie Wilson's office.
Maybe in about 20 minutes.
He's just going
into a meeting.
Sure.
My XO wrote in a report,
I was the best officer
he ever served at sea with,
and the worst officer
he ever served in port with.
You can look it up.
I must've graduated
from Annapolis
with the second most demerits
of any midshipman
in the history
of the Naval Academy.
Well, who
had the most? I want
to sleep with him.
It's hotter here in D.C.
Than in Nacogdoches,
so I hope you don't mind,
I took off a few
of my clothes.
Well, I'm just gonna have
to live with that, Jane.
Just call me angel
of the morning, angel
Just touch my cheek
before you leave me
Come on over here. I'm gonna
show you the best view
in the District.
You want some of this?
No, no, I got this.
I like both.
Well, it must be
great being me.
I've heard it is.
Iwo Jima Memorial.
There's the Lincoln.
Washington. Now follow it
around to the right.
The Jefferson Memorial.
The Arlington Bridge.
And there's the Pentagon.
Oh, that's the Pentagon.
That's the Pentagon.
How about I show you
the second best view
in the District?
Why, Jane, would you like...
Well, that was predictable.
Just give me one second.
Hello?
That was an
extraordinary thing
you did today.
Who is this?
It's Joanne.
Joanne!
Why, gosh, how nice
to hear from you.
Could I call you back
in a little bit?
Is Ronald Reagan
in your bedroom
right now?
No.
Then I'm considerably
more important
than whoever is.
Is anything wrong?
This is gonna take
just a second or two.
Okay, I'm all yours.
What did I do that
was so extraordinary?
"Double it."
'Cause I was told
you didn't have
a girlfriend.
What?
You told Jim Van Wagenen
to double it.
Well, shit, Joanne,
I don't know what
you're talking about,
and if I did,
it'd be classified,
and I'd wonder
where you got
your information
on the Subcommittee.
Oh, what do you care, hon?
It's a little matter
of national security
and I can't help but think...
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
Hold on.
I am sorry,
but I was told
you didn't have
a girlfriend.
I don't.
This isn't my girlfriend.
It's the sixth
wealthiest woman in Texas.
Which is still pretty good.
Okay, so, hi.
A friend of mine has
made a terrific movie
about the need
for American aid
to Afghanistan.
He's made a movie?
Yes.
I'm gonna run this movie
Friday night at my house
at a fundraiser.
You know, you've never
been to my house, Charlie.
You want me to come
to Houston and see
a movie?
There'll be women
and wealthy donors.
See you Friday.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey.
Mmm-mmm.
Thank you, Joanne.
Okay. I know it was difficult
for you to come in here,
hat in hand.
That's not the kind
of upbringing, I guess,
is the word I'm looking for.
It's not the kind of man
you are. I understand that.
I'm not looking to humiliate
you or exact a price
in any way,
so why don't you
just apologize?
We'll call it water under
the dam, and we'll go
about our business.
Excuse me,
what the fuck?
What?
What the fuck
are you talking about?
Clair George said you
were coming in here
to apologize.
No, I'm supposed to come
in here so you could
apologize to me.
According to whom?
Clair George.
You told me to go fuck myself.
I'm supposed to apologize
to you?
Also, water goes over
a dam and under a bridge,
you poncy schoolboy.
Clearly there's been
a miscommunication between
Clair George and somebody.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Does this look all right?
It's fine.
Thank you.
I can sand it
down a little.
I, I don't know.
I have no fucking idea
who this guy is.
He is here to fix the glass
that you broke the last time
you were here.
Could you just excuse us
for a second there?
Yes.
You tell me to go
fuck myself
and I'm supposed
to apologize?
You break my window,
I'm supposed to apologize?
The Helsinki job was mine!
The Helsinki job was not
yours. If it was yours,
you'd be in Helsinki.
Alan Wolfe stood
in this office!
Alan Wolfe
is no longer the Director.
Yeah, it was on the books!
Alan Wolfe is no
longer the Director
of European Operations.
He does not make
those appointments. I do.
Promises were made.
Not by me.
I've been with
the company for 24 years.
I was posted
in Greece for 15.
Papandreou wins that election
if I don't help the junta
take him prisoner.
I've advised and armed
the Hellenic army.
I've neutralized
champions of Communism.
I've spent the past
three years learning
Finnish!
Which should come in handy
here in Virginia!
And I'm never,
ever, sick at sea.
So I want to know
why I'm not gonna be
your Helsinki station chief.
You're coarse.
Excuse me?
For Helsinki, I need someone
with diplomatic skills.
You don't have them.
Is that right?
That is right. And I
don't know why the hell
I didn't fire you
when you broke
my fucking window!
Oh, yes, sure
you do, Cravely.
Look, Gust...
Yeah, you're fucking
Roger's fiancee
and you know I know.
I'm not... I'm not even
gonna dignify that with
a response.
Yeah, yeah, you're
dignifying her in the ass
at the Jefferson Hotel,
room 1210.
But let me ask you.
The 3,000 agents
Turner fired
was that because they lacked
diplomatic skills as well?
You're referring
to Admiral Stansfield Turner?
Yeah, the 3,000 agents.
Each and every goddamn one
of them first or second
generation Americans.
Is that because they lack
the proper diplomatic skills?
Or did Turner not
think it was a good idea
to have spies
who could speak the
same language as the people
they're fucking spying on?
Well, I'm sorry,
but you can hardly
blame the Director
for questioning the loyalty
to America of people that
are just barely Americans
in the first place.
Yeah, well, I'd like
to take a moment
to review the several ways
in which you're a douchebag.
Get the fuck
out of my office!
Yes, sir.
Before I end
your career, asshole.
Yes, sir!
Yeah, my friend,
I'm gonna need
you for a second.
God damn it!
My loyalty?
For 24 years,
people have been
trying to kill me.
People who know how.
Now, do you think that's
because my dad was
a Greek soda pop maker
or do you think that's
because I'm an American spy?
Go fuck yourself,
you fucking child.
How was I?
Thank you.
There's a woman in
Aliquippa, Pennsylvania,
named Nitsa.
And she thinks
she's a witch.
Yeah, she offered
to put a curse on
Cravely for me.
Yeah?
And she...
She asked me do I want
a professional curse
or a health curse.
"If it's a health curse,
I can do it right away,
"but a professional curse
takes longer."
Well, I'm living proof
she's right about that.
Did you get the brownie?
Oh, no, sir, I didn't.
I got you.
I'm reading transcripts
of phone conversations
between French
and German generals
arguing over office space
at NATO headquarters
and analyzing wiretaps
out of Mercury Bay,
New Zealand.
You know,
historically, a hotbed
of anti-American activity.
Yeah, nobody will come
near me. I'm in the weeds.
You know,
a typical case officer
doesn't walk into his
boss's office and tell him
to go fuck himself. Twice.
I just told you,
I paid a witch in
Pennsylvania $80
to put a curse
on Henry Cravely for me.
Do I sound like
a typical case officer?
No.
Well, then,
let's assume I'm not.
Listen. If you're really
not doing anything,
why don't you come upstairs
and work with us?
What are you doing?
Killing Russians.
Our next slave girl
is a Texas rose named
Ashley Rensler.
Ashley is prelaw at U. T.,
and her three sorority sisters
from Delta Delta Delta
will wash your car
or truck
in special outfits
they have chosen
for the occasion.
So, who wants their wheels
cleaned clean as a whistle
by a 19-year-old lawyer
and her three friends
from Tri-Delt?
I have 10,000,
who'll give me 11?
11, 11, I got 11.
I got 15 right here.
Thank you very much.
Oh, my God,
she is a Minute Woman.
No, she's a Tri-Delt.
No, she is a
Minute Woman, Charlie.
Oh. Joanne.
Yeah, she's
a direct descendant of
George Washington's sister.
Says she had a great uncle
who was killed at the Alamo.
Former Miss Cotton Bowl.
Had her own local
television talk show.
Look. Pakistan's
Honorary Consul
to Houston, Texas.
How's that
for a title, huh?
This is
an ultra-right wing group
of anti-Communist fanatics.
They're not
ultra-right wing.
What are they?
Well, they're
ultra-right wing.
What are you doing
hanging around
this woman?
Did you hear me say
she was a former
Miss Cotton Bowl?
You are unbelievable.
Oh, come on.
You're gonna love her.
And, you know, one of
the things she's trying
to do over there
is liberate the women.
And what better
way than through
a slave girl auction?
Charlie.
So sorry for keeping
you waiting.
Oh, it's no problem,
Joanne.
This is Bonnie Bach.
So nice to meet you.
It's a pleasure meeting you,
Mrs. Herring. This is
a wonderful party.
Why don't you
give us a few moments?
Yes, sir.
Oh, Bobbie, if you could
ask someone for a Bombay
martini up, very dry?
Oh, I'm not
a slave girl,
actually.
I'm the Congressman's
administrative assistant.
Isn't that wonderful
for you.
Yes.
Two olives, please.
Tell them it's for me,
they'll know.
Certainly.
She doesn't like me.
Everybody likes you.
She's a liberal.
Well, I'm a liberal.
Not where it counts.
Have you seen the house?
Well, I've seen
the downstairs,
what's upstairs?
Fourteen bedrooms.
I should have a look.
What did you think
of the movie?
What, that thing
we just saw?
The reason
for the party, yes.
Well, I'm not an expert
in the field or anything,
but the production quality
seemed amateurish to me.
Yeah, I'm not
submitting the thing
for a Golden Globe
nomination, Charlie.
You know what
I'm talking about.
Well, as a member
of the Defense Subcommittee,
did you think
I wasn't aware
that the Soviet Union's
invaded Afghanistan?
Yes, I believe
my government is aware,
but I was wondering
if they were thinking
of doing anything about it
other than boycotting
the Olympics, which
I think you'll agree,
was a fairly
impotent response
to the greatest
national security
threat we've faced
since the
Cuban Missile Crisis.
Well, I don't think making
more movies about it
is gonna do the trick,
if that's what
you're asking.
It's not.
Exactly how much power
do you have as a member
of the Subcommittee?
Which one? I'm on two.
Foreign Ops.
Eight members and myself
hand out 11 billion
in foreign assistance.
And what about
the Defense Subcommittee?
Our budget is hidden.
It is also unlimited.
Yeah.
Would you like
to see my room?
Yeah.
So, unless I'm wrong,
and that would be
unusual for me,
you sit at the intersection
of the State Department,
the Pentagon and the CIA.
You meet in a soundproof room
underneath the Capitol,
and you preside over
a secret and unlimited
budget
for the three agencies
you would need to conduct
a covert war.
Isn't that right?
I also have seats
at the Kennedy Center.
Isn't that how you were able
to double the CIA budget
for black approps
in Afghanistan
just by saying so?
Why are you only asking me
questions you already
know the answers to?
Why is Congress
saying one thing
and doing nothing?
Well, tradition mostly.
Come here.
Okay.
I do not understand
the energy women
have after sex.
You're dancing around,
you're baking a pie.
Charlie?
Yes, ma'am?
Why is the CIA running
a fake war in Afghanistan?
They're doing
everything they can.
They're doing it badly.
The CIA is arming
the mujahideen.
Where do you think
they're getting
their weapons?
They're arming them
with 12.7 millimeter
Dishukas
which would be good,
except the Soviets have
specifically armor-plated
their Hind helicopter
to resist
a 12.7 millimeter shell.
We sold Pakistan F-16s,
but didn't give them
the look-downlshoot-down
radar.
If this were a real war,
State would issue
a white paper outlining
the Communist threat
the way they did
in El Salvador.
If this were a real war,
there'd be a National
Bipartisan Commission
on Afghanistan, headed
by Henry Kissinger the way
they did in Central America.
If this were a real war,
Congress would authorize
$24 million
for covert operations
the way you did in Nicaragua.
If this were a real war...
You may be
the sexiest woman ever.
I'm not kidding.
You are Helen of Troy.
Are you patronizing me?
What do you want me
to do, Joanne?
This is what
I want you to do.
I want you to save Afghanistan
for the Afghans.
I want you to deliver
such a crushing defeat
to the Soviets
that Communism crumbles,
and in so doing,
end the Cold War.
I'll tell you,
I'd do it, too,
but I got this
Dairy Queen problem
in Nacogdoches.
Don't underestimate me,
Charlie. Believe everything
you've heard.
What exactly
do you want me to do?
Go to Pakistan
and meet with Zia.
Zia?
Mohammed Zia ul-Haq.
He's the President
of Pakistan.
I've already arranged it.
You've arranged a meeting
between me and the
President of Pakistan?
Yes.
You're going
to Israel next week
to meet with Zvi Rafiah
about the Lavi jets.
I want you to tack Pakistan
on the end of your trip.
And meet
with the President?
Let him convince you
that it's a Christian
imperative
to let the Afghans
rid their country
of Communism.
Okay. It's not likely
the President of Pakistan
is a Christian,
but I'm gonna do this
for you, Joanne,
'cause you saved my ass
once with the pro-lifers
and I owe you my seat
in Congress and because
you look very good naked.
But I have to tell you,
I'm elected by Jews.
How many Jews do you have
in your district?
Seven.
But congressmen aren't
elected by voters,
they're elected
by contributors,
and mine are in,
well, New York,
Florida, Hollywood,
because I'm one
of Israel's guys
on the Hill.
And I don't know
how they're gonna feel
about me taking up
the cause of Muslims.
Well, that's
your problem.
Yes, it is.
Go fight this war
and win it, Charlie.
Everything possible is
on the line, including
your manhood.
Oh, I was afraid you
were gonna say that.
Well, I guess it ain't
gonna be twice tonight.
Well, I guess
somebody can't count.
Oh, darling,
I was talking about me.
Congressman Charlie Wilson.
Mr. Congressman.
Mr. President.
Yeah.
Joanne Herring speaks
very highly of you.
Oh, well, thank you, sir.
Thank you.
These are two
of my brightest advisors
when it comes
to the problem
of the Soviets.
This is Brigadier Rashid.
How do you do?
Pleased to meet you.
Colonel Mahmood.
How do you do?
Pleased to meet you.
Please come.
Thank you.
You must be thirsty.
Can we get you a drink?
Oh, actually I'd love
a glass of ice and
any kind of whiskey.
Rye, Canadian.
Uh...
I'm sorry, Congressman,
we don't have alcohol
in the Presidential Residence.
Of course, you don't.
I apologize.
Fruit juice?
Bet a lot of people
make that mistake.
No.
Okay.
Brigadier?
So you understand
the situation on
our border?
Yes, sir, I think I do.
And I think it's terrible.
And I know I speak for
all the people in the Texas
Second Congressional District
when I say our thoughts
and our prayers
are with you.
All the people
of the Texas Second
Congressional District,
you say?
Yes, indeed, sir.
Three million Afghan refugees
are living like poorly
treated livestock.
Another two million
have fled into Iran.
And two million
more angry men
is just what the doctors
ordered for Iran,
don't you think?
People are dying
by the tens of thousands.
And the ones that aren't
are crossing into Pakistan
every day.
Would you like
to know how many?
One fifth of Afghanistan
now lives
in Pakistan's
North-West Frontier Province.
So, what I have
been wondering is
why your State Department
would send someone here
who thinks
he understands
the problem.
'Cause I don't think
the prayers of the Texas
Second Congressional District
are going to turn
the trick.
Well, now, I wasn't sent here
by the State Department,
Mr. President.
I was asked to come here
by our friend in Houston.
So this is
a courtesy call.
I don't need courtesy.
I need airplanes,
guns and money.
Well, we just doubled
the CIA budget
for covert ops...
From 5 million
to 10 million.
That's right.
Is that a joke?
No.
Is that meant
to be a funny joke?
No, sir.
Congressman,
what they're saying is
$10 million from the U.S.
To fight the Russian Army
is such a low figure
that it can be mistaken
for a joke.
I caught up to the
sarcasm there, sir.
Let me be clear.
The United States is
eager to assist you.
No, you're not.
You're not.
Absolutely not.
I went to Oxford
and I know what
that word means.
The U.S. Is not eager
to assist us.
Well, now it's
my understanding that we
offered to sell you F-16s.
You didn't want them.
Because you refused
to sell us the radar.
So to hell with that.
And this is emblematic
of American fence sitting
when it comes
to fighting the Soviets.
To hell with it!
You sell us the planes
but not the radar.
You offer Afghans rifles
from the First World War
while Soviet helicopters
are killing everything
they can find,
people, animals,
food supplies.
So to hell with it!
Yeah.
You sell
the Israelis the radar,
so that's why he says,
"To hell with it."
Again, I understood. Yeah.
Also, the arms and funding
should flow through us.
I'm sorry?
That's been part
of the problem.
The arms and the funding
should flow through us.
We have experience
with warfare of this kind.
And your CIA has
an unimpressive
track record.
Oh. I wouldn't say that.
They missed 130,000
Soviet soldiers walking
into Afghanistan.
Okay, we blew that call.
I would say so.
Well, I don't want
to use up any more
of your hospitality,
so I will take
your message back
to my committee chairman,
and we will give it
our fullest attention.
Let me walk you
to the door.
I learned about you
before you came here.
I learned that you're a man
of many character flaws.
I am.
But I also learned
that you never
promise anything
you cannot deliver.
No, I don't,
Mr. President.
Then promise me this.
Go to Peshawar
and see the refugee camps.
Right now. Today.
Go to Peshawar and see
with your own eyes.
I have a helicopter
waiting to take you.
All right, I'll do it.
Thank you,
Mr. Congressman.
Mr. President.
All right, you,
come on.
How did it go?
Well, there were
three of them.
It was like getting slapped
around by a Pakistani
vaudeville team.
You know
you've pretty much
hit rock bottom
when you've been told
you have character flaws
by a man
who hanged his predecessor
in a military coup.
Can we go home now?
No. No, we have
to make one more stop.
I've seen enough.
About 350 people
in three small villages
at Kandahar.
But instead of doing
it all at once,
the Russians would
make the parents watch
as they slit
the throats
of the children.
So, the Russians
gathered all the defectors
and piled them like wood
in the center
of the village.
Then they ran over them
with their tanks.
I saw
something shiny on the ground.
I thought it was a toy.
When I reached down
to grab it, it exploded
in my hand.
I should have known.
Because last year
my little brother tried
to pick up a piece of candy.
It split him in half.
It takes more work to take
care of a wounded child
than a dead one.
So when the Russians
cover fields with toy mines,
adults who might help
with the war effort have
to take care of the children.
You can see yourself.
Like a bug.
They're beautiful.
How many children
do you have?
She had six.
So, what do you want to be
when you grow up?
Hi. I have Congressman Wilson
here to see the station
chief, Harold Holt.
Down the hall.
Second door on the left.
I'll wait outside.
Look, normally,
a congressional delegation,
we'd give them a courtesy
briefing on the situation,
but as you can see,
it's getting pretty late,
we don't have a whole lot
of time anyway, so...
Well, make the time.
Huh?
Fuck your time, Harold.
I'm on Defense Appropriations.
I'm catching a plane
back to Washington
in just a few minutes.
Now, I need a full
classified briefing
right now.
Hundred and twenty thousand
Soviet troops in all.
Hundred and twenty thousand?
40th Army is garrisoned
in the cities
and in the airports.
Your seventh and eighth
infantry divisions
are in Kabul.
The 18th in Mazar-e Sharif,
the fourth armored...
Anything inside?
I'm sorry?
They controlling
anything inside?
Soviet advisors
have appropriated
the Afghan intel service
and the ministries.
Which ministries?
All of them.
Anyway, the fourth armored
covers Bagram Airbase.
Seventh Armored is...
Why ain't they shooting down
them helicopters?
I'm sorry?
The helicopters, Harold.
Why ain't we giving them
something to shoot down
them helicopters?
The helicopters
are a problem.
You think?
Congressman...
They're shooting
at Soviet gunships
with Enfield rifles.
That's basically what
Davy Crockett used.
The Soviet Hind gunship
is especially armor plated
to resist bullets.
Yeah, I know, I know.
So you tell me what you
need to shoot them down.
What do you mean?
Tell me what you need.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
You tell me what you need,
and I will go about
getting it for you.
Congressman, I appreciate
your generosity,
but a sudden influx of money
and modern weaponry
would draw attention.
What?
A sudden influx
of money and modern...
Wait, it would
draw attention?
Yeah.
Why, I don't even know
what that means.
This is the Cold War.
Everybody knows about it.
Should I continue
with the briefing?
Have you been to these
refugee camps? Have you
heard these stories?
Congressman, I am required
to give you a briefing.
Should I continue?
No. Thank you.
You know, I had a neighbor,
growing up, with a name
right out of Dickens.
Mr. Charles Hazard.
And Mr. Hazard didn't like
the neighborhood dogs
messing up his flower beds.
One day, I heard
a bunch of yelling
from across the street,
so I ran on over
to Mr. Hazard's,
and there were about
15 grown-ups standing
around my dog, Teddy,
who was writhing
on the ground
in obvious agony.
Blood was pouring
out of his mouth.
Mr. Hazard had
ground up a glass bottle
and put it in a bowl
of dog food and
fed it to him.
What did you do?
Well, I got some gasoline
and burned down
his flower beds.
But that wasn't
satisfying enough.
And then I remembered,
Mr. Hazard was
an elected official.
He was the head
of the town council.
His reelection every two years
was a foregone conclusion.
So come Election Day,
I drove over to
the black section of town.
Now, these people
hadn't voted in any of
these elections, so...
I was only 13,
but I had a farmer's license
and I filled up my car
with black voters
and drove them
to the polling place
and then waited,
then drove them on home.
But before they got out
of the car to vote
I said, "I don't
mean to influence you,
but I think you should know
"Mr. Charles Hazard
has intentionally
killed my dog."
About 400 ballots were
cast in that election.
I drove 96 of them
to the polls.
Hazard lost by 16 votes.
And that's the day
I fell in love
with America.
What time do we land?
7:30 a.m. In D.C.
I want the CIA
in my office
at 10:00.
Assistant Deputy Director
or higher.
Tell them that if
I don't see someone
at 10:00,
I'm gonna start docking
their allowance at a rate
of $1 million a minute.
Yes, sir.
And get me another
one of them, would you?
Yes, sir.
The AKs,
RPG-7 grenade launchers
and 82 millimeter mortars
are coming into Pakistan
by air and sea,
and then trucks take them
to the Afghan border.
Then we take them
across on mules,
which are running
a little more than
we thought.
The mules?
They're 2,400 a piece,
plus we got to get them
checked out.
For what?
Diseases. Foot and mouth.
Plus they have to have
their ears cleaned.
The mules are getting
better health care
than the Afghans.
Plus, they're
gonna cost a little extra
if we want them pre-trained.
To do what?
Walk over a mountain
with ammunition
on their back.
Aren't they born
with that instinct?
I mean, isn't that
something they want
to do naturally?
You think Afghanistan might,
one day, think about building
some fucking roads?
Gust.
Yeah?
I got something for you.
I need you
to be specific...
The whole thing
has changed. Get your diary.
I'll show you.
Okay.
No problem.
Thank you.
He should be here
any moment.
Don't worry about me.
I'm fine.
Good morning.
Good morning, Congressman.
Welcome back.
Yeah. Marla.
Suzanne.
Welcome back.
Who are you?
This is Gust Avrakotos.
He's come up from Langley
to bring you the information
that you wanted.
Bonnie!
Yes, sir?
I said Assistant Deputy
Director or higher.
I know, sir. I called...
No, Assistant Deputies
don't come
to the Hill
without a subpoena.
I'm the guy you want
to talk to, Congressman.
I'm on the Afghan desk.
You're on
the Afghan desk?
Yeah.
Well, I wouldn't be
too proud of that. I just
got back from there.
Oh, I know.
And that's a hell
of a flight, too.
That nine hours flying time
against the jet stream.
Probably had to stop
in Brussels, plus the
time difference.
I'd be a little grumpy
myself.
I ain't grumpy
because of the plane.
We want to give you this
'cause we know you
like single malt.
It's called Talisker,
and it's mentioned in a
Robert Louis Stevenson poem,
The Scotsman's Return
from Abroad.
"The king o' drinks,
as I conceive it,
"Talisker, Isla
or Glenlivet!"
Who are you again?
Gust Avrakotos.
Have Bonnie come
into this meeting.
Yes, sir.
What's the gift for?
It's from the Afghan desk
for doubling the budget
for the mujahideen.
Oh. Well, thank you.
It was nothing.
Well, it's a nice
bottle of Scotch.
Must've been hard to get.
No, doubling
the budget was nothing.
I mean, $10 million
for covert ops against the
Russian Army is meaningless.
What are you, an infant?
Now, you hang
on just one second.
I don't remember your name.
Gust Avrakotos.
Yeah.
Okay, you mind
if I call you Gus?
Yeah, well, my name's Gust
with a "t," but I don't care.
Fifteen hours ago, I offered
Harold Holt the keys
to the safe, okay?
I stood there in the office
in Islamabad, and I said,
"How much do you need?"
And I was apparently
annoying him.
Well, Harold Holt's
a massive tool, Congressman.
He's a cake-eater.
He's a clown.
He's a bad station chief.
And I don't mean to cast
aspersions on a guy, but
he's gonna get us all killed.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, how does he expect
to defeat the Soviets in
Afghanistan without...
He said, "A sudden
influx of money..."
Yeah, an influx of money
and new weaponry
would draw attention.
He's not trying to defeat
the Soviets, Congressman.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Excuse me.
I'm the Congressman's
aide, Bonnie Bach.
Gust Avrakotos.
Gus, I need the room
for a second.
Sure.
Jailbait!
Whoa, whoa. Hey, hey.
Whoa, all right.
Just tell me
what's happening.
A Justice Department
task force that was
formed last year
to investigate
reports of sex between
members of the House
and their male interns
has recently widened
to include the use
of recreational drugs
by senators and congressmen.
Do you know a man
named Paul Brown?
He doesn't
have to answer that.
Keep going.
Oh, shit.
Paul Brown, under
investigation by federal
prosecutors for fraud.
He wanted me to invest
in some TV show for Crystal.
Well, he's saying
he witnessed you
doing cocaine nine times
in a fantasy suite
in Las Vegas.
Brian Ross at NBC is
breaking the story.
All right, guys. I was
in Las Vegas with Crystal
and Paul Brown,
because she wanted me
to talk to him about
this thing.
There was cocaine?
I want you to go
in the other room
and start on a statement.
Let's get Stu on the phone.
Okay, I'll call him.
Okay, Bait,
you just need to start...
It's all right,
everybody.
It's gonna be all right.
I want to get back to...
Gus!
You having problems?
No.
What do you mean,
he's not trying to
defeat the Soviets?
Well, he wants to bleed them.
Payback for Vietnam.
Make it so they just have
to keep sending troops in,
keep sending money,
and troops, and money
until they just go out
of their fucking minds
the way we did.
You mean to tell me
that the U.S. Strategy
in Afghanistan
is to have the Afghans
keep walking into
machine gun fire
till the Russians
run out of bullets?
That's Harold Holt's
strategy.
It's not U.S. Strategy.
What is U.S. Strategy?
Well, strictly speaking,
we don't have one.
But we're working
hard on that.
Who's we?
Me and three other guys.
Would you excuse me?
All right,
what do you have?
"Representative Charles Wilson
has learned he is joining
several members of Congress
"who are under investigation
by a Justice Department
task force that is..."
Don't say task force.
It makes it sound
like Eliot Ness
is running the thing.
Okay.
Who is running the thing?
Who's the prosecutor?
Rudolph Giuliani,
New York, Southern District.
You know him?
No.
Well, it's been going
on forever. We should
say that, too.
"Representative Charles Wilson
has learned he is joining
several members of Congress
"who are under investigation
by the Justice Department
"in what is now
an 18-month long,
wide-ranging examination
"that has resulted
in no convictions."
"Congressman Wilson
has not been charged
with any crime,
"nor has he been questioned
by the authorities.
"He denies any allegation
of illegal or improper
behavior
"and will fully cooperate
with the ongoing
investigation."
Okay. Run it by Stu.
Yes, sir.
Gus!
You and three other guys?
Yeah.
Well, I'll tell you
what I told Harold Holt.
I can get the money.
Now, the 10 million is a joke?
Fine. What do you need?
To do what?
To shoot down
the helicopters.
If we can help them shoot down
the goddamn helicopters,
everything's gonna
start going our way.
You know, there's
a story about a Zen master
and a little boy.
All right, and... Yeah.
It's Stu.
You should be on this.
Stu?
No. No,
it's gonna be fine.
It was a party in Vegas.
Lot of drugs,
lot of people
I don't know.
I was there with Crystal Lee
and this guy Paul Brown
who wanted me to invest
in a TV show for Crystal.
I don't know.
I don't know, it's
gonna be like a Dallas
set in Washington.
What... Stu,
what does it matter?
Okay.
Will Crystal back up
your story that you
weren't using?
Just go put out
the statement.
You know what?
You never should have been
in the same room, Congressman.
Gus!
Yeah.
The Swiss make
an antiaircraft gun
called the Oerlikon.
Listen, Charlie.
Twenty-millimeter cannon,
high rate of fire.
I know the Oerlikon.
Don't forget
the limo driver.
What do you mean?
Well, you took a limo
from the casino to
the airport.
Maybe it's easy enough
to track down a limo driver,
hand him a subpoena,
ask him if anything
was going on in
the back seat,
so, you know,
in terms of cleaning
up this...
Were you listening
at the door?
I wasn't listening
at the door.
Were you standing
at the goddamn door
listening to me?
No.
How could you even...
That's a thick door!
You stood there
and you listened to me?
I wasn't standing at the door.
Don't be an idiot.
I bugged the Scotch bottle.
What?
Yeah, it's got a little
transmitter on it.
I got a little thing
in my ear. Get past it.
I don't believe this. Who the
fuck... Who the fuck are you?
It's not in my ear right now.
Take it easy.
I was gonna tell you about it,
but I had to leave the room
for a second
'cause you were getting
indicted.
I ain't getting indicted.
Is there a camera in here?
No, that's a little paranoid.
That's right.
Will you take the bug
off my Scotch bottle now?
Sure.
I saw two kids,
had their hands blown off
when they tried to pick
up something shiny.
Sometimes the kids think
those bombs are toys.
For children to pick up.
Yeah.
They're raping the women
and...
Yeah.
...bayoneting the pregnant
ones.
It's as bad as it can be.
But they still want to go out
and fight the Red Army.
Each and every one of them.
I've never seen anything
like that.
No, me, neither.
Let's be clear. I want to kill
Russians as much as you do.
Is the Oerlikon the right gun?
Is that what they should have?
Now, you know what?
You've had a long flight.
You're under a lot of stress.
You're under arrest.
I ain't under arrest.
Do you drink?
Oh, God, yeah.
Well, should we try
this Scotch,
or is it gonna release
sarin gas when I open it?
Oh, I don't think so,
but open it over there.
How'd a guy like you get
into the Agency?
What, you mean a street guy?
You ain't James Bond.
And you ain't
Thomas Jefferson,
so let's call it even.
Deal.
Since there's no other reason
I should be here,
let's assume it's 'cause
I'm very good at this.
They need to shoot down
the helicopters, Gus.
They need at least,
what, 50 Oerlikons.
Yeah, it's gonna cost
a lot more than $10 million.
And I say for the fourth time,
I can raise the money.
Yeah, how?
Is the Oerlikon the gun
I should be recommending?
I'm not sure.
Who is sure?
A weapons guy named
Mike Vickers.
I'll call him.
Yeah. Let's call him
right now.
All right, here's a test.
You see the nerdy-looking kid
in the white shirt
playing against
the four guys at once?
Yeah.
Which one of the guys do you
think is a strategic weapons
expert
with the CIA?
That was a trick question,
Charlie.
It's the nerdy-looking kid
in the white shirt.
All right, no reason this
can't be fun, you know.
Mike!
Yeah, just a second.
Need you now, Mike.
Keep playing.
Mike Vickers, this is
Congressman Charles Wilson
of the Defense Appropriations
Subcommittee.
How are you, sir?
Fine, thank you.
How old are you?
I'll be 30 next week.
This is the CIA's weapons
expert?
One of them.
But he's the most senior.
Look...
Mike!
Yeah, bishop to queen's
knight 7.
See? He's playing
without even looking
at the board.
That's a useful skill
if Afghanistan's ever invaded
by Boris Spassky.
Did my office not make
it clear to Langley that
I'm in no mood
to be fucked around with?
Charlie...
You answer to me or
you answer to Jim Baker.
Which do you want?
All right, the guy's a fucking
Green Beret, Charlie.
He trained with the SEALs.
No one's trying to fuck
with you!
Mike?
Yeah, what was your move?
Knight to queen's bishop 5.
All right, queen to king's
rook 3.
Guy on the right, you don't
want to trade queens with me.
Shit.
All right, I apologize.
Okay.
Everybody friends?
As a former naval officer
myself, Mike, I should've
known better.
As a former naval officer,
I'd have been surprised
if you had.
Now, what the fuck?
Hey.
He said he was sorry.
What can I do for you, sir?
All right, he wants
to make a recommendation
to his Subcommittee.
Now, the Swiss made Oerlikon
S.T.A. Antiaircraft cannon,
that's what you'd use
to shoot down the Ml-24 Hind
gunship in the mountains,
right?
Well, the Oerlikon's
a good start,
but the Russians will
just start flying higher
altitude missions.
So what else do they need?
Same thing you give us.
AK-47 s, AK-74s, AKMS.
The Soviets didn't
come into Afghanistan
on a Eurail Pass.
They came in T-55 tanks.
The fighters need
RPG-7 anti-tank
grenade launchers,
Katyusha 107 mm rockets,
wire mines, plastic mines,
bicycle bombs, sniper rifles,
ammunition for
all the above
and frequency-hopping radios
and burst transmitters
so these guys aren't
so fucking easy to find.
Well, I've written it all
in a report you can read.
You'd be the first
one who did.
Send a copy of it to me
by secure courier right away.
I will. All right.
All right.
There was a report?
It's not that simple.
Why not?
Well, for one thing
it's covert.
When an Afghan freedom fighter
gets captured,
it can't be with
an American-made
weapon on him.
That's how a cold war turns
into an actual war,
and that's something
you want to keep
a good eye on.
So anything we give them
has to look like
it could have plausibly
been captured from
the Soviets.
Yeah, that's right.
You know who's good at that?
Israel and Egypt.
That's right.
You know what Vickers
just described back there
could cost as much
as $40 million.
I can get the appropriation.
But how?
I want to know how are you
gonna get the approval
of Congress
when they're saying no
to the Contras for nothing,
for $5 million, a request
made by the President?
When a black approp makes it
through this Subcommittee,
the full body has
to vote on it blind.
They know the dollar amount,
but they don't know
what it's for.
So, theoretically, your
$10 million can become
40 million
without anyone ever noticing
but the Russian Army.
Because Congress
wouldn't know what
it was voting on.
That's the beauty of it!
All you need are the nine
other Subcommittee members.
All I really need is
the Committee Chairman.
Doc Long.
And with Doc's backing,
you'll get the votes of
the other Committee members.
Yep.
I don't believe you.
I don't care.
And until the phone rang
this morning, Charlie,
I didn't know
I'd never heard of you.
Well, ask around.
I did.
And what'd you find out?
That your greatest legislative
achievement in six terms
was getting reelected
five times.
Anything else?
That you hold more IOUs
than any member of the House.
How about that?
I represent the only district
in America that doesn't
want anything.
They want their guns,
they want low taxes,
that's it.
I can do favors.
I get to vote yes a lot.
Now, me and three other guys
are killing Russians.
I mean, is it possible
that I've met the only elected
official in town who can help?
Give me a week
to set things up.
Go pack a bag.
I have a friend,
an arms dealer in Israel.
He's who we need for this,
God help us.
Should be interesting.
Yeah.
All right.
We need you, Zvi.
You're gonna be our man
inside the Israeli Parliament.
I'm not in the Israeli
Parliament.
That's what's gonna
make you so effective.
No one has your pull
with the 10th Knesset.
No one has your relationship
with the Speaker.
And we are gonna...
We're gonna need your arm
around Menachem,
when he finds out that
we're working with
Egypt and the Saudis.
Tell him.
Tell him why we need him.
I'm not saying anything.
Why not?
I don't know who the fuck
these two other guys are.
Well, ain't they bodyguards?
Not ours.
Zvi?
Now, just to sum this
up in a nutshell.
You want me
to move Israel
toward a partnership
with Egypt, Pakistan
and Afghanistan.
And Saudi Arabia.
Well, just a couple of
problems I can foresee
off the top of my head.
Look.
Charlie...
I know.
...Pakistan and Afghanistan
don't recognize our right
to exist.
Calm down.
We just got done fighting
a war with Egypt
and every person who has
ever tried to kill me
and my family,
has been trained
in Saudi Arabia.
That's not entirely true, Zvi.
I mean, some of them
were trained by us.
Gus, come on.
It's his sense of humor.
It's a bit of an
acquired taste.
Now, Zvi, look at me.
This is the front
of the Cold War.
It's not in Berlin,
it's not in Cuba,
it's not in Czechoslovakia.
It's in a pile of rocks
called Afghanistan.
These are the only people
who are actually shooting
at the Russians.
Now, you and I know we have
to get Soviet-made weapons
into the hands
of the mujahideen.
And you and I know
where the largest stockpile
of Soviet weapons
outside the Soviet Union is.
I can't tell you offhand
how many
and what kind of weapons
we've confiscated.
I can. These are Keyhole-11
satellite photos.
They've been degraded
so I can show them to you.
All right, that's
a five-wheeled chassis tank.
That's not the Mk.1,
that's the T-55.
And it and four others are
about 12 miles from here.
What do you want tanks
in mountains for?
Oh, we don't. I just
wanted you to know I know
you got them.
$35.5 million.
Which you'll be able
to appropriate.
Yeah.
Without the press asking
questions about it.
You know,
there's good news there,
because the press is going
to be busy asking about
a weekend in Vegas
and his pending arrest
on charges of narcotics
possession.
Oh, Gus.
Shit, Charlie.
It's nothing.
Is this true?
No, for our purposes,
it doesn't really matter.
Thank you.
I was just explaining to him
that as long as the press
sees sex and drugs behind
the left hand,
you can park a battle carrier
behind the right hand
and no one's gonna
fucking notice.
What the hell happened?
It's not germane.
It's not germane
to these people
who are fighting and dying,
and being massacred
in their homes.
Now, for the love of Christ,
will you help us help them
shoot down these fucking
helicopters?
I love you, Charlie,
but you are a grown man
who still hasn't learned
to look both ways before
he crosses the fucking street!
Yes, I'm in.
But I don't like this guy.
I know how you feel.
What happens now?
You come with us to Cairo.
This meeting's gonna
be run professional?
Oh, absolutely.
We'll be talking
to the Deputy Defense Minister
while his boss gets
a belly dance from a friend
of Charlie's.
What?
A good friend of mine
back in Texas
is a well-known
belly dancer.
It's always been her dream
to perform in Egypt,
so she's our way in.
While she's dancing for
the Defense Minster, we'll
be talking to the Deputy.
Oh, my God.
No, she's supposed to be good.
That's an extraordinary
woman.
Oh, yeah.
That's not any belly dance
I'm familiar with.
That's why I wanted the
Defense Minister to see her.
This is your girlfriend?
Carol's a friend.
She's an old friend.
I understand her father
didn't allow dancing because
of the religion?
Yeah, that's correct.
And what religion is that?
You know, she's a Baptist.
As I was saying, the Russians
will learn, I'm quite
afraid the hard way,
to fear God's vengeance
upon those
who oppress his humble
servants who submit
to him in Islam.
Their skulls will hang
from the treetops.
You can do whatever you like
with their skulls, I suppose.
What has Gus here concerned is
a SA surface-to-air missiles
you all have.
For some reason, he thinks
they were stored poorly.
No, no, no, the SA-7 s
were stored properly.
Excuse me. What about
the oppression of my people?
Oh, Zvi.
I beg your pardon?
Fellows, we have
to do this now.
I am about to arrange
for $35 million worth of guns
to be put into the hands
of Muslims!
I meant no disrespect.
Oh, really?
Well, anyway, that...
None of this is important.
You have Soviet-licensed
factories that can put
out Kalashnikovs
at a rate of 25,000 a week?
That's correct.
What about city warfare
devices?
What kind?
Bicycle bombs, limpet mines,
plastic, tripwire mines?
Yes, yes. Whatever you need.
We can't improve
the price now,
but when we come back
for more, we'll make
it up to you.
I agree.
All right.
Hey, you did good back there
ignoring the religious shit.
'Cause these people are
totally fucking unspooled,
and I'm not just talking
about the Muslims.
Zvi's all right.
Oh, I know he is.
He is Mossad, by the way.
What I'm talking about is
your friend in Houston.
Now, she's got to stop
throwing fundraisers and
she's got to stop doing press.
Joanne is raising awareness.
She's using
a non-secular vocabulary
and framing this
as a religious war.
And America doesn't
fight religious wars.
Is that right?
Yeah, that's why
I like living there.
Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
This is your captain.
We will begin our initial
descent
into Washington
Dulles Airport.
I got to go down
to Houston, so...
... I would like to thank you
and hope...
Well, talk to her.
Yeah, I'll talk to her.
You want me to go into
business with the Israelis?
Just for this one purpose,
yes, Mr. President.
The Israelis have the largest
stockpile of Soviet-made
weapons in friendly hands.
I know that.
I need to trust that
this arrangement
will remain secret.
Pakistan and Israel would
have to appear to be enemies
in the public eye.
Yeah, I don't think
that's a tough sell.
You have authority
to do this?
None whatsoever. In fact,
I'm pretty close to
violating the Logan Act.
Well, I don't know
what that is.
But, Charlie.
Yes, sir.
If I see one fucking
Star of David on a crate...
You won't. I promise.
Hey.
Excuse me.
You want me to take a look
at those remarks?
Why?
Just... Well,
your introduction,
want me to look it over?
It's an introduction, Charlie.
I'll be fine.
Today we honor President
Zia ul-Haq of Pakistan.
Before we go any further,
I would like you all
to know this,
President Zia did not
kill Bhutto.
In the time that
he's been President,
the fortunes of Pakistan
have changed radically.
I've asked you all here
today...
You disappeared.
Well, they weren't
selling alcohol in there.
It's a traditional
Pakistani gathering.
You think they might be
a lot happier over there
if they could just get women
and booze in the same room
at the same time?
I think they'd be a whole
lot happier over there
if the Communists got out.
"Zia did not kill Bhutto."
That's not something you
usually hear in introductory
remarks.
He didn't, Charlie.
Bhutto had a trial
and was found guilty.
Shocking verdict.
What did you need
to talk to me about?
Joanne, darling,
dial down the religion.
What?
It could alienate people
whose support we need.
It's luncheons like this
that are raising the
money we need.
This thing is not gonna
get done by ballrooms
full of people
in the Houstonian Hotel.
It's gonna get done
by the CIA, Israel,
Egypt and Pakistan,
and it's gonna get
done quietly.
Now, you start making
people think
we're trying to convert
everybody to Christianity.
I was saved by Jesus Christ,
Charlie, and I am not
ashamed of it.
My fervor is not about
religion, it's about
freedom of religion,
which we have, they want,
and the Communists
are slaughtering them for.
And I get it.
Just tamp down the fervor.
Well, I can't modulate
God's will, sweetie.
You can try.
Now, I got to get back to D.C.
They've set up a briefing
for me at Langley.
On what?
On getting the guns.
Afghanistan's barely
a country.
There's no phones or roads
outside the cities.
It's likely that a villager
would live his life
without having contact with
another village just three
miles down the road
unless he was going
to war against them.
Now, my thinking is instead
of 400,000 sloppy guys,
we concentrate on
several elite forces
totaling about 150,000.
Give these guys
real training,
20 different courses covering
irregular warfare disciplines.
And do you have anybody
in mind?
The most successful rebels
today are in the
Panjshir Valley.
They're called the
United Front of the
Council of the North.
We've earmarked them
for 10 million in weapons
and 10 to 15 agency advisors
for training.
Who's their leader?
Ahmed Shah Massoud.
He's Tajik, so he's not well
liked by the Pashtun.
So the... What,
the Tajiks have a problem
with the Pashtuns?
Well, they say when a Tajik
wants to make love to a woman,
his first choice is always
a Pashtun man.
It's funnier in
the original Pashto.
All right, I've heard enough.
I'm going to go get our money.
All right, don't fuck
us up now.
Awesome pep talk.
Afghanistan, Egypt, Pakistan
and Saudi Arabia,
these are all totalitarian
dictatorships.
And they'd like to blow the
only democracy in the region
right into the Mediterranean.
Now, you heard me say
that Israel's gonna
be on board.
Oh, well, Zvi Rafiah's
out of his mind.
These people are draconian
thugs, and in an evil
and twisted derby
between the Communists
and the Fundamentalists,
it's 6-to-5 and pick them,
as far as I'm concerned.
No, you're wrong about that,
Doc, and you know
you don't mean it.
In Pakistan, a blind girl
gets raped, but there's
a witness.
Now, in Pakistan it takes
four witnesses.
So the rapist walks away
and the girl is in prison.
Can you tell me why?
Well, fornication.
That's right.
Mr. Chairman, President Zia
is the only one willing
to shoulder the risk
of actively training
and funding the mujahideen
while Egypt
and Saudi Arabia...
Now, the Saudis are matching
any funding from Congress?
That's right.
So when you say 40 million
to me,
you're really talking
about 80 million.
Only 40 from us.
You want to put $80 million
in the hands of these people?
No, see, Doc, now, if you took
a trip with me to the border,
you'd stop calling them
"these people."
They are farmers and children
mostly, and they are fighting
our enemies for us.
I know.
And that should be
impossible for America.
I know.
It should be impossible
for America
to sit on the bench while
little kids and their
mothers fight our enemies.
Now, all you have to do
to change that is to
support me
in the Committee,
Mr. Chairman.
I'm sorry, Charlie,
but doubling from 5
to 10 million is one thing,
but, you know,
I just can't get behind this.
Joanne Herring's
residence. Who's speaking?
Miss Herring, Congressman
Wilson for you.
Hello.
Hey.
Tell me what's happening.
Well, I need Doc Long,
and he's not getting on board.
Now, he's a church-going guy,
so I thought,
you know, maybe you could...
So now you need God.
Yeah. Let me give you
his private line.
I've got it.
Trish!
Yes, ma'am.
Boss?
Yeah.
Hey, that's a nice sweater.
Oh, thank you.
The Washington Times wants
to know if you've ever
been in rehab.
Well, what are you gonna
tell them?
That you won't go to rehab
'cause they don't serve
whiskey there.
Well, that's why you're
the press secretary, boo-boo.
I've got Stu on the line.
Can you jump on?
Yeah.
Hey, Stu, it's me.
All right.
No, she's not a stripper, Stu.
She just posed for
the cover...
Oh, what the hell
difference does it make?
They're talking
to Crystal today.
Yeah.
Giuliani subpoenaed
the limo driver.
Oh, that's what Gus
said he'd do.
Well, the limo driver said
he didn't see anything.
He didn't see anything.
So Giuliani subpoenaed
every limo driver
between Arlington and Silver
Spring to see if any of them
can recall you using cocaine.
Joanne Herring's
on the phone.
Hey, you.
We're all leaving
in the morning.
You're kidding?
No.
Well, what did you have
to promise him?
There's a blind girl in jail
'cause she was raped.
Yeah.
You're gonna get her out.
What, I got to bust somebody
out of jail?
Don't be stupid, Charlie.
You're gonna tell Zia
to pardon her.
That's Doc's condition.
I'll fly in tonight.
Buy me a drink?
Yes, ma'am.
We're almost there, Charlie.
I'm going back to Pakistan
tomorrow!
Let's party!
Charlie!
Oh, that was... I'm gonna...
You want a refill here,
darling?
Thanks.
Can we get another round?
Mario!
Oh, Charlie.
Hey, Joanne.
Can I call you Joanne?
Yes.
You'll want to dress
considerably more modestly
when we're at the border.
Well, thank you, but I have
been passionately involved
with the cause of the Afghans
for three years.
I've been there many times.
Okay, well, then I'll just
go fuck myself.
I am not easily shocked,
Mr. Avrakotos.
I knew you two were gonna
hit it off right away.
Charlie!
Sorry, Stu's on the phone.
You can take it at the bar.
Stu. This can't be good.
How'd you hook up
with Charlie?
Are you also passionately
involved with the cause
of the Afghans?
No, I just wasn't really
doing anything else.
I mean, how did you
get into the CIA?
Oh, I didn't. I'm with
the Department of Agriculture.
Food and Plant Division.
Specifically apple imports.
Now, you don't seem like
the apple type.
I know.
What's that mean?
Where are you from?
What do you care?
Are you a Catholic?
Greek Orthodox, Mrs. Herring.
That's still Christian.
Imagine my relief.
What's your problem with me?
You know, I've found,
in my business,
that when people with time
on their hands get involved
in politics,
I start forgetting
what I'm supposed to be
shooting at.
That would be in the apple
import business.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll have to remember that.
Please do.
It's over!
It's over! It is over!
That was Stu, and it is over.
Wait, wait, wait.
Crystal didn't name you?
Well, she witnessed
me doing coke
in the Cayman Islands.
Oh, shit, Charlie.
No, it's all right. That's out
of the Justice Department's
jurisdiction,
so it is over.
I'm going home!
Gus, Joanne, the most
important trip of our
lives is in the morning,
so let's get plenty of sleep.
I'm going home.
Jailbait, slap my hands!
Yeah!
Mario, this is all on me.
Yes, sir.
He may be in trouble with
the press, but he stayed
out of jail.
You don't see
God's hand in this?
Well, reasonable people
can disagree,
but I don't see God anywhere
within miles of this.
On the other hand,
if you slept with me tonight,
I bet you I could change
my mind in a hurry.
Oh, you would.
Yeah.
I'll see you on the plane.
Sluts.
Doc's eating this up.
Yeah?
We're gonna get the money.
Charlie?
Charlie!
Guy's a little senile.
Don't be fooled.
He chairs a Subcommittee?
Mmm-hmm.
Charlie, Joanne, this has been
an absolutely eye-opening
experience.
I mean, it's absolutely
stunning.
Tell them what we saw,
Mr. Papadropolous. Tell them.
They only want to go back
there and fight.
And you're their savior,
Mr. Chairman.
Oh, I wouldn't go
that far, no.
Watch this.
She's gonna lock it right
on up.
Mr. Chairman,
these people have been
waiting for you. They have
been sitting here
and bleeding and waiting
and praying for you.
It's only gonna be a man
like you who can save them.
We know, don't we,
about our men,
what they can do
when they summon
themselves.
Charlie, I think
they want you to make
some remarks.
No, you should do it,
Mr. Chairman.
These people have been
waiting a long time for you.
Show Muriel what you can do.
Show your wife.
I'm a little bit emotional
about what I've seen
here today.
Show her.
You can do it.
Go on.
All right.
Papadropolous.
Well, it's Greek.
It's in the ballpark.
My friends,
my son served in Vietnam.
He was wounded fighting
in battle against
the Soviet oppressors.
I didn't know that
about his son.
So, you see,
I'm no stranger,
no stranger at all to
the horrors and atrocities
of the Communists!
Thank you so much.
I talk about God for
one simple reason.
As God is my witness today...
We need him on our side.
... these Russian gunships,
every last one of them,
are gonna be blown right
out of the sky.
We're gonna see that you
have guns and we're gonna
see that you have training!
Thank you.
Well, what I think's got
Gus worried
is that sooner or later
God is gonna be on both sides.
This is good against evil.
And I want you to know
that America's always
going to be
on the side of the good.
And God will always punish
the wicked!
God is great!
This has been
a year of setback
and frustration.
And the Soviet Army,
more than at any time
since the war began,
Now has the upper hand.
The mujahideen are
pinned down.
The Afghan resistance has
been sanctified by
the United States,
but the support has not been
translated into military
hardware.
The guerrillas still cling
to the Kalashnikov,
but it's not enough.
They're waiting in vain
for bigger modern weapons
to turn on the Red Army.
The guerrillas survived
the raid.
The Soviets now are conducting
some of the heaviest bombing
of the war.
The Soviets have put more
troops and equipment back in.
Communist bastards.
Don't send us rice
and bandages,
give us weapons
so that we can shoot
down their gunships.
It's called the MILAN
anti-tank missile.
Can the Afghans
win without it?
No.
End of discussion.
I would like
to have the previously
approved sum increased
by an additional 30 million,
bringing the total
appropriation to 70 million.
I'd like to introduce
the MILAN anti-tank missile.
We've got 300 in the field.
Yeah!
Yep.
Let's kill some Russians!
Voting to pump up the money
for the freedom fighters
is the only way
for the northeastern liberal
to prove that he's serious.
How much are you asking for?
I'd want to go from 70 million
to 100 million.
And if you vote for me,
I can deliver the Black
Caucus for the farm subsidy.
And they asked him,
quite reasonably enough,
"How did you vote on that?"
And I swear to God,
he looks over
at his staff guy.
He had to check with
an aide for an answer
to that question.
I don't know how that guy
stays in office.
It was the Bamian-led group.
They set an ambush here
at the Fuladi Bridge.
What'd they get?
Four supply trucks coming out
of Bagram Airbase.
They hit a Soviet motorized
rifle battalion on horseback?
You bet your ass.
Then these guys are
pretty good.
We can't control this
thing anymore.
The man stood in my office
in Islamabad, and I told him,
"A sudden influx of money
"and weaponry..."
Could you hand me that belt,
please?
Thank you.
I mean, how is it possible
that this congressman
of no particular importance
is doing this by himself?
I will admit it's not
unimpressive.
Is this the war we want
to be fighting, Henry? Huh?
Harold, whatever he's doing,
believe me, it's working.
The CIA estimates that
seven out of every 10 times
the muj fires a Stinger,
a Soviet chopper or a plane
falls out of the sky.
Now, Russian MiGs
go for $20 million,
Stingers go for 60-70,000.
What do you want to do?
Well, I'd like to double
to 250 million.
Remind me again,
where did this thing start?
5 million.
Hello?
Is this Mrs. Joanne
King Herring Davis?
Where's it at, Charlie?
How's the honeymoon?
Am I ever gonna see you
naked again?
Where's it at, Charlie?
500 million.
Matched by the Saudis.
One billion dollars.
That's right.
Billion with a "b."
Where does this rank relative
to other covert wars?
There's never been anything
else like it.
Since when?
Ever.
I miss you, Charlie.
I, Joanne,
I always miss you.
I better go.
There's nothing
wrong with that!
And out in Polk, there's
the polecat who took
us over the side there.
You know, that's the truth.
What do you got?
Is that Gus? You got it.
Hey, Gus!
Congratulations on your
reelection.
Yeah, thank you.
Tell me what you know.
All right. Doc Long
is gonna lose.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We saw that coming.
Yeah, so who's gonna be
our wallet now?
John Murtha.
And is that good news?
Yep.
Why?
I was his vote on
the Ethics Committee.
You know, you're a very,
very easy man to like,
Congressman.
Call me tomorrow morning
at high noon.
I will. Bye-bye.
We present you with
this Stinger tube.
There was wild
jubilation inside the
country of Afghanistan
as last weekend it became
the first country in history
to defeat the mighty
Soviet Union.
The retreat of Soviet military
power from Afghanistan
is complete.
The last of Russia's regular
army invasion force is out.
Fear and uncertainty
were mixed with joy today
as the commander
of Soviet troops
followed the last of his men
across the border.
CBS News Moscow correspondent,
Barry Petersen, begins
our coverage.
It was the last hurrah.
The final Soviet combat troops
crossing the Friendship Bridge
on the border
between Afghanistan
and the Soviet Union.
The Soviet commander,
Lieutenant...
Look what you did, Charlie.
Hey, it's... Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey!
It's traditional to make
a gesture towards
the vanquished.
Gus, it's your honor.
Okay.
Reports that some Afghan
units have...
Well, here's to you,
you motherfuckers.
... determined to show
the world that the era of
Soviet military intervention
in other countries
is now over.
Well, I told you.
Told me what?
All we had to do
was shoot down
the helicopters.
Listen, not for nothing,
but do you know the story
about the Zen master
and the little boy?
Oh, is this something
from Nitsa,
the Greek witch of Aquilippa,
Pennsylvania?
Yeah, as a matter
of fact, it is.
There was a little boy,
and on his 14th birthday
he gets a horse.
And everybody in the village
says, "How wonderful!
The boy got a horse."
And the Zen master says,
"We'll see."
Two years later, the boy falls
off the horse, breaks his leg.
And everybody in the village
says, "How terrible!"
And the Zen master says,
"We'll see."
Then a war breaks out,
and all the young men
have to go off and fight,
except the boy can't
'cause his leg's
all messed up.
And everybody in the village
says, "How wonderful!"
And the Zen master says,
"We'll see."
So you get it.
No. No, I don't
'cause I'm stupid.
You're not stupid.
You're just in Congress.
Send them money.
You can start
with the roads.
Move on to the schools,
factories.
Gus, now, it's a party.
Restock the sheep herds.
Hey.
Give them jobs,
give them hope.
I'm trying. I'm trying.
Yeah, well, try harder.
I'm fighting
for every dollar.
Yeah, yeah.
I took you from 5 million
to a billion.
I broke the ice on the Stinger
and the MILAN.
I got a Democratic Congress
in lockstep behind
a Republican President.
Well, that's not good enough
'cause I'm gonna hand you
a code word classified
NIE right now,
and it's gonna tell you
that the crazies have
started rolling
into Kandahar like it's
a fucking bathtub drain.
Jesus, Gus, you could depress
a bride on her wedding day.
Hey.
Listen to what
I'm telling you.
You did a hell of a job for
the son of a soda pop maker.
"We'll see,"
said the Zen master.
$1 million for school
reconstruction?
Oh, shit, Charlie.
Listen.
He's like the congressman
from Kabul.
Did you hear me say it was
a million, not a billion,
for school construction?
Yeah, we heard you.
Everybody heard you, buddy.
They heard you in Dover,
Delaware.
Well, I sure hope I'm not
annoying you, Bob,
'cause that's the last thing
I want to do.
Look...
I was in the Roosevelt Room
with the President last week.
You know what he said?
He said, "Afghanistan?
Is that still going on?"
Well, it is.
Half the population
of that country
is under the age of 14.
Charlie.
Half the population is
under the age of 14.
Now, think how fucking
dangerous that is.
They're gonna come home
and find their families
are dead,
their villages have
been napalmed.
And we helped kill the guys
who did it.
Yeah, but they don't
know that, Bob,
'cause they don't
get home delivery
of The New York Times.
And even if they did,
it was covert, remember?
This is what we always do.
We always go in with
our ideals
and we change the world
and then we leave.
We always leave.
But that ball, though,
it keeps on bouncing.
What?
The ball keeps on bouncing.
Yeah, we're
a little busy right now
reorganizing Eastern Europe,
don't you think?
We've spent billions.
Let's spend a million
on H.R.118 and rebuild
a school.
Charlie, nobody gives a shit
about a school in Pakistan.
Afghanistan.
So, for the first time,
a civilian is being given
our highest recognition,
that of Honored Colleague.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the Clandestine Services,
Congressman Charles Wilson.
Bravo, Charlie.