'Pushkin's Poems'
Luggage?
Have a safe journey, Doctor.
My name is Nicolai Borodinski,
I'm from Russia.
I am traveling from Moscow to Paris.
One night please. Thank you.
You have to pay in advance.
Goodbye.
Good day.
Good night.
Russian? Me too.
Where are you from?
Odintsovo, close to Moscow.
I am from Novgorod.
Aren't you going to ask me
if I would like a drink?
I'm sorry.
What would you like to drink?
And what brings you here?
I'm on my way to Paris...
...to study, science - medicine...
...and to improve my French.
A Doctor...
I also wanted to go to Paris...
...to follow my love.
But he turned out to be a bastard...
...and now I'm stuck in this swamp.
Stupid.
Love destroys everything.
Love is an illusion.
Why don't you return to Russia?
That's a long story.
I will go back, to Moscow,
in a few years.
When I have finished my studies.
You're homesick already.
But time goes so fast...
Maybe I'll see you again...
...on your way back home as a Doctor...
...then I'll go with you.
I'm Nina.
Borodinski... Nicolai.
Meet Bruno...
...he's obsessed with me.
A stupid bastard and very jealous.
What did she say?
What did you say?
Her name is Elise...
...and that was the Count.
He is not a real Count,
he bought the title...
...like he bought this hotel,
like he buys everything...
...and everyone. All this... is his.
He's a dirty old man.
But he's not to be trifled with.
Don't you understand?
He owns everything.
Including Elise...
She's lucky.
He does everything for her,
he's good for her.
Forget about her...
...and go on to Paris.
You have no chance.
One night... again.
Again?
I want to have flowers delivered.
A big, beautiful bunch of flowers.
I want...
Not a good idea...
...and a waste of good money.
I would like...
He wants to have a bunch
of flowers delivered to Elise.
Large! Very large!
The accompanying words.
I remember a wonderful moment.
As before my eyes you appeared.
Like a vision, fleeting, momentary.
Like a spirit of the purest beauty.
Then to my soul an awakening came.
A Godlike face, an inspiration.
And life, and tears, and love.
Your signature.
You see? You don't have a chance.
Tell me about her. Who is she?
Listen. I love her very much.
She has been through so much.
You could never understand.
Now she is happy, leave her be.
You have nothing to offer her.
I must tell you something.
No one knows this...
It is a secret and hard to understand.
You have never known poverty
and humiliation.
Elise comes from a small village in Holland.
She was the daughter of a day-laborer...
...and never knew love.
Her father beat and abused her as a child.
He also murdered her mother...
...beat her to death.
God rest her soul.
So she learned to hate men.
Her father was caught,
and later himself killed, in prison.
Elise was lucky, and ended up
in a German orphanage...
...which hired her out to a noble family,
where she worked as a domestic servant.
They taught her to speak French,
play the piano and good manners.
Good manners...
but these people also abused her.
She fled and ended up here.
Under my protection.
Now she no longer suffers poverty,
she has everything her heart desires.
She is happy...
...even though she doesn't know
what love is.
What is this?
You can have it.
Don't throw these out.
Elise is coming soon.
Don't forget, she is a whore.
She costs money...
...a lot of money, money you don't have.
I can arrange a 'rendezvous' for you.
But just once.
No one, no one at all, may know!
If someone finds out,
everything will be lost.
You have to give me your word of honor.
Yes or no?
Then you will go away for ever.
You will never return. Never.
For my services...
I do this for you.
If the Count finds out
something very bad will happen.
It would be a disaster for Elise.
You have to wait.
Remember our agreement.
The key.
To her room.
Stay here.
What?
What do you want?
What do you want!
I am leaving and wanted to say
goodbye before I depart...
...only to say goodbye to you.
Good. Well... goodbye.
Farewell then.
Yours?
Another night.
Please go away.
Leave me alone.
You asked me...
...to come here.
Forget what happened.
Forgive me.
It is my fault.
If you really care for me,
you will leave now.
Please...
Go away.
Tomorrow.
I will just stay tonight.
Where were you?
Young man... take a seat.
Anyone can win.
Fortune favors the bold.
I've not seen you here before.
Who are you?
I can't understand you,
I don't speak German.
l-no-ski speak-i Germani,
Russki, Russki.
What's that!?
Send for a Doctor immediately.
A Doctor straightaway!
You must go now. Quickly.
I want to thank you.
I am ashamed
you have to see me like this.
I like having you near me...
...but we cannot be together.
This is our destiny.
I have nothing...
I have nothing to offer you.
I don't have a choice.
Where is she?
She was unwell, she is sleeping.
But... she is sleeping!
She feels bad, she is asleep,
let her rest.
I promise you...
I promise you I will come back.
And then I will take you away with me.
But first you have to get well.
Forgive me.
I am sorry.
You know I have
your best interests at heart.
'I will come back. Wait for me.'
The lady cannot see you now.
I have to know how she is.
I have a gift, then I will go.
I only wanted to see you one more time.
I beg you... please don't come back.
I beg you... forget me.
Please.
I am sure that he is leaving now,
and will not return.
We will not be seeing him again.
What do you want?
You have slept for two whole days.
A lot of rest, not too much movement.
Most likely your bone isn't broken...
...but is it a bad bruising of your leg.
I think.
You were lucky.
That will be 150 Marks.
Here.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
I am very sorry, but now that the Count
is no longer paying for your stay here...
...someone else must foot the bill.
Once again, my question is not only
entirely justified, but also self-evident.
Who is going to pay for all this?
This is all we have.
- That's not enough.
The Doctor said I have to stay here,
in your bed.
Your French is perfect.
My compliments.
You must rest, sleep and eat well.
How are you, Elise?
For you. From Paris.
It is much too expensive.
I don't want you to give me things.
What use is it to me? It's too late.
That's all I could get for the jewelry.
I am going. See you tomorrow.
My days dragged quietly by...
...nothing was new.
No Godlike face...
...no inspiration.
No tears...
...no life...
...no love...
...no you.
Then to my soul an awakening came...
...and there again your face appeared.
Like a vision, fleeting, momentary...
...like a spirit of the purest beauty.
And my heart beat with a rapture new...
...and for its sake arose again.
A Godlike face, and inspiration...
...and life...
...and love...
...and tears...
...and you.
It is enough. For the time being.
For now. But we will be back.
Who let them in?
They came in all by themselves.
They will take everything.
What are we supposed to do?
Have you any idea what you are doing?
Of course, it is nothing to do with me.
But how do you think we can carry on?
How will it end?
It is no good.
She has nothing but debts.
She is not well.
Since you turned up,
she has got ill again.
She must go outside...
she needs fresh air.
We must leave here.
Outside? Fresh air?
She cannot leave here.
Do you still not understand?
We are leaving this place.
Going away from here.
The coach is here.
We must go.
We are leaving.
Your departure is in order...
...but the lady has some unpaid bills.
And they are quite large.
You are free to go...
...but the lady must stay here
until the debt has been cleared.
The lady has made her own bed...
Scandal. Blackmail.
It is much too large, this is impossible.
It is impossible for the bill
to be so large.
This is blackmail.
A scandal!
What is this, it cannot be.
Swindle!
The lady cannot leave
without paying her bill.
The gentleman may go.
You must go alone.
Please. It is hopeless.
Leave me.
I swear I will never leave you.
It is impossible to leave the hotel.
He has posted guards everywhere.
Every day, the debts just get bigger.
You should never have come back.
Elise's love for you is destroying her.
She has tuberculosis...
...and needs peace and quiet.
That is the only thing that helps.
Please, go away.
I'm going.
Actually you should leave.
That would be best for Elise.
Maybe it is better that I leave.
Go away...
...so that everything goes back
to the way it was before.
There is someone there.
There is someone.
Sleep, my sweet girl...
...my beautiful...
Bayushki Bayu.
Quietly the moon is peeking...
...into your cradle.
I will tell you fairy tales...
...and sing you sweet songs.
I want you to leave.
I don't want...
I want you to forget me.
I want us to say goodbye, for good.
You must forget me.
It is better.
Better for you.
Don't touch me.
It's all my fault.
I have made up my mind.
It's over.
We have to stop.
Go now.
I beg you!
I don't love you any more.
I have nothing more to give you...
...and you have nothing more for me.
You know nothing of me.
Life is temporary.
We will have a beautiful memory.
You must set yourself free from me.
Life is one big goodbye.
We each have to follow our own path
and each lead our own life.
You will find a new companion.
I am sure of it.
I hope she will love you as much as I do.
Be strong, you can not leave now.
Damn.
Trust me, there is nothing wrong
with these cards.
Trust me. It is a brand new deck.
Help Nicolai.
Here...
...for your services rendered...
Once a whore, always a whore.
Elise never loved anyone but you.
I beg you, give her one more chance.
Everything Elise did,
was out of love for you.
And I know how much you love her.
I beg you, don't go away.
Don't go away.
Where is he?
He is gone.
He escaped.
The Count is dead.
He is really gone.
He will return and I will wait for him.
I know he loves me.
She has tuberculosis...
...her resistance is too low.
There is nothing more I can do.
She won't live to see the spring.
The disease can't be stopped.
The hotel is closing...
...where can she go?
What can we do now?
I will stay with her.
You can leave without worrying.
It will not take long.
She is exhausted.
In my opinion, a matter of days.
Thank you, Doctor.
What is it?
What are you doing?
Are you leaving?
I love everything...
...that has a warm enchanted feeling...
...like the spring and love...
...and dreams and fantasies.
Everything we call poetry.
When spring comes again...
...everything will be well.
They are waiting for you...
...you must go.
It will be alright.
I love you.
This is Nicolai's...
...would you give it to him
if you see him.
You promise?
I promise.
I have to wait here for him...
...otherwise he won't be able to find me.
Olga will take care of me.
Thank you, Doctor.
Nicolai?
What are your symptoms?
Nicolai, it's you!
It's me. Nina.
Don't send me away.
You still have those beautiful hands.
A little older.
Nina...
How many years?
How many winters?
You know how it goes.
The hotel closed down...
...after the death of the Count.
I went with Bruno...
...but he soon found another woman.
I later found out he was killed in the war.
I have only just been allowed
to return to Moscow.
It wasn't easy to find you.
Why did you come looking for me?
Elise is dead...
She is buried there.
How have you been, all these years?
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Although...
the body is not so strong as it was.
I'm alone, my wife died two years ago.
Children?
Two sons...
...killed in the war.
God rest their souls.
Terrible.
That wretched war.
That's also the reason
I couldn't find you sooner.
But I had to find you...
...I promised Elise.
Did you ever go back?
When I left the hotel...
...Elise stayed behind.
She said she was going to wait for you.
I said I would give you this, from her.
Thanks, Nina.
'Dear Nicolai. I know you love me,
and I will wait for you, forever. Elise.'
Where is that woman?
I let her out. Fifteen minutes ago.
A Godlike face, an inspiration;
And life, and tears, and love...
...and you.
Sleep, my sweet girl...
...my beautiful...
Bayushki Bayu.
Quietly the moon is peeking...