THE TALL BLOND GUY WITH ONE BLACK SHOE
Somewhere in New York...
You were arrested at customs in New York...
...trying to get through with a car
containing 40 kilos of heroin. Do you confess?
Yes. I've asked for
a lie detector test.
Because I'm telling the truth.
And you say that you're not...
...a drug trafficker?
- No, I'm not.
Whom are you working for?
- The counter intelligence of my country.
I came from the USA on a mission.
I'm not a drug trafficker.
What kind of mission?
The head of my service told me
to get the drugs to the USA.
He should be held responsible
for the matter.
I'm innocent.
Somewhere in Paris...
Yes. Come in.
Back from holidays already, sir?
Sit down.
What's this mess, dear Bernard?
I'm more surprised than anybody, sir.
- Really?
Yes. I found out through the press.
I'm astonished.
Somebody's making a fool of me.
It's nasty.
Very nasty, sir.
- This trafficker pretends...
...he's working for me, but he isn't.
- He's not working for me either.
Well for whom does he work then?
- I don't know, sir.
This situation could cost
me my job. You will...
...succeed me as head of the service.
- No matter who'll succeed you...
...I'm sure he'll try
to follow in your footsteps.
With the same goals and energy.
Thank you, dear Bernard.
Have you ever seen this
trafficker?
Never, sir.
It's a fake!
A fake? That's possible.
Bloody well done then,
but it's possible.
Alright... that was all.
You can go to work.
Bernard.
Bernard?
Yes, sir?
Did you receive my case of wine?
Yes, I wanted to thank you.
You shouldn't have...
- I said to myself:
What's a good present to
give to Saint Bernard?
First I thought of a cask of rum.
And then I remembered
that our friend Milan...
...loves good wine.
- But a case of Mouton-Rothschild!
And from 1970.
- It's excellent.
Store it in a good cellar and
drink it to my health in ten years.
I hope we'll drink it together, sir.
Why not?
Yes, sir.
The thing with the car failed.
I didn't find dear Bernard
in very good shape.
No, not very.
- He should take a holiday.
Come in, dear Perrache.
- He just arrived home, sir.
Excuse me, sir. How was
your holiday, sir?
It was a good holiday, Perrache.
Very good.
Very quiet.
We had a good rest.
Mother came back in great shape.
A cure of 10 days makes her
10 years younger.
We didn't have great weather, but
the climate is very invigorating.
When we came back to Paris,
we felt like we were suffocating.
The cure is mainly about
fresh air.
There is no pollution yet
in the Puy-de-Dôme.
It was nice. And the mud
baths were marvellous.
Hot mud really relaxes the nerves.
And afterwards they put you
under ice cold water.
He's also bugging your apartment.
A car full of drugs...
...microphones in the statues.
Milan doesn't stop at anything.
He's behind the affair with the car,
but I can't prove it.
I discovered the microphones
by coincidence.
It was well done.
He's working hard for it.
- I hate careerists.
They never get very far.
- We should remind him that...
...it's not his job to do
what he can to replace...
...you as the head of the service.
Why the microphones?
- Milan played a dirty trick on me...
...and he's expecting me to hit back.
It is fun to imagine him...
...trembling with fear behind
his phone tapping equipment.
He should keep that on.
He'll catch a cold.
Milan deserves to be
taught a lesson.
I don't want an assistant who confuses
intelligence with dirty games.
The best duck pâté
I've ever had.
Mother had three servings.
She wouldn't listen to reason.
I told her: "Mother, you're going
to be sick".
But, dear Perrache, I didn't
make you come here...
...to tell you about my holiday.
Tomorrow morning, at 9:30,
a man arrives at Orly.
This man should be able to help us
quickly clear up...
...this dirty American mess.
You have to look after him.
Alright, sir.
I hope we can keep the service
out of this affair.
Of course, sir.
- This man will need protection.
Make sure he's safe
and take Poucet and Chaperon with you.
I have faith in them.
- Yes, sir.
Nine thirty at the airport.
Don't be late, Perrache,
It's important.
And a big secret.
Understood, sir.
- Do you like Italian food?
What?
Tomorrow morning, at Orly,
at nine thirty...
This man should be able to help us
quickly clear up...
...this dirty American mess.
- Damn!
The guy we're meeting...
Who is it?
I don't know
- Excuse me?
I don't know. Go to Orly, tomorrow
at nine thirty and pick a man.
I don't understand.
- Yes, pick one. Choose anybody.
A man from the crowd.
As anonymous as possible.
It doesn't matter at all
who you'll pick.
It's make believe.
What matters is that
Milan takes the bait.
I'll tell you what you'll be looking for
at the airport, dear Perrache:
...an asshole trap!
Who is this guy we have to protect?
Well? Who is it?
- You don't need to know.
Follow him discretely.
He can't notice a thing.
Arrival from Sydney.
Flight Air France nr 704, gate 17.
Is your guy from Australia?
Arrival from Sydney,
Air France flight 704, gate 17.
Choose anybody...
...a man from the crowd...
...as anonymous as possible...
Choose.
It's make believe...
Is he from Australia?
- No.
It's nine thirty.
Arrival from Munich...
He's from Munich.
Arrival from Munich,
Lufthansa flight 320, gate 12.
Is he a musician?
Is that him?
- No.
Maybe he missed the plane.
He'll be there.
Is he black?
That's him.
A tall blond guy with a black shoe.
Michel!
Excuse me, sir. I made a mistake.
François Perrin, 32 years old, single.
Violinist. Lives at 24 Rue de I'Alouette,
7th arrondissement. Arrived from Munich.
There's no file about him?
- No, sir.
Not with the intelligence service,
not with Internal Affairs.
He made a phone call from the airport.
- To whom?
To his dentist.
- And the violin case?
I want to know tomorrow who
he is and what he's going to do.
That's not a lot of time. 24 hours.
- It's all the time we have.
We have to neutralise him right away.
- Do we kill him?
I want to know what he's up to.
Go to work.
Do what it takes. Discretely.
We don't want to get caught.
Poucet and Chaperon don't know you.
Alright, sir.
- Botrel!
Why a black shoe?
Why a violinist?
- You said to pick anybody.
Yes, but why a violinist?
Because he had a black shoe.
Hello! Hello! Hello!
What? Who's speaking?
- Its doctor Müller from Munich.
You're a murderer, a butcher.
You executed him in a terrible way.
Poor Prokofiev!
Maurice, don't be an asshole.
I'm soaking, just out of the bath.
You didn't recognise me, idiot.
Do we still meet at 4?
Listen, Maurice, I lost a filling
at the airport. My tooth hurts.
Whatever, I'll be there at 4.
- I swear. I called the dentist.
Doctor Michaux can't see me until
tomorrow morning. And it hurts.
Alright, see you at 4.
- But...
Keep listening. Don't miss it
when Toulouse contacts him.
Alright, sir.
- We have to make him leave the house.
What's the name of the dentist?
- Michaux.
It's Mr. Perrin.
- Keep it open. What?
He says he's suffering badly.
- Keep it open. Alright, listen...
I'll do him in between.
Tell him to come in an hour.
Keep it open.
In an hour? Perfect.
Hello?
Hello? This is Dr Michaux's practice.
The doctor can see you...
...in an hour if that suits you.
- Alright. Well, that's great.
That's very friendly. thank you.
It's hurting a bit less.
But I'll be there in an hour.
He changed shoes.
Renault 15, orange red.
Number plate 2868 X 075.
Hello?
He's not going to the dentist.
Hello, sir.
- Why not?
I don't know, sir.
- Why isn't he going to the dentist?
Why not?
- He's going to the park.
Excuse me, sir, what?
He's going to the park...
He's going on the lake.
He's renting a boat.
- What's he doing on the lake?
Yes, what's he doing on the lake?
- He must have noticed us. No problem.
We'll wait for him at the dentist's.
What's he doing on the lake?
He's rowing.
Ah, yes. He's rowing.
- Rowing. - Rowing.
Not too close. Go to the island.
- I'm hot.
He's on the island.
In the restaurant.
He's throwing bread at the ducks?
Damn.
Hello, can you hear me?
5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0.
I can hear you fine.
Hurry. He's finished lunch.
They made him leave his place
and they're bugging the apartment.
They must be finished by now.
Milan took the bait.
He brought all his men.
- Our little plan has already shown us...
...who are in Milan's secret team.
That's good, isn't it?
There are too many people I don't
know in my own service.
Alright. You can go have lunch.
- There was a black guy at Orly...
A big black guy wearing a woollen coat.
I picked a tall blond guy...
...with a black shoe over a tall
black guy with a green woollen coat.
Listen, old man, if you want to produce
literature, wait until after you're retired.
Enjoy your lunch.
Won't you finish your leaks,
Louis?
No, thanks, mother.
Yesterday was Bernard Milan's birthday.
I hope you remembered?
- Yes, mother, I remembered.
Born in Epinal, in the Vosges,
on 28 March 1940.
Only son, late arrival...
His mother, Marie Bugeaud.
45 years old, teacher.
His father, Gérard Perrin, 55 years old,
teacher and amateur violinist.
Two teachers, retirement
came quickly.
Uneventful childhood.
His father introduced him to music.
Practising catholic.
- Homosexual?
No. Goes to the conservatory
of Strasbourg at the age of 13.
Leaves at 15 to spend
a year at a sanatorium.
Lost his virginity to the head nurse.
- How do you know?
A letter.
Relax, muffin, I'm not pregnant.
Cured, he goes to the conservatory
of Paris. First price...
28 months of military service.
Participates in none of the colonial wars.
Serves his time in army bands.
First violin in a string orchestra
for 5 years now.
Often travels abroad.
Also to the USA.
There! He worked in the USA.
I knew it.
But none of our people know him.
- But of course.
He's a super agent, working on his own.
- We took this picture from his place.
In a drawer, under a pile of shirts.
There's a message on the back.
Decode that for me.
As fast as you can.
Our specialists have been on it
for an hour. - Good.
Seemingly, an uneventful life.
- A perfect cover.
So, do we kill him?
- No.
I want to know what he's up to.
His eyes give him away.
What's he doing?
No. I told you a hundred times
you have to hold the violin correctly.
Look, hold it well
and make it really long.
Pull, push, look at me,
pull, push...
What kind of a clown is he?
François Perrin - Violin lessons
Too loud.
- Yes, the water mike is too loud.
Well, turn it down.
- No. I'd turn the others down too.
What's that idiot doing?
- Very bizarre.
Yes, it's bizarre.
He flushed?
What do you mean, he flushed?
No, I don't understand.
There must be a reason.
It's broken.
You're nervous, dear Bernard.
- I didn't see you.
And the difference is that I
always see you.
I have another little
present for you.
It's a concerto for violin and orchestra,
played by a very talented young man.
Listen to it tonight, to relax.
The violinist's really very talented.
What is it?
- Paulette.
Hello, my love.
- Hello, Paulette.
Paulette, Paulette, Paulette, listen.
I have to talk to you, Paulette.
I've been thinking a lot in Munich.
We can't go on like this.
We have to make a decision, Paulette.
We can't continue the secrecy,
the lies.
Are you recording this?
- I dreamt of you last night.
Paulette, please. I'm telling you
this is not fair...
...towards Maurice.
- Maurice's a loser.
He gets what he deserves. I dreamt
you were tearing off my clothes.
You had big burning hands and
you tore off my clothes.
Paulette, please,
leave my shirt on.
You've torn it. Are you happy now?
You're hurting me.
Hold me with all your strength.
- Stop. You're making me fall.
Oh, François...
- Paulette! Paulette! Paulette! Paulette!
Paulette!
- François! François! François!
François! François! François!
- Paulette! Paulette! Paulette!
François!
- Paulette! Ah, Paulette!
François...
- Paulette! Paulette!
- Paulette.
How does a horse sound?
- No.
Yes, how does a horse sound?
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Stop that, shit!
So, was Munich nice?
- I'm really a loser.
No.
Yes. I should have gone to
the dentist, but I got scared.
Why?
- Afraid.
I went to have lunch at the lake.
They expect me at the dentist and
I go to the lake. I'm a loser.
Well, go tomorrow. Does it hurt?
I don't know...
Scared...
By the way, do you know who's
coming at 4?
No.
- Maurice.
Maurice? What for?
- We're going bike riding in the park.
That's funny. I play horses with
you at 2 and I see your husband at 4.
He wants to get me in shape.
If only he knew...
Whose little ear is this?
- Mine.
Whose little eye is this?
Whose little mouth is this?
- Mine.
Whose cigarettes are these?
They're being bugged 24/24.
A florist's van's driving around
the building constantly.
Milan won't have a clue,
because he set up the trap himself.
We just put the cheese in the cellar
and Milan built the trap around it.
And what's going to happen
to the little cheese?
Excuse me?
- What if Milan gets rid of the tall blond guy?
That would be very stupid.
Doesn't it bother you to send
this clown to the slaughterhouse?
Does it bother you?
The tall blond guy with the black shoe...
you picked him.
Does that bother you now?
- No, sir.
Ok, hurry up, lazy bastard!
Hurry up. To work!
- Don't be stupid, Maurice.
Come one, let's go!
You've got some egg there.
- Don't be stupid, Maurice.
I bought cigars. Do you want one?
- That's nice, yes.
You'll smoke it later
and think of me.
Ok, go! To work!
He's leaving on bike with a guy.
Yes, a bicycle.
I want a photo.
He's supposed to go to the park,
unless he decides to go to the dentist now.
Don't be stupid, Maurice!
I can't follow a bike
through Paris.
Go.
Careful, they're turning.
- I can see that.
It's punctured.
- Or he didn't put the valve on right.
Do you think?
Or his tires are porous.
Shit!
Look at those little bikes.
Having a flat?
No, we're playing a game.
- There's no more quality, these days.
I remember before the war...
I'm talking before the war, gentlemen...
...they produced quality then.
- Smoke this, grandpa.
Thanks, boys... thanks.
This is going to take a while.
- His bike's completely messed up.
Now, they're running.
They put their bikes away.
He stopped. The tall blond guy
stopped and is talking to someone.
Micro canon.
Come on, you can't stop every
500 meters, lazy bastard.
Come on, we've hardly started.
- Maurice, I have to talk to you.
No way. You're not quitting. Go!
- It's about Paulette.
Play me the complete recording
of the woman again.
Paulette! Hello, Paulette.
I have to talk to you, Paulette.
I've been thinking a lot in Munich.
We can't go on like this.
A good shower
and you'll feel great.
What's that?
- Listen, Maurice...
See you tonight.
- What an idiot. What an idiot.
Maurice's a loser.
He gets what he deserves.
I dreamt you were tearing
off my clothes.
You had big burning hands and
you tore off my clothes.
Hey, stop!
Paulette! Paulette!
Paulette!
The guy on the bike's behind us.
- How does a horse sound?
No.
- Yes, how does a horse sound?
No...
Paulette has an affair with a florist.
- What?
I just caught them...
...in a delivery van. They were
going for it on the plants...
...and they said terrible things.
- Come in and sit down.
What's wrong with you?
- Nothing. Shaving cream...
...in my toothpaste.
- I stopped next to this van...
...and I hear Paulette' voice.
I fell off my bike...
...for the first time ever.
- Paulette and a florist? That's absurd.
Stop that. It's irritating.
- I told you I had shaving cream...
...in my toothpaste.
- First, I thought I was dreaming.
And then she talked about me. She said:
"Maurice is a loser."
And then she said terrible things.
François, my wife's hysterical.
Go wash your mouth.
The guy sounded a bit like you.
- Which guy?
The florist.
But that's crazy. Paulette with
a florist in a van.
It's nuts!
- But I'm telling you I heard them.
She asked him what a horse sounds like.
- But... what?
She asked him to sound like a horse.
He did and I fell off my bike.
What are you doing?
I'm calling her.
- But I'm telling you it was her...
...in a van with a horse...
- Hello, Paulette.
Hello, François speaking.
I'm here with your husband.
No, I'm fine. I'll give him to you.
Hello? Who's that?
Is that Paulette?
Good, no, yes, yes...
Yes, oh no, no, no, yes,
alright. I'll be there right away.
Yes, we did go for a run.
She's been home
for an hour with my mother.
Well, see? You were dreaming.
But...
- It's strange, François.
They found the mike in the flowers.
- Damn!
We're not getting anywhere, this way.
- We're going in circles.
We're going in circles.
He's been making fun of us since the start.
He's playing with us.
He's very good!
- We have to take him to the property...
...and execute him.
- No. We're going to try something else and...
Hello, yes? Musical instruments?
Musical instruments. Old ones.
Go to some antique shops and...
...rent some recorders, sitars,
violas d'amore, violas da gamba...
I don't care. Send it all to
85 Rue des Vignes.
We're going to have some fun.
Mr Perrin?
I saw your little ad for violin
lessons at the record shop.
Can I come in?
The lessons are not for me,
but for my son.
I have a six year old
and he loves music.
Six years is the right age, I think.
I'd prefer lessons at home.
He's so young.
My father also collected
old instruments.
He died last year.
He left it all to me.
- I see.
I don't know much about it but I
think some instruments are interesting.
If you like, I can show you
when you come to the house.
The little one's on holiday at the moment.
He won't be back until next week.
I don't intend to keep the collection.
Too many memories.
I see.
You could at least have a look.
But you'd have to be quick.
When?
- Let's see...
Tomorrow is impossible.
So is Wednesday.
What are you doing this evening?
- Today?
I invited a few friends.
Would you like to come over?
This is my address: 85 Rue des Vignes.
See you tonight.
No, tonight's impossible.
I have a concert in Gaveau at nine.
You can come over after midnight.
I go to bed very late. See you later.
She's leaving the building.
No, we don't know her.
Tall, beautiful, blonde, leopard-skin.
Distinguished, you know?
Stop.
There he is.
- There he is, sir.
Come.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Did the concert go well?
My friends just left.
Yes, they're such early birds.
Maybe I'm here too late.
- Not at all. I was expecting you.
What would you like?
Champagne, whisky, cognac?
I'd like a bit of champagne.
It's great... here.
Yes, there are some nice items.
- A giraffe piano.
The rest is in the cellar.
- In the cellar?
We can have a look later
if you like. Have a seat.
Not there. On the couch
is more comfortable.
It's so good to relax.
I'm glad the others are gone.
So nice. A bit of intimacy
from time to time.
Yes, that's true... that's true...
The others are gone. That's true...
- You seem tense.
Do I intimidate you?
- No, no, not at all.
It's hard to believe.
- What is?
All that...
But it's nothing special.
- Yes, yes. For me, it's very special.
The most beautiful woman who
ever rang my doorbell...
...and that same evening, I'm drinking
champagne in her apartment.
Is it cold enough?
Yes, yes, perfect.
- Are you hungry?
No, not right now.
Would you mind if I take of this jewellery?
I've had a hard day.
I'd like to get comfortable.
- By all means.
I'll be right back.
Serve yourself a drink if you want.
What is this...
He's very good.
I see...
I lost my cigarette...
It's better like this.
Take of your jacket.
You'll feel better.
Why don't you take off
your clothes?
What?
Take off your clothes.
I wouldn't mind a bit of champagne.
You're pulling my hair.
- No, it's stuck.
What's happening?
- The zipper's stuck.
You're hurting me.
- Excuse me. I'm so sorry.
It's the first time it got stuck.
Damn! Damn!
Damn!
Well?
- I don't know... it's crazy.
I can't stay here all night.
- No. We need a pair of scissors...
...to cut the bit that's stuck.
- In the bathroom.
I'll get it.
- Ouch!
Oh, sorry.
- I have to go with you.
Yes, that's better. Wait.
Don't get up. Stay on your knees.
Right. Now slowly go to the bathroom.
I'll follow.
I'm sorry. That's it.
It's a nice little apartment.
After you. Please.
What kind of a clown is this?
Done.
Did you hurt yourself?
I'll keep your hair.
Ok, go.
I'm sorry. It's crazy.
Aren't you hungry at all?
- I wouldn't mind a little bite now.
Cold chicken, roast beef, ham?
- A bit of chicken would be nice.
Oh no!
We'll have dinner on the bed.
My nose's bleeding. I think it stopped.
The bagpipes hit me.
The bagpipes?
- The bagpipes.
But I'm better now. I'm better.
Eat.
- I'm sorry. I'm not hungry anymore.
I'll turn off the lights. You get
undressed and get into bed.
You've had enough problems for tonight.
The platter.
I think I knocked it over.
How many sugars?
- Two.
He's taking his time to get undressed.
Are you separated from your husband?
- Yes.
And the little boy's in the countryside?
With his grandparents?
- Yes.
What does that idiot care?
- No comments please.
I'm in bed.
Some coffee?
- No, no, no.
My feet are frozen.
- That's alright.
What a strange day.
- Why?
It started this morning. My mates nailed
down my shoes in front of the door...
...of my room, in a hotel in Munich.
- I see.
They're always playing pranks on me.
I left my shoes outside...
...so they would be polished
and they nailed them down.
I had to go home wearing
one brown shoe and one black shoe.
And then there was toothpaste
in my shaving cream.
And shaving cream
in my toothpaste.
And nobody finds that strange.
And then I went running in the park,
with a friend and he had visions.
Otherwise a very normal guy.
Sports-loving, strong.
Not the type for hallucinations.
And suddenly he hears voices.
And then at the concert tonight,
I snapped a string.
And now I'm in bed with you.
And then you kiss me.
And my feet are frozen.
Ok, they're having sex.
They're making love at
85 Rue des Vignes.
As you can see, your protégé
enjoys certain perks.
Do you feel good?
- Yes.
Me too.
I'm going to tell you something
I never told anybody.
Yes?
It's a secret.
- I see.
I'm not only a violinist.
I also do something else.
I'm a composer.
- What?
I'm also a composer
but nobody knows that.
I wrote an opera. It took me three years.
And I'm still working on it.
I'll publish it when it's finished.
What?
- I feel like dedicating it to you.
What are you doing?
- I'll play it to you.
What?
- Only the main theme.
You're not going to play the violin now.
- You're the first one to hear it.
I'm warning you. It's very modern.
- Come on, François!
What's that?
- What is it?
Turn down the volume.
Enough.
Don't you like it?
- It's very beautiful, but not now.
It's very beautiful but
who wants an opera at 3 AM?
Are you angry?
- Not at all.
Come here then.
Yes, you're angry.
- Absolutely not.
Come here.
And there we go again.
We won't get anywhere tonight.
Take him to the property.
- Yes, sir.
Oh là là! You made me lose
a night, idiot!
You should have confronted him.
Toulouse's paying him and I'll pay him more.
Can't you use your head
from time to time?
When? When he gets
my hair in his zipper?
When he hits himself with bagpipes,
writes an opera, makes love to me...
...very well, by the way.
- We're going in circles, damn.
We're going in circles.
- Sir...
What?
- I don't think he's a pro.
Well, I don't care what you think.
Get dressed and go to the shop.
Oh, my Christine!
Oh, my Christine.
Christine?
- No, it's Paulette.
Ah! Hello, Paulette.
- Who's Christine?
Listen, Paulette, don't come
to my place this afternoon.
I met a wonderful girl
last night and I think I love her.
Are you pulling my leg?
- No, I'm not joking.
Poucet and Chaperon are the problem.
If we could get rid of them...
...there'd be no problem. Easy.
- Easily said...
I want the violinist here in one hour.
- Perrache just arrived at Toulouse's.
I won't wear a coat this morning.
- It's not cold, sir.
I'll stay in the office for a bit.
I have a meeting at the ministry at 11.
I see.
- Yes, the violinist finished his job.
He's going to report to us at 11.
Some people are in for a
nasty surprise, Perrache!
Find me the violinist right away
and kill him.
You have one hour.
Hello?
- François? François?
I'm calling you because I'm sad.
I can't stop crying. It's crazy.
Have pity on me, François.
I love you.
Yes, yes, I love you.
I'm lost when I'm not
in your arms.
I won't ask you to sound like
a horse. I promise, François.
But don't leave me, darling.
You must have achieved what
you wanted. Milan has gone mad...
...and the violinist is a dead man.
- Look at the road when you're driving.
Tell Poucet and Chaperon to stop
surveillance and go home.
They did a good job.
Stop surveillance... but then the
tall blond guy will be killed.
Stop questioning my orders
and look at the road.
Tell Poucet and Chaperon
to go home. Do it.
Chaperon? Perrache speaking.
The boss wants you to
tighten surveillance.
They're going to try something,
this morning. Be very vigilant.
They're going through the garden.
We're too old for this.
- Hush! Don't move.
Where's my tie?
I think it's in the living room.
Hello?
Hello, François. Christine speaking.
I have to talk to you.
I'm in the café on the corner.
Yes. Come right away.
It's very urgent.
Hello, Christine? Christine?
Talk to me, Christine.
Hello, Christine...
What are you doing here?
Go home. Mr. Milan doesn't want
you hanging around here.
Understood?
He's gone.
- Yes.
Don't move.
Come on, we're not going to
shoot each other, are we?
We're colleagues. We're not
going to kill each other, are we?
A blonde. Beautiful. She was here
3 minutes ago. She made a phone call.
Yes, she left.
- What do you mean, she left?
Well, she just left.
Maurice! Sorry, I can't see you now.
I'm meeting somebody.
There are 3 corpses
at your place.
What?
- 3 corpses at your place.
I came to kill you.
There are 3 corpses at your place.
What's wrong with you now?
- Come have a look.
But...
But Maurice, why did you want to kill me?
- You two jerked me around.
Both of you. I caught Paulette
on the phone, hypocrite!
Hypocrite! Bastard! Go in.
Well?
I don't understand...
- Come, sit down.
There were 3 corpses in this room.
- Yes, of course.
I'm not crazy, François.
- Of course not.
I heard Paulette on the phone.
- Yes. And you heard her...
...have sex in a van yesterday and
today you saw 3 corpses at my place.
Not a good sign?
- I'm not a doctor, you know.
Drink a glass of water.
- A glass of water?
Yes, it'll do you good.
A big glass of water
I'm not thirsty.
- Look at your face.
I'll get you a glass of water.
- But I'm not thirsty at all.
Here.
I'm not doing well, François.
Not well at all.
There are 3 victims, sir:
Two of Milan's men and Chaperon.
- Excuse me?
They had it out with
each other, but I assure you...
...the tall blond guy is fine.
- I thought I told you to tell...
...Poucet and Chaperon to go home.
- Really? I must have misunderstood.
I told them to tighten
surveillance.
You definitely misunderstood.
I'm very sorry, sir.
I didn't mean to go against you.
I only wanted to protect
an innocent person.
Well, you failed anyway.
Now is the hour of truth.
Milan's entering the scene.
On one side, there's Milan with...
...all his gang and on the other side
the tall blond guy with the black shoe.
This should end in a big showdown,
like in good western movies.
I have to go for a pee.
- Alright, go then.
Come with me.
- Oh, come on.
Please, come with me.
- Leave me alone.
Christine!
You were told not to come back here.
Get in.
Christine! Christine!
Christine!
- Sir, your glasses.
Lucien!
- My God!
François?
François!
Get up.
Come here.
Turn around.
- Like this?
Very good.
I'm colonel Milan,
the assistant of your boss.
Oh! Sorry, sir.
Excuse me.
Thanks.
Perrache!
Perrache.
The tall blond guy
with the black shoe.
Who is it?
It's an asshole trap, sir.
What's going on with you?
- Nothing. I'm fine.
Maurice. But Maurice...
- Go upstairs. Everything's fine.
Everything's going smoothly.
You'll see everything's fine.
You don't seem to be doing too well.
- I have a musician's insurance.
Social security...
If I find a good clinic...
...they'll refund me everything.
Hello, madam. Goodbye, madam.
Christine. Where were you?
I looked for you everywhere.
I'll tell you an incredible story.
Mysterious death of colonel Milan.
Toulouse says:
"Milan was a remarkable man."
Maurice.
Darling.
- Bye bye, Paulette.
Maurice.
Stay here. Don't move.
Come say goodbye to François.
Goodbye, François.
The doctors are reducing his
tranquillizers. He's getting better.
He has no more nightmares.
See you tomorrow. I'll be there at 2.
- See you tomorrow.
Everything will be back to
the way it was, darling.
Better go home.
He'll catch a cold.
Come.
Have a good trip. Be good in Munich.
- Bye bye.
Going to Munich?
- No. To Rio, in Brazil.
Ah, to Rio.
That's not the same desk.
No, let me.
I'll check it in myself.
Hey, sir!
Christine? Are you alright?
- I'd be better in your arms.
Do you love me?
- Yes, I love you.
When he'll be back from Rio...
- Yes, sir.
...and come back he will,
you must contact him.
After all,
the guy has a talent.
Everybody has the right
to a private life.
Article 9 of the Penal Code.
THE TALL BLOND GUY WITH A BLACK SHOE