Road Number One
Episode 19
This program has received production support
from Korea Creative Content Agency (KOCCA).
This drama spans the first year of the Korean War,
which broke out on June 25, 1950 and raged for three years.
Most of the events of the Korean War
have been dramatically recreated
and do not reflect any actual individuals or troops.
1950, war-torn and bitterly cold,
passed into the new year,
and yet, spring came once again.
Contrary to the expectations
that war would soon come to an end,
intense battles unfolded near the 38th parallel,
and the war continued mercilessly.
2nd Company, who spent the
winter recovering at Dae Jeon Hospital,
braced themselves for battle as they were deployed
on the front lines near the outskirts of Seoul.
Bombing within position!
Everyone take cover!!
Because I wanted to live,
I did it because I wanted to live.
I'm sorry.
It's me.
It's me, Su Yeon.
Su Yeon.
Su Yeon!
Forgive me.
Su Yeon.
Shin Tae Ho, I'm going to get discharged.
Lee Jang Woo, can you really abandon your Company?
Su Yeon is waiting in Yeongchon.
Attention!
Salute Captain!
At attention!
Aboard vehicle!
Aboard!
Hey you punks!
Fight fast and smart!
If I hear rumors you guys are moving sluggishly,
I'm going to rush out there and give you hell!
Oh Jong Ki!
You just take care of yourself and live well!
What? Oh Jong Ki?!
Hyungnim! Stay healthy!
I'm gonna miss you.
Stay healthy, big Hyungnim!
So long Jong Ki Hyung!
Stay healthy!
Bye!
You sons of bitches!
Don't die.
You gotta stay alive.
[May 1st, 1951, near Paju.]
This is Magpie 1, come in Black Kite.
Hey.
It's 1st Platoon Leader.
This is the Captain.
It's the enemy field artillery corp.
Judging from the size of the camouflage net,
it looks like they have at least 20 cannons.
Have you seen them with your naked eyes?
- I haven't been able to get closer.
- What kind of shoddy recon is that?
Don't you even know that the Chinese
soldiers are using logs to masquerade as cannons?!
Approach closer and confirm
whether they're real or not and report!
We don't have time.
If they are real,
as soon as they reload their ammunition,
they'll fire at our troops.
Hey 1st Platoon leader,
are you the Company Commander?!
If you receive an order, you carry it out!
Over!
What did he say?
So, did the Captain tell us to return?
We're going to approach closer until we
can confirm their fire power with our naked eye.
Excuse me?
We should relay the recon report to the superiors.
What?
If it is as Lieutenant Shin says,
not only our Company,
but the main force of the battalion
behind us will be in danger.
I think at least reporting it for now …
Hey Kim Duk Shil.
You become a Lieutenant a mere month ago,
and you're giving me advice?
Yes, I'm sorry.
If a perennial platoon leader
and a newbie lieutenant spouts nonsense,
did you think that I, as the Company
Commander would say, "Yeah sure, let's do that"?
Listen carefully.
The Company moves as I, the Commander orders.
Impudent punks, who are you trying to teach?
Who am I?
You think I got this Captain
rank by just farting around?
From the bloody stench
of the Nakdong River front line,
to the near-dead Pyeongyang,
don't you know I'm a hero of heroes
who fought all sorts of hardships?!
2nd Company!
Move out!
Is Captain Lee Jang Woo really not coming?
Our real Commander of 2nd Company.
Is that guy really going
to continue to lead our Company?
Why did a guy that left come back?
He needs more field experience to get promoted.
Be quiet.
If Captain Han Young Min hears, he'll get pissed.
I really don't like him.
Where do you think you are, pouting like that?
He'll hear you, pal.
Let him hear me.
But, what's happened to Captain Lee Jang Woo?
Did he really abandon us and get discharged?
Do you think I'd know?
Captain! What should we do?!
Captain!
Hide.
We gotta take cover!
Take cover!
2nd Company!
Disperse!!
Disperse your platoons!
3rd Platoon, disperse! Disperse!
Disperse! Disperse!
Captain!
Lieutenant, the Company is
getting fired on and is retreating.
What's the damage?
I don't know the details yet,
but I think the Captain has been killed.
Let's move.
Get down.
We're totally isolated in
the enemy territory, aren't we?
It looks like the Chinese
army have already seized this area.
There's no route to escape.
In the jaws of death like this,
I really wish he were here.
Who do you mean?
Who do you think?
Captain Lee Jang Woo.
The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
He makes me lie down in green pastures.
He leads me beside still waters;
he restores my soul.
Are you leaving now?
I'm going to regiment headquarters
and report for discharge,
and then I'll go to the reserves.
You made the right decision.
Forget all about this battlefield,
and start a new life.
You take care of yourself too, Sergeant.
And do something about that temper of yours.
That kid says she's going
to keep me as a brother forever.
Even if I have to force myself,
I'm going to pretend to be good.
But, weren't you the
one who demoted me to private?
Now that we're parting,
what's with the Sergeant, Lee Jang Woo?
2nd Company's Senior Sergeant
will always only be you, Hyungnim.
Captain Lee.
I almost didn't get to say goodbye.
I heard you went out to support a field hospital.
I have to pack some medicine and go back out.
The situation on the front lines has worsened.
Ah, I shouldn't have said anything.
Please stay healthy, Captain Lee.
You too, Captain Yoon.
By the way,
I have a request.
If you see Lieutenant Shin,
please tell him to at least write me.
How can someone be so heartless?
I'm on my way to report for discharge.
I know.
I just thought I'd ask, in case.
If you see him, just give him the message.
Then …
Who do we have here?
Lee Jang Woo!
Have you been well, sir?
What's going on?
Shouldn't you be with the division about now?
How's 2nd Company doing?
It's chaos.
The Company Commander was killed,
the bulk of the Company is retreating,
and 1st Platoon has been
caught isolated in enemy territory.
Though, it doesn't really
have anything to do with you anymore.
- Then …
- 1st Platoon means …
You're asking because you don't know?
It's Shin Tae Ho.
1st Platoon.
Magpie1, this is Black Kite Commander.
Magpie1, respond.
Isn't that the Captain's voice?
Magpie1, this is Black Kite Commander.
Magpie1! Come in!
This is Magpie1 Leader.
Come in, Black Kite Commander.
Shin Tae Ho,
it's Captain Lee Jang Woo.
Do you hear me, Shin Tae Ho?
It's Lee Jang Woo.
Captain!
Oh my God.
Is it really Captain Lee Jang Woo?
Is this a dream or real?
Report your location.
Map.
Our current position is in the
vicinity of Charlie Hotel 3356 3675.
Homing to the right,
the enemy's infantry battalion is on the move.
The battery is front and center.
We're breaking through to the right, immediately.
I'm connecting to base.
Immediately now,
we're breaking through to the right.
We're moving.
Recon team!
We're moving to the right.
Run!
To the right. Hurry!
To the right, to the right. Run!
Shin Tae Ho, we're 2nd Company.
You will absolutely live and we'll meet again.
Don't stop and keep running!
Don't stop. Run.
Keep running!
Shin Tae Ho, run.
2nd Company and I are waiting.
Don't stop. Run!
2nd Company!
It won't be long now.
Don't stop, keep running!
Keep running!
The Captain and 2nd Company are waiting!
Get down!
Lieutenant, it's our troops.
We've been saved!
Here, here, here!
Here!
In Je!
You get caught isolated in enemy territory.
You've lost all your military
discipline since I last saw you!
We were on our way back to camp.
You didn't have to come back on our account.
Now it really feels like 2nd Company! Doesn't it?
Saying the same thing over will just make
our mouths hurt. Do we really even need to say it?
I was waiting.
My boys,
I kept seeing them in my head.
I couldn't just go.
Because they're you're
Company Captain Lee Jang Woo.
Captain!
As the Battalion Commander,
this is my final order.
At the same time,
as Regiment Commander, it will be my first order.
2nd Company will move immediately to Yeongchon,
and build up defense preparations.
You're going to your homeland, 2nd Company.
To your hometown, Yeongchon.
Homeward!
I see it! I see it!
What is it?
What do they see?
It's still the same. That tree!
That tree is the first to welcome us.
Stop running!
Hooray!
This day has finally come.
I occasionally had nightmares.
This field turned into ruins,
and the tree collapsed.
It seemed so real, it was terrifying.
I never imagined I'd be returning
to an unchanged Yeongchon.
I made a promise to someone under this tree.
It was a promise of marriage.
I see.
When I look back, I wonder if it was all a dream.
Still, for some reason,
it seems fitting for promises to
be made under this tree, don't you think?
Hyungnim,
is it all right to call you that from now on?
No!
When's your birthday?
June, 1927.
June.
Then, I suppose it's okay.
Because mine's in March.
Fine.
Call me Hyungnim from now on.
I don't think I can.
I take back the Hyungnim.
Since we were born in the same year,
I think it's better we become friends.
Do you know how long the days are in May and June?
In three months, do you know how
many times a fort can be won and lost?
All right.
I'll regard you as Hyungnim from now on.
Thanks.
And, I'm sorry.
If you're sorry,
then have a good life with Su Yeon.
And be a good Hyungnim to me.
Little Brother, can I ask you a favor?
If, if by chance,
something happens to me,
look after Su Yeon for me.
You can do that for me, can't you?
Now that we're in a position
to wait for the end of the war
and hope for happy days,
why are you asking that all of a sudden?
That's why I said "if."
Can you make that promise?
Don't worry, I'll look after her for you.
Thanks.
Then, you've promised.
Captain!
Lieutenant Shin!
Come quickly. The sun's going down on us.
Okay, we're coming.
Aigoo, wait for me!
Geez, what's up with that?
Wait for me!
Baby,
do you know who's come?
Your dad has come to meet us.
Your dad.
Su Yeon.
Hello, Hyungsoonim*. (*Hyungnim's wife.)
Captain, no matter what,
you'll spend tonight out of the barracks.
What?
Give them to me.
We'll go there first.
2nd Company!
Yes, sir!
We're headed to our barracks immediately!
You came.
Have you been well, Su Yeon?
Our baby too?
Baby, Daddy's kept his promise.
He came back.
You should say hello.
This little guy is kicking me.
The baby's really strong.
I'm sure he's a boy and he's just like his dad.
So pretty.
My baby's mother.
Are you crying?
No.
My heart,
my heart is laughing.
Right. From now on, we laugh.
Okay.
I will.
Look.
I'm laughing now.
Su Yeon, I'm not dreaming right now, am I?
You didn't know? We're in a dream.
A dream we'll never wake from.
So, don't worry.
So then, before the war, 2nd Company lived here?
It's a long ways away.
It's a really long way away from Daegu.
Let's see, let's see.
This was my spot.
This was Hong Ki's.
And this was Ju Hwan's.
Those bastards.
Don't cry.
Hong Ki and Ju Hwan are gone,
but you have me and Go Man Yong.
That's right.
We'll use these spots now.
Sitting in for Hong Ki and Ju Hwan
will be Park Dal Mun and Go Man Yong.
Aigoo, it's all good.
[Captain Yoon Sam Soo]
I'm not speaking as your Captain,
but as your hyung!
You have to be cold, Tae Ho.
Cold and unemotional.
How can this Captain die, leaving our Tae Ho?
Hyungnim, I think I can
truly become a soldier now.
One like you, Hyungnim.
For the rest of my life, as a soldier,
protecting family and loved ones,
I will offer up my life.
Ahh, gently.
Now, the left arm.
You're dirty!
Oh, Su Yeon, that hurts.
You're going to take off all my skin.
What do you mean that hurts?
A Company Commander can't even tolerate this?
See, you should have
at least kept yourself washed.
I'm standing out on a live-or-die
battlefield with bullets flying.
When do I have time to wash?
There will always be some excuse.
A magpie is likely to call you Hyungnim.
Ooh, look at this murky water!
What are you trying to see, embarrassing me?
Huh?
- What?
- Where are you going?
- Come here!
- What are you trying to look at?
Come here, I'm trying to wash you!
Are you not going to come out?
Come out!
Hey!
Lee Jang Woo!
Oh.
Jang Woo.
Lee Jang Woo.
Come out!
What's the matter?
Does it hurt?
Being in this room makes me think of long ago.
Me too.
The time I snuck a peak
when you were taking a bath.
Back then, if I were the young master, I probably
wouldn't have let me get away with that either.
A servant boy daring to set
my eyes on such a pretty little lady.
Right?
Does it hurt?
Still?
No.
I'm sorry, about this scar.
I always feel bad about it.
Come here.
This isn't a scar.
It's a medal.
A medal I received in my fight
to be with you since I was young.
Right, it's a medal.
It seems like it's been such a long time,
but it's been just a year.
Yes, it's felt like a really long time.
Su Hyeok Oppa, Su Hee,
your father,
and our baby ...
They all departed,
and only the two of us remain.
No, the three of us.
Shall we lay down?
What should we name our baby?
Il Nam. Or if it's a daughter Il Soon? (Il = One)
Oh! That's too corny.
What are you talking about?
We're going to have about 10 kids,
so we have to make the names easy.
That way the kids can remember the names.
Il Nam, Yi Soon, Sam Nam, Sa Soon,
(Yi = two, Sam = three, Sa = four)
Oh Nam, Yuk Soon, Chil Nam
(Oh = five, Yuk = Six, Chil = seven)
I like refined names.
C'mon, listen …
Il Nam, Yi Soon, Sam Nam, Sa Soon …
No, I don't like them, I don't like them!
Oh Nam, Yuk Soon, Chil Nam …
One, two!
- One, two!
- Park Dal Mun.
Take it easy.
No way. If we want to plant all these,
there isn't even time to take a piss.
Aigoo, as if we don't
already know you're a farmer.
One, two!
- One, two!
- 3rd Platoon Leader!
Yes, sir!
Wanna take me on?
Excuse me?
You don't remember?
What we did last year during the rice-planting?
Of course I remember.
I believe you lost back then.
The losing platoon buys the makgeolli*.
(*unfiltered rice wine).
3rd Platoon!
Everyone gather up!
1st Platoon, gather up!
I'm not sure we can win
with such a feeble horseman!
Why do you talk so much, huh?
Don't you worry!
When I'm on horseback, I fly!
Lieutenant Woo Bum Jin was
the best horseman in this game.
Right, he was.
Who was he?
Was Lieutenant Woo part of our Company?
Yeah, when the North came down with their tanks,
he died in a suicide charge.
It's not the tanks, it's the wheels!
Aim for …
With bravery.
That's right, with bravery.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for bringing it up.
So then, just leave it up to me!
In the spirit of Lieutenant Wu Bum Jin,
I'll take you right down!
The losing team buys the makgeolli!
And it's 20 laps around the drill field!
Get your head in the game!
They say you notice the missing
people more than the ones present.
A lot of people have departed over the year.
Yes.
Lieutenant Woo always beat me at this game.
Even if I asked him to give me a break,
he never did.
Even as I think of how
thankful I am to have survived,
sometimes, I'm overwhelmed with feeling guilty,
wondering if it's really
okay to laugh like this so easily.
Wondering if our departed
comrades would be saddened.
Happiness and sadness are
all left to the people that remain.
We can only do all we can to survive,
even when we are feeling guilty.
It's only now that we've been able to laugh.
I'm sure no one in heaven is protesting.
Your team lost fair and square,
so go and get the makgeolli.
- Right.
- Park Dal Mun, get to it!
You said you fly on horseback,
what a bunch of crap!
Oh look at this!
We lose because the horse is weak,
and you're trying to blame me?
Aigoo, really!
Hey, hey, hey!
You guys can quarrel amongst yourselves,
but go and get the makgeolli.
I'm feeling pretty thirsty.
But,
I don't really know the local streets here.
So, maybe someone who knows the
roads could go with Dal Mun Hyungnim?
Whoa, sounds like you're trying to get out of it.
Stop making excuses, and get going.
Just past Yeongchon bridge,
if you go a little further,
you'll see a place called the Widow's House.
Get going!
Get going, guys.
How am I gonna do 20 laps
around the drill field? Aigoo.
You do my share and take 40.
All right, 1st Platoon!
Where are you going, Hyungsoonim?
I'm on my way back from a house
call to the village chief's house.
Did you lose again today?
We won.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
I suppose he'll be well in no time,
since an angel's been to see him.
Platoon Leader!
The Regiment's engineering corp
is headed toward Yeongchon bridge.
- The engineering corp?
- Yes, sir!
The enemy route has changed, and so just in case,
they've ordered the Yeongchon
bridge to be prepared with explosives!
Has our military situation worsened critically?
No, I don't think it's gotten to such a point.
I think it's just a move to be prepared.
Shall I go and fetch the Captain?
No, we'll take care of this ourselves.
He's taking a well deserved break for a day.
2nd Company!
Oh my, oh my! Aigoo!
Aigoo, be careful!
You keep spilling like that
and the road will be dead drunk.
The road is uneven, what can I do?
That's why I said let's take the main road!
What the hell is this?
The ahjumma said this was the fastest way!
What's the rush?!
- We can take our time.
- Aigoo, really!
Are people from your town all as slow as you?
What are you talking about?
I was famous in our town for being impatient.
Aigoo.
If he's anything like you,
your kid is going to take his time coming out.
"Wah. I'm a coming.
Just wait a little while" Just like that.
Aigoo, why?
Does it make you that
happy thinking about your kid?
You know it.
When the war is over and I get back home,
we'll come up with a name.
And, I'll carry him on
my back and show him our fields.
Geez, why not give him a weeding
hoe instead of a rattle and put him to work?
He's got to learn if he's gonna work those fields.
Aigoo.
Wait, wait, wait.
When we go back home,
you have to deliver on your
promise to find me a sweet pretty gal.
Did I say that?
Of course!
After you said we'd be brothers,
you made that promise.
I think the ahjumma was right.
Huh?
Looking down at the area down there,
I think we're pretty much there.
About the girl, about the girl …
- I don't know!
- You promised!
I don't know!
That's really low, man!
Forget it!
What are you doing?!
You got me mad and hot, why?
Hey! The Company will
be waiting with such a thirst!
Give it here!
Tell me you'll keep your promise about the girl.
I said give it here.
So you can take it?
Wanna try to catch me?
If you've got the nerve, give it a shot.
Hey!
Come here.
Oh my god! What is this?
Snap out of it!
Hyungnim, save me.
Is anyone here?!
Help us!!
Someone's hurt!
You can do it.
You can do it, Shin Tae Ho.
Platoon Leader!
What happens if these don't go off?!
Just connect them like I showed you!
Park Hong Ki!
I'm sorry,
Du Sik,
Hong Ki,
Ju Hwan.
Unload them carefully.
I'm 2nd Company 1st Platoon Leader, Shin Tae Ho.
I'm Engineering Corp Lieutenant Shin Chang Ho.
- We'll leave it to you, then.
- Yes.
We'll be installing them immediately.
All right.
Put that there.
From now on, we will regulate
all people using the Yeongchon bridge.
Do your best in each of your posts to be on guard.
Yes, sir!
One year ago, in this exact spot,
we had the same mission.
We failed then,
but this time, we will absolutely not fail.
- To your positions.
- To positions!
Hello! Someone please come!
Can't you hear me?!
Am I bleeding a lot?
No. In a battlefield, that's just a piece of cake.
When we get to camp, it'll heal just like that.
That's right.
I was so lucky to have
gotten treatment at the hospital,
and then I throw a tantrum. I'm being punished.
But, why am I so sleepy?
Snap out of it!
You can't fall asleep!
Don't fall asleep!
I'm sleepy.
This won't do.
If we stay like this, we'll get nowhere.
So, I'll rush and get someone.
Hyungnim, don't go.
I'm scared.
What if I die here?
Are you crazy?!
Who's gonna die?!
No matter what happens, I'll make sure you live,
so you just stay put here!
Got it?!
Man Yong!
You can't die!
You absolutely can't die!
You poor kid!
Hyungnim!
Hurry back!
I will!
What should we do?
Go Man Yong and Park Dal Mun haven't returned yet.
They don't know the roads really well,
so I wonder if they took another route.
Big trouble! Big trouble!
Lieutenant!
Big trouble!
Man Yong, our Man Yong is on the brink of death!
What are you talking about?
Park Dal Mun!
I'm asking you what happened!
Man Yong stepped on a mine!
What?
I was going to carry him,
but he's lost so much blood, I came on my own.
- Medic!
- Byung Gu!
Yes, sir!
- Go Man Yong stepped on a mine.
- What?
- How's his condition?
- There’s nothing below his ankle.
And, he keeps saying he's sleepy.
I don't think the emergency kit will do it.
The medical officer will have
to look at it and operate immediately.
Then get him immediately!
He went back to the regiment medical corp earlier.
What?
What do we do?
Our Man Yong!
What do we do about our Man Yong?!
Captain!
It's Shin Tae Ho!
What is it?
Go Man Yong stepped on a mine.
A mine?
Yes, he went on an errand with Park Dal Mun, and …
Anyhow, he needs surgery immediately,
but there are no medical officers.
I think Hyungsoonim is going to have to help us.
I'll go and get ready right away.
You were going out to support the civilians today,
so why are you dressed in uniform?
There was an order sent down
to set up explosives on Yeongchon bridge.
What?
The Engineering Corp are working on it now.
Why didn't you report this?
It wasn't a serious situation,
and you were resting.
I didn't want to bother you.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I should have
stayed in the barracks with you.
No, sir.
The wounded soldier is
north of the Yeongchon bridge.
While I bring him back, I'd like you
to prepare for surgery at the Yeongchon clinic.
We just got a transmission
from Regiment operations.
An American scouting plane discovered
enemy movement in a southwest direction.
It appears the numbers are quite large.
Are they coming this way?
That's not clear.
Regiment operations have mandated
top security alert at 19:30.
Captain.
Please save our Man Yong.
He's about to die!
Don't worry.
It'll be all right.
It's been over 2 hours
since he stepped on the mine.
The bleeding would have continued.
At this rate, the danger is high.
I should be the one killed.
I should have carried him down no matter what.
I'll go with Park Dal Mun and
get him down here as fast as possible.
You can't.
You move him and he could go into shock.
We have to ensure he's in stable condition first.
It would have probably been more
dangerous for him if you'd carried him down.
You did the right thing.
Where's the patient?
Lead the way.
Su Yeon.
We don't have time, Jang Woo.
We have to hurry and
do something with the patient.
You can't. That's towards the north.
I will bring back Go Man Yong.
If you want to save the patient,
a doctor has to go directly.
I said you can't.
Jang Woo.
I'll count on you.
Captain.
Hurry back.
We don't know how the situation will change.
All right.
Thank you!
Thank you so much, Doctor!
Su Yeon!
Hurry back!
I'll be waiting!
All right!
I'll be right back!
Captain, do you think it will be all right?
You know how strong Su Yeon
gets in the presence of the wounded.
Let's put our faith in her.
We have our own work ahead of us too.
This time, we have to protect Yeongchon.
You haven't forgotten your promise, right?
Right.
Hey, put those on this side.
The rigging is complete.
Thank you. We'll take it from here.
Until we're no longer on top security alert,
we've been ordered to stand by in Yeongchon.
Finish connecting the detonator,
and then we're on standby in the vicinity.
Yes, sir!
Don't worry; our men are highly skilled.
If the order comes,
we can blow the bridge immediately.
I hope we don't have to see how skilled they are.
Please help me to see someone.
Who?
Who are you looking for?
Tomorrow, and the next day,
why did I think it was such
a given that you'd be next to me?
My woman and my child are up there.
I have to go myself.
Captain,
I'll be waiting.
What is this?
The regiment has sent the order.
As soon as we see the main force of the enemy,
we blow up the bridge immediately.
Su Yeon, get up;
The Chinese army is approaching.
Then, just one minute. Wait one minute more.
Are you crazy?
Let go, you bastard!
- Lieutenant!