Presented by
Showbox / Mediaplex
Produced by
TPS Company
Distributed by
Showbox / Mediaplex
January 1953
Seoul
SHlN Ha-kyun
KO Soo
We want reunification!
No 38th Parallel!
Panmunjeom
Written by
PARK Sang-hyeon
Directed by
JANG Hun
Here's the list of POWs
we're sending back.
Like this line, the military demarkation line
has to be drawn.
One centimeter above,
0.5 km
South took over K hill
three days ago.
We have that hill now.
The line is wrong.
If you want to keep arguing about it
Why don't we just go out into the field
and check it out for ourselves?
General
Yesterday, K hill was taken
by the north.
Here we go again.
Your discharge is
upon a truce, right?
It's been dragging
for a year and half.
I know.
You'll be transferred
to the investigation unit.
What?
No way.
They're shorthanded there.
Busy purging commies
and traitors in the South.
A lot of them are
falsely accused.
KANG, watch your mouth.
They fed the NK soldiers
cause they were threatened
with guns.
And you call them
commies?
We can't help it.
They're collateral damage.
Purge pro-Japanese
pawns first.
Shut up!
Goddamn it!
This is serious shit.
You're a ClC officer.
What were you thinking?
Am I going to jail?
Why couldn't you
hold your tongue?
A breakdown of discipline
isn't tolerated at ClC.
You're not going to jail.
Go to the eastern front.
The eastern front?
Investigate this.
"Dear my beloved mom."
"l don't see the truce
happening anytime soon."
"We're losing comrades
in combats everyday."
This was written
by a NK soldier.
Right.
It was delivered
to this lady a week ago.
Through our MPS.
How's that possible?
There's a mole.
It was sent from
Alligator Company.
Didn't they lose the hill
the other day?
Right.
I would recall those bastards
and put the screws on them.
But that hill is very important
for the talks.
The company captain
got killed recently.
He was reported as a KlA.
But you know what?
What killed him is a gun
we officers use.
Doesn't it smell?
A new captain is leaving soon.
Go with him.
Thanks.
You won't be thankful
once you get there.
Wait.
Do you know
KlM Su-hyeok?
He was in your platoon.
Yes, we were friends
from college.
He went missing in action.
No.
He's in Alligator Company.
He's alive?
Jun 27, 1950
Uijeongbu
- Su-hyeok!
- Eun-pyo?
Su-hyeok!
Su-hyeok, are you okay?
Look at me.
Don't let me die.
Get up if you wanna live.
Come on, get up.
Sit!
Sir?
Get up.
Get up!
Turn around.
Now!
Move it!
Look, dumbasses.
Do you know
why you're losing?
why you keep running?
Let me tell you.
That's because you don't know
why you're fighting.
This war will end
in a week.
When it does,
we'll need you.
Go home and help us later
rebuild the nation.
We'll treat the wounded.
You can go.
See you again
when we're reunified.
- Eun-pyo?
- Su-hyeok!
- Let go!
- No!
Just leave.
Eun-pyo?
Su-hyeok!
- Hey, Cruit.
- Private NAM Sung-sik!
That's good.
Keep it loud.
Sir!
Yes, sir!
Do you know
where we're going?
Yes, sir.
To the eastern front, sir.
10th Division...
1st Company of 1st Battalion,
moron.
How old are you?
17, sir.
17...
17 is an adult.
KANG Eun-pyo, right?
Yes, sir.
Why'd you put in a transfer
for the eastern front?
A man of ambition,
aren't you?
This war will be over soon.
And those who fought
at the front line will rule.
The front line is
where soldiers should be.
Right, Private?
Yes, sir! I'm ready to die
for our country!
The Eastern Front
Camp Cayman
No greetings?
You!
Get over here.
- Why?
- What the...
- Who stole my cigarettes?
You bitch!
- What the hell!
- Enemy!
Hey!
A POW is on the loose!
Get him!
Yes, sir!
Put it away, bitch.
I'm not a POW.
Why are you wearing
an enemy uniform?
Cause I'm cold.
Are you shitting me?
You call yourself a soldier?
Take it off.
Take it off now!
Stop yelling.
You're hurting my ears.
What are you doing?
I have it on inside.
I can't believe this.
Who are you?
Who am l?
What's this?
This is ridiculous.
Alligator my ass.
Sorry I'm late.
What's up with your accent?
Oh, I'm from the North.
I left home
20 years ago.
So I'm not red at all.
An acting commander?
No, sir.
MSG. YANG Hyo-sam.
The acting commander
will be here soon.
What are you doing here?
Hi.
Who are these kids?
This isn't a playground.
Send them away.
They're war orphans.
We've been looking
after them.
Damn, it's a mess here.
Let's go.
What a life.
An alligator?
How old are you?
State your rank
and name.
Alkaloid?
Where'd you get this?
What are you?
SHlN ll-young.
A captain?
You're the acting commander?
Respect your superior.
First Lieutenant
KANG Eun-pyo.
Aero-K.
We call it Aerok Hill.
2.5 kilometers in radius.
It's a strategic point,
covering these two points.
The enemy had it
7 hours ago.
But we took it back
on our 6th attack.
Many guys got wounded
and tired.
So the regimental commander
put us on a break.
Well done.
Listen.
I'm determined to end
this battle of attrition.
It won't be as easy
as you think.
What?
Sorry, sir.
We'll set up AA guns
on the foot of the hill.
Anti-aircraft guns?
But they have no air power.
You use them
only for fighters?
With AA guns,
our defense line here...
What if we lose them
to the enemy?
Then we're fucked.
He's right.
We're still here,
thanks to USAF air strike.
If they take our AA guns,
we can forget the air support.
Look.
We won't lose them.
Set up AA guns right now.
That's not good.
Who are you?
First LT. KlM Su-hyeok.
Sorry I'm late.
First Lieutenant?
Not only are you alive,
you made First LT from Private.
In 2 years?
Officers die in battle fields,
and you get promoted fast.
Hey, you had this?
What, you've lost
your faith?
No, I just pray
for different things.
I used to ask God to save,
but now to kill.
Kill whom?
Anybody.
This won't be over
unless one side is gone.
Eun-pyo?
What's a ClC officer
doing here?
We have intel
about a mole here.
What?
That's bullshit.
I know.
Let's toast
to our new captain.
Fill your cups.
Here you go.
What's this?
It's water.
It can be either
water or booze.
It's all in your head.
Listen up.
Wake him up.
To the regimental commander
who put on this party for us.
Let's toast.
Before that...
We lost a lot of men
in the last combat.
Let's toast to them first.
Go ahead.
Comrades, good bye.
Good bye!
Sorry about earlier.
You're here
to catch a mole?
Pour me a shot.
You look old.
I fought
in the Liberation Army.
- Against Japan?
- Yes, in Manchuria.
Mt. Hwabaek Battle
in 1941.
I got this badge
from an interim government.
It was dark at night.
Japs were coming,
and we were out of ammo.
We were ready to die.
Where are you going?
It is getting exciting.
"The eastern sky lit up
with artillery support."
I've heard it so many times
I know it by heart.
I'm sick of it.
What the...
Smarter than you look.
With artillery support...
No, he's not smart.
He'd be stupid
not to know it by now.
Enough of that.
Cruit?
Let us hear you sing.
NAM?
Private NAM Sung-sik!
Where's my platoon?
Why didn't you invite us?
Il-young?
Shit.
Eat this.
Eat it.
What's wrong?
It's okay.
We're retreating now
but we will strike back.
Where are you going?
Wake up, man.
We're not in Pohang.
Knock it off!
Why bring that shit up?
What?
Did food make you sick?
Why is it so cold?
What is it?
He thinks
we're in Pohang.
- Pohang?
- Forget it, guys.
It's behind us.
Where's my platoon?
Damn it!
Cheer up, guys.
Let's have some fun.
Come on, show us
some moves!
Fuck!
NAM, sing us something
that's big in Seoul.
- Sing!
- Come on.
¢ÜLook at me, dear
Not that old shit.
Something new!
You're stabbing
the dead here.
What are you doing?
Hi.
Let's eat.
When will the war end?
What?
I bet you've talked
to high-ranking officers.
When?
Truce talks began
two fucking years ago.
It can be any day now.
And it's been 2 years.
Any idea how many
have died here?
It gets confusing.
Did he die?
Or was it someone else?
It's sick.
Did I see him
in the barracks?
Shit.
That Cruit?
What a song.
¢ÜHeard from a distance...
¢Üa loud gunshot,
¢Ülike a lullaby,
¢Ütakes me home
¢Üin my dream.
¢ÜMy home,
¢Ümy sweet home...
¢ÜBefore a bowl of water...
¢Ümom prays for my safety.
¢ÜHer shining gray hair
¢Übrings tears to my eyes.
Get up!
Up!
Turn the lights on!
Get the hell up!
Get up!
Come on!
Listen.
They took Aerok Hill back.
Get your gear
and standby.
AA guns?
AA guns!
Can't even last a day.
He shits,
and we clean it up?
This is bullshit.
If he doesn't know shit,
he should listen.
This was unthinkable
back in 1941.
We had 2 principles.
Minimum activities
and maximum focus.
A chatterbox
got killed first, right?
Shut up, funny boy.
We're wide open.
If Two Seconds sees us...
At least one will die.
What's Two Seconds?
If you know too much,
you'd be too scared.
You'll find out soon.
Look! After the combat,
write me the lyrics to that song.
Okay.
If you don't get killed today.
Machine guns.
AA guns.
That bitch is still alive.
They're digging foxholes,
expanding the defense line.
This is a piece of cake.
They're reserves.
I can't see past the hill.
Let's shoot and see.
If they have more men
over that hill?
We'll be trapped like rats.
We have their uniform, right?
Yes.
Comrade!
Why didn't you
answer the radio?
I've been calling you
from there.
What?
A radio?
Nobody radioed, right?
No, sir.
Are you sure
it's not broken?
Where'd you get
those boots?
What's your unit?
Get this asshole!
1 and 2, 11 o'clock.
3 and 4, 12 o'clock.
Man-seok?
Got them.
Move it!
One the ground, fuckers!
We heard the gunfire.
What's going on?
Answer it.
Do you copy?
Tell him
it was an accident.
It was an accident, sir.
A volley fire always works!
Radio HQ.
Dragonfly 2,
you're good to go.
We've been hit!
Fuck!
We're moving to 0-2-4.
Blow it.
What are you doing?
If we let them live now,
they'll kill us later.
Move to 0-2-4!
Hurry, sir.
Damn it!
They're back!
After the air strike,
move to the trench
before they come out
of the foxhole.
What the fuck!
Cry and I'll kill you!
To the trench!
Move it!
Medic!
To the trench!
We need to take out
that gun.
Let's just fucking charge!
He's too far.
Grenades will fall
30 meters before the pillbox.
- What?
- Get your grenades.
What are you doing?
I can't let you.
If they fall short,
I die.
Shit!
On my mark!
Now!
I can't see him.
He made it!
Charge!
Fucking commies!
Too late to turn back.
We gotta get up there.
I will lead.
2nd platoon in flank!
Go!
Keep going!
Fuck.
Motherfuckers!
Eating corn power
and hiding out like rats!
- Put your hands up.
- Don't kill me.
It's a white flag!
Ceasefire!
Cruit.
You okay?
It's okay.
He looked younger
than me.
It's kill or get killed.
Right?
Let's go.
Damn, I almost peed
my pants.
Damn Yankees,
they destroyed everything.
It'll take forever
to restore this.
We have to restore it?
Or what?
You'll ask the enemy?
Wow, you hung like a horse.
You damn kid...
Aerok Hill stands
on those bodies.
Remember that asshole who said
this war would be over in a week?
How could I forget?
He's here.
What?
Yep, it's him.
He put on airs and said...
This war would be over
in a week.
You don't know
why you're fighting.
I wanna ask him
why we're fighting.
Lieutenant!
What are you doing?
It's almost gone.
Come on.
What's wrong?
Are you drunk?
We have booze?
MSG. YANG said...
it'd help me
forget what happened.
Come on, drink it down.
Hey, that cup is mine.
Give it back.
- Give me some.
- Get your own cup.
This is mine.
Eun-pyo, come sit.
Drink with us.
Where'd you get the booze?
What's this?
Oh, we didn't draw that.
Some commie did.
Fucking idiot!
What's that in your hand?
It's nothing.
"Thanks for sending my regards
to my family in the South."
KlM Su-hyeok.
What's this?
Please, let it go.
Put it down.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
YANG, put it down.
He's a ClC officer.
If he talks, we're dead.
You think
this is nothing?
You've been talking
to commies?
Is this
what you're here for?
It's really nothing.
Explain it then.
Do you know how many times
this hill changed hands?
Nobody knows.
I counted up to 30, though.
We didn't wanna
carry all this shit back
when we pulled off this hill.
So?
We buried things
in this bunker.
Socks, clothes,
chocolate from Yankees.
Ammo, cigarettes,
boots
Because we'd be back.
When we took this hill back,
guess what we found here.
What?
Damn flies.
Crap.
What's this?
Let me.
Son of a bitch!
- It stinks.
- Stay away from me.
What the...
"Thanks for the chocolate,
cigarettes, and socks."
Fucking commies!
This is why
Communism's gotta go!
I'll kill them all!
Where are you going?
Let go!
Calm down.
So pissed off
we weren't ourselves.
So we buried a letter
cursing them.
You buried a letter?
Yes, we were not
thinking right.
Otherwise, we would've buried
grenades or a time bomb.
And then?
As always, we lost the hill
and took it back.
What's this?
I know.
Don't.
Okay.
What the...
Isn't this booze?
Booze?
This is rice wine
from the North.
Dump it.
It might be poisoned.
Are you sure?
This is booze.
Dump it.
I'm not hallucinating.
It really is booze.
- Damn.
- Ki-young.
Just to make sure...
Smell it.
Fine.
Wait.
Hold on.
If they wanted to kill us,
they wouldn't have left wine.
That's right.
They would've buried
a grenade instead.
You're right.
Why give us booze?
Fuck it.
I don't care if I die.
What's wrong?
Let me have another sip.
- Smart ass!
- This is the real thing!
- Give me some!
- Wait for the go!
That booze...
It was bribery.
Buried with it was
a thick envelope.
In it was a few letters.
Letters?
Some NK solders were
drafted from SK.
And some defected to NK
and enlisted.
They left letters
for their families back home.
So?
So I mailed them all.
You did?
Yes, I did.
Since then, we've buried
cigarettes for them.
And they did booze,
matches...
We're always low
on matches.
Isn't this nice?
That's it?
What else did you expect?
You think we leaked
military secrets?
Putting our lives at risk?
YANG, put it down.
I wanna hear
what he has to say.
Do you have anything to do
with the death of a former captain?
He was shot in the head
at point blank.
The pistol used to kill him is
what we officers use.
Of course.
It was his pistol.
What?
He shot himself
while running from a battle.
He was a piece of shit.
But I reported him as a KlA
out of courtesy.
You saw it?
One of the boys did.
Where's he now?
He died today.
One you buried earlier.
Where did you find
his body?
In the creek
north of the hill.
Listen, Eun-pyo.
There's nothing
you can dig out here.
Even if you do...
Nothing you can do about it.
What makes you so sure?
Just leave
before you get killed.
I will.
But...
Now is not the time.
KIM Su-hyeok...
What are you doing here?
Yours?
You live nearby?
Have you seen anything
suspicious around here?
Go home.
You're not safe here.
Hold on.
It's chocolate.
Don't come back.
Guys, get up there!
Medic!
June, 1953
3rd platoon lost 8 men.
And 23 got wounded
and need to be evacuated.
Most of them are
severely...
We don't have men
to evac them.
Request the regiment
for an evac team.
Get out of here.
What's this?
Disobeying my order?
No.
We need at least 30 men
to evac 23.
There's no way.
That's not it.
When will the war end?
What?
Give me the letters.
So many things to say!
- I'm here.
- Come on.
"Thanks for the lyrics to
Night at the Front Line."
"Do me a favor.
Send my family this picture."
Wait.
Give it here.
"l don't think I will see them
ever again."
This CHA Tae-kyung kid
has a pretty sister.
Come on.
Stop drooling.
She's pretty, so what?
If her brother is red,
she is too.
Give it here.
His sister is a fox.
Who's this?
CHA Tae-kyung.
She's cute.
I'll keep it.
Mail this.
You can't do that.
Forget it.
Yeah, forget it.
What do you think
of my future wife?
I have the address.
I can visit her after the war.
This girl...
What's going on
with damn truce talks?
This is bullshit.
The war has been in a deadlock
for 2 years now.
And half a million
have died so far.
It's crazy, isn't it?
Damn.
Look, NAM.
Why can't we stop fighting
during truce talks?
You should be a CO
for the UN forces.
Yeah, that's right.
You don't mind?
You're funny.
Move.
What's this?
It's a pair of goggles.
Here.
- If I put them on...
- Give them here.
Made in Germany.
Wow, Lieutenant.
They look horrible on you.
Here, Cruit.
That's not fair.
He didn't do anything
to deserve these.
They're for him.
It's for the lyrics
to that song.
You don't know that.
Come on.
Take them.
Move.
Why don't you sing it for us?
Sure.
One, two, three, four
¢ÜLeaves are falling...
¢Üinto the night
¢Üat the front line.
¢ÜFalling down silently...
¢Üdews are so cold...
We have intel
Chinese army will set up
a strategic base here.
Any word from Recon?
Nothing?
We lost contact with them
on the north ridge.
It's been 8 hours.
They might've been sniped.
If that's the case,
it must be Two Seconds.
That piece of shit
turned up again.
Two Seconds?
It's our nickname
for this enemy sniper.
Why Two Seconds?
The body goes down first.
And 2 seconds later,
a gunshot is heard.
That's why.
From 680 meters away?
Yes.
He must've modified
his rifle.
He's killed about 30
of our men.
How are we gonna
get him?
I'll get him.
Can you do it?
Give me 10 men.
Where the fuck is he?
He's not here.
Let's go back.
Not yet.
We searched everywhere.
He's not here.
You've been holding it, huh?
Let me see your dick.
Are you nuts?
Come here.
Get your ass over here.
No way!
Come on.
We're leaving soon.
Come here.
So you can beat me?
No way.
- It's Two Seconds!
- Get down!
No!
Don't go.
I can't move my leg.
Don't fall for a trap!
Stay put!
Where'd he shoot from?
Sergeant YANG...
Sergeant YANG!
Don't move.
Stay there!
Sung-sik!
Help me.
I don't wanna die.
Sung-sik!
Don't!
- I want him to shoot again.
- What?
One more shot.
We have to get him.
He's waiting for us
to take the bait.
Are you crazy?
Fuck.
Sung-sik, grab it.
Hang in there!
Grab it.
Reach for it.
That's good.
We got him.
Commo!
Stop.
Stop shooting me!
Sung-sik.
Give me your hand.
Requesting
an artillery attack.
The coordinates are...
Give me your
goddamn hand!
Lieutenant...
Come on!
Sung-sik...
Die, Two Seconds.
Sung-sik!
Where the fuck is he?
He couldn't have made it.
His body must've been
torn into pieces.
No, he's alive.
What?
He walked.
Fuck!
Poor Sung-sik.
He was so young.
So what?
This is a battlefield,
and anybody can die.
Is there an order
who dies first?
Age means nothing
in war.
Chocolate?
Was it that boy who sang?
Lieutenant KANG!
Where are you?
This way, guys.
Fuck.
An artillery attack
for a single sniper?
I should've taken out
the commo first.
The 2nd Corps of
Chinese Army is
setting up a new point
in the northwest of Aerok Hill.
First LT. KANG?
Are you listening?
Put your head together!
To hold the defense line...
Got something to say?
Sung-sik died
because of you.
Many have died.
This is war.
Is this how?
How you made First LT
from Private in 2 years?
I guess it is.
I did what I had to do.
I bet you did.
Each and every time.
Now you're going
for captain?
Should I salute you?
The war killed Sung-sik.
That's bullshit, asshole!
Excuse me?
My arm will grow back
when I grow up, right?
I said no.
It won't, will it?
It will grow back,
and I'll be normal again, right?
Look.
Are you a lizard?
Arms don't grow.
You'll be armless
until you die, freak!
Motherfucker!
It'll grow back!
You call yourself human?
Tell me it will!
No, I'm not human anymore.
I died long ago!
3 years of hell!
What do you expect?
Shut the fuck up.
What do you know
about war?
Things are worse
in the rear.
You're not the only one
fighting a war.
Everybody is in hell!
You don't know a thing
about hell.
NAM Sung-sik.
Kids like him die
everyday.
Hundreds of thousands
have died.
And why the fuck isn't
this war ending?
What do you know
about hell?
What is hell?
Is it Pohang?
Tell me!
Where's my platoon?
Where's everybody?
Move.
Don't get closer!
He's completely crazy.
Thank God
he doesn't have a grenade.
He's not crazy.
He's on and off.
Can't you see him?
Have him transferred.
He will receive
a dishonorable discharge.
It's not fair
for a man of bravery.
What?
You sons of...
Where's my platoon?
It got wiped out!
Can't you remember?
SONG Hyung-jong!
AHN Hyun-su!
KANG Hyuk-pill!
JUNG Man-su!
JUNG Kyu-won!
Who else?
NAM Guk-bae, SHlN Chang-su
They all died.
When we fled Pohang,
2nd platoon got wiped out.
Why?
If so...
Why am I alive?
Tell me, PFC. SHlN!
Captain, no.
Don't.
Stay back!
Why am I the only one alive?
Tell me!
Sang-uk.
Look at me.
Don't you remember?
What happened
in Pohang?
Why'd everybody die
except you?
Enough!
That's enough.
Look at me.
It's me, ll-young.
No!
Get him!
Doc!
You were lucky.
It missed the bone.
You don't feel pain,
do you?
He's hooked on morphine.
What is it?
What happened
in Pohang?
Fuck Pohang...
August 17, 1950
Pohang
What are we gonna do?
Retreat!
Take us with you!
- There's no time!
- Are you crazy?
Let's go!
Get the fuck back!
We can't take no more!
You're leaving us to die?
There's no room!
Get back, assholes!
Let's go!
Climb on!
Get us out of here!
Hit it!
Fuck!
Captain!
Bro.
Bro!
You killed our own men!
You crazy bastard.
Why are you trying
to kill yourself?
Who's to blame him?
He saved us all.
Didn't he?
Who could deny that?
Tell me.
Tell me!
Tell me,
you fucking cowards!
He's right.
You saved us.
Why can't you admit that?
2nd platoon got wiped out
in combat.
Il-young.
It's not your fault.
Heard that, Private?
You killed our men to survive.
Don't waste your life now.
Su-hyeok...
- Sang-uk!
It's okay.
Send them away with him.
No more kids here.
We've had so many battles.
But this one will be the last one
over Aerok Hill.
We've heard that
more than enough.
I'm sick of hearing that.
How dare you!
Keep quiet.
Carry on.
The Chinese Army
will lead the attack.
When the ROK asses
pull out
we'll wipe them out
on their retreat.
Got it?
Take sure
they don't get away.
What's the point?
One minute, it's ours.
And next minute, it's theirs.
What if they take it,
and an armistice is signed?
That's a suicide!
If they take away our men
Aerok will be stranded.
We can't defend
against those Chinks.
So?
We desert Aerok
and set up a new defense line.
We cut off
their line of supply.
Then focus our fire
on them.
What the fuck!
Who do you think you are?
A commander-in-chief?
Know your fucking place.
Have you fought
against those chinks?
Do you even know
who Peng Dehuai is?
They have more men
than our ammo.
Did you know that?
Son of a bitch.
Contumacy in times of war
results in what?
Say it.
Contumacy results in what?
Punishment on the spot.
Standby to attack
along Hakang ridge.
Answer me.
Sir.
Repeat it!
Along Hakang ridge.
Standby to attack.
KANG?
Standby on the north ridge.
Repeat it.
Captain SHlN was
right about this.
He's saved our ass
quite a few times.
Soldiers live and die
by orders.
But this is like dying
for nothing.
The visibility is bad.
I can't see shit.
And we can't hear shit
because of the rain.
Contact!
They're here!
It's chinks.
They're too many!
No word from HQ?
We have to pull out.
Aerok is completely surrounded.
Give us your order.
Not so fast.
We gotta wait.
I can't get Capt. SHlN
on the radio.
That means...
He and his men are dead.
- Get HQ on the radio!
- Yes, sir!
Sir, it's Chinese army.
We're outnumbered.
I know, but...
What'd he say?
We're defending the hill.
We'll fight to the end.
He doesn't know
the situation here.
We have to retreat now.
Fuck!
Il-young is dead.
We're all gonna die!
Motherfucker!
Should I send you
where ll-young is?
You should've listened
to ll-young!
Soldiers die
when they're told to!
No!
Captain, don't do it.
Our captain is dead.
By the military law
I'm in charge now.
We're pulling out.
Yes, sir!
By the military law?
If you kill me,
you're in charge.
Can you get our boys
out of here?
If you can, shoot me.
We don't have time.
Get all the survivors
to Ridge 315.
- Move!
- Yes, sir!
If we make it...
I'll have you
court-marshaled.
Keep going!
Leave him!
We're fucked.
Put up a white flag!
We gotta go.
Go!
Save your ass!
Get out of here!
I'm not leaving behind
anybody anymore.
Get up.
Fuck!
Sergeant YANG!
Sergeant Yang!
Why didn't you just
leave me?!
Funny boy.
Wait for your turn.
Mt. Hwabaek Battle
in 1941.
I got this badge
from an interim...
YANG!
Fuck the badge!
We're out of ammo.
I guess this is it.
It's Capt. SHlN!
He's alive!
How are you holding up?
When that flare goes out
fire all the trench mortar
and get out of here.
If they fall for it,
they'll be shooting at each other.
Take your men and go.
I'll be right after you.
No matter what,
we're sticking together.
You're in charge now.
Save your men.
Focus!
Trench mortar!
Fire!
Damn chinks.
The US recon aircraft is up,
and they're gone.
Let me ask you something.
Was it you?
Did you kill
the former captain?
What makes you
think I did?
Because Capt. YOO will be
reported as a KlA.
You've seen enough.
Isn't your job over now?
What?
It's not enough?
Murders, treachery,
disobeying orders.
Those are my charges?
That's right.
I report you
and my job is over.
So is yours, asshole.
I'd rather die out here.
Two fucking Seconds.
It didn't echo.
He's nearby.
Listen up.
I count to 3, and we all run
in different directions.
He's fast,
but he can't kill us all.
Some of us will live.
One!
Two!
Three!
I see you, asshole.
I got him.
You...
CHA Tae-kyung?
Fuck.
Su-hyeok!
No.
Don't come!
Su-hyeok!
Eun-pyo, don't come.
Su-hyeok...
Go!
Su-hyeok!
Eun-pyo...
Don't come,
or you'll get killed.
You know what?
I think I died long ago.
You, me.
Everybody
in Alligator Company.
Even Two Seconds.
She also died long ago.
Like Sung-sick...
We've killed too many.
We should be in hell.
Stop talking.
But hell can't be
worse than here.
Killing each other...
I die today, and...
Stop it!
You're not dying, asshole!
Eun-pyo.
My mom...
Yes, Su-hyeok.
I can't remember her face.
Su-hyeok?
Su-hyeok!
No.
No!
Sorry...
We got booze, too.
"Goggles are handy
in summer. Thanks."
It must be that boy.
He's dead.
I killed him.
They killed many
of our comrades, too.
What does it say?
"Hey, CHA Tae-kyung"
The photo is mine!
And don't worry about your sister.
I'll take good care of her.
Let's stop fighting, assholes.
What is it?
What does it say?
"Let's stop fighting, assholes."
That's all?
Pretty much.
I bet they're sick
of this war.
So are we.
Why are we fighting then?
¢ÜLeaves are...
¢ÜFalling...
KIM Su-hyeok
¢Ülnto the night...
¢Üat the front line...
Sir!
Comrade Captain!
The war is over.
Listen to this.
The armistice has been
signed by...
The war is over!
It's over!
Thank you!
We made it alive!
Thank you, sir!
Lieutenant KANG!
How could this happen?
Why couldn't you survive
another day?
The war is fucking over.
Sir...
It's okay to be hurt.
You can cry.
Bro...
Fire!
Rest in peace.
- Goodbye!
KIM ll-sung.
Enemy!
Goodbye!
You fought well!
I guess it's really over.
Let's go.
Lieutenant!
What?
KIM Su-hyeok.
Let's go.
Sir!
Attention!
We, hereby, sign
an armistice agreement
to stop the bloodshed
and suspend any open
hostile activities
until a complete peace is
achieved on the peninsula.
Conditions of an armistice
under this agreement
are to be strictly forced
by all the parties involved.
It was signed at 10 a.m.
on July 27.
However...
The supplementary provision
states clearly
that the armistice agreement
takes effect as of 22:00
on July 27, 1953.
12 hours after it was signed.
We still have
12 hours left.
We'll launch a full attack
on all the fronts.
12 hours from now,
it's gonna be our land.
Captain SHlN.
Sir?
Take the north ridge
of Aerok Hill.
Didn't you hear me?
My company isn't
in good shape, sir.
It's the last combat.
Deal with it.
Show us what you got.
12 hours of all-out war?
That's crazy!
Tell me!
Why are you laughing?
Did you expect
to survive this war?
Comrade...
I was stupid to be hopeful.
Get all the squad leaders.
We're ending this war.
No matter what it takes,
I'll save my men.
He said that
winning the war is to survive.
To stay alive.
Su-hyeok said that?
Yes.
He said our enemy wasn't commies,
but the war itself.
We'll take Aerok back
from the north ridge.
We were nicknamed
Alligator Company
by American troops.
Do you know why?
Alligators lay about 50 eggs.
More than half are eaten
by other animals.
And most of those hatched
fall prey to other animals.
Only one or two survives.
But you know what?
One or two alligators
that survived out of 50
grow up
to rule the swamp.
That's alligators.
We're facing the last combat.
In the past 2 and half years,
500 thousand have died.
But we've survived!
We're alligators!
We rule the combat field!
Got that?
Yes, sir!
Who's the strongest?
Alligators!
Who's the fittest?
Survive for 12 hours!
Stay alive!
So we can go home.
We can't see them.
But they're very close.
Less than 100 meters away.
What are you doing here?
You can't leave me out.
We're in this together.
It's just another 12 hours.
Damn, it's foggy.
The whole world is
telling us to fight.
And this fog is telling us
not to.
That's right.
If it stays this foggy
the USAF can't strike.
And they might call off
this operation.
Right?
Once the fog clears,
they'll bomb this hill.
Once they do,
we'll charge.
If we survive this...
I'll call you Bro.
So stay alive.
Make sure you do.
Son of a bitch!
Stop crying, asshole!
I don't wanna fight.
Stop crying, bitch!
Stop it!
Stop it, asshole!
Fuck me.
Who the fuck is singing?
No.
It's them.
¢ÜFalling down silently...
¢Üdew is so cold.
¢ÜNot able to sleep...
¢Ütossing and turning...
¢Ül heard my mom's voice
¢Ütelling me ways of a man.
¢ÜDon't I miss her voice.
Fuck.
¢ÜHeard from a distance...
¢Üa loud gunshot,
¢Ülike a lullaby,
¢Ütakes me home in my dream.
¢ÜMy home,
¢Ümy sweet home...
¢ÜBefore a bowl of water...
¢Ümom prays for my safety.
¢ÜHer shining gray hair
¢Übrings tears to my eyes.
We' re fucked.
Motherfuckers!
Die, asshole!
What's this?
Asshole.
Do you copy?
Stop bombing!
We're behind the enemy line!
You're killing us all!
We gotta pull out now!
You remember me,
don't you?
You said
it would end in a week.
You're still alive.
Dumbass.
Let me ask you this.
Here's what you said
3 years ago.
Do you know
why you're losing?
That's because you don't know
why you're fighting.
Why are we fighting?
I knew it.
I knew what it was.
But...
It's been too long.
I forgot.
Son of a bitch.
Stop any hostilities
on all the frontlines.
I repeat.
Stop any hostilities...
Stop any hostilities
on all the frontlines.
repeat.
Stop any hostilities
on all the frontlines.
Repeat.
Stop any hostilities
on all the frontlines.
Directed by
JANG Hun