Behind the White Tower
Scalpel.
6 milimeters of epinephrine!
What are you doing Dcotor Jang?
Uou always say you're condifent.
But don't you think I know the alternate procedure!
You don't think I'm your kind,so let's do it in my way.
Are you pulling my leg?
He did humilliate himself.
Should I transfer him out,if things get out of hand to appease you?
Do you have someone in mind?
Is this really necessary?
You're already a renowned surgeon.
I don't understand why you're so consumed to get that position.
We have a different perspective in life.
I can't believe you.
-Can you hear me, out? I told you to let go.
I'm sorry.
Sorry I was imprudent.Please forgive me.
Hello, Dr. Lee.
Dr. Jang come to see me.
He volunteered go to our branch hospital.
I know we can't send him for our hospital's sake, but he insists.
If he made that decision I believe we should respect it.
I see. I guess we should do that.
I know it was a difficult decision.Thanks for volunteering.
Please set up the branch hospital for us.
Episode 3
Chief, it's time to make your rounds.
Okay, let's go.
Did something good happen to you?
No, it's nothing.
How are things with you, Dr. Hong?
What are you talking about?
Although I haven't expressed my thoughts, I know you're working hard.
You're too kind. I have much to learn.
I haven't taught you much.
You taught us through your actions. We have much to learn from you.
Thank you for your consideration. I should take better of you.
You'll receive plenty of opportunities by being patient and working hard.
Thank you. I'll do my best, Chief.
- Let's make our rounds.
- Yes, Sir.
- What happened?
- It just happened.
Why didn't you discuss an important matter like that to me?
I'm sorry.
Weren't you adamant about not going?
Why aren't you saying anything?
All I can say is that I'm sorry.
He's definitely worth being assistant director.
It's not funny, father. If we don't do anything, my career is over!
You're not as smart as I thought you were.
Then why did you operate on the assistant director's patient?
I did because her case was rare.
That's why I like you.
You need that kind of passion to become chief of surgery.
I'll take care of it, so don't worry.
I can get you out of this mess in no time.
What is it, Father?
There's a way.
Let's just say, it'll be a good opportunity to test our friendship.
Let's have dinner tonight. You'll find out about them.
Anyhow, how much did you pay for the painting?
It was originally $30,000, but I got a 10% discount.
Woo Yong Kil, painting is $27,000.
It's a nice painting, but oh well...
Can't you just accept it?
I don't think it's right.
As you know, he doesn't like to hear he receives bribes.
That wasn't our intention, it was just a small gift.
Tell me about it. He needs to be more flexible.
But he's so conservative, it's hard on me sometimes.
I'll temporarily hold onto it.
Tell me when he's no longer upset.
Okay, I will.
What did Dr. Jang do to upset my husband?
It just makes our relationship uneasy. You should give him a hard time about it!
I will!
Why did Dr. Jang make such a sudden change of decision?
I don't know since he didn't tell me.
I thought something happened between you two.
Pardon? Nothing happened between us.
- I'm only kidding.
- I see.
He volunteered on his own accord.
However, I'm just a bit concerned.
I don't want people to make assumptions that I coerced him.
You were worried about that. I'll alleviate that for you.
I'll explain to the other board of directors.
I would appreciate that.
- The patient is recovering well.
- That's good.
Can I move to a regular room?
I'm bored, and I feel like I'm burdening everyone.
Let's stay for one more day.
Thank you for taking good care of her.
Let's all have dinner today.
I think it's better to have dinner after next week's seminar.
Okay.
Let's just have dinner today.
Yes, Sir.
If you're butting heads with someone powerful, just find someone stronger.
There's no absolute authority. Everyone has a nemesis.
- Yes, nemesis.
- Hello.
I told you not to wear your hospital gown!
- Dr. Yoo!
- Dr. Min!
You should've waited for me inside.
I wanted to finish listening to this.
Come here. Let's go in.
Is everyone here?
Everyone's here except for the people in surgery and on duty.
Dr. Jang isn't here for personal reasons.
He'll be busy because he'll be transfering to our branch hospital.
Let's have a drink.
I want to clarify that this is just a temporary transfer.
Dr. Jang will return once I retire.
Yes.
Be sure there aren't any problems with the transition.
- Where did you hike today?
- Mt. Bukhan.
I walked along the mountain ridges.
It almost took me 10 hours to complete.
- Do I stink?
- Not really.
You're so amazing.
I'm planning on going to Himalaya next year.
Wow.
Oh, this is my son-in-law.
Say hello to the chair of the medical association.
He's also the President of the Myongin University Medical Alumni Association.
My name is Jang Joon Hyuk.
I heard much about you.
We're drinking until we're drunk, okay?
I have a higher tolerance now that I hike.
You can't leave me hanging, okay?
Oh no, we're dead.
It's Yongkil.
Isn't he the assistant director at your hospital?
Hi Yongkil!
I didn't have any reception in the mountain.
What's up?
What? Really?
If you keep this up, I'm not going to help you from now on.
Of course, you need to be good to me.
Tomorrow?
I'm meeting someone from the Public Health Association.
He should've said something after he took the shot.
I can't distinguish if we drank or not.
Although temporary, isn't it odd to transfer Dr. Jang?
It's definitely strange.
Does that mean all we have to do is brown-nose him?
What do you mean? He's retiring soon.
That's right. Then I'll have to brown-nose you.
Be careful of what you say.
You scared me. You should've made some noise.
It's only a joke.
- Dr Jang.
- Yes, Sir.
Keep this in mind. We're at war now.
- I'll support you.
You have to keep your head on straight.
I'll keep that in mind.
I'm grateful to know you. Don't you agree?
Here you go. Bottoms up. And I want to hear you sing.
Sorry?
Yeah, sing a song for us.
Yes.
Nice.
He's a really good singer.
Where did you learn how to sing?
- Thank you.
- Hang on.
You should have this.
I'm giving you because you sang well.
- Take it.
- Dr. Yoo...
My hands are going to fall off.
Yes... thank you.
This is expensive. Hold on to it well.
You should put it on.
Don't worry.
I'm the only one that can push Yongkil around.
- Got that?
- Of course.
Who's going to take me home?
My car's right here. Let's go.
Goodbye, Sir
Bye.
What's up?
The light was on.
Did you have a drink?
Why is life so tough?
It's because you're spreading yourself thin.
If you focus on being a doctor, it won't be as tough.
- I can't live like that.
- Life will be tougher for you.
I think I'm bothering you.
Try to sleep. You'll feel much better.
Honey, where are you?
Are you back? How was the surgery?
Good. Wrap that painting up.
- I'm going to give it back.
- Really?
I'll wrap it up, but don't ask me to deliver it.
- Do you know how embarrassing it was?
- I'm sorry.
You should do better, so I can lift my head high.
- Okay, don't cringe.
- It hurts.
What's this?
It's a long story.
What is it? Where did you get such a tacky watch?
Take it off this once.
Even though it's tacky, my life depends on it.
Why weren't you at the dinner last night?
I had to take care of something.
We might not have time to throw you a farewell party.
It's okay, I'll be here often.
Is your wife accompanying you?
I haven't told her yet, so I'm not sure.
If you're going alone, you should stay at the staff residence.
All you have to do is pay $100 per month and come up every weekend.
Yes...
- Hi Dr. Yoo!
- What brings you here?
I came here because I missed you.
This is the Medical Association Chair, Dr. Yoo Pil Sang.
This is the chief of surgery Dr. Lee Joo Wan, and this is Dr. Jang Jun Hyuk.
Dr. Jang?
What an honor
to meet such a wonderful surgeon!
You're too kind.
Chief, haven't we met before?
- Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Isn't Dr. Jang the next chief of surgery?
- No, I'm not.
- What do you mean?
The chief will support you, and so will the assistant director.
In addition, our alumni association will support you.
You're definitely the next successor.
- Don't you agree?
- Well...
What are you talking about?
We have to wait until we tally up the votes at the board of directors' meeting.
I know.
I'm just saying Dr. Jang should win fair and square.
If not, that's completely unfair!
Don't you agree?
Pardon? You're right.
Stop talking nonsense. Why did you come here?
See? I'm already booked.
Why would I come in person and ask you a difficult favor?
I already confirmed I'm going.
I already told them you're lecturing too.
Do you want me to cancel the pharmaceutical seminar for you?
It's okay, I'll do it myself.
You're my best friend.
Honestly, you're the best in geriatrics... You quack.
The Medical Association Chair seems pretentious.
He seems to be a humorous and nice man.
Don't be bothered. Everyone's different.
I'll prepare transitioning my role.
If Dr. Jang is eliminated, then who is the next chief of surgery?
Do you think we'll recruit someone?
- Hello.
How was my farewell party yesterday?
Sorry?
- Yesterday was just a dinner.
- Really?
I'm glad you had a good dinner.
- Can I talk to you, Gun Ha?
- Yes.
I can't believe my career of 20 years went down the drain like this.
It's completely unfair.
What's done is done, but I'm frustrated you might get hurt as well.
I was planning on promoting you to assistant professor...
I can't promise you anything now.
Dr. Jang!
I'll do my best with the other doctors to overturn the decision.
No, don't do that. What if something happens to you?
I'll be wise about it and take the lead.
What if something does happen to you?
That won't ever happen.
Then I'll put you in charge. Thank you.
Don't worry.
I don't know what the chief is up to, but justice will prevail.
I wonder who it is... He must be an alma matter of the chief.
Ah, that's what it was!
What?
A few days ago, I saw something that the chief printed out.
It was a resume.
As I look back, I think they were resumes of the candidates for the next chief.
What?
Who were they?
He took them away from me before I could take a look.
Really?
Why are you being stubborn?
Nurse, can you tell her for me?
You should listen to your mother.
You'll feel uncomfortable if you move to another room.
The nurses take really good care of me.
It's not like I'm recovering faster because you're here.
I won't nurse you, so just stay here.
- No, I don't want to.
- People will talk behind our backs!
Your father is the chief of surgery
How could you be so selfish?
I'm a patient. Shouldn't I do what I want?
Don't you agree?
I transferred them from pediatrics to the department of surgery.
Is it because of the surgery?
The chief of pediatrics tranferred me because
he said she could receive surgery as soon as the chemotherapy reduces the tumor.
I hope things go well this time.
Jin Joo, show me a magic trick.
Don't lose hope.
Just once... please?
Jin Joo's happy and optimistic.
A patient's perspective is very crucial when it comes to fighting off a disease.
Wow, that's so cool. You're so great.
- Dr. Choi!
- Hi, Yu Jin!
- Hello, Madame.
- Hi.
- I didn't know you're here.
- Yes.
She should be at the special room.
But she doesn't care about her father's reputation.
It's okay to be around other people. You made a good decision.
Thanks.
You'll have fun being next to a kid magician.
Jin Joo, say hi. This is Yu Jin.
Hi. Are you a magician?
- Can you show me?
- Are you nice?
What? Why?
She only shows her magic to nice people.
She's nice, show her.
- Wow.
- This is a regular rope.
Watch carefully.
- Wow!
- Wow, that's amazing!
That was wonderful!
I know Chairman Yoo Pil Sang very well.
He's a very close friend of the assistant director.
I didn't know he was so pretentious.
But without him, Dr. Woo couldn't have become the assistant director.
Is that so?
He's a very influential person in the medical world.
He used his influence to elect someone with all the votes.
I guess everyone has their special talents.
I have to go now.
Okay, I'll see you at the wine bar later.
Hello, chief Yoo.
- I brought you the budget for...
- I have to go to the restroom.
I'm already nervous.
I feel like you're going to tell me something that
you can't mention here at the hospital.
It's not a big deal.
I just wanted to buy you a drink out of gratitude.
- I'll see you later.
- Okay.
Where are you going?
I'm going home to get some clothes.
Don't you know nursing isn't necessary at our hospital?
But I should. People are watching.
Don't push yourself too hard.
I don't know. I'll do it for one more day.
- Bye.
- Okay.
Resume
- What's going on?
- The door was locked.
- Did you lock it?
- Why would I?
That's strange.
This is the budget for Dr. Koh's 77th birthday reception.
What about the invitation?
I haven't gotten to that yet. i'll get that to you as soon as possible.
Goodbye.
Dr. Roh Min Kook's resume
Think of it as cultivating cancer cells
to find the appropriate chemotherapy for the patient.
Dr. Choi is an expert in cultivating cancer cells.
I'm sorry, but can you do another presentation for our board of directors?
Of course, anytime.
Can you tell the managers to come to the conference room?
Yes.
Come to think of it, you've been the chief of thoracic surgery for the past 6 years.
You helped me a lot. I am who I am, thank you.
Stop saying that. We're good friends.
But I'm telling the truth.
But sometimes I wonder
if the cooperation will be as strong when I leave.
I'm not too sure about Dr. Jang.
I understand. He may be a good doctor, but he's not humanistic.
That concerns me the most, now that I'm retiring.
You're a wonderful person to feel responsibility for that.
I want him to be the next successor
but for the sake of our hospital, my conscience won't allow me.
What would you do if you were in my shoes?
Well, I would've thought of an alternative plan.
If that's what you thought, can I tell you my opinion?
When I was contemplating about the issue
someone recommended me a candidate.
Who is it? It's my turn to help you.
I'll nominate the candidate at the board of the directors' meeting.
Is that so? I feel like I'm on top of the world.
I don't know if you heard of him but...
What are you discussing about?
Isn't Yun Jin having a fast recovery if she moved to a regular room?
Yeah. Aren't you going to come and visit?
I will. I bet she's upset.
Isn't she unique?
I can't believe she goes on strikes with that kind of patients.
She seems to live life to the fullest.
I think she has a lot in common with you because you both are rigid.
I can't believe I have so many boring people around me.
I agree. The stew looks great.
From the looks of you drinking, I guess you met your match.
Guess who it'll be out of the two.
I don't have to look.
It'll be Dr. Roh Min Kook who graduated from John Hopkins.
He's the best liver transplant surgeon from brain-dead donors.
His works have been on SCI 73 times.
- How did you know?
- Chief Lee told me.
He must've come by.
I'm upset. Why did he make me eavesdrop on an important issue like that and make me spy?
Who did he come with?
The chief of thoracic surgery.
They watch over each other's backs.
Are you confident to beat Dr. Roh?
Dr. Roh... he's the only one I consider a bigshot in my field.
Stop. Mention the replies from liver transplant patients.
Next.
Stop.
Mention the 90% success rate.
Next. Okay.
This will end my report on the 100 case study of dividing the liver
and transplanting them to two recipients.
Turn on the lights.
- The editing seems great.
- Are there any questions?
What are the risks of the procedure?
Just like any other liver transplant procedures
your liver may malfunction or have an adverse reaction.
Do you consider that a question?
Doctors are coming from around the world.
Who would ask such a pathetic question?
Dr. Jang, I think you've been too negligent.
Shouldn't you do the best until the very end?
I'm sorry.
Due to the time constraint, let's end this here.
Before lunch, I want 3 questions from each of you.
I want you guys to stay.
- How could he still haze in this day and age?
- I don't think that's the case.
What do you mean? Everyone knows the department of surgery is the strictest.
If something were to happen, I wouldn't have honorary retirement.
- I'll make sure that won't happen.
- Do a good job.
Chief!
Can you give me the list of the guests for the symposium?
I don't have one.
The chief resident told me you printed out resumes of our special guests.
- He said Dr. Roh and...
- Oh, that.
It's not for the symposium.
The surgical association needed it to make a handbook.
I see. Why would you do that in person?
I can do that for you.
No, it's okay. I already sent it.
Keep up the good work.
Did everything go well yesterday?
Yes. I had positive responses.
- I hope everything works out.
- Me too.
Tell him we'll have to think about it.
Didn't you want to do this?
That's before I knew his relationship with Dr. Woo Yong Kil.
I've observed Dr. Choi for the past 10 years.
And he's a wonderful doctor!
I know, but it won't be wise to upset Dr. Woo.
Let's disregard his proposal.
Hi Dr. Oh.
- Do you have a meeting?
- I have a seminar.
Everyone will appreciate it because you're such a good speaker.
Oh, stop it.
It seems like many good researches cannot be done due to the tight budget.
I know you're busy, but can you choose the best projects?
Is that so?
Isn't that what the assistant director is for?
Goodbye.
- Dr Yoo!
- Hello.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Let's go in. He's doing his seminar.
Did you see my watch at the room salon?
I forgot I was holding onto it.
Thank you. I thought I lost it.
I'm sorry I was wearing it. I didn't want to lose it.
No, it's okay. Let's go in.
Understanding Gerontology
Gerontology is the study of aging.
It can be divided into
Biological Gerontology, Social Gerontology, and Geriatric Medicine.
Today
I'll be covering geriatrics along with social gerontology
to emphasize the importance of this field.
Generally speaking
a person over the age 65 should consult with a Geriatrician.
However, a geriatrician should be consulted
when an older person has considerable impairment and frailty.
Come on in.
I was impressed by your seminar.
Let me introduce you to Dr. Min.
He's the vice chair of the medical association and also Dr. Jang's father in law.
- I see.
- My name is Min Choong Sik.
No wonder Dr. Jang came.
He said he was busy and went back to the hospital.
He said he couldn't miss this seminar for the world.
Really?
I'm sorry for burdening you.
Oh...
This is the stipend for the seminar.
It's only the amount for gas.
Thank you.
I want to give you more, but it's a fixed fee.
Instead I'll buy you a wonderful dinner.
Let's go.
Okay.
- You should've waited inside.
- Because I was nervous.
- How's everything?
- It's not easy.
I didn't bring money because he didn't want me to.
- Father.
- Okay.
Let's just trust Dr. Yoo since he's very suave.
Should I order more alcohol?
It's okay, have a seat.
- I was out of line.
- No, it's okay.
Good friends tend to fight.
Of course, I'm jealous of your friendship.
Here.
Come in!
Would you like to give him a shot? He must be thirsty.
- Let's have a drink.
- Yes.
Dr. Jang, you need to serve Dr. Woo well.
- Yes, I will.
- Do your best.
If you're going to help him, help him all the way.
Fine, fine.
- Let's work together.
- Thank you.
The construction progress is pretty fast.
Yes it is. It's looking good.
Is the director's office at the top?
- I suppose.
- You have to be the next director.
We'll have to see.
By the way, I've made my decision on the transfer.
Is that so?
But we'll be sending Dr. Moon instead of Dr. Jang in your department.
Pardon?
I think there will be more losses than gains.
Everyone was against sending him.
- What's wrong?
- I feel dizzy.
I see.
It's a relief. I was about to write a petition.
Really? Did the interns obey you?
They said they would since I was leading.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
I need to print Dr. Koh's invitations out. Who should I say is hosting it?
What are you talking about?
The chief should be the host since Dr. Koh is from our department
but not many people will show up.
If the assistant director is the host, it'll be a success, but he's an internist.
Yes. Besides, the chief is not in a good mood right now.
- If the assistant director is the host...
- We shouldn't do that.
Let's have the chief as the host. We shouldn't upset him.
Okay.
- Let's follow the rules.
- Yes.
- I understand.
- The president was very grateful.
He really wanted to invest in your research.
So I was wondering if we could buy you a new machine
since you used a lot of our pharmaceutical products in your research.
No thanks.
The president and I both think that you shouldn't stop this valuable research.
I could buy you a cell growth chamber
and we'll provide all the reagents and experimental mice you need
The president already approved it.
If things settle down, we'll officially sponsor it.
Can you temporarily continue the research like this?
Thank you. Please send my thanks to your president.
Yes.
There are no such things as secrets in life.
Besides, my research cannot be secretively done.
Please mention to your president
I would wait until he can officially sponsor my research.
Honestly, everyone does this under the table.
Let's be the ones who play it by the rules.
Thank you.
It's such a nice painting. I'm so happy.
The painting looks better here in my house.
- It looks more graceful.
- You hung it at your house.
Sorry? For a while...
- I'm sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
I can't believe we're our husbands' puppets.
That's why they say a woman's fate depends on her husband.
What?
I can't believe you're saying that in this day and age.
Sorry? Isn't it so?
I guess it's somewhat true.
Do you want to go shopping to make us feel better?
- Pardon?
- Let's go, I'll buy you a purse.
That isn't necessary.
- I know you want one.
- Of course, I do!
- It's a big problem.
- I think you jumped the gun.
Just because the assistant director made
that decision doesn't mean he's partnering up with Dr. Jang.
He probably had his reasons not to transfer him.
No, we've had coffee together before, and they were pretty close.
I should've known then. What if...
Don't overreact. If so, there's always another way.
What is it?
If they grabbed hands with the assistant director
we'll have to work with Dr. Oh.
He's the most revered person in the medical field, so he's very influential.
Also, he doesn't like people like Dr. Jang.
That's right, he doesn't.
Leave Dr. Oh to me. I'll be sure to persuade him.
Okay, I'll rely on you, but we need to do this immediately.
In 2000, Dr. Lee Seung Kyu and
his surgically team at the Asan Medical Center successfully transplanted livers
from 2 people into one patient for the first time in history.
There were many participants due to the family-oriented Korean society.
Our hospital has also performed this procedure
150 times and has a 95% success rate.
Do you have any questions?
Please go ahead.
Congratulations on an amazing success rate.
I was wondering if two partial organs were transplanted in
wouldn't they sink below and as a result cause poor blood circulation.
... place of an original size liver...
That's a wonderful question.
In order to prevent that from happening
we insert a tissue extender to fill in the empty space.
However, wouldn't the extender enlarge
the partial liver and become a hindrance?
It may if you were to leave in its original state.
We will monitor the organ growth
through a CT scan and remove water when necessary.
Then you would have to remove the tissue extender
once the organ has growed to its full size.
Yes, that's correct.
The timing of the surgery will vary depending on the recipient's condition.
Yes, thanks for answering my question.
Can you tell me who you are?
I'm sorry I didn't introduce myself.
My name is Roh Min Kook, and I'm from Johns Hopkins.
Let me introduce you to Dr. Jang Jun Hyuk.
I'm Roh Min Kook, I always wanted to meet you.
I too wanted to meet you.
I was impressed by your article on the Lancet.
Thank you.
I also read up on all your articles that you release.
Thank you. Let's discuss about our research.
Aren't you busy, Dr. Jang?
He's busy wrapping things up. You should go now.
By the way, who's the host for Dr. Koh's 77th birthday reception?
It's the assistant director, Dr. Woo Yong Kil.
When did my name change to this?
This reception isn't necessarily for the medical staff.
It'll be more effective if the assistant director hosts it
because we'll have more guests and receive more donations.
That may be so, but it'll seem pretentious if we receive donations.
Change the host to me, even if we have to reduce the budget.
I think that'll be difficult to do.
Difficult?
I've already sent out the invitations to confirm the RSVPS.
It'll arrive...
You say you discuss matters with me, but you always do things on your own.
- I was trying to rapidly...
- Forget it.
That's what bothers me about you the most.
I warned you many times, but you never changed.
You'll have to fill in my shoes when I retire.
If you keep this up, even if I recommend you
people will oppose of you.
Along with being a good surgeon
you have to be insightful and have a good personality to be a good doctor.
I'm trying to change according to your constructive feedback.
But you haven't at all!
If you keep this up
I maybe not be able to recommend you as chief of surgery even if I want to.
What if that happens to you?
I highly doubt that would happen.
If that were to happen,
I won't stay put.