Who are you?
Hello, I'm Nancy Drew.
It's nice to meet you.
May I ask who you are?
- Guess.
- All right.
I'm guessing you two are working
with Lawrence McNabb...
...the locksmith,
he gives you the keys...
...and you're responsible
for the recent burglaries.
However, you should know
the DA is only interested in McNabb...
You two could make a deal with him.
- And that Charlie the security guard
is about to walk through that door.
Hi.
Listen to me. L'll get Pastor Murray
to drop the charges...
...if you agree to
some kind of counseling.
Anger issues don't just go away.
- I don't need a shrink.
- Yeah, you do.
He gets cranky when he hasn't eaten.
I told him, "Go have a snack."
I said, "Before we get here,
you better have a snack."
Oh, one summer,
we're on Fire lsland...
Not with that story again.
Hold on.
What's that?
My sleuth kit.
Flashlight, fountain pen, notebook,
magnifying glass, fingerprint powder...
...digital recorder...
...and one of Hannah's lemon bars.
Bess,
is Nancy okay?
Are you kidding?
She's loving it.
- Here he is.
- Nancy?
Hi, Ned.
I had this dream
during my nap today...
...you went to California,
met that guy on Smallville...
...and you got amnesia...
...and forgot you ever met me,
and then I turned into a squirrel.
Anyway, what do you
think that means?
Ned, can we talk about this later?
I'm just a little busy.
Yeah, sorry.
All right, okay.
Not appropriate, Ned.
You take naps?
What's going on?
Ls she okay?
Hey, now don't worry.
I just talked with her. She's doing fine.
Nancy's my best man.
I mean, she would be
if she were on the force.
Fine. Therapy.
Great.
L'll call the DA back.
I just wanna thank you, Nancy Drew.
I've always heard
the nicest things about you...
...the way you solve mysteries
and you help people.
Steve?
Please don't thank her for turning us in.
I think Crankenstein needs
another lemon bar.
I thought the Crankasaurus was extinct.
I don't know about this.
Well, I'm sorry, Cranky Doodle Dandy.
I can't do this.
Gary, we made a deal.
Deals go wrong.
Hey. Where is she?
We need her.
You take that side.
Hey, Gary, look.
Hey!
Let's get out of here.
It's Nancy!
Hi, everybody.
Hold it there.
Hold it right there.
Hold on, Nancy.
We got the fire department here.
That's all right, chief.
L'll be down in a jiffy.
Hang on, Nancy.
Are you okay?
I'm fine, Dad. Really.
In the sleuthing business,
this kind of thing happens all the time.
It really isn't a big deal.
It is a big deal.
I ran from the courthouse in the middle
of that eviction case, which the judge...
...he didn't appreciate.
Where is your car?
Around the corner.
Is now a better time?
Because I wanted to give you this.
Well, your hunch was right
on the nose, Nancy.
Just wish you could have
clued us in a little earlier.
- Safe as usual.
- All right, Nancy, right here.
Hi, Nancy.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Nancy, what are we going to do
without you?
Lt's only for a few months.
L'll be back.
The image of your mother.
Do you remember her at all?
No.
She was such a lovely woman,
so kind and intelligent.
Just like you, Nancy.
- Bye, everybody.
- Bye-bye.
So long, Nancy.
Shall we all pray
for her safe journey to California?
Sure.
Dear Lord,
please watch over Nancy Drew...
...and protect her as she strives
to solve mysteries...
...that are beyond the abilities
of local law enforcement agencies.
Dad, I'm...
I want you to promise no more sleuthing,
at least while we're in California.
You'll go to school, shopping,
spend some time with teenagers.
It's what you're supposed to be doing.
Give it a try.
You know, I've always picked cases
that help people.
- Others first.
- That's right.
But this one is a little different.
If everything goes well,
I could start making some real money.
We have enough money, Dad.
L'll be the judge of that, thank you.
At any rate, I'm starting something new.
I can't be worried about...
How you doing, John?
Yeah, l'll meet you at the deposition
as soon as my train gets in.
Well, we don't have an airport out here.
I wish I was kidding.
This is a terrible development.
What are you gonna do?
You have a mystery to solve in la-la land.
L'll figure something out.
I hope.
Ned.
With all the commotion,
I didn't get to give you this.
I needed a new compass.
The old one's wobbly.
Thank you.
In case I'm not with you
on your birthday.
That's so sweet.
I just don't know if l'll get to use it.
Why?
My dad let me choose the house we're
gonna live in, so I chose one with...
With a mystery.
But not just any mystery. One of the
greatest unsolved cases of all time.
Dehlia Draycott.
The movie actress.
Before your time.
Twenty-five years ago...
...at the height of her fame,
she disappeared for five months.
Nobody knew where.
And when she came back,
she threw a giant party.
She never went downstairs
to greet her guests.
She was found floating in the pool.
Dead.
Gee, that sounds like fun.
I know, right?
But I didn't tell my dad about the house
and he's not letting me do any sleuthing.
There was a hostage situation.
I can kind of see his point, but...
Hi, Ned. Bye, Ned.
Gotta scoot, Nancy.
Mr. Drew.
Some pfeffernüsse, just in case...
...and some ginger cupcakes,
your favorite.
You're gonna get hungry,
I know it.
- Nancy, hold on.
- Thank you so much.
- Bye, guys.
- See you soon.
- And have a safe train ride, okay?
- L'll miss you.
Don't get hurt.
Please, you have to keep in contact.
Ned? Don't worry
about that guy from Smallville.
- He's not my type.
- Nancy.
You have a type?
Chief McGinnis! I just wanna let you
know I'm not sleuthing anymore. Bye.
Nancy Drew not sleuthing anymore?
I don't think so.
Hi, this is Carson Drew.
I'm running a little late.
Dad? Don't you think people
who talk on cell phones miss things?
- Like what, hon?
- Like that woman in the street?
Mr. Drew? Nancy?
Yes.
Hi. Thank you so much
for not running me over.
I'm Barbara Barbara,
of Barbara Barbara Realty.
You're here.
I'm gonna get right out of your way.
How do you love it?
Gorgeous.
Welcome.
It's not exactly what I had
in mind, especially given the price.
Well, as I told your daughter on the
phone, you do pay a premium for my...
Oh, I am such an oaf.
As you were saying, you pay a premium
for history, architectural significance.
I mean, Dad, look at this woodwork.
- Yeah, what she said.
- Who's this?
Dehlia Draycott, the great film legend.
This was her home.
Didn't your daughter tell you?
We've both been somewhat busy.
Oh, excuse me. Gotta... Yeah.
Hello?
Do you know what? With a little
tweaking, you could be adorable.
Thank you?
Yes, you're just a makeover
waiting to happen.
I'm gonna give you
the name of my stylist.
Oh, come on, let's go upstairs.
I can't wait to show you.
Did you hear something?
I suddenly got a chill.
Have a look around, if you want.
Don't be afraid.
Please don't be afraid of me.
I'm here to help you.
You don't understand, I want to...
I want to help you.
I love that.
They fall for it every time.
That's a projector.
It's from one of her old movies.
There are so many booby traps
all over this house.
People get so scared sometimes,
they wet their pants.
Where's the gift shop?
That's the spirit.
Miss Barbara Barbara, I know I called
asking for a house with a mystery...
...but things have changed, and...
It's complicated,
but we're gonna need a different house.
Honey cheeks.
Read the fine print.
No refunds, no exchanges.
And besides, you know, there's nothing
else available, in your price range.
I'm gonna use the gents',
then run to that deposition.
Watch this.
Something just happened in the
bathroom which I'm at a loss to explain.
The house has a haunted theme.
It's like a theme park.
It's so fun, right, Dad?
No.
Oh, did I mention?
There's a strange caretaker.
He lives in an apartment down the hill.
What's your name?
Leshing. Let me know
if there's anything I can do for you.
Nancy Drew.
Thank you very much.
Leshy?
We need to talk about the lawn.
Dad?
Mr. Leshing?
Someone stole my moccasins
and an important folder.
Mysteries just find you, don't they?
I'm letting the professionals handle
this one. I'm on hold with the L.A.P.D.
Calling the police to solve a crime.
I like it.
It's been 57 minutes.
They must be having a busy night.
- Yes, I'd like to report a theft.
- I'm fine!
A favorite pair of moccasins
and a Pee Chee folder have been stolen.
Please send an officer over
immediately.
Someone must have told a joke
over at the precinct.
Yeah. That's it.
Because it would be irresponsible for
a police department to laugh at a crime.
You're right.
Dad?
- Hello?
- Leshing, this is Nancy.
I needed to prove your whereabouts.
Go back to sleep.
Someone's in the house.
How did you get here so quickly?
Lf you're accusing me...
The attic.
How is it possible for someone
to be in the attic...
...and escape
while we're coming up the stairs?
Ls there another staircase?
No.
Do you believe in ghosts, Mr. Leshing?
I am a ghost.
The Four Seasons isn't haunted.
What do you say?
Dad, you hate hotels.
Spa treatments.
Room service.
These books must have been Dehlia's.
May I borrow some?
Lf it were up to me, I wouldn't let
anybody in the house, period.
But you're paying the rent,
so do what you want.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean...
Good night.
I like him.
So turns out there's a mystery
here after all.
Dad, that mystery stuff is so boring
to me now. I've completely moved on.
That was really just a phase, you know,
like papier-mâché or puppets.
It's over, done, finished,
gone forever.
Got it.
Z, I'm sorry to have vanished
like I did.
I know you have been looking for me.
Something important happened last week.
I can 't be the Dehlia I was anymore.
I'm writing a new will.
I need to make provisions
for someone else. D.
D is Dehlia, but who's Z?
Who's the "someone else"?
No.
You're not sleuthing.
No, sirree.
You're just reading a letter
that happens to be a major clue...
...in a fantastically famous mystery.
That means nothing to you.
You're gonna go to bed
and be reasonable, Nancy.
You're going to a new school.
You're gonna make wonderful friends.
You're a normal teenager.
You really are.
Yeah.
- Yes.
- The quadratic formula:
Negative-B plus or minus
the square root of B-squared...
...minus four A-C, all over two A.
I only had enough time
for 12 flying buttresses.
But in actuality, there are 26.
Then l'll be brief.
O happy dagger!
Thank you. Please.
This is thy sheath.
There rust, and let me die.
The show is Pippin.
And I just wanted your name.
Hey, baby. How you doing?
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hi, I noticed you were wearing
penny loafers.
Did your podiatrist suggest them
or are you being ironic?
I like old-fashioned things.
Oh, we've noticed.
Penny loafers are practical.
Well, we may be on the brink
of a penny loafer fashion moment...
...or not.
That was awesome.
- Give that cupcake back.
- Shut up.
Come on.
That's a good cupcake.
Principal Fineman, I feel strongly...
...students should be given a more
nutritious alternative in the cafeteria.
Perhaps a salad bar.
A salad bar. Terrific idea.
Hi. I think the principal
wants to yell at me or something?
Let's see. Oh, yes.
There may be lead paint in
the shed next to the volleyball courts...
...but I can't be certain until
the lab report comes back.
Lead paint.
That's bad, right?
Very bad.
But there's no need to panic.
Finally, I urge you
to offer a course in CPR.
I noticed it wasn't
part of your curriculum.
I'm certified and I have found
great peace of mind...
...knowing I may
save a life someday.
So hot, so hot, so hot, hot!
Yeah, we know we're hot
Sorry that you're not
We go:
Cha-ching, where's the money?
- Oh, my God!
- Corky!
Oh, my God. No, no, no.
No, my brother's choking!
My brother's choking!
Does anyone know CPR?
I do. I know CPR.
Excuse me.
Don't worry.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Oh, my God.
Oh, you idiot!
You were supposed to kiss her.
Lip-lock. That was the plan.
I'm looking forward to the journey.
And I don 't care
if a woman unaccompanied...
...is considered to be shameful.
I've done nothing wrong.
My heart is...
Yes? Your heart is?
Cut.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, I don 't know how much more time.
And action.
I'm looking forward to the journey...
...and I don 't care that...
- I feel sick. I need to stop.
- Cut.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
The door was unlocked.
The shutters had rusted closed,
and the bulbs were all burnt-out.
Leave it on.
I haven't been here
since the night she...
You were here the night she died?
How long did you work for her?
Year I got out of the service,
I went to work at the studio.
They sent me over here
to project a film for her...
...and she asked me to stay
and take care of her, so I did.
That was 1971.
When she disappeared,
did you know where she was?
No.
She never married
and she seemed to be very private...
...but there must have been a...
There must have been a man...
Someone she loved?
Every man who met her
fell in love with her.
It just couldn't be helped.
I just don't know
if she ever felt love herself.
Hi. Yeah, I'm sorry
about the weirdness the other day.
I have to say,
my feelings were a little bruised.
But, thank you, Corky.
An apology is the sign of a gentleman.
Inga roped me into the shenanigans.
She's my sister,
but I also think she might be the devil.
Also, you know, I thought
if you gave me mouth-to-mouth...
...it would be a fantastic way for us
to get to know each other.
The truth is, you're awesome.
By the way, did you know
there's a mystery to this house?
I know.
I only recently discovered that movies
aren't shot from beginning to end.
So I took the last movie
she ever made...
...and reassembled the shots
in the order they were photographed.
Okay.
I just noticed something strange.
The last month before she disappeared,
she's only shown from here up.
Maybe she was pregnant.
She didn't have any kids.
Never married and no kids.
It's just a hunch.
Also, the photograph in this magazine
is dated just after her reappearance.
There's an X on her robe.
I believe that insignia will tell us
where she was hiding.
I've called the hospitals and hotels
that include the letter X...
...but so far, nothing.
I need to talk to someone
who's an expert in clothing.
Oh, and one more thing.
She's often with this man,
but he's always obscured.
A hand at the edge of a picture,
a silhouette...
...even a blur.
I think she called him Z.
I have to find out who this man is.
I just have to solve this case.
What do you think?
I think the ability to sleuth
is an attractive quality in a woman.
Hey, don't they have a Costume
Department on the set of every film?
Yeah, but you should know
that movie people are kind of crazy.
Oh, goodness.
How crazy can they be?
- Really crazy.
- Dude, are we on yet?
No, I gotta be on one more...
You're fine.
- Oh, I just had a question.
- And I'm all out of answers.
You look '50s. Go to set.
- But I was just wondering if maybe...
- Now!
Here we go. Okay, we're moving. We're
moving, people. We're on our way.
We are moving!
Hey, guys, this is good.
They got the feed up.
All right, let's just shoot the rehearsal.
Has anybody seen Mr. Fancy-Pants?
Right here, you idiot.
Nickname, I love a nickname.
It's not a nickname, Andy.
It's not a nickname.
You really are an idiot.
- All right.
- Copy that. On our way.
Okay, we're shooting the rehearsal!
- Stop with the bowing.
- Excuse me, sir. No, sir. No, l...
By the way, it's "action,"
not "begin the acting."
- When you're right, you're right.
- Action.
Locking it up! Last looks, everybody.
Last looks.
- Walking away. Walking away.
- Quiet, please.
And we're rolling.
- Rolling!
- We're rolling!
- You're cute.
- Thank you.
Okay, you hate crime, and action!
Hold him right there, boys.
Spider Weintraub.
As I live and breathe.
You have the right to remain silent.
You have the right to an attorney...
Excuse me, I'm sorry, but...
- What?
- I'm sorry. This just feels inauthentic.
Feels what?
Well, the scene takes place in the '50s,
but you're reading Miranda to the suspect.
Excuse me. Why in the name of sweet
Christmas is this tiny person talking?
Well, reading of Miranda
upon arrest wasn't law until '63.
Is that right?
The scene is still delicious, either way.
- What's your name, hon?
- Nancy Drew.
I'm Bruce.
All right, l'll tell you what, why don't
you direct the movie, Nancy Drew?
Oh, my God!
Should we cut?
Listen, Nancy, would you consider,
you know, directing this film?
Because we can
get rid of this guy in a second.
Is there a law against common courtesy
in Los Angeles?
Courtesy is so awesome.
I'm really into it.
In my book, courtesy counts.
I'd like to read that book, Nancy.
It's not an X.
They're palm trees.
Okay. What does that mean?
The insignia on her robe.
It's...
Something Palms.
Oh, now I get it.
Just kidding, I don't.
Southern Pines.
California Hot Springs. No.
Twin Palms Bungalows and Spa.
There was a fire some 20 years ago
and all the records were burned.
And on top of that,
I'm afraid our guest list is confidential.
Where's the closest hospital?
All the children born in one week
24 years ago?
Yes. Well, all the ones given up
for adoption.
The birth mother,
she may have left money for the child...
I'm sorry, but those records are sealed.
Only a court order
can open those records.
And only by a child seeking a parent.
Are you the child?
No.
But thank you, anyway.
Here's a blondie for your trouble.
Did...? Did you make these?
No. Hannah, our housekeeper
back in River Heights, did.
She sent over a tin.
She's a wonderful baker.
It's so weird. My mother made these
when I was a kid.
I haven't had one in years.
It's so perfectly moist.
Come here.
The county recommends a pediatrician
to new adoptive parents.
The doctor's files aren't sealed.
This might help.
- Thank you.
- And you didn't get that from me.
Twenty-four years ago.
Wow, that is so long ago.
Yes. It would have been
a first appointment, a newborn.
I know it seems a little "disorganisized"
but I know where everything is.
Right there. Here it is.
There were two newborns that week.
No, make that three.
Oh, but I don't think
I can release any information.
Let me call headquarters.
Maybe that's them.
- Hello?
- Hey, girl. It's Jimmy.
Oh, Jimmy. Yeah, no, I was
looking for it, then I found it. I found it.
I did find it and it's...
That's not it, but it's pink.
And it wasn't...
No, it wasn't where
I thought it was...
- I think it's yellow.
- Because I put it somewhere else.
Yeah. Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
I'm gonna have to call you ba...
I'm gonna have to call you back.
Nice try, squirt. Nice try.
Hello, I'm looking for Jane Brighton.
Are you Jane Brighton?
Are you Martine Dahlberg?
Yeah. Why?
I was just wondering, were you adopted?
Are you Susan Thabit?
Were you adopted?
- Are you Martine Dahlberg?
- Yes.
Were you adopted?
Hello...
Can I help you?
Sorry, no.
No.
- No.
Nope.
- No...
Hello?
Ls there a Jane Brighton here?
That depends on who's asking.
Were you adopted?
Yeah.
Who are you?
You're who I'm looking for.
I am?
Hi.
You're kidding.
Did your parents tell you
that you were adopted?
Lt wasn't hard to figure out.
I mean, I didn't look anything like them.
My mother passed away,
and then my father...
I had to get away from him.
I left home early.
Dehlia Draycott.
Dehlia may have made a
provision for you.
If we prove you're her daughter,
there may be some money.
Is this some kind of a practical joke?
Oh, no. I don't joke.
I get that a lot.
I'm 12, but I skipped a few grades.
Because you were ahead academically?
Heck, no. There just wasn't any action
in junior high...
...so my dad made a few calls.
Anyway, I was wondering
if we could do, like, a dinner thing?
Like, Saturday-ish?
Not a date.
Corky, you've been really nice to me...
l'll show you the sights.
We'll have a few laughs.
- But there's this guy
in River Heights.
Oh, ouch. Okay.
Well, you still need to eat,
and it's not a date.
Okay. Seeing as how it's not a date...
- What was th...?
- Go. Go, go, go.
That car, it almost hit us.
- Hurry! Go, go, go!
- Hey!
I wonder who tried to kill us.
Yeah, I'm wondering that too.
In fact, I'm kind of freaking out about it.
Well, usually when someone tries to
kill me it's because I'm onto something.
Oh, you have a cut.
There were dealer plates on the SUV.
I made note of the make, year and model.
Plus, the damage sustained from hitting
the barrier could help us identify it too.
You're just not like the other girls,
Nancy.
Hello?
Do not look into this
Dehlia Draycott business.
If you proceed, you will be harmed.
Do you understand?
We're not interested
in mudslide insurance...
...but thank you for calling.
Have a nice day.
Whoa, what's this?
I apologize, sir.
Allow me to introduce myself.
My name is Nancy Drew.
It's very nice to make your acquaintance.
I've been trying to set up
an appointment, but...
Posture, eye contact.
Pay attention, people, that's breeding.
I was just wondering if I could have five
minutes to discuss something with you.
Any time at all.
Here's my card.
Thank you.
It's about one of your clients,
a movie star.
All my clients are movie stars, muffin.
Well, I may have found
some evidence suggesting that...
- Astonishing.
- It may imply that...
Absolutely astonishing.
As I was saying...
I'm very disappointed, senator.
Well, as you know,
you do owe me a favor or two.
Well, talk to somebody else on your staff.
Maybe they can help you out on this.
Jane? Are you there?
Hi. I saw the lawyers who represent
the estate today and they...
It's all right.
I don't need any help.
What? Don't you wanna know
if you're Dehlia's daughter?
Just leave us alone, okay?
You seem like a really nice person.
I'm sorry.
The will is in the Chinese box.
So there is a will.
See for yourself.
Miss Draycott collected chinoiserie.
Last year, the owner sold off the most
valuable pieces, against my wishes.
Do you remember
the name of the dealer?
You ask a lot of questions.
Is it this place? I noticed the ad
was circled. Do they have the box?
Let me tell you something, young lady.
Everyone who has tried to piece
this thing together has run into trouble.
Hello?
So you should be getting an early
birthday present/reward thing...
...for going along with my
"no sleuthing while in California" thing.
Dad, you shouldn't have.
I don't really deserve it.
Yes, you do.
I know it hasn 't been easy for you...
...and this'll make me feel less guilty.
But what is it?
Just walk outside.
Hi. My sister dropped me off
and now she won't go away.
Leave!
My roadster.
Dad, how did you get it here?
Happy almost-your-birthday.
Ned.
You drove this all the way here?
Yeah, it wouldn't fit in my suitcase.
I've missed this car so much...
...and you.
I've missed the car and you.
Ned, Corky. Corky, Ned.
Ned is my...
...really good friend from River Heights.
River Heights, right.
That's in one of those fly-over states.
Wait. Did I interrupt something?
Yes, actually. You did.
Hello?
- Hello? Nancy?
- Oh, Dad. Thank you so much.
We have to go.
Corky's going on a date with her?
Whoa, Nancy Weirdo has,
like, two dates.
That other one is cute.
I don't usually go for the
just-back-from-slopping-the-hogs type...
...but he's cute.
Hello.
Would you like to order some drinks?
L'll have a glass of milk, please.
Milk. How refreshingly wholesome.
L'll have the exact same thing.
Who is this person?
Nancy and I met,
and things just clicked.
We laugh, we talk.
We keep it real.
- Keep it real?
- We're basically best friends.
It's funny that she
never mentioned you.
Hey, buddy,
she wants your drink order.
Can I get an iced latte?
No latte in Chinese restaurant, silly.
Yeah, silly.
No latte in the Chinese restaurant.
Don't talk to me.
All right.
Wow, this is fun, huh?
Ned and I have known
each other since second grade.
He helped me solve the mystery
of the missing chalkboard erasers.
It was a janitor.
Fantastic.
Oh, my gosh.
How funny.
Here we are and here you are.
Hi, what's your name?
Ned?
You're not sure?
No. I mean, yes, I'm sure.
Why are you here?
Hey, hey, guys, don't gang up on me.
I'm sensitive.
Hello. I'm looking for a box.
That is, one in particular.
What kind of box?
Chinese?
Well, you've come to the right place.
So this is why
you wanted Chinese food.
What are you guys doing in here?
This is so nonlinear.
Everybody pick a row.
Check inside each box.
We're looking for a will.
- Wait, what's over there?
- Hey.
Ned, did you see this box yet?
Nothing there.
- No, no, no. Don't... Don't touch.
- Corky.
Hey, watch the top.
That is very expensive.
- Hey there. Come here.
- You see this? Lt's big.
Put that down.
What? You think you're funny?
Do you think you're funny?
So not cute.
There is one more.
So, Nance, what's the deal
with you and Ned?
Do you hear something?
No, I mean, are you two like a thing?
Excuse me, I have to defuse this bomb.
No kidding.
Love is a battlefield.
Nancy.
That's the SUV that tried to run
us down. The side's damaged. Come on.
What was that?
Are you okay? What was that?
- Hurry, we're losing them.
- Oh, so you meant literally a bomb.
What was that? What was that?
Are you okay?
Hello?
They turned up that street!
Hold on. I thought we were
driving away from them.
That's why I got in the car.
- Buckled up?
- I'm fine.
Buckling up.
Say we do catch up with them,
what happens then?
Seriously.
It gets my goat when
someone tries to kill me. It's so rude.
But it only makes me
wanna try harder.
Then let the horses run.
We will go the posted speed limit
and no faster.
Everybody in the universe
drives over the speed limit, Nancy.
Nancy is trying to say
the ends do not justify the means.
Your means will lose them.
It's important to judge the ends
and the means independently...
...to do what's right.
Didn't you promise your father
that you wouldn't sleuth?
Aren't you breaking that promise?
What are you gonna do?
I have to stop working on this case.
I have to stop and be normal.
What's this?
Oh, just normal stuff.
Normal teenage stuff.
Okay. Carry on.
- He just pinched me!
- Deal with it.
If we're gonna baby-sit him,
we should get paid.
Ned, why is your shirt all wrinkled?
Because my closet's 6 inches deep.
That's not possible.
How could...?
Show me.
What are you guys doing?
"Hey, Corky. We're super glad
you asked. Would you like to tag along?"
Seriously. Oh, God.
What is going on?
I just fell down.
But I'm fine.
I still don't know what's going on.
Whenever you feel like letting me know.
A secret passageway.
So this is how the intruder
has been getting upstairs.
This is nuts.
Ned, will you get my flashlight?
Lt's in my kit.
Wouldn't this be considered sleuthing?
Who are we kidding?
I can't stop.
Once I find the will
and determine the identity of Z...
...l'll tell my father everything.
He'll understand.
I mean, how else am I
gonna help Jane?
Lt's important.
Don't you think?
Yeah.
What was that?
I think we just had an earthquake.
Hello?
Nancy.
Are you all right?
Where are you?
I'm in the basement.
Do you see anything?
I found a tunnel and I'm going in.
If I'm not back in 10 minutes,
something bad's happened.
I don't think that was a joke.
I lay there on the ground
Who will wind the clock when I'm away
Hi.
A tunnel in the laundry room.
What the hell is that all about?
John Leshing.
He's a tenant in this building.
He's the caretaker
of the Dehlia Draycott estate.
If anyone knows about the tunnel,
he does.
That man has always
given me the willies.
The drowning-kittens type.
You know what I mean?
Hi. These are for you two.
- Here you go.
- Okay.
These are for you two.
I hope you attend.
I know that she's weird,
but we have to go.
Why?
Ned, my future husband,
is gonna be there.
Jane? Lt's me, Nancy.
I was wondering if you and Allie
wanted to come to a party.
Oh, my goodness.
Wow, guys, your streamers look great.
Let's see yours.
Yeah, yours are all right.
Downloading's cool...
...but nothing sounds like vinyl.
You couldn't be more right if you tried,
Nancy.
Yeah.
- Hi.
I brought a few friends.
I hope you don't mind, all right?
No.
Oh, I didn't get the memo
about it being a retarded theme.
Hey, Ned.
Hi.
Oh, can I take your coat or...?
Okay.
Refreshments are in the dining room.
We'll be having a taffy pull
later, guys.
- Come on in.
- Hi.
Hi.
Refreshments in the dining room.
Oh, hello.
Hi. Oh, you look lovely.
Leshing, come quick!
So did you grow up in River Depths?
Tell me about it. Is there a river?
River Heights.
Yeah, there's a river.
Oh, I knew that. I totally knew that.
How did I know that?
Hey. Hey.
Oh, you wanna dance, right?
Hi.
I just wanted to ask you if you knew
about the secret passageway.
I think you got your answer.
Are you Z?
Miss Drew, I suggest you rejoin
your guests and enjoy the party.
Hold on.
Hello?
- I warned you...
...drop this Draycott business.
Who is this?
- Please, stop calling here.
- Nancy?
Oh, hi, Dad.
Where are you?
I'm going to be even later to your party
than I said. I'm sorry, honey.
Is everything all right?
Sounds a little crazy there.
Yeah, everything's totally mellow.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely. Hurry home.
Happy birthday, Nancy.
Back off, man.
Somebody call 911.
You! You know CPR, come on,
do something. Trish is choking!
This is not a joke.
Out of the way, out of the way.
Coming through.
Oh, my God. Do something,
do something. Somebody call 911!
They'll be here in 10 minutes.
Does she have any allergies?
She's insanely allergic to peanuts,
but she didn't eat anything.
I had a peanut butter cookie,
and we were making out.
Oh, my God.
I need a knife and a ballpoint pen.
- Here.
- Here you go.
Everybody, unless you've had
advanced emergency medical training...
...you must never attempt this
on your own.
Holy crap.
You know, I have to admit...
...I thought you were some insane, freak,
idiot person before, but you're not.
You're pretty terrific.
Anyone can learn
emergency medical procedures.
I'm talking about
how great the party was.
Saving Trish's life was fantastic also.
Anyways, I'd like to take you
and your little friend Ned out shopping.
You really do need a decent outfit.
What happened?
Lt was a lively party.
Almost everyone had a good time.
- I take it you're Nancy's father.
- That's right.
We responded to a complaint
from a neighbor.
Dad, this is Sergeant Billings.
No, no, no.
Let me say something.
You had a wild party.
You blew it out when Dad was MIA.
Damage was done.
Things went amuck. I get it.
Congratulations.
Getting rowdy is part of being
a normal, non-sleuthing teenager.
All right. That's a first.
Come on. Come on.
Hi. Obviously someone here
needs a little help with their look.
Oh, it's not that bad.
Oh, please, it's a fashion teardown.
You have some nice pieces.
They're just not really working together.
Me? I was talking about her.
Oh, sorry.
Wow, where did you get that dress?
I made it from one
of my mother's patterns.
It is just darling.
I love the sincerity.
I have to take your picture.
You know what? I just remembered
how much I really hate this store.
Excuse me?
I wish you could stay longer.
My mom said if I stayed past the
weekend she'd turn my room into a den.
Really?
Anyway, Nancy, I just want you to know
I'm not interested in that Inga person.
In fact, she scares me.
And that if you like this Porky guy...
Corky.
- It's all right with me.
Ned, he's 12.
You just seem to really like
having him around.
Ned, can I ask you a question?
Can you tell when a girl
is thinking how much she likes you...
...wondering if you like her, thinking
how important it is how you feel...
...before she says anything more
about how she feels about you...
...because she's already saying
how she feels in her own way?
Can you repeat the question?
Your cab's here.
Sorry to see you go, Ned.
L'll see you soon.
Bye, Ned.
Jane, are you all right?
No. Child Protective Services, they...
They took her. They took Allie.
They said I was an unfit parent,
but it isn't true.
I didn't do any
of the things that they said.
Come in, come in.
You're always able to help people.
I can certainly try.
Why don't you come
downtown tomorrow?
I will. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Sure. What's the connection?
How did you two meet?
I'm Dehlia Draycott's daughter.
You're what? Wait.
Dad, it's so late.
Jane's tired and so am I.
Let's go over all this in the morning,
in the promising light of a new day.
Right.
Have you been sleuthing?
Dad, do you really think
I've been sleuthing?
- That's not answering my question.
- You're not answering mine.
- Your what?
- What?
I'm going to bed.
Good night.
Listen, I have to tell you something.
Right after you first found me,
someone came to my apartment. A man.
He said if I ever tried to prove that I was
Dehlia's daughter, that I would regret it.
That's why I was afraid
to talk to you that time.
- What did he look like?
- He was big.
Dark hair. Scary.
And he had one pale blue eye
and one very, very dark.
Someone is filing grievances against you,
but I don't know who yet.
But it isn't true.
None of it happened.
How can they just take a kid
away from its mother?
I believe you. And I think
a judge will too. It just takes time.
We'll get her back. I promise you.
Now, is there anyone
who might have something against you?
Dad, look,
there's something I need to tell you.
It has to do with this whole...
Carson!
Nancy.
After Jane's little revelation, I found out
who the lawyer for the estate was...
...and I gave him a call.
He and I are going to talk privately.
Do you have your car?
Down the block.
What are you two...?
Dinner, tonight.
I've got a lot of questions...
...and I think you
just might have the answers.
Feel like some hot cocoa?
- Channel presents
The Life and Death of Dehlia Draycott.
It's so weird.
I never used to think about her at all...
...and now I see her everywhere.
What if I am an unfit mother?
I don't know what I'm doing.
No one taught me what to do.
Jane...
Nancy, I don't think you understand
what it's like growing up without a mom.
Actually, my mother died
when I was very young.
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
You've been so nice to me.
Sometimes, I think I can remember her.
But I never know if what I remember
is something I saw in a picture...
...or just made up.
She's...
She's a mystery.
Someone in the village told me
that the will is in the Chinese box.
Wait a minute.
What are we looking for?
A clue.
It's empty.
You must make the dragon bow.
- The will.
- I must've fallen asleep when I heard this.
I've finally found it.
Dehlia used a clue from one of her movies
to show someone where to find the will.
Now all I have to do
is make the dragon bow.
Okay, you lost me at "dragon."
L'll be back later.
Hello? Hello, Mr. Louie?
Are you in there?
Hello?
I'm sorry to interrupt your dinner, but
this means so much to my two friends.
It's fine.
It's the will.
If you want it, you can have it.
Thank you so much.
"I give all my property and assets
to my daughter born July 28th, 1981."
I knew it.
- Dad. I have to talk to you.
- Hi, honey.
What number are you calling from?
My cell phone.
The one you gave me.
I didn 't give you a cell phone.
Honey?
I have to get off this phone.
Everything's fine. See you tonight.
Nancy...
So they're the ones
who've been breaking in.
Oh, Mary, you're exaggerating.
No one blames you for Henry's death.
Least of all Jezebel.
You've got to stop.
It's not your fault, Mary.
You do believe that, don 't you, baby?
You don 't think
I was born bad, do you?
I could never care if you were.
Mary, I love you.
Go check on her.
Wait. I want to see this part.
Kids will love it just for making chocolate
pasta for those delicious desserts.
Besides pasta, you can also make
pie crust, cinnamon rolls...
She's not there.
- Look again.
- She's not there.
- Excuse me.
- Hey!
Go get her!
Hey!
Hey.
She's getting away! Jump!
Go, go, get the car!
You idiots.
Right there.
- Hi, Dad.
- Are you okay? What happened?
Just your run-of-the-mill car accident.
I swerved out of control because...
Because men were chasing me.
I've been working on a case.
I'm gonna give you two some time.
Thank you.
- I started to tell you today.
- You could have been killed.
Do you realize that?
- I was just trying to do the right thing.
- This is a very dangerous city.
- The world is not like River Heights.
- I know.
I mean, I tried to be normal.
I really tried.
I just start working on something
and I can't stop.
I wonder where you got that from.
I mean, the idea of a girl out there
without her mom...
Dehlia wanted to leave Jane the estate,
and I found the will.
Like you always say, "Others first."
I just wish that
you'd talked to me about this.
L'll be okay, Dad.
We'll work it out. You're my guy.
Hey, kiddo.
Mr. Biedermeyer.
Your father and I were going over
some business when we heard.
I hope you're all right.
I'm fine.
Good.
He's offered me some consulting work.
I can do it from home...
...so we can go back
to River Heights.
And he pays a lot.
You know, I couldn't help but
overhear before about the mystery.
- Did you ever find the will?
- I did.
Dehlia used one of her movies
as a clue.
It was hidden in the secret compartment
of a Chinese box.
Nancy always gets
to the bottom of things.
Well, my firm would certainly
be interested in seeing that will.
You know, Mr. Biedermeyer
wasn't always just Dehlia's lawyer.
He was her manager as well,
from the start.
He made her who she was.
Then he brought her account
to his law firm, and...
Well, it's time to sign on the dotted line.
That's quite a signature.
It's my middle initial.
For Zachary.
Z.
Where is the will?
Where is it, honey?
Do you know?
You know, this is a little awkward.
His firm stands to lose
more than a little income...
...if the money from the will
really does go to Jane.
Dad, we have to get out
of this car now.
Why?
Excuse me, sir,
can you please stop the car?
Nancy!
Dad, get away from them!
Excuse me, miss?
Oh, hello, honey.
The phone's over there, honey.
Sergeant Billings.
Do you know if a Dashiel Biedermeyer
rented in this building?
No. No, he owns it.
He owns the house you're in too.
He's a very rich man.
There she is.
Is there a back door anywhere?
Yes, honey, right over there.
Tell Sergeant Billings
to send a car to the house.
Get her!
Open up!
Open this door!
- Break it down.
- Come here.
Where's the will?
I don't think I should say. It's
my insurance that you won't hurt me.
L'll squeeze it out of you.
Tell me something first.
I'm just really curious.
Why did you kill Dehlia?
After she gave up the baby,
she went kind of crazy.
She was gonna quit the business
and run off with that caretaker.
He was the father.
Whatever. She was my only client.
She was gonna fire me.
I spent 20 years of my life
building up her career.
I got mad.
I reacted violently.
I felt kind of bad about it for a while,
but I'm okay with it now.
Leshing is Jane's father.
- Does he know about the baby?
- It doesn't matter! Now where's the will?
Lt's right here.
Come here.
Give it to me!
Give me the will!
Just do it.
If you shoot me, it'll leave all
sorts of evidence. Very messy.
Strangulation leaves
a traceable handprint.
What do you suggest?
The best way to kill me?
Let me think about that.
Enough of this crap.
Put the gun down.
Hey!
I'm just really curious.
Why did you kill Dehlia?
After she gave up the baby,
she went kind of crazy.
She was gonna quit the business and...
Nancy?
Oh, my gosh,
you won't believe what's happened.
Hey, Mr. Biedermeyer. Inga Veinshtein.
I'm in water polo with Courtney.
Your granddaughter.
Yeah. I remember you.
Hey, Lurch, digging a hole or something?
- Okay. We had to show you this.
- Oh, my goodness!
Lt's called "The New Sincerity."
Yeah, I'm on the forefront. I see
something cute, I start wearing it...
...and in like five seconds, it's a total
trend. Penny-loafer fashion moment.
I need to borrow that coat.
Leshing, thank you so much.
You're welcome. Nancy.
There's something you should know.
It's about Jane.
She's your daughter.
- Hey, you with the shovel.
- No. It's him.
Have you seen my father?
Lt's a party!
Nancy, darling, are you okay?
Oh, good, good.
- Oh, hi, honey. How are you?
- Hi, Mr. Drew.
I was locked in a trunk. What happened?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Okay, let's get him up.
All right, easy, easy, easy.
Looks like my new job
might not work out now.
Yeah. Maybe not.
So, what exactly happened?
Dad, do you really wanna know?
Yeah.
Do I?
I don't know what to say.
Nancy, I want you to know
I appreciate how hard it was...
...for you to do the right thing.
I'm very proud of you.
You know, Barbara Barbara Realty
would be delighted...
...to continue to rent
this property for you.
Thanks, but no, thanks.
Well, what are you gonna do
with this place?
I'm gonna live here, with my kid
and anyone else who needs a place.
I think maybe you and I
should talk this over before you make...
Feel free to leave at any time.
Allie. Allie. Come here.
There it is.
Just like clockwork.
What?
Postpartum depression.
You're sad the case is over.
That's ridiculous.
I'm glad it all worked out.
You're only happy when there's trouble.
This I know for sure.
But that's who you are
and it's all right with me.
Ned, that's so sweet.
- Nancy?
- Yes?
Phone call.
Long distance from Scotland.
Something about the Loch Ness monster
and some missing diamonds.
Another case.
THE END
Subtitles by: Reklame