Star Documentary KPOP Hero
[The Birth of BoA the Amazing Girl]
[BoA debuted with this song when she was as young as Min-jung]
[Remembering the old times, she dances along!]
[Things are heating up]
[Even SHINee is dancing]
BoA is excited because a girl is dancing to her song.
BoA first appeared with this song around the same age as that girl.
She's a new face.
A fearless rookie entering the world of singers.
This is BoA's first stage.
BoA was a 13-year-old girl back in the year 2000.
She left a strong impression with her debut song "ID; Peace B."
Not only is her singing and dancing perfect...
But it's hard to believe that she's just a young girl with her stage manners.
However, we could see her fresh charms befitting her age on various variety shows.
Hello everyone! I'm BoA, Inkigayo's new VJ.
I'll do my best on Sunday afternoons in my duty for Inkigayo's growth.
Please trust me.
Is it love or fate?
It's Lee Jung-hyun.
It's "Prince of the Sea."
I'll hit 20.
This isn't it.
All the popular songs are here.
Even I would watch Inkigayo.
BoA is a cute girl.
Don't tease me with the title of my song!
My next song was titled "Sara."
But fellow celebrities and managers would say...
"Buy us food" or "What are you buying?" (Buy sounds like Sara)
I want to buy so don't tease me.
I'm singing my song but that hurt my feelings.
I finished my first album and preparing a special album.
I'm really scared since I'm going to another country to work on it.
Please wait for me and watch this last broadcast to the end.
I love my fans!
- I'll do Lee So-ra. - Oh? Lee So-ra?
Ready?
- That was good. - Another one?
- You have another one? - Go on. Do it then.
What is it?
It's Lee Soo-man.
Another?
[Lee Jung-hyun]
I remember when BoA used to be like that.
She was cute.
We're doing this in advance?
I don't know if it'll work but it should, right?
A new face for 2001.
She is a rookie who's reborn.
This is BoA's "Sara."
With another song after a strong debut, we could see another charm to it.
She grabbed everyone's attention and shows her true qualities in Japan.
BoA, the star of Asia, is an amazing girl who conquers even Japan.
[Asia's Star Takes Japan by Storm]
BoA studied English and Japanese even before her debut for her foray abroad.
She prepared her foray into Japan as she debuted in Korea.
She was already prepared as a K-pop hero.
She debuted in Japan in 2001 after debuting in Korea.
She released her first single "ID; Peace B" in May.
She released a total of 7 singles.
All went on the Oricon music charts and her potential in Japan was confirmed.
Her 4th single "Listen to My Heart" happened to be used in a commercial.
It ranked third on the Oricon music charts.
After releasing her first album "Listen to My Heart" in Japan...
She was the first Korean artist to rank first on the Oricon album charts.
She became Asia's shining star.
This is a recording studio in Japan where the young BoA records.
16-year-old BoA makes her foray into the Japanese music market.
Today is a very important day.
I'm doing my first broadcast for my 4th single "Listen to My Heart."
She's starring in a live show called "Tokyo Musics."
She's obviously nervous since it's her first live show on air.
I'm nervous.
Applause!
The show begins.
The Japanese audience cheer her exceptional dancing and singing.
She runs to the sub control room after it's over to monitor herself.
She smiles satisfied and sings along.
BoA and her staff are pleased with the first broadcast.
Harajuku is the center of Japanese youth culture.
We found out how much the Japanese know about BoA.
- Do you know BoA? - Yes.
What do you think of her?
She's cute.
Do you know any of her songs?
"Kimochi wa Tsutawaru."
What's different about BoA from other artists?
She's very mature and nice even though she has 1-2 year age gap from us.
Do you think she can be successful in Japan?
Yes!
Her foray into Japan was a success.
She was a model for various magazines and appeared on many live music shows.
She made herself known as the artist from Korea.
How is her place in Japan?
My place is being revealed for the first time ever.
Is it always this clean?
BoA's room 10 minutes ago!
She was busy during those 10 minutes.
I was running here and there during those 10 minutes.
She usually watches videos of shows or music to deal with homesickness.
She's a 16-year-old girl even though she's an artist with several albums.
I practiced the dance moves.
Her only friend in this unfamiliar country is this robot puppy.
Hello.
It's name is Babo (stupid).
It's mom!
Hello?
Mom!
A mother's voice always feels like a sweet break.
You went? Really?
You know I'm doing fine here in Japan, right?
I really miss you.
I can't cry with you.
I didn't say this often in Korea but I love you mom!
She slowly cemented her position going back and forth from Korea and Japan.
The song she released in 2002 in Korea made her the top solo female artist.
The name "BoA" reminds us of this song.
[BoA's Song]
"No. 1" is the title track of her 2nd album released in 2002.
Her strengths and charms were shown in this europop song.
She reaches the top and strengthens her position as Korea's top female artist.
[Her exceptional singing and charisma stands out on stage]
[Norwegian composer, Ziggy, partook in this europop style dance song]
[Like the title that shows her determination to be the best artist...]
[This song contributed to BoA's rise to the top]
"Valenti" is a latin style dance song and sixth single released in Japan.
It was released in a special album in Korea.
It is also BoA's most sold single in Japan.
[Her matured singing and flashy moves stood out in this latin style song]
[It's the title track of her special album upgraded from the song released in Japan]
She gets a big present at the end of the year with the best song that goes well with her.
The grand prize of the Seoul Music Award goes to...
BoA! Congratulations!
Congratulations!
Congratulations to BoA!
She's the grand prize winner of the 2002 SBS Gayo Daejun!
Maybe she followed the title of her song...
She stood as No. 1 while shedding tears of joy.
Her No. 1 fame wrote gayo history in her name and can be found in various places.
[Means "first" or the title track of BoA's second album]
As the No. 1 star, she became a model for cosmetics commercials.
She did the voices for "Over the Hedge" in Korean and Japanese in 2006.
She's the first Korean artist and youngest to walk the red carpet at the Cannes Film Festival.
Her position as the No. 1 artist continued on.
[A rock dance song with strong, intense beats, guitar sounds, and rhythm]
[It's the title of her 11th single released in Japan and 2nd single in Korea]
[BoA gives off a powerful image by transforming to a rocker]
[The song was used in a Japanese cell phone commercial]
[She attended the MTV Asia Awards representing both Korea and Japan]
[She sang "Rock with You" with labelmate Trax as a special stage]
She attended the 2004 MTV Asia Awards representing both Korea and Japan.
She received an award as Korea's most popular artist...
And a special award as Asia's most influential artist.
She's the first K-pop artist to perfrom in Indonesia.
She's still popular in Japan as Asia's star.
Many great artists around the world made offers to this No. 1 Korean female artist.
They're good-looking!
BoA introduces the members.
He's Brian the mischievous one.
- I think he was joking. - It was a joke.
That was strong.
But you can tell how mischievous he is in the next few clips.
She's memorizing the lyrics before the actual recording.
She recorded first with Shane the lead vocalist.
They recorded without prior practice but seem satisfied with the harmony.
She's not intimidated at all.
She worked well with Mark but now they even play around.
["Flying Without Wings" will be included in both BoA and Westlife's album]
Look at how mischievous Brian is.
He livens up the mood on the spot with various things.
BoA finished her recording and we met with Westlife.
I was worried while recording.
It was hard since it was my first time recording with foreigners.
They played around and made me feel relaxed so the recording went well.
They even played pool and were sad when they had to part.
They were sad when they parted because they became close.
"Atlantis Princess" is the title track of her 3rd album released in 2003.
The fairytale-like lyrics and her uniquely soft voice stood out.
[The lost childhood dreams and hopes are compared to the legendary Atlantis]
[The fairytale-like lyrics went well with BoA's soft voice]
She released her 4th album a year later. A colorful rhythm stands out in "My Name."
It's an urban dance genre and we can see how see grew in a year.
[A bouncy and intense acoustic guitar rhythm...]
[Goes well with the colorful club music in this urban dance genre]
[BoA's matured charm can be felt in this song]
[Her pelvic dance, unique moves, and such things attracted attention]
A flashy performance as good as her exceptional singing.
It's the greatest charm and strength of BoA's dance songs.
Another charm of BoA's songs shined in ballads as well.
Let's rank BoA's special ballads.
[Ranking - BoA's Ballads]
Feel the beauty of sentimental ballad by the young BoA with "I'm Sorry."
BoA's "Mayday! Mayday!" means "I cry out desperately to touch you."
"My Prayer" is a song like a desperate prayer.
A special meeting between BoA and Kim Dong-ryool's ballad "Stand By."
The quintessence of her profound sentiment can be felt in "Tree."
"Girls on Top" and comeback after 5 years, but BoA is still on top.
[BoA on Top! Comeback after 5 Years]
BoA turned 20 in 2005 and released an intense new song.
"Girls on Top" is the title track of her 5th album.
She made a great impact with this song that cries out against male chauvinism.
The move where she sings on top of a male dancer drew attention.
[Like the title, it cries out against male chauvinism and bias]
[It's an intense dance song with a message warning about that]
[Her style completely changed to go along with the song]
[A unique move in singing on top of a male dancer attracted attention]
After her 5th album, she focuses on her activities in Japan and the US.
She released her 6th Japanese album in 2008.
[All 6 albums including her debut album took 1st place]
[After Ayumi Hamasaki, she took 2nd out of all the artists in Japan]
This is how she strengthens her position in Japan.
But she doesn't stop here and attempts a bigger stage in 2008.
She announces her foray into the US at a press conference in 2008.
She revealed "Eat You Up" her debut song in the US.
[Her debut song for her foray into mainstream American music]
[It's a reverse beat dance track filled with her unique energy]
[It got favorable reviews and was #1 breakout on Billboard's Hot Dance Club Play]
[It was remixed later as "Low" with Flo Rida]
She makes her Korean comeback in 2010 after such a passionate attempt in 5 years.
"Hurricane Venus" is the title track of her 6th album.
She was a charismatic Venus for her 10th anniversary.
She partook in writing the words and came up with the title.
[The lyrics portray a woman with a strong love like a hurricane]
[And it goes well with the refined, intense sounds]
[It's the title track of her 6th album released after 5 years]
[She partook in writing the words and came up with the title]
[For her 10th anniversary, her captivating voice and upgraded performance stood out]
I now have many juniors after I came back.
- And idol groups. - Yes.
- But we're around the same age. - I know, right?
Maybe it's because I'm back home but it feels warm.
What I like the most is eating my mom's cooking.
That's really important.
And all the lights are on when I come home.
Since you were alone abroad.
Her 5-year absence in Korea paled in comparison to her performance.
She was still on top.
[It's about a woman inviting her lover to her own game]
[Such unique content is delivered with her captivating voice]
She's reborn as a musician with a sense of maturity.
[BoA Grows as a Musician]
BoA sat in the judge's seat and not the stage in 2012 on KPOP STAR.
[An attractive, clear voice]
I like your voice because it's pure and clear.
I'm curious how your voice will sound with different songs.
You lack individuality.
There are people we incline to even though they can't sing.
I have my doubts.
You have a nice voice and you're born with it.
But...
I don't know how your voice will go with gayo.
- I want her to sing that... - How will you get the beats?
It's because you won't be singing only rhythmical songs, right?
I'm worried about that.
In the next round...
We want to hear you sing gayo in the next round.
I was surprised.
There were bad dancers who think they dance well.
But...
To be able to dance like this in your situation is...
It really moved me.
I can't continue.
Kim Soo-hwan's dance was pure.
He put a lot of thought into each and every move.
The detailed parts...
She showed she is a seasoned artist with sharp remarks and kind advice.
Her beauty was rediscovered in this show as well.
She became a new fashion icon with her elegant and refined styles.
BoA is pretty but why did she look prettier on this show?
Maybe because it's SBS?
We at SME wait for those with great performance and singing.
She was a judge again for season 2.
You talk about being chic That went against who I am
You blindly lifted your leg And placed it on your other leg
You crossed your legs That's disgusting
My legs are falling asleep Feels like they're numb
You talk about being a snob That went against who I am
I clenched my fists and pounded the desk Everyone's eyes were on me
You crossed your legs They're rather twisted
It started from the toes Feels like my growth plates closed
Their perspective was interesting.
They had witty lyrics and sang well.
I really look forward to their stage and how they will sing in their style.
- You pass. - Thank you.
[Raccoon Boys prepared SHINee's "Sherlock"]
[Arranged in their style]
[SM experts observe sharply]
It was dull.
[Shock]
Their previous songs were good. It's not easy doing that again.
It's like worrying over the 2nd album because the 1st was a hit.
Raccoon!
[What special measure will BoA take?]
Change your song.
Make it quick and show it to us.
I'm worried if they could display their skills because they are intimidated.
They received training in recovering their color.
They needed a female voice and I recorded for them.
[BoA featured in their music recording!]
- Hello? - It's me.
- What did you do? - I slept.
- Sleep more. - Okay, I love you.
I love you too.
[Just hearing her voice makes them happy]
This is awesome!
This is what I'm talking about.
Because she did this, we have a sense of duty to do well.
[Secret weapon featuring BoA]
Her eyes and talent for discovering raw talent and polishing them shined.
Hi, I'm BoA, a judge on KPOP STAR.
She received a special award at the 2012 SBS Entertainment Awards.
2012 is also an important year where she grows as a musician.
She presents "Only One" in 2012 for her 7th album.
A song she wrote became the title track for the first time since her debut.
This confirmed her talent as a musician.
[It's a midtempo R&B with heavy drumbeat, sweet piano melody, and grand orchestra]
[It contains the sad heart of a lover before breaking up]
[BoA's captivating voice shined]
[She wanted an acoustic song with less computerized sound]
[A song she wrote became the title track for the first time since her debut]
This is a lyrical hip-hop where the lyrics are expressed with dance.
The performance was memorable like a scene from a musical.
Her labelmates participated as well.
SM Romance of the Three Kingdoms.
What is that?
Her dance partners got together for a performance battle.
[A representative from TVXQ, Super Junior, and SHINee]
I was chosen first as BoA's dance partner for "Only One."
Then it was Eunhyuk and Taemin.
They're BoA's dance partner.
[Yunho, Eunhyuk, and Taemin were BoA's dance partner!]
For example, I did it today and Eunhyuk did it tomorrow.
I got nervous because we took turns.
We didn't see each other until the rehearsal.
We just told each other to do our part and do well.
He'll say, "You always do well."
On the day of the performance, we're busy changing clothes.
Taemin and I will get ready and be like this near the stage when it's Yunho's turn.
I feel this energy as I go up the stage.
I'm determined before I begin.
I cast a spell on myself to live up to the expectations.
"I'm sorry but I'm the best." I say that for that moment.
That's right! You need that!
Eunhyuk looks at me after I'm done.
"Your expression was very good."
Then Taemin will say, "They liked it."
You evaluate each other.
We evaluate each other but I thought, "What's going on?"
Luckily for me, I went first.
I did a lot of research while monitoring him.
What feel to give?
Yes, but what can I do to stand out?
I wanted to get a good evaluation since people write comments.
I watched Yunho's performance and his expression is really good.
He takes control and goes in.
All he needs to do is just walk in and dance but he doesn't do that.
He does that...
and starts acting!
Do that again!
Start!
Since he touches his lips as he comes in, he has this overwhelming charisma.
You can do that too.
I can't do those things.
I watched Taemin's performance and it's like a beautiful picture.
- Stimulates maternal instinct. - He has this charm I don't have.
It was hard for me to deal with her seniority and overcome that wall.
I thought I need to get close first and talked a lot during practice.
I couldn't get into the emotion during practice.
I thought about what I should do and during the camera rehearsal...
I thought, "Forget this," and was very assertive.
Wasn't there physical contact?
The manager and staff said it was good because I did it with confidence.
Even BoA liked it.
[I like assertive young men]
What about you, Eunhyuk?
It was awkward.
It wasn't about dancing as time went by.
I wanted to make news according to how intense the physical contact is.
Of course!
Yunho danced with his face almost touching her face.
The first move is putting hands together.
But Taemin didn't do that and stroked her head.
He's younger than her...
He was stroking her head.
So I was thinking what to do.
I decided on a kissing performance for the last performance of Inkigayo.
There would be no issue greater than this.
I told BoA that I'll go for it.
Go where?
BoA said to do it if I can.
So I went.
I approached her.
- Anchovy approaches. - I approached...
I didn't know but her headset's mike was right in front of her mouth.
I couldn't draw close to her lips but I was really nervous.
I tried but it was awkward.
[Let's check it out!]
They each put on a great performance because of such competition.
You sure grew up.
BoA just had her 10th anniversary.
She did grow up and grow up well she did.
What did she think she will be in 10 years?
What do you think you'll be doing in 10 years?
- In 10 years? - Yes.
Well... I'll know when that time comes but I want to be a good wife and wise mother.
- No one will believe me but... - You do look like it.
Really?
I think I'll have a beautiful family.
I also want to learn composition so I might be doing that.
- How old are you? - I'm 14.
Then you'll be 24 in 10 years. You want to get married early?
I'm only 24 in 10 years.
That's right.
Seems like you forget your age at times.
Do you currently have a boyfriend?
Me? I really want one.
She wants one.
- There's a present I want. - We're not objects.
She could say that since it's her birthday.
But people tell me that he'll appear when the time comes.
I lived like that for 28 years.
When did you last date?
- About 2 years ago. - 2 years ago?
Did it end well?
Yes, you know how it is.
It's him! It's "only one."
Don't connect it like that.
This is when you're really vicious.
You'll be meeting someone in the future but who's your current ideal man?
That's right. I think many want to know.
I don't have an ideal man. If he just likes me then...
10 years passed but she's still single.
She's very simple and wants a man who likes her. Will she meet her soulmate?
She held her first exclusive concert in 2013.
It was a time to look back on her best performances.
She presented a concert befitting her name.
Let's look forward to her stage she'll create in 15-20 years.