You know, B-flat. B-flat.
Yeah. Not too slow.
Go.
I think it's seen
just as a hobby of mine.
Some people want to come,
and others don't.
Millions and millions of people
don't have the slightest
interest in this music,
whether it's played by me
or Sidney Bechet or anyone else.
[New Orleans jazz playing]
I never liked that dog.
I don't like dogs,
but even amongst dogs,
that dog I especially hate.
'Cause it's wild...
You feed it and walk it,
but there's no return.
I'm always afraid
that the dog will lick me.
[Soon Yi]: She french-kissed
a friend of mine.
He was talking and she put
her tongue in his mouth. Yes.
- Do you know
that it is a medical fact
that dogs' mouths
are cleaner than people's?
[Woody]: I would rather
be bitten by the dog
than licked by it. I mean it.
- I can arrange that.
- I would rather
the dog bit me than...
- But I'm telling you that's true.
Dogs' mouths
are cleaner than humans'.
- Yeah...
- It's the truth.
It actually is.
- It's disgusting.
[groaning]
Let me know
when we arrive in Paris.
- Hold on one second.
- Well, if you don't make noise
and keep the dogs away from me,
maybe I can get some sleep.
- Hold up one second.
You're on my coat.
- Our goal
is to see that you sleep.
G'night, baby.
- I don't want to be bothered.
- Croissants.
[dog whining]
[Woody]: Get those buns
away from that mutt.
I never eat
at 4:30 in the morning.
I'm always unconscious.
- It's 1 0 after 5:00.
- Ten after 5:00?
I should be on the treadmill.
[Soon Yi]: The next morning,
we should leave at 1 1 :00.
Don't you think?
- If we leave at 1 1 :00,
when am I going
to do my underwear?
[laughter]
Well, you know,
the tour started off
just me and the banjo player
saying what a nice idea
it would be
to play a couple of places
in Europe just for fun.
And then, you know,
two weeks later,
this arduous tour was set.
- I think once you start playing...
- Yeah.
- The actual act of playing is fun,
but we're all, you know,
leaving home,
then I'm going to places
that I've never gone to in my life.
- You're only going overnight.
- Yeah... Well...
You know, in New York,
you know, I can live my life
just going from my house
to where I make films,
to the theatre,
to the movies,
to Madison Square Gardens,
to you know, just to...
And I don't need...
I never feel a sense
that I have to get away
on the weekend or anything.
In fact,
it would be a punishment to me.
If someone, you know,
one of those times
when I've had to,
for one reason or another,
go away on the weekend,
you know, I count the minutes.
Paris...
doesn't have
the excitement of New York.
On the other hand,
it's more beautiful.
[humming]
And I love the weather in Paris,
because I don't like sun,
and Paris has great gray weather
almost all the time.
Soft light.
It's really beautiful.
So I'm always very happy
walking the streets of Paris,
'cause, you know,
I like the idea
that you can do things late at night.
The funny part of it is,
in New York,
I don't keep late hours at all.
But I like to know
that if it's 3:30 or 4:00 in the morning
and I want a bowl
of duck-wonton soup, I can get it.
Now, I don't get it,
because who needs that
at 4:00 in the morning?
[bells tolling]
[playing scales on clarinet]
I practice every day
of my life, just about,
because I couldn't play at Michael's Pub
every Monday night,
even at the level I play,
I couldn't do that without practicing.
I mean, my lip wouldn't hold out,
I wouldn't be able
to play anything at all.
They may like the novelty
for the first 1 5-20 minutes,
then, as an hour goes by,
and they're hearing
New Orleans jazz, I mean...
- But they're coming
to hear that.
You know,
so there'll be
a certain enthusiasm.
- A big problem is that...
that I'm not a sufficient-enough
musician to hold their interest.
If you have a concert
and have a real artist out there
who can play...
If this was, you know,
Sidney Bechet or John Coltrane
or somebody that can...
then, just to hear them play,
you don't need anything else.
They're endlessly
creative and great.
But, you know,
that doesn't obtain here.
You know, this has...
this has a different quality to it.
- So every country we go to,
that you only do one show,
you see it as the closing?
- Yeah.
- It makes no sense.
- You see it as the opening?
- Yes. Tonight's the opening.
- You know, I'm sure there's something
we're going to find out.
Unless it's nothing,
unless it's the same thing
we do at Michael's Pub,
you know,
we're not gonna bore them.
Just say hello
and a couple of lines,
and then get on to the playing.
You know, at some point,
maybe introduce the musicians.
[Letty]: That's it?
- Yeah. That's more than it.
That's the maximum.
- D'you have a good trip?
- Oh, yeah. It was a breeze.
I went over to Paris first,
just 'cause I had to get
one night of sleep,
you know, to get over it.
And Paris is the only place
outside of New York that I can survive.
You know what I mean?
I can't come
right to another country.
I have to go to Paris,
then I know I'm in Europe.
- Really? You like it?
- Then I can go from there.
And they built it...
exact replica of my $1 2 Ramponi.
I told them I only wanted
two keys here, no more.
- It's amazing. It looks
like an old one, but it's brand-new.
- I didn't want
any extra weight on it.
- When you guys sit down,
just start into a blues in C.
- Then we just go,
play whatever we want,
take it like we're playing at Michael's.
- All right.
- How many people
are out there?
What's the capacity
of this room?
- It's... I don't know.
- I think they said, like, 1,700.
- 1,800.
- That's hilarious.
Yeah. Theoretically,
this should be fun for us.
[laughter]
You know? It should not have
a sense of obligation, or... or...
You know, we should
just have a good time.
- Yeah.
- It should be our pleasure.
[applause]
Uh, we want
to say hello to you,
and I don't know
if you can understand me,
I can't speak any, uh, Spanish...
'cause I didn't pay attention
in school years ago.
[laughter]
The, uh... we're very honoured
to be playing here in Madrid.
Uh, and, uh...
I think we're gonna
play for you tonight
the music of New Orleans.
It's, uh....
it's the original
birthplace of jazz,
as you undoubtedly know,
and, it's, um, very primitive music.
And, uh, it will be composed
mostly of blues
and ragtime and dance music
and, uh, parade music,
so, you know,
if you sit back and relax,
and we'll do our best
for the next hour and a half or so,
and sing some songs for you
and play music,
and thank you all for coming.
[applause]
- It's sort of like
an ancient dialect of jazz.
It's not something
you can find anymore.
It's hard enough to find
any kind of old jazz.
This type is non-existent,
even in New Orleans,
where it originated,
it doesn't exist anywhere.
- What we're trying to achieve
is crude,
and makes the word "crude"
a very acceptable term.
We like it. Most people think
of crude and go "ugh,"
but crude is the term
that should be used,
but it should be used
in a very favorable light.
- When I was a teenager,
I heard some New Orleans jazz
and became completely
obsessed by it.
So much so that I ran out
and bought an instrument
and learned to play it.
There's nothing between you
and the pure feeling of the playing.
There's no cerebral element
to it at all.
There's something
about New Orleans jazz
that just rings a bell in me
for some inexplicable reason.
It's like taking a bath
in honey or something.
[applause]
What do we do,
we're playing New Orleans jazz.
There's very little interest in that
even in its country of origin.
And they're...
they're loving it.
I mean, the problem was
getting off and out of there.
I mean, that should be
our biggest problem.
We'll be very curious to see
if that reaction is the same
with the Swiss or the Germans.
Oh, yes, come in.
[Soon Yi]: Do you have the tip?
- Yeah, I have it.
Here, guys.
- Thank you.
- Okay. I have to get
my multivitamin,
baby aspirin, antibiotic...
- Okay. Is this you or me?
- That's the Spanish omelet.
- Oh. How appropriate.
Here you are.
- Oh, thank you.
[Soon Yi laughing]
- Just our normal
average breakfast.
The shower was excellent,
wasn't it?
- Yes. Great pressure.
The problem is...
that it comes down
over the drain.
- Right.
- The drain's not in the corner.
- Uh-huh.
- So you have to stand
close to the drain,
so if you put a mat in there...
- Is that what you did?
- Yeah, 'cause I can't stand
on plain marble.
You have to put it over the drain
and then the water doesn't drain.
- Right.
- Um, the question is--
- Can I just see your omelet?
- You don't like yours?
- No. Can I switch?
It's, you know--
- Can I have the cover? Oh.
- It's very hard.
It's like eating a rock.
And it's very heavy.
- Why'd you give it to me?
[Soon Yi laughing]
- I won't have any breakfast!
You might like it.
- Um, the question is,
should we do the same...
all the same tunes tonight,
'cause the running order
of them is so effective.
My impulse is not to.
- No, I wouldn't.
It'll get boring.
Especially for us.
- Yeah.
Yeah, probably get boring for us.
Then it becomes a show, I guess,
and then it's no fun anymore.
- Right. The crowd outside
was hilarious.
It's, like, for a rock concert,
but you were an older guy.
- Yeah. That's great.
[chuckling]
[cheering]
That's right,
I'm a...
a much-beloved older figure.
- That's right.
- You see, I think your mistake
was ordering a Spanish omelet
just 'cause you're in Spain.
[laughing]
- I thought that was appropriate.
- It's, like, vulcanized
or something.
- Right. It's like lead.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, bad break for me
that you ordered it.
- You couldn't have asked
for a better night than last night.
- I know.
Uh, the band was very good.
- You should tell the band
they were very good last night,
and not only speak
to Eddy Davis.
You know, like yesterday,
in the... backstage--
- Mm-hmm.
- --you were talking only to Eddy Davis,
and he was the intermediary,
and then spoke,
relayed the message to the band
when you're in the room
with everyone.
You look like a crazy.
[Woody laughing]
- All right.
- You should tell them all
that they were very good.
- I did. I mean, I think I did.
- You should just make sure,
'cause it's nice to hear it.
A compliment is always nice.
- Well, I think I did tell them
they were good. I hope I did.
- Right. 'Cause you tend
to latch on to one person.
- Remember, Eddy put
this whole thing together.
He knows all the guys
in the band.
He hired them.
- Right. I was relieved
you got the names down
of the band.
- I mean, some of the guys I know,
so I know their names, but, uh...
a couple of them
I didn't know,
and I had to read
the booklet of the tour.
- You had a great night.
- Had a good reed.
We sounded great last night.
We really sounded
like one of those bands.
I don't think Preservation Hall
would've done any better.
- No, definitely not.
- You know what I mean?
- Not with the guys
they got nowadays.
- Like we knew
what we were doing.
- We liked the way
you handled the audience
and spoke like that
three different times.
- Well, I will speak to them,
'cause they expect to be spoken to.
Otherwise, I'd prefer not to, but, uh--
- Yeah, they showed
you speaking on television.
- And you remembered
everybody's names.
What's that about?
- I got them figured out.
That was easy.
- Very impressed
- And the tunes.
- The tunes, that's right.
[applause]
- Merci beaucoup.
Je vais presenter
le orchestra.
Ah, the trombone is Dan Barrett.
[applause]
And trumpet is Simon Wettenhall.
On drums, John Gill.
[applause]
The bass is Greg Cohn.
Our beautiful piano player
is Cynthia Sayer.
[applause]
And the banjoist,
and the director, is Eddy Davis.
[applause]
- Where'd I get that?
When this music started,
it was not unlike rock 'n' roll.
It was a new form
of earthy music that was pop,
and everybody was having
a good time and it was fun.
So, really, I would prefer
to link the revival
and these early musicians
with rock 'n' roll and whatever else
is a pop form of music.
I like it as a pop form.
I like to express myself,
I like to have a good time.
The Near North Side of Chicago
is where a nightclub
called Mr. Kelly's was.
And they would bring in
Barbra Streisand, Trini Lopez,
and Woody Allen
would come there.
Woody Allen was just a young
stand-up comedian at the time.
The next thing I know,
Woody's agent is coming down
saying, can he sit in with the band?
That would've been probably
in the very early '60s,
and I became aware
that he was very serious
as a clarinetist.
[applause]
[Woody]: Tonight's going
to be a different concert.
You know, we're relying
a little too much on...
[Letty]: Crowd-pleasers.
- Crowd-pleasers, yeah.
- But remember,
a certain percentage of the people
who are coming to see you
are seeing you not
because of your music,
but because
you're in the movies,
so therefore,
they want to be entertained.
- We're gonna play hard-core
New Orleans music,
esoteric tunes and--
[Soon Yi]: You don't want them
to get up and leave, do you?
[Letty]: I think
there'll be no encore tonight.
[Soon Yii]: I know. I think
we should stay home.
I'm bringing my book
tonight, right?
- I think they're coming
to see you play the lead,
you know, and move your clarinet
up and down. They like that.
- Your leg bopping op and down,
your head shaking, all of that.
- When you lean forward--
- But that I'm doing legitimately.
That I'm not putting on.
- You know when she came
to Michael's Pub to see you play?
That's the most movement
she's seen from you
from the whole time
she's known you.
- The most movement?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Yep. That's what she said.
- What does she expect?
I'm not gonna bop my head
and tap my feet
when I'm talking about politics
or literature or something.
I'm not gonna, you know,
keep time and...
Right?
- Yes.
- I mean, be reasonable.
- No, you can--
- I'm appropriately animated
for a human
in the context
within which I exist.
- You ready?
- You know the trouble
in all the countries.
They only have trouble
in some of the countries.
We're not in those countries.
- We'll show them around.
- You're afraid
I'll be kidnapped by terrorists?
- Where should we start?
- Uh, this is the living room.
Franz Josef used to bring
his dates here.
This is where we sleep.
- The humble bedroom.
- Yeah. It's a cozy little bedroom.
If the ceilings were
just a little higher,
it would be perfect.
Now, whenever I travel,
I always have to have
my own bathroom,
because I'm crazy.
So I always wind up
taking an extra room,
or an extra suite of rooms,
and it gives me
my own bathroom in there,
and I can place all my unctions
and vanishing creams
and cosmetics
that give me this look.
- Do you want to speak
to your mother?
- Okay, hold on.
- Hello?
Okay.
- Can I have a stiff drink?
- I'm fine.
Yeah. Yeah.
This is very easy.
Yeah, it's very easy.
It's easy. It's easy.
It's no problem.
It's no physical
problem at all. No.
- You can talk to Daddy, too.
- Yeah, you should talk
to your father.
- Is Daddy there?
He's in the lobby.
[laughing]
He was in the lobby yesterday
and a couple came in
and went to their apartment
on the 27th floor and he went with them.
- Omigod!
[laughter]
- Well, did they let him in,
or did they...?
[laughter]
Oh.
- He's 96. We can't expect more.
- I have to go.
Okay.
Goodbye.
Oh...
It's grueling.
- I know.
I did think
there was something mysterious
when they announced
our concert here
and then the theatre
burned down a month later.
[laughter]
I thought they were trying
to tell me something.
- Here'll be some waves.
Oh, not bad.
- I'll be all right.
I'll just get to the hotel
and lie down for a while.
I'll see Venice
maybe next time.
No, I like it.
- Mm-hmm.
- Because it's like heading
into the midtown area, you know?
I could sing, if you like.
[Soon Yi laughing]
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- Uh, excuse me.
Please, wait. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Okay?
- All right.
- So you can have this bathroom.
- Right. Thank you.
And I'm gonna have
the one in the other room.
You know, the other room
may have a double bed in it.
- Oh, really?
Yeah. Then I won't slide
into the cracks.
Oh, is it two beds?
- It's two beds.
- Two beds pushed together, right?
- Yeah.
- Hmm. It's a concept
they haven't gotten used to here.
And now, a ritual
as old as the city itself:
I give out my laundry.
- Okay.
- I give them specific instructions
so they know what to violate.
- Here. You can just
write it on this.
- Oh, okay. Yes.
Uh, my name, no starch,
and do we want it back
with holes in it or, uh...
or do you want it
the way we send it in?
- Remember,
you're not signing an autograph.
- All right, I'll write it more clearly.
- Is it this one or this one?
- No, no. That's the dusting lady.
That's the maid.
Yeah, those little drawings
are confusing, you know?
The one with the knife in her hand
is the one not to press.
It's beautiful. Beautiful.
Thank you so much.
We have to be careful.
The mayor has many enemies.
We'll go to the Fenice
and look at it.
We were gonna play there.
We were gonna open there.
I know. I know.
Uh, before it burned down,
it was, you know,
a great work of art.
[Soon Yi]: Omigod.
There's just nothing.
- It's... it's a complete...
complete annihilation.
[mayor speaking ltalian]
- You have this every day, right?
- You have to please the...
[reporters speaking ltalian]
- Ah, it's incredible.
I couldn't believe
the devastation in there.
I was amazed.
I knew it was a catastrophe,
but you're not prepared
for anything like that.
I don't really understand
why they're all after me.
It's the same photo, no?
The same?
- It's all the same.
- Yeah, I know.
It's so funny, it's the same, uh...
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you. Thank you for the book.
I look forward to reading it,
and it's a pleasure to meet you.
And I'll see you this evening.
- Yes, yes. This evening.
- Thank you very much.
I'll see you tonight.
- Thank you.
I'll see you later.
- This is a great way
to achieve maximum tension -
going out in a gondola.
You know?
Your knuckles are white...
The heartbeat is raised...
Ah, they look
like they're having fun.
- Uh-huh.
- I see.
- That's what we look like.
- I see. Oh.
If that's what we look like,
we should get our money back.
It's quiet back here, you know?
- Mm-hmm.
- The gondolier could cut our throats
and no one would know.
[footsteps overhead]
Thought I heard footsteps
on the bridge.
[water rippling]
What's that?
- That's a frog.
- A frog?
- It sounds like a frog.
It's not a frog. It can't be.
But it does sound like one, doesn't it?
- Yeah.
Maybe it's a special Venetian frog.
- Mm-hmm.
- Made of glass.
Ah... Venice!
My God.
[chuckling]
Yes, you're right. It's me.
It's me. You've seen me
in those films. I'm the guy.
Just try not to throw
the cameras.
- Eh! Woody!
- Woody!
- Oh, hi, fellas.
Don't get too excited.
I come here
a few times a year.
Hey, guys. Yes.
Hi, fellas.
[nervous chuckling]
They won't pay 1 0 cents
to see one of my movies,
but passing on the gondola,
they love it.
- Oh, there's the guy again.
[camera clicking]
- Ah...
we're gonna have
to teach him a lesson.
- What are you gonna do?
- Knock his fucking teeth out.
- I'll just go right inside.
[speaking ltalian]
- Tonight... tonight is okay.
Tonight is okay.
But not now. No more.
- Is for me. For me.
- Okay. Okay.
- Thank you.
[bells tolling]
[Woman]: Why are you here?
- Because I think
he plays so-and-so.
I want to be sure
he plays better than...
I don't think so well.
But I want to...
to feel
that he is better than I think.
I'm very...
[speaking ltalian]
- Suspicious.
- I'm very suspicious.
That's right.
And, Woody, be careful.
Play well, huh?
- The evening's performance
is, of course,
dedicated to the Fenice Theatre.
The proceeds tonight
are going to help rebuild it.
[applause]
Okay, let's go out there and do it,
because I gotta eat.
You know, I mean,
I can't be eating 1 2:00 midnight.
It's havoc on my stomach.
[Eddy]: This looks
like he's just saying,
"Oh, let's play a tune and go."
That's not true.
It's very well thought out.
He's often said to me,
"That or this won't work now."
He also says, "Well,
"the audience
is maybe liking it a little too well.
Let's see if we can push it
another direction."
So, same as, I think,
in his filming,
he's doing the same thing
out here on the road.
[applause]
[Woody]: Do something
to get them out of here.
Flood the house.
Turn the sprinkler system on.
Ah, perfect.
Food, food!
- I love him!
[man speaking ltalian]
He's wonderful.
- Did he stink?
- I changed my mind.
It was a really pleasing concert.
Very peaceful, very nice,
and just like I used
to listen in New Orleans.
Exactly... exactly the same style.
Very, very pleasing -
nice musicians,
wonderful... Yeah.
I didn't believe him.
He was more than my imagination.
[Woody]: lmagine having to tote
that bass around everyplace?
- Yes. Exactly.
- They should've told him
when he was a kid, you know,
flute.
How many people
have we got here?
- A lot.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
- Well, how many does the boat take?
- Seventeen.
- Is he going to back up
all the way?
- Huh?
- Is he going to back up
all the way?
- That's the front.
- This is the front?
- Yeah. Turn around.
- Oh.
- You're sitting the wrong way.
- Where's the captain?
- Up there. Higher, so he can see.
- Oh.
- He's up here.
- Oh, I see. I see.
This is the front.
Okay. I see now
why I failed geography.
Ah!
Ah, well, here we are.
Oh, hey, Chester,
I could get used to this.
- Check claim?
- I am so glad to see you,
because all my life
I wanted to see you.
- Oh, well, thank you very much.
- Really.
Because you have humour.
You are so intelligent.
- Oh, don't stop. Don't stop.
Keep going.
- You're so intelligent.
- I'd like to help a little here.
- Really.
- Thank you.
Very nice of you.
Thank you so much.
You're a Venetian?
- No. I am from Ancona.
In the middle...
near the Adriatic Sea.
- So you're here just, uh...
- No. For you. Really!
You are so happy
to be so intelligent.
- Yes, it is a burden,
though, sometimes.
- It's a big part...
- You have too much to know.
- Yes, with this much intelligence
comes great responsibility.
You know, it's lonely at the top.
Can we eat,
or do we wait for everybody?
- We can't wait for 1 00 people--
- So you just eat.
- I'm eating.
- Mm!!!
- Mm!
- Asparagus.
Starting to fade a little bit.
This guy's got to have
sweets someplace here.
Want to gad about?
- Yeah.
See if we can find, uh...
some chocolate Graham crackers
or something.
There's the band.
They're eating like they're going
to the chair. I can't believe it.
Nice leisurely walk
for lunch now.
- Would you like to start
with your usual pasta,
noodles with tomato and scampi?
- Yes.
- And then the sea bass.
- Perfect.
- Your usual one.
"My usual meal." Mm.
I dream about it sometimes.
- Thank you.
The DGAAward is tonight.
So how do you feel
about them giving you
a lifetime-achievement
kind of thing?
- It's very nice. It's fine.
But, I mean,
you can't delude yourself
into thinking that it really has...
meaning and that... you know,
that your work is, you know...
anything special.
'Cause you can get...
You could, if you wanted to organize,
get a group of people
that would come forward -
if you took the time,
and it wouldn't take much time -
to say, "l don't think we should
give this guy something."
- But when you receive
as many honours as you do,
it does mean that generally
people enjoy your work,
and there are enough
legitimate organizations
that feel it's worth honouring.
- They have given one to Kurosawa--
- Maybe it's only American.
- --they have given one to Bergman,
but not to Fellini,
and I don't understand that.
I don't want to say anything,
but I can't imagine,
in this lifetime,
that I could be eligible
for this thing prior to him.
You know,
when I was a little boy,
I remember that Jose Ferrer,
who I liked very much,
won the Academy Award
for Cyrano de Bergerac.
And that was the same year
that Marlon Brando
played Stanley Kowalski
in Streetcar Named Desire.
Now, to me, I was just
an adolescent at the time,
but it was so absurd
that any actor ever
could've been chosen
as giving the best performance
of the year other than Marlon Brando.
It didn't... You know,
I-l-I knew then that, you know,
that it's totally subjective.
- Your work
has a European... affinity.
[Woody]: Only post facto,
because people say to me,
"Why is it that your films
do so well in Europe -
all over Europe -
and not very well
in the United States?"
You know, Steven Spielberg
said that, uh...
he likes to make the films
that he liked when he was a kid.
And Sydney Pollack
also told me that.
He said, "l like to make the films
that I liked when I was growing up."
And I feel the same way.
I like to make the films
that I liked when I was growing up.
And the films that I liked
when I was growing up
were foreign films,
for the most part.
But in terms
of contributing an art form,
jazz is really it.
You know, I was brought up
in, really, the early '40s.
I mean, I would wake up
in the morning,
and while I was dressing,
the radio would be on,
or having dinner,
we listened to the radio,
and what you'd hear
at that time,
as part of your everyday fare,
was Artie Shaw
and Benny Goodman
and Tommy Dorsey and...
You know, turn on the radio,
and Billie Holiday would be singing,
or Louis Armstrong
would be playing,
and that's what
our popular music was.
So for me,
that era was so strong
and made
such an impression on me, uh...
that the music that I love
is, for my money,
the best period America
has ever had musically.
I think I'm at the apogee of...
this disgusting invention.
- I haven't hit the peak yet.
- I started a moment
before you, and...
I assume this is the peak.
If the peak is any higher,
I'm going to sit down
on the treadmill and...
just let it carry me along.
[playing clarinet]
This is dead as a doornail.
You know?
- This one was made
especially for you.
- This one?
- Yeah.
- I know, but, uh... I'm blowing
my brains out to make it sound good.
[applause]
[blowing harder,
playing more softly]
[audience laughing]
[clapping]
[applause and cheering]
[audience clapping along]
[Woody]: Down by the Riverside
In "F '."
Down by the Riverside in "F ',"
[band playing]
I'm gonna lay down
my sword and shield
Down by the riverside
[audience clapping along]
[clapping along]
Down by the riverside
Gonna lay down
my sword and shield
Down by the riverside
I ain't gonna
study war no more
Ain't gonna study
war no more
Ain't gonna
study war no more
Ain't gonna study
war no more
[applause]
[band playing]
- Whoo!
- More!
[applause]
[applause continues]
Merci beaucoup.
Vous etes tres gentils.
Demain matin, je dois...
je dois vol a Milan.
Nous jouons
demain soir a Milan.
[audience members
speaking French]
Je peux pas
comprendre frrancais.
Je peux parler,
mais pas comprendre.
[audience members
speaking French]
Oh!
Ah!
Il va avec moi.
[laughter]
Merci encore.
C'est un... vraiment, vraiment,
un reve qui est venu vrai.
[applause]
Merci.
[applause continues]
- You picked up a few words,
haven't you?
- Hey, they were good,
weren't they?
[kisses]
- They were.
- Let me just put my...
my old man's sweater on.
Look how young I look.
- I know! It's amazing!
- I look like such a dope,
such a goofball.
- Let me see.
Nerd comes to mind.
- That's very cute.
- Yeah, he looks cute.
- I do look like a nerd, yes.
Yes. I'd like to get it...
wide, so when I blow into it,
I don't have that feeling.
So it's completely open.
You know, the same openness
as the Selma that I was playing,
or the Ramponi.
They're very, very open.
And... and so, I'd like to,
you know,
open it as maximum as I can.
- Maximum, yes.
- Really--
- It's not a problem.
[motor whirring]
- Oh, I see.
- Bonjour.
- We practice a burrow
inside of the hole.
But now, on the new models,
we have very different burrows.
Different... polycylindrique
is the name...
- And different burrows
on the lower joint and upper joint.
- Probably things like that
that, um... you know,
Bechet played on,
or, you know,
people of that era.
- That's a very pretty one.
[man speaking French]
- This is amazing.
- C'est pas mauvais, hein?
- Ah, c'est incroyable.
C'est juste....
It's very much in tune.
It's probably not a good
recommendation for you.
[playing]
- Yeah, it's amazing.
- Yeah. Can you...?
I mean, it's, uh...
it's just amazing, yeah.
- That sounds like the Good Times
jazz recordings right there,
what you just did.
- This-this-this is perfect.
- Yeah.
- But these, they don't, uh...
these they don't sell,
they just exhibit.
Je peux l'acheter?
- Ca appartient a Buffet.
Moi, je veux bien.
Can I buy this?
- I think it's part of our history.
- Yes.
Well, think about it
for a minute.
This would be perfect for me.
- If we can find a solution,
we will let you know.
- Because this is perfect...
for the kind of music that we play.
- Hello.
Are you ready?
- I'm lost. I'm... Yeah.
- Come on.
I never swam
in my own apartment before.
[Soon Yi laughing]
Except during plumbing emergencies.
Uh, my glasses.
I can't swim with my glasses.
- No. Let's get in.
Ready?
- Ready for what?
Oh, I can stand.
- Mm-hmm.
You're in the shallow part.
- I'm in the shallow water?
- Yeah. Come on.
- I want to read the Trribune.
All right, one more time,
and then, uh...
- Afew more times.
- Now, how do you get out?
- The same way you came in.
- Wait a sec.
Oh, this is... this is not for me.
I'm like a...
- No, it was very good.
- I like the other kind of sports.
I like sports with a ball.
Thank you.
You know, this being Milan,
I just hope the laundry
doesn't come back breaded.
- So how did you sleep?
- I was afraid to get up
and go to the bathroom
in the middle of the night.
- In case you bumped
into someone?
- No. I didn't know
who was living or lurking...
You know, I mean,
you look down that hallway...
You know, it's just strange,
because it's just the two of us
in this big apartment, you know?
And access to it -
people have access to it.
You know, who knows--
- Right. When I got up this morning,
the place was crawling.
Thank you very much.
- When John clocks this joint,
he's going to... faint.
He won't believe it.
- You know what?
They forgot my toast. Shhh.
- Oh, really?
- That's okay. That's okay.
- Well, you know, it is--
Don't mention it.
- You know,
I think it's his first job.
I think he's a reformed
serial killer.
They're trying
to rehabilitate him.
Would you like
some orange juice?
- Would you like some toast?
- Uh, no, no.
No, thank you.
- No, I'm fine. There's plenty for me.
Hey, John, come in.
It's cozy, isn't it?
- This is unbelievable.
- You want some breakfast?
- I love your robes.
- You have to button your button.
- Oh, okay. How are you, sweetheart?
- Did they stamp your hand?
Look next door.
We can bring all our friends here.
They're used to classy people, I guess -
dignitaries, politicians.
They get 2 scuzzballs like us,
you know,
it's like 2 kids locked into
FAO Schwartz overnight or something.
- This is unbelievable.
- I know! It's unbelievable!
[both laughing]
This kid who was eating...
eating out of garbage pails
in Korea, on the streets,
is-is now...
- He's locked it.
I can't take a shower.
Well, we're the first people
to ever use this place.
We're the guinea pigs.
We're the shakedown crews
for the place.
You know, nothing works.
[Water running]
- Yep. Still freezing cold.
I'm hoping someone
can take care of the problem.
[Water running]
- I'll-I'll catch up with you later.
I'm going to shave,
shower and everything,
and, you know,
put my eyedrops in.
[Water running]
[knocking on door]
- Woody?
[speaking ltalian]
[Water running]
Oh, this one gets hot water.
This is when I shut the door.
Good-bye.
- I never saw so many people
as walking around in the...
The housekeepers
have housekeepers.
[man speaking ltalian over PA.]
- He's great, because he can do
whatever he would like to do.
He's trying to be, on his films,
what maybe he is,
so that's just great,
and what we would like
to do, maybe.
My mother,
she's madly in love with him.
And so, I said,
"Okay, let's go and do it."
So I made this big present,
and she was nearly crying for that.
And here we are. Let's see what
he's going to do with his jazz band.
- What'd you do
with that horn yesterday?
You bore the barrel out?
- Yeah, 'cause it's, uh...
- Does it feel better,
opened up like that?
- No.
[laughter]
I'm going to try
and use it anyway.
[applause and cheering]
[applause continues]
[Woody]: Like the lights are out...
Ah...
could we get the band
out here or something?
Could we get some
of the band guys out here?
- One, two, three...
[man singing]
- You said it!
Well I ain't seen
that evening sun go down
[laughter]
I ain't seen
that evening sun go down
Man: Ah-ha!
'Cause my baby
she done left this town
[applause]
- Thank you.
Thank you very much
for sitting through us in the dark.
[laughter]
Um, I don't know
what happened, but...
you know, these are the things
that make life interesting,
I suppose.
Um, thank you again for coming.
It was great to play for you -
greater even in the dark
than in the light.
[laughter]
That's it for us,
ladies and gentlemen...
[kisses]
So thank you again.
It was a great, great pleasure.
[applause]
We'll be right backstage.
Let's get out of here.
Follow the light.
I thought there was gonna be -
God knows what -
I thought there was
gonna be a stampede.
In New York, by this time,
there would be 1 6,000
television sets missing.
Just quickly,
'cause I'm due at--
- Grazie, grazie. Bravo.
- Oh, thank you.
- Grazie.
- Thank you.
- You're the humorist
of the century.
- Thank you. I must go,
because my mother's
on a respirator.
The reed. It's the reed.
- Come on in.
- Hello.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- You, too.
- I'm Tatiana Mantovani.
I'm a journalist.
I'm here just to give you this.
- Oh! Thank you.
The spaceship has landed.
"Thank you, Woody..."
- For your so...
How do you say?
Brave heart.
'Cause... at the Esmeraldo,
one night there was no light,
and you were so secure,
and you continued to play.
- Yeah, some people
are just heroes.
- Yes, a hero...
- At least I know that it's...
I guess it's hereditary.
You know, I have a tendency to--
- One picture, please?
- Oh, yes, sure.
[Soon Yii]: Oh, my God,
there are so many
people out there.
It's funny.
- Soon Yi, they'll recognize you
because you're Asian.
- You think I'm the only Asian
in the hotel?
[Woody]: No, no,
don't blow my cover.
They'll start throwing
pebbles against the window.
What do I do? I'm scared.
- There are hundreds of people.
A thousand people out there.
You just cannot get through.
We're gonna go out the back.
No one tell them.
- I'm scared.
- Hey, I like that.
- You know what you do?
You go to the door, you wave,
and then you walk
back up the stairs,
and then you sneak back down
around the other way
as you go out the stairs.
That way they'll never know
where you're going from. Trust me.
- No, but don't you think they're here
because they know
he's going to the mayor this time?
- I don't think they know that.
- You think they just camped out?
Maybe when you come back
into the hotel,
before you come upstairs,
you could just go to the front door -
not open it - and just wave,
because all those people
are waiting to see you.
It seems a shame.
It doesn't seem quite right.
- You can't afford
to lose your own people.
- You sure they're there for me?
'Cause I don't want to go out
and wave if it's not for me.
It'll be embarrassing.
They may be here for Berlusconi
or Mick Jagger or somebody.
- No, I don't think so.
[scattered applause]
[Woody]: The funniest thing to me
is meeting all the mayors.
- Oh, yeah, sit down.
[Woody]: I got nothing to say to them,
they got nothing to say to me.
It's a photo op for the mayors,
and I get my little present.
Grab the swag.
Put it in a gunnysack somewhere.
- Thank you very much.
[Mayor]: I imagine
that you are very busy, sir.
- Holy God.
- Want me to say hello?
- Yeah.
- Just gonna say hello.
- Woody!
[applause]
Thank you, Woody!
-... to say hello
and... and thank you
to everybody.
- Thank you! Thank you, Woody!
- How are you?
All right, all right?
- Am I all right? Yes.
- Thank you
- Okay, let's go.
- Thanks, fellas.
I just thought l...
I'm coming out
for a glimpse later,
if you don't mind waiting.
- Where are we going
to put these flowers?
- You want to keep the flowers?
- Yeah.
- That's why I hate to get flowers.
'Cause the burden
is always on the receiver.
[Letty]: All you have to do
is call the housekeeper.
[Woody]: Oh, no.
Then the pullman's gotta come up.
[Letty]: And ask him for slippers.
[Woody]: I gotta have
a beer or something.
[Soon Yi]: The mayor was very nice
and very good-looking.
- Yeah, but thank God
he couldn't speak English.
So they have this retrospective
of my films here.
They always show,
with equal respect,
the films that were not successful
in the United States.
[Letty]: Right, but those films
were successful in Europe,
so they don't see them as--
- Yes, "Another Woman"
and "Stardust Memories"
and "lnteriors" and "September."'
- Yes, but they were equally
successful here.
- So they don't--
- I know.
They definitely gained something
in the translation.
I don't know what it was...
but in the United States,
they were--
[Soon Yi]:
Maybe it's your voice dubbed.
- No, I'm not in any of those movies.
[laughter]
[Letty]: That must be it.
- It's amazing.
But isn't it interesting--
- Although "Bullets" did very well.
- I've known her how long now,
seven years, five years?
I don't know how long.
She's seen so many of my films.
She's never seen "Annie Hall."
- How could you have
never seen "Annie Hall"?
- And she's so friendly with Keaton.
She loves Diane.
And she would love "Annie Hall."
It's the perfect picture for her.
- I've never gotten around to it.
I've never read anything of his.
Of all my pictures,
which I don't have a high opinion of,
that one I think you would like.
I think you would have
a particularly good time.
- Everybody loved it, first of all.
- My favorite is "Manhattan."
- You should probably go in
with one of your...
you, you know,
teenage twitty friends
and see "Annie Hall."'
Probably 'cause you'd like it,
that's all.
I wouldn't recommend necessarily
seeing any of the others,
but that one
I think you would like.
I saw "lnteriors" when I was young.
- What did you think of "lnteriors"?
- I would rather not say!
I mean, I was very young,
so I couldn't--
- Oh, I see.
- Listen,
most Americans that saw the picture
would've agreed with you.
- Right. I couldn't sit through it.
It was long and tedious and... yeah.
- Right.
- Europeans like pictures that drone on,
and I'm good at making pictures
that drone on.
[Letty]: I need slippers,
and she needs slippers here.
- And also no face towels.
You know those small ones?
- Yes, I understand.
- Okay, thank you, washcloths.
Woody?
- Yeah?
- Someone's staying in the hotel,
and they would like
to take a picture of you.
Of course, noWs not a good time.
- Well...
- So what should I say?
- Tell 'em it's not possible.
[Letty]: Say no, he's very busy
and he has to go to the concert.
Tell 'em it's not po--
- Wiill you tell them?
- Tell 'em in no uncertain terms.
Jesus, people are just crazy,
you know?
I'm sorry.
[Woody]: Mr. Allen hates taking photos.
- No, I understand, but he can't.
- Just put the phone down.
- He's busy getting ready
for the concert.
Why do you negotiate
for 1 5 minutes?
- But thank you
for your interest.
- It's amazing. Do 500 pictures a day,
1 0,000 autographs.
They don't have to call
the hotel room and pressure you.
- Bye.
[hangs up]
Well, you see, this was the problem.
Their husbands won't believe
that they saw Woody Allen
without a photograph.
- So when I go down in the lobby later
on the way to the concert,
I'll stop and do a photo.
I've never said no to anybody.
- Now you tell me!
After I tell her it's not possible,
he's going to the concert,
no way, no photographs--
- I'm sorry.
I said no to nobody
on this whole European trip.
- He's already resting.
- I know.
I always get a little depressed.
- Oh, why?
- At some point during the day,
I always do.
Ah, you know...
You're in a strange town and...
[Letty]: And your tooth bothers you.
- And I gotta do it tomorrow.
- You've heard only
wonderful things about Bologna
and the people in it.
- The truth is, I've been
apprehensive about coming.
- But you've heard very good things
about the people in Bologna,
and you've heard
that the town was beautiful.
- But I get a little spooked
by medieval towns.
They're too sinister for me.
It's, like, winding medieval streets.
I couldn't take it today -
we were driving around in the car -
you drive through those things,
and, uh, you know...
I like nice, big, wide-open spaces--
- That I wouldn't say!
- Oh, I shouldn't
tell them that, right?
- "You got a hell
of a town here."
"l know with a couple of valium
I could really learn to love it."
[applause]
[speaking ltalian]
Before we begin
the conversation,
first, I want to thank everybody
for coming here.
I'm very, very honoured
to be here.
It's a great pleasure for me.
But you should know one thing.
In the United States,
I'm a very, very famous
claustrophobic.
[laughter]
This is not a joke.
So after the questions are over,
I would appreciate it
if everyone would keep their seats
while I walk up the aisle
and collapse.
Otherwise,
the experience
will be very, uh, traumatic for me.
And now anything
you want to say is okay.
[applause]
- Woody, is this reality?
- For me,
it's a total digression from reality.
The whole trip
has been, you know,
because I live
a very quiet life.
I live in my apartment,
I get up, I work,
I take a walk
on the Upper East Side.
You know,
it's a quiet, normal life.
The life of the writer, mostly.
You know, the filmmaker.
This whole trip,
between the fans and the responses
and the places...
- Slide that finger up,
you got the seven.
- Yeah.
[strumming banjo]
- I like that.
Experiments in modern writing.
- It's my Neil Hefti arrangement
of Sidewalk Blues.
[laughter]
- I can't see,
because there's a light in my eyes.
Ah, okay, does somebody
have my horn?
- Yes, we've got it.
- Oh, okay. Great.
You look very pretty.
- Thank you.
- Very pretty.
Uh...
I gotta get a reed.
- Okay. Over there.
- Yeah, go that way.
- Where's my coat?
- I have it.
- I'll be okay. I'll be okay.
[screech]
I could play in here.
Gonna have the concert right here.
Move the audience in here.
It'd be perfect.
Oh, God, I should live so long.
Now don't go away
As they sang
love's old sweet song
On Moonlight Bay
- We're playing shorter tonight.
Good to see you.
- I am very, very pleased.
- Thank you.
- I make the presentation.
- What present--
- Yes.
I say, "Now, ladies and gentlemen,
Woody Allen."
- Oh, no,
we usually don't do that.
Usually we just come out
and play.
No presentation.
They just come out,
they begin to play,
and I come out.
Whenever you're ready,
you just tell us,
and we'll go out and play.
- I don't say, "Ladies and gentlemen"?
- No, nothing at all.
Just nothing at all.
As soon as he comes back in here,
you can wander out and...
- Very good.
[speaking ltalian]
[Woody]: Uh, what is he doing?
- He's making an introduction.
- You want to...
to just go out and play?
- In the middle of his speech?
- Yeah.
Yeah, come on, let's just go.
Let's just go.
Okay, okay.
Come on, let's go.
- This guy put 'em to sleep.
Shine
toesies and nosies
And you'll frind
Trhat everything
will turn out frine
Folks I'm shouting to ya
Everyone's gonna
howl out to ya
You make
the whole world shine
That was the jury, definitely,
out there tonight.
- Yeah, it was, uh...
The second we walked out,
they were...
anaesthetized.
This was definitely...
[Soon Yi]: What'd you think
of the crowd?
- What?
- What'd you think of the crowd?
- I thought
they were a little reserved.
We were wondering
why you were staying on so long.
- Yeah. We thought you'd play
Little Place Like Home even sooner.
I didn't know what to do.
- I was just, uh, you know--
- I think there were people there
who enjoyed it,
but there were others who were
probably there as an obligation.
- Right, right.
- They were waiting for it to be over.
- That's why I played longer,
'cause I knew
there were people out there
who were there
with an obligation,
and I wanted
to torture them.
- Fantastico.
- Thank you so much.
- I am very, very happy.
- They were a very good audience.
- People are very happy.
- Very nice people.
- And the music is fantastic.
If it's possible, I take you
to question for the television?
- Sure.
- Okay.
What is for you
the music and the clarinet?
For your heart?
- Well, it's a hobby.
I do it 'cause I love it.
I'm not doing it
for the money.
I'm doing it
just for the amusement,
and I hope the people like it, too,
because, you know....
But I could tell they did.
They were tapping
their feet tonight.
They were just great.
- Thank you very much.
- Okay, thank you.
- Thank you for the concert.
- No, thank you, thank you.
- Thank you, grazie.
- These two gentlemen
paid for all of this.
- Very happy to meet you.
- Oh, how are you?
- How long you've been playing
without stopping not even a minute.
- But this was shorter.
In a concert,
we play longer than this.
We cut it down tonight,
because we didn't want
to keep the people too long.
We didn't think it was...
I know they want to eat.
Oh, my goodness.
There's a coronation.
Wow. Look at this.
Isn't this incredible?
- May I introduce you my wife.
- Yes, please.
Hello. How are you?
This is Soon Yi Previn,
The notorious Soon Yi Previn.
- Hello.
- You missed a hand there.
They're more animated now
than when we played for them.
If you need my coat,
you can have my coat.
Any time you want my coat,
you can have it.
'Cause I have another.
Well, first going out,
you know, it was the height
of all that...
in the newspapers at the time,
and we just never allowed
our pictures to be taken together.
So if we were on the street
and there was a paparazzi,
we would just, you know...
And then--
- We would have to take a walk
on the terrace.
- Then as reality set in,
you know, um...
We, you know,
became more and more
open and direct about it,
but, uh...
So now they're asking,
"Can you give her a kiss?"
And now I do, you know.
You want to get out
on the terrace for a while?
- Yes. I'm coming.
I'm coming.
- Doesn't the city
look beautiful?
- It does.
- It looks great.
I can never look at this view
without thinking of the opening scene
in "La Dolce Vita,"
where the helicopter's
flying over Rome,
with the Christ statue.
- That's right.
- Or the Mary statue,
or whatever it was,
and blessing it.
Are you gonna be sad
to go home?
You gonna miss Europe?
- No, no.
I mean, I like this trip a lot.
You know, it's been fun.
We've been on the go constantly.
- Mm-hmm.
- But...
- 'Cause, uh, I know
I've got the kind of personality
where when I'm here in Europe,
I miss New York,
and when I'm in NewYork,
I miss Europe.
- You want to be here.
- I just don't want to be where I am
at any given moment.
I would rather be somewhere else.
And there's no way
to beat that problem,
because no matter
where you are,
it's chronic dissatisfaction.
Anhedonia.
[Letty]: So how do we all feel
now that we're coming
down to the wire?
[coughing]
- I have a terrible cold.
The first time I've gotten sick
in Europe with a cold ever, I think.
I mean,
it's like a real classic head cold.
What a drag.
I was looking forward
to giving a good show tonight.
[sniffling]
I didn't want to just go out there
and make it an achievement
if I get through the show.
I wanted to be very good.
'Cause if I'm not good,
these people will hate me
in my own language.
- He's just so brilliant.
Everything he does is good.
- I've been a Woody Allen fan
for a long time and a jazz fan,
and it seemed to me
a logical thing to do:
to have them both in one session.
- So we've come to meet him.
- Is there something in particular
about his sense of humour
that attracts you?
- Uh, his Jewishness.
- If I'm feeling down, I just put on
"Annie Hall" or whatever,
and he just makes me laugh.
He just makes me laugh.
- I can't breathe.
I feel weak.
[Letty]: You had soup?
- Yes.
[Woody]: Yes, disgusting soup.
- Oh. Well...
- If they're in this state,
they want consomme.
- And he just took
his temperature.
And he didn't have one. It's normal.
And then he sticks the thermometer
back in his mouth,
hoping it'll go up a point.
- I'm not hoping.
I'm just trying to check.
- He keeps it in forever.
[laughter]
- You'll get caught up
in the audience,
and you'll be fine.
- That's right.
As soon as they start clapping,
you'll forget it all.
- You think so? Not me.
Maybe Jolson was like that.
- You'll be throwing kisses.
- Yes.
[applause]
[iazz playing]
- Kansas City!
[applause]
[playing "Home Sweet Home"]
- There's no place like home.
It usually means that the dance,
or the picnic or the funeral
or whatever it is they're at,
is over,
and everyone goes home.
The orchestra goes home,
the audience goes home.
They resume their lives,
pick up the broken pieces
and try and go on.
And that's
what it means for us.
It's sort of the end
of our... our concert.
So I just want to say
on behalf of the orchestra,
it was an incredible privilege
to play for you tonight.
Really, really
a great, great privilege.
Thank you so much
for coming, really.
[applause]
[cheering and whistling]
- That was a great finale!
[audience cheering louder]
- Thank you, thank you.
Have a good trip back.
- Okay, we'll see you in NewYork.
- Bye!
- We'll see you all back in the city.
All right, bye now.
- Feel better.
- We'll do this again.
[laughter]
Hey, it's great. It's over.
There was a time
I was looking forward
to that whole
formidable list of dates.
- Mm-hmm.
- And now?
- "Oh, God, I'm gonna be in Turin,
I'm gonna be in Bologna,
I'm gonna be in Spain,"
and now it's history.
- She didn't want them
to unpack it,
you know... alone.
[Woody]: Okay.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
[Letty]: Hello, hello, hello.
- Hello.
[Letty]: Here, Dad.
We want to show you
what we got,
what Woody got in Europe.
Woody, you want
to explain these?
- This is a medal
from the theatre.
- It's a medal.
They gave you a medal.
- What theatre?
- It's from the theatre in Venice.
- Oh.
- Well, don't you want it?
- Yeah. Why not?
- I know, but what are you
gonna do with it?
- Put it my... Save it.
[Letty]: No. You'll put it out here
with his other stuff.
- This was awarded to me
by the fire department in Milan.
- "Crazy Woody"!
- No, it says "grazie," not "crazy."'
It says here I single-handedly
saved some lives in Milan,
and the fire department
gave me this.
- Uh-huh, uh-huh...
There was a terrible,
terrible emergency.
Actually, what happened
was the lights went out,
but I didn't panic
and saved the lives
of a lot of people
from being stomped to death
and trampled to death.
Feel that. It's heavy, isn't it?
- Oh, and how.
- You always liked
that kind of lucite stuff.
[Letty]: That was from the theatre
in Venice that burned down.
- You're a very lucky man.
- I ought to engrave this.
- I thought they engraved it.
Oh, this is from, uh...
it's from Madrid.
- It was engraved
over there, huh?
- All he cares about
is where it was engraved.
What's the difference?
- This is a D.W. Griffith Award,
distinguished achievement
in motion pictures.
This was given to me
for managing to live to 60.
- Given to you?
- Yeah, mm-hmm.
Because I'm alive
and in good health.
- Whoever did the engraving,
it's beautiful.
Let me tell you something,
this is real good engraving.
- Uh-huh. One would get
the feeling he was an engraver.
- D.W. Griffith.
D.W. Griffith.
I remember him years ago.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- You don't remember me practicing
the clarinet in my room?
- Yes, we... I do.
- Yes. You shut the door.
I remember.
You shut the door and played.
You didn't play it loud.
Yes, I remember the fella coming in.
He was a black man.
- Gene Cedric was a great,
great jazz clarinet player,
who I called up on the telephone
and asked if he would...
I saw him play in town.
I asked if he would come
to the house,
and he only charged me
$2 per lesson.
- I don't remember.
- Two dollars, but he'd come
all the way in from Harlem.
- I remember the man
coming to teach you.
- Yeah, and neither of us
could read music or anything,
and we would just sit
in the living room,
and he would try
and help me in some way,
and he was helpful.
- Remember he took tap?
- Remember I took tap-dancing lessons?
- Oh, yes, I remember that.
You did a lot of good things,
but you never pursued them.
[Letty]: Had you gone on, you would
have been a good tap dancer.
- I would've been a tap dancer.
- You'd have been a tap dancer,
which is bad.
- Why is it bad?
- It's very hard for people
in show business
to make a living.
- You wanted me
to be a pharmacist.
- A pharmacist or--
- So you don't remember
anything else?
You don't remember if I used
to listen to the radio a lot
and listened to music
all the time?
- Oh, yes, you listened to that,
but I wasn't concerned.
You were in your room,
your room.
You stayed there most of the time,
just came out to eat.
[Letty]: You lived in your room.
- What did you have
in your room?
- What'd I have in my room?
- Did you have a Victrola?
- Yeah. Don't you remember?
Were you an uninterested parent?
- I wasn't an uninterested parent.
I took you wherever I thought
was good for you.
- Like where?
What does that mean?
Hebrew school?
- Like Hebrew school.
That was good for you.
Yes, that was very good for you.
- All that time-wasting junk.
- No, that wasn't time-wasting--
- So would you say
that you were the exact
wrong kind of parents for me?
Would you say that you were
the exact wrong kind of parents?
- I think I was too strict.
- She was too strict.
- You used to beat me and beat me
and beat me every day.
[Lettty laughing]
Every day.
- How did I beat you,
with a stick?
- No. Wiith your hand,
with a strap, with...
Oh, you used to beat me
every day.
I could've grown up
to be a drug addict or a criminal.
- Did they offer you drugs?
- Why?
- Or a criminal.
- But you weren't brought up
in that kind of a household. I'm sorry.
You were brought up
in a household
that knew right from wrong,
acted right.
And don't think for a moment
that you are what you are
by yourself. You're not.
You had help.
You had help from parents.
You listened.
Don't give all the credit to you.
- You had an idea
that you could write a script,
that you're a big shot.
That's a lot of hokum.
Don't mean a thing.
- I'd still be better off
if I was a druggist, right?
- By the--
Maybe you would be.
Maybe you'd do more
business as a druggist
than you did as an actor.
- I probably would do more
business as a druggist.
- More people would
come into the drugstore
than go to the films!
That's probably true!
- Maybe you would--
- That's right.
If I had a good drugstore,
I'd probably get a bigger audience
than I get for my movies.
So how do you feel now
about the fact
that both Christopher and l
go out with Asian women?
- I personally don't think it's right.
[Dad]: You go where?
- That's me, my opinion.
- Wiith Chinese women.
- Not Chinese, Asian.
- Christopher's--
- Cheryl's not Chinese. I'm not--
- I would've liked him
from the beginning
to fall in love
with a nice Jewish girl.
- A nice Jewish girl?
- lnstead of a nice movie actress.
- That's why the Jews
someday will be -
not in your time - be extinct.
And that's very bad.
- This is truly the lunch from hell.
[laughter]
- I didn't think that Woody
would turn out to be this successful.
I knew he had a terrific brain.
He didn't show
any other talents.
He showed a lot of talent
in his sports.
But he did say to me years ago,
that if he had
to choose a career,
he would choose music.
Anyhow, that's that.
- He did a good job, though.
- Yeah. I should hope
you would know it.
- What one of his films
do you like?
Do any come from his real life?
Do you see any of him in them?
- Sometimes I do, yeah,
but very seldom.
He adds or subtracts
from his life.
He'll tell you a story,
or he'll have a movie
that will be
not like his life,
and some of them
he adds on,
but, no, he doesn't want
to make a movie of his life,
I mean,
have people know that.
I like it
because he tells you a story.
Even though it may not
be true, the stories,
or it may be farfetched,
but it's a story.
That's what I like.
All right, sir, go home.
Look down look down
Trhat lonesome road
Befrore you travel on
Look up look up
And meet your maker
For Gabriel
blows his horn
I'm weary totin'
such a heavy load
Strolling down
that lonesome road
Look down look down
Befrore you travel on
DVD Subtitling: CNST, Montreal