[Star of the Universe Episode 5]
You're forgetting something.
You're already dead
Hello?
Wooju, the president wants to meet for drink.
I'm running.
- At this time?
- Give me the phone.
Wooju! What are we going to do about...?
Hello?
Why's he out this late?
Leave him be.
And stop coddling him.
That's why he's so weird.
Lately ,all celebrities have been
in scandals left and right.
It took us so long just to get this far.
Oh, man...
There's nothing we can do about it.
Let's get some fried rice.
- Sir!
- Yes?
- Two bowls of fried rice.
- Sure.
Is Wooju coming today?
Actually, he's got a lot of work to do.
Well... Of, course he does.
- Sir.
- You should call a driver.
I only had two glasses of soju.
Thank you for the meal.
- Okay. Be safe, yeah?
- Yes.
- I should call you a driver.
- It's okay.
Oh no, it must be his time.
Let's go. It's right about time.
-Sinc & corrected by KieKie Rizkya-