[Episode 4]
I love drinking solo.
Since my job entails talking all day,
having this time when I don't have to...
this solitude...
is the best.
I have a couple of rules for myself
when I drink solo.
First: I have to drink in a place
with a luxurious atmosphere.
Second: I have to snack on
something luxurious while I drink.
Third: I have to drink
with some class.
I must never allow my blood alcohol level
to get above 0.08 percent.
That's the legal
blood alcohol limit.
That's the sweet spot. That's how much
I can drink without feeling cruddy.
Hey!
I hate people like this who
drink too much and black out.
A time just for myself.
A time of healing.
This is the reason why
I love drinking solo.
Wow!
Professor Jin! You acted so cold
and yet you're considerate enough
deep down inside to let
me into the joint class!
Wow, he's having some
delicious beef tripe, eh?
Looks delicious.
I'm going to eat that too!
It looks similar enough, so I'll just
think that it's tripe and eat it.
All right... one.
And here's a huge one!
How about a whole ton?
Having beer with tripe is the best!
Wow, we even have similar
tastes, Professor Jin!
Shall we have a toast together since
we're in the same joint class now?
Clink!
A morpheme is the smallest
linguistic unit that carries meaning.
She gets cuter and cuter
the more I look at her.
Hey, Jin Gong Myung.
What are you doing?
Huh? I'm having a drink
while studying hard.
Studying hard, my ass!
How the hell are you going to get
any studying done while drinking?
Also, who told you that you
could touch my alcohol? Huh?
Come on, stop being so petty!
I'm warning you.
Never touch my alcohol again.
No, not only that.
Don't touch any of my
things at all! Got that?
All right, already!
Just turn off the lights.
I'm going to sleep here.
What do you mean you're sleeping?
Clean this up right now!
As you can see, I had two
entire bottles to myself.
I'm so dizzy that I can't do anything!
My bad.
I'll clean it up tomorrow.
Oh, I can barely move my body!
Really now?
Don't clean it then.
I'll do it.
You will?
Yeah. It'll be hard for you to go help
out at the orchard starting tomorrow.
This is the least I can do.
I'll clean it!
I'll clean it, okay?
Give that here.
You're not going to the academy
tomorrow since it's the weekend, right?
I'm going out of town
because of work
so don't you dare cause
any trouble until I get back.
So the house will be
empty this weekend?
Don't cause any trouble!
If the house looks just
like this when I get back
I'm shipping you over to
the orchard. Got that?
Okay. Go on upstairs.
Go on!
So that means that I'll be
the only one here, right?
This is going to be a hell
of a great weekend!
If you cause any trouble whatsoever,
I'll straight-up kill you!
Yes, sir.
"I'll straight-up kill you!"
Jin Yi, why are teachers
from Seoul going to lecture
at a new academy that opened
outside of the city this weekend?
The instructors teaching in
Seoul are famous nationwide
so it's to help with
marketing, basically.
About 1,000 kids will be
gathered together there.
So we can promote our academy
and ourselves there too!
So it'll be great
for you too!
Yeah, of course! If a teacher from
Seoul visits one of these things once
their street cred goes up and
they are eligible for bigger bonuses!
Wow, you're so lucky!
Yeah. It'd be nice if you
could come with us too!
Too bad it's just me, Professor Jin,
and Professor Min.
It would've been so nice if
the director gave you a chance too
since you're in
the joint class now.
You know, I really don't
like that director of ours.
No, it's fine.
I'm just a newbie after all.
Just going to watch you
all is an honor in itself!
Yeah, this is exactly
why I like you.
Because of your
ever-flowing positivity!
Oh yeah, Jin Yi.
Soy fermented crab is
in season right now.
Want to have some
with a little bit of soju?
Yeah, I really want to.
But I can't drink alcohol
for the time being.
To tell you the truth,
I might be pregnant!
What? Oh no!
What do you mean, "oh no"?
I'm so happy right now!
You're not even married though!
What could possibly be
good about that?
Exactly. Since I'm not married,
this will definitely lead to marriage!
My darling Min Ho kept
pushing marriage back
because he said he didn't
feel financially secure enough.
So I just went
and pounced on him!
Hey, who cares about that
kind of nonsense at this age?
Being childless is an even bigger
issue than financial insecurity!
Are you... sure that
you're pregnant?
Yeah. My menstrual cycle
is always predictable.
But it's three days late now!
So I thought it was strange
and looked up symptoms.
And... the results
were positive!
I've been irritable
because of that, and look.
My chest got even
bigger than usual, right?
- Oh, Jin Yi!
- What?
I'm going to see a doctor as soon
as I get back from Yeosu.
Then... maybe the dream I had last
night was a baby-related dream?
A baby-related dream?
Oh my gosh! No, it's because
I had a dream last night
and I was collecting tons of
clams from the seashore.
Oh! Does that mean it'll be
a daughter since I saw clams?
Oh my gosh!
Oh, just a second.
Yes, Director?
Where are you again?
Yes, Chief Kim.
So you've arrived?
Okay. Watch over the part-timers and make
sure the preparations go okay.
We'll be leaving
in 10 minutes or so.
Okay.
Why isn't Professor Min here yet?
It's almost time for the train!
Oh my gosh!
What is this now?
Oh, Director.
Youse tired, aren't 'cha?
- Huh?
- What is this?
Are you Lee Byung Hun
from "Inside Men" today?
Wow, you're right
on the mark!
Wait, so you're going to go
to Yeosu looking like that?
You go to Yeosu, Professor Hwang.
I'm going to Moil Island
and have me a drink.
Oh, really, now?
I reckon the train for Moil Island
is over there, so don't follow us.
You're embarrassing us, damn it.
Come on. Let's go.
Oh, Professor Jin isn't here yet.
He said he'd come by
himself in his own car.
Figures. He even drinks alone.
Let's all go, then.
What the hell are you doing?
Move this arm of yours!
Hey! Move!
I think Mr. Lee Byung Hun
is asking for a tip.
Geez, you're so ridiculous.
Let me see here.
Stop it already!
- Stop it!
- I'll end you!
Excuse me.
Here we go.
This is the spot.
We should've just gotten
a cab. What is this?
Hey, I barely managed to
get these seats, okay?
There aren't any seats
because it's the weekend.
Hand that over.
I'll put it up.
What the heck is in there?
Wait a second.
Where's my laptop?
- It's not in there.
- Did you leave it in the café?
Oh, yeah! The café! I asked them
to charge it and forgot to get it back!
I'll be right back.
Wait! The train leaves at 10:00 a.m.
sharp! We only have five minutes!
Really? Oh no! I have all of the
information about our academy there!
Ha Na, you go.
You can go there and get
back within five minutes, right?
- What?
- Really?
Of course! You can run 100
meters in 17 seconds, right?
And you were always the
best at running back in school!
That was a long time ago!
What are you doing?
Run, damn it!
- What?
- Run!
- Hurry!
- Yes, sir!
- What's going on?
- Run, Professor Park! Run!
Run!
Our director... no. A man in his forties
asked you guys to charge his laptop.
Oh!
- Is this it?
- Yes! Thank you!
There's one minute
before it leaves!
No! No!
No!
Oh no!
Damn it!
No!
Excuse me, can you get me a KTX ticket
for Yeosu? The earliest one possible.
The earliest one is
the 4:00 p.m. train.
Isn't there one that leaves
any earlier that that?
I'm sorry, but the trains before
that one are all booked.
Man, but the lecture starts
at 4:00 p.m.! What do I do?
Yes, Director?
Yes, but the earliest train
is leaving at 4:00 p.m. What do I do?
Yes, Director?
I was just about to leave.
What?
What do you...
No thank you. Why should I
have to take No Geu Rae in my car?
It's not like she's lecturing.
Just send her home.
Your laptop has
nothing to do with me!
At any rate, I won't be
driving her down to Yeosu with me.
Just be aware of that.
Take No Geu Rae and diminish
my own quality? No thanks.
I'm sorry.
I know you wanted to drive
down there leisurely
which is why you
didn't take the train
so I'm sorry to be a nuisance.
Whatever. To be precise, the one
who was a nuisance was the director.
How could he leave his laptop
behind? He's so careless.
But still, I'm sorry.
At any rate, I'll be totally silent.
Well, that's that, but...
why didn't you tell me the truth?
Excuse me?
What do you mean?
About the promotional wet wipes
and the gift certificates.
It seems like you were
not aware of either.
So why didn't you say anything,
when I got angry at you?
Apologize.
What?
Why do I need to apologize for that?
Of course you need to!
Thanks to you, I was made out to be the
crazy one who had one-sided assumptions!
Oh, um, sure.
I'm sorry.
- Is that why?
- What?
What do you mean?
Did you let me into the joint class
since you yelled at me for no reason?
I was actually quite curious.
Why did you change your mind when
you were so adamantly opposed to it?
There's no other reason.
Shall I just say that I saw
a sliver of potential in you?
What?
Wait, really?
What's with that expression?
I'm just so happy!
I've just been getting
insulted by you all this time.
So to hear you say that you
saw a sliver of potential in me
I'm so touched!
Stop overreacting!
I didn't say "potential."
I said "a sliver of potential."
A sliver.
So what? The important thing is
that you saw any potential in me at all!
I told you to stop overreacting!
I'm sorry.
But... I can't help it.
My mouth keeps smiling on its own.
Wait right here.
I'm going to get some coffee.
Um, Professor Jin!
You must be tired. Please get some
rest. I'll go get the coffee.
No thanks.
I have no intention of having you
buy me coffee when you earn so little.
Come on! I may only be earning
30,000 won per hour now
but I have the potential
to earn more later on!
I'm grateful to you for letting me into
the joint class and for the ride, too.
I, who has a sliver of potential, really
want to buy you a cup of coffee.
What would you like to drink?
An Americano like how chic you look?
Or a caffé latte
like how smooth you are inside?
Just get whatever.
Yes! I, who have a sliver of potential,
will go and buy some right now!
What should I eat?
Yeah, Gong Myung?
What? Why a drive
all of the sudden?
Oh... your Big Bro's car?
Okay. Come to the front
of my student hostel, then.
Okay.
What manners!
I wanted it first.
I picked it up first.
It's still mine, though!
No, it's not!
It's mine!
Why, you little--
Wow.
Hey! Go halfsies with me.
Let's be fair. Share.
Wow. Hey, Jung Chae Yeon!
You think you're hot because guys
are throwing themselves at you here?
Get it together, all right?
You're totally ugly!
You're... you're uglier
than this scrubber, here!
You're uglier
than this damn scrubber!
Yeah, wait. No.
You're uglier than this crushed can.
You're not the top beauty.
You're like the top beast!
Shut it. Go back to your room
and study or something.
It seemed like you're going
on a drive or whatever.
But if you came all the way to
Noryangjin to study, then study.
Why is it any of your business what I
do, whether it may be a walk or a drive?
Also, is "If you came all the way to
Noryangjin to study, then study"
all you know how to say?
Ugh, you're more like
the "Top Despicable Person!"
Geez. Just you watch,
Top Despicable Person.
If that ever happens again, I'll put
the ramen packet in my underwear!
Man... I'll bet that Dong Young is locked
up in here and won't come out.
What a pathetic guy.
What the...
He didn't lock it?
This bastard.
Looks like he's still stealing food
out of the hostel's cabinets as usual.
Now, let's see here...
Joo Yeon, I truly loved you.
You should completely forget
about a guy like me and be happy.
Mom, Big Sis, older brothers... thanks
for looking out for me all this time.
I really wanted to repay the
money you lent me after I passed
but it looks like I'm leaving
you without being able to do so.
What the hell is this fool up to?
My friends
Gong Myung and Ki Bum...
I'm sure that it was tough on you to
look after a pathetic guy like me.
I'll be reborn as a rich guy in my
next life and buy you tons of alcohol.
I don't know who will discover
this letter, but don't look for me.
I'll already be eternally
slumbering in the ocean.
What does he mean eternally
slumbering in the ocean?
Why are you watching
someone else sleep?
Just because.
You look pretty when you're sleeping.
What the hell are you saying, you
crazy bastard? It's too early for this!
You can have this.
You know that this is my
favorite shirt, right?
What's with this cruddy gift
that I never asked for?
Do you want me to use this
as a rag or something?
Take this and go away
before I kick you!
You damn idiot.
Fine. Just keep making
funny jokes like that
and live your life as
a good, earnest person.
What kind of craziness are you
spouting so early in the morning?
Ki Bum. Let me hug you, just once.
What are you doing?
Why are you acting like this?
Seriously, what's with you?
Didn't you say you were heading to Yeosu
for your part-time job at the academy?
I'm going to get going
now to Yeosu.
To the ocean.
So he was planning to
drown himself in the ocean?
After leaving behind
a suicide note?
Damn it, I should've noticed
when he was acting up before!
He's probably not
dead already, right?
Oh yeah. This bastard
doesn't have a phone.
Damn it!
Yes, Director.
Yes, we're on our way now.
Yes. Yes.
Oh my!
What are you doing?
Yes, Director. I'll give you
a call once we get there. Yes.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't see you
because I was on the phone.
But why are you sitting on this side?
You drive from this point on,
Ms. No Geu Rae.
What? Me?
Is there another No Geu Rae here?
Of course I mean you!
I'm tired, so I need
to get some rest.
Why are you standing there like that?
You're not going to do it?
Well, um... I'm afraid I'll get into
an accident with your expensive car.
So are you telling
me that you can't right now?
Um, no! I, who have
a sliver of potential, will try!
A person with potential
can overcome any obstacle!
Yes! I'll do my best to drive!
Yes, me, who have potential!
You would think that I asked
her to cover for a Formula One driver.
Such a low-quality human being...
Ms. No Geu Rae.
You're driving a bit too
slowly, don't you think?
Do you think we'll be able to make
it to Yeosu today at this rate?
Oh, yes. I'm sorry.
Ms. No Geu Rae!
Aren't you driving too fast?
I said we're going to Yeosu,
not the afterlife!
Are you trying to kill us?
Oh, yes! I'm sorry!
Geez... are you serious?
Are you trying to get revenge
on me for asking you to drive
with this shoddy driving?
No, of course not!
Why would I do that to my mentor?
- Mentor?
- Yes!
Just like Oh Geu Rae in
"Misaeng" had Manager Oh
I, the Oh Geu Rae of Noryangjin,
have you, Professor Jin!
You even said that I had potential!
So I'll consider you
my mentor from now on.
No thanks. Just drive
properly, please.
Geez. Having you drive is making me
more tired than driving myself.
Just stop at the next rest stop.
I'll drive the rest of the way.
No, it's fine! I, who have potential,
will get it together and drive well!
Trust me, who has potential!
Dong Young...
please be alive! Please!
Step on it, man!
Let's go!
Hey, what if I get into
an accident doing that?
Big Bro loves this car!
If he knows I took it out, I'm dead!
If I run into him in Yeosu,
I'm really done for.
Why would we run into him there?
I told you, there's a reason why!
He can't be dead already, right?
Dong Young! You can't die!
Stop overreacting, man!
He wouldn't die!
How could you say that
after reading this?
Want me to read it
for you again?
"Joo Yeon, I truly loved you."
"You should completely
forget about a guy like me and..."
Dong Young!
Geez, seriously?
If I knew things would end up like this,
I would've given him a huge hug!
I would've accepted
his shirt that said "Kick"
instead of telling him to
go away before I kicked him!
Hey, stop crying, already!
If I knew things would end up like
this, I would've been nicer to him!
I cursed him out like crazy the other day
for drinking all the soup in the ramen
and said that he was a
bastard without a conscience!
I shouldn't have done that!
And when he said he'd poop in my room
because the hostel's toilet was clogged
I shouldn't have told him to piss off
and let him poop in peace!
Dong Young!
Damn it, this crazy bastard!
I told you, stop crying!
I'll get out here, so come
upstairs after you park.
And make sure you park in a wide spot
so my car doesn't get scratched.
Wait! I'm not good at parking.
So are you telling me that you can't?
What?
Um, no. I, who have potential,
will park this car well.
People with potential don't
give up on anything easily!
I, who have potential, will do
my very best to park!
Oh, darn.
What do I do?
Wow.
She loves the word
"potential" that much?
I thought she was a wily fox, but
she's actually a sucker for compliments.
I thought he'd refuse until the end,
but he went to pick you up?
Wow! How uncharacteristic
of that premium trash.
I'm not going to call him
premium trash anymore.
He's not premium trash to me
anymore. He's something else now.
- He's my "Premium Savior."
- What?
- "Savior?"
- Yes.
At first, he treated me like trash
because of my credentials
but he ended up putting me
in his joint class too.
Yeah, I know! He said he wouldn't
allow it over his dead body.
I wonder why he changed his mind?
Well... he said that
he saw my potential!
Wow, you must be so happy!
Oh, what's wrong, Jin Yi?
Does your stomach hurt?
No. I think the baby is stressed out
because of the long train ride.
Were you tired,
my poor Cherry?
Cherry?
That's her name for
when she's in the womb.
- Cherry.
- Oh.
You said that you think it'll be
a girl based on your dream too.
Do you really want a girl?
No, it's because my honey
and I conceived her at Cherry Hotel.
Oh man! How embarrassing!
What? Oh, you.
Yes? Yes, I'll be right there.
It's starting soon!
If my belly gets bigger,
it won't be long
before I can't lecture with
this perfect body anymore, right?
How do I look?
Do I look good?
You look amazing!
They said that we'll be giving
autographs after the lecture too.
Hello, everyone!
We can do it!
English grammar.
My name is Hwang Jin Yi.
All right, everyone.
English is so, so hard
that your chests were
filled with worry, right?
Don't you worry about
a thing anymore.
After all, I, Hwang Jin Yi, am here!
Even those whose grades
have dropped like this...
can have them go up like this.
Oh, my hip.
I'll get your grades up like this!
Just trust me!
Follow me.
Thank you!
Aw, geez.
Are all of youse good today?
I'm our academy's Lee Byung Hun,
Min Jin Woong.
Hey there.
So you want to know what makes me
our academy's Lee Byung Hun, eh?
I'm an "inside man," you see.
So I'll expose all of the "insider" top
secret information to you in my classes!
Hey, you. Yeah, you.
The one falling asleep.
Go to a deserted island and get
yourself a drink of water or somethin'.
Naw, naw.
Go have some cold noodles, instead
Wait, no. Don't yawn. Go to bibimbap
and have a bowl of Jeonju!
All right, everyone. Korean History
is all about memorization.
You must not memorize
things in a foolish way.
Then how must you
memorize things, you may ask?
First, understand the flow.
Then, memorize things.
You must understand
the flow of things first
and then memorize
things after that.
I'll tell you how to understand the flow
and what you must memorize.
I don't drone on.
I only talk about the heart of things.
As for the questions...
Wow. Look at that charisma.
He really isn't a top-level
instructor for nothing!
To think that someone like that
acknowledged my potential!
Yeah. I'll only walk on
a nice path from now on.
Therefore, if you just take
my classes diligently
you can get top scores
in Korean History without a problem.
I hope that you will
put your trust in me.
Yes, I trust you.
I completely trust you!
Can I take a photo?
Go ahead.
Thank you!
Can you hug me just once
so that I'll do well on my exams?
Oh, sure.
I hope you pass!
Good luck!
Autographs only, okay?
Here's Professor Min who teaches Public
Administration! Anyone taking that?
Professor Min is here!
Yes, yes, come.
Oh, Student! You must be so
tired from all your studying!
Sit. Have a seat.
Here. I'll massage you before
I give you my autograph, okay?
- Oh, geez.
- Ow.
- I'm not even massaging you that hard.
- That's not it!
I want to get Professor Jin's
autograph, but I don't have a pen.
Can you lend me one?
- Just take 'em all.
- Thank you!
Looks like my style is
being cramped a bit, eh?
What the hell? I feel like
we're just leftovers.
Yeah. Aw, man.
Maybe I shouldn't have done
the Lee Byung Hun impression?
Maybe I should've chosen
something younger and more popular?
Now you're blaming
Lee Byung Hun of all people?
Hey! Would a guy who said he'd die
just be working here calmly?
He said that he'd be eternally
slumbering in the ocean
so shouldn't we look there first?
Hey, how are we going to search
that huge ocean in such little time?
Let's just search the other places first.
And if he's dead, he won't be here.
Hurry! Go look!
Got it.
You look over there.
- I'll look here!
- Okay.
Damn it all... he has to be
here somewhere.
Who does he think he is, a celebrity?
Huh? Wait a second.
Someone get Professor Jin some water!
- Hey, part-timer!
- I'll get it.
- Okay, then. Go.
- Korean teacher!
- It's a shame--
- Ow!
I'm sorry.
- Oh, are you all right?
- Yes.
- You're not hurt, are you?
- No, I'm fine.
Are you okay,
Professor Park?
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm fine. Are you really okay?
Hey! I found Dong Young!
- Huh?
- Hurry!
That bastard.
Why, I ought to--
- Hey!
- You!
What the.. what are
you doing here?
How could you ask that when you
disappeared after writing a suicide note?
- You think we'd just sit still?
- How could you think about dying?
Who the hell cares
about some damn woman?
What do you mean, some damn woman?
She was my everything.
I don't have any desire to live
on without her in my life.
Shut up. Why would you be
working part-time here then?
I may be leaving,
but I can't be irresponsible.
I'm going to tie up all my
loose ends before I go.
And just where the hell do
you think you're going?
Don't be like that, you bastard!
- Dong Young.
- Yes, sir?
Good work. I have to go
back to Seoul, so I'll pay you now.
This is the something special
that I mentioned last time.
- Thank you, sir.
- Yes, good work.
Um, sir?
Yeah?
You're short 10,000 won.
Oh, really?
Here.
- Keep up the good work.
- Goodbye.
Even though I may be leaving,
I don't want to go empty-handed.
And just where do you
think you're going?
Stop saying such scary things,
you pitiful bastard!
I thought you were dead!
[Yeosu Briefing Session]
All right, then.
Good work, everyone.
Unpack your things at our accommodations
and let's have a drink.
We're all the way
in Yeosu, after all.
No thank you.
Why? Are you going to drink by yourself
again even though we're here?
Yes. I'll drink alone.
I like it that way.
Then.
Get home safely.
Rest well!
Gosh, he's being so difficult.
Oh well, we will just go
drink without him then.
I will go change
into something comfortable first.
Director Kim.
Hey, Directer Choi!
Including Professor Jin
you came all the way here
with good instructors.
- Thank you very much.
- Don't mention it.
We're one family,
so we should help each other.
I appreciate that.
Ah, I almost forgot.
For your efforts today
it's not much, but please take this.
Why are you doing this?
Don't do that and please take it.
Come on, it's okay.
Thank you then.
I wish the Yeosu academy
all the best. Good luck!
Good luck!
By the way, the Korean professor
Choi Yoon Hee was supposed to come.
- She didn't come, huh?
- Professor Choi?
She recently quit.
What?
She's the Korean instructor
working on the eighth floor.
Until recently, she wanted
to join our joint class.
She quit her job?
You didn't know that?
Her husband is being
transferred overseas.
She's following him, so she quit.
That's how Professor Park
got in instead of her.
If not, why would
Professor Jin take her in?
- What?
Gosh, why are you doing this?
I said I want to be alone.
What do you mean you want to be alone?
You'll jump in the water, won't you?
You can't go anywhere today.
Stay with me at all times. Got that?
Hello.
Please have a look and order.
Let's just eat first.
What would you like to eat?
The least expensive dish.
Then it's halibut and squid.
I will order it then.
Seriously, what should we do with him?
Hey, what's the most expensive dish here?
- The most expensive dish?
- Yes.
It's a croaker.
- A croaker?
- Yes.
Excuse me, please bring us
a large croaker sashimi.
Are you crazy?
Don't worry. I got it.
Who knows?
If he tries something expensive
and delicious that he hasn't tried
he might be motivated to go on.
Don't do anything stupid.
I really have no desire to live.
You punk, seriously.
Hey.
Don't do that.
When the dish comes out, just try it.
I'm okay.
He wanted to die earlier,
but now he has a big appetite, huh?
Don't do that.
This will be the last sashimi
I will try on this earth, right?
Is that why?
It's better than I expected.
Hey, stop talking and live it up.
Joo Yeon isn't
the only woman in the world.
Hey, you said
her boobs were a size C cup.
Now that you two broke up
it opens the possibility of you
finding women with a D or E cup.
It means nothing if it's not Joo Yeon.
I will end my life.
Excuse me,
can you bring us the fish stew now?
When you're about to end your life,
you ask for a fish stew?
Be quiet.
It's all good as long as he eats well.
Excuse me, please make it spicy.
No, make it clear and not spicy.
My stomach has been
bothering me recently.
My doctor told me not to eat spicy food.
When you're about to die,
you worry about your stomach?
Stop it, punk.
I will go to the bathroom.
Sure, do that.
- Go.
- Okay.
Why do you keep questioning him?
What if he really ends his life?
Hold on.
Is it okay to send him
to the bathroom alone?
What if he bites his tongue and dies?
I will go check.
Hey, it's okay.
If he were thinking about dying,
would he order a fish stew?
He wouldn't kill himself
because he wants to eat the stew.
Gosh, I can't even drink because of him.
What's this about?
He wanted to die earlier, but he's
the one who is having most fun now.
Be quiet.
You're right.
This will be the last ride I will enjoy.
Is that why?
This is more fun than I thought.
Why do you keep saying
it's the last time?
Please change your mind.
I told you.
My life without Joo Yeon is meaningless.
I will fly away like this.
High and above.
Don't do that, Dong Young.
Where would you fly away to?
Ki Bum.
Don't try to stop me.
God, please forgive me for making
the wrong decision to end my life.
But I can't go on without Joo Yeon.
Stop it and sit down. It's dangerous.
Gong Myung, I have nothing to fear.
I have nothing to
look forward to in this world.
I said, just sit down already.
Hey!
I almost died!
What was that? You said you'd die.
Now you're scared?
Well, what do you mean I'm scared?
Park Ha Na.
Do you still feel grateful
to Jin Jung Seok?
He's your premium savior?
I take it back.
He's undoubtedly premium trash.
So...
when he made you fill in for the
Korean instructor on the eighth floor
he went on and on
saying you had potential and all
he made you all happy.
Can he play someone like this?
He's a bastard and premium trash.
Oh my, I should use only nice words.
Oh my, it's not good for my baby.
I'm sorry, baby.
Mommy is very sorry.
You must be furious.
I wish I could drink with you.
Now I can't drink when things are sad.
I can't drink when things are good.
Becoming a mom isn't something
that happens every day!
Gosh, I need to pee.
What do I do now?
Seriously, the premium trash
is an asshole.
Seriously.
What's wrong, Jin Yi? Jin Yi!
What's wrong? What is it? Jin Yi!
Jin Yi! Jin Yi!
What do I do now?
I just got it.
What? What did you just get?
I just got my period.
I wasn't pregnant.
What do I do?
Professor Hwang, you're
drinking so much and so fast.
Too much.
We have our rooms to stay in tonight.
We will be drinking all night.
You don't want to
get wasted all by yourself.
Please leave me alone.
Eat in between drinking.
It won't be good for your stomach.
True. Eat something.
If you've come to this area
you should try this.
Stop it already.
You should know when it's appropriate.
What is that?
Why did the alarm go off
when it's only 6:00 p.m.?
Isn't it supposed to go off
at 10:00 p.m.?
It's just that to be able
to get home by 11:00 p.m
I should get going now.
So I set it for earlier.
So you're saying you're going home now?
Yes...
I don't have classes to teach tomorrow,
so I don't have to stay here.
My wife is scared of going to bed alone.
Please enjoy.
I will leave first.
Director Kim.
- I love you.
- Forget it.
It's all good that you're
the only one who is worried?
Good for you that you're married!
What's going on with her?
Sorry. Sorry.
I think she's drunk.
No, I'm not.
By the way, I hate the ones who take off
first in the middle of drinking.
We should never let
people like him drink with us.
It's so irritating.
Hey, President Lim.
Nice to hear from you.
Your business is doing well?
You didn't answer my call earlier.
What do you mean why I called you?
I came down to Yeosu and all.
So I thought I'd give you a call.
Where?
Are they pretty?
How old are they?
Wow, jackpot!
Okay, I will be right there.
All right then.
Gosh, what should I do?
It was a friend of mine
who lives down here.
His family member just passed away.
I will have to go and pay my respects.
Just hang here.
Wow, seriously?
Men are all the same.
They are all after
young and pretty ones. Don't you agree?
The reason why my Min Ho
hasn't asked me to marry him is
not because he's too busy with work.
Isn't that because he wants
to meet a younger woman?
Maybe he's just making
an excuse with his work?
- Why are you doing this?
- You don't know how I feel.
You really have no idea how I feel.
I wonder what
Joo Yeon is doing right now.
Is she getting ready to leave work?
Or having some drinks with her coworkers?
Gosh, I really don't
want to live any longer.
Hey.
If you don't want to live,
what would you do?
Just pull yourself together
and go back to studying.
So you can have your revenge
on Joo Yeon who's left you.
What revenge?
I will just leave this world.
There is no hope for me to go on.
When you're thinking about dying
you sure want a lot of things.
Are you sure you want to die?
- What?
- When you were thinking about dying
you devoured the sashimi and stew.
And you put on a seat belt
to be safe in the car?
I agree.
He's not thinking about dying.
Why is he making us
worry and go to all this trouble?
What did you say?
Guys, do you want me to really die?
What are you talking about?
- You're just acting ridiculous.
- I agree, man.
How long are you going
to play that card on us?
Fine, you punks!
I know how ridiculous I am right now!
I was serious about ending
my life and came here.
True. When I came,
it was scarier than expected.
So I was making excuses to stall...
I must have looked
ridiculous to you guys.
I agree!
I even think I'm pathetic.
I deserve to die.
Now...
Do not try to stop me, seriously.
I will definitely end my life.
Goodbye, guys!
Goodbye, Joo Yeon!
Hey, what if he really dies like that?
Don't worry.
Help!
Go help him, will you?
- Oh man.
- Gosh.
Help!
Go help him, will you?
- Oh man.
- Gosh.
Help!
I don't want to die! I don't!
Help me!
You loser.
What do you think you're doing?
Just stand up.
I have a cramp in my legs.
I can't straighten my legs.
You're something.
Save me.
Hold me, please.
Let's get him.
I have a cramp.
I'm all wet, bastard.
We've been going out for five years now.
If I've been waiting for him this long,
he should ask me to marry him.
Why? Why has he taken this much time?
He made me want to be pregnant like this.
Why is he making me feel so pathetic?
Jin Yi, please stop drinking.
You will get really sick if you continue.
I don't care.
I can't even get pregnant.
I will just let my body get sick.
I will let it get as sick as it can.
Jin Yi, oh my, are you okay?
Did it get in your eye?
You know the dream
I had about clams last night.
Conception dream, my butt!
He's a bastard who deserves
to be eating clams crying.
Don't worry.
I know how much Min Ho loves you.
Does he really?
Do you really think so?
Of course.
When I don't have a boyfriend
are you bragging in front of me?
But because you're here comforting me
I really like that.
Anyway, premium trash is so weird.
Why? What about him?
When it comes to drinking
we should drink with others
talking about our deep thoughts
and releasing stress.
That's how it should be done.
He doesn't want to hang out with others.
What fun is it to drink alone?
I agree.
I wonder why he drinks alone.
Why am I drinking solo?
The reason why I drink solo is...
I don't have to
see something unnecessary.
Gosh, can you walk at all, Jin Yi?
I don't have to waste
my energy unnecessarily.
Hold on, Jin Yi.
You shouldn't throw up again. Here.
I don't have to spend
my money unnecessarily.
It's time for myself only.
It's my healing time.
That's why I drink solo.
Wow, is this the place
our academy got for us to stay?
We will have a room there, right?
I think so.
Hurry up. I'm freezing to death.
Good then.
You can freeze to death then.
You punk, I hate you to death.
Good then.
Since you want to die,
you can hate me to death.
- Stop it, man.
- You stop it!
If you say you want to die ever again
I will personally kill you myself.
Wait up, man.
I will make him hate me to death.
Ah, that's right.
- Aren't you hurt?
- No.
I wonder if
she's applied any ointment yet.
Jin Yi, here.
What's wrong with my life, seriously?
Jin Yi, stop being upset
and get some sleep.
I'm in no position
to comfort anyone right now.
I'm as upset as she is.
Hi, Gong Myung.
What? A question?
Can I explain it later?
I'm down in Yeosu for work.
What? You're in Yeosu too?
Here it is.
So?
You came down here with your friend
who works at the academy?
You gave up studying?
What do you mean I gave up studying?
I came to just get some air.
But here I am thinking about studying.
I came to ask you a study question too.
Fine. What is your question?
I already had a few drinks
with the other teachers.
I wanted to give you
the answer next time, if possible.
So what is the question
you were dying to ask?
Well, it's just that...
It's about Gae Mang Mae Ga that
you talked about in class last time.
What? Gae Mang Mae Ga?
It's not Gae Mang?
- Was it Pok Mang?
- It's Jae Mang Mae Ga.
When you don't even know the title,
how can you possibly have a question?
Actually...
I saw you get hurt earlier,
so I came to ask.
I came to give this to you.
Really?
Thank you.
You're touched, aren't you?
I'm the only one who cares about you.
I agree. You're the only one.
By the way, Teach
do you have a boyfriend?
I don't.
I'm too busy making a living.
- No need for a boyfriend?
- Come on.
Because you're too busy making a living
you should have a boyfriend.
Then you will have something
to look forward to in your busy life.
Come on, you give me no choice.
I should set you up with someone.
You're here. Say hi.
What? Didn't you come alone?
Hello, I'm Jin Gong Myung.
Shall we start going out from today?
You!
How dare you play
a trick on your teacher?
Do you want me to hurt you?
Come on, I wasn't playing.
You really want to get smacked or what?
I do want to get smacked.
How would you do it?
You... stop playing around.
Go back to Seoul
and get back to studying. Got it?
As I get to know her,
she's my type more and more.
What have I done today?
What a bastard premium trash is!
I'm someone's replacement?
I'm filling in for someone else?
Damn it!
He should've told me the truth.
He took me in after seeing my potential?
Bullshit!
Do you want to eat spoon worm?
Spoon worm?
That's not what I said.
Wait, if he took me in
to fill in for someone else
It's better to say straight up
that I'm filling in for someone else.
Do you want to eat octopus?
Why suddenly octopus?
That's not it.
By the way...
I feel like having octopus.
Love is a lie...
Laughter is also... a lie...
- What do you want?
- You look pathetic.
What are you doing here alone?
Have a drink with me.
No thank you, No Geu Rae.
Don't interrupt my free time.
Don't do that!
Have a drink with me, okay?
I have something to tell you!
Excuse me!
Can I have one more glass
and raw octopus?
I'm sorry.
We're all out of octopus.
Can you just have squid instead?
The squid is really good today.
Since there is no octopus
you're saying eat squid
as the replacement, right?
Fine, I will have squid.
Here is the raw squid.
Squid, I will be upfront with you.
You're not what I wanted at first.
What I wanted was octopus.
But she's out of it.
You came out as the replacement.
What are you doing right now?
What do you mean?
It needs to know the truth.
Squid, don't get all excited.
I didn't order you
thinking about your potential.
I couldn't order octopus.
I had to order you as the replacement.
If you get all excited
it will make you look pathetic
just like me.
I asked what you were doing.
Seeing the squid
come out to replace octopus
is like seeing myself.
I... heard everything.
Because the Korean teacher
on the eighth floor quit
you took me in your joint class
to fill in for her.
I'm... just like this squid.
But what did you say to me?
You said you took me in
after you saw my potential?
Why did you lie? Why?
Are you happy that you made a fool of me?
You're seriously... such a jerk.
You're just like your real name, jerk!
This lady, seriously.
If you're that bothered, then quit.
What is this?
Aren't you going to let me go?
Are you mad? I'm sorry.
I forgot my place again and acted rashly.
Whether I'm the replacement or not
I should be just honored
to get into your joint class.
I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me, No Geu Rae.
Excuse me.
This lady, seriously.
I really can't deal with her.
How can you just leave?
- You should take your girlfriend.
- What do you mean my girlfriend?
This low-quality woman is my girlfriend?
Am I crazy?
I have nothing to do with her.
Tell her to find a way home.
I have no reason to care.
Gosh, seriously...
I can't just toss her here.
What is this?
Everything about her
reeks of subpar quality.
Oh my.
Professor Jin is carrying me on his back.
No way.
Am I dreaming?
That's right. This is a dream.
I'm saying this because this is a dream.
Even if it was brief
I was happy.
After I moved to Noryangjin
I felt very insignificant.
And it was tough.
I felt like someone
was recognizing my talent.
Hearing that I had potential...
I was very happy even if it was brief.
Gosh, I'm hot. Hot!
Hot.
Gosh, I'm cold.
Give me a blanket. Blanket!
I'm saying I'm cold. Blanket.
Blanket.
I'm cold. Cold.
What was that?
She asked for it a minute ago.
I'm saying it's cold. Blanket!
Blanket!
Gosh, you No Geu Rae, seriously.
Am I a replacement?
I'm filling in for someone else?
What did she hear?
You're Professor Choi Yoon Hee
who teaches Korean, right?
Yes, this is Jin Jung Seok.
It's just that I heard you
applied to join my joint class.
I'm sorry, but you won't be
able to join us at this time.
Ah, is that right?
It's okay.
I actually couldn't join your joint
class for a personal reason.
My husband is being transferred overseas.
I am going to have to quit.
Ah, are you?
By the way, which instructor
are you thinking about working with?
She's a new instructor named Park Ha Na.
Ah, she's the one
who came from a prep school.
True.
What is she like?
Well, she has potential.
She's a good enough instructor
to join in my joint class.
I'm cold...
Blanket!
For Gong Myung.
Please.
Sleep already.
She's a woman after all.
She looks best when sleeping.
[Let's Drink]
I like drinking solo.
Since my job entails talking all day
having this time
when I don't have to is the best.
Is she perhaps the Korean teacher?
Professor.
You're mistaking me with somebody else.
Come on. You're Professor Park Ha Na.
You're my favorite student, Gong Myung.
Can I be your boyfriend
rather than your favorite student?
- Ki Bum, let's stop being friends.
- Sure.
What? Stop being friends?
Go tell Gong Myung also.
You've never had a crush
on an idol, have you?
- I had a crush on SHINee.
- Was it Minho from SHINee?
Didn't they go to school together?
- Did they really?
- Get up.
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
Go ahead.
There you go.
Use your waist.
He must be furious with me.
Gosh, this is crazy.
After finding out that
he took me in as a replacement
I can't believe that I did that.
I can't avoid him tomorrow.
Now she's trying to see how I feel.
Why did she act that way then?
I think it will be better to have
No Geu Rae next to me.
Before I told Professor Jin
that I wouldn't be able to join his class
he contacted me that Professor Park
would take over the Korean class.
To him, it's very unfair.
The boss thinks he might
have feelings for you.
Stop being so flexible
just to try and make me happy.
Be confident and say what you want.
"Be confident and say what you want!"
Does he really have feelings for me?