(Episode 8)
(Cho Gap Soo's case, Hyungjae Group)
(Cho Gap Soo)
(Kwak Young Shil, Missing since 1996)
Ma?
Ms, Min,
What is this?
It has nothing to do with you,
Yes,
it does,
That's my mom,
(Kwak Young Shil, Missing since 1996)
(Baek Sang Ho)
Baek Sang Ho?
Baek Sang Ho speaking,
I told you that I'd call you,
You should go,
Hi, You should've called first,
Did you eat?
Yes, I ate,
Is something wrong?
You look terrible,
It's nothing, I'm fine,
Mom,
About Kim Mi Jung whom we mentioned earlier,
I found her medical report earlier,
But some things were strange,
I searched the ID number on her chart,
and it was someone else,
Her name and address are all different too,
Really?
Was there anything odd,,,
when she was in the hospital?
Like what you see in the news,,,
about people who fake,,,
someone's identity and send them,,,
to a mental institution to take their money,
If Kim Mi Jung was also in such a situation,
the Kim Mi Jung that you know,,,
may not really be Kim Mi Jung,
Right?
Don't you have something to say to me?
The Hyungjae factory,
The sexual torture of female factory workers,
You've heard of it, right?
In 1986,
when Cho Gap Soo was a detective,
The sexual assault of female workers,,,
who had gone on strike,
I was the prosecutor on the case,
I dragged Cho Gap Soo to trial,,,
based on the victims' testimonies,
but we lost,,,
for insufficient evidence,
So?
What does that have to do with my mom?
The one victim from the incident,,,
who could not be located,
Seo Jung Soon died,
and the day after he was found not guilty,,,
I want to file a report,
Yes, go ahead,
It's regarding Cho Gap Soo,
I have a tape,,,
where Cho Gap Soo admits,,,
what he did 10 years ago,
Back then,
I was sure that informant was Kwak Young Shil,
But I couldn't meet her,
Instead,
I saw someone else,
Look who it is,
It's the just prosecutor,
Min Ji Sook,
Kwak Young Shil, who had the evidence,
and Cho Gap Soo,
who wanted to hide it, were at the same hospital,
Then Kwak Young Shil disappeared,
Do you think that was a coincidence?
Do you think Cho Gap Soo had nothing to do with it?
Are you saying that man abducted my mom?
It's a reasonable deduction,
So I investigated it as an abduction for a while,
but there weren't enough leads,
No way, My mom wouldn't,,,
Sexual torture?
No way,
That can't be,
My mom is a cheerful person,
I never once saw her,,,
cry, cringe, or even sigh,
And she's a crybaby,
She'd freak out about a tiny cut,
How could she,,,
Sexual torture?
If she really experienced something like that,
she couldn't have survived a single day,
(Hyungjae Factory Case File)
You check it yourself,
There must've been an error,
You remember,
The hospital computer was so old,,,
that it would break all the time,
The nurses struggled, always having to input,,,
the patients' information over and over,
It must've been inputted incorrectly back then,
And Kim Mi Jung,,,
saved your life, I owed her big,
I wouldn't be mistaken about that,
I mean it,
Believe me,
Okay,
This was on the floor,
Who is he?
A patient's guardian,
Jin Wook,
Make sure to eat,
You look like you've lost weight,
You too,
I'll see you,
(Congratulations 2016's New Prosecutors)
Let's take a look at my son,
You look great,
You were nagging before,
That was because I was upset,
You wanted to be a doctor like me at first,
- Did you prepare an oath? - Yes!
I will become courageous to fight injustice,
I will become caring to those who are weak,
I will be just and follow only the truth,
It's so corny,
Anyway, who do you take after?
Don't beat around the bush, I take after you,
I'm like a clone of you from head to toe,
That's true,
You'll do well,
I trust that you'll become a good prosecutor,,,
who reveals the truth for the victims,
(Hyungjae Factory Case File)
(Name: Kwak Young Shil)
(Complained about aching and dizziness,)
Injuries caused by contact with an external object,
uterine hemorrhage, ruptured rectum,
You have nothing to be ashamed of?
There's no reason to be ashamed,
Ma Yi Deum, play with me!
Come on, I'm reading!
Why are you always reading to become?
- A doctor, - A doctor?
Sure, a doctor, That would be nice,
You can help the sick,
You can go to remote places,,,
- and volunteer too, - Volunteer?
I'm not going to do that,
I thought you were going to become a doctor,
Yes, I'll become one and earn a lot of money,
All you talk about is money,
People will think your mom is homeless,
I'm not doing this just for myself,
I'm doing this for you,
You don't know anything,
Is that so?
- Gosh, work hard, - Stop it,,,
Let me live a luxury life thanks to you,
Mom,,,
For future Yeongpa mayor, Cho Gap Soo,
- Cheers, - Cheers,
Mr, Oh, when you stood in front of Heo,,,
and told him he'd get 10 years for the bribe,,,
along with getting disfranchised,
I felt so good,
You're flattering me,
I only told him we should do it by the law,
He should be flattering you,
It's thanks to you he got to unify everyone,
He'll be elected for sure,
Am I right, Mayor Cho?
I'll be serving you for the rest of my life,
Will I get to see such beauties all my life?
Of course!
You're just my style,
(Hyungae Law Group)
(Witch's Court)
- What? - Hey, Ahn Tae Kyoo,
Bottoms up,
Honey!
What a man! You're crazy,
You have something on you,
Is it a cut?
I'm sorry,
It's not like you got hit, Where did you get that?
I did get hit,
Really?
That's amazing,
Do someone like you get beat up too?
Are you that amazed?
It must be good to be so easily amused,
Come on, we're having fun, Don't mess it up,
Come on,
I'm just playing,
Are you done being amazed now?
Then smile a little,
Smile,
Go,
You smiled,
Happy?
Yes,
I enjoyed it so much,
- Yes, - It's nothing,
- I enjoyed it a lot, - I'm glad,
All right,
- Please invite me again, - I will,
Take care,
What's going on?
It's nothing,
Ma'am, please come down!
- Come down, - We'll help you!
What are you doing? Come down!
Be careful, it's dangerous!
She should come down,
I said, come down!
Please come down!
Cho Gap Soo! Bring Cho Gap Soo!
I,,,
I won't go down until he comes here!
Bring Cho Gap Soo!
Isn't that Prosecutor Ma Yi Deum?
What does she have to do with Cho Gap Soo?
Let's report it to the news desk first,
Call Cho Gap Soo right now!
Bring him here!
Bring Cho Gap Soo!
Cho Gap Soo!
Get down!
Please come down!
You have to get down!
Mr, Yeo,
Okay, I'll come right now,
What? Ma Yi Deum?
Yes,
I don't know what it's about,
but he's adamant about seeing you,
She'll jump if you don't show up,
She's been making a scene for two hours,
What does that have anything to do with me?
Are you telling me to pull her back in?
Sir,,,
You visited her at the hospital,
and she's even in your campaign video,
If something bad happens,
they'll draw you in,
I'm worried,
Before I go,
I should at least know what it's about,
I can't go there to have feces,,,
thrown at me,
I still think,,,
you should go,
Ms, Ma,
What is it?
Why are you putting yourself in danger?
You might get hurt,
Please come down so we can talk,
Okay,
Cho Gap Soo!
What did you do to my mom?
What did you do to Kwak Young Shil?
Ms, Ma,
Why are you,,,
asking me about your mother?
Then who should I ask?
In 1986,
you raped her during interrogation,
and in 1996,
you abducted her before she could report you,
The criminal is right in front of me,
Now that I know you're safe,
I'll be going,
What is this?
On the day my mom disappeared,
you were also at the same place,,,
my mom was,,,
last seen before she disappeared,
Is it a coincidence?
What are you trying to say,
Ms, Ma?
Isn't it spelled out for you?
That day,
my mom went to report to Ms, Min Ji Sook,
and you saw her,
You figured leaving her alone,,,
would ruin everything you did to get acquittal,
Of course you can't just watch,
That's why you kidnapped her,,,
and got rid of the evidence,
Shamelessly, you became a commissioner general,
and then a politician,
Now, you're eyeing to become a mayor!
Do you have evidence?
I'll find it soon,
Do you know why,,,
your mother disappeared?
Because she tried,,,
to reveal things,
If you don't want to turn out like her,
it'd be best to remain quiet,
Great,
This is the way you should act,
This makes me a reason to live,
I'll find the evidence soon,,,
and get a warrant to arrest you,
You can look forward to it, Cho Gap Soo,
What an exclusive,
Can she find the evidence?
Ms, Ma's mother's name is Kwak Young Shil?
Is that her mother?
We'll interview those around Cho Gap Soo first,
Where is Ms, Ma?
It's over,
She's safe, so don't worry,
I think the disappearance of Ms, Ma's mother,,,
has something to do with Cho Gap Soo,
(Cho Gap Soo Returns to Work After 12 Days,,,)
Anyway, I feel sorry about what happened,,,
to her mother,
Can you take me home?
You said you have something to say to me,,,
at the hospital, right?
I'll tell you later,
I'll give you exactly one hour,
No matter what you do, stop them!
If they mention kidnapping on the internet,
you will never set foot,,,
in Yeouido again,
Understand?
Yes,
Mr, Baek, where are you?
I told you,,,
not to let Tae Kyoo come in here,
I'm sorry, sir,
Who did he come with?
Did he come alone?
Play it,
Okay,
(Min Ho)
The number you're calling is not available,
You'll be connected to voicemail after,,,
Hand me all CCTV footages,
Check if he was caught on any other cameras,
Yes, sir,
- Hey, - This is bad,
Where did you go?
I'm sorry,
Did popping champagne for a few days,,,
make you go soft?
I heard, What should I do about that prosecutor?
I suggest having Mr, Oh pressure,,,
If we're gentlemanly, she won't get it,
If she wants to throw turd in my face,
I will,,,
throw turd in hers,
I'll look into it,
(Ms, Min)
Hello, Ms, Min,
So?
Do you feel better after causing a ruckus?
I heard from the reporters about last night,
It was a personal matter,
You don't need to make excuses,
I understand how you felt and why you did it,
I'm sure you couldn't stop thinking about your mom,,,
after talking with me,
It was obvious Cho Gap Soo would play dumb,
I'm sure you wanted to throw the reporters bait,
and find out where your mom was,
But sorry,
Some got the hidden camera videos of you,,,
from Kim Sang Gyoon's case,
They didn't upload the entire video,
but just a few screen shots,
to make you trending online,
It's obvious who's behind it,
I feel terrible,,,
about your mother too,
But Ms, Ma,
Cho Gap Soo won't be caught that easily,
You need to be rational,
You can take a few days off if you need,
No,
I'll go work,
That makes no sense,
How could you print that?
This is a violation of human rights,,,
and defamation,
- Take it down now, - Sir, Sir?
Even the president is concerned,,,
with digital sexual crimes,
How could you write an article like this?
Yes, Please delete it,
Thank you,
Thank you for your help,
Not at all,
This is all for the CAGU family,
Mr, Koo,
Yes?
What is all of this?
I was thankful and felt bad for last time,
You must miss home cooking since you live alone,
I showed off my skills a little,
- You made all of this? - Yes,
It isn't much, Please eat,
But I don't know if I deserve this,
Well,,,
Okay, Thank you, Ms, Son,
Thank you,
What should I eat first?
Are we having a feast or something?
Look how pretty the food looks,
It looks like banquet food,
I packed a lunch,
You haven't eaten yet?
I wish you could join us, but I made two servings,,,
Can we join you?
- We'd love to, - Here,
It's two servings,
I haven't had home cooking in ages,
I get home too late to even cook for myself,
- Thank you, Ms, Son, - Sure,
- Mr, Koo, Please eat, - Sure,
Ms, Seo, Eat up,
Eat up,
- You too, Ms, Son, - It's so yum,
- This is incredible, - Try this,
Kong Soo Ah is missing,
What happened?
This is her call record for yesterday and today,
The highlighted number is Eel's burner phone,
It looks like she went out after getting his call,
She couldn't have,,,
(Call, or your granny will be in danger,)
So she disappeared after the trafficking,
Yes, We couldn't find,,,
any communication thereafter,
Anywhere she could've gone?
Her grandmother and friends,,,
have no idea where she is either,
So there's no way of locating her?
That's why I called you,
There's someone she called at the end,
(Domestic call)
(Ma Yi Deum)
Yi Deum, please help me,
I'm at Hyungjae Hotel, K,,,
Bring me Cho Gap Soo!
Cho Gap Soo!
I won't go down until he comes here!
Ms, Ma,
Yi Deum, please help me,
I'm at Hyungjae Hotel, K,,,
Hyungjae Hotel?
There is no room with K in the name,
Did you check that right? Check again,
Are you sure it's our hotel?
There must be a mistake,
We tracked her cell phone, and it was Hyungjae Hotel,
I'm sorry I can't be of assistance,
Then may we check the security videos?
We need to check from 7pm to this morning,
I'm sorry,
It violates our clients' privacy,
We're looking for someone, Please,
There's nothing else I can assist you with,
- My apologies, - Look,
Something may have happened to a kid,
I'm sorry, but,,,
we have our situation as well,
Are you kidding me? What situation?
A person's life is at stake, but you won't help?
Bring a warrant,
Then we'll cooperate,
We will, so wait,
If anything is missing or destroyed,
you'll be accountable,
I'll add on your refusal to cooperate,,,
and hold you legally accountable,
Got that?
Let's go,
Do you know how important the situation is?
What?
He always gets out of any trap we set,
- I have a question, - Yes?
Last night,,,
What's that?
That's him, right? Eel!
Get over here!
Eel,
Who are you?
Darn it,
Stop chasing me,
You're dead!
I'm a prosecutor, Sorry,
Excuse me,
Manual? I can't do it,
Okay,
Wait, Hold on, Prosecutor, Sorry,
Let's take a break!
Stop, Mr, Eel!
Mr, Eel, I need to talk to you, Hold on,
You must be tired,
Mr, Koo!
Sorry, Go, Go already,
Leave,,, Leave me, Go!
You can do it! Go!
Bicycle,
Stop coming! Darn it,
Hold on,
Where's Soo Ah?
Who are you?
Where's Kong Soo Ah?
- Hold on, - Seriously,
Did you get him?
Yes,
The phone has been turned off,
Please leave,,,,
(Heo Yoon Kyung)
Did Min Ho come to work?
As you can see,
Okay,
He said he was going to the kingdom yesterday,
You should check there,
Please watch what you say,
Did you forget,,,
that the 100,000 dollars,,,
incorporated confidentiality?
Of course, I know that,
I just wondered,,,
if I could help like last time,
(Min Ho)
No,
(Uninstall)
Hey, hey, Wake up,
Hey,
Tae Kyoo,
Hey, If you were drunk, you should've gone home,
Why did you drive?
Will we,,,
be okay?
It was too dark last night,,,
It was dark,
So where did you drive my car in the dark?
You dragged me here with you too,
If there's a single scratch,
you're dead,
Hey,
Don't you,,,
remember?
- Last night, we,,, - "We"?
You and I aren't on par to be lumped together,
Don't you agree?
Just because I partied with you,
you think you're on my level,
Yes, but,,,
Last night, what you and I did,,,
What about last night?
Other than you,,,
drinking expensive drinks thanks to me, what?
What else?
Hey,
- Ahn Tae Kyoo, - Seriously,
Chicks or dudes,
Those without money are all the same,
If you're good to them,
they think they're special and get annoying,
What?
Hey, Get out,
What are you doing? Get out, you rat,
Hi, Sang Ho,
It's me,
She took off with my precious money,
That witch,
You had a sick minor,,,
do that just to make a few bucks?
"Just"?
It was one large,
And to be honest, Soo Ah was the one,,,
who got excited when I mentioned money,
- What? - That wench,,,
was blinded by greed,,,
and took off with the money,
Hold on, Isn't this,,,
embezzlement or something?
Look,
How could so much money,,,
exchange hands for a sex trafficking done via chat?
How could you trust him enough to send her there?
I sent her after making sure he checked out,
She's my ace,
I wouldn't have sent her just anywhere,
I see, You checked him out,
That means you have the client's information,
Come on,
What information do you have?
If I tell you,
what will you do for me?
You seem to be confused,
I mean,
I should gain something,,,
to give you information or something,
Look,
All of this is being recorded,
Everything you say, Your attitude,
They may be held against you later,
Are you threatening me?
You don't know how to make deals,
You should be begging me right now,
Aren't you going to find Soo Ah?
Wait,
Look, sir,
I'll drop the charge for,,,
sex trafficking of a minor,
This is being recorded, right? Clearly?
Clearly,
Finding Soo Ah is more important,
We need to save a life,
Gosh, Soo Ah, Okay,
We have to save Soo Ah,
Here,
This psycho sent me his ID,
And he said Hyungjae Hotel was his,
Doesn't it seem like there's something huge?
Okay, That was clear, Now get me out,
Clearly,
Your cell phone will be taken as evidence,
And if anything happened to Soo Ah,
I'll tack on aiding and abetting to your charges,
Shut your trap and wait,
Wait, Hold on, It was all recorded,,,
Hey!
This is why no one trusts people in law!
Don't delete this recording!
I'll check it all!
I'll check all of it!
Did you check Baek Min Ho's identity?
Yes, No sign of forgery,
and I confirmed his identity,
I texted you his current address,
Okay,
Baek Min Ho,
You're inside, right? We're prosecutors,
Baek Min Ho?
Baek Min Ho,
You're inside, right? We're prosecutors,
Baek Min Ho?
Hey,
What are you doing?
You are trespassing,
A high school girl went missing last night,
Your cooperation will be appreciated,
Missing?
You know her, right?
I don't know,
You saw her last night,
But you don't know her?
I don't think so,
(My big bro)
You chatted with her around 8pm last night,,,
and checked her photo,
Then you promised to meet an hour later,
I said I don't know,
What about this?
You even sent your ID via chat,
How could you not know?
You met Kong Soo Ah, didn't you?
Why don't you take that?
Did you find her?
Not yet,
Min Ho,
Do you remember anything other than,,,
that it was in the woods?
Hey, Prosecutors,,,
are here right now,
You must find her first,
No matter what,
What?
(Danger: Fall Risk)
Where were you between 8pm and 2am last night,
and what were you doing?
I was at my law office,
You were working until that late?
Yes, I focus better when it's quiet,
You can go and check what time I left,
Which law firm?
Hyungjae in Gangnam,
Happy now?
Goodbye,
I said to leave,
Yes, I focus better when it's quiet,
Hyungjae in Gangnam,
Cho Gap Soo!
Bring me Cho Gap Soo!
Bring Cho Gap Soo!
Hyungjae's office was quite?
Although I created that ruckus last night?
- Yes? - We found Kong Soo Ah,
This was found next to her body,
(Baek Min Ho)
Gap Soo,
Please,,,
save Min Ho,
(Witch's Court)