(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
A burn... A burn scar?
She should have a clear burn scar on her right shoulder.
I spilled water on her by mistake while making formula...
and gave her a burn scar.
Then Yuh Ri...
What's wrong? Joo Ho.
Did you recall something?
Do you remember something about my daughter?
Yul Mae. What are you doing here?
Yul Mae. Why are you here during your time off?
- Let's talk outside. - Hae Joo.
Don't cut me off.
Yul Mae.
You said you had something to confess about the design leak?
The thing is...
Yul Mae. Don't hesitate. Please tell the truth.
We need your testimony.
How did our team's design...
end up in the marketplace?
I'm sorry.
Ms. Koo Hae Joo made me do it, so I had no choice.
I copied our team's design and gave it to her.
I'm sorry, Mr. Chairman.
Hae Joo threatened to divorce Moo Yul if I didn't do it.
I couldn't have my brother get divorced because of me.
What are you talking about?
When did you give me the design?
Is everything you said true?
If you are lying,
you will be held accountable.
Yes, it's true.
It's not fair, Mr. Chairman.
Please don't fire me.
And Hae Joo, please don't divorce Moo Yul.
Stop lying!
Dad.
These jerks put her up to it.
They made her lie and frame me.
That's enough.
Stop resisting,
and ask for forgiveness.
Hey, Yuh Ri.
How dare you do this to me?
Uncle. Do you want the company that badly?
Tell me, Yul Mae.
Who made you say this?
These people made you say that, didn't they?
Stop it, Hae Joo!
If it weren't Do Chi and Yuh Ri,
was it my mom?
Did she tell you to say I was behind it, when she did everything?
That's not true.
I haven't even met Ms. Hong recently.
Mom was responsible for the design leak all by herself.
I didn't know anything.
Believe me.
How could Ji Won have gotten the design?
It would've been impossible without your help.
How would I know?
My mom does anything it takes, if there's something she wants.
Hae Joo! Shut your mouth.
If you insist you're innocent,
call your mom.
Let's have everyone gathered here.
Joo Ho. What do you remember?
Why did you ask about my missing child's burn scar?
No. It can't be.
Yuh Ri can't be Ji Won's daughter.
Joo Ho. Anything is fine.
Tell me anything you remember, no matter how small.
I must find my daughter.
My poor daughter...
who almost froze to death on the hard, cold ground.
I need to find my daughter.
Ji...
Ji Won.
- Hello? - Come to my office now.
What is it?
I need to ask you something Come right now.
Okay. I'm coming.
Joo Ho. Stay here for a bit.
I need to go to the office.
Don't go anywhere. You have to stay here, okay?
This...
is Yuh Ri's baby picture.
Then...
(Love Orphanage)
Yuh Ri...
Ji Won. Yuh Ri is your daughter.
The one you abandoned at Love Orphanage.
The daughter you think is dead!
That's right. I was in the accident while going to Ji Won...
to tell her about Yuh Ri.
(100 Days)
Yuh Ri really was...
Ji Won's daughter.
Ji Won.
Did something happen?
The chairman asked me to come in.
Hae Joo is in a very bad position.
Yuh Ri brought proof that Hae Joo...
asked you to leak their design.
- So? - Hae Joo is denying it.
She said you did it on your own.
That's why...
Father called you here to talk to you and her together.
Yuh Ri.
How dare you try to hold Hae Joo back?
Okay. Leave it to me.
Ji Won.
- Ji Won! Ji Won. - Mr. Son.
Moo Yul.
Get me Ji Won.
Ji Won.
Sit here.
What is it?
Why did you call me here?
Ji Won.
Tell the complete truth.
Hae Joo asked you...
to leak our team's design, didn't she?
Tell me.
Is it true that Hae Joo had you do it?
Because she had to win?
Did she steal Do Chi's team's design and ask you...
to flood the market with it?
Hae Joo.
This is my chance.
I have to win Hae Joo over.
Well...
- The truth is... - What do you mean?
Hae Joo asked me to do it?
She had nothing to do with it.
Hae Joo never even mentioned your design to me.
She was busy all the time working on her own design.
Seeing her,
as a parent, I wanted to make sure she won.
That's why I stole Yuh Ri's design.
Stop lying.
You don't even work here.
How did you get our design?
Yul Mae, who gave Hae Joo the design,
testified that she did it.
I went to Yul Mae...
and made her steal your design.
So why did she say it was Hae Joo?
Did you put her up to it?
Did you make her lie?
- Ji Won! - Hey!
Ji Won.
I need to see Ji Won.
Why do you want to see her?
But...
what is that?
Ji Won's lost...
Never mind.
Ji Won should be here.
I lost my cell phone.
So please get her for me. It's urgent.
She just got here and left...
with Hae Joo's father.
She isn't here right now.
Then call her for me.
Tell her I have something urgent to tell her.
Tell her it's about her lost daughter.
It seems like she isn't picking up.
She must have gone somewhere far.
Really?
Darn it. I have no choice.
I'll have to wait until I can reach her.
Okay.
I'll go then.
The picture he was holding...
looked like Yuh Ri's baby picture.
Did he get his memory back?
Fine.
If you insist on lying, we have no choice.
Ji Won.
We'll press charges against you for leaking our design.
What? You'll press charges?
Yes.
We have to get to the bottom of this in court.
Uncle. Yuh Ri.
You're blinded by your greed to take over the company.
Will you sue your own family for it?
Do you want to make a mockery of our family?
Do you think that will scare me...
into backing off?
Not a chance!
Fine. Let's go to court.
I'll prove Hae Joo's innocence.
Stop it, all of you!
Unless you want to tell the world of our family's sordid problems,
calm down.
First, I'm canceling Do Chi's reassignment...
and Yuh Ri's termination.
The successorship decision...
- is also canceled. - Dad!
I stole the design by myself.
Why is Hae Joo being punished for it?
You said so yourself,
that you'll give the company to the winner of this contest.
Make it clear that Hae Joo...
will take over Wid Group!
Stop it, Ji Won!
We can't let you...
decide who will succeed the chairman like this.
Enough! Everyone get out.
Go back to your offices!
Ji Won.
How long do you think you can protect Hae Joo as your daughter?
We'll be watching.
Act like an adult. Please.
Hiding behind your mother's back and doing evil deeds.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Thanks Mom.
I didn't know you would stay by my side.
I told you.
I'm always on your side.
I'm sorry...
for hurting your feelings.
I don't care what happens to me as long as you're okay.
As long as my Hae Joo is happy and successful,
that's good enough for me.
I'll talk to Dad...
to let you move back home.
Okay. Thanks.
Don't worry. As long as I'm around,
I'll protect you all the way.
I'll make sure Yuh Ri won't drag you down.
Fine. Strangle your own daughter...
with your very own hands.
So cruel, that she can't even breathe.
Even still, I will never forgive you.
They say one mistake is more of an experience.
You repented and confessed,
so it'll be fine.
What are you babbling about?
Are you judging me?
She's stupid, but it's okay because she's pretty.
Yuh Ri.
Am I fired now?
Mr. Koo. Will you fire me?
Will I be unemployed again?
Go home for now.
You're still on vacation.
Thanks for having the courage to come.
Mr. Koo will do all he can,
to prevent your termination.
Really?
You mean it? Will you really, sir?
Mr. Koo is a man of his words.
You can trust him.
- What is he saying now? - Let's go.
Ji Won...
really loves her daughter.
It's like an obsession.
Protecting and covering up a child's wrongdoings...
isn't true motherly love.
It's sad.
Did that child...
have a unique mark or anything on her body?
- Like a birthmark, or... - A scar.
She had a burn scar.
A burn... A burn scar?
Joo Ho...
definitely remembered something about my lost child.
(Hong Ji Won)
Why isn't he picking up?
I have to see him...
while he still remembers.
How did it go?
Did you tell them the truth?
You told them that Hae Joo made you do it, right?
What choice did I have?
It shows on my face if I lie.
Good. Good job.
You can't live with that on your conscience.
It's better to take your punishment sooner than later.
Actually. Here.
Drink this.
If you're going to punished more,
you'll need your energy. Here.
Drink.
- Mom! - Drink more. Good.
Welcome home.
What are you doing here?
It's been 30 years, but my home is still the same.
What's wrong with me from coming here?
You must be hungry. Let's eat.
Why aren't you coming? The food is getting cold.
Sit down.
I made some American food. I hope you like it.
What are you doing?
What right do you have to touch our kitchen?
Be considerate of the person who cooked and sit.
Don't embarrass me in front of the kids.
Don't get any ideas. You aren't our family.
You and I split up over 30 years ago.
Yes, you and I may not be family,
but I'm still Hae Joo's mom.
She accepted me as her mom.
That gives me the right to at least touch the kitchen.
Anyway, the position as your wife is vacant right now.
You're going to divorce Ji Won too.
Mee Hee!
That's enough, Dad.
Regardless, she gave birth to me.
And she came back for me.
What happened to this family?
I don't know how to face my father after I die.
Thank you.
What will happen now?
Is she living with us?
That's fine too.
Good. Your dad is in a bad mood,
so I'll go for now.
I'll move in another day.
That's right. I'll go to the office tomorrow.
I need to discuss something with you.
Discuss? What do you need to discuss with me?
I will be giving you wings.
To my daughter, Hae Joo,
as your mom and a designer.
Welcome home, Mommy and Great-uncle.
Hi, Bom.
Did you have a good day?
Were you watching TV? Did you finish your homework?
I had way too much homework today.
But I finished. So I'm playing.
Pat me on the bottom.
My good girl. You're the best.
I should spend a lot of time with you tonight.
My schoolbag. I didn't pack my schoolbag yet.
- You're home. - Yes. We're back.
How did it go at the office?
We exposed Hae Joo for the design leak.
She insisted it wasn't her,
and Ji Won took the blame for everything.
But we don't believe them.
I got another chance to win successorship.
But is Father not home?
No. He went out in the afternoon but hasn't come home yet.
Actually, he said something odd before he left.
Something odd?
That he thinks he'll remember something important very soon.
That's what he said.
He'll remember something important?
I'll check the area for him.
Okay.
Why isn't Ji Won coming home?
Yuh Ri will be worried.
I'm sorry, but may I borrow a pen and some paper?
Sure. Here you are.
Thank you.
Call me.
I remember who your daughter is.
Joo Ho.
The person you have reached is unavailable.
Why can't I reach Joo Ho?
I have to talk to him while he remembers.
Forget this.
Why does that hyena...
keep crawling back here?
Who is it?
Joo Ho!
Has she lost her mind?
She needs a salt shower for sure.
Wait.
Where's Joo Hoo?
Joo Ho!
Why are you looking for my father?
- What are you trying to do to him? - Move.
Joo Ho. Joo Ho!
- Joo Ho. - What do you think you're doing?
Where's Joo Ho?
Why are you looking for my father?
I need to see him right away.
I have something to ask him.
Not only is he not here, but even if he were,
I wouldn't let you see him.
Get out before I call the police!
Your father knows about my daughter.
He got his memory back!
- He got his memory back? - That's right!
Your father came to me.
He remembered that my child...
had a scar and came to see me.
I have to see him right away...
before he forgets again!
After all you did to torment us,
you're begging my father to help you find your child?
Find your daughter on your own.
Leave my father alone.
And get out of here.
If you barge in here again,
I'll press charges for trespassing.
The person you have reached...
Where can I find Joo Ho?
Why won't he answer his phone?
Where did you go?
Do you know how worried the family was?
I was looking in the area for you too.
Sorry. Let's go in.
Don't tell my father that Ji Won was here.
It'll stress him out, rather than help him get his memory back.
Of course I won't.
Father.
Where were you?
We were worried because we couldn't reach you.
He left his phone somewhere.
Gosh.
Were you worried? Sorry.
I haven't been myself all day.
Is something wrong?
No.
It's nothing.
Excuse me. I'm going to bed first.
Sure.
My daughter.
Where are you?
Ji Won.
Help me pick out a tie.
Ji Won. Ji...
She isn't here anymore.
Come in.
What is this?
It's what the madam prepared for you every morning.
She made me promise not to forget it.
What do you plan to do now?
Will you really kick Mother out of this house...
and let your birth mother in?
That wouldn't be enough.
I have a plan.
You can't keep anything from me.
That's the only way I can help.
Mr. Son's visit to the office yesterday really bothers me.
Mr. Son came to the office?
He was looking for Mother while you were in the chairman's office.
He had a picture of her with a baby,
and I think it was Yuh Ri.
A picture?
Do you see this?
- What is that? - Give that back!
It's a picture of the real daughter of that woman whom you call "Mom."
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
You're right.
That's Yuh Ri's baby picture.
If he saw it,
he must know it was her.
If he was looking for Mom after seeing that...
No. We can't let them meet.
Did she not see my note?
If she had,
she would've come here or at least contacted me...
through someone else.
Grandpa.
Bom.
Didn't you go to school today?
It's our school's anniversary.
It is?
Bom.
Do you have your grandma's phone number?
I lost my phone,
so I don't have her number.
Mokdong Grandma?
No. Ga Ya's grandma.
- I'm scared of her. - What?
Why are you scared of her?
You don't have to be scared of her.
She's your real grandmother.
What?
Once she finds out...
that you are her one and only real grandchild,
she'll love you a lot from now on.
I'll explain later.
So do you have her number?
I do. Just a minute.
Although the design launch failed because of what happened,
since the chairman pushed off deciding his successor,
I'm sure that he will give another mission soon.
Excluding the items we worked on with Angela Choi,
we have designs that we developed solely on our own,
so let's start over with those.
- Hello, Father. - Hi, Yuh Ri.
I have good news.
Good news?
Oh Ki Sup requested a visit.
He wants to meet with us.
I'll head there first. Meet me there right away.
Okay. I'll leave now.
What is it?
Oh Ki Sup requests for a visit. He wants to see us.
He must have had a change of heart.
Why is this here?
So this was why I couldn't reach Joo Ho yesterday.
Seriously. Oh no.
Oh no.
Mom.
Hae Joo. What brings you here?
It's nothing much.
I thought it over,
and I felt bad kicking you out like that yesterday.
I wanted to talk over some tea.
- Is that okay? - Really?
I was just about to step out.
Do you want to wait here? Let me change first.
Call me.
I remember who your daughter is.
Joo Ho.
I left a note and a voicemail about Yuh Ri.
Why won't she call?
Did she not get them?
He got his memory back.
I can't let them meet each other.
- Is someone here? - What?
I think someone's just pulling a prank.
It's okay. I'll go out and check.
Hae... Hae Joo.
- What are you doing here? - Where's your mom?
I have something to tell your mom. It's urgent.
I have something to tell you too.
Talk to me first.
If it isn't urgent,
let's talk after I talk to...
It's urgent too.
It's about my mom's daughter.
Her real daughter.
What?
You are going to sue Ji won, right?
She broke her promise to get me out.
So I can't sit back and do nothing.
I'll confess everything she did...
to Son Joo Ho.
What a relief...
to see Oh Ki Sup change his mind.
It is.
Now that he's completely on our side,
Ji Won won't be able to worm her way out.
It turns out that she is living with Hae Joo after moving out.
Let's go.
I wonder what that brazen woman will say.
What is it?
What do you plan to tell my mom?
Do you plan to tell her that Yuh Ri is her real daughter?
Hae Joo.
You knew?
Don't tell her.
What's the point now? What's the use?
They were strangers to each other for over 30 years.
They've been sworn enemies.
Why does it matter now that they're mother and child?
That's why she must know.
We have to sweep away all the hatred...
that is between them.
- They're blood. - Mr. Son.
I need to stop them from hurting each other any further.
- They need to know. - No.
Let them live in ignorance as they have been.
Just tell Yuh Ri...
to move to another country with Uncle Do Chi and Bom.
If they don't see each other, they won't be able to fight anymore.
Mr. Son.
Please help me.
You know how important my mom is to me.
I don't want to lose my mom to Yuh Ri.
Hae Joo.
Hae Joo?
Where did she go?
A voicemail?
Who is it from?
Ji Won, it's me.
I remember everything about your daughter.
Look.
Do you know what this is?
I'm pressing charges against you for faking my father's death,
abduction, and false imprisonment.
Oh Ki Sup agreed to testify in court...
to everything you did.
You can't get out of it this time.
You...
are finished now.
Please, I'm begging you. Don't tell her.
I don't mean forever. Just not now.
Please wait. Give me some time.
No.
I can't do that.
I have no right to keep them apart.
They've been apart for 30 years. That's already too long.
I can't delay any longer.
I asked and pleaded with you,
- but you'll tell my mom? - Ji Won...
didn't know Yuh Ri was her daughter...
and did all sorts of terrible things to her.
I must stop it before she does anything worse.
She must get on her knees...
and beg Yuh Ri for forgiveness before it is too late.
That's what's best for Ji Won.
No! You can't go.
You can't go to my mom!
- Hae Joo. - No!
For their entire lives,
they must never know that they are mother and child.
That's...
my revenge for my dead son.