Subtitles by KBS World
Okay. I'm hanging up.
Oh, why wasn't she more careful?
Dongok got into an accident and got hurt.
But one of the singers at the club didn't show,
so I have to cover for him.
Can you drop by and check on them?
Why don't you go?
If mom finds out, she'll lose it,
so don't let her find out.
Are you hurt anywhere else?
If you feel any pain later on...
Come in!
Who... Are you?
I'm Ms. Kang Dongok's guardian.
She was wearing a helmet,
so she didn't get seriously hurt.
I ran a few basic tests,
but there are only superficial wounds.
Okay, thank you.
But the driver wasn't wearing a helmet,
so she should go to a bigger hospital...
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
So what happened?
That's crazy. I knew he'd do something,
but I didn't know he'd go so low.
I mean, how could a person do...
Hold on, hold on.
The treatment is finished,
so you can take her home.
Okay, so tell me. Yeah?
Man! How could that be?
Dongok.
Kang Dongok.
Dongok...
It's me, Dongseok.
I know.
Are you okay?
Should we go to a bigger hospital?
I'm sorry.
For what?
For everything.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry, Dongseok.
There's nothing to be sorry for.
So don't say you're sorry.
I'm sorry, Dongseok.
If you say you're sorry one more time!
I'm going to get really mad!
Uh, okay. I won't say that.
It's my fault. I'm sorry, Dongseok.
Excuse me, but I need you to come with me.
If you want to die, do it alone!
Why would you take my sister
along for the ride?
Come out right now!
You better come out!
I can't come out!
If I do, you'll kill me! I'm not crazy!
Oh, your mouth seems to be working fine,
so you must be okay!
Get out of there!
No! I'm never coming out!
You...
Come out on the count of 3
or I'll break this door down!
1, 2, 3!
Kang Donghui.
What do you want?
Dongok's asking for you.
You should go.
Cha Haewon! Come out right now!
Get out, Donghui.
Mind your own business and get lost!
I said open the door!
Get out.
You get lost!
Get out!
Donghui.
Dongseok...
Are you... Fighting?
Don't fight, Dongseok.
Don't fight, Donghui.
Don't fight...
Donghui.
We're not fighting. We weren't fighting.
We were just kidding around. Honest.
- Honest?
- Yes, honest.
Let's get out of here.
I'll tell you why we were
kidding around like that.
Let's go.
Haewon, come out here.
I heard you got hurt.
Come on.
Cha Haewon!
Is Dongok okay?
I'm sorry
for letting Dongok get hurt.
What are you doing? Let me go!
What are you doing?
Let go of me.
Huh? Let go!
- What are you doing?
- Just get in!
What are you doing? Where are we going?
To a bigger hospital.
Yellow's "baby seed"
runs to Red's "baby house"
and becomes one with Red's "baby seed."
What does this mean?
Who's Yellow and who's Red?
Were you sleeping during the documentary?
Yellow is dad, and Red is mom.
Dad's seed meets mom's seed
and they become a baby.
Oh, why is it so complicated?
I'm not doing my homework.
What's really weird isn't that.
Mom!
Hey.
Are you doing your homework?
Eat this while you do it.
Yes!
Mom, may I ask you a question?
Of course! What's your question?
When you had us, you were 56 years old?
Yes, I was.
You weren't going through menopause?
The book said women
go through it in their 50s.
Menopause? What's that?
Is that food?
You don't need to know that.
I'll explain it to you when you're older.
Oh! I forgot!
I left the kettle on the stove!
Eat this up and go to bed.
Wasn't that a bit odd?
Something's fishy, don't you think?
Whoa! You nose works so well!
How did you know I farted?
It didn't even make any sound.
Soshim, what's wrong?
Did something happen again?
I thought they were little babies,
but they're all grown up.
Who? Dongwon and Dongju?
Yes.
They asked how old I was when I had them
and asked about my menopause.
Kids these days know everything.
Wow! Dongju's a real sharp one!
Her favorite TV show is "Ask Anything."
Just wait. Soon, she'll uncover
who her real mother is.
I know!
We can't hide the truth forever.
They'll find out that Donghui isn't
their brother but their father.
How long should I keep this a secret?
Why didn't you put Donghui
as their father on their birth certificates?
Because I didn't want to ruin my son's future.
If anyone knew they were Donghui's kids,
who would ever want to marry him?
He said he wanted his name on the birth
certificates, but I locked him up in his room
and went to get their birth certificates.
You were so considerate...
You're such a thoughtful person!
I could never do something like that.
Wait, I told Donghui to apologize to grandpa,
so where is he?
I'm not too heavy?
You're not heavy.
I could carry 10 of you on my back.
We could've taken your motorcycle.
You want to get on a motorcycle after
being hurt on one?
No, not really.
I can bring my motorcycle home tomorrow.
I like giving you a piggy back ride.
Haewon...
She got hurt because of me.
We were on the scooter,
and I dropped my bag,
so I got up to pick it up.
That's how we got hurt.
She should've driven better.
Haewon gave me the head thing,
so she got hurt much more than I did.
She deserves it!
Why?
She's rude and mean.
Haewon is nice.
No, she's not.
She is.
You don't know what you're talking about.
Dongseok is nice, too.
By that standard, serial killers are nice, too.
Dongseok is nice, and Haewon is nice, too.
By those standards, witches are nice,
the Grim Reaper's nice,
and Hitler is nice, too!
What?
Let me down!
I don't want to talk to you.
This is crazy.
Fine, fine.
I'm sorry.
Dongseok is nice, Haewon is nice,
everybody and anybody's nice.
Happy?
Promise me you won't
fight with Dongseok anymore.
I won't, I won't.
Are we good?
We're good.
Get on my back.
Dongok?
Yeah?
You...
Yes?
You don't hate Dongseok?
I don't.
That must be nice.
Not hating Dongseok.
It is nice.
I can call you a cab, if you want.
You know how expensive that would be?
Please take me home.
I can do it myself.
This is because
I'm in so much pain, exhausted,
and sleepy,
and I didn't want to die just yet,
so I did everything you wanted to do.
But don't rub it in.
What if I want to?
Text me your account number,
and I'll wire you the money you spent on me.
Okay.
What's your number?
I'll need it to text you my account number.
I'll just give it to Donghui.
You think he'd give it to me?
Then I'll give it to Dongok.
You don't want me to know your number?
Is she hurt seriously?
No, just a bit.
Shh, be quiet.
We can't let mom find out.
I know.
She asked me where Dongok went,
and I told her she was with Haewon.
I told her I'd open the door for her
and that she could go to bed.
You're so smart! Who do you take after?
Dongseok!
Where do you live? Which way is it?
My name is Cha Haewon.
My dream is marrying you, Dongseok.
I've made my decision, so you should...
My dream is to grow up quickly
and leave this town.
So I won't see idiots like you ever again.
I won't give up on you.
I'll make you fall in love with me.
I'm serious. I can do it.
How are you feeling? Are you okay?
What happened?
I didn't want to wake you.
And I didn't know where you live.
Where do you live?
This is your home?
No, my office.
I'll send you the money.
Seunghun.
What the heck!
Where were you last night?
Do you know how many times I called you?
My phone got smashed.
Who's in that car?
Who were you with last night?
What were you two doing all night?
Can't you tell from her face?
Haewon's hurt.
Who are you?
Me?
Kang Dongseok.
You're Oh Seunghun, right?
I'm going upstairs.
I remember you.
Don't you remember me?
Of course I do.
My grades weren't as good as yours,
but I'm still smarter than you.
Haewon was in a scooter accident.
She may have delayed symptoms from
the accident, so if that happens,
take her to see a doctor.
Were you with Haewon all night?
I'm sure her treatment didn't last all night,
so what were you doing?
Why should I tell you what we were doing?
Tell me! I have a right to know!
Haewon is my girlfriend!
Then ask her yourself.
See you around, Seunghun.
He thinks he's so special!
Cha Haewon! You stay right there!
What did you do with him all night?
I slept.
What? You slept?
I got a shot, and I slept in his car.
That's the best excuse you've got?
Give me the details.
What did you do in the car with him?
Seunghun, I'm in a lot of pain right now.
You're in pain? I'm in pain, too!
Stop pretending to be in pain and talk.
Didn't you say you were in love with me?
So what were you two doing together?
Don't close your eyes!
You feel too guilty to face me?
Open your eyes and tell me what you did!
Seunghun, are you going to marry me?
Whoa, why are you bringing that up?
About last night with Kang Dongseok...
Seunghun, if you're going to marry me,
I'll tell you what I did with Kang Dongseok
for each hour I was with him.
I'm going home to change.
Hey! Hey!
Whoa! My neck's stiff!
I already have someone in mind.
Oh?
Oh, right, right.
Your boss, Oh Seunghun?
I heard you've been chasing after him.
It's not like that.
He's interested in me, too,
but he's playing hard to get.
Dongseok said something came up last night.
But he's coming home tonight,
so just hold on, father.
You told me that 3 times already.
I did?
I've been absent-minded lately,
so I repeat things over and over.
Maybe you should get examined for dementia.
Don't worry.
I won't get that. I must stay healthy
to take care of you.
I won't cause you any pain from now on,
so please don't get sick, Soshim.
If something happens to you, I'll just die.
Okay, I'll never ever get sick.
Have some water, father.
What's Donghui doing?
Did you kill my precious grandson?
Donghui.
Huh? What? Are you in pain?
No, I'm not.
Why are you sleeping here?
In case I needed to take you to the hospital.
Are you really okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Tell mom you tripped on the stairs.
If you tell her the truth, she'll pass out.
Okay.
Get up. You need to go to school.
Kang Dongju! Hey.
Whatever. Keep sleeping.
Sleeping's more important than school.
You didn't go home last night?
No. Something came up.
Can I see where Mr. Han's accident occurred?
Right now?
Yes, right now.
I can take you there,
but did you know they wanted to cover it up?
Mr. Han was really stressed out about it.
If you're worried about me,
I appreciate the thought.
If you're trying to get in my way...
Now that you say they wanted to cover it up,
I'm even more intrigued.
Does that make me crazy?
This was where the accident occurred?
But this isn't an accident-prone location.
Mr. Han's a careful driver, and since it was
nighttime, I'm sure he was even more careful.
He tried to avoid a car coming
from the opposite direction?
Where does this road lead to?
Is there a lot of traffic at night?
It's a shortcut to the expressway,
but at that hour, there's hardly any traffic.
Only the locals take this road.
You said there was no black box in the car?
Right. Mr. Han had one installed in his car,
but it was gone.
Are you sure it was gone?
I was the one who got it installed for him.
Who's this Bae Taejin guy he was meeting?
He runs 12 massage parlors in this area.
He called Mr. Han that night.
Mr. Han was on his way to see him.
You said Mr. Bae's body was found
1km away from here?
Yes, a bit less than 1km.
2 men who were supposed to meet each
other got into accidents 20 minutes apart.
1 died and the other was seriously injured,
but both were deemed as accidents.
It's certain, then.
Huh? What is?
Let's throw out all previous records,
and start this investigation from scratch.
Okay. I got it.
Keep a close eye on that rookie prosecutor
and find out what he's up to.
Father!
Okay. I'll talk to you later.
You!
What have you been up to lately? Huh?
Uh, I'm not really up to anything.
I've been working hard, meeting customers.
Father!
Some girl called me.
She said she's carrying your child,
and asked what she should do.
Who?
Who would dare to do that?
Did she say her name was Yeongsuk?
Or Yunjeong?
You bastard!
I'm sorry, father!
You...
When you do something,
you have to learn to take responsibility!
How can you let her call me!
Am I your secretary?
I'm sorry, father! Please don't kill me!
So...
Is Haewon still chasing you around?
Yes.
Is she out of her mind?
How could she fall for a man like you?
She has to be nuts!
Man!
Hello? Haewon!
Cha Haewon! My baby girl!
It's your father.
Why won't you call home?
Your mom's been pouting about it.
It's raining here.
It's been pouring since afternoon.
The rain made me miss you even more,
so I had some rice wine.
My baby girl, Haewon.
I know studying abroad is hard,
but can't you come home to see me?
Why did you ask to see me?
Haewon, I'll call you again.
Did you do this?
Is this all your doing, Oh Chisu?
Oh, look at you!
What happened to your face?
Who did you beat up this time?
You wouldn't know even if I told you.
How embarrassing.
I'm so ashamed of you!
If your dad saw you like this from heaven,
he'd try to come back to punish you!
What's that?
Good or bad, you're still my daughter,
so I brought these for you,
but I shouldn't give them to you.
I can't give them to a girl who gets into
fights all over town.
Go drink some tap water instead.
I'm giving this to your sister.
You can't just give them to someone else!
What's 3 times 8?
3 times 8? Why?
The multiplication table. 3 times 8.
You don't know that?
I'm trying to test you.
Haeju says
the shock of your father's death
has driven you a bit mad.
I haven't gone mad.
3 times 8 is 21! Right?
Haeju, are you still sleeping?
Cha Haeju, wake up!
Oh, leave her alone. Don't wake her up.
She needs her beauty sleep.
My Haeju,
have nice dreams and sleep tight.
You're my only hope now.
Sleep well and get more beautiful,
and find a rich man to marry,
and rescue me from this hell, Haeju.
My princess.
My darling girl.
Mom! Did you buy this with my credit card?
So what are you going to do about that?
What are you going to do?
If you keep messing with me,
I'll kill you, Cha Haewon!
Cha Haewon, you!
Donghui...
Let me go, let me go.
Why do you talk so violently
even in your dreams?
Your real life is violent enough.
You should at least have sweet dreams.
Why are you in my room, old woman?
Your mom sent me.
What does she want?
Go to your grandfather
and apologize and promise
never to yell at him again.
Or else she's going on a hunger strike.
Your mom hasn't eaten since last night.
If something happens to her, I'll kill you.
I'll rip you to shreds!
You're getting old, so don't push yourself.
Trying to teach him a lesson might kill you.
I know your hunger strikes have
worked in the past for Donghui many times.
You stopped him from moving in with Sohui,
his kindergarten sweetheart.
You stopped him when he demanded you to
let him marry his middle school teacher.
And when he was in high school,
he fell in love with actress Lee Yeongae,
and he wanted to quit school
to become her body guard.
Your hunger strikes did work all those times.
But Donghui's an adult now,
and you're much older.
And I think this is getting kind of old.
Uncle's right, mom.
You can't threaten me into apologizing!
This isn't a threat!
Your mom hasn't eaten since last night.
She's going to starve herself to her grave!
Still, I'm not apologizing.
Fine. Don't apologize.
You wouldn't mean it anyway.
So don't ever apologize.
Don't.
Oh, Soshim!
Mom!
What's wrong with me, Ssangho?
Soshim! Keeping this up will kill you!
Who cares?
Just let me die.
I should be struck by lightning
for having a good-for-nothing son like him,
so it'd be better off if I starved to death.
At least I'd die being skinny.
That's a cheap shot, grandpa.
Cheap shot?
You're a man and older than I am.
Yet you used your daughter-in-law to
make me apologize to you.
Don't lecture me, boy!
Soshim! Donghui's trying to lecture me!
Grandpa!
Soshim!
Donghui's yelling at me now!
When did I yell at you?
Soshim! Donghui's trying to hit me!
I'm sorry. You're really something...
What did you say? I can't hear you.
I said I'm sorry.
I'm old and going deaf. I can't hear.
I said I'm sorry, so you can beat me up!
Why would I beat my precious grandson up?
Oh, my precious boy, have a candy.
Fine.
Say, "Ready, action."
Ready.
Action!
Dongsu, despite how things turned out,
I've never blamed you once.
If you were me, you wouldn't have, either.
We do what we're told.
We do what we're told, right?
Did someone tell you to kill me?
What's he saying?
Hello.
Your timing is unbelievable.
I was about to say
"You go... To Hawaii."
Did you get some practice?
Why are you teaching Haeju Chinese?
I'm not making enough money working for you.
I've been taking care of her since last week.
You stay out of this.
I need to talk to him about going to China.
But Haeju,
are you sure you studied?
Of course!
Introduce yourself in Chinese.
That's a piece of cake.
"I love you."
No? Then...
"Did you eat?"
You think you can work in China?
You can't even speak the language.
I can memorize all these in 10 minutes.
You're funny.
I know how you did in school.
Why don't you fix that accent of yours?
Hey, Cha Haeju!
Yes, director.
Oh, hello.
Director?
What director? From where?
Do you have to do this?
Yes!
There's only 1 spot open on the home shopping
channel, so Haeju can take this one.
And when something else comes along,
Dongtak, you can take it.
Shut up!
Okay, then.
Who makes it look more delicious?
Auditions for eating blue crabs in soy sauce!
Let's do this.
Start!
You've stolen my heart!
My love, blue crabs in soy sauce!
Since you're all so handsome,
the soju's on the house.
So please come again.
Goodbye.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Promise me you'll be back!
Thank you.
Some of the onions I delivered were rotten?
Not all of them, just a couple.
Even so, I'll exchange them for you.
I'm sorry.
I'll bring you another sack tomorrow.
Oh, she stinks!
Doesn't she take showers?
That stain on her jacket's a month old.
How gross!
She's too busy working.
Ssangho, when a man is a neat-freak,
women don't like it.
That's why you're still single.
I'd rather be single for the rest of my life
than marry a woman like her.
I'm sure she has a boyfriend.
You shouldn't be so mean.
If there's a man who says he likes her,
I'd pull all my hair out and give it to him.
Okay?
Didn't you miss me?
I did.
Let me see...
Look at your hand!
Oh, right!
I ordered this for you.
What's this?
You don't look so well these days,
and you've lost weight.
That's because I'm old and I drink a lot.
So have this and get healthy.
It's okay. You drink it.
Just seeing your face makes me feel alive.
You're my red ginseng.
This is a gift. Take it.
Man!
Men are supposed to give gifts.
Women are supposed to give love.
Ssangshik!
I want to stay longer,
but the principal might want me.
Oh, you should go.
Come here.
Drive carefully and don't get sick!
Don't go showing off your strength.
Remember, you are a lady. Got it?
Got it.
See you later.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
- Yes! Goodbye.
Mul! Dongju!
Shouldn't you be going home?
We're going to the nurse's office
to get our friend.
A friend? Who?
Iseul.
Dongwon's ex-girlfriend.
Uncle Dongwon was two-timing?
He was seeing you and Shin Minji, too?
Aunt Dongju, did you know about this?
Yes...
And you didn't try to stop him?
You think Dongwon would listen to me
if I told him not to be a two-timer?
Not really...
This is why you should've gone out with me!
The girls at this school have no taste in men!
What's so great about Kang Dongwon?
Why does everyone want him?
I get better grades, and I'm more handsome.
Does Mul like you, too?
Were you in a love triangle?
We weren't. I only love Dongwon.
Dongju, you're his twin sister,
so can you help me get him back?
I may be his twin sister, but I can't do that.
Why would you even want him back?
Ms. Kim...
Cheon Iseul!
Get over that two-timing jerk!
Get over him and find someone else.
Dongwon's not the only man on earth.
Find a new boyfriend,
get married,
and have lots of children!
Ms. Kim!
What you just said
isn't appropriate to say to a 9-year-old girl.
I know...
What's wrong with me...
I'm so sorry, girls.
I have a fever, so I'm not myself today.
Oh, boy!
He's going to be just like Donghui...
Can you stop the car for a second?
If you want to catch the broker,
there's the way that you go to the
legal aid cooperation.
It's too far, and you don't even
speak Korean so well,
so I'll file a complaint on behalf of you.
Thank you, thank you.
And here's the address and phone number of
the foreign labor center.
It's a safe place, so you can stay there with
your baby for a while.
They also provide vocational education,
so if you need it, just tell me.
Thank you, thank you.
By the way, do you have any powdered milk?
That can't be!
I just used it at another place.
Try swiping it again.
I tried it 5 times. It says it's suspended.
Why don't you call the credit card company?
No... That can't be.
Then, can you give me this on credit?
Excuse me?
I'll bring you the money tomorrow.
I'm a regular here.
Just give me these on credit.
I can't do that.
Then what about the sashimi, the beef,
and the hairtail they cut up for me?
My family needs to eat them tonight.
Here.
Why don't you charge it on my credit card?
Okay. The total is $181.25.
Excuse me, but who are you?
Have we met before?
Are you from this neighborhood?
It's been a while. I'm Kang Dongseok.
You haven't changed a bit.
We give out the fastest loans.
Women get special interest rates.
Happy Cash.
We give out the fastest loans.
Women get special interest rates.
Haewon, Haewon!
Happy Cash.
Did you suspend my credit card?
That's not yours, it's mine!
You know what happened
to me, because of you?
Can't you see I'm working?
We can talk at home...
Because you suspended my credit card,
Kang Dongseok paid for our stuff, girl!
That dumb, vulgar boy, the housekeeper's son!
The very boy who used to eat our leftovers!
He paid for our stuff!
He was showing off, boasting,
laughing at us for losing everything!
Oh! How humiliating!
Why did he have to see me like that?
Oh, the humiliation!
It was so humiliating!
Prosecutor Kang Dongseok!
What are you doing here?
How are you feeling?
What's this?
The money my mom
borrowed at the grocery store.
It's okay. I just wanted to...
Take it.
This is for the hospital bills and the ride home.
I better get going.
You two make a cute couple!
Kang Donghui!
If you're so worried about Haewon,
then you should start dating again.
Like in the old days.
Subtitles by KBS World
Then why don't you come back
as my uncle in your next life?
I'll do that! Yes, I will!
He might seem like a hooligan,
but he doesn't beat people up for no reason.
You're his mom. Why can't you see that?
Donghui, Dongtak, Dongok.
Who knows what mess they'll get into next?
There's a reason why I'm going bald.
If you weren't so below us,
I'd let you marry my son.
Can you come see me?
Can you come and hold me a while?