Subtitles by DramaFever
Then...
who's the culprit?
The culprit?
It's Young Joon.
What... what did you say?
The person who committed
murder on that night...
was Sung Young Joon,
your younger brother.
I felt bad for causing your death
through the car accident
so I helped to hide the fact that
your brother was the murderer.
Where do you think...
Young Joon got the money to
attend medical school?
I paid for his tuition.
I did all that...
because I felt bad for
what I had done to you.
You... expect me to believe that?
Well, I can't believe that.
It'd be best for you to believe me...
before everyone else
gets here, though.
This is the transfer statement.
Young Joon's tuition
and living expenses
are all listed in there.
[Transfer Statement]
[Chungho Foundation]
[Sung Young Joon]
This can't be.
[Automatic Transfer
from Chungho Foundation]
[Sung Young Joon]
This can't be!
He was supposed to stay with
Chairman Cha, so where is he going?
I'm sorry, but could you
wait here for a bit?
All right.
Thank you, I'll be right back.
Geez, where did he go?
Driver Hwang's wife is here to see him.
- Let's talk for a bit.
- The detective will be here soon.
We can talk then.
You said that Min Joon's uncle
didn't take the blame for the incident
just for the money.
And you wanted to know the other
reason why he agreed to it, correct?
Young Joon wasn't home then.
He was with Tae Hoon's father.
They seemed like
they were pretty close.
[Cardiology Department Sung Young Joon]
Where were you
on that night?
Huh?
Where were you on
the night of my accident?
Tell me.
Tell me that you were
somewhere else, please!
Why should I have to tell you that?
What?
I'm so damned sick and tired
of talking about that night!
I have nothing to discuss
with you, so get out of here.
- Sung... Sung Young Joon.
- I said get out!
Did you...
did you accept money from
Chairman Cha?
Did you accept money for
tuition and living expenses from him?
Did you really do that?
The help I've agreed to give you...
Let's just keep that between us.
No.
No, huh?
You really didn't?
Why would I accept his money?
Stop being so ridiculous,
and get out.
What do you think is the reason?
Min Joon's uncle did accept
money from me, of course.
And yet...
you don't think the money
is all there was to it?
Well, you're right.
That wasn't all there was to it.
Where do you think Min Joon got the money
to open such a big restaurant?
If he didn't have the money...
he would've been working
in someone else's kitchen.
I was told that Min Joon's uncle's
acquaintance invested in the restaurant.
The investment for
Min Joon's restaurant...
that was my money.
What?
Is that true?
Didn't he say that the money
was from "CEO Park?"
You can go and ask him
yourself, if you'd like.
But why?
Why did you invest your
money into Min Joon?
Because despite everything,
you're still his father?
Because that was the promise
I made with Min Joon's uncle.
Min Joon's uncle...
really cared about
Min Joon quite a lot.
The main condition he had
was that I take care of Min Joon.
You do know that his restaurant
will close down...
the moment I withdraw
my investment, right?
If you don't want to be the cause
of Min Joon's ruin...
then go back to Australia...
immediately.
Where have you been?
Driver Hwang's wife
just disappeared, too.
What is going on here?
Hey, what about Chairman Cha?
What did he say?
Did he admit to his crime?
What happened? Why are you
acting like this all of the sudden?
Ho Bang.
I think that we'll have to
give up on this now.
Hey, what are you talking about?
Why would we give up?
Let's just forget about
all this, okay?
Let's not investigate this further,
and just let it be.
I saw Young Joon earlier
this afternoon.
He was with Tae Hoon's father.
They seemed like
they were pretty close.
Tell me where you were.
You went to the hospital, right?
Detective!
How did it go?
Um...
Did... something happen?
What about my aunt?
I'm sorry to tell you this, but...
Oh, it's my aunt.
Just a moment.
Aunt!
Where are you?
Min Joon.
I'm heading to the airport right now.
The airport?
But, why?
Sorry, but I need to hang up now.
Aunt!
Can you tell me what that was about?
I'll be going now.
Aunt!
Why have you suddenly changed
your mind about testifying?
You weren't like this
up until a short while ago.
I couldn't bring myself to say anything
when I was actually facing your father.
Your uncle and I were also
in the wrong, Min Joon.
What?
I'll be honest and
tell you everything.
Your uncle...
received money in exchange
for taking the blame.
We were desperate for the money
to pay our daughter's hospital fees.
We had to try anything we possibly could
for our only daughter.
So we wanted to let her get
the surgery before she died.
I'm sorry.
Your uncle carried that
secret to his grave
so I didn't think I had the right
to bring it up again.
I do understand that you want to...
make Chairman Cha
pay for his crimes.
But I'm sorry.
Just forget about it,
and live your own life happily.
And I wish you success
with your business.
I'm sorry.
Is he not home yet?
The lights are off, too.
Hae Sung!
Sung Hae Sung!
He must not be home.
Where did he go?
Who's the culprit, then?
It's Young Joon.
Here we go.
Here it is!
Wow!
- Wow!
- Eat up.
- Thank you for the meal!
Thank you for the meal!
How is it?
Yum!
The food you make
really is the best, Big Bro!
Hey, Sung Hae Chul. Why didn't you
wash up before eating, though?
Wow!
You really are going to make
a great husband one day!
Well, duh.
You know that you have to study hard to
find someone as good looking as me?
Sure, whatever.
Young In.
Sung Young In!
You're not leaving without
eating again, are you?
What, and listen to you nag at me
all day because of it?
- I'll eat, I'll eat.
- Eat up, it's delicious.
Sung Hae Sung.
The kids are going to treat you like an
outcast if you keep nagging at them!
Why are you here?
Did you sleep in Young In's room again?
Yeah, so that I could eat
the breakfast that you cooked.
- Oh yeah, Hae Sung.
- Yeah?
Close your restaurant today.
You and I need to go somewhere.
You want me to close
the restaurant for today?
- Why, where are we going?
- You'll see.
He has a really masculine face
so he looks handsome in different ways
based on what hairstyle he has.
Please be mindful of that.
This isn't too bad, either.
But this won't do because
he looks too handsome like this.
Perfect.
I like this.
Excuse me.
He has broad shoulders,
so he looks great in suits.
Please be mindful of that.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, I'm all set.
How do I look?
You look so cool!
So cool!
Let's hurry and go.
We'll be late.
But, where are we going?
You'll see when we get there.
Let's hurry and go.
The Hippocratic Oath.
"I solemnly pledge to dedicate my life
to the service of humanity."
"The health and well-being of my patient
will be my first consideration."
"I make these promises solemnly,
freely and upon my honor."
Hae Sung.
Young Joon.
Thanks to you, I was able to graduate
medical school.
I'll become a great doctor.
And I'll repay you for struggling
so much for my sake.
Thanks, Big Bro.
Don't be good to me,
be good to your patients instead!
Looks like Big Bro is nagging again.
Congratulations on graduating,
Young Joon!
When it comes to nagging,
Sung Hae Sung can't be beat.
It's been so long since all of us
have gotten together like this.
We can get together
more often now.
Yeah, let's do that.
I'm hungry, Big Bro.
Oh, really? Let's hurry and
go eat something, then.
You have to eat jjajangmyun
on your graduation day.
I'll buy. Let's go!
- Really?
- Wow!
- Let's go, let's go!
- Let's go!
- What should we get?
- I want kkangpoongi.
Hurry up!
Coming!
So it was just a dream, huh?
Are you awake now?
Hey, Jung Won was
worrying about you earlier
so I told her that
it was nothing.
All right.
Thanks.
Go and get some
fresh air, or something.
If you keep acting this way, Jung Won
will realize that something is up.
Yeah.
I'll tell Jung Won to tell the folks at
the restaurant that you can't work today
so go and get some fresh air
by yourself, or something.
Okay?
I did give him money.
And in exchange for that,
your uncle went to prison.
So what?
What did you say to my aunt
to have her
fly back to Australia
without even testifying?
Why are you asking me that?
Go and ask your aunt that!
I have work to do, so stop saying
frustrating things and leave!
Let me make this one thing clear.
I vow...
to make you pay for what you did.
You punk!
I'll make you keenly aware of the fact
that money can't solve everything.
I'll make one thing very clear, too.
Stop messing around.
You'd better listen to me, because
I'm telling you this as your father!
My father?
Fine.
I'll keep that in mind, Father.
"Father"?
You'd better remember
my words too, Father.
Is he, by any chance...
Mr. Cha Min Joon!
Have you been well, sir?
You remember me, don't you?
I met you at your restaurant.
I'm Jung Won's friend.
Yes, I do remember.
Your food was so good,
and I've been meaning to come back.
It's quite nice to
run into you here.
Oh, but what brings you by here?
I had some business here.
Goodbye.
Ah, okay then.
How dare he show up here?
Why was he here?
Why?
Tell me.
Why did your son come here?
Have you been keeping in touch
with him behind my back?
I thought you said Tae Hoon
was the only son you had!
How long has this been going on for?
Since when has he been in touch
with you, and visiting you here?
This was the first time.
And we haven't been in touch
before that, either.
Why did he come here if you two
hadn't been keeping in touch?
There must have been a
reason why he came here!
He stopped by just because.
Just because!
And he won't be coming back, either!
"Just because"?
And you expect me
to believe that?
I was far too naive.
I actually believed you when you told me
that you didn't keep in touch with him.
I completely fell for your lie.
I'm telling the truth!
Don't you feel sorry towards Tae Hoon,
who loves and respects you so much?
Why are you bring up Tae Hoon?
Why are you bringing
Tae Hoon up at a time like this? Huh?
Father.
What's going on here?
You two don't look very happy.
What were you talking about?
Oh, it was nothing.
[Farming District (Last Stop)]
Hey!
This is the final stop!
Aren't you going to get off?
Oh... um, yes.
Oh dear!
Oh my!
Get out of the way!
Oh!
Oh no!
The baby!
Oh dear!
Oh my!
Oh, it wasn't a baby.
Oh dear!
Oh dear, this is terrible!
Oh my!
Oh no, what happened?
Well, you see, my crane's
brakes were acting up.
Oh dear, what do I do?
I almost killed him!
You almost made me
lose all my corn!
- Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Oh, no!
Well, we should hurry
and call 911!
Yes, let's hurry and call them!
You think he should be sent to
a big hospital in Seoul?
We did what we could,
but he's still unconscious
so I think it'd be best if we transferred
him to a bigger hospital.
Oh my.
What do I do?
I'm done for.
- Please prepare for the transfer.
- Yes, sir.
Please calm down,
and take a seat here.
Please wait here.
Bring the hospital bed back there, and
be inconspicuous about it.
- All right.
- Hurry, hurry!
Yes, ma'am.
The wound is gone!
Yes!
Oh.
Oh! Oh!
Oh, Granny!
Um, what happened?
Here, drink this.
You haven't even eaten anything,
but sleep for the past two days.
What?
Two days?
That's right, two days!
I think I became dizzy
all of the sudden, and fainted.
You stopped my crane with your
bare hands, and lost all your energy.
That's why you were
unconscious for two days.
Oh.
But, where are we?
We went to a hospital
but I saw your wounds disappearing,
so I quickly brought you to my house.
What?
Other people won't be able
to understand your state of being.
After all, you have to keep it a secret
that you're a "being who returned."
Oh... how did you know that?
Ten years ago, my husband also came
and left as fast as he'd come.
Really?
When I saw that you stopped
my crane with your bare hands
I knew then what you were.
My husband was also incredibly strong
when he came back.
That's not the strength
of an ordinary human.
At any rate, I became sure when I saw
your wounds disappearing at the hospital.
Because the same thing
happened with my husband.
When he used a lot
of his strength at once
he was drained of his power,
and passed out for a day or two.
Oh, I see.
But, why did you come all the way
to the countryside, dressed like that?
I just kind of somehow ended up here.
Oh my.
You must have a lot on your mind.
Your face is full of worry.
Yes.
Well, we can take our time
discussing that later.
Do you want to eat?
How about I get one of my chickens?
Um, Granny, was I really
passed out for two whole days?
Yeah!
By the way, who's Jung Jung Won?
You kept calling for her,
even in your sleep.
Oh, well...
Jung Won must be so worried.
Can I make a phone call?
Is she your girlfriend?
Jung Won will get really mad at me
if I don't call her soon.
Ignore me for two whole days now, huh?
This is how you want to play this?
Fine, go ahead, then!
Maybe something has happened to him?
He's probably okay, right?
He's probably fine, right?
Pardon me.
Is there someone by the name
of Ms. Jung Jung Won here?
Yes, that's me.
Oh, I see.
You know Mr. Sung Hae Sung, correct?
Yes. Has something happened to Hae Sung?
No.
Mr. Sung Hae Sung is currently safe,
healthy, and doing quite well.
He wanted me to tell you
not to worry about him.
I'll be taking my leave now, then.
Excuse me!
What do you mean,
he's doing well?
Where is he, and what is he doing?
Excuse me!
Just a moment!
Sung Hae Sung.
You're healthy,
and doing well?
So you're really going to be like this?