I usually get up about
seven and let the cat out.
And, in these dark mornings,
I just nip back to bed again
and turn on the TV,
and lie till about,
say, half past seven,
get ready and start my porridge.
Yes, that's for the hens.
Sometimes I keep out...
if I'm going to have
something with tatties,
I keep out a couple for myself.
SHE CHUCKLES
They are very good tatties.
Just nearly there.
COCK CROWS
Before, I used to count.
And the fox just nipped off the lot.
RADIO: '..Like to ask a
question with regard to..."
It's all talking on that station.
And the fox thinks there's people about,
because they don't like people.
SHE CHUCKLES
They're just lovely.
They're old ladies.
Got an egg.
How many do you get a day?
Oh, well, sometimes two,
sometimes one, sometimes none.
Sure you know, guys, you...
don't rush forward,
you'll get all the shots you want.
Mr Trump will spend time
with you afterwards as well.
If you spread out, guys,
you'll get the best view.
Give my pipers a bit of space.
BAGPIPES START PLAYING
Hello, everybody.
Better believe it. Good.
And everyone knows Martin Hawtree.
He's the architect of the site.
How are you? Nice to see you.
I was born on the farm that
I worked on during the war.
But I wasn't brought up on that farm,
because my father was a lorry driver.
Well, he was actually a
ploughman in his younger day.
There's a ploughing match,
now, my father did ploughing.
That's my father.
He was a prize plougher. My father.
He has lots of cups and medals.
We used to go and watch them.
I know my father's style of ploughing.
See how he is, look.
See, he's over, bent.
This is where we lived.
That's the shop at
Whitecairns, which is no more.
And there's the Daniel's buses.
My eyes aren't as good
as they used to be.
When I was here first,
it was March we saw them.
And then, last year, it was February.
That's two there that
used to come every year.
And we knew it was the same
two because of its long neck.
They are beautiful birds.
CHATTER
..I'm shaking hands with
people and I said, "Whoa."
LAUGHTER
Miss Scotland. Come here a minute.
So you won't be going to the
Miss Universe Pageant in...
And who's going, who's going?
- How do you rate her? Good?
- Yeah.
- You think she's good?
I don't know, I'd need to...
SHE LAUGHS
Are you from this area?
Thank you.
BAGPIPES PLAY
There are so many familiar
faces from the press
who've really been amazing
supporters of the project.
This is really a circle of our friends.
This was really a celebration of our friends.
A celebration of people
that supported us.
It was spectacular for me yesterday
to be able to walk the final
version of the course with my father,
to say, you know, "This
is now what we are doing.
"This is what will be etched
into this land for ever."
As Lord Provost of the city,
yesterday, it was my pleasure
to welcome these two gentlemen.
We look at the plans that you've got
to produce this absolutely
outstanding golf course.
The excitement in this is
absolutely, outstandingly wonderful.
Any questions, gentlemen?
Very nice question.
Mr Trump, what would you say
to the many local residents here
who feel that you've run
roughshod over planning legislation
and environmental issues simply
because you've got lots of money?
It's a very interesting question,
because, honestly, this
is a very popular project.
We've had great support from the council
and great support from
the political leaders.
We've saved the dunes, and,
from an environmental standpoint,
it's a much better situation than
it was before we bought the site.
You can sometimes see the deer.
You know, coming out of
these trees across there.
They jump the fence no problem.
So beautiful.
I know they're wild, but
they're not too scared.
You know, they just
seem to...put up with us.
- Do you want me to face forward maybe?
- Yeah.
Watch this.
What was the first thing he said to you?
"Give this man a job," he says.
Give this man a job. I
says, "I've got a job."
Then he kept saying it, three times
he said it, "Give this man a job."
I says, "I've got a bloody
job! I don't want a job."
THEY LAUGH
Keep this short, ladies and
gentlemen, the rain's coming.
Give me an umbrella.
No, I'm just, you see, I happen
to be a very truthful person.
His property is terribly maintained.
It's slum-like, it's disgusting.
He's got stuff thrown
all over the place.
He lives like a pig. And I did say that.
And I'm an honest guy.
And I speak honestly, and I think
that's why some people like me
and some people probably don't like me.
But I think he'd do himself a great
service if he fixed up his property.
And I'm not talking money,
it's not a question of money,
it's a question of a
little manual labour.
I says, "That explains everything
on his shed." Just take a look.
"He's nothing but a compulsive
liar." That's what I said, aye.
Mr Trump, if you had a message
for Michael Forbes this afternoon,
- what would it be?
- No. I have no message.
- I don't speak to him.
- You quite enjoy it.
And feel that, in the end, your
sort of power and money will win out.
No. I don't view it as power and money.
I think that principle will win out.
But my people made deals
with him on two occasions.
My representatives have absolutely
made two deals that he broke.
So he knows that.
His people know that,
whoever his people may be.
Oh, well...
Nobody's complained
about it up to now, eh?
He passed us this
morning and just flew on
in his top-of-the-range Range
Rover with blacked out windows.
Oh, I missed getting a super photo
of him the first time he arrived here.
The wind got him on the escarpment.
And I thought the press would have loved that,
I could have sold that picture for a fortune.
His hair was sticking out like that.
You know, the whole
lacquered thing had come off,
where it's all wound around,
and was out to a point.
Damn it.
This is my husband's
hat, aboard this boat.
He was chief petty officer on deck.
It's a bit dusty.
There he is, look,
under the red umbrella.
Where he is just now,
which is just looking
slightly to the right,
is where he was hoping
to put in the clubhouse.
And where he was going to
put it in, it tends to flood,
because the water all runs
down off the land into there.
So have difficulty
putting a clubhouse there
unless it's on stilts.
My father, he sang songs
that you never hear of today.
And he used to sing a song,
"You'll never miss the water
till the well runs dry."
Which is a very true saying, isn't it?
It really shouldn't matter
if the applicant is
Mother Theresa of Calcutta
and she wants to carry
out the development
in order to raise
money to help the sick.
Or indeed even if it's Donald Trump.
The permission isn't to the
person, it's to the land.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
I'd now like to welcome a representative
from the Green Party to the stage
- local councillor Martin Ford.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Thank you very much. For
those of you who don't know,
in Aberdeenshire, we have a council
who gives Donald Trump
everything he asks for,
and can't make up their minds
whether to throw people out
of their own homes to help him.
Firstly, I think it's important
for people not from the
northeast of Scotland
to have some sense of the build-up.
In 2006, I think that was
the first official state visit
by Mr Trump to Scotland.
'His plan is for the Menie
Estate at Balmedie, near Aberdeen.
'On it, he will create two golf courses,
'a 450-bedroom hotel
'and housing, as well as holiday
apartments and golf villas.
'An investment of £1 billion.'
'Multimillion-pound golf resort
in Aberdeenshire is rejected.
'The chairman of a committee
of Aberdeenshire councillors
'used his casting vote after a
three-hour meeting was deadlocked.'
All the parties had committed
themselves to sustainable development.
And you could apply the tests
of sustainable development
to the Trump proposal.
And it failed them. It
failed them in spades.
'The Trump Organization has confirmed
'it will now pull out of Scotland
'after bitter rejection at Balmedie.'
We are very disappointed.
Ultimately, we can go and develop
the project somewhere else.
We'll be fine.
I think it's the people
of Aberdeen and the shire
that were really let down
by their council today.
It was predicated on
long-distance tourism.
It was predicated on people
flying across the Atlantic
to play a few games of golf and
flying back across the Atlantic.
It was predicated on utilising
an irreplaceable and
diminishing resource
of, effectively, natural habitat.
'Mr Trump also reiterated
his concern about a proposal
'to build an offshore wind
farm close to his site.'
When I look out on to the ocean
from the 18th hole of Trump
International Golf Links,
to be honest with you,
I want to see the ocean.
I don't want to see windmills.
Good evening. There's
renewed hope tonight
that American tycoon
Donald Trump's plans
for a £1 billion golf
development in Aberdeenshire
will go ahead.
In a dramatic twist, the
Scottish Government have called in
the controversial planning application,
taking it out of
Aberdeenshire Council's hands.
'Never before has an application
been called in in this manner...'
By calling in an application
that had already been refused,
it's inescapable that the
government has, in some way,
expressed the view that it does
not want the application refused.
'Today, almost two years on
'from when he first
announced his proposals,
'the Scottish Governments have
given the tycoon the green light.'
Well, I think the message would be
I'm going to build for the people
of Scotland the greatest golf course
anywhere in the world,
there'll be nothing like it.
And it's going to be done
environmentally perfect.
'The Menie Estate is in the constituency
'of First Minister, Alex Salmond.'
The balance of opinion among
people in the northeast of Scotland
and among my constituents
is very strongly in favour.
And that's because we can see
the social and economic benefits.
I mean, 6,000 jobs across Scotland.
1,400 local and permanent jobs
here in the northeast of Scotland.
That's a very powerful argument.
I think that outweighs
the environmental concerns.
There's not many people
looking to invest £1 billion
in this local economy.
It's right in keeping with
our development strategy
that inward-bound tourism is
key for the city and shire.
That's what we're here to support.
And in partnership with Mr Trump,
I believe we can do that together.
I thought it was the biggest
thing that had happened
in the northeast since
oil was discovered.
- No, no, CPO!
- ALL: You will be the next to go!
Early in 2009, Mr Trump's legal
people approached the council
with suggestions as to how they
might justify to councillors
the use of compulsory purchase.
'The Trump Organization have asked
the council to consider using CPOs,
'and councillors decided
it was inappropriate
'to reject the use of
compulsory purchase orders
'without a full report.'
It leaves a big cloud over
our heads, that's all it does.
Disappointment mixed with
fury, to be quite honest.
This is an action of people with
no conscience and no willpower.
This is typical of the
sort of thing that we get.
Oh, it's very typical.
It's very typical for
councillors like yourself
to defer decisions that are
critical to people's livelihoods.
And you failed. You failed.
'I am thrilled with the outcome.
'They continue to diminish the
importance and nonsensical motions
'put forth by Mr Ford,
'and, hopefully, these
will be the last few minutes
'of his political career.
'Because I think he's blown
'virtually everything
he's ever touched.'
Since that time, the residents at Menie,
in their own homes,
have been living with the
threat of the possibility
that they would be forced to
leave them against their will.
- Just bang the window.
- Jesus, how do you do business with someone who doesn't have a door?
I look at his place, and it's a pigsty.
Do I regret that? No, I
don't regret, it's a pigsty.
It turns out, actually,
we've got a collection
of remarkable principled people,
who have recognised what's
right and what's wrong.
And have said they are
not standing for wrong.
Ben,
what we wanted to ask you...
Have you ever thought about moving?
Um... No.
You see, the thing is, I'm
still working the place myself.
It's my living.
All my relations have been
salmon fishing all their lives.
My great-grandfather, my
grandfather, my father, all my uncles,
they're all salmon fishers.
It's just in the blood, you
know, you just have to do it.
I was 14 and half, I went
down to fish with my uncle
when I left school.
I worked with him for a few years
and I went trawling.
Everybody knew everybody, you know.
All the salmon fishers knew
everybody. It was great.
It was cotton nets back then.
They rotted quick, so they
had to make a lot of nets.
These new ones, they're
made of plastic, polythene,
they last a lot longer and
they are lighter, you know.
So you needed a full crew to
work the old nets, you know.
This boat this size
here, you'd have needed
probably six, six men to
pull one of these nets up.
Now you can do it with two, you know.
Still am, I still am fishing.
I haven't done it for
the last couple of years,
because I've been bothered by my back.
But I'll get going again next year.
I have to tow my boat down to the beach.
It's not like here you
come out of a harbour.
I have to launch it off the beach.
Well, I have nets on the
beach, stake nets, you know,
and I'll be towing anchors through his golf
course as well, because that's how we do it.
We just tow the anchors, we don't
lift them onto trailers and things.
I'm looking forward to it.
HE CHUCKLES
A lot of local people don't see
Michael as a particular problem.
They see him as someone
who is standing up for
what is rightfully his.
And they don't believe all the claptrap
that Trump's PR machine put
out about a hard-nosed farmer.
You know, he's standing
up for what's his.
Why shouldn't he? Why
wouldn't he? You know.
This is, actually,
zoned for the housing.
On the crest of that hill, between
David Milne's property there,
is going to be the eight-storey
blocks of time-share apartments.
My house, originally a
coastguard station, built in 1954,
but there's been a station
here since about 1860 something.
There's a row of five
cottages, here to my right.
They are coastguard cottages.
The occupants were originally
workers in the coastguard.
So if, when you look at the drawings,
you see something that looks
like a crashed space shuttle...
..that's the hotel.
And where my home is, is
meant to be a car park.
The buildings that you see,
just a little further over there,
the other side of the green
field, that's Mike Forbes' place.
Again, under threat
of compulsory purchase.
Down below here, this white building,
that's the home of the Munro family.
Again, under compulsory purchase threat.
"No compulsory purchase,
no more Trump lies,"
on the top of the postcard.
"The hoose down the road to the dunes
"where once you could roam free."
'I've been here a long time, near
on three decades, that's a long time.
'Most of my adult life has
been spent in this house.
'I've brought my family up
here. Findlay was born here.'
Here he is. Hi, pet.
'And then, this man,
this foreigner comes in,'
and because he's got a few
pounds, they reckon, in his pocket,
a bit of a name, and we're just
cast aside, we're in the way.
I think it's an awful
way to treat people.
That was just when we moved
here, I was expecting Findlay -
he was, as I say, born here, so...
As you can see, the
difference from a few years.
This was taken in
excess of 25 years ago.
Me with the children
and my mother, paddling.
Oh, it was just glorious.
You realise what you've got and
what's going to be taken away.
Are you going to Cruden Bay?
Maybe I should take a
cruise up in the old Zodie.
MUSIC: "Janie Jones" by The Clash
Well, I'd just left art college in 1974.
And I moved to London. It's
where I continued my relationship
with, at that time, John Mellor,
who most people know as Joe Strummer.
Having extricated myself
from the music industry,
I chanced to meet Kim, my partner.
It must have been worse yesterday,
because the winds were terrific yesterday.
It's a bit rough today, isn't it? So
you are taking it out of the water, then?
I used to come up here
with my grandmother
and my aunt and my cousins,
on the bus from
Aberdeen, in the mid '50s,
with our bandy catchers, and
playing commandos on those dunes.
It was a fantastic open space
within reach of ordinary
people from Aberdeen.
And the only wild stretch has been
swallowed up by this development.
Now, that is primarily what drives
me to say it shouldn't happen.
It's a real mosaic of habitats.
You've got everything from open
sand to shrubs to trees to wetlands.
A greener Scotland is effectively a myth
if something like this
is allowed to happen.
And lots of areas are either
destroyed, moved around,
sanitised, disturbed,
and they'll be a few bits
left scattered around as a kind
of mitigation of this development,
this very damaging
two-golf-course development,
and the whole package is wrong.
Welcome to our little world, McIntyre.
This is a bay in a million.
And this harbour is a natural for
blasting in the underground tanks.
Incredibly steep, isn't it?
These sorts of models give
us vital clues to understand
the interaction of waves on beaches,
the interaction of the
beach and the upper beach.
And then, the availability of sand
to be blown into sand dune systems,
such as we've got on
the Aberdeenshire coast.
In Menie, what we've got
is a very, very clear model
of sand moving in a northerly
direction. Crystal clear.
That is very interesting from
the point of view of science,
from the point of view of understanding
how our landscapes
adjusts to climate change.
It is the only one left.
And once we've lost the only one left,
we are dealing with
essentially artificial systems.
And the problem with
artificial systems, of course,
is that, because we've
meddled with them in some way,
we don't actually know what
the forward track might be.
These are tees that are built
onto very steep sand dunes.
So they will have to
be built up artificially
by movement of sand from
elsewhere on the site.
Up to eight metres vertically
will have to be emplaced.
And that will involve moving
biblical amounts of sand from A to B.
So not only do you lose
the natural dynamism
that this area is noted
for scientifically,
you will stabilise it, so
you'll lose the dynamism.
But also, you will be constructing a
largely artificial sand dune environment.
Well, I've stabilised the dunes,
and that means the dunes
will be with us for ever.
And that's good, because dunes
can be gone with the wind.
I mean, dunes can move and
shift and sometimes they do.
But when you stabilise them,
they're with you for ever.
So I've stabilised
them, and, ultimately,
I think that's going
to be a great factor
and a great thing for
Scotland and for Aberdeen.
These wilderness environments
are our equivalent, if you like,
of the Amazon rainforest or
the swamps in South America.
Many of these wilderness environments
have been lost around the world,
and, in Britain, we've got
very, very few of those left.
And what's happening here is
that we are losing yet another.
We've had tremendous support
from the environmental groups,
so I'm very happy about that.
I mean, we've had great,
great environmental support.
I've received many environmental
awards over the years.
I think the greatest thing I've
ever done for the environment
is what I'll be doing
right here in Aberdeen.
But when we went to our meetings,
we had tremendous support
from major environmentalists
and environmental groups.
Is my hair OK? It's blowing all over.
Have a look in the lens.
I can't see it. Do you have a
mirror, Emily? Give me a mirror.
'There are no environmental
organisations that I know of
'that favour this development.'
Who has a mirror?
RSPB opposed it.
SEPA, the Scottish
Environmental Protection Agency,
Scottish Natural Heritage were
violently opposed to this development.
The World Wildlife Trust
were against the development.
The Ramblers Association
I know of no credible
environmental organisations
that favoured such a development
on environmental grounds.
This is an accolade site. A Site
Of Special Scientific Interest.
The highest conservation accolade
that this country can bestow.
And yet, we allow a golf
course to be developed on it,
which will remove the
scientific interest completely.
And it's something of a personal tragedy
and great sadness across
the scientific community.
It is alarming!
Well, look what security
did to me a long time ago -
came out of nowhere, stopped my car,
hands on bonnet, and I got a scare.
They're saying that's for the lorries,
that cars and pick-ups and
everything can still use our road.
Look, we've got a gap
in the trees already.
Well, those trees are seemingly coming
down, which they shouldn't be taking down.
They're targeting Mike Forbes.
That's where their spring
is, up in these trees.
Mike, you are going to have
problems with your water.
I'm really horrified to see
this bank. I mean, what is it?
I think it's a road, and that
these trees are coming down.
This is absolutely horrendous.
That will be the end of the spring.
Who are you with?
I'm a freelance.
As all the rest of the press,
anyone who comes in
here, would have the...
Do you want to turn that
off or to leave it on or...?
I'll just leave it on, yeah.
As I'm sure you are well aware,
we've had a lot of damage here.
If I was causing damage...
No, no! I'm only putting
you in the picture.
You know, I'm just basically
overlooking from this bank.
Shouldn't be any health and safety
considerations, should there?
No, no, no, no, there isn't.
But again, I would ask you to
announce yourself to the site.
It's the wish of the clients.
If you wish to film on site,
we've no issue with it at all.
You know, there's no problem.
Sorry?
I'm just freelance, yeah.
Hi, there.
Hello. What you doing down here?
Just doing a bit of filming.
If you're freelance, are
you filming for yourself?
Yeah. Just filming for myself.
- There's a lot of publicity going on about this area just now.
- Yeah.
And a lot of this area down here
is now classed as a work site.
Yeah.
So for health and safety reasons,
you should really be
contacting the department.
- This is estate land...
- Right. But I thought, there's not a sort of
right to roam, is
there not, in Scotland.
There is, but not within vehicles.
But I wasn't in a vehicle, though.
But again...
Excuse me one second, could you
switch your camera off, please?
But, of course, you can't
cut across the dunes now,
because they've built this road.
That's the road they've built,
they've laid those across
the natural drainage,
so they're trapping
water all over the place.
Look, look at that.
It goes up and down with
the tide, all this lot.
- Oh, hello.
- Hello, how are you?
It's terrific, that water.
Yes, well, they've virtually dammed
us and they've put in that road.
Mike's concern is, where
are they going to pump it to?
Trees suck up water, that's
why the trees are planted.
Now they've taken the trees
away and buried them in a hole.
Took 'em away and buried them in a hole.
They dug a big hole over the back there.
They took all the trees and put
them in a hole and buried them.
HE CHUCKLES
According to my neighbour,
he says it was 400 trees
they buried over there.
Oh, me.
Marram grass being stripped into blocks
and taken away in huge dumpers.
And as you can see from
the last time we were here,
there's been vast
quantity of sand taken.
I just can't believe it.
Be interesting to see where
all this sand is coming from.
That's the sand dunes that's driving it.
It's the sand dunes from over
there they are putting on over here.
I didn't think they
were allowed to move 'em.
That should be on now. Yeah, that's it.
And then, you just press
that, that button there.
Yeah, the one on the right.
- Yeah.
- So I'm filming...all this.
To come here every day,
you really get an idea of the
destruction that's happening.
Also notice there doesn't
seem to be anybody coming down,
checking on anything.
There's nae naebody.
You never see a...the only
person you ever see is security,
keeping...keeping people away, really.
I look at Mr Forbes
and his disgusting
conditions in which he lives.
And that people have to look at that.
And it's about time
that somebody spoke up.
It's almost like, in fact, it
is like a slum-like condition.
For people to have to look at
this virtual slum is a disgrace.
Mr Forbes is not a man that people
in Scotland should be proud of.
Mr Forbes is not a respected man
among the people that he lives with.
I mean, people have come up to
us, they've written us notes,
they've written us letters, that
this guy is all sorts of things.
And I won't say it. They're saying it.
Mr Forbes lives in a pig-like
atmosphere. It's disgusting.
They are really lovely, genuine,
honest, authentic people.
And they are really sincere people.
And, yeah, an absolute pleasure to
be involved in a project with them.
David McCue, he's an artist.
And he got in touch with me,
asking me if it would be OK
if he did an art exhibition.
I said, "Yeah, if you like, yeah."
So we were going to do it
in a marquee tent out here.
But he wasn't for that. He had
to have it in that shed there.
Why, I don't know, but he
had to have it in that shed.
HE CHUCKLES
The worst shed I've got, and
he had to have it in that.
I think we'll just stick
with that for just now.
I think if we put all four up...
I love the barn,
because the minute you started
to change and put things in there,
it kind of recontextualised the work
in exactly the way I hoped it would do.
It was great meeting
Michael's wife, Sheila.
Seriously, what the hell
do you think you're doing?
She's really feisty and
has a great sense of humour,
a great sense of who she
is, her own kind of identity.
Sheila chooses to sometimes
be out of the limelight,
but other times, I think it's
important to hear her voice too.
The drawing represents...
as a metaphor for, "Behind
every successful man,
"there's a strong woman."
I really wanted to find for
myself what the truth was,
at what was happening at that site.
Like the security
presence, for instance.
And that is really stressful
for Sheila and Michael,
and Molly as well.
You know, that's their homes.
And there would just be a vehicle
that would circle their land
and stop, pause and then move off again.
But it's intimidating.
And I certainly felt like
that the week that I was there.
This one, for me, was very much
the very typical Trump stance
and pose that he does very often.
It's almost like a trademark,
the way he gestures
and his body language.
Obviously, referenced
Warhol quite considerably
with the repeat pattern
of the dollar sign,
that's like a brick wall -
you've hit a brick wall, dead end,
kind of scenario.
The media has been
coming down to this place,
it's been talking about it as a
slum, which it certainly isn't.
And to be able to sort of show
off the interior of that barn,
which we've always just
seen the exterior of,
and get a real glimpse into the
history, the heritage of the space.
I glimpse out of the back square
that looks onto all of
the other properties,
which are in a similar position
of maybe coming under
compulsory purchase.
It was just...it was perfect.
20 turns up, I'll be happy.
HE LAUGHS
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
It's in grossly bad taste,
which, of course, is spot on. Yes.
We all need a hockey
stick or a baseball bat.
I really wanted an interactive
piece. That was quite important.
That they weren't just passively,
you know, looking at pieces of work.
ALL: Yeah!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
I've seen some of them in the
computer...David's computer.
But they don't look the
same in the computer.
The Trump paintings, the accent's
very much on the red. The anger.
Whereas Michael's
very much the cool blue
and the relaxed greens
that reflect the diversity
of where they come
from and what they mean
and what their intentions are, you know.
I think these intentions are very angry.
Very self-motivated.
Very self-interested.
The way they display their wealth
and their attitude, you know.
It is very much a contrast
with what goes on here.
But you would expect that.
I mean, he's an international figure,
and Michael's a very...local figure.
He's very much appreciated
by his local friends
and people who know him.
A lot of local people here are
certainly a lot more down to life,
you know. I think living
in the real world, you know.
And it just shows you, you know,
the support we have round about.
..Absolute bias in favour of Trump.
- Aye.
- And reporting his negative and destructive comments about you.
- It's very personal, isn't it?
- I know, I know.
Flying about is a
most extravagant thing.
And building a property
and golf development here
to attract American golfers
is...is just contrary to
environmental way of life
that we will have to lead.
It's a personal gift
to Michael and Sheila.
It feels important for me
to give something to them
for all the help that they've given me.
Like all my paintings, I find
it very difficult to talk about
while it's in its early stages.
Um... But it's going to
be an image of Michael
on the salmon fishing boat.
It was a Saturday, and Michael
was washing the Land Rover,
and he also washed Sheila's car.
And then, the hose went to a trickle.
And he says, "Oh, the
water's surely off."
So he came over and said to
me, "Be canny with your water,
"because I think it's going off."
You see that line of trees.
Well, just at this end here,
that's where my well is.
Well, it's a
spring-cum-well.
As you can see, the lorry is
going around there just now.
They built the road on top of my spring.
Well, I think my water is more important
than his bloody road just now.
But, uh...not to them, eh?
I phoned up. They keep saying
they are going to fix it -
I'm still waiting.
You'd think it'd be a priority.
See, no water. Dry.
How long has that been going on for?
That's since last Saturday.
They were digging up
there on the Friday,
and Hewison from down the road here,
he went up and complained
there was no water.
They said they would
get it fixed right away.
Well, that's a week now I've been
waiting and still haven't done it.
I got the police down, and they won't
have nothing to do with it either.
Would be different if it was
the other way around, like.
If it was me cut off their water,
I would have been charged by now.
I'm really pissed off. I'm
running out of clean clothes.
Dishes are piling up.
You know, you need water.
I've been taking water out of the
burn to have a wash in the morning.
It's not right.
I needed water for the hens,
because they drink a lot of water.
My plants outside and
my two greenhouses.
So I took the barrow and...I call
it a "rooser", the watering can,
and a piece of rope tied to a paint pot.
And I dipped in the
paint pot in the burn
and filled the rooser and just
rode the barrow back up again.
And then Michael said, "There's
a wee drop coming from the hose,"
his hose, "So you'll
get some for drinking."
Nothing. Dry.
This is just another
ploy, as I say, with Trump,
to get, to piss people off, you know.
It's not on.
I'm really pissed off as well
that the police is all
one-sided, you know.
They says they're not biased
- of course they are.
HE CHUCKLES
Yeah.
No, I'm just trying to work
out the facts, basically.
No, it's not an angle.
It's not an angle.
I'm just trying to work out
why if Michael has been
without water for a week...
- You know, rather than...
- You know, why...?
Yeah.
What are we looking at over here, then?
Quite a mess now.
We seem to have
inherited a new lake here.
Um... Mr Trump, I don't
know what he's doing.
But he's scraped all this.
Oh, here's the police now.
That's the police there.
You get a photo of them.
'Next thing was the security van
'comes sneaking around the corner there
'and told the police you
were over with Suzy Munro.
'And then, they just
took off up the road.
'And before they went away,
I says to them, I says,'
"Who are you going to charge now?
And he says, "We don't charge
anybody. We're the good guys."
With all due respect, sir, would
you mind turning the camera off?
What's it about?
I bet you they've been
on the phone about this.
Your visit there.
It's absolutely sickening.
Absolutely sickening. This
is what it'll have been about.
I tell you, I hope they get on
to the Environmental Health today,
because having no water for a
week and no toilets, no facilities,
is an absolute disgrace.
They've removed all the
topsoil off the ground.
I mean, this is almost
like a flood plain.
As you can see, with the
bulrushes and everything,
it's just marsh ground.
And, of course, common
sense would tell you
- that the water, you know, flows down to the...flows down to the sea.
- Yeah.
Common sense would tell anybody that,
so that's going to have to be rectified.
I'm not...
But, as I say,
I think Environmental Health is
the next port of call for them.
- But we'll just have to wait and
see what transpires today. - Uh-huh.
Who's in charge between
the two of you, gentlemen?
We're just here as individuals.
What are you here for?
That's no problem.
Um... Could I take a
note of your name, please?
- Why?
- Because there's been an alleged breach of the peace
up at the Menie Estate this morning.
Oh, God.
And, as such, we are making enquiries.
So could I have your name, please?
My name is Richard Phinney.
OK. And yourself, sir, could
I have your name, please?
Yeah, I'm Anthony Baxter.
'And then, he just became
more hostile and more hostile
'and lunged at you,
gave you no explanation.'
What we need to do now...
No, you do not!
You are being detained under Section 14
of the Criminal Procedures
Scotland Act 1995, do not...
- What's he done?
- Richard, can you grab that? Richard, grab the camera.
Let go of the camera.
Let go of the camera
before it gets damaged, sir.
'And then, the next thing I know,
'you're wrestling over the
bonnet of Findlay's van,
'this policeman attacking you,
trying to pull the camera off you,
'still not giving you any
reason why, what you've done.
'I think it was totally out of order.'
- Don't do that to me!
- Right, sir, you're being detained...
'Then, slammed the handcuffs on,
'and I saw your wrist
was grazed and everything.
'And that was totally out of order.'
That's disgraceful!
Will you loosen those cuffs, please?
Will you loosen those cuffs, please?!
This is a very sad state of affairs.
- They are hurting my arms.
- Sir, if you'd stop shouting.
Look, will you stop doing that to me!
It's 8:30 in the evening.
I've just got back to my car,
after being in the police
cells for four hours.
We also had our camera confiscated
and our footage
confiscated by the police.
I think it was Susan
that said, you know,
and I was quite upset about it.
I thought, "Oh, gosh, a nice lad
like Anthony being taken into jail."
God, I couldn't sleep,
thinking about it, you know.
I thought, "God, what
like is the Trump people?"
They're horrors.
"Two men charged over filming at Trump."
I'm sick of seeing this "golf
will put northeast on tourism map".
I don't know what he's
wanting to hide here,
but this keeping people away off
this huge swathe of land's not right.
And then, there's that hostile
attack on Anthony for no reason,
the police wouldn't give any reason.
The mess he's making?
Well, there's something.
I mean, I've never seen
anything like this, anywhere.
It's against the law to
cut off anybody's water.
And if they had damaged it,
though, supposed it was an accident,
they should have been
supplying him with water.
There and then. You know.
Oh, aye.
'On his hit show, The Apprentice,
'Donald Trump's word trumps all.
'And it appears that power extends
to his business venture in Scotland.
'At least for now.
'Recently, two British journalists
found themselves arrested
'at the site of Mr Trump's
golf resort near Aberdeen...'
You are being detained under
Section 14 of the Criminal...
That's quite incredible.
That is just, that's bullying and
harassment. That really is shocking.
It's an assault on journalists
trying to do their job.
It's completely out of order.
Certainly people from around
the world have been taken aback
that this type of thing could happen.
Where journalists are actually
arrested, violently arrested,
handcuffed, taken to the cells,
having been fingerprinted,
DNA tests, having their equipment
taken off them, kept in the cells.
No, I've never seen anything like this.
I know people who have been
done for contempt of court,
covering court cases and
refusing to expose their sources.
But this was just an interference
in journalists trying to film
what really is a public interest story.
'From New York, the
greatest city in the world,
'it's the Late Show
With David Letterman.
'Tonight, Donald Trump.'
This is the guy, this
is the classic story.
Donald Trump, big American,
comes, wants to buy up his ranch,
or his farm, and he says, "Nope." So is he
going to sell or is he not going to sell?
I don't know, I don't need it. It's not in the
way of what I'm doing. It's on the outskirts.
- And if I buy it, that will be
fine. - Right. - But nothing I need.
So they are using me as an
excuse not to build their hotel.
They're saying, "Oh, it's
an eyesore, a pigsty,"
whatever they want to call it, you know.
But it's a working place. There's
going to be stuff lying about.
I don't throw nothing out,
because you never know
when it's going to be handy.
And I'm bloody sure no other farmer
would throw anything out either.
I was sitting in here,
I was on my computer,
I was looking for parts for my tractors.
And Mickey Foote phoned
in the afternoon and says,
"Do you know there are
diggers on your land?"
So I had a look out and I
saw the diggers working away.
So go over and tell my
mother what was going on,
just in case she got excited.
I was disgusted and felt ill about it.
I mean, all that happening
on Michael's land,
that they wanted to buy!
I took my title deed with me.
And I says, "You better just put
everything back where you got it."
And there were two policemen there.
I shouts, I says, "Who's the boss here?"
They didn't do anything about it.
They were guarding THEM pulling
up the poles and putting up fences.
And I tried to show them on
the title deeds what was mine,
and they weren't interested.
They says, "We are just down here to
make sure there's no damage caused."
Bloody damage, they were
ripping up the place.
This is the one I used
to use with my father.
I see them burst it all.
That was the police who was
supposed to be watching it,
that there was no damage done.
It looks really respectful,
eh? They burst it all.
They surely phoned the
security. Here they come now.
They've got a road made now.
HE CHUCKLES
That's my land, aye.
Not now, that belongs to them now.
No, I've seen enough of this.
This here is the original
Menie salmon fishing plans.
And it shows you here,
in black and white,
that this is the land here
for Menie salmon fishers.
But they are saying in the papers today
that their plan supersedes my plan.
This here is Trump's
plan of the same area.
Is here, with this corner cut off.
Andy Wightman.
Mike Forbes.
Good to see you, good to see you.
What a bizarre goings-on.
I'm glad you can laugh
about it sometimes.
- Well, you have to. - Oh,
aye. - You have to, you know.
If you have a dispute with your
neighbour about whose land is whose,
you seek to resolve it amicably
and, ultimately, you
would go to the courts.
You don't grab it. You know,
you don't nakedly grab it.
I mean, that's what
they did in the past.
If everyone was to do that,
it would be a state of
strife across the country.
The police are correct in that where your
boundary is is not a matter for the police.
It's not a criminal
matter. It's a civil matter.
- They shouldn't have been here.
- They shouldn't even have been here.
And the fact that Trump
has got a dispute here,
thinks he owns this land,
that's a civil matter.
Before all this happened,
they put in a line of flags.
Little red flags, with pieces of wire.
And they put them in here.
I removed them all. And
I was charged with theft.
There was all these little bloody
red flags all over the place.
And they were a danger,
cos my grandsons play down
there, and they were sharp wires.
27 I pulled out of my land.
27 of these bloody things.
Is that charge still...?
The Prosecutor Fiscal sent a letter
back saying they'd dropped it,
but if I do anything like that again,
I will be severely dealt with.
So I'm guilty.
You know, I'm guilty and I would
have preferred if it went to court.
I mean, to me, that suggests,
you know, double standards.
And very, very political policing.
Have you ever come
across a case like this?
No, no, no.
This is unprecedented.
That's a bit stupid, isn't it?
They've left an access there, look.
Where's it go? Nowhere.
How can he say that's
better than nature? Eh?
HE LAUGHS
Boy, the man lives in cuckooland.
That flag stands for freedom
and for a country that you are
passionate about, presumably.
Used to be. I used to be.
Until Salmond gave them the
right to destroy the bloody links.
I voted for SNP for 35 years.
I'll never ever vote
for them again. Never.
They've done this country wrong.
They're giving it away to the Americans.
HE CHUCKLES
'American tycoon Donald
Trump has jetted into Aberdeen
'ahead of receiving an honorary degree
'from the city's Robert
Gordon University.
'This afternoon, the
Tripping Up Trump campaign
'handed in a 6,500 signature petition
'against the university's decision.'
It's really quite sad
to see what he is doing.
I thought it was going to be done
with a little tweak here and there,
but it's not, it's just been flattened,
especially the bit beside us,
and he's just moving south.
Awful that our, you know, our country
have let him take an SSI and that,
and I'm sure he's having a
quick smile to himself, you know.
They swarm around him like flies.
Whenever he's here.
And I mean, it's just a joke.
I also think it's just
so false, you know.
All these people arriving
suited and booted.
And, "Yes, Mr Trump." "No, Mr Trump."
What has he done here to deserve this
but destroy a Site Of
Special Scientific Interest
and a beautiful dune system?
The people love what we're doing.
They love that I'm spending hundreds
of millions of pounds on doing it.
They love the fact that
I'm creating a lot of jobs.
Mr Trump doesn't appreciate
just how much this system moves.
None of these things
will ever come back,
cos the conditions
will be totally changed.
All these damn chemicals
on the greens, and...
Ah, me.
You just wonder where it's
going to end with this.
The last time he was here,
he made quite a rather sour comment
about myself and Findlay and the dog.
You, know, "Demonstrators."
And I thought, "I'm not a
demonstrator. I live here."
This one was from the students.
And any gift from the
students I always valued.
Because I thought that
was what my work was about.
From the moment I decided
that I was going to hand
my honorary degree back,
my thoughts were all about how I
could get the maximum publicity.
Because I knew that simply handing
it back in a private manner,
it would simply be put away
and that would be the end of it.
How difficult is it for
you to return this degree?
It's not difficult at all.
I'm going to march in that door
and ask whether the
Principal is available.
If he isn't, it will
be given into the desk.
And that will be it.
Because somebody's got to
stand up to these people
and make sure that the world knows
there are people who
don't approve of this.
I don't approve of bullying.
I don't approve of bullying to
the people on the Menie Estate.
That is my honorary degree certificate.
Not wanted! Not wanted!
APPLAUSE
For someone in such a
significant and serious position
to take what is obviously a very
personal and determined stance
is a very positive thing for us.
And we are here in pure support
of Dr Kennedy and his position.
Donald Trump has said he
thinks you cannae be too greedy.
He believes that you should
be brutal and powerful.
He believes that sacking
people is not a bad thing.
He boasts of the number
of people he's sacked.
These are not the sort of
qualities I would expect of a man
who is to receive an honorary degree.
APPLAUSE
He feels very strongly.
And I think, under those circumstances,
it isn't a difficult decision to make.
David, what happened inside?
Well, Professor Harper wasn't available.
And so I saw one of
the Vice-Principals.
But, of course, she's
following the party line
that Mr Trump is a very
successful entrepreneur,
he's a billionaire, and, of
course, that tells you everything.
- (ON RADIO)
- ' "They're making a mockery of the system,"
'in the words of Dr David Kennedy,
'who's handed back his honorary
degree to Robert Gordon University.
'And he has this message for the tycoon.
'Don't trample on your neighbours.'
Don't destroy the
environment of Aberdeen.
This is part of the jewels of
Scotland that are being destroyed.
My view is take your money
elsewhere. We don't want it.
A positive paper, but it's
letting people know the truth.
Because we feel that people
don't know the realities
of this development.
And if they did know,
they'd think twice.
There's some people in Aberdeen
that really want this development
to go ahead. Powerful people.
And they're not letting the
word out on what's going on.
- Have you been out at Menie House?
- Yes.
And have you seen some
of the ramshackle dumps
that are round there?
If you mean Michael Forbes'...
I'm not referring to anybody specific -
I'm talking in general terms.
- Have you seen it?
- Um... I've been to Menie, yes.
Here's the point.
You take in wealthy people from
all over the world, flying in,
and they're playing there
and they're looking at houses
that are in bad condition,
with ramshackle tractors
and old farm implements
lying over there.
Do you think that does any good
to the vision of Scotland
throughout the world?
BAGPIPES PLAY
'American billionaire Donald
Trump defied his critics'
to pick up an honorary degree from
Aberdeen's Robert Gordon University.
He's pledged to build the
world's greatest golf course
on the Menie Estate in Aberdeenshire.
'Today, Aberdeen's
Robert Gordon University
'recognised US tycoon Donald
Trump's ability to make money.
'Now a Doctor of Business
Administration...'
- Just a casual shot against the railing would be quite nice.
- Lovely!
Can we get the "You're
Fired" again, Mr Trump?
Thank you very much.
Hello, everybody.
Is the course on schedule?
Yeah, the course is in perfect schedule.
In fact, if anything,
it's ahead of schedule.
And I am very happy to report
that everything we've done...
I think it's even coming out
better than we had anticipated
in our wildest dreams.
It's going to be really spectacular.
There doesn't seem to be
people against the job.
The only one I see is
this gentleman right here,
who I've never seen before until
yesterday when he started screaming.
Question? Real journalists.
I want real journalists.
Mr Trump, I wonder what
you'd say to Dr David Kennedy.
He handed back his degree last week
and said that your honour was an
insult to decent people everywhere,
and also accused you of bullying
people on the Menie Estate.
And, I mean, I myself have
been arrested, handcuffed
and put in a prison cell for four hours
whilst interviewing your
representative, Mr Paul O'Connor,
on the site. I just wondered whether
you felt that was the right way
to treat people and whether, in
fact, you had anything to hide.
I never heard of Mr Kennedy.
I don't know who he is.
So I can't really refer.
I mean, you're asking me about a
person that I've never heard of.
Dr David Kennedy, the
former Principal of...
I've never heard of him. I'm sorry.
This is a very popular job.
It's only questions like you ask
that, you know, cause trouble.
- Any other questions?
- Yes, Mr Trump, I just wonder if you could tell us
- how many local people...?
- One question per journalist.
- How many local people were employed on the site at the moment?
- A lot.
We have a lot of local people
employed and we are just...
Can you give us a number?
I don't have numbers.
We are just beginning,
but a lot of people.
And there will be more and more.
We've had hundreds of
people doing the marram,
we're ready to start
the marram grass again.
That's a very big project.
But we've got a lot of local
people employed on the site.
But it is an Irish contractor.
So I'm going to go and phone the
police shortly and let them know.
Take it from there. I've
also spoken to a lawyer.
I'm phoning in connection
with an incident number you
already have on your books.
Incident 56, of the 18th of October.
In other words, yesterday.
Well, it was regarding,
we expected certain persons
to come on to our land yesterday
and cut down and remove a fence.
That didn't happen.
However, they have come on TODAY
and cut down and removed that fence.
This is the letter that we received.
They are saying that I "have a fence
"and part of a shed (or other building)
"erected on land belonging to them."
They are saying that they now
intend to remove the fence -
you'll notice I'm not given
the option to remove it myself -
and that they may,
if they choose, put the fence
back up on their drawing.
As far as the shed goes,
they're giving me 72 hours
or they are going to raise
an action in the Sheriff Court
to have it removed.
If you take the double
garage, it's sitting here.
OK. I have a stick shed sits here.
There's an old brick shed from
the coastguard days sits there.
And the house actually
sits in about here.
Out here, there is a pole for
the overhead electricity line.
They are claiming, at the moment,
that this boundary, actually,
runs something like that.
And here, they're tying to take
the back wall off my garage.
We've been very nice.
We've tried to be very nice.
We actually just
learned that one of them
may have built their house on our land.
We learned that last night,
when we were doing a survey.
One of the people actually have a
big chunk of their house on our land.
So we're having that checked out.
You'll find out.
I've come home today. I
see the fence is missing.
That's a police car that
was in here this morning.
Which makes it eight, nine, ten
o'clock this morning or thereby.
So it will be interesting to see
what time the fence actually came down.
They hit the power line yesterday.
240 volt supply to my house.
Mr Trump's workmen severed
the line with the digger,
popped the line, and, of
course, everything shorted,
and it cut everybody off.
It's working away, quite
the thing. There you go.
Power went out.
The fence that they put
up without my permission.
"The attached invoice is now due.
"Please arrange payment for
half of this invoice, £2,820,
"to be made payable to Trump
International Golf Links, Scotland."
I got out of my bed this
morning, the whole house shaking.
Things falling off Findlay's shelf.
But this is getting bigger by
the day. It's incredibly high now.
Did you ask the builders what
they were doing with this?
Findlay did.
What did they say?
It's Mr Trump's instructions.
- Mr Trump's instructions?
- Yeah.
To put all this earth here.
Yeah, to block our view, to harass us.
Obviously. There's no bank on
the plans. Anything like that.
Oh, I don't know what to do.
It's...rather meaningless.
Took them a maybe a week, ten
days, to actually construct.
So there's quite a lot of work involved.
There's a lot of time involved, there's a
lot of effort involved. For no real purpose.
Get it done and don't spend a lot.
'It's all on Donald J Trump's
Fabulous World Of Golf.'
Sarah, I want to get rid of that house.
Who cares? Who cares?
You know what, who cares? It's our
property. We can do what we want.
We're trying to build the greatest
course in the world, this house is ugly.
There are some houses, quite
far away from the course,
but, nevertheless, they are in view.
But we are berming some of the area
so that you don't see the houses.
I don't want to see the houses.
And nobody has a problem with it.
I guess maybe the people
that live in the houses have.
There's a great big pond here.
Now, the more mud they're scraping,
the water is all bubbling up.
I was just waiting for that.
The water?
Yeah, water table, they've hit it.
It's supposed to be a putting green.
I could cope, I suppose you'd
have to cope with a putting green.
Not that I'd like balls
flying in my garden.
But they've come today,
"We're making a car park."
No, you're not, it's not on your plans.
That big mound in front of us
that shouldn't have been done.
Not on the plans.
Cos there's just the dunes there, Kim,
but the bit we used to
walk over onto the beach.
I took photos on Anthony's camera.
I mean, we got a shock. We
just stood and looked round.
Totally flat. Sand
everywhere. Everything gone.
'I'm imagining now how
beautiful it must be.
'These dunes on the
beautiful coast of Scotland.
- 'The west coast of Scotland?
- Well, yes, more or less.'
And... Uh, what do you
mean, "more or less"?
LAUGHTER
It's such a big area, it
covers a lot of territory.
'It's so beautiful.
'It is beautiful, but I'll
make it more beautiful.
'Actually, when I finish, it
will be far more beautiful.
- 'Really?
- Yep. That's right.'
I'm not fond of Donald Trump.
And I wouldn't want to come all
this way to go play a new course,
nor one of his facility courses, so...
I'm not sure that it's going to
be a very successful operation.
You know, he's pretty gaudy.
I mean, that is the way he does things.
You know, he's a New Yorker.
HE CHUCKLES
So...I'm sure it will
be a spectacular course.
I'm not sure it will fit in with,
you know, the tradition, so...
He says it's going to
be the best in the world.
Well, Donald would say
that, wouldn't he, you know?
Trump will price it most
likely outside of my range.
Of course, there will
be some local workers.
The question is, what proportion
of workers will be local.
And there, I think that
the estimates that are made
in the economic impact
study are wildly optimistic.
I mean, if I were Irish,
I'd be delighted if Irish
workers were being employed.
If I were Polish, I'm delighted that
Polish workers are being employed.
But they're not going to be
creating jobs in the local economy.
And indeed, migrant workers
tend to remit a lot of their
wages back to where they come from.
So they wouldn't be spending
within the local economy.
If a British developer came along saying
that they wanted to build 500 houses
and a 450-bed hotel on
an area of wild beauty,
remote from any large city,
which was going to destroy
what is the most highly
protected type of site we have,
a Site Of Special Scientific Interest,
which was, by all accounts,
a unique type of site,
they would be laughed out of court.
Think of Mr Trump as a poker player.
And he's got a hand, but he's
also bluffing the local authorities
and the Scottish Government to
give him planning permission.
That planning permission is
immensely, immensely valuable.
Thousands of millions
of pounds, probably.
Just to get the planning permission.
So his job is to persuade people
that there's huge economic benefits.
That's his job.
But we should be critically
cautious in accepting numbers
which come from the Trump camp.
And from what you've
seen of those numbers,
do you think there has
been enough caution?
No, I don't think there's
been enough caution
in critically
interpreting those numbers.
It's not surprising that sort
of city fathers might be deceived
by a glamorous international
superstar like Donald Trump.
I do find it more surprising
that the Scottish Government,
who I thought was quite canny, has
fallen for it in the way they have.
BAGPIPE PLAYS
This is the pond where
all the ducks were.
I don't know what they've done,
but they've now, as you can see,
got this fenced off
with this orange netting.
It's horrifying, of
course, to see, you know,
the sand just piled up
like that, willy-nilly.
This was a pristine and
fantastic dune system,
and now parts of it are in
the process of being wrecked.
And that's very sad.
And as things stand at the moment,
much of the rest of it is
going to be wrecked as well.
BAGPIPE PLAYS
Fine, fine, eh.
It's good, this is great.
My name's Michael. I'm
just up from Glasgow today.
Just to offer you some support.
Excellent. Thank you.
Good luck.
- Hi. How are you doing?
- Fine day for it.
- To show you a bit of support.
- Thank you very much.
ALL: Come and join us!
Join us!
It's good to see that there's
so many young people here
supporting justice.
And I'm at one with
them. I agree completely.
And I find it very, very, very pleasing
to see so many people turning out today
in order to support the
people who are being victimised
by Donald Trump and
his profit-making ways.
I'm very proud, yah.
It gives you a boost.
It really gives you a boost.
You know, when you are down in the
mouth about what is going on here
and then you get all these people
supporting you, it's really good.
Yeah, I'm really proud.
What kind of things
have they been saying?
Oh, just keep up the fight.
It's always the same, every time.
Keep up the fight. I'm doing my best!
HE LAUGHS
Can I help you, gentlemen?
Yes, I'd like to use the telephone.
Is there one in the hotel?
There's a phone box just
across the road at the jetty.
You'll need some change.
Aye, you can talk to anyone
in the world from there.
Could you change this
for me? Ten's the lot.
Now, I don't think I'll manage that.
You got any change, lads?
'The gentleman here would like to make a very
important long-distance phone call. Intercontinental.
'Come on, give me your change.'
RINGING TONE
'Trump Organization.'
Oh, hello there, yes. I was
wondering if I could speak
to Donald Trump, please?
I'm calling from Scotland,
just recording this call
My name is Anthony Baxter.
'OK, what was it regarding?'
Yes, I'm making a documentary
about the Trump Golf Course
development north of Aberdeen
and just wondered whether I
could speak to him about it.
'I could give you the email address...'
Yeah, I did email Rhona a few
times, actually, last year...
'Do you have the correct email address?'
I think so, because she
returned the email saying
that he was too busy to do
an interview at the time.
- So I just thought I would touch base.
- '..if you like.'
Right, I did do that, and then,
I didn't hear anything back.
I mean, I don't mind waiting
for her meeting to finish.
It's just that I've only
got so many 50p's here.
And I can't just speak to Mr Trump's PA?
'Hold on a moment.'
OK.
OK, thanks.
COINS DROP INTO TELEPHONE SLOT
- 'Hello?'
- Hello.
'OK, sir, I'm sorry, but that's the
only possibility, to email Rhona.
'I'm sorry, I have to take other calls.'
SHE HANGS UP THE PHONE
MUSIC: "Cover Your
Eyes" by Karine Polwart
♪ You can tear these dunes asunder
♪ Pound this wonder into dust
♪ With your cruel
hands And crooked hearts
♪ Laden with lust and expensive lies
♪ But the haar will stumble in
♪ To cover your eyes
♪ The haar will stumble in. ♪
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd