- Mom?
- I`m here.
Ma.
You've forgotten.
- How could I forget this.
Are you sure this is the right thing?
It feels its a bit better if we thought talk about it..
- Yeah I do.
- We don't have any other option, Clara.
We'll gonna be fine.
If I get off earlier I can pick you up.
- I take the bus.
If I get off earlier I've a couple of
things to do for Jenny's party.
Don't worry.
Have a good day.
- You too, Mom.
How you doing?
- I don't know.
How are we paying for all this?
We put up the house.
- I knew it.
Because of you I'm still alive.
We decided together.
- What did you all decided together?
To live on the street?
For 18 years.
Your mother and I have been paying off the house.
Just to fuck it all.
Next year I'll  be a licensed electrician.
So theres no more illegal odd jobs.
It'll gonna be fine.
I never wanted to be a burden.
Don't say that, Dad.
I`m leaving but.
- So you got what you've been waiting for.
Yeah, I got it.
- What it write?
That's not your concern.
- Then go to hell.
That's exactly where I m going.
And if I make it back, I'm going to make
so much money, you`re gonna love me again.
Your brother would fare better if
the family members visited more often.
A year is long time for someone in his condition.
I am the only family Ronald has.
I try to get down here as often as I can.
Overall his condition is still borderline.
Mr. Valdez.
If he skip his medications even for a day
it could be serious.
Yes, ma'am.
Sign here and here
and I'll have him release.
Your brother is here to get you.
You have to go.
They take care of you over there?
- Yeah.
Look. Its a new car?
Yeah. You like it?
- Yeah.
- Lets go.
When I turned five years old,
I got a little kitten.
And he was so cute that I
took him to bed with me every night.
I want a little lamb.
and I'll take him to bed every night too.
People don't keep sheep inside, Silly.
- I know.
Didnt you hear we dont keep sheep inside ...
and we dont take them to bed with us.
My little lamb has to be all white
with black ears.
Why black ears?
- That way,Then he wont get mixed up with the other sheep.
- I'll be able to recognize him.
- Very clever.
Thanks, Mom.
What's going on man?
Hey wait a minute. What the hell you doing, goddamn it?
What the fuck you doing?
Let me the fuck outta here.
Let me out of here.
- A lot of people would want money.
- Thank you.
That was his job, theres nothing I can do for him.
Maybe a few days.
Can I get you anything? Coffee maybe?
- I`m good no.
No, babe.
So whats this job about, man? Dope?
No, nothing like that.
You need somebody take care off?
- No.
Just asking for a good word.
Where do you want to go, my place?
- Listen, I m broke.
I`m on the street.
Hey, I havent forgotten what you
did for me when I was away.
If this thing works out
I set you up for good.
How long exactly will it take?
- One day.
Jesus, you make all that cash in one day?
- If I make it
You made it last time, right?
- That was last time.
If my luck always doesn't run out,
you can count on me.
- Vincent, you still live at 135 Kissam Avenue. Talbot, Ohio?
- Yeah
You have a phone number I can reach you at
if I have any further questions?
Sure. 2165550145.
Okay Vincent I think thats about it. Thank you.
Do you recall anything else he could have told you
about this affair?
No. I already told you he never
spoke about it.
Even when he was high?
- No.
Did anyone else come into the house
besides the paramedics and the police?
There was an electrician.
He was the one that called 911.
Thank you, Mrs. Harrison.
Did you sleep okay?
- Yeah I feel much better now.
Did you tried that medication?
- No.
The doctor says you're not suppose to skip a dose.
Fuck her. Feel much better without it anyway.
Town full of fucking towels you know.
All that fuck.
I know we're going to make it.
You better Ignore that shit.
Have you going for a job and nothing else.
- What do you think?
- Youre very handsome.
They`re gonna love you.
Unshackle his legs.
Hey mister, You in charge here?
You going to tell me what's going on?
How do you feel?
- How do I feel?
I've been in those goddamm box for two and half days man.
Tell me whats going. What do you want from me?
Give him a shower change his
clothes, something fresh.
Where are you all taking me man?
Fuck you.
What about his stuff?
- What are you talking about?
Give it to him.
Fuck you guys
Mr. Harrison?
- Yeah.
Tomorrow at noon,  go the PostNet store
at Grand Central.
Wait.
- 200 West 39 Street.
With the key that you found with the
cellphone you'll open box 253.
Inside you'll find another train ticket
with more instructions.
The ticket will be to Macomb.
But you get off one stop before Macomb.
One stop before. Is that clear?
- Yeah.
Ticket, please.
He's getting off at Macomb.
- What time do we arrive?
The train gets at 3:10.
Can I help you guys with anything else?
- No, thank you.
Can I have a bottle of water and
a ham sandwich?
Are you guys Flinck?
- Yeah, get in.
I want to go here.
Do you know it?
- Yeah.
Is it far?
- No, its around the corner.
That is 17.70.
Keep the change.
- Thank you.
Give me your phone.
Get in the car.
Which number is it?
- 13.
Come on.
Stand in the middle of the carpet.
Take your clothes off
Faster.
Take off the rest.
Get dressed.
You did'nt find it strange to up and load
somebody in the middle of nowhere?
The guy who is paying me is a customer.
So he knows everyone.
- You havent seen anything else unusual?
- No.
I just left him here
and I left.
Follow me.
Have a sit.
What's that?
I can explain, I know ...
- Shut up.
Go get Jack.
You're probably wondering what I'm doing here.
- Quiet.
Mr. Goma.
Is this the young man who is playing tonight?
Yes, that's him.
Very courageous.
Two million.
700,000 at number six.
What's going on?
Who is he?
what do you mean he's the guy I picked up at the train station?
He is not who I was expected.
Well, he had the number.
- Harrison's dead.
What are you talking about?
- He overdid.
And who the fuck are you?
An electrician.
I was working in his house.
Give me your ID.
Did he tell you about this?
- I over heard him talking.
I knew he was waiting for a letter
and could be a lot of money.
So I took it and
followed the instructions.
You know what this is about?
- No.
No, no idea.
Follow me.
Do you think the cop saw him?
Maybe we should get out now.
If we leave and the cop show up.
Then the others that we think we rat it. We`ll be dead men.
Where you going?
- I should go in and talk to him.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
If the problem, me being here, then
I think I should leave.. I'll leave.
It's too late.
What If I dont want me here?
You have to play now.
600,000 on No 13.
Good luck.
Attention. The first round is about to begin.
Attention.
- I am asking the guards to please distribute the bullets.
One bullet to each player.
We are born only once
and we die only once.
You must be philosophical?
You are the descendent  from the great Schopenhauer.
Let all gamblers please step back.
Please gentlemen.. back up.
Backup.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Please.
Players.
Load your bullets into the cylinders.
What's going on 13?
Do you have a problem No.13?
No no no one gets up into the ring.
I`m asking you to step down immediately.
He doest know how to load his gun.
Enter.
Pay attention. Open it like this.. the bullet.
Alright, enough.
Take your places.
Raise your weapons.
Higher
I want to see them.
Spin your cylinders.
More. Go on, keep it up.
Aim.
cock your hammer.
No.13, no turning around.
Players, all eyes on the bulb .
When the bulb lights up, you shoot.
Attention, nobody move.
No. 13 did not shoot.
Mr. Joe Carver, if your man does not shoot
We will.
And you will be fined.
What the fuck are you doing,
pull that trigger!
Shoot, shoot you son of a bitch.
I`m going to count to three.
- Shoot!
One
- Shoot.
Two.
Everyone, out of the ring.
- Are you done with your little drama?
- Fuck you.
This is the last time you
try to bullshit, you get it?
How much money they are paying you to watch my ass?
What the fuck is it to you.
I'll give you 50 times more of
what they are giving you.
To get my ass out of here.
If you have that kind of money,
why the fuck did you come here?
What do you think I just
waltz in here?
These people kidnapped my ass.
You like money, huh?
How's two million sound?
You know what you can do with two millions, huh?
You can get high class pussies, fancy cars
all the bubbly shit you can think of.
I can do nothing for you sir.
I wont think about it.
Whats the matter? You dont like money?
- It's impossible.
Hey wait a minute, come on, come here.
My man is out, I want to bet on yours.
- Sure.
I take 50 points of the top,
just for this round.
Okay!
Want some more, Vin?
- No.
We all do it ...
- I said, no!
Hey, you lost your player, didn`t  you?
- Son of a bitch.
Sure you bet on the right man?
Dont worry about him,
He has what he needs.
Look I do not know what you deal with this guys.
I think i can deal you better.
60-40, 60 for you and 40 for me.
You have to bet at least 400,000.
Player number six, he is the most experience.
You know what I`m talking about?
- I know your player.
Make your offer,
I just made mine.
60-40 it is.
Place your bets, gentlemen.
All you up! beat them
Move it, lets go!
Now.
I said move it, lets go.
Get him on his feet, now.
You, get him on his feet.
On your feet, gentlemen. On your feet
Two bullets in each weapon.
Two bullets.
Players, load your bullets
into the cylinders.
Raise your weapons.
Higher.
Spin your cylinders.
Keep it up, Keep it up, faster..faster..faster.
Stop.
Aim.
Cock your hammers.
Dont look me in the eye.
Eyes on the bulb.
Out of the ring.
Drop your weapons, now.
You were lucky. The bullet is in the chamber
he didnt have time to shoot.
One more round and we are through.
Bring him to me.
Doctor, to the ring.
He cannot continue.
Hold on, hold on, this is a fucking game or a slaughterhouse?
My player didnt die in the game,
he is still alive.
What the hell was that.
- You know the rules.
Hans... Hans.
When you start something, you must
stay with it until the end.
Nobody forced
you to do this.
You got two for two.
You are great. You are great
How much you won
for the first two rounds?
2.9 million.
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me...
You need to pick your number.
what you got?
We'll be standing behind plate 13.
I'll bet the 2.9. plus an additional 1.2.
If you make it to the end,
you make a lot of money.
What the fuck do you care?
Just making conversations.
Three millions, okay? Three millions
I'll give you three million dollars.
- That could change your life forever.
- How do you plan to get all this money?
Listen, me and a couple of my boys,
we hit this armored car in Mexico.
My two partners got blown away.
I got away for about a day and a half.
I had enough time left to get rid
of the truck and hid the money.
If you got that kind of money,
how is it they let you out of prison?
You`d have shove that gold mine for them.
They beat my ass but I didnt talk, okay.
I didnt say a goddamn word, if i said so
maybe they would have smoke my ass and take the money.
I got the money
I got a lot of fucking money.
You finish the game and you'll leave
peacefully. In any case theres no way you escape.
They'll blow both of us before we get to the front door.
You get a better chance
to survive in the ring.
Just give me something to write.
- I want my money.
- Dont worry about the money.
It is important that you go it all the way.
It's pretty fucked up, huh?
These two are brothers.
I hate that fucking number.
Calm down.
- Just let it go.
- Calm down a little bit.
Forget about it
You shot two already.
You shoot three you get a bonus.
Aha. That would be wonderful.
- How much do I have?
- 1.1 million.
Listen man. I got all the details of where
I buried all the money in this little map here.
Listen me, man. I got a son.
He's doing some time. He got
another 18 months to go..so..
If anyhing happens to me,
if I dont make it out of here...
Take this note this out of pocket, go get their money
and I want two split it away.
- We got a deal?
- Okay you got it.
Thirteen.
No.6
No.3
You can take him now.
You're going down.
What the fuck do you want?
Alright, enough.
Why isnt your player in the ring?
He must step up immediately.
- He will be there..he will be there
- The third round is about to begin.
What is wrong with him?
- Just another case of the rottens.
Get him up there.
Give him his gun.
For the third round,
I will ask the guards ...
To distribute three bullets to each player.
Three bullets.
Sir, please.
Can I have a chair for my player?
He's not feeling too well.
He wants a chair for number three.
He can hardly stand up.
Get him a chair.
Thank you.
Players, load the bullets
in there cylinders.
Raise your weapons.
Spin your cylinders.
Stop.
Aim.
All players eyes on the bulb.
Out of the ring.
Collect the weapons.
Gentlemen, we are in the
last stage of our game.
The duel.
On the table there a 5 bullets.
Three white, two black.
The blacks will designate the duelists.
I will now call the gamblers representing No 6,
9, 13, 17 and 3.
I will ask that you unwrap the bulbs high above
your heads so that everyone can see.
Gentlemen, good luck.
Gentlemen, place your bets.
Wa..wait.
I'll accept any offers under 85%.
Nothing less than 300,000.
Hey, let him go.
What the fuck are you doing?
Nobody tortures a survivor. Nobody.
Fuck. You know that story I told you
about all that money.
All that money I told you about, huh?
All that money you think you going to be hold unto it.
Huh huh. All that money...
You think you're man enough to hold onto Jimmy,
Would be your dick.
Okay son. Happy trails partner.
What's going on between you two?
- I just want to get the fuck out of here.
Get dressed and come get your money.
You are free to go.
Happy trails to you '.
Until we meet again.
Happy trails to you, motherfuckers,
until we meet again. Happy trails to you
Mr. Grubber, I would like to bet on your boy.
Our player has no experience
and at this stage of the game its important.
- How much do you want?
- I want 80%
No.. no.. no, that's too much.
The two brothers are not offering you much better.
Beside we launch up five to one.
You'll need more money, everyone is betting on them.
Alright, we will do business.
It's almost time Ronald.
If this works out well Jasper,
I want my fucking share.
Of course.
But theres not a lot of people bet on us.
- We're not going to make that much money.
- Shut your fucking mouth, Shut your fucking mouth!
I fucking know you.
I know you.
I've been.... thinking a lot, lately.
What are you talking about?
Mommy and daddy left you
enough money to look after me.
You stucked me in that fucking hospital.
The hospital costs a lot of money.
You've all money on me
playing this fucking game, these past years.
You are a fucking  wiseter.
- That's horseshit.
Well I am but I said it now.
and I want my fucking money.
Against the wall.
- Shift.
- What?
less too fucking times too big.
All the same.
One.
Two.
Three.
- Good for you?
- okay.
Players to the center of the ring.
Raise your weapons.
Spin the cylinders.
Cock the hammers
Eyes on the bulb.
When it lights up, you'll shoot..
Attention gentlemen, the duel will continue.
I ask for an additional bullet in each cylinder.
One, two, three, four.
Players, please step forward.
Raise your weapons.
Spin your cylinders.
Stop.
Aim.
Cock your hammers.
When the bulb lights up, you shoot.
Heh heh.. thats when the odds are against me.
Gentlemen. The game is over.
It`s finished.
And the winner is number 13.
Congratulations, 13. Congratulations.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck up.
Well done, man. Well done.
Have a seat..
Congratulations, 1 million 850 thousand dollars.
You realize how lucky you are?
Your opponent won the last three duels.
- Are you satisfied?
- Yeah.
If You want we can give you a ride.
- Where?
- It doesnt matter.
We can drop you off at the
nearest train station..if you like.
Yeah, I get my things and
meet you downstairs.
- Would you like a drink?
- No, thank you.
- Where you going?
- I'm going with him.
You get into the room get our coats.
So your total's going to be 38.
Thank you.
Yes,this is  Claudio, the cab driver from yesterday.
Yeah I just saw your guy
he's out at the station.
We are in the station.
He is on your side. Thats your guy, that's him.
Blue jacket, seated.
Excuse me sir, can you come with us.
- You want him uncuffed?
- uncuff.
Leave us alone. Thank you.
Where did you hide the money?
What are you talking about?
Sit down.
I said sit down.
You are not under arrest, Vincent.
And you wont be if you tell me everything
I want to know back there.
I've never met him.
- Dont bullshit me.
I`m telling the truth.
Why did they picked you at the intersection
if they were looking for Harrison?
The driver didnt know Harrison.
When he pulled up,
I flashed him a signal.
A signal?
A piece of cardboard with a number.
- Where did he drop you?
- Somewhere in a forest.
What happened?
When we got there two other guys
were in another car.
When they saw me,
I knew I was screwed.
I told them Harrison was dead.
and I was going to take his place.
But they didn't go for it, either they didnt believe
me or whatever.
They didnt want me there.
I saw one of the men had a gun,
when he reached for it, I reacted.
I ran and I just kept running.
- Did they chased you?
- They chased me, they shot at me.
But I just kept running.
I ran so hard that I lost a heel on my shoes.
If you saw them again, would you
be able to identify them?
Of course.
Could you take me to that place
in the forest?
I was in a panicked.
I've been running for hours.
It was dark. How do fuck do you
expect me to remember where I was?
But if we took you to that intersection,
you get your bearing, right?
The driver blindfolded me.
You're lying.
I`m telling the truth.
Put your boots back on.
Can I go now?
$22, please.
Mom.
-Vince.
How's dad?
How is everything?
Everything is the same.
He was wondering about you.
- Where are you?
- I`m still in Chicago.
- How much longer?
- Not long, I'll be home soon.
Wha-- what happened? Everything go okay?
- I send some money in the mail.
Certified mail.
- Money?
- A lot of money.
If you are not home,
Have Clara wait for it, okay?
What do you mean money? From where?
I will explain everything later.
Just make sure somebody is home.
You're scaring me, Vincent.
Are you in trouble?
No, everything's fine.
Just make sure somebody is home tomorrow.
- Vincent, please tell me what is going on?
- I love you.
18.25.
How much for the lamb?
That is not for sale.
- I'll give you $100.
- For the lamb?
- Yeah.
It's snowing.
Going far?
I'm going home.
Where?
Ohio.