Did you save your patient, Daddy?
Of course.
You know I'm the best.
Sure. And me?
You're the best at being naughty.
Something else.
Something else? Hold on...
You're the best little girl in the worId.
Hold my hand.
I'll deliver my invitations after Iunch.
Your party's in 2 weeks.
Oome with me.
Princess, I'm beat.
Ask Mom, she'll help you.
No, I want to go with you.
Daddy's tired, Jasmine.
After school, ok?
No, I'll just do it by myseIf.
Hey...
I didn't get my dessert.
My dessert.
Thank you.
There.
If no one's home, leave
the invitations in the mailbox.
I know, Daddy.
I Iove you.
I need to sleep.
Mute the phone on yourway.
I'm onIy going in 15 minutes.
We have time.
Sylvie, I'm exhausted.
You can just lie there.
I'll take over.
Hi.
I brought Jasmine her homework.
What do you mean?
She wasn't at school this afternoon.
Is she sick?
No.
You didn't see her?.
- No.
Thanks.
Jasmine?
Jasmine.
Why didn't they call?
They Ieft a message.
She wasn't at school after Iunch.
Didn't you answer?
I was asleep. You know.
Ok.
When did you wake up?
Around 2:30.
And you onIy listened to it now?
Do you normally drive her to school?
Yes.
Well, she often goes on her own.
Does she waIk with anyone,
a friend?
Not today.
- Not today?
How was she? What was she wearing?
She was wearing a pIaid skirt and...
...gray tights with boots.
Brown boots with...
She was carrying invitations.
Did she have a hat or a schoolbag?
Awhite coat with fur.
- She had a braid.
Thank you.
ShouId we follow her route to school?
Sure.
We couId go to the park,
ask her friends.
We can go right now.
- Yes.
In case she calls.
We'll find her.
She's aIways with Ben,
who lives there.
We'll find her.
- Or in the fieId in back.
You go here, I'll go there.
She never does this.
She usually calls or...
Does she know peopIe there?
She has friends,
she's aIways with them.
We'll Iook over there.
Jasmine?
Yes?
Ok.
Dr Hamel, stay here. Dr Hamel.
Dr Hamel.
Dr Hamel, stop.
Don't go there, Dr Hamel.
Don't go there.
Seven Days
Seven Days...
Dr Hamel?
Detective Sergeant Mercure speaking.
Sorry to bother you at this difficuIt time.
We think we've found
your little girI's murderer.
Murderer?.
We have solid material evidence.
Plus we analyzed the DNA...
...of the sperm we found.
lt matches the suspect's DNA.
ln my opinion the trial will be a formality.
Hello?
Dr Hamel?
Step aside, pIease. Step aside.
Mr. Lemaire?
- Do you have anything to say?
A new twist in the case
of 8-year- old Jasmine Hamel...
...found raped and murdered four days ago.
Already...
...the police have found enough evidence
to arrest a prime suspect.
He is a 31-year- old laborer...
...named Anthony Lemaire,
who moved to Drummondville
a few months ago.
He'd previously lived in St Hyacinthe,
where he was charged for sexual assault.
He was released for lack of evidence.
But now,
in the case of Jasmine Hamel,
the evidence seems more conclusive.
How Iong will he get?
About 15 to 25 years.
25 years.
Where are you going?
The hospital.
Work will do me good.
So soon?
Maybe you shouId go back to the gallery.
It'll help you forget.
I don't want to forget.
See you tonight.
This isn't for a friendly game of poker.
Not asking questions and keeping
your trap shut is part of the contract.
It sounds kind of suspicious.
This is a small town here, Mr...?
I toId you, it won't happen here.
How Iong can I think it over?
20 seconds.
There are other towns,
other handymen.
$25,000.
$20,000.
Apartment for rent...
How are you spending your days?
You know, I'm at the hospitaI.
That's not true.
I called.
I even Ieft messages on your cell.
Oh yeah...
You never listen to messages.
What I'm asking is simpIe.
For two minutes' work you pocket $10,000.
Think fast.
$5,000 now, $5,000 after.
$20,000, as agreed.
PIus $10,000 a day if you don't talk.
What?
Every day for a week
you'll get another $10K.
UnIess you talk.
If you talk, I'll know.
$10,000 a day?
You can be sure I won't talk.
We won't meet again.
day one...
Dan, are you aIright?
Wake up. Wake up.
Open your eyes, come on.
What is it?
- Oan I help?
I'm a doctor.
He bIacked out.
I don't know what's wrong.
Get him out, he needs air.
What happened?
- I dunno. He just fainted.
Hold him up, I'll get my bag.
Dan?
Dan, talk to me. Open your eyes.
Hey. Hey. Stop.
What are we doing here?
Where are we, fuck?
The driver is being questioned.
We located the van.
Your husband drugged him.
The driver Iost consciousness.
We don't know how he pulled it off.
What's he trying to do?
We expect to find Lemaire's corpse
within a few hours.
No, impossible.
That's not like Bruno.
So you don't know anything?
No.
You said your husband has been out a lot.
l thought he was going...
That he...
That he what?
I don't know.
Do you aIways know where your wife is?
My wife is dead.
You don't know where he might be hiding?
A hoteI, a country pIace, a cottage?
No.
We wanted to buy something
but we never got very far.
I want you to write down
everyone you know.
Relatives, friends, everyone.
We'll question his colleagues
at the hospitaI.
Ok.
You understand,
we have to tap your phone.
Shit.
Hey?
What's going on?
Why am I tied up like this?
What is this?
You bastard.
What do you want?
What's going on?
Who are you, dammit?
It wasn't me, man.
I swear, it wasn't me.
Wait till my trial, you'll see.
It wasn't me.
Man, Iook me in the eyes.
It wasn't me, fuck.
I've never seen your daughter.
I didn't do anything.
Untie me, we can talk.
Ok?
I'll help you.
I'll help you, man.
I'll help you find the reaI killer.
I hate pedophiles too,
just like you.
I hate the bastards.
What are you doing?
What are you gonna do?
Stop fucking around.
Stop joking.
Fuck.
I can't Iast like this.
I can't Iast.
Jesus Ohrist.
You're sick, fuck.
Shit.
Don't leave me like this.
Fuck you, you sick bastard.
Sick piece of shit.
The security cameras caught this right
after Lemaire entered the courthouse.
day two...
Have you found out who it is?
We're working on it.
Fuck.
Fuck you.
Fuck you. Goddammit.
Go to hell.
It wasn't me, shit.
Goddammit.
You're committing a major injustice, man.
It's you who'll go to jail,
you asshoIe.
A stunning development
in the Jasmine Hamel case.
Her father, Bruno Hamel,
is believed...
...to have kidnapped the prime suspect.
We have no other details for now.
If I were Hamel,
I'd cut off his balls.
And make sure he was conscious
while I did.
Hello?
Yesterday l smashed his knee.
That's just the beginning.
lt's your turn.
Tell me what to do next.
I want you to stop and come home.
l was hoping you'd understand.
No one approves of what you're doing.
Yourfamily, your friends.
Fuck 'em.
It's for Jasmine.
I owe it to her.
You aIso think I owe it to her.
l didn't say that.
You aIso think I owe her a debt.
You have to come home, Bruno.
We'll help each other.
I hoped you'd see.
This is Detective Sergeant Mercure,
Dr Hamel.
If you turn yourseIf in now,
the mitigating circumstances...
...l'll turn myself in.
Next Friday, my daughter's birthday.
l'll kill him and then turn myself in.
We'll find you before.
I don't think so.
You're not a vioIent man, Dr Hamel.
Not deep down. I know it.
What else do you know?
- What you're feeling.
I'd be surprised.
My wife was shot six months ago
in a grocery...
...by a young thief, for 58 bucks.
Didn't you want to kill him?
Yes.
But l knew it was pointless.
Where is he?
ln prison, where he belongs.
And that satisfies you?
At night, lying in your big empty bed,
does it console you to know
your wife's killer is in jail?
Does it make your life more bearable?
Bye, Sylvie.
The trace failed.
Wait till I get out of here.
Wait till I get out of here, asshoIe.
Fuck you.
Fuck off.
day three
PIeau, it's Mercure.
My ring rolled under the door.
Oan you get it?
Why don't you do it?
It's in the bedroom.
Without my ring, I can't face it.
I put the board back like it was.
Thanks.
Herve, you shouId...
A Drummondville eIectronics salesman
recognized Hamel.
The doctor bought $4000 worth
of stuff, incIuding a Iaptop.
A Iaptop?
Ok.
I didn't know why he wanted
to get in, I swear.
It onIy took a minute.
He went in, came out...
I saw Bruno once at the hospitaI.
I didn't expect him
to come to work so soon.
Hamel paid me to crack the van door.
There's not a Iock I can't open.
SurgicaI instruments,
antibiotics,
even an artificiaI respirator.
They all went missing Iast week.
After he paid me,
he sat in the parking Iot...
He's such a caIm man, so gentIe.
I must say,
I find it hard to believe.
You're not gonna charge me.
I Iearned my Iesson.
Besides, I was cooI,
I toId you everything I know.
It's your tum to be cooI.
SeriousIy, I have to get to school.
The food's so I Iast Ionger?
I'm telling the truth.
Leave me aIone.
Want me to confess, is that it?
I did it.
I did it, man. I confess.
But I'm sorry.
Shit, I'm so sorry.
So sorry.
I don't know why I did it.
I'm sorry, man.
Ow.
I'm sorry.
Ok?
I confessed, shit.
Isn't that what you wanted?
I'll say it again to the judge.
I'll be behind bars for years,
you can be sure.
I confessed, shit.
Stop.
I'll go to jail for life.
What more do you want?
I'll do anything you want.
Anything.
AIright, to summarize.
Hamel wants to torture the guy
undisturbed. Where does he go?
A cottage? He doesn't have one.
A moteI room?
We'll keep searching,
but in a radius of 100 km,
there's a shitIoad of 'em.
A moteI's not the pIace to torture
a guy, too many peopIe around.
So back to a cottage.
Did he break into a friend's pIace?
We checked all the cottages
of his colleagues, friends, relatives.
AIright.
Maybe he rented one?
That's risky too.
Even if he paid cash,
the owner might remember him.
That leaves the abandoned cabin
in the woods.
Did he find it by accident?
Did he have it built?
In the woods... Where?
Ohrist, we got nothing.
Does it really matter?
After all, Lemaire's a child rapist.
Why shouId we bust our ass...
...to save a guy who murders little girIs?
It's not Lemaire I want to save.
day four
There's no point torturing me.
It won't bring back your little girI.
After you finish me off,
what'll you do?
Only three days left
till the deadline runs out...
...and still no sign of Bruno Hamel.
How is the doctor's wife,
Dr Sylvie Berube,
coping with this difficult situation?
Jean Fafard spoke with her.
lt's hard. l have nothing to say.
You don't approve of his actions?
l think...
...l think that his grief has driven him mad.
I'm sorry.
Mrs Berube?
ln the Middle East...
What made you tell the press
I've gone crazy?
I'm not crazy,
I've never been so Iucid.
Oome back. Stop all this.
How can you ask that?
If you Ioved Jasmine,
you'd know this is for her.
You're doing it out of guilt.
You finally said it.
You think it's my fault, right?
It's you who...
- Who what?
You could've gone with her.
But you wanted to fuck.
While you were having your orgasm,
your little girI was being raped.
If you'd answered the phone or
listened to the message, maybe...
Maybe. Screw your maybes.
ShouId we just hide in a comer and cry?
I'm doing something, Sylvie.
Argh.
They're really going at it.
He was calling from St Julie.
Trace the call. Now.
He's Iosing it.
- Anyone wouId in his shoes.
Fine, but we have to capitalize on it.
Ooncentrate on cottage
rentaI agencies around St Julie.
Search every home recentIy occupied,
one by one.
Every day of my life...
...has been marked by vioIence.
And more of it...
...isn't going to help me.
When I was a kid
I was abused and beaten.
I know what it is to suffer.
I need help, man.
Help, not more vioIence.
What's that?
What is it?
Ourare?
It's to...
Curare.: paralyses the motor system
but not consciousness.
Don't do it.
I can't take it.
You're worse than me.
day five
I figured out what you did.
Fuck yourfood.
I'm not gonna shit out of
my stomach again.
So?
What do you got pIanned now?
How you gonna amuse yourseIf?
Go on,
I can't wait to see.
Worst thing is, you don't even
seem to be enjoying yourseIf.
Finished aIready?
Running Iow on motivation?
I'll help you, ok?
Your daughter wasn't the onIy one.
Those little sIuts...
I killed three others too.
Marion HouIe,
Laurie Thibodeau...
...and OharIotte Masson.
I fucked 'em...
...and then I killed 'em,
all three.
But your little girl,
Jasmine...
She was the best.
She was the prettiest.
ReaI pretty.
Fucking tease.
The way she was dressed.
She deserved to get her cunt reamed.
While I was fucking her,
she kept calling you.
She said,
'Daddy. Daddy.'
Where were you?
Kill me.
Herve? It's Hamel on two.
He wants to talk to you.
Yes, Dr Hamel?
You didn't answer last time.
What was the question?
The fact that your wife's murderer
is in prison,
does that make life more bearable?
No.
Too bad we didn't talk before.
It's too bad, yeah.
I don't know why I called.
I shouIdn't have.
That's not true.
You know why.
l can help you.
You can't even help yourseIf.
You're drowning, Dr Hamel.
And you're starting to realize it.
Yeah.
Let me sink.
The trace worked.
We'll be there in 2 minutes.
BoIduc and his men are aIready in the area.
How precise is it?
Within 50 meters. They onIy need
to search a few houses.
MontreaI.
No.
We've got the address.
BoIduc's on his way.
Marion HouIe.
Oharlotte Masson.
Laurie Thibodeau.
Yes.
Yes, Bruno Hamel.
Oheck the names, you'll see.
Police.
Nobody here.
A remote-controlled computer?.
What do you mean?
Where's he calling from?
We're identifying his ISP.
We'll call them,
it shouIdn't take Iong.
Yes.
It's up north in Oharette.
He subscribed using a fake name.
Get the IocaI guys in there.
Yes.
We're at the address.
There's a laptop and a cell phone,
but no Hamel.
He's hiding somewhere else.
Hello.
With the gas?
$46.19.
I know who you are.
I'm with you.
Thanks.
You've been Iooking near Oharette.
Because that's where he's hiding.
He called from there,
but he may not be there.
day 6
- He has to be.
He called his wife 15 minutes
after seeing her on TV.
In 15 minutes on a dirt road
you can't drive more than 25 kms.
Ok.
But it's still a huge area.
There are tons of cottages.
We'll put all our men on it.
We traced all Hamel's calls
to the Oharette pIace.
He called TVATV just before we got there.
Who did he speak to?
We never thought they'd find
our little Laurie's killer.
Knowing that Bruno Hamel
has him prisoner,
we not only approve, we urge him on.
l want you...
...to make him suffer, Dr Hamel.
Make him suffer as much
as he made my Marion suffer.
One person disagrees,
the third victim's mother,
Mrs Diane Masson,
a widow who raised her Charlotte
alone in St Hyacinthe...
...until Anthony Lemaire ruined her life.
l think what Dr Hamel is doing is pointless.
lt won't help him, or me,
or anyone.
For me, that man doesn't exist.
That horrible event happened 4 years ago.
l went on with my life.
I'm all alone,
but I'm alive all the same.
St Hyacinthe.
Yes.
Diane Masson.
What you said on TV is disgusting.
Why did you bring me here?
For you, that man doesn't exist?
We'll see about that.
I don't want to see him.
I don't want to.
No.
Let me go. Let me go.
I said Iet me go.
You bastard.
I don't want to go.
I don't want to see him.
No.
- Look at him.
Look at him.
That man doesn't exist?
He doesn't exist?
Look at him.
Go on.
Go ahead.
I know you want to. Finish him off.
Oome on.
Now's the time.
Do it, finish him off.
Kill him.
- I won't.
Kill the bastard.
Kill the fucker.
- No.
Finish him off.
I'll give you time to realize he exists.
Let me out. Let me out.
Let me out.
I won't do it, I toId you.
PIease.
PIease, Iet me out.
Let me out, pIease.
PIease.
PIease, Iet me out.
I'd erased that man from my life.
You can't.
- Yes, you can.
It's hard,
it takes Iong, but you can.
By bringing me here,
you destroyed that.
It's like...
It's like you killed my girl a second time.
Every time you torture that man,
you kill your own daughter.
Ow.
Hey.
Take me to the police.
Ooncentrate on waterfront houses,
by a Iake or river.
Forget rentaI cottages.
Masson's convinced Hamel
broke into a private home.
He's using Masson's car, a red Saturn.
We have the license pIate.
day seven
I'll go there.
It's an hour away.
I want to be in Oharette when
they find him. Keep me posted.
Fuck.
Oall Mercure. We found him.
Detective Mercure?
Sergeant Ooutu.
We just called the SWAT team.
We'll move in now.
Yeah.
I don't want...
- He won't just wait for us.
There's been no movement?
Nothing. Maybe he's still asleep.
Oall an ambulance. Tell them no siren.
Is this Hamel's hideout?
You found him? Is Lemaire dead?
No comment yet. Step back.
- Oome on.
Keep those guys far away.
And make sure
they keep their mouths shut.
Here we go.
Is he trapped?
He's trapped.
It's her birthday today.
She wouId have been 9.
Bruno Hamel?
This is Detective Sergeant Herve Mercure.
You're surrounded.
Oome out with your hands up.
Bruno Hamel.
Drop your gun.
Dr Bruno Hamel,
you are under arrest for kidnapping
and attempted murder.
You have a right to immediate
Legal counseI. Do you understand?
Do you understand?
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used against you.
I didn't kill him.
Dr Hamel?
Do you still think vengeance
is the right answer?
No.
So you regret what you've done?