SubText: MITA.326
I fled him down the nights
and down the days.
I fled him down the arches of the years.
I fled him down the labyrinthine ways
of my own mind.
And in the mist of tears, I hid from him,
and under running laughter.
Come on, Darcy!
- Come on, babe, let's go for it!
- Go for it, Mom, go for it!
Is she hot or what? For
an older chick, I mean.
You talk too much.
What can I get for you?
So, what's up with the advertising genius?
- We got our first client last week.
- Wonderful!
Yeah, it's the biggest car dealership
in Cleveland.
They want a new approach. Something
that skews younger, so...
- You waited all night to tell us this?
- I'm sorry.
Ben, wonderful!
That's amazing. That's amazing,
you two kids...
I mean three kids.
Just coming all this way just to party
with the old folks. It's just...
Mom, are you okay?
I'm sorry, just...I think I do need
to go powder my nose after all.
You're the best. You're so lucky.
Got a good man, good...
couple of kids, and you even still
got your figure.
Your figure is fine, Betty.
Bob certainly noticed.
My mother would say, Count
your blessings, babe.
Oh, I do. I do.
You know that guy Beadie?
Over in New Hampshire?
He got another one. A
gay divorcee, like me.
- What do you mean? The...
- Yeah.
The news anchor on channel eight?
You know, the really cute one?
He said it makes it an even dozen.
She was tortured.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
- I'm drunk.
- That's okay.
- Go back to your family.
- Okay, are you okay?
Yeah. I just need a little
more time by myself.
Alright, I'll see you later. Okay.
I was going to save this until later,
but...
Happy anniversary, Mrs. Anderson.
You're a Pisces.
Oh, my God, Bobby, they're beautiful!
They're beautiful, thank you.
Hey, hey, hey, cut it out. Just save that
for later. Save it for later.
Let me try them on.
There. Now, how do they look?
They were made for you, hon.
- Would you hold that?
- Yes.
And we'd better get back in there. They're
gonna think we got a room.
Honestly speaking, I wouldn't mind.
Alright, ladies and germs,
what we have here is the best accountant
in our little company.
In the same vein...
Best damn accountant in the US of A!
And you want to know why? You want
to know why? Because he's careful...
Okay, because he checks his work...
And look out IRS, because when he has to,
he covers his tracks.
Enjoy!
Thank you for this.
Hi. I just wanted to thank everybody
for coming tonight,
and just take a minute of your time.
When Donnie and I decided
to have this party,
it was really as a way of saying thank you
to our parents.
For your love and support and for putting
up with us for the past 25 years.
But really, to thank them for their love
and their respect and their
devotion to each other.
Through hard work and a little help
from their kids...
and lots of love.
My parents have created
something very rare.
A good marriage.
We love you guys.
- Well, got the house to ourselves.
- Yes.
We do.
Am I gonna get lucky tonight?
Well, if you bring me some fizzy water...
to settle my stomach a little.
You just might.
- Oh, I want you to be on top.
- Well, we'll see.
Here I come, ready or not!
Yeah, well hopefully we both will.
Thank you.
Bob...
Are you my bad, bad girl?
- Are you my naughty boy?
- I am. I can't help it.
I'm powerless over my nature.
I hope you're not powerless over
the long list of honeydews
I have for year 26, Mr. Anderson.
Come on over here, you naughty little boy.
That was terrific.
Good.
Happy anniversary, you naughty little boy.
Yay!
Okay.
A 1955 double-dye wheat penny.
Robert Anderson's great white whale.
Christ. Is that uncirculated?
No, but better than good.
I'd call it VG.
I found it on yesterday's pennies
from Heaven Blog.
The guy who owns it has it listed for like,
I don't know, $15,000, which is ridiculous,
but I think I could get it for 9.
Let me buy it for you. Let me,
an anniversary present.
- Like your fish earrings. Yes!
- No...no, no, no, no.
- Those fish earrings didn't cost $9,000.
- No, I know, but I want to.
Oh, no...
It's not the...look..look,
if I find it, then it's...
- Then it's fate, it's karma.
- I know, I know, but...
I just thought, you know, it's our
anniversary, and it's special...
But maybe...going once,
going twice...
I'm sure that one day...
I will find one in my change.
Until then...
- Yes, you enjoy the hunt.
- Yes, I enjoy the hunt.
Okay. Alright.
- Great. They're home.
- Oh, you're such a mom.
I know I am. I'm just powerless
over my nature.
Does an accountant ever eat
a good breakfast?
- Good shot Ma.
- Don't say Ma. It sounds so ignorant.
Ma!
Ma Ray, Ma Barker, Ma Jug,
you went out last night Ma!
Always blame the woman!
Well, as James Jones says in
From Here to Eternity,
God dealt women all the best the cards.
- Right between the legs.
- Sexist crap!
- Daddy, I can't believe you said that!
- Daddy, it sounds so ignorant!
- Bad dad.
- Stop it, stop it.
- So when will you be back?
- It depends on the traffic.
I have to drop in on the famous Mr. Gaines
before I leave.
You're not crazy about my...
secondary career as a kingpin collector...
But I am the best accountant in the firm.
- Yeah, no conceit in our family.
- No.
Don't forget to thank him for
the tasteful toilet seat.
Will do. Right after I ask him for a
corner office with an ocean view.
- Oh, you're bad. You're bad. Goodbye.
- Bye.
- You take good care of my baby.
- Oh, you bet I will, Ma.
- Love you.
- I love you.
- Drive safe.
- I will, I always do.
Don't miss your flight.
Bye!
- Call me! Bye, sweetie.
- Bye.
...and although police refuse to comment,
sources close to the investigation confirm
that elements of the crime suggest
that it was the work of the notorious
serial killer who calls himself Beadie.
Yes, that's right Dave. Marjorie Duvall
moved here
to the picturesque town of South Gansett,
New Hampshire
after her divorce five years ago.
Co-workers reported her missing last Wednesday
after she failed to show up for work.
Ms. Duvall's body was discovered
early this morning by a jogger
in this remote area of the abandoned
South Gansett railway station.
If this was, in fact the work
of the notorious serial killer,
police can soon expect to receive
Ms. Duvall's identification cards,
along with a taunting note
from Beadie in the mail.
About a dozen downtown businesses
were boarded up Wednesday,
and glass littered sidewalks following
two nights of protests
over the police shooting of
an unarmed black man.
There were few people on the streets
as the archdiocese
cancelled classes in two inner-city
Roman Catholic schools.
Police urged curiosity seekers
to stay out of the...
And me and mine have cleared
a straight path for you.
Aim here.
For the center.
Oh, no. No.
Oh, come on.
Poop!
Yes, he goes, but he never really leaves.
Let's see here...
These are mine! I was looking for these.
Male expiration.
Shit. Shit!
That makes an even dozen.
She was tortured.
Oh, my God.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
- Hi, this is Darcy.
- And this is Bob.
We're not able to come to the phone right now,
but leave a message if you want to.
And if it's about collectible coins,
make sure you leave a message.
Remember, change comes from within!
If that's you handsome...
get your tight little buns over here.
My..my husband's out of town.
Very funny. I tried you before.
I was on the phone with Pets.
You know, she got home fine, and..and
Donnie did too. It's just...and she's...
just going crazy over those,
bridesmaid's dresses.
You okay?
Well, to quote the famous
Robert Anderson, I'm...
upright and sniffing the air.
How did it go today?
Well, I picked up 17 lady liberties
at a good...
no, at a great price.
As for that idiot's taxes,
the less said the better.
Oh, dear.
Your voice sounds thick. You haven't
been crying, have you?
Well, I just, you know...
After I talked with Pets, I just...I started
thinking about my..my sister.
You know, she was a year younger...
than Pets when she died.
Well, honey, if I jump in the car and turn
around, I can be home in no time.
No, no, no, no. Don't do that. I...
after the day you've put in,
it's just a...
I'd be worried you'd fall asleep
behind the wheel.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. In fact...
did I...since you're in Vermont anyway,
Did I...did I mention that...estate sale
in Rutland?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I checked it online
back at the motel.
Lot 75 steel pennies.
I mean...look,
if you're okay and I can square it with
Gaines, do you mind if I stay another day?
More time for me and the pool boy.
- Well, lock up tight.
- Always.
I know you loved your sister, honey.
Yes. Yes, I did.
- And I love you.
- I love you.
Beadie...
Incredible as it may seem, Beadie has been
living on this suburban Cleaves Mills street
since the late 1980s, with his wife
of 25 years and two children,
who are just now finding out that they
have grown up under the shadow
of New England's most notorious killer.
Or so they claim.
Many are asking how much
Darcelene Anderson knew
about her husband's other life as Beadie.
She knew nothing!
Ask yourself if you really need
one of these tonight.
Yeah, well, I think tonight I do.
You just had had to fucking look,
didn't you?
Any more coffee, darling?
Yeah, sure. Just a half a cup.
You know what, forget about that coffee.
It'll just keep me up anyway.
Just the check please.
Comin' up.
A slut reading a slutty novel.
No...
Hi.
- You've been cheating at the candy again.
- Oh, my...
Jesus, you scared the life out of me.
As Moses said to the children of Israel,
what goeth in the mouth today,
is showeth in the butt tomorrow.
Bob...
What are you doing here? You're
supposed to be in Vermont.
- We need to talk.
- What?
You come sneaking in here at 3:30 in
the morning because we need to talk?
I lay for a while in that stupid motel.
After we talked.
And then I went out for something to eat,
all the while trying to convince myself
that...
what I was thinking wasn't true.
But I didn't get to where I got
by dodging the truth, so,
I jumped in the blazer and I hit the road.
Really? Gosh, I don't know
what you're talking about.
I really...I just don't have a clue.
It's and as for the candy,
you know people in glass houses
shouldn't throw stones.
Well, there you go with your
passive-aggressive stuff again.
You never change.
I can read you like a book, honey.
You're upset.
And it's my fault.
And I'm sorry from the bottom of my heart.
You found my secret hiding place
in the garage.
I really have n...absolutely no idea. I
don't know what you're talking about.
You did a great job putting everything back
where it belonged,
except the box was a little to the left
of where I usually put it.
And I love that box, because, you know,
Petra..Petra gave it to me.
And there was a rubber band missing.
Beadie always uses two rubber bands.
Belt and suspender rule.
But...I found it.
Under your car. Which, by the way, needs
an oil change, which you always forget.
Sometimes you can be so smart
about some things.
And so dumb about others.
Like clearing the search history.
You always forget to do it.
- What?
- The search history.
It's the first thing I checked
when I came in.
And...okay,
I admit it.
I had a pudding cup. So I guess I am
a person that lives in a glass house.
Really, you checked my computer?
You dirty sneak!
Darc, I've been doing it for years.
I have a very bad friend that
does very bad things,
and when you're a man in that position...
You have to stay current
on those closest to you.
And since the kids left home,
that would be you.
And you haven't just been checking
on Marjorie Duvall.
You've been checking on all of them.
Whoops!
Who's...bad friend? What..what bad friend?
The kid I chummed around
in junior high with.
I told you about him after we were married.
- Yeah, but he's d...
- Dead, yeah.
Got hit by a truck chasing a baseball
onto the street. Poor old Brian.
You're not making sense, Bob.
I guess you'd have to be there.
There were these girls
that snooted us in the 8th grade.
Diane Ramage. Laurie Svensen.
And a couple of others.
Anyway, Brian came up with this idea that
we would catch one of them alone.
Well, maybe two. One for each of us.
We were going to say to them...
that if they fucked us real good
like they fucked their boyfriends
on Saturday night,
we'd let them live.
And this was...
this was all your friend Brian's idea?
Well...
Look,
those girls were snoots.
Like..like..like Betty next door.
Did you see the way that she was running
her tits all over me at the party?
Well, yeah, she was drunk.
Yeah.
But, Darcy, you have
to realize that...
I didn't kill those women.
Not really.
It was another person inside my head.
I fought it
for years, the voice.
And then I just...
I just thought, I'll do it, once.
Get it out of my head. If I get caught,
I get caught.
At least, at least it won't be
in my head anymore.
Won't have to think about it,
wonder what it would be like.
All these years, you've been fighting him.
Is that right? The Beadie inside you?
Yeah, yeah. I have, and I could
fight him forever if...
if I thought that there
was a future for us.
If there was some way that
we could, you know, just...
turn the page.
Well, if I don't...
I suppose that I become Beadie's next.
Oh, Darcy, come on.
Honey, this is not some..some movie
where the psycho husband
chases the screaming wife
around the house.
I would never let Beadie hurt you.
You know that, don't you?
Anyway...
Even if you were to turn me in,
I wouldn't lift a finger.
But...
But?
You have to think about the kids.
And you have to think
about yourself, Darcy.
Honey, you have to think about yourself!
Who is going to believe that you lived with
me for all these years and you didn't know?
- I didn't...
- Didn't even suspect.
I didn't, I didn't, I didn't, not once.
You know, and then you would have to move,
and the Anderson coin and collectable
company would be blackballed,
I can promise you that.
And, you know, then there's the kids.
They have to live with the shame
and the humiliation and...
Stop it, don't say that! Don't talk
about them when you talk about
this!
- Don't ever, just don't do it!
- Okay, okay. Can we..can we, look...
Can we just put it behind us, honey?
Oh, God. I don't know.
Okay.
Just let me think about it, Bob.
- Let me think about it.
- Sure, sure.
It's okay, I understand.
I'm really tired.
It was a long drive. It was exhausting.
Could you turn out the light, honey?
Would you mind?
Stupid bitch!
Did you really think I was going
to let you live?
Did you really think that I was
gonna let you live? Did you?
Bob?
I didn't kill those women. Not really.
It was another person inside my head.
Bob?
I just thought, I'll do it, once.
Get it out of my head. If I get caught,
I get caught.
At least I won't have to think about it,
wonder what it'd be like.
Darcy!
Darcy, I'm home!
Darc...
Pizza?
I didn't feel like cooking.
- Yeah, but what about your acid reflux?
- I took a Zantac.
Okay.
Well, since we're gonna be bad...what
do you say we have a little wine?
I'll take that as a yes.
I'll have another.
Wow, you took a couple of Zantacs,
didn't you?
That's the one you left upstairs
on the little table.
Did I?
Must've forgot that I had it in my hand.
I was going to cut myself an apple,
but I forgot the apple too.
You know what it's like when you get tired.
You forget stuff. It's mushroom.
- You have to promise me.
- What?
You have to promise me that
you're going to stop.
- Yes, honey, whatever you say.
- The most solemn...
Never go back on it promise.
I do. I told you that yesterday.
And we could never talk about this again.
I get that.
And you're not to send...
the Duvall woman's ID to the police.
I need more than promises, Bobby.
You dig a hole in the woods...
somewhere, and you bury
that woman's ID in it.
If I do that...
Are we good?
Of course we are.
- You're good.
- I am good.
- You're going to stay that way, aren't you?
- I am.
Good, that's settled. Go ahead
and eat your pizza then.
Oh, my God!
That's hot!
Don't take such big bites and
you won't burn your mouth.
Mother knows best.
And, Mom, I'm still waiting on 20 RSVP's.
And they're all his relatives!
And he says that they're coming, but
how am I supposed to know that?
- Why wouldn't they RSVP?
- Relax honey. Take a deep breath.
The wedding is still weeks away, okay?
Mom, I think it would've been easier
if we had just eloped.
Now that would've broken my heart.
And your dad's, of course.
- How is the old fella?
- Oh, you know Dad.
He's upright and sniffing the air.
Hey, have you talked to Donnie? Are you sure
that he's cleared his schedule,
because...he's become this damn
success story and, just...
Pets, your brother will be there
with bells on.
- And if he's not, your dad will...
- Kill him? God, I hope so.
Something like that.
- Alright, I love you, Mom.
- I love you too.
- And stop obsessing?
- Alright, I'll try.
- That's a plea.
- Okay.
- Thanks, Mom.
- Bye.
Our champion, Sable.
Sable, and where are you from?
Sable's from Harlem!
Isn't that wonderful?
- Any luck finding the great lost penny?
- No, not yet.
But you know, all good things
come to those who wait.
- This is nice.
- Yeah.
It's...how long has it been since we've had
a..a girl..girl afternoon?
I don't know, a couple of months?
I guess.
That's right, because you and Bob
are so tight.
- Yeah.
- I don't know how you do it, Darc.
- Honestly.
- Yeah, neither do I.
Oh, he's on the road, yeah?
Yeah, yeah. He's just in Portsmouth.
Some little stationary company got their
taxes all snarled up, you know,
and there's a coin show tomorrow, but...
you know, he'll be back tomorrow.
- Oh, with him, it's always a coin show.
- I know, I know.
Does he actually have any other hobbies?
- Let me clear these for you here.
- No, I'm not finished.
- That's..that's alright.
- I'm not done!
- Sorry.
- Right.
Darc?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, you know, it's just the wedding.
Petra keeps calling every night,
and every night there seems
to be a new problem and...
Shit just rolls downhill, and...
- That's it, that's it.
- Yeah.
Exactly. And..you know, I just...
I worry when Bob's on the road.
You know, when he's away.
How about dessert? Enough.
You're right, Bob. I can do it.
...friends have no knowledge
of the missing funds.
In other news a Portsmouth woman
was found murdered
in her apartment late this morning.
Mikaela Blake, age 42, had
been shot three times.
Police have taken Ms. Blake's
common-law husband into custody,
and sources close to the investigation
say he's confessed.
Of course, if the next one is Beadie's,
she belongs to you, Darcy.
There's a fix-it muffler four blocks
down on Rayburn Avenue.
Maybe you missed it? You only go past it
every day when you go to work.
Yeah, well, you know.
They fix the problem, charge you
three times what it's worth,
and then point out six other things.
And then...some big snooty guy
looks at you and says...
Hey, I'm just telling you,
it's your decision.
Can you hand me the adjustable wrench?
Darcy?
You okay, Darc?
I saw you looking at Betty.
Yeah, well...that skirt
was pretty short.
It's hard not to look.
Well, then you're going to have
to try harder, aren't you?
It's a big week next week?
Petra's big week.
You want to hand me the adjustable?
I want to get out of here.
- Thank you, honey.
- You're welcome.
- Honey, limo's here.
- I'll be down in a couple of minutes!
- I brought you some fizzy water.
- Oh, thanks.
- Oh, my God.
- What? What's wrong?
You look gorgeous.
No, no, no. None of that. I'm going to
have to fix my mouth all over again.
But...thank you. Thank you.
You're very sweet.
So, go on. I'll be down in
just a couple minutes.
Daddy...
Congratulations.
Quick, get a picture.
Brian, get over here. Come here!
Folks, ladies and gentlemen, it's time
for the father and daughter dance.
Let's get 'em out here.
Let's see them move, give them some room.
Okay, guys, everybody dance!
May I?
You may.
Enjoy.
Darcy! You're missing your own party!
- Hi, I'm just rehearsing my toast.
- You'll be fine.
Honey, this is a beautiful wedding.
I'm so happy for you!
Thank you, Betty. Thank you.
Bob...
I think he..he might have
a little thing for me.
Betty...
Yes, on a few occasions I have suggested
that he put his eyes back into his head.
Okay.
I just want you to know that I have never
encouraged it and I never would.
Because you're my best friend.
I know that, honey.
- You are such a peach.
- I know.
You deserve every good thing
that's happened to you.
- I'll see you later.
- Okay.
- Bob, what's wrong?
- Nothing.
Nothing, everything is finally right.
Oh, honey...
If I was a poet,
I could tell you how grateful I am
for this second chance.
To be here, to see all of this, but...
I'm just a lousy, coin collecting
accountant.
So all I can say is thank you.
Thank you so much.
Come on.
- We need to get back in there.
- Yeah.
Mrs. Moore? Mrs. Moore?
- Are you alright?
- Darcy!
- Petra?
Darcy! Darcy!
Darcy.
- Darcy!
- What?
Darcy, you're never going to believe it?
You're never going to believe it.
- You're scaring the Jesus out of me, what?
- Pick a hand.
What? I don't want to play games, Bob,
what...
Come on, come on, come on,
pick, pick, pick, pick!
You read my mind. But you always could.
- Found it in the change bear.
- You just found this?
- Let me see this.
- I was just going through the change.
Oh, my gosh. How many years have
you been searching for this?
Since I was 14 years old.
- Isn't it great?
- I know. I'm so happy for you.
So, what do you think? Is it fine
or very fine? You're the expert?
- Well, I'd love to say VF, but...
- I know, I know, I know.
- But it's better than VG.
- Oh, definitely better than VG. Definitely.
You know what, if your dad was here,
he would be cracking open a bottle
of champagne. I just know it.
Well, I will take care of that tonight
at Pearl of the Shore.
Oh, Bob. I..I don't know.
Come on, come on. Put on
your prettiest dress...
I will buy as much champagne
as you can drink.
Well, okay. How about as much champagne
as you can drink,
and I'll drive home? It's
your find, after all.
Deal.
Alright, one more time!
Yes!
- Am I going to get to be a naughty boy?
- Oh, you might.
You might.
Come here, come here.
Oh, I'm going to go upstairs and I'm
going to get out of this dress.
And...
if you bring me some fizzy water
and a wedge of lime,
you just might get lucky mister. But...
- it will cost you.
- How much?
For you? Just a penny.
Wait...
For safekeeping.
- I want you on top, alright?
- Yes. With the mirror.
Hey, now, hurry up, hurry up,
you naughty boy.
Here I come, ready or not!
- Are you my bad, bad girl?
- Are you my naughty boy?
- Why did you push me?
- Maybe it was female exploration.
I so hoped that the fall would kill you.
I knew it might not.
Yeah, here I am, Bobby! Oh, I'm on top.
Just the way you like it, right? Right?
Okay. That's fine. That's fine.
That's fine. I'm fine.
911, what's your emergency?
This is Darcelene Anderson calling
from 24 Sugar Mill Lane.
My husband just fell down the stairs and
I think I might...he might be dead.
I'm going to need you to go over and
check to see if he's breathing.
I already have help on the way.
For I am the resurrection and the life.
And he who believeth on me,
even if he die,
yet shall he live.
So we commit thy servant,
Robert Anderson, to the ground.
In the sure belief that the good works
of his honest life
will recommend him to thee
on the day of judgment.
Hang in, Mom. Almost finished.
Would the family like to approach?
Rest in peace, Pop.
Miss you, Dad.
They were very special to me.
Then why didn't you put them
in the coffin?
I forgot, Pets. But, hush.
May the lord bless you and keep you.
May the lord raise up his face upon you.
Nice dress. If it was any shorter
you could see her a...
Don't you ever.
Ever!
- She's just upset.
- Boy, is she ever.
Do you think there's any booze
in that limo? I could use a drink.
Yeah, I'm buying.
Thank you so much, Mrs. Anderson.
God bless you.
You too father. You're very welcome.
Some good comes of our greatest losses.
If you say so.
Hello.
Mrs. Anderson.
Yes. Can I help you?
Yeah, I...
Well, thank you.
Holt Ramsey. I'm with...
office of the state's Attorney General.
Does RET mean you're retired?
Well, I'm an old dog. They toss me
a bone now and then, I chew on it.
I think I've seen you. Have
you been here before?
According to the Hindus, we all have.
Yes. What can I do for you, Mr. Ramsey?
Inside would be better.
My, this is...
a lovely home you have here missus.
Look...
a place for everything, and
everything in its place.
My wife would have approved.
How I miss her.
Just the way I imagine
I miss your husband.
Yes.
What may I do for you, Mr. Ramsey?
I'm sorry, or is it Detective Ramsey?
Donkey ears since anyone
called me detective.
No, you go straight to Holt.
That'll do me just fine.
But, the thing is, I get bored,
just the TV for company, so...
I thought to myself...
I'll...what the hell, I'll take that drive
down to Cleaves Mills
and I'll just ask a few
of my little questions.
Here.
Have a look.
Turn it over.
- Oh, I see you do know my name.
- Indeed I do. Both your names.
Bob, Darcy. BD. Beadie.
Look at you.
Look at you both. Rubbing our noses
in it the whole time, weren't you?
I'm sorry.
There are twelve women
who are dead missus...
I'm surprised you can laugh at that.
Sit down. Sit down right there,
and just be quiet. Troublesome man.
- Never touch that stuff.
- You know you're crazy.
Could be.
But I noticed you haven't
asked me to leave yet.
I mean...
I probably don't have much
of a case, you know that.
You have no case.
Doesn't matter, missus.
There are ways, and there are ways.
Once I come upon this fella,
way far upstate.
Killed his wife, two kiddies.
Tried to make it look like home invasion.
I chewed on that old bone.
Got a taste for it.
Chewed that bone 'til the fella
got nervous and he ran.
- And what happened to him.
- I chased him.
Right up into the Haynesville Woods.
You know?
Where the song says there's
a tombstone every mile.
Well, he crashed. And I crashed
right after him, and that's how I
got this leg,
not to mention this steel rod
that I got in my neck.
I can tell you when it's going to rain.
And the kid that you were chasing?
What did he get?
He got death.
Burned to death in his car.
Saved the state...40-50 years
room and board in Shawshank.
You are quite the hound of heaven,
aren't you, Mr. Ramsey?
I fled him down the night
and down the day.
I fled him down the arches and veers.
I fled him down the labyrinthine ways.
- And so on.
- Did you learn that in school?
Methodist youth fellowship.
I won't let you ruin my children's lives.
Well,
if you think about it, missus,
it wasn't me put ruin in their way.
You think about it.
Go ahead if you want to, but...
I don't think you'll get away with it twice.
What's the worst thing that you ever did?
Come on. It's just the two of us.
And you know what they say:
Two can keep a secret,
if one of them is dead.
And you'll be dead soon enough, won't you?
You recall that fella I told you about?
The one who killed his wife and kids?
Well, after he wrapped his Mustang
around a tree, I...
I just sat and I listened to the screams.
For quite a while.
Finally they stopped.
And then I called it in.
And who else knows?
Only you.
Because...
people wouldn't understand, would they?
Tell me something...
Just what was it that you...
threw into the grave.
They were the earrings that my husband...
gave me for my 25th anniversary.
They were fish earrings because
I was a Pisces, he said.
And they belonged to Marjorie Duvall.
He raped her.
And he murdered her.
And stole her earrings,
and gave them to me.
And I thought, Oh, he's just so thoughtful.
Marjorie Duvall's ID...
was in this box.
The box that his daughter made him
for a school project.
He promised to stop.
- Did you believe him?
- No.
But I needed time to..to think, and...
I wanted to spare my children.
You didn't come here to kill me.
You never would've brought this if you had.
There's one thing that
I can't quite get by.
The initials.
B..D.
Beadie.
Beadie was something else.
When my husband was a boy,
he had a friend who was killed
in an accident.
It was a boy with...fantasies.
His name was Brian Delahanty.
I guess he didn't like his first name
very much, because...
when my husband was a kid,
- he used to call him...
- BD.
Would you have caught him?
Oh, yeah.
It's blurred,
like it's two pennies.
Yeah.
Some people are that way too.
I'll go now. And...
You'll do what you have to do.
Missus.
The only thing I have to do...
is pay my taxes.
It's not for me to punish you.
You know your kids are gonna...
talk about how much they miss
dear old...Dad.
And tell their grandkids about
what a fine fella grandpa was.
You're just going to sit there
and listen. Nod, smile...
once in a while,
even have to talk about the good old days.
I can live with that.
Darcy.
Come over here, close to me.
You did the right thing.
Now would you mind putting
my music on for me?
All you big and burly men
who roll the trucks along
You'd better listen, you'll be thankful
when you hear my song
You have really got it made
if you're hauling goods
Any place on earth but those
Haynesville Woods
It's a stretch of road up north in Maine
That's never, ever, ever seen a smile
And if they buried all the truckers
lost in them woods
There'd be a tombstone every mile
And if they buried all the truckers
lost them woods
There'd be a tombstone every mile
Count 'em all
There'd be a tombstone
Every mile
When you're talking to a trucker
that's been hauling goods
Down the stretch of road in Maine
they call the Haynesville Woods
He'll tell you that dying
and going down below
Won't be half as bad as driving
on the road of ice and snow
It's a stretch of road up north in Maine
That's never, ever, ever seen a smile
And if they buried all the truckers
lost in them woods
There'd be a tombstone every mile
Count 'em all
There'd be a tombstone
Every mile
I can see you smile
And I can hear you
Say hello
You're everywhere I go
Such is my love
Even though I try
I can't forget
the way you sigh
My heart can't help but cry
Such is my love
I just go on
Longing for your kisses
Still thrilling to your charms
I never spend a day without dreaming
You're right here in my arms
If you only knew
The restless nights
my heart goes through
I'm helpless, what to do
How can I hide
The tears I keep inside
Such is my love
The tears
I keep inside
Such is my love