The inevitable always happens
Sorry sir, you were saying something
No doubts about your alacrity,
But the inevitable always happens
You were saying something
about my alacrity
All these security officers l´ve seen,
make me wonder,..
whether you are men or machines
He doesn´t understand Hindi, does he?
No sir
Ever wondered? ln the lndian
subcontinent, our part of Asia,..
how many presidents,
how many prime ministers,..
have been killed
in the last 50 years?
ln our own country,
lndira Gandhi, Rajiv Gandhi
ln Bangladesh, Mujibur Rahman,
ln Sri Lanka, Premdasa
ln Pakistan, Zia-ur-Rehman
The next name on this hit list
is our Prime Minister
l am here gathering evidence, names,
of those behind the entire conspiracy
Diplomacy was just a ruse,
The evidence is in a little floppy
l´ll hand it over to you
when we reach the hotel
lf something happens to me, you will
hand it over to the Prime Minister
This 2-inch y 2-inch floppy is more
precious than your life or mine
No one dies
No one kills
Not l,..
l´m not the one who´s saying that
lt´s there, written in the Gita
l am merely a tool
´Tool, merely
ln this game of puppetry,..
l am the hunter,..
you are my prey
what´s in a face?
´What is in a face? Mere happenstance,
that you are a Manu verma,..
and l, a Raghavan
Therefore,..
please, not to mind
Good is bad
bad is good,..
in the false light,
it´s all true
´True-False, who knows what?
One´s a lesser evil than the other
But they all look-walk the same,
it all seems to measure the same
Set fire to Truth,
find a Lie burnt out
Good is bad
bad is good,..
in the false light,
it´s all true
Black is black,
black as Death
But life´s a kaleidoscope of colours,
to be diced, piece by piece
´What´s unborn of sin,
in sin is bred
Dregs spat out,
breed hunger
´What was, is no more believed,
what the eye beholds, is unbelievable
what was all pervading,..
no longer dwells on this earth
´Trust your instincts,
it´s ugly
Once what bred
in every festering wound,..
is no more, nowhere,
you´re told
Good is bad
bad is good,..
in the false light,
it´s all true
l stopped your transfer orders
on grounds of lapses in the,..
Defence Minister´s security detail,
Home Ministry says, you want to see me
ln private
This file contains whatever the
late Defence Minister had to tell me
But the floppy containing the details
which he wanted to give me,..
isn´t yet in my possession
Your name is the next on the hit list
´Who is behind it, we can know only
from the Defence Minister´s assassin
According to this note,
this information,..
ought to remain only between
you and me?
Because your staff is not beyond
the pale of suspicion, sir
Anytime, Anywhere
Mahadev, wash your hands
l won´t
No,..
Don´t wash
Don´t
No, l will
You won´t?
- l will
You won´t,
- l won´t
l will
where´s Raghavan?
One minute
Please hold
l,..
don´t hold
Yakub goes on hold for no one
l´ll wash
One minute
You killed the defence minister,
You got a big price
won´t you give a piece
of the pie to Yakub?
Threatening me?
- Not threat
Tax
Brother sends
A joker?
No one gets killed
No one kills
l´m not the one who´s saying that
lt´s there, written in the Gita
l am merely a tool
ln this game of puppetry,..
l am the killer,..
you are a corpse
Not to mind
Tax
Make sure no one´s left out
´You´ve sent the jeep to the airport?
- Yes, if the flight isn´t late,..
he should be arriving anytime
Don´t touch anything
until Manu arrives
what´s for breakfast?
l don´t see the purpose
in transferring you,..
from vlP security to Crime Branch,
- Just missing you
Me? Or thieves, robbers and murderers?
- Pradhan, l don´t assume,..
you woke me out of my sleep and hauled
me overnight from Delhi for no reason?
what´s this?
- Piece of rubber
Found at the place of crime
Often used for making masks
for films
Rameez was Yeda Yakub´s chauffeur,
an underworld collector
Your underworld types
have interesting names
Same with Yeda Yakub´s throat,
Same modus operandi
Corpse is in the health club, Upstairs
Looks like gang war, Pradhan,
You called me from Delhi for this?
´The assassin himself sent me a message,
to have you called in, Urgently
Message?
with a signature
Killing isn´t only his calling,
Pastime too, looks like
One who leaves his signature
on his work is no simple killer
He´s challenging us,
catch me if you dare
l´m getting Supriya and Gita over here,
- Strange! For all my invitations,..
you never found the opportunity,
And now for the sake of an assassin,..
you´re ready to move en famille?
Friends can be refused, Pradhan,
Not foes
How much longer?
- Here he comes
l can´t see the connection
between the two murders
But the modus operandi is the same,
- Who might be his quarry now?
Still at work? lf you will bring
the office to the dining table,..
l might send dinner to office, right?
- Only the cheeses, Not the kebabs
They´re great
Manu, don´t you sometimes get
the feeling that we married cooks?
And such pretty cooks
´Why only cooks? Nurse, governess,..
Gardener,..
- Washerwoman
Secretary,..
- Housekeeper,..
Accountant, all rolled-into-one,
- All-in-one, let´s eat
where are the kids?
These cartoons and video games
are for little kids, l hate it
But Mummy thinks l´m mad about these,
like other kids
´You know Dipu, scientists
have found a new solar system
Just imagine, a whole new Sun!
lt´s planets
Maybe even people will be there,
- Yes! Also Shah Rukh Khan
why didn´t Manu marry all these years?
- That´s what my father asked him,..
when he went to ask for my hand,
You know what he said?
what,..?
- Guess
Maybe he never found the right girl?
- No
´Then,..?
- He said, he forgot
He forgot to marry?
- He forgot
That line you´ve never heard
My father is so serious,
Even he broke out laughing
How did you win him over?
- He was in love too
But he never dared, Because my father
was his senior, And l was in college
But l had decided, That gave him
the confidence to woo my father
Pradhan, our kids are either
growing up too fast,..
or maybe we just notice
things too late
´Yes, they are growing up,
But in what conditions?
The situation is going from bad to
worse, l feel scared telling him,..
about honesty and integrity, Am l
making him too weak to face,..
the world that is to come about?
ln the coming times of hypocrisy,..
lies, dishonesty, cold-bloodedness,
will he be able to survive?
Sometimes, l feel like retiring
and going back to the village
´You can retire from a job, not from
life, lt´s the coming times,..
´that we´re fighting for,
- Still, of late l miss my village
Particularly, the rains,
- Let´s make it someday, together
To watch the rains in the village
l´ve put the word out to my informers,
ln the underworld,..
things like this don´t stay hidden
So what stays hidden?
Tell us some too
what´s in the tiffin box?
Dipu hasn´t eaten?
Everyone has eaten, This is
for me and this one
´The two of them are locked in battle,
- Oh yes, they aren´t getting married
Good night, Mister Forgot
Forgot,..?
Got it?
Come over,
- Sure
Are boys really such fools?
Had l been a fool, would your Mummy
have married me?
who knows? l wasn´t even born then
This night
ls mine
Like the lizard, it crawls
Like rolling Death´s dice,..
lt swallows, it devours,..
this black, venomos night
Blink,.., you will miss the link
this complicated night
From silence it draws its might,..
this night that moves
lsolation,.. it´s isolation
´Your heart will forever be lonely,..
it´s crazy
Every person is a ruin,..
every heart isolates
another
lt stuns, it strikes,..
this night of Death´s rolling dice
The night turns darker suddenly,..
my veil will slip out of his hands
´They´re ashore;
and yet they drown
lt´s the night that
brings the storm
On bare bodies that speak,..
this is night that simmers
l know who you are
who are you?
Your assassin
Any last wishes?
Only too die, nothing else
You got a last wish?
- Only you, No other wish
How have you been Hanif-Brother?
- All by your grace
who killed Yeda Yakub?
You are asking too big a price
for saving my life once
Name
when did you start smoking?
Raghavan
Dog gets card
Dog, goes for the card
Mahadev-Brother, dog goes
fetches card
Fetches card
Fetches
Dog goes,..
- Fetches card
won´t even die!
Fetches card, Dog fetch card
Dog fetch card
Dog fetches card
we´re playing another game
One,..
- Two
Three,..
- Four
Eighty,..
- Ninety
Count till,..
- A full hundred
Have you counted,..
- Till a hundred?
There´s the thief,..
- Getting away
ln all, 18 Raghavans,
6 in lock-ups, serving life
10 ordinary criminals,
One in death row, awaiting hanging
That leaves one,
what about him?
1983, Age 1 1
She used to work, like me,
Raghu asked for money
She refused, He burnt her alive
Burnt his own mother alive
Age 16, From remand home to
Arthur Road jail, warden´s murder
Mr Deshmukh was a religious man,
He tried reading the Gita to the boys
To reform them, Raghavan took
Gita lessons, But
No one dies
No one kills
l´m not the one who´s saying that,
lt´s there, written in your Gita
1990, Age 18
Jailbreak, Missing ever since,
- Anyone else in the family?
An only brother, was
´That Madhavan? Poor fellow, he was mad
Live till you can
No one dies
No one kills
l´ll get an ambulance
Raining, back home in the village
No one dies
No one kills
´You are a soul, you aren´t born,
you don´t die
As one discards used clothes
for the new
Only form changes,
faces change
´That, which we know as Death, is Life
Of late l miss my village
Particularly, the rains
How are you related to Raghavan?
- As woman to man
Husband or lover?
Killer
what else do you know about Raghavan?
- lt´s beyond my comprehension,..
why the police is interested
in what l know of Raghavan
Answer the question
l didn´t ask that,
- You asked me what l know of him
´What he does, where he goes, who he
meets, address, means of livelihood
Raghavan never asked my age,
l never asked his income
we never wasted time
over silly questions
Do l still have to tell you
what kind of business?
That´s apparent
l know what you want to know from me,
what you don´t know is,..
you´re wasting your time,
- You think you´re very smart?
Raghavan thinks l´m beautiful too
No,..?
But l don´t know of too many girls
who´d care for a killer´s adulation
´Yes, he might wash his bloody hands
before he touches you
The expensive gifts he buys for you
are bloodstained
l don´t know which Raghavan you´re
referring to, The Raghavan l know,..
slakes my thirst with his fire
Have you ever used fire
to slake your thirst, officer?
lf you want, you can make life
easier for me, lf l want,..
l can make life difficult for you,
l want Raghavan
As much as l knew,
l´ve told you
lf you don´t say, Narang will,
- Was l called here for time-pass?
No, my interrogation continues
´The question isn´t where Raghavan is,
Question is whether you know, or not
Question isn´t whether
you will divulge
Answer is, l know how
to make you talk
No one dies, no one kills
You´re gone
You too
l´m Arjun Srivastav, l´ve been deputed
in Mr Pradhan´s place
l needn´t have been sent to
wrap up the rest of the case
Any clerk can do it,
- l see
Using an academy-topper for a cook
is a waste of talent, And why waste?
l´d say, it´s an insult
Had you called me in before
Raghavan was nabbed,..
l´d show you what Arjun Srivastav is,
l´ve majored in criminal psychology
Raghavan would´ve been in jail
in two days
So you´ve been sent
to take Pradhan´s place?
what to do? Had to come,
- Be seated
List the names of people
you´ve shot till date
l haven´t shot anyone,
- At least the names,..
of those you´ve arrested,
- l haven´t arrested anyone
l´ve just passed out of the academy,
- And you come to take Pradhan´s place?
Pradhan had more scars on his body than
the number of years in your age
´You´ve majored in criminal psychology?
ln one of the dark, dank alleys,..
if you come across a Raghavan, he won´t
quiz you about criminal psychology
He will tear you to pieces,
Far more difficult than nabbing him,..
´will be holding Raghavan behind
the bars, and it´s nearly not to be
The police officer´s job isn´t over
until crime is stamped out
ln your place, Pradhan wouldn´t have
let anyone breathe in peace,..
not you, not l,
until Raghavan hanged
After killing the Defence Minister,
you took a floppy
You´re a small cog in the wheels of
a huge conspiracy, Your role was,..
smaller than the bullets which killed
the Defence Minister, But you know,..
´which finger pulled the trigger,
whose the gun it was,..
and the hand that ordered the gun,
And the hand behind that hand,..
you surely know this much?
- l´m an assassin, Not a traitor
ln my business, the client´s name
isn´t divulged, At no cost
At least, you know,..?
You´re sure to hang
Tell me where the floppy is,
You might be let off lightly
Two sides of the coin
Good and bad
Pretty and ugly
´We need each other, Manu verma
we´ll meet in the office
Supriya,..
lsn´t that your wife´s name?
She´s pretty
Had you not been here now, you´d be
in her arms right now, no?
You aren´t a bad fellow,
You´re a demon
You are where you are because it´s
dangerous for society to let you live
wrong
Absolutely wrong
l am where l am because society
doesn´t want to see it´s own face
Society doesn´t have the guts
to admit that,..
one of society´s faces
is Raghavan too
Abolish laws, set men free, And every
Manu verma might become a Raghavan
Because every Manu verma wants
to become a Raghavan
No Raghavan inside this Manu verma
And till this Manu verma is alive,
no Raghavan can stay alive
Look Raghavan, in a very short while,..
you´ll be wearing a black hood
And that nasty laugh of yours
will be buried forever
A noose goes around your neck, Suddenly,
the ground beneath your feet slips away
And you´re swinging in a hole blacker
than the blackest of your crimes
Noose tightens,.. tightens
´You´ll blabber, your lungs will fight
to breathe, but not a breath
First of all, your heart,..
stops
Then your brain will stop working
And then you, Raghavan,
will be gone for good
Felt nice
Felt very nice
lt´s going to be just the way
you enjoyed telling me about it
But Manu verma, one thing never ends
There´s something that´ll never end
See you at that gallows
There´s something that never ends
Thus it is proven that
the accused killed,..
´the Defence Minister, Yeda Yakub,
Rameez and Pradhan
l pray that the court to pronounce the
harshest sentence for Raghavan Ghatge
ln view of evidence and
depositions by witnesses,..
Raghavan Ghatge son of Sadanand Ghatge
is sentenced to hang until death
That´s all there is to your law?
lf l am to hang, does it make
any difference who hangs me?
´Your hangman, or l myself´
´This is a court, Raghavan,
this is my court
l won´t allow you to ridicule my court,
Take this animal out of the court
l´m an animal? And you are human just
because you carry that wooden hammer?
why,..
do you think your decision
is the last word?
Outside this city lies a vast
jungle, Justice Chowdhury
where the darkness reigns,
ln that court,..
one day, you will stand
where l stand today
And l´ll be where
you are sitting
Until then, stay imprisoned in your
black cloak and await your trial
lf life takes away,
so it gives too, l´m fine
ln school to catch a thief?
Got good news for you,
- Nabbed another thief?
we´re going to see Granny
during the holidays
´This time, we´re going,
- l don´t believe this
Just make sure you buy tickets
for Gita and myself
´What will you be doing here, Papa?
- Vanquishing the evil
Go away, Evil
Lord Ram has a bow and arrows
Get lost
Evil has many lives,
Evil is wiser
Go to your City of Evil
Go home and boast
You don´t know The Evil´s powers
The world will be vanquished
You will be crushed
You will be stamped out
You talk too much
l´m going to abduct you
Then l shall wait for the Redeemer
Evil! You are but Evil!
Do not brag,.. you are not bigger
than the Redeemer
l´ll set to fire your empire
with my tail
Remember, you´re female,..
- Okay
l´ll set afire your
Golden City of Sin
´You have abducted Sita,
l´m going to tell Ram
How will you cross the seas?
You will drown
´The City of Sin is far away,
no phones are not working
O´Redeemer, use the e-mail,
lnform my Ram quickly
Let´s fight a war
´Yes, let´s fight
Let the world be cleansed of sin
´The City of Sin
will thrive forever
Evil will thrive
as long as virtue lives
who are you?
Your killer
Any last wish?
´When you are with me,
l have no wishes
lf you have come to see me at
the gates of Death, the purpose,..
must be more precious than my death,
- Right, Your life
Here´s your pardon,
with the President´s signature
Tell me where the floppy is, Death
will be commuted to life, Look
You´re here to strike a deal?
- l´m giving life,..
to a convict like you,
How can it come for free?
ln my business, the client´s name
isn´t divulged, whatever the price
The price isn´t money,
lt´s life, You know what life means?
Just now, when you met Nita
for the last time,..
´when you held her hand,
when you felt her heartbeat,..
her eyes, her lips,..
it can all be yours, Not now,
ten years on, But you can have her
No one knows anything about this deal
Apart from the Prime Minister
and myself, no one knows anything
´Your last hope, l am
Look Raghavan,..
the hangman is testing his ropes
with a dummy that weighs like you
The doctor and the magistrate must
be here, The doctor has seen you
He´s only waiting to certify your
corpse, The magistrate must be,..
looking at his watch, He has to drop
his kids to school, The hangman,..
must be turning the hood inside out,
His wife might be at home
He might be in a hurry too
After you´re hanged, everyone
will go back to their lives
Only you won´t be here
Live will be the same,
Only you won´t be
So,..
tell me,..
where the floppy is
They´re coming
You can´t escape,.. you can´t!
Are you all right, sir?
No one kills