Sync and corrections by R3V0LV3R.
Okay, Sam, you ready?
I'm gonna mic you up.
Caleb, thanks
for helping out, man.
Thank you.
You're a good little brother,
even though you're adopted.
- Is he adopted?
- No!
- Test the microphone.
- Okay. Test, one, two...
This is the beginnings
of Sam and Nate...
- Yes.
- ...and we have spent
many years together
as best friends...
- Yes.
- ...and now, we're gonna
continue our adventure.
- Our journey.
- Some... wait, wait.
- Wait, wait.
So, this is what
I do for a living.
It's a family-owned business,
and you'll see here
we have a ton
of different kinds of fish,
some morays, some red fins...
There he goes,
Vincent. Okay.
Okay, so you take this,
you put it in the bag,
and you fill it up.
This gives it oxygen
so that they can live in there
for about 24 hours
while they're traveling.
And you take it under
here, you seal it,
and it's all ready
to go. So, that is...
- " That's my life"
- ...what my day job is.
" What a great job."
You wanna do
a dance number on here?
" Oh, a-di-dee-di di-dee-di-dee
di-dee-di-dee-di."
" We're pirates two,
we're pirates three."
" We're pirates four and five."
- Hi, how are you?
- Hey.
Please get off the structure.
- Sorry about that.
- There you go.
- Sorry.
- Thanks.
Okay, so we want to show you
how resourceful we can be.
We're very resourceful.
Winners are resourceful.
- So we have this thing called free time!
- Free time!
Yes, free time.
What we do is we see how
much fun we can have
and how long we can go
without spending one dollar.
So, when we come
play putt-putt,
we bring our own putters,
and then I do this.
Balls galore!
Is that a good way
to end it, Caleb?
Caleb, did you know that you
sister was such an athlete?
So, we come here
to blow off steam, to...
if we're upset about something,
we can come and just hit the
balls and let it all out.
It's part of our free time.
So, we try to see
how long we can go
without spending any money,
and we know the guy's here,
so they let us hit, and...
it's a lot of fun.
I really love going
to batting cages.
You want more?
Should we just do
our singing first?
It'd be another great way
for us to express ourselves.
Not only that, but it'd be
a great chance to travel.
- Sam here...
- I've never left Arizona.
- Never left Arizona.
- Not to say...
I've been down to Tucson,
and I've been up north,
but I've never left Arizona.
" She's never left Arizona."
And I really would love
the opportunity to travel.
" She'd love
the opportunity to travel."
It would be the first time
I'd get to explore the world.
" Explore the world,
circumnavigation."
And I would get to do it
with my best friend,
so that would be even more fun.
" Best friends
potty-trained together"
I'm pretty sure I was
potty-trained before we met.
Okay, I w... I wasn't.
I wasn't.
" Sam and Nate."
" Sam, the best woman
and the best man."
Bam!
Sam, you are
so beautiful blurry.
Why are you so blurry?
'Cause you're an idiot.
- Oh! Watch it, buddy.
- Okay, well, let's go. We have one left.
Put this on you real quick.
Uh...
This is not
an interesting shot at all.
Do you mind if we
go somewhere else?
Um, let's go
to the go-karts.
- No...
- How about Camelback Mountain?
- We could hike up it...
- Why are you laughing?
- ...and do talking.
- Sounds good. Let's do that.
Okay. Let's do it.
Go grab the car.
" Onward."
" Ho."
As we're going,
we're going to finish
filling out our questionnaire.
We have about, like, 20 pages
worth of stuff that we have to fill out.
- No... No...
- Too bad. You have to.
- I have been procrastinating for the past month.
I don't want to fill
those questions out.
- Okay.
- There are too many.
- We're doing it anyway.
- All right, fine.
"What is the worst"...
I know, they always
have the hardest
questions, too.
"What is the worst experience you've
had with your teammate?"
Uh, let's see,
I remember that one time
you came over
and you weren't invited,
and you just knocked
on the door, and I...
- Sorry, I...
- "Excuse me, I just got out of the shower."
Um, no, it's hard
to say with you.
You're so, like,
little miss perfect.
I don't know, like, what's the worst
thing you've ever done to me?
Oh, oh, that's easy for me.
Uh, the time you got so drunk
I had to baby-sit you
for, like, six hours.
- When was that?
- Okay, so Nate got so drunk,
and we went
to a movie earlier,
and so he had eaten popcorn,
and he puked it up and
then he tried to eat...
- I did not! That's sick!
That's gross!
- You don't even remember anything from that night!
- I did not do that.
- Don't film me eating this candy bar.
- I got...
I got her that 'cause...
It's gonna make her
big and fat,
and then she won't have
any choice but to date me.
There'll be so much more
of you to love!
"If a genii granted you
one wish, what would it be?"
- Friends.
- Okay, if the genii granted one wish...
- Uh, that's hard.
- Maybe some better clothes.
- Okay. Okay.
- One wish.
- Uh, my own theme park.
- Okay.
I would want
my own amusement park,
and I would build
roller coasters
that were, like,
themed after my friends.
Like, you would have
your own roller coaster.
- Awesome.
- The Sammy Roller Coaster.
- I'll come and sign autographs.
- Yeah, definitely.
And it would be awesome
because it would be
really, like, curvy like you.
- Thank you.
- But it also will reflect your mood swings.
So, there would be one part
that would be like, "Aah! ".
- And then another part would be...
- Aw, how sad. Amber Alert.
What's an Amber Alert?
It's when a creepy dude puts
you in the back of his truck
and tries
to tickle your wiener.
- Ha ha ha...
- Dude, you are nasty.
Okay, I think
my one wish would be...
It's probably
your scout master!
- That's not funny! That's not funny!
- That's just a bonus.
- What... hey.
- Next question is...
Wait. Sammy,
hang on a second.
- Wait just one second.
- Okay.
I'm not... okay.
Is that a...
that's a gray Honda, right?
It looks...
more blackish?
Steel, maybe?
Steel?
Okay, um, pretty sure
that's probably a gray Honda.
- What reality show...
- That's a gray Honda there.
- What reality show contestant do you relate with?
- That is a gray Honda.
- That's a gray Honda.
- Okay, good job.
Oh, okay, well, on...
on the thing,
on the sign thing
it said gray Honda.
Are you trying to get
out of these questions?
- Yes, I am.
- We're almost done!
I definitely am trying
to get out of the questions.
Stay focused. What reality show
contestant do you relate to?
- I don't...
- Come on!
I don't relate to reality...
first of all reality shows
are the furthest thing away
from reality you could
possibly get.
There's nothing about
reality on those shows.
Okay, if you had to pick one...
and I'm saying
that's a gray Honda,
And the sign said gray Honda.
Do you know how many
gray Honda's there are?
That's probably
the most common car
in the whole entire world.
- All right, okay.
- If you had to pick
the most-selling car
in the world, that's it.
Okay, but what if that's the one
the sign is talking about?
Okay, the chances
are very, very slim.
- I will bet you...
- Okay...
- Okay, I will bet you...
- Reality show!
You'll bet me that you'll
finish the survey right now?
I mean, maybe.
I mean, that's
kind of a big bet,
I don't think the sign
said what color it was.
Okay, what reality show
contestant do you relate with?
Uh, fine!
Flavor Flave!
Okay, if another teammate...
I think that's the gray Honda.
There's no way
that's the Honda.
I will bet you
a million dollars.
I will bet you you stop asking
me these stupid questions.
- If that's the gray Honda from the sign,
- All right, stay focused!
- Come on, we're almost done with this.
- Sam! Sam, wait!
- Stay focused!
- No, Sam, I don't want to do this anymore.
Why am I wasting tape on this?
- Who wants to watch...
- Shh! Listen.
If this is the car, then you have
to stop asking me these questions.
Okay, if this is the car,
you can...
- Okay.
- ...I will throw these out the window.
Throw them
out the window. Yes!
Okay, if this is
the gray Honda on the sign...
Okay, but until then,
we have to stay focused.
- Okay, well, look...
- ...if another team...
drops...
- That is the car.
- That's the car.
Wait, wait.
What do you want?
What should I do?
- Don't get too close.
- I'm not, I'm not.
- I'm just looking at the license.
- What if that is it?
That is it.
That's the license plate.
That's exactly
what the sign said.
It's the same license plate.
Okay, let me call...
That's the same
as the license plate.
That's the same car!
That's it!
Okay, okay,
I'm calling the police.
All right, fine.
He's probably whatever.
He's probably...
It's probably the, um...
like a custody battle or
something, you know what I mean?
It's probably, like, a parent
who wants custody of their kid,
and, you know,
they're just fighting.
It's not like it's like,
you know, serious.
Well, it could be
very, very serious.
- Should I keep taping?
- Samantha Green.
- We're traveling west on the 60...
- You got it?
I feel like we're
on Cops right now.
Okay, I think we see
the Amber Alert car.
No, no, no,
we do see the Amber Alert car.
This is the Amber Alert car.
Yes, gray.
Yes. Yes!
Okay. Um...
You feel like Cops, buddy?
Um, how fast is it going?
- Sixty-five.
- About 65.
Kind of shot like Cops, yeah.
This is Officer Riley.
No, he's going pretty calm,
not erratic at all.
I've been doing this beat
for 20 years.
- Watch the road!
- Just... will you drive?
- I'm all right.
- Be safe!
- I am!
- Okay, yes.
So, should we follow it?
What should we do?
Should we try and get
in front of it?
Okay, okay.
We won't. Okay. Okay.
Um, okay.
- No, we can't see anything inside the...
- Time to switch out the battery.
If we want to, we can just
follow it at a safe distance.
Okay, well, then,
we're not gonna do that.
We got a lot of stuff
we need to do,
so we're not gonna
follow it, obviously.
We're not police officers,
so, whatever.
No, we have to follow it.
Get in the right lane.
What do you mean
we're gonna follow it?
Get in the right lane.
We have to follow it.
No, we don't.
We're not policemen, Sam.
They said we could
as long as...
They said...
they said that we could,
but we don't have to
if we don't want to.
Get in the right lane.
One more over.
- Oh, my god.
- One more over.
Sam, this is...
this is not a good idea.
This is our civic duty,
or our responsibility.
Oh, my god.
Our civic duty?
I mean, to be good
members of the community.
Sam, it's probably some dude
who has a custody battle
over their kid!
It's probably a mom or a dad...
We don't know the story,
and it's not our job...
like you said, we're not cops.
It's not our job to find
out what happened,
it's just our job... we
saw it, we're following.
It's not our job to follow it!
- It's not our job.
- We can! They said we can at a safe distance.
Look, just drive the car.
You called the cops.
That's all we can do.
I mean, how long is it gonna take
for them to get here, anyway?
Okay, there... he's...
bah-bah-bah-bah!
- What? Aw, come on.
- Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry.
You... you said
you called the cops, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay, well then...
- They said...
- They'll be here any minute, right?
Well, they said there was
a ton of calls right now,
and so it could take
up to 15 minutes.
- What?!
- They're probably just eating doughnuts.
Well, I don't want to follow
this guy for 15 minutes.
All right, when you look inside
and it looks like
it's, like, nothing...
You stay normal, and I
will try to look around.
Maybe it's, like, a little old lady
or something and it's a mistake...
can we please just
go about our business?
Little old ladies
could kidnap kids, too.
Caleb, get down!
No, it's fine.
He can't see me.
He's fine.
He's fine!
- Can't see a thing.
- He's fine.
It's tinted.
I can't see anything, either.
I know, I can't see anything.
Okay, let me call again.
I'll tell them that he got off.
- Okay.
- So they know.
Traveling south, we think.
You think this is south?
On... McClintock.
Okay.
Ask them how long
it's gonna take.
How long is it gonna take
for you guys to get here?
We're right here...
I mean, we think
this is the car.
This is the car.
It's the car, and we got
shit we need to do today.
So... and I'm not
a policeman.
- Shh!
- I'm not a... I'm not a police officer!
- I don't care what she hears.
- All right, thank you.
Fifty, right? But I think he's
going way faster than that.
Okay, well, make sure
you get up there.
I am not gonna get... I'm not
gonna break the speed limit.
- You can just... ugh!
- I'm not gonna break the speed limit because...
You're gonna lose him if
you don't get up closer.
Do you know how many points I
have on my license already, Sam?
Get up closer.
I'll take the ticket.
- I have got so many points!
- Just hurry up!
- I'll tell... them.
- All right, I'm driving faster.
Okay, hurry, hurry, hurry.
- I can still...
- You're gonna lose him!
I can still see him.
Do you not care if we lose him?
- If we...
- Do you understand...
- Sam!
- Do you understand what is at stake here?
No, I don't.
Please explain it to me.
This is not like...
this could be anyone.
This could be a little kid all
by themselves in that car.
- Yeah?
- A little kid that could be molested and murdered.
- It's a stepchild.
- A little kid
with their whole life
in front of them,
and we are the one
in between this kid
getting murdered
and killed or not.
No, I don't...
I totally disagree with that.
I think you're blowing this
way out of proportion.
Don't get so close to it!
You're getting... blowing
this way out of proportion.
I think it's better
if we stay back, anyway,
'cause then he won't
be able to...
he can probably see the camera!
We're filming him!
Yeah, Caleb, don't
let him see you.
- He can't see me.
- Okay, he's turning. I'm going straight.
No! No! Go left!
Are you freaking kidding me?
- Go left!
- All right, hang on a second.
- Oh, my gosh, don't lose him!
- I'm fine. We're fine.
Whoa! We're fine.
We're fine. We're fine.
Oh, my gosh, watch that.
- We're fine. We're fine.
- Oh, my gosh!
We're fine.
We're fine. It's just
a little bumpy road.
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
We're gonna lose him!
It's better if we stay back.
That was stupid!
Just stay on the road
and follow him!
Do you not care
about little kids?
Do you not care? Do you
have no heart at all?
Of course I care
about little kids!
You like kids getting
molested and murdered?
I hate that!
That's horrible!
Are you trying to help
this guy molest...
Of course I'm not
trying to help him!
Just stop arguing!
Where did they go?
They're gone!
Right there, right there!
- It's a yellow light. I can't.
- Oh, my gosh! Hurry!
Aw, shit.
Oh, shit, oh, shit.
Nate, you're gonna kill us!
Just hold on.
Aw, shit.
Oh, my gosh. Nate,
what are you doing?!
I'm trying to follow him
so you don't yell at me!
We just ran that red light.
I swear to God,
if I get pulled over
...that Amber back there
it'll be your fault,
and you're gonna pay for my
ticket if I get a ticket!
Just drive like
a normal person...
I am driving like
a normal person,
but you're yelling at me!
Won't you get up there
a little bit closer?!
We're freaking following
him a mile away.
Swear to God if I get
a ticket because of that,
- If there was a camera...
- I cannot believe that you're worried about a stupid ticket.
- There's not a problem.
- Ooh, 60 is average!
There's no child
being molested up here!
Oh, really? You know that?
You know that for a fact!
- I know that for a fact!
- No. No!
So you're thinking they put an
Amber Alert up for no reason.
They just want to see if people
will go chase around a car.
I think that most
of the Amber Alerts...
The police have such a
freakin' sense of humor!
- ...and those people...
- They just think it's hilarious for us to chase around a car...
- I'm not gonna yell over you.
- ...for no reason.
- I'm not gonna scream and yell over you.
- Well, just follow this car...
I'm gonna be quiet
and let you yell at me,
and when you're done yelling
I'll tell you what I think.
- Okay, fine. Go ahead.
- Obviously you don't want to listen to me.
Okay, what?
Oh, my gosh. Here.
- Just... stay back a little bit.
- All right, just calm down.
All right, look. If...
if anything, all...
most of those
are parents who are divorced
and they're having custody
battles with their kids,
and they keep the kids
for the weekend.
Maybe they kept them over
too long over the weekend.
They kept them Monday, Tuesday.
The mom gets pissed
the dad is spending more time...
And if that was the case, fine.
- That's what this is.
- But you don't know what the case is.
And, yes, it's weird
that it's tinted windows,
but everybod... there's a lot of
people that have tinted windows.
It's sunny here!
- He's braking here.
- All right, all right.
Just pay attention! We can't
just goof around about this.
All right, nunchuck me.
- Here you go, Jackie Chan.
- Nice!
- Yes!
- You guys!
Like that's really
gonna hurt any one.
Put those down.
- If he see us...
- I'm sorry.
This is not a joke.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. You're right.
So, not get out
of the car then?
- Come on.
- Get your butt in here.
- Don't get out of the car!
- This is not a joke.
- You're right, I'm sorry.
- Nathan!
- That was stupid. I'm sorry.
- Just be...
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- ...an adult for once.
- Okay, I'm an adult.
- Okay, thank you.
- Now try not to get so close next time.
- I'm sorry.
Look at you!
You are so messed up right now.
- Well, let's just...
- Why are you so upset?
- You don't even know who this person is.
- Well, we don't know
who this person is,
but it could be any one.
- Yeah, but...
- If it was Caleb we would be right up there,
and we would wanna
bang on the door
and break a window
and pull the guy out.
If it were Caleb,
Caleb would kick his ass.
- What? High five.
- No one's touching my wiener.
- It's not a joke.
- You're right, I'm sorry.
It's a little kid that can't...
That can't kick a person's ass.
- You know, like, they're just...
- I know, okay.
- You're right, I'm sorry.
- ...ln there by themselves,
and we're the only ones that can
help them and tell them anything.
- So we need to follow them.
- Hey. Hey, Sam.
- It's just...
- Well, we just need to be on top of it.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't let him get away.
- Don't get upset. Are you okay?
- I'm fine. I'm fine.
Don't worry about me. Just make
sure that we get up there.
I got all this traffic coming.
I can't do anything.
Just keep your eye
on him, okay?
- Just keep looking.
- Caleb, can you see him?
- He just pulled in to the gas station.
- Don't lose him.
I'm not gonna kill us
over this, you know?
- I mean...
- You don't have to kill us.
What is he doing?
Where'd he go? Is that him
right there getting gas?
Gas station...
All right, well,
I don't know what to do.
I mean, like, what are we
supposed to do?
Okay, let's just watch.
Should I park?
What... I mean...
Okay, there he is.
We just sit here,
and we'll just wait.
- What is he doing?
- We're just gonna sit here and wait for him
to start going in, and then we'll just...
- Okay.
...maybe keep
following him, I guess.
- 'Cause we're supposed to...
- Where is he?
Why is he just sitting there?
It's probably because
he knows we're watching him,
and he's watching us.
I know, I can't see anything.
He could be staring
right at us right now.
He probably is.
- There he is.
- If he looks over here,
Caleb, get the camera down.
Well, they could also use
it to help prosecute him.
He looks like
a regular dude, Sam.
He looks like a regular guy.
Look at him.
What do you expect
him to look like?
I mean, I don't know, he's kind
of, like, a good-looking dude.
He's kind of handsome.
I don't know.
I mean, I don't know what
child molesters look like.
- Well, you can't, you know...
- He looks...
- ...go on appearances alone.
- I'm not.
I'm saying he looks
fine, like he...
Why don't you go tackle him?
Oh, yeah.
Like I could take that guy.
- Take him down, Nate.
- Are you serious?
That guy would kick my ass.
Even if he isn't,
you know, like, whatever,
even if he's
completely innocent,
he could still kick my ass.
He's going.
He's leaving.
Yeah, well, just... we'll just
wait for him to come back.
Sam, what are you doing? Sam, you get
your ass back in this car right now!
Shit. Sam. Sam. Sam.
Come back here!
Oh, my god, what the hell
is wrong with her?
What is she doing?
What is she doing?!
Oh, she's calling me.
She's calling me.
Sam...
Sam, you come back
here right now. I'm get...
I'm gonna freaking kill you.
I can't see anything.
It's too dark.
Listen, Sam, if he comes
back, I'll tell you.
Okay, I'll tell you
if he comes back.
- Just listen!
- Keep a lookout for me.
I can't see anything
in this stupid car.
Wait, I see like,
some paper work.
The window!
The window's cracked
a little. I can see in.
- He's not coming yet?
- No, he's not!
Just come back here!
- Oh, my goodness.
- What, what, what?
Hey, little girl.
Hey, can you hear me?
- Wake up!
- Oh, my god.
Can you hear me?
Are you okay?
Hello, can you hear me?
Little girl, wake up!
I can't get her.
Sam, there's
a little girl in the car?
There's a little girl
in the car?
Should I break the window
or something?
No, don't break the...
it's probably his daughter!
It's probably
his daughter, Sam!
What if it's not?
Sam, there's nothing
we can do, okay?
You just need
to come back here.
What are you doing?
He's coming out.
- Sam, he's coming back! He's coming back!
- Tell her to come back.
- Get out of there! Get out of there!
- It's him?
- Yes. Just walk. Just walk.
- Did he see me?
- No. No, he didn't see you. Just walk.
Is he looking at me?
What's he doing?
He's just... he's...
he didn't see you.
You're fine.
Just walk.
Just don't run.
He did not see you.
You're fine.
Just walk over to the car.
Everything is fine.
- Does he see me?
- Nope. No, he's not looking. No, he's not looking.
- He didn't see you.
- Oh, my gosh, there's a little girl in the backseat.
That was so stupid!
I cannot believe you did that!
There was a little girl
in the backseat.
Okay, so give me the
camera. I put my mic...
- I put my mic in the backseat.
- What? Why did you do that?
Because if we have a headset,
we can put the headset
in the camera
and listen to what's
going on in there.
Well, yeah, but what about...
the little girl's probably his daughter!
We'll know!
We'll be able to tell!
All right, all right,
all right, let me...
- Do we have a headset?
- I don't... no, I don't have a... no!
- He's leaving!
- Where's your...
We have to follow him.
We have to save...
All right, hang on.
Here, use my auxiliary cable.
- Here, hook it into the back.
- ...receiving.
- We should be able to hear it on the car speakers.
- ...plugged in.
It's on...
It's on the...
it's on the wrong thing.
Here... here,
push that.
God, I hope this works.
How's that?
- No, that's something.
- Don't get too close to him.
And, Caleb, get down. If we're
close, we don't want him to see us.
We're not gonna get too close.
What is that?
- Is that in his car?
- Uh, yeah, I think it is.
- Hi, I...
- You totally did it.
- It works.
- That's totally in his car.
Oh, my god. I cannot
believe you did this.
This is so crazy.
You know how many laws
we're breaking right now?
Who cares about laws?
You're freakin'
MacGyver here.
That's 7028.
What'd he say?
I don't know, 7028?
Okay...
that's what he said.
- That was his address.
- Thank you.
7028.
Well, um, I'm just
looking at my bill,
and there's this charge for..
- Where's the little girl?
- Yeah, she's sleeping...
...$95, and I don't
text that much,
So I'm wondering...
He's talking
to his phone provider!
He's talking about his bill
- Why is that so funny?
- Because!
I'm not...
Why is that funny?
I just think it's funny
because, you know...
- I don't text.
- Listen to him!
Listen to him!
He sounds so casual.
He's talking about his bill.
It's not like he's...
Don't you think if he
kidnapped a little girl
he wouldn't be talking to his
phone provider about his bill?
Just because he's talking
to his phone provider...
- You need to stay close...
- I'm trying.
I'm going as fast
as I can here.
- I mean...
- Just because he's talking to his phone provider,
I mean, molesters have phones.
- Yeah, but, I mean...
- You're going out of the max range.
- You can't go that far.
- Did we lose him?
- We gotta get closer.
- Aw, shit reception!
Oh, there he is,
oh, there he is.
- Yes, Sandhill.
- Stay up with him.
Sandhill!
That could be,
like, his password
or the name of something.
- Could be nothing.
- Or his address.
- Sandhill...
- Or a city? I don't know.
Hey, I did that.
- Just be quiet a minute.
- I don't know, like...
Sandhill Apartments
or Sandhill Retirement Home.
You should be up close to him.
I don't have time for this.
I need to, uh...
Is it his last name,
Mr. Sandhill?
- Could be.
- I mean, I don't know.
- Shh, just listen!
My ex-wife doesn't have a line
to my phone, does she?
My ex-wife doesn't
have a line to my phone.
- Okay...
- He has an ex-wife.
If he has an ex-wife,
why did she divorce him?
Well, she's obviously
still alive.
- You know I don't text!
- Maybe he's not a murderer.
It's not the...
it's not the money.
Don't you think if he was gonna
kill somebody, it'd be his ex-wife?
Maybe he did kill her.
Oh, that's classic.
Yeah, your supervisor
can call me back
at his... or her...
earliest convenience.
The one that I called from.
This phone.
- Yes, it's 602...
- Get his phone number!
602...
No, you've done
a great job. Thanks.
Uh...
That's it.
That's the number.
All right, great!
Give me the number.
I'll give him a call right now.
- I'll call him right now...
- Oh, yeah, you're gonna call him? No!
- I'm gonna get involved!
- We can give it to the police.
The police will know...
they can track it
and find out exactly who he is.
Give me the number. I'll call
him and be like, "Hey! ".
- Shut up!
- "Are you a child molester?"
Now, that would put
the kid in danger.
Oh, shit, okay, here we go.
All right.
Don't get too close to him.
I'm not, I'm not, I'm not.
I'm not getting too close.
Put your camera down.
What road are we on?
- I have no idea.
- Okay, he's pulling over.
- Yeah, well, good!
- He's pulling over.
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Sam!
Whoa... Sam!
Don't ever grab the...
Why isn't he getting out? Why
isn't he coming over yet?
He's gonna come over here and kick
my ass, that's what he's gonna do!
He's gonna come over here...
he might have a gun!
He might have a bat,
a crowbar...
Do we have a bat?
Do we have something
that we can protect
ourselves...
No, we don't have any weapons!
There's three of us
and one of him.
My nunchucks,
that's what we have.
Okay? Maybe we could nunchuck
him with the padded nunchucks.
- Oh, my gosh.
- What? Oh, god.
- He's getting out.
- I'm driving. I'm getting out of here.
Caleb, get down. Give me the camera.
Give me the camera.
- This is a bad idea.
- You are just not listening.
Hide the camera, for God's sakes!
I can still see it.
- I'm hiding it.
- This guy could kill us!
- How about right there?
- Is he looking at me?
Oh, my gosh, he's coming up!
He's coming up!
- Lock the door!
- All right, all right.
- What is he gonna say?
- I don't know.
Maybe we should just...
I'm just gonna drive.
- No! No!
- Yeah, get out of here!
What am I supposed
to say to him?
We can't just leave
the little girl here.
What am I supposed
to say to him, Sam?
I don't know.
Okay, roll the window down.
Do not roll down the window!
- Roll it down.
- I don't want to roll it down.
- Hi.
- Oh, shit.
- Problem? Having some car problems?
- Hey!
- Oh, uh, are you okay?
- No, we're not having car problems.
Is your car? Are you having
problems with your car?
- No, we saw... we saw...
- Pulled off,
and thought you maybe
you had some problems,
so we pulled off
to see if you were okay.
You been following me to find
out if my car is running okay?
- Yeah...
- No! No!
Your car looks like
my buddy's car, actually.
No, we are following
you because...
I-I know why you're
following me, okay?
I-I think it's
that Amber Alert.
- Yeah!
- Okay.
- Uh...
- And you have a little girl in your car.
- Yes, I do.
- Uh, is she okay?
- Yes, that's my daughter.
- And we're gonna call the police right now.
I've already talked
to the police. It's fine.
And you have
to stay right here.
No, I've talked to the
police. That's fine.
Have them come here,
I'll talk to them again.
Believe me, it shocked
the hell out of me.
I saw my license plate
on the Amber Alert.
So I'm actually kind of surprised
that you were paying attention,
and now we're here.
So, I just wanted to clarify
and clear the air and come
talk to you personally.
It's my daughter.
I'm trying to get her
back to my ex-wife.
I'm about ten miles away,
and I'm a day late.
Okay, well, if someone
is on the Amber Alert
we can't really trust, like...
- Well, I know...
- Well...
You could be a big fat liar
for all we know.
Well, Sam, I mean, it's kind of what
I've been saying the whole time.
I mean, I-I...
this kind of thing
happens all the time...
- No, yeah.
- ...with custody battles or whatever.
This is exactly
what I've been saying!
- Well, I...
- I know I sound like a...
it's a typical story.
I got a crazy ex-wife.
I never get to see my child,
and I finally got her
for a weekend
and I kept her a little long.
- Yeah.
- That's the story.
- And I am a day late.
- Man...
Talk to the cops.
I've worked it all out.
You can call them.
I just got off the phone.
I've got the number.
The phone is in my car.
We can go talk to them
together, if you'd like.
- Okay, yes. Yes.
- No, no, no. No, Sam!
- We want to call the police.
- No, Sam! Hey, hey!
- We need to make sure it's okay.
- Sam, we don't need to do that.
- We've done enough.
- Or, better yet, my daughter's in the car.
We can wake her up
and talk to her.
- Yes!
- No, don't worry about that.
- Would you like to do that?
- Let's wake her up!
- Let's go.
- No, no, no, don't worry about it.
- Yes!
- We have bothered you enough.
We've been following you,
and I'm really embarrassed.
And to tell you the truth, I
just feel like a freaking idiot!
- No, no, no, don't feel like an idiot.
- I feel so stupid!
I think it's wonderful.
I think it's amazing
that you guys were actually
paying attention and...
That's real nice that you...
thanks for being
so cool about it.
Well, well, cool? No! No, you
were on the Amber Alert.
- I know.
- He just... Sam!
- Believe me, I was shocked my self.
- We need to call the police.
He just explained that
it's probably... I mean...
- Okay, well...
- ...his ex-wife.
Obviously you're not good
with this, you're not cool,
- So what do I need to do?
- No, I'm not cool, because...
- What do I need to do?
- Who knows?
I just...
I don't trust...
I don't know you,
I don't trust you.
I just want to make sure
the little girl is okay.
- Sam...
- Do you want to come to my ex-wife's house?
- I'm ten miles away.
- Listen, listen.
Just hang on
one second. Sam.
I think we...
this is embarrassing.
This is embarrassing,
and he's obviously
just a regular dude,
- And this is stupid.
- Are you sure? Are you sure?
- This is stupid!
- I'll do whatever you need.
You can call the cops,
you can look at my ID..
- We appreciate it, man.
- ...talk to my daughter, whatever you need.
We really appreciate it, man,
for you being so nice.
I think it's amazing
you guys were doing this.
I thought you'd be
so pissed off
'cause we've been
following you or whatever.
No, I was a little concerned,
but I kinda figured it out.
When did you...
when did you notice us.
I thought I was being
pretty stealthy, actually.
I thought I was
hiding pretty good.
You've been watching
too many movies.
Okay...
Okay, yeah, I guess so.
Okay, well, are we okay?
All right...
- Are you sure?
- Sam, it's fine.
He's... it's fine, dude.
It's fine, dude.
Thank you. Thank you for
being so cool about this.
I'm sorry for all the...
I feel stupid about it.
I feel really stupid.
You've got my license plate.
- Turn me in.
- Yes, definitely.
Okay, good-bye!
Have a good...
have a good night!
So, wasted an entire day
doing this stupid shit.
Let's just cut
our losses and go.
We lost a microphone.
Let's just go, okay?
Obviously he's a regular guy.
He seems like
a regular, nice guy
who is having serious problems
with his ex-wife.
We know he had
an ex-wife. I mean...
Oh, he's pissed.
I mean...
That does not seem
like the same guy...
- We're going home.
- See? Something shady.
Naw, he seems...
he's just pissed off about...
he's just pissed off at us!
Get up!
Is that my daddy?
I told you, you're not
seeing your daddy again.
I'm scared.
I don't care!
Just shut up!
- Nate! Nate!
- Oh, my god.
Oh, my gosh!
I know, I know, I know, I know.
We let him go!
I know!
I'm sorry.
Okay, okay, turn around.
I'm calling the police.
- I'm calling the police.
- Sam, we're not gonna turn around!
He went that way!
I saw him go that way!
- Oh, my...
- We have to turn around, the next turn!
Look, all right!
All right!
I'm sorry,
but I still don't think
we need to keep
following him, though!
Oh, my gosh!
Are you kidding me?
You let him get away!
You let a little girl
who's gonna be killed...!
No, Sam, there's...
what are we supposed to do?
What are we supposed to do?
He's obviously an...
Hello? Hello, yes!
We were following
an Amber Alert car.
Tell the police to hurry up!
He pulled over, we pulled
over to talk to him.
We thought
he was fine! He...
- We heard the car...
- Sam, quit screaming.
Just talk to the lady.
We heard him, and he was
saying that he was gonna...
it wasn't his dad!
It wasn't her dad!
We need... well... well,
we have a microphone...
we put a microphone in the car.
I know! We wouldn't have
been following them
and talk to him if
you guys would show up!
There's no police!
We haven't seen any police yet!
We have to turn around!
We have to follow them!
Sam, just talk to the lady.
We are gonna follow them!
This dude could hurt us
if we follow him.
We're on 347.
They're going south.
We saw.
He's going south.
Yes, we are gonna follow them!
- No.
- Well, if there were police here we wouldn't have to!
- Sam, we can't follow him.
- Yeah!
Sam, we... we...
if we follow him...
Okay, turn around! Now,
turn around and go back!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Did you hang up on her?
- You let him go!
- I know...
- Because, Sam...
- You talked me into it!
- Sam...
- You talked me into leaving!
- I know, because...
- You talked me into leaving the little girl!
- Sam!
- Right here!
- Okay, okay, okay, okay!
- Turn the car around!
- Sam! Sam!
- We cannot leave her!
- Sam! Sam! Sam!
- We have to!
- Sam, listen.
- We have to follow them!
- I'm gonna turn...
- Sam, I'm gonna turn around, okay?
- Okay, we have to hurry!
- Okay, just stop.
Just listen to me
for a second! Just listen!
He's gone already.
I know, we lost reception, obviously,
because we're too far away!
We have to hurry!
Move, car!
That is not fair for you
to put that on me!
- Go around! Go around!
- Do not put that on me.
Like I... like it's
all my fault!
It's my fault too!
I should've followed my gut.
I should've said,
"Shut up! Shut up!"
And we need to get in that car!
That's what I should've done.
I should've gone with my gut!
- No!
- And, no, I don't!
I just listen to you and I
don't know what I was thinking!
I'm going over...
I'm pushing 100, Sam!
- I'm pushing 100 miles an hour.
- Come on, come on, come on.
We are gonna catch him, okay?
We're gonna catch up to him,
we're gonna find him.
- I...
- Can you see him?
I can't tell.
I don't even think...
that looks like
a Mercedes to me.
I don't think that's him, Sam.
- No, that's him.
- Maybe I can zoom in.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, that is him.
Get up there.
Get up there closer.
All right.
All right!
- All right.
- Oh, shit, that is him.
That is him, you're right.
- I don't want to...
- You have to stay up there with him!
What are we supposed
to do, ram him off the road?
Sam, if he sees our car he might
do something to the little girl.
He's already gonna do
something to the little girl!
Yeah, but he knows
what our car looks like!
Just stay so we can see him.
Sam! Sam!
There's a police car!
- Oh, my gosh.
- There's a police car right behind us!
Oh, my gosh! Yay!
Freakin' finally.
You're going down, buddy!
- You see him!
- Nail his ass!
Oh, man, this is
gonna be great.
Caleb, keep filming it, man.
I'm getting it.
I'm filming.
Make sure we get all of this.
Whoo!
Whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo!
There he is!
- Pull over.
- Get him! Get him! Get him!
Go! You gotta get him!
He's the Amber Alert car!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
That's the car!!!
That's from the Amber Alert!
That's the Amber Alert car
right there!
Is this guy an idiot!
Look at the license plate!
Sam! Sam, Sam, he wants
me to pull over.
- No, because...
- No, no, no, no!
He'll figure it out
eventually. Keep going!
No, no, no,
he's pulling me over!
No, go out in the left lane.
Go in the left lane!
Nate, just keep going!
I can't!
It's a police officer!
No, we can't let him
get away again!
- I'm pulling off. I have to!
- No! No, no, no, no!
All right, just...
just relax...
Oh, my gosh.
No, no, no, no, no!
Just stay in the car
and we'll explain it to him!
- Just stay in the car and we'll explain it to him!
- No, I have to tell him!
No! Ugh!
What should we do?
Should we get out?
All right. Sam!
No!
What part of "pull over"
don't you guys understand?
What the hell is going on?
- Keep going!
- ...Amber Alert car.
- What car?
- It's a gray Honda...
...Amber Alert.
When did you guys see it?
Like, an hour and a half ago.
I'm telling you,
it's right there!
We've been following
him for hours.
- All right, stay there.
- Go get him!
There's a little girl
at stake right now!
Relax.
Stay right there.
Just relax. Sam,
he is on our side.
I think that, you know,
he's gonna help us out.
He's long gone by now.
Okay, he's just gonna be gone.
No, he's... no, he's not.
No, he's not, Sam!
He's calling in right now.
He's gonna check it,
and do you think that...
do you think that that...
the Honda can outrun this, the police car?
- Hurry, hurry.
He's gonna catch up to him, and
everything's gonna be fine, okay?
I guess we just need to...
he's on our side!
You said gray Honda, right?
- Gray Honda, yes.
- All right.
They confirmed
there is the Amber Alert.
- I'll go track him down.
- Okay, great!
You guys, I need you to go back
to the sheriff's office,
- Go back to the station...
- Okay.
- Make sure you find the deputies there.
They're gonna want to take your
statements and see that video.
- Okay.
- All right?
We'll definitely show them
the video and everything.
Go ahead and shut it off.
You can't videotape while we're
out here on the highway.
Shut it off.
Come on.
All right, well,
we should get in the car.
We should go.
We should keep looking.
What do you mean, get in the
car and go and keep looking?
Well, this, you know, we should
keep looking till they find her.
- What, no! No!
- Right?
That's what we just
talked to him about.
We actually were face to face
with a real police officer,
- And they're taking care of it.
- I know.
- No, I know, it's great, but we...
- Don't you...
The more eyes out there
looking for her, the better.
- All right...
- You know how long it took us to find him?
- And then we want to make sure.
- I was just kinda...
Stop complaining
with me and let's go.
Can we at least stop
and get something to eat?
No!
...that she's all right.
That's when I'll be happy.
- So, go right at this light.
- Okay, got it.
Okay, so take a right
at this street.
Should we talk
to these people, or...?
No, those are just kids.
What's this car up here?
It looks like a gray
Honda or something.
This all feels really,
like, just pointless to me.
Don't you think
this feels kinda like...
Well, it's pointless
unless we find her.
I mean... ah.
- This just seems like...
- It only takes one street,
one car that we happen
to see, you know?
I mean, I know
it's a long shot, but...
It is! It...
...but why not take
the long shot?
It's a long shot.
'Cause it's worth it.
Go left here.
I'm just trying
to be realistic, Samantha.
It's definitely, like,
needle-in-a-hay stack situation.
Officer Murray
gave me this number,
and I just wanted
to call and see
if there was any word
about the Amber Alert.
They're not gonna
know anything yet.
Yeah, they would know
if they found her.
Blood sugar is really low,
and I just...
my hands are shaking.
I needs something to eat.
Don't be such a baby.
I'm not being a baby!
I'm just saying, we haven't
eaten anything all day.
I'm starving.
It's been a crazy day today.
Can we at least get something to eat?
That's all I'm saying.
All right, like,
20 more minutes.
20 minutes?! Why are
you, like, so gung-ho?
Like, we have...
there's a police officer...
Hello? There's
a little girl missing!
I know!
You keep saying that.
I'm trying to do
the right thing here.
I'm driving around,
but there's nothing we can do!
It's gone!
They're gone!
Well, we just have
to keep looking.
She's probably... I'm saying
she's probably already dead!
Don't say that!
If we had tried
to attack him back there,
he probably would've
killed us, okay?
For all we know.
I don't know.
But think about her.
- Think? I am think...
- Think about her.
I don't give a shit
about her! How about that?
about that little girl!
I don't care about her!
Why would you say that?
I don't care!
What is wrong with you?
I don't care about her!
I want... I want us
to be safe.
- I am not a police officer!
- She needs help!
She is alone in the car.
She has nobody!
There's three of us.
We have each other.
She has no one!
No one except that
slimy, disgusting freak!
Just how can you
not care about her?
I do, I care.
What if it was Caleb?
What if it was me?
What if I was in that car?
- Sam...
- What if he had me in there?
I love you more than anything
in the whole world, Sam.
If it were you,
it would be different.
If it were you, it would
be totally different.
What are you doing?
What are we doing?
I'm hungry.
Do you want me to keep filming?
Yeah, yeah. We need
to keep filming.
I mean, that's our one...
last chance, our
one last hope of...
him still being out there.
We could still hear him.
The car's off.
Dang it.
Um... do we have...
that headset around
here somewhere?
All right, put these in.
Keep the camera on.
Let's keep listening.
I'll listen.
Hopefully we'll hear something.
I just wanted to talk
to Officer Murray.
Is there any news at all?
All right, is there
anything that we can do?
He got called away.
They don't even...
I can't even talk
to him for an hour,
but obviously
they haven't found anything.
They don't know anything.
Nobody's looking for her.
- No, no, we need to hear.
- Shut it off.
Just in case we...
in case he drives by
or he lives around here,
we'll be able to hear him.
We're gonna keep filming.
What are you doing?
Sandhill. Maybe
it's his address.
I'm gonna do a search.
What are you
talking about, Sandhill?
He said "Sandhill"
on the phone.
We didn't know why,
but I'm just gonna check
and see if there's
a street around here.
Sandhill.
Sam, I-I...
I don't know how to deal
with this situation,
and I've handled it
badly, and I screwed up,
and I just feel like
I need to say I'm sorry,
that I feel like our
friendship is more important.
There's a Sandhill Road.
Two and a half minutes
to get there.
We have to go.
We have to at least
check it out.
We have to see, I mean...
if it's where he lives.
He... that's where
he would take her.
- Right here.
- ...like a thing that just goes on and on.
- Okay, right here. I got it.
I'm not trying to be...
like, I'll stay up
with you all night,
you know, if I have to,
but at the same time...
- Take a left.
- ...there has to be a point
where you have
to call it quits.
You know what I mean?
For all we know,
a lot of time has gone by.
We could take the footage
to the cops.
We'll tell them Sandhill Road.
We'll give them
that information,
and that...
and that'll be it, right?
Yeah, I...
That'll be it, right, Sam?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That'll be it.
Okay, so take a right here.
This should be it.
Right here.
Mm-hmm. Sandhill.
That's it.
Sandhill Road. Yep.
- All right.
We're here.
Just go super slow.
We just gotta listen.
I don't hear anything.
Maybe stay closer
to the right-hand...
- Okay. All right.
- ...of the way, here.
All right, and then all right.
Oh, look, I think
this is it, Sam.
This is the whole street.
Okay, well, turn around,
and we'll stay
on the other side
on the way back.
Not much to it,
and, uh, I didn't hear anything.
Now, is there
another Sandhill Road?
Is there somewhere else?
I mean, there has...
is this it?
No. This is it.
All right. I mean...
Okay, just sitting...
This is it.
Okay, keep going slow.
I'm going as slow as I can.
I mean, there's only...
one, two, three...
like, ten houses.
We could knock on each door
and find out exactly
who lives in them...
Sam, no.
We're not doing that.
...and what
is going on.
We're not doing that.
What if you knocked
on his door?
on the guy's door?
Then at least we'd find him
and we'd at least
know where he is.
That'd be the last door you
knocked on in your life, okay?
Okay, turn around.
Do a U-turn.
I mean, even if we knocked
on his neighbor's doors,
there... I mean...
Maybe they would
recognize his car.
If we went and said, you know,
"Have you seen
this car in the area?"
Well, look for his car!
I don't even see it.
I don't see his car.
Well, there's garages.
I don't... I mean,
yeah, I guess
he parked it
in the garage, I don't know.
Is this turned up?
Yeah, it's turned up.
I mean, they could
be quiet right now...
I don't know.
You think that
the microphone would give off
some kind of signal
or interference or something.
Maybe you'd hear something.
I don't hear anything.
All right.
I think that...
I think that might be it, Sam.
I don't...
if the microphone were here,
we'd be able
to pick it up, you know?
- So...
- I know.
I haven't heard anything,
so I think that...
we should just...
call it quits, okay?
I mean, there's
nothing else we can do.
Yeah.
We gotta get
Caleb back home, too.
I mean, like, this isn't
fair to your bro.
I was just hoping
that we'd be able
to find something, you know?
I know. I know.
I did, too.
I know.
I understand.
I just don't know
what else to do.
Sam, there's nothing more
you could've done.
Sam, you've done everything.
You've gone above and beyond
what any normal person
would've done.
You've done more than what
any one else would've done.
But it's sad that it's
obviously not enough.
Like, we don't know
what's going on
right now with her,
where she is...
- I know.
- It's just so hard.
It's be a horrible day,
so I'm just gonna
take you home...
and we'll give
the footage to the police,
um, in the morning,
or what, you know...
We could drop...
we could stop by
the police station
and give them
all the information
that we have.
Okay, we'll do that. We'll stop
by the police station and then...
...wait
a whole night.
Okay, we'll give it
to them tonight,
and then tomorrow, you know...
Did you hear...
- Did you hear that?
- Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
- Is that...?
- That's the microphone.
That is it!
Go back!
That's the microphone, okay.
- What is that noise?
- I don't know. I don't know.
We must've just passed it.
I don't know why it just
picked up the signal.
Okay, it has to be...
it has to be one
of these two houses right here.
Yeah. Yep.
I think so. Okay.
- Keep going.
- I don't see any lights on.
No, it has to be
those two up there.
No, you're right.
The signal gets...
Call the police!
All right. I'm all right.
I'm gonna call the police.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna call the police.
What is that noise?
What are they doing?
Hello? Hello,
this is...
yes, this is an emergency.
I wanna see my mommy
and my daddy.
- Nathan Riley.
- Tell them she's still alive.
- I'm hearing her voice.
- Nate, tell them to hurry up!
- Ma'am.
- She's in there.
Yes, we've be following
this car all day,
the Amber Alert.
Wait! Sam,
what are you doing?
- Shh!
- Sam!
Oh, my...
yes, ma'am, I'm here.
No, no. I'm...
everything's fine.
I mean, my friend
just got out of the car.
So... no, she's...
she's safe. It's fine.
Listen, we've been following
this car all day
for the Amber Alert that...
the gray Honda.
Called off? Why? Why did
you call off the Amber...?
I don't understand.
No, ma'am!
No, it's a real emergency.
Listen. We are
at the guy's house, okay?
We... we found
where he lives,
and we need you
to get a patrol car
out to Sandhill Road.
It's this tiny
little neighborhood.
Sandhill Road.
I don't... I...
it's one of the houses
in this neighborhood.
I hear a metal noise,
whatever it is,
I hear it coming
from this house.
- It's in there?
- It's this one right here.
- It's this one.
- Okay, yes, ma'am.
Sandhill Road.
- Okay, pull up over here.
- Okay, all right. All right.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Yes, ma'am.
We won't.
We won't do anything.
Okay, you're sending
a patrol car?!
No, ma'am, we're fine.
I'm just talking to my friend.
We're fine.
We're just... aw!
- Are they coming?
- Yes, thank you. Thank you.
Leave me alone.
This will be fun.
We 're just...
we're just, uh...
we're playing, right?
- Oh, my... oh, my...
- That's all.
- What are we gonna do?
- God, that's so gross.
- This asshole!
- What...
What can we do, Sam?
The police will be
here any second.
- Mommy...
- She's scared.
I know... I know.
Of course she is.
What if we ran your car
into the house?
I don't like you!
What? What are you
talking about?
- Sweetheart...
- I'm scared.
- Okay...
- No, we're not gonna run our car into the house.
At least throw a brick
into the window.
- I mean...
- That'll stop him, won't it?
No. It might
make things worse!
If you even think
about screaming...
- What is he talking about?
- Or running, I promise you,
I will go back to your house
and I will kill
your mommy and your daddy.
- What is he... what?
- This freakin' guy's sick.
- I want my mommy.
- We have to do something.
We have to do something.
You have two choices,
here, little girl.
You can either do
what I ask you to do...
What does he mean
he's gonna kill her parents?
...or I will force you
to do it.
- And I might like that just a little bit more.
- Oh...
- What a...
- Do you understand?
He said he's gonna kill...
he's gonna kill her parents.
I wonder if he's
just scaring here.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
I mean, maybe
he's murderer, too.
- I guess he's a murd... what?
- Shh. Hello.
Um, turn it down.
Turn the volume down.
Do what? Shit!
Um, hi. This is
the supervisor.
We, um, you talked
to one of my employees
earlier about text messaging...
Oh, right, right, right, right.
And the, uh, I know it's late,
but we were re viewing
your case, your account,
- And...
- Free texting.
Give him free texting!
We, um, we have
a great opportunity for you.
A limited time only,
we can offer you
three free months of texting.
Free Internet, free text...
Free Inter...
free Internet.
- Promotional deal.
- It's a promotional deal.
You need to shut up.
You're too loud.
Uh, yeah. All you have to do
is do, like, a short survey.
- Yeah, yeah, that's good.
- And it'll only take a few minutes.
And we'll give you
$200 cash credit.
- $500.
- $500 cash credit.
No. No, no, no.
No, it's not valued...
valuable tomorrow.
- It's only good for tonight.
- Right, that's it.
Tonight, we have
to do it tonight.
We're working on our numbers.
Give me the phone.
I want to talk to him.
- Um...
- I'll be the survey guy.
- Hello?
- What?
- What is it?
What, what, what, what?
- He hung up.
- Oh, shit.
We gotta turn it back up.
- Uhh!
- What is going on?
Okay. Now, I'm just
coming back there, okay?
- I just want to come back...
- Oh, my goodness.
Oh, my goodness,
we have to do something.
I can't just sit here.
Sam, we have to wait
for the police!
They'll be here any second.
- We have to do something.
- I know. They're...
- I can't sit here. I can't sit here.
- Sam! Sam!
Sam, the police are gonna
be here any second, okay?
It'll be any second.
Why aren't they talking?
What is he doing?
What is he doing?!
- What is he doing to her?
- I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't know. Shit.
Hurry, hurry,
hurry, hurry, hurry.
Uh, I...
Come on, come on, come on!
I... I can't.
I can't sit here.
Wh... Whoa, Sam, wait!
What are you doing?!
Sam, where are you going?
Sam!
Sam! Get back
in the car.
Shit! Sam!
Listen, I'm gonna
go to the store,
and I'm gonna pick up some
candy for our party tonight.
Oh, God!
Sam, he's coming...
he's coming out of the house!
He's coming out of the house!
- I'm gonna go to the store...
- He's coming out of the house!
Get in the car!
...and I'll be
right back, all right?
- He's coming out?
- Yes, yes, yes!
- He's leaving.
- But why?
Wait, wait, wait. He said he was going
to the store to get some candy.
What he said... Caleb,
is that what he said?
- Yeah, that's what he said.
- He's going to the store.
- Okay, get down! Get down!
- He's gonna come out.
- He's coming out?
- Yes, yes, yes.
You think he'll
leave her inside?
I don't know! I don't know
what his plans are!
He told her he'd be right back.
- I don't see anything.
- Caleb, you've got to stay down.
Stay down.
I just don't wanna... I just
hope he doesn't see our car.
Oh, my god, I hope
he doesn't see our car.
Get down!
Oh, shit, that's him.
That... he... I saw him wa...
he got in...
he got in that car.
That... that...
that's not his car, though!
That's not his car. It's,
like, a white minivan.
Get... Caleb, you'd
better get down!
I'm down.
He can't see me.
Okay, okay, he's going.
I don't think he saw us.
I don't think he saw our car.
Okay good.
He's gone!
Whoa-ho! Whoa, Sam!
Damn it!
Sam! Sa...
Where are you guys going?
Sam, come back!
Come back!
Pick up, pick up the phone,
Sam! Pick up the phone!
Okay, she's coming back.
She's coming back.
She's coming back right now.
Get in the car!
Okay, I couldn't see anything.
I need, like, a flashlight.
- Sam...
- Do we have, like, a flashlight in here?
If he caught you
if he came back
from the store
and he caught you,
what are you thinking?
Is there a light
on that camera?
- Sam...
- I mean...
Okay, here's our window.
We gotta go right now.
- No!
- I need both hands.
I need one of you
to come and help me.
You need to light
the way so I can
grab her and get in
and do all that.
Sam, the police are gonna
be here any second, okay?
He could be back
any second, too.
Yeah, exactly.
He could be back.
And he has a gun
and he could kill you.
Caleb, I need you
to come with me.
We just need to wait
for the police.
No, Caleb is not going, no!
- Nate!
- Are you kidding me?
- He's your little brother!
- Okay, give me the camera.
- What are you talking about?
- This isn't a good idea!
The police are gonna
be here any second. Sam!
Come on!
Oh, it's...
How do I get this off?
Hey. Ow! It's me!
It's me! It's just me!
Oh, my gosh, Nate,
do not do that.
Let's just get this over with.
This is just... they're,
like, screwed in too tight.
- Uhh!
- Yeah, is it... it's locked?
Yeah, it's locked.
Here, let me try.
Uhh! Uhh!
Uhh! Sam, there is
no way in this house.
Aw, shit!
Sam, what are you doing?
Be careful!
You are gonna cut yourself!
- Here, hold the camera.
- All right. Ah... I got it.
All right, so the garage has to
be on the opposite of this wall.
It's definitely on the
other side of the house.
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Let's go...
- Okay, shine the light in here. Yep.
- Okay.
Hey, now, wh... what?
Turn it off!
We gotta go, Sam!
It's too loud, come on!
Let's go! Come on,
come on, come on!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, my god.
She's not in there.
Where would she be?
...Down here.
It's not in here.
- I don't see it.
- Are you sure it's not in here?
Where else would she be?
I need some light!
Look, look, Sam. There's
something wrong with that.
The girl's not here,
the mic's not here.
Don't you think there's
something wrong with that?
Well, we need to find the girl.
Okay, well, he said
he was gonna go to the store.
- Put the light up there.
- I don't...
See if we can see. It looks
like an attic or something?
All right, just be
careful, all right?
I got the ladder.
I'm holding on, all right?
- She up there?
- I don't see anything.
Oh, my...
Wh-what? What is it?
I don't know.
It's like a bat or something.
All right, come on.
Come on, get down.
I got you.
We have to do this quick, Sam!
He could be back any second.
I mean, I don't know
how far away...
- Stay with me.
- All right, all right, I'm here.
I need to see the light.
All right, come on,
come on, keep going.
Nothing there...
- I don't know where else she could be.
- Oh, my god.
Oh, my god, Sam, he's got,
like, a full arsenal
of weapons over here.
Uh, this gun
is completely loaded!
They're probably all loaded.
Come on, Nate!
Oh, shit.
Damn it!
I need the light.
I can't see anything!
I know, Sam, I'm just saying,
like, he's got a lot of guns.
- Hello, little girl!
- Little girl, if you can hear us, make a noise!
Aw, shit.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh!
Oh, my god!
Psycho!
What is this?
What the hell is this?
Hurry! Come on!
Come on!
- We have to find her!
- I know, Sam, but look!
- Come on, we have to find her!
- Jesus!
Oh, my god.
Wait! Wait!
- Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
- Come on!
Shh! Shut up!
Nate, if you don't follow me,
I can't see anything!
- Sam! There's something here. I heard something!
- Come on!
There's nothing in here!
Come on, let's go!
Let's go!
No, no, no.
Hello?
- I can't see anything without you!
- I'm... Okay, I'm...
this is it, Sam!
This is the end of the house!
- There's nothing left!
- ...door.
- What, is it locked?
- It's locked.
All right, here.
Take this.
She has to be in there.
Aw, shit.
All right.
Ohh! Here, I'll take it.
I'll take it.
I got it.
Oh, my god.
What is this place. What...
Right over here. Put it over here.
Let me see.
- This is some kind of...
- Is there anything back there?
Some kind of trophy room
or something.
Now, careful.
There's a lot of...
Hello? Ugh!
Oh... don't touch it.
We have to be faster, Sam.
I mean, this is...
we're taking way too long.
Oh, I think...
I think I found something.
- What?
- Looks like there's maybe another room
or something.
Shine it.
- Okay.
- Get the light in here.
Yeah, don't... don't...
don't just...
wait, wait, wait.
Oh...
Hurry!
Get in here!
- I need some light!
- All right!
Hurry up!
- Oh!
- What?
- What is it?
- Stay over there, Nate.
What? Did
you find her?
Stay right there.
What?
There. Are you okay?
- Sam?
- What's your name?
Don't worry,
we're here to help you.
We're here to help you.
Don't, don't, don't.
She's w... she's already...
Are you okay?
- What?
- It's gonna be all right.
We're here to help
you. Don't worry.
Oh, God, she's in a cage!
- Nate, stay back.
- She's in a cage!
It's okay. Don't scare her!
Don't scare her!
Are you okay, sweetheart?
She's already freaked out!
Sweetheart?
- Oh, my gosh!
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean to scare you.
- The mic.
- What?
- He knows we're here!
- I told you! I knew it!
Okay, hurry.
Get something to open this.
- What? Okay!
- Like, something to pry it with. Hurry!
I'm hurrying!
All right, we're gonna
get you out of here, okay?
- Cover your eyes.
- Is she all right?
We need something harder.
This is not gonna work.
Sometime heavier or...
All right,
all right, all right!
Sam, there's nothing in here!
It's just a bunch of shit!
Hurry!
Uh. Aah!
I found a hammer!
Hurry! Good, good!
Here, take it,
take it, take it!
Oh, God.
It's not working!
Watch out. Aaah!
All right, get back.
I've got the hammer.
Caleb, are
the police here? What?
- He's here.
- The guy is at the house.
- He's going in right now.
- Oh, no, we gotta go.
Guy's got a gun...
Caleb, you better run! Run!
- Run, Caleb!
- Caleb!
We gotta get her!
We gotta get her out of here!
Grrr!
All right, help me!
I can't do it by myself!
- We have to go!
- No!
- Right now!
- All right, all right, all right!
Come on, come on,
we have to get her out!
- Okay, okay.
- We have to get her out!
- We have to!
- Grrr!
We have to get her...
Come on!
Oh, oh!
Are you okay?
All right, are you okay?
- Come here.
- Come on, let's go!
Here you go.
I got you. I got you.
Come on. Hurry.
I'm coming.
We got you.
Oh, Sam, be quiet!
Shh shh shh!
Wait, wait, wait.
- Shh. Turn the light off.
- We have to be quiet.
He could be anywhere.
Okay.
Shh.
- Not yet.
- Where are we?
Hang on.
Come on, come on.
Sam, keep her quiet.
Shh, shh, be quiet. Be quiet.
- Okay?
- You're okay. You're okay.
Shh...
We're almost there.
Here, take the camera.
Just take it, take it.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Where are you going?
Where are you going? Nate!
Nate! Where are
you going?
Okay, so, um,
I know we've been, like,
really kinda like, uh...
- Goofing around.
Having a good time.
- Which is always good.
- I wanna say right now
that, um, and I know I haven't
talked to you about this,
but, like, I don't know if I'm
gonna see you, like, after this.
You know, we only
have a few more years,
maybe, we're gonna
be friends hanging out,
and you're gonna,
you know, what happens
when you find some guy
and you get married
and you go off and whatever...
- Well, we'll always be friends.
- I won't see you anymore.
Yeah, but you know
how people's lives
kind of take different paths.
So, this is, I feel like,
One Last race will be,
like, maybe,
our last big
adventure together,
like, one that will,
like, be...
go out with a bang, you know?
How do you feel about that?
Yeah, I think we'll be able
to have a lot of fun
and kind of act like kids,
like we have been for the
last few years, and...
'Cause we're not
getting married...
Are we?
Do you wanna marry me?
- I'll... I'll do it.
- Yeah, right.
Why are you laughing like that?
Have you never even
thought about that?
You never thought
about us, like, you know?
I like you. You're, like,
one of my best friends.
Oh, okay.
That... okay.
I love you! You're,
like, my best friend.
I know, okay, I love you too.
But...
I'm too fat.
I'm just kidding.
I'm sorry.
It got awkward.
But, I mean, you...
but... but...
you know, seriously, though...
No, I know what you're saying.
Like, yeah, who knows
what's gonna happen
in the future with our lives
and growing up
and having to be,
maybe, responsible adults.
Right, so?
Mm-hmm.
I wanna have, you know,
like, one last
big thing with you.
- It's cheesy.
- No, it's not cheesy.
Can we kiss right now?
No, your brother's right there.
Never mind.
Just kidding.