AMBULANCE
Tim, no matter what happens,
we stick to the plan, understand?
Don't worry,
it's gonna work, Frank.
Then the plan
has to be followed exactly.
In. Out. Then straight
to Kiel with Mom. Got it?
- No shooting, no deaths.
- Right.
Because I'm not
going back to prison.
I don't want you going through
the same shit I went through.
We get hold of the $25,000 and
tomorrow Mom will get her treatment.
This is her last chance.
Look at me ...
This one's for Mom.
- For Mom, yes.
- Tim?
Are you sure about this?
- Okay ... Are you ready?
- Yes.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah! No shooting, no deaths.
Right! Let's go.
This is a robbery!
What're you doing?
No shooting, I said!
You fucking idiot!
Come out with your hands above
your head! The bank is surrounded!
- Fuck. The car! What do we do?
- Run ...! Run!
- Come on!
- Stop!
- Let's take this!
- What are you doing?
- It's an ambulance. You can't!
- What are we gonna do?
- Come on!
- Shit!
- What the hell happened in there?
- She set off the alarm.
I said there was to be no shooting!
That's the only thing I told you!
- Did they hit you?
- No ... That way! Go!
Can you steer with that cast?
Did you drop your gun?
- What do we do now?
- To the harbor! The getaway car.
You're too dumb
to be my brother.
- It was just a warning shot.
- Watch out!
- Come on, man.
- Go now, god dammit!
- What are you doing?
- Is it enough?
It's plenty.
No! What do we do now?
They're coming, Frank!
What do we do?
- What are you doing?
- Out of the car with your hands up!
- The siren. Find the siren.
- Brilliant, Frank!
- Don't turn that shit on.
- Get out, hands over your head!
- That's it!
- Jesus ... It works!
- This is a great getaway car.
- It glows in the dark.
It's the worst getaway car
you could find. You clown!
Yeah! They're stopping!
- And the getaway car?
- A Volvo S-80.
I stole it out in the suburbs.
It's hidden where we arranged.
A-95 ... A-95 ... Come in!
Come in ... Who are you?
Stop the ambulance immed ...
What are you doing?
... visual contact with ambulance.
Request reinforcements ...
There are 3 cars on their way to
the roadblock at South Harbor Plaza.
South Harbor Plaza ...
Okay ... Turn there! Come on!
They're headed along Vasby
to Ring Road ll. Over.
The ambulance is probably
on Tømmergrav Street, or else ...
We've got to get around
the roadblock. There! Left!
No, left!
Haven't you learned it yet?
"Right, left, right, left"!
- Good ... Straight ahead.
- How'd you know about the radio?
I don't want
to go back to prison again.
- Cool!
- No, it's just what you do ...
- Until you're busted again.
- If you're busted.
Tim, you promise me
you won't learn to love this.
Sure.
- What?
- Yes!
Spoiled little brat.
Yes. We are here.
Drive in there.
- I hope you got us a decent car.
- Don't worry, it's new.
Svanholm, come in. Answer.
Give me that walkie-talkie.
Come in, Svanholm. Answer.
Give me that walkie-talkie!
Come in ...
Come in, Svanholm.
Don't look in there! Don't let them
see our faces. Come on!
- Where's the car?
- It's over here.
No. This isn't
fucking happening, Tim!
I just parked it here!
Who'd steal a stolen car?
The only thing I asked you
was to get us a car!
What do we do?
The ambulance!
Throw down your weapons!
All the exits are covered!
Open that door.
Open that door, I said!
Shit!
Open!
Come on, Frank!
We're surrounded.
What the hell are we gonna do?
What're you doing?
What are you doing?!
Do something about her!
- Give me your hands.
- I'm sorry. I won't do anything.
- He's had a heart attack.
- Bring your hands here ...! Come on.
Do you have a cell phone?
Do you have a cell phone?!
No, I ... No!
- What do you call this, then?
- He needs intensive treatment!
No! No!
No! Stop!
No! Help me! Untie me!
Fuck!
What's happening here?
Shut up back there!
Fuck!
Yes, man!
As a getaway car, it's pretty okay.
With sirens and all ...
Shut up! We make a robbery in 2 days.
We should have prepared for 2 weeks.
What the hell
did you have in mind? Wait?
In two weeks she'll be dead!
- The IV drip's running out! Untie me!
- Can't you keep your mouth shut?
What's your name?
What's your name?!
- Julie.
- You have to let us do our job here.
The doctor was coming when you ...
No! Stop that! I'm only a nurse.
No! You can't do this!
Honestly, Frank, what are we going
to do? He's lying back there, dying.
- Get another car.
- What?
That one over there.
Take that one.
I need your car. Get out!
No, no. Just get out.
Easy.
Easy movements. Calm down.
Just get out now.
"MOM"
Sorry, I just have to take this ...
- Mother ...? What?
- I can't breathe.
- Can't breathe?
- Where are you?
Help!
They've stolen the ambulance!
- You want me out?
- Mom, we'll be there fast as possible.
They've stolen the ambulance!
Help!
- What's happening? A problem?
- Shut up!
- What about her?
- Fuck her! Come!
You can't leave without me
or else he'll die!
- Come on, god dammit!
- Okay. Jump in.
- What the hell? On the phone?
- It was Mother.
She can't breathe.
God dammit.
- What the hell are we gonna do?
- The map. Where are we?
We're ... here.
We'll take small roads
down to the boat.
Turn back.
He has to get to the hospital.
Straight ahead.
One kilometer.
His blood pressure is under 1 00.
His heart could stop at any time!
- Are you not listening?
- What now?
Just keep driving straight.
How long will it take
to get to Mom's place?
How should I know
if I don't know where we are?
Look, there's a sign.
Look ... Look at this.
This is a human being.
- Don't look at it.
- See here ... See here!
Today's his birthday.
The whole family was there.
He was opening presents
and he collapsed.
There they are again.
How the hell
can those cops do it?
A GPS ...
There must be a GPS somewhere.
- GPS?
- The cops can find us if we have one.
Find it!
Look around the radio. Break it open.
You'd think I had a GPS up my ass.
I just get out
and I'm up to my neck in no time!
- Is this it?
- No. Pull it out, dammit!
What's that in the back?
That thing, there.
- Come on.
- Jesus ...
That's it. Let me see ...
That's it.
No, no, no!
Don't let them see us.
See that truck over there?
Throw it in the back when we go by.
- But it'll hit those cows.
- Who cares. Throw it!
- Did you do it?
- Yeah.
- Yes, man!
- All right!
You're a genius, Frank.
I've had practice. For five years.
And eight years of "higher
education" at the state prison.
- Should we throw them out?
- We don't have the time.
- We need another car.
- He's regained consciousness.
- Where are we?
- On the way to the hospital.
- Just relax. What's your name?
- Ejvind.
Ejvind, we'll make sure ...
- Where's Sarah?
- She's on her way to the hospital.
Where are the children?
They've been notified. They'll be
at the hospital. Just take it easy.
Easy, Ejvind ... Everything will be
okay ... when we get to the hospital.
That's why you should
keep away from this kind of thing.
All units: Ambulance A-95 last seen
at the intersection of Køge Road.
Check Lellinge area. The army
has put a helicopter at your disposal.
- A helicopter?
- Jesus, it's right here.
Fuck. There it is!
The forest!
- No!
- Can you see it?
No!
He's falling out!
Stop! No!
- Shut up!
- Stop! Stop!
What are you doing?
No!
- Stop! I can't hold him!
- Shut up!
- Frank ...
- He's falling out!
Untie me! Untie me!
- What are you doing?
- Easy, Frank!
- What the hell are you doing?
- Come on ...
- That's it.
- I have him!
Keep on holding him!
What happened to your arm?
Is it broken?
Well?
It was the security guards.
- They broke it.
- She's just trying to make you talk.
My mother ...
Our mother ...
... is about to die.
Cancer. She's only 56.
They've given her up.
"You've only got two weeks left."
Two weeks!
"We can't do any more for you."
Who can stand to hear something
like that? I wouldn't leave.
So they called security
and that's why ...
- Jesus Christ, man!
- The operation is $25,000 in Kiel.
Shut up!
That's what it'll cost
at a private hospital.
You ... You have to help me.
I've never done this alone before.
It's not his fault that ...
Are you the one
getting treatment now?
- I need your help.
- Get out of there, dammit!
Frank, you're gonna have to ...
He's about to die back there!
He's going to die!
He can't survive this!
- We get life in prison if he dies.
- 10 years. Not life.
- You've got to ...
- Got to what?
Mom's dying!
Ten years or life, what do I care?
I just got out of prison.
Sonja and I have just had the bandit.
I want to be a father to him.
He's going to get to know
his grandmother, too.
We're going to be a family now.
All of us.
This is our last chance.
He's dead! He's dead!
Stop the car!
He died!
Give me your hands.
We only have four minutes!
And I don't know this equipment.
This is my third time out.
There's a specific procedure ...
- Call the hospital ...
- The cops can trace us!
He's dead, Frank!
Here ... Don't call the cops.
Hello ...? Give me the
National Hospital trauma center. Fast!
My name? I'm standing here with a
heart attack victim. Give me a doctor!
It's a heart attack!
There's no pulse, no breathing.
I don't know what to do.
I can't ...
Easy, Frank. Easy!
I lost the connection!
Close the door! Hurry!
Yes, I should what ...?
No, there's no pulse at all.
Hello?
I can't ...
It takes two people.
Isn't there someone
who can help you?
Okay ...
Okay, just wait a moment ...
Are you going to help me?
Are you?
Unpack this. Hurry. There's
supposed to be electrodes inside.
These. They have to be attached
here. Come here and help.
It goes up there.
Take that tape-backing off.
Up there. There.
Then ... we turn it on here ...
They're on now. Yes.
Get away! Don't touch the stretcher.
I'm not!
Don't touch the stretcher.
- Defibrillating ...
- Yes ...
What's happening?
He's not responding ...
What should I do?
His last chance
is a shot of adrenaline.
In the heart?
Take some
of those cleaning pads.
- These?
- No. The small ones.
- And an ampule ...
- Hold this.
And clean ...
What? I have the syringe.
What's written on it?
Just adrenaline.
Okay, I'll make him ready ...
You just clean his chest, okay?
- How much?
- That's fine.
Everything's ready.
What should I do?
Just hold this for me.
For me ! What'd you say?
About 4 centimeters
from the middle. Okay.
How can I know if it's straight?
Yes, I'll mark it now.
Okay ... I should what?
I've never tried this before ...
Okay. I'll do it now.
Hold him.
- All the way through?
- Yes.
Come on ... Come on ...
It's beating! It's beating!
Yes!
Where's the phone?
It worked!
Yes ... yes ...
This is fantastic!
Yes, okay, the mask goes on.
Give me the mask.
Yes, it's beating regularly.
Yes ... Thank you.
Get him
to the hospital immediately.
Good. Now we'll ...
Well done.
A-95 ... Do we have contact?
Okay, we've got to move on.
Get him out.
What? He has to
get to the hospital now.
Get them out. We don't have the time.
This isn't the Red Cross.
Watch out for the drip.
- Listen ...
- A-95, come in.
- You've painted the ambulance.
- Isn't it pretty?
He's got to go to the hospital.
Did you see what happened?
We brought him back to life.
I think we can find
a little hospital along the way.
What are you talking about?
Didn't you see that helicopter?
Didn't you say Mom couldn't breathe?
A-95, come in.
We can use them as hostages
if the police will negotiate.
You keep your mouth shut
and take out that stretcher, Tim.
- You do as I say!
- Ow, my arm!
- I'm your own brother!
- It's for your own sake.
- You can't do this to me!
- It's Mother or him. Understand?
What the hell are you doing?
Are you sick in the head?
Get that stretcher out!
- Do you hear me?
- A-95. Are the hostages unharmed?
- We need help ...
- Stop or I'll smash your head with it!
Help with that stretcher!
Get moving!
- Take that end.
- Get him out!
Hit it, hit it!
Get it out.
Get away.
Stop! The mask.
He'll die without oxygen!
- Bring it with him.
- I can't. It's attached.
Don't do that! Don't. Stop!
There's only one reserve
oxygen flask. There's only ...
... 25 minutes left.
Our mother was given 2 weeks. It's
a drag when people give up on you.
25 minutes.
That's cold-blooded murder!
We'll call an ambulance for you after
we've left. You just stay here.
Get this out of the way.
- No. They'll never find us here.
- We're going now.
He won't make it! No! Wait!
You can't go.
There's only 25 minutes of oxygen!
Tim, you can't do it!
He'll die! He'll die! Don't leave!
A-95, are we in contact?
A-95, come in. We have to know
if the hostages are unharmed.
What the hell
is happening with you?
- I can't do this. Can't you see?
- See what?
I don't believe it. We've only been
at it 40 minutes and you're crying.
- I'm calling.
- We have to get out of the area first.
To the right, over there.
To the right, god dammit!
How the hell did you take care
of Mom all the years I was gone?
I was there, at least.
- Why are you wearing that jacket?
- What do you mean?
That's the one Father had on
when he had his accident, you idiot.
Put your seat belt on.
You don't understand a damn thing.
Fuck!
This is too much.
There's a gas station down here.
Keep going straight.
Through town
to the gas station. There!
Cry baby.
- Gas or diesel?
- Wait a second ... Diesel.
God dammit, man!
Just wait. We'll stay here.
He's only got 19 minutes left.
I'm calling.
No phone calls
until we're on the road again.
What had you thought of telling Mom?
That we'd won the lottery?
I'll think of something.
We should take that one.
That's a 2CV, Tim.
It does 80 kph, at the most.
It's only getaway car
that's worse than this piece of shit.
That little one there.
He looks like my son.
We'll be playing
football before long.
How long can it take to fill
the tank on that baby stroller?
It's Mother.
Hi ... What?
Are you breathing better?
Come on, she's leaving.
Go!
What?
No, I'm not with him.
Listen ... You just have
to be ready at one o'clock.
Because we're going to Kiel.
Don't worry about that.
We'll all go together.
Just get
your things packed and then ...
Wait a second, Mother ...
- What the fuck ...
- Come on, children.
No, there's nothing wrong. Just be
ready. We're coming at one o'clock!
See you, Mother. Bye.
- Watch out. There might be a bump.
- Did she ask if I was there?
Frank, she ...
Why'd she do that?
She doesn't want
anything to happen to anyone.
I knew it! That dumb bitch
is fucking everything up again!
"Dumb bitch"? Mother?
Is it Mother
you're talking about?
If you think she's a dumb bitch,
why are you doing this at all?
I'm going to call now.
Hello ...?
We need an ambulance.
A heart attack ...
The address ...? Mine?
Oh, the address of the accident.
Find it on the map!
- Relax.
- We're trying to find it on the map.
- We drove off the map.
- What?
What's the name of that forest?
- I don't know.
- What do we do now?
Listen, it's in a forest that ...
Yes, I ...
Fuck, man, what are we gonna do?
- He's got 13 minutes left.
- Listen ...
It's not our fault
he's had a heart attack.
He's going to die anyway.
Don't you get it?
We're here now!
- Aren't we?
- We're going back, Frank.
We're going back.
No, we're not.
Mother's five minutes away.
We'll pick up my car.
Then we drive to the harbor, get on
the boat and we're back on schedule.
Frank?
Jesus.
Fuck.
- I'll call an ambulance.
- No, don't!
Everything's under control.
Nothing happened. I'm okay.
- You should go to the hospital.
- It's okay. Just go.
We ... Me and my brother
were doing a little drinking, so ...
Just go. Thanks, anyway.
- I'll just call ...
- Just go! Can't you just leave?
- You should see yourself.
- Leave now, dammit!
Are you okay, Frank?
- Are you okay?
- Get back ... Yeah, I ...
What the fuck happened?
- What happened to your forehead?
- Sorry, Frank. We have to go back.
Take it easy. You've fucked up
enough. Take a look at that car.
- You'll have to drive.
- What are you talking about?
I mean it.
We can't just let him die.
What the hell are you doing?
Threatening your own brother?
Get that branch out,
then get in, and we're leaving.
Get in the car! Get that branch out
and we're out of here!
Get in and we're leaving!
Start the car.
This project ...
- It's just ...
- Try again.
- This is unbelievable.
- Turn the car around.
Tim ...
You don't mean that.
What's happening to you?
To me? No one dead, remember?
That wasn't part of the plan.
The plan stopped
when you fired a shot in that bank.
We're driving back
to pick them up.
We'll find some local hospital.
And then we'll leave again.
Last time you pointed a gun at me,
it was a water pistol. Remember?
You don't have
the nerve to shoot, do you?
Do you have the nerve?
Huh, Tim?
Do you?
Point that away, okay?
We might drive over a bump.
Jesus, Timmy,
we shouldn't be fighting.
Now we're all going to be a family.
You and me and Mother, right?
We'll catch that boat
and just sail away.
When Mom's well
we'll start all over.
- All of us.
- We'll do all that, too ...
Afterwards.
I saved his life.
I can't just abandon him.
Hold on ...
That's not your lunch, is it?
- I need some sugar.
- I can't believe this!
It wasn't Mom who packed
that lunch for you, was it?
Jesus ... How much
does she know about this?
Nothing. She thinks
I'm at the job training class.
Don't eat that now.
Put it away.
She stopped making my lunches
after the accident.
What are you talking about?
What's this got to do
with the accident? I'm hungry.
Put that food away.
- Turn here.
- This is pure suicide!
You shut up.
There's two minutes left!
It's her ...
Stop!
We've come to fetch you.
We'll drive to the hospital.
Come on, jump in!
There's no more oxygen.
His lips are completely blue.
Come!
Further in, further in!
Further!
Will he make it?
Where are we?
- Is he okay?
- Yes. It was just in time.
What happened?
It was just a branch.
Let's get the stretcher into the van.
You've got to stop that bleeding.
Otherwise you'll pass out.
- The stretcher ...
- He can wait a second.
He has oxygen.
You mustn't lose more blood.
- Let's get going.
- We've got to take care of this.
- Does it hurt?
- It's okay.
I'll try to be careful.
No!
Can't I even go piss?
Come on, Julie,
we've got to hurry.
Were you the one
who made him come back?
Yeah.
- What an idiot he is.
- It's my brother you're talking about.
You don't know the shit
he's been through since Father died.
Your father? When?
14 years ago.
It was on a motorcycle.
He and Frank were out taking a ride.
That's how he got
that scar on his forehead.
Father's death hit him hard.
Then he went to prison ...
Seven robberies.
They locked him up
for eight years.
I think he's trying
to make things good again now.
There ... I'll just wipe this off.
Give me your hand.
There ... You have to hold this
drip up. You've lost a lot of blood.
Ow! My arm's hurt.
I can't hold it. Just hold that.
- What?
- Hold this. Come on, take the gun!
What are you doing, man?
We've got to get going now.
We have to get
the stretcher into the car.
Which local hospital
can take care of him?
- Næstved Hospital.
- Næstved ...
Okay, grab the stretcher.
We're going now.
Give me the money.
I'll take care of Mother.
What are you talking about?
We're not splitting up now.
This is just a little detour.
Can't you see how much trouble
you've already caused me?
Frank ... I'm your brother.
And we two help each other.
Help?
By driving me into a tree?
And then shoot at me afterwards.
Is that help?
No, but ...
- Tim ...
- Shut up.
This is
a totally ridiculous plan ...
... but we'll do it.
Come on,
let's get that stretcher in.
Watch out here ...
Come on, lift!
Push over there.
Here's your drip.
Is he okay back there?
I think he'll make it
to the hospital.
- What now?
- I've got to piss.
- Now?
- You wouldn't let me before.
Frank?
Hello?
- What the hell are you doing?
- Trust me. I know what I'm doing.
Can you hear us? This is ... A-95,
the ambulance. Can you hear us?
Hello, A-95. Come in.
- Can you connect us with the police?
- That's enough!
- Give it to me! I've got an idea.
- Just a moment. Stay in contact.
This is the police.
Bjørn Egelund.
We're planning to deliver
the patient at Næstved Hospital -
- on condition of immunity.
We need to know
if the two hostages are safe.
They are. But they won't be unless
you give us immunity to Næstved.
Næstved ... Wait ...
- We don't negotiate with terrorists.
- Terrorists? What do you mean?
I must know the hostages are alive
before we can negotiate.
Let me speak with one of them.
You're not giving her this!
Trust me, Frank ...
Okay, I'm grabbing it back
if she squeals.
Don't say anything
about where we are. Got it?
Just hold that button in.
I know.
- Hello.
- Bjørn Egelund.
With whom am I speaking?
- Julie Svanholm.
- Are you okay?
I'm fine, and these aren't terrorists.
They're just normal ...
- That's enough!
- She's doing fine, as you can hear.
- And the patient?
- He's sleeping.
You're looking at 3 years now.
If anyone dies, you get life.
We've set in all our resources,
you're driving in an ambulance ...
- Do we have a deal?
- Deal?
Yes. Immunity to Næstved.
Wait ...
- Yes, immunity. Free the hostages.
- You don't believe him, do you?
Stop here.
- Right.
- Left.
- What?
- You mean "right", don't you?
What are you talking about?
There's Næstved.
And there's Fakse.
There's a hospital
in Fakse, too.
How about that!
How the hell did
you know that, Timmy?
I learned to read.
That's my little brother speaking.
Tim Elo Hansen. Way to go, my boy!
... Næstved Hospital will be
discreetly surrounded in 10 minutes.
- They fell for it!
- "Discreetly surrounded"!
Tim?
Tim, are you okay?
Did your drip run out? Let me see ...
Yes. I'll just take this out.
- Tim ...
- Tim? Are you okay?
Hey ... Are you there?
Come here.
Take deep breaths.
Is it helping?
Hey, that's great ...
Don't you want some?
- No, thanks.
- Come on. It really works.
You're almost 40. You've been
in a serious traffic accident.
You need some, too.
Come on, try it.
Okay, give it to me, then.
- Wow!
- Keep your eyes on the road.
Give me one more.
Too much can get you stoned.
- Boy, does this stuff work!
- It's good, isn't it?
Focus, Tim!
Everything's under control. Wow!
You're an angel.
You don't happen to be interested
in my spoiled-brat little brother?
- Who can't score girls?
- That's enough, Frank.
Hey, your lunch!
Shouldn't we have a little sandwich?
Oh, good idea ...
26 years old and Mother still
makes your lunches. That's far out.
It's been quite a while.
Oh ... I'm sorry.
Won't you have one?
Well ... Yes.
Our mother made them for us.
Well, this isn't
supposed to be a picnic.
- Where's that hospital?
- What's this street?
Ask her.
Hey, excuse me.
Do you know the way to the hospital?
Yes ... Straight ahead
and then make a left.
Thank you.
Straight ahead and then to the left.
It should be down here ...
All entries to Næstved Hospital are
covered. Ready for ambulance.
Næstved!
Boy, are they gullible.
How far is it to Mom
from the hospital?
We have to go back
20 or 30 kilometers.
Ten minutes if Frank drives.
There it is!
We'll make the boat.
Tomorrow Mother will be in treatment.
Dammit, Frank,
we're going to make it.
What did you expect?
Where does one deliver
someone like him?
The ambulance
entrance is ... there. There!
What the hell are you doing?
I guess it's about time ...
to say goodbye.
I'm sorry about all this.
What the hell was that?
Jesus Christ, Frank!
What do we do?
No! No!
Stop!
Stop the car!
- Stop! Stop!
- Fuck him!
Stop! Stop!
No! The money!
I'm driving now!
What are you doing?
Give me those keys.
Give me those keys!
- Tim!
- He's stuck!
- What are you doing?
- He's stuck.
- We're leaving.
- Throw down your weapons!
I'll blow her head off!
Give me those keys, Tim!
I mean it, god dammit!
- He'll fall out. It's murder.
- Drop your weapons!
- No!
- Don't do that.
- That's not going to work.
Hear the pulse gauge.
He'll die!
The area is surrounded!
We're surrounded.
We might as well give ourselves up.
Couldn't we try
and get a doctor out here?
I'm so tired
of your ridiculous ideas.
I'm not going back to prison.
I'm going home to my son.
Now give me those keys.
I'll count to three.
- One!
If you drive away, Frank ...
... you'll be shot.
You'll wreck your own life
as well as his.
The bandit's life. Sonja's.
Is that what you want?
Give me that.
We're finished, anyway.
- Why do you ...
- Stop! Don't come any closer.
Two!
Give me that pistol.
Do you want to ruin everything?
Ruin everything ...? Me?
Suddenly
everything's my fault, huh?
I'm doing this for our sake.
If we leave ...
What the hell are you doing?
You've always ruined
everything for me!
Always!
This isn't
just about those keys, is it?
- We're brothers, we can't ...
- We can't what?
Don't come around telling me
what to do and what not to do.
You and Mother, man. You two.
You're so damn ...
What are you talking about?
You don't understand
a fucking thing.
I was the one
driving the motorcycle that time ...
Yes, when Dad died.
He wasn't driving.
It was me. It was the first time
he let me drive than damn bike.
And she's hated me ever since.
Not once.
She didn't visit me once in prison.
Not one, single time.
Do you realize that?
Do you think
I did it on purpose? Huh?
Do you think it was my fault?
Frank, how could I know ...? If it
was an accident, it's not your fault.
Tell that to Mother!
Everything's
always my fault, isn't it?
But it's always
such a shame for little Timmy.
- You're so holier-than-thou.
- Was it just to buy Mother back?
This was my only chance ...
to have a family.
And you've just blown it,
you fucking idiot!
I hate you and Mother!
Jesus ...
Frank, I love you.
Frank ...
Frank?
Tim ...?
Frank ...?
Tim!
Stop, stop.
I'll do what I can
to help your mother.
Can you hear what I'm saying?