Bless me father for I have sinned
in thought, word and deed.
Would you like to tell me your sins?
Last night, I killed a man.
I killed many men.
It's who I am, it's what I do.
In fact, I'm supposed to kill
someone tonight.
Tell me, why must this person die.
Because, he deserves to die.
You don't want me to try to
stop you, tonight.
I can't stop you,
won't stop you.
You're not the only one who
has sinned, Father.
What's your darkest sin?
I was married once.
I did horrible things to
my wife and child.
What kind of things?!
I burned him.
Scarred him.
He was hiding out.
Yes, I know ...
father.
The Confession  1x09
"Chapter 9"
Subtitles by josmndsn
My God, I'm so sorry,
I'm so sorry.
You're sorry!
I know, there are no words
that I can say.
You're right.
There is nothing you can say.
I was a different man then.
You were supposed to love us,
protect us.
Now, you have after all this time,
no excuse.
I have made ...
terrible mistakes.
Mistakes!
You tortured me.
You killed my mother.
No, that's not true.
She commited suicide.
You really believe that?
Your mother was an ill women.
Made so because of your abuse!
No, she jumped.
She jumped from the balcony.
Have you told yourself your version
of the story so many times
that you actually believe it?
I know what happened.
I was there when she did it.
So was I.
It's because you're lazy
and you don't care anymore.
Don't hurt me, don't hurt me.
Don't hurt me.
Come here.
Stay away from me, please.
Stay away from me!
Get back in the fucking house!
Leave me alone!
You don't tell me what to do.
What are you gonna do?
Are you gonna jump?
Help me.
Well, go on, do it.
Do us all a favor, jump,
jump, jump!
Jump!  Do it!
And, maybe, for once in your
miserable life,
you'll actually follow through
with something
and do it right.
Please.
I can't take any more.
(mockingly)  Oh, ...
I can't take anymore.
(chuckles) I'm telling you,
you better do this,
because if I get my hands on you,
you'll wish you had.
I'm so sorry.
You're pathetic.
I knew you'd never have the
nerve to do ...
She jumped.
I didn't kill her.
Of course you did!
You might not have pushed her,
but you might as well have.
What choice did you leave her?
Endless beatings from you.
Or, death.
That was my first lesson on how
cheaply we value life.
And, after you abandoned me,
I spent three days in that apartment
until the building manager
found me.
I spent the next ten years,
in and out of foster homes.
I didn't think anything could
be worse than you.
I was wrong.
Shall I tell you about the abuses?
How many old men laid their
hands on me
and shared me with
their friends?
Please, ... don't.
I've hated you for a lifetime.
Imagine my surprise when you
passed by me on the street.
At first thought,
I wasn't sure it was you.
I think it was the collar
that threw me.
So, I came back ...
and I waited,
and I waited.
Then, finally, you came out.
You walked right by me.
The second I looked into
your eyes, ...
I knew it was you.
This person ...
that you're going
to kill tonight, ...
is me, ... isn't it?
Subtitles by josmndsn