Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Pick a spot.
Take a dump. Let's go.
Who's that?
Hey.
Evening.
Hey, Vaughn.
Hey, Jack.
I see he's got you well trained.
Who's walking who, right?
Whew.
How you, uh...
how you holding up?
It's day by day, you know.
But I'm gonna be all right.
Yeah, these things take time.
Hmm.
Well, exercise helps.
I've been running a lot.
And I've been lifting weights.
Can you tell?
I got two tickets to the gun show.
You're a funny son of a bitch, Vaughn.
No, I mean I got two
tickets to the gun show.
Now look, I've got my van
parked right down the street.
You and I are going
to take a little jog.
What's this about, man?
I think you know what this is about.
No, I don't know what this is about!
I think you do... know...
what... this... is... about!
Turn your ass around...
and we're gonna run up the road.
All right, Vaughn.
Come on.
Turn around.
Turn around! Let's go.
Damn it, Vaughn!
Turn around. Let's go.
Go home, Max. All right!
Come on, let's go come on...
We're gonna jog.
We're gonna jog. Run.
What are you doin'?
Run. Run!
Let's go. Run.
Come on, let's go. Run.
Almost done.
You dug that pretty quick.
But then again, it is fresh dirt.
All right. One more.
One more.
All done.
Put the shovel right over here.
Right there.
What?
Come on...
Hey!
Open it.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
No, man.
Open it.
Don't make me do this, friend.
Ooh-hoo.
What the fuck?
God! Ohhh!
Comfy?
Vaughn, don% do this, man.
Look... I swear to God...
no one's going to know
anything about this.
I'll never tell anybody.
I'll never tell a soul.
Oh. Oh, please.
Please. Oh, no. Please don't do this.
Vaughn! Look, man, we go way back!
What, it's gonna be our little secret?
Yes, it is.
I don't think so.
Come on.
I'll tell you what, maggot-meat...
What?
I'll leave the light on for you.
Jesus!
Vaughn!
Woo-hoo.
Fuck.
Vaughn!
I don't have air!
So someone give me an
impression of The Telltale Heart.
Who wants to start?
Danny?
I thought the blue eye was kinda cool.
Okay. Anything else?
He really loves exclamation points.
All right.
Hey, Travis. What about you?
What is Poe really telling
us about this murderer?
Hmm. I don't know.
Oh, come on, Travis...
we don't have optional
participation in this class.
Say you were encouraging a friend
to read it. What would you tell him?
I'd say... you're inside
this killer's head.
The longer you're in
it, the scarier it gets.
Why is it scary?
Because he's crazy.
Are you sure?
Well, he keeps telling us that he's not.
Abby, what do you think?
I would have to agree with Travis.
He's definitely crazy.
Anyone that would kill somebody
just because they had a funny eye.
Damn right. And he slab-chops the dude.
So, Brian, you're saying he
cuts him into little pieces.
Right. Then he hides it
all underneath the floor.
So why would he go to all that
trouble to hide the body...
if he's gonna confess?
I guess because he knew
the cops could hear it.
You know? The heart beating and all?
But Miss Moore, I don't
think it was beating.
I think he just thought it was
beating because he was mental.
Yeah, he was nuts, so
he was hearing shit.
Stuff.
Okay. Okay.
So what would make somebody
keep hearing something...
a sound, if it's all in his head...
that would drive him to confess?
Travis.
Uh, it was, uh... guilt.
Don't forget, we continue
with Macbeth next week.
I want you to review
Act Ill this weekend.
To get us in the mood, Travis
and Abby will do a scene...
as Macbeth and Lady Macbeth.
Maybe you can come by
for pizza, like sevenish?
Sure. We should really go that way.
Okay, Brian. Hold on.
Ooh. "Never shake thy gory locks at me."
What?
Sit worthy, my friends.
My lord often thus.
Macbeth. Yeah.
No one has any idea what
you two are talking about.
Isn't that where he sees the ghost?
Yeah.
You won't have any
trouble nailing that scene.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
Uh, does anyone else
getting tired of pizza?
Danny, you can get wings.
Abby, we should go.
What are you talking about?
It should come easy...
since I saw something strange
the night my sister died.
Like a... like a ghost?
I don't know what it was.
But I saw something.
No, no, please, we're all friends here.
Why don't you share with us?
Brian.
No, I'm just curious. Let me guess.
You called your ghost Richard Headen...
you know, in Dickhead for short.
Kinda like what they call you.
Mm. You're funny.
Aren't I? I'm a funny guy.
Brian, it's his sister.
Oh, fine, he brought it
up. It's not my fault.
Nice, Brian.
Travis.
Mr. Sovic.
You were supposed to come see me.
Yeah.
Travis, you've never come out
for track or baseball, have you?
Nope.
All you do is P.E.
Yeah, just P.E.
Track tryouts are next week.
I'd like to see you out there.
I gotta go...
Listen a second.
You know what's neat about track?
Hmm.
There's always a goal.
You're always running towards something.
Now, you see...
I think you'd be good at that.
Just not interested.
Not interested, huh?
I see.
I guess I've been wasting my time.
What was all that crap?
The hell if I know.
Let's go.
Sovic's a creep.
Yeah.
Is he even married?
It wouldn't surprise me if he wasn't.
Probably not, man.
Ahh, I think he's got
a thing for Miss Moore.
Ohhh, that'd be interesting.
Gotta mow Ely's lawn tomorrow?
Yep.
Doesn't it ever creep
you out being around him?
Not really.
Dude. With those dead bodies?
I'm pretty sure Ely keeps
them in the funeral home.
Mr. Ely?
- Boo!
- I'm all done.
Here.
Travis, you didn't set
the mower low enough.
I thought I did it the way you wanted.
What I said on the last cutting...
is that I wanted it really low...
so that it looks good until spring.
Now, wasn't that clear?
I guess.
Well, you just have to do
it over again, that's...
Yes, sir.
You know, uh...
my dear wife, Rosemary...
taught your sister...
um, what was her... Ellen?
Erin.
Erin. Taught her in the sixth grade.
Hm. Yeah.
Here you go, just put it right in here.
Said she was a really smart young lady.
Very special.
Now they're both gone.
Here, back to work.
Hey, Travis.
Hey.
So, Danny said that you
weren't gonna go tonight.
Yeah, got some homework to do.
Travis, you can do
homework whenever you want.
So...
So what?
It's just... that you promised that...
you would tell me about
the whole ghost thing.
I just... don't want this
getting around school.
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
I promise.
[Travis, off? One night,
when I was seven years old.
Some strange noises woke me up.
They were coming from my sister's room.
Erin?
Erin.
Leave my sister alone!
My mom
called 9-1-1.
I knew there was nothing they could do.
Don't go, Erin. Please don't go.
I knew she was gone
I'm sorry, Travis.
I just stood there.
Frozen.
I'm sure you couldn't have
changed anything if you tried...
She'd be 21 now.
Our minister came over that night...
to try to comfort my mom...
try to make her not feel guilty...
that this was meant to be.
What kind of crap is that?
Did you try and tell
your mom what happened?
Yeah.
First she believed me, then, um...
it was just to calm me down.
I wonder if my mom
would even believe me...
if I told her I saw something like that.
Probably not.
But I'm glad you told me.
Hear it not, Duncan, is a knell...
or for hell.
Something like that.
Thou hath made me
drunk, hath made me bold.
Um.... Hmm.
Well, at least it seems like
we have the majority of it down.
Yeah. You do, anyway.
Oh, El Camino! God, I'm awesome.
Your car is not that nice.
My car is amazing.
That will take you any day.
No. No, it will not.
El Camino is king.
Yo, it's the Macbeth's.
Ha, ha, how are you guys?
You guys are really into
this acting thing, huh?
I am too. The ghost,
in... in the play...
he gets stabbed by Macbeth, right?
Well, Macbeth had him killed.
Perfect. I'll play the ghost.
You want to play the ghost?
Yeah.
Yeah. Sure, why not?
Right? No, I can come on
with the ketchup on my head...
and then at the end,
I will lick the blood.
Oh, sort of like a Buffy
Macbeth kind of thing.
Hell, yes.
Okay, all right. That
sounds great. Can we go?
I want to get to Chestnut
Square before it gets late.
Yeah.
Abby? Back by ten.
Leave your cell phone on.
Yes, Mom.
Thank you. Brian.
Hey.
One passenger at a time with
that new license of yours, please.
Of course, Mrs. Harwood.
And I always take good
care of my passenger.
Thank you, Brian.
I love that sweater, Mrs. Harwood.
Okay, Danny.
Your mom's so hot, I'm sorry.
Really? That's my mother.
Come on.
She's hot. What's with the
be back by ten shit, though?
Don't get me started.
That's early.
Come on, Abby.
You got one more strike.
Let's see if you can do it.
Don't you listen to
him, Abby, all right?
He's just trying to psych you out.
Watch and learn, Brian.
You get it, girl.
Go, go! go!
I'm pretty sure I just won.
Just saying.
Travis, did the bowling ghost
knock the pins over?
That's not really funny.
It's just a joke. Calm down.
Just get out of my face.
Whoa, hey dude.
Calm down. Brian...
No, no, I'm the victim here, okay?
It's his fault. We're just bowling here.
We are just bowling.
All right, I'll stop, I'll stop.
Sit down.
I don't wanna sit down.
You sit down.
Brian.
Have you seen them?
No, no.
Real ghosts? Like just dancing around?
Colin saw them when he was walking by.
He said they were all shimmering.
Can you guys lay off already?
My God! We're not talking about Travis.
Jesus. Okay, so where did
Colin see these things?
Outside, in the front lawn.
He said they drifted
in through a wall...
and he could see them
through the window.
That is complete horse shit.
I know. It's what he said.
Who's house is this at?
Vaughn Ely's.
Travis mows his lawn.
I've never seen anything like that.
You mow his lawn during the day.
Ghosts come out at night.
It's probably Ely walking around...
with a sheet on top of his head.
So wanna go check it out?
Really?
Really.
No, no, no. You are
not driving this car.
Brian. Give me the keys.
All right, let's go!
Oh, it's so dark tonight. Oooh...
S0 what's Ely's deal?
He's all right.
He's a freakin' weirdo, man.
You gotta be if you're...
one of those, uh, "morticianers?"
Yeah, yeah, morticianer.
Yeah, that... that guy.
Sticking those tubes in people
and sucking all that snot out.
That's gross, Brian.
Oh, you're welcome.
Was he married to the mayor's sister?
Yeah, but she died a couple years back.
What does he pay you to mow his lawn?
Twenty bucks.
Twenty... twenty bucks, that's it?
Yeah, I mean, I only mow the front.
Why?
He never lets me in the back yard.
I figure he does it himself.
That's weird.
I would completely believe
this house is haunted.
It gives off such a weird vibe.
I think you just like
to be scared, Abby.
Brian.
No, seriously.
No, Brian, look.
Shit.
See? I told you.
He lives alone, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, so who is that?
This house is so haunted.
Nobody's gonna believe this.
I'm still not convinced.
Brian, we all saw it.
Maybe one was Ely, but
the other one was...
How do we know it was a freakin' ghost?
Then what was it, Brian?
I don't know, maybe Ely had a hot date.
You know, he was dancing with her...
before he mixed the milkshake.
It was not a hot date.
It was just... something wrong.
Well, maybe if she was a ghost...
she'll show up in class in a second.
Give that Macbeth ghost some company.
Are you a man?
Aye. And a bold one...
that dare look on that
which might appall the devil.
A shame itself.
Why do you make such faces?
When all's done, you
look but on a stool.
Prithee, see there!
Behold! Look! Look! How say you?
If charnel houses and graves
send those that we bury back
then our monuments shall
be the maws of kites.
Asshole.
You know I don't like that.
I know that grade's shit, but who cares?
I do.
Travis, wait.
Why aren't you trying?
Honestly? Cause I don't give a shit.
Well, wh... what do you care about?
Maybe if Erin were...
No, no, just say it! Say it!
If Erin was still alive...
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have.
You know, Mom, people die every day.
You can't change it.
And you sure as hell can't change me.
What's up?
It's Vaughn Ely, what's
the word on my van?
Vaughn, I hate to tell you.
It's the torque converter.
Well, how much is it gonna cost?
It'll be close to 1500...
1500 dollars?
How come anytime anything goes wrong
with the car, it's 1500 dollars?
Now look, man, it is what it is.
You want me to fix it or not?
It's gotta be ready by Saturday.
How long on that van?
It's gonna be at least a week.
Vaughn, it's gonna be tough...
Alright, just have it done.
Yeah.
You all did a great job
with the sonnets today.
We have come a long
way with Shakespeare.
By the way, I won't be
here this afternoon...
so if you need anything, please
check with me after class.
Wait, where's she going?
Basher.
You know, her old man's
been missing for two years.
She's gonna get a divorce.
Hey, Travis? Can I speak
with you for a moment?
It's about your Macbeth exam paper.
I thought I got an A on that.
Actually you got a hundred.
The highest grade in the class.
Well, then what?
Well, that test proves
what you can do...
when you apply yourself.
But so far this semester
your grade is a D.
You didn't even turn in
that book report last week.
Guess what grade I had
to give you on that?
Hmm.
Travis, here's the deal.
You wanna work on
getting your grade up...
I'll help you.
But that's gotta be your decision.
Can I go now?
Go ahead.
Miss Moore...
Yes?
I'm sorry about your husband.
Thank you, Travis.
♫ Go, Orange! ♫
♫ Go, Black! ♫
Hey, sweetie.
Hi, Vaughn.
Sylvia.
How nice to see you.
Enjoying the game?
Oh, yes. I always enjoy it.
Down! Set!
Hut!
Go, Tigers!
Woo!
You know, I think we
have our quarterback...
for this year and the next.
That Williams kid is good.
Yeah. He can fire the ball.
And he makes good decisions.
He's smart.
Sorta like you when you won
that state title back in, uh...
Don't go there. Too long ago.
Yeah, listen, Vaughn,
I wanted to tell you...
I really appreciate all your
work on the Booster Club...
especially after you lost Rosemary.
Yeah, my Rosemary. She
loved coming to the games.
We're just, I mean, I'm glad to do it.
I tell you, it makes a big difference
when there's a lot of fans out here.
Tigers up by seven as
we head info halftime.
Hey, look, there's Travis.
Hey.
You guys are looking good out there.
Thanks.
Why don't you come down?
Er...
alright.
So, Travis, you don't
normally go to football games.
Not usually.
Is there a reason you're at this one?
Well, I heard there was this
really good cheer leading team.
I thought' I'd check them out.
Cute, Travis. Real cute.
Gotta say, man, it
was a beautiful throw.
You are an amazing man.
Aw, well, thanks.
I still can't believe we saw a ghost.
We didn't see shit.
No, we didn't.
What's it gonna take to convince you?
Okay, first of all, we gotta
make sure Ely is not home...
and second of all, we gotta go back.
Okay, I've got an idea.
He only has one car, right?
Yeah, a funeral van.
Okay, so if the van's not
there, then Ely's not home.
Dude, isn't his garage in back?
No, he has another carport.
You can see if it's there.
- That'll work.
- But it's a bad idea.
No, that's a great idea.
I mow his lawn. He trusts me.
We can't spy on him.
Screw him. Let's go.
Alright.
Alright, so the van isn't there...
which means he's not home.
Guess what? The show started.
Unbelievable.
I'll say.
Now you're convinced?
I am convinced that something...
really freakin' weird is going on.
Gotta be ghosts.
I wanna go see 'em.
You are seeing them.
No, Danny, I mean I wanna
go see them up close.
Come on. Let's go, guys.
Abby, are you... are you kidding?
Danny's right, guys. Ely
could come home at any minute.
Are you scared, Travis?
Brian, don't.
No, I'm just curious.
He's our ghost expert
yet he's pussing out.
I just don't think it's right.
Oh, okay, that's cute.
Brian! Brian, just stop.
I need somebody to stand guard anyways.
Travis, if you see him pull up...
just come run and get us.
Alright, let's go.
We're doing it! Go!
Come on!
Let's go around the side.
Hey, genius. Window's open.
What about the screen?
I got it, I got it.
Got a criminal past that
I don't know about, Brian?
There's a lot you do not know about me.
Okay, just go inside.
What is wrong with you?
Danny!
Did you hear that?
I don't hear anything.
That's the point. It stopped.
Maybe we better haul ass.
No, I wanna go upstairs.
Yeah, come on, let's go.
Hey, wait.
Danny.
Brian!
Oh my God.
She's dead.
Dead?
It's okay, it's fine.
It's not fine! This is crazy!
I know it is, but it's not my fault!
You're freakin' crazy!
Everyone was in on this!
Jesus Christ!
Vaughn.
Come on, let's go!
What are you doing in my house?
Uh...
This is bad.
It's bad.
Get out.
Go.
Run, you little shits!
Your friends left you. Are you scared?
Yeah.
Travis, we gotta go!
No, wait. Where's Danny?
Ely caught him! Travis, come on!
No! I'm not leaving him!
Travis! Travis!
Please, stop!
Mr. Ely, please. Just
let him go, please.
He didn't mean any harm.
You want me to let him go?
Please.
Say please.
Please let me go.
Okay.
Stairs can be very dangerous.
Most accidents happen in the home.
There, you little shit! Is
that clear enough for you?
What's going on?
Come on. Let's go.
Where's Danny?
Let's go! Come on! Let's go! Run!
9-1-1. State
your emergency.
This is Vaughn Ely.
I need an ambulance and
the police right away.
There's... been a terrible accident.
I'll wait for them outside.
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go.
Now in a minute I'm
gonna let your folks in.
You're gonna be released
to their custody.
Wait, so we're not going to jail.
Well, you'll have to go
before a judge in the morning.
A lot depends on Mr. Ely.
He's the one who
should be going to jail.
Yeah, we have been through this.
Why don't you believe us?
Brian and I both saw that thing.
Young lady, we searched that house.
There was no dead body.
But we saw it and it was there.
It was up there on the bed.
Alright, kids, listen...
What about what happened to Danny?
Why don't you arrest Ely for that?
You have Travis as a witness.
In our investigation, we determined...
that Danny fell down those stairs.
He did not fall down the stairs, okay?
Ely pushed him and then
he stomped on his head.
Alright, listen.
Travis, I know you're scared.
But lying's gonna make it worse.
Well, I'm not lying.
And I'm not scared.
Come in.
Sarge, here it is.
Thank you.
All right, these are the
pictures we took in the bedroom.
You see a mannequin.
The closet door open...
and some sewing stuff in there.
That's not it.
That's not what we saw.
And you were nosing around...
you opened the closet door...
We didn't touch the door!
This is bullshit!
Watch your language.
What?
Sargeant, that was the hospital.
I'm afraid your friend is dead.
These kids, when they do things,
they don't realize the consequences.
Phil, I... I know what goes on.
Kids make up stories about morticians.
I work with dead bodies.
It's all a big joke,
until somebody gets hurt.
I'm sure sad it had to happen.
It's tragic for everybody.
That boy's family...
I can't imagine what
they're going through.
Mm.
It's beyond me.
Vaughn, like I said...
you don't need to come on down there
if you're not pressing any charges.
Everybody's suffered enough.
You're a good man, Vaughn.
Honey-bunny.
There you are.
See, Rose?
I told you they wouldn't
find you up here, huh?
No. No, honey.
We have to stay here a few more days.
Just in case. Safety first.
All right?  Hm?
And then we're gonna
party like rock stars.
Nighty night.
I'd like to talk for a second.
There's nothing to talk about, Mom.
Police don't believe me,
you don't believe me, so...
tell me, what do you want to talk about?
I believe you.
Oh, bullshit.
No, this is the same
like when Erin died.
What?
You don't believe Ely
broke Danny's neck, do you?
Okay? For once in your life,
tell me the fucking truth! Please!
I love you so much.
I couldn't bear for
something to happen to you.
Please promise you'll never
go near Vaughn Ely again.
And you know why I
want you to promise me?
No.
Because I'm afraid.
I'm afraid what that man may do to you.
Now does that sound like the truth?
Sorry I yelled.
So you promise me?
Danny was my best friend.
Oh, Travis. I know, honey.
We all loved him.
But please promise me.
I promise.
I do believe...
we have you looking better...
than when you broke into my house.
May there be abundant
peace from heaven...
and light upon us and upon all Israel.
And say Amen.
May God comfort you...
along with the mourners
of Zion, Jerusalem.
Travis, I'm so sorry.
Thanks.
Did you get a chance to
talk to Danny's parents?
I went over there yesterday
and talked to them.
Have you guys noticed the way
everyone was staring at us?
It's like it's our fault.
They know how much we loved him.
Yeah, well, it's pissin' me off.
I mean, I know we weren't
supposed to be there, but...
we had some fun and
then this accident...
Accident?
Whatever.
No, I told you what happened.
He killed Danny. I told you.
Will you GUYS just stop.
Nothing's ever your fault, is it?
I mean, it's always somebody else's.
I mean, don't you think we're all...
partially to blame for Danny's death?
To blame, yeah, okay, we...
No, no, we did enough.
We never should've gone in.
I thought this would be different.
I really did. That maybe
I could count on you.
Yeah? For what?
What do you think?
Help me prove he killed Danny.
I didn't kill anyone.
And I don't appreciate you spreading
gossip and rumors about me...
to make yourself look good.
Oh, yeah? What the hell do
you think you're doing here?
It's my job.
I'm still on the clock.
We know what you did, Ely.
Abby? Careful.
Man, that guy creeps me out.
The guy's more than just a creep.
Travis.
You can count on me.
Mr. Harwood.
Travis, she's grounded.
I'm just wondering if I
could maybe talk to her.
Travis, it's late.
I think she still has some
homework she needs to finish.
Dad, I finished all my home work.
We'll just be on the porch.
Alright. For a little while.
Well, I'm not your
dad's favorite person.
I'll bet your mom's
not terribly fond of me.
Well, Abby, um...
I know. We broke into the house.
We didn't do anything
to cause Danny's death.
We shouldn't feel guilty
for what Ely did to him.
It's not our fault.
You're right.
It's not your fault.
But it's different for
me because I was there.
I saw it.
And I didn't do a damn thing about it.
Just like Erin.
I mean, if I'd done something...
You went in there.
You tried to help Danny.
And he's dead.
Travis, did you have any idea...
what Ely would do
when he re-ache-d..
The bottom of the stairs?
What do you mean?
Did you know he was
gonna break Danny's neck?
Well, I mean, it happened so fast.
See? That's what I'm saying.
You didn't have a chance to react.
The guts to go in when nobody else did.
And I'm proud of you for that.
Thank you.
Abby. It's getting late.
Good night, Travis.
Pile just keeps growing.
Looks like everybody brought something.
It's not gonna bring him back.
Abby, they all believe Ely.
But if we can prove he's crazy or...
He's a total psychopath, and
we're the only ones who know it.
What if we had a photo of that body?
Then they'd have to believe
us or at least ask questions.
She's definitely not a mannequin.
But where is she?
I bet she's back in the bedroom.
Why would he put her back?
Who knows? He's weirder than shit.
For some reason, he
likes her in that bedroom.
I'm going in tonight.
You're not going in without me.
Yeah, I am.
Travis, don't be all macho...
and try to tell me
what I can and can't do.
I know you want to help
but it's not gonna happen.
I'm not...
Travis! Just shut up.
Okay.
Compromise.
You can be my lookout.
Okay, we've been here
over an hour, Travis.
I don't think he's
going anywhere tonight.
Give it a few more minutes.
How'd you get out of your house?
I told my mom I'm at Karen's.
She's having this like
slumber party thing.
I thought you were grounded.
I am but I convinced her to let me out.
I'm kind of on parole.
Anyway, I left my phone at Karen's.
So I told her that if anybody calls...
just to tell them I'm in the shower.
Look.
I guess now's our chance.
Yeah. Come on.
No, you can't do that.
It's padlocked, come on.
Let's go.
Come on. You can do it.
Can you make it over the fence...
if we have to get out fast?
Yeah. I can.
This house is so creepy.
No shit.
We just need to get in
and get out before...
You okay?
What was that?
I don't know.
You're kidding me.
You know, I'll bet...
Travis...
Alright, come on.
Oh, God.
Remember, stick to the plan.
Get in and get out and take a picture.
Look, just stay here, okay?
If you see anything or hear anything...
you get out. Don't wait for me.
What if we get separated?
I'll find you.
Thanks for being you.
Just hurry, Travis.
Come on, Travis.
Damn it.
Yoo-hoo.
Where is she?
Well, that depends.
If you're talking about Rosemary...
don't worry about her. She's safe.
But if you're talking about Abby.
Uh, I don't know.
What did you do to her? Tell me!
Travis, you're in no
position to be making demands.
You are a burglar... and this is Texas.
And in Texas, we can shoot burglars.
You killed my best friend.
You're fucking crazy.
Are you scared now?
No!
Abby! Abby!
Shit.
I chased him out through here...
and I took a shot at him as
he was going over the fence.
Is that his flashlight?
No, that's mine
I dropped it when I... Thank you.
Came out.
Don't worry, Vaughn. We'll
find him. He won't get far.
You were a great wide receiver.
You caught everything I threw to you.
Yeah, well man, we were a good pair.
Yeah.
Broke a lot of records.
So you took one more shot...
as he ran for the fence.
Yeah, I probably
shouldn't have done that.
I mean, that was twice in one week.
Yeah, yeah.
Shooting them in the
house is one thing...
but you don't shoot
a burglar in the back.
Especially outside.
You're lucky you didn't
hit the neighbors.
I was upset.
I was scared, really.
It's enough to get you frazzled.
Hey, Vaughn...
what are you doing with this tarp?
I'm putting in a tomato patch.
It helps, uh, kill the grass.
Tomato patch, hm.
You're going green.
Hm.
Let me ask you something.
Does this work pretty quickly?
Yeah. You just spread out the tarp...
and in a couple of
days, everything's dead.
I'm definitely gonna have
to get me one of these.
You wanna see where
he went over the fence?
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
No!
No, no, no!
In my haste, I forgot to lock the box.
Totally my fault.
Gets dark in there, doesn't it?
You want a night light?
Here. Take it.
Don't be rude. Take it.
See you later.
Open!
What happened to you, son?
I fell on one of those...
those things that stick out of the
cement that are really sharp on...
Rebar.
Rebar?
Yeah, those steel rods,
they call them rebar.
Oh. Yeah.
Travis, this is a local anesthetic.
I need to get you numb
so I can close the wound.
Don't worry.
You won't feel a thing
when he sews you up.
Dr. Walker...
It's not you fault, you know.
What did you say?
I said it's not your fault.
They leave rebar sticking
up all over the place.
Travis, are you all right?
It's not your fault, Travis.
It's her time.
Well, it's not Abby's time.
What's that? Are you okay?
It wasn't the minister
talking to my mother.
He was trying to tell me.
Travis, when your mother gets here,
you're gonna tell her the truth.
I know a gunshot wound when I see one.
That lie you told...
don't you feel a little guilty?
I used to.
Okay. Well, I will be right back.
Uh, actually, can I borrow your phone?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Brian.
Wassup?
Look!
I could really use your help right now.
Abby's in trouble.
Thank God you weren't killed.
Mom.
Travis, listen to me. You don't
realize how serious this is.
Yes. I do.
Even if you don't believe me, you
have to tell them Ely has Abby.
Travis, what are you gonna do?
She may still be alive.
If I'm gonna save her, I need to go now.
God.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Not
so fast, Travis. Not so fast.
Don't let him out of your sight.
Miss Penny, they're
gonna keep him overnight.
The doctor's like to check
him out in the morning.
The DA is gonna charge
him with burglary.
Later on they may
certify him as an adult.
Oh, dear God.
Be a good idea to get a good lawyer.
What about what Travis
said about the Harwood girl?
Yeah, don't you worry. I'm
gonna check that out personally.
Thank you.
Phil?
Hey, Russell. Ls-is Elaine in?
Yes. Elaine?
Has there been an accident?
Oh, no, no. There's not an accident.
There's just a boy. A juvenile
got arrested tonight...
and he said that Abby was with him.
I don't put much stock
in what this kid says...
but I need to make
sure that Abby's safe.
Yes, she's at her friend's
spending the night.
I'll call and make sure
she's over there. Okay?
Thank you.
Sorry to disturb you so late.
Hi. This is Abby's mom. Is she...
No, no, no, that's okay...
Don't get her out of the shower.
Okay. Yeah.
She's there. I... everything's
fine. I talked to her friend.
Good, good. You know, like I said,
I didn't think there was much to it.
So, y'all have a nice evening.
You, too.
Thank you.
Officer Alvarez. Hey.
Brian. I know he's your
friend but you can't go in.
I just wanted to see how he's doing.
He's okay.
Yeah? Did you see him?
Yeah, the wound is on the
side. It's not bad at all.
Hey, uh, did you hear we're...
we're undefeated this year?
Yeah. Angie told me that.
Yeah. You know, she's at every game.
She told me you've thrown
a touchdown in every game.
I don't know how I do it, but yeah.
Well, tell Angie I said hey, okay?
Sure
- I'll tell him.
You know, I know it's a lot to ask...
but is there any way that I can
go in there for like half a second?
Absolutely not, Brian. Positive.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Have a good one.
Brian.
You have one minute.
Thanks.
- Hi. So what happened?
- Ely got her.
- Are you shitting me?
- No one believes me.
It's gonna be morning till
they find out she's missing.
Great. So, we gotta bust out of here.
Got any ideas to get past him?
Yeah, I got a couple.
Travis, look, what you said about me...
No, no, you were right.
I pushed everyone to go
in there and I screwed up.
No.
We screwed up.
Hey there.
He says it's starting to hurt.
I guess they numbed it when they stitched
him up, but I think it's wearing off.
Could be, yeah.
You think the nurse'll
give him something?
I bet they already have.
Yeah, that's right.
It's down here, right?
Dammit, kid.
Three-oh-four in
dispatch. I got a run.
He got to the stairs before...
- I could grab him
- What?
He got' to the stairs
before I could grab him.
Who, Alvarez?
Travis. I'm sorry, Sarge.
We're a couple blocks away. We'll cut
him off and we'll come around the back.
All right, Jesse, check it out.
Travis. Travis!
Travis, you come here.
Get in!
He's going left. He's going left.
I'll take it around the block. I got it.
The game's over, Travis.
Don't move, kid. You hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
Woo, you guys totally saved my butt.
Damn.
Son of a bitch.
Dammit, Brian.
Ls Charlie working the parade tonight?
Get on the horn. Tell him to look
for a kid who has a bloody T-shirt on.
All right, Brian. What
were you and Travis up to?
He's gotta fake left two sweep right.
Usually a good gainer
if I can sell the fake.
Wha... Take him to the station.
We're looking for a
kid in a bloody T-shirt.
At the parade. Hold.
Hey, hey. Hey, you.
Please be all right.
Ooh-hoo.
She's not in there.
Where is she?
Travis.
You're a caution.
You know what a caution is?
It's a troublemaker.
So, you and I...
we're gonna do a little job.
Put your hands behind your back.
You wanna help me on a
little job, don't you, Travis?
What freaking job?
You're just a typical teenager,
aren't you? Just mention work...
Where the hell is Abby?
What are you, in love
with her or something?
I think you have a crush on her.
Stand up. Come on.
About face. Let's go.
Phil, you don't really think he's
gonna come back here again, do you?
What if he did?
Vaughn might be just a tab
bit upset, don't you think?
Vaughn.
It's Phil Nickerson.
I don't know. Maybe he
went out with someone.
Yeah. Lights are on.
Nobody's home.
I don't like this.
I'm gonna check around the back.
Vaughn?
Vaughn.
Sshhh.
Vaughn, its Nickerson.
Everything looks okay.
Let's go.
You set up the town, son.
Come on.
I got a surprise for you.
You can see now.
Both of our girls.
Get in.
Get in. There you go.
Everyone nice and cozy.
Brace yourself.
Travis.
I'm scared.
Me, too.
Where are we going?
I don't know.
He's not gonna let us go, is he?
I don't think he lets people go, Abby.
I'm sorry.
You came back for me.
Listen. You're gonna get out of here.
Look at me. Look at me.
You're gonna get out of here.
Bite the duct tape. Bite it.
Now, when you get out of here,
I want you to run for help...
but he might come after you, so
stay off the main roads, okay?
You hear me? Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
Okay? I'll find you.
Okay?
I'm not leaving you, Travis.
Yes, you are. Now bite it. Go.
Bite!
Okay...
Come on, Travis. We
got a little job to do.
Let's go.
You're gonna need this.
Come on.
You girls sit tight.
Right over here. Come on.
Ah, man. I've done that up tight.
Okay. Here you go.
All right.
Dig. Right here.
Dig faster.
Keep digging...
Thank you for your patience, sweetheart.
Almost done.
All right', that's enough.
Put the shovel on the side.
Open it.
I'm a mortician and that makes me gag.
Who is this?
That's Jack, Travis.
The two of you are gonna be great
friends. You're gonna be roomies...
Who is this?
Oh, would... Yeah,
you're a junior, right?
Si! via Moore is your English teacher.
That's Silvia's long lost husband, Jack.
Why did you put him in there?
You're young, stupid...
so you don't know these things, okay?
When another man fucks your wife...
there's gotta be some payback.
You have to punish him.
I had to punish my Rosemary, too...
and that broke my heart.
But she asked for forgiveness...
and I have a soft spot
for those that I love...
so I told her that she
could stay home with me.
But she's dead.
Oh, we had a funeral.
I put a casket in the
ground but she wasn't in it.
Jack there, Jack was at the funeral.
He just sat there the
whole time looking at me...
like I had no idea that
he was screwing my wife.
Joke's on you.
Ha-ha.
Rose, she and I are doing fine...
Never better.
Until you came along...
causing all that trouble.
You're a psycho. You know that?
I'm love sick is what I am.
Because of you, I had to
put Rose into the ground...
until the shit storm that
you caused blows over.
Now, get his maggot eating
ass out of there. Now.
Don't you make me do it or I'll
put a bullet in your head first.
Ashes to ashes.
Shit to shit.
Dirty work, huh?
You know, don't you worry.
I got a nice old spot'
picked out for you...
and Jackie here and
your little girlfriend.
No.
Rosemary wouldn't like it.
She knows what' you did to her.
What are you talking about?
When you put her in
and you shut that lid...
and throw that dirt on
her, she's gonna hear it.
And you think she's gonna like it?
No. She's gonna be pissed.
Rosemary understands
it's only temporary.
Oh, does she?
Might be forever 'cause
she knows you don't mean it.
Shut up!
She hates you.
Shut up! Shut up...
or I'll put a bullet in your
sorry little ass right now.
How about you go ask her for yourself?
She's right behind you.
Oh, you think I'm joking? Look.
Rose?
Vaughn, you don't know
what it was like...
to die alone.
How do you live with yourself?
Don't be hateful.
You're disgusting.
I hate you.
No. Don't be hateful.
You're not my Rosemary.
Go to hell.
Get in!
Die.
No!
Rose!
Help me! Help!
Abby.
Like I said on the phone...
you're gonna be mighty proud.
We are proud...
of both of them.
The kids did a really
smart thing out there.
They came right here after it happened.
By the time we dug him up...
old Vaughn had been in
there over two hours.
What are they gonna do with him now?
You know...
you came back for me.
I guess that makes us even.
Come here.
Woo-hoo. Hey!
Hey!
I'm feeling better now.
God. First chance I
get, I'm so out of here.
Huh?
Hey!
Ah. Huh?
Huh?
Love sucks.
All right.
♫ Ah ah Ah ah ♫