Encode by AreLift - SharedMovieLink
Hi! I'm Raj!
People have always
called me a kid.
thatwas to suggest
that I was an orphan.
Itwas then Mrs. Godinho came into
my life and gave me her love.
Thatwas a signal that I was
no longer all alone in the world.
She taught me something very nice.
Do so much good to others
that they never lack goodness
Itwas Mrs. Godinho
who taught me music...
and she wanted me to become
a very big singer some day
When I grew up, I started
dreaming of someone
My dream-girl
this was a signal that there was
someone, who was made only for me
I can't explain why, but I think
Mumbai is the city...
where a career and
my dream-girl await me
You mustwonderwhat `signals'
I'm talking about
According to Mrs. Godinho, God always
gives us the right signals
And it is we who
can't see them
I've always been fond
of body-building
Which is why I've kept away
from cigarettes and alcohol
If there is something I ever drink,
it's a cup of hot tea
A cup of hot tea!
And my beloved to
make me drink it up
May she be dark of skin,
or fair
But someone who
will embrace me
I wish I could meet her;
and every sorrow would vanish
When I leave home every morning,
after giving her a kiss
And every moment I spend then
missing her
For her, I will live and die
What else have I to do?
There will be
happiness for me
But nothing will have
meaning without her
May she be fair of skin,
or even dark
But she will embrace me
Every sorrow would vanish,
if only I could have her
She'll open the door for me,
when I return every evening
She'll hug me tightly
and say she loves me
She come to me
all dressed up
And relieve me of
the stress of the day
She'll be different
from the others
She'll be my wife
A cup of hot tea
And my beloved
to make me drink it
May she be fair-skinned
or dark
But someone who
will care for me
All my worries would vanish,
if only I could have her
There it is!
The signal to go to Mumbai!
Raja!
- Aba!
Hurry up, buddy!
How are you?
- Delighted!
At last! You've got the green signal
to come to Mumbai!
Knowwhat Mrs. Godinho says?
In Mumbai, you will make
your life and find ittoo
Watch out! You're going to be
a superstar in a few days!
You'll find your dream-girl too!
So how's your uncle?
- Don't mention that name.
Why not?
- The bloody miser!
God had rather made me an orphan,
than give me an uncle like him!
I thought I'd put up
with you and your uncle.
He doesn't let me live with him.
Why would he allow you?
Really?
- Of course.
So what do you do for a living?
And where do you stay?
I work at my uncle's
fruit-juice shop, all right!
But I live in my own house.
- What?
Oh yes!
- Your own house?
A house in Mumbai!
Do you like it? Great, isn't it?
- What place is this, by the way?
Now look; I have nothing
that God has given me.
Whatever I have is what I got
from the Municipality!
It's a gift from
the city of Mumbai!
Priceless stuff, I must say.
- All stolen. Real hard work, I say.
And what do you call the place?
- My home.
It's better than
living on the pavements!
If it wasn't for the roof and the
walls, it's worse than the pavements!
You can't think of bathing
without water, can you?
So you mustn't
call your house names.
Life is difficult in this city.
You'll get to know very soon.
That I know.
This is the city where
I will find everything.
Now tell me; what should be
my first step in the city?
Simple. You must buy a bike.
- What has that to do with singing?
This is a city of pretenses.
Those with vehicles
take off before anyone else.
We'd need money for that.
- Sure, we would.
Let me open the Reserve Bank's locker.
- Hurry up.
Here you are! Count it!
- Not me. Do it yourself.
It's 500 bucks!
- How about the time deposit?
Here's another 500 Rupees!
That makes it a grand!
But how will we get a bike in 1000?
- We've just got to open an account.
The same old gag, you mean?
Damn it!
You have given me these
post-dated checks, thank you.
Now for the last formalities. Sign
the papers and take away the bike.
Go ahead, son.
Sign it.
What's biting someone?
- Not me.
It's out there!
It's four guys against one!
Listen, son...
that isn't unusual.
Guys who issue dud checks
get beaten up like that.
Those guys are from
the financing agency.
They have their own style
of recovering money.
Dangerous style!
- 35 checks out of 36 were honored.
But his last check bounced. Why?
- Such beating for one dud check?
Sure... but you needn't worry.
Why not?
- You guys come from good families.
Do we?!
Forget our checks.
We even carry cash that bounces!
He doesn't, he means.
- Right!
That's my pen!
That's not the way you sit?
- This is Mumbai.
You never know who does
what behind your back.
Get going.
I'll handle the rear end!
Hold it! Here's the studio!
The guard saluted us because
we arrived on a bike.
Orthey wouldn't care!
This is a very big studio.
There's no one here, ma'am...
- No meetings without an appointment!
Abdul! You're empty-handed!
No fruit-juice for me?
No juices. I bring a singertoday.
Raju. My friend from Goa.
What a singer!
... is Mr. Mishra in?
Please hold this blazer.
We'll go and see him.
Punk! I don't get to see the owner
in the ten years I do the rounds here!
And you guys justwalk in
and getto meet him!
Listen, bag of bones!
He'd blow you away with his breath!
No! Don't breathe...!
Go on inside!
What's your problem?
- They've gone in. So will l.
I won't let you in!
- I'll force my way in!
Whatwill you do in there?
- Well...? What will l?
Why was I here, mister?
- To ask for the whereabouts.
This address, right?
- Yes. Take Bus No. 80.
Get off at the last stop.
That's where your house is.
Thank you very much!
Bus No. 80...
Absent-minded man!
He forgets to sing once he's here...
and goes back home. It's been
happening for 10 years!
Mr. Mishra, that friend of mine I spoke
about is here. He's a great singer.
Give him a chance, sir.
It'd make his life.
Everyone who comes here
claims he's a great singer.
Does anyone say he can't sing?
When is Sonu Nigam arriving?
- Any moment now, sir.
The name is Raju. From Goa.
I want to be a singer.
Throw him out, guys!
- Relax... I want to be a singer.
Do you know, darling;
I'm in love with you
You know it, darling;
I'd do anything for you
What a singer!
You're fantastic!
You're a top singer!
Oh yes you are!
I'll be a singer, won't l?
- Will you?
Who made Udit Narayan what he is?
I did!
And who made Kumar Sanu's career?
And Mohammad Rafi...?
- Rafi, too?
No! He made my career!
Now quickly record your songs
and bring the cassette to me.
Isn't it the music companies
which records the songs, sir?
I'll explain this to you.
I've heard you sing.
But how's the boss of my company,
Mahesh Hirwani, going to do that?
I want your songs recorded
so he can listen to it.
How much will it cost us
to have the songs recorded?
Maybe a hundred thousand
or 150,000
150,000?!
- Maybe 200,000
200,000?!
You have the talent.
You're going to make money!
200,000 bucks! That isn't money
we can find in our pockets!
My careerwill be
finished for 200,000
We haven't money for 2 liters
of petrol. And he wants 200,000!
I can't push this anymore.
- Get your Uncle to pay for gas.
I'll go to him. He must be angry
I haven't still gone to the shop.
We'll buy gas with the money
I bring from him.
Who's made a shop out
ofthis bus shelter?
Hey mister... who's made
a shop out of that?
It's still a bus-shelter, mister.
A company's beautifying it.
Still a bus stop! Strange!
It looks like a shop!
That's a shop, Aba.
- It's a bus stop.
It's a shop!
- A bus stop!
Take a good look.
That's your uncle's new shop.
You look very happy.
Have you scored with a girl?
No, uncle.
- Why are you late, bloody dog!
I got held up, uncle!
Butwhy are you eating the remains?
Remains, eh? I'll tell you.
This is a sweet-lime.
The juice in it is my principal.
Everything else in it
is my interest.
And you know, I never
let go of my interest!
You've earned so much in interest.
You must at least eat well, uncle.
God is kind. I eat the remains
of sweet-lime and orange.
I used to sell sugarcane juice
when I first came to Mumbai.
Fortwo years, I lived only
on the remains of sugarcane!
I'm glad, you didn't sell coconuts.
- Shut up!
You've turned up after lunch-hour.
You lose half your salary!
I have news, uncle. A friend of mine
from Goa is selling his shop.
What's the big deal? He isn't
giving it away forfree, is he?
It's as good as free, uncle!
How much would a 20 by 10 sq. feet
space sell for at Carter Road, Bandra?
For anything between
1.5 or 2 million.
He's giving it away
at 200,000!
At 200,000?
Butwhy's he giving it away
so cheap, my boy?
He lives in Goa. How'd he know
of the prices in Mumbai?
He's selling it at Goa's prices.
By Jove!
I'm going to buy that shop!
I'm going to buy it!
Where is this friend of yours?
- Out there... must I call him?
No! Don't call him in!
Let him remain there.
I'll get some unadulterated
juice for him.
Go on... Hurry up, my boy!
The miser's fallen for it.
Do you want 20,00,000 instead?
Don't be greedy. We need 200,000.
And that's all we'll take.
This is Raju, uncle. And that's
my uncle. Notworthy of any praise.
Sit down...
and have some juice.
You're my nephew's friend,
after all.
My nephew told me that you're in
trouble and want to sell your shop.
Don'tworry. You will have no
problems till I'm around!
I'll buy that shop!
No sweat, uncle. There was this chap
here today. The deal's almost through.
But the deal hasn't been struck.
- No! We only got talking!
No deal yet.
- And why not?
He wanted to pay me by check. I want
cash because I'm leaving for Goa.
He wants it in cash, you see.
- I see!
You can never say with these guys!
You must always get paid in cash!
I'll pay it to you in cash.
Just you come with me! C'mon!
He really doesn't
deserve any praise!
Here's 200,000!
200,000? Or is it
two watermelons?
Dangerous times, you know.
I've got to hide my dough!
I put back in the fruitwhat
I earn from it... open it!
My word, Uncle!
If only I knew...
I'll start my new shop tomorrow and
serve you the first fruit-juice!
It's made, uncle!
The shop's got made!
Why's he laughing so much?
- He's happy, you see.
He's going to Goa
and he's delighted.
Fantastic! You've got the dough!
We'll make a great cassette!
And you will be
the superstar!
This is the first time it has
happened in my 17 or 18 years
happened in my lifetime
There's someone...
There's someone I keep
thinking about all the time
I dream of her,
on silent nights
Lost I am,
in things I do not know
The breeze blows
the veil in the air
It sets my heart racing
Steady me, my friends
I seem to be losing myself
Caught up, I always am,
in these tresses
Footsteps awaken me
Why am I always
chasing memories?
My heart beats
in loneliness
I don't know
whom it pines for
Tell me, someone.
I want to know...
What's wrong with me?
Include my name too in the
list of the crazy lovers
This is the first time it has
happened in my lifetime
There is someone...
There is someone I keep
thinking about all the time
Hey! What's up with you?
Stop dreaming!
You are the real star.
He's only shaking his leg. And the
guys are going ga ga over the girls!
You're going to be a big star!
This cassette... it's worth 200,000.
Once the music company owners listens
to it... he's going to be fantastic!
Let Misra make you star.
I'll deal with my uncle later.
How are you...?
- Okay.
Why the long face? Where's Misra?
- Up there.
Up there? Have they
built another floor?
No. He's dead.
No, Misraji! You can't
leave me like this!
This was no age for him to die!
You wouldn't have died had
you waited for some more days!
I want to die!
Deliver me, O Lord!
Look! There's the owner of Music
Gramophone Company... Mahesh Hirwani!
Go and see if the
ambulance has arrived.
Get up... hurry!
It's okay... relax.
What's all this, Maheshji!
- He's dead... so what?
Do you know what he wanted most?
- Sure.
He wanted my company
to be at the forefront.
No?
All right. He wanted our company to
always find the money... right?
No!
- No? So what did he say?
What's he saying?
Mr. Mishra wanted him to be
a successful singer!
What?! These bloody
aspirants...
Take them away...
I wonder where these
guys land up from!
Take the madcap away!
Go on.
Weeping can make you tired.
- Sure.
Why are they noting our license number?
- Must be a no-parking zone.
Butwhen did the traffic cops
take to dressing like that?
They aren't the cops
brothers, are they?
No... I think they're
those thugs!
The first check we
issued has bounced!
Go on...
- I'll find a way.
What's the point in
eying the bike now?
What do you mean?
- The guy who owned it is dead.
- He's dead. His body's lying inside.
We'd even get the corpse
to pay us, okay? C'mon guys!
Sit!
The moment I open my shop, the
customers make a beeline for it!
That's what you get when you
have a shop on a busy road!
Thanks a million, Lord!
Let the queues continue!
Where have they gone?
They must've taken my shop
for a bus-shelter!
It's an earthquake!
Help!
Everything's okay out there...
so why's my shop being shaken up?
Somebody stop them!
Police! Police!
What's happening here?
- Stop them, lnspector!
They've squeezed my shop!
Who asked you to start a shop
at a public bus shelter?
Is this a bus-shelter?!
No! It can't be true!
This is a railway station!
There'll be trains here soon!
Have you gone mad?
- Sure! I've gone mad!
I've gone mad...!
I've lost 200,000!
My stuff is all garbage!
Stop this guy! He's the
one who has robbed me!
Stop! Where do you think
you're going?!
Get down! Get down!
Inspector! Itwas this guy
who sold me that shop!
Look... your uncle.
There are cops too.
Who sold the shop to you?
- Good God!
He's the one who sold it to me!
He's the one!
The bloody crook!
Get him, constables!
Go on, mister...
he's targeting everyone.
What the hell have I done...?
Forgive me...!
Get him, constables!
This guy's really gone mad!
It's my misfortune, Aba.
We've lost 200,000. And I haven't
even got to be a star.
Neither did I find my dream-girl
nor is my dream realized.
God keeps giving us those signals.
But we're fools not to notice them.
Take Misra's death,
for instance.
That is to suggest that I have
entered the wrong lane.
Mrs. Godinho's back there in Goa.
I think I'll go to her.
What? You have ruined my life.
And you'll go back to Mrs. Godinho?
Very well. You had to come along
and spoil things even more for me.
There's your signal...
so go to Goa!
You've been a great support, Aba.
- And that was a mistake?
I'll give you something
before I leave.
Whatwill you give me anyway?
- The bike's all yours.
The keys belong to you. And this
cassette is for your uncle.
Those thugs will beat me up
forthe bike...
and my uncle will beat me up
forthis bloody cassette!
Happy Diwali, fatso!
- What Diwali?!
He's only wishing you.
- I'm doomed, anyway!
Now either kill me.
Or I'm going to kill myself!
Right now!
Do you want to kill someone?
Look at this.
It's a bride.
The train's coming...
get out of the way!
Get the hell out of there!
Don't be crazy!
Leave the girl alone!
Get out, Raju!
The train's coming!
Thank God forthe car
which saved her life!
Take herto the operation theatre
and inform Dr. Chander. Quick!
Do you know her, sir?
- Of course.
Who brought her here?
- Her husband did.
I want you to check
this man's mental health.
He started a fruit-juice shop
at a bus shelter.
We want to know if he's really mad
orwhether he's faking it.
Why have you come in here?
Please go out.
This is an operation theatre.
- Take him away.
No... I won't go out.
That's the lady's husband.
Please, doctor...
- Now look, son.
but you must go out.
- Please don't do that, doctor.
Nothing will happen to your wife.
- My wife...? Oh yes! My wife!
She's lying there all-alone!
And I've never let her be lonely.
How can I leave her like this?
Please let me be here with her.
Quietly. In a corner.
The nurse's given me a sleeping pill.
- An injection. Not a pill.
May I sit down?
What's happened to my child?
What's wrong, dear?
On the day of a festival?
How's Pooja, K.D.?
What injuries has
she received?
No injuries as such.
She has suffered a head injury.
Back there... at the rear end.
Because of which she had
a brain hemorrhage.
Because of the force of the blood,
she's now in a coma.
We have conducted an operation to
lessen the pressure on her mind.
In medical terms, we call this
a state of coma vigil
Which means, she can hear, listen and
understand. But she can't speak.
Pooja will be all right,
won't she?
If only you had agreed to Pooja's
marriage with Romi, sir...
we wouldn't have had
to see this day.
But Pooja is already married!
- What?
She was brought here
in a bridal dress.
It was her husband
who saved her.
Romi...?
- Of course.
Where is he?
Romi has risked his own life
to save Pooja.
Did you... jump before a speeding
train to save Pooja's life?
I only did my duty.
- You have saved not Pooja alone...
you have saved the
whole family, son.
Why only Pooja? I'd have done it
for anyone in her place.
I was wrong, son. We turned down the
match, without even meeting you.
We thought you weren't good enough
for Pooja and for ourfamily.
I have nothing to do with what you
thought and what you nowthink, sir.
That's because...
- How were we to know, son...?
that you'd be the angel
to come into our lives?
Thank a million, Lord, for
sending him into Pooja's life.
Now look, ma'am. I have nothing
to do with Pooja or you.
Just please forgive me.
And please let me go.
Don't say such things, son.
I realize I've made a mistake.
That I should have
at least have met you!
I should have tried to understand you.
Please forgive me, son.
Please forgive me...
- Who are you folks?
Who on earth are all of you...?
Please let me go... please!
My boss is asking for pardon. You
mustn't leave Pooja in this state!
I seek your pardon, sir!
I have enough tensions in life.
I've got to sing... I mean, go!
...how am I going to explain?!
Get this straight, my good man.
I must see Mr. Oberoi.
Maybe. But he's in the lCU after
a heart attack. You can't see him.
Damn it! Is this a hospital
or is it a prison?
Now look; I'm not keeping well.
I'm going to get a heart attack.
Let me meet him...
- Skip the drama!
Well, all right.
Here you are.
You're trying to bribe me, are you?
I'm not going to let you in at all!
What a madcap!
Make him see reason!
What are you doing here?
Go to yourwife.
Look at him!
He barged into a funeral the
other day. And he's here today.
You let those two-penny guys in
and stop rich folks like me!
That chap is Mr. Bharat Oberoi's
son-in-law.
Maybe... what?!
- That's right.
Mr. Bharat Oberoi's son-in-law.
He's Pooja's husband.
Pooja even has a husband...
the jerk!
Why am I always
the fall guy?
I'm not blaming you.
Butwhy me?
I'm leaving now. Tell yourfolks
that I'm not Romi.
That you metwith an accident and l
happened to be there to save you...
is a signal that you have
a long life ahead of you.
And make sure you
drive slowly in future.
What is it now?
- I've heard what you said to her.
Have you? Then you must know
I'm Raj. I'm not Romi.
So go and tell them! Please!
- No! I can't tell them!
My boss has had a heart attack.
I can't tell him all that.
You don't think I'm a doctor, do you?
- You knowwhat state Pooja is in.
Should I tell him that you're not
Romi... I don't know what'll happen.
Please stay back! I have seen hope
in his eyes since you have arrived.
Who are you anyway?
And what makes you so interested?
I'm nothing more than an accountant.
But I've been with him for 30 years.
He has always treated me
like a brother.
I beg for his life...
Please don't go away.
He treats me like nothing, okay?
So I beg of you for my life...
I've taken enough in life anyway.
Give me a break. Please!
See?... now step aside.
Son-in-law! How are you?
- You, sir?
Don't embarrass me
by calling me sir!
Son-in-law?
- You're Pooja's husband.
Why didn't you tell me you're
Mr. Oberoi's son-in-law?
Fantastic! You are
Mr. Oberoi's son-in-law!
What's fantastic about that?
It's indeed amazing,
son-in-law.
Honestly, when I saw you weeping
at Misra's funeral the other day...
I knew for sure that
it was a son-in-law...
that you have the
Goddess's blessings.
What a melodious way
of crying! Indeed!
I've yet to see a son-in-law cry,
errr... sing, like you!
You are undoubtedly the
son-in-law No. 1!
And what happens to this cassette?
- To hell with this one!
I'll have a fresh one recorded
for you... just you see!
I'll give it a release so grand
that no son-in-law...
...I mean, no singer
has ever had!
So just drop in
at my office tomorrow.
The son-in-law...
my Statue of Liberty!
Find Romi quickly, Goverdhan.
Brother's been asking for him.
Go ahead. I'll find him.
Romi ought to be with my brother.
That's what the doctor says.
So bring him quickly.
God Almighty... where will
I bring him from?
And whatwill I tell them?
Stop crying... Romi's here.
Really?
- Yes.
I thoughtthat if playing Romi
could save Bharatbhai's life...
so why not? Saving a life
is anyway a noble deed.
You're a great boy...
Let's go. He's asking for you.
Open your eyes, Bharat...
Iook who's here.
I will hold something against you.
Why wasn't I born as your son?
Open Sesame!
- Hey! This is her bag.
Correction. It was hers.
It now belongs to us.
Look! Jewellery worth
half a million.
A laptop. The stuff's
worth over a million!
My life is made, Raju!
I'm shedding tears of joy!
- Don't cry. I'll return the bag.
Return it?! Whateverfor?
- To steal is a sin, Aba.
I see! A sin, eh?
We conned my uncle into buying a bus
shelter as a shop. Wasn't that a sin?
We did that for my career.
- I see.
Wasn't it a sin to issue a check
for 30,000 when you had just 1000?
Thatwas to further my career.
- Oh great! For your career!
And now that I land some dough,
it's all wrong!
Now look; I did every wrong only
for my career. And I've got my break.
Who's giving it to you?
- Know whose daughter she is?
She's the daughter
of Bharat Oberoi!
And Mahesh Hirwani...?
- What's up?
Is he dead?
- He's giving me the break!
I see. He's going to die soon.
Know what Mrs. Godinho
always says?
We meet God at every step in life;
it's just that we don't recognize him.
Have you ever been
drenched in the rains?
Sure. On many occasions.
- Has anyone offered you an umbrella?
Sure.
- You didn't recognize him
I did. It was Babban!
- It wasn't Babban...
It was God!
- God? Babban?
Have you ever lay there,
without anything to eat?
It's happened so many times.
- Did someone come and feed you?
Sure. The milkmaid did.
- It wasn't the milkmaid.
That was God, too.
I met God last night too.
And God gave me a break.
- I see! God has given you the break!
How could I forget to tell you?
I met God last night too.
Who?
- The one who gave you the break...
and gave me this bag!
- Hold it!
I'm going to return that bag!
- You can't take away what God gives!
God hasn't given you that bag, Aba.
You've stolen it from him.
And it's a sin to steal from God.
Give that to me, Aba.
Take it!
No! Not anymore, please!
How are you?
- I'm okay, no thank you.
How many fingers are these?
- Five, thank you!
And who am l?
- The lnspector!
Where are you, at the moment?
- In a hospital, no thank you!
Was that a bus-stop or was it
a fruit-juice stall?
It was a bloody bus stop!
Looks like he's all right, doctor.
Are you hungry?
- I'm famished!
What will you eat?
- Remains of all the fruits!
Give him some more shock, doctor.
He isn't all right.
No worry. That's the mental ward.
Such noises are commonplace.
It's day already... wake up.
Here's your bag.
It was with my friend.
You'll find everything intact. Except
5000 Rupees, which my friend has spent.
But I'll return the money as soon
as you regain consciousness.
I had told you that I would
never meet you again.
But Mr. Goverdhan has requested me
to stay back...
and play Romi till your
dad gets well.
I have my interests at heart too.
I'm a singer, you know?
Mahesh Hirwani is going to
release an album of mine...
because he thinks
I'm your husband.
My life is made!
Someday I will recite
a song for you.
Why someday? Let me recite it
for you right now.
You must give me a big hand
if you like the song, okay?
Itwill laugh;
itwill cry
Itwill find someone;
and itwill lose someone
In solitude, itwill suffer
That's every heart in love
Come, Romi... they're asking for you.
Has Mr. Goverdhan arrived?
- Not yet. But come on.
They want to ask you something.
What? What do they want to ask?
- Why are you scared?
I'll come after
Mr. Goverdhan arrives.
Of course he will arrive.
Now come on... C'mon!
How can I believe that
you are Romi?
Give it a thought.
When the accident occurred,
Pooja was at the wheels and you...
That's Monty from America.
He's my sister-in-law's son.
And this is Romi.
I can't believe he's Romi.
Any proof?
- I am the proof.
I know he's Romi.
Pooja had once introduced
me to him.
Really? When was that?
- Actually, when Pooja and l...
went to buy a computer for her,
we had lunch together. Right?
You have spoilt her
with your indulgence.
You kept her secretwithout
telling us anything.
I thought I'd tell you
when the time came.
When are we doing the recording, sir?
- We're doing it, son-in-law...
it'll be done in good time.
Just don't worry!
Don't mention his name as
son-in-law on the album.
He's kidding!
The album will have it
in bold print: Romi!
Not Romi. It oughtto be Raj.
- Raj?
Your name is Romi!
- Right.
Butthe album will say Raj.
- Why?
Why did Yusuf Khan choose
to call himself Dilip Kumar?
Because thatwas a
lucky name for him.
I see!
So Raj is a lucky name for you!
So we'll call you Raj.
What's the big deal?
When are we doing the recording?
- We're busy this year.
But I promise. Yours will be the
first album next year.
A year? Impossible!
I had told you, Raj. HMV promises
to release the album in 3 months.
And what did Polygram say?
- 15 days, they promised.
So let's go!
- Hold it, guys
You guys getworked up
for nothing!
Wow! You're into Moonwalking!
You're a born star!
Sit down... Go on.
- What for?
It'll require at least 8 days to...
- 8 days!
That's a very long time.
- Be reasonable, guys.
You know what a busy music composer
Anu Malik is, don't you?
He's away in Europe.
You must wait for him to return.
Besides, Pooja's in hospital.
Would it be okay...
to record itwithout her?
- It's Pooja I'm doing all this for.
Pooja will spring to herfeet,
the moment she listens to my song.
Mr. Goverdhan!
- Congratulations!
All ourtensions are over!
- They're over!
We have no problems in future!
- No problems!
Let's go and tell
Bharatbhai the truth!
Here's where the problem lies.
I won't tell Bharatbhai the truth.
Why not?
- I don'twant to!
Like you didn'twant it earlier.
- You have evil on your mind.
No matter what. I won't tell him!
- I'll go and tell him then.
So I'll tell him!
I'll go and tell him the truth!
- I'll tell him too...
aboutthe conspiracy you had hatched!
- What plan?
Whose plan?
- Have you forgotten what you told me?
The old man has millions!
He'll die of a heart attack.
That you'd strangle the girl and
we'd split the millions between us!
What rubbish...
are you talking!
I could never imagine you'd
be such a cheapskate!
I'm not a cheapskate!
You're compelling me to be one!
Go out... I've got to make her change.
- Okay, we're going out.
Not him. He's her husband.
He'll help me.
Go on... please.
- Listen to me!
Please pull that sheet.
She has...
She has a mole there!
- God!
Disgusting! Bloody disgusting!
I've never seen such a husband.
He shut his eyes...
when I asked him to change his
wife's clothes and grabbed my skirt!
You're an amazing man!
You aren't as rotten
as I thought you were.
And you're a much better man
than I thought you to be.
You know Mahesh Hirwani, don't you?
Sure. I do know him.
What is it about?
He thinks I'm really
Bharatbhai's son-in-law.
How many fingers on my hand?
- Five fingers, thank you!
Who am l?
- The lnspector, no thank you!
And who's that?
- The doctor!
Are you hungry?
- I'm famished, I swear!
And what will you eat?
- Rice and lentil-curry. Anything!
Very good! He seems to be
all right now, doctor.
Now tell me; why did you start a
fruit-juice stall at a bus stop?
There was this scoundrel who claimed
to own it and sold it to me!
How much did you buy it for?
- 200,000!
Whom did you buy it from?
Speak up... whom did
you buy it from?
Itwas that scoundrel
I bought it from!
Itwas that scoundrel!
He isn't all right, doctor!
Give him the shock!
Once the recording is over,
I'll tell them that I'm not Romi.
Know something? Whatwould God lose
if you were the real Romi?
Are you coming or going?
I've been looking for you.
Mr. Goverdhan! It's you
he's talking to!
I couldn't tell whether he was
talking on the phone or addressing me.
I have news for you.
There was a call from Jahnvi.
Really...? That's my
daughter who called.
What did she say?
- She's returning to lndia tomorrow.
I want some important medicine from
the U.S. Could Jahnvi bring it?
You ought to be happy
your daughter is returning.
Jahnvi and Pooja keep no secrets.
She must surely know about Romi too.
Jahnvi and Pooja are
more like sisters.
Even at home, no one has ever
discriminated between them.
They've grown up together.
Should Pooja have something,
Jahnvi too got it.
Whenever the bangles tinkle...
Whenever the anklets tinkle...
Whenever it pours...
My heart calls out
My love, O my beloved
Day in and day out,
my heart calls out...
My love, O my beloved
Why is there a pounding in my heart?
Why does it pine so?
What have you done to my heart,
O heartless one?
My sleep vanishes;
I'm restless
The things that loneliness
does to me
My face is flushed
of its color
I lower my eyes
out of shyness
I feel shy, even when
I look at the mirror
Why have you made me pine...?
Why have you taken away my peace?
Whenever a boy meets a girl...
it awakens a desire
in my heart
When the bridal cymbals
are played somewhere
Whenever they deck up
the bridal palanquin...
I go crazy at heart
and yell out
Please come with me. I have
something to discuss with you.
I'll be back soon.
- Okay, father.
Can't you see where you're going?
That's Jahnvi... my daughter.
Why does it always happen to me?
- What happened?
Nothing really... I thought
I'd run away from here.
And I ran into my life...
must I run away now? Or mustn't l?
No need to run away!
Jahnvi has never met Romi!
She only spoke to him
over the phone.
Care for some tea?
- No thank you.
No... don't cry, Biji.
You mustn't cry.
Make her see reason, dad...
We ought to be happy that
Pooja's life was saved.
We were saved before something
drastic could happen.
And what's so seriously
wrong anyway?
I spoke to the doctor
before I arrived.
Know something? This is exactly
what happened to Superman, too.
Yes! And he's back to his
flying ways already.
All Pooja now has to do
is to simply get up.
We've taken enough of
your drama, okay?
Remember? You had planned a dance
competition for us, on my return?
You were supposed to do an lndian
dance and I'd perform a Western.
I've even learnt new steps!
All right... now tell me
how's your married life?
I've penned a couplet.
Want to hear it?
I've filled up tubs with
my tears, as I remember you
The uncouth man that you are;
you simply bathe in it!
What happened, dear?
- I ran into a madman out there.
I went to wash the cold-drink
he spilt on me.
You washed itwith
yourtears, did you?
God protect your
friendship with her.
Come, Jahnvi.
Let me introduce you to Romi.
That's Romi.
This is Jahnvi.
And you said she hadn't
ever met Romi!
That's what I thought. That she had
only spoken to him overthe telephone.
Have you seen Romi?
- No.
Pooja told me that he was short,
had brown eyes and curly hair.
But this chap...
In that case, you're
not Jahnvi either.
Pooja told me that Jahnvi's
fat and ugly...
that she's squint-eyed
and has a bucktooth.
But all that is not true.
You're very beautiful.
Getwell, Pooja.
And I'll fix you!
Tell him, Biji.
It's Diwali today.
We won't be celebrating it...
butwe must have a prayer.
We have to adhere
to our customs.
So come over to our place
this evening.
Okay?
- Certainly.
It's your place too, son.
Glory be to the Goddess of Wealth
The Gods too pay
obeisance to You
Glory be to Thee
My husband got this bungalow built
when my son was just 15 years old.
The prasad.
- You look beautiful.
Knowwhat Mrs. Godinho says?
It's fun to celebrate
Diwali with yourfamily.
Take some prasad?
- It has 150 calories!
I can't eat that!
- Go on. It's in the name of God.
All right. I'll try some.
You're calorie-conscious,
aren't you?
No wonder you have
such a great figure.
Happy Diwali everybody!
Please give me a smile!
Welcome, Master. Let me introduce
you to my son-in-law.
Your son-in-law?
- Yes. He's Pooja's husband, Romi.
I've met him.
- Forget it.
I have forgotten it.
Please remind me where.
He's a singer. He's training
Pooja in classical dance.
But he has this characteristic...
he's very absent-minded.
So tell me where we have met
lt'll refresh my memory.
Must l? In everybody's presence?
- Sure! Go ahead.
The Master and I participated
in a dance-contest.
He danced so well that
he dropped his pants.
Did that really happen?
- Yes... have you forgotten it?
But you mustn't forget that
he's Pooja's husband, Romi.
May I show Romi Pooja's room, dad?
- Certainly.
Why just the room?
The house belongs to him... go on.
This is Pooja's room.
- It's nice.
And where's your room?
- This is the one.
And which is Pooja's room?
- This is our room.
Didn't Pooja tell you
that we share the room?
She did. And I forgot.
So many perfumes... but why have
two of each?
That's because Pooja likes
whatever I like...
and I also take a liking to
whatever Pooja approves of.
Look at this... we even have
the same kind of cell-phones.
Aren't they nice?
But what happens if the two of you
fall for the same guy?
That's impossible.
- Why?
Because Pooja has already
approved of you, Romiji.
Don't you approve of me then?
- Well, I do.
But not in the same way.
- In what way, then?
Pooja told me that
you're good at poetry.
So tell me the first couplet
you recited for Pooja.
Everyone I come across...
appears to be like you
Looks like I'm going
to go mad...
for, I'm in love with you...
I wait for you
No wonder Pooja loves you
so much, Romi ji.
What the hell are you doing?!
I didn't know your preferences
had changed so much in six years!
Oh come on! I'm pretty hung up myself.
It's her I see every place.
I find her in you, too.
- Really?... happens, I guess.
Does it really?
- Of course.
Lovers are like alcoholics.
They imagine the bottle everywhere.
But spare me and
let me go to sleep.
I was dreaming about the milkmaid.
Know what...?
Will we only dream about girls?
Get up.
What's up with you?
I've got your address
with great difficulty.
What's so difficult?
This is an easy place to find.
What would you like to drink?
Let me get something.
Aba! Get up!
- Who's that?
Me... Jahnvi's here.
How about some juices?
Sorry! No juices!
That's my friend, Aba.
Greetings!
And good-bye!
- Good-bye!
Dad says you have fulfilled
his desire for a son.
He has sent you this little gift.
- Oh yes. Small guitar indeed.
What's in the guitar anyway?
- The car-keys.
What car is it?
- An Opel. It's out there.
Why's it out there?
- Because it can't be brought in.
Dad has had the left-wing of
the bungalow vacated for you.
You will live with us.
He has given me status
with all this respect.
On the other hand, he belittles me
by asking me to live with them.
Thank Dad on my behalf.
All I want is love. Your love.
And love from everyone else.
Because there is nothing I can
give you, except for my love.
Know what Mrs. Godinho
always says?
Those who possess love are
never to be considered poor.
How about some tea
and buns?
Abdul! At least send for
some tea and buns!
Looks like you've won again.
I've won again!
Maybe you're lucky at both.
Maybe you're beloved is very much
with you... and you don't know it.
I don't understand.
- Let me explain.
As Mrs. Godinho always says...
God shows us the signal
at every place...
but it is we who
can't understand.
We meet so many people
in our lifetime.
But then, we come across
an individual...
whom we feel like meeting
time and again.
We are happy in his company.
We are sad, when he goes away.
That's the signal then.
One of us will have to leave...
The two of you will leave.
I will stay back here. Okay?
Let Romi stay back, father.
- No, dear. He's tired.
He's tired... Go on.
- You ought to relax, sir.
The two of us will spend
the night chatting away.
Only one person is permitted
to stay here. Just one.
Drop her home then, okay?
Go on, dear.
That's even better...
I haven't brought my car...
will you give me a ride?
I certainly would, had the
elevator been working.
Will a bike do?
- The bike, yes.
They seem to be
mopping the floor.
You mustn't fall while
you try to steady me.
You've fallen down!
- To steady you.
What?
- You need to fall to steady yourself
Shall we go?
That's not the way.
We'll fall again.
It's fun to be with you.
We're going to be together for life.
- Now tell me something.
You took Pooja to the
Goddess's temple, didn't you?
Don't even talk about that temple!
I've forgotten where it is!
And I wondered whether...
- What?
I was wondering if you could take me
to the temple in the morning...?
As Mrs. Godinho always says,
Never mess with the Gods
You have opened my eyes!
Why's she so formal with me?!
Is this any time to return?
Excuse me! Who are you
to question me?
I see the interest
Romi's showing in you.
What for?
- We're going to the temple.
Know something, Monty?
The temple isn't meant for devils.
So why's Romi going there?
Come on...
How much time will it take?
Another 15 or 20 minutes?
Ifwe walk fast like this,
we'll make it in 15 minutes.
At this rate...
we'll take 20 minutes.
Ifwe walk as slowly as this,
it'll take us 25 minutes.
30 minutes in slow motion and we won't
reach there ifwe don'twalk at all!
Why do I get the feeling that there's
something you wish to say to me?
Howwill I tell her?!
Pooja and you are so very alike.
That's justwhat she said to me.
Why do I feel there's something
you wish to say to me...?
And what did you say
to herthen?
I said...
I love you
I cannot live without you
You're very much in love,
aren't you?
Pooja's very lucky
to have found you.
You're luckierthan
Pooja is!
You will meet someone like me,
who will love you very much.
You want that, don't you?
Well, Romiji...
How many more questions to go?
- This last.
How do find it without Pooja?
Great!
You mean my heart?
Howwill I tell you
about what I feel?
Everyone I meet
appears to be like you
Looks like I'm going to go mad...
in love with you;
while I wait for you
I've realized it after meeting you.
- What is it?
Love is a strange feeling
where one forgets oneself.
Why does it happen?
This is where the limits
to craziness begin
It's your face I see
in every other face
How will I even think
of anything but you...?
It's you who clouds
my mind
This is one helplessness
I have never known
It's true.
Believe me, my love
I should know what it means
to be lonely
I'm going to go mad;
I think so certainly
I'm in love with you;
I await you
What's okay? No one is.
Not she. Not you. Not I
I don't think anything's okay
Love is a high
you can never be free of
It's a bond between
two innocent hearts
A bond, you can never break
It's truly said,
whoever has said it...
You can never forget
your first love
I like meeting you
and talking to you
What are you thinking about?
I've been wondering about
what you're thinking.
I wish I could forever rest
in your dark tresses
To look at you;
to desire you...
and to be lost
in a world of my dreams
Ever since I have
set my eyes on you...
I remember nothing else
I even take the fairy tales
for true now
I'm going mad...
I think
Couldn't God find a place
farther away?
You mustn't crack
such jokes.
Tell me something.
There's a temple near your house.
So why drive for 5 hours, walk for
another 2 hours and come here?
God is God, no matter
what place it is.
You drove for 5 hours, walked for
2 hours and came here... what for?
For my love, of course.
- Right.
God puts those in love
to a test.
But He never lets anyone
return empty-handed.
So hurry up and ask for
whatever you want.
I have a problem.
I've always been to the Church
with Mrs. Godinho.
I don't know how to pray
in a temple.
Whether you do this, this
or this...
...always pray with
all your heart, okay?
What have you asked for?
- And what did you ask for?
I've asked for love.
And I've prayed to her to
breathe life into your love.
Really?
- Yes.
How about making a wish together?
You will certainly have your love.
I promise.
Here are the offerings.
It isn't right for a married woman to
go without vermilion in her parting.
Will you apply the vermilion?
How is my wife?
What's up? Why doesn't
someone tell me?
How is my wife?
Why don't you tell me how my wife is?
So no one's saying anything.
But why are you so quiet?
Why don't you say something?
Why are you in bed?
You must get up.
For my sake.
Don'tworry.
I'm here.
Now no one can take us apart.
Rahul, what's going on?
Go to your cabin.
Doctor, why are you taking me away from
my wife? She's sick. She needs me!
She's going to be fine.
Go to your cabin.
Take him away.
I'm not going.
What's wrong with her?
Metwith an accident.
Yes, car.
Come.
Why do people make cars?
Even if they make cars, why do
people have to travel in cars?
You tell me, people can walk too.
That was Rahul. A patient
in our mental ward.
My Papa has inconvenienced you.
I apologize for him
- Was that your Papa?
- Yes. Ever since Mama's death...
..he has been sick. Please
forgive him and pray for him.
When he was here...
...how come...
..you were looking so afraid?
Monty, you got your brains
in the wrong place.
You're a suspicious fellow.
Goverdhan has known him all along
Don't you ever say things
like that about Romi.
Look Pooja is absolutely normal.
I have been through
all her medical reports.
She needs no further
treatment in this hospital.
May God bless us on
this auspicious day
May you live long
May the apple of our eyes
live long and all be well
You are our only hope.
Let all be well
Come, come in son
No son! Notthe leftfoot.
The rightfoot.
It's a ritual.
When husband and wife step into
their home forthe firsttime...
The rightfoot is the bestfoot
to putforward. It's a good omen.
Come in.
Whenever Pooja came home,
she would make the place so lively.
This homecoming isn't quite like that.
Times are changing so fast
... it gives me the jitters
Yes?
- Do something.
- Yes?
Find a good boy and get
Jahnvi married right away.
She's your daughter. You find the
boy. As forthe wedding, anytime.
What's the hurry?
Let Pooja recover first.
You could look for a boy afterwards.
- The wedding will happen...
only after Pooja has recovered.
But she can get engaged before that.
- I have a suitable boy.
- Forget that one. I'm here
I'll look for a boy. After all,
I too have a responsibility...
..towards this family. Besides,
there might be someone she likes.
If that was the case,
she would've surely told me.
- How could she possibly tell you?
- Romi is right.
All right, then find outwhether
she likes someone. If not...
I'm giving you the responsibility.
Find a good boy for her.
Your Daddy has given me
a responsibility.
What?
To find a suitable boy for you.
Someone like me.
Tell me something.
Have you chosen someone for yourself?
Why do I get a feeling...
that you're going to marry
someone you like...
..not someone your family wishes?
No. I'm going to marry someone
whom my family prefers.
Who else but you can decide best
about your own life?
They are my elders.
And about my life...
they'll take a careful decision,
won't they?
Besides, do you think they will
get me married off to a nobody?
This is your life.
Will you spend the rest of your life
with someone whom you don't love...
with someone you don't even know?
- Now you're serious!
I can't deny my folks their happiness.
- All you care for are your folks?
- What about my happiness?
- You too will be asked to opine
After all, you're the
senior son-in-law.
And irrespective of whom I marry,
you are the one...
who will sing at my wedding.
You will, won't you?
Tell me, which song
is it going to be?
To tell you I love you
Somebody kill me
Leave me to simmer
What is the heart and love?
Forget that
Love is nothing but a game.
Kill the whole issue
Just ensure that you're never sad.
But you always fall short!
If this is the song you'll sing,
the marriage party will run away.
What I don't want is happening
and what should happen isn't!
And you're spitting away!
Try to understand me.
I am so tense!
Why does this always happen to me?
why? The right things never happen!
And what shouldn't happen
do take place. Do you follow?
Just as staying hungry
is not a matter of food.
Similarly I don't have
to explain to talk less.
No you're explaining to me?
Sit down and I'll explain to you!
- It's a commode.
- Sit on it!
- Jahnvi's problem is...
- Yes?
When I tell her something...
She thinks it is Romi speaking.
- Whereas it is me not Romi!
- You said that.
When I tell herwhat's in my
heart, she thinks it's Romi.
Whereas it is not Romi!
It is l!
Because I'm me not Romi!
I am Romi but I'm not Romi. I'm me!
You're bleating like a goat.
You'll be slaughtered like one!
Enough now. Let's eat dinner.
When I open my heart to her,
she thinks I have no character!
Why and how does she think that?
You knowwhat a character I possess!
Then? Today I'll tell her
everything clear-cut.
I am me, she is her
and you are you!
- I am me.
- I'll tell her that too!
Tell her. Then what?
She'll love the real you!
She will hate you!
Then don't ask me why you
only find girls in dreams!
Why not in real life? Don't ask me
And what about Mahesh Hirwani?
He will cancel your recording!
- Then clap your hands at home.
- Why don't you keep shut?
Whatwould you say if
you were Mrs. Godinho?
- Me..?
- Yes.
- I'd be Mrs. Godinho?
- What would you say?
If I were her, I'd say...
Imagine it. Your first recording..
- The song is a sure hit.
- Yes.
- Your songs are playing all over.
- Your posters are put up
everywhere. - Yes...
- Not only kids, even
- Fathers are dancing!
You are super hit!
- Your pictures in the papers...
- Are being printed!
- Girls queue for your autograph.
- They do!
- Car, bungalow...
- Secretary!
and you'll get your dream girl too!
I will get her, isn't it?
Speak on my master, my bread
winner Mr. Oberoi.
- My finance giver.
- Romi here.
Same thing, son-in-law.
- What's the news?
- Has Anu Malik returned?
Everything is done.
Anu Malik is here.
And Sameer is here to
write the song.
And the publicity is
on in full swing!
Now I'll throw 1000000
cassettes in lndia.
And 2000000 cassettes abroad!
- When is the recording?
- Tomorrow.
My master, it's at 2.
Please come to the studio.
Caught you!
- I won't let go!
- Are you mad?
Come to prison!
You turned me mad!
Now you don't recognize me!
You cheated me out of 200000!
Thanks to you the world thought
I'm mad. Gave me electric shocks!
Have you experienced it?
The world turns dark!
The body starts smoking!
I won't let you go! Pay me back!
- Sorry, uncle.
- Uncle?
You recognize me?
Why did you do this to me?
I want to know why?
I had problems.
I'll pay your 200000.
Of course I'll take the 200000!
But I also want the interest!
All right. Here is the
money for the interest.
This is the interest money.
When will you pay the principal?
Can I fool the uncle of my friend?
Trust me, uncle.
Don't cry. Okay.
But I won't spare you!
I'll go home on the motorcycle!
Twerp! Get off the motorcycle!
- What is it nitwit?
- What does that mean?
This is my motorcycle. I'll
charge you for sitting on it!
- Is it yours?
- Is it your Pop's?
Catch him! He's running away!
The cheat is taking the bike!
Wasn't the bike yours?
He'd given me the bike as interest
for the 200000 he owed me!
Did he fool you too?
He fooled, cheated and
deceived me. I am ruined!
He cheated me of 200000!
You thrashed me?
If all of you beat him..
I'll pay you 500 bucks!
- What?
- 5000, 10000, 20000, 50000!
I'll pay you a lakh!
Break his arms and legs!
He has cheated me twice before.
Once I lay my hands on him,
I'll settle all scores.
Sir!
I remember. You are Raju!
My name is Romi. What is it?
But remind me of the time we met.
You were in the ladies compartment
of the train. With no pajamas!
The ticket checker caught you
and the police hit you with sticks.
- I bailed you out!
- Good Lord! Did this happen?
- Yes.
- Sir...
You may leave. I wish to discuss
something importantwith Romi.
Do you know what this is?
Yourfather has nominated me.
This means henceforth
your house, your offices..
Your businesses and properties..
I own all of them!
I thought yourfatherwas
very smart, a good businessman.
But yourfatherturned out
to be a big fool!
If I want, I can get
yourfamily to the road!
And I can make yourfather beg!
Pooja...speak up.
Try my dear.
Lift your arm, my child.
Which arm had she lifted?
- Lift your arm.
- Make an effort.
There's no reason to be depressed.
This is good news for us.
I came here to become a singer.
To earn some money!
That is why I needed your support.
But now you and your Daddy
will need me all your lives!
You slapped me, right?
Nowthe echo ofthat slap will
be heard by yourfamily forever!
I'll bring yourfamily to the road!
And I'll place a begging bowl in
yourfather's hand and make him beg!
Come on, slap me. Slap me!
Hit me. Come on!
Slap me, abuse me.
Butwake up.
I don't want to be the master.
I don't... everyone will be so happy.
They were so happy when
you raised your arm.
Now I can't bear to see them sad.
Please wake up.
Please get up.
You won't get up?
You won't? Don't get up!
I'll go and tell everyone
right now I'm Raj not Romi!
Afterthatwhetherthey call
me a fraud or send me to jail..
I don't care!
Because you'd be responsible for it!
What are you doing here?
- Who is Raj?
- Where is Raj?
God! What now?
Raj is dead!
Raju is dead without dying!
Look, he's innocent.
I admitwhatever he did was
because he wants to be a singer.
Now he's acting as Romi
because he loves you.
He loves you a lot.
The truth is he wants to be
Pooja's brother-in-law not yours.
Today is his first recording.
Forgive him today. Tomorrow
I'll get him there personally.
- What does he think? He..
- Where is Raj?
What a voice! See that?
He hasn't sung a note and
you're showering praise.
He even clears his throat in tune.
Just a minute.
- Sing something.
- Heart...
Slightly lower pitch..
- Heart, heart...
- Fantastic!
Just a minute, Mahesh. Lower octave.
Sing in a lower pitch.
Try to understand. He's the
son-in-law. I'll go low if you wish.
- Now begin.
- You're being funny.
I want him to sing in a lower pitch
and you're sitting down for nothing.
- You're being foolish.
- You're being silly.
He's the son-in-law, can't climb
down. He'll always remain high.
- You sing on.
- Heart...
The crazy heart
what's he singing?
I tell you dear, I love you
The heart is crazy
Crazy...
Crazily in love
The heart is turning crazy
Crazily in love..
Lost in love.
Why would I get the feeling
you want to say something to me?
Tell me what to do
Do I live or should I die?
The eyes would smile
but be filled with tears
I had everything but for you
What else do you need?
Life is nothing without you
Love me so much that
I lose my senses
I should die without you
Not be able to bear separation
Love abounds everywhere
that I set my glance
My prayers have been answered
I came to ask you for my love.
Today she is with me.
But cure the person
who brought us together.
Jahnvi's union with me will be
the signal that you heard me.
Do me anotherfavor.
Make Pooja stand on her feet.
Mrs. Godinho always says,
you get what you ask for others.
Hence forth I won't
ask you for anything.
Give Pooja a new lease of life.
Breathe live into Pooja.
My Pooja is all right!
My Pooja!
You are all right?
You are all right!
Son, Pooja is fine now.
You've always been
with us in our sorrow.
We'll be together
even in this joyous moment.
Why is she crying?
She would wipe our tears
and is crying herself.
She's been holding back
hertears for so many days.
Let her cry.
See who I've brought.
Yes...
Too much exertion isn't good.
- Let her rest.
- Nothing to worry.
She was sleeping for some days
Now she is awake.
In a few days, Pooja will...
Let her rest.
Listen...
Where are you going?
Stay with me.
Yes, you stay here.
Why did you save me?
If you can pretend to be Romi
to save my Daddy and me..
Can't I act as your wife
to save your career?
You need rest. Your husband
will come and see you later.
The heart loves the one who
was a stranger till yesterday.
The one who gave me life,
I want to die for him.
Both sisters got
cheated by the same man!
You are Romi! Pooja's husband!
How will I face Pooja?
I swear I am Raj not Romi!
You are lying! You thought
Pooja isn't going to wake up.
So let me trap Jahnvi!
God! Such a deception!
Thank God I don't have other sisters!
What? Master, leave that instrument.
Do you remember who I am?
I've met you somewhere.
Yes, I remember!
- Listen to him.
- You are Romi, our son-in-law.
No, I met you in the music company.
- Yes, I remember!
- Listen...
We danced together and
my drawstring broke...
Sit down and play music!
- I'm going!
- Please don't go.
You...you're a big Romi!
No, I'm a big Raj!
- You are Romi!
- Ask your Dad if you don't trust me.
- what's wrong?
- Tell her who I am.
He's Romi, our son-in-law.
- Your brother-in-law.
- No, Jahnvi...
- What's wrong?
- Tell her who I really am.
- Really?
- Yes.
Dear, this is Raj not Romi.
He is Raj, he became Romi
because I asked him to.
Butwhy did Pooja call you Romi?
Even I didn't understand that.
My album will be released in
2 days. To save my career.
Butwhy are you trying to
convince herthat you're Raj?
- Because we love each other.
- What?
What? What?
Now you don't raise a problem!
The problem has been solved.
My daughter likes the one I do.
What could be better than that?
Leave the hand.
Stay within limits.
You know very well
that I'm Raju not Romi.
I'm leaving. Nowwe won't meet.
Take care of yourself.
Drive carefully.
My accident and your saving
me is a signal of the fact...
I have to live a long life with you.
- You!
- Yes but how did you guess?
Your perfume.
How did you suddenly drop in?
Can't a wife come to see her husband?
Sure. Definitely.
Hasn't sister-in-law come?
- She's making arrangements.
- What?
We're throwing a party at home
And here's your dress.
- I do have clothes.
- The party dress code is fusion.
You must be there by 8.30.
We'll be waiting for you.
The heart is anxious, the weather
is great. My beloved, I wait for you
I too waited for your
grandfather like this.
Grandma, you've been
through a lot because of me.
- Yes. - You must've thought
I considered her Sita!
It is true.
In our times we had
neither disco nor club.
But there's so much for you.
Yet if you return home pure...
You are today's Sita.
There comes Romi!
You're quite late.
The dogs made me run the other way.
- No, you're looking great.
- You too.
Come along, everyone
is waiting for you.
Come here.
You're looking fantastic!
Nobody can take their eyes off you.
Am I really looking so beautiful?
He's lying! I didn't
ask him to buy it.
Listen to what Romi is saying.
I was saying,
Mrs. Godinho always said.
One must praise what one likes.
My internal feeling is
this pair is very good.
Now you are lying.
No, I spoke the truth both times.
These are internal feelings.
The heart never lies.
Your daughter is wonderful
but your son-in-law...
He's a real gem!
Yes and he's very proud.
Pooja is now better.
I think I'll send her away
in a day or two. - Good idea.
Come here.
- What are you doing? If..
- lf..?
What will Daddy say?
What will grandma think?
If Pooja sees us?
Whatwill Ramu think?
Is that it?
Why are you standing far? Come close.
Closer still.
Closer....
Daddy is here!
She's fooling around.
- Come down when you finish talking.
I want you to meet somebody. - Yes.
what are you doing?
Whatwill people think?
Can't help it. Can't control.
- What??.
- I'll clear everything in the morning
That I'm Raj not Romi.
When will you get us married?
You talk tomorrow.
The marriage the day after.
- Why not tomorrow evening?
- Too early.
Stay in control. Get a hold on.
You will marry Jahnvi.
No.
Don't worry, I said it won't.
You're always on the phone!
I was talking to the GE
about the flight.
I'll find a good time in a day or
two and talk to brother and Jahnvi.
Itwill laugh'
Itwill shed tears
It has to lose;
It has to possess
Morning and evening, in
solitude, it will sigh
Every heart that falls in love
In every eye...
It grows like a dream
Nobody has control over a heart
that thuds crazily
It will stay awake;
It will have to fall asleep
It will live
It will have to consume venom
It will die for a handsome face
You give away your peace of mind
Why do you take anxiousness?
This is one such craziness...
...that gives its' life for love
It will have to keep mum.
It will have to speak out
It will have to bear
the pain of separation
Try as others might,
it won't get tired
- Good day.
- Caught him!
He is Raju who took 200000 from me!
And sent me to the asylum!
Nab him and call the police!
I was given current!
- Call the police!
- Stand here!
- You won't say a word. Quiet!
- He'll cheat you too.
Is your name Raju not Romi?
Why don't you answer?
Romi or Raju? You cheated us!
You played with ourfeelings!
Why did you do this? Why?
Is this how you repay our love?
Is this what Mrs. Godinho taught you?
Call her. Let us see her.
Is this how one cheats?
I told you another lie.
There's no Mrs. Godinho.
She left me when I was six.
I mean, she died.
She sometimes comes to
meet me, take care of me.
But since you came into my life..
She never came to meet me.
She must have thought
Raju has found his family.
Now I'm not needed.
But it doesn't happen thatway.
It doesn't.
I need you. Badly.
I am sorry I said this.
Don't so much that
it neverfalls short.
But it always falls short!
What's wrong?
Daddy, why did Romi leave...?
You knew he was Raju not Romi?
Yet you supported him?
I supported him because
he is a boy with a good heart.
what did he do as Romi?
Think ofwhat he could've done!
He acted as my husband but
nevertook advantage of me.
You knew everything yet..
Daddy, you even gave
him power of attorney!
He could have taken over
all your wealth if he wanted.
Romi for whom I left you all
was the one greedy for wealth!
It was later that I realized
he loved my money not me.
I wanted to give my life for Romi.
But Raju saved my life.
And this is how you
treated that Raju.
That wasn't good.
- Not good at all.
- Dear....
Do so much that it
never falls short.
Yet it always falls short.
Yes, it falls short.
- He's my childhood friend.
- Good day.
You don't have a family.
And we don't have a son.
Why do you test my love?
You are my life.
Why do you take my life?
Please don't get mad at me
like you did at Pooja!
Raju really loves me!
He wants to marry me!
If he doesn't marry me,
he will die!
Will you waste all the tears on me?
Why don't you understand?
He's my Dad.
How can I tell him
that I love you?
What would you say if you were me?
I would say...
And what would Dad say?
Do you really think
Dad will say this?
Then I'll go and tell him now!
What is this?
- What? Meaning you..
- Yes, Daddy.
I don't knowwhen
I fell in love with Raju.
What do you think?
Is marriage a game?
What is his status compared
to ourfamily and ours?
Is this what I had said?
...when you told me about Romi.
But now I won't say that.
I always want to see
happiness on your face.
- I'm very happy today!
- So am l!
My news will knock your brains out!
What I will tell you
will knock your brains out!
Come in. Then we'll see
who will knock outwhose brains!
First shut the door!
- First you tell me. - No!
- First you tell me!
- What?
- I was going to tell Dad.
But I already told him!
What?
We both fell in love together!
Our choice is the same from
childhood. So the boys too will be!
No, fine if they are similar.
But shouldn't be one boy!
Orthere will be a twist
in the story!
- Tell me. - No.
- Tell me...
Tell you something? He's handsome
but an even better human being.
- Now you tell me.
- I won't!
Tell me...
I've lived a life but incomplete.
Once I find him,
life will be complete.
wow! Poetry!
- Tell me, Pooja!
- As if you told me all!
- Tell me!
- Okay.
His name is...
I won't tell!
Okay, listen...
Let's both tell each other
without saying a word.
I knew you'd like Monty!
- lsn't it?
- But I didn't know you'd like Raju.
You don't know Raju.
I was not conscious.
When I regained consciousness,
I knew what true love means.
Honest, I'd have died
if I hadn't found Raju.
You like Raju, don't you?
I like him if you do.
Calm down.
I'm missing mother a lottoday.
Look, my child...
We are very lucky.
I was wondering how long it
would take to repay sir's debt.
God gave us the opportunity
in this very birth.
I can give my life
for Pooja not just Raju.
I always...
The heart of one daughter had to break
Look, don't you worry...
I'll fix everything.
No. Pooja has just
got a new lease of life.
Don't you want Pooja to be happy?
Then you won't say a word.
Or I'll getvery angry!
- Do you understand?
- I didn't know my child had grown up.
- You listen to me!
- Please listen Raju...
Speak up.
Come on!
Pooja means more to me
than a real sister.
And Dad is dearer than my father.
Not once did they make me feel
I'm an accountant's daughter.
I'm highly obliged to them.
- Me too.
- I want herto be happy.
- Me too. - But if she finds out
about us, she won't take it!
So please marry Pooja.
Said your piece?
Now may I speak?
May I speak?
You are now 19 years old.
I want you to live to a 100.
Will you sacrifice your coming
81 years for those 19 years?
Do you know what 81 means?
Marriage, husband. Children.
Daughter-in-law, son-in-law.
Their children!
Will you give this all up?
If they have obliged you..
Kept you home for 19 years..
Call them here. I'll keep
them for 19 years and a day!
Do you love me?
Then please marry Pooja!
Listen to me.
I love you a lot. Marry Aba.
Because he's done me many favors.
He kept me in his house
for 19 days! 19 days!
I love him a lot.
Will you marry him?
Will you? Answer me!
Please marry Pooja.
Don't you want to marry me?
Then even I don't want to marry you!
Marriage causes the problem.
I'll marry neither you nor her!
Are you happy now?
Why are you crying?
Be happy. Come on. Go.
Do you know what you're doing?
In any case, there's no other way.
Give it another thought.
Unless I leave,
Raju will never marry Pooja.
On every branch of the tree...
flowers do not necessarily bloom
Everyone always gets not
the love he seeks
In solitude and music
Amongst your own
In the shadows...
It will smile even
on thorny paths
- Sing a song.
- Get lost!
- Move behind.
- No, it's all right.
Okay, give it fast.
Jahnvi, my child...
That's what I'm saying.
Pooja is getting married.
How do I look?
You look good in everything.
The other dress too is lovely.
Wearthat and show us.
Darling, it's getting late.
Now tell me how I look in this dress.
Pirouette and show us.
You're looking lovely in this too.
- Grandma...
- She wants to show this to Raju.
She wants to impress him.
Did Jahnvi have to leave now?
She could tell me what suits me best.
And in which dress Raju would like me
Raju himself has come.
You tell me, how do I look?
You're looking beautiful.
I want to say something to you.
But there's no need
to say it. I know it.
But I'd like to hear you say it.
- Pooja, I don't...
- Won't this dress look better?
- I don't know.
- Pooja, wear it for him!
- Son...
- Yes?
We were coming to meet you
for Pooja's hand in marriage.
- The priest hasn't arrived.
- I'll check.
Pooja is so happy.
Pooja's happiness is
now in your hands
May God keep both
of you happy forever.
- where are the coconuts?
- Coming...
It has fallen short.
Your existence doesn't matter.
Pooja? Tribhuvandas here.
Your jewelry is ready.
When should I send it over?
I'm Jahnvi.
You've dialed he wrong number.
- I've dialed the right number.
- No...
Maybe I've brought Pooja's phone.
Call on my cell and you'll
be able to talk to Pooja.
Right. Also the solitaire
setfor both of you is ready.
- It's very pretty.
- I don'twant it now.
You won't get such a
pretty thing again.
Give it to Pooja on my behalf.
What are you doing? Do you
know what Raju is going through?
He's leaving all of us and
going to Goa permanently.
He says he will only marry Jahnvi.
Why should I marry Pooja?
And he is right. Both of
you love each other so much.
Why should he marry Pooja?
I don't understand anything.
Why do you want him to marry Pooja?
Today you have shown...
The difference between your own
daughter and an adopted one.
Why did you ask herto sacrifice?
Why didn't you ask me?
Why didn't you talk to Jahnvi?
Why didn't you convince her?
And you...
You'd told me, your rescuing me
was a signal of the fact...
I have a long life to live.
Then how did you assume I would die?
The man I like...
My sister loves him.
My sisterfinds hertrue love.
What could make me happier?
But you... were not fair
to my Jahnvi.
Not fairto my Jahnvi.
All of you have been unjust to her.
Where is Jahnvi?
I ask you, where is Jahnvi?
She left for America an hour ago.
Why do you like when
you're not good at it?
Which flight leaves for
America during the day?
Swear by me and honestly
tell me where Jahnvi is!
In orderfor you to marry Raju..
So she is marrying Monty.
I'm in a rush today.
Thrash me tomorrow.
Smart Alec!
We won't spare you today!
Rascal! We're not allowed
to eat onions by our religion.
I knowthis today.
It's wrong to take advantage of
anyone. You run, I'll manage them.
- You run away!
- Go, I say!
Where are you going?
Put the wedding necklace
in the bride's neck.
I tell you, my beloved,
I love you
What are you doing?
Why are you doing it?
- Answer me!
- For you, stupid.
You want to lose your life
for my happiness?
Will you just stand there
orwill you come here?
Brother-in-law.
- Come on.
- Yes, son.
Hit me as much as you want.
I've eaten lots of onions.
Beat me here. I'm a sinner!
Hit me here.
I was thinking of what the dress
code should be in Jahnvi's reception.
I think it should be
swimming costume!
There's a lot of love
in this world.
You only need to lift
your eyes to see it.
Man's coming to this world is a signal
There is somebody in this world
who is meant only for him.
Every heart that falls in love..
It will sing a song
The loverwill be
recognized among a million