It's Officer Eddy.
I'd like you
to come into the station.
Oh, is it about the house,
'cause I could...
Dwight, sweetheart,
I'll explain.
Okay?
Just come with me.
I apologize for the mystery.
I don't mean to scare you.
You're not in any trouble.
Everything's fine.
You'll be fine.
But, honey, someone brought
this by our stoop,
and I just thought
you should be somewhere safe
when you found out...
With somebody.
He's going to be released...
...and I don't know
how much you...
They are missed.
It's an awful thing
he did to them.
I'm just gonna hold you here
for a little while...
Do you sell stamps?
I just want this
party over with.
Wade doesn't know.
Yeah, if you stop
talking out of your ass.
You putting him on your books?
♪ Gonna shine on everyone ♪
♪ Come a little bit closer ♪
♪ You got to hear
those three little words ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Come a little bit closer now ♪
No, she talks too much.
Yeah, I'm not used to it.
She talks shit
or she talks too much?
- What? Me too, man?
- Yeah.
Maybe.
Just let me piss.
I haven't done it alone
in ten years.
Hey, man.
You all right?
Yeah.
I got some shit lined up.
You might wanna wash your hands.
No, man.
I don't piss on my hands.
Hey, you want order
another beer?
Yeah.
I'll order some shit.
I hear that.
You motherfucker!
Come on, man.
What are you doing
in there? Beating off?
Yeah, we should've had
a hooker waiting.
Let's go.
The party's for you.
Ow!
Let's go, brother.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, fuck!
♪ This be the moment
I was waiting for ♪
♪ What's happening boy? ♪
- ♪ Can't wait no more ♪
- ♪ Moose ♪
♪ Bulletproof ♪
♪ Moose ♪
♪ Bulletproof Moose ♪
♪ I care less about
the fortune and fame ♪
♪ Lay down my flow
when I'm doing... ♪
Did you hurt Wade?
Yeah.
Wade hurt my parents.
I don't think he did.
Let's look
at the windy conditions.
Of course, with the
thunderstorms themselves,
the winds could be quite strong
and areas of fog are possible.
If you've been to the gas pump
in the last couple weeks,
you've probably felt
the stinging
of some of the fastest climbing
gas prices in years.
So where...
Small dogs and cats
should be kept in an enclosure
if left unattended, as coyotes,
oh, are able to jump...
Two, three, four, five.
One more time.
One, two, three,
four, five.
- Hey.
Got a late start.
Would you mind moving
the sprinklers into the bushes
- in, like, 20 minutes?
- Sure, yeah.
And then just turn it off in 15.
The girls did Shrinky Dinks last night.
Could you put them in the oven?
Ten minutes, 350, something like
that. It's on the box.
Thank you.
Bye, girls.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Dwight?
Hey, Sam.
You have a good day.
Thank you so much.
Hi.
I wish I had more time.
Got an asset inventory
that can't push.
Do you need money?
No.
Did you get my letter?
I sent it after
I crossed the bridge.
- It was a postcard.
- No. When?
A couple days ago.
Well, postcards take more time.
Dwight, I'm not following.
I sent it on my way
to Deerfield.
I know he's out,
if that's why you're here.
The DOC sends a notification
and a restraining order.
Let's not...
I'm sorry I left.
I'm sorry, too.
With this busted sandwich.
I have had worse.
You need to put the registration
for the Bonneville in your name
if you still have it.
I have an extra set of keys
if you want them.
It's gone.
As far as the estate goes,
you're still owed $2,800.
There's still a box
of your things...
You can keep it all.
I don't want it, Dwight.
No. That's fine.
I'm not used to talking
this much.
That's what people do.
I know.
How's Delaware?
You knew?
Not exactly where.
We still try to go
every few years
to keep the tradition.
Mostly for the kids.
You know I have two kids now?
I know.
I mean, I...
I saw you
a couple of summers ago.
You were on the boardwalk.
You didn't say anything?
I...
I looked a mess.
So why now?
Wade Cleland gets released.
Well...
I thought there'd be something
on the news, but...
There's nothing.
I killed him.
Wade Cleland, I killed him.
What?
Bullshit.
When?
I think yesterday.
Oh, God, Dwight.
I thought he'd kill me first.
I'm glad he didn't.
And I'm glad he's dead
and I hope he suffered.
Excuse me.
You got ketchup on yours?
I don't.
Sorry.
Thanks.
Clelands still live up
on East Hundred.
The older one,
he owns limousines.
- Yeah.
- How great is that?
Operates out of Charlottesville.
Every time I see one pass
through town
or on the way to the airport...
Fucking June, fucking prom...
- You don't own the...
- Where are your children?
Home with the sitter.
Let's get back in your car.
- What?
- They never called the police.
Okay, it's ringing.
She's not picking up.
No, no, no.
Oh, no.
Wait.
- Oh, God.
- What's wrong?
I'll turn myself in
here, if that's what you want,
but I can't do it until I know
that you're safe,
that the kids are safe, so...
The Clelands
need to be arrested.
All of them?
For what?
Look, I...
Just go.
You can call the police
from Pittsburgh
if that's what you want.
Just so long as you're not here.
It's my house, Dwight.
They know that.
The car is registered here,
and it's not worth...
Is there a gun in the house?
Course not.
Duck. My duck.
Your duck.
♪ Don't call me baby ♪
Okay.
I only told work, nobody else.
I'd forgive you
if you were crazy,
but you're not.
You're weak.
I got him.
Hey. Were you coming for me
or for her?
Were you coming
for me or for her?
Ah.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Frame's too small ♪
♪ Too pretty for this picture ♪
♪ Gonna take it's toll ♪
♪ When's it gonna
catch up to you ♪
♪ Leave the bar ♪
♪ And burn the bridge that
brought you to the alcohol ♪
♪ Days seem hazy ♪
I, uh...
I just...
- Yep.
- ♪ Got no voice ♪
♪ You know it's calling on you ♪
♪ Got no choice ♪
Fuck.
I had an accident on my leg.
Hey, is somebody out there?
Hey!
I'm in the trunk!
Let me out!
Is that you?
Help!
Let me out!
I'm dying!
Let me out, you son of a bitch.
Help!
Let me out of here!
Not until I have a gun.
Shit, I can get you a gun.
Hey!
I got to get out of here!
I'm thirsty!
My leg's broken!
- Mrs. Gaffney, hi.
- Yes?
I was looking for Ben.
Is he still in town?
No, he moved a while ago.
It's Dwight, from Orange High.
I just...
Oh.
I'm so sorry, I...
Mr. Gaffney's upstairs
asleep and...
I didn't recognize you, Dwight.
Okay, this is where he works.
This is where he lives.
He moved when he got back
from Japan.
He was deployed.
You might need a map,
'cause it's out of the way
off of...
I have a map, thank you.
So are you in a rush?
Sort of.
Yes, ma'am.
Otherwise I'd offer you
some tea.
I'd love some tea.
Good.
Ben works late, anyway.
They play
God-awful music there.
Excuse me.
I was looking for
a band member...
What?
I was looking for a band
member named Ben.
Ben Gaffney.
And I think he was supposed...
- You mean Benny?
- Yes.
Yeah, he's here.
He works the bar.
He's not in the band.
That's fine.
Do you know what time
he goes home?
Ben.
Hey, Ben.
Ben!
It's Dwight...
Evans.
Oh.
Wow, man.
You look square.
I've been away.
Yeah, man.
No shit.
Just peaced the fuck out, huh?
Same year El Duce
got hit by a train.
Yo, put the first 200 miles
on this thing
stapling up
your missing posters.
I never thought of that.
So are we getting beers or...
Look, I need to warn you
that I'm here,
that I came to you
because I need a favor,
and it's a big one.
Sure.
What do you need?
You remember James Henry's
brother's party
with the stripper at his shop?
Haven't really thought back
that far in a while.
Where is it?
I got this Polaroid of you
and me with the stripper.
It's hilarious.
We look terrified.
Ben, I need to hurry.
Right.
You hunt?
No.
Target shooting mostly.
Mountain bike...
What do you need this for?
- I'd rather not...
- Oh, no, no.
Hey, no, man.
The less I know, the better.
What do you need out of the gun?
At range?
At close quarters?
Close up or far away?
Oh, close up, probably.
I don't know.
- Hopefully not at all.
- Roger that.
All right.
Let's see what we got.
Enfield Mark III, Circuit Judge,
a Mosin,
my current personal favorite.
Bolt Action.
It's heavy.
Plus surplus ammo's cheap.
- How much do you weigh?
- I don't know.
All right.
Picked this up this year.
Shoots its own
9-millimeter cartridge.
But you got to load it
slide back with a stripper clip.
Nothing that's special to you.
Just whatever's
the least expensive.
All right.
Here.
Mini-14.
Gun show, no papers.
It's carbine.
That just means it's short.
Semi-auto.
It fires every time
you pull the trigger.
20 rounds, very reliable.
And I got extra ammo.
You recognize it?
It's the A-Team gun, man,
from the show.
Except theirs were stainless.
What's up with that?
It's an arrow wound.
So...
You're, like, in this.
- Yeah.
'Cause I was just blowing smoke
up your ass, bro.
Thought about calling the cops.
Please don't.
Not yet.
I don't have a speech.
I just need you
to trust me, please.
I do trust you, bro.
But I can't send you off
like this.
I could train you.
CQB, man.
Surprise, speed,
violence of action.
I just need...
I just need somewhere quiet
right now.
I got 16 acres.
Take the road we came in on
till it ends.
You'll see the targets.
You ever killed anyone?
Two on purpose.
Can I get a thing of water?
Stay in the trunk.
That's easy.
My leg's broke.
Were you coming for me
or for her?
- Who?
- You came to my sister's house.
Were you coming for me
or for her?
Look, man.
You.
Why didn't you just
call the police,
send me to jail?
Same as you.
Just keeping it in-house.
What if I surrender?
I accept.
To the police.
You don't get to do what you
did and just lock yourself up.
Shit, I'd give you props
if he wasn't my brother,
or if he deserved it.
Which one are you again?
Teddy.
Who's the boy in the limousine?
He's just a boy.
Not a concern.
He said something about Wade.
He said he didn't think
he'd hurt anyone.
Couple dead niggers
might disagree.
He just meant Wade
didn't kill your parents.
That's not true.
Well, that settles it, then.
That's how this works, man.
The one with the gun
gets to tell the truth.
Problem is, you don't know shit.
Tell me.
I should've done the time.
Are you saying you killed them?
Nope.
What are you trying to do?
What are you trying to do, man?
Goddamn!
Fish in a barrel!
Stop it!
Whatever you're trying
to say, say it.
I didn't do it.
Wade didn't do it.
Our father, Big Wade,
shot your dad.
You don't fuck with a
man's wife, his family.
Whatever my dad did,
he did with your mom.
Together... it was a mistake.
Well, shit's not a mistake.
Both of my parents are dead.
Your mother being in the car, that
was a fuck-up. I'll give you that.
If what you're saying
about Wade is true, then...
Big Wade had cancer.
Couldn't let him die in prison.
I'd have done the time,
but I had two strikes.
Little Wade,
he could take the plea.
- Call them.
- Who's them? The cops?
Your family.
What do you want me to say?
We're all gonna...
we're all gonna meet up
somewhere public,
and this is gonna end.
Okay.
Don't say my name,
and don't mention the gun.
And we're in Kentucky.
You ever been to Kentucky?
Hey, call me back now.
They're not answering.
Can I call the house?
Yeah.
Shut up.
I'm fine.
It's my leg.
Yeah, I'm with him.
He's here.
I'll try, but we already
been through that.
All right.
She wants to talk to you.
- Who's she?
- My sister.
- She's bossy.
- Throw it on the ground.
Keep that thing pointed right
at my face.
I ain't going anywhere.
Turn your head.
Look away.
It's all over
as far as I'm concerned.
You hear that, sis?
Don't go starting...
There's nobody home,
stupid fuck!
They're hunting.
Yeah!
Fuck!
Fucking legs are asleep.
I'll die.
I should.
But my sister
never did anything to you.
So please just tell me.
You bet.
I got the gun.
You get the truth.
Not to satisfy
your fucking curiosity, Dwight.
Just know that the man
that killed your parents
didn't die by your hand.
He smoked and he drank and he...
I guess he didn't fuck
'cause of the cancer,
but he watched
all his favorite TV shows,
and he died a free man.
You're gonna die
like your whore father did.
Shot in the fucking face.
Or how about first
we open up that belly?
You want to see your guts steam?
Must have something in there,
since you took Wade from us.
And for that your sis...
Wait.
Just the one?
- Yes!
- Sorry.
I had to wait for him to aim
before I could shoot.
It had to be legal,
at least on my part.
His... his head...
That's what bullets do.
Jesus.
I am not impressed.
You missed from two yards?
Hey, let's go, man.
I'd like him off my property.
- OK.
- Come on.
One, two, three.
This is Wade Cleland?
It's his older brother.
Wade's already dead.
Wipe this off your face.
He's probably got hepatitis.
Pick that up.
Throw that in here.
Don't forget to wipe that off
before you get rid of it.
You got the keys?
Yeah.
Show them to me.
What about the rest of his head?
Coyotes will get that.
Long as there's no teeth.
They're not gonna
let this end...
Not now.
Yeah.
Well, I'm switching you
to buckshot.
Yeah.
Doesn't have the stopping power
of a 12-gauge,
but you seem comfortable
with it.
It shoots slugs too,
but you wouldn't hit anything.
It's only five shots, though,
so the Steyr
is your secondary weapon.
You get another eight rounds,
plus you got the stopping power
of a .45.
Hey.
Hey, man.
I know this is personal.
That's how you'll fail.
No speeches.
No talking.
You point the gun.
You shoot the gun.
Hey, I threw a few MREs in here.
Uh...
Nice.
I lost mine.
Or shot holes in it.
I'm sorry...
I brought all this to you.
I'm glad you did.
Otherwise you'd be dead.
You know what I mean.
If it were my family, I might do the same.
I don't know.
But I'm not helping out
'cause this is right.
This is ugly, man.
If you ever find that Polaroid
of us and the stripper,
do me a favor.
Yeah?
Destroy it.
Okay.
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets, No regrets ♪
♪ I'm living the life
of a king ♪
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ I've been a lot of places ♪
♪ And I've seen a lot
of things ♪
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ Even when I'm sad ♪
♪ You can still hear me sing ♪
♪ If it should be, I'll say ♪
♪ That he calls me today ♪
♪ Well, I've no regrets ♪
♪ For this life I live ♪
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets, no regrets ♪
♪ Now, how lucky can I be? ♪
♪ And I sure hope, oh, yeah ♪
♪ That you have love like me ♪
♪ A happier person ♪
♪ I know you'll never see ♪
♪ If it should be, I'll say ♪
♪ That he calls me today ♪
♪ I've no regrets
for this life I live ♪
♪ No regrets ♪
♪ I've got friends ♪
♪ And I got my health ♪
Monday. 7:38 P.M.
Hey, when you're home,
stay there.
Had to swap out a tire
to tow her four down.
Hello, this is Officer Downey
with Community Corrections
calling to reach Wade Cleland.
You had a urine analysis scheduled this
morning, which you did not attend.
- Yeah, shut up.
- I'm fine. My leg.
I'm with him.
He's here.
Why don't you keep that thing
pointed right at my face?
I'm not going anywhere.
Look away.
Turn your head.
It's all over
as far as I'm concerned.
You hear that, sis?
Don't go starting any...
End of messages.
Hey, you've reached
the Cleland residence.
You know what to do
and when to do it,
so get to it.
End of messages.
Hey, you've reached...
Hey, you've reached
the Cleland residence.
You know what to do
and when to do it,
so get to it.
Hello.
It's me.
Fuck!
- There's a message!
- Play it!
Jesus.
Hello. It's me.
Um, Dwight Evans.
Wade is dead.
Motherfucker, shut the fuck up.
And... Teddy is dead, too.
He told me everything.
- I'm gonna fucking kill him!
- Goddamn it!
I didn't kill him.
I mean,
I... I guess I did.
But it doesn't matter.
By my count, that's two of yours
and two of mine.
I don't know how this ends,
but I'd like it to...
Um...
...or it can keep going.
I just need my sister
to be left out of this.
That's why we're going
to Pittsburgh,
you dumb son of a bitch!
What the fuck are you?
- It's him!
- I'm sorry.
We're gonna fucking kill you.
I wish you would have.
Call if you want
to talk this through.
You... you people...
I'm sorry to bother you at home.
- I took all the guns.
- Don't shoot us.
I've been here awhile.
I've been trying
to think of reasons
not to do this,
to end your family.
I mean, there's a thousand.
But there's one why I should.
Fine.
We'll leave her out.
How can I trust that?
After everything I've done.
It's not our problem.
Yes, it is.
- Go! Blow his head off!
- Kill him, William!
- I don't want to.
- Your whole family will die.
Stop!
I don't know much about guns,
but I'm pretty sure
I've got more bullets than you.
Don't kill him.
If he dies tonight,
your father killed him.
He killed everybody here.
I think you did your job,
William,
but I still got to finish up.
Quickly, I think.
It's funny.
That hurts less than the, um...
The arrow.
You can leave that gun.
Just wipe it off.
My car's down the road a ways
in the woods.
But it's dark.
He's my father's son.
Teddy told me about Big Wade,
the cancer.
Don't you mention their names.
You know what's awful?
Just 'cause my dad loved
your mom...
...we all end up dead.
The keys are in the car.
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets, no regrets ♪
♪ I'm living
the life of a king ♪
♪ I've no regret ♪
♪ I've been a lot of places,
oh, yeah ♪
♪ And I've seen
a lot of things ♪
♪ Even when I'm sad ♪
♪ You can still hear me sing ♪
♪ If it should be, I say ♪
♪ That he calls me today ♪
♪ Well, I've no regrets ♪
♪ For this life I live ♪
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets, no regrets ♪
♪ Now, how lucky can I be? ♪
♪ And I sure hope, oh, yeah ♪
♪ That you have love like me ♪
♪ A happier person ♪
♪ I know you'll never see ♪
♪ If it should be, I say ♪
♪ That he calls me today ♪
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ For this life I've lived ♪
♪ No regrets ♪
♪ I've got friends ♪
♪ And I got my health ♪
♪ And I got love ♪
♪ And that's my wealth ♪
♪ What more ♪
♪ Could anyone ask for? ♪
♪ I'm so happy ♪
♪ I could shout ♪
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets, no regrets,
no regrets ♪
♪ I've been living
the life of a king ♪
♪ I've been a lot of places,
oh, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ And I've seen
a lot of things ♪
♪ Even when I'm sad ♪
♪ You can still hear me sing ♪
♪ If it should be, I say ♪
♪ That he calls me today ♪
♪ Well, I've no regrets ♪
♪ For this life I've lived ♪
♪ No regrets, no regrets ♪
♪ Oh, no regrets, no regrets ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa-oh ♪
♪ No regrets, no regrets ♪
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
♪ Oh, no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, no regrets ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ No regrets,
no, oh, no regrets ♪
♪ No regrets ♪
♪ You can leave ♪
♪ Your dead-end mouth ♪
♪ I can see you ♪
♪ Got nothing to say ♪
♪ So leave me be here ♪
♪ Gonna destruct in my ♪
♪ Own way ♪