"THE CABINET
OF DR. CALIGARI"
Act 1
"Spirits surround us on every side -
they have driven me from
hearth and home, from wife and child."
"She is my bride..."
"What she and I have experienced
is yet more remarkable than the story
you have told me."
I will tell you...
"In the small town,
where I was born..."
"...a traveling fair
had arrived."
"Him..."
"My friend, Alan..."
Come to the HOLSTENWALL FAIR!
WONDERS! MARVELS! MIRACLES!
SIDESHOWS - ALL NEW
"Come, Francis--
let's go to the fair."
"The Town-Clerk is in
a bad mood today."
Dr. Caligari
"Wait!"
"I want a permit to operate
my show at the Fair."
"What kind of a show is it?"
"A somnambulist."
"Step up! Step up!
See the amazing CESARE,
the SOMNAMBULIST!"
End of Act 1
Act 2
That night the first
of a strange series
of crimes occurred.
...Murder!
"A stab wound from a strange object
caused the death of the Town-Clerk..."
"Step up! Step up!
Behold for the first time...
Cesare, the somnambulist!
Cesare the miraculous!
23 years of age!
Who has slept for 23 years.
Day and night...
He is about to wake up from his rigor mortis...
before your very own eyes.
Don't miss this!"
The cabinet of
Dr. Caligari
"Wake up, Cesare!
I, Caligari, your master,
command you!"
"Ladies and gentlemen!
Cesare knows all secrets.
Ask him to look into your future."
"How long shall I live?"
"Until dawn!"
Murder
in Hollstenwall
Reward 1000 Mark
On the way home...
"Alan, we both love her,
but no matter who she chooses,
let us remain friends."
Night...
End of Act 2
Act 3
"Herr Francis! Herr Francis!
Herr Alan is dead - murdered!"
"The prophecy of the
somnambulist?!"
"I will not rest until
I have solved this mystery!"
"I shall ask the police
for permission to examine the somnambulist."
"A Murderer! Help!
A murderer!"
"Wake him!"
HOLSTENWALL MURDERER CAUGHT
Attempts Third Killing
End of Act 3
Act 4
Anxious about the
long absence of her father...
"I swear I have nothing
to do with the two murders.
So help me god."
"It's true that I tried to
kill the old woman..."
"...and I thought they would blame
the mysterious murderer again..."
"Is my father,
Dr. Olsen, here..."
After the funeral...
Night...
Cesare!
"It can't have been Cesare.
I've been watching him
for hours, asleep in his box."
End of Act 4
Act 5
"Is the prisoner safe
in his cell?"
"Let me see him"
Madhouse
"Do you have a
patient named Doctor Caligari?"
"You may want to ask
the director of the institute directly."
"But... HE is Caligari!"
While Caligari is sleeping
in his mansion...
"He's asleep."
SOMNAMBULISM
A Collection from Upsala University
Published in the year 1726
"His special studies."
The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari
In the year 1703, a mystic named Caligari visited the small towns
Of Northern Italy traveling around with his somnambulist named Cesare.
For months he caused great panic in town after town
by repeated occurences of murder
committed always under
the same circumstances.
He ordered his somnambulist, who he had brought completely under his control
to carry out his adventurous plans.
To evade any suspicion, Caligari put a puppet
which resembled the somnambulist
into the wooden box in which the somnambulist used to sleep.
My diary
March 12th
At Last... At last... A somnambulist was admitted
to the asylum this morning.
...Afternoon.
Now nothing stands in the way of my long cherished ambition.
At last I can put the Caligari theory to the test - -
I now shall soon know if this patient can be compelled
to perform deeds he would shrink from in his normal waking state.
Can he be made to commit murder?
Obsessions.
"I must know...
I must understand his secret.
I must become Caligari!"
You must become Caligari
CALIGARI
End of Act 5
Act 6
"The sleeper has been found
dead in the ravine."
"Put down your mask -
You are DOCTOR CALIGARI!"
"From this day on this raving madman
has not left his cell."
"See, there is Cesare.
Do not let him prophesize
for you, or you will die!"
"Jane, I love you -
will you marry me?"
"We who are of royal
blood may not follow
the wishes of our hearts."
"You all think I am insane. It is not true.
It is the director who is insane!"
"He is Caligari!
Caligari..."
"At last I recognise his mania. He believes me
to be the mythical Caligari.
But I think I know how to cure him now."
THE END
subtitles by humankebap