25.000 English
PAL-DVD RETAiL subrip © 16-11-2014
The Calling (2014)
Hey, Dale.
-Good morning, Hazel.
-How we doing?
I'm great. There you go.
Extra bacon today, okay?
-Great.
-Here you go.
Thanks so much.
Hey, you know,
I hate to bother you with this,
but there's more of those
cross-country ski tracks.
-They go right through my property.
-Yeah. Well, winter's almost over.
-I know that, but can you stop...
-Yeah, yeah, I will. Okay.
Thank you.
-What?
-I need to talk to you.
I'm eating. Can't you see I'm eating?
Hang on.
-Okay, I'll wait for you inside.
-Okay.
Here. So what's up?
Could you take that, please?
Yeah. Bob Chandler has been trying
to reach his mother all morning.
She's not answering.
-And?
-Well, he's getting back this afternoon.
Jolene stopped by and knocked on the door.
No answer.
-So, he's hoping that you'll pass by...
-Good morning.
...make sure that Delia's okay.
And why can't you do it?
Because my shift ended while
you were eating your breakfast.
All right.
Let me take care of that for you.
Thanks. Yeah, just top it up?
The cell phone.
No, it's fine.
It's been sitting in that box
for three months.
It's comfortable there.
-Get some sleep.
-Will you stop by Ernie's on the way?
There was a call about
some sort of fracas over there.
-A "fracas"?
-That's what I said, "fracas."
"Fracas." I think it's...
-Try Delia again.
-Okay.
Delia, it's Hazel.
I'm letting myself in.
Delia?
Yeah, I'm at Delia's.
Get over here as fast as you can,
and call Spere. Yeah.
You got here fast.
This is wild.
Yeah.
You knew her?
Yeah. All my life.
She went to my mom's church.
I've never seen anything like this.
What can you tell?
Well, it looks like a knife
to the neck.
Yeah.
But I'll have to bring her to the city
and get a full report from the coroner.
-It could take a couple of weeks.
-I can't wait two weeks.
Do me a favour,
take her to the church first.
I'll meet you there
and you can see what you figure out
and then take her to Mayfair Grace
for the autopsy.
I can't do that. Protocol.
I know what the protocols are.
I guess so. Sure. She's your friend.
Thanks. I appreciate it.
Tommy, if you're gonna puke,
don't do it here.
-No, I'm okay.
-You sure?
Maybe I better go outside
and wait for Bob to get here.
-Yeah, I think that's a good idea.
-Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay. You okay?
Yeah.
What about cars?
Were there any cars around
that you didn't recognise?
Yeah, there were cars.
I mean, that you didn't know,
that you hadn't seen before?
Yesterday, parked over there,
there was one.
A dark one.
-Black?
-Like, dark grey.
Grey. Okay.
And did you see the driver?
No.
How about the make?
Maybe Ronny will remember.
He knows cars.
If Ronny does figure out anything,
would you have him call me?
Yeah.
She's getting big.
Oh, God.
I'll get this.
I'll take him in the back.
Thanks.
I've been trying for months
to get her into hospice care.
I knew this day was coming
and I just never figured
it was going to be like this.
So, did she have any family heirlooms
or expensive jewellery
or anything in the house?
-You think someone was trying to rob her?
-I don't know.
Was she expecting anyone,
I mean, besides you?
No.
Can I see her?
Not yet. Let's...
In a bit.
So, as you can see,
this cut is surgical.
Through the windpipe and oesophagus
on the first cut.
And the second deepens all the way
down to the spinal cord.
Was he trying to get a trophy?
Well, another cut and it was his.
So, I'd say no.
What happened to the finger?
He broke it before she died.
You can see the swelling.
That's definitely before.
So she did fight back.
It would be the only sign.
Didn't see anything else.
Her face looked like
she was screaming when she died.
That's a horror movie myth,
faces frozen in terror.
Mostly the dead look drunk.
This was clearly manipulated.
You have to wait until rigor mortis
sets in, about three hours.
And then, you have to hold
the mouth and tongue in that position
until the muscle sets.
For how long?
I'd say another hour.
He was standing over her
with his fingers in her mouth.
When I was a taxidermist I actually
tried it on this tabby cat, and I...
We're not equipped for this,
and you are in no shape
to be chasing anyone.
That leaves me. This is something
I can't handle on my own.
What, are you complaining about this
before we even give it a try?
We need to get Mason to
assign a homicide detective.
We are detectives. This is our town.
We can do this.
Don't let your personal shit
cloud your judgement.
-What are you talking about?
-Your words. Your words.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
I don't understand. All I have to say is
I'm gonna do this with or without you.
So if I have to, I'll do it alone.
Fuck you, Hazel.
Thanks. I knew you'd get onboard.
What?
I don't think you get this good
on the first try.
Over here.
Move back. Give her some space.
I heard about Delia.
That was fast. Who told you?
Trudy Davis.
Everybody's over at the church.
Why aren't you there?
'Cause I wanted to be here
when you got home.
Well, I'm home, so you can go.
You know,
it would mean a lot to everybody if...
Please, do not start with
your Sundays of sunshine shit.
You can knock it all you want,
but when you were in the hospital,
they were there for you.
I didn't ask them to be there for me.
It was my back, and they made it
into some kind of community tragedy.
It wasn't just your back.
You were about to have a baby.
Well, that was a long time ago.
And I can count on one hand the number
of times you've talked about it.
All right, look,
I will go to the funeral. Okay?
What do you want to eat?
Nothing. I'm going out.
-With who?
-With Andy.
Will his wife be there?
I hope so.
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
I was starving. I went ahead.
-I got you a drink.
-Thanks.
What's going on? You okay?
It's this back.
I gotta have an operation for the,
you know, disc thing.
Again? What about the shots?
They're not working.
One doctor says it's autoimmune.
The other one says
it was the original operation.
I don't know.
-When do they want you to have it?
-Six months ago.
Hazel.
I mean,
your stubbornness is gonna kill you.
There's worse ways to go.
Listen, there's a great rehabilitation
facility. It's in North Bay.
Are you crazy?
I'm not leaving my house.
Your mom can't carry you.
I'd like to see her try.
Maybe I can help some. I could come
over maybe once or twice a day.
What would your wife say?
My wife?
My wife would say that you're having
surgery to get me under your roof again.
She's a riot.
Here you go, Hazel.
You two seem to be in sync.
You jealous?
You gotta go.
No, I should go.
I should go, Hazel.
I'll get you next time.
Wait. I mean, while I have you here,
I just thought maybe
you could help me with this.
This asshole cop got me
on the way back from hockey.
Sure.
Okay, thanks.
Okay.
We don't open for a couple of minutes,
but come on in.
It's cold.
Have a seat wherever you like.
Coffee's brewing.
Some hot water, if you have.
That one of those green teas?
It's damiana, natural tonic.
Get a lot of truckers this time of the morning,
but you don't look like a trucker.
I'm not.
Well, cook should be here any minute
if you want to see a menu.
Just berries, if you have.
Yeah.
Sorry, it comes with melon.
Are you a doctor?
I specialise
in methods that
conventional medicine ignores.
What kind of methods?
Many diseases can manifest
through our environment.
What we eat, how we live,
and just as we may create our illness,
our bodies can be healed.
And that works on...
On sick people?
If they are pure of heart
and mind, yes.
My daughter Rose is...
She's sick.
They call them seizures,
but it's like she falls over dead.
They think it's a brain tumour.
How old is she?
She's 12.
"And straightway,
the damsel arose and walked,
"for she was of the age of 12.
"And they were overcome with wonder."
Mark 5:42.
Excuse me.
Pretty good month.
What are they talking about in there?
Something about an Oldsmobile.
-I'm just gonna leave those there.
-Yeah, okay.
So are you liking it here so far?
Yeah, it's great.
You know, if you need any help finding
an apartment, I know lots of places.
I'm good. Thank you.
Okay.
-Stop flirting and get him in here.
-She...
So I found three late '80s Olds
in the system.
One's on cinder blocks,
the other two are accounted for.
So that means that the one Jolene saw...
-Didn't come from here.
-Right.
-This is Ben Wingate.
-Good morning.
Good morning, Mr Wingate.
And where did they find you?
Toronto. 52 Division.
You transferred from Toronto to here?
Yes, ma'am.
Whose wife did you screw?
-It was my choice.
-Why?
I thought it was nice.
-It's not nice.
-No, it's not nice at all.
But it is interesting, isn't it,
that he shows up
when we have our first murder
in four years?
Is that that?
No, I didn't set that ring.
And how do you answer it?
Just press the button. That... Yeah.
Stop. Shut up. How do you do that?
The bottom one.
Shit, I broke it.
Give me that.
I will fix this.
Dismissed.
My mother lived her whole life
in this town.
She was one of the original members
of Civitan Zone 5.
Every year, and I can remember,
she would put on her best dress,
go out
and sell Claxton cakes at Christmas.
She once told me that
if I speak at her funeral,
to make sure everyone here remember her
how she was before the sick.
The Delia Chandler who had great gams
and could kick over her head.
And who loved her family
and her community.
Oh, God, here she comes.
-Andrew.
-Hey.
-Glynnis.
-Hey, Hazel.
I know you call him Andy.
I'm just trying to be respectful.
Well, I call him Andrew. You can
call him whatever the hell you want.
But if you want to be respectful,
stop parking your car outside our house.
-Excuse me, but some people have jobs.
-Ray, could you...
My job happens to be
to take care of this community.
-What is your job? Because... At the bar?
-You and Andrew happen to...
Why don't you go down the way?
Why don't you go there for a while?
I feel bad for Andy. I really,
I want him to be happy, I just...
-Hey, we got a dead body out in Chamberlain.
-What does he see in her anyway?
I mean, really. What did you say?
Dead body out in Chamberlain.
Potential homicide.
That's not us.
Well, Mason wants us to
go out there, so it is now.
He called you and not me?
-Body in there?
-Yeah.
Victim's name?
Michael Ullman.
The horse trainer found him
this morning.
She had the week off.
Okay. I'd like to talk to her.
I don't know where she is.
I told her that she could leave, I...
All right, relax.
Do you know where she lives?
Do you have her phone number?
Okay, I'd like you to call her,
ask her if she's seen
an old make Oldsmobile,
grey, maybe between '85, '89.
You can do that now.
-Yeah.
-Good.
Go.
What is it?
No stomach.
What do you mean there's no stomach?
It's been removed.
Hazel?
What is it?
I think I found his stomach.
Two murders in three days,
couple of 100 klicks apart.
Something's in the air. Full moon?
You think he's smart enough
to know our jurisdiction lines?
-You think this is connected to Delia?
-Well, it's...
A gruesome crime scene.
No forced entry.
I don't think so.
I mean, the victims couldn't be
more different.
An old lady in town.
Rich guy on a farm.
What's the connection?
His face looked pretty weird,
didn't it?
It could have been manipulated
but it wasn't so obvious.
Would it show up in the autopsy?
Not if he was wearing gloves.
Thank you.
You guys?
All right.
Don't put your drink
on my photo album.
You're gonna get a mark on it.
I haven't looked at these
in a long time.
Look at those false eyelashes.
Remember those?
Yeah, they were ridiculous.
Remember at your wedding
when you started laughing
and you laughed so hard you cried
and your eyelashes
slid down your cheek?
I'm not the one that
started the laughing, you did.
No, I didn't. No. I was laughing
because you were laughing.
Once you started I had to join in.
You have such an infectious laugh.
You have a terrible memory.
I don't have a terrible memory.
That's exactly what happened.
I miss that laugh.
Okay. Well, enjoy your corpses.
Thank you. I was just calling to see
if there'd been any recent murders
in your jurisdiction.
Sure, I can hold.
Who is that?
Hamilton Police Department.
They're not sure they've had
any murders?
Yeah, I'm still here.
Got your requisition
for more manpower.
Didn't I send somebody to you?
Yes, but we still only have
two detectives, me and Ray.
Well, that should be enough
to solve one murder.
Two.
-We think this is the work of a...
-Oh, good God.
No, please.
Serial killer.
Serial killer?
Do you know what we call
two murders here?
The morning shift.
You should do stand-up.
Wait a second.
This is your way of convincing me
to give you the permanent
Commanding Officer job,
with a suicide attempt on your record.
You lost your chance when they had to pump
painkillers out of your belly in the ER.
I'm telling you about two murders.
Do you think I give a shit what my title is?
You would have been forced into retirement
without me, so watch your mouth.
All right.
Hazel, you want my attention,
you got it. What do you have?
Look.
You see how her mouth was manipulated?
We think his was, too.
And there was no forced entry
in either case,
and Ullman's body was just a few miles
over the jurisdictional line.
And?
Well, so he's spreading his targets
far enough apart
and he's changing the profile of the victims
so that we don't connect them.
Serial killers leave calling cards.
They want the world to know
what they're doing.
I'm telling you,
I know that this is the same guy.
You know nothing.
You are guessing and you want me to
give you manpower to follow a hunch.
All I need is one detective
with profiling experience.
You know, if I knew that sending you to
Chamberlain was going to trigger this,
I would have sent somebody
who was better equipped.
But, as I said,
I don't have anybody else.
No. No specific age or gender.
No, it could look like anything.
Yeah. Yeah, the mouth.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
No, it could look like a suicide.
Could you send that over to me?
Is she upstairs?
She's sleeping.
I just...
I don't think now is a good time.
I'm sorry.
I understand.
Wait.
Can you open your mouth for me?
Stick out your tongue.
What happens just before
you fall down?
-It smells funny.
-Like what?
Scrambled eggs.
Do you like scrambled eggs?
Not any more.
I don't like scrambled eggs either.
What is it?
This is mistletoe.
It's like Christmas.
This is my favourite part.
There.
I'm not drinking that.
Do you like honey?
Yeah.
Could you bring us some honey?
I'm going to die, aren't I?
Well, we're all going to die.
That's how God intended it.
But how we live and how we die,
that can be meaningful.
Do you want to get better?
I forgot to tell you.
These cups are magic.
If you sing to them,
they'll make the tea taste better.
Your turn.
Keep singing.
I looked into that stuff
you asked about.
She had an email account.
Traded gardening tips
with a cousin in Calgary,
and she visited
a soap opera chat room.
She kept busy.
That she did.
The only thing she bought was
a gold cross necklace on overstock.com.
I don't remember her wearing necklaces.
It's my wife's birthday next week.
It's gonna be weird
getting something from her now.
She never said it out loud, but
she'd been suffering for a long time.
I could see she was ready to go.
It was in her eyes.
Maybe he did her a favour.
Doesn't make it right.
I know.
But it helps me sleep.
Wingate.
You're gonna want to see this.
Okay.
Maybe I should walk you through that.
-No, that's fine. Good night. Thank you.
-Okay, are you sure?
Do you like curry?
Yeah.
I love curry.
Well, Hazel, let the kid in.
I finally got all these files
I've been chasing down
and I think we're missing something
with the faces.
This is Gary Dewer, found by his son,
hanging from a chandelier.
Plastic bag over his head. Look at...
The tongue is pressed down
towards the teeth.
Four days later, Adrian Grunwald,
mouth found open.
And then we have Morton Halfe.
Look at this. His mouth
is almost identical to Dewer's.
-Like Ullman's.
-Yeah.
What's the connective...
You know, what are we missing?
All the mouths are clearly manipulated.
Is it like a code or something?
How's the curry?
It's great.
Thank you. It's delicious.
Glad to see
someone's eating my cooking.
So, why did you transfer
from Toronto to here, really?
I mean, don't give me the bullshit
about a small town life.
My partner died last year.
On duty?
He wasn't a cop.
The guys on the force
didn't take that news so well.
Well, how do you like it here so far?
Excuse me, I ask a lot of questions.
-It's an occupational hazard.
-No, that's okay.
-Are you a reporter?
-No.
Judge. Retired.
Well, then, Your Honour,
I like it.
I mean, it's slower.
But, I think that's good, you know.
It gives you kind of more time
to think.
Exactly.
You been calling your mother?
All right, stop it.
What? Kids should talk
to their mothers.
And some mothers talk too much.
-Meaning me?
-Yes.
-Okay.
-You're my mother. You're talking too much.
-I'm hardly talking at all.
-Okay.
-You're grilling him.
-I'm not!
I'll clear. I'll clear.
Next.
Looks like he's singing.
Next. What about this one?
The mouth's pressed together.
What if...
Seriously,
what if he's saying something?
-He's not saying something, he's dead.
-No.
-Well, is he saying anything?
-It's like a... Look, it's like a...
Buh, like a buh.
No, it's mmm...
Mmm, mmm. Muh.
-Well, go to the next one.
-The upper lip is bent. It's "buh."
-That's it, go on.
-But you bend your upper lip with a "muh."
Now do it again.
Say a sentence that has a "muh" sound
and a "buh" sound.
You're going to see the difference.
Your mother got hit by a bus.
Okay, yeah.
Do you see... "Your mother..."
"Muh" and "buh,"
they're two entirely...
Okay, try it again.
Okay, that's a mouth
that's wide open, right?
Go back.
If you look at it,
the lips are curled in. "Mmm."
You're right
if you're talking about Portuguese.
I don't speak Portuguese.
Or maybe it's not what
they're saying as individuals.
Maybe they're syllables
and whoever manipulated their mouths
is saying something with them all...
Will you be quiet!
Well, some of them don't look like
they're saying anything together.
Maybe it's in the wrong order, then.
Well,
it's the order that we found them.
Well, maybe it's a different order.
Maybe it's the order in
which they were killed.
How about if we try it
going from west to east?
So, that would be Dewer,
Grunwald, Fortnum. Try that.
Okay.
Faster.
The vowels?
Think about how many vowels.
Vowels make you open
your entire mouth.
I mean, think about it.
Something buh or muh,
it's slow but it's something like a...
Jesus.
Lie-bee-la.
Lie-bee-la. Lie-bee-la?
No, no, no, it's Lie-bee-ra.
It's an "R". Look at...
Look at his mouth.
That's an "L." Now can you flip
to Ruby Marshall, please?
Yeah. See how the tongue is
kind of on the side of the mouth?
That's an R. It's "ra."
As in, "You're wrong."
Lie-bee-ra-ri-e.
It's Professor Plume in the lie-bee-ra-ri-e
with the candlestick.
I'm done.
Hey, guys. What if it isn't English?
What do you mean, like French?
They were all Catholic.
It's Latin.
I guarantee you, this is Latin.
Latin? Who speaks Latin?
People in Latin America.
Oh, God. It...
Listen, it sounds like Latin.
-It's not that.
-Lie-bee-ra.
I guarantee you that's Latin.
Well, I know the words,
but I don't actually speak the language.
Now, Father Price at Saint Xavier,
he was a linguistics professor.
He could help.
When you get to be my age,
it's a comfort to have those reminders
of some accomplishments.
-Sit, sit down, please.
-Thank you, Father.
They're your students?
No.
We used to take in orphans
and find them homes.
But you don't any more.
No.
But you didn't come here
to talk about that.
No.
Could you help me and tell me
what that means?
Libera.
It's the imperative of the Latin verb
that is at the root of liberty.
Liberate.
Well, let me see.
With the E following,
eos. Libera eos.
Deliver them.
So does that phrase mean
anything special to you?
Libera nos domine.
Now, that's quite a common phrase.
Free us, Lord.
Libera.
Re-eos. Liberare eos. Liberare eos.
And what does that mean?
Set them free.
So, they're similar.
Similar, yes, but not at all the same.
Do you...
Do you know anything about
the history of the written Bible?
Well, I always thought
it was kind of like
a 2,000-year-old game
of broken telephone.
Let me explain.
The Bible, as we know it,
was composed around 400 Anno Domini.
It contained an oral component,
because elements of that Bible were
prohibited from being written down.
Forbidden songs. Blessings conferred
upon the closest of Christ's disciples.
These were meant to be communicated
only between high priests,
because once the blessing was offered,
the listener became the keeper of it.
And the speaker,
on certain occasions,
offered himself up as a sacrifice.
For what?
Liberare eos.
A sacrifice to set them free.
So you do know what it means.
I have...
Here.
When the women went to complete
the burial rites at Christ's tomb,
they found it empty.
Their service was rewarded by
the Holy Ghost with that prayer.
A consecration against death.
So immortality?
No, not quite.
Liberare eos
is a prayer of resurrection.
Okay.
Back then, people had deeper faith.
Blind faith.
Profound faith.
Well, how exactly does it work?
I promise I won't tell anybody.
It required 12 willing souls
to sacrifice themselves
to bring back the one.
Now, the operative word is "willing."
Once the final life was given,
the prayer was spoken aloud
and witnessed.
And then those 12 disciples
who sacrificed themselves
were granted eternal salvation.
And the chosen one was reborn.
I mean, you know,
this is early Christian mysticism.
This pre-dates even the Vatican.
And do you really believe this stuff?
I did, yes, once.
But times are different now.
Unwavering belief in the church
is difficult to sustain.
Perhaps, I mean, I think,
quite possibly,
with good reason.
I find it fascinating
that someone like you
would be interested
in unearthing this prayer
that has been for 1,500 years,
by and large, lost.
I think somebody may have found it.
If you can sleep on the floor,
why can't I sleep in my chair?
'Cause I'm special.
-Let's go up.
-You certainly are.
Hey, do you remember that gold cross
that Delia Chandler bought online?
-Yeah.
-They never got it.
Nothing showed up at Delia's either.
-So?
-Overstock.com shipped it to a PO box
in Port Hardy, BC,
addressed to Jane Buck.
-BC?
-I called Delia's son.
He's never heard of her.
The post office wouldn't give out
any information over the phone.
So I looked up Jane Buck
in the local white pages and guess what?
What?
There's a phone number and home address
10 miles from that PO box.
Go for it.
-Hello?
-Hello.
Is this Jane Buck?
Who is this?
This is Officer Ben Wingate,
from the Fort Dundas Police Department.
You wouldn't happen to know anyone
by the name of Delia Chandler, would you?
This isn't a good time.
Okay. When would be a good time?
Could be a lead.
Come on, you gotta let me go.
I would love to let you go, but
I don't have the money to fly you there.
My mom gives me AIR MILES every year
for Christmas. I've never used them.
I found our Olds.
This is where he got the ticket.
Okay. Well, let's start
knocking on some doors.
So you just let him in?
I spoke with him for
quite a while at the diner.
My daughter was very sick
and I believed that he could help her.
I was desperate.
Nothing else was working.
What did he look like?
Tall, thin.
He had a big bag.
Dark coat. Sandy blonde hair.
Beard.
I remember he had kind eyes.
I don't know if that helps.
Okay, so you let him in
and then what happened?
He gave her some tea.
He came out,
he said she was sleeping.
So I looked in on her.
She looked peaceful, so I let her rest.
Then she woke up screaming,
vomiting, burning up.
I took her to the hospital.
They told us it was a 50-50 chance
she'd make it through the night.
Two days later the vomiting stopped
and the MRI was clear.
Yeah, hon.
I want to show you a drawing.
Okay. Excuse me just for a second.
Killers kill. They don't heal.
You know, Jesus raised
a little girl from the dead.
She was about that age. It was
one of his top 10 miracles, actually.
-You're referencing scriptures now?
-I did my research.
-Okay, so you really believe that this guy...
-I think she believes that this guy...
-Hi.
Simon said you would come.
His name is Simon?
And did Simon say anything else?
He said the police would be
looking for him.
That they would say he did bad things.
But he's not bad.
He taught me a song.
# Simple Simon went to look
# if plums grew on a thistle
# He pricked his fingers very much
# which made poor Simon whistle
Great. Thanks.
...today with a high of plus four.
There is a snowfall warning, though.
Expect up to 10 centimetres
of snow overnight.
For the coast of Haida Gwaii,
rain, a high of plus eight,
inland rain as well as
a high of plus seven degrees.
Hazel, sorry.
These came for you from the coroner.
-Great. Thanks.
-Do you need anything?
-No.
-Coffee or ibuprofen, I...
-No, I'm fine, thanks.
-Okay.
-Do you want me to do anything for you?
-No.
-Okay, well, let me know.
-Okay.
-Awesome. Okay.
-You are relentlessly cheerful.
-Well, I try.
Yeah.
Where are we going?
Warren, hi. It's Hazel.
Yeah, quick question.
Ruby Marshall,
was she sick when she died?
Yeah, I know her head was
in the freezer. I'm asking...
Sarco...
And is that terminal?
Okay, thanks, yep.
That really helps me.
Okay. Bye.
Hey! This is private property.
You don't leave, I'm gonna call the...
Jane Buck?
Let me see that.
Just want to ask you
a couple of questions.
I just bring in the mail.
For who?
You can't arrest me.
I haven't done anything.
I'm not gonna arrest you.
Just tell me what's in the camper.
Gifts.
Who from?
The disciples.
What?
You can't go in there.
-Then let me...
-You don't have a warrant.
-You cannot go in there.
-Please. Miss, step aside.
You don't know what you've done.
You don't know what you've done!
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
Okay.
No, I didn't touch anything.
I took some pictures
with my cell phone.
I just got the hell outta there.
Did you call the BC police?
No. I figured it would be better
to keep a low profile.
What about the body?
He's been soaking in
formaldehyde for months.
I don't think he's going anywhere.
So do you think that your mom
has enough points to get you to Montreal?
What are you doing?
You think that's where he's headed?
Well, he started in BC,
he's been going east ever since.
I think it's a good bet.
You could go there, get a car
and check out the Eastern Townships.
I'm on it.
Hazel, we can't let this green kid
go out on some wild goose chase
on his own dime.
What other choice do we have?
I'll call Mason.
Give me two days,
then you can call Mason.
If Wingate makes any kind of mistake,
this guy walks on a technicality.
He's not gonna make a mistake.
-I'm telling you she was expecting him.
-What do you mean?
Well, the dress she was wearing,
that was delivered from the cleaners
the day before.
And she vacuumed the carpet.
You're over-thinking this.
No. She was wearing pantyhose.
Delia only wore pantyhose
when she went to church.
Well, maybe she was going out
for lunch.
No, she was trying to impress him.
Now we're getting off track.
It's simpler than that, Hazel.
He was preying on the weak.
He was preying on the faithful.
When was the last time you went
to church?
-My cousin's wedding.
-To pray?
The only god I ever prayed
to was Guy Lafleur.
Exactly.
Now he was promising them salvation.
In exchange for what?
In exchange for their deaths.
So why butcher them?
It's for show, just to confuse us.
Then how did he find her?
There is nothing weird in here.
Are you sure
you know what you're doing?
Maybe I should call Melanie.
There's nothing.
Well, maybe somebody erased it.
Wait.
Wait, wait.
Look at that.
What am I looking at?
Massach, faithforthedying.com.
We have nine victims
who said three-quarters of
the prayer of resurrection.
There were 12 apostles.
So he needs three more victims
to finish the prayer.
Okay, so this email address is actually
linked to a bunch of different websites.
Most of them are chat rooms talking
about cancer, suicide, heart disease.
That's how he's recruiting them.
What's LTP?
Let's talk privately.
Okay, see this T Lawrence?
I need to find out
where that person lives.
Are you ready to begin?
Of course.
If you are going to be a part of this,
I will have to cleanse you
of your transgressions.
Close your eyes.
Yeah, I'm pulling up now.
Okay, what can you see?
Looks clear.
There's no cars in the driveway.
-See if you can get a little peek inside.
-Okay.
There's nobody home.
What do you want me to do?
Well, see if you can peek
in the window, see what's inside.
You're not sending him in there.
This may be our only chance.
-He's a kid, for Christ sake.
-He's a police officer.
You wait for backup, Wingate.
We don't have time to wait.
I'm gonna go around back.
Standard procedure, Wingate.
-No! No! Just back off.
-You call for backup, you wait.
-Come on, he's gotta get in there.
-Call for backup.
The guy's gonna get away.
We're not gonna wait.
-No. No. Back off.
-Wingate, call for backup and wait.
Come on. You go ahead.
Check out the window.
-Wait for backup. You secure the perimeter.
-Go around the back.
He can't wait!
The guy's going to be gone!
There's blood.
There's blood everywhere.
-Stand down, Wingate!
-No! No!
Wait for backup!
Wingate, proceed. Listen to me.
Where are you?
Wingate! Tell me what's going on.
I'm in the backyard.
Don't listen to Hazel!
You are risking his life.
You are throwing away your job and mine.
This is my job!
I'm going in.
Wingate?
Wingate!
Ben?
Ben? Ben?
Hello, Hazel.
Who is this?
Well, you know who it is. Otherwise,
you wouldn't send poor Ben out to
look for Dr Lawrence, would you?
I swear to God, if you touch...
Hazel, relax.
He looked so tired.
You've been working him so hard
I gave him something to sleep.
Did you get my package?
I have to go now, Hazel.
But I have faith...
Our paths will cross again.
Yeah. This is Detective Ray Greene
from Fort Dundas PD.
I need a full response unit
to 76 Dollard Street.
There's an officer down.
Mason offered me the CO job
six months ago. I turned it down.
Maybe you should have taken it.
Is it on?
Today I'm leaving this body
that has tortured me for years.
But it has given me
the moments I treasure.
Running, as a child,
dancing with my husband.
Bringing my son into this world.
I want to live,
but not like this.
I love you and I want you to know
that I'm trusting my body
to someone worthy,
who will cleanse my spirit
and bring me home.
Remember me as I was.
Thank Dr Reiner for his kindness.
Give Jenny a big kiss from grandma.
I had the photos blown up
that I took in the trailer.
It's Delia's necklace and all the other
gifts the victims sent to Simon.
No. Come back here.
Really, how are you doing?
Actually, he had that syringe
to my neck
before I even saw his face.
Yeah.
-What?
-My God, I'd swear...
This is Father Price in this picture,
like 30 years ago.
What is a picture of Father Price
doing in a trailer
halfway across the country?
What I'm about to undergo
is a sin in His eyes.
Are you afraid, Father?
Today is my day ofjudgement,
of reckoning.
Of course I am.
Of what?
You know, Peter.
Of being told that my mistake,
my mistake alone
is what led us here to this sin.
Gabriel's sufferings led me to
the prayer. And the prayer is pure.
It was never meant to be used
this way!
Only Christ can raise the dead.
Christ is in us all.
You taught me that.
I am allowing you
to trespass on my soul.
It's a sin, Peter. It's a sin.
I'm the one committing
the sin, Father, not you.
When all the sacrifices are complete,
God will forgive the trespasses.
May God forgive us both.
I would like to pray.
Of course, Father.
Our Father,
which art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass
against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom,
the power and the glory,
forever and ever.
Amen.
Where's your pain today, Father?
Everywhere.
I love you, Father.
Father Price.
Father Price?
He's not here.
Sister, excuse me.
I'm sorry to have to do this now,
but could you tell me if you know
what happened to any of the boys
in this picture?
These two boys,
Peter and Gabriel Mallick.
We could only find a home
for one of them.
Father Price chose
to send the younger boy,
Gabriel.
We didn't ask a lot of questions
in those days.
Broke his heart when he learned
how he had suffered.
Peter found him, took him in.
They moved out West.
Away.
But it was too late.
He was never the same.
Gabriel took his own life last year.
A few weeks later,
Father Price grew ill.
Cancer.
He felt it was God's way
of punishing him.
When was the last time
that you saw Peter?
Three months ago,
after his brother's passing,
he came to Sunday service.
Said he was going on a long trip.
And a few weeks ago
he called Father Price.
-Really?
-Yes.
I figured out who he is.
His name is Peter Mallick
and he changed his...
We know.
-What do you mean, you know?
-We got into his email account.
We know who he is.
We know where he's going.
Carl Smotes.
We're coordinating with the RCMP
to put him into protective custody.
When?
It's not your concern any more, Hazel.
-What? What are you talking about?
-We can handle this.
No! I wanna be there.
What do you mean, you can handle it?
I'm the one that figured it out.
I'm the one that told you about it
-in the first place.
-You're done!
-And you wouldn't even listen to...
I'm not done! I wanna be there.
What do you want from me,
an apology?
I am sorry. You were right.
There's a serial killer.
Does that make you feel better?
Fuck you.
-Hello?
-Hey, it's me.
Did they get him?
No. It's gonna be a long night.
They brought in the cavalry.
You should be here.
The guys are all really impressed
with what you did.
You saved a man's life.
Well, if he was talking to Simon
then that meant he wanted to die.
So I don't think he's gonna be
too happy.
Well, when he shows up,
we're gonna get him.
What if he doesn't show up?
I don't know.
I mean, he's come this far.
I don't think he's gonna stop now.
One away from getting
his 12 disciples?
He's coming.
Are you still there?
Yeah, I'm here.
I have my day off tomorrow.
Why don't I come by?
I'll cook you dinner.
Goodnight, Wingate.
I'll get you something for that.
Why did you bring me here?
You brought us together.
You heard the calling when
everyone around you could not.
And you chose to become a part of it.
This is where
we're supposed to be, together,
under the eyes of God.
And this is where it will end.
No.
-For your pain.
-No.
All the disciples
gave themselves willingly.
Murdering you would not honour
the prayer.
Do you want your pain
to end or do you not?
It is your choice.
It's remarkable, isn't it?
What is it?
A hybrid of many plants.
Grown here.
You could be helping people
instead of
doing this.
I am
helping people.
I know you lost your brother and
you'll do anything to bring him back.
But what is the point?
I mean, he killed himself.
He doesn't want to be alive.
He wanted to die.
Everyone deserves a second chance.
Hazel, I lost my brother
but I never lost my faith in God.
When he returns,
he will be cleansed,
as will you.
Can you imagine a day
when you're not clouded
by all that alcohol?
No.
Tell me something beautiful,
something good that
you've brought to this world.
Nothing.
Have you ever loved? Really loved
someone?
Someone other than yourself?
What have you lost, truly lost,
that had some meaning for you?
My baby.
This is your chance.
Drink this and all your suffering
will be gone.
Drink this
and bring meaning to your life.
and offer the disciples unto God.
Drink this
and bring life back to this world.
Let go.
I can't.
I want another chance, please.
It's okay.
It will all be over soon.
Andrew, nice to meet you. Gladys.
-No, it's Glynnis.
-Okay.
Ben?
Hey, man. Come on in.
Yeah.
I'm gonna come back again
another time.
You sure?
Yeah.
Give this to her for me?
Yeah, okay.
Thanks.
Sorry. Should I...
-Should I...
-Come on in.
How is she doing?
-Drugs finally knocked her out.
-Right.
She's probably got quite a tolerance.
Yeah.
-Andrew and his wife are in the hall.
-Oh, dear.
-I'll go head 'em off.
-Okay. Do I... Right.
-Hey.
It's from Ray.
The flowers are from me.
I'm allergic.
Why am I not surprised?
This is also from me and Ray.
-You did it.
-We did it.
What about his brother?
Vancouver PD sent some guys
to recover the body.
I just haven't heard anything yet.
Let me know.
I'll be out in that hall
until I know, okay?
Okay.
I want my mom.
These drugs must be working.
You're awake.
What's this?
Ray. He didn't bring glasses
or ice or anything.
Forget about it.
You look terrible.
Yeah. It's better than dead.
Much better.
Police!