(CAMERA CLICKING)
I missed you.
Let's get
the door shut.
(GIGGLING)
(MOANING)
(CLICKING)
(FEMALE DISPATCHER CHATTERING
OVER RADIO)
(OFFICER CHATTERING)
POLICEMAN:
Stay behind the line, please.
Fix your collar.
What do we got here?
Looks like a shooting.
Inside?
Yeah.
This is clear
all up through here?
Yeah, it's clean.
Who's the first officer?
Pinola, sir. He's inside.
Central took a call
from one of the neighbors,
wouldn't give
a name.
Uh-huh.
At 8:23,
that there was
a rape and a robbery
going on here.
What time is it, Dickey?
9:01.
Get this gentleman's name,
would you?
How you doing?
Pinola, how you doing?
PINOLA: Not too bad.
Who's smokin' in here?
Come on.
Tom, you done
with the photos?
Yes, sir.
You get something close
on this blood trail here
and the butts
in the ashtray?
Yes, sir.
Great. Thanks.
Give me
some gloves, please.
POLICEMAN:
Here you go, sir.
(SIREN WAILING)
KYLE: No lividity.
She hasn't been gone long.
Go on, Dickey.
Take a look at her.
You may not remember
the woman you were with
last night,
but you won't forget her.
Pinola, she was dead
when you came in?
PINOLA:
Yes, sir. Uh, I couldn't
find a pulse in her, sir.
What time was that?
About, uh, 8:40.
Uh, 8:42 exactly.
We got any witnesses?
PINOLA: Nobody.
No defense cuts.
Fingernails are clean.
Why don't you check
the windows and the doors?
Boy, whoever did this
fucked up all over
the place, didn't he?
The Gong Show
of murder.
What's her name?
Felicity Turner.
KYLE: Married?
Yeah. Has a daughter, too.
She doesn't know it yet.
She's out with some friends.
Lamar says maybe, uh,
rape and robbery.
Is that what you say,
Dickey-boy?
That's right.
She's wearin'
a gold watch, Lamar.
Robbers don't leave
gold watches behind,
do they?
See that hole
in her head?
You know what that is?
Hard contact wound
is what that is.
You gotta be angry enough
to press the gun
smack against the head
to do that.
His unhappiness shot her
in the bathroom.
First in the head,
then in the chest.
He left her lyin' in there.
He left the bullet
in the bathroom wall.
Then he sat around a bit,
thinkin' about
what he had done,
sweatin' up his socks.
Maybe he had
a cigarette or two.
Started gettin' the idea
his life was over.
So he drags her
out of the bathroom
into the kitchen,
tryin' to make it
look like a rape.
Then he calls the police.
He hadn't fucked up enough,
so he goes back
into the bathroom,
and begins to clean the blood
off the bathroom wall.
Never heard of
a rapist or robber
who does your apartment
afterwards.
I don't think you're gonna
find any signs of forced entry
because it wasn't
a rape or robbery.
It was her old man.
You find him,
you find the gun
that put the bullet
in the bathroom wall.
There's no reason
he would have thrown it away.
Done everything else wrong.
Are you ready
for me to take her?
She's all yours.
Deceased is
black female,
approximately
35 years of age.
You don't much
like it here,
do you, Lamar?
I'm fine.
(PAGER BEEPING)
He likes it.
He just doesn't know why.
ASST. MEDICAL EXAMINER:
What do you mean?
Makes him feel alive
to see someone dead.
LAMAR: Lamar here.
What's up?
Well, her husband
was just picked up
at the bus station
with a .32 caliber
in his B.V.D's.
And they're taking him
to the office.
Looks like
a .32 to me.
Yep.
Kill someone in Brayton,
Kyle Bodine's gonna get you.
Don't think
it takes any brains.
Murder is a dumb shits.
You always screw it up
sooner or later.
Lamar, you shouldn't
be doin' this.
This is nothin'
that a man like you
should be
spendin' his life at.
(TELL ME WHAT I WANT
TO HEAR PLAYING)
* Talk to me, baby
* Tell me what I wanna hear
* Say that you love me
* And you wish
that I was there
* I miss your sweet kissing
* Your love and affection
I don't see her.
Who?
My dancing lady.
Maybe she's here,
maybe not.
But if I see her tonight,
I'm gonna fall in love.
I can just feel it.
* If only by telephone
KYLE: What'd you forget?
My wallet.
I left it in the car.
I'll be back in a minute.
* But what hurts so bad
* I know you're not alone
* Tell me what I wanna hear
* I wanna hear
a long, long time *
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hello.
Do you mind
some company?
Am I safe
talking to you?
I don't know.
We live
in dangerous times.
And we meet
in dangerous places.
I've had too much to drink
in this one.
I know another one.
No, there's something
about tonight that wants
a place like this.
It's where
you end a holiday.
Oh, you've been
on a holiday?
Sort of.
I don't much like holidays.
Poor baby.
You an orphan?
(LAUGHS)
Yeah. I'm an orphan
of destiny.
I see life and
all its dirty details.
You know how it is.
Sure, I know how it is.
You had a hard day
at the office.
You could say that.
And you'd like to relieve
the stress.
Sounds like
a good idea to me.
Only maybe you're confusing me
with another kind of woman.
No, I'm not.
I'm not confusing anything.
Well, maybe it's just me.
I have to go.
Wait a minute.
I thought we were doin'
pretty good here.
We were.
Now I have to leave.
Don't go, please.
Let me start
all over again.
You started just fine.
In fact, you just about
swept me off my feet.
I did?
I said, "just about."
I really do have to go.
I'm expected.
So why are you here?
Thought I'd meet
somebody interesting.
And I have.
So there's no sweepin' you
off your feet?
No.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure,
but I can't help
admiring real effort.
Here she is.
Thanks a lot.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
RUPERT: Rachel?
(DOOR OPENING)
Rachel, what are you
doin' out here?
Just getting some fresh air.
You're out here drinkin'.
It don't look good,
you being out here drinkin'
so all the damn neighbors
can see.
They're all asleep.
Where were you?
Playing cards. I told you.
I forgot.
You always forget.
I don't want you out here
drinkin' anymore.
(DRILLING)
Rachel?
That's your name,
isn't it?
Rachel Munro.
Do I know you?
We met last night.
Last night?
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I didn't recognize you.
I don't have
my contacts in.
Kyle Bodine.
Rachel.
You already know.
How'd you find me?
It wasn't hard.
I wanted to apologize
if I said anything stupid.
No, you didn't. I...
I just, uh,
I had to leave early.
I had a little too much
to drink, is all.
I don't do that very much.
It was a holiday,
you told me.
Did I?
Yeah.
What else
did I tell you?
Not a lot.
You're lying, aren't you?
I'd like to
see you sometime.
That's not possible.
Anything is possible.
Not that. I'm sorry.
Maybe I'll
call you anyway.
I'll call the police.
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
Call me.
How much is that one?
SALESWOMAN: This one?
(GUN COCKING)
What do you want with
a big 9-millimeter?
How much is it?
Six hundred.
And I'll throw in
a couple clips.
What did you do today?
Put in some new flowers.
The Azaleas are coming in.
I saw them.
They look real nice.
(CAT MEOWS)
You guys hungry?
Sure as hell look hungry.
Here you go.
(EXCLAIMS)
Should we get
to feed you again?
Is something wrong
with you, honey?
What do you mean?
Well, you're acting
like you're keeping
something from me.
Well, how am I acting?
Like I'm having
a wild sexual affair?
Are you?
No!
Why do you say that?
Excuse me.
Sit down, God damn it!
I'm talking to you.
Shit.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Homicide. Dickey.
Mr. Kyle Bodine.
Who should I say is calling?
Hold on.
It's for you.
She's got no name.
Hello.
How you doin'?
Sure. Where?
Okay. What time?
All right.
I'll see you then.
Bye.
You're not married, right?
No.
How come?
I don't know.
You're married
to your work?
(PIANO PLAYING)
You don't look like
a real detective.
You're supposed to
wear white socks,
aren't you?
What color are
your socks?
Blue.
And black.
You're very colorful.
That's what detectives wear.
Do you carry a gun?
Yes, I do.
Where?
Can I see it?
What are you gonna do?
Shoot the chef?
What kind is it?
It's a .38,
2-inch snub-nosed.
Because of the short barrel.
You never shot anyone,
have you?
Not really.
Bet you wouldn't
tell me if you had.
Thank you.
Bye, honey.
Bye.
You take care now.
You, too.
I'll call you.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Watch your dress.
(FROGS CROAKING)
Thanks.
(OWL HOOTING)
You wanna go out?
(WATER TRICKLING)
Look at that moon.
KYLE: My grandmother
used to call that
a China moon.
Like a big
old plate of China.
She said people would
get affected by them.
That they'd do
strange things.
Do you believe that?
I don't know. You gonna
do somethin' strange?
Do feel like it sometimes.
You're so beautiful.
What do you do out here?
Drink beer and
row around the lake.
Just get kind of stupid.
Go skinny-dippin'.
The water's so nice
and warm.
You ought to jump in.
It's okay?
Yeah. Sure. Go ahead.
Oh!
It's wonderful.
Are you coming in?
(WHISPERING)
Put your arms around me.
Kiss me.
Why did you cry?
Rachel?
Tell me.
It's your tenderness.
I haven't had
much of that.
How bad is it?
I don't wanna talk about it,
not when I'm with you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait a minute.
What's goin' on?
Talk to me.
Okay, just talk to me.
I can't.
Okay.
All right, sweetie,
you don't have to.
It's all right. Come on.
(MACHINERY RUMBLING)
Mr. Bodine.
Speak, Dickey-boy.
So what do you do
for boredom?
I never had the problem.
Bullshit. You've got
the most boring life
a man ever lived.
You'll grow into it.
Trust me.
Yeah.
(BOYS CHATTERING)
Get it, man!
LAMAR: 3-pointer!
See that?
Mmm-hmm.
Call the pistons.
Sign the kid
for five million.
It could happen.
Yeah, and I'd still be
pulling down 26.5 a year.
And worth
every goddamn cent.
Right?
Right.
What color was
his t-shirt?
Who?
Kid who made the basket.
White.
How the hell
would I know?
You wouldn't know,
'cause you've got
no eye for detail.
Well, I think I do
when it's important.
It's always important.
Everything you see,
every minute of the day.
But you don't see nothin',
'cause you're bored.
Lamar, the kid wasn't
wearin' a shirt.
You're an okay cop,
but these are keepin' you
from bein' a good cop.
Then why'd you
partner with me?
I mean, you had a choice.
I keep hopin' you might
surprise me someday.
Well, one day, I might.
Don't strain yourself.
I might be
incapable of surprise.
Could be, in this lifetime,
I'm all surprised-out.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(DOG BARKING)
(DOOR OPENING)
Hi.
Oh, Kyle!
I waited for you all day.
Did you miss me?
Yes.
So how is she?
Who?
Your Cinderella.
Come on.
I tell you everything,
and what do you tell me?
Who's dead
and who's done it.
You don't wanna
tell me about her,
do you?
How come?
You think I'm gonna
take her away from you?
(CHUCKLING)
All right, man.
Good shot.
Is she putting out
for you?
I got nothing goin' on.
Fuck you.
What, are you gonna
get upset?
Perhaps.
Please don't, Lamar.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
We have to talk.
Listen, I wanna forget this.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
What do you mean?
Take me for a ride?
In this?
How well can you swim?
How soon they forget?
I will never forget?
You wanna go inside?
I envy you, Kyle.
You're so comfortable
in yourself.
Wish I could be you.
What's wrong?
I'm in a trap.
I can't get out of it.
Divorce him.
I love you.
I know I can't
give you what he can.
That's not it.
Whatever I got,
it's yours.
Whatever you want,
I'll get.
Whatever you need, I'll do.
Kyle, stop. Please.
You gotta decide.
You either
stand up to him
and leave him,
or you stay with him
and you try to work it out.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Rachel, my God.
Hi.
What are you doin' here?
I wanted to surprise you.
(WOMAN CHATTERING OVER PA)
Well...
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Mr. Munro,
you have a call, sir.
Mmm-hmm.
He won't give his name.
Says it's personal.
Rupert Munro.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Who the fuck is this?
What don't make
much sense to me
is why two
smart guys like us
chose this poor-ass
police life.
(LAUGHING)
I had a reason
for doin' it.
(CAN OPENING)
It'll come to me.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Any unit that's 10-8,
can you take an 877?
Domestic in progress.
201 Cypress.
C.I.D. 159. We're close.
We'll respond to 201 Cypress.
C.I.D. 159...
Since when are we doing
domestic violence?
(ENGINE STARTING)
C.I.D. 159.
We're 10-97, code 4.
We'll... We'll handle it.
C.I.D. 159, 10-4.
LAMAR: Police.
Everything's fine.
Sir, do you live here?
Nothing happened, really.
Yes, I do.
What's your name?
My name's Rupert Munro.
I'm with the Munro
American Bank.
Yes, sir,
I know who you are.
Where's your wife, Mr. Munro?
She's inside. She's fine.
This is nothin'.
It's embarrassing
is all it is.
We'd like to speak
with one of you inside
and one of you outside.
What the hell's goin' on?
We're gonna take a look
inside your house.
I told you nothing happened.
This is stupid!
Mr. Munro, why don't
you come over here
and have a seat?
KYLE: Mrs. Munro!
Mrs. Munro?
Rachel?
Oh, baby.
Kyle.
Are you all right?
He got a call.
He knows
I'm seeing someone.
Here.
Are you all right, ma'am?
Do you want us
to arrest your husband?
Lamar, I'll take care of this.
Get back outside with Munro.
Okay.
Do you want us
to take him in?
What good would it do?
He'd be out tomorrow,
wouldn't he?
Probably.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Nice house, Mr. Munro.
How much you pay
for a place like this?
None of your
goddamn business.
Your wife doesn't wanna
have you arrested.
Well, it was just
a little spat.
You don't get arrested
for a little spat.
Don't touch her again.
Who are you talkin' to?
You, fuck!
Got a smart mouth,
little man!
Are you all right?
Yes.
Why didn't you tell me?
(WATER RUNNING)
Rachel,
you don't have
to put up with him.
Divorce this son of a bitch.
Get rid of him.
Yes, you're right.
I wanna get rid of him.
I've dreamed it
100 times.
Every night, all night long.
I bought a gun.
Where is it?
I want it. Where is it?
I could fly to Miami.
What are you talkin' about?
I'd wait a day
and drive back at night
and do it.
What's happening to you?
Come on.
Would you just sit down
with me for a second?
No. I'm okay.
Come on. Just sit down.
All right?
Don't.
What?
Don't!
I just wanna...
Let me go!
Rachel!
Rachel! Come here!
(ENGINE STARTING)
Open the door!
Rachel!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Ra...
Mrs. Munro, you're in 330,
and you have a letter.
Your bags will be right up.
Enjoy your stay.
Thank you.
(RINGING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
LAMAR: Kyle.
Yeah.
Where were you?
What do you mean
where was I?
You were supposed
to be in court this morning.
Nobody can get
a hold over you.
This dipshit lawyer
is screaming for dismissal.
What's going on with you?
(SEAGULLS CAWING)
I'll be right out.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
BUNNY: Hello, Kyle.
Bunny, my man,
how are you?
Not too bad.
How about yourself?
Good to see you.
I need you to make
a call for me.
Sure, man.
Anything you want.
I want you to
call the police.
I thought you was
the police.
Pack of smokes.
FEMALE DISPATCHER ON RADIO:
B.P.D. 197, 877.
Domestic in progress.
201 Cypress.
B.P.D. 184, 10-99.
That's Munro's place,
isn't it?
Yeah.
C.I.D. 159.
We were there before.
201 Cypress.
B.P.D. 197 and 184. 10-22.
C.I.D. 159,
I show you handling.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
What do you want?
One of your neighbors
reported a woman here
callin' out for help.
Not here.
Maybe I could
speak with your wife.
She's in Miami.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Thank you, sir.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Kyle?
Kyle.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I was lookin'
all over for you.
I had to get away.
I was crazed that night.
I just needed some time.
I called you and called you,
but you didn't answer.
I had rented a car so I could
come back tonight.
I don't care
about him anymore.
I have to be
with you, Kyle.
Don't ever leave me
like that again.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Can we go away?
Yeah.
Really?
(CHUCKLING)
You mean it?
Let's go tonight.
I love you.
Do you want me
to come in with you?
No. If he comes home,
you can't be there.
How much time do you need?
15 minutes.
All right. I'll wait
in the street.
Rupert?
(ENGINE STARTING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(KEYS JINGLING)
Rachel,
are you comin' or goin'?
Now, just hold on there
a minute.
I'm leaving.
Now, give me the bag.
We'll talk about this.
No!
Give me the bag!
Don't!
What have you got
in here, huh?
Everything but
the kitchen sink. My God!
I'm calling
the police!
Don't you touch me.
Don't! Don't!
We'll just have a little
roll in the hay...
No! No!
...and talk about it
in the morning.
(SCREAMING)
I just want
my conjugal rights!
Let me go!
And you're not
goin' anywhere!
No!
Where'd you get that?
Get away!
Rachel, give me the gun.
Rachel...
Get away!
(EXCLAIMS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Rachel?
Oh, Jesus.
What happened?
He threw me
against the wall.
He wouldn't let me go.
I thought he was
gonna kill me.
I got to call the police.
It's justifiable homicide.
You can't.
If I don't call the police,
it's murder.
It's an unregistered gun!
I didn't check out
of the hotel.
They'll say
I came back here to kill him.
Did you?
No.
God help me,
Kyle, please.
If you ever loved me,
trust me now.
Put down the phone, please.
I'll go to prison.
Help me.
(DIAL TONE BEEPING)
You said you'd protect me.
Do it now.
Don't call them.
Please.
Put down the phone.
Okay.
A 9-millimeter.
How many times
did you shoot him?
Twice.
Where were you,
and where was he?
I was here.
He was over there.
Give me a change of clothes.
And I need some rope.
Some rope and some sacks.
(RACHEL GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Go back to the car.
Get the sacks and the rope.
Be right back.
If they begin
to suspect us,
they're gonna say
all kinds of things
to try to turn us
against each other.
They'll try to make us
betray each other,
and you can't
believe them.
Just tell me
what to do.
You go straight
to the hotel.
Don't let anybody
see you go in.
Don't call me.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Here you are, ma'am.
Thank you.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello.
RACHEL: Kyle? I...
I know you said
not to call...
Hold on.
Are you all right?
I can't go back there.
KYLE: You have to.
Call his office, wait a day,
then call the police.
Rachel, you can't
call me here again.
You understand?
Okay.
I'll call you when I can.
How come you're so quiet
about this girl?
What do you want to know?
She's got long fingernails?
Not particularly, no.
How come you're all cut up?
(MEOWING)
Hi, June. I'd like to
speak to Rupert, please.
He hasn't come in yet,
Mrs. Munro.
We're trying to
locate him right now.
Well, would you have him
call me when you do?
JUNE: Yes, I will.
Thank you.
Kyle, you remember
the banker Munro?
We were at his house?
Yeah.
His little wife
just reported him
missing in action.
KYLE: When was
the last time you saw
your husband?
The day after you were here.
LAMAR: Thursday last?
Yes. It was the day
I went to Miami.
And, uh,
you came back yesterday?
RACHEL: Mmm-hmm.
Did you call
your husband at any time
when you were in Miami?
No.
Do you know if
he was in any danger,
or if there was anyone
that might wish to harm him?
No.
KYLE: Has he
done this before?
Has he done what?
Traveled unexpectedly.
No.
Do you mind
if we take a look
around the house?
Yeah, go ahead.
LAMAR: Thank you.
Was your husband
here alone
while you were away?
Yes.
Did you notice anything
funny about the house
when you came back?
No.
No open doors or windows?
How long has
that been broke?
A couple of weeks.
They're easy enough
to fix, you know.
How'd it break?
Closing it, I think.
What kind of car was
your husband driving, ma'am?
It was a black Buick.
LAMAR: Do you
want to canvass?
Yeah.
Let's take a look
at the rest
of the house first.
Did you see
how nervous she was?
Was she?
Oh, man,
she was so tight.
You could have bounced
a golf ball off her.
The window was jammed.
It didn't move.
Yeah. So?
She was lying.
You think she was lyin'
about the rest of it?
I don't know.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
(ALL CHATTERING)
KYLE: What's up?
It's his car.
It's clean.
How long's it been here?
We don't know.
Light bulb here is busted.
Someone knew
what they were doin'.
They're gonna
wanna see you again.
RACHEL: Why?
They found his car.
They're gonna
ask you some questions.
I'm scared.
It's gonna be okay.
You just got to
stick with your story.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
She's a cuckoo bird.
She's had psychiatric care
off and on for 4 years.
She tried to
commit suicide 2 years ago
with a mouthful of valiums,
and she's filed
for divorce 2 times.
(SIGHING)
Munro's car
was wiped clean.
No fingerprints.
If this was murder,
someone knew
what they were doin'.
Wasn't no cuckoo bird.
Good work.
KYLE: Will you please
state your name,
and present address?
RACHEL: Mrs. Rachel Munro.
I live at
201 Cypress Avenue.
On the evening
we were called
to your residence,
July 17,
did your husband
strike you?
I guess he did.
Why?
I don't know.
We have arguments sometimes.
What was the argument
on that night?
You don't have
to answer that.
My husband was
accusing me of having
an extramarital affair.
LAMAR: Had you?
Uh, Mr. Dickey,
my client is here
to make a statement
regarding where she was
at the time,
not her sexual druthers.
How many times
did he strike you?
RACHEL: It wasn't
much of anything.
In detective
Bodine's report,
it states "There are clear
signs of physical abuse."
"A slap."
What happened
after detective Dickey and I
left your home that night?
I slept on the side porch,
and in the morning,
I called a taxi.
It took me to the airport,
then I took
a 10:00 flight to Miami.
You were there
Thursday through Sunday,
returning home Monday morning?
Yes.
Did you call your husband
from the hotel?
No.
I wanted to be alone.
LAMAR: Did you
call anyone else?
No.
You returned Monday
the 22nd, right?
RACHEL: Right.
What time did you arrive?
About 11:00.
KYLE: Did you call anyone
when you got home?
Yes.
Who did you call?
The first person?
Yeah.
I phoned my husband's office.
I spoke to his secretary.
Who else did you call?
No one.
Well, I thought,
if your husband
was the first,
there would have
been someone else.
There was no one else.
Saturday night,
before your husband
was first missed,
a neighbor noticed
your house lights were on
until almost 3:00
in the morning.
Could someone
have been there?
I don't know.
Mrs. Munro,
we're gonna wanna take
another look at the house.
They inside?
Yeah.
Maybe they'll find him
under the bed.
(LAUGHING)
Where was she?
She was in Miami,
at the Registry Hotel.
Checked in Thursday last,
checked out Monday morning.
Now, Saturday night at 9:37,
she called her husband here.
Got him just
before he went out.
At 11:41 p.m.,
she called him again
at the Brayton Country Club.
She said she didn't
make any calls
from the hotel.
Yeah, that's what she said.
Sunday,
at 10 a.m.,
she had brunch, poolside.
Stayed there all day.
They got her signature
and everything.
What do you think?
I don't know.
She was in Miami.
Maybe she got one
of her lover-boys
to come over here
and kill him.
Maybe.
Maybe you're guessing.
No, I'm not.
Hell, everybody knows her.
She's gonna get
a load of dough.
Don't it bother you
how come she's so nervous?
You think she's nervous?
What do you think she is?
She's got a reputation
all over town for
having her way with men.
Is that so?
I've heard stories, yeah.
What kind of stories?
She used to entertain men
when her husband was away.
Who told you that?
Oh, come on, Kyle.
What do you think
is goin' on here?
There was nothing
in the car,
not a fingerprint.
Rupert Munro
was a big guy.
So wherever he went,
somebody carried him.
You know she got
one of her lover-boys
to come over here
and kill him.
Where would
they put the body?
You tell me.
LAMAR: It was raining
so hard that night,
no one's gonna dig a hole
in the mud in rain.
(DOOR OPENING)
Hello, sugar.
Hi.
Thanks a lot.
How's it going inside?
Ah, we haven't found
anything yet.
All right.
Here she comes.
I brought you
some lemonade.
It's fresh.
I made it this morning.
Thank you.
KYLE: Who was in your
hotel room in Miami?
RACHEL: What?
Who called Munro
from your room?
I... I don't know what
you're talking about.
You know.
You put someone in there
and you came up here
to kill him.
I didn't.
Tell me the truth,
God damn it!
Oh, please. I am.
Nobody was there.
Somebody's lyin'.
This doesn't make any sense.
Kyle.
Mmm.
Just got a call.
Someone saw a car last week
parked up by Camelia lake
at night.
A shiny black car.
Who made the call?
Anonymous.
MAN: Find anything?
DIVER: Can't see anything.
WOMAN: We got nothing.
We're coming in.
Maybe we'll have
to come back.
You think it's here?
I don't know.
I need a hand.
So that's it.
WOMAN:
Wait. Wait. Uh, I think
we got somethin'.
Oh, Jesus.
I think we got him.
Think it's him.
Got yourself
a big ol' murder, Kyle.
From the patent
decomposition of the body
and water temperature
of 72 degrees,
it is estimated the deceased
has been in the water
for a period of seven days.
Last Saturday.
DR. OCAMPO:
The body evidence says
two gunshot wounds,
medial thoracic perforating
the lower third
of the sternum.
Evidence of slight
powder flecking.
No evidence of exit wound.
Uh, second wound is
above the right eye.
Patent evidence of powder
and gas scorching.
Exit wound, uh,
lateral to second vertebra.
You're gonna get a bullet.
Bit smashed up,
but a bullet.
May I?
Let me see.
Looks like a .38.
Yeah. Maybe a 9-millimeter.
Practically the same.
Let's measure it.
Lee, can I have
the caliper?
Thanks.
LAMAR: A .38.
Something wrong?
LAMAR: What's wrong?
(KYLE GRUNTS)
No, that's a .38.
Here's a surprise for you.
What?
DR. OCAMPO:
There's water in the lungs.
So?
Two gunshot wounds in him,
and he was alive
at the bottom of the lake.
Cause of death,
asphyxiation by drowning.
Kyle.
Look what's stuck
in the heel of his shoe.
What is it?
Glass.
I can't be sure yet,
but this looks like
the original
Victorian glass.
I think it's the same kind
you found on Munro's shoe.
This is where it happened.
KYLE: Maybe.
Her lover-boy or someone
came in.
There was a struggle.
The victim was hit
in the head and shot twice.
Thinking he killed him,
he took him to the lake
and dropped the car.
We have no fingerprints
in the whole place.
He knew what
he was doin'.
He wiped
the place clean.
I think he ran
the damn humidifier
to melt down
the prints.
We'll find a print somewhere.
We should.
We know he was here.
Kyle, we found something.
My, my.
Look what we got here.
Dig it out.
Well, Kyle,
you were right.
Sooner or later,
they all fuck up.
(HAMMERING)
Look at that.
A perfect .38.
Look at them riflings.
Gonna be easy
to match this to a gun.
All we need now
is the gun.
Who was with you in Miami?
I was alone.
You been sleeping with
anyone other than me?
No.
Uh, why are you
asking me this?
I've been hearing things
about you.
Don't let them
do this, Kyle.
You said they would try
to change your mind,
and now they're doing it.
Where's the gun?
What gun?
The gun
you shot him with.
You threw it away
at the truck stop.
That was a 9-millimeter.
I know.
(EXHALES)
What are you saying?
The bullet they took out
of your husband's body
was shot from a .38.
The bullet they took out
of the wall today was a .38.
But I shot him
with a 9-millimeter.
You saw it.
BALLISTICIAN:
This is the bullet that was
taken out of the wall
at Munro's house.
This is the bullet that was
taken out of Munro's body.
The riflings match perfectly.
They were both fired
from the same gun.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
What are the pits
on the bullet that
came out of Munro?
I don't know.
Sand will pit a bullet
like that, won't it?
Mr. Bodine, the human body,
as wonderful as it is,
contains 1.5% calcium,
1% potassium, 65% water,
and after 5:00,
some what-all percentage
of alcohol,
but (CLICKS TONGUE) no sand.
Thank you very much
for your help.
Any time.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Kyle.
Mmm-hmm?
The captain wants
to talk to you.
What about?
Something about
the Munro case.
Kyle, now were
you seein' her?
No.
You never went to
see her alone
in her house?
No, sir.
Y'all were called out
there, weren't you?
Yes, sir.
Yeah. A couple times.
Her husband filed
a complaint with us.
Said you used
abusive language.
(LAUGHS)
Did you say that?
LAMAR: He didn't
say nothing, Captain.
Guy was a jerk.
This is a lie.
What was this,
a domestic violence call?
LAMAR: Yes, sir.
Well, you took
a special interest
in this one, didn't you?
No, not really.
Where were you
a week ago
Saturday night, Kyle?
I was at home.
Munro was shot
with a .38, wasn't he?
KYLE: According to
the autopsy report, yeah.
You carry a .38 special,
don't you, Kyle?
You know I do.
May I see it?
You fired this recently?
Yes, I have.
We recovered a bullet
from that bedroom wall.
The rifling marks
are clean.
Won't be too hard to tell
if it came from your gun.
I'm puttin' you on
administrative leave
until such time
as we know that.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Good morning.
Sorry, Kyle.
You're gonna have
to come with us.
What's goin' on?
LAMAR: You tell me.
You're the one who
gave him the wrong gun.
What are you
talkin' about?
Wrong serial number.
You didn't give him
your gun.
The captain wants to
see you again.
I'll be right with you.
Got to tell you, Kyle,
you got a lot
of people upset
who can't believe you've
done somethin' like this.
Did you see her socially
at any time?
No.
The night you met her,
the bartender showed you
a credit card receipt
with her name on it.
Mmm-hmm.
Did you call her
or contact her
in any way?
No.
She wasn't calling you
here at the office?
No.
Who was?
I don't know what calls
you're talkin' about.
What are you protectin'
her for, Kyle?
Where's the service revolver
signed out by you?
Serial number 0876B?
I told you, I don't know.
Someone took yours, Kyle?
KYLE: Maybe.
Who would that have been?
I don't know.
You never went
to her house to see her?
No.
Smarten up, Kyle.
You're gonna fry for this,
and she's gonna walk.
Now that must've been what
she had in mind all along,
don't you think?
Now, we find your gun
or any evidence
that puts you there,
and you're gone.
Unless, of course,
you wanna help us.
Kyle,
she's gonna walk.
She'll be real rich.
She's gonna get $12 million.
CAPTAIN:
The state attorney
will cut a deal with you.
You could be out
in a couple of years.
Is that you?
You got my money, Lamar?
You got the ticket?
Uh-huh.
Let me see it.
You'll get the rest
when I get mine.
KYLE:
How much did you pay Dickey
to follow your husband?
What is he to you?
Rachel, start talking.
Rupert was going to
leave me with nothing.
Lamar told me
how to do it all.
How to do what?
Set up Rupert's death.
Where to meet you,
the gun, Miami.
Everything.
So we were just a lie?
No.
It changed, Kyle.
It changed after I met you.
I came back from Miami
to be with you.
You didn't even
check out of the hotel.
You came back to kill him.
No.
No. We were going away.
Who made the phone calls
from your room?
Lamar must have put
somebody in there.
Who made the phone calls
from your room?
I don't know.
I just wanna
know the truth.
Tell me the truth!
I am!
Don't look at me
like that, Kyle, please.
I'm not a stranger to you.
Yes, you are.
Don't say that.
I love you.
I don't wanna hear it.
My life was over
till I met you.
Stop it!
I love you.
Then why didn't you tell me?
If you love me,
why didn't you tell me?
I'd have lost you for good.
I don't wanna hear
any more lies!
No more lying!
You were just fucking me,
weren't you?
I was loving you,
and you were fucking me!
(RACHEL GASPING)
You should have just
told me from the beginning.
Why didn't you just tell me?
I tried to
get out of it.
Please believe me.
(SIGHING)
Call Lamar.
Tell him you wanna see him
at J.J.'s tonight.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHING)
Hello, Dickey-boy.
Kyle.
You're a big
disappointment to me.
There was nothing
I could do for you.
Maybe not.
You know,
you figured this one
like you knew it
all along.
Yeah.
I went to school
on you, Kyle.
You sure did.
I listened to
everything you told me.
I knew you did it.
You made too many
mistakes, Lamar.
What are you
talking about?
You took this,
didn't you?
I don't see
my name on it.
You see the compass
on your dash?
How did you know about
the $12 million trust?
She tell you?
Why would she do that?
Maybe you were
gonna help her
kill her husband.
I didn't. You did.
Yeah. But you're going to
jail with me anyway
because of this.
You see?
It's all pitted from sand,
just like the bullet
they took out of Munro.
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
You switched my gun,
didn't you? My .38.
You shot it into sand
and then you got the bullet.
In the autopsy room
when nobody was lookin',
you switched it with
a 9-millimeter slug
that they pulled
out of Munro's chest.
No one's gonna believe that.
Then you fired
my .38 into the wall
at Munro's house.
So the slug from the wall
and the slug
from the body match.
And they're both
from my gun.
You got a desperate
imagination, my man.
(SIGHING)
How did you know
where the body was?
Did she tell you?
What do you think?
I don't know.
All you got to do
is to get the mileage
from the car.
And you know how far away
the lake is.
Get up,
you son of a bitch.
Ah.
Don't fuck yourself
upwards, Kyle.
Let's go.
Sit down.
I told him everything, Lamar.
Where's my gun?
I don't have it, Kyle.
(GUN COCKING)
Give me the goddamn gun.
It's in my car.
If you've cooked up
something, Lamar,
I'll blow your
fucking head off.
Let's go outside.
Get up! Let's go.
Wait for me, Rachel.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Move.
Are you gonna shoot me, Kyle?
If I have to.
Well, you won't have to.
How much were you in for?
A lot.
The lady was desperate.
Then she wanted
to call it off,
but the money smelled
too good.
Why me?
Why not some fucking bozo
off the street?
Why did you have to go
set up your own partner?
It had to be you, Kyle.
Anybody else, you would
have cracked the case
and busted me.
You got that right.
But you know what?
You were never the fall guy.
You were my insurance.
Fuck you, Dickey-boy.
You screwed up.
First the pictures,
then my .38.
You kept it too long.
Open it up.
(KEYS JINGLING)
Come on.
Where is it?
Under the driver's seat.
It's not too late, Kyle.
Shut up.
Toss the gun in the lake.
You can forget
it ever happened.
Shut up!
POLICEMAN:
Police! Stop right there!
He's got a gun!
(GUN FIRES)
Kyle!
(GROANING)
Kyle?
Stay with me.
I was never
gonna leave you.
Kyle.
No.
No, no, no.
(FEMALE DISPATCHER
CHATTERING ON RADIO)
(SOBBING) No! Oh, no!
(SIREN WAILING)
Rachel.
Kyle was right.
Sooner or later,
they all fuck up.