(birds chirping)
Boy:
LUTHER!
COME ON.
COME ON, CLIVE.
HURRY UP.
YOU'RE SLOW AS SHIT, CLIVE.
COME ON.
I'M COMING.
(panting)
LUTHER, WAIT UP!
COME ON.
SEE WHAT I MEAN?
I TOLD YOU IT WAS SOMETHING.
THE BASTARD FELL
FROM THE CLIFF.
THE GUN WENT OFF
AND HE SHOT HIMSELF,
DUMB OLD FUCKER.
COME ON OVER HERE.
COME ON NOW, CLIVE.
HE AIN'T GONNA BITE YOU.
LOOK WHAT I FOUND ON HIM.
THE BASTARD'S SHARP.
I REALLY DO GOTTA GO.
YOU AIN'T GONNA TELL NOBODY
ABOUT THIS, ARE YOU?
YOU AIN'T NOTHING
BUT CHICKENSHIT.
THIS IS OUR SECRET,
YOU HEAR ME?
Man:
MELISSA, IT WAS JUST
THE ONE TIME, I SWEAR.
Melissa:
OH, AND THAT'S SUPPOSED
TO MAKE IT OKAY?
Man:
COME ON, MEL.
PLEASE DON'T DO THIS.
I SAID I WAS SORRY.
I WISH I COULD
BELIEVE YOU.
I MEAN IT.
I NEED TIME TO THINK.
OKAY.
OKAY, I UNDERSTAND.
UM, TOMORROW
LET ME TAKE YOU OUT
FOR DINNER.
I WON'T BE HERE
TOMORROW.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
RAINERSPOINT.
I'VE GOT A PART IN A PLAY.
RAINERSPOINT?
WHERE'S THAT?
A LONG LONG WAY FROM HERE.
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW.
WELL, HOW LONG
WILL YOU BE GONE?
THREE WEEKS, MAYBE A MONTH.
I DON'T KNOW.
OKAY.
WELL,
CAN I AT LEAST HELP YOU LOAD
YOUR THINGS INTO THE CAR?
NO, THANKS.
MELISSA,
I'M REALLY SORRY.
(pop song playing on radio)
(insects chirping)
YES!
(dials)
(bird screeches)
(tires screeching)
(owl hooting)
(heart beating)
(engine idling)
(water running)
(facet squeaks, water stops)
WELCOME, ROSALIE.
NOW I'M GONNA TAKE
REAL GOOD CARE OF YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'M GONNA GET YOU
ALL FIXED UP.
OH, YES, MA'AM.
YOU AIN'T GOT
NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT.
I'M GONNA TAKE
REAL GOOD CARE OF YOU.
YOU'RE A GIFT.
YOU'RE A GIFT FROM GOD.
(distant children playing)
(cell phone rings)
HELLO.
YES, HELLO.
MY NAME IS JEROME.
I'M THE STAGE MANAGER
FOR "FIRES OF FREEDOM."
IS MELISSA THERE
BY ANY CHANCE?
UH, NO, SHE'S NOT.
I'M HER SISTER.
YEAH YEAH,
I KNOW, CATHY.
MELISSA HAS MENTIONED
YOU TO ME BEFORE.
AND BESIDES,
YOUR NAME AND NUMBER ARE
ON HER CONTACT SHEET.
You're who we're to notify
in case there's an emergency.
WHOA WHOA WHOA,
AN EMERGENCY?
HUH-UH, HUH-UH.
DON'T COME AT ME
WITH ALL THAT DRAMA.
IT AIN'T THAT DEEP.
SLOW YOUR ROLL, SISTER.
WE'RE JUST TRYING
TO LOCATE HER.
For some reason or another
she hasn't arrived yet.
WELL, SHE LEFT
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
SHE SHOULD HAVE BEEN
THERE BY MIDNIGHT.
DID YOU CALL
HER MOTEL ROOM?
BABY, I HAVE BLOW-UPTUATED
THE PHONE LINES AT THE MOTEL.
SHE HASN'T CHECKED IN.
JEROME, YOU GOTTA
DO SOMETHING.
THOSE KIDS WON'T STOP
MESSING WITH THE FOG MACHINE.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GETTING
ON MY NERVES, DON'T YOU?
ALL YOU KIDS ARE JUST
MAKING MY BOWELS LOCK UP!
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
LISTEN, HON,
IF YOU SEE YOUR SISTER,
PLEASE INFORM HER
THAT IF SHE ISN'T
HERE BY NOON TOMORROW,
WE'LL HAVE TO REPLACE HER.
WELL, I'M SURE
SHE'LL BE THERE.
I HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT.
CIAO.
"BLUE SUEDE SHOES."
Man on TV:
"Blue Suede Shoes."
(laughs)
SEE?
"BLUE SUEDE SHOES,"
YOU IDIOT.
MORNING, DELLA.
GOT A DELIVERY FOR YOU.
HEY, JUSTIN.
HOW'S YOUR MOM?
WOULD IT HURT HER TO PICK UP
THE PHONE AND CALL SOMETIME?
WHO ARE THEY FOR?
MISS MELISSA ADAMS,
ROOM 108.
MIGHT AS WELL TAKE 'EM BACK.
SHE AIN'T HERE.
SUPPOSED TO CHECK INTO
HER ROOM LAST NIGHT,
BUT SHE NEVER SHOWED UP.
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN CALLING
THE WHOLE DAMN DAY
LOOKING FOR HER.
WELL, HOW ABOUT
HANGING ON TO 'EM FOR ME
JUST IN CASE SHE DOES
SHOW UP?
WHATEVER.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER, DELLA.
OKAY.  HEY...
TELL YOUR MAMA TO CALL ME.
"MELISSA, LOVE YOU LOTS.
DARIC."
Man on TV:
It is.
Congratulations, son.
You just won a bonus round.
HOT DAMN.
BONUS ROUND.
(engine starts)
(men chatting)
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
HMM?
LOOK AT 'EM.
SO ANYWAY, WHAT ARE WE
GONNA GET INTO TONIGHT?
A BUNCH OF PANSIES.
EVERY SUMMER
THIS TOWN'S TOOK OVER
BY PANSIES
AND DRUG ADDICTS--
"FIRES OF FREEDOM."
"FIRES OF FREEDOM"
BURN MY ASS.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT--
I'D LIKE TO PUT A BULLET
IN THE MEDULLA OBLONGATA
OF THE BASTARD WHO THOUGHT UP
THAT DAMN PLAY.
YOU'RE JUST ANGRY BECAUSE
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO DO
A LITTLE WORK OVER THE NEXT
COUPLE OF MONTHS
INSTEAD OF SITTING AROUND
ON THAT FAT ASS OF YOURS.
WELL, I FIGURED
YOU WOULDN'T MIND.
IT'LL GIVE YOU A CHANCE
TO JACK THEM PRICES UP AGAIN.
I GOTTA ADMIT
THERE'S NOTHING I LIKE BETTER
THAN A LITTLE TOURIST MONEY.
(door slams)
WELL, I'LL BE.
AFTERNOON THERE, CLIVE.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
NO, NOTHING, I SUPPOSE.
YOU KNOW, IN ALL THE YEARS
I'VE BEEN RUNNING THIS PLACE
THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I CAN REMEMBER
CLIVE MERCER
COMING INTO MY STORE
TWICE IN THE SAME MONTH
TO BUY ANYTHING.
HUH.
THE OLD GOAT
MUST LOVE SOUP.
YEAH, THAT'S ALL
HE EVER BUYS--
CREAM OF CHICKEN SOUP.
REALLY?
LOOKS LIKE HE MIGHT BE DOING
A LITTLE BIT OF SPRING CLEANING.
IN THE MIDDLE OF JUNE?
MAYBE HE FORGOT
TO WIND HIS CLOCK.
I'M AFRAID OLD CLIVE
DOESN'T HAVE
A WHOLE LOT OF CLOCK
TO WIND.
HUH.
(distant train horn blowing)
(country music playing on radio)
(bells jingle)
Woman:
HEY, DON'T GO.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU TODAY?
MISS BENTLEY?
SHE'S DEAD, HON.
BEEN DEAD, WHAT,
10 YEARS, I GUESS?
THIS IS MY PLACE NOW.
THE NAME'S JEWEL.
WHAT'S YOURS?
MY NAME IS CLIVE MERCER.
WELL, CLIVE, WHAT MIGHT YOU
BE LOOKING FOR TODAY?
ANYTHING IN PARTICULAR?
SOMETHING FOR YOURSELF MAYBE?
OR PERHAPS SOMETHING
FOR THE LITTLE LADY?
WONDERFUL.
FOLLOW ME.
NOW THIS IS WHERE MOST OF
THE LADIES START.
AND THEY GO ON AROUND BACK
TO THE UNDIES AND THINGS,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
SO WHAT'LL IT BE?
OOH, NO, NOT THAT ONE.
FOR CHRISSAKE,
THAT'S A FASHION SUICIDE.
I THINK I'D BETTER HELP.
WHAT SIZE IS SHE?
I CAN TELL ALMOST EVERYTHING
ABOUT A WOMAN
BY WHAT SIZE SHE WEARS.
OH, COME ON,
YOU'VE GOT TO KNOW
WHAT SIZE SHE IS.
IS SHE A SIX OR A SEVEN?
IS SHE ABOUT MY SIZE?
I'M NOT SURE, MA'AM.
WELL, HOW ABOUT
THESE MANNEQUINS?
COULD ONE OF THEM
BE HER SIZE?
I SEE SOMETHING
HAS CAUGHT YOUR EYE.
BUT-- BUT THAT'S
A WEDDING DRESS.
IT'S EXPENSIVE.
Man over phone:
Listen, I'm afraid
our hands are tied
until 48 hours
from now.
SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO CHECK
INTO HER MOTEL ROOM
LAST NIGHT
AT RAINERSPOINT, TENNESSEE,
BUT SHE NEVER ARRIVED.
AND NOBODY'S SEEN HER.
AND SHE HASN'T
CALLED ANYBODY.
SOMETHING TERRIBLE
HAS HAPPENED, I KNOW IT.
Man:
Let's hope not, ma'am.
If she was going to Tennessee,
you might want to call
local law enforcement
out there.
They can probably do more
for you right now
than we can.
I MIGHT JUST DO THAT.
THANK YOU, SERGEANT.
Well, if you don't
hear from your sister
by this time tomorrow,
let us know.
We'll see what we can do.
- I KNOW IT'S HERE SOMEWHERE.
- (clattering)
I'M NOT GIVING UP,
ROSALIE.
I KNOW IT'S HERE.
(clattering continues)
(fly buzzing)
I FOUND IT.
I FOUND IT--
MAMA'S PICTURE BOOK.
(owl hooting)
THIS HERE IS MY DADDY.
HE DIED WHEN I WAS
REAL YOUNG.
THEY FOUND HIM
DOWN BY THE CREEK
WHERE HE GOT KICKED
IN THE HEAD BY HIS HORSE.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN,
MAMA SAID.
NOW THIS HERE--
THIS HERE'S MAMA.
SHE'S PRETTY, ISN'T SHE?
SHE WAS ONLY 15
WHEN THIS PICTURE WAS TAKEN.
AND THAT WOMAN
STANDING THERE BESIDE HER--
THAT WAS HER MAMA.
THAT'D BE MY GRANDMA.
THEM FLOWERS
THEY'S HOLDING--
THOSE ARE ROSES.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
THEY HAVE FLOWERS.
I KNOW SOME
OF THESE PEOPLE, BUT--
WELL, THEY MUST BE KIN,
OR MAMA WOULDN'T HAVE
PUT THEM IN HERE,
BUT I CAN'T THINK
OF THEIR NAMES RIGHT NOW.
WELL, THAT'S HOW
I AM SOMETIMES.
I MEAN, I HAVE GOOD DAYS
AND BAD DAYS FOR REMEMBERING.
(chuckles)
SEE, I KNOW
THESE RASCALS.
SEE, THAT LITTLE BABY
RIGHT THERE--
THAT'S ME.
(laughs)
AND THAT'S
MY BROTHER NATHAN.
HE WAS FIVE YEARS
OLDER THAN ME.
OH, AND THIS IS NATHAN
IN HIS UNIFORM.
HE JOINED THE ARMY
RIGHT AS SOON AS HE
GOT OUT OF SCHOOL.
A VIET CONGER
SHOT HIM IN THE HEAD
WITH A SNIPER'S BULLET
AS SOON AS
HE GOT OVER THERE.
HE SHOULD HAVE NEVER
RUN OFF
AND LEFT ME AND MAMA
LIKE THAT.
HIM GETTING KILLED CAUSED
MAMA TO HAVE ANOTHER STROKE
AND SHE NEVER COULD
EVEN WALK AFTER THAT.
THIS HERE--
THIS IS ROSALIE HOBART.
SHE WAS A NURSE
THAT DOC MOSLEY SENT OVER
AFTER MAMA HAD
HER STROKE.
SHE WAS THE ONLY WOMAN
THAT I EVER MET
THAT TREATED ME
LIKE I WAS SOMEBODY
AND NOT JUST LIKE
SOME RETARD,
LIKE MOST PEOPLE DO.
SHE STAYED WITH US
FOR 10 YEARS.
AND THEN
ONE DAY SHE JUST
DIDN'T COME ANYMORE.
AND I HEARD
THAT SHE GOT MARRIED
AND MOVED AWAY.
THAT NURSE THEY SENT AFTER HER
WAS JUST MEAN.
SHE WAS MEAN, SPITEFUL.
SHE'S THE ONE THAT CAUSED
ALL THAT TROUBLE FOR ME.
NOW I DON'T KNOW WHO THESE
OTHER PEOPLE ARE WITH MAMA,
BUT THOSE BUILDINGS
UP THERE--
MAMA SAID
THAT THAT USED TO BE
ALL THERE WAS
OF DOWNTOWN RAINERSPOINT.
ISN'T THAT SOMETHING?
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
IT SURE HAS CHANGED
SINCE THEN, AIN'T IT?
WAIT A MINUTE, YOU--
YOU'VE NEVER EVEN SEEN
DOWNTOWN RAINERSPOINT,
HAVE YOU?
WELL, WE CAN FIX THAT,
BY GOLLY.
WE CAN FIX THAT.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT--
SUNDAY MORNING
WE'LL GET IN THE CAR
AND WE'LL GO FOR A RIDE.
AND I'LL SHOW YOU
SOME SIGHTS.
I CAN'T FIND
MY OTHER CARD.
COULD YOU JUST
CHECK IT AGAIN, PLEASE?
RUN THE NUMBER
AND CHECK THE NAME.
IT'S A "C", NOT A "K".
IT'S JUST VERY IMPORTANT
THAT I GET ON THE ROAD
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
OKAY, BUT YOU'LL CALL ME
RIGHT BACK?
OKAY, THANKS.
HEY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT, DARIC?
WELL, IT'S ABOUT MELISSA.
WHAT ABOUT HER?
HAVE YOU SPOKEN TO HER--
SINCE SHE LEFT FOR
RAINERSPOINT, I MEAN?
NO.  WHY?
WELL, I DON'T WANT
TO WORRY YOU OR ANYTHING,
BUT I THINK
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
I HAD SOME FLOWERS
WIRED TO HER MOTEL ROOM
THIS MORNING,
BUT THE FLORIST
CALLED ME BACK AND SAID
HE COULDN'T DELIVER THEM
'CAUSE SHE WASN'T THERE.
HE SAID THAT SHE HADN'T
EVEN CHECKED IN YET.
I KNOW.
NOBODY UP THERE HAS A CLUE
WHERE SHE IS.
IT'S LIKE SHE JUST
VANISHED SOMEHOW.
THE WORST PART IS,
NO ONE REALLY SEEMS
ALL THAT CONCERNED--
NOBODY BUT ME.
THAT'S WHY I'M GONNA GO
LOOK FOR HER MYSELF.
HEY, WAIT.
DO YOU WANT TO RIDE WITH ME?
YOU'RE GOING
TO RAINERSPOINT?
YEAH, I ALREADY GOT
THE MAP AND EVERYTHING.
LOOK, I STILL LOVE
YOUR SISTER
DESPITE WHAT YOU
MIGHT THINK.
SO DO YOU WANT
A RIDE OR--?
ALL RIGHT.
BUT I'M PAYING
FOR MY SHARE OF THE GAS.
- FAIR ENOUGH.
- (phone rings)
I HAVE TO GET THIS.
- HELLO.
- Melissa Adams's sister?
YES, WHO IS THIS?
THIS IS JEROME.
I'M CALLING TO INFORM YOU
THAT THE NOON DEADLINE
HAS PASSED.
THEREFORE, YOUR SISTER
HAS BEEN OFFICIALLY FIRED
FROM OUR PRODUCTION.
LISTEN TO ME,
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
TAKE YOUR FUCKING PLAY
AND SHOVE IT UP YOUR ASS.
CIAO.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I'M SORRY TO LEAVE YOU ALONE
FOR SO LONG, ROSALIE,
BUT THAT MAILMAN--
HE WAS AWFUL LATE.
OH LORD.
OH.
OH, ROSALIE,
THERE NOW, THERE.
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE
FINE NOW.
THAT WAS ALL MY FAULT.
(sniffing)
OH.
THIS HEAT.
I'M GONNA FIX YOU
A BATH, OKAY?
WE GOTTA KEEP YOU
PRETTY AND ALL.
SO YOU'RE SURE THIS IS
THE WAY MELISSA WENT?
YEAH.
I'M SURE.
I'VE DRIVEN UP HERE
WITH HER BEFORE
WHEN SHE WAS STILL
AUDITIONING FOR PARTS.
OH.
HOW DO YOU EXPECT
WE'LL TRACK HER DOWN?
WELL, I WAS THINKING
WE'D STOP AT THE GAS STATIONS
ALONG THE WAY
AND WE'D ASK THE MANAGERS
IF THEY'D SEEN HER.
RIGHT.
I'M SURE SHE'S ALL RIGHT.
THE ONE THING
MELISSA DOES BEST
IS TAKE CARE OF HERSELF.
YEAH.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THIS NICE COOL BATH
OUGHT TO HELP.
I GOT SOME STUFF
THAT'S GONNA KEEP YOU
SMELLING NICE.
I'LL JUST USE
THE WHOLE THING.
MAYBE WE SHOULD SHAMPOO
YOUR HAIR A LITTLE BIT.
(humming a tune)
YOU LIKE THAT HYMN?
MAMA USED TO
SING THAT TO ME
WHEN I WASN'T FEELING
ALL THAT WELL.
THERE'S WORDS TO IT,
BUT I CAN'T REMEMBER 'EM
RIGHT NOW.
WELL, THAT'S ENOUGH
SHAMPOO.
WE'LL GET YOU
RINSED OFF.
I WANT YOU TO LOOK
REAL PRETTY TONIGHT, ROSALIE.
I GOT SOMETHING REAL SPECIAL
PLANNED FOR YOU.
(distant train horn blows)
CATHY, WE'VE WASTED
A LOT OF TIME
STOPPING AT PLACES
LIKE THIS.
NOW ACCORDING TO THE MAP,
WE'RE JUST 30 MILES
FROM RAINERSPOINT.
DON'T YOU THINK IT'D BE BEST
IF WE JUST WENT AHEAD
AND DROVE THE REST
OF THE WAY THERE?
DARIC, THE ONLY REASON
I STOPPED
IS BECAUSE WE'RE NEARLY
OUT OF GAS.
OH.
BUT WHILE YOU'RE PUMPING IT,
I MIGHT AS WELL SHOW THEM
MEL'S PICTURE.
IT'S YOUR TURN TO PAY,
BY THE WAY.
(country song playing on radio)
HELLO?
- HEY.
- YOU GETTING GAS?
- YEAH, BUT WE'RE PAYING
AT THE PUMP.
OH, WELL, YOU WANT
SOME CIGARETTES?
NO, THANK YOU.
I'M LOOKING FOR SOMEONE.
I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU COULD HELP ME.
- WELL, SURE.
- GREAT.
RING ME UP, HONEY.
I'M IN A BIG HURRY.
I GOT ME A HOT DATE.
OF COURSE, I COULD ALWAYS
CANCEL IT.
TAKE THIS BEER
YOU GOT RIGHT HERE,
PUT IT RIGHT BACK
IN THE COOLER,
'CAUSE I AIN'T
SELLING IT TO YOU.
I'M A FULL-GROWN MAN.
I'M OVER 21 YEARS OLD.
I DON'T CARE
IF YOU'RE 91.
I STILL AIN'T SELLING YOU
THAT BEER.
- WHY THE HELL NOT?
- I'LL TELL YOU WHY--
BECAUSE MY BEST FRIEND'S
HUSBAND WAS KILLED BY
A DRUNK DRIVER LAST MONTH,
LEAVING HER WITH NO MONEY
COMING IN
AND THREE LITTLE BABIES
TO FEED.
AND FROM THAT DAY ON
I VOWED
THAT NO ALCOHOL OF ANY KIND
WOULD BE SOLD ON MY SHIFT.
NOW YOU CAN REPORT ME
TO MY BOSS
AND YOU CAN GET ME FIRED.
I DON'T GIVE A RAT'S ASS
'CAUSE I GOT PRINCIPLES.
YOU'RE A CRAZY BITCH.
HERE'S YOUR MONEY.
THIS IS MY BEER.
- NO.
- GIVE ME THAT BEER.
GIVE ME THE BE--
(groans)
I'M SORRY.
WHAT WAS IT
I COULD HELP YOU WITH?
- COULD YOU TAKE A LOOK
AT THIS PICTURE?
- SURE.
THAT'S MY SISTER.
SHE'S MISSING.
NO ONE'S SEEN HER
IN TWO DAYS.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE NOW.
I HAVE.
- YOU HAVE?
- WELL, YES.
SHE STOPPED IN HERE
TO GET GAS AND BUY A MAP.
SHE SAID SHE WAS HEADING
FOR RAINERSPOINT
BUT SHE DIDN'T KNOW
IF SHE WAS ON THE RIGHT ROAD.
DID SHE SAY ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT.
THANK YOU.
MY PLEASURE.
AND I HOPE YOU FIND HER.
- THANK YOU.
- ALL RIGHT.
(door opens and closes)
A DOG TICK.
(snaps)
(owl hooting)
(hissing)
(bluegrass waltz playing)
I SURE HOPE
YOU LIKE SOUP.
I'M NOT MUCH GOOD
AT COOKING.
THIS IS PRETTY MUCH
ALL I EAT.
BUT I EXPECT THAT MIGHT CHANGE
NOW THAT YOU'RE HERE.
(chuckles)
THERE NOW.
I'LL SAY THE BLESSING.
GOD IS GREAT.  GOD IS GOOD.
LET US THANK HIM TO OUR FOOD.
BY HIS HANDS WE ALL ARE FED.
GIVE US, LORD, OUR DAILY BREAD.
AMEN.
THIS IS GONNA BE
A SPECIAL NIGHT, ROSALIE,
SPECIAL FOR BOTH OF US.
OH, I GOT A BIG SURPRISE
FOR YOU AFTER SUPPER.
BUT I'M NOT GONNA SAY
NOTHING ELSE.
I WANT TO KEEP YOU
GUESSING.
I PRAYED AND PRAYED
THAT THE LORD WOULD
SEND ME SOMEBODY
TO SPEND MY LAST YEARS WITH
HERE,
SO THAT I WOULDN'T
BE ALONE.
AND MAMA ALWAYS TOLD ME
THAT IF YOU PRAY
LONG ENOUGH AND HARD ENOUGH,
YOUR PRAYERS
WILL BE ANSWERED.
MAMA WOULD APPROVE
OF YOU.
(sniffs)
YOU SMELL LIKE MAMA.
I HOPE IT'S NOT TOO HOT
FOR YOU, ROSALIE.
USUALLY I DON'T EVEN BOTHER
HEATING THIS STUFF UP.
MM, IT'S GOOD HOT.
(burps)
SORRY.
IN CHINA THAT MEANS
YOU LIKE YOUR SUPPER.
JESUS.
THIS PLACE IS CREEPY.
IT'S NOT EVEN 10:00
AND EVERYTHING IS CLOSED.
THE MOTEL IS STILL OPEN.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
(bluegrass song playing)
When I was single
Marrying was
all I craved
But now I am married,
Lord
I'm troubled
to my grave
Lord, I wish I was
a single girl again...
I GOT SOMETHING
FOR YOU.
Dishes to wash
And springs to go to
I've got no one
to help me, Lord
I have it all to do
Lord, I wish I was
a single girl again...
IT WAS MY MAMA'S,
AND HER GRANDMA'S
BEFORE THAT.
I HOPE YOU LIKE IT.
Both of them
so hungry, Lord
They can't raise up
their heads
Lord, I wish I was
a single girl again...
(music continues)
(exhales)
I'M GONNA MAKE YOU
THE HAPPIEST WOMAN
IN RAINERSPOINT.
ANYTHING YOU WANT
I'LL GET YOU.
'CAUSE YOU ARE
GOD'S GIFT TO ME, ROSALIE,
AND I'M GONNA MAKE SURE
YOU HAVE THE BEST
THAT ANY WOMAN COULD WANT.
I LOVE YOU, ROSALIE.
I wish I was dead
Lord, I wish I was
a single girl again...
OH.
OH, I UNDERSTAND.
I-- I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY.
I UNDERSTAND.
I JUST BETTER GET
THESE DISHES
BACK TO THE KITCHEN.
I'M SORRY.
OH, MAN.
IT FEELS GOOD
TO STRETCH OUT.
YOU CARED A LOT FOR MEL,
DIDN'T YOU?
I STILL DO.
I LOVE HER.
THEN WHY DID YOU
SCREW AROUND ON HER?
WELL,
IT'S LIKE I TOLD MEL--
IT WAS JUST A LAPSE
IN JUDGMENT.
I KNOW IT'S AN AWFULLY
PAT ANSWER,
BUT IT'S THE BEST
I'VE GOT.
MEL SAID SHE WAS
ONE OF YOUR STUDENTS.
YEAH.
SHE WAS IN THIS PHOTOGRAPHY
COURSE THAT I WAS INSTRUCTING.
SHE WAS ALWAYS
FLIRTING WITH ME.
AND THEN ONE NIGHT
SHE VOLUNTEERED TO STAY BEHIND
AND HELP ME CHANGE
THE CHEMICALS IN THE DARKROOM.
IT WAS A ONE-TIME THING.
AND I FELT GUILTY AS HELL
WHEN IT WAS OVER.
AND YOU'VE BEEN ONE
MISERABLE BASTARD EVER SINCE?
ABSOLUTELY.
OH, MAN.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I MEAN, YOU KNOW MEL
BETTER THAN ANYBODY.
YOU THINK SHE'LL EVER
GIVE ME ANOTHER CHANCE?
STRANGER THINGS
HAVE HAPPENED.
SO YOU STILL THINK
THERE'S HOPE?
WELL, YEAH, I GUESS.
WE SHOULD GET SOME SLEEP.
WE'VE GOT A LONG DAY
AHEAD OF US.
YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
HEY...
DON'T WORRY.
WE'RE GONNA FIND HER.
I JUST HAVE THIS
GUT FEELING, YOU KNOW?
I KNOW.
WELL, GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.
THANKS FOR COMING ALONG,
DARIC.
NO PROBLEM.
WELL, ROSALIE,
IT'S SUNDAY MORNING.
NOW I PROMISED YOU
A RIDE INTO TOWN.
IT'LL BE GOOD.
WE CAN GET TO KNOW
EACH OTHER BETTER.
IT'LL DO YOU SOME GOOD
TO GET OUT FOR SOME FRESH AIR.
OH, MY.
MAMA'S SUMMER HAT
JUST SUITS YOU TO A "T",
DON'T IT?
(air conditioner humming)
ORDER UP, WANDA.
Sheriff:
HE SEES ME AND HE MAKES
A BEELINE RIGHT FOR ME
JUST A-SWINGING THAT
TIRE IRON OVER HIS HEAD
AND KAI-YAYING.
(laughs)
OF COURSE, HE'S DRUNKER
THAN NINE MIDGETS IN A VOLVO,
SO HE WINDS UP
TRIPPING OVER HIS OWN FEET,
STICKING THAT TIRE IRON
THROUGH HIS LEG.
CONSIDERING HE WAS
NAKED AS A JAYBIRD,
IT PROBABLY COULD HAVE BEEN
A WHOLE HELL OF A LOT WORSE.
JOHNNY RAY NEVER COULD
HOLD HIS LIQUOR.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
SEE, ROSALIE?
AIN'T IT EVERYTHING
I SAID IT'D BE?
LOOK.
LOOK RIGHT OVER THERE.
THAT'S MR. WEBBER'S
SHOE STORE.
HE'S THE MAN THAT MADE
THESE BOOTS FOR ME
WAY LONG TIME AGO.
AND LOOK RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S THE SHOP WHERE
I GOT THE DRESS FOR YOU.
OH, AND LOOK
RIGHT OVER THERE.
THAT'S WHERE--
(tires screech,
crash)
SHERIFF, YOU MIGHT WANT
TO COME SEE THIS.
DAMN IT TO HELL.
I WISH YOU PEOPLE IN THIS TOWN
WOULD LEARN HOW TO DRIVE.
ISN'T THAT
OLD CLIVE MERCER?
YEAH, BUT WHO'S THAT WOMAN
IN THE CAR WITH HIM?
I DON'T KNOW.
ALL RIGHT.
(engine grinding)
I WAS TRYING
TO EAT MY BREAKFAST.
WHAT ARE YOU MONKEY NUTS
DOING OUT HERE?
ALL RIGHT, JUST HANG BACK.
LET ME TALK TO HIM FOR A SECOND.
(engine grinding)
HEY, BUDDY.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
YOU ALMOST HIT
THAT BOY'S TRUCK.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT'S YOUR STORY?
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON
OUT HERE?
WELL, ASK HIM, SHERIFF.
HE'S THE ONE ABOUT HIT ME.
GOD, MAN, WHAT YOU GOT
IN THERE, A SKUNK?
HEY.
LOOK OUT, LOOK OUT.
WHOA WHOA WHOA.
HEY HEY HEY.
GET BACK HERE, DAMN IT.
OH, LORD.
OH, ROSALIE, I SHOULD HAVE
NEVER TOOK YOU OUT
IN THIS HEAT.
OH, I'M SO STUPID
SOMETIMES.
(footsteps)
(exclaims)
WELL, HEY THERE, BECKY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING WALKING
ALONE, ALL BY YOURSELF, HUH?
MAMA SENT ME TO THE STORE.
OH?
WHAT YOU GOT IN THERE?
JUST GROCERIES, IS ALL.
OH, IS THAT SO?
I GOTTA GET HOME,
MR. SPOOLE.
- FIRST YOU'RE COMING
HOME WITH ME.
- LEAVE ME ALONE.
YEAH, WE'LL JUST
CUT THROUGH THE WOODS
SO AS NOBODY COULD SEE.
STOP.
WELL, I'LL BE
A SON OF A BITCH.
OW!
IF YOU TELL YOUR MAMA AND DADDY,
I'LL GET YOU WHERE YOU SLEEP!
YOU HEAR ME?
CLIVE, CLIVE,
WAIT A MINUTE.
CLIVE!
CLIVE.
OPEN UP.
NOW I KNOW YOU'VE GOT
A GIRL IN THERE.
HELLO, LUTHER.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
I AIN'T SEEN YOU
IN A COON'S AGE.
CUT THE SHIT, CLIVE.
I WANT TO MEET
THE WOMAN IN THE HOUSE.
AND DON'T TRY LYING,
ACTING LIKE SHE AIN'T HERE,
'CAUSE I SEEN YOU WITH HER
ABOUT A MINUTE AGO.
SHE'S NOT UP TO MEETING
NOBODY RIGHT NOW.
WE JUST GOT BACK FROM TOWN
AND SHE'S AWFUL TIRED.
WELL, WHO THE HELL IS SHE?
WHERE IS SHE FROM?
SHE'S JUST A COUSIN,
IS ALL,
UH, FROM POLK COUNTY.
AND SHE'S JUST GONNA STAY
A FEW DAYS
AND GO BACK.
LAST TIME WE TALKED YOU SAID
YOU DIDN'T HAVE NO KIN.
YOU SAID YOU WAS
THE LAST ONE.
(spits)
WHO IS SHE, CLIVE?
COME ON, YOU CAN TRUST ME.
WHAT, IS SHE SOME GAL
YOU MET SOMEWHERE,
MAYBE AN UGLY ONE,
MAYBE ONE THAT COULDN'T GET
NO OTHER MAN?
HEY, HAVE YOU
PUT IT TO HER YET?
I THINK IT'D BE BEST
IF YOU LEFT NOW.
WHAT DID I DO?
YOU GET OFF MY PROPERTY!
I MEAN IT!
OKAY.  OKAY.
I DON'T WANT
NO TROUBLE, CLIVE.
LOOK, I'M LEAVING.
THAT THERE'S
LUTHER SPOOLE.
HE THINKS
HE'S A FRIEND OF MINE,
BUT HE'S NOT.
HE'S A DIRTY ONE.
OH, ROSALIE.
I CAN'T PAY HIM
NO NEVERMIND RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE THE ONE
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
YOU'RE NOT LOOKING
RIGHT AT ALL.
I MIGHT NEED TO GET
SOME MORE STUFF,
MAYBE GIVE YOU
ANOTHER BATH.
MAYBE IF I LET YOU
SOAK FOR A WHILE...
(slurping)
YOU KNOW, THEY SHOOT
EGG-SUCKING DOGS.
(laughs)
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
NEVER MIND.
YOKE'S MY FAVORITE PART.
SHERIFF BULLOCK.
YEAH?
WE'D LIKE TO SPEAK TO YOU
IF WE COULD.
CAN IT WAIT TILL I'M DONE
EATING BREAKFAST?
NO, IT CAN'T.
MY SISTER'S BEEN MISSING
FOR OVER TWO DAYS NOW.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
GET BACK TO THE STORE.
MY NEPHEW'S GONNA STEAL ME
BLIND IF I'M GONE TOO LONG.
I GOTTA GET MYSELF.
I GOT THREE OIL CHANGES
WAITING ON ME
BACK AT THE STATION.
YOU TAKE A MINUTE
AND YOU TALK TO THESE
NICE FOLKS, OKAY?
SEE YOU LATER.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS HER PICTURE.
(slurping)
YOU SAY
THIS SISTER OF YOURS
IS AN ACTRESS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
(chuckles)
LET ME TELL YOU A LITTLE
SOMETHING ABOUT ACTORS--
THEY'RE A FLIGHTY BUNCH.
THEY LIKE LIVING LIFE
IN THE FAST LANE.
WHEN THEY BLOW
INTO TOWN HERE EVERY YEAR
TO DO THAT DAMN PLAY
THEY FIND OUT PRETTY
BY-GOD QUICK
THIS AIN'T NEW YORK
OR LALA-WOOD.
RAINERSPOINT'S DOWNRIGHT
BORING TO THEM.
THERE AIN'T NO COCAINE PARTIES
OR SEX ORGIES
TO SATISFY THEIR
DECADENT LIFESTYLES.
AND EVERY YEAR
THERE'S ALWAYS A FEW OF 'EM--
USUALLY FIRST-TIMERS
JUST LIKE YOUR SISTER--
WHO WIND UP QUITTING
'CAUSE THEY JUST
CAN'T HACK IT.
SHERIFF...
(chuckles)
MY SISTER NEVER HAD
A CHANCE TO FIND OUT
IF RAINERSPOINT
WAS BORING OR NOT.
WE THINK SHE DISAPPEARED
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN HERE
AND A GAS STATION
30 MILES AWAY.
NOW WE WOULD REALLY
APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU HELPED US
FIND HER.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING, MISSY?
THIS MIGHT COME AS A REAL
BIG SHOCK TO YOU
AND MR. FOOTLOOSE
OVER HERE,
BUT WE GOT A WHOLE LOT MORE
IMPORTANT PROBLEMS TO TAKE
CARE OF RIGHT NOW,
PROBLEMS THAT TAKE
PRIORITY
OVER LOOKING FOR SOME
MISSING ACTRESS.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT--
IF YOU WANT TO LEAVE
THAT PICTURE,
I WILL TRY
TO SHOW IT AROUND
IF I GET THE TIME.
HOW ABOUT THAT?
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
CALLED HIM A LARDASS.
NOW HE'LL NEVER
HELP US.
HE WASN'T GONNA HELP US
TO BEGIN WITH, DARIC.
WE'RE ON OUR OWN.
SO WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
WE STOP EVERYBODY WE SEE
AND WE SHOW THEM
MEL'S PICTURE.
WE BUG THE HELL OUT OF THEM
IF WE HAVE TO.
SOMEBODY IN THIS SCREWED-UP
TOWN HAS SEEN HER.
ALL RIGHT, CLIVE.
THAT'S GONNA BE $13.83.
SORRY WE ONLY HAD
SIX BOTTLES OF DISINFECTANT.
YOU PRETTY MUCH
CLEANED US OUT.
WE'LL GET SOME MORE IN
NEXT WEEK.
IS EVERYTHING
ALL RIGHT, CLIVE?
I'VE NEVER SEEN YOU IN TOWN
AS MUCH AS I HAVE THIS WEEK.
YOU GOT COMPANY?
WHAT'S WITH HIM?
I'M NOT SURE.
BUT I GOT AN IDEA.
I JUST HOPE TO GOD
I'M WRONG.
(door squeaks)
UH, AHEM.
HOWDY, MA'AM.
MY NAME'S LUTHER--
LUTHER SPOOLE.
I LIVE CLOSE BY.
I HOPE I DIDN'T
WAKE YOU UP.
YOU MIND IF I SIT DOWN?
I JUST THOUGHT
I'D STOP BY
AND VISIT YOU A SPELL.
CLIVE SAYS THAT YOU--
OH, SHIT.
(spits)
(flies buzzing)
(chuckles)
(doorbell jingles)
WELCOME...
TO MY WONDERLAND
OF LEFTOVERS AND JUNK.
MY NAME IS JEWEL.
- HI, I'M CATHY.
- I'M DARIC.
IT'S A PLEASURE.
WE WERE WONDERING
IF YOU COULD HELP US.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR SOMEONE.
YOU'VE COME
TO THE RIGHT PERSON.
I KNOW ALMOST
EVERYONE IN TOWN.
ICE TEA?
NO, THANK YOU.
THIS IS MY SISTER.
SHE'S BEEN MISSING
FOR OVER TWO DAYS NOW.
I'M SORRY,
I HAVEN'T SEEN HER.
I'D REMEMBER THAT FACE--
VERY EXPRESSIVE.
WHAT SIZE IS SHE?
SIZE?
WHAT SIZE DOES SHE WEAR?
I CAN TELL A LOT ABOUT A PERSON
BY THEIR SIZE.
SHE'S A 6, I THINK.
NICE.
NOT TOO MANY WOMEN IN THIS
TOWN BUYING SIZE 6,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
(laughs)
WELL, THAT'S NOT TRUE.
SOMEBODY WAS IN HERE
THE OTHER DAY,
GOT MY WEDDING DRESS
I BOUGHT AT A YARD SALE.
IT WAS SIZE 6.
COULD THAT HAVE BEEN
MY SISTER?
OH NO, IT WAS A MAN.
HE SAID HIS NAME
WAS CLYDE.
WALKED WITH A LIMP,
LIKE SOMETHING WAS WRONG
WITH HIS LEG.
I DON'T BELIEVE
HE'S ALL THERE,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
DID HE SAY
WHO HE BOUGHT IT FOR?
YEAH, THE LITTLE LADY.
THANK YOU.
SURE I CAN'T INTEREST YOU
IN A BARGAIN?
OH, NO, THANKS.
YOU'VE BEEN A GREAT HELP.
I HOPE YOU FIND HER.
WE WILL.
CATHY, WAIT UP.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND OUT
WHO THAT GUY WAS.
LOOK, A GUY WALKS
INTO THE STORE
AND HE BUYS A DRESS
THAT HAPPENS TO BE
THE SAME SIZE AS
YOUR SISTER.
SO?  THAT DOESN'T MAKE HIM
A KIDNAPPER.
HOW DOES THAT MAKE
ANY SENSE?
SENSE?  GOD, DARIC,
NONE OF THIS MAKES ANY SENSE.
OKAY OKAY, CALM DOWN.
OKAY.
LOOK, WE NEED TO ASK AROUND
A LITTLE BIT
BEFORE WE STARTS ACCUSING
SOMEONE OF KIDNAPPING.
IT'S A VERY SERIOUS
ACCUSATION, OKAY?
SO LET'S ASK AROUND FIRST.
ALL RIGHT?
ROSALIE, I'M BACK.
THE STORE DIDN'T HAVE
EVERYTHING THAT I NEEDED, BUT--
ROSALIE!
ROSALIE.
ROSALIE, WHERE ARE YOU?
WHERE--?
ROSALIE.
- EXCUSE ME.
- YES?
- HEY.
- HI.
I WAS JUST WONDERING
IF YOU'D HAD ANY LUCK
FINDING YOUR SISTER.
NO, WE HAVEN'T.
OH, I'M SORRY.
WE WERE TALKING TO THE LADY
WHO OWNS THE THRIFT STORE
A FEW MINUTES AGO AND--
- JEWEL?
- YES.
SHE WAS TELLING US
ABOUT A MAN
WHO CAME IN THERE
THE OTHER DAY.
WHAT WAS HIS NAME?
UH, CLYDE.
CLYDE.  HE WALKED
WITH A LIMP AND HE--
CLIVE.
CLIVE MERCER.
DO YOU KNOW HIM?
A LITTLE, YEAH.
WHAT DID HE DO?
HE BOUGHT
A WEDDING DRESS.
HE TOLD HER IT WAS
FOR THE LITTLE LADY.
DO YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
COME HERE.
MAYBE I DO,
MAYBE I DON'T.
I AIN'T 100% SURE.
THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS
CLIVE'S BEEN
IN MY STORE TWICE.
HE BOUGHT SOME DISINFECTANT
AND SOME EXTRA CANS OF SOUP,
YOU KNOW, LIKE THERE WAS
SOMEBODY UP THERE
THAT HE HAD TO FEED.
IT'S A WOMAN.
I KNOW THAT BECAUSE
I SAW HER IN THE CAR
WITH HIM THIS MORNING
WHEN HE DROVE
THROUGH TOWN.
WHERE DOES THIS
CLIVE GUY LIVE?
ON THE OTHER END OF TOWN,
OFF KNOB HILL ROAD.
IT'S WHERE ALL THE OTHER
CRAZIES LIVE.
LOOK, DON'T YOU GUYS
GO UP THERE ALONE.
YOU TAKE THE SHERIFF
WITH YOU IF YOU GO.
(twig snaps)
SHIT.
WHERE IS SHE?
DAMN IT, CLIVE.
JESUS CHRIST.
I WAS GONNA BRING HER BACK.
I JUST WANTED--
(gagging)
WHERE IS SHE?
NOT HIM.
NOT HIM!
YOU STUPID BASTARD.
I'LL SHOW YOU
WHAT A REAL MAN CAN DO.
(screaming)
HEY.  HEY.
SHE STINKS.
(laughs)
(thunder rumbling)
WELL, HE'S THE ONLY
MERCER ON THE ROAD.
IT'S GOTTA BE HIM.
LOOK, I THINK WE SHOULD
GO BACK AND GET THE SHERIFF.
DAMN IT, DARIC,
WE'VE WASTED ENOUGH TIME.
IF HE HAS MEL UP THERE,
THERE'S NO TELLING
WHAT HE'S BEEN
DOING TO HER.
LET'S GO.
LOOK LOOK, WE DON'T KNOW
HOW HE'S GONNA REACT
WHEN HE SEES A STRANGER
ON HIS PROPERTY.
I THINK MAYBE
I SHOULD GO ALONE.
I CAN TAKE CARE
OF MYSELF.
YEAH, BUT YOU'RE CRAZY.
WHAT?  HAVE YOU HAD THAT
ON YOU THE WHOLE TIME?
IS IT LOADED?
DARIC.
OKAY OKAY, LISTEN.
I'LL GO
SCOPE OUT THE HOUSE.
YOU STAY HERE
AND GET ON YOUR CELL PHONE
AND TRY TO GET AHOLD
OF THE SHERIFF.
GET HIM UP HERE.
FINE.
BUT TAKE THIS.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
IF HE SEES ME WITH THAT,
HE'LL GO STRAIGHT
FOR HIS SHOTGUN
OR CROSSBOW
OR WHATEVER.
I'LL TAKE THIS INSTEAD.
IF HE THINKS I'M A HARMLESS
WILDLIFE PHOTOGRAPHER,
HE'LL BE LESS INCLINED
TO BLOW MY HEAD OFF.
OKAY.
(thunder crashing)
IT'S JUST THUNDER.
YEAH, WELL,
WHERE THERE'S THUNDER
THERE'S LIGHTNING.
HEY, LOOK,
IF IT STARTS TO RAIN
BEFORE I GET BACK,
ROLL UP THE WINDOWS.
I'D HATE TO RUIN
THE UPHOLSTERY.
DARIC,
BE CAREFUL.
WELL, EVERYTHING'S FINE.
I'M JUST OUT
FOR A FRIENDLY STROLL
IN THE LAND
OF "DELIVERANCE."
(rhythmic knocking)
(knocking continues)
(thunder rumbling)
(flies buzzing)
HELLO?
MR. MERCER?
MY NAME IS DARIC LOMAX.
I'D LIKE TO SPEAK TO YOU
FOR A MOMENT, IF I COULD.
MR. MERCER?
(thunder crashing)
OH MY GOD.
MELISSA!
(metal rattles)
UH, HELLO?
MR. MERCER.
(clears throat)
(door closes)
HELLO?
WHO'S THERE?
(screaming)
CATHY!
CATHY, CALL FOR HELP!
NO!  NO!
(thunder crashing)
Man:
Sorry to keep you
waiting, ma'am.
Sheriff Bullock's
at lunch right now.
Can I take a message?
YEAH.
TELL HIM IF HE DOESN'T
GET UP TO THE MERCER PLACE
AND HELP ME FIND
MY SISTER,
THEN I'M GONNA KICK
HIS FAT ASS ALL THE WAY
DOWN MAIN STREET.
(rain pattering)
HELLO.
MR. MERCER, I'M...
CATHY.
THAT FELLER
WHO WAS UP HERE BEFORE--
HE SAID THAT YOU MIGHT
COME UP
IF HE WAS GONE
TOO LONG.
DARIC.
HE'S NOT HERE?
NO, NOT RIGHT NOW.
UH...
HE WAS LOOKING
FOR HIS GIRLFRIEND
AND I DIDN'T KNOW
NOTHING ABOUT HER.
SO I SENT HIM UP
TO LUTHER'S
SO THAT HE COULD
ASK HIM.
HOW WOULD I GET
TO THIS LUTHER'S?
OH, WELL, FROM HERE
YOU JUST TAKE THAT
LITTLE TRAIL BACK YONDER.
AND IT ONLY TAKES
ABOUT 10 MINUTES
IF YOU DON'T GET LOST.
BUT YOU SHOULDN'T GO
UP THERE NOW,
NOT IN THIS WEATHER.
UH...
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
COME IN
AND WAIT FOR HIM
TO GET BACK?
I COULD MAKE US
SOME COFFEE.
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
(coughs)
OH, I'M SORRY
ABOUT THAT SMELL.
THAT DANG SEPTIC TANK'S
BEEN BACKED UP ALL WEEK.
OH, IT'S OKAY.
SO...
DO YOU KNOW
THAT FELLER'S GIRLFRIEND?
I'M HER SISTER.
SISTER?
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SEE HER PICTURE?
ALL RIGHT.
SHE SURE IS
A PRETTY THING,
JUST LIKE YOU.
HER NAME'S MELISSA--
MELISSA ADAMS.
WE BOTH HAVE--
I DON'T WANT TO KNOW
ALL THAT.
THERE'S YOUR PICTURE BACK.
HOW ABOUT THAT COFFEE?
OH, YEAH.
I'M SORRY.
COMING RIGHT UP.
(Cathy coughing)
I'LL BE THERE
IN A MINUTE.
OKAY.
(flies buzzing)
(coughing)
OH.
HEY.
I WAS GONNA
BRING IT IN THERE.
I DON'T LIKE
BEING ALONE.
OH.
ME NEITHER.
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
OKAY, HERE YOU GO,
ROSALIE.
NOW THIS IS GONNA BE
THE BEST CUP OF COFFEE
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
I PROMISE.
I GUARANTEE IT.
OH.
OH, LORD.
I FORGOT TO PUT
THE COFFEE IN THERE.
I'M SORRY.
I'LL GET IT.
(exclaiming quietly)
ROSALIE.
- (water dripping)
- (panting)
(exclaiming)
(coughing)
(screaming)
(crying)
(coughs)
WELL, THAT DIDN'T
SOUND GOOD.
WHAT THE HELL?
THERE IT IS.
THAT'S OVER
BY KNOB HILL ROAD.
OH, DAMN.
OH, DAMN WHAT?
YOU KNOW THOSE PEOPLE
WHO WERE LOOKING FOR THAT
MISSING GIRL?
I SORT OF TOLD THEM
THAT I THOUGHT
CLIVE MERCER
JUST MIGHT HAVE HER.
- YOU WHAT?
- I TOLD THEM NOT TO GO
OUT THERE WITHOUT YOU.
HOLLIS, YOU DUMBASS,
YOU MIGHT HAVE DONE
GOT SOME PEOPLE KILLED.
HELL, I GOTTA GO
UP THERE NOW.  COME ON.
(Cathy banging, whimpering)
OH, NO NO NO.
(grunts)
(exclaims)
(Cathy screams)
WHY ARE YOU ACTING
THIS WAY, ROSALIE?
(grunts)
WHAT IS WRONG
WITH YOU, ROSALIE?
I'M NOT FUCKING ROSALIE!
NO, NOT YET.
BUT YOU SOON WILL BE.
THIS TIME, ROSALIE,
IT'LL BE BETTER.
I PROMISE.
LUTHER CAN'T HURT YOU
NO MORE.
NOW STOP ALL THIS.
WE'LL BE HAPPY AGAIN SOON,
YOU'LL SEE.
(grunting, panting)
(exclaims)
(grunting)
THAT'S ENOUGH, ROSALIE.
GO TO HELL!
(screams)
YOU SICK FUCK.
(siren wailing)
I ONLY WANT TO MAKE YOU
HAPPY, ROSALIE.
(gunshot)
CLIVE, PUT IT DOWN.
I MEAN WHAT I SAY,
GOD DAMN IT.
I JUST WANT TO START OVER,
IS ALL.
- IT'S NOT WORTH IT.
- CLIVE, DON'T BE A FOOL.
CLIVE, GOD DAMN IT,
I'M NOT SHITTING YOU.
I WILL FUCKING BLOW YOUR
HEAD CLEAN OFF!
I LOVE YOU, ROSALIE.
NO!
(screams)
- (screaming)
- JESUS, GIRL.
(Clive continues screaming)
CAN YOU WALK?
DARIC, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE DEAD.
IT'S OKAY.
I'LL CALL AN AMBULANCE.
SONS OF BITCHIN'
OUT-OF-TOWNERS.
(rock music playing)
MY FACE MAY NOT BE
THE ONE
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR
I'VE GOT THE VOICE
BUT YOU WANT
SOMETHING MORE
NO MEANING LEFT
WHEN THIS IS THROUGH
A PACKAGE SIGNED
AND SEALED BY YOU
BUT I DON'T CARE
'CAUSE I'M STILL
BEATING DOWN YOUR DOOR
I'D GIVE MY SOUL
JUST TO GET A TASTE
OF A WORLD WHERE
TALENT GOES TO WASTE
FOR YOUR
GOLD RECORD GUARANTEE
SO TAKE ME
I'M READY TO LEAVE
MY SENSE OF SHAME
I'M PREPARED
TO PROSTITUTE MY NAME
ALL I ASK IS
15 MINUTES' FAME
SO TAKE ME
I'M WILLING TO SELL
MY SENSE OF WORTH
TO BE BIGGER
THAN ANYTHING ON EARTH
ALL I ASK IS
15 MINUTES' FAME
AND I WILL WEAR
YOUR NOOSE
AROUND MY NECK
I'LL TURN MYSELF INTO
A NERVOUS WRECK
YOU'LL READ ABOUT ME
EVERY DAY
WATCH MY MORALITY
DECAY
RESERVE YOUR JUDGMENT
FOR THE ZEROES
ON YOUR CHECK
I'D GIVE MY SOUL
JUST TO GET A TASTE
OF A WORLD WHERE TALENT
HAS NO PLACE
IN YOUR
GOLD RECORD GUARANTEES
SO TAKE ME
I'M READY TO LEAVE
MY SENSE OF SHAME
I'M PREPARED
TO PROSTITUTE MY NAME
ALL I ASK IS
15 MINUTES' FAME
SO TAKE ME
I'M WILLING TO SELL
MY SENSE OF WORTH
TO BE BIGGER
THAN ANYTHING ON EARTH
ALL I ASK IS
15 MINUTES' FAME
YOU WANT A SUCKER
YOU CAN PLAY
TO MOLD HIS IMAGE
OUT OF CLAY
AND BE YOUR
OVERNIGHT CLICH
WELL, HERE I AM
SO TAKE ME
I'M READY TO LEAVE
MY SENSE OF SHAME
AND PRETEND
THAT YOU RESPECT MY NAME
ALL I ASK IS
15 MINUTES' FAME
SO TAKE ME
I'M WILLING TO SELL
MY SENSE OF WORTH
TO BE BIGGER
THAN ANYTHING ON EARTH
ALL I ASK IS
15 MINUTES' FAME
SO TAKE ME
TAKE ME, TAKE ME
I WANT
MY 15 MINUTES' FAME
TAKE ME.
(instrumental music playing)