Subtitles by DramaFever
[Episode 19]
You do this, and ta da.
What is this?
Are you serious?
Is he crazy?
What are you doing here?
When did you get here?
Who are you?
You don't seem like the doctor in charge.
I'm the doctor in charge
of the patients' rooms.
Yi Ryung looked so bored by herself,
so I took her out for some air.
Oh, and my aunt needed to
go back to the store.
She did?
You're not cold?
She should be okay,
I already gave her my cardigan.
It's not a cold day,
but it's still better to be safe.
Is that what this was for?
Thank you.
Thanks to you, she's warm and I'm warm.
It's very good.
I didn't know you had a brother.
- Oh, that's--
- What brother?
If you mean a close relationship
where we could start dating...
then that is possible.
To simplify it...
she's someone
I'm sort of raising.
We are totally not related
and this could turn into
any kind of relationship.
I thought I saw you somewhere. You're...
If you're a resident right now,
then who is your professor?
Professor Song Ae Joo.
Professor Song.
Professor Song and I work out together.
I wonder if she's still
working out these days.
- Yes, she is.
- I should give her a call.
Since you say you're in charge
of our Yi Ryung
I should find out
what kind of person you are.
That's not very necessary for you to do.
Why?
Maybe you're using
your position as a doctor
to get closer to your patients.
Maybe you're not working
during work hours
and are hanging out with your patients.
Maybe you're not doing your research
and looking into photosynthesizing.
I should find out about all of this.
[High End Crush]
What does it mean
that you're "raising me"?
It's true, I am raising you.
You used to sleep and eat under my roof.
I was there in the
emergency room for you
and I took you
to a patient room.
Then I stayed with you
until your aunt got here.
Don't you think all of this
is equivalent to raising?
You know that all of this
doesn't mean the same thing.
I don't know what you were thinking
but to me, it means the same thing...
- Are you mad?
- Why do you keep asking me that?
You constantly look angry.
Are you annoyed
because I called you so late at night?
- What are you talking about?
- You're not looking at me.
I'm not mad at you.
I like you being dependent on me.
I would have preferred if you didn't
call me just because of the hospital.
What I hate...
is that when I stand in front of you...
I become sensitive and petty.
You don't know anything.
I used to despise girls who were cunning.
I think a little differently these days.
I prefer girls who
actually understand me.
I know exactly what they're thinking.
But I don't have a clue with you.
When can you get discharged?
They're going to run more tests tomorrow
and I'll get discharged the day after.
When is your aunt coming?
She is going to be here tomorrow again.
But my fever went down
and I'm not that sick anymore
so she doesn't necessarily need to come.
Until then...
don't talk to him even if you're bored.
What?
He likes you.
He has other intentions...
and he might take it the wrong way
if you keep talking to him.
What are you talking about?
He's just a doctor.
Are doctors not men?
Can you just listen to me when I talk?
You have to say things that make sense
in order for me to listen!
Why would he like me when
we just met today for the first time?
I don't know what the reason is
but it only takes two seconds
to decide if you like a person or not!
Just because you're like that,
is everyone else the same way?
Yes, everyone is like that.
Everyone does that!
What do you know about men?
You don't know anything.
Men are humans too,
what wouldn't I know?
We're all the same.
You don't even know what my feelings are.
So how do you feel?
These are my feelings towards you.
I told you.
I did this much...
You're still going to act
like you don't know?
Do you want me to
wet some towels for you?
It's okay.
What are you doing?
Aren't you going to work?
Are you okay?
I actually feel better.
Since you did everything you could,
you shouldn't have many regrets.
You got smacked by the girl you like,
risked your life hiking
provided her with a house,
bought her flowers, dinner, and clothes.
You tried to make her jealous,
you went to visit her in the hospital
and you still try
to hold on to her dearly.
You don't even need to really date her.
You did everything you could
for two people who didn't even date.
This is the most high end crush
that I've ever seen.
Perfect!
I can even feel
the difference in class...
It's high end, it's perfect,
and unbelievable!
I just can't believe it!
I'm awed by your innocent feelings.
Jeez!
Are you done?
Are you sure you don't have
anything else to say?
You're going to do more?
People don't do more than this.
They do what they can,
then stop around here.
Why? Because not everyone climbs up
to the top of Mount Everest.
You did this much,
I doubt anyone saw that coming.
Oh, seriously!
You just need to sign one more thing.
Get out.
Control your temper.
There is nothing we can do
since the hospital bill was already paid.
We can take care of it
if you bring in the person
who paid for the bill but...
[CEO Choi Sae Hoon]
No, no, no, no.
Hello, this is Yoo Yi Ryung.
I'm getting discharged today,
and regarding the hospital bills...
Hello?
Why don't you call me?
Who is she?
She's good.
She's a new singer.
Choi Sae Hoon is definitely good.
I wasn't too sure
if it would work, but it did!
Oh, this guy!
I'm going to get her
no matter what.
How is Choi Sae Hoon these days?
There are no words about him
signing a contract with her.
Do you think he might have given up?
No, that's not possible.
He's the type to never give up.
It's better for us...
because if we bring her in...
Choi Sae Hoon will die from
his aggravation.
What's wrong? What happened, huh?
Drink this.
I broke up with my boyfriend.
You had a boyfriend?
Who doesn't have a boyfriend these days?
He said he can't trust me.
He said he doesn't even know
if I like him or not.
He's crazy, how would he know how I feel?
He should just believe me
when I say I do.
It's not easy saying that to someone.
Because I like you.
You just need to give me a chance.
He's asking me why I like him
when he's just average.
How would I know
how things ended up this way?
I didn't want it to end this way,
but it already happened, what can I do?
These are my feelings towards you.
I did this much...
You're still going to act
like you don't know?
He's saying I'm too much for him.
I'm so speechless.
If that's so, he should be
thankful and good to me.
But instead, he breaks up with me?
If by any chance...
any slightest, slightest chance,
I like you...
then it's like winning the lotto for you!
It's better than winning
the lotto 10 times!
You're very pretty,
I can understand why he's doing this.
He said we are too different.
There are no two people
who are exactly alike in this world!
He used to say that we had so many
things in common in the beginning.
He said all that just to hit on me.
I think people recognize you.
Wipe off your tears.
How can they
when I'm crying with my hat on?
They recognize you.
Me?
You keep running away
from the shoot, right?
Did something happen between you two?
Do you want me to give you a ride?
No.
Are you still sick...
You look fine now. I'm glad.
Thanks to you.
Oh, the hospital bill...
I have to go.
Take care of yourself.
You still look a little sick.
What do you want to do?
Think about it.
I like you...
and I don't think I'll change...
at least for now. No...
I don't think I can change.
At least for now?
You don't expect me to like you
for the rest of my life, right?
I might.
But if you tell me
that you don't like me...
then I'm going to try
not to be like this.
I can't wait too long,
so think about it quickly.
If you want to do this,
then you come to me.
If it's possible...
the earlier, the better.
Subtitles by DramaFever
[High End Crush]
An article came up, an article!
If I can't have her,
then I'm going to break her!
I think he is trying to lower
our company's image.
Big news! Big news!
Our CEO is involved in a scandal.
What? They weren't able to stop it?
Did you know
that our CEO is going to China?
I heard that he's not going to be
back for a while.
Why is he so impatient?
What are you doing?
I don't know how this happened...
I think I like you.