Please have pity.
In the name of God.
You idiot!
Come out or we'll kill you all!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
We're Ossetian!
We are friends!
This is all they had on them.
We found a second camera in the car.
I can make the women talk.
You will not touch my daughters!
They are Ossetians like me.
We are like you.
I am a Cossack, old man.
And the next time
you raise your voice at me,
I will cut you open
while your daughters watch.
Daniil. Daniil...
Take the father first.
No, you can't do this!
If there is a video recording,
we have to find it.
We don't need a PR nightmare
like the Americans in Iraq.
Don't worry, we'll find it.
Sir, we just received word that
the second invasion front has launched.
Good.
They already know everything.
Where is the recording? Tell me!
Tatia, do not play games with me!
These men may be Ossetians,
but they will not wait forever.
May I begin, Colonel?
Hold on.
We must think of ourselves now.
Not two strangers!
You think they wouldn't leave us?
They will abandon us like the world has!
Tatia, tell me where the recording is?
We can use them as shields!
Tatia!
No, I can't trust you.
Tatia, I'm your father...
They need my help.
No. You'll be safer with your friends.
Medic!
- Are you okay?
- It's nothing... just my arm.
Medic I said!
Get them!
Get the vehicles started!
That guy's crazy.
You're abandoning your post?
By order of the President.
All troops are to fall back
and report to defend Tbilisi.
Gori is going to fall.
I'm sorry. I have my orders.
Friendlies!
Hold your fire!
Have you seen ground troops?
Hear that?
Defensive positions!
Move out!
Don't resist, Captain.
Sir, they're not resisting.
My husband, Mikheil Taboshvili.
Killed in Eredvi village.
My father.
My mother-in-law, Natalia Okropiridze.
My mother, Natalia Okropiridze.
As my parents were being evacuated
and they were crossing the road,
a mine exploded in front of their car and
shrapnel hit her straight in the temple.
She died on the spot.
Zambakhidze Tamar, my mother.
My wife.
Our grandmother.
My parents were tortured.
Their throats were slit.
They were buried in our backyard,
and that's all we know.
This is Nodar Otiashvili, my father.
We used to live
in Kvemo Achabeti village.
I am the son of Socrate Gogidze.
I was told by the Red Cross
that he was buried in our garden.
He had been hanged.
I am Marina Kakhbiashvili.
I used to live in Kehvi village.
On August 8th, we left.
My husband stayed there.
My son and my husband.
My son left that night.
My husband stayed in the house.
Ekaterine Papelishvili, my grandmother.
Subs made by Paul C