I don't know much...
But this much I do know.
You often think you're alive...
when you're actually dead.
Life, real life...
You only find out what it is
when you've lived it to the fullest.
It's time, Léo dear.
- Hey! Easy!
- Sorry.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Are you warm enough?
- It's summer, Maryse.
- They said it'd be cool today.
- Bye.
Ms. Ventura's office.
No problem.
Everything's fine.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Yes, I'm meeting him tomorrow
with the new plans.
Léo?
The Le Bic Park DVD?
It's on its way.
It should be there this afternoon.
Everything is ready, Madam Mayor.
I'm sending you my best man.
Chuck Émond.
No, she's on the phone.
Can I help you?
What?
His wife is going nuts.
She hasn't heard from him
since yesterday!
He'd better not be
having another breakdown,
because this one
will be his last!
Did you try his cottage?
No answer.
Find him!
I want him at Le Bic tomorrow!
If he ever shows up,
everything is in there.
Except the mayor's envelope.
Forget it.
We're calling off the meeting.
What a crazy day!
Fix me a drink
before you leave.
My good little Léo...
Always there for me.
Olive or lemon?
Leave that, would you?
We're both so tense.
It'll do us good.
I could go.
- Where?
- Le Bic.
Instead of Chuck.
I did the legwork.
I know the file from A to Z.
Funny, you look
like you mean it!
I could use
a change of scenery.
I guess all you'd have to do
is go, do the pitch,
and you're back the next day.
You'll take my car.
What was Ms. Ventura thinking?
Throwing you to the lions
like that!
It was my idea.
And you're telling me now?
Right before you leave?
I didn't want to talk about it
all night.
This is insane,
if you ask me!
Enough already.
I'll be back tomorrow night.
I left my number on the fridge.
Bye.
I'm telling you, Léo,
this feels wrong!
Call Ms. Ventura back.
Tell her you don't feel well.
Take the day off.
I'll pamper you!
The mayor called the meeting
specifically for our project.
They're expecting me.
You? Talking to all of them?
You can barely
put two words together!
You'll make a fool of yourself!
Léo? What was that?
- I have to go.
- No!
We need help,
if you don't mind.
Shit!
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hi.
It's useless.
The tire's completely blown out.
And no spare?
There's a garage nearby.
Give us a ride?
Yeah, sure.
I'm Léo.
Léo Huff.
Lou.
And this is Roch.
Not from around here?
No.
- Quebec City?
- Montreal.
What's your line of work?
I'm an engineer.
I'm making a presentation
at Le Bic tonight.
A big project
to help the area.
What would we do
without you Montreal folk?
He was born with a smile
plastered on his face!
This is the first time
I've been here. It's...
Beautiful. Really beautiful.
Take the next left.
There will be spinoffs
of tens of millions of dollars.
Tens... of millions...
of dollars...
We're talking 110 full-time jobs
and 125 part-time jobs.
And... that's not it.
Yes, that is it.
Believe in yourself.
We're talking 110 full-time jobs
and 125 part-time jobs.
Simulated-
- Mr. Huff?
- Yes.
Pauline Courchesne.
Delighted.
- Did you have a nice trip?
- Yes, very nice.
Ready for tonight?
No choice.
Ah. Right.
Here.
Thank you.
Ms. Ventura said that a thicker one
will follow if it all goes through.
- See you tonight.
In addition to promoting
good family fun,
the project promises to be
very lucrative for your community.
We expect to see
about 100,000 visitors
the first year.
And that's a conservative figure.
We have a simulated image
to give you a better idea.
This is the bay right now.
Yes, it's beautiful.
And this is AquaBic Park.
Notice the green waterslides
that blend in
with the environment.
The entire ecosystem
will be screwed!
Think of the jobs!
250 jobs!
It's not like
we don't need them!
Like the 150 Calswell jobs?
We don't want his crap!
Easy for you to say!
You have a job!
They won't lay their concrete here!
Over my dead body!
Please...
Go back to Montreal
with your stupid waterslides!
Put them on Mount Royal!
Shove them up your ass!
Yeah! Yeah!
It's always the same bunch,
the same sorry bunch
that come to whine.
It's like they have
nothing better to do.
But most people understand
that we're here
to make the right decisions.
Seems like their minds are made up!
In the 15 years I've been mayor,
there hasn't been a single project
I wanted to pass
that hasn't gone through.
Tell that to Ms. Ventura.
Good night.
FUCK OFF POLLUTER
Have you at least been there?
I'm sorry?
To Le Bic Park.
Have you gone?
I saw it in the distance
when I drove in.
It's not the same from far away.
You have to lose yourself in it
to understand.
Roch and I go...
used to go at night all the time.
To smoke and relax...
Sometimes until the sun came up.
Don't you think some things
are so beautiful...
they shouldn't be touched?
I don't know.
How much is this baby worth?
$70,000? $80,000?
Something like that.
Will the waterslides...
pay for next year's model?
Is there a lighter in here?
I don't know. I don't smoke.
Yeah, as long as you're loaded,
you might as well stay healthy.
Married, settled,
big house,
winters in Florida?
Do I look that boring?
You want a ride?
I'd be happy...
Shit!
- What?
- He's going to kill me!
What's wrong?
You're not out hunting?
Get in the truck!
Shut up, you fucking big shot!
We were just talking!
It's true.
We were only talking!
What did I say?
Mind your goddamn business!
So you like talking?
- You like talking?
- You're hurting me!
- Right!
- Stop!
I didn't do anything!
Jesus Christ!
Take your clothes off!
Fuck! Take your
goddamn panties off!
There was something
between the two of you!
Nothing would've happened!
I saw you looking at him.
Something was going on
there. Admit it!
You know you're the one I love.
Christ!
See this ass?
Who does this ass belong to?
It's yours.
And who do these
little tits belong to?
They're yours.
And this, you slut?
Whose is this?
You're hurting me!
There!
There! You like that?
You fucking like that? Goddamn!
Fuck!
Fuck! Jesus!
You should be OKfor a while now!
I can't fucking believe it.
I'll be gone hunting
for three days.
Don't leave the house.
Not even for milk.
Understand?
- Understand?
- Yes...
Hello?
I've left you a dozen messages.
You're not returning my calls?
Well, I finished late and...
Where are you?
At the motel.
I'm asleep. I mean, I was asleep.
The car is in the room?
No, I'm parked outside the motel.
I fell asleep in the car.
The presentation wiped me out.
How did it go?
Léo? Are you there?
Yes, I'm here.
Good, listen...
Sorry, I didn't want to bother you.
It's just that...
When I saw you before...
When I saw you before
with that guy,
I was worried.
I shouldn't have come.
It's my office.
I should take it.
Have a seat.
Thanks.
That's pretty strong lemonade!
If you don't like vodka,
I can fix it for you.
What do engineers drink?
No, this is fine.
How can you breathe like that?
Earlier on,
you saw us?
Yes.
A little.
Be honest.
Did you come here to save me
or screw me?
Because I've had enough of guys
trying to get into my pants!
OK, fine.
I think I'll go.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to make sure
you weren't like the others.
Really, I have to go.
When I saw you
on the side of the road,
I don't know why,
but I knew I could trust you.
You seem like a good guy.
You don't mind eating from the pot?
No, it's fine.
What are you doing with that guy?
My mother met him a while back.
She brought him here.
At one point, she caught him
making a pass at me.
She got jealous and took off.
Roch stuck around.
For three days, it was wonderful.
We only got out of bed to eat.
It's when we left the house
that things went bad.
If I even looked
at another man, pow!
And it's only gotten worse.
You have to do something.
Call the police.
I take care of my own problems.
And you?
Yourwife?
Maryse.
Any kids?
If she knew you were here,
wouldn't she freak?
Yes, she would freak!
- Can you play?
- Yes, but it's out of tune.
That doesn't matter!
Come on, play something!
No, I never play
in front of other people.
Come on! Please!
It's out of tune.
Completely.
Want some breakfast?
I think I should go.
Is there a law that says so?
You can go back anytime!
You're the boss, right?
Yes...
You are coming back today, Léo.
No, I'd rather not drive.
I don't feel well.
I can't get along on my own.
I need you!
I don't feel up to it.
Hey, what's going on?
COTTAGE FOR RENT
What are you doing here?
I thought I'd park my car here
in case someone drove by.
You broke the lock?
No, the wood was rotted away.
I barely touched it.
What's wrong?
This is how it started with Roch.
He started going through my stuff.
If we can't trust each other,
I'd rather you leave now.
Lou?
I borrowed some shampoo.
For supper,
I was thinking ravioli
or ravioli... or maybe ravioli.
I'm sorry for before.
It's a bit spicy!
Oh yeah?
So?
You're not sorry you stayed?
You mean me?
I like being with you, Léo.
I like being with you, too.
Sorry...
I think I'm a little tipsy!
I'm scared, Léo.
Like, really scared.
You have no idea!
He'll never lay
another hand on you. I swear.
I won't let him.
That's not what scares me.
I'm... I'm afraid
of what I'm going do to him...
when he gets back.
The son of a bitch!
If you do that,
it'll stay with you
for the rest of your life.
I'm in a whole lot of trouble.
I'd understand
if you wanted to leave.
Where do you want me to go?
There's nowhere in the world
I'd rather be at this moment.
I'd like to give you a present.
Go get your car keys.
Not even a hint?
No.
You're beautiful.
You're cheating!
Don't peek.
- Are we almost there?
- Yes.
I don't know you.
What if you're crazy?
You could throw me into a ditch...
All you'd have to do
is keep hold of my hand.
OK... don't move.
It'll be all right.
Trust me.
Get your stuff
and come with me!
It wouldn't do any good.
We have a day's head start.
He'd find me.
He wouldn't give up.
We could go far away.
Very far.
We could cross the border,
if you want.
Lou...
I'll give up everything.
Léo...
I have one bullet left.
You want it in the face
or in the balls?
- Listen, let's talk.
- Shut up!
Want to kiss his dick before
I splatter it all over the wall?
Roch... please don't!
Let him go!
It's my fault! Mine!
It's yourfault, for sure!
Fuck!
Now, let me take care of this, OK?
OK, damn it!
- Hi!
- Hi.
Have you heard about
what they plan to build
at Le Bic Park?
Yes.
Abunch of us
are fighting the project.
We have a petition.
You're a fast one!
Michelle.
What a lovely name!
- Are you from here?
- Yes.
My name is Francis Fradette.
My friends call me Frenchie.
Move your foot, Frenchie!
- Are you busy tonight?
- I'm in a bit of a hurry.
We're getting together later
at the church hall.
- Please move your foot.
- Want to join us?
Yourfoot!
There'll be wine and cheese.
Will you move
your goddamn foot?
Nobody talks to you like that!
I can't take it anymore!
Don't you get it?
You bang that one all night long,
and this asshole
asks you out for cheese!
Did you French him?
I did what had to be done.
Be grateful!
- Did he get a blow job?
- Cut it out!
The blow job wasn't necessary!
We have one guy dead outside
and anotherwho's about to come to!
There was something
between you two!
Let's get going!
You never call me "cute"!
Enough!
You have no idea
how much I love you.
If you love me, be a man
and get your ass in gear!
You slept with her,
you prick!
Untie me, please.
Did you sleep with her?
Answer me or I'll cut it off!
No, I didn't.
I swear!
I've always loved the smell of gas!
How about you?
OK, all right!
I... I touched her.
A little.
What did you do?
What do you mean?
It was really fast!
Ablow job?
What?
I kiss that bitch.
I need to know
what she puts in her mouth. Fuck!
No!
Listen...
I'll leave.
I'll never see her again.
I swear. I'll never come back.
No, Lou's not the kind of girl
you can forget.
After Lou,
there's no going back.
No, not for me.
She won't be it for me.
You're tied up.
You reek of gasoline.
And you just did my girl.
Believe me, you'd rather eat
a plate full of shit
than take what's coming next.
What are you doing? No!
No! Don't do that!
Listen! Stop!
I'll tell you everything...
I'm going to see to
our little princess.
Then I promise
we're going to have some fun!
- Léo?
- Lou!
Oh my God! I was so scared!
I thought he killed you!
- What's going on?
- I knocked him out.
No! Untie my hands first.
When he came back upstairs,
he was out of his mind!
Are you all right?
The gun.
Let go of her!
OK, boss!
Go ahead!
Fucking clown!
Before you use it...
Stop, Roch, please!
You shut up!
Or I'll scalp you!
Hands off her, motherfucker!
Well, well.
The engineer has grown a pair!
Hands off her, I said.
Go ahead. Show her
how much of a man you are!
Aim here and shoot!
Go ahead!
Is that what you want?
Afucking pussy
who can't even defend you?
Fuck you!
Léo...
Fuck!
Let's stay calm.
Keep cool.
Look at me.
What's done is done.
There's no turning back.
We have to call the police.
That's not an option
for a girl like me.
We have to get rid of the body.
We'll throw him in the river.
Give me the gun.
Are you OK?
Bring your car
to the back door.
Open the trunk.
No more of this.
OK, help me
get him out of here.
We didn't have any choice.
It was him or us.
Exactly.
That's good.
We've gone far enough!
We have to go back after!
We'll vanish, just the two of us.
Without a trace.
And start again somewhere else.
Every day will be perfect.
Every single day.
It won't be that easy.
- We need money.
- I have money.
- Yourwife? Your job?
- I'll do what I have to do.
I can make it happen.
I don't want to hang around here.
I've got a bad feeling.
I just need a little time.
- How much time?
- Alittle.
- Christ! It's the engineer!
- It's the engineer!
- Bastard!
- Go home!
- Screw off!
- Go away!
Hello.
Sit down.
I prefer to stand,
if that's OK.
Sit down!
Who do you think you are?
I leave you tons of messages.
You hang up on me.
And then not a word!
Things are piling up
at the office.
What happened?
I...
You what?
I met someone.
Awoman.
Did she do that to you?
Yeah.
Well, your nose
is pretty clean, so I guess
I can let this one go.
But we have to make up
for lost time.
Why do you want to ruin Le Bic?
Have you ever been there?
Do you know how beautiful it is?
If this is how
you pitched the project...
I'm not coming back to work.
- What do you mean?
- I quit.
Hold on!
My keys?
This is my fault.
I shouldn't have sent you there.
You're stressed out.
You're exhausted.
No, actually, I feel fantastic.
Come on, this isn't you!
Take a few days...
Relax. We'll talk about it later.
You've known this woman
for how long?
Three days?
Yes.
After 22 years?
There's nothing left, Maryse,
except our old habits.
I love our old habits!
I love you!
Léo, there'll be a draft!
Crazy trip! What was she thinking,
sending you there?
I'll never thank her enough.
It's her!
That's what it is!
Ms. Ventura...
I guess I knew it all along!
No, stop it.
The way she looks at you!
Maryse... I quit my job.
I'm not going back to work.
I don't understand.
There's nothing to understand.
I just can't do this anymore!
How am I going to get along
without you?
And you? Without me?
Without your job?
Think about it for two minutes.
How are we going to live?
Oh, I don't feel good.
Not good at all!
You're tired. It's late...
I'll give you your shot
and you can go to bed.
How am I supposed to sleep?
I'll give you
a little something.
I think I can scrape together
$125,000 or $150,000.
That won't last long.
Think of your lifestyle.
All the nice things you have.
With you, I'd leave
with $10 in my pocket!
Wait until two years from now
when we're broke.
I won't be
anywhere near as cute then.
There's anotherway,
but it's complicated.
I can't stay here.
I'll go crazy!
I feel like the cops
will show up any minute!
Getting that much money
together isn't easy.
Try harder, Léo!
A guy like you has clout!
I want it to work out for us.
I want to put all the chances
on our side.
Me too.
The power of attorney
is only for your joint account.
Your wife has to sign
for the rest.
We've known each otherfor ages.
She's really
under the weather these days.
I'd like to avoid
making her go out.
I'll do something for you.
I'll give you all this
and you have her sign it at home.
For our good customers,
we can always find a way
to work things out!
Thank you.
Have a good day!
Don't you find it
small in here sometimes?
Sit down.
It's time for
a serious heart-to-heart, Léo.
We want to know what happened
at Le Bic.
I told you.
Like you told me
about the woman you met there?
I'm ready to forgive you.
I think...
All I want is the truth.
- Is there anything else?
- Yes, there's something else.
I had my carwashed.
They found this in the front seat.
- I went hunting.
- Hunting? Right!
You're against hunting!
Léo, that's enough...
You want the whole truth?
Yes.
I'm warning you:
I won't hold back.
We'll sit down over a coffee,
and I'll tell Maryse everything.
Everything.
Tell me what?
What's going on?
I'm in trouble, Maryse.
- Shouldn't you go to the police?
- No.
Definitely not.
I need money.
I need a lot of money.
I don't know
where that bullet came from,
but there's one thing I do know:
You're not playing me
for the fool anymore!
And you won't get your hands
on our savings.
Tomorrow morning, first thing,
I'm calling the bank.
It's my money.
I'm the one who earned it!
It's no more yours than mine.
And it's definitely not
your little whore's!
I just want half!
My half!
Not in my lifetime!
You won't get a penny!
You've lost yourway,
my poor little Léo.
You're living in a bubble.
And when it bursts,
you'll have nothing.
I'm defrosting a pork roast
for supper.
I'm cooking it in milk,
just the way you like.
In case you're interested.
That's my job.
I don't want
to talk about it ever again.
Things will get back to normal.
Go get ready.
I'll be right there.
Life isn't perfect, you know.
You have to make do.
And appreciate what you've got.
That's the problem, really.
We're happy.
We just don't know it.
What's taking so long?
I'm listening to you.
You know what I'd like now?
I'd like you
to play the piano for me.
Actually, I thought
I'd go to the bakery...
Some pastries
after supperwould be nice...
When you get back then.
Are you all right?
Yeah!
Incredible! You can put
almost anything in poutine!
Chicken, barbecue sauce,
Italian sausage...
- How about shrimp?
- I've never heard of that.
We've prepared a report
on poutine just for you.
It's fascinating how big a role
poutine plays in our lives.
The bullets!
They weren't real!
What are you talking about?
It's so far-fetched.
I don't know how I fell for it!
Calm down, Léo.
Put Roch on so I can
tell him off in person!
OK, yes, I conned you.
But it's not what you think.
The plan was to blackmail you.
You raped me.
Roch caught you.
You shot him.
That was the story.
Are you done laughing at me?
The scratches on yourface.
Your semen in my underwear.
Yourfingerprints on the gun.
You were done for!
Except...
After the time we spent together...
the night at Le Bic...
I couldn't go through with it.
All of it
was Roch's idea.
I had no choice!
Do you understand?
He's lost it completely!
The guy we threw into the river...
he killed him.
This poor guy
who was going door to door!
I don't know what to do...
Do you realize
what I've done for you?
Fuck!
He knows they weren't real.
Why did you change the plan?
I warned you not to!
I told you we had to make
the son of a bitch pay!
Don't panic, goddamn it!
He won't turn his back on me.
He's in love.
Maryse?
Léo, is that you?
Can you talk?
He's in the shower.
There's no turning back now.
I have to see you.
Except no more bullshit.
I lied to you, too.
I'm not...
I'm not an engineer.
I'm a secretary.
The Mercedes isn't mine.
It belongs to my boss.
I make $36,000 a year.
I live in a tiny bungalow
in the city.
$153,000 is all I have.
It's not a fortune,
but we can live on it for a while.
The days I spent with you...
were the best days of my life.
Do you love him?
Do you want-
That's all that matters to me.
No, I don't love him.
Do you think that we...
I don't know, Léo. Maybe.
I have something
I want you to hear.
It's for you.
Just listen, please.
Stupid shit!
It's him!
Do you think I don't know?
We were talking cash!
Don't bullshit me.
You don't love me.
You used me.
I had to tell him something.
Just look at yourself.
You're all torn up.
He's getting to you,
the son of a bitch!
I love you!
Don't you get it?
Lou?
I have a plan.
I have a plan, too,
you motherfucker!
I want $250,000,
not a penny less,
by tomorrow.
Or a certain somebody
gets hurt
real fucking bad!
And then it'll be your turn!
I love you, too.
You know how late it is?
It's important.
Are you going on a trip?
I need money.
$100,000.
Small bills or big bills,
Léo, dear?
Twenties.
For tomorrow morning.
No way.
But you send those envelopes
to the mayor...
and others, too.
That's my business.
If that got out,
it wouldn't be good for the project.
Are you threatening me?
Call it what you like.
Your timing is bad. Poor you.
The mayor called.
Her nephew has disappeared.
He was going door to door
with a petition against the project.
It's too controversial now.
I'm not touching it.
Listen...
Tell me what's wrong,
and I'll handle it.
You're not handling anything.
All you have to do
is give me the money I'm asking for.
The woman I met is in trouble.
She needs me.
And I don't?
Get out!
I never want to see you again!
Lou?
Roch?
Put the shovel down!
I have the money.
But not on me.
You won't get a penny
until I see Lou.
You should know
the bullets are real this time.
The door!
Come on out, Princess!
There she is.
Now, hand over the money.
It's at Le Bic.
In the park.
Let's go then!
When we get there, you get some of
the cash, but not all.
He's a riot,
this dickhead of yours!
You get the rest once you let us go.
Fuck you, you asshole!
What are you going to do?
You going to shoot me?
Go ahead!
Flush your $250,000 away!
Stop, you fucking psycho!
Why?
I'm having fun!
Stop or I'm turning
into the ditch, I swear!
Don't move!
Give me all the cash.
Not a penny less,
or she's a goner.
Right, my little slut?
- Is it much farther?
- Just a little.
Get out!
Get out.
Don't move!
Come back,
you fucking bitch!
That's enough...
I know a spot
near the ocean in Maine...
I thought for a couple of days...
You were ready to let him leave
with all that?
I want us to be together.
What would we have done
without any money?
We would've lived on love
and fresh water.
And the $50,000
I hid in my spare tire.
We're free!
Do you know what that's worth?
Everything is perfect!
So perfect.
I'm like you, Léo.
I want to be happy, too!
Forget Maine.
Look around here.
It's so beautiful...
It's heaven, Léo...
And it's yours.
All yours.
We're going to pray hard
for it to stay the way it is.
Yes, I know.
I don't look
like much right now.
But I've lived.
Really lived.
True, not for very long.
But I've lived.
Subtitles by Shonda Secord
Processing by Vision Globale