www.titlovi.com
You should be in bed.
-I do not sleep.
What are you doing?
I'm not sure yet.
Them.
Go to sleep now. -But ...
Jacob!
In autumn 2005, consisted of
between six foreign liaison
police "cooks" designated
by the terrible events.
This is their story.
Going somewhere?
I need to go to the patient.
I will be late.
Father, menemmehän game tomorrow?
-Absolutely.
But the conditions are these:
You must be well-behaved
and do as mother says.
We'll see.
....
This man has changed lives, often
in a better direction.
Ladies and gentlemen, may I introduce
my good friend Robert Moretti.
I will be brief, that we're
drinking and eating.
Times are tough for many, and
many of us going so well.
We want to see them or not,
they are everywhere.
Today I ask you, which you have paid one thousand U.S.
dollars Dinner
think about what
else you can do.
Do not forget the rest of the world
just because you're doing well.
Hopefully you are hungry, because
this is an expensive dinner.
Free yourself Start a new life
Hey, Sofia.
What are you still doing here?
I was hoping that we could talk.
-Okay, sit down.
I meant somewhere else.
-You can offer me a drink.
Okay, let's go for a drink.
Say you get married and
return to Italy.
They came to visit yesterday.
Two people.
Why do not you?
-I know you better than anyone.
Answer the question.
They want me to prove that you were under
the influence while shooting him.
It's funny.
I pulled you into this hell,
and now do you get me out.
I'm not going just for this work you out.
I do not intend to prove.
When you have seen such things which I, begins
to live according to their own rules.
You can not take the law into your own hands.
-It 's over, Sofia. I'm gone.
At my age a man starts
to look back-
and the purpose of looking for something,
something to be proud of ...
I have looked behind me, and
I do not see anything.
I see only darkness
and ugliness.
When I moved here from Italy, I left everything behind.
Do you understand?
You can still change things.
There is no place where to escape
from what I have become, Sofia.
Hello.
What has happened?
A car accident.
Parents and two daughters.
The oldest and parents died,
The youngest is paralyzed from the neck down.
He is in room 309
I can stay to keep an eye
on him if you want.
You look exhausted. Go home.
Sorry. It went a bit violent.
That probably covers it.
Have we're even?
Do you understand?
Have we're even? -Yeah.
Where? -Home.
Thirteen.
Over.
Seventeen.
Twenty.
Sometimes, when luck is not on my side,
it could be switched to finish.
Does not involve luck.
Vodka, please.
Thank you.
Not to worry.
Wake up now.
All is well.
Nothing to worry about.
What's going on?
Where am I? -We do not know.
Who are you?
How long have you been here.
We do not know.
We woke up just like you.
-Who brought us here?
It is trying to figure out.
Why so much effort to see
kaappaamiseksemme?
Here you must be a way out.
We have tried everything.
Here is not no way out.
Hey, baby. I'll handle this.
I'll do you get out of here.
Everything will be okay.
Not organized.
It's time.
You must follow me.
This way.
Be careful.
Sit down.
Listen. Listen to this moment.
I just need a minute
of your time.
You do not need to do this.
I would like to cooperate.
Do you understand?
You you're doing.
It is going very well.
At peace now.
Follow me.
Open it.
Pick up the dice.
What is this? Noppa-six pages.
You let fate decide
Robert's life.
I can not do it.
You, if anyone can.
Roll the dice.
If you do not act, he will die without
the opportunity to be reborn.
Now you understand.
Roll the dice.
What came from?
This is your game.
-This is not a game.
Do not be tricky.
Put a bullet in the gun.
Listen.
We can agree on something.
I have a lot of money.
This is not about the money.
He dies within five seconds.
Five. Four.
We can agree on something.
Three.
His life is in your hands, Mark.
Two.
Next hits him on the head.
Two wasted opportunity to save him.
It was stupid.
Yes or no?
I'll do it. -Do it.
You can do it. One occasion.
Do it!
Seems to suicide.
Robert Moretti.
The gun was in his hand.
He founded varankeruuohjelman victims of the recession.
Billionaire.
Dressed up as a beggar in front of his own house.
A devilish way to
send a message.
Press falls for this.
Speaking of the boss wants to press
the body away before entry.
You would not be able to do anything.
It's not your fault.
How does it change the fact that
I shot their brains on the wall?
He knows her. -What do you mean?
Recognized him when
you saw his face.
If you know something, say it.
I do not know him!
I do not know who he is, who you are,
or what the hell are we doing here.
I just want to ...
There is no place where to escape
from what I have become, Sofia.
Tomorrow you go to work ...
... You call them and
tell the truth.
That's it. Lorun end.
It is God's will.
Go away.
-You can still change things.
What are you doing here still? Go to sleep.
-I have to go to the morgue.
He shot himself, that's it.
We already have enough to do.
Mark here.
Leave a message, I'll call back.
Did you find anything? -Kind of.
I have looked at a head injury.
Angle of the bullet
does not match.
The bullet went in here, went
down and came out here.
Set would have had to hold it.
Possible but not likely.
I think someone else
shot higher.
How about this?
Small burns.
Strange ... It is also this one.
What is it?
, Came before the shooting.
Maybe he defended himself? -I doubt it.
No signs of struggle.
And no sniper osaisi to clean and stitch the wound.
Why bother?
To make this appear to suicide.
Then, head trauma is a
better proof of that.
Could you write a report? -Sure.
FATHER'S FOLDER
I told you to go home.
Come with me.
He can not very well.
You gotta see it.
Not ... -Open the box.
They are not for you.
I do not touch them,
you sick bastard.
Ingredients are easy to find:
Pseudoephedrine, iodine, red
phosphorus matchbox ...
Sure, you know.
Junkie used the dose may be
as high as 10 milligrams.
If you throw one, he gets 10 mg.
If you roll a six ...
... He gets 60 mg.
Put in our bodies almost by
just to keep us alive.
Melody's body has struggled so much
that he will probably take 50 mg.
But you ...
He hardly takes more than 30 mg.
Show your arm.
Show him how it feels
to grow without love.
A wasted life, neglected,
forgotten, and the ugly.
All of which were rejected
by the love for him.
So damaged that she had poisoned
herself to feel alive.
If your mother could see you now, do
you think he finally care about?
Sometimes we have more in common
with foreigners than we think.
Throw noppaa.Anna her new life.
-Do not do it.
For 10 seconds of time.
Ten. Nine. Eight.
Seven. Six. Five.
Four.
Three.
Two. -Excuse me.
Your body is fighting
to keep you alive.
It is the darkest truths that must
be close to death, saved.
Così ho tanto amore ... Fri te.
I told you to go home.
Torrential evening?
The worst of my life.
What were playing? -Blackjack.
You would have tried the dice.
-I do not play dice.
Statistically, the blackjack is the only
game in which players have a good seam.
There are three types of lies:
Vale, whacking lie ...
-... And statistics.
How many lost?
More than I could afford.
I have a suggestion.
You believe in statistics
and probabilities,
and I believe in destiny.
I suggest that this time you
let fate be resolved.
Odd I win.
You have to make one, three,
or five things that I ask.
An even you win.
For two, four or six
thousand dollars.
You're not serious.
-Death serious.
One, three, or five things ...
What kind of things?
I do not know yet.
Do you leave things often
in the hands of fate?
You will not guess at all.
Play.
You lost. -You win.
You do not need to give money.
Dice will not resist.
I can not take them.
Go home, Lisa.
Go home.
Six thousand chips, thank you.
Zach!
-What are you doing
here, Claire?
I need some stuff now. Now.
I am not a drug dealer, Claire.
-You are a psychiatrist.
Recipe should be enough
for at least a month.
Did you take your kids in?
-Who weakling vahtisi
at this time?
Clear. Calm down now.
I want what you have at home.
Wait in the car.
I will bring it there.
He is hungry.
Promise me you will not take them before you get home.
They are very strong.
Claire!
Survive this, I promise.
Stay awake.
You need to stay awake.
Do not touch me!
Let her go!
You. Your turn.
Do not do this.
I can help you. Seriously.
The same way as for
helping to Claire?
What's happening here?
Who are you?
-Would, if I had a name?
I certainly would like
to tuoliisi analysis.
You will kill me before
I do anything to him.
He died.
Claire.
Her child was crying for 12
hours before someone heard.
Exactly.
Such you have become.
Would you like to save the Melody?
This is your chance.
I ...
I tried to save them, but ...
... I could not help everyone.
-I know how you feel.
Lets see how successful now.
Give a little, so you may save them.
Too much, so they die.
The difference is that
this time fate decide.
It is much safer, right?
Roll the dice.
Give him a new life.
Look at me.
You need to listen to, so you're
ready to see what happens.
You know the world does not understand
you when you return.
But they can see what
you have become.
They see ...
They see what they look like.
Check for all the hospitals?
Okay, thanks.
This was the third.
He was naked in the middle
of the street.
The taxi was driven over him.
He says there is no other.
No name, no papers.
She was probably raped.
He had a stitch marks on the hands and
wrist burning traces of tobacco.
He's just a kid.
Steven center, said he
saw something similar.
Hello.
I am a detective Valentin.
My name is Sofia.
What is your name?
You have traces of burning
on the wrist.
Do you remember how
you got them?
You can tell if you were a street girl.
I did not come to arrest you.
I came to help you.
Do you know this man?
Have you seen him before?
If something happened, if
you know something ...
Other lives are at stake.
You can help me to save them.
You will not be able
to save anyone.
He argues that the feeling of Moretti.
-Why did he conceal something?
Robert Moretti killed himself.
If you want to murder,
it is sufficient here.
In the case of a murderer,
why did not he been dead?
Both had burns in the same
place, as the characters.
Moretti was labeled number
one, he was number three.
She felt Robert Moretti.
Did he say so?
Let me tell you what it is.
You're tired, your partner has disappeared,
and the areas to be paranoid.
Do you see what is happening here?
People are afraid, Sofia.
Latest miss paranoid wild accusations
by the police.
Vuodit Moretti story the press-
and therefore we may find a pile of burning
junkies traces here and there.
I did not speak magazines.
-That 's enough.
We are talking about, when you have something useful.
Go home now.
Hold a public holiday.
Could you make a list during
the last week lost?
I look forward to.
Hey ...
Show me your hand.
Show me your hands.
What is that?
I have two.
How did you get those?
Now I get it.
We do not want to talk about
it, but because we are here.
It is unique, what unites us.
We were chosen because we were
trying to kill ourselves.
No, we are condemned.
We suffer so that we can
be cleansed of our sins.
Do you realize how
insane you are?
These damn idiots ...
I can not stand this anymore.
We condemn, Mark.
It is God's plan.
God? What happened to you? Tell your story.
I want to hear.
We are here together.
Come on, tell me now.
I've seen before God for
all believers sighted.
Something happened to them, and
they seek God all the answers.
Do you want to know why am I here?
Since I do not care anymore
about anything.
I've lost the ability to feel.
A month ago I got an alarm.
I was close to the house,
so I went there.
The door was open,
so I went inside.
And there he was, middle of the room
slaughtering knife in his hand.
He had broken in, stabbed the
mother and three children-
and put the bodies into the
ring the living room.
Then he turned to me and said:
"This is God's will."
God does not exist, Diane.
Not a plan.
Only you and your actions.
What has happened?
A car accident.
Parents and two daughters.
The oldest and the parents died.
The youngest is paralyzed
from the neck down.
How long has he been missing?
Three days.
Did he say anything
before leaving?
He was ...
worried about their work.
It is confidential, and I've
always respected it.
If you know something, it
can help in finding her.
He has been depressed for two years.
He is forced to leave.
He ordered too many drugs
for some patients.
Being investigated, and he
has not taken it well.
I ...
What, Mrs. Emmett?
I fear for him.
I'm afraid he hurt himself.
Can I keep this?
Please look for my husband.
Her children need her.
I'll try.
Do you think my nagging for fun?
I wonder what happened
to it last year?
Mark?
Take the computer lab.
These were found beside the bed.
Liquid antidepressants.
His office is a mark here,
the weapon is gone.
Can we have a minute?
Are you okay? -Yeah.
It's over. Go home.
We loved all of your father.
But I will allow a move here just because
you went to Mark the warranty.
He was like a father to you, but
the thing is you get too close.
You can not do this.
-You are no longer
my hommissani.
You closed my father's story before we had the answers.
Do not do it again.
Mark took the drugs and has disappeared.
Would you like to visit as well?
My father did not kill himself.
And how do you explain this?
Mark did not want to be snubbed,
and satuit face the thief.
Or do you not tell the whole story?
Go home.
Let me out!
What's going on?
What's happening?
-But you understand it, Zach.
Eksyneestä the case of a woman.
Eventually, death was
the only way out.
He made the impossible, was rejected by
his faith, and jumped off a bridge.
He sank into a river
full of remorse,
but hey, the story
ended, or what?
God would not let him die.
Not yet.
Someone rescued her.
But he was not fully rescued, as
he still made his death inside.
You're here because
you chose it.
Again can only be getting
a new life.
You must choose to face death and
see it in the eyes of another.
Who is really gone?
Who deserves a second life?
We do the opposite.
I can not respond to his death.
-It is part of God's plan.
How do I save him?
Tell me what to do.
They are one, and Zach is below
the surface for one minute.
Save him!
Dice INTENT
We tried.
This is a test.
You must not let this break you.
You did everything you could.
I had a daughter.
He was born ill.
Have you ever held a sick
child in your hands?
It does so painful, that
the heart is broken.
I heard my daughter's
painful cries ...
... I could not do anything.
He died in my arms
two years of age.
I I would die with him.
I'm sorry.
Your wife has been missing for
five days, and you notice now?
This is not the first time.
My wife often disappear-
and then appears as if
nothing had happened.
Sean!
Thank you.
He has escaped from
Sean's birth.
We suspect that he has been hijacked
by a very dangerous person.
All these data would be helpful.
He began to drink Sean is born.
He stopped studying.
We had money worries.
He began to play the fewest our money.
I do not know much
about his doings.
Do you have photographs of
Lisa, which I could take?
Thank you.
What's your name? -Jacob.
I no longer want to die, Jacob.
-It is no longer in your power.
You can not do this.
He did not want to die.
-I 'm here decided, it's you.
Not him. Not so.
I decided I did this, it's you.
The body is about six liters of blood.
Liter may be released
without danger.
Two liters of going into shock.
More than three liters
to know death.
If you throw four or more,
his body will die.
You were lost for more than two
liters, when I found you.
Not ... -Yes.
Is not it ironic.
You've got my blood, but still
I know you to be a part of me.
Open the box. -No ...
Roll the dice.
Give him a new life.
No, no ...
Give me a second chance.
-Our Father which
art in heaven ...
Stop, please.
No, I do not want! Please!
Good Lord, no!
For thine is the kingdom ...
Stop it! No!
Why did you have requested.
It was not easy.
Did you read this?
Crazy.
Re-birth, the dice according
to the will to live ...
Do you think the book of wet?
-I do not know.
What did you find the author?
-His name is Jacob Odessa.
Jonah's father built half of the city
and shot himself in the age of 60,
9-year-old Jacob's next.
He has toured in mental
hospitals all his life.
1995, he tried to kill himself and
ended up in a Roman hospital.
He got the name of patients' Jacob Odd.
" He wrote a book
in the hospital.
He returned in 2000, sold their
possessions and disappeared.
Sofia ... Be careful.
Yeah? -Did you get the book?
Who's there? -I am looking for.
See you at 4507 B
South Side Layer.
Come alone.
What are you doing?
-Give me yours.
Mark?
What are you doing, Mark?
-I am not going to
die like them.
I do not like this. No, Mark ...
Mark ...
No, Mark. You can not do this.
Look at me, Mark.
Do not do this, please.
Look at me!
Mark!
Do not do this, please.
-I 'm sorry, Lisa.
No! Good Lord!
Help him, somebody!
Hurry up!
Help him!
"When you have seen the
kind of what I" -
"Begin to live according
to their own rules."
Do not you?
Stay here.
Do not move.
You need to go.
Find a way out of here.
What are you gonna do?
-I have to stop this.
You have to get involved. Go.
This is over.
This is over, when
I say that it is.
You have to stop at the end of the search
and start looking for a new beginning.
Are you alone? -I.
Follows.
You control a nice man.
Here you do not get
a lot of guests.
You do not understand well enough what is happening.
You have not been warned enough.
I have lived here for three years.
I have not seen the light
of day in three years.
They are found everywhere watching us.
You will certainly feel them?
Who? -Sekopäät.
Religions have abandoned the people,
governments have betrayed
They are looking for some salvation.
-As the book?
It just does not take into account time of publication,
but it started something like:
Tests.
Studies in people who have decided
to discontinue life-
faced with the death of dice.
Surviving are completely, but
they never talk about it-
because they know the other observing.
-Who is the other?
The disciples, the survivors, joined the
cult, who live according to the dice.
So suicide is murder, the victims
of the experiments?
If you examine in more detail, you will
see that many had been marked.
Suicide is not just entertained.
People are dying constantly.
You were a part of this?
-Yes, I survived.
When I got back out, I tried to
expose it, to tell my story.
It then appeared to
be a good idea.
They are so desperate that doing
anything to protect him.
His disciples consider him a savior.
-Jacob Oddia? Jacob Odessaa?
Congratulations, you've
done your homework.
Her family built a half of the city.
He sold everything, except one.
The only place in the city in which
to decide the fate of the dice.
Are you one fails?
Of those who were floating
in rivers.
Which is found lifeless
and forgotten forever.
Or synnytkö again?
You told me once: "At my age a man
looks back searching for meaning."
We offer a purpose.
Opportunity to change lives,
starting with yourself.
Dice chose you.
You will be entered
in the sixes.
You get to choose from.
I'll make it easy for you.
It is the last choice ever.
Start a new life in
the old or die.
You have not thought about this the right way.
Otherwise, you know ...
... That I ...
... I fear more to life ...
... Than death.
You're not my father.
I knew that the Palais.
You killed him.
-No dead can not kill, Lisa.
They had their established lives of prisoners.
I gave the opportunity
to start over.
I have to go back.
Do you understand?
I need to get my life back.
You think you can come back to kill me?
This is not no turning back.
You've changed, reborn,
awakened to life.
What if I ask you to join me?
Give me a new life?
Rescue me, as I saved you?
Do not move!
Maybe not.
Please do not get your problem?
If you kill me, there is nothing to
hold you in the right direction.
Vajoat probably on
the bottom again.
I do not have to rescue you.
If I die ...
... You die.
Maybe we meet again in another life.
Maybe all is different.
Police!
Do not move!
Do not move and lower the gun!
Lisa?
Can you hear me? Danger is over.
Take him.
At my age ...
... Starts to look back ...
... And look for something
to be proud of.
Something which is supposed to.
I have looked behind me.
I do not see anything.
Eventually I will die alone.
ROME
Free yourself Start a new life
Tervetuloa.Aloitamme soon.
-Thank you.
Okay, kaikki.Aloittakaamme.
Thank you for coming.
I know how hard you had to
walk through that door.
It is proof that you are
willing to start over.
[StB] Releases 2011 SimplyTheBOSS
http://www.opensubtitles.org/
Preuzeto sa www.titlovi.com